(CLOCK TICKING)
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
(CLICKS, COMPUTER CHIRPS)
Hmm?
(MUTTERING)
(REPEATED CLICKING, COMPUTER CHIRPING)
(SIGHS)
(TRAIN CLACKING)
(LINE RINGING)
(OVER PHONE):
Hi. Todd Maher, eHarmony.
How can I help you today?
Hi. I can't seem
to leave a wink for someone.
I don't know, is my page broken?
Do I... do I maybe have
a broken page or...?
Oh, I've never heard
of that, but okay.
Uh, you're trying to use
your eHarmony account
for the first time?
I am.
Okay. Uh, I'm looking
at your profile.
We have a pretty intricate
matching algorithm.
That's what distinguishes us from
other online dating services.
Yeah, I like that.
Actually, I'm just trying
to leave a wink for one person.
Cheryl Melhoff?
She started in my division
at work about a month ago,
and I overheard her
near the bagels
saying she was on your site.
Uh, okay, that's unique,
but let me ask you,
you left a lot of this stuff,
like... like the "Been There,
Done That" section,
you left it blank.
Yeah, I think I skipped it.
Okay, well, you got
to help me out here, man.
Don't skip stuff.
Okay, well, I haven't
really been anywhere...
noteworthy or mentionable.
Have you...
have you done anything
noteworthy, mentionable?
(DOG BARKING)
Hello? You still there?
Can you hang on a second?
(TRAIN CLACKING)
(BARKING CONTINUES)
Oh, my God!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Go, go, go! Get out!
Get out! She's gonna blow!
Go! Go!
Chips!
Over here!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Chips!
Thank you! How'd you know
about the building?
I heard barking,
thought I smelled gas.
Oh, I hope it's okay.
I engineered a prosthesis for Chips while
I was sprinting down the stairwell.
Little hip-joint assembly
with a drop-ring lock
and an anterior pelvic band.
God, you're noteworthy.
I just live by the ABCs.
Adventurous, brave, creative.
TODD: That's everything
I want in a man.
TODD (OVER PHONE):
My man?
Hey, my man, you still there?
(SIGHS)
Hey.
What, did you pass out or...?
No, I just, like, zoned out
for a second.
Oh, okay.
Do you do that a lot?
Uh, a normal amount,
I guess.
Yeah... I, uh...
I got to run. Sorry.
O-Okay, but we...
we need a lot more...
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hey, bad day to be late.
We just got acquired.
What?
Yeah, over the weekend.
WOMAN: Walter, happy birthday!
(WHOOPING)
He's 42 years old!
Odessa, what are you doing here?
Mom made you your favorite
clementine cake.
Aren't you supposed to be at the retirement
place with her getting the piano moved in?
Yes, I was there.
It's, like, halfway done.
Piano is out of the van,
it's on the street.
Everything's fine,
but I just got a phone call
about a really big audition,
so can you go finish it?
No, I can't; I'm late.
Walter, I...
I don't think you're seeing this
from what I need.
What do you...
What do you need?
I need to be Rizzo in Grease.
I don't understand that.
My audition... Rizzo.
Rizzo?
Rizzo.
She's tough and tender.
Do me a favor, please.
Make sure Mom's piano gets
moved in all the way, all right?
Don't go to Rizzo.
Oh, thanks, Walter.
Happy birthday!
Guess what.
We just got acquired.
Yeah, I heard.
Yeah.
There's gonna be changes,
downsizing of us
into some kind
of dot-com thing possibly.
I wonder how
this thing goes down,
how the transition's
gonna play out.
I could probably tell you.
Ted Hendricks,
managing director
of the transition.
Hey. Tim Naughton, sales.
Gary Mannheim, graphic design.
And what do you do, cake man?
Oh, uh...
I, uh... (CHUCKLES)
I do the, um...
The cake's just for today.
I'm not a cake man.
I do, uh... I-I deal dirctly...
"Dirctly"?
directly with, uh,
LIFE's photo units...
I'm sorry, I was really getting
into this song.
I stopped listening to you.
♪ She'll only come out at night,
the lean and hungry type... ♪
I was saying, you know
who looks good in a beard?
Dumbledore, not you.
(LAUGHTER)
Guy...
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
Guy?
What do you do?
I'm a negative asset manager.
Worth the wait.
(BELL DINGS)
♪ Mind over matter... ♪
(TED CONTINUES SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Ted.
Donny.
You feeling tough?
Feeling good.
TED: Well, got to make
some tough calls ahead.
You've been here before, yeah?
TED:
Yeah, so this is it, huh?
DON:
Yeah, the house of pictures.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Hey.
Hi.
How was your weekend?
I...
I had an awesome weekend.
WOMAN: And what did you do
this weekend?
Um, let's see.
I bathed in Arctic mountain water
while my Latin lover
recited verse to me.
You slut.
I know.
Actually, I waited for my refrigerator
repairman who never came.
WOMAN:
I'm so sorry.
I'm gonna call you later.
Okay.
(SPANISH ACCENT):
The ice, yes?
She moves like a woman.
I'm Walter. Mitty.
Cheryl. Melhoff.
Where have you been?
Testing the limits
of the human spirit.
Hmm, I'd like to climb your hair,
test that out.
Perhaps I can contact you
possibly through
my poetry falcon.
Poetry falcon.
I like that.
(BIRD SCREECHING, PHONE RINGS)
Do you think if I hit him with
a paper clip, would he move?
Yeah, I don't know.
Do it. Oh, hello.
I actually threw
a toner box at him once.
Yeah? Did he move?
No, I-I missed.
That's a great story.
Ground control to Major Tom.
Can you hear me, Major Tom?
Oh.
Wow.
DON: Moving on, as they say.
TED: Yeah.
DON:
Uh, conference room,
uh, more of these stations here
where people sort of
do their thing.
Uh, layouts here for...
Morning, Hernando.
There's a new nut pouch.
Did you hear?
Uh, yeah.
I... met him.
We're gonna be evaluated.
They won't be able to.
We do intricate
details back here.
Yeah.
It's tricky and bewildering.
I should evaluate you;
you should evaluate me.
(CHUCKLES) I don't think
they'll let us do that.
Just saying.
Hey, how long has
this neg roll been here,
out in the open?
It's a Sean O'Connell.
It came in this morning.
There's a present, too.
He sent you a present
on your desk.
Sean O'Connell
still shoots on film.
That results for me
in a man crush.
Hey, you want to mount these?
Seriously?
Sure.
(CHUCKLES)
SEAN: Heard rumblings
LIFE's done, man.
Wanted to say thanks.
Take a look inside.
A gift for all the years
of hard work.
Sorry about the neg roll.
I spilled some blood on it while
self-stitching a gun wound to my abdomen,
but number 25 is my best ever.
The quintessence of LIFE,
I think.
I trust you'll get it
where it needs to go.
You always do.
What'd you get?
Um, it's a wallet.
With LIFE's motto on it.
Here you go.
Where's 25?
It's not there.
(KNOCKING)
Hey.
We need negative 25.
Sean O'Connell sent a telegram.
An actual telegram.
A 100-year-old dude came
in a little hat.
Uh, so there's a floor meeting.
Bring 25.
It-it's here somewhere.
We'll find it.
Okay, make a contact sheet
of these frames
as soon as you can, and don't
say anything to anyone.
Yeah.
I just wanted to inform you all,
uh, reluctantly, that...
I guess just start back
from the beginning.
(MAKES REWINDING NOISE)
Okay.
I just wanted to inform you all
reluctantly that, uh,
this month's issue
will be our last.
(CROWD MURMURING)
What?
Yeah, what?
That's some bull.
DON: Yeah.
Sad...
news for sure.
Now, you're all valued employees,
but as we undergo this transition
to, uh, LIFE Online,
we wanted to be candid
with you that, uh,
some of you will be determined
non-vital employees
to the new, uh...
the new partnership,
and we'll be deciding which of those
positions will be remaining with us
over the course of the next week.
Uh, also, we feel sad about that,
as you can see.
(GROANS)
Now, for some good news.
We are very excited for...
All right, Don.
Ted Hendricks, managing director
of the transition.
Never fun, this stage.
Uh-uh.
But we do have ahead of us
the privilege
of publishing what will be
the very last issue
of LIFE magazine.
(CLAPS)
And for the final issue,
we just received a telegram...
come on...
from Sean O'Connell,
who has never, I'm told,
been willing to speak
with the executives here.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, he broke his long silence
and shared his thoughts with us
through that... that old man.
Sean O'Connell.
"I expect full consideration
"of negative 25 for cover.
"My most grand,
the quintessence of LIFE."
The... what is that?
What-what is that?
It means, like, the fullest
and most rich.
Okay.
So our cover will probably
be the most famous ever
because it really will have the
big quintessence of all time.
Very full and so rich.
So let's see this thing, huh?
Let's see it.
Can we... What do we...
What am I doing up here?
What's going on?
We'll receive it now
from Negative Assets.
This gentleman here.
Negative Assets.
Last man in.
What's that?
Ah, Major Tom.
Can I, uh,
get that?
Uh, it's, uh, being processed.
All right, well, let's do it.
Let's process some quintessence.
Come on.
Go.
Now.
That's why I'm clapping.
Wait, when do we go to press?
Two and a half weeks.
CHERYL (WHISPERING): Please don't worry.
You're going to be fine, okay?
You've been here forever;
I'm sure he won't...
Don't worry, it's gonna be fine.
It was nice talking to you.
Well, guess I'll talk
to you later. Okay.
Hi.
I'm, uh, Walter.
Cheryl.
Mitty.
Melhoff.
Yes, You, uh...
you work in Photo Accounts,
right?
I do.
Negative Assets.
Yes. I'm...
Yeah.
Processing the last cover photo.
That's-that's a big deal.
Yeah, it's, uh... there's, uh...
We have a glitch.
Mini on that one right now.
I wanted to say to you,
do you maybe
have an address
for Sean O'Connell?
Um, it's not really
that easy with him.
He moves around so much.
I don't.
Yeah, he's on a freelance.
I don't know where,
and he doesn't have a phone.
No phone? He's old-school.
Yeah.
(CHUCKLES) Well...
Um, but, you know, um,
why don't I check with Peg?
I know she just processed
a check for him,
and we could track
his payout, maybe,
find him that way?
Cool.
Very cool.
Okay.
Okay. Walter.
Yes.
All right.
(BELL DINGS)
I'm on it.
Okay.
(CHUCKLES)
Thanks.
Yes, okay. Oh,
are you coming?
Yes, I'm not.
Yes, I have to stay.
Here's the contact sheet.
HERNANDO:
What do you see?
WALTER:
This photo cluster, these three,
they're the only printable ones.
He took them around
the same time he took 25.
They could give us a clue
to where Sean is.
Blow them up, all right?
Cool.
(BIRDS SINGING)
CHERYL:
Hey.
Walter, right?
Yeah.
So I called Peg about Sean.
She's gonna get back to me.
Oh, hey, thanks.
Cool glasses.
Very Sand People.
These? These are...
No, these are loupes.
They're for work.
They magnify the, uh...
Is that 25?
Can I see?
That's, uh, no.
I can't quite find 25
just now.
You can't find it?
Yeah, that's why
I'm trying to find Sean.
I'm trying to track him
down somehow
with, uh, these other images.
His whereabouts?
Yeah.
I take this class,
Writing the Mystery Novel.
Anyway, they say the key
is to work backwards.
You connect the clues and then
scatter them so they seem unrelated.
There's, like,
a whole science to it.
May I?
Sure.
Okay.
Thumb.
Yeah, it's a...
It's an unknown thumb.
Okay.
Uh, water?
Just water, I guess?
Yeah, just water.
Okay.
And, um...
like, a curved piece of...
some kind of part of a thing.
(CHUCKLES)
But, hey, you know,
the thing with clues, my teacher says,
is you really only need one good one
and then they'll connect,
and you'll be like,
"Oh, yes, of course,
unknown thumb, water.
I should've seen this
the whole time." Ah!
(LAUGHING)
Yeah, yeah, I'll be like,
like...
Well, anyway, I should get back
and try not to get fired.
Hey, Cheryl?
I have something creative
I've been working on, too.
Oh.
A little side project.
(PIGEONS COOING)
Walter, it's amazing.
Walter.
I was just saying I'll let you
know when I hear back from Peg.
Okay.
Thank you.
(CHUCKLES)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hey, Odessa.
What?
WALTER: Is there a larger
apartment available
the piano could fit in?
'Cause that's a memento
of our mom's.
That's a really big...
Most people sell their really big
mementos before they move here.
My dad bought it for her
the year they were married,
and it means a lot to her.
That's a villa.
It's a little more costly,
but it has a more generous,
piano kind of size living room
for you, though.
Yeah.
Yeah, this is good.
On move-in, you'd need first month's,
last month's and full deposit.
That's, uh, $4,700.
Great.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah, we'll take it.
I'll get the paperwork.
The new villa comes open
in three weeks.
I'm guessing.
Okay.
Happy birthday.
Stretch Armstrong!
Stretch Armstrong.
That's cool.
Yeah.
Isn't that awesome?
Wow.
This was your favorite thing
when we were little.
Do you remember?
Yeah.
You want to do it?
Uh, yeah, all right.
Come on, Stretch!
Good, good!
Okay, come on, we got to go.
WOMAN:
A villa, okay,
but hey,
I'm not the Queen of Sheba.
WALTER: You got to have room
for your piano.
You can stay at my place until it's ready.
Well, I won't be cramping your scene.
My scene? No.
Yeah.
And I'm sorry we couldn't
get you in here today.
ODESSA:
Walter!
Look what I found!
Th-This is from you
and Tim Linderman.
Did you remember,
we were gonna backpack Europe?
That June Dad died?
Man!
What is in here?
That's my Walter box,
so those are my
Walter knickknacks and keepsakes.
ODESSA:
Oh, you made the best mix tapes.
Oh, man.
What? What's that?
Travel journal Dad gave me.
ODESSA:
Oh, you should donate that...
because you never used
it... to a poor kid.
A poor kid who's
going to travel to Europe?
What...
Look at you
and your dad.
Is that my tournament one?
MOTHER:
He was so proud of this.
Sharing your accomplishments
with the whole world.
It's from the
Fairview Smalltowner, Mom.
Well, I really liked
that nifty Mohawk.
You know, when your daddy died,
and then you went
to work in that pizza place,
the one that was named
after a father...
had that father kind of name.
Papa John's.
Yeah. Delivery.
And I thought perhaps
that it-it was really sad
for you working in a restaurant
named after a father,
after your father just died.
I never even thought about that.
Probably 'cause I didn't
call Dad "Papa."
You had a weird style.
That wasn't my style.
That was a uniform... KFC.
Mmm. My worker bee.
(LAUGHING)
(CELL PHONE RINGTONE PLAYS)
Aw.
(LAUGHTER)
"Word in the water"?
Okay, you know what?
I got to go.
We're getting you
into a villa situation, okay?
Okay.
Good, everybody?
My worker bee
and my performance artist bee.
Aw, thank you, Mom.
(BELL DINGS)
Hernando.
Hey.
I don't see anything.
Upper middle.
It's faint.
There's a word in the water.
I'm getting nervous, Walter.
Hey, this is an ocean.
That's a boat.
"Erkigsnek."
He was near this boat.
(BELL DINGS)
See you in a few.
I'll check the mailroom.
Final cover.
Big responsibility.
Oh, is that my quintessence?
Uh, this is... No.
We're, um... we're prepping
the wetting agents
on that to start the process.
Really? Because it looks like
you're playing with toys.
Oh. No, this is, uh...
this is a gift.
Mmm.
Yeah, um,
the negative needs
to go through
a very technical...
I'm sorry.
I can't have a professional
conversation with you.
You and your little blond pal.
Okay.
Let's...
You can't walk through
the office with him, hmm?
Let's have it.
So I'll put it away.
Give me the toy, man.
No.
Now.
Hey!
This is a place
of business,
not a place
of jelly-man toys.
Get off it!
No, I'm taking it!
You can't just take my stuff.
It's mine! Give it to me!
No!
(GROANING)
Stop fiddling with sweets
and little men!
I'm trying to do my job!
(TED GRUNTS)
(TED YELLING)
(HORN HONKING)
(GRUNTS, YELLS)
(GRUNTS)
(HORN HONKS)
(TED LAUGHS, WALTER GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(TIRES SQUEAL)
(GRUNTS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(BELL DINGING)
Are you the Tin Man?
Need a little oilcan?
Jesus.
Picture.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
TODD (OVER PHONE):
Hey!
Hey.
What's up?
Um, who is this?
Todd, from eHarmony.
Oh. Hi.
Yeah, when I lost
you there, I was saying
we need to beef your profile up,
make it, you know, not blank.
Real quick, let's build
your "Been There, Done Thats."
Um, okay.
Uh, been there... um...
Phoenix.
I forgot why.
Uh, then, uh, Nashville,
but that was just the airport
on the way to Phoenix,
so I don't know if that...
Uh-huh. Well, hey, man,
I was thinking,
if you work with this girl,
why don't you just, you know,
humanly invite her out?
No, no, no, I'm...
I'm trying to do,
like, a "Piña Colada Song" thing.
Piña... "Piña Colada Song"?
Yeah, you know, a guy posts
an ad looking for a lover,
and then his wife answers it,
and turns out they were soul
mates and didn't even know it,
and they end up making love
in capes... or on a cape.
It-it's a song? Can you sing
a little bit, just...?
Uh, yeah, you know...
♪ If you like piña coladas ♪
♪ Gettin' caught
in the rain... ♪
You know that song?
Oh, I have to go.
Is that Hall & Oates?
Hey.
Is that another clue?
Yeah. This one's okay.
Yeah?
There's a boat there, I think.
"Er... kig..."
"Snek."
Erkigsnek?
Yeah.
Sounds like a real clue.
Yeah, it's the boat's name.
Hmm. Have you Googled it?
I was on my way to.
Oh.
Yeah. N-U.
That's the, uh, first two
letters of the port city.
Buffering.
(ELECTRONIC CHIMING)
So... the park.
I got to run up there
and pick up my son.
He's skateboarding with a friend.
Do you want to walk up with me?
Starting now?
Yeah, starting now.
Okay.
Yeah, we got to figure this out.
It's a big deal.
You lost a Sean O'Connell.
Yeah, I used to work at Nabisco.
And then I had
a... change,
and I decided to apply to LIFE.
Thought it would be
more colorful,
less regular, I guess.
You know, I just like
the idea of it.
Um, I like the motto
of the company.
Do you know it?
Uh, "To see the world..."
"Things dangerous to come to..."
"Things dangerous
to come to..." Yeah.
"To see behind walls..."
Yeah.
Yeah, I, um...
I got this from Sean.
He gave this to you?
Yeah.
I like that: "to draw closer."
So, what's he like in person?
Sean?
Yeah.
Uh, well, I haven't
actually met him.
I... I mean,
we talk a lot, but I've...
I've been his point guy here
ever since I started.
How long ago was that?
16 years.
16 years?
Oh, my gosh. Wow.
Well, you have nothing
to worry about.
With the layoffs, I mean.
I've been here for a month.
(CHUCKLES)
"Last in, first out," right?
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh, sorry.
It's Rich's dad.
Oh. It's your, uh...
Um...
Former... newly former.
But we've been sort
of... I don't know.
You know, I don't need to get it.
(LAUGHS)
So, what kind of skateboard
does your son have?
(LAUGHING):
Um, I have no idea.
It's oblong.
I don't know.
Why?
No, I just, um...
I used to...
I was kind of into the scene.
Like...
Oh.
The skateboard scene?
Yeah.
Wow.
Hi, Peg.
Yeah, Sean O'Connell.
We actually, uh,
need to find him.
Uh-huh. Yes.
If you could hurry.
Kickflip.
Yeah.
It's a good one
for the repertoire.
I'm Walter.
Rich.
Yeah, we think he might know
something or have an asset we need.
You know, you just got to get
a little more snap,
get that thing up there.
Want me to, uh,
show you something?
Sure.
Here.
Like your trucks.
Thanks.
Check this out.
Know about the flick?
Uh-huh.
Yeah, we-we-we've finished
processing his April work order.
Yes, it's kind of important.
Okay.
Did you forward the job 1090's?
Or his last salary?
Wow!
Okay.
Wow.
Here you go.
That was awesome.
So it could be either place.
Thanks, Walter.
Okay.
Thanks, Peg.
All right.
Hey. So, um...
Sean's definitely
not in New York.
Peg said she sent multiples.
I don't know if you know
how it works with him.
She sends copies 'cause we never
know where's he's going to be.
And this week, she sent 1090's
to Princeton, New Jersey.
Oh, great. Train ride.
And one to Greenland.
(CHUCKLING):
Just in case.
Greenland, the country?
That's, um... you can't take
a train there.
No. (CHUCKLES)
Well, maybe he's in Jersey.
Yeah.
Yeah, is your phone done
buffering with that ship's name?
Oh. Um, yes.
Look. Here it is.
Nuuk, Greenland.
That's...
Yeah. (LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
Come on, that's a good lead.
You should follow that up.
Yeah, follow it up in Greenland.
Yeah. Why not? Go.
Crack the case.
Listen to your wallet.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Sorry. It's my, um...
it's Phil again.
Um, maybe he fell
down a well or something.
Maybe I should get it.
Hey, buddy. Here.
Rich, Rich, Rich!
Not so fast. Here, here, here.
Take that. Take that.
Yeah.
I understand.
Okay.
Bye.
He did fall down a well.
But I don't care.
I just want to be with you,
you know?
Really?
Let's run away together.
Let's make every moment count,
starting now.
Sweet.
Can I tell you something?
Anything.
I have that
Benjamin Buttons thing.
Where you get old
but smaller or whatever
and become a gradual
old baby or something.
I didn't see the movie,
so I don't really know
how it works.
But I have it.
We can still build
a life together.
Cool.
I like your snappy little suit.
WALTER (WEAKLY):
I bought it at a doll store.
Oh, cool.
My little heart
is no bigger than a quarter,
but it's as full as Fort Knox.
You're the bravest man
I've ever known.
I love you, baby.
Not like "baby," like,
because you look
like a little weird baby-man.
I get it.
Thank you for such
a wonderful life.
You're... I...
Shh.
Just nestle in here and die.
(EXHALING)
Good-bye, Walter.
Bye! Walter!
CHERYL:
Walter.
Bye.
Oh. Sorry.
I was just...
Where do you go?
I-I started, uh, thinking about...
Oh, no, it's okay.
I was probably boring you
about my broken refrigerator.
No.
Rich!
My son's running into
the street. I-I have to go.
Yeah.
Oh, I wanted to tell you, um,
that song, "Major Tom,"
back there,
when the beard guy was...
he doesn't know
what he's talking about.
That song is about courage
and going into the unknown.
It's a cool song.
Rich!
Yo.
Where's my thing?
Oh, it's in a silver bath.
(STAMMERING)
I don't even know what language
you're speaking right now.
You know, you got to
take me seriously.
I got a magazine to execute here.
And bosses to answer to.
So next time I see you,
I see that picture. Okay?
Hey, dream machine.
Hello?
I just... I-I want proof
you heard me.
Next time I see you...
You see the picture.
(SNAPS FINGERS) That's right.
(SIGHS)
Any luck, Hernando?
I turned the place
upside down... 25's not here.
I searched Receiving, too, man.
This never happens.
I'm telling you,
it's nowhere, Walter.
I mean, maybe he didn't
even send it.
Maybe it's still on him.
Walter?
Walter!
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Something ♪
♪ Filled up ♪
♪ My heart ♪
♪ With nothing ♪
♪ Someone ♪
♪ Told me not to cry ♪
♪ Now that ♪
♪ I'm older ♪
♪ My heart's ♪
♪ Colder ♪
♪ And I can ♪
♪ See that it's a lie ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh... ♪
(MUSIC STOPS)
(AIRPLANE ENGINE WHIRRING)
Hi.
Do you have any cars available?
Yeah.
We have a blue one and a red one.
I'll take the red one.
(DOG BARKING)
(CREAKING)
(DOG CONTINUES BARKING IN DISTANCE)
MAN: ♪ You were working
as a waitress ♪
♪ In a cocktail bar ♪
♪ When I met you ♪
♪ I picked you out,
I shook you up ♪
♪ And turned you around ♪
♪ Turned you
into someone new... ♪
Hi.
Can I ask you...
Uh, could-could someone
receive mail here?
An American?
Sean O'Connell?
I think he might have
received mail at this address.
You want a drink?
Uh, okay, yeah.
I guess, uh...
♪ Oh, don't you want me? ♪
A small beer shoe.
So-so could somebody
get mail here?
Heli mail.
Heli mail?
We helicopter mail
to the ships when they pass by.
We are pub and helipad.
Yeah, wait, the, um,
the Erkigsnek?
Yeah, Erkigsnek.
Erkigsnek.
We flew mail to her Tuesday.
Gonna take it down a little here.
I just want to speak
from the heart.
I lost a good lady.
I feel this song is helping me
feel like I'm not alone.
Even though I-I pretty much am.
Come on, let's sing it.
Everyone.
Let's sing it together.
♪ Don't you want me, baby? ♪
So, do you know
who-who flies the mail out?
Do you know... do you have,
like, regular pilots or...?
Hey, man.
Just keep going, man.
Hey, I'm...
Sing it.
No, no, thank you.
I don't... I'm all right.
Oh, come on, man, go on.
That's...
♪ I was working
as a waitress... ♪
Yeah, I-I know.
I'm just, I'm okay.
Thank you.
I'm-I'm on a business trip.
I'm working.
Come on, man,
this song's important to me.
Uh...
Yeah.
Yeah, I... Okay.
Sing it.
♪ I was working as a waitress
in a cocktail bar ♪
♪ That much is true. ♪
Okay?
That sucked.
Well... Okay.
Do your work.
You don't have to push.
Oh.
Can you stop it? Don't poke me.
What if I poke you? What if...
Would you stop it?
Do your work, man.
Don't-don't poke me.
Do your work.
I'm poking you.
What am I doing? I'm poking you.
Stop, stop poking me.
Don't poke me!
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
BARTENDER: Hey!
Hey, stop!
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
Come on!
Wait! Wait!
Wait! Your thumb!
I have to talk to you
about your thumb!
(PANTING)
MAN: Yeah, I flew mail
out to the Erkigsnek Tuesday.
Gave him a ride.
He took that photo
of my hand on the stick.
I'm just...
blown away I located your thumb.
There's, like,
eight people in Greenland.
I mean, it's a...
(CHUCKLES) It's a good place
to find a thumb.
(SIGHS)
Don't cheat on your lady, man,
when you live in a country that
only has eight people in it,
by the way.
So, uh...
You're scrappy.
You're... (CHUCKLES)
You're a...
You're a little scrappy Duncan.
(LAUGHS)
So, you're trying
to find this guy.
Yes, yeah.
Yeah, well, I'm flying
some radio parts out there
in, uh, five minutes.
He may still be on the boat.
Really?
Yeah.
Maybe you could come with me.
Yeah, or maybe I could...
just, you know,
call him on the, uh,
on the boat phone.
The boat phone?
Yeah, the phone on the boat?
You mean the ship-to-shore?
Yeah, maybe I could just...
I could, you know,
I could ask him
on the ship-to-shore.
The radio's broke.
That's-that's why
I'm flying out there now.
Oh.
You're flying out right now?
Just gonna finish my beer.
The weather doesn't look so great.
It's not.
Looks like there's a
storm moving in.
Yeah.
A-brewin'.
You're just...
You're just gonna...
finish your beer
and then fly a machine?
Yeah, kind of...
I'm kind of nervous
about the storm.
I just want to get a coup...
a couple of beers down.
Okay, I'm not gonna go with you.
(BELCHES)
Okay?
Yeah.
Whatever.
See you, man.
Okay, see you.
Okay.
(SIGHS)
(DOG BARKING)
(BELLOWS)
Shut up!
(DOG BARKING)
(SIGHS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
CHERYL:
Hi. Hello, everyone.
Hi, uh...
Hello, Nuuk. (CHUCKLES)
Sorry, I'm a little nervous.
Okay.
This one goes out
to Walter Mitty.
He knows why.
(PLAYING DAVID BOWIE'S "SPACE ODDITY")
♪ Ground control to Major Tom ♪
♪ Take your protein pills ♪
♪ And put your helmet on ♪
(ENGINE STARTS)
DAVID BOWIE:
♪ Ten ♪
♪ Ground control to Major Tom ♪
♪ Nine, eight ♪
♪ Seven, six ♪
♪ Commencing countdown ♪ ♪ Five ♪
♪ Engines on ♪ ♪ Four ♪
♪ Three, two ♪
♪ Check ignition ♪ ♪ One ♪
♪ And may God's love be ♪
♪ Liftoff ♪
♪ With you... ♪
("SPACE ODDITY" BY DAVID BOWIE SWELLS)
♪ This is ground control
to Major Tom ♪
♪ You've really made the grade ♪
♪ And the papers want to know ♪
♪ Whose shirts you wear ♪
♪ Now it's time
to leave the capsule ♪
♪ If you dare ♪
♪ This is Major Tom
to ground control ♪
♪ I'm stepping through the door ♪
♪ And I'm floating
in a most peculiar way ♪
♪ And the stars look
very different ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ For here am I ♪
♪ Sitting in a tin can ♪
♪ Far ♪
♪ Above the world ♪
♪ Planet Earth is blue ♪
♪ And there's nothing
I can do... ♪
Hey.
Glad you came.
You comfortable?
What?!
Are you comfortable?!
No!
Hold on tight!
Hey! There she is!
Where do we land?
We don't.
What?
We don't land.
Okay, Walter.
Huh?
I was gonna drop the radio parts
into the boat.
You take them; they're
right next to you.
These?
Yeah.
Just jump in the boat.
You got them?
Just jump in the boat?
Yeah!
Yeah, you're doing great, Walter.
What do you mean,
"jump into the boat"?
What would be the best way
of reaching you to stay in touch?
Uh, I don't know.
Wait.
What do you mean,
"jump into the boat"?
It looks far away.
Yeah, but you got to go now.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
No!
No, no, no, Walter!
I meant the other boat.
The little boat.
(SHOUTING, GASPING)
Help!
(SAILORS SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGES)
Help! Help!
MAN (OVER SPEAKER):
Try to remain calm!
The pontoon boat
is coming for you.
You have at least a minute
before you freeze.
What?!
You're safe.
There's something here!
There's a fin here, I think!
We are traveling
through a porpoise school.
Don't fear the porpoise.
I don't think it's a porpoise!
I'm telling you, it's a porpoise.
Be friendly.
It will protect you
from the sharks.
Okay!
Come here.
Hey.
(SCREAMS) Jesus!
(SHOUTING) Okay, that's a shark.
That's what I said!
Jesus!
Stop befriending it!
Kill it!
It's not a porpoise!
MAN (OVER MEGAPHONE):
Poke his eyes out!
Fight it!
(GRUNTING)
(COUGHING)
Oh, my God, oh, my God.
That really happened.
Real face.
Sorry for palming your face.
I just... Oh, my God.
A pilot boat came.
They took him four hours ago.
Before the storm.
Took him where?
Iceland.
Is...
Is there any way
that we could radio him?
I... It's very important
that I discuss something
with him. I...
You jumped into the ocean
with our radio components.
They're lost.
Correct?
Yeah, that's correct.
(MAN SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(MUTTERING)
You're American?
Yeah.
Excellent.
Fonzie.
(CHUCKLES)
Come on, I'll-I'll find you
some dry clothing,
home slice.
(CREAKING)
Will this work for your items?
Oh, yeah.
Thank you.
Hey, I'll take this, buddy.
Okay.
Hungry?
Sure.
I got some kick-ass cake, man.
Oh, thank you.
Looking good.
You can keep it.
Hey, this is...
Is this...
This is clementine cake.
This is clementine cake;
my mom makes this.
Yeah, Sean brought it.
Yeah.
Good.
Is this Sean's?
Yeah, he wrapped the cake in it.
This is a shoot itinerary.
It's a field itinerary
for-for a photo...
Did he say anything
about where he was going?
No, he didn't say much.
He was just taking
pictures of these guys,
you know, the Chilean deckhands.
He even gave me some tips
for my Instagrams.
(SHUTTER CLICKS)
Facebook friends?
Yeah, sure.
Great.
What-what is... what is Eyjaf...
Eyjafallajokull?
Eyjafjallajokull.
Excuse me?
What is that?
Well, it's in Iceland.
It's a volcano.
A volcano?
Yeah.
May 2, that's tomorrow.
Do you think there's any way
that we could possibly land
in Iceland?
Yeah.
Yeah?
We have to in the morning.
Great.
'Cause you lost the radio.
Right, yeah, sorry.
I mean, sorry, but that's...
Well, I-I-I just have
to get to Ey...
Eyjafjallajokull.
Right. Eyja...
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(SIGHING):
Oh, man.
Hey, I'll see you
on Sesame Street, man.
Okay, you're here,
and this is Eyjafjallajokull.
It's, uh, 15 kilometers.
All right, okay.
You can take the shore bike,
but you better get going, man.
Yeah, he didn't write
a time on that clue paper.
No, man, hurry, because of...
What? I-I don't...
I don't understand.
What he means, man,
is you have to hurry
because there's a bunch of horny
Chileans who want to go to a strip club.
There's only one bike.
(HORN BLARING)
Hurry, Walter, hurry, run!
Go! Go!
(SHOUTING IN ICELANDIC)
Stay gold, Pony Boy!
♪ Hey! ♪
(MAN SHOUTING IN ICELANDIC)
(PANTING)
♪ Hey! ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ La la la la ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ooh. ♪
(PHONE RINGING)
(PANTING)
Hello?
TODD:
Hey, what's up?
Todd? From eHarmony?
Yeah, yeah, what's up, man?
Uh, not much.
How have you been?
Good.
It's, uh, it's early here.
I just got up, man.
I was thinking about you.
Where are you?
Los Angeles.
Hey, uh, so your profile
still hasn't received any winks
even though I put
that you've been to Phoenix.
Oh, I, uh, I jumped
out of a helicopter yesterday
into the ocean
and had a shark fight.
Yeah, yeah, listen,
I was mentioning before,
people who daydream too much,
they're not content...
No, it was real.
I really did.
Really?
I'll put down adrenaline junkie.
Well, what kind of a shark?
Was it like a...
Hey, Todd,
I can't really talk right now.
I'm on my way to a volcano.
What the...?
(BIRDS SCREECHING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(BLEATS)
(PANTING)
(SPEAKING ICELANDIC)
Hey. Hi.
Hey, you guys...
you guys speak English?
I'm looking for Eldgos Street.
Eldgos?
Uh...
Is that a street?
Is this Eyjafjallakuta?
Eyjafjallakuta?
Something like that?
(CHUCKLES)
Eyyafallakuta?
Eyyaflutakuta?
Eyftu...
It's a longboard.
Yeah.
Is that... What is that?
Is that, like, Thor or...?
Odin?
Like, a Norse god?
It's cool.
Hey, would you, uh...
Would you maybe want
to make a trade?
I know a kid who would
love that board.
(SPEAKING ICELANDIC)
It's cool.
Look, he stretches.
Here, come and check it out.
Yeah, he's fun.
Yeah, lots of stretching fun.
Want to do it?
(SPEAKING ICELANDIC)
Yeah?
Great, great, thank you.
(MAN AND WOMAN SHOUTING IN ICELANDIC)
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
Hello?
(MAN SHOUTING IN ICELANDIC)
Hi. Hi.
Hey, do you, uh...
do you speak English?
The hotel is closed.
(SPEAKING ICELANDIC)
Okay, yeah, um, I'm just...
I'm trying to find this guy,
this man, Sean O'Connell.
I think that he possibly,
he might have stayed here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I got a plane for him.
At 1:00, there.
15 minutes.
He's at airfield
in Stykkisholmur.
Yeah, yeah, in the valley,
next town south.
Okay, where is it?
Stykkisholmur.
Tickishoumer.
(SPEAKING ICELANDIC)
Is it straight down that way?
(SHOUTING IN ICELANDIC)
Okay, thank you!
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
It's all right! I know him!
(PANTING)
♪ Step in front
of a runaway train ♪
♪ Just to feel alive again ♪
♪ Pushing forward
through the night ♪
♪ Aching chest and blurry sight ♪
♪ It's so far, so far away ♪
♪ It's so far ♪
♪ So far away. ♪
(BIRD SQUAWKING)
(GRUNTS, PANTING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(CAR HORN HONKING)
(SHOUTING IN ICELANDIC)
What's going on?
Where is everybody?
Eldgos!
Come, Eldgos!
Eldgos. Eldgos.
Yes, yes!
What-what does that mean?
Eretion.
Eretion?
Erection.
Erection?
Yes! No!
(SCREAMS)
Eruption!
Eruption?
Yes.
(LOW RUMBLING)
(MAN SHOUTING IN ICELANDIC)
Sean.
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
Faster! Go faster!
Holy shit! Faster!
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
Oh, my God!
(ENGINE RATTLING)
(BRAKES SQUEAKING)
Thanks for coming back for me.
I really appreciate it.
I hope you find your man.
Thanks.
Yeah, there's a motel
near the pizza place there.
Good luck.
(CHILDREN PLAYING,
INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(LINE RINGING)
CHERYL:
Photographic Accounts.
Cheryl?
This is Cheryl Melhoff.
Hey, it's Walter. Mitty.
Hey, I walked down
to say hi to you
about an hour ago
and you weren't there.
That's 'cause... guess what.
I'm in Iceland.
Iceland?
Wait, w-wasn't it Greenland?
Yeah, yeah, it was.
(CHUCKLING): You know that
they're not the same place?
No, no, no,
I-I went to Greenland,
and then I got
on a fishing vessel
tracking Sean, and...
and ended up here in Iceland.
You're in Iceland.
Yeah, at a Papa John's.
Hey, I got more clues.
What-what did you find?
There's a date that Sean wrote
and some words on a cake wrapper.
"Rajqawee," "Buzkashi"
and, uh, "Warlocks."
Wait, they have
a Papa John's in Iceland?
Yeah, I just had to...
just left.
Did you get kicked out?
No, I just needed to leave.
Just the atmosphere
and the, uh...
cups.
Hey, I was right on Sean's trail.
Then I lost him.
Strong little man.
Thanks.
No. Rajqawees means
strong little man
in, like, 40 Arabic countries.
And Buzkashi is goat hockey
in Central Asia.
And, uh, "Warlocks..."
Yeah, um, I was hoping
they would connect.
Hmm.
So you said
that you left Papa John's
because of the cups?
Is there something I should
be aware of as a customer?
No, I just, uh, I worked there,
that's all. I just...
I used to have a Mohawk and, uh,
a backpack,
and I guess this idea
of who I wanted to be
and what I wanted to do.
And, uh...
Yeah?
Nothing, just...
Just, uh, I was pretty close
with my dad,
and he died when I was 17
on a Tuesday,
and we didn't have any savings,
so I got a haircut that Thursday,
and, uh, a job,
the same Thursday.
Papa John's?
Yeah.
Your dad let you have a Mohawk?
He shaved my head.
Oh, that's a good dad move.
Yeah.
Is it nice there?
Yeah, it is.
It's...
It's really beautiful.
Well, it's pretty sucky here.
Human Resources has already started
letting some of the staff go,
so it'll be a lot different
when you get back.
Hey, I picked
something up for, uh...
Oh, I think I lost you.
Oh, you know what, I'll catch
you up when I see you.
Great.
Okay, all right.
I'll... Okay.
Um, okay, bye, Walter.
Bye, Cheryl.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
What's going on?
MOVER: All the way in.
All the way to the back.
They shut down two floors.
Why do you look rugged?
I see you.
Hey! I see you!
What did I say?
I see you.
The photograph.
Now. Let me see it.
He looked it up.
There's no such thing
as a "silver bath."
Listen, there was uncertainty
about the negative.
I thought...
I understood that, hopefully,
it was in Iceland...
It was in your care!
If you just give me
some more time...
You're fired.
We'll make another cover.
Hey!
More than a million... way more...
negatives have come through my office.
I have never mislaid one.
Put it on a plaque.
Hang it at your next job.
Now I got to explain
this to the board?
ASSOCIATE: Yeah, I'm sure Sean
O'Connell will be thrilled.
Hey...
TED: Tell me again...
who is this guy?
You okay?
Yeah.
That's cool.
It's a skateboard.
It's for Cheryl's son.
Cheryl's not in.
She was let go.
I told you, man, it's bad.
Hey! That's my fern.
Thank you.
(DOORBELL CHIMES)
(DOG BARKING)
Hi.
Can I, uh...?
Yeah, is, um...
Is this, um...
I'm looking for Cheryl Melhoff.
You want Cheryl?
Yeah. She's, um...
We work together,
and she was, she was
helping me with a, um,
with a work thing that...
Cheryl?
Honey?
There's some guy here.
(DOG BARKING)
CHERYL: What?
CHERYL: Shh!
Bud, stop it.
PHIL:
From work.
CHERYL: Um, uh, okay, hold on.
I'm on the phone.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
ANDY RICHTER (ON TV):
It's Conan.
Tonight,
First Lady Michelle Obama,
Walter Mitty!
Can we... can we talk
about your love life?
I think people would be interested.
I don't think...
You don't want to know
about my love life.
(LAUGHTER, CHEERING)
I think they do.
Yeah, I think
they do. Yes.
Uh, now, I don't believe
everything I read.
There's a scandal?
Little...
little scandal?
A little scandal, yes. Uh...
She was back with her
husband or something...
then she fell for you?
You know, where there's smoke,
there's fire.
That's all I'm gonna say.
You're awesome, Walter.
Well, thanks. Hey, thanks.
Sure.
CONAN: I don't think
Can you turn this off?
You realize I am bumping
DRIVER: It stays on.
Dame Judi Dench 'cause I want
to talk to you more.
I'm just going to get out.
Hey, Mom.
Hi, honey.
Oh, Walter,
you gotta tip these guys.
We got the piano back safe, Mom.
You back from your work trip?
WALTER:
Yeah, this morning.
MOTHER:
Hungry?
WALTER:
Mm-hmm.
I'm making soup.
Thanks.
Hey, tipping time now.
(WHISPERS): Let's go.
This is all I got.
MOVER: Thank you.
Thank you very much.
ODESSA: All right, thanks, everybody.
For all your hard work.
MOVER:
Yeah. We appreciate it, ma'am.
ODESSA: You did great.
You just let yourself out.
He's good for this.
MOVER: What'd I tell you?
MOTHER: You gonna
stay for dinner?
ODESSA:
Oh, Mom, I'd love to.
I think I'm just really wiped out
after supervising moving
that thing all day.
I think I just need to go
to yoga and then just crash.
MOTHER:
What is it? A class?
Yeah, it's yoga.
It's a class.
I go to the hot kind,
where they heat the room.
Have you heard of that?
Mm. Sure.
You have?
It's good for you.
ODESSA:
Oh, It's great for you.
You just get it
all out of your system.
You just get all your sweat out,
you just get everything,
all your fear.
I'm waiting on a call
about an audition, and I just...
MOTHER:
Ooh, that Grease show?
Yeah.
Rizzo?
ODESSA: Yeah. I'm really
excited about it.
MOTHER: I haven't
even heard of that.
ODESSA: But I just
gotta get it... I just...
what's good about this is that
I just don't worry about it.
Just get out of my head.
MOTHER:
Is that good, too?
ODESSA: I feel like it's good
in a class like this.
I mean, I'm not going to get
paid for it, which is fine.
It's not about money.
Ah, wonderful.
And I feel like, you know,
it's just for kids,
but I think it's important
for them to start early.
I'm really thrilled, Mom.
You know, I think I'm just
going to enjoy it.
Just standing in front
of people and talking.
MOTHER: You'll be
good at that.
Yeah.
You'll really be good at that.
I think so, too, Mom.
Hey, Mom?
MOTHER: Yeah.
Did somebody take a picture
of your piano, like, a week ago?
MOTHER:
I did.
With Sean's camera.
Sean O'Connell's camera?
Yeah, he came to visit.
Mom, what?
Yeah.
He wanted to know about
your work schedule,
when you left,
when you came home.
He said you really
understood LIFE.
He was really interested
in your work.
You...
Mom, why didn't you tell me?
I told you.
I told you in the produce aisle.
I remember that.
Oh, maybe you were...
Odessa, what is it you call it
when he goes into
one of his little places?
Oh, zoned out.
You do that now and then.
MOTHER:
What's the matter?
I got fired.
I lost a picture of his.
Can you find it?
No, I don't know where he is.
He's some... someplace
with warlocks or...
Warlords.
No, warlocks.
No. Warlords.
Sean said he had to meet
with warlords very soon,
and maybe he would take my cake
so that he could get permission
to trek through
the wilds and places.
He said he wants to
photograph snow leopards.
How about that?
Who?
"Ungoverned Afghanistan."
MOTHER:
Mm-hmm. That's where Sean is.
Crazy Afghanistan.
Yeah.
In the upper Himalayas.
Mm-hmm.
They can't let you go.
You were Sean's partner.
He told me that you
were the person
who worked the hardest
to make sure his work was
realized the way he wished.
You finish his work.
(CHICKENS CLUCKING)
♪ Heaven is a switchboard
that you want to fight ♪
♪ She would even miss you
if you taught her sight ♪
♪ Power politician
leaning to the right ♪
♪ Baby's got a trust fund
that she'll want ♪
♪ To go off like that ♪
♪ Get off of my stack ♪
♪ Leave a little window ♪
♪ Now we wear same-colored
yellow uniforms ♪
♪ Sky is burning but at least
we know we're warm ♪
♪ Go and run yourself
a million miles ♪
♪ Hoping that the colors
run out ♪
♪ And you go off like that ♪
(CHEERING, LAUGHING)
♪ Get off of my stack ♪
♪ Stack. ♪
(WIND WHISTLING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hey, Todd.
TODD:
Hey, what's up?
Not much.
Hey, good news.
Your profile
really rounded out, man.
That-that volcano-shark combo.
That is money in the bank.
Get ready to get a lot of winks.
Okay.
But, um, something else.
Cheryl Melhoff...
uh, she's not on here anymore.
Withdrawn.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Hey, man, where are you now?
Himalayas.
(LAUGHING):
The Himalayas.
Oh, I love it.
Wait a minute...
that is a kick-ass "Been There."
Todd, I'm gonna keep this short.
I have to make oxygen choices.
Oh, hey, I get it. Go!
Anyway, you have a profile now.
Congratulations.
Cool, but... you know what?
Would you take me off?
I can't really
swing that $500 yearly.
MAN:
Hey.
Oh, um... well...
Hey, man.
You're sure?
'Cause I feel like
we're really onto something here.
TODD: I mean, this is...
Do you mind?
I'm working.
This is one of the best
profiles I've ever done, and...
and our refund policy, well,
you know, we don't have one...
Todd, I gotta go.
Sean.
Yeah.
It's... it's Walter.
Mitty.
Walter Mitty.
Seriously?
How the hell did you get up here?
I just, uh...
I've been looking for you.
Sit down.
I'll sit.
Well, take your time.
Settle in.
Try to be real still, okay?
There's a snow leopard.
Right in this ridge.
So we have to try to be
very, very, very, very still.
(WIND WHISTLING)
They call the snow leopard
the "ghost cat."
It never lets itself be seen.
Ghost cat?
Beautiful things don't
ask for attention.
Sean, there was a...
(PANTING)
negative that got
separated from your roll.
I'm taking a lot
of heat over it at work.
It never came with
the roll that you sent.
The last roll
you're talking about?
Yeah.
The 25.
You're sitting on it.
Why am I sitting on it?
It's in your wallet.
That was the gift.
The photograph.
The wallet was just something
I could put it in.
So I put it in a little slot,
the little picture
holder in there.
I thought it'd be cute.
I told you, "Look inside."
In the note.
You said, "Look inside."
I thought you meant,
I thought you meant
look inside
of the wrapping paper.
Yeah? Well, you got a real
nice surprise coming.
No, I don't have it.
I don't have it anymore.
Whoa.
(WIND WHISTLING)
What the hell were you thinking?
I mean, I-I'm sorry,
I've admired you
for a very long time,
but that is not
a good move, at all,
with a valuable negative.
Sorry, I just...
I-I thought it would be
a playful kind of thing.
Playful?
Too playful.
I see what you're saying.
With the cover, I should have
been more straightforward.
But can I ask you?
I mean, if you don't mind...
what did you do
with the wallet?
Chucked it.
Well, that hurts my feelings.
No... man, I liked it
very much.
I appreciated it very much.
So you threw it away?
I...
So you have no idea what it was.
The photograph.
It's a shame.
It was a beauty.
(MEN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
How'd you find me, anyway?
(DISTANT SHOUTING CONTINUES)
My mom.
Cool lady.
Knows how to bake.
Yeah.
Hey, why did you...?
Shh.
(WIND WHISTLING)
When are you gonna take it?
Sometimes I don't.
If I like a moment...
I mean, me, personally...
I don't like to have
the distraction of the camera.
I just want to stay... in it.
Stay in it?
Yeah, right there.
Right here.
Now it's gone. It's gone.
(SIGHS, SNIFFS)
(MEN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
That looks like fun.
I think I'm gonna jump in.
Hey, what-what was
the picture, Sean?
We're going to be odd-numbered
if you don't join.
What was the picture?
Let's just call it
a ghost cat, Walter Mitty.
♪ What's in your hand? ♪
♪ You're pinned down
to routines ♪
♪ Elevate and leave ♪
♪ A flickering screen ♪
♪ Where nothing is compromised ♪
♪ Nothing's lost ♪
♪ When everything is realized ♪
♪ Nothing's crossed. ♪
(JET ENGINES WHINING)
(WHEELS SCREECHING ONTO RUNWAY)
(ELECTRONIC CRACKLING, WHIRRING, BUZZING)
(DISTORTED, MUFFLED WHISTLING)
(DISTORTED HISSING, SPRAYING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(POWERING DOWN)
(DOOR CLANKS SHUT)
MAN:
You made the watch list.
How'd you get to Afghanistan?
There's a travel ban.
(SIGHS) Through Yemen.
Violent place.
That's why
the air fare's only $84.
Can I have my fife back?
Do you know
anyone in Los Angeles?
No.
Any acquaintances? Okay.
Any companions?
Anybody here
who might be able to verify
that you're Walter Mitty?
TODD:
Walter Mitty?
Yeah.
Todd Maher, eHarmony.
Hey.
(CHUCKLES) Thank you.
Thanks. I really...
What?
Come here, come here.
Oh, backpack. Ah!
Big hug! Oh!
Airport prison, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Tell me all about it
over a Cinnabon.
Come on, Cinnabon.
(CHUCKLES)
How long were you
detained for, by the way?
Like, 17 hours.
(CHUCKLES) Wow.
How's that Cinnabon taste?
Really great.
That's like...
That's frosted heroin.
That's what you're eating.
My friend, that's what you're
having right there, man.
It's good.
Mmm. By the way,
you got 300 winks
before I took down your profile.
Three... in, like,
the space of two hours.
It was crazy.
I thought I was selling
concert tickets.
I never checked.
Oh, because of the, uh,
the-the piña colada girl
that quit?
Yeah.
Yeah, Cheryl.
Cheryl, who...
did not respond to a single wink
the whole time she was on there.
That's a choosy lady.
♪ That's a choosy lady. ♪
How's the, uh,
daydreaming going?
Lately, less.
Good.
Less is good.
Thanks for the pastry.
Yeah, well, you owe me.
(CHUCKLES)
I'll send you a check
as soon as I sell the piano.
You have a lot on your plate.
What are you gonna do now?
Go out and get another job.
Boom.
I'm sorry, Walter, I just...
What?
You are so not
how I pictured you.
What-what?
How-how did you picture me?
I pictured you
as a little gray piece of paper,
but now I see you
and it's like Indiana Jones
decided to become
the lead singer of the Strokes
or something like that.
(CHUCKLES) It's nuts, I know.
Sorry, Mom.
What for?
Dad bought it for you.
It was my responsibility.
Oh, Walter.
We're all grown here.
We're all good.
(SIGHS)
Ooh, that's heavy-duty,
that sum.
You should put this
in your wallet.
I don't have one.
Oh.
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
Found it in the trash.
I always save your knickknacks.
(CHUCKLES)
Thanks.
Got it, Mom?
Got it.
Watch the stairs.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
TED:
I think this works.
Heart of America,
different generations,
this says it all.
Oh, hey, welcome.
Wait, I'm sorry, not welcome,
not an employee.
Sorry.
There's the picture
Sean wanted... 25.
You have two days
to print for cover.
There's your quintessence.
Hey.
Do you know our motto?
LIFE.
I'm lovin' it.
That's... no.
That's-that's McDonald's.
This thing that you do,
Ted, where you come into a place
and you push people out...
you should know
that those people
worked really hard
to build this magazine.
They believed in the motto.
And I get it,
you got your marching orders,
and you have to do
what you have to do,
but you don't have
to be such a dick.
Put that on a plaque
and hang it at your next job.
What was it?
Sasquatch? A unicorn?
The negative?
Yeah.
I didn't look.
(SCOFFS)
(CHUCKLES)
You were a good boss, Walter.
Thanks, man.
Thanks.
Hey, Walter, what's up?
Check this out.
(CHUCKLES)
See you!
Hi.
Walter Mitty, severance package.
(LAUGHTER, INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Hey!
Cheryl!
Hey.
Hey. Hey.
I got that e-mail
from Rich yesterday.
He's really good.
Walter, thank you.
That was... that...
that was just
a really cool thing to do.
I just saw it in Iceland.
He loves it, and I'm
taking him this afternoon.
Cool.
Hey, I wanted you to know
you weren't boring me.
That day in the park...
I-I was...
I was thinking about...
I hope this doesn't
sound weird, but...
I was thinking about you.
When I was in Greenland...
they do karaoke there,
and I had to get
on this helicopter
with a very drunk pilot,
and I started to imagine you
singing "Major Tom."
Anyway,
it got me on the helicopter,
and it just...
got me where I wanted to go.
So what happened to you?
You sort of fell
off the face of the earth there
for a little bit.
I came by, and I...
your husband answered,
so I figured I should just go.
Uh, Phil.
He was fixing my refrigerator,
and he's not my husband.
(CHUCKLES)
I guess I imagined that...
I thought maybe you
got back together.
You have a good imagination,
but no.
Hey, my sister got
this role in Grease.
Rizzo.
Not on Broadway;
in some weird church.
Do you want to go with me?
I made that sound
really not good, but...
Yeah.
Yeah?
Yeah, yeah.
I would love to.
Grease in a weird church?
You kidding? (CHUCKLES)
Rizzo, that's...
that's the best part.
Yeah, Rizzo.
(CHUCKLES) Tough and tender.
Yeah.
Great.
Are you, uh... are
you heading uptown?
Uh, uh, sure.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I actually always
related to Rizzo more.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Was it the, uh, smoking
and the teenage sex?
No, she was just real, I guess.
Oh.
The last issue,
it should be here.
It came out this morning.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Man, Walter.
Should we go buy one of those?
Yeah, I was probably gonna...
Probably gonna
go back later?
Yeah, yeah.
I just didn't want to seem
uncool and get one right away.
♪ There's a rhythm
in rush these days ♪
♪ Where the lights don't move
and the colors don't fade ♪
♪ Leaves you empty
with nothing but dreams ♪
♪ In a world gone shallow,
in a world gone mean ♪
♪ Sometimes there's things
a man cannot know ♪
♪ The gears won't turn
and the leaves won't grow ♪
♪ There's no place to run
and no gasoline ♪
♪ Engine won't turn
and the train won't leave ♪
♪ Engines won't turn
♪ I will stay with you tonight ♪
♪ Hold you close
till the morning light ♪
♪ In the morning
watch the new day rise ♪
♪ We'll do whatever
just to stay alive ♪
♪ Well, the way I feel
is the way I write ♪
♪ Racing like the thoughts
of a man who lies ♪
♪ There is a truth
and it's on our side ♪
♪ Dawn is coming,
open your eyes ♪
♪ Look into the sun
as the new days rise ♪
♪ And I will wait
for you tonight ♪
♪ You're here forever
and you're by my side ♪
♪ I've been waiting all my life ♪
♪ To feel your heart
as it's keeping time ♪
♪ We'll do whatever
just to stay alive ♪
♪ Dawn is coming,
open your eyes ♪
♪ Look into the sun
as the new days rise ♪
♪ There's a rhythm
in rush these days ♪
♪ Where the lights don't move
and the colors don't fade ♪
♪ Leaves you empty
with nothing but dreams ♪
♪ In a world gone shallow,
in a world gone mean ♪
♪ But there is a truth
and it's on our side ♪
♪ Dawn is coming,
open your eyes ♪
♪ Look into the sun
as the new days rise. ♪
(SONG ENDS)
(UP-TEMPO ROCK SONG BEGINS)
♪ Step outside,
gonna step outside ♪
♪ I'm gonna step out... ♪
♪ Step outside,
time to step outside ♪
♪ I'm gonna step outside,
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ House on fire,
leave it all behind you ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Dark as night,
let the lightning guide you ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ Step outside,
gonna step outside ♪
♪ I'm gonna step outside,
time to step outside ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ House on fire,
leave it all behind you ♪
♪ Living life ♪
♪ Feeding appetites ♪
♪ Stake through ♪
♪ Every heart stop in the mood ♪
♪ Being glad ♪
♪ Breathing appetite ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ House on fire,
leave it all behind you ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Dark as night,
let the lightning guide you ♪
♪ Step outside,
time to step outside ♪
♪ I'm gonna step out ♪
(GENTLE ACOUSTIC GUITAR
INTERLUDE)
♪ Broke tooth one day ♪
♪ Something's not the same ♪
♪ Blank head ♪
♪ Crossed eyes, sweep the floor ♪
♪ Feel your presence ♪
♪ In your absence ♪
♪ Shut the door ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ House on fire,
leave it all behind you ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Dark as night,
let the lightning guide you ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Step outside,
time to step outside ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Gonna step out ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ Step outside,
gonna step outside ♪
♪ I'm gonna step outside,
time to step outside ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ House on fire,
leave it all behind you ♪
♪ Step outside,
time to step outside ♪
♪ Better step outside,
♪ Better step out. ♪
(SONG ENDS)
(JAUNTY ACOUSTIC GUITAR TUNE PLAYS)
♪ You know I love my lady ♪
♪ We've been together so long ♪
♪ Like a worn-out recording ♪
♪ Of my favorite song ♪
♪ So while she
lay there sleeping ♪
♪ I read the paper in bed ♪
♪ And in the personal columns ♪
♪ There was this letter
that read ♪
♪ If you like piña coladas ♪
♪ Or getting caught in the rain ♪
♪ And the feel of the ocean ♪
♪ And the taste of champagne ♪
♪ If you like making love
at midnight ♪
♪ In the dunes of the cape ♪
♪ Then you're the lady
that I look for ♪
♪ Come with me and escape. ♪
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org