I, too, want my family safe.
Is our little prince uncomfortable?
Does he want his pillow fluffed?
Special treatment for the special boy!
Isn't that what you wanted?
[Lucy] You look like Mum.
Mum hasn't had a dress like this
since before the war.
We should bring her one back.
A whole trunk full!
If we ever get back.
I'm sorry I'm like that.
We used to have fun together, didn't we?
Yes. Before you got boring.
Oh, really?
[screaming, laughing]
- [growls]
- [screaming]
Please don't try to run.
- We're tired.
- And we prefer to kill you quickly.
[shouting]
- [horn sounding]
- Susan!
- [screaming]
- [snarling]
Get back!
Peter! Ah!
Come on.
We've already been through this before.
We both know you haven't got it in you.
Peter! Watch out!
- [growling]
- [snarling]
[roaring]
No! Stay your weapons.
This is Peter's battle.
You may think you're a king,
but you're going to die...
...like a dog!
- [Susan] Look out!
[both screaming] Peter!
[straining]
- [yelping, barking]
- After him.
He'll lead you to Edmund.
Peter.
Clean your sword.
Rise, Sir Peter Wolf's-Bane,
Knight of Narnia.
- [metal clanging]
- [indistinct chatter]
The minotaurs will take the left flanks.
We'll keep the giants in reserve
and send the dwarfs in first.
- [growling]
- [snarling]
- [yelping]
- [hooves stomping]
Ah!
The prisoner!
[moaning]
[breathing heavily]
[groans]
[Ginarrbrik] You're not
going to kill me?
Not yet.
[snorting]
We have work to do.
- [indistinct chatter]
- [horses whinny]
[gasps] Edmund!
What's done is done.
There is no need to speak to Edmund
about what is past.
Hello.
- Are you all right?
- I'm a little tired.
Get some sleep.
And Edmund...
...try not to wander off.
Narnia's not going
to run out of toast, Ed.
I'm sure they'll pack something up
for the journey back.
We're going home?
You are.
I promised Mum I'd keep you three safe.
But it doesn't mean
I can't stay behind and help.
But they need us.
All four of us.
Lucy, it's too dangerous.
You almost drowned!
Edmund was almost killed!
Which is why we have to stay.
I've seen what the White Witch can do.
And I've helped her do it.
And we can't leave these
people behind to suffer for it.
I suppose that's it then.
Where are you going?
To get in some practice.
[laughing]
[horse whinnies]
Come on, Ed! Sword point up,
like Oreius showed us.
- [Edmund] En garde!
- [Peter] Now block.
- [Edmund] Hey!
- [Mr. Beaver] Peter! Edmund!
- [whinnying]
- Whoa, horsie!
- My name is Philip.
- Oh.
[stammers] Sorry.
The Witch has demanded
a meeting with Aslan.
She's on her way here.
Jadis, the Queen of Narnia!
- [male voice #1] Go away, Witch!
- Empress of the Lone Islands!
[male voice #2] You don't belong here!
Go away!
[growling]
[crowd murmuring]
You have a traitor in your midst, Aslan.
His offense was not against you.
Have you forgotten the laws
upon which Narnia was built?
Do not cite the Deep Magic to me, Witch.
I was there when it was written.
Then you'll remember well
that every traitor belongs to me.
- His blood is my property.
- [swords unsheathing]
- Try and take him then.
- [grunting]
Do you really think that mere force
will deny me my right...
...little King?
Aslan knows that unless I have blood,
as the law demands,
all of Narnia will be overturned
and perish in fire and water.
That boy will die
- on the Stone Table...
- [crowd murmuring]
...as is tradition.
You dare not refuse me.
Enough.
I shall talk with you alone.
She has renounced her claim
on the Son of Adam's blood.
[cheering, applause]
How do I know your promise will be kept?
[roaring]
[cheering]
[crickets chirping]
[sighing]
[footsteps]
- Susan!
- Mm?
[horse whinnies]
Shouldn't you both be in bed?
We couldn't sleep.
Please, Aslan.
Couldn't we come with you?
I would be glad of the company
for a while.
Thank you.
It is time.
From here, I must go on alone.
But Aslan...
You have to trust me.
For this must be done.
Thank you, Susan.
Thank you, Lucy.
And farewell.
[sighs]
[squealing]
[howling]
[snarling]
[screeching]
[hissing]
Behold. The great lion.
[all laughing]
- [growling]
- [crowd yelling]
- [snorting]
- [cheering]
Do you want some milk?
Why doesn't he fight back?
- Bind him!
- [snorting]
Tie him up! Get him!
- [moaning]
- Wait!
Let him first be shaved.
[crowd cheering]
Bring him to me.
[howling]
[crowd silences]
[growling]
[howling]
You know, Aslan,
I'm a little disappointed in you.
Did you honestly think by all this
that you could save the human traitor?
You are giving me your life
and saving no one.
[chuckles]
So much for love.
[cheering, grunting]
Tonight...
...the Deep Magic will be appeased!
[cheering]
But tomorrow,
we will take Narnia
- forever!
- [cheering]
In that knowledge,
despair...
...and die!
- [grunts]
- [gasps]
[groaning]
[both sobbing]
[crowd cheering]
The Great Cat...
...is dead!
- [cheering]
[howling]
- General.
- [snorting]
- Prepare your troops for battle.
- [grunting]
[roaring]
However short it may be.
[distant howling]
It's too late.
He's gone.
He must have known what he was doing.
[squeaking]
Get away! Get away, all of you!
No. Look.
We have to tell the others.
- We can't just leave him!
- Lucy, there's no time.
They need to know.
The trees.
[rustling]
[grunting]
Be still, my Princes.
I bring grave news from your sisters.
[indistinct chatter]
She's right.
He's gone.
Then you'll have to lead us.
Peter, there's an army out there
and it's ready to follow you.
- I can't.
- Aslan believed you could.
And so do I.
The Witch's army is nearing, sire.
What are your orders?
[screeching]
They come, Your Highness, in numbers
and weapons far greater than our own.
Numbers do not win a battle.
No. But I bet they help.
[growling]
[roaring]
[horn sounds]
[cheering]
I have no interest in prisoners.
Kill them all.
- [roaring]
- Ahh!
- [screeching]
- Go on!
Look to the sky!
- [grunting]
- [screaming]
[screeching]
Are you with me?
To the death.
For Narnia and for Aslan!
Go!
Go! For Aslan!
- [whinnies]
- [growls]
[roaring]
[snarling]
[noise silences]
[noise resumes]
[birds chirping]
We should go.
I'm so cold.
[wind howling]
- [rumbling]
- Ah!
Susan!
Where's Aslan?
What have they done?
[both] Aslan!
[Aslan chuckles]
But we saw the knife. The Witch.
If the Witch knew
the true meaning of sacrifice,
she might have interpreted
the Deep Magic differently.
That when a willing victim
who has committed no treachery
is killed in a traitor's stead,
the Stone Table will crack
and even death itself
will turn backwards.
We sent the news that you were dead.
Peter and Edmund will have gone to war.
We have to help them.
We will, dear one, but not alone.
Climb on my back.
We have far to go
and little time to get there.
And you may want to cover your ears.
[roaring]
[grunting, roaring]
Fire!
Yes!
Fall back! Draw them to the rocks!
- [horn sounds]
- That's the signal. Come on!
Where are we going?
Hang on!
Fall back!
Go on, fall back!
- [whinnying]
- [grunting]
[grunting]
Stop!
[groaning]
[shouting]
[sobbing]
[blowing]
[heartbeats]
[cracking]
[Tumnus groaning]
[Tumnus gasping]
[laughing]
Susan, this is...
- Mr. Tumnus!
- [gasps]
Come, we must hurry
and search the castle.
Peter will need everyone we can find.
Ah!
[screeching]
Edmund! There's too many!
Get out of here!
Get the girls and get them home!
You heard him! Let's go!
[roaring]
Peter said get out of here!
Peter's not king yet.
[yelling]
[gasps]
[silence]
[groaning]
Ah!
[roaring]
lmpossible!
Ah!
It is finished.
- [Susan] Peter!
- [Lucy] Peter!
Where's Edmund?
[gasping]
- Edmund!
- [gasps]
Ah!
[coughing]
When are you gonna learn
to do as you're told?
[blowing]
[laughing]
[horns sounding]
To the glistening Eastern Sea,
I give you Queen Lucy the Valiant.
[Aslan] To the great Western Wood,
King Edmund the Just.
To the radiant Southern Sun,
Queen Susan, the Gentle.
And to the clear Northern Sky,
I give you King Peter,
the Magnificent.
Once a King or Queen of Narnia,
always a King or Queen.
May your wisdom grace us
until the stars rain down
from the heavens.
[all] Long live King Peter!
Long live King Edmund!
Long live Queen Susan!
Long live Queen Lucy!
[cheering]
[Tumnus] Don't worry.
We'll see him again.
- When?
- In time.
One day he'll be here
and the next he won't.
But you mustn't press him.
After all, he's not a tame lion.
No.
But he is good.
Here.
You need it more than I do.
[breathing heavily]
Are you all right, Philip?
I'm not as young as I once was.
[horse whinnies]
Come on, Ed.
- Just catching my breath.
- That's all we'll catch at this rate.
- What did he say, Susan?
- "Wait in the castle.
- I'll get the stag myself."
- [chuckling]
What's this?
It seems familiar.
As if from a dream.
Or a dream of a dream.
Spare Oom.
- Lucy!
- Not again.
- [Peter] Lu?
- Come on!
These aren't branches.
[Edmund] Ow! Ooh!
- They're coats.
- [Edmund] Susan, you're on my foot!
[Lucy] Peter, move off!
- [Peter] Stop shoving.
- [Edmund] Stop it!
I'm not on your toe!
[all grunting]
[Kirke] Oh!
There you are.
What were you all
doing in the wardrobe?
You wouldn't believe us
if we told you, sir.
Try me.
[Kirke] I don't think
you'll get back in that way.
You see... I've already tried.
Will we ever go back?
Oh, I expect so.
But it'll probably happen
when you're not looking for it.
All the same...
[whispers] best to keep your eyes open.
[Aslan roars]