The Lion King (1994) - 23.976 fps (Subs for Hard at Hearing)
[Jungle sounds]
[Lion roars]
MAN: * Nants ingonyama *
* Bagithi baba *
CHORUS:
* Sithi uhhmm ingonyama *
* Ingonyama *
* Nants ingonyama *
* Bagithi baba *
* Sithi uhhmm ingonyama *
* Ingonyama *
* Siyo nqoba *
* Ingonyama
nengw' enamabala *
* Se-to-kwa *
* Ingonyama
nengw' enamabala *
* Asana *
* Ingonyama
nengw' enamabala *
* Se-to-kwa *
* Ingonyama
nengw' enamabala *
WOMAN: * From the day
we arrive *
* On the planet *
* And, blinking,
step into the sun *
* Ingonyama
nengw' enamabala *
* There's more to see *
* Than can ever be seen *
* More to do *
* Than can ever be done *
* There's far too much *
* To take in here *
* More to find *
* Than can ever be found *
[Squawking]
* But the sun rolling high *
* Through
the sapphire sky *
* Keeps great and small *
* On the endless round *
* It's the circle of life *
* And it moves us all *
* Through despair and hope *
* Through faith and love *
* Till we find our place *
* On the path unwinding *
* In the circle *
* The circle of life *
[Purring]
[Rattling]
[Crack]
[Sneezes]
* Ingonyama
nengw' enamabala *
* Se-to-kwa *
* Ingonyama
nengw' enamabala *
* Se-to-kwa *
* Ingonyama
nengw' enamabala *
* It's the circle of life *
[Trumpet]
* And it moves us all *
[Screeching]
[Yelping]
* Through despair and hope *
* Through faith and love *
* Till we find our place *
* On the path unwinding *
* In the circle *
* The circle of life *
[Drum beat]
[Squeaking]
[Sniffs]
[Thump]
[Squeaking]
Life's not fair, is it?
You see, I...
Well, I shall never be king.
Heh heh.
And you shall never see
the light of another day.
[Chuckles] Adieu.
Didn't your mother tell you
not to play with your food?
What do you want?
I'm here to announce
that King Mufasa's on his way.
So you'd better have
a good excuse...
for missing the ceremony
this morning.
Oh, now, look, Zazu.
You've made me lose my lunch.
Ha! You'll lose
more than that...
when the king
gets through with you.
He's as mad as
a hippo with a hernia.
Oooh. I quiver with fear!
Now, Scar,
don't look at me that way.
Help!
- Scar?
- Mm-hmm? Hmm?
Drop him.
Impeccable timing, Your Majesty.
Ptoo!
Ugh.
Why, if it isn't
my big brother...
descending from on high
to mingle with the commoners.
Sarabi and I didn't see you
at the presentation of Simba.
That was today?
Ohh, I feel simply awful!
[Screeching]
Must've slipped my mind.
Yes, well, as slippery
as your mind is...
as the king's brother...
you should've been
first in line!
[Snap]
SCAR:
Well, I was first in line...
until the little hairball
was born.
That hairball is my son...
and your future king.
I shall practice my curtsy.
Don't turn
your back on me, Scar.
Oh, no, Mufasa.
Perhaps you shouldn't
turn your back on me.
[Roars]
Is that a challenge?
Temper, temper.
I wouldn't dream
of challenging you.
Pity. Why not?
As far as brains go,
I got the lion's share.
But when it comes
to brute strength...
I'm afraid
I'm at the shallow end...
of the gene pool.
[Sighs] There's one
in every family, sire.
Two in mine, actually,
and they always manage...
to ruin special occasions.
What am I going to do with him?
He'd make
a very handsome throw rug.
Zazu!
And just think,
whenever he gets dirty...
you could take him out
and beat him.
[Mufasa chuckles]
[Dramatic music playing]
[Chorus singing]
[Music swells]
[Thunder]
[Muttering]
Hmm. [Laughs]
Simba.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Dad! Dad!
Come on, Dad,
we gotta go! Wake up
- Uhh!
- Sorry.
[Snoring]
Dad. Dad.
Your son is awake.
SIMBA: Dad, Dad, Dad...
Before sunrise, he's your son.
Dad! Come on, Dad.
Uhh! Uhh! Dad!
[Crash] Whoa!
Uhh! You promised.
- OK, OK. I'm up.
- Yeah!
[Yawn echoes]
MUFASA: Look, Simba.
Everything the light touches
is our kingdom.
SIMBA: Wow.
MUFASA:
A king's time as ruler...
rises and falls like the sun.
One day, Simba, the sun
will set on my time here...
and will rise
with you as the new king.
- And this'll all be mine?
- Everything.
Everything the light touches.
What about that shadowy place?
That's beyond our borders.
You must never go there, Simba.
But I thought a king
can do whatever he wants.
There's more to being king...
than getting your way
all the time.
- There's more?
- Ha ha. Simba...
[Dramatic music playing]
MUFASA: Everything you see
exists together...
in a delicate balance.
As king, you need
to understand that balance...
and respect
all the creatures...
from the crawling ant
to the leaping antelope.
But, Dad,
don't we eat the antelope?
Yes, Simba,
but let me explain.
When we die,
our bodies become the grass...
and the antelope eat the grass.
And so we are all connected...
in the great circle of life.
- Good morning, sire!
- Good morning, Zazu.
Checking in
with the morning report.
Fire away.
- What are you doing, son?
- Pouncing
Let an old pro show you
how it's done.
Stay low to the ground.
[Whispering] Yeah, OK.
Shhh... Not a sound.
Take it slow. One more step...
... then...
Aah!
[Laughs]
That's very good.
- Zazu!
- Yes!
Sir!
News from the underground.
Now, this time...
Sire!
Hyenas in the pride lands!
Zazu, take Simba home.
- Dad, can't I come?
- No, son.
[Sighs]
I never get to go anywhere.
Oh, young master, one day,
you will be king.
Then you can chase
those slobbering, mangy...
stupid poachers
from dawn until dusk.
Hey, Uncle Scar! Guess what?
I despise guessing games.
I'm gonna be king of Pride Rock.
Oh, goody.
My dad just showed me
the whole kingdom...
and I'm gonna rule it all.
Heh heh!
Yes, well, forgive me
for not leaping for joy.
Bad back, you know.
[Thump]
Hey, Uncle Scar.
When I'm king...
what'll that make you?
A monkey's uncle.
Ha ha ha!
You're so weird.
You have no idea.
So, your father showed you
the whole kingdom, did he?
Everything.
He didn't show you
what's beyond that rise...
at the northern border?
Well, no.
He said I can't go there.
And he's absolutely right.
It's far too dangerous.
Only the bravest lions go there.
Well, I'm brave.
What's out there...
I'm sorry, Simba,
I just can't tell you.
Why not?
Simba, Simba,
I'm only looking out...
for the well-being
of my favorite nephew.
[Scoffs] Yeah, right.
I'm your only nephew.
All the more reason
for me to be protective.
An elephant graveyard
is no place...
for a young prince. Oops!
An elephant what? Whoa!
Oh, dear, I've said too much.
Well, I suppose you'd have
found out sooner or later...
you being so clever and all.
Just do me one favor.
Promise me you'll never visit
that dreadful place.
- No problem.
- There's a good lad.
You run along now
and have fun.
And remember,
it's our little secret.
[Upbeat music playing]
- Hey, Nala.
- Hi, Simba.
Come on. I just heard
about this great place.
Simba! I'm kinda
in the middle of a bath.
SARABI:
And it's time for yours.
Mom!
Mom, you're messing up
my mane!
OK, I'm clean.
Can we go now?
Where are we going?
It better not be anyplace dumb.
No, it's really cool.
So, where is
this really cool place?
Oh. Around the water hole.
The water hole?
What's so great
about the water hole?
I'll show you when we get there.
Oh. Mom, can I go with Simba?
What do you think, Sarabi?
Well...
- Please.
It's all right with me.
- All right!
- Yeah!
As long as Zazu
goes with you.
No, not Zazu.
ZAZU: Step lively.
The sooner we get
to the water hole...
the sooner we can leave.
So, where are we really going?
- An elephant graveyard.
- Wow!
Shh! Zazu.
Right. So how are we
gonna ditch the dodo?
ZAZU:
Oh, just look at you two.
Little seeds of romance
blossoming in the savannah.
Your parents
will be thrilled...
what with your
being betrothed and all.
- Being what?
- Betrothed. Intended.
Affianced.
Meaning...?
One day, you two are going
to be married.
- Yuck!
- Eww!
I can't marry her.
She's my friend.
Yeah, it'd be so weird.
Sorry to bust your bubble...
but you two turtledoves
have no choice.
It's a tradition
going back generations.
When I'm king, that'll be
the first thing to go.
Not so long as I'm around.
In that case, you're fired.
Nice try.
But only the king can do that.
Well, he's the future king.
Yeah, so you have to
do what I tell you.
Not yet, I don't.
And with an attitude
like that...
I'm afraid
you're shaping up to be...
a pretty pathetic king
indeed.
Heh. Not the way I see it.
* I'm gonna be
a mighty king *
* So enemies beware *
* Well, I've never seen
a king of beasts *
* With quite so little hair *
[Doink]
* I'm gonna be the main event *
* Like no king was before *
* I'm brushin' up
on lookin' down *
* I'm workin' on my roar *
Thus far,
a rather uninspiring thing.
Aaaah!
SIMBA: * Oh, I just
can't wait to be king *
You've rather a long way to go,
young master...
if you think...
* No one sayin' "Do this"*
Now, when I said that...
* No one sayin', "Be there"*
What I meant was...
* No one sayin' "Stop that"*
But what you don't realize...
* No one sayin', "See here"*
Now, see here!
SIMBA: * Free to run around
all day *
Well, that's definitely out.
* Free to do it all my way *
* I think it's time
that you and I *
* Arranged
a heart-to-heart *
SIMBA:
* Kings don't need advice *
* From little hornbills
for a start *
* If this is where
the monarchy is headed *
* Count me out *
* Out of service,
out of Africa *
* I wouldn't hang about *
Aah!
* This child is getting
wildly out of wing *
SIMBA: * Oh, I just
can't wait to be king *
[Thud]
* Everybody, look left *
[Gasps]
* Everybody, look right *
* Everywhere you look,
I'm *
* Standing
in the spotlight *
Not yet!
CHORUS: * Let every creature
go for broke and sing *
* Let's hear it in the herd
and on the wing *
* It's gonna be
King Simba's finest fling *
ALL: * Oh, I just
can't wait to be king *
* Oh, I just can't wait
to be king *
* Oh, I just can't wait *
[Trumpet]
* To be king *
[Boing] [Trumpets]
[Knees knocking]
[Thud]
[Song ends]
ZAZU, MUFFLED:
I beg your pardon, madam...
but... get off!
Simba? Nala!
[Laughing]
All right! It worked!
- We lost him.
- I am a genius.
Hey, genius, it was my idea.
Yeah, but I pulled it off.
- With me!
- Oh, yeah?
Raar!
- Ha!
- Uhh!
- Pinned ya.
- Hey, let me up.
Raar!
[Laughing]
- Uhh!
- Pinned ya again.
[Rumbling]
This is it. We made it.
- Whoa.
[Birds squawking]
NALA: It's really creepy
Yeah. Isn't it great?
- We could get in big trouble.
- I know. Ha!
I wonder if its brains
are still in there.
There's only one way to know.
Come on,
let's go check it out.
Wrong! The only
checking out you will do...
will be to check out of here.
Oh, man!
We're way beyond the boundary
of the pride lands.
Look. Banana Beak is scared.
It's Mr. Banana Beak
to you, fuzzy...
and right now we are all
in very real danger.
Danger? Ha!
I walk on the wide side.
I laugh in the face
of danger.
Ha ha ha ha!
[Laughter] Huh?
[Laughing]
Well, well, well, Banzai,
what have we got here?
I don't know, Shenzi.
What do you think, Ed?
[Crazy laughter]
Just what I was thinkin'.
A trio of trespassers!
And quite by accident,
let me assure you.
A simple navigational error.
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait, wait.
I know you.
You're Mufasa's little stooge.
I, madam,
am the king's major-domo.
- And that would make you...
- The future king.
Do you know what we do to kings
who step out of their kingdom?
[Scoffs]
You can't do anything to me.
Heh heh.
Technically, they can.
We are on their land.
But, Zazu, you told me
they're nothin'...
but slobbering, mangy,
stupid poachers.
Lx-nay on the upid-stay.
Who are you callin' upid-stay?
My, my, my. Look at the sun!
It's time to go!
What's the hurry?
We'd love you to stick
around for dinner.
Yeah, we could have
whatever's... lion around!
Wait, wait, wait,
I got one, I got one!
Make mine a cub sandwich!
What'd you think?
[Laughter]
[Grunting]
What, Ed? What is it?
Hey, did we order
this dinner to go?
No, why?
BANZAI:
'Cause there it goes!
[Panting]
[Squawks]
NALA: Did we lose 'em?
SIMBA: I think so.
Where's Zazu?
The little major-domo bird
hippety-hopped...
all the way
to the birdie-boiler.
Oh, no!
Not the birdie-boiler!
Aaaah!
[Laughing]
Hey, why don't you pick on
somebody your own size?
- Like you?
- Oops.
[Chomp]
Aaah!
ALL: Boo!
[Laughing]
[Growling]
[Dramatic music playing]
Aah!
SIMBA:
Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh-uh-uh!
Aaah! Uhh!
[Hyenas snarling]
NALA: Simba!
Aah!
[Bones clatter]
Rraar... Uhh! [Snarls]
[Panting]
- Uhh!
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
Rraar! Rraar! Rraar!
Heh! That was it?
[All laugh]
Do it again. Come on.
[Loud roar]
ALL: Huh?
[Roaring]
Oh, please, please!
Uncle, uncle!
- Silence!
- We're gonna shut up right now!
Calm down.
We're really sorry.
If you ever come
near my son again...
Oh, this is your son?
- Oh, your son?
- Did you know that?
No. Me? I didn't know...
No, did you?
- No, of course not.
- No.
- Ed?
[Rattling]
[Roars]
Heh heh. Toodles.
[Barking]
Dad, l...
You deliberately disobeyed me.
Dad, I'm sorry.
Let's go home.
I thought you were very brave.
[Dramatic music playing]
MUFASA: Zazu.
- Yes, sire?
- Take Nala home.
I've got to teach
my son a lesson.
Come, Nala.
Simba...
[Sighs] Good luck.
Simba! [Echoes]
[Dramatic music playing]
Simba,
I'm very disappointed in you.
- I know.
- You could've been killed.
You deliberately
disobeyed me...
and what's worse,
you put Nala in danger.
I was just trying to be brave,
like you.
I'm only brave
when I have to be.
Simba, being brave...
doesn't mean
you go looking for trouble.
But you're not scared
of anything.
I was today.
- You were?
- Yes.
I thought I might lose you.
Oh. I guess even
kings get scared, huh?
Mm-hmm.
- But you know what?
- What?
I think those hyenas
were even scareder.
[Laughs]
'Cause nobody
messes with your dad.
- Come here, you.
- Oh, no! No!
Aah! Rrr! Uhh!
Aah! Come here!
[Both laughing]
Gotcha!
[Panting]
- Dad?
- Hmm?
We're pals, right?
Heh heh. Right.
And we'll always
be together, right?
Simba, let me
tell you something...
that my father told me.
Look at the stars.
The great kings
of the past...
look down on us
from those stars.
- Really?
- Yes.
So, whenever
you feel alone...
just remember
that those kings...
will always be there
to guide you...
and so will I.
BANZAI:
Man, that lousy Mufasa.
I won't be able
to sit for a week.
[Ed laughing]
It's not funny, Ed.
[Laughing hysterically]
Hey, shut up!
[Laughing]
[Snarling]
[Barking]
Will you knock it off?
[Yelps]
Well, he started it.
SHENZI: Look at you guys.
No wonder we're dangling...
at the bottom
of the food chain.
Man, I hate dangling.
Yeah? You know,
if it weren't for those lions...
we'd be runnin' the joint.
Man, I hate lions.
- So pushy.
- And hairy.
- And stinky.
- And, man, are they...
BOTH: U-u-u-ugly!
[Both laugh]
SCAR: Oh, surely,
we lions are not all that bad.
- Ohh.
- Oh, Scar. It's just you.
We were afraid
it was somebody important.
Yeah, you know, like Mufasa.
- Yeah.
- I see.
- Now, that's power.
- Tell me about it.
I just hear that name
and I shudder.
- Mufasa!
- Ooh! Do it again.
- Ooooh!
Mufasa! Mufasa! Mufasa!
[Giggling]
SHENZI: Ooh, it tingles.
I'm surrounded by idiots.
Now, you, Scar,
I mean, you're one of us.
You're our pal.
Charmed.
Oh, I like that.
He's not king,
but he's still so proper.
Did you bring us anything
to eat, Scar, old buddy?
Did ya, did ya, did ya?
I don't think you
really deserve this.
I practically gift-wrapped
those cubs for you...
and you couldn't
even dispose of them.
[Gasp]
[Muffled]
Well, you know...
it wasn't exactly like
they were alone, Scar.
Yeah. What were we
supposed to do...
kill Mufasa?
[Chewing]
Precisely.
Huh?
[Drums beat]
[Song begins]
[Steam hissing rhythmically]
* I know that your powers
of retention *
* Are as wet
as a warthog's backside *
* But thick as you are *
* Pay attention *
* My words
are a matter of pride *
* It's clear from
your vacant expressions *
* The lights
are not all on upstairs *
* But we're talking kings
and successions *
* Even you can't be
caught unawares *
- Oh!
- Aah!
* So prepare for
the chance of a lifetime *
* Be prepared
for sensational news *
* A shiny new era
is tiptoeing nearer *
* And where do we feature? *
* Just listen to teacher *
* I know it sounds sordid *
* But you'll be rewarded *
* When at last
I am given my dues *
* And injustice
deliciously squared *
* Be prepared *
Yeah, be prepared.
We'll be prepared. For what?
For the death of the king.
Why, is he sick?
No, fool,
we're going to kill him...
and Simba, too.
Great idea.
Who needs a king?
* No king, no king,
la-la la-la la la *
Idiots!
There will be a king!
- Hey, but you said...
- I will be king!
Stick with me, and you'll
never go hungry again.
- Yeah!
- Yeah! All right!
All right!
Long live the king!
ALL: Long live the king!
* King, king, king,
king, king, king, king *
* It's great that
we'll soon be connected *
* With a king who'll be
all-time adored *
* Of course,
quid pro quo *
* You're expected *
* To take certain duties
on board *
* The future
is littered with prizes *
* And though
I'm the main addressee *
* The point that
I must emphasize is *
* You won't get a sniff
without me *
Aah!
* So prepare for
the coup of the century *
* Be prepared
for the murkiest scam *
* La la la *
* Meticulous planning *
* Tenacity spanning *
* Decades of denial *
* Is simply why
I'll be king undisputed *
* Respected, saluted *
* And seen
for the wonder I am *
* Yes, my teeth
and ambitions are bared *
* Be prepared *
* Yes, our teeth
and ambitions are bared *
* Be prepared *
[All cackling]
[Music stops]
SCAR: Now, you wait here.
Your father has
a marvelous surprise for you.
Ooh, what is it?
If I told you,
it wouldn't be a surprise.
If you tell me,
I'll still act surprised.
Ho ho ho!
You are such a naughty boy.
Come on, Uncle Scar.
No, no, no, no, no.
This is just
for you and your daddy.
You know, a sort of
father-son... thing.
Well, I better go get him.
- I'll go with you.
- No! Heh heh heh.
No. Just stay on this rock.
You wouldn't want to end up
in another mess...
like you did with the hyenas.
You know about that?
Simba,
everybody knows about that.
- Really?
- Oh, yes.
Lucky Daddy was there
to save you, eh?
Oh, and just between us...
you might want to work on
that little roar of yours.
Oh, OK.
Hey, Uncle Scar,
will I like this surprise?
Simba, it's to die for.
[Bird cawing]
[Dramatic music playing]
- Shut up.
- I can't help it.
I'm so hungry.
I got to have a wildebeest.
Stay put.
Can't I just pick off
one of the little sick ones?
No. We wait for the signal
from Scar.
There he is. Let's go.
Little roar. Puhh.
Rarr!
Rrrarr!
[Roar echoes]
[Rumbling]
[Rattling]
[Birds cawing]
[Dramatic music playing]
[Gasps]
[Chorus singing]
[Barks]
Oh, look, sire,
the herd is on the move.
- Odd.
- Mufasa, quick!
Stampede in the gorge.
- Simba's down there.
- Simba?
Oh!
[Grunts]
Zazu, help me!
Your father is on the way!
Hold on!
Hurry!
There, on that tree.
Hold on, Simba!
[Crack] Aah!
Uhh!
Oh, Scar, this is awful!
What'll we do?
Ha! I'll go back to help,
that's what I'll do.
I'll go back... Oof!
[Splat, thud]
Uhh!
[Chorus singing]
[Crack] Aah!
- Uhh!
[Roars]
[Gasps]
- Rraar!
- Dad!
[Roars]
MUFASA: Scar!
Uhh! Brother! Help me!
[Roars]
Long live the king.
[Dramatic music playing]
- Aah!
- No!
[Music stops]
[Coughs]
[Echoes] Dad!
[Rustling] Dad?
[Dramatic music playing]
Dad?
Dad, come on.
You got to get up.
Dad?
We got to go home.
[Echoes] Help!
Somebody!
Anybody.
Help. [Crying]
[Sniffles]
SCAR: Simba.
What have you done?
There were wildebeests,
and he tried to save me.
It was an accident.
I didn't mean for it to happen.
Of course, of course
you didn't.
No one ever means
for these things to happen...
but the king is dead.
And if it weren't for you,
he'd still be alive.
What will your mother think?
[Sniffles]
What am I going to do?
Run away, Simba.
Run.
Run away and never return.
Kill him.
[Panting]
[Dramatic music playing]
Huh?
[Growling]
[Snarls]
[Gasps]
[Snarling]
Unh! Uhh! Uhh!
[Branches snap] Uhh!
Whoa!
[Sighs]
- Ooh!
- Whoa!
Yow!
[Laughing]
Aah! Ohh! Yeow!
Hey, there he goes.
There he goes.
So, go get him.
There ain't no way
I'm going in there.
You want me to come out
looking like you, cactus butt?
[Yelps]
But we got to finish the job.
Well, he's as good as dead
out there anyway.
And if he comes back,
we'll kill him.
Yeah! You hear that?
If you ever come back,
we'll kill you!
[Laughing]
Mufasa's death
is a terrible tragedy...
but to lose Simba,
who had barely begun to live...
[Sniffles] For me,
it is a deep, personal loss.
So, it is
with a heavy heart...
that I assume the throne.
Yet out of the ashes
of this tragedy...
we shall rise to greet
the dawning of a new era...
in which lion and hyena
come together...
in a great
and glorious future.
[Hyenas whooping]
Ohh, ho ho.
[Soft music playing]
[Vultures cawing]
BOTH: Yaah!
Get out! Get out!
Get out of here!
I love this!
Bowling for buzzards.
Hee hee hee!
Gets 'em every time.
Ha ha ha!
Uh-oh. Hey, Timon,
you better come look.
I think it's still alive.
Eee.
All righty,
what have we got here?
[Sniffs]
[Grunts]
Jeez, it's a lion!
Run, Pumbaa, move it!
Hey, Timon,
it's just a little lion.
Look at him.
He's so cute and all alone.
- Can we keep him?
- Pumbaa, are you nuts?
You're talking about a lion.
Lions eat guys like us.
- But he's so little.
- He'll get bigger.
Maybe he'll be on our side.
Ha! That's the stupidest
thing I ever heard.
Maybe he'll... Hey, I got it.
What if he's on our side?
Having a lion around
might not be such a bad idea.
So, we're keeping him?
Pbbt! Of course.
Who's the brains of this outfit?
- Uh...
- My point exactly.
Jeez, I'm fried.
Let's get out of here
and find some shade.
Mmm. Uhh.
- You OK, kid?
- I guess so.
- You nearly died.
- I saved you.
Well, Pumbaa helped... a little.
Thanks for your help.
- Hey, where you going?
- Nowhere.
Gee, he looks blue.
TIMON:
I'd say brownish gold.
No, no, no.
I mean he's depressed.
Oh.
Kid, what's eating you?
Nothing. He's at
the top of the food chain.
Ah ha ha ha ha ha ha!
The food chain! Ha ha.
Ahem.
So, where you from?
Who cares?
I can't go back.
Ah, you're an outcast.
That's great. So are we.
What'd you do, kid?
Something terrible...
but I don't want
to talk about it.
Good. We don't want
to hear about it.
Come on, Timon.
Anything we can do?
Not unless
you can change the past.
Kid, in times like this,
my buddy Timon says...
you got to put
your behind in your past.
No, no, no. Amateur.
Lie down
before you hurt yourself.
You got to put your past
behind you.
Look, kid,
bad things happen...
and you can't do anything
about it, right?
- Right.
- Wrong!
When the world
turns its back on you...
you turn your back on the world.
That's not what I was taught.
Then maybe
you need a new lesson.
Repeat after me. Ahem.
- Hakuna matata.
- What?
Hakuna matata.
It means "no worries."
* Hakuna matata *
* What a wonderful phrase *
* Ain't no passing craze *
* It means no worries *
* For the rest of your days *
* It's our problem free *
* Philosophy *
* Hakuna matata *
- Hakuna matata?
- Yeah. It's our motto.
What's a motto?
Nothing.
What's a motto with you?
[Both laugh]
Kid, these two words
will solve all your problems.
That's right.
Take Pumbaa, for example.
Why...
* When he was a young warthog *
[Sings sour note]
* When I was a young warthog *
- Very nice.
- Thanks.
TIMON:
* He found his aroma *
* Lacked a certain appeal *
* He could clear the savannah
after every meal *
PUMBAA:
* I'm a sensitive soul *
* Though I seem
thick skinned *
[Breaks wind]
* And it hurt that my friends *
* Never stood downwind *
* And, oh, the shame *
* He was ashamed *
* Thought of changing my name *
* Oh, what's in a name? *
* And I got downhearted *
* How did you feel? *
* Every time that l... *
- Not in front of the kids.
- Oh, sorry.
* Hakuna matata *
* What a wonderful phrase *
* Ain't no passing craze *
* It means no worries *
* For the rest of your days *
Yeah, sing it, kid.
* It's our problem free *
* Philosophy *
* Hakuna matata *
Welcome to our humble home.
SIMBA: You live here?
TIMON:
We live wherever we want.
Yep. Home is
where your rump rests.
It's beautiful.
[Belches] I'm starved.
I'm so hungry
I could eat a whole zebra.
Ah, we're fresh out of zebra.
- Any antelope?
- Nuh-uh.
- Hippo?
- Nope.
Kid, if you live with us,
you have to eat like us.
This looks like a good spot
to rustle up some grub.
Ew, what's that?
A grub.
What's it look like?
Ew, gross.
Mmm. Tastes like chicken.
[Slurp]
Slimy, yet satisfying.
These are rare delicacies. Mmm.
[Crunch] Piquant,
with a very pleasant crunch.
You'll learn to love them.
I'm telling you, kid,
this is the great life...
no rules,
no responsibilities.
Ooh, the little
green-filled kind.
And best of all, no worries.
Well, kid?
[Insects squishing]
Oh, well. Hakuna matata.
[Slurps]
[Gulps]
[Smacks lips]
Slimy, yet satisfying.
That's it.
[Upbeat music playing]
* Hakuna matata *
* Hakuna matata,
Hakuna *
* It means no worries *
* For the rest of your days *
* It's our problem free *
* Philosophy *
SIMBA: * Hakuna matata *
TIMON: * Hakuna matata *
* Hakuna matata *
* Ooh ooh ooh *
Brr!
* Hakuna matata *
* Yeah *
* Ta-ta *
TIMON: Ha ha ha!
ZAZU: * Nobody knows *
* The trouble I've seen *
* Nobody knows *
* My sorrow *
Oh, Zazu, do lighten up.
Sing something
with a little bounce in it.
* It's a small world
after all *
No, no! Anything but that.
* I've got a lovely
bunch of coconuts *
* Deedle dee dee *
* There they are
a- standing in a row *
[Hums along]
BO TH:
* Big ones, small ones *
* Some as big
as your head *
I would never have had
to do this with Mufasa.
What? What did you say?
- Oh, nothing.
- You know the law.
Never ever mention
that name in my presence.
I am the king!
Yes, sire, you are the king.
I only mentioned it
to illustrate the differences...
in your royal
managerial approaches.
BANZAI: Hey, boss.
What is it this time?
- We got a bone to pick with you.
- I'll handle this.
Scar, there's no food, no water.
Yeah. It's dinnertime...
and we ain't got
no stinking entrees.
It's the lioness's job
to do the hunting.
Yeah, but they won't go hunt.
Oh, eat Zazu.
Oh, you wouldn't want me.
I'd be so tough and gamy and...
Oh, Zazu,
don't be ridiculous.
All you need is a little dung.
I thought things
were bad under Mufasa.
- What did you say?
- I said Muf...
Unh! I said... Que pasa?
Good. Now get out.
- But we're still hungry.
- Out!
[Yelps, laughs]
[Simba belches]
Whoa. Nice one, Simba.
Thanks. Man, I'm stuffed.
Me, too. I ate like a pig.
Pumbaa, you are a pig.
Oh. Right.
[Both sigh]
[Smacks lips]
[Soft music playing]
- Timon?
- Yeah?
Ever wonder what those
sparkling dots are up there?
TIMON: Pumbaa,
I don't wonder, I know.
PUMBAA: Oh? What are they?
They're fireflies...
fireflies that got stuck in
that big blue-ish black thing.
Oh, gee.
I always thought
they were balls of gas...
burning billions of miles away.
TIMON: Pumbaa, with you,
everything's gas.
Simba, what do you think?
Well, I don't know.
Oh, come on.
Give, give, give, give.
- Nah.
- We told you ours. Please?
Well, somebody once told me...
that the great kings of the past
are up there...
watching over us.
Really?
A bunch of royal dead guys
are watching us? Pbbt!
[Timon and Pumbaa laugh]
TIMON: Who told you
something like that?
Yeah, yeah.
What mook made that up?
Yeah, pretty dumb, huh?
- Aw, you're killing me.
- Yeah.
TIMON: Whoo. Ohh.
Was it something I said?
[Dramatic music playing]
[Sighs]
[Sniffs] Hmm.
[Grunting]
[Tinkling]
[Humming]
[Crack]
[Chorus singing]
Hmm. Simba?
He's alive?
He's alive!
[Laughing]
[Laughing harder]
It is time.
[Music fades]
* A wee ma way,
a wee ma way *
a wee ma way... *
* In the jungle,
the mighty jungle *
* The lion sleeps tonight *
* In the jungle,
the mighty jungle *
* The lion sleeps to... *
I can't hear you, buddy.
Back me up.
* A wee *
* Eee-eee-eee *
* A pumbaa-bum-baa-way *
Pumbaa? Pumbaa?
[Pumbaa humming]
Hmm?
Yeah.
[Slurps]
Unh. Oop. Hmm. Timon?
Unh.
[Dramatic music playing]
[Growls]
Aah!
[Roars]
[Panting]
Pumbaa?
[Roaring]
- Pumbaa! Pumbaa!
- Aah!
Pumbaa, Pumbaa!
Hey, what's going on?
She's going to eat me!
TIMON: Huh?
Whoa! Jeez, why do I always
have to save your...
Aah!
[Roars]
Don't worry, buddy.
I'm here for you.
Everything's going to be OK.
Get her! Bite her head!
Go for the jugular!
The jugular!
See, I told you
he'd come in handy.
[Roaring]
[Growling]
Nala?
Is it really you?
Who are you?
It's me... Simba.
Simba?
- Whoa!
- Aah!
- But how did you...
- How did you... Wow!
Where did you come from?
It's great to see you!
Hey, what's goin' on here?
What are you doing here?
NALA: What are you doing here?
Hey! What's goin' on here?!
Timon, this is Nala.
She's my best friend.
- Friend?
- Yeah.
Hey, Pumbaa, come over here.
Huh?
Nala, this is Pumbaa.
Pumbaa, Nala.
Pleased to make
your acquaintance.
The pleasure's all mine.
TIMON: How do you do?
Whoa, whoa! Time out!
Let me get this straight.
You know her, she knows you.
But she wants to eat him,
and everybody's OK with this?
- Did I miss something?!
- Relax, Timon.
Wait till everyone finds out
you've been here all this time.
And your mother...
what will she think?
She doesn't have to know.
Nobody has to know.
Of course they do.
Everyone thinks you're dead.
They do?
Yeah. Scar told us
about the stampede.
He did?
What else did he tell you?
What else matters?
You're alive, and that means...
you're the king.
King? [Scoffs]
Lady, have you got
your lions crossed.
King? Your Majesty...
I gravel at your feet.
Mwah! Mwah! Mwah!
Stop it.
It's not "gravel,"
it's "grovel."
And don't!
He's not the king.
- Are you?
- No!
- Simba!
- I'm not the king.
Maybe I was gonna be,
but that was a long time ago.
Let me get this straight.
You're the king?
And you never told us?
Look, I'm still the same guy.
But with power.
Could you guys excuse us
for a few minutes?
Whatever she has to say...
she can say in front of us,
right, Simba?
Mmm... maybe you'd better go.
It starts.
You think you know a guy.
[Pumbaa groans]
Timon and Pumbaa...
you learn to love 'em.
What?
What is it?
It's like you're back
from the dead.
You don't know how much
this will mean to everyone...
what it means to me.
Hey, it's OK.
I've really missed you.
I've missed you, too.
[Scoffs] I tell you, Pumbaa.
This stinks.
Oh, sorry.
Not you, them!
Him, her, alone.
What's wrong with that?
* I can see
what's happening *
What?!
* And they don't have a clue *
Who?!
* They'll fall in love *
* And here's the bottom line *
* Our trio's down to two *
Oh.
[French accent]
* Ze sweet caress *
* Of twilight *
* There's magic everywhere *
* And with
all this romantic *
* Atmosphere *
* Disaster's in the air *
WOMAN: * Can you feel *
* The love tonight? *
* The peace
the evening brings? *
* The world, for once *
* In perfect harmony *
* With all
its living things *
SIMBA: * So many things
to tell her *
* But how to make her see *
* The truth about my past? *
* Impossible,
she'd turn away from me *
NALA: * He's holding back *
* He's hiding *
* But what, I can't decide *
* Why won't he be the king
I know he is *
* The king I see inside *
CHORUS: * Can you feel *
* The love tonight *
* The peace
the evening brings? *
* The world, for once *
* In perfect harmony *
* With all its living things *
* Can you feel *
* The love tonight? *
* You needn't look too far *
* Stealing through *
* The night's uncertainties *
* Love is where they are *
* And if he falls *
* In love tonight *
[Sniffles]
* It can be assumed *
* His carefree days *
* With us are history *
* In short, our pal *
* Is doomed *
[Both crying]
SIMBA:
Isn't this a great place?
NALA: It is beautiful...
but I don't understand
something.
You've been alive all this time.
Why didn't you come back
to Pride Rock?
Well, I just needed
to get out on my own...
live my own life.
And I did, and it's great.
We've really needed you at home.
No one needs me.
Yes, we do.
You're the king.
Nala, we've been through this.
I'm not the king. Scar is.
Simba, he let the hyenas
take over the pride lands.
- What?
- Everything's destroyed.
There's no food, no water.
Simba, if you don't
do something soon...
everyone will starve.
- I can't go back.
- Why?
- You wouldn't understand.
- What?
No, it doesn't matter.
Hakuna matata.
- What?
- Hakuna matata.
It's something
I learned out here.
Look, sometimes
bad things happen...
Simba...
And there's nothing
you can do about it...
so why worry?
Because it's
your responsibility.
Well, what about you?
You left.
I left to find help,
and I found you.
Don't you understand?
You're our only hope.
Sorry.
What's happened to you?
You're not the Simba I remember.
You're right. I'm not.
Are you satisfied?
No, just disappointed.
You're starting
to sound like my father.
Good.
At least one of us does.
Listen, you think
you can just show up...
and tell me
how to live my life?
You don't even know
what I've been through.
I would,
if you'd just tell me.
- Forget it!
- Fine!
She's wrong.
I can't go back.
What would it prove, anyway?
It won't change anything.
You can't change the past.
You said you'd always
be there for me!
But you're not.
And it's because of me.
It's my fault.
[Cries]
[Rafiki singing]
* Asante sana,
squash banana *
* We we nugu,
mi mi apana *
* Asante sana,
squash banana *
* We we nugu,
mi mi apana *
* Asante sana,
squash banana *
* We we nugu,
mi mi apana *
* A-do-de-do
da-do-ba-de-do *
[Chuckling]
[Sighs]
RAFIKI: * Asante sana,
squash banana *
* We we nugu,
mi mi apana *
[Yawns]
Come on,
will you cut it out?
Can't cut it out.
It'll grow right back.
- Ha ha ha ha!
- Creepy little monkey.
Will you stop following me?
Who are you?
The question is, who are you?
[Sighs]
I thought I knew.
Now I'm not so sure.
Well, I know who you are.
Shh. Come here. It's a secret.
* Asante sana,
squash banana *
Uhh! Enough already!
What is that supposed
to mean, anyway?
It means you are a baboon,
and I'm not.
[Laughs]
I think
you're a little confused.
Wrong! I'm not
the one who's confused.
You don't even know who you are.
Oh, and I suppose you know.
Sure do.
You're Mufasa's boy.
[Gasps]
- Bye.
- Hey, wait!
[Female chorus singing]
[Panting]
You knew my father?
Correction...
I know your father.
I hate to tell you this...
but he died a long time ago.
Nope. Wrong again!
Ha ha ha!
He's alive,
and I'll show him to you.
You follow old Rafiki.
He knows the way. Come on!
[Upbeat music playing]
Don't dawdle. Hurry up!
Hey, whoa, wait, wait.
Come on. Come on!
Would you slow down?
Uhh!
[Rafiki laughing]
Stop!
Shh.
Look down there.
[Sighs]
That's not my father.
That's just my reflection.
No. Look harder.
RAFIKI: You see?
He lives in you.
MUFASA, ECHOING: Simba.
Father?
[Rumbling]
Simba, you have forgotten me.
No. How could I?
You have forgotten
who you are...
and so have forgotten me.
Look inside yourself, Simba.
You are more
than what you have become.
You must take your place
in the circle of life.
How can I go back?
I'm not who I used to be.
Remember who you are.
You are my son,
and the one true king.
Remember who you are.
No! Please, don't leave me!
MUFASA: Remember.
- Father!
- Remember.
Don't leave me.
MUFASA: Remember.
[Rumbling fades]
[Wind howling]
RAFIKI:
What was that? Ha ha!
The weather... Pbbah!
Very peculiar,
don't you think?
Yeah. Looks like the winds
are changing.
Ahh, change is good.
Yeah, but it's not easy.
I know what I have to do...
but going back means
I'll have to face my past.
I've been running from it
for so long.
[Thwack] Ow!
Jeez! What was that for?
It doesn't matter.
It's in the past. Ha ha ha!
Yeah, but it still hurts.
Oh, yes, the past can hurt.
But the way I see it,
you can either run from it...
or learn from it.
[Whoosh] Aah!
You see?
So, what are you going to do?
First, I'm gonna take
your stick.
No, no, no, no!
Not the stick!
Hey! Where are you going?
I'm going back!
Good! Go on!
Get out of here!
[Laughing]
Whoo! Ha ha ha!
Whoooo! Whoooo!
[Music stops]
[Snoring]
[Groaning]
[Snoring] Grubs! Grubs!
[Groans]
Hey. Hey, wake up.
[Both screaming]
It's OK! Whoa, whoa!
It's OK! It's me!
[Sighs]
Don't ever do that again.
Carnivores... Oy!
Have you guys seen Simba?
I thought he was with you.
He was,
but now I can't find him.
- Where is he?
- Ha ha ha!
You won't find him here!
Ha ha!
The king has returned.
I can't believe it.
He's gone back.
Gone back? What do you mean?
Hey, what's goin' on here?
Who's the monkey?
Simba's gone back
to challenge Scar.
- Who?
- Scar.
- Who's got a scar?
- No. It's his uncle.
- The monkey's his uncle?
- No!
Simba's gone back
to challenge his uncle...
to take his place as king.
BOTH: Oh.
[Dramatic music playing]
[Chorus singing]
[Wind howling]
NALA: Simba, wait up!
It's awful, isn't it?
SIMBA: I didn't want
to believe you.
What made you come back?
I finally got some sense
knocked into me...
and I've got the bump
to prove it.
Besides, this is my kingdom.
If I don't fight for it,
who will?
- I will.
- It's gonna be dangerous.
Danger? Ha!
I laugh in the face of danger.
Ha ha ha!
I see nothing funny about this.
Timon, Pumbaa,
what are you doing here?
At your service, my liege.
We're gonna fight
your uncle for this?
Yes, Timon.
This is my home.
Talk about your fixer-upper.
Well, Simba,
if it's important to you...
we're with you to the end.
[Dramatic music playing]
[Snarling]
Hyenas. I hate hyenas.
So, what's your plan
for getting past those guys?
- Live bait.
- Good idea. Hey!
Come on, Timon. You guys
have to create a diversion.
What do you want me to do,
dress in drag and do the hula?
[Song begins] Luau!
* If you're hungry for a hunk
of fat and juicy meat *
* Eat my buddy Pumbaa here
because he is a treat *
* Come on down and dine
on this tasty swine *
* All you have to do
is get in line *
- * Are you achin' *
- Yep, yep, yep.
- * For some bacon? *
- * He's a big pig *
- Yep yep.
* You could be
a big pig, too, oy! *
[Both scream]
[Growling]
Nala, you find my mother
and rally the lionesses.
I'll look for Scar.
[Thunder]
Sarabi! [Echoes]
[Hyenas snarling]
[Barking]
[Thunder]
Yes, Scar?
Where is your hunting party?
They're not doing their job.
Scar, there is no food.
The herds have moved on.
No, you're just not
looking hard enough.
It's over.
There is nothing left.
We have only once choice.
We must leave Pride Rock.
We're not going anywhere.
Then you have
sentenced us to death.
- Then so be it.
- You can't do that.
I am the king.
I can do whatever I want.
If you were half the king
Mufasa was...
I'm ten times the king
Mufasa was!
[Roars]
SCAR: Mufasa? No, you're dead.
SARABI: Ohh.
Mufasa?
No. It's me.
Simba. You're alive?
How can that be?
It doesn't matter.
I'm home.
Simba?
Simba.
Oh, I'm a little surprised
to see you... alive.
[All gulp]
Give me one good reason
why I shouldn't rip you apart.
Simba, you must understand.
The pressures
of ruling a kingdom...
Are no longer yours.
Step down, Scar.
[Laughs]
Oh, well, I would, naturally.
However, there is
one little problem.
You see them?
[All snarling]
They think I'm king.
NALA: Well, we don't.
Simba's the rightful king.
The choice is yours, Scar.
Either step down or fight.
Must this all end in violence?
I'd hate to be responsible for
the death of a family member.
Wouldn't you agree, Simba?
That's not gonna work, Scar.
I've put it behind me.
But what about
your faithful subjects?
Have they put it behind them?
Simba, what is he talking about?
Ahh...
so you haven't told them
your little secret.
Well, Simba,
now's your chance to tell them.
Tell them who is responsible
for Mufasa's death.
I am.
It's not true.
Tell me it's not true.
It's true.
You see? He admits it!
Murderer!
No, it was an accident.
If it weren't for you,
Mufasa would still be alive.
It's your fault he's dead!
Do you deny it?
- No.
- Then you're guilty.
No, I'm not a murderer.
Oh, Simba,
you're in trouble again.
But this time,
Daddy isn't here to save you...
and now everyone knows why!
- Unh!
- Simba!
[Boom]
[Fire crackles]
Now, this looks familiar.
Hmm.
Where have I seen this before?
Let me think. Hmm.
Oh, yes. I remember.
This is just the way your father
looked before he died.
[Gasps]
And here's my little secret...
[Whispers]
I killed Mufasa.
YOUNG SIMBA: No-o-o-o!
No! Murderer!
No, Simba, please.
Tell them the truth.
Truth? But truth is in
the eye of the behold...
All right.
[Gags] All right.
I did it.
So they can hear you.
I killed Mufasa!
[Roars]
[All roaring]
PUMBAA: Hee-yah!
TIMON: Excuse me.
Pardon me. Comin' through.
Hot stuff. Whoo!
[Grunts]
[Roars]
[Hyenas yelp]
[Thwack]
[Screams]
[Hyenas snarling]
Waah! Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
Yaaow!
[Hyenas yelping]
[Panting]
Aah! Whoo-hoo-hoo!
- Let me out! Let me out!
- Let me in! Let me in!
[Hyena laughs]
Please, don't eat me.
PUMBAA: Drop 'em!
Hey, who's the pig?
- Are you talkin' to me?
- He called him a pig.
- Are you talking to me?
- Shouldn't have done that.
- Now they're in for it.
They call me... Mister Pig!
Aaaaah!
Take that, you stupid...
Take that, and that!
[Screaming]
[Yelping]
Run, you yellow-bellied...
BOTH: Whoo! Whoo! Whoo!
[Roars]
[Thunder]
Murderer.
Simba, please.
Please, have mercy.
I beg you.
You don't deserve to live.
But, Simba, I am... family.
Heh heh.
It's the hyenas
who are the real enemy.
It was their fault.
It was their idea.
Why should I believe you?
Everything you ever told me
was a lie.
What are you going to do?
You wouldn't
kill your own uncle.
No, Scar. I'm not like you.
Oh, Simba, thank you.
You are truly noble.
I'll make it up to you,
I promise.
And how can I prove
myself to you?
Tell me. Anything.
Run.
Run away, Scar,
and never return.
Yes.
Of course.
As you wish... Your Majesty!
Aah! Aah!
Uhh!
[Roaring]
[Thump]
[Roars]
[Fire crackling]
Ohh. My friends.
Friends? I thought
he said we were the enemy.
Yeah. That's what I heard.
- Ed?
[Laughing]
No, no. Let me explain.
No, you don't understand!
No, I didn't mean... No! No!
[Shouting]
[Fire roars]
[Dramatic music playing]
[Rattling]
It is time.
[Music swells]
[Thunder]
MUFASA: Remember.
[Roars]
[All roar]
* Se-fi-le *
* Baba ti-tabo *
* Maye babo busa lomhlaba *
[Chorus singing]
[Trumpet]
* Ubuse ngo xolo *
* Ubuse ngo thando *
* Ingonyama
nengw' enamabala *
* Till we find our place *
* On the path unwinding *
* In the circle *
* The circle of life *
* Circle of *
* Life *
[Music stops]
[New song begins]
[Chorus singing]
[Song ends]
[New song begins]
ELTON JOHN:
* There's a calm surrender *
* To the rush of day *
* When the heat
of a rolling wind *
* Can be turned away *
* An enchanted moment *
* And it sees me through *
* It's enough
for this restless warrior *
* Just to be with you *
* And can you feel *
* The love tonight? *
* Tonight *
* It is where we are *
* It's enough *
* For this wide-eyed
wanderer *
* That we got this far *
* And can you feel *
* The love tonight *
* Tonight *
* How it's laid to rest? *
* It's enough *
* To make kings
and vagabonds *
* Believe the very best *
* There's a time
for everyone *
* If they only learn *
* That the twisting
kaleidoscope *
* Moves us all in turn *
* There's a rhyme and reason *
* To the wild outdoors *
* When the heart
of this star-crossed voyager *
* Beats in time with yours *
* And can you feel *
* The love tonight? *
* Tonight *
* It is where we are *
* It's enough *
* For this wide-eyed wanderer *
* That we got this far *
* And can you feel *
* The love tonight *
* Tonight *
* How it's laid to rest? *
* It's enough *
* To make kings and vagabonds *
* Believe the very best *
* It's enough *
* To make kings and vagabonds *
* Believe the very best *
[Song ends]