[ Boy ] All right, everyone! This...
is a stickup! Don't anybody move!
Now, empty that safe!
Ooh-hoo-hoo! Money, money, money!
[ Kissing ]
Stop it! Stop it,
you mean, old potato!
Quiet, Bo Peep,
or your sheep get run over!
Help! Baa!
Help us!
Oh, no, not my sheep!
Somebody do something!
[ Voice Box ]
Reach for the sky!
Oh, no! Sheriff Woody!
I'm here to stop you,
One-Eyed Bart.
Doh!
How'd you know it was me?
Are you gonna
come quietly?
You can't touch me, Sheriff!
I brought my attack dog
with the built-in force field.
Well, I brought my dinosaur
who eats force-field dogs.
- [ Growling ]
- Yipe, yipe, yipe, yipe!
You're going to jail, Bart!
Say good-bye to the wife and tater tots.
[ Giggling Excitedly ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Baby Squealing,
Laughing, Cooing ]
You saved the day again, Woody.
[ Voice Box ]
You're my favorite deputy.
You've got a friend in me
Come on, let's
wrangle up the cattle.
When the road looks
rough ahead
And you're miles and miles
from your nice, warm bed
- Round 'em up, cowboy!
-Just remember
what your old pal said
- Round 'em up, cowboy!
-Just remember
what your old pal said
- Round 'em up, cowboy!
-Just remember
what your old pal said
Boy,you've got
a friend in me
- Yee-haw!
- Yeah,you've got a friend in me
Hey, cowboy!
Some other folks might be
a little bit smarter than I am
- [ Whinnying ]
-Big and stronger too
- Come on, Woody.
-Maybe
But none of them will ever
love you the way I do
-It's me and you, boy
- [ Laughs ]
-And as the years go by
- Whoa!
- Whoa! [ Laughing ]
- Our friendship will never die
- Whoo!
- You're gonna see
-It's our destiny
- [ Laughing ]
- You've got a friend in me
-All right!
- Yeah,you've got a friend in me
- Score!
- You got a friend in me
- Wow! Cool!
-[ Mom ] What do you think?
- Oh, this looks great, Mom!
- Okay, birthday boy--
- We saw that at the store!
I asked you for it!
- Okay, birthday boy--
- We saw that at the store!
I asked you for it!
- Okay, birthday boy--
- We saw that at the store!
I asked you for it!
- I hope I have enough places.
- Wow, look at that! That's so--
- One, two-- Four. Yeah,
I think that's gonna be enough.
- Oh, my gosh, you got--
- One, two-- Four. Yeah,
I think that's gonna be enough.
- Oh, my gosh, you got--
- One, two-- Four. Yeah,
I think that's gonna be enough.
- Oh, my gosh, you got--
- Could we leave this up till we move?
- Well, sure!
- We can leave it up. Now go get Molly.
- Yeah!
- Your friends are gonna
be here any minute.
- Okay. It's party time, Woody.
- Yee...haw!
-[ Running Footfalls ]
[ Baby Squealing ]
Howdy, little lady.
[ Squealing ]
Somebody's poisoned
the water hole.
- [ Cooing ]
- Come on, Molly.
Oh, you're getting heavy.
- [ Cooing ]
- Come on, Molly.
Oh, you're getting heavy.
- [ Cooing ]
- Come on, Molly.
Oh, you're getting heavy.
-[ Molly Cooing ]
-See you later, Woody.
[ Door Closes ]
Pull my string!
The birthday party's today?
Okay, everybody,
coast is clear!
- [ Squeaks ]
- Ages 3 and up. It's on my box.
Ages 3 and up. I'm not supposed
to be baby-sitting Princess Drool.
[ Tires Squeal,
Motor Revs ]
- [ Weebles Gibbering ]
- [ Bell Dings, Siren Wailing ]
- [ Siren Wailing ]
- Hey, Hamm.
- Look, I'm Picasso!
- I don't get it.
You uncultured swine! What're
you lookin' at, ya hockey puck?
[ Squeaks ]
[ Weebles Gibbering ]
- Hey, Sarge, have you seen Slinky?
- Sir! No, sir!
Okay. Hey, thank you. At ease.
- [ Siren Wailing ]
- Hey, uh, Slinky?
Right here, Woody.
I'm red this time.
- No. S-Slink--
- Oh, well, all right.
You can be red if you want.
- N-Not now, Slink. I got some bad news.
- [ Shouts ] Bad news?
Shh, shh, shh!
-Just gather everyone up
for a staff meeting, and be happy.
- Got it.
- Be happy!
- Ha, ha, ha, ha!
- Staff meeting, everybody!
Snake, Robot, podium please.
-[ Siren Wailing ]
Hey.
[Jabbers ]
Hey, Etch. Draw!
-[ Ding ]
- Oh! Got me again.
Etch, you've been working
on that draw. Fastest knobs in the west.
Got a staff meeting, you guys.
Come on, let's go.
Now, where is that-- Oh.
Hey, who moved my doodle pad
way over here?
[ Roaring ]
- How're you doin', Rex?
- Were you scared? Tell me honestly.
I was close to being scared
that time.
I'm going for fearsome here,
but I just don't feel it.
I think I'm just
coming off as annoying.
[ Coughs ]
Ow! Oh, hi, Bo. Hi.
I wanted to thank you, Woody,
for saving my flock.
Oh, hey,
it was, uh, nothin'.
What do you say I get someone else
to watch the sheep tonight?
[ Sheepish Giggle ]
Oh, yeah! [ Mutters ]
Remember, I'm just
a couple of blocks away.
- Yodel-ay-hee-hoo!
- Come on, come on.
Smaller toys up front.
[ Slinky ]
Hey, Woody, come on.
[ Toys Tittering,
Buzzing, Dinging ]
-[ Sheep Bleating ]
-Ahem!
- [ Squeaks ]
- Oh, thanks, Mike.
- [ Loud Feedback ]
- Okay-- Whoa, whoa. Step back.
-[ Hamm ] For crying out loud.
- Thank you.
- [ Amplified Blowing ]
- [ Amplified ] Hello? Check.
That better? Great.
Everybody hear me? Up on the shelf,
can you hear me? Great.
Okay. First item today:
Uh... oh, yeah.
Has everyone picked a moving buddy?
- [ Rex ] What?
- Moving buddy? You can't be serious.
I didn't know we were
supposed to have one already.
- Do we have to hold hands?
- [ Toys Gibbering ]
You guys think
this is a big joke.
We've only got one week
left before the move.
I don't want any toys left behind.
A moving buddy.
If you don't have one,
get one!
All right, next.
Uh, oh, yes.
Tuesday night's plastic corrosion
awareness meeting...
was, I think,
a big success.
And we wanna thank Mr. Spell
for putting that on for us.
- Thank you, Mr. Spell.
- [ Electronic Voice ] You're welcome.
Okay. Uh, oh, yes.
One, uh, minor note here.
[ Quietly ] Andy's birthday party
has been moved to today.
- Wait a minute here!
- [ Toys Complaining ]
What do you mean the party's today?
His birthday's not till next week!
What's goin' on down there?
Is his mom losin' her marbles?
Well, obviously she wanted to
have the party before the move.
- I'm not worried.
You shouldn't be worried.
- Of course Woody ain't worried.
He's been Andy's favorite
since kindergarten.
Hey, hey.
Come on, Potato Head.
If Woody says it's all right, then,
well, darn it, it's good enough for me.
Woody has never
steered us wrong before.
Come on, guys. Every Christmas
and birthday we go through this.
But what if Andy gets
another dinosaur, a mean one?
I just don't think I could take
that kind of rejection!
Hey, listen,
no one's getting replaced.
This is Andy
we're talking about.
It doesn't matter
how much we're played with.
[ Chirping ]
What matters is that we're here
for Andy when he needs us.
That's what we're
made for, right?
Pardon me. I hate to break up the staff
meeting, but... they're here!
Birthday guests
at three o'clock!
- Stay calm, everyone!
- [ Agitated Gibbering ]
Hey!
- Uh, meeting adjourned.
-[ Creaking ]
Ho, boy! Will you take a look
at all those presents?
I can't see a thing.
Yes, sir, we're next month's
garage sale fodder for sure.
- Any dinosaur-shaped ones?
- Oh, for crying out loud.
They're all in boxes, you idiot.
[ Rex ]
They're getting bigger.
- Wait, there's a nice
little one over there.
- [ Child ] Hi!
[ Screaming ]
- [ Mr. Spell ] Spell: trash can.
- [ Rex ] We're doomed!
All right! All right!
If I send out the troops,
will you all calm down?
- Yes! Yes! We promise!
- Okay! Save your batteries.
Very good, Woody.
That's using the old noodle.
Sergeant, establish
a recon post downstairs. Code Red!
- You know what to do.
- Yes, sir!
All right, men.
You heard him. Code Red!
Repeat, we are at Code Red.
Recon plan Charlie. Execute!
Let's move!
Move, move, move, move!
[ Door Creaking ]
[ Children Shouting ]
-[ Child Chattering ]
-[ Children ] Yeah!
-[ Chattering, Shouting Continue ]
-[ Mom ] Okay, come on, kids.
Everyone in the living room.
It's almost time for the presents.
[ Kids Shouting,
Chattering Excitedly ]
[ Shouting, Chattering
Continue ]
[ Hamm ]
All right, gangway, gangway.
And this is
how we find out...
- what is in those presents.
- [ Robot Humming ]
[ Kids Chattering,
Shouting ]
[ Mom ]
Okay, who's hungry?
Here come the chips!
I've got Cool Ranch
and barbecue! Ow!
What in the world-- Oh!
- I thought I told him to pick these up.
-[ Ice Clinking In Glasses ]
Shouldn't they be there by now?
What's taking them so long?
Hey, these guys are professionals.
They're the best.
Come on!
They're not lying down on the job.
[ Moaning ]
G-G-Go on without me!
J-Just go!
A good soldier never
leaves a man behind.
[ Kids Shouting,
Chattering ]
-[ Mom ] Okay, everybody, come on.
- [ Boys Shouting ]
Everybody settle down.
Now, kids. Everybody--
You sit in a circle. No, Andy.
Andy,you sit in the middle there.
- Good. And-- Which present
are you gonna open first?
-[ Chattering Continues ]
-[ Child ] Mine!
-[ Sergeant ] There they are.
[ Soldier On Monitor ] Come in,
Mother Bird. This is Alpha Bravo.
- This is it! This is it!
Quiet, quiet, quiet!
- Come in, Mother Bird.
Andy's opening the first present now.
[ Static ]
Mrs. Potato Head! Mrs. Potato Head!
Mrs. Potato Head!
Hey, I can dream,
can't I?
The bow's coming off.
He's ripping the wrapping paper.
It's a-- It's--
It's a--a lunch box.
- We've got a lunch box here.
- A lunch box?
- Lunch box?
- For lunch. [ Laughing ]
Okay, second present.
It appears to be--
- Okay, it's bed sheets.
- Who invited that kid?
[ Kids Shouting,
Chattering ]
Oh! Only one left.
- Okay, we're on the last present now.
- Last present!
It's a big one.
It's a--
- It's a board game!
Repeat, Battleship!
- Whew!
- [ All Cheering ]
- [ Hamm ] Hallelujah!
- Yeah! All right!
- Hey, watch it!
Sorry there,
old spud head.
Mission accomplished. Well done, men.
Pack it up. We're goin' home.
So did I tell ya? Huh?
Nothin' to worry about.
I knew you were right all along, Woody.
Never doubted ya for a second.
Wait a minute. Oh!
- What do we have here?
- Wait! Turn that thing back on!
Come in, Mother Bird!
Mom has pulled a surprise
present from the closet.
Andy's opening it.
He's really excited about this one.
- Mom, what is it? [ Gasps ]
-[ Sergeant ] It's a huge package.
Oh, get outta the-- One of the kids
is in the way. I can't see.
- It's a--
- [ Kids Together ] Wow!
- [ Static ]
- It's a what? What is it?
- [ Potato Head Screams ]
- Oh, no!
- Oh, ya big lizard!
- Now we'll never know what it is!
- Way to go, Rex!
- No, no! Turn him around!
Turn him around!
- He's puttin' 'em in backwa--
Here, you're
puttin' 'em in backwards!
Plus is positive, minus is negative!
Oh, let me! [ Grunting ]
- [ Andy ] Let's go to my room, guys!
- [ Boys Shouting ]
Red alert! Red alert!
Andy is coming upstairs!
- [ Grunts ] There!
- [ Soldier] Juvenile intrusion!
Repeat, resume
your positions now!
Andy's coming! Everybody,
back to your places! Hurry!
[ Hamm ] Get to your places!
Get to your places!
- [ Rex Screaming ]
- Where's my ear? Who's seen my ear?
Did you see my ear?
Out of my way! Here I come!
Here I come! [ Groans ]
[ Boys Shouting ]
[ Andy ] Hey, look,
its lasers light up. Take that, Zurg!
Quick, make a space.
This is where the spaceship lands.
And he does it like that.
And he does a karate chop action!
[ Mom ] Come on down, guys!
It's time for games!
[ Boys Shouting Excitedly ]
- What is it?
- Can you see it?
- What the heck is up there?
- Woody, who's up there with ya?
- [ Coughing ]
-[ Slinky ] Woody?
- What are you doing under the bed?
- Uh, nothin'. Uh, nothin'.
I'm sure Andy was just
a little excited, that's all.
Too much cake and ice cream,
I suppose. It's just a mistake!
Well, that mistake is sitting
in your spot, Woody. [ Chuckles ]
- [ Gasps ] Have you been replaced?
- What did I tell you earlier?
No one is getting replaced.
Now, let's all be polite and give
whatever it is up there...
a nice, big
Andy's-room welcome.
[ Gulps ]
[ Heavy Breathing ]
- [ Buzzes ]
- Buzz Lightyear to Star Command.
Come in, Star Command.
-[ Buzzes ]
-Star Command, come
in. Do you read me?
Why don't they answer?
[ Gasps ] My ship!
Blast! This'll take
weeks to repair.
Buzz Lightyear mission log,
stardate 4-0-7-2.
My ship has run off course
en route to sector 12.
I've crash-landed
on a strange planet.
The impact must've awoken me
from hypersleep.
Terrain seems
a bit unstable.
No readout yet
if the air is breathable.
And there seems to be no sign
of intelligent life anywhere.
- Hello!
- [ Karate Yell ]
[ Screams ] Whoa! H-Hey!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Did I frighten you? Didn't mean to.
- [ Buzzing ]
- Sorry. Howdy. My name is Woody.
- [ Buzzing Continues ]
And this is Andy's room.
That's all I wanted to say.
And also, there has been
a bit of a mix-up.
This is my spot, see,
the bed here.
Local law enforcement.
It's about time you got here.
I'm Buzz Lightyear, Space Ranger,
Universe Protection Unit.
My ship has crash-landed
here by mistake.
Yes, it is a mistake because,
you see, the bed here is my spot.
I need to repair
my turbo boosters.
Do you people still use fossil fuel, or
have you discovered crystallic fusion?
- Well, let's see. We got double-A's.
- [ Gasps ]
Watch yourself!.
Halt! Who goes there?
Don't shoot!
It's okay. Friends.
- Do you know these life-forms?
- Yes! They're Andy's toys.
All right, everyone,
you're clear to come up.
I am Buzz Lightyear.
I come in peace.
Oh, I'm so glad
you're not a dinosaur!
Bye-bye. Thank you!
Now, thank you all
for your kind welcome!
- Say, what's that button do?
- I'll show you.
- [ Voice Box ]
Buzz Lightyear to the rescue!
- [ Toys ] Oh!
Hey, Woody's got something like that.
His is a pull string.
- Only it's--
- Only it sounds like a car ran over it.
[ Hamm ] Oh, yeah, but not like this.
This is a quality sound system.
Probably all
copper wiring, huh?
So, uh, where you from?
Singapore? Hong Kong?
Well, no. Actually, l-I'm stationed up
in the Gamma Quadrant of Sector Four.
As a member of the elite
Universe Protection Unit
of the Space Ranger Corps,
As a member of the elite
Universe Protection Unit
of the Space Ranger Corps,
As a member of the elite
Universe Protection Unit
of the Space Ranger Corps,
I protect the galaxy
from the threat of invasion...
from the evil Emperor Zurg,
sworn enemy of the Galactic Alliance.
Oh, really?
I'm from Playskool.
And I'm from Mattel.
Well, I'm not really from Mattel.
I'm actually from a smaller company that
was purchased in a leveraged buyout.
You'd think they'd never seen
a new toy before.
Well, sure. Look at him. He's got more
gadgets on him than a Swiss Army knife.
- [ Buzzing ]
- Ah, ah, ah, ah! Please be careful.
You don't want to be in the way
when my laser goes off.
Hey, a laser! How come
you don't have a laser, Woody?
It's not a laser! It's a--
It's a little light bulb that blinks.
- What's with him?
- Laser envy.
All right, that's enough!
- Look, we're all very impressed
with Andy's new toy.
- Toy?
T-O-Y. Toy!
Excuse me, l-I think the word
you're searching for is "Space Ranger."
The word I'm searching for I can't say
because there's preschool toys present.
Gettin' kinda tense,
aren't ya?
Uh, Mr. Lightyear,
uh, now, I'm curious.
What does a Space Ranger
actually do?
He's not a Space Ranger!
- He doesn't fight evil
or, or shoot lasers or fly!
- Excuse me.
- [ Toys ] Ooh!
- Oh, impressive wingspan! Very good!
Oh, what? What?
These are plastic. He can't fly!
They are a terillium-carbonic alloy,
and I can fly.
- No, you can't.
- [ Sighs ] Yes, I can.
- You can't.
- Can.
- Can't. Can't. Can't!
- I tell you, I could fly around
this room with my eyes closed!
- Okay, then, Mr. Light Beer, prove it.
- All right, then, I will.
Stand back, everyone!
[ Electronic Hum ]
To infinity and beyond!
[ Airplane Whirring ]
- Can!
-[ Rex ] Whoa!
- Oh, wow, you flew magnificently!
- [ Whistling ]
-I found my movin' buddy.
-Thank you. Th-Thank you all. Thank you.
That wasn't flying!
That was... falling with style.
Man, the dolls must really
go for you. Can you teach me that?
- [ Laughing ] Golly bob howdy!
- Oh, shut up!
You know, in a couple of days,
everything will be just
the way it was. They'll see.
- [ All Chattering ]
-[ Woody ] They'll see.
I'm still Andy's favorite toy.
I was on top of the world
livin'high
- [ Andy Laughing ] Whoa!
-It was right in my pocket
I was livin'the life
Things were just the way
they should be
When from out of the sky
like a bomb
Comes some little punk
in a rocket
[ Laser Buzzing ]
Now all of a sudden some
strange things are happening to me
Buzz Lightyear
to the rescue!
Strange
Things are happening to me
Things
-Strange
- Ha!
- Things are happening to me
- [ Loud Roar]
Ain't no doubt about it
I had friends
I had lots of friends
Now all my friends
are gone
And I'm doin'
the best I can
To carry on
-I had power
-[ Chorus ] Power
-I was respected
-Respected
But not anymore
And I've lost the love
of the one
Whom I adore
Let me tell you 'bout it
Strange
- Things are happenin'to me
- [ Slinky Grunts ]
Strange
Things
Things are happenin'
to me
Ain't no doubt about it
Strange
Things
- Things
-[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Grunts ]
Finally!
[ Sighs ]
Hey, who's got my hat?
[ Squeaks ]
Look, I'm Woody! Howdy, howdy, howdy!
Ah-ha! Ah-ha, ha, ha!
Gimme that!
Say there, Lizard and Stretchy Dog,
let me show you something.
It looks as though I've been
accepted into your culture.
- Your chief, Andy,
inscribed his name on me.
- [ Together] Wow!
With permanent ink too!
Well, I must get back
to repairing my ship.
Don't let it
get to you, Woody.
Uh... let what? I don't, uh--
What do you mean? Who?
I know Andy's
excited about Buzz.
But you know he'll always have
a special place for you.
- Yeah, like the attic. [ Chuckling ]
- All right, that's it!
- [ Tonal Humming Sound ]
- Hmm. Unidirectional bonding strip.
Mr. Lightyear
wants more tape.
[ Humming ]
Hmm?
Listen, Light Snack,
you stay away from Andy.
He's mine, and no one
is taking him away from me.
- What are you talking about?
Where's that bonding strip?
- [ Beeping Sound ]
And another thing:
Stop with this spaceman thing!
- It's getting on my nerves!
- Are you saying you wanna lodge
a complaint with Star Command?
Oh-ho, okay! Ooh, well, so you wanna
do it the hard way, huh?
- Don't even think about it, cowboy.
- Oh, yeah, tough guy?
- [ Mechanical Whoosh ]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Choking ]
[ Choking Continues ]
[ Panting, Sniffing ]
The air isn't... toxic.
How dare you open a spaceman's helmet
on an uncharted planet!
My eyeballs could've been
sucked from their sockets!
You actually think
you're the Buzz Lightyear?
[ Laughing ] Oh, all this time
I thought it was an act!
Hey, guys, look!
It's the real Buzz Lightyear!
You're mocking me,
aren't you?
Oh, no, no. No, no, no, no, no.
Buzz, look, an alien!
- Where?
- [ Laughing ]
-[ Laughing Continues ]
-[ Dog Barking ]
-[ Barking Continues ]
-[ Boy Laughing ] Yes!
- Whoa!
- Uh-oh.
- I thought he was at summer camp.
- They must've kicked him out
early this year.
- [ Robot Buzzing ]
- [ Rex ] Oh, no, not Sid!
-[ Sid Grunting ] Incoming!
-[ Dog Barking ]
- Who is it this time?
- l-- I can't-- I can't tell.
Hey, where's Lenny?
- Right here, Woody.
- Oh, no, I can't bear
to watch one of these again.
[ Woody ]
Oh, no, it's a Combat Carl.
- What's going on?
- Nothing that concerns
you spacemen;just us toys.
I'd better
take a look anyway.
-[ Sid Shouting ]
-[ Buzz ] Why is that soldier
strapped to an explosive device?
That's why: Sid.
- [ Barking ]
- Hmm, sure is a hairy fellow.
No, no, that's Scud,
you idiot.
- That is Sid.
- [ Sinister Laughter]
- You mean that happy child?
- That ain't no happy child.
He tortures toys,
just for fun!
- [ Barking ]
- [ Grunting ]
Well, then we've got
to do something.
What are you doing?
Get down from there!
- I'm gonna teach that boy a lesson.
- Yeah, sure. You go ahead.
- Melt him with your scary laser.
- [ Buzzing ]
Be careful with that!
It's extremely dangerous.
He's lighting it!
He's lighting it! Hit the dirt!
- [ Bo Screams ]
- Look out!
-[ Explosion ]
-[ Scud Barking ]
- Yes! He's gone! He's history!
- [ Laughing ] Whoo!
- I could've stopped him.
Buzz, I would love
to see you try.
Of course, I'd love
to see you as a crater.
- The sooner we move, the better.
-[ Sid Shouting ]
Yeah!
[ Laughing ]
[ Crickets Chirping ]
[ Andy ]
To infinity and beyond!
[ Imitates Rocket Sounds
And Explosions ]
All this packing
makes me hungry.
- What would you say to dinner
at, oh, Pizza Planet?
- Pizza Planet? Oh, cool!
[ Mom Laughs ] Go wash your hands,
and I'll get Molly ready.
-[ Andy ] Can I bring some toys?
- You can bring one toy.
-Just one?
- One toy?
- [ Sighs ]
- Hmm.
- Will Andy pick me?
- [ Liquid Swishing ]
" Don't count on it"?
[ Groans ]
[ Yells ]
[ Thud ]
[ Buzz Humming ]
[ Humming Continues ]
Mmm!
Buzz! Oh, Buzz!
Buzz Lightyear.
[ Panting ] Buzz Lightyear,
thank goodness. We've got trouble!
- Trouble? Where?
- Down there.Just down there.
A helpless toy, it's--
it's trapped, Buzz!
Then we've
no time to lose.
- I don't see anything!
- Oh, he's there!
Just,just keep looking!
- What kind of toy-- [ Gasps ]
- [ Gasps ]
Oh! Whoa, whoa! Oh!
- [ Screams ]
- [ Together] Buzz!
Buzz!
- [ Toys Chattering ]
-[ Slinky ]
I don't see him in the driveway.
- I think he bounced into Sid's yard!
- Oh! Buzz!
[ Horn Honking ]
Hey, everyone, R.C.'s trying to
say something. What is it, boy?
- He's saying that this was no accident.
- What do you mean?
- I mean Humpty-Dumpty
was pushed... by Woody!
- No!
-[ All ] What?
- Wait a minute.
You-- You don't think I meant
to knock Buzz out the window,
do you? Potato Head?
- That's Mr. Potato Head to you,
you back-stabbing murderer!
- [ Gasps ]
Now, it was an accident, guys.
Come on.
Now, you, you
gotta believe me.
We believe ya, Woody.
Right, Rex?
Well, ye-- N--
I don't like confrontations!
Where is your honor, dirt bag?
You are an absolute disgrace!
You don't deserve to-- Hey!
You couldn't handle Buzz cutting
in on your playtime, could you, Woody?
Didn't wanna face the fact that Buzz
just might be Andy's new favorite toy.
So you got rid of him.
Well, what if Andy starts playing
with me more, Woody, huh?
You gonna knock me
outta the window too?
- I don't think we should
give him the chance.
- [ Sergeant ] There he is, men.
- Frag him!
- Let's string him up
by his pull string!
-[ Hamm ] I got dibs on his hat!
-[ Bo ] Would you boys stop it!
- Tackle him!
- No, no, no! W-W-Wait!
I can explain everything!
[ Andy ] Okay, Mom, be right down.
I've gotta get Buzz.
[ Sergeant ]
Retreat!
Mom, do you know
where Buzz is?
-[ Mom ] No, I haven't seen him.
- Psst!
[ Mom ]
Andy, I'm heading out the door!
- But, Mom, I can't find him!
- Honey,just grab some other toy.
Now, come on!
Oh, okay.
I couldn't find my Buzz.
I know I left him right there.
Honey, I'm sure he's around.
You'll find him.
[ Ignition Starts ]
[ Chittering ]
It's too short!
We need more monkeys!
There aren't any more!
That's the whole barrel!
Buzz, the monkeys
aren't working!
We're formulating another plan!
Stay calm!
Oh, where could he be?
[ Service Bell Dings ]
- Can I help pump the gas?
-Sure! I'll even let you drive.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, when you're 16.
- Yuk,yuk,yuk! Funny, Mom.
-[ Laughing ]
Aw, great. How am I gonna convince
those guys it was an accident?
Buzz!
Buzz! Ha! You're alive!
This is great!
Oh, I'm saved! I'm saved.
Andy'll find you here;
he'll take us back to the room;
and then you can tell everyone
that this was all just a big mistake.
Huh? Right?
[ Panting ] Buddy?
I just want you to know that even
though you tried to terminate me,
revenge is not an idea
we promote on my planet.
- Oh. Well, that's good.
- But we're not on my planet, are we?
- No. [ Screaming ]
- [ Buzz Grunting ]
[ Buzz Grunting,
Spacesuit Buzzing, Beeping ]
[ Screaming, Groans ]
Okay, come on!
You want a piece of me?
[ Yells ]
[ Squeaking ]
- Owww!
- [ Voice Box ] Buzz, Buzz,
Buzz Lightyear to the rescue.
- Aah-ouch!
-[ Mom ] Next stop.
- Pizza Planet! Yeah!
-[ Door Slides Shut, Ignition Starts ]
-[ Door Shuts ]
- [ Gasps ] Andy!
[ Panting ] Wh-- Doesn't he realize
that I'm not there?
[ Loud Gasp ]
I'm lost!
[ Sobs ]
Oh, I'm a lost toy!
[ Sniffling, Sobbing ]
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
The local sheriff and I seem to be at
a huge refueling station of some sort.
- You!
-[ Truck Approaching, Horn Honking ]
[ Brakes Squealing ]
[ Engine Idling ]
- According to my nava-computer, the--
- [ Gasps ] Shut up!
-Just shut up, you idiot!
- Sheriff, this is no time to panic.
This is the perfect time to panic.
I'm lost. Andy is gone.
They're gonna move from their house
in two days, and it's all your fault!
My-- My fault? If you hadn't pushed me
out of the window in the first place--
Oh, yeah?
Well, if you...
hadn't shown up in your stupid
little cardboard spaceship
and taken away everything...
- that was important to me--
- Don't talk to me about importance!
Because of you the security
of this entire universe is in jeopardy!
What? What are
you talkin' about?
Right now, poised at
the edge of the galaxy, Emperor Zurg...
has been secretly building
a weapon...
with the destructive capacity
to annihilate an entire planet!
I alone have information that reveals
this weapon's only weakness.
And you, my friend,
are responsible...
for delaying my rendezvous
with Star Command!
You... are... a... toy!
You aren't the real
Buzz Lightyear! You're a--
You're an action figure!
You are a child's plaything!
You are a sad, strange little man;
and you have my pity.
- Farewell.
- Oh, yeah?
Well, good riddance, ya loony!
- " Rendezvous with Star Command."
-[ Car Approaching ]
-[ Driver ] Hey, gas dude!
-[ Attendant ] You talkin'to me?
- Yeah, man. Can you help me?
- Pizza Planet? Andy!
- Do you know where
Cutting Boulevard is?
- Oh, no!
I can't show my face
in that room without Buzz.
- Buzz! Buzz, come back!
- Go away!
No! Buzz, you gotta
come back! l--
-[ Engine Revving ]
- I found a spaceship!
It's a spaceship, Buzz!
Come on, man, hurry up! Um, like,
the pizzas are getting cold here!
-[ Attendant ]
Uh, Cutting Boulevard, huh?
- Yeah,yeah. Which way?
Now, you're sure this space freighter
will return to its port of origin...
- once it jettisons its food supply?
- Uh-huh.
And when we get there, we'll be able
to find a way to transport you home.
- Well, then, let's climb aboard.
- No, no, no, wait, Buzz! Buzz!
- Let's get in the back.
No one will see us there.
- Negative.
There are no restraining
harnesses in the cargo area.
- We'll be much safer in the cockpit.
- Yeah, bu--
- Buzz! Buzz!
-[ Driver ]
That's two lefts and a right, huh?
- Thanks for the directions, okay?
- Yeah. And remember, kid--
- Buzz!
- [ Ignition Starts ]
[ Screams ]
It's safer in the cockpit
than the cargo bay. What an idiot.
- [ Tires Screech ]
- [ Grunts, Groans ]
-[ Stereo.:Rock ]
- [ Tires Squealing ]
[ Yelling, Groaning ]
[ Screams ]
[ Car Horn Honking ]
- [ Brakes Screech ]
-[ Door Signal Buzzing ]
[ Man On P.A.]
Next shuttle liftoff is scheduled for...
- T-minus 30 seconds and counting.
- [Jets Humming ]
[ Robot ]
You are clear to enter.
Welcome to Pizza Planet.
[ Woman On P.A.]
The white zone is for immediate pizza--
- Sheriff!.
- [ Grunts, Groans ]
There you are.
Now, the entrance is heavily guarded.
We need a way to get inside.
- [ Coughing ]
- Great idea, Woody.
I like your thinkin'.
[ Robot ]
You are clear to enter.
- Welcome to Pizza Planet.
- [ Buzz ] Now!
Quickly, Sheriff!.
The air lock is closing.
[ Woman On P.A.]Jones, party
of five,your shuttle is now boarding--
[ Boy ]
Hey, Mom, can we have some tokens?
Ow! Watch
where you're going!
Sorry.
[ Groans ]
[ Man On P.A.]
...nine, eight, seven, six,
- five, four, three,
- [ Children Shouting ]
two, one.
What a spaceport!
Good work, Woody.
[ Beeping, Fires ]
Mom, can I play Black Hole?
Please, please, please?
- Andy!
- Now, we need to find a ship
that's headed for Sector 12.
Wait a minute.
No, no, no, Buzz! This way.
- There's a special ship.
I just saw it.
- You mean it has hyperdrive?
Hyperactive hyperdrive.
- [ Chattering ]
-And Astro, uh, turf!
- Where is it? l-I don't see the--
- Come on. That's it.
Spaceship!
All right, Buzz,
get ready. And--
- And the universe explodes!
- Okay, Buzz, when I say go,
we're gonna jump in the basket.
Buzz!
- [ Grunts ] No!
- [ Andy ]
Hey, Mom, if I eat all my pizza,
- can I have some alien slime?
- This cannot be happening to me.
[ Gasps ]
[ Objects Squeaking ]
- A stranger.
- From the outside.
- [ Aliens Together] Ooh!
- Greetings. I am Buzz Lightyear.
- I come in peace.
- [ All Gibbering ]
[ Man On P.A.] Before your
space journey, re-energize yourself...
with a slice of pepperoni,
now boarding at counter three.
[ Buzz ]
This is an intergalactic emergency.
I need to commandeer
your vessel to Sector 12.
Who's in charge here?
[ Aliens ]
The claw!
- The claw is our master.
- The claw chooses who
will go and who will stay.
- This is ludicrous. [ Gasps ]
- Hey, bozo,you got a brain in there?
- [ Laughing ] Take that!
- [ Buzzing ]
Oh, no! Sid!
- Get down!
- [ Grunts ]
- What's gotten into you? I wa--
- You are the one that decided
to climb into this--
Shh! The claw, it moves.
[ Aliens Squeaking ]
[ Squeaks ]
I have been chosen!
Farewell, my friends.
I go on to a better place.
Gotcha!
A Buzz Lightyear?
No way!
-[ Coin Clicking ]
-[ Alien Squeaks ]
[ Squeak ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Claw Buzzing ]
- [ Sid ] Yes!
- [ Gasps ]
Buzz! No!
[ Grunting ]
- Hey!
- [ Grunting ]
- He has been chosen!
- He must go.
- Hey!
- What are you doing? Stop it!
Stop it, you zealots!
- Do not fight the claw.
All right!
Double prizes!
Let's go home and... play.
[ Sinister Chuckle ]
[ Chatters, Grunts ]
[ Humming ]
Sheriff, I can see
your dwelling from here.
- You're almost home.
- Nirvana is coming.
The mystic portal awaits.
Will you be quiet?
You guys don't get it, do you?
Once we go into Sid's house,
we won't be coming out.
- [ Barking ]
- Whoa, Scud! Hey, boy!
-Sit! Good boy.
- [ Growling ]
- Hey, I got something for you, boy.
- Freeze!
- [ Growls, Panting ]
- Ready, set, now!
- [ Snarling ]
- [ Alien Squeaking ]
Hannah!
Hey, Hannah!
- What?
- Did I get my package in the mail?
- I don't know.
- What do you mean you don't know?
- I don't know!
-[ Sighs ]
- Oh, no, Hannah! Look,Janie!
- What? Hey!
- She's sick!
- No, she's not!
- I'll have to perform
one of my operations.
-[ Hannah ] No!
- No, not Sid's room. Not there.
- Hey, give it back!
Sid! Sid!
- Oh, no, we have
a sick patient here, Nurse.
-[ Banging On Door ]
- Prepare the O.R., stat!
[ Sinister Chuckle ]
-[ Hannah Shouting ]
Patient is... prepped.
No one's ever attempted
a double bypass...
brain transplant before.
Now for the tricky part.
Pliers!
I don't believe that man's
ever been to medical school.
[ Chuckles, Imitates Nurse ]
Doctor, you've done it!
Hannah!
-Janie's all better now.
- [ Screaming ]
-[ Hannah ] Mom! Mom!
-[ Sid ] She's lying!
Whatever she says,
it's not true!
[ Departing Footfalls ]
[ Gasping, Shuddering ]
[ Voice Quavering ]
We are gonna die.
I'm outta here!
Locked.
- There's gotta be
another way outta here.
-[ Rustling ]
Uh, Buzz?
W-Was that you?
- [ Teeth Chattering, Gasps ]
-[ Creaking ]
[ Rustling ]
[ Creaking ]
Hey, hi there,
little fella.
Come out here.
Do you know a way outta here?
[ Gasps, Teeth Chattering ]
[ Gasps ]
- [ Gasps ]
-["Pop Goes the Weasel"]
[ Yells, Muttering, Gibbering ]
B-B-B-B-Bu-- Buzz!
- They're cannibals.
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Buzzes ]
- Mayday, mayday.
- Come in, Star Command.
Send reinforcements.
- [ Teeth Chattering ]
Star Command, do you copy?
- [ Buzzing ]
- I've set my laser from stun to kill.
Aw, great. Great. Yeah, and if anyone
attacks us, we can blink 'em to death.
-[ Rustling ]
- [ Rex ] Hey, you guys,
I think I found him!
- Buzz, is that you?
-[ Cat Yowls ]
Whiskers, will you
get outta here!
- You're interfering
with the search and rescue!
-[ Car Approaching ]
[ Gasps ]
Look, they're home.
Mom, have you seen Woody?
- Where was the last place
you left him?
- Right here in the van.
Oh, I'm sure he's there.
You're just not looking hard enough.
He's not here, Mom.
Woody's gone.
[ Gasps ]
Woody's gone?
Yeah, boy,
the weasel ran away.
Huh? Huh?
I told you he was guilty.
Who would've thought he was capable
of such atrocities?
Oh, Slink,
I hope he's okay.
[ Sid ] Oh, a survivor.
Where's the rebel base? Talk!
I can see
your will is strong.
Well, we have ways
of making you talk.
[ Sizzling ]
Where are your rebel friends now?
[ Sinister Chuckle ]
[ Sid's Mom ]
Sid,your Pop Tarts are ready!
All right!
-[ Sizzling Continues ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Grunting ]
Are you all right?
I'm proud of you, Sheriff.
A lesser man would've talked
under such torture.
I sure hope
this isn't permanent.
Still no word from Star Command.
We're not that far from the space port.
The door. It's open!
We're free!
-Woody, we don't know what's out there!
-I'll tell you wha-- [ Screams ]
- They're gonna eat us, Buzz!
Do something quick!
- Shield your eyes.
[ Buzzing ]
It's not working. I recharged it
before I left. l-It should be good for--
You idiot! You're a toy!
Use your karate chop action!
- Get away! Hoo-cha!
- Hey! Hey! How're you
doin' that? Stop that.
Back! Back,
you savages! Back!
- Woody, stop it!
- Sorry, guys, but dinner's canceled!
There's no place like home!
- There's no place like home. [ Gasps ]
- [ Snarling ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Muffled Yell,
Gasping ]
Another stunt like that,
cowboy, you're gonna get us killed.
- Don't tell me what to do.
- Shh!
[ Snoring Continues ]
[ Heavy Breathing ]
[ Voice Box ]
Yee-haw! Giddyap, pardner!
- We got to get this wagon
train a-movin'!
- [ Snarling ]
[ Growling ]
- Split up!
-[ Scud Growling ]
[ Sniffing ]
[ Snarling ]
Hmm?
[ Growling ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Snarls, Panting ]
[ Man ] Calling Buzz Lightyear.
Come in, Buzz Lightyear.
- This is Star Command.
Buzz Lightyear, do you read me?
- Star Command!
[ Boy ] Buzz Lightyear responding.
Read you loud and clear.
Buzz Lightyear,
planet Earth needs your help.
- [ Boy ] On the way!
- [ Chorus ] Buzz Lightyear!
[ Announcer ]
The world's greatest superhero!
Now the world's greatest toy!
Buzz has it all!
Locking wrist communicator!
-[ Boy ] Calling Buzz Lightyear!
- Karate chop action!
- [ Boy ] Wow!
- Pulsating laser light!
-[ Boy ] Total annihilation!
- Multi-phase voice simulator!
[ Voice Box ] There's a secret
mission in uncharted space.
[ Voice Box ] There's
a secret mission in uncharted space.
And best of all,
high pressure space wings!
- To infinity and beyond!
- [ Announcer #2 ] Not a flying toy.
[ Announcer #1 ]
Get your Buzz Lightyear action figure...
- and save a galaxy near you!
- [ Chorus ] Buzz Lightyear!
Available at all Al's Toy Barn outlets
in the Tri-county area.
[ Sportscaster ]
And welcome back...
to the Point Richmond
Bowling Championship.
[ Sportscaster Continues ]
Out among the stars I sit
Way beyond the moon
In my silver ship I sailed
To a dream
that ended too soon
Now I know exactly
- Who I am and what I'm here for
- [ Chirping ]
[ Woody's Voice ]
You are a toy! You can't fly!
And I will go sailing
No more
But no, it can't be true
I could fly if I wanted to
Like a bird in the sky
If I believed I could fly
Why, I'd fly
To infinity and beyond!
Clearly, I
Will go sailing
No more
- Mom! Mom, have you seen
my Sally doll?
- [ Click ]
[ Mom ]
What, dear? What was that?
Never mind!
[ Rattling ]
Oof!. Oof!.
[ Groans ]
Buzz, the coast is clear.
Buzz, where are you?
[ Buzz's Voice Box ] There's a secret
mission. in uncharted space. Let's go.
[ Hannah ]
Really? That is so interesting.
Would you like some tea,
Mrs. Nesbitt?
- [ Gasps ] Buzz!
- It's so nice you could join us
on such late notice.
- Oh, no!
- What a lovely hat, Mrs. Nesbitt.
It goes quite well
with your head.
[ Clears Throat, Imitating Mother]
Hannah! Oh, Hannah!
Mom? Please excuse me, ladies.
I'll be right back.
What is it, Mom?
Mom, where are you?
Buzz. Hey.
Buzz, are you okay?
[ Slurring ] Gone!
[ Sniffles ] It's all gone.
All of it's gone.
Bye-bye. Whoo-whoo. See ya.
- What happened to you?
- One minute you're defending
the whole galaxy.
And suddenly you find
yourself suckin' down Darjeeling with...
Marie Antoinette
and her little sister.
[ Chuckles ]
I think you've had
enough tea for today.
Let's get you
outta here, Buzz.
Don't you get it?
You see the hat?
- I am Mrs. Nesbitt! Ha-ha-ha-ha!
- Snap out of it, Buzz!
[ Hysterical Chuckling,
Squeaks ]
l-l-l-- I'm sorry. l--
You're right.
I am just a little depressed.
That's all.
l-- I can get through this.
- Oh, I'm a sham!
- Shh!
- Look at me.
- Quiet, Buzz.
I can't even
fly out of a window.
The hat look good?
Tell me the hat look good.
- The apron is a bit much.
- "Out the window"!
Buzz, you're a genius!
- [ Crying ]
- Come on, come on. This way.
Years of academy,
training, wasted!
Ha, ha. B-3.
- Miss! G-6.
- Oh!
- You sunk it. Are you peeking?
- Heh, heh!
Oh, quit your whinin' and pay up.
No, no, not the ear.
- Give me the nose. Come on.
- How about three out of five?
[ Straining ]
Hey, guys! Guys! Hey!
- Son of a building block. It's Woody.
- He's in the psycho's bedroom.
- Ha, ha! Hi!
- Everyone! It's Woody!
- Woody?
- You're kidding!
Ha! We're gonna
get outta here, Buzz.
Buzz?
[ Imitating Airplane ]
[ Sputtering, Crashing ]
- Hey, look!
- Woody!
Oh, boy, am I glad
to see you guys.
- I knew you'd come back, Woody.
- What are you doin' over there?
It's a long story, Bo.
I'll explain later.
Here! Catch this!
[ Bo ]
Ha!
- Whoa! I've got it, Woody.
- He got it, Woody.
Good goin', Slick. Now just,
just tie it on to somethin'.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait. I got
a better idea. How 'bout we don't?
- Hey!
- Potato Head.
- Did you all take
stupid pills this morning?
Have you forgotten
what he did to Buzz?
And now you wanna let him
back over here?
No! No, no, no, no, no! You got it--
You got it all wrong, Potato Head.
Buzz is fine. Buzz is right here.
He's with me!
- You are a liar!
- No, I'm not. Buzz, come over here.
Tell the nice boys that you're--
that you're not dead.
[ Gasps, Sputters ]
Just a sec!
Buzz, will you get up here
and give me a hand?
[ Chuckling ]
That's very funny, Buzz.
- This is serious!
-[ Rex ] Hey, Woody! Where'd ya go?
[ Potato Head ]
He's lying. Buzz ain't there.
Oh! Hi, Buzz!
Why don't you say hello
to the guys over there?
[ As Buzz ]
Hiya, fellas! To infinity and beyond!
Hey, look!
It's Buzz!
Hey, Buzz, let's show the guys
our new secret best friends handshake.
Give me five, man!
Something's screwy here.
So you see we're friends now, guys.
Aren't we, Buzz?
[ As Buzz ]
You bet. Give me a hug.
Ho-ho! Boy, I love you too.
See? It is Buzz.
- Now give back the lights, Potato Head.
- Wait just a minute.
- What are you tryin' to pull?
- Nothing!
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Group Murmuring ]
- [ Grunts, Retches ]
- Oh, that is disgusting.
- Murderer!
- No! No, no, no, no, no!
- You murdering dog!
- It's not what you think. I swear!
- Save it for the jury.
I hope Sid pulls
your voice box out, ya creep.
No, no! No, no!
Don't leave! Don't leave!
Ya gotta help us, please! You don't
know what it's like over here!
Come on.
Let's get outta here.
Go back to your lives, citizens.
Show's over.
[ Woody ]
Come back! Slink!
Slink! Please!
Please! Listen to me!
No! No! Come back!
Slinky!
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Thumping, Clattering ]
Buzz! Go away!
You disgusting freaks!
Aaah!
All right, back!
Back, you cannibals! Aah! Oof!.
He is still alive, and you're
not gonna get him,you monsters!
What are you doin'?
Hey. Hey, they fixed you.
But-- But they're cannibals.
We saw them eat
those other toys.
[ Quacks ]
Uh, sorry. l-l-I thought
that you were gonna--
[ Chuckles ]
You know, you know, eat my friend.
[ Woody ]
Hey, no, no, wait, hey!
- What's wrong?
-[ Sid's Mom ] Sid?
[ Sid ]
Not now, Mom! I'm busy!
- Sid! Buzz, come on!
-[ Mom ] You left that door open.
Get up! Use your legs! Fine!
Let Sid trash you, but don't blame me!
It came!
It finally came!
Ha, ha!
"The Big One."
" Extremely dangerous.
Keep out of reach of children. "
Cool!
What am I gonna blow?
Man. Hey, where's
that wimpy cowboy doll?
[ Buzz Buzzing ]
Yes. I've always wanted
to put a spaceman into orbit.
-[ Tape Peeling ]
-[ Sid ] Heh, heh.
Now. Yes.
[ Sinister Chuckle ]
-[ Thunderclap ]
- Oh, no!
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Oh, man!
Sid Phillips reporting.
Launch of the shuttle
has been delayed...
due to adverse weather
conditions at the launch site.
Tomorrow's forecast: sunny.
[ Sinister Chuckle ]
Sweet dreams.
[ Footfalls Approaching ]
[ Mom ] I looked everywhere, honey,
but all I could find was your hat.
But what if we
leave them behind?
Oh, don't worry, honey.
I'm sure we'll find Woody
and Buzz before we leave tomorrow.
[ Door Creaks, Closes ]
[ Rex Gasps ]
I need air!
Why will you quit
movin' around?
I'm sorry. It's just that I get--
I get so nervous before I travel.
How did I get stuck
with you as a moving buddy?
Everyone else was picked.
[ Snoring ]
[ Bo ]
Oh, Woody.
If only you could see
how much Andy misses you.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Straining ]
Psst. Psst! Hey, Buzz!
Hey.
Get over here and see if
you can get this toolbox off me.
Oh, come on, Buzz, l--
Buzz, I can't do this without you.
I need your help.
I can't help.
I can't help anyone.
Why, sure you can, Buzz.
You can get me outta here.
Then I'll get that rocket off you,
and we'll make a break for Andy's house.
Andy's house, Sid's house.
What's the difference?
Oh, Buzz. You've had a big fall.
You must not be thinking clearly.
No, Woody. For the first time
I am thinking clearly.
You were right all along.
I'm not a Space Ranger.
I'm just a toy, a stupid,
little, insignificant toy.
Whoa, hey, wait a minute.
Bein' a toy is a lot better
than bein' a, a Space Ranger.
- Yeah, right.
- No, it is.
Look, over in that house is a kid
who thinks you are the greatest.
And it's not because
you're a Space Ranger, pal.
It's because you're a toy.
You are his toy.
But why would Andy want me?
Why would Andy want you? Look at you!
You're a Buzz Lightyear.
Any other toy would give up
his moving parts just to be you.
You've got wings.
You glow in the dark. You talk!
Your helmet does
that, that, that whoosh thing.
You are a cool toy.
As a matter of fact,
you're too cool.
I mean, I mean, what chance
does a toy like me have...
against a Buzz Lightyear
action figure?
All I can do is--
[ Voice Box ]
There's a snake in my boots.
Why would Andy ever want
to play with me...
when he's got you?
I'm the one that should be
strapped to that rocket.
[ Birds Chirping ]
Listen, Buzz,
forget about me.
You should get outta here
while you can.
[ Chirping Continues ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Clattering ]
Buzz? What are you doin'?
I thought you were--
Come on, Sheriff. There's a kid
over in that house who needs us.
Now let's get you out of this thing.
[ Grunts ]
Yes, sir!
- [ Straining ]
- Come on, Buzz. We can do it.
- [ Grunts ]
-[ Engine Approaching ]
Woody, it's the moving van.
We gotta get outta here now.
[ Grunts ]
Come on, Buzz.
All right.
[ Grunts ] Buzz!
- Hey, I'm out!
- Almost there.
[ Sputters ]
I want to ride the pony. [ Snores ]
Phew. Woody?
Woody? Are you all right?
I'm fine. I'm okay.
[ Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
[ Clock Clatters On Floor,
Ringing Stops ]
Oh, yeah!
Time for liftoff!. Whoo!
To infinity and beyond!
Whoo-hoo!
[ Growls, Barks,
Snarling ]
- Aah! Back, back.
-[ Barks, Yelps ]
- Down, down!
-[ Barks ]
- Okay, what do I do?
Come on, Woody. Think.
-[ Toys Clattering ]
Guys!
No, no, no, no! Wait!
Wait. Listen, please.
There's a good toy down there, and he's
gonna be blown to bits in a few minutes.
All because of me.
We've gotta save him.
And, uh--
But I need your help.
[ Toy Creaking ]
Please. He's my friend.
And he's the only one
I've got.
[ Tapping Morse Code ]
-[ Toy Trumpeting ]
-[ Tapping Continues ]
Thank you.
Okay, I think I know what to do.
We're gonna have
to break a few rules.
But if it works,
it'll help everybody.
[ Sighs ]
-[ Pounding ]
-[ Sid ] Houston to Mission Control.
Come in, Control.
Launch pad is
being constructed.
- [ Growls ]
-[ Woody ] All right, listen up.
I need Pump Boy here,
Ducky here.
- Legs, you're with Ducky.
- [ Quacks ]
RollerBob and I don't move
till we get the signal. Clear?
- [ Quacks ]
- Okay. Let's move!
[ Barks ]
[ Barking Continues ]
[ Quacks ]
Wind the frog.
-  [ " Pop Goes the Weasel" ]
-[ Dog Snarls ]
- [ Chitters ]
-[ Frog Revs ]
[ Straining ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
- Wait for the signal.
-[ Frog Revs ]
[ Quacks, Mutters ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Blubbers ]
- [ Ringing ]
- Go!
- [ Growls ]
- [ Engine Revving ]
- [ Barks ]
- All right, let's go!
[ Hannah ]
I'll get it!
Now!
- I'm coming. I'm coming.
-[ Ringing Continues ]
- [ Quacks ]
-[ Barking Continues ]
[ Barking ]
- [ Yelps ]
- Scud!
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Snarls ]
- [ Barks ]
- Stupid dog.
[ Barking Continues ]
Lean back!
[ Sid ] Uh, Mission Control, is
the launch pad construction complete?
Uh, roger. Rocket is now
secured to guide wire.
We are currently obtaining
the ignition sticks.
- Countdown will commence
momentarily. Stand by.
- Let's go.
Hey, Ma! Where are the matches?
Oh, wait. Here they are. Never mind.
- Woody! Great!
Help me outta this thing.
- Shh!
- What?
- It's okay.
Everything's under control.
- [ Whispering ]
Woody, what are you doing?
- Houston.
All systems are go.
Requesting permission to launch--
Hey? How'd you get out here?
Oh, well. You and I
can have a cookout later.
[ Chuckles ]
Houston, do we have
permission to launch?
[ Imitating Radio Static ]
Uh, roger. Permission granted.
You are confirmed
at "T"minus ten seconds.
And counting.
Ten, nine,
eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two,
- one!
-[ Woody's Voice Box ]
Reach for the sky!
- Huh?
- This town ain't big enough
for the two of us.
- What?
- Somebody's poisoned the water hole.
- It's busted.
- Who are you callin' busted, buster?
- [ Whimpers ]
- That's right.
- I'm talking to you, Sid Phillips.
- [ Gasps ]
- We don't like bein' blown up,
Sid, or smashed or ripped apart.
- "We"?
That's right!
Your toys!
Mama!
Mama! Mama!
[ Gasps ]
[ Squeaks ]
Aaah!
[ Gasps ]
- [ Gasps ]
- Mama!
From now on, you must take
good care of your toys!
Because if you don't,
we'll find out, Sid.
We toys can see
everything.
So play nice.
Aaah!
Ha-ha! We did it!
We did it! Ha-ha! Yes!
The toys!
The toys are alive!
N-Nice toy.
Aaah!
- [ Whimpers ]
- What's wrong, Sid?
- Don't you want to play with Sally?
-[ Sid Sobbing ]
Nice work, fellows.
Good job.
Comin' out of the ground, what a touch.
That was a stroke of genius.
Woody.
- Thanks.
-[ Horn Honks ]
[ Woman ]
Everybody say, "Bye, house!"
- Woody! The van!
-[ Andy ] Bye, house.
[ Grunts ]
- We gotta run! Thanks, guys!
-[ Car Door Slides Closed ]
[ Ignition Starting ]
- Quick!
- [ Grunts ]
[ Engine Revving ]
Just go.
I'll catch up.
[ Grunts ]
[ Truck Approaching ]
[ Both ]
Aaah!
Come on!
[ Growls ]
- [ Grunts ]
- You can do it, Woody!
[ Grunts ]
I got it! Woo-hoo-hoo!
-[ Scud Barking ]
- I made it.
- [ Gasps ]
Aaah! Get away,
you stupid dog! Down!
- Down! Aah! Aah!
- Hold on, Woody!
[ Grunts ]
I can't do it.
-[ Cloth Ripping ]
- Take care of Andy for me!
- No!
- [ Yelps ]
- Buzz!
- [ Snarling ]
[ Snarling, Barking ]
- [ Grunts ]
-[ Scud Barking ]
- Ow!
- Are we there already?
- Woody?
- How did you--
- How'd he get here?
- Where have you--
- What happened?
- Ow!
- What's goin' on?
- What's he takin'?
- Aha! There you are!
- Hey. What's he doing?
- [ Whimpers ]
- Aah!
- He's at it again!
- [ Barks ]
- [ Horn Beeping ]
-[ Barking ]
- [ Engine Revving ]
Ha, ha, ha!
- Get him!
- Come on!
[ Gasps ]
[ Barking ]
- [ Roars ]
- Ah, ah, no, no!
[ Barks ]
- [ Barks ]
- No, no, no, no! Wait!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
- [ Barks ]
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
[ Groans ]
[ Barks, Pants ]
- Pig pile!
- [ Grunts ]
Aaah!
[ Horn Honking,
Tires Screeching ]
- [ Barking ]
- [ Horns Honking ]
-[ Woman ] Get outta that car!
-[ Man ] Move it!
Whew.
No! Please!
You don't understand!
Buzz is out there.
We gotta help him.
- No!
- Toss him overboard!
No, no, no!
Wait! Aah!
- Hooray!
- So long, Woody!
- [ Sighs ]
-[ Horn Honking ]
Aah!
Oh! Woody!
- Oh! Well, thanks for the ride.
- Look out!
Aaah!
- Now let's catch up to that truck.
- [ Beeps ]
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
Guys! Guys! Woody's riding R.C.
- What?
- And Buzz is with him!
- [ Horn Beeping ]
- It is Buzz!
Woody was telling the truth.
- What have we done?
- Great! Now I have guilt.
We're almost there!
Rocky, the ramp!
[ Grunts ]
Look out!
Quick! Hold onto my tail!
- Attaboy, Slink!
- Oh! Woody!
Woody! Speed up!
- Speed up!
- The batteries!
They're runnin'out!
[ Slinky ]
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa! Aah!
[ Timon And Pumbaa ]
Hakuna Matata
What a wonderful phrase
- [ Giggles ]
- Aaah!
- I can't hold on much longer.
- Slink! Hang on!
- Aaah!
- Ouch!
[ Mourning Dove Cooing ]
Great!
Woody! The rocket!
The match! Yes!
Thank you, Sid!
[ Car Approaching ]
No! No, no! No!
No! Oh, no!
No, no, no, no, no,
no!
[ Sobs ]
No!
- Woody! What are you doing?
- Hold still, Buzz!
- Ha-ha! Ha-ha!
- You did it!
Next stop.:Andy!
Wait a minute. I just lit a rocket.
Rockets explode!
[ Teeth Chattering ]
I should have
held on longer.
Look! Look! It's Woody
and Buzz comin' up fast!
Woody!
[ Rex ]
Aah! Take cover!
Aaah! This is the part
where we blow up!
Not today!
[ Fireworks Crackling ]
Aaah!
Hey, Buzz!
You're flyin'!
This isn't flying.
This is falling with style.
[ Woody ]
Ha-ha-ha!
To infinity and beyond!
Uh, Buzz,
we missed the truck.
We're not aiming
for the truck.
[ Thudding ]
Hey, wow!
-[ Mother ] What? What is it?
- Woody! Buzz!
- Oh, great,you found them.
Where were they?
- Here in the car!
See? Now, what'd I tell you?
Right where you left 'em.
[ Giggles ]
- Which one can I open first?
- Let's let Molly open one.
[ Sergeant ]
Frankincense, this is Myrrh.
- Hey, heads up, everybody.
It's show time.
- Whoa! It's time!
Ohh! Oh, Bo.
There's got to be a less painful way
to get my attention.
Merry Christmas,
Sheriff.
- Say, isn't that mistletoe?
- Mm-hmm.
- Ooh!
-[ Kissing Sounds, Bo Giggles ]
Maybe Andy will get
another dinosaur.
Like a leaf eater. That way
I could play the, uh, dominant predator.
Quiet, everyone!
Quiet!
[ Sergeant ] Molly's first
present is Mrs. Potato Head.
Repeat: a Mrs. Potato Head.
Way to go, Idaho!
Gee, I'd better shave.
-[ Radio Whining ]
-[ Sergeant ] Come in, Frankincense.
Andy is now opening
his first present.
- It's --[ Static ]
- Buzz. Buzz Lightyear,
-[ Sergeant ] I can't quite--
-you are not worried, are you?
- Me? No, no. Pfft.
-[ Sergeant ] Make out--
No. No, no, no, no. Mm-mm.
[ Sergeant ]
A large box-- It's-- It's-- It's--
- Are you?
- [ Chuckles ] Now, Buzz,
what could Andy possibly get
that is worse than you?
[ Andy On Monitor]
Oh, what is it? What is it?
- [ Puppy Barking ]
- [ Andy ] Wow! A puppy!
[ Chuckles ]
Ooo, ooo, ooo, ooo
You've got a friend in me
When the road looks rough ahead
And you're miles and miles
from your nice, warm bed
You just remember
what your old pal said
Boy,you've got a friend in me
Yeah,you've got a friend in me
You've got a friend in me
- You got troubles
-And I got 'em too
There isn't anything
I wouldn't do for you
If we stick together
we can see it through
'Cause you've got a friend in me
You've got a friend in me
Some other folks might be
a little bit smarter than I am
Bigger and stronger too
Maybe
But none of them will ever
love you the way I do
[ Together ]
It's me and you, boy
And as the years go by
Our friendship will never die
You're gonna see it's our destiny
You've got a friend in me