♪Egyptian, German, Polish, Arabic
and Russian parts translated by by♪  XQ2☻♥
Death to the false god.
Protect him.
Ten fights, ten victories.
The winged warrior,
The Bird of Prey,
The Angel of Death:
Angel!
A round of applause for Porky!
The next contender
comes directly
from the Munich Circus
Ladies and gentlemen
the only one who could confront an angel
is the Devil himself
We presnt you
the astounding
the fantastic
Nightcrawler!
High voltage,
the mutant's lament!
Are you lost, little mouse?
The fight's over there.
You're hot.
Ah, you think so?
They're over there!
- Good night, Henryk
- Same to you, Milos
- Hi, darling.
- Hi.
You sell carpets?
You can't come in here.
Is the carpet for sale?
I told you...
Earthquake!
Are you all right?
She's fine.
- Then let her go.
- We'll let her go.
We just want to talk.
You're not wearing badges.
No metal.
Some men say they saw something
in the factory, today
Something that doesn't make sense.
Hold your weapons.
You've been a good citizen, Henryk.
A good neighbor, a good worker...
- I've been told.
- It's true.
But no one in town
knows the truth.
Everybody knows.
I am Henryk Gurzsky
Jakub, I've eaten
with you at your home
And you lied the whole time.
I let a murderer into my home.
Is this you?
Are you the one they call Magneto?
I'll turn myself in.
Please let my daughter go.
Go with your mother.
Please.
Don't leave me.
I won't let them take you away.
What is it?
Is she one of them?
- Tell her to stop.
- She can't control it.
You frighten her.
I won't let them take you!
Make her stop!
Do you know what we do to thieves?
Choose a hand.
Enough.
If you're wth her, I suggest
you leave while you still can.
Go.
Who rules this world?
What language is that?
Clown! What's your weapon?
Take it out.
Sorry.
Do you feel sorry, really?
Now, you do.
I've never seen another
mutant in this city.
Do you speak Egyptian? Arabic?
Purified.
Henryk, please.
Don't do this.
All your towers and temples
shall fall.
The dawn of a new era will arise.