Even now I can feel it
Buried somewhere deep inside.
... watching me.
... waiting.
But you know what scares me the most?
When I can't fight it anymore...
... when it takes over ...
... when I totally lose control ...
... I like it.
Who am I? You sure you want to know?
The story of my life is not for the faint of heart.
If somebody said it was a happy little tale,
If somebody told you I was just your average ordinary
guy, not a care in the world,
Somebody lied.
But let me assure you
This like any story worth telling,
is all about a girl.
That girl.
The girl next door.  Mary Jane Watson.
The woman I've loved since before I even liked girls.
I'd like to tell you that's me next to her,
Aw heck, I'd even take him.
Hey stop the bus! [Laughing from inside the bus]
That's me.
Tell him to stop please!
Hey stop the bus!
Stop the bus! He's been chasing us since Woodhind Blvd.
Thank you.  Sorry I'm late.
Don't even think about it.
You're so lame Parker.
Midtown High Seniors, No wandering.
Proceed direct ...Knock it off...
Remember, it is a privilege to be here.
We are guests of Columbia University
Science Department,so behave accordingly.
Let's not have a repeat of our
trip to the planetarium.
C'mon people, let's stay together.
Proceed up the steps and into the building.
Dad would you ask Hoskins to drive around the corner please.
Why? The entrance is right there.
Dad these are public school kids,
I'm not showing up for the field trip in a Rolls.
You want me to trade in my care for a Jetta just because
you flunked out of every private school I ever sent you to?
It wasn't for me.
Of course it was.
Don't ever be ashamed of who you are.
I'm not ashamed of who I am, it's just..
-Just what Harry?
Forget it.
Hey Pete!
Hiya Harry.
Harry! Won't you be needing this?
Thanks Dad.
Um, Peter may I introduce my father, Norman Oswald.
Peter, I've heard so much about you.
It's a great honour to meet you sir.
Harry tells me you're quite the science whiz.
Y'know, I'm something of a scientist myself.
I read all your research on nanotechnology. Really Brilliant.
And you understood it?
Yes, I wrote a paper on it.
Impressive.
Your parents must be very proud of you.
I live with my aunt and uncle, they are proud.
Hey you two! Let's move!
Nice to meet you.
-I'll see you again.
-Yeah.
He didn't seem so bad.
Not if you're a genius.
He'd love to adopt you.
There are over 32,000 known species of spiders
in the world. They're in the order aranae ...
Wow, that's amazing! This is the most advanced
electron microscope in the eastern seaboard.
It's unreal.
Arachnids from all three groups possess varying
strengths which help them in their constant search for food.
For example, the Delena spider, family Sporacidae,
has the ability to jump to catch its prey.
For the school paper?
Next we have the netweb spider, family
Philus Tetidae, Genus Cucacamia.
It spins an intricate funnel shaped web whose strands
have a tensile strength proportionately equal
to the type of high tension wire...
Leave him alone.
Or what?
Or his father will fire you father.
What's Daddy gonna do?  Sue me?
What is going on? The next person who talks
will fail this course. I kid you not.
This grass spider hunts using a set of
relexes with nerve conduction so fast
that some researches believe it
almost borders on precognition...
-Those guys are jerks.
-...an imminent awareness of danger, a "spider-sense".
Hey look at that spider.
Some spiders change colours to blend into their environment.
It's a defense mechanism.
Peter, what makes you think I would want to know that?
Who wouldn't?
Over five painstaking years Columbia's genetic research facility has...
Gonna talk to her now?
No, go on, you talk to her.
-Disgusting.
-I hate the little things.
-I love 'em.
-Yeah me too.
You know, spiders can change their colour to blend into their environment.
Really?
Yeah, it's a defense mechanism.
Cool.
...combining the genetic information from all three spiders into these fifteen genetically designed super-spiders.
There's fourteen.
I beg your pardon?
One's missing.
I guess the researchers are working on that one.
Did you know that this is the largest
electron microscope on the eastern seaboard?
You were talking throughout this entire
presentation.  Let's go talk about how we listen.
I don't know what it's like at those fancy private schools but ...
Hey, could I take your picture?
I need one with a student in it.
Sure. Yeah, where do you want me? Over here?
Yeah, yeah that's great.
Don't make me look ugly.
That's impossible.
Perfect.
-That good?
-Great.
That's great. [she giggles]
MJ, let's go.
Wait, thanks!
Parker.  Let's do it.
We've solved the horizon glide. And the multi-G balance issues.
I've already seen the glider.  That's not what I'm here for.
General Slocum, good to see you again.
Mr. Balkan, Mr. Farthus.
-Norman.
-Mr. Osbourne.
Always a pleasure to have our board of directors pay us a little visit.
I want to see the progress report on Human performance enhancers.
We tried vapour inhalation with rodent subjects.
They showed an 800 percent increase in strength.
Any side effects?
-In one trial yes.
-It was an aberration.
All the tests since then have been successful.
And in the trial that went wrong what were the side effects.
-Violence, aggression ... and insanity.
-And what do you recommend?
That was only one test.
With the exception of Dr. Strom our entire staff
certifies the product ready for human testing.
Dr. Strom?
We need to take the whole line back to formula.
Back to formula?
Dr. Osbourne!  I'm going to be frank with you.
I never supported your program.
We have my predecessor to thank for that.
Norman, the General gave the go-ahead to request aerospace to build a prototype of their exoskeleton design.
They test in two weeks.
And if your so-called performance enhancers
have not had a successful human trial by that date,
I'm going to pull your funding.
I'm going to give it to them
Gentlemen, ladies.
And the Lord said, "Let there be light."
And Voila!  There is light! Forty soft glowin' watts of it.
Oh good boy, God will be thrilled.  Just don't fall on your ass.
I'm already on my ass, May.
When the plant senior electrician is laid off
after thirty-five years what else would you call it?
I am on my ass.
Hand me that dish, the green one.
The corporation is downsizing the
people and upsizing the profits.
Ben, you'll get another job somewhere.
Well, let's look at the paper and see.
Here are the want ads what do we got here?
Computer .. computer salesman, computer engineer, computer analyst
... my Lord even the computers need analysts these days.
May, I'm sixty eight years old, I'm too old for computers and
besides I've got a family to provide for.
I love you and Peter loves you.  You're the
most responsible man I've ever known.
We've been down and out before, but somehow we've survived.
Yeah,..
Oh, hi sweetie, you're just in time for dinner.
How you doing buddie?  How was the field trip?
I don't feel well, I'm going to go to sleep.
You won't have a bite?
No thanks, had a bite.
Did you get some pictures Peter?
I gotta crash, everything's fine.
What's that all about?
[synthesized transfer-RNA .. into these fifteen
genetically enhanced super-spiders...]
Dr. Osbourne, please.  The performance enhancers aren't ready.
The data just doesn't justify this test.
I'm asking you for the last time.  We can't do this.
Don't be a coward. Risks are part of laboratory science.
Look let me reschedule.  With the proper medical staff and a volunteer.
-If you just give me two weeks...
-Two weeks!?
We'll have lost the contract and Oscorp will be dead.
Sometimes you've got to do things yourself.
Get me the Promochloraparazine.
For what?
It begins catalyzation when the
vapour hits the bloodstream.
Forty thousand years of evolution and we've
barely even tapped the vastness of human potential.
Norman? ...
Norman!
... Norman!
Oh my God!
Oh my God! Norman.
Norman.
Norman, no.
Back to formula?!
Weird.
[knock]
Peter?
Yeah.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Are you better this morning?
Any change?
Change?
Yeah. Big change.
Well, hurry up!  You're going to be late.
Right.
-Goodness me.
-I thought you were sick.
-I got better. Bye guys!
You haven't eaten anything,
have you got your lunch money?
Yeah I've got it.
Hey Michaelangelo don't forget
we're painting the kitchen right after school.
-Got it?
-Sure thing Uncle Ben.
-Don't start without me.
-And don't start up with me.
Teenagers, raging hormones they never change.
...you're trash! You're always going to be trash just like her.
-I have to go to school.[sobs]
-Aw, who's stoppin' you.
Hi MJ ...Hey MJ, I don't know if you realize
this but we've been neighbours since I was six
and I was wondering if maybe we could get
together sometime and do something fun ..
or I don't know, I thought it'd be fun to get to know each other ...
...or not...
Hey, stop the bus.
Dad? Dad, are you all right?
Harry, ...[groan]
What are you doing on the floor?
I don't know.
Have you been there all night?
I ... last night I was ...
What?
I don't remember.
-Mr. Osbourne.
-Sir I asked her to wait in the foyer.
-I'm sorry my father's not feeling well-
-Mr. Osbourne, Dr. Strom is dead.
-What?
-They found his body this morning in the lab.
He's been murdered sir.
What are you talking about.
-And the flight suit and the glider,--
-What about it?
It's been stolen, sir.
Wow! Great reflexes.
-Thanks.
-No problem.
Hey, blue eyes.  I didn't notice without
your glasses.  Did you just get contacts?
Well, see ya.
Parker?
Think you're pretty funny don't you, freak?
-Flash it was just an accident.
-My fist breaking your teeth is the accident.
-C'mon Flash, stop.
-I don't want to fight you Flash.
I wouldn't want to fight me neither.
Help him Harry.
Which one?
All yours man.
Jesus Parker, you are a freak.
Peter, that was amazing.
Peter.
Go web!
Fly!
Up up and away web!
Shazam!
Go!
Go! Go web go!
Tally-ho...
[sounds of shouted argument]
Were you listening to that?
No.  Well, I heard but I was just taking out the trash.
I guess you can always hear us.
Well, everybody shouts.
Your aunt and uncle don't.
Oh, they can scream pretty good sometimes.
Listen, MJ, about today ... at school with Flash ...
You really freaked us out.
I'm sorry.
Is he ok?
He's just happy you didn't give him a black eye for graduation.
So where you going after you graduate?
I want to move into the city and hopefully get a job as a photographer.
Work my way through college.
What about you?
Headed for the city too. Can't wait to get out of here.
-I wanna ...
-What?
C'mon, try me.
I wanna .. act.  On stage.
Really?  That's perfect.  You were awesome in all the school plays.
Really?
Yeah, I cried like a baby when you played Cinderella.
Peter, that was first grade.
Well, even so.
Sometimes you know people.
You can just see what's coming.
What do you see coming for you?
I don't know.  Whatever it is...
It's something I've never felt before.
And what for me?
For you, you're going to light up Broadway.
You know,
you're taller than you look.
I hunch.
Don't.
Come take a ride in my new birthday present.
I gotta go.
Bye.
Oh my god, gorgeous! Look at it!
Hop in. Pretty exciting huh? Don't scratch the leather.
Cool car.
Peter, what's going on in there?
I'm exercising.  I'm not dressed Aunt May.
Well, you're acting so strangely Peter.
Ok, thanks.
[evil laughter]
Something's bothering him.
Maybe he's too embarrased to tell me what it is.
Maybe I'm too embarrased to ask him.
I don't know, I just don't know anymore.
I'm going to the downtown library, I'll see you later.
-Oh, wait Pete! I'll drive you there buddy.
-I'll take the train.
-No I need the exercise.  Just go on, go go go.
-Thanks for the ride Uncle Ben.
-Now wait a minute, we need to talk.
-We can talk later.
-We can talk now. If you'll let me.
What do we have to talk about, why now?
Because we haven't talked at all for so long,
your Aunt May and I don't even know who you are any more.
You shirk your chores, you have all
those weird experiments in your room.
-You start fights at school.
-I didn't start that fight, I told you that.
-Well you sure as hell finished it.
-What was I supposed to do, run away?
No, no you're not supposed to run away.
But, Pete look, you're changing.  I know, I
went through exactly the same thing at your age.
No, Not exactly.
Peter, these are the years when a man changes
into the man he's going to become the rest of his life.
Just be careful who you change into.
This guy, Flash Thompson, he
probably deserved what happened.
But just because you can beat him
up doesn't give you the right to.
Remember, 'With great power
comes great responsibility'.
Are you afraid that I'm going to turn
into some kind of criminal?
Quit worrying about me ok? Something's
different. I'll figure it out.
Stop lecturing me, please.
-I don't mean to lecture and I don't mean to
preach. And I know I'm not your father--
Then stop pretending to be!
Right.
I'll pick you up here at ten.
[chanting 'Bonesaw, Bonesaw, Bonesaw...']
Ladies and Gentlemen,
Give it up for Bonesaw!
For $3000 is there no one here man enough
to stay in the ring for three minutes
with this titan of testosterone?!
Who?!  I know ... the Flying Dutchman!
Next.  There's no featherweight division here smallfry. Next.
No no.  Sign me up.
Ok. You understand the NYWL is not responsible
for any injury you may and probably will sustain while
participating in said event and you are
indeed participating of your own free will?
Yes.
Down the hall to the ramp.
May God be with you. Next.
Winner!
Are you ready for death?!
Bonesaw is ready!
Will the next victim please
enter the arena at this time.
If he can stand just three minutes in the
cage with Bonesaw McGraw the sum of $3000 will be paid to...
-What's your name kid?
-The Human Spider.
The Human Spider? That's it. That's the best you got?
Yeah.
Aw that sucks.
The sum of $3000 will be paid to ...
The Terrifying, the Deadly,
the Amazing Spiderman!
My Name's the Human Spider.
-I don't care get out there.
-No he got my name wrong.
Get out there you moron.
Bonesaw's gonna eat you up and spit you
out little man, I hope you brought your mommy with you
we're gonna break you, I'm gonna rip
off all eight of your feeble legs one by one
Oh my god! Oh my legs!
I can't feel my legs!
[chanting 'Kill kill kill']
Hello? Guys?
Will the guard please lock
the cage doors at this time!
Hey listen! It's some kind of
mistake, I didn't sign up for a cage match!
Hey, unlock the thing!
Take the chain off!
Hey freak-show!
You're going nowhere!
I gotcha for three minutes.
Three minutes of P-time.
What are you doing up there?
Staying away from you.
That's a cute outfit.
Did you husband give it to you?
[chanting 'Bonesaw Bonesaw Bonesaw']
Kick his spider-ass
- yeah! Get him!
That's it! That's it!
Ladies and Gentlemen give it
up for the new champion, SPIDERMAN!
Now get outta here.
A hundred bucks? The ad said three thousand.
Check it again webhead.  It said three grand for three minutes.
You pinned him in two.  For that, I give you a hundred, and you're lucky to get that.
I need that money.
I missed the part where that's my problem.
-Hey what the hell?!
-Put the money in the bag.
[Hurry up!]
Hey he stole the take!
Stop that guy!
Stop him, he's got my money!
Thanks!
What the hell's the matter with you, you let him go!
Cut him off in the lobby and call the cops.
You could have taken that guy apart.  Now he's going to get away with my money.
I missed the part where that's my problem.
You gotta get back. Get back, alright.
C'mon folks, keep moving. Keep moving, let's go.
Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
Hey stay back, stay back.
That's my Uncle!
What happened.
Car jacker, he's been shot.
We just called the paramedics, they're on the way.
Uncle Ben, Uncle Ben.
Uncle Ben?
Peter.
I'm here Uncle Ben.
They got the shooter. He's headed south on fifth avenue.
We got three cars in pursuit.
Who's there?
Don't hurt me. Just give me a chance. Just give me a chance!
What about my Uncle? Did you give him a chance?! Did you?!
Stop that guy!
Thanks.
See ya.
Freeze! We've got the place completely surrounded!
-Good evening General.-
Good to see you.
Our exoskeleton has real firepower General Slocum.
If it does what you say it can I'll sign that contract tomorrow.
I assume you're confident about this test.
Absolutely, Captain Curtis is our top pilot.
Now what about your commitment to Oscorp?
Nothing would please me more than to put Norman Osbourne out of business.
We are picking up an unidentified object closing fast.
What the hell is that?
Can you see anything?
Oh my God!
-Say chess.
-Chess!
Oh Darling, I'm so proud of you, you look so handsome up there.
Pete. Good news. My Father got the place in New York so we're all set this Friday.
Oh that's great!
You made it.
It's not the first time I've been proven wrong.
-Congratulations.
-Thanks Dad.
Peter.  The science award.
-That's terrific.
-Yeah.
I know this has been a difficult time for you.  But I want you to try to enjoy this day.
Commencement, the end of one thing. The start of something new.
You're like a brother to him, that makes you family.  And if you ever need anything just give me a call.
Can I fix you something.
No thanks.
I missed him a lot today.
I know.
I miss him too.
But, he was there.
I can't help thinking about the last thing I said to him.
He tried to tell me something important and I threw it in his face.
You loved him and he loved you.
He never doubted the man you would grow into.  That you were meant for great things.
You won't disappoint him.
'With great power comes great responsibility'.  Remember that Pete.  Remember that.
Hurry up!
This is not a man. My brother saw him building a nest in the Lincoln Center fountain.
They think he's human.  They think he's a man.  Could be a woman.
Tommy, get a load of this.
...the ropes come out and he climbs up the ropes like a spider web.
I see the web and it's a signature and I know Spiderman was here.
The guy protects us.  You know, he protects the people.
Some kind o' freaky-loo or somethin'. Wakadoo.
He stinks and I don't like him.
Don't move!
Guy with 8 hands.  Sounds hot.
He has those tights and tight little--
-Dresses like a spider, he looks like a bug
We should all just give him one big hug
look out here comes the Spiderman.
Who is Spiderman?!
He's a criminal, that's who he is.
A vigilante.
A public menace.
What's he doing on my front page?
Mr. Jameson your wife is on line one she needs to know if--.
Mr. Jameson there's a page six problem.
-We have a page one problem, shut up.
-Well?!
-He's news.
-These are really important clients they can't wait.
-They're about to.
-He pulled six people off that subway car.
-Sure from a wreck he probably caused.
Something goes wrong and this creepy-crawler is there.
Look at that, he's fleeing the scene.  What's that tell you?
He's not fleeing, he's probably going to
save somebody else. He's a hero!
Then why's he wear a mask, hmm? What's he got to hide?
She just needs to know if you want the chintz or the chanel in the dining room.
Whichever one's cheaper.
Mr. Jameson it's like this, we double-booked page six.
See so both Macy's and Conway's have three-quarters of the same page.
-We sold out four printings.
-Sold out?
Every copy.
Tomorrow morning. Spiderman. Page one with a
decent picture this time. Move Conway to page seven.
Make it page eight and give 'em 10 percent off. No make it 5 percent.
-That can't be done --
-Get outta here!
Problem is we don't have a decent picture.
Eddie's been on it for weeks, we can barely get a glimpse of him.
Aw, what is he, shy?
We can get a picture of Julia Roberts in a thong we can certainly get a picture of this weirdo.
Put an ad on the front page.  Cash money for a picture of Spiderman.
He doesn't wanna be famous?  Then I'll make him infamous!
Hey!
Buzz off!
MJ. It's me. Peter.
Hi!
Hey.
What are you doing around here.
I'm begging for a job. How about you?
I'm headed to an audition.
An audition? So you're acting now?
Yeah, I work steady.
In fact, I just got off a job.
That's great MJ.
You're doing it.  You're living your dream.
Hey counter girl!  Your drawer was short six dollars!
Next time that happens, I'm gonna take it outta your cheque!
Excuse me Miss Watson!  I'm talkin' to you. Hey!
Yes Enrique, I get you.
Well, it better not happen no more,
hear me? Don't roll your eyes at me.
Some dream huh?
It's nothing to be embarrassed about.
Don't tell Harry.
Don't tell Harry?
Aren't you guys living together?
We're going out, didn't he tell you?
Oh yeah, right. I think he'd hate the idea of my waiting tables.
He'd think it was low or something.
It's not low. You have a job. Harry, doesn't live on a little place I like to call earth.
No, no I guess not.
Thanks Pete.
We should catch up sometime.
Let's get some lunch some evening.
Uh, I'll come by and have some of your moondance coffee some day.
And I won't tell Harry.
No, don't tell Harry.
I won't.
I won't tell Harry.
Stormin' Norman's making his weekly inspection.
He's spent half of it on the phone.
I'm glad you're here. I need your help. I'm really lost here.
Are you all right? You look like you just got second place in the science fair.
No I, uh, was late for work and Dr. Connors fired me.
You were late again? I don't get it. Where do you go all the time?
Around.
Peter Parker. Maybe you'll tell me who she is.
Who's that?
This mystery girl Harry's been dating.  When do I get to meet her?
Oh, sorry, Harry hasn't mentioned her.
Hey Peter you're probably7 looking for a job now right?
Dad maybe you can help him out.
No I appreciate it but I'll be fine.
It's no problem.  I'll make a few calls.
No I couldn't accept it sir. I'd like to earn what I get.
I can find my own work.
I respect that. You want to make it on your own steam. That's great. That's great.
What other skills do you have Parker.
I was thinking of something in photography.
Hello.
Let's go! Let's move it!
Watch the street!
Cheese!
They're crap. Crap. Crap. Mega-crap.
I'll give you 200 bucks for all of 'em.
That seems a little low.
Take 'em somewhere else then.
Sir your wife said that tile you want in the foyer is out of stock.
Tell her we'll just put a rug there. Sit down!
I'll give you 300.  That's a standard freelance fee.
-Tear up page one.  Run that photo instead.
-Headline?
-'Spiderman Hero or Menace?
Exclusive Daily Bugle Photos.'
-Menace? He was protecting that--
-Tell you what, Atticus you take the pictures I'll make up the headlines, ok?
That ok with you.
Yes sir.
Goodie. Give this to the girl up front. She'll see you get paid.
I'd like a job sir.
No jobs. Freelance! Best thing in the world for a kid your age.
Bring me some more shots of that newspaper selling clown, maybe I'll take 'em off your hands.
But I never said you have a job.
Meat! I'll send you a nice box of Christmas meat. Best I can do. Get outta here.  Bring me more photos.
Hi.
Mr. Jameson told me to give that to you.
Oh, welcome to the Daily Bugle.
Thank you.
I'm Peter Parker. I'm a photographer.
Yes, I can see that.
As of today, Oscorp Industries has surpassed Quest
Aerospace as the principal supplier to the United States Military.
In short ladies and gentlemen of the board, costs are
down, revenues are up, and our stock has never been higher.
Wonderful news Norman. Wonderful. In fact, it's the reason for selling the company.
What?
Yes, Quest Aerospace is recapitalizing in the wake of the bombing.
Expanding. They made a tender offer that we can't ignore.
Why wasn't I told.
The last thing they want is a power struggle with entrenched management.
The deal is off if you come with it.
The board expects your resignation in 30 days.
You can't do this to me.
I started this company.
You know how much I sacrificed?!
Oh Max please.
Norman, the board is unanimous.
We're announcing the sale after the World Unity Festival.
I'm sorry.
You're out Norman.
Am I?
Welcome to Oscorp Industries'
Unity Day Festival.
Let's hear it for Macy Gray!
MJ, why didn't you wear the black dress?
It's just, I wanted to impress my father.
He loves black.
Well, maybe he'll be impressed no matter what.
You think I'm pretty.
I think you're beautiful.
MJ would you do me a favour?
I forgot my drink inside.
Oh hi Mr. Fargus.  Have you seen my father around.
Well, I'm not sure if he's coming today.
What is that?
It must be new this year.
That's our glider!
What the hell was that?
Ha ha ha ha!
Oh my God! Harry!
MJ!
OUT AM I!?
Hello my dear.
It's Spiderman.
C'mon move kid.
Mommy!
Hold it right there.
I surrender.
Oh boy.
Hold it right there.
Impressive!
Help!
Mary Jane!
Hold on!
Watch out!
We'll meet again Spiderman!
Well, beats takin' the subway.
Don't mind us, she just needs to use the elevator.
Wait! Who are you?
You know who I am.
I do?
Your friendly neighbourhood Spiderman.
Incredible? What do you mean he's incredible?
No alright. Wait, stay there, I'm going to come over.
No, I'm going to come ove--alright fine will you call me in the morning.
And we'll go and have breakfast and I want to buy you something.
Because I want to, it'll make you feel better.
Ok, and what do you mean incredible.
Alright, I'm sorry.  Sleep tight, don't let the bedbugs-- [click].
She's alright. She's just a little rattled.
Look Pete, I should have told you about us.
You should know I'm crazy about her.
It's just, you know, you never made a move.
You're right, I didn't.
I'm going to get some rest.
I'm going to stay up for a while.
What was that thing?
I don't know.
Whatever it is, somebody has to stop it.
Somebody there?
Somebody?
Who said that?
You've known all along!
Where are you?
Follow the cold shiver running down your spine.
I'm right here!
I don't understand.
Did you think it was coincidence.
So many good things all happening for you. All for you Norman.
What do you want?
To say what you won't. To do what you can't.
To remove those in your way.
The board members. You killed them?
We killed them. Remember? Your little accident in the laboratory.
Performance enhancers.
Bingo. Me! Your greatest creation.
Bringing you what you've always wanted.
Power, beyond your wildest dreams. And it's only the beginning.
There's only one who can stop us.
Or ... imagine if he joined us.
Spiderman. And the Green Goblin.
Green Goblin. Like that? Made it up myself.
These weirdo's all gotta have a name now.
Hoffman, call the patent office, copyright the name Green Goblin, I want a quarter every time somebody says it.
Spiderman wasn't attacking the city he was trying to save it. That's slander.
It is not! I resent that. Slander is spoken. In print it's libel.
You don't trust anybody, that's your problem.
I trust my barber.
What are you his lawyer? Get out of here!
Let him sue me, get rich like a normal person.
That's what made this country--
Jameson, you slime!
Who's the photographer who takes the pictures of Spiderman?
I don't know who he is.  His stuff comes in the mail.
-You're lying!
-I swear.
He's the one who can bring me to him.
I don't know who he is.
-You are useless you...
-Set him down tough guy.
-Speak of the devil.
-Spiderman! I knew you two were in this together.
Hey kiddo. Let mom and dad talk for a minute will you?
Sleep!
Wake up little spider.  Wake up.
No, you're not dead, yet.  Just paralyzed, temporarily.
You're an amazing creature Spiderman. You and I are not so different.
I'm not like you.  You're a murderer.
Well, to each his own. I chose my path, you chose the way of the hero.
And they found you amusing for a while.  The people of this city.
But the one thing they love more than a hero is to see a hero fail. Fall.
Die trying.
In spite of everything you've done for them, eventually they will hate you.
Why bother?
Because, it's right.
Here's the real truth.  There are 8 million people in this city
and those teeming masses exist for the sole purpose
of lifting the few exceptional people onto their shoulders.
You and me, we're exceptional. I could squash
you like a bug right now but I'm offering you a choice.
Join me. Imagine what we could accomplish together, what we could create.
Or we could destroy.
Cause the deaths of countless innocents in selfish battle again and again and again until we're both dead!
Is that what you want? Think about it hero!
In spite of everything you've done for them, eventually they will hate you.
Hey, it's me again.
Hey.
How was your audition?
How'd you know.
The hotline.  Your Mom, told my Aunt, told me.
So you just came by?
I was in the neighbourhood, needed to see a friendly face.
I took two buses and a cab to get in the neighbourhood but ...
So how'd it go?
They said I needed acting lessons. A soap opera told me I needed acting lessons.
Let me buy you a cheese burger. The sky's the limit up to seven dollars and eighty for cents.
I'd like a cheese burger, oh but I'm going out to dinner with Harry.
Come with us.
-No thanks.
How's it going with-- Ah nevermind. It's none of my business.
It's not?
Why so interested?
I'm not.
You're not?
Well, why would I be?
I don't know. Why would you be?
I don't know.
Sorry you won't come with us.
I better run tiger.
Hey check it out man..
Hey where you going baby, come on.
Get off me!
Wait.
You have a knack for getting in trouble.
You have a knack for saving my life.
I think I have a superhero stalker.
I was in the neighbourhood.
You are amazing.
Some people don't think so.
But you are.
It's nice to have a fan.
Do I get to say thank you this time?
Wait...
I have to get in there! My baby's in there! My baby's in there!
-I can't let you in there, the roof's about to collapse.
-Let me go! My baby!
Look, up there!
Save my baby please!
No!
It's ok, your baby's fine.
Oh my baby!
Bless you Spiderman! Bless you.
There he is, don't let him get away!
Hold it right there!
You're under arrest, I'm taking you in.
Oh my God, there's somebody still up there.
I'm going.
I'll be here when you get back.
Not coming back chief.
Go! Go!
Where are you?!
I'm going to get you out of here!
It's ok!
You're pathetically predictable, like a moth to the flame.
What about my generous proposal? Are you in or are you out?
It's you who's out Gobby. Out of your mind.
Wrong answer!
Oh great.
No one says no to me!
MJ would you stop goofing around?
Harry relax!
He's here.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
Ah, Aunt May, I'm sorry I'm late.
Work was murder.
I picked up a fruit cake.
Why thank you Mr. Osbourne, we're so glad you could come.
-You look great.
-Thanks.
Who's this lovely new lady?
MJ I'd like you to meet my father, Norman Osbourne.
Dad, this is Mary Jane Watson.
Hi.
How do you do? I've been looking forward to meeting you.
Happy Thanksgiving sir.
Now where is Peter. He'd better have remembered that cranberry sauce.
Oh, that's weird, I didn't know he was here.
Peter?
Is that you?
Pete?
How strange. There's nobody here.
Bit of a slob isn't he?
All brilliant men are.
Hey everyone!
Peter!
Sorry I'm late. It's a jungle out there, I had to beat an old lady with a stick to get these cranberries.
Thank you. Now then everybody sit down and we can say grace.
It all looks delicious.
Norman! Will you do the honours?
Why Peter, you're bleeding.
Oh, yeah, I stepped off a curb and got clipped by one of those bike messengers.
Let me see. Oh my goodness. Oh that looks awful.
-It's nothing.
-I'll get the first aid kit.
Then we'll say grace. This is the boys' first Thanksgiving in this apartment and we are going to do things properly.
How did you say that happened.
Bike messenger. Knocked me down.
If you'll excuse me, I've got to be going.
Why?
Something has come to my attention.
Are you all right?
I'm fine, just fine.
Thank you Mrs. Parker, everyone, enjoy the fruitcake.
Dad! Dad, what are you doing?
I plan this whole thing so you can meet MJ and now you've got to leave?
I've got to go.
Dad, this girl is important to me.
Harry, please. Look at her.
Do you think a woman like that is sniffing around because she likes your personality?
Your mother was beautiful too, they're all beautiful,
until they're snarling after your trust fund like a pack of ravening wolves.
You're wrong about her Dad.
A word to the not so wise about your little girlfriend,
do what you need to with her, then broom her fast.
Thanks for sticking up for me Harry.
You heard?
Everyone heard that creep!
That creep is my father. If I'm lucky I'll become half of what he is so just keep your mouth shut about stuff you don't understand.
Harry Osbourne!
I'm sorry Aunt May.
Spiderman is all but invincible but Parker -- we can destroy him.
I can't.
Betrayal must not be countenanced! Parker must be educated.
What do I do.
Instruct him in the matters of loss and pain.
Make him suffer.
Make him wish that he were dead.
-Yes.
-And then grant his wish.
But how?
The cunning warrior attacks neither body nor mind.
Tell me how!
The heart Osbourne! First we attack his heart!
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who tresspass against us.
Lead us not into temptation but deliver us --
Deliver us!
Finish it! Finish it!
..Evil!
Aunt May! Is she going to be ok? What happened?
Yes she's going to be ok. Look you're going to have to leave right now.
Those eyes, those horrible yellow eyes.
He knows who I am.
I'm sorry.
Will she be ok?
She's going to be fine.
She's been sleeping all day.
Thanks for coming.
Of course.
How are you?
You ok about the other night?
I just feel bad about leaving Aunt May.
Have you talked to Harry?
He called me.
I haven't called him back.
The fact is, I'm in love with somebody else.
You are?
At least, I think I am.
It's not the right time to talk about it.
No, no, go on. Would I know his name, this guy?
You'll think I'm a stupid little girl with a crush.
Trust me.
It's funny.
He saved my life twice and I've never even seen his face.
Oh him.
You're laughing at me.
No, no I understand.
He is extremely cool.
But do you think it's true all the terrible things they say about him?
No, no, not Spiderman, not a chance in the world.
I know him a little bit, I'm sort of his unofficial photographer.
Has he mentioned me.
Yeah.
What'd he say?
I said...
he he asked me what I thought about you.
And what did you say?
I said...
uh, Spiderman, I said,
the great thing about MJ is
that when you look in her eyes
and she's looking back in yours
everything feels
not quite normal
because you feel
stronger
and weaker at the same time
you feel excited
and at the same time
terrified.
The truth is, you don't know what you feel,
except to know the kind of man you want to be.
It's as if you've
reached the unreachable...
And you weren't ready for it.
You said that?
Well, something like that.
Hey.
Dad?
Dad is that you?
What is it?
Well, you were right about MJ.
You were right about everything.
She's in love with Peter.
Parker. And how does he feel about her.
Well, he's loved her since the fourth grade.
He pretends like he doesn't but there's no one Peter cares for more.
I'm so sorry.
I haven't always been there for you have I?
You're busy. You're an important man, I understand.
That's no excuse.
I'm proud of you.
And I've lost sight of that somewhere but I'm going to make it up to you Harry.
I'm going to rectify certain inequities.
Wake up little spider. Wake up.
Go home dear. You look awful.
You look beautiful.
I don't like to leave you here.
Oh but I'm safe here.
Can I do anything for you?
You do too much. College, a job, all this time with me.
You're not Superman you know.
A smile.
Finally, I haven't seen one of those on your face since Mary Jane was here.
Hey, you were supposed to be asleep.
You know, you were about six years old when MJ's family moved in next door.
And when she got out of the car and you saw her for the first time
you grabbed me and said,
"Aunt May, Aunt May is that an angel?"
Did I say that?
You sure did.
Well, Harry's in love with her.  She's still his girl.
Isn't that up to her?
She doesn't really know who I am.
Because you won't let her.  You're so mysterious all the time.
Tell me, would it be so dangerous to let Mary Jane know how much you care?
Everybody else knows.
I'll be right back.
Oh come on pick up.
Hi it's me sing your song at the beep. [beep]
Hi MJ, it's Peter. Are you there.
Well, I'm just calling to check up on you.
Will you call me when you get in ok?
Alright, well ... don't, don't go up any dark alleys.
Hello?
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Can Spiderman come out to play?
Where is she?
Itsy bitsy Spider went up the water spout,
down came the Goblin and took the Spider out.
Ha ha ha ha...
Goblin, what have you done?
Spiderman!
This is why only fools are heroes.
Because you never know when some lunatic will come along with a sadistic choice.
Let die the woman you love,
or .. suffer the little children.
Make your choice Spiderman!
And see how a hero is rewarded.
Don't do it Goblin!
We are who we choose to be.
Now choose!
Everyone stay still.
Aghh...
Ahoy up there! We're going to bring the barge right under you.
Aiiee, he's coming back!
Listen, I need you to climb down.
-I can't!
-Yes you can!
MJ, you can do it.  You have to.
Trust me.
Hold on tight. Go quickly.
Hurry!
I can't I can't do it.
Hang on Mary Jane!
-He's not gonna make it.
-He's gonna make it.
It's time to die!
Come on up here dumb guy I got a little something for ya.
Leave Spiderman alone.  You gonna pick on a guy trying to save a bunch of kids?
You mess with Spidey you mess with New York.
You mess with one of us you mess with all of us.
Spiderman watch out!
Misery. Misery. Misery.
That's what you've chosen.
I offered you friendship and you spat in my face.
You've spun your last web Spiderman.
Had you not been so selfish, your little
girlfriend's death would have been quick and painless
but now you've really pissed me off
I'm going to finish her nice and slow.
MJ and I
we're going to have a hell of a time!
Peter! Stop! Stop.. It's me.
Mr. Osbourne.
Peter, thank God for you.
You killed those people on that balcony.
The Goblin killed them, I had nothing to do with it!
Don't, don't let him take me again!
Help me. Protect me!
You tried to kill Aunt May. You tried to kill Mary Jane.
But not you. I tried to stop it.
I couldn't stop it. I would never hurt you.
I knew from the beginning, if anything ever happened to me
It was you that I could count on
you Peter Parker would save me and so you have.
Thank God for you.
Give me your hand. Believe in me. As I believed in you.
I've been like a father to you.
Be a son to me now.
I have a father.
His name was Ben Parker.
Godspeed Spiderman.
Oh.
Don't tell Harry.
What have you done? What have you done?!
Hey.
I'm so sorry man.
I know what it's like to lose a father.
I didn't lose him. He was stolen from me.
One day Spiderman will pay.
I swear on my father's grave, Spiderman will pay.
Thank God for you Peter, you're the only family I have.
No matter what I do, no matter how hard I try,
the ones I love, will always be the ones who pay.
You must miss him so much.
It's been so hard without him.
There's something I've been wanting to tell you.
When I was up there,
and I thought I was going to die,
there's only one person who I was thinking of.
And it wasn't who I thought it'd be.
It was you Pete.
I kept thinking, "I hope I make it through this,
so I could see Peter Parker's face one more time."
Really?
There's only one man who's always been there for me.
Who makes me feel like I'm more than I ever thought I could be.
That I'm just, me,
and that's ok.
The truth is ... I love you.
I love you so much Peter.
All I wanted was to tell her how much I loved her...
I can't.
You can't what?
Tell you,
everything I mean.
There's so much to tell.
Yeah, there's so much to tell.
I want you to know that I will always be there for you.
I will always be there to take care of you.
I promise you that.
I will always be your friend.
Only a friend, Peter Parker?
That's all I have to give.
Whatever life holds in store for me,
I will never forget these words,
'With great power comes great responsibility.'
This is my gift, my curse.
Who am I?
I'm Spiderman.