ALL: (SINGING)
Happy birthday, dear Janice
Happy birthday to you!
WESLEY: It's my anorexic boss' birthday.
(ALL CHATTERING)
This means there's a certain amount of
inter-office pressure
to stand around the conference table
eating crappy food
and pretending to worship her.
That's so good.
WESLEY: Acting for five minutes like Janice
doesn't make all our lives miserable
is the hardest work I'll do all day.
My job title is account manager.
I used to be called
an account service representative,
but a consultant told us we needed
to manage our clients
and not service them.
(TRAIN RUMBLING)
(MOANING)
I have a girlfriend whom
I neither manage nor service.
That's my best friend, Barry,
fucking her on an IKEA kitchen table
I picked up for a really good price.
I'm finding it hard to care about
anything these days.
In fact, the only thing I do care about
is the fact that I can't care about anything.
Seriously. It worries me.
My name is Wesley Gibson.
My dad walked out on my mom
when I was seven days old.
Sometimes I wonder if he ever looked
into my baby blues eyes and asked himself,
"Did I just father the most insignificant
asshole of the 21st century?"
Well, if you could get me the consignment
to me by the 28th... Yeah.
Do you have the numbers in front of you?
MR X: Relax.
If your name had come up,
you'd be dead already.
We've had some unexpected losses recently.
We'd like to know
where our competitor
is getting his munition.
It's clean.
Meaning?
Meaning it's untraceable.
Your competitor's very smart.
(HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
Get down!
(BULLETS WHOOSHING)
(EXCLAIMS)
Fuck it.
(HEART BEATING)
(HEART BEATING RAPIDLY)
(SCREAMING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(GUN FIRES)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
No one leaves the Fraternity, Cross.
CROSS ON PHONE:
I have a new perspective on the Fraternity.
MR X: Careful.
You don't destroy something that's been
around for a thousand years.
CROSS: It's already destroyed.
He broke the code.
I have to stop this.
- Really?
- You know this.
So why don't you face me yourself?
Never send sheep to kill a wolf.
CROSS: They were just the decoys.
Goodbye, Mr X.
(WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTS)
(BACKWARD VOICES)
(CLICKING)
MR X: Never send sheep to kill a wolf.
They were just the decoys.
CATHY: Wesley!
What is it?
What do you mean, "What is it"? Listen.
(RUMBLING)
Well, how am I suppose to sleep
with all that fucking racket?
When are we gonna move so we don't
have to wake up to that shit?
I kind of like it.
WESLEY: It helps to drown out the sound
of your annoying, fucking voice.
Now, please, let me sleep.
Have you even thought about our talk?
Yes.
Which one?
Perfect. That's perfect.
Feed Annabelle.
(MEOWS)
(RUMBLING)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Sorry.
(LAUGHING) Oh, my fucking God.
I hope that's not my billing report
sitting on your desk.
Holy shit on an altar, it is.
I want that report on my desk in one hour.
Okay, everybody,
we're all gonna stay an extra hour...
WESLEY: Want to hear something sad?
I need an ergonomic keyboard
to keep my repetitive stress injury in check.
Just the fact that I repeat something enough
that it causes me stress is fucking sad.
Nice job, dude. You seen Barry?
He had to go to the dentist. Again.
Yes!
(MOANING)
Barry!
You think they have that
morning-after pill here?
That thing works.
Crush it up, put it in her omelette,
"Hey, baby, breakfast in bed."
You can never be too safe.
Oh, God.
I lost my wallet somewhere.
All this together?
- No, no.
- Yes.
He is the man.
- How much is it?
- Oh. Plus this.
PHARMACIST: $20.42.
(WHISPERING) Watermelon.
Chicks dig it.
Thanks.
See you next time.
PHARMACIST: Have a good night.
I love these energy drinks, man.
I'm almost, like, kind of on
an energy drink cleanse,
where I do one for breakfast
and then, like, two or three for lunch.
WESLEY: I'm the man?
(SCOFFING) Yeah, right, Barry, I'm the man.
In fact, I'm so much the man,
I have a standing prescription for
medication to control my anxiety attacks.
God, I wish I had something else
to relieve my stress.
Hello, Wesley.
WESLEY: You know, there are people,
beautiful people,
you just wish they could see you
in a different setting, a different place,
instead of where you are,
what you've become.
(WHISPERING) Nicole is so hot.
What?
Boom goes the dynamite.
WESLEY: But most of all,
you wish you weren't such a pussy
for wishing for things
that will never change.
JANICE: Good God A'mighty, you're over
here like it's spring fucking break,
and I still don't have that billing report.
Why do I even keep you around, Wesley?
I'll get it done, Janice.
(SCOFFING) Like I never heard that before.
"I'll get it done."
(HEART BEATING)
"I'll get it done. I'll get it done, Janice.
"I'll get it done."
(INDISTINCT DISTORTED CHATTERING)
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
Why don't you have anything
to say for yourself?
(DISTORTED) I'm sorry.
Well, you're worthless.
I'm the one who's sorry I hired your ass.
(HEART BEATING RAPIDLY)
(HEART BEATING SLOWER)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
WESLEY: You know what the best thing is
about the end of the day?
Tomorrow it starts all over again.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(HEART BEATING)
- Hi. How you doing?
- Good.
- I'm sorry?
- You apologise too much.
Sorry about that.
I knew your father.
My father left the week I was born, so...
Your father died yesterday on the rooftop
of the Metropolitan Building.
Sorry.
(LAUGHS)
Look, the liquor rounds
are just over there, so...
Your father was one of the greatest
assassins who ever lived.
The man who killed him is behind you.
(HEART BEATING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
This guy's just shooting up...
Sorry. Sorry.
(ELECTRONIC BARKING)
(TYRES SCREECHING)
What... Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
What the fuck just happened?
Please! Please! Please drive faster.
- Please be quiet.
- Please drive... Please drive faster.
Please... Please understand
that I care about my life!
I don't know what the fuck
you did to piss this guy off,
but you're gonna have to let me out
and call the cops!
Hey! Hey!
(SIREN WAILING)
What are you doing? Oh, shit!
Are you crazy?
Oh, shit!
I think we lost him. I think we lost him.
Could you let me out
at the next corner, please?
Shit!
Fuck!
Oh, shit!
He's right there!
Look, I'm an accountant.
I'm just an accountant.
Oh, fuck!
He's fucking persistent, you know.
Fuck!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
You kick his ass!
Shoot him!
What are you doing?
What are you shooting our car for, huh?
- Are you crazy?
- FOX: Grab the wheel.
WESLEY: Where are you going?
Get back in here!
Oh, my God!
(WESLEY EXCLAIMS)
Oh, damn! I'm sorry.
- Gun!
- What?
FOX: Under the seat!
WESLEY: Here.
(HONKING)
(SCREAMING)
(FOX GRUNTS)
WESLEY: Oh, shit!
(SIRENS WAILING)
Shit!
(HEART BEATING)
- WESLEY: Look out!
- Get out!
Look out! Oh, my God!
Shit!
WESLEY: I'm sorry!
(CHATTERING ON POLICE RADIO)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
OFFICER: Behind you!
(OFFICERS SHOUTING)
(ELECTRONIC BARKING)
(POP MUSIC PLAYING ON CAR RADIO)
(FLY BUZZING)
(GASPS)
Fuck.
Shit. Shit.
(EXCLAIMS)
Hello.
I don't have any money or...
SLOAN: I thought he'd be
taller.
Taller?
Sir...
Sir, I've been trying to explain
to the lady here that I'm an accountant.
I'm an account service representative...
I'm an account manager.
And I'm sure that if you call
my boss, Janice,
she'd fill you in on whatever
has gone wrong.
You can contact her by email or...
She'll put you straight.
SLOAN: Shoot the wings off the flies.
I don't know what that means.
Shoot the wings off the flies.
I really think you have me mixed up
with somebody else.
(HEART BEATING)
On three.
Either you shoot, or I do.
One.
Okay.
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
Two.
I can't even see them!
(HEART BEATING RAPIDLY)
Three.
(GASPING)
Okay. Okay.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(HEART BEATING SLOWER)
That's impossible.
SLOAN: A lot of things for you
weren't possible before today.
What you experienced, Wesley,
was not a panic attack.
Your heart was beating in excess of
400 beats per minute,
sending abundant amounts of
adrenaline into your bloodstream.
This allows you to see and react faster
than normal.
Only a few people in the world can do that.
Your father could do it and you can do it.
With a little work,
you can learn to control these attacks.
Stay away from me.
Just stay back from me.
I have a gun, sir. All right?
My name is Sloan.
This is Fox.
And the others you see around you
are all very good at killing.
So, if I were you,
I'd keep the gun pointed at me.
You don't wanna point it at any of them.
That's better.
- You're insane.
- No.
Insanity is wasting your life as a nothing
when you have the blood of a killer
flowing in your veins.
Insanity is being shit on, beat down,
coasting through life
in a miserable existence
when you have a caged lion locked inside
and a key to release it.
This gun you're holding is an Imanishi 17.
It belonged to your father.
He could conduct
a symphony orchestra with it.
And you're going to use it to kill the man
who shot him down in cold blood.
- I can't...
- The same man who tried to kill you tonight.
Your father was one of us.
A fraternity of assassins.
The weapons of fate.
We've transferred all of his assets
over to you.
And let me assure you, they are substantial.
It is your long-awaited destiny
to join us.
Back off. Back off.
You don't know anything about me.
Stay away from me. Stay away from me.
You stay away from me?
You stay away from me, please?
Will you let me through?
(SCREAMS)
(TRAIN RUMBLING)
WESLEY: You know when you have a dream
and you're half awake,
but it's still in the fringe of your brain?
Then you open your eyes
and you're so damn glad it was a dream.
(CLANKS)
This was nothing like that.
(HEART BEATING)
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
(TRAIN RUMBLING)
I'm sorry. Could you just give me
one second? Thank you.
Oh, shit.
(SIGHS)
(WHISPERING) Wesley.
What's up with you?
What do you mean?
You're... You're here early.
Is... You seem a little pepped up.
- You all right?
- Well, yeah.
Yeah.
I guess I feel
kind of different.
Whatever. I'm gonna go get
some Post-it Notes. Do you want one?
- No.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Jesus H. fucking Popsicle,
I still don't have my billing reports,
but you've got time to sit here
and Google your ass off.
Well, I know one thing.
You've got your review
coming up next week,
and I can't wait to start checking me off
some big fucking boxes.
Attitude, poor! Performance, poor!
(HEART BEATING)
Management skills, poor!
(SCOFFS) Works well with others.
That's a fucking joke.
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
What is this bullshit? Who's this prick?
Some loser gets his head blown off
at the Metropolitan...
Shut the fuck up!
She has one single iota of tenuous power.
She thinks she can push everyone around.
You don't need this.
(SOFTLY) I understand.
Junior high must have been kind of tough,
but it doesn't give you the right to treat
your workers like horseshit, Janice.
I know we laugh at you, Janice.
We all know you keep your stash of jelly
doughnuts in the top drawer of your desk.
But I want you to know
if you weren't such a bitch,
we'd feel sorry for you.
I do feel sorry for you.
But as it stands, the way you behave,
I feel I can speak for the entire office
when I tell you
go fuck yourself.
(WHIMPERS)
Yeah. That was great, bro. Who's the man?
I'm the man.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHUCKLES)
That's a bad idea.
Couldn't find your keys, huh?
That could be handy.
You going to teach me that?
I might need that.
So, Fox, right? What is that?
Is that a call sign?
Is it like Maverick in Top Gun?
You could tell me,
but you'd have to kill me?
(LAUGHING) I'm just kidding.
(ROCK MUSIC CONTINUES)
(WORKERS SHOUTING)
SLOAN: Peter!
Check the shuttle rotation on this STB.
It should be 300 per minute.
This kind of cotton weave,
the opposing thread count should be 4,000.
Hey, this is pretty awesome, huh?
Is it a front?
- Front for what?
- I don't know.
Assassinations.
You may think this is a front for something,
all I can tell you is this is a textile mill.
And George...
George, go help Peter up there.
Yeah.
This is a textile mill.
And a damn good one.
WESLEY: Yeah, that's cute,
but that's bullshit, right?
I mean, all these guys are killers,
aren't they?
I think you owe me some answers.
All right. Clearly I don't understand,
but do you make sweaters
or do you kill people?
(WORKERS STOP CHATTERING)
That's an awful lot of questions over coffee.
Are you sure you're ready for the answers?
Yes, I'm sure.
I can't go back.
Not to my life.
SLOAN: He's all yours.
All right. We're up.
REPAIRMAN: How you doing?
I'm The Repairman.
What do you repair?
A lifetime of bad habits.
- Okay.
- Would you do me a favour?
Just put your arms behind your back.
- It's okay.
- I don't know...
- Just behind your back.
- Is this okay?
REPAIRMAN: Just relax.
WESLEY: Is this part of it?
REPAIRMAN: There we go.
- You going to put a bag over my head?
- REPAIRMAN: No. There's no need for a bag.
- That's not too tight, is it?
- No, that's nice.
Why did you come here, Wesley?
Well, you brought me here, remember?
(GROANING) What the fuck did you do that...
(HEART BEATING)
(GROANING)
How many punches
did The Repairman throw
before he was counting sheep?
Well, I haven't spent a lot of time
having my face smashed in before, all right?
- Did you spend a lot of time with knives?
- At breakfast, lunch and dinner.
WESLEY: Fuck.
It was a rhetorical question, culo.
You interrupt me again,
I use the business end.
Here's what you need to know, puto.
Knives are easy to hide.
They don't jam and they never
run out of bullets.
(COUGHS)
They come in handy
when you have to do some
close contact work.
What the fuck, man?
- Come here. Come here.
- WESLEY: What?
BUTCHER: Now, try to cut me.
WESLEY: What?
Try to cut me. Hey!
- Just stick me with that...
- Be careful with that. That's sharp.
- Just stick and stick and stick.
- Why?
- Seriously, man, I could hurt you.
- Hey!
Okay, pussy.
- I'm not a pussy.
- You're a pussy.
- No, I'm not a pussy.
- You're a pussy!
I'm not a pussy. I got a healthy respect
for the human condition.
- Fuck that, you pussy!
- I'm not a pussy!
- You're a pussy!
- Come on, pussy.
- I'm not a pussy!
(EXCLAIMS IN PAIN)
(SCREAMING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
Hi. How you doing?
What the fuck?
The fuck!
(HUSHING) Just a moment. Just a moment.
Sorry.
WESLEY: Hello? Hey!
Hey, come back! Hey!
You must drink. Drink. Yeah.
(COUGHS)
- What is this?
- This is the recovery room.
This bath stimulates white blood cells
and speed up the process.
In here, bruises, cuts, breaks
heal in hours, not days.
You shitting me?
- What is that? Vodka?
- Yeah.
- Are you Russian?
Get up.
This is The Gunsmith.
He knows more about a piece than anybody,
and he's gonna teach you how to use one.
- How you doing?
- Pretty good.
- You know that Seltzer broke his leg?
- FOX: Oh, really?
GUNSMITH: Yeah, in three places.
FOX: How'd he do that?
GUNSMITH: Jumped off a building.
FOX: So, is he okay?
GUNSMITH: Yeah. It's pretty bad, though.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, you guys, that is so realistic.
He's been in recovery for, like,
three days now,
and they say they're not even
gonna let him out.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
Hey, we can't shoot a dead woman!
She might be somebody's mom...
(GUN FIRES)
You need to know what it's like
to put a bullet in a body.
FOX: Why are you here?
You know, I thought I was learning to be
some kind of super assassin.
You know, if I wanted to get beat up,
I would have stayed in my cubicle,
you know.
Fuck.
FOX: All right, shoot the target.
From there.
- You want me shoot through Wilbur?
- I want you to curve the bullet.
How am I suppose to do that?
It's not a question of how,
it's a question of what.
If no one told you that bullets flew straight
and I gave you a gun
and told you to hit the target,
what would you do?
Let your instincts guide you.
WESLEY: How the hell did he do that?
Can you do that? Can you do that? Hello?
Hey, I think that's my old train.
FOX: Still is.
(SCREAMING)
Shit! You fucking asshole!
Come on!
Let's go.
Are you out of your fucking mind?
Oh, shit. Oh, shit. Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
(SCREAMING)
Oh, God, I feel... I feel... I feel...
I feel kind of good.
GUNSMITH: He got Rictus.
Perfect shot. Impossible angle.
Cross is taking us out one by one.
And Wesley is the only one
who can get to him.
Cross gets closer with each hour.
Get back to work.
FOX: See that?
- It's a shuttle.
- Okay.
I want you to try and catch it.
You want me to stick my hand in there?
Yes. I want you to catch it.
(SCREAMS)
(EXCLAIMS)
You wanna put a gun to my head?
I can just slow things down
like with the flies.
You need to learn
to control that by yourself.
(HEART BEATING)
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
This is bullshit! Fuck this!
SLOAN: How's it going today, Wesley?
No. Fuck the loom and fuck The Repairman!
I can shoot the wings off the back of a fly!
I'm ready!
You're ready when Fox says you're ready.
- Who put her in charge?
- I did.
(WHISTLING)
Wesley.
(CHUCKLES)
People think you use cheese
to catch these beauties.
But they go apeshit for peanut butter.
Your father was a big fan of this. Watch.
(WATCH BEEPING)
Plastic explosive and peanut butter!
Sorry, Mickey.
Five, four, three, two, one.
Hey. Hey, Russian.
Good for one. Yeah.
Imagine if you had a thousand.
They really fucked you up, didn't they?
What the hell did they do to you?
(WHISTLING)
Throw you in front of a moving train
for no reason?
Beat the shit out of you?
You know, you can say it,
this place is bullshit. It's bullshit, huh?
Bullshit!
(WATER SPLASHING SOFTLY)
Repairman. Five minutes.
Heads up out of the question?
Fuck.
You're a waste of my fucking time!
Why are you here?
I don't know, so hit me.
- Why are you here?
- I had a shit life, so why wouldn't I?
I wanna kick your fucking ass!
Tell me what you want me to say.
- FOX: Why are you here?
- I don't know!
FOX: Why are you here?
- Why are you here?
- I don't know why I'm here.
FOX: Why are you here?
Why are you here?
I don't know who I am.
- What did you say?
- I said...
I said I don't know who I am.
Do you really want to know who you are?
Yeah. It's my room.
No.
This was your father's room.
WESLEY: What happened?
SLOAN: A member
of this fraternity went rogue.
WESLEY: Cross.
He started by killing
the one man who was better than him.
Your father.
Blindsided him on a rooftop.
Betrayed him.
Everything in this room,
books, weapons, clothes,
belonged to him.
Now they belong to you.
Find a connection in this room, Wesley.
It may be the only way
of finding out who you are.
WESLEY: Now I know why I could never care
about anything before this.
I was living a lie.
Finally, I have a chance to step
into my father's shoes.
Grow a pair. Live the life I was born to live.
I've been pissing it all away
like it was another fucking billing report.
I have to train harder.
I have to be as good as my father.
On these shelves, Wesley,
are the records of the Fraternity kills,
everything you will need to kill your target.
WESLEY: To kill Cross,
the man who betrayed the Fraternity
and murdered my father, I must prepare.
I have to become his student,
memorise every move he ever made,
every attack he ever executed.
When he dropped a patient in an airtight
room surrounded by Secret Service agents.
When he took out that
businessman in the elevator.
His bullets untraceable, of course.
Or how no matter what the weapon
or how he eliminated his target,
he was always one chess move ahead.
One move more prepared.
One step quicker.
One shot more precise.
In fact, in all my research,
I found that he never missed a target.
Not until me.
(YELLS)