Gimme a beer.
Frostier?
Charles Frostier.
Yes.
Georges Duroy.
With the Sixth Hussard's,
Algeria, '95.
Yes. Georges Duroy.
Yes.
You look terrible!
Let me buy you a drink.
When's the last time you had a proper meal?
'Scuse me!
Champagne!
What have you been doing all these years?
I only just got out!
I'm hoping for better luck in Paris.
You couldn't look for a better time.
Paris is filthy with money.
Rotten with it.
If you can't succeed here,
you might as well lie down and die.
Yes!
Even the whores are getting rich!
And me, ex-soldier,
living on the Boulevard Hausseman.
Political editor of the
"La Vie Francaise".
We're going to be the newspaper
that brings down the government.
I'm working as a clerk at the railway office.
I don't have your connections, Charles.
Had to make money somehow.
And we can't go on looting spree anymore,
we're not in the desert.
Why don't you come to dinner.
Tomorrow night.
Come and meet my wife.
Well, the thing is, uh...
I don't have any evening clothes.
Well, here.
Buy some, hire some, come at 7:30, yes?
Yes.
- Good!
Georges Duroy.
What name shall I give?
- Georges Duroy.
Mr. Georges Duroy.
I am Madeleine Frostier.
You're married to Charles?
Of course.
Charles told me all about you.
Madame Francaise de Marelle.
Madeleine.
- Clotilde.
You look lovely.
I'm Clotilde.
You can call me Clotilde.
Madame Pierre Rousset.
He's frail. Gout's going to his kidneys.
He'll become a member of the Academy
for the rest of his life.
And so everyone will be satisfied.
You're awful.
It's this knife, Duroy.
What?
He's not used to eating like this.
I believe you've only just returned
from your posting in North Africa.
You were in Algeria?
Yes.
Charles and I were first there together...
five - five years ago?
- Five years.
He was a little thinner then.
Where were you garrisoned?
I was garrisoned at the frontier.
Very edge of the Sahara.
I once heard a very foolish story
about the desert.
May well be a myth but I find it
rather romantic.
I was told that the sands - sing?
Oh, it's true. It's an effect of the wind
on the dunes..
it makes kind of music.
And what does it sound like?
It sounds very sad and mournful.
At least it does to a lonely soldier.
Euw...
But how could you be lonely?
In there, the women are divine!
The women are ravishing,
and yet, I was still homesick.
Sand storms and mangy dogs,
that's what I remember.
You could run something extraordinary about this.
I think it would be timely.
- Timely? Why?
Don't you read the newspapers?
- No.
The government are trying to take Morocco.
Yes.
"For the good of the Moroccan people",
of course.
But surely, nobody wants war.
- That won't stop them.
No, but we will.
Think of it.
An eye-witness view.
A handsome young soldier
on the frontier.
Homesick and alone.
His adventures,
his insights.
The diary of a cavalry officer.
What do you think, dearest?
What fish are we having?
Oh, yes, let's change the subject.
I can't bear politics.
Men talking about men,
fighting with men about men.
Bores me stupid.
What does interest you?
Well...
I like enjoying myself.
What do you enjoy?
Well, I don't know...
Everything.
All right, you!
"Diary Of A Cavalry Officer."
I want the first article in the morning.
You realize he's never written a word?
I'll help him get started.
We'll write it as a letter to a friend.
Dear
Henri,
I'm sorry I haven't written for so long.
It is almost a month
since I first set foot
in this glorious land.
I do not know that the heat
would agree with you, dear friend,
but I know you would share
my enthusiasm for the people.
If only I could convey to you
the true wonder of the souq.
The scent of cinnamon and saffron,
heavy on the warm air.
She was wearing a simple dress,
and a shawl against the sun.
The colour of...
pomegranate blossom.
She needed no other ornament.
The simple perfection of her face
and the beauty of her smile
I cannot describe.
All I know is,
that with one look,
and one look alone,
I was hers.
I like being a journalist.
I hope you don't think I'm going to write
all your articles for you.
No.
I would never presume...
I meant something quite different.
I know what you meant.
Let's be clear.
I have no interest in being your mistress.
There's nothing more boring to me
than an infatuated youth.
I know perfectly well that love
for you is an appetite.
Makes idiots of you all.
Look at me, please.
I will never be your mistress.
You understand?
Yes.
- Good.
Then we can be friends.
Real friends!
Now I can give you some advice.
The most important people in Paris
are not the men.
are their wives.
Call on Madame Rousset.
She likes you.
Madame Rousset likes me?
Not like that.
Never like that.
No.
Her husband values her opinion
above all others'.
One good word from her is worth
ten years of grovelling to him.
But you may very much enjoy
a visit to my friend Clotilde.
She's such wonderful company.
And her husband is very often away.
If there's ever...
any way I can repay your kindness...
May I present Georges Duroy?
We're helping him get on his feet.
This is the Comte de Vaudrec.
The Comte is our best and closest friend.
Duroy!
Mr. Rousset.
You remember Georges Duroy?
"Diary Of A Cavalry Officer."
Your article was a success.
Write me another.
Put him on a payroll, Frostier.
If you think so...
You'll get five francs for this article,
five for the next.
And two hundred a month.
Plus ten centimes a line,
any articles you manage to place.
Here.
Give this to the Chief Cashier.
What's the matter?
Can't believe your luck?
Hello, I'm Laurine.
You're George.
Please sit down.
Maman will be down shortly.
What's your favourite game?
Tag.
Tag?
Well...
you...
are it!
Who's it?
You are!
- I'm going to catch you!
Get Georges!
Tag!
Who's chasing who?
You're chasing us!
It is time for Laurine to take her lunch.
- I want to stay with Georges.
Well, perhaps you'll permit me
to call on you again.
Come soon, Bel Ami.
Kiss!
Bel Ami!
She never hugs anyone.
I'm so glad you called.
- When can I see you again?
I'll come to you.
Tomorrow.
You should come today.
Well, I hope you haven't gone
to too much trouble.
Would you like a drink?
- Yes.
Yes, I would.
I'm a bit nervous.
- So am I.
Do you think it'll take the both of us?
I'd like to do this again.
- I'd like to do this now.
I mustn't come to your room, you know.
Anyone might see.
I can't risk a divorce.
I would lose Laurine.
And I don't want to embarrass my husband.
He's a good man.
A love nest is what we need.
A little place where we can go to be alone.
From time to time?
I would pay for it.
My money...
to spend on me...
on something I want.
What you're reading?
It's a letter for my father.
Every week he puts on his best suit
and goes to the priest.
And the priest writes a letter for him.
And every week it's the same thing.
Your mother sends her blessings...
Pigs have diarrhoea...
When you're getting married?
My father's a peasant.
He's never left his village.
And he's asking me for money.
I'd like to see where you grew up.
I'd like to see you there.
Promise me something.
Don't bring your other women here.
I don't have other women.
All men have other women.
Not me.
Honestly?
Don't lie to me.
Honestly and truly.
Champagne!
Hello.
- Hello.
I was talking to your friend here.
Georges.
I think you've mistaken me for somebody else.
So I see.
Not so friendly after all, are we?
Now that you're not looking for a cheap fuck!
Clo!
Don't you dare touch me!
- That was before I knew you.
Clotilde!
All you had to do was say hello to me.
Who are you to speak to me?
Who am I?
Beggar!
Duval.
- Yes?
No!
You still owe me forty.
I need to eat too.
Why don't you try earning it?
"Diary Of A Cavalry Officer."
Whatever happened to that?
Perhaps you can get my wife to write it.
Perhaps you think you can draw your salary,
and she will do your job for you!
Now I - I brought you into my home,
I fed you, I clothed you.
And how do you repay me?
By learning to play Cap'n Bo-
I mean, My Go-
You shut up, I'll write it now!
You will, will you?
There you go, Frostier.
Did you really write this?
Yes.
You write like an errand boy.
Rousset shall see this.
Frostier!
Pompous idiot.
He can talk!
Couldn't even write his own name
without his wife to spell it for him.
You know what they say about her.
What?
You know,
Vaudrec?
You shut your mouth!
You don't know her.
Mr. Rousset regrets to inform you
that your services are no longer required.
Pack up and get out!
You're on your own, Duroy.
No women to help you here.
Madame Rousset.
I hope you'll forgive me for intruding.
Mr. Duroy.
I wanted to make a gift to you,
these pears,
I received from my parent's orchard
in Normandy today.
How very kind.
Would you care to join us?
I would, thank you.
Will you eat a pear, Madame Rousset.
Well, um... yes, I think I might.
Head of Gossip.
Head of Gossip?
Ah, Duroy.
You remember my wife.
Mr. Duroy.
Now, do you remember Madame de Marelle?
Of course.
Well, Bel Ami.
Don't you have a smile for your old friend?
Let's go in to dinner, ladies.
We have pages and pages of gossip for you.
Madame Frostier.
Bel Ami.
I thought you'd forgotten me.
- Impossible.
I missed you so much.
Why didn't you come to me?
I thought you didn't want me anymore.
I'll always want you.
I must go.
My husband will be wondering where I am.
My other husband.
Your rich husband.
- The father of my daughter.
Will you lace me up?
Don't forget to tie a double bow.
Like your husband does it?
Poor Charles.
He won't live to see another spring.
Madeleine has taken him to the sea,
but it won't help.
Poor thing.
She won't be a widow for long.
Thank you for coming.
You're the only one.
How is he?
I brought him to Cannes to make him better.
But I'll bury him here.
They're my favourite.
Thank you.
You come to see me die?
No.
Just come to escape the city.
Because I'm going to live.
- Yes.
I am.
I'm going to live.
- Yes.
Help me!
I want to go...
for a drive!
You're not strong enough.
- Help, help...
I want you to listen to what I have to say.
And try to understand.
Don't be angry.
I only want you to know that with one word
you can make me happy.
You can make me your friend,
your brother,
or you can make me your husband.
My heart and my body are yours.
You have to understand,
I am not like other women.
Marriage to me is...
partnership, contract between equals.
I will not accept authority,
jealousy,
questioning my conduct.
I insist on being free.
- Of course.
You must give it more thought.
It is an important decision for us both.
Clo.
Just tell me.
Tell me quickly.
I'm getting married.
Of course, you must.
Who is she?
Madeleine Frostier.
You've chosen exactly the woman you need.
Yes.
And you love her.
Clo.
- No.
No. I'll be fine.
The government insists that it is
abandoning its set eyes on Morocco.
No, no, better.
The government insists that it's listened
to the will of its people
and abandoned its set eyes on Morocco.
Georges. The papers.
This is so boring.
This endless to and fro.
They say this,
we say that.
Yes, you're right.
It's as stale as old bread.
Wasn't there a deputy? Who was it?
I know it's here somewhere.
He bet his moustache
the government was lying.
Sarazin.
We should give Sarazin's moustache
a column of its own.
Georges!
It's brilliant!
That is brilliant!
Rousset will love it.
I've been thinking...
the political editor
of a leading newspaper,
should have a more memorable name.
Something...
a bit grand.
Where are your parents from?
My parents are from Cantelaux.
You remember?
We didn't have our honeymoon there.
Georges...
Duroy de Cantelaux.
No, it's not quite right.
Duroy de Cantel.
Madeleine, I'm from Cantelaux.
I prefer that.
No, no, no, listen.
Georges
Duroy
de Cantel.
Say it again.
Georges
Duroy
de Cantel.
Madame
Duroy
de Cantel.
"Sarazin's moustache".
This is exactly what we need.
Originality of thought.
Print!
Sit!
They're for my wife.
Georges!
Oh! Thank you.
You know how I love them.
One can never have too many.
The Comte was just leaving.
Oh, not for my sake, I hope.
No, no.
I have business to attend to.
Thank you, Paul.
Thank you.
And give my regards to your wife.
I wish her better health.
You are too kind, Mr. de Comte.
That'll be all.
What did he want?
It's Tuesday!
He always comes on Tuesday.
And when are your politicians arriving?
In half an hour.
- In half an hour!
Yes.
In half an hour.
I invited  Laroche.
You must pay special attention to him.
He's going to be Foreign Minister one day,
I promise.
Georges.
We are going to bring this government down.
I want the word on front page
of every newspaper.
I want it on every wall.
On every shop window.
I want every man, woman and child to know,
that this government is lying.
Frostier can dig something up.
What's that?
What?
You just called me Frostier.
Ah, force of habit.
Don't be offended.
It's easy mistake to make.
How do you mean?
- And...
we should look into troop movements.
Logistics.
Yes.
Laroche, you can help us here.
I know a couple of officers, who are
sympathetic to our cause.
You can talk to...
Laroche will tell you what to write.
Look at these exports to Algiers.
Why are we going from shipping hundreds of tons
of grain here,
to...
Look, look.
Thousands of tons here.
Why?
I don't know.
To - to feed an army.
To feed an army.
This is it!
Who is supplying the grain?
Georges, that's the question!
Georges, I need to work.
My brilliant wife.
All right.
Madeleine.
Madeleine, slow down, slow down.
Madeleine!
Look.
The're going to invade.
La Vie Francaise
has found proof.
Of course.
It's Tuesday.
The Comte de Vaudrec must be arriving soon.
Incontrovertible proof
of the government's true intentions
toward Morocco.
We never talked about that,
have we?
Comte de Vaudrec.
Man,
who arrives unannounced.
Who knows all the servants better than I.
buried...
deep amongst the dreary columns
of our trade finance.
What is he to you?
Where no one will think to look.
- What is he to you?
Do you want to be the man,
who brought down a government?
Or do you want to be a fool?
Just waiting for Laroche.
You know my daughter Suzanne?
So pretty.
And another for Bel Ami.
It's what mamman calls you.
Well, I have from time to time.
I hope you don't mind.
Call him whatever you like.
Our Foreign Minister!
Thank you! Thank you, my good friends!
My excellent, hard-working friends!
'Coz I'm afraid I have bad news for you.
Our work has only just begun!
We have a great task ahead of us.
Our achievements in government
must dwarf our achievements in opposition.
There will be battles.
There will be conflicts.
But they will be fought
not on the sands of Morocco,
but on the floor of the Chamber.
My first act as Foreign Minister,
is to recall General Pertain from Algiers.
There will be no Minister of War
in this government.
Hear this my friends,
people of France...
I don't have to ask how you are...
I've been very pleased for you.
How's Laurine?
- She still hasn't forgiven you.
She calls you Mr. Frostier now.
She's too young understand.
And you?
You made a good marriage.
We all have to do it.
And I miss you.
Our love nest feels cold without you.
You kept it on.
I'm an optimist.
Morocco is safe!
Come, play a hand.
Sit!
Let my boy deal.
I'm warning you,
I'm on a winning streak.
I'm more powerful than a king.
Not as rich.
Not yet anyway.
In a mere morning,
I empty the Chamber Of Deputies
and fill it again with men of my choosing,
with nothing more than words on a page.
They're not your words, though.
Are they?
How's married life?
How do you get along with Vaudrec?
He visits quite often.
I dare say it's only fair, after all,
he does own the apartment.
Duroy?
Yes, he set them up at the apartment
after he married Madeleine to Frostier.
He married
Madeleine to Frostier?
Well, he introduced them, and,
then he paid the dowry.
So...
I suppose that's how you pull it...
Vaudrec is a father to her.
Perhaps.
Why don't you go and enjoy the party.
I'm sure the ladies will want to dance.
Bel Ami.
What brings you here?
You were caught in the rain.
No, I didn't come here by chance.
I don't mean to frighten you.
I expect nothing.
I ask for nothing.
I don't even know what I'm doing.
I'm sorry if I offended you.
No.
No, you’re not offended me.
But we must talk of it no longer.
Shall I leave?
Shall I stay?
Is there any hope for me?
You are trying to seduce me in a church.
I've never h-
had a lover, before.
Look at me.
Does your husband tell you
you're beautiful?
Virginia.
Virginia!
Georges.
Whose arms are these?
They're mine.
And whose lips...
- Virginia.
Whose lips?
They're my lips.
Come on!
Get dressed!
When will I see you again?
- Please, leave.
My beautiful Georges.
My darling boy, please tell me.
Tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
Yes, tomorrow.
Georges?
Georges.
Madeleine will be wondering
where you are.
Madeleine?
Madeleine!
Where's my wife?
She's with the Comte de Vaudrec.
What?
He died, this morning.
I have asked you here today
Madame Duroy de Contel,
to hear the will of the Comte de Vaudrec.
The Comte has named you, Madame,
as the sole inheritor of his estate.
The value of which stands at
1 080 015 francs,
and 29 centimes.
There is one complication.
The nature of the legacy.
The nature of the legacy?
If you'll forgive me, sir...
it is unusual for an estate
to be left solely to a married woman.
It would normally
be left to the husband.
And why is that?
To avoid any suggestion of...
forgive me,
impropriety in the relationship.
What was he to you?
What was he thinking,
the stupid old bastard?
He should have left it all to me.
That would have been much better for you.
He must have known
what people would make of it.
He must have realized how it would
compromise you.
Unless it was done in innocence.
The fatherly gesture?
He was like a father to you,
wasn't he?
A guardian.
I can't accept it.
I must protect my reputation.
I don't want a million francs.
Come on, let's not be hasty.
I'm sure we can reach some kind of...
But the will is there,
for all to see.
I can only redeem it by rejecting it.
But if I, your husband,
chose to accept it,
then who is to question me?
Indeed,
to refuse,
is to admit the shame.
Whereas,
to accept,
is to deny it.
Good.
Perhaps your old man
wasn't so stupid after all.
Don't speak of him.
What was he to you?
Tell me.
Tell me, I deserve an answer.
He is...
a man I have lost.
The man I am...
grieving.
You wanted...
to be something small,
something squalid,
and contemptible.
He was my friend.
My father,
and my lover.
You loved him.
How will I live...
You haven't been to see me for a while.
For a whole week I waited
for a word from you.
Georges.
My beautiful boy.
- Don't call me that!
They're not for you.
You're meeting someone else.
Take me with you.
I need to talk to you.
Just for a while.
Remember where you are!
You shouldn't have seduced me.
You should have left me where I was.
A happy and faithful wife.
Please, let me come with you.
Please, just for an hour.
I've got something so important
to tell you.
Something to your advantage.
It's about my husband.
Please.
If you're going to cry,
you should leave.
Please, Georges.
Oh, my darling Georges.
My beautiful boy.
I have been so clever.
So discreet.
I've asked all the right questions.
And listened carefully.
Oh, come on!
What?
Our new government is going
to take Morocco.
Virginia.
The new government came to power,
I brought them to power,
on the promise that they would not.
That's the whole point.
Don't you see?
No one's expecting it.
My husband and Laroche have been hatching
this plan for a long time.
The first troops sail tonight.
Tonight?
But they would have included me.
They don't trust you.
They think you're too impulsive.
Too greedy, they say.
Not used to having money.
They think that you'll give them away.
They think I'm too greedy?
- They don't know you as I do.
Over the past few weeks,
they've bought the entire Moroccan loan.
They've bought every copper mine in Morocco.
Every last one.
They stand to make 70 million apiece.
70 million?
He's spending it already.
He's going to buy The Ballet Saint-Honorary©.
70 million and I've shamed myself for a pittance.
Aren't you proud of me?
Don't you love me?
Haven't I done well
finding this out, my darling?
I've bought shares for you too.
And they'll make you at least
seventy thousand.
I don't want your pennies!
They're not worth the price
I've paid for them!
No!
You disgust me!
- But I love you!
I don't want your love.
I've never loved you.
Your smell.
It turns my stomach!
Because you smell of him!
Your filthy husband!
I used to laugh every time I'd had you
to think I'd sent you back
to him with my sweat on your skin,
when all the while,
it was me!
I was the one getting fucked!
Me!
Get out of my house!
- Just listen to them, Georges.
Get out!
Get out of my house!
Listen to them, Georges.
Just listen to what they have to say!
I am going to ruin you.
Don't be a child.
Consider your best interest.
There's still money to be made.
You think I've robbed you?
You're not my responsibility.
The opportunity was there
for anyone who had eyes to see it.
You!
You are an embarrassment to Charles.
A failed soldier,
barely literate.
He said you'd never amount to much.
Seems he was right.
Pity you didn't marry more wisely.
You'll be missed.
You knew!
Don't be absurd, Georges.
How could I know?
I'm a woman.
I'm not invited to the card game.
Who was it today, hm?
Clotilde?
Or Virginia?
Or both!
And yesterday?
You stupid,
stupid man!
You, complete and perfect man!
I poured my talent into you!
My intelligence.
My vision into you!
I had no conception
of the depths of your emptiness!
Nothing.
There's nothing there.
Nothing but rage.
Like dumb animal.
That's what you are.
An animal.
I thought I could teach you.
But what I should have done
was train you!
Excuse me.
I always liked your audacity.
I don't need to hide my face,
I'm not the criminal.
You're not going to throw me out?
- No.
Stay. Drink my champagne,
dance with my wife.
Yours, I see,
is already spoken for.
Georges.
Georges?
I've been such a fool.
Why do you come back to me?
I don't know.
Perhaps because you never
expect me to.
I am sorry I hurt you.
It is worth saying.
I've never seen such a host
of bucktooth cretins.
Everyone a noble bankrupt.
All here for Suzanne
and her 30 million francs.
Open this door or we will force it!
Who is it?
Police.
Madame, Madeleine Duroy
de Contel?
Wife of Mr. Georges Duroy
Yes.
Madame Duroy de Contel.
I have found you here in a place
that is not your home.
With Mr. Francaise Laroche.
Do you admit to this man
as your lover?
I admit it.
Madame I have no choice
but to charge you with adultery.
Is there anything you wish to say?
- No.
Let's leave her in peace.
We have no further business here.
What should I do?
Should I go?
No, stay.
Finish, if you like.
Well,
you'll hear from my lawyer
in a few days.
Good-bye, Georges.
Good-bye.
I couldn't get away!
They were shouting and screaming on and on.
My mum wouldn't stop crying and wailing,
she was like a mad woman.
I wish I could see their faces
when they find me gone!
Papa will turn blue.
We'll need two rooms.
Good night, Suzanne.
- But...
I need a good-night kiss.
You should get some sleep.
But I...
- Get some sleep.
Papa.
Maman.
He will not marry her.
- I should have seen it coming.
He will not marry her!
I will not...
Stop it!
He will marry her!
He must marry her!
And you will accept it, Virginia!
This is as much your doing
as it is mine!
My doing?
Your infatuation for him
infected my daughter!
He will marry her,
and I will be glad of it.
What more can a father wish for,
than to see his daughter
with a man he can respect?
She's only a child.
Do you love her?
- No.
She's of no interest to me.
Poor little Suzanne.
Suzanne's her father.
Just some perfect miniature.
You've ruined her.
I haven't. I'm going to marry her.
Did you sleep with her?
No.
You didn't sleep with her.
I didn't touch her.
I didn't need to.
It was enough for people
to think I had.
I don't know you at all.
You do.
Oh, do I?
He planned it.
You planned it!
You've ruined Laroche.
You humiliated Madeleine.
You humiliated her!
All, so you could take Suzanne.
Suzanne chose me because I was
the only one she wasn't
allowed to have.
And me?
Did you ever think,
how this would hurt me?
It has nothing to do with you.
Then why am I in pain?
I don't know.
You didn't even tell me yourself.
I had to hear it from my husband.
You think I'll forgive you anything.
I will not be stopped, Clotilde.
I will marry her.
You're just one of them, after all.
Just another,
selfish, brutal man.
Just another thief.
It's not enough to be loved, is it?
Oh, you must be a king!
No.
It's not enough to be loved.
Even by you.
I loved you when you had nothing.
I don't understand
why you must be so proud.
I don't understand.
- It's because you've never been poor.
Trying to scrape out some miserable
scrap of an existence!
I can't live like that.
Like my father.
Working to the bone,
and then down on his knees,
every week,
praying to God that the next
life will be better.
Well, there is no next life.
The flesh,
it rots in the earth.
It rots.
I have seen a man die.
And I am going to live.
It's so clear to me.
I thought you'd understand.