♪ ["THE BLOWER'S DAUGHTER"
BY DAMIEN RICE PLAYING]
♪ And so it is
♪ Just like you said
♪ It would be
♪ Life goes easy on me
♪ Lost
♪ Of the time
♪ And so it is
♪ Ahe shorter story
♪ No love, no glory
♪ No hero in her sky
♪ I can't take my eyes
off of you ♪
off you ♪
♪ I can't take my eyes
off of you ♪
off you ♪
♪ I can't take my eyes
♪ And so it is
♪ Just like you said
it should be ♪
♪ We'll both forget
the breeze ♪
♪ Most
♪ Of the time
[CAR TIRES SQUEALING]
♪ I can't take my mind
off of you ♪
off you ♪
♪ I can't take my mind
off of you ♪
Hello, stranger.
♪ I can't take my mind
off you ♪
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
Sorry.
Looking for a cigarette.
I've given up.
Thank you.
Got to be somewhere?
Work.
Hmm.
You didn't fancy
my sandwiches?
Don't eat fish.
Why not?
Fish piss in the sea.
So do children.
Don't eat children, either.
What's your work?
I'm sort of
a journalist.
What sort?
I write obituaries.
[WOMAN OVER P.A. SYSTEM]
[SIGHING]
Are we in
for a long wait?
She was 21
when she came in.
[GIGGLING]
Does it hurt?
I'll live.
Do you want me
to put your leg up?
Yes, please.
WOMAN ON P.A. SYSTEM:
Joanna bates.
Who cut off your crusts?
Me.
Did your mother cut off your
crusts when you were a little boy?
Yes, I believe she did.
You should eat
your crusts.
You should
stop smoking.
How long was I out?
About 10 seconds.
Then what?
You came to.
You focused on me.
You said,
"hello, stranger."
What a floozy.
The cabbie crossed himself,
he went,
"thank fuck. I thought
I'd killed her."
[CHUCKLING]
I said, "let's get her to a hospital."
He hesitated.
I think he thought
there'd be paperwork
and he'd be
held responsible.
So I said
with a slight sneer,
"please just drop us
at the hospital."
Show me the sneer.
Very good, Buster.
Thank you.
I told you, I've given up.
Try harder.
You live here?
Just arrived
from New York.
Takin' a vacation?
I'm on an expedition.
Where's your baggage?
Where are you staying?
I'm a waif.
A red bus.
Policeman or "Bobby."
Observe
the distinctive helmet.
[GIGGLING]
Saint Paul's cathedral.
Please note
the famous dome.
This is a truly
magnificent tour.
It's the London the
tourists never get to see.
What's this?
I've no idea.
[MAN WHISTLING]
[PUPPY BARKING]
ALICE:
They're all people who died
saving the lives of others.
I've been here before.
20 years ago, we came here.
My mother's dead.
My father and I came here
the afternoon she died.
She was a smoker.
She died in the hospital,
actually.
Is your father still alive?
Hanging on.
He's in a home.
You're late for work.
You sayin' you want me to go?
I'm saying
you're late for work.
ALICE: How did you end
up writing obituaries?
Um, well, I had dreams
of being a writer,
but I had no voice.
What am I saying?
I had no talent.
So I ended up
in obituaries,
which is the Siberia
of journalism.
Tell me what you do.
I want to imagine you
in Siberia.
Really?
Hmm.
[CHUCKLING]
Well, we call it
"the obits page."
There's 3 of us:
Me, Graham, and Harry.
When I get to work,
without fail...
Are you sure
you want to know?
Well, if someone
important died,
we go to the "deep freeze,"
which is, um,
a computer file
with all the obituaries, and we--we
find the dead person's life.
People's obituaries
are written
while they're still alive?
Some people's.
Then Harry, he's the editor,
he decides who
we're gonna lead with.
Then we make calls,
check facts.
At 6:00, we stand around
the computer
and look
at the next day's page
and make final changes.
Add a few euphemisms
for our own amusement.
Such as?
"He was
a convivial fellow."
Meaning he was
an alcoholic.
"He valued his privacy."
Gay.
"He enjoyed his privacy."
Raging queen.
What would my euphemism be?
"She was disarming."
That's not a euphemism.
Yes, it is.
What were you doing
in New York?
You know.
Well, no, I don't.
What, were you studying?
Stripping.
Look at your little eyes.
I can't see my little eyes.
Why'd you leave?
Problems with a male.
Boyfriend?
Kind of.
And you left him,
just like that?
It's the only way
to leave.
"I don't love you anymore.
Goodbye."
Supposing you do
still love them?
You don't leave.
You've never left somebody
you still love?
No.
This is me.
Enjoy your stay.
Please remember our traffic
tends to come from the right.
Bye.
[LAUGHING]
Do you have
a girlfriend?
Uh, yeah. Ruth.
She's called Ruth.
She's a linguist.
What's your name?
Alice.
My name is
Alice ayres.
♪ [OPERATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[CAMERA CLICKING]
[SIGHING]
Good.
I'm just gonna change the film.
Are you ok for time?
Mmm-hmm.
Do you mind
if I smoke?
If you must.
I don't have to.
Then don't.
I liked your book.
[CLICKING]
Thanks.
When's it published?
Next year.
How come you've read it?
Your publisher
sent me a manuscript.
I read it last night.
You kept me up till 4:00.
[CAMERA CLICKING]
I'm flattered.
Is your heroine
based on someone you know?
Yes. She's someone
called Alice.
Mmm.
How does she feel
about you stealing her life?
Borrowing her life.
I'm dedicating
the book to her.
She's pleased.
Mmm.
[CLICKING CONTINUES]
Do you exhibit?
Sometimes.
I have a thing next year.
DAN:
Portraits?
Mmm-hmm.
Of who?
Strangers.
How do
your strangers feel
about you stealing
their lives?
Borrowing.
Am I a stranger?
No. You're a job.
[CLICKING]
And you're a sloucher.
Sit up.
You didn't find it
obscene?
What?
The book.
I thought it was accurate.
About what?
About sex.
About love.
In what way?
You wrote it.
You read it till 4:00.
Don't raise your eyebrows.
It makes you look smug.
But you did like it?
Yes, but I could
go off it.
Stand up.
Any criticisms?
I'm not sure
about the title.
Got a better one?
The aquarium.
So you liked the filth.
You like aquariums.
Fish are therapeutic.
Hang out in aquariums,
do you?
When I can.
Good for
picking up strangers?
Photographing strangers.
Come here.
♪ [OPERATIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
You're beautiful.
I don't kiss
strange men.
Neither do I.
[CLICKING]
[SIGHING]
Do you and this Alice
live together?
Yes.
[MUSIC STOPS]
Are you married?
Yes.
No. Yes.
Which?
Separated.
[CUPBOARD OPENING]
Do you have any children?
No.
Would you like some?
Yes, but not today.
Would Alice
like children?
She's too young.
She works in a cafe
near here.
She's coming to meet me.
Quite soon.
Why are you
wasting her time?
You're judgmental.
You're devious.
I'm not
wasting her time.
She's completely
lovable.
And completely unleavable.
And you don't want
someone else
getting their dirty hands
on her.
Men are crap.
But all the same--
they're still crap.
[DOORBELL RINGING]
Your muse.
You've ruined my life.
You'll get over it.
Dan.
Your shirt.
You all done?
Hmm.
How's the photographer?
Good. Professional.
Rigorous. Beady.
One of your lot.
What, female?
Americano.
Come on.
Anna?
Alice.
Hi.
Sorry to interrupt.
No, we've just finished.
Would you like
some tea?
No, thanks.
I've been serving it
all day.
Can I use your loo?
Sure. Just through there.
[DOOR CLOSES]
She is beautiful.
I've got to see you.
No.
What's this?
Patriotism?
I don't want trouble.
I'm not trouble.
You're taken.
I've got to see you.
Tough.
You kissed me.
What are you, 12?
[DOOR OPENS]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
ALICE:
I'm a block of ice.
Will you take my photo?
I've never been photographed
by a professional before.
I'd really appreciate it.
I can pay you.
Uh, no, I-I'd like to.
Only if you don't mind.
Why should I?
Because you'll have
to go away.
We don't want him here
while we're working, do we?
No, we don't.
Right. I'll be in the pub
on the corner.
Have fun.
Thank you.
Good luck
with your exhibition.
Good luck with your book.
[DOOR OPENING AND CLOSING]
So you've got an exhibition?
Yeah.
I read Dan's book.
You've had quite a life, huh?
Thanks.
He said you work
in a cafe?
I am a waitress.
That's a temporary thing?
No.
Why don't you
come over here and sit?
[CLATTERING]
[CAMERA CLICKING]
You live here?
I do now.
Because you're single?
Mmm-hmm.
Who was your
last boyfriend?
[CHUCKLING]
My husband.
Was he English?
Very.
What happened to him?
Someone younger.
You've got a great face.
Doesn't everyone?
I suppose so.
I just...
From the book, somehow
I thought you'd be less...
What?
[CLICKING]
I--I don't know what,
exactly.
[CHILDREN PLAYING OUTSIDE]
How do you feel
about him using your life?
It's really
none of your business.
When he let me in
downstairs,
he had this look.
I just listened
to your conversation.
I don't know what to say.
I'm not a thief, Alice.
Do you want a drink?
I have some vodka in the fridge.
We could have a drink.
Just take my picture.
[CAMERA CLICKING]
Good.
[KEYBOARD KEYS CLACKING]
[KEYS CLACKING]
Shit.
[UNZIPPING]
[PHONE RINGING]
[COUGHS]
Yeah.
What's the histology?
Progressive?
No. Sounds like an atrophy.
Ok. Bye.
[SIGHING]
Bollocks.
[INHALING]
Hmm.
[PAPER RUSTLING]
[CHUCKLING]
Jesus.
[PHONE RINGING]
[sighing]
FEMALE TEACHER: All right,
children, it's time to go.
Come on, please. Quickly.
Quickly.
[CHILDREN TALKING]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
LARRY:
Anna?
I got the coat.
The white coat.
So I see.
I'm Larry. The doctor.
Hello, Dr. Larry.
Feel free to
call me "the sultan."
[CHUCKLING]
I can't believe
these things actually happen.
I thought if you showed up,
you'd be an old trout.
But you are
bloody gorgeous.
Well, thank you.
Fish. You gotta respect them.
Have you?
Of course.
We were fish. Long ago.
Before we were apes.
You mentioned a hotel.
No rush.
Actually, there is.
I've got to be
in surgery by 3:00.
Are you having
an operation?
No, I'm doing one.
Are you really
a doctor?
I said I was.
You are Anna?
[CHUCKLES]
I'm sorry.
Did I-- did I photograph you?
Did we meet somewhere?
Come on. Don't play games,
you nymph of the net.
Excuse me?
You were up for it
yesterday.
Oh, was I?
Yeah.
"Wear my wet knickers.
"Sit on my face.
Cum-hungry bitch."
Ok.
[CLEARING THROAT]
Why do I feel
like a pervert?
I think you're the victim
of a practical joke.
I am so sorry.
It's ok.
No.
We spoke
on the net last night.
Now you've seen me--
I wasn't on the net last night.
Where were you between the
hours of 6:45 and 7:00 P.M.?
That's really
none of your business.
Where were you?
On the net, talking to you.
Well, I was talking
to someone.
Someone pretending to be me.
I think you were talking
to Daniel Woolf.
Who?
This guy I know.
It's him.
No, I was talking
to a woman.
How do you know?
Believe me, she was a woman.
I got a huge...
She was a...
She wasn't, was she?
No.
What a bastard.
How do you know him?
I don't really know him.
I took his photograph
for a book he wrote.
I hope it sank
without trace.
It's on its way.
There is justice
in the world.
What's it called?
[CHUCKLING]
Oh.
The aquarium.
What a prick!
He's advertising.
But why would he
pretend to be you?
I think he likes me.
Funny way of showing it.
Can't he send you flowers?
Extraordinary thing,
the Internet.
[HORN BLOWING]
Possibility of genuine
global communication.
The first great
Democratic medium.
Absolutely.
It's the future.
2 guys wanking
in cyberspace.
He was the wanker.
I'll say this for him,
he can write.
Is he in love
with you?
I don't know. No.
Are you in love
with him?
I hardly know him.
But you're sort of
interested.
I think he's interesting.
No, don't. I look like
a criminal in photos.
Please. It's my birthday.
Really?
[CLICKING]
Really.
BALLOON VENDOR: Come
on, get your balloons.
[LAUGHING]
Happy Birthday.
BALLOON VENDOR: Come on,
get your balloons.
Thank you.
ALICE: This man comes into
the cafe today and he says:
"Hey, waitress,
what are you waiting for?"
Funny guy.
So I go,
"I'm waiting for a man
to come in here
"and fuck me sideways
with a beautiful line
like that."
What did he do?
Asked for a cup of tea
with 2 sugars.
Hmm.
[WATER SPLASHING]
I'm waiting for you.
To do what?
Leave me.
I'm not gonna
leave you.
I totally love you.
Why is this?
Please let me come.
I wanna be there
for you.
Are you ashamed
of me?
Of course not.
I told you
I want to be alone.
Why?
To grieve.
To think.
I love you.
Why won't you let me?
It's only a weekend.
Why won't you
let me love you?
[WATER SPLASHING]
Buster.
[SIGHING]
Let's go to this thing,
then I'll get my train.
I'll be away one night.
I'll be back
before you know it, ok?
♪ [MUSIC PLAYING]
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
WOMAN: Do these people pay you?
Or do you pay them?
[MAN SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
[WOMAN LAUGHING]
Like it?
No.
LARRY: What were
you so sad about?
Life.
What's that, then?
Hmm.
So what do you reckon,
in general?
You wanna talk
about art?
I know it's vulgar
to discuss the work
at an opening of the work
but someone's
got to do it.
I'm serious.
What do you think?
It's a lie.
It's a bunch of sad strangers
photographed beautifully,
and all
the glittering assholes
who appreciate art
say it's beautiful
because that's what
they want to see.
But the people
in the photos are sad
and alone.
But the pictures
make the world
seem beautiful
so
the exhibition's reassuring,
which makes it a lie.
And everyone loves
a big, fat lie.
I'm the big,
fat liar's boyfriend.
Bastard.
Larry.
Alice.
So you're
Anna's boyfriend.
A princess
can kiss a toad.
Frog.
Toad.
Toad, frog, lobster.
They're all the same.
So how long have you
been seeing her?
4 months.
We're in the first flush.
It's paradise.
All my nasty habits
amuse her.
You shouldn't smoke.
Fuck off.
I'm a doctor.
I'm supposed to say things like that.
You want one?
No.
Yes. No.
Fuck it, yes.
[LAUGHING]
No.
I've given up.
Oh.
So Anna tells me
your bloke wrote a book.
Any good?
Of course.
It's about you, isn't it?
Some of me.
Oh? What did he
leave out?
The truth.
Is he here, your bloke?
Yeah, he's over there
talking to your bird.
My boyfriend's here.
He's here? Where?
There.
With Alice?
I believe
you're acquainted.
I've never
seen him before.
No.
But you've spoken.
Well, conversed.
Corresponded.
I wrote to him?
On the net.
You sent him to the aquarium.
I happened to be there.
Nice work, cupid.
We need to talk
about this.
No, we don't.
He's very pretty.
She is very tall.
So you're a stripper?
Yeah.
And?
You take care, now.
I will.
You, too.
That's the way it should be.
He's very funny.
Excuse me.
Nice to meet you.
Pleased with
the success?
Yes, absolutely.
Yours was the best.
You were
the belle of the bullshit.
Who were
those awful people?
Where do they come from?
Why should we care?
You get this one.
You'll miss your train.
I'll be fine.
Come on, it's cold.
I'll see you on Sunday.
TAXI DRIVER:
Where to, love?
DAN:
Taxi!
[BRAKES SQUEALING]
Um...
Sorry.
TAXI DRIVER: Why don't you
make up your bleedin' mind?
ANNA: Good night.
Thank you so much.
I appreciate your coming.
I'll call you tomorrow.
See you next week.
Thanks.
MAN:
Thanks very much.
I thought you'd gone.
I forgot this.
So he's a dermatologist.
Can you get
more boring than that?
Obituarist?
Failed novelist, please.
I was sorry
about your book.
Thanks.
I blame the title.
WOMAN: So we pull out
our Christmas crackers
with those appalling jokes.
My guy says,
"hang on.
These are second-rate jokes.
I've got a first-rate joke.
Sit back and take notice."
So we go, "ok, what's the joke?"
And he says:
"It's based on
a Christmas Carol
which is why it seems so
relevant on Christmas day."
I haven't even seen you
for a year.
Yes, you have.
Only because you stalk me
outside my studio.
I don't stalk. I lurk.
And when I'm not there
you look for me.
How do you know
if you're not there?
Because I am there,
lurking from a distance.
[WOMAN CONTINUES TALKING]
Look at me.
Tell me you're not
in love with me.
I'm not
in love with you.
You just lied.
I'm your stranger. Jump.
[CARS HONKING]
Hello, stranger.
Hello.
Intense conversation?
His father died.
Were you spying?
Lovingly observing
with a telescope.
He's taller
than in his photo.
His photo's
a headshot.
Yeah, I know.
But his head implied
a short body,
when, in fact,
his head is deceptive.
Deceptive?
Yeah. He's actually
got a long body.
He's a stringy fucker.
I could have him.
What?
If it came to it,
in a scrap, I could have him.
Did you tell him
we call him cupid?
No, that's our joke.
I had a chat
with young Alice.
Fancy her?
Of course.
Not as much as you.
Why not?
You're a woman.
She's a girl.
She has the moronic beauty
of youth, but she's sly.
She seems open to me.
Yeah. That's how
she wants to seem.
You forget you're dealing
with a clinical observer
of the human carnival.
Am I, now?
Oh, yes.
Hmm.
You seem more like the cat
that got the cream.
Stop licking yourself.
That's the nastiest thing
you've ever said to me.
That's horrible.
I'm sorry.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
[DOOR LATCH CLICKING]
[KEYS RATTLING]
[PAPER RUSTLING]
Where have you been?
DAN:
Work thing.
Had a drink with Harry.
You never have one drink
with Harry.
You know
he's in love with you.
No, he's not.
Is he?
Did you eat?
I'll make you something.
I'm not hungry.
[SIGHING]
What?
This will hurt.
I've been with Anna.
I'm in love with her.
We've been seeing each other
for a year.
It began at her opening.
LARRY:
Have a nice one.
TAXI DRIVER:
Cheers, guvnor.
Cheers.
[DOOR BANGING]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Don't move.
I want to remember
this moment forever.
First time I walked
through the door,
returning from
a business trip,
to be greeted by my wife.
I have, in this moment,
become an adult.
Thanks for waitin' up,
you darling.
You goddess.
[sighing]
Hmm.
I missed you.
How about some tea, hmm?
Jesus, I'm knackered!
Didn't you sleep
on the plane?
No, because the permed German
sitting next to me
was snoring like
a messerschmitt.
What's the time?
Uh, about midnight.
Time. What a tricky
little fucker.
My head's in 2 places.
My brain actually hurts.
Do you want some food?
No, I need a bath.
I'll run it for you.
No, I'll--I'll
have a shower.
You ok?
Hmm.
How was the thing?
As dermatological conferences
go, it was a riot.
[CLEARING THROAT]
How was the hotel?
Someone told me
that the beautiful people
of the paranoid hotel,
the concierge,
the bellboys and girls...
Did you know this?
They're all whores.
Everybody knows that.
I didn't.
Oh.
[glass clinking]
I don't suppose you'd
fancy a friendly poke.
[CHUCKLING]
I just had a bath.
Right.
Well, I'll see to myself,
then,
in the
Elle decoration bathroom.
You chose that bathroom.
And every time I wash in it
I feel dirty.
It's cleaner than I am.
It's got attitude.
The mirror says,
"who the fuck are you?"
You chose it.
Doesn't mean I like it.
We shouldn't have this.
I hear middle-class guilt.
Working-class guilt.
Why are you dressed
if you just had a bath?
We needed some milk.
You ok?
Mmm-hmm.
You?
Yeah.
I'm going.
DAN:
I'm sorry.
Irrelevant.
What are you sorry for?
Everything.
Why didn't you
tell me before?
Cowardice.
Is it because
she's successful?
No, it's because
she doesn't need me.
[ZIPPING]
Did you bring her here?
Yes.
Didn't she get married?
She stopped seeing me.
Is that when we went
to the country?
To celebrate
our 3rd anniversary?
Did you phone her?
Beg her to come back?
When you went
for your long, lonely walks?
Yes.
You're a piece of shit.
Deception
is brutal.
I'm not pretending
otherwise.
How?
How does it work?
How do you do this
to someone?
Not good enough.
I fell in love
with her, Alice.
Oh, as if
you had no choice?
There's a moment.
There's always a moment.
"I can do this, I can give in
to this, or I can resist it."
[SNIFFLING]
And I don't know
when your moment was,
but I bet you there was one.
I'm going.
It's not safe
out there.
Oh, and it's safe in here?
What about your things?
I don't need things.
Where will you go?
Disappear.
The sultan has returned
bearing gifts.
Thank you.
[PAPER RUSTLING]
They're beautiful.
Here's a thing.
Alice was at the hotel.
What?
They sell these arty postcards
in the lobby.
I bought one
to boost your sales.
"Young woman, London."
And I checked for your book
in the museum of modern art.
And it was there.
Someone bought one.
This guy with a ridiculous
little beard.
He was drooling
over your photo
on the inside cover.
He fancied you, the geek.
I was so proud of you.
You've broken New York.
You're wonderful.
Don't ever forget it.
[SIGHING]
Can I still see you?
Dan, can I still see you?
Answer me.
I can't see you. If I see you,
I'll never leave you.
What will you do
if I find someone else?
Be jealous.
You still fancy me?
Of course.
You're lying.
I've been you.
Will you hold me?
[SOBS]
I amuse you,
but I bore you.
No, no. No.
You did love me?
I'll always love you.
I hate hurting you.
Then why are you?
'Cause I'm selfish.
And I think
I'll be happier with her.
You won't.
You'll miss me.
No one will ever love you
as much as I do.
[SNIFFS]
Why isn't love enough?
I'm the one who leaves.
I'm supposed to leave you.
Make some tea, Buster.
[SIGHS]
[CABINET DOOR OPENS]
[DOGS BARKING OUTSIDE]
[ALARM BLARING]
Alice?
[FOOTSTEPS PATTERING]
Why are you dressed?
Because I think
you might be about to leave me
and I didn't want
to be wearing a dressing gown.
I slept with someone
in New York.
A whore.
I'm sorry.
Why did you tell me?
I couldn't lie to you.
Why not?
Because I love you.
It's fine.
Really? Why?
Something's wrong.
Tell me.
Are you leaving me?
Because of this?
Why?
Dan.
Cupid?
He's our joke.
I love him.
You're seeing him now?
Since when?
Since my opening last year.
I'm disgusting.
You're phenomenal.
You're so clever.
Why did you marry me?
I stopped seeing him.
I wanted us to work.
Why did you tell me
you wanted children?
Because I did.
And now
you want children with him?
Yes.
I don't know.
But
we're happy,
aren't we?
You're gonna go
and live with him?
You stay here if you want.
Oh, look, I don't give a
fuck about the spoils.
You know, you did this to
me the day that we met.
You let me hang myself
for your amusement.
Why didn't you just tell me the
second I walked through the door?
I was scared.
You're a coward,
you spoilt bitch.
Are you dressed
'cause you thought
I might hit you?
What do you think I am?
I've been hit before.
Not by me.
Is he a good fuck?
Don't do this.
Just answer the question.
Is he good?
Yes.
Better than me?
Different.
Better?
Gentler.
What does that mean?
You know what it means.
Tell me.
No.
I treat you like a whore?
Sometimes.
Why would that be?
I'm sorry, you're--
don't say it!
Don't you fucking say:
"You're too good for me."
I am, but don't say it.
You're making
the mistake of your life.
You're leaving me
because you believe
that you don't deserve
happiness,
but you do, Anna.
Did you have a bath
because you had sex with him?
So you wouldn't smell of him?
So you'd feel less guilty?
How'd you feel?
[WHISPERING]
Guilty.
Did you ever love me?
[WHISPERING]
Yes.
[SOBBING]
[DOG BARKS IN DISTANCE]
LARRY:
Did you do it here?
No.
Why not?
Do you wish we did?
Just tell me the truth.
Yes, we did it here.
Where?
There.
On this?
We had our first fuck
on this.
Did you think of me?
When?
When did you do it here?
Answer the question!
This evening.
Did you come?
Why are you doing this?
'Cause I want to know.
Yes, I came.
How many times?
Twice.
LARRY:
How?
First he went down on me,
and then we fucked.
Who was where?
[SIGHS]
I was on top,
then he fucked me
from behind.
That's when you came
the 2nd time?
[ANNA SIGHS]
God.
Why is the sex
so important?
[YELLING] Because I'm
a fucking caveman!
Did you touch yourself
while he fucked you?
Yes.
You wank for him?
Sometimes.
And he does?
We do everything
that people who have sex do.
You enjoy suckin' him off?
Yes.
You like his cock?
I love it.
Like him coming in your face?
Yes!
What does it taste like?
It tastes like you,
but sweeter.
That's the spirit.
Thank you.
Thank you for your honesty.
Now fuck off and die
you fucked-up slag.
♪ ["WORLD OUTSIDE"
BY THE DEVLINS PLAYING]
♪ Say you believe it,
all of your lies ♪
♪ Tell me you feel it
and don't compromise ♪
♪ Oh, no
♪ I will still be there
for you ♪
♪ You're lighting my dreams
light up my skin ♪
♪ You're so far away,
you're holding it in ♪
♪ I'm looking around
watching it spin ♪
♪ God my world outside
♪ Is changing something
within ♪
[WOMAN EXCLAIMING]
♪ Tell me you reach it
some of the time ♪
♪ what you're searching for
[PEOPLE EXCLAIMING]
♪ Does the love
that surrounds you ♪
♪ Get you down
and kick you to the floor? ♪
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
I love you.
♪ ["SMACK MY BITCH UP"
BY PRODIGY PLAYING]
ALICE:
Thank you.
What's this room called?
The paradise suite.
How many paradise suites
are there?
8.
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
Do I have to pay you
to talk to me?
No. But if you want
to tip me,
you're welcome.
Thank you.
I used to come here
a million years ago.
It was a punk club.
The stage was...
♪ [MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING]
Everything is a version
of something else.
20 years ago.
How old were you?
4.
Christ.
When I was in flares,
you were in nappies.
My nappies were flared.
You have
the face of an angel.
Thank you.
What does your cunt
taste like?
Heaven.
[MEN WHOOPING]
How long
have you been doing this?
3 months.
Straight after he left you?
No one left me.
Nice wig.
Thank you.
Does all this turn you on?
Sometimes.
Liar.
You're telling me
it turns you on
because you think
that's what I want to hear.
You think I'm turned on
by it turning you on.
The thought of me
creaming myself
when I strip for strangers
doesn't turn you on?
Put like that, yes.
[MOANS]
[MEN CHEERING]
Are you flirtin' with me?
Maybe.
Are you allowed
to flirt with me?
Sure.
Really?
No, I'm not.
I'm breaking all the rules.
You're mocking me.
Yes, I'm allowed
to flirt.
To prize my money
from me.
To prize your money from you,
I may do or say as I please.
Except touch.
We're not allowed
to touch.
Open your legs.
Wider.
♪ Smack my bitch up
[MAN WOLF WHISTLES]
Show me.
So what would happen
if I touched you now?
I'd call security.
What would they do?
They would ask you to leave
and ask you not to come back.
And if I refused to leave?
They would remove you.
Those are security cameras
in the ceiling.
I think it's best
I don't attempt to touch you.
I'd like to touch you. Later.
I'm not a whore.
I wouldn't pay.
Why the fuck
did he leave you?
What's your job?
A question.
You asked me a question.
So?
It's a chink in your armor.
I'm not wearing armor.
Yes, you are.
You know you are, too.
Why are you
calling yourself Jane?
Because it's my name.
We both know it isn't.
You're all protecting
your identities.
There's a girl out there
who calls herself Venus.
What's her real name?
Pluto.
LARRY:
You're cheeky.
Would you like me
to stop being cheeky?
No.
What's your name?
[MEN WHOOPING]
Daniel.
Daniel the dermatologist.
I never told you
my job.
I guessed.
You're strong.
There's another one
out there.
Judging by the scars,
a recent patient of Dr. tit.
Calls herself cupid. Who's gonna
tell her that cupid was a bloke?
He wasn't a bloke.
He was a little boy.
I want you
to tell me your name.
Please.
Thank you.
My name is Jane.
Your real name.
Thank you.
My real name is Jane.
Careful.
[MONEY RUSTLING]
Thank you. Still Jane.
I've got about
another 500 quid here.
Why don't I just give you
all this money
and you tell me
what your real name is
Alice?
I promise.
Thank you.
My real name
is plain Jane Jones.
I may be rich,
but I'm not stupid.
What a shame, doc.
I love 'em rich and stupid.
[YELLING]
Don't you fuck around with me.
I apologize.
Accepted.
All the girls
in this hellhole,
the pneumatic robots,
the coked-up baby dolls,
and you're no different.
And you all use stage names to con
yourselves you're someone else,
so you don't feel ashamed
when you show your cunts and
assholes to complete strangers.
I'm trying to have
a conversation here.
You're out of cash, Buster.
I paid for this room.
This is extra.
We met last year.
Wrong girl.
Talk to me!
I am.
Talk to me in real life.
I didn't know
you'd be here.
I know who you are.
I love you.
I love everything about you
that hurts.
♪ ["HOW SOON IS NOW?"
BY THE SMITHS PLAYING]
[SOBBING]
She won't even see me.
You feel the same.
I know you feel the same.
You can't cry in here.
Hold me. Let me hold you.
We're not allowed
to touch.
Well, come home with me.
It's safe.
Let me look after you.
I don't need
looking after.
Everyone needs
I'm not your revenge fuck.
I'll pay you.
I don't need your money.
You have my money.
Thank you.
"Thank you." "Thank you."
Is that some kind of rule?
Just being polite.
Do you get a lot of grown men
crying their guts out here?
Occupational hazard.
Have you ever
desired a customer?
Yes.
Then put me out of my misery.
Do you desire me?
Because I'm being pretty fucking
honest about my feelings for you.
Your feelings?
Whatever.
No, I don't desire you.
Thank you.
Thank you sincerely
for your honesty.
Do you think you haven't give
us anything of yourselves?
Do you think because you
don't love us or desire us
or even like us,
you think you've won?
It's not a war.
♪ I need to be loved
♪ Just like everybody
else does ♪
If I asked you to strip
right now, would you?
Of course.
Do you want me to?
No.
Alice,
tell me something true.
Lying is the most fun
a girl can have
without taking
her clothes off,
but it's better if you do.
You're cold.
You're all cold at heart.
[SHOUTING]
What do you have to do
to get a bit of intimacy
around here?
Maybe next time
I'll have worked on
my intimacy.
No, I'll tell you
what's gonna work.
Is that you're gonna
take your gear off
right now.
And you're gonna
turn around very slowly,
and you're gonna bend over
and you're gonna touch
the fucking floor
for my viewing pleasure.
Is that what you want?
What else could I want?
[MEN WHOOPING]
[CHATTERING]
♪ [OPERATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[MAN COUGHING]
[DAN LAUGHS]
I'm sorry.
What happened?
Traffic.
Do you want to
go stand in the back?
No, let's have a drink.
You look flushed.
[MURMURS]
You have no need to run.
Vodka tonic?
Yes.
Vodka tonic
and a guinness, please.
Sure.
How was it?
Fine.
You had lunch?
Mmm-hmm.
Then what?
And then we left.
And?
There's no "and."
You haven't seen him
in 4 months.
There must be an "and."
How is he?
Terrible.
♪ [WOMAN SINGING]
Keep the change.
BARTENDER:
Thank you, sir.
DAN:
How is his dermatology?
He's in
private practice now.
Is he?
Hmm.
Was he weeping
all over the place?
Some of the time.
Poor bastard.
Was he difficult?
Are you angry
that I saw him?
No. It's just
I haven't seen Alice.
You can't see Alice.
You don't know where she is.
I haven't tried
to find her.
You know why
I saw him.
He's been begging me for months.
I saw him so he'd sign.
So has he signed?
Yes.
[CHUCKLES]
Congratulations.
You're a divorcee.
Double divorcee.
Mmm.
Sorry.
How do you feel?
Tired.
I love you.
And I need a piss.
Mmm.
I hate this place.
At least it's central.
I hate central.
Central London's
a theme park.
I hate retro.
I hate the future.
Where does that
leave me?
Come back.
You promised you wouldn't.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
How's work?
Oh, Jesus. Work's shit, ok?
[SIGHS]
Do they have waiters here?
I love you.
Please come back.
I'm not coming back.
Sign.
No pen.
Pen.
Give me back my hand.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Sign.
I'll sign on one condition.
We skip this.
We go to my sleek new surgery
and we christen
the patients' bed
with our final fuck.
I know you don't want to,
and I know you think
I'm sick for asking,
but that's what I'm asking.
For old times' sake.
[SCOFFS]
Because
I'm obsessed with you.
Because I can't get over you
unless...
Because I think, on some small
level, you owe me something
for deceiving me
so exquisitely.
For all these reasons,
I am begging you
to give me your body.
You'd be my whore.
And in return,
I will pay you
with your liberty.
You do this,
I swear I will not
contact you again.
I'm going to the bar.
I assume you still drink
vodka tonic?
[WATER RUNNING]
[DRYER WHIRRING]
[DOOR OPENING]
♪ [OPERATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
You slept with him,
didn't you?
[EXHALES]
What do you expect me to do?
Understand.
Why didn't you lie to me?
Because we said we'd always
tell each other the truth.
What's so great
about the truth?
Try lying for a change.
It's the currency
of the world.
I did what he wanted,
and now
he will leave us alone.
I love you.
I didn't give him
anything.
Your body?
If Alice came to you,
desperate,
with all that love
still between you,
and she said that she
needed you to want her
so she could get over you,
you'd do it.
I wouldn't like it either,
but I'd forgive you.
It's kindness.
No, cowardice. You...
You haven't got the guts
to let him hate you.
I'm doing this
because I feel guilty,
and because I pity you.
You know that, don't you?
Yes.
Feel good
about yourself?
No.
It's gone.
We're not innocent anymore.
Don't. Don't stop loving me.
I can see it
draining out of you.
It's me, remember?
It was a stupid thing to do,
and it meant nothing.
If you love me enough,
you'll forgive me.
Are you testing me?
No.
I do understand.
No. He understands.
All I can see
is him all over you.
He's clever,
your ex-husband.
I almost admire him.
You going to tell him?
I don't know.
Better to be truthful
about this kind of thing.
Sign.
[PAPER RUSTLING]
I forgive you.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Sign.
DAN:
I think you enjoyed it.
He wheedles you into bed.
The old jokes,
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]
The strange
familiarity.
I think
you had a whale of a time.
And the truth is I'll never
know unless I ask him.
Well, why don't you?
[AUDIENCE CHATTERING]
[ALL CHATTERING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[WATER SPLASHING]
[BELL BUZZES]
[INTERCOM BUZZING]
Yes?
You can go in now.
I want Anna back.
She's made her choice.
I owe you an apology.
I fell in love with her.
My intention was not
to make you suffer.
So where's the apology?
You cunt.
I apologize.
If you love her,
you'll let her go
so she can be happy.
She doesn't want
to be happy.
Everybody wants
Depressives don't.
They want to be unhappy
to confirm they're depressed.
If they were happy, they
couldn't be depressed any more.
They'd have to go out
into the world and live,
which can be depressing.
Anna's not a depressive.
Isn't she?
I love her.
Boo-hoo. So do I.
She's gone back to you because
she can't bear your suffering.
You don't know who she is.
You love her
like a dog loves its owner.
And the owner loves the dog
for so doing.
You'll hurt her.
You'll never forgive her.
Of course I forgive her.
I have forgiven her.
Without forgiveness
we're savages.
You're drowning.
You only met her
because of me.
Yeah. Thanks.
It's a joke.
Your marriage is a joke.
Here's a good one.
She never sent the divorce
papers to her lawyer.
Now, to a towering
romantic hero like you,
I don't doubt
I am somewhat common.
But I am, nevertheless,
what she has chosen,
and we must respect
what the woman wants.
[INTERCOM BUZZING]
If you go near her again,
I swear I will kill you.
Mmm-hmm.
Ok.
I have patients to see.
When she came here,
do you think she enjoyed it?
I didn't do it
to give her a nice time.
I fucked her to fuck you up.
A good fight is never clean.
And yeah,
of course she enjoyed it.
As you know,
she loves a guilty fuck.
You're an animal.
Yeah? What are you?
You think love is simple.
You think the heart is like a diagram.
Have you ever seen
a human heart?
It looks like
a fist wrapped in blood!
Go fuck yourself. You writer!
You liar!
You go check a few facts
while I get my hands dirty.
She hates your hands.
She hates your simplicity.
Listen, I spent the whole of the
last week talking about you.
I know
all your little ways.
Anna tells me you fucked
her with your eyes closed.
She tells me
you wake in the night
crying for your mother,
you mommy's boy.
I could go on.
Shall we stop this?
It's over. Accept it.
You don't know
the first thing about love
because you don't
understand compromise.
[DAN SNIFFING]
[SOBBING]
[LARRY SIGHS]
Don't cry on me.
[SOBBING]
I'm sorry.
I don't know what to do.
You want my advice?
You go back to Alice.
She'd never have me.
She's vanished.
No, she hasn't.
I found her, by accident.
She's working in a club.
Yes, I saw her naked.
No, I did not fuck her.
You spoke to her?
[INTERCOM BUZZING]
Yes. Yes, I know. One minute.
How is she?
She loves you
beyond comprehension.
Your prescription.
It's where she works.
Go to her.
[SNIFFLES]
Thank you.
You still pissing about
on the net?
Not recently.
I wanted to kill you.
I thought
you wanted to fuck me.
Don't get lippy.
I liked your book,
by the way.
Thanks. You stand alone.
With Anna.
You still writing obituaries?
Busy?
I was made editor.
Yeah? How come?
Previous editor died.
[CHUCKLING]
Alcohol poisoning.
I sat with him
for a week in the hospital.
I really do have
patients to see.
Thank you.
For what?
Being kind.
I am kind.
Your invoice is in the post.
[PHONE RINGING]
Dan.
[PHONE CONTINUES RINGING]
I lied to you.
I did fuck Alice.
Sorry for telling you.
I'm just not big enough
to forgive you.
Buster.
[DOOR CLOSING]
ALICE:
Show me the sneer.
Beautiful.
You'll wake up the hotel.
[WATER RUNNING]
ALICE:
Fuck me.
Again?
We have to get up at 6:00.
How can one man be so
endlessly disappointing?
That's my charm.
Mmm.
So where are we going?
My treat.
Where are we going?
My holiday surprise.
My rules.
Where are we going?
[GUFFAWING]
New York, New York,
New York.
Oh, you angel.
You did remember
to pack my passport?
Of course.
It's with my passport.
And where's that?
In a place
where you can't look.
No one sees
my passport picture.
Mmm.
When we get on the plane,
we'll have been together
4 years.
What about the gap?
You mean trial separation?
Didn't work out.
Happy anniversary.
I'm going to
take my eyes out.
What was in
my sandwiches?
Tuna.
How many stitches
did I get?
2. But you should have had 3.
What was your euphemism?
Disarming.
Too easy, Buster. Next?
That park.
Who'd I go there with?
Your father.
Were the chairs
in the hospital gray or blue?
No idea.
Trick question.
They were green.
You are a trick question.
[LAUGHING]
How come
we never took a vacation?
[WATER RUNNING]
We went to the country.
Doesn't count.
You were off
making sneaky phone calls
to that witch
we do not mention.
Come to bed.
I need a smoke.
How'd you manage
to give up?
Deep inner strength.
Why me?
You could have
chosen anyone. Why me?
Because you cut off
your crusts.
[LAUGHS]
And this.
[BOTH MOAN]
When are you going to
stop stripping?
Soon.
You're addicted to it.
No, I'm not.
It paid for this.
Tell me what happened.
Nothing happened.
But he came to the club.
Lots of men come to the club.
You came to the club.
♪ ["SMACK MY BITCH UP"
BY PRODIGY PLAYING]
ALICE LAUGHING:
The look on your face.
DAN:
What a face.
Mmm.
What a wig.
I saw this face,
this vision
when you stepped into
the road.
It was
the moment of my life.
This is
the moment of your life.
You were perfect.
I still am.
On the way to
the hospital,
I kissed your forehead.
ALICE:
You brute.
DAN: The cabbie saw
me kissing you.
He said, "is she yours?"
I said, "yes, she's mine."
She's mine.
So he came to the club,
watched you strip,
you had a little chat,
and that was it?
Yes.
You're not trusting me.
I'm in love with you.
You're safe.
You had every right.
I just want to know.
Why?
Because I want to
know everything.
Because I'm a lunatic.
Tell me.
Nothing happened.
You were living
with someone else.
What are you justifying?
I'm not justifying anything.
I'm just saying.
What are you saying?
I'm not saying anything.
I just want the truth.
Where are you going?
Cigarettes.
Everywhere's closed.
I'll go to the terminal.
When I get back,
please tell me the truth.
Why?
Because I'm addicted to it.
Because without it
we're animals.
Trust me.
[DOOR OPENING]
[DOOR CLOSING]
[AIRPLANE ENGINE HUMMING]
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
[ELEVATOR DOOR OPENING]
[GLASS CLINKS]
[DAN LAUGHS]
I don't love you anymore.
Since when?
Now.
Just now.
I don't want to lie,
I can't tell the truth,
so it's over.
It doesn't matter.
I love you.
None of it matters.
Too late.
I don't love you anymore.
Goodbye.
Here's the truth
so now you can hate me.
Larry fucked me all night.
I enjoyed it.
I came.
I prefer you.
Now go.
I knew that.
He told me.
You knew?
I needed to hear it from you.
Why?
'Cause he might
have been lying.
I had to hear it from you.
I would never have told you,
because I know
you'd never forgive me.
I would. I have.
Why did he tell you?
Because he's a bastard.
How could he?
Because he wanted this
to happen.
But why test me?
Because I'm an idiot.
Yes.
I would have loved you
forever.
Now please go.
Don't do this, Alice.
Talk to me.
I am talking. Fuck off.
No, I'm sorry.
You misunderstand.
I didn't mean to--
yes, you did.
I love you.
Where?
What?
Show me.
Where is this love? I...
I can't see it.
I can't touch it.
I can't feel it.
I can hear it.
I can hear some words
but I can't do anything
with your easy words.
Whatever you say,
it's too late.
Please don't do this.
It's done.
Now please go,
or I'll call security.
You're not in a strip club.
There is no security.
[HANDSET CLATTERING]
Why'd you fuck him?
I wanted to.
Why?
I desired him.
You weren't there.
Why him?
He asked me nicely.
You're a liar.
So?
Who are you?
I'm no one.
[SPITS]
Go on, hit me.
That's what you want.
Hit me, fucker.
[AIRPLANE ENGINE WHIRS]
♪ ["THE BLOWER'S DAUGHTER"
BY DAMIEN RICE PLAYING]
♪ And so it is
♪ Just like you said
♪ It would be
♪ Life goes easy on me
♪ Most of the time
♪ and so it is
♪ The shorter story
♪ No love, no glory
♪ No hero in her sky
[CHATTERING]
♪ I can't take my eyes
off of you ♪
off you ♪
Welcome back, miss Jones.
Thank you.
♪ I can't take my eyes
off of you ♪
off you ♪
♪ I can't take my eyes
♪ And so it is
♪ Just like you said
it should be ♪
♪ We'll both forget
the breeze ♪
♪ Most of the time
♪ And so it is
♪ The colder water
♪ The blower's daughter
♪ The pupil in denial
♪ I can't take my eyes
off of you ♪
off you ♪
♪ I can't take my eyes
off of you ♪
off you ♪
♪ I can't take my eyes
♪ Did I say
♪ That I loathe you?
♪ That I want to
♪ Leave it all behind?
♪ I can't take my mind
off of you ♪
off you ♪
♪ I can't take my mind
off of you ♪
off you ♪
♪ I can't take my mind