Previously on Kyle XY...
-What are you doing?
-I'm keeping a list: What makes Kyle an alien.
He's this super brain with amnesia.
He barely knows what you're saying sometimes, but does calculus like
it's two plus two.
I'm telling ya, Kyle is not human.
-You don't...you don't have a belly button.
-No.
-Why not?
-I don't know.
-Anyway, I should apologize.
-I screw up all the time. Maybe it's your turn.
-Do they have any suspects?
-No. Not yet.
-Does this mean anything to you?
-No.
Stephen, I think someone's breaking in.
-This is Tom from our security company.
-Hello, sir.
-You just happened to be driving by?
-Yeah. It's a lucky thing, huh?
Thanks, man.
It's pretty wet out there.
Whew! You're Kyle, right?
-The amnesia guy?
-Yeah.
You broke the window at my party.
My dad had an aneurysm over that one.
-Sorry.
-He has aneurysms over everything.
So, whatever. It's cool.
You mind?
You know, Lori's sleeping.
Well, yeah. It's pretty late.
I need a place to crash.
I know it wasn't too smart to climb in
through a window in the rain.
You're bleeding.
-Crap. Sorry.
-It's okay, but what happened to you?
It's a long story. It's too boring.
Hey, you got an extra blanket or something?
I'll crash on your floor.
-What is this place?
-My bedroom.
Where's the bed?
-You sleep in a tub?
-Yeah.
Trager said you were a head case.
I mean, not like rudely.
Whatever. It's cool.
The rain should let up by morning.
Actually, it won't let up until 2:27 tomorrow afternoon.
Yeah. Whatever.
-Tell me you're joking.
-No. He's right in here.
This is so not good.
What are you doing here?
I got a fight with my dad. Needed a place to crash.
If my parents find you, I am dead.
And that is nothing compared to what
my dad will do to you.
Relax, Trager.
No. They will never believe that you weren't in my room.
The one time I'm not actually doing anything wrong?
Today, of all days?
What did you do to your head?
Slipped on some wet leaves.
Drink much?
I can just sneak out.
They'll never even know I was here.
They better not.
Just don't make a sound.
Oh, man! You're up too early!
I thought I'd have at least another half hour to get breakfast ready.
-Guess I'm turning over a new leaf.
-Happy birthday, honey.
Oh! Thanks, Mom.
-I love you.
-Oh, I know.
I love you, too.
Good morning.
It's nice to meet you, Mr. Trager.
I'm Declan McDunaugh.
I just stopped by to wish Lori a happy birthday.
Declan, huh?
Well, it's nice to finally meet you.
Do I smell pancakes?
So, what happened to your head?
Went up for a dunk on the court and landed the wrong way.
-You play ball?
-Shooting gun.
-Cool. More pancakes?
-Oh, thanks.
You make a great blueberry pancake, Mrs. Trager.
They're Lori's favorite.
I make them every year to celebrate her birthday.
Because we're so happy she was born.
I'm ignoring you.
Good move.
If your birthday means that you're one year older,
Doesn't that mean we're celebrating
one year closer to death?
Well, guess that's one way to look at it.
I think I just lost my appetite.
Don't worry, Lori.
The average lifespan for the American woman is 79.2 years.
If you were Japanese, you would have a few more years, but it's still not so bad.
Whose idea was it to let him read the encyclopedia?
Hey, we should bring out Lori's baby pictures,
Reminisce over the awkward years.
At least I'm out of mine.
Birthdays. Baby pictures. Blueberry pancakes.
They were talking about memories and traditions, but I had none of my own.
You gonna eat that or what?
Kyle, everything okay?
I'm fine.
Seems like it will never end, doesn't it?
3 more hours.
You think?
You know.
It's easy for me to process data from global weather satellites.
I just can't figure out why the rain triggers nightmares.
-Are you having bad dreams?
-Last night.
What was it about?
I'm not sure.
Well, don't dismiss it.
Every piece of information from your head counts.
And dreams are a reflection of what's going on in our subconscious.
-Where memories are stored.
-Exactly.
The brain is a powerful tool--especially yours.
And yet it can't tell me something as simple as my own birthday.
Well, that's something we'll fire out together.
The science of weather came easily to me.
It was numbers, data, and patterns.
What I couldn't figure out, no matter how hard I tried, was me.
Where's Declan?
Geeking out with Josh.
Put a guy in front of a video game,
and there goes half his personality.
Well, try growing up in the Pink Floyd era and replace video games with pot.
It's so tedious.
-You're baking?
-I bake.
You make.
It's a special occasion, okay?
Cut me some slack.
Okay. I'm just saying you don't have to bake a cake for me.
Well, birthdays are all about cake.
I guess I'm just not feeling the birthday thing.
But you love your birthday.
Not this year.
So Kyle's just bummed out because he knows the aliens are on their way back to get him.
It's the rain.
They travel in lightning bolts, like in War of the Worlds.
Cool it, Josh.
You got a better theory?
Oh, ax guy in the corner. Get him!
Oh, great. It's spreading.
Hey, hon.
Did you know Lori has decided to hate her birthday?
Does that mean we still have to suck up to her?
Oh, 'cause you were doing such a good job.
Probably because she's in a fight with Hillary.
She's in a fight with Hillary?
Hey, Kyle, come on in. We'll play teams.
Kyle, what's wrong?
-Is this from your dream?
-I think it's a memory.
You saw him in your dream last night?
And then again earlier, like a flash.
But you don't recognize his face?
No. He just popped into my head.
But I checked the weather archives.
The last major storm we had was the night before I woke up in the woods.
Maybe this is a memory from then.
It's definitely a possibility.
No, I'm tired of possibilities.
I need something to be real.
Well, that's the problem with amnesia.
Your mind only unlocks information when it's ready.
But there are other methods-- hypnosis, drugs.
-You've been studying.
-I need to understand myself.
I get it, Kyle. I do.
And I promise you, if I believe there's
a viable alternative to the wait-and-see method, I'll give it a shot.
But those kinds of aggressive therapies
can work against you.
You just had what may have been your first memory.
I don't want to risk a setback.
Can you trust me on this?
The power line's down.
What are you doing?
Tom.
Sorry to startle you, Mr. Trager.
There's a bunch of houses in the neighborhood that have lost power.
I'm just doing the rounds, making sure
everybody's okay.
Well, I'm really glad you're here.
Our foster son Kyle drew a picture of someone staring in at him from the window.
At first we thought it was his imagination, but now I'm not so sure.
What if it's the same person that broke into the house last week?
-You said something about that he drew a picture?
-Yeah.
I should probably look at that.
-All right. It's inside.
-Yeah. Let's do that.
I hear you're anti-birthday.
Word travels fast.
My last birthday, my dad couldn't be
bothered to be in town,
So I raided the liquor cabinet in protest.
At least you got blueberry pancakes.
Your favorite.
Parents like me. What can I say?
Seriously, what's your deal?
I'm just feeling particularly friendless
right now.
Makes celebrating another year of life sort of bleak.
I'm your friend...kind of, I think.
Yeah. After you duped me into losing my virginity?
-I didn't dupe you.
-Please. Water, bridge.
So, what really happened to your head?
Seems like whoever asks gets a different story.
I told you, I fell.
Before or after your fight with your dad?
Can we drop this, please?
You know, my mom's a therapist.
I mean, you could--
Trager, it's no big deal.
Seriously.
No scandalous family drama, no horrible tales of abuse.
Let it go. I'm fine.
Door!
-Hi.
The power's out at my house, and I didn't want to be home alone, so I thought I'd come over here.
-Where's Charlie?
-At his house.
Why didn't you go over there?
I guess I just wanted to come over here.
Josh said you remembered something.
I still don't know what it means.
Well, it'll come back to you.
I'm beginning to wonder if it will.
I think you should get out of the tub.
You're wallowing.
"To indulge oneself immoderately,
as in wallowing in self-pity."
I'm wallowing.
It's depressing.
-What are you doing?
-I'm gonna wallow with you.
-This is strange.
-Yep.
Here it is.
That's a...
That's a lot of detail.
Yeah. You recognize him?
No.
No. I've never seen him before.
Did Kyle say when he saw him?
No. He was pretty spooked by the whole thing.
He didn't say much.
Okay. Uh...
I'll circula it at the security company,
And I'll pass it over to the police
and maybe they can I.D. him.
Great. Thanks.
I really appreciate it.
No problem. Just doing my job.
-Did you give him the picture?
-Yeah.
Poor Kyle.
He was so sure it was a memory and not a dream.
I wish it was.
I don't like the idea of someone trying
to break into our house.
It's strange that both times somebody tried to get into Kyle's room.
-Do you ever wonder if Kyle--
-What?
No. No, it's ridiculous.
After everything we've witnessed, nothing is ridiculous.
No one's reported him missing,
And he's capable of doing things that no normal child or no normal human being should be capable of.
I'm not saying that I believe in Josh's crazy theories, but...
But?
Maybe he's not missing for a reason.
Maybe there's someone out there that knows exactly where he is.
Maybe they're watching him.
You mean like little green men?
No. No, but, you know,
with all of this, it's so crazy.
It just kind of makes you wonder.
-Yes?
-We've got a problem.
He's starting to remember.
Board games?
Well, anything's better than sitting around dodging real conversation.
-You went in my room?
-Get over it.
Mystic Vision? I don't think so.
Yeah. We don't want to play that.
-What is it?
-It's a Ouija board.
You ask it questions and supposedly the spirits spell out answers.
When in reality, it's usually some idiot
moving the pointer around.
Well, we should do something.
This rain's not letting up anytime soon.
Well, actually, it's letting up in 32 minutes, according to KZRE weather over here.
Not anymore. The wind shifted.
-I bet did.
-Let's play.
It's totally fake, Kyle.
I don't care.
No! Seriously, find another game.
Josh!
Looks like the spirits are total pervs.
One word, dude--internet.
How do we start?
Yeah?
I'm hoping you have a plan.
Are you still there?
You ought to take an hour to stop the family from asking any more questions.
Good.
Because if his memories get any clearer,
the family's gonna become a problem.
I'll take care of it.
Okay. I'll go first.
Who is the biggest queen bee bitch at Beachwood High?
"L"...
"O"...
"R"...Josh!
What can I say? The spirits speak the truth.
Okay. My turn.
How badly am I going to destroy Declan's high score once the electricity comes back on?
No spirit can help you with that, junior. You're toast.
-Can I go next?
-Knock yourself out.
When's my birthday?
Kyle, you know this is just a game.
For 12-year-olds.
Hey, if anyone can get a Ouiji board to work, it's him.
Just concentrate, Kyle.
I don't--I don't think...
Who's moving the pointer?
7...8...
1...2...
Ooh, I'm getting freaked out.
2...
7...
7-8-1-2-2-7.
-What does it mean?
-7-8-1-2-2-7.
-You had to have been pushing it.
-Spelling out your alien birthday?
I wasn't.
-Well, you don't think you were.
-I wasn't.
What is that?
A Kyle file.
I've documented every out-of-the-ordinary event and unusual behavior
ever since we got him.
"Made...contact...with...spirit...world."
Whoa, buddy! This is classified.
This is ridiculous. He's not an alien.
He's not even a good weatherman.
The rain? It stopped.
This doesn't make any sense.
Neither do any of the Chicken Little
conspiracy theories Josh has been spouting.
You guys aren't seriously buying any of this?
Kyle isn't supernatural.
He's just some kid with no memory and annoying accurate knowledge of the encyclopedia.
-You don't know that.
-It's just a game.
There's no such thing as spirits or ghosts.
When you're dead, you're dead.
-Buried, rotting.
-Declan, shut up.
-No. It's okay.
-No, it's not okay.
Oh, God. Your dad.
I'm sorry.
There was a sudden drop in the barometric pressure.
The crackling rise of static electricity in the air,
And the subtle smell of ozone.
Get back inside, now!
-What the hell are you talking about?
-Just come on!
-That was weird.
-What was that?
Nothing. It was nothing.
Hallelujah!
Ready to get your ass kicked?
You wish.
So, how's your day going?
It's a fiesta.
-Kyle channeled a supernatural dimension.
-What?
The Ouija board.
It spelled out some weird number for him.
He was totally pushing it.
Well, of course he was, but he may not realize he was doing it, in which case,
maybe it's another memory trying to claw its way out.
Did he say he knew what the number meant?
Of course not. That would be too easy.
Well, I have to talk to him about it.
He asked it when his birthday was.
Yeah. He's having a really hard time with that today.
Everyone's weird today--even Declan,
who's usually dependably unweird.
So, what's going on with him?
I don't know. He won't talk to me.
And I haven't mastered the art of shrinking like you have.
Well, sometimes the easiest way to get somebody to open up is to just be there for them without judgment when they're ready to spill.
Yeah. See, that's the problem.
I live for judgment.
You and Declan definitely seem to be getting closer.
Ah, I guess.
I guess you probably feel that you're ready for more.
Physically, I mean.
Are you shrinking me right now?
Shrinking, moming, you know.
Whatever works.
Stick to baking. It's less mortifying.
Oh, you know, life can be mortifying sometimes.
And trust me, sometimes sex can be, too.
That's a strain from the usual
"when 2 people love each her, they make beautiful magic" script.
Well, that's true, too.
It's just that it doesn't always happen that way, especially if you
rush into things.
You're right.
-I am?
-I'm not ready.
What'd you find?
9,734 hits for 7-8-1-2-2-7.
Try "7-8-1-2-2-7" and "alien."
That's not funny.
How about "freaky meteorologist"?
Try "7-8-1-2-2-7 birthday."
Nothing.
Doesn't matter. I've got the whole thing figured out.
How?
You sure you can handle it?
My theory is, you're an alien-human hybrid.
The meta-geeks who created you put you here to be their lab rat.
Maybe he's here to check the climate for its inhabitability?
-Yeah. That would explain the weather thing.
-Stop.
Seriously, they're watching you interact
with us humans, taking notes,
So they can wipe us out and replace us with a master race of hybrid freaks.
Then, when they've done enough recon,
they'll beam down and take you away.
-Please stop.
-Josh, I don't think you should--
No, it's okay.
Because here's the beauty of it--
It's totally out of our hands,
and there's nothing we can do to change it.
-So you just gotta go with the flow, you know?
-Josh!
I don't want to hear any more!
How is this supposed to make me feel?
"Searches for alien mothership"?
"Sleeps in the bathtub"?
"Memorizes the encyclopedia."
"Predicts lightning."
This is fun for you?
Everyone around here gets a kick out of it,
but this notebook...
This is the only thing I know about my entire life!
-Kyle--
-Mom, I didn't--
I need you to go upstairs.
Please. All of you.
No! I can't feel like this anymore!
I don't want to be this freak in Josh's notebook.
I need to know who I am.
Kyle, I want you to listen to something, okay?
Come on. Sit down.
Just forget about everything else that you're feeling right now.
And just listen to the sound of my voice.
Now, find the rhythm of the other sounds
in the room.
Listen to the water dripping off the gutter.
Breathe into that sound.
Let it fill you up.
Let your mind and your heartbeat connect to it.
Good.
It's all gonna be okay.
I am the scum of the earth.
You're not scum.
Maybe, like, algae.
Nobody knew how much that stuff bugged him.
Here I am today, whining because I'm not psyched about the way my life has turned out.
And he's wishing he could remember the things he regrets.
I've been upset about things that have happened to me in the past, but at least I have one, you know?
He's just this total blank.
It doesn't sound so bad to me today.
But it feels bad.
Kyle feels bad.
It sucks.
Come on in, Tom.
I've got some information about your intruder.
Hi there.
How're you doing?
I know you.
Well, you probably recognize me from patrolling the neighborhood.
-You said you had some news?
-Yeah.
According to the police, there was a hit-and-run in the neighborhood around 2 a.m.
No one was hurt, and it was probably
caused by the weather.
And not reckless driving, but one of the drivers fled the scene, which is a crime, so...
Why would he be lurking outside our house?
Who was lurking outside our house?
Well, we didn't want to worry you, Kyle,
but we found some blood on the sill outside your window.
We think that man from your drawing must have actually been at your window.
Hit-and-run?
In my room, now.
Okay. I panicked.
I was on my way home, it was really hard to see, and I skidded and hit another car.
I freaked out and drove off.
The light, it was on in Kyle's room,
and he let me in.
I couldn't go home. My dad would have murdered me.
I don't get you. Every time I think
you're a good guy, you do something to completely annihilate yrself!
You think I don't know that?
You can't honestly believe that I don't recognize I'm a total disaster of a person.
I'm sorry.
I'm judging.
I get mad, and that's what I do.
Look, I know we've had a lot of back and forth and...
Played a lot of idiot games with each other, but you've been a really good
friend to me lately.
And if you need someone to be that for you, I'm here.
That's what I want you to know.
What do I do now?
Depends on which guy you want to be.
I have to turn myself in.
I'm so dead.
I'll visit you at county.
-You don't really think--
-No. You'll be fine.
And it's the right thing to do,
so you can go home and pat yourself on the back for not being totally unredeemable.
This friendship thing might work out okay, huh, Trager?
Sure, McDunaugh.
Spring cleaning?
I don't want to be reminded of what I can't remember.
See, I think you've got this all wrong.
You do?
Yeah. You may not have anything to hold onto right now,
But maybe tomorrow, there'll be a new memory.
And the day after that, another one.
And soon, you'll be drowning in them.
Maybe.
But see, the rest of us.
As we grow up, our memories get dimmer.
And we try anything we can to stop them from disappearing completely.
If you ask me, you got the better deal.
Thank you.
For what?
For making me feel better.
You make me feel like there's hope.
Everyone needs hope.
It's what gets us through the rough spots.
Will you tell me about him?
-Who?
-Your dad.
Sure.
But not here.
In here.
Wallow Central.
First off, he was nothing like my mother.
But she was fferent around him.
I mean, it was impossible not to be...
Lighter, happier.
I remember this one time, he took me to get my ears pierced...
So, Kyle doesn't have a serial stalker.
Or little green men watching over him.
Just a teenage boy, afraid to tell his dad what he did.
Yeah.
By the way, Lori's not a virgin anymore.
You segue to that?
Thought I'd rip the bandage off quickly.
-Did she tell you?
-No. Of course not.
But I was talking to her about not being ready for sex yet, and she agreed with me.
Oh! Man, I am not ready for this!
It's Declan.
That car-wrecking, home-invading--
-Stephen!
-I'm gonna kill him.
You slept with Shelly Peterson when you weren't much older than Josh.
You are not allowed to use something I said after 10 tequila shots on our honeymoon against me.
Did it screw you up for life?
That's not fair. It's different for girls.
-Isn't it?
-I think she's fine.
You know, talking to her earlier,
there's something there, like...
I don't know. Whatever she's experienced
has made her more together.
She's growing up.
We don't have to worry about Josh, do we?
Josh still stashes porn in his board games.
He's not up to being anywhere close to being sexually active.
Hey, if Declan was the person at the window,
who's the man in Kyle's drawings?
The police station's gonna be a party
compared to what I got coming to me at home.
Well, here's one from the Parental Manipulation Handbook--
Just apologize, cry a little, throw out a few self-loathing comments.
He'll end up trying to make you feel better.
You know what you said earlier about me duping you into having sex?
You know, it's really not a big deal.
It is.
You should know that no matter what Hillary said to give me the push.
She made me realize I was about to lose you.
That's why I asked you out.
Because I wanted to.
Thank you for that.
It's a shame that it sucked so bad.
Goodbye.
Happy birthday, Lori.
How are you feeling?
Better.
Lori told me about the number you discovered.
7-8-1-2-2-7.
You want to talk about it?
Tomorrow.
-Can I help?
-Sure.
I'll go gather everybody.
I'm not mad at you.
Thank God.
Look, if you're gonna be part of this family, you've got to understand all the traditions.
Okay.
Here we go.
1, 2--
No! Wait, wait!
I was thinking, if it's okay with Kyle.
I want to share my birthday with you.
At least until you remember when your real birthday is.
Thank you.
Come here. You can help me blow out the candles and make a wish.
He could wish to age better than Lori.
Do you know what you're gonna wish for?
Don't say it out loud or it won't come true.
It's another birthday tradition.
That doesn't make any sense.
You're right. Screw it.
What do you wish for?
I think I'll keep with the tradition.
Okay. Let's do it.
Josh!
It never gets old, does it?
With a flash of the camera, the Tragers gave me the first page of my history.
It may not go back as far as Lori's or Josh's.
But I finally have a beginning.
And then my birthday wish came true.
It made me feel like anything, anything was possible.
What does the forecast say?
"Sunny, in the 60s through Tuesday."
Rain.
Damn.
Kyle, what's wrong?
That's him.
Detective, there's a Nicole Trager on the phone for you.
-Put her through.
-Yes, sir.
Mrs. Trager, what can we do for you?