[CAT MEOWING]
MAN:
Eight o'clock.
All's well. Misty weather.
[VIOLIN PLAYING]
- Here ye are, me lad.
- Thank ye.
A press gang. A press gang!
MAN 1: The press gang!
MAN 2: Let's get out of here!
In the king's name!
Well, we got all the fish
we need in one net.
- Line them up, boatswain.
- Aye, aye. Line up, lads!
Lads, bow your necks and weep.
You're in the king's navy.
I'm no seaman, sir. I'm a tailor.
What's that, your needlework?
No chin music.
- What ship?
- The Bounty, for the South Seas.
- The South Seas?
- That's the end of the world.
No, he sailed there with Captain Cook.
He knows the brown gals
gay as kiss-me.
- Who's the captain?
- Bligh.
- Bligh!
- Seize him!
How long will we be gone?
Till there's enough frost
in hell to kill snap beans.
How long is that, sir?
I've got to know.
- Two years, lad.
- Please, don't take my husband.
When we had a baby,
Tommy left the sea.
He don't want to serve in the navy.
- It's true, sir.
- Sorry, the king needs six men.
You can't take him! It's like forever!
I can't take them and not take him.
No, you can't take him!
I won't let you!
- Lass, lass.
- It's two years! No! It's two years!
This is England's new venture
in science, in trade, in discovery.
Who else but Sir Austin Byam's
son should go?
But two years.
- I understand, my dear.
MAN: Ship ahoy!
Bob.
Behold! The elder son of the sea
and heir to all its oceans.
Uniform by Jeeves.
[LAUGHING]
It's so new, it creaks.
I'll come back an admiral,
with a necklace for you.
Pearls as big as coconuts.
I'll name a nice shiny island
after you, Sir Joseph.
- I owe you for my appointment.
- You've been appointed for one purpose:
To make me a dictionary
of the Tahitian language.
I've made that clear to Captain Bligh.
- What's he like, sir?
- Captain Bligh?
He's a seagoing disaster.
His hair is rope yarn.
His teeth are marlinespikes.
BYAM:
Marlinespikes? Good.
Sounds rather terrifying. But perhaps,
as your father used to say:
"A taut hand at sea is better
than a slack one."
You'd have made a rare sailor, ma'am.
Why don't you stow away, Mother?
I've considered it. Very seriously.
Well, here's to the voyage
of the Bounty.
To the voyage of the Bounty!
Still waters and the great golden sea.
Flying fish like streaks of silver
and mermaids that sing in the night.
The Southern Cross, and all the stars
on the other side of the world.
Bless my soul.
To the voyage of the Bounty!
Is that the Bounty?
No, sir. That's the flagship of the fleet.
There's your little pint-pot.
BYAM:
That's the Bounty for Tahiti?
She isn't very big, is she?
It ain't the size that counts, youngster.
It's the salt in the lads that man it.
- Where's your sweetheart?
- She married a sailor.
Oh.
It's Ellison, sir.
He tried to break ship.
- On deck, Morrison.
- Aye, sir.
- Churchill.
Break ship, would you?
I can't face it, sir. Not two years.
I might not come back.
Then she's left with the baby.
Flog me, send me to jail,
but don't take me, sir!
Don't.
Now, listen to me, Ellison.
The sea's hard, but you whistle it off.
Do your spit and polish and you'll
come home with the seals...
...following in admiration.
I was like you when I first came to sea,
Cumberland moss all over me.
Now it's turned to barnacles.
That's better.
On this voyage, if you get in trouble,
come to me. I'll see you get justice.
But if you're wrong,
look out for squalls.
Now, get your chin up.
Go on deck. Say goodbye to your wife.
- You've got her aboard, sir?
- And the baby.
- Come on. Shake a leg.
- Thank you, sir.
- So you're going to the South Seas?
- Aye.
Here. Take this with you.
You can buy your own island.
Ten shillings.
Ten? I ain't seen the king's face
on a shilling for so long...
...I've forgotten which George it is, but
I'll take it and pay you when I get back.
Sailor! You're not coming back,
not in this little half-walnut.
WOMAN:
Here you are. Diamond brooch.
Real gold, mister,
owned by Captain Kidd.
With a map of the treasure
under the works.
Here. Stand clear with the tinware, Joe.
You keep leeward
of the ship's gentlemen.
All right, now. Ta-ta. Ta-ta!
Mr. Byam? I'm Fletcher Christian,
lieutenant and master's mate.
- You'll be my instructor.
- Yes, in navigation and trigonometry.
You'll have a watch, keep order,
go aloft to mend canvas, reef and furl.
Otherwise, your time is your own.
Mr. Christian, in my hands,
the ship is safe.
I understand.
"A little child shall lead them."
Come along, I'll show you below. You
there, take Mr. Byam's box to his berth.
- Ahoy, Mr. Christian!
CHRISTIAN: Ahoy!
Excuse me.
Good morning, sir.
Nothing lost, Mr. Christian.
Think I've got enough
for a two years' voyage?
CHRISTIAN:
You know your draft better than I do.
My lad, nobody can estimate my draft,
least of all myself.
- Easy, easy.
- What makes her roll so?
Here's a navy for you.
Rum in the skimmers today
and blood in the scuppers tomorrow.
This is our ship's surgeon.
We call him Mr. Bacchus.
- He's never told us his real name.
- I've forgotten it.
Pleased to meet you.
Mr. Byam, I should never
have gone ashore.
England's only an island,
and all islands are alike.
I'm going below. Bear a hand.
Easy, now. Easy.
Oh, Tommy, I'm afeard.
This ship's unlucky.
They've changed the name.
Well, I changed your name, didn't I?
Was that unlucky?
Oh, Tommy.
One, two...
Three of us in here?
My dog at home has a bigger
kennel all to himself.
I can see we shall be as friendly
as tomcats in a sack.
Mr. Stewart? Mr. Byam.
Drop in anytime, Byam.
I'll be just 10 inches away from you.
- A pleasure, Mr. Stewart.
- I hope you'll like the ship.
- I'd like any ship, Mr. Stewart.
- Johnny Newcomer.
Oh, yes, Mr. Byam,
the amiable Mr. Hayward.
- How do you do?
- Mr. Hayward has been two years at sea.
And a man who's been two years at sea
should know how to lash his hammock.
Yours looks like
a Frenchman's knapsack.
All right. On deck, all of you.
Mr. Maggs?
This here Captain Bligh, sir.
Now, you being ship's clerk...
...would you call him a gentle officer?
If I was you, I wouldn't be
calling him anything.
Oh, no, no, no, Mr. Maggs, no.
Never call anybody anything.
But I do hope he is gentle because I'm
his messman and I frighten so easy.
It runs in our family, Mr. Maggs.
My mother was frightened by
my father before I was born...
...and I've been frightened ever since.
Do you know there's times when
I can hardly hold a glass in my hand?
- Silence. The captain's coming aboard.
- Oh, oh.
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
MAN:
Company, atten!
Mr. Christian, clear the decks
of this rabble.
Very good, sir. Clear decks.
Everybody ashore. Clear decks.
- Mr. Fryer, we sail at six bells.
- Sail at six bells.
- We got our rights here.
- Off ship, Joe. Off ship.
I'm not going until the ship sails.
Hey, you can't do that!
Flogging through the fleet.
We're included.
- A compliment to the Bounty, Sir Joseph.
- Yes.
Mr. Christian, pipe the ship's company
at five bells to witness punishment.
Would you care to see the flogging?
No. The only discipline
I know is science.
There's science in using a
cat-o'-nine-tails. Watch my boatswain.
I really must be off.
I came aboard merely to introduce Roger.
Goodbye, my boy.
This won't be all cakes and ale, Roger...
...but your family's followed the sea
for seven generations.
Not one ever failed in his duty.
In a tight place,
that's all you'll need to remember.
- I'll try to, sir.
- Sure you will, my boy.
- Goodbye, Mr. Bligh.
- Goodbye, Sir Joseph.
What does it mean, sir,
"flogging through the fleet"?
Sentence of court-martial,
two dozen lashes at each ship.
What was the man's crime, sir?
Struck his captain.
But that's over 300 lashes.
I don't understand why...
Can you understand this?
Discipline's the thing.
A seaman's a seaman, captain's
a captain. And a midshipman...
...is the lowest form of animal life
in the British navy.
Now you know what
a midshipman is.
[BELL RINGING]
[DRUM ROLLING]
MAN 1:
Line up!
MAN 2:
Port oars!
Ship's company, off hats!
Article 22: "If any officer, mariner
or other person in the fleet...
...shall strike or offer to strike
any of his superiors...
...and being convicted,
he shall suffer punishment...
...inflicted on him by
the sentence of a court-martial."
Ship's company, on hats!
- Mr. Morrison, two dozen, I believe.
- Two dozen it is, sir.
- The man is dead, sir.
- Dead?
- Shall I dismiss the men, sir?
- What?
Certainly not.
We'll proceed with punishment.
Boatswain, do your duty.
Come along with you. Do your duty!
[WHIP CRACKING]
Bloody murderer.
Mr. Byam!
MORRISON: Punishment counted out, sir.
- Mr. Morrison, come aboard.
- Mr. Fryer, make ready to sail.
- Starboard watch, secure for sea.
Starboard watch, shorten and cable!
Stand by to go aloft!
In captain's gig, Mr. Christian.
Both watches, hoist!
FRYER: Hoist away!
- Topsails.
Way aloft!
Winds offshore!
You'll take the mizzenmast, Mr. Byam.
What's the matter, afraid to go aloft?
Why, it's child's play.
That man they flogged.
He was dead.
Get aloft. Bear a hand.
Mr. Morrison, start those men.
[MEN SINGING]
Tallyho!
Child's play.
MAN:
Anchors aweigh, sir.
Let fall!
Down from aloft!
Down from there! A dozen for
the coat of the last man down!
Please, sir!
CHRISTIAN:
Skipper Hayward!
Mr. Hayward!
- I'll take care of him.
- Keep hold!
Hoist away!
Set courses, royals and gallants!
FRYER:
Royals and gallants!
Starboard bridges,
aweigh with the anchors.
- Ship ready.
- Give her lee helm.
Lee helm, sir.
- Steady.
- Steady, sir.
There she goes. Her anchor's up.
Oh, Mary, it's such a little ship.
My Tommy will bring her home.
TOGETHER:
Hurrah!
- We're under canvas again, Mr. Christian.
- Yes, sir.
- It's our third voyage together.
- Not of my choosing.
So the port admiral told me.
Well, you're here. I requested you.
I like having a gentleman as my
subordinate, being a self-made man.
I admire you for that, sir.
And for very little else?
Sailing orders?
Tahiti direct by Cape Horn.
Winds permitting.
If we can't make westing,
we shall have to go by Africa.
Then we'll have to get
supplies at Simon's Bay.
We'll need them. This ship has
less food than a prison hull.
And I don't trust that clerk of yours.
Who asked you to meddle
with my clerk?
Can't get much from a hungry man.
I have to work these men we feed.
Rascals and pirates.
Did you see them growl at the flogging?
I'll teach them what flogging's like.
My advice, sir, if you'll take it,
is not to be too harsh with them.
We're sailing 10,000 miles together
for the next two years.
- It's like a powder magazine.
- I don't want your advice.
I've my own way with seamen.
They respect one law, the law of fear.
- My officers should remember that.
- I can only tell you what I think!
They come from jails and taverns, but
they're English and they'll sail anywhere.
I'm not interested in what you think.
I expect you to carry out whatever
orders I give, whenever I give them.
I'll carry out your orders, Mr. Bligh.
Then we understand each other?
Perfectly.
- Any orders for the deck?
- No.
- That all?
- Yes. You may go.
Thank you, sir.
- She's flying, Mr. Christian.
- Tahiti direct, sir.
Tahiti direct, Mr. Christian.
Pass it on: No change of
sail without my orders.
Put two men at the wheel.
- We'll carry on or carry under.
- Very good, sir.
- Southeast by east.
- Southeast by east, sir.
No change in sails...
...except for captain's orders.
- Good.
Mr. Byam, you'll stand by
for midshipman's school.
Aye, aye, sir.
BLIGH:
You! Hold up, there!
Never empty your buckets into the wind!
Find the wind, you idiot!
Find the wind and then choose your rail.
Get below!
We're off around the world, boys.
Light hearts and tight britches.
Off around the world.
Oh, dry up, you cub.
Is it human, or what do you think?
I can't stand yowling water babies.
[SINGING "ROCK-A-BYE BABY"]
Blast you! I told you not
to swing that lantern!
You don't mean it makes you seasick?
An old buccaneer like you? La-di-da.
I'll knock more tar out of you
than it'll take a month to mix.
- Come on, blowhard.
- Oh, stow it, will you?
I can't make head or tail
of this navigation.
Don't worry. If you get tangled,
I'll jump in and pull you out.
You'd better not try and fool
Mr. Christian.
Mr. Christian holds no terrors for me.
I can wade the seven seas
and never wet my shirt.
They have whales that can sink a ship,
but I can sink the whale.
Behold, the face that launched
a thousand ships.
Gentlemen.
Today's navigating problem:
Given the altitude of Polaris, could you
find your latitude, Mr. Stewart?
To lead up to it...
...ordinarily, the shortest distance
between two points is a straight line.
Uh, but this is not true of navigation.
We must consider winds and currents...
Yes. Suppose you considered
the problem.
STEWART: Yes, sir.
- Perhaps Mr. Stewart means that it's...
...like that lantern, sir.
We assume it should hang straight
down, but because the ship is rolling...
...it swings to and fro.
But by watching it closely...
You disagree with Byam, Mr. Hayward?
He knows the lantern makes me seasick.
He's doing it to break up the lesson.
- Stewart doesn't know his problem.
- Still, his original theory interests me.
Please, sir.
Proceed, Mr. Byam. You were saying,
by watching the lantern closely...
What seems to be the trouble,
Mr. Stewart?
Watch the wind, Mr. Stewart.
It's not there. It's there.
Is that the face that launched
a thousand ships?
[HICCUPS]
One navigation problem
and three wrecks.
Smart as paint, you are.
Why, you ungrateful swab.
After I've given my all
for the honor of the class.
Byam!
It wasn't my fault.
He came behind and struck me.
- Is that true, Mr. Byam?
- I'd rather not say, sir.
So you want to fight?
I'll cool you off.
Get to the masthead and stay
there until I call you down.
BYAM: All the way, sir?
- All the way.
- Get below or go aloft!
- Yes, sir!
Rather heavy weather
to send him aloft, isn't it?
They must learn this isn't a beer garden.
If you don't teach them, I will!
Look alive, you crawling caterpillar!
- Where's Byam?
- I couldn't help it, Stewart.
When the man looks at me,
I want to jump overboard.
Where's Byam?
- The old man sent him aloft.
- You let him take the blame, huh?
Here, here!
You've started enough trouble!
Time you learn discipline!
Get into your hammock...
...before I put you over a gun!
- Yes, sir.
Get up!
You see, sir? It isn't my fault.
They're only jealous because
I've been at sea before.
Who did that?
I did, sir.
Come here.
Good.
[BELL RINGS]
How she creaks. Wind's a gale.
I'm too old to envy young Byam aloft.
- Splice the main-brace, Mr. Morgan.
- I'll take it to kill germs.
What? Waste my brandy?
Here, you use the ship's drinking water.
It would shrivel me wooden leg.
Did you ever hear how I lost my leg?
- No, no, but we will.
- Well...
- I'm worried about Byam.
- Oh, he'll weather it all right.
Well, I left my leg with
John Paul Jones back in '78.
We came astern with a Yankee.
Up went our colors and our captain hails,
"What ship is that?"
"American ship Ranger," roars Jones,
and up go his colors.
"Louder, you Yankee pip-squeak,"
our captain yells.
"I can't hear you!"
"Can you hear this?" says Jones,
and he lets go a broadside.
Thundering guns.
You all right?
- Nothing lost, Mr. Christian.
- Look after him, Mr. Morgan.
Keep her head up!
MAN:
Starboard!
Get him below, to the surgeon!
Mr. Christian!
- Who brought that man down?
- I did, sir!
But I sent him aloft!
He's gone under. The top's no place.
I know his place. Time you knew yours.
Maintain discipline, not break it!
Send him aloft again!
Mr. Bligh, he's had enough!
That's right, lad. Drink another.
You'll be as right as a truism.
If you'd lost a leg, now...
I lost mine in action against
the French, off Jamaica.
A French surgeon did the trick for me.
He apologized in French,
and I cursed him in English.
- How is he?
- I'm all right, sir.
He'll go anywhere.
Get to the masthead again, Byam.
- I've taken my punishment, sir.
- Get to the masthead!
I've had a bellyful of that masthead
from Captain Bligh!
- You can't make me go back again!
- Byam.
It was Mr. Christian
brought you down, lad.
Thank you, sir.
I didn't understand. Captain's orders.
- You mind?
- No. Let him have it.
Here, you'll need this.
Here's something else you'll need.
You're a plucky youngster.
If necessary, I'd be happy
to cut off your leg anytime.
Thank you, sir.
- Lf anything happens to that lad, Bligh...
- Christian!
Christian, careful!
CHRISTIAN:
Ship's company, off hats.
O, eternal God, who alone
spreadest out the heavens...
...and rulest the raging sea, who has
compassed the waters with bounds...
...until night and day come to an end...
...receive into thy almighty
and most gracious protection...
...the persons of us, thy servants
and the fleet in which we serve.
Preserve us from the dangers of the sea
that we may be a safeguard...
...unto our gracious lord
King George and his kingdoms...
...and a security for such as pass on
the seas upon their lawful occasions...
...and that we may return in safety
to enjoy the blessings of the land...
...with a remembrance of thy mercies
to praise and glorify thy holy name...
...through Jesus Christ our Lord, amen.
TOGETHER: Amen.
- Ship's company, on hats.
The ship's company
will bear in mind...
...we are at sea
under the articles of war.
Perhaps you are unaware
that the articles of war invest in me...
...the authority to order punishment.
During the recent heavy weather, I've
watched you at work on deck and aloft.
You don't know wood from canvas, and
it seems that you don't want to learn.
Well, I'll have to give you a lesson.
You, you, you, step forward.
You three are
a disgrace to saltwater!
Ten days on half rations.
What's your name?
- Thomas Burkitt, sir.
- He's a thief, sir. Dartmoor Prison.
- A thief.
- Convicted. Offered a choice:
Dartmoor Prison or the king's navy.
You've been to Dartmoor Prison, Burkitt?
- Yes, sir.
- It seems you prefer the navy.
You may regret that choice
before this voyage is over. Your name?
Thomas Ellison, sir. Pressed into service.
I've got a wife, a baby.
I asked your name, not the history
of your misfortunes. Your name?
- Smith.
- Not you, you idiot! You.
- William Muspratt, sir.
- Have you got a wife, Muspratt?
Have you got a wife?
Two, sir.
The ship's company will remember that
I am your captain, judge and your jury.
You do your duty
and we may get along...
...but whatever happens,
you'll do your duty. Go forward.
CHRISTIAN:
Lively, lads.
Thief. Nobody calls me a thief
but the men I steals from.
Half rations.
You there!
Who did that?
I can't tell you, sir.
- Mr. Morrison.
- Aye, sir.
- Report that man for two dozen lashes.
- But...
I done it, sir.
Pick it up.
Put it back.
- Mr. Morrison, lay on with a will.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Bligh, these men aren't
king-and-country volunteers.
They've been brought aboard
by press gangs.
In a week, I'll get some spirit
without flogging.
Teach them who's master
and never let them forget.
- Mr. Morrison!
MORRISON: Aye.
Before we see port, I'll make them
jump at a midshipman's jacket...
...even if it's hung
on a broomstick to dry.
Give this man his two dozen. When I ask
for information, I expect to get it.
- I didn't hear the watch call, sir.
- Why not?
Sorry, I was cleaning brass
for Mr. Byam.
That's true, sir.
Stretch this man over a gun
and give him two dozen lashes.
But I was responsible, sir.
Byam will be in charge
of the punishment.
Two dozen.
That's enough, Mr. Morrison.
MAN: Man overboard!
- Bring a line!
Idiot. I'll have to teach
my top men not to fall off the ship.
Mr. Morrison!
When you get him onboard,
stretch him with a rail to dry him off.
I can't stand it. I got to get water.
Get back to your work.
I wanted water for my knees, sir.
I can't stand it. Please, sir.
- What is it?
- This man left his work. Wants water.
Look, sir, it's the sand
worked in cruel.
- I wanted water to wash it.
- I'll give you water.
Mr. Morrison, keelhaul this man.
MAN:
Haul away!
- Well?
- The man is dead, Mr. Bligh.
Mr. Bligh, I've seen calms and doldrums,
but not one like this in 40 years.
- The men in the boats are worn-out.
- Not the way they're pulling.
- Put new men into the boats.
- Mr. Morrison, pipe the men.
Change the boat crews.
Dive in with your mess, lads.
The boats are alongside.
Mr. Byam, look at this bit
of meat, sir. It's alive.
I'm sorry, lad.
There's nothing I can do about it.
This bit of meat was
mined in a rock quarry.
- Here, I'll change with you, lad.
- Thanks.
It's alive, all right...
...but they're fresh meat anyway.
Mr. Byam, I'm reporting
these two men unfit for duty.
- Very good. You men are relieved.
BLIGH: What's the delay here?
You realize we're waiting
for these men to pull us into a wind?
The men haven't finished mess,
and these two are unfit for duty.
- Unfit?!
- My orders, sir.
If they can walk, they can work.
Put them in the boats and get
these other men out immediately.
Any sign of a breeze, sir?
I'm about at the end of my rope.
Keep up your stroke, man.
I'll whistle a wind up for you.
[WHISTLING]
Can't we...?
- Can't we rest a spell, sir?
- No, and keep your hatch closed.
This is the cask with
only one cheese in, sir.
- What's this? What's this?
- Two cheeses are gone.
- What?
- Two 50-pound cheeses missing.
- Stolen, of course, sir.
- Thieves and jailbirds!
- What?
- A hundred pounds of cheese gone.
They'd steal canvas off a corpse.
- Strange. I checked the stores myself.
- Cheeses can't fly, fool!
They've been stolen, of course.
Stop allowance of cheese
until the theft is made up.
- Yes, sir.
- Pardon, sir. Back in Portsmouth...
...that cask was opened by you...
...and Mr. Maggs had the cheeses
carried ashore.
- Silence!
- Perhaps you'll recollect, sir.
- Maggs had me take them to your house.
- You insolent scoundrel!
MAN: But I remember very well, sir.
I didn't get to see my wife that day.
Boatswain, spread-eagle that liar
to the rigging till sundown.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Wind off the starboard bow, sir.
- Man the lee board braces!
TOGETHER: Aye, aye, sir.
Here. Get that.
Well, Mr. Christian, if your rascals
are any good, bring us into the wind.
Boats!
- Pull, lads! Pull!
- Lay into it, now. Get up.
Send her up, Burkitt. Pull!
CHRISTIAN:
Mr. Byam, pull up their strokes!
Pull! Pull!
- Mr. Hayward, speed up!
- Mr. Byam, use your rope's end!
CHRISTIAN: Come on, lads, pull!
- Come on, pick them up.
CHRISTIAN:
Pull!
We're almost in!
Put your weight in it!
Good lad, Muspratt. Pull, lads!
We're in!
- We're in!
CHRISTIAN: Well done, there!
Shall I call the boats in, sir?
They've done their job.
What do you expect me to do,
knight them? Hoist the boats.
- Aye, sir.
- Good, lads! Good, lads!
Well, we are out of
the doldrums at last, sir.
I told you to spread-eagle that liar.
Why hasn't it been done?
Very good, sir.
Come along, McCoy.
[GROANING]
There's nothing more
powerful than brandy.
I threw a brandy bottle overboard once,
empty one, off the coast of Madagascar.
Three years later, I picked it up
in a river in Portugal.
It had gone back
to its home vineyard for more.
You would've made
an excellent historian.
You have a profound contempt for facts.
BACCHUS: I don't despise facts, sir,
I'm indifferent to them.
[BELL RINGING]
Water. Water.
Cheese, Mr. Christian?
No, thank you, sir.
- Mr. Byam?
- No, thank you, sir.
- Mr. Fryer?
Perhaps the surgeon
wants cheese.
No, thank you, sir.
It's bad for my innards.
To the best of my recollection,
Mr. Christian, you're partial to cheese.
Not tonight, sir.
Burn me. I believe
you're with the men.
If you'll allow me,
I think you've been unjust.
- Unjust?
BACCHUS: A bit of cheese, more or less.
Unjust? In other words,
you say I'm the man who lied.
CHRISTIAN: I didn't say that, sir.
- You implied it.
I've no doubt that Maggs disposed of
the cheeses without your knowledge...
...but I can't understand your treatment
of the man who obeyed orders.
Maggs is my clerk. It's not
for my men to question his orders.
Nor for you to question mine!
I want your apology.
I have nothing more to say, sir.
Then you can dine elsewhere
on what you can get!
- Mr. Bligh.
- Byam.
Gentlemen.
Come, he implied it,
didn't he, Mr. Byam?
Well, I can also dispense
with your company!
Thank you, sir.
So you're all against me,
officers and men.
Won't eat cheese, eh?
Before I'm done with you,
I'll make you eat grass!
I'm so hungry, if my mother
would reach out to pet me...
...I'd have a bit of her hand.
There's fish there, all right,
but they're making jokes about the bait.
You see...
If I could prove what I suspect, l...
No, I wouldn't.
I'm so weak, I'm peaceful.
Muspratt, Burkitt,
look here, supper.
What?
Why...
Why, Mr. Christian, sir.
Take a look at this, sir.
Supper for six men.
Four pounds, they calls it.
If that weighs more than 2,
I'll eat the cat-o'-nine-tails.
- It ain't pig. It's horse meat.
- We pulled our hearts out for this breeze.
- And what do we get? We starve.
- Well, little meat, no distemper.
Keep the wind in the sails
and out of your stomach.
If it's any comfort,
the officers are in the same boat.
Not Captain Bligh.
He's getting fat, the dirty, thieving...
Burkitt!
Any more of that,
and I'll clap you in irons.
Yes, sir.
Buckoes. Buckoes.
Here's your supper.
- Thompson, get your hook and line.
- Right.
See him? He's a big one, eh?
- Here you are, Burkitt.
- Right.
Well, we've got to have bait.
Sharks ain't seamen. They expect to eat.
We've got to have bait.
- You want to risk this for a meal?
- Aye.
- I'm willing.
- Yeah.
If the hook don't kill him, that pork will.
Let it go.
There he goes. There he goes.
- Got him.
- On deck with him.
- Easy, now. Easy, now. Easy, now.
- Hold him.
You first, Burkitt. Choose for your mess.
- Thanks, mates.
- Yeah, fine catch you've got there.
You know I must have a slice, eh?
- Shark eat shark?
- You forget yourself.
You give me a slice, a nice, large one,
and I'll say nothing.
Tell him, you slimy quill-pusher.
Take your slice!
[VIOLIN PLAYS]
[GROANING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
At ease, lads. At ease.
Well, how's our shark-killer, huh?
He's cut to bits, sir.
He'll be all right.
What's a flogging?
A few blows and a few "ohs,"
and then you put on your shirt.
- Here.
- Thank you, sir.
Now, if you'd lost a leg, my lad...
I left mine with a Spanish pirate
off the coast of Trinidad.
A bullfighter did the trick for me.
He was so drunk he nearly
cut off the wrong leg.
Hey! Here.
You'll be all right.
A bit tattooed on the back perhaps,
but just the right style for Tahiti, eh?
- Hey, fiddler, give him a tune.
- Aye, sir.
- Good night, lads.
- Good night, sir.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SINGING]
Listen, Byam. You can flog
those fellows, starve them...
...but they'll bob up again with a fiddle.
- Music at sea...
...I never imagined
how beautiful it was.
BLIGH: Master-at-arms,
stop that infernal jamboree.
- It's worse than two cats on a fence.
MAN: Aye, aye, sir.
The old death's-head.
I've never known a better seaman,
but as a man, he's a snake.
He doesn't punish for discipline.
He likes to see men crawl.
I'd like to push his poison
down his own throat.
You both have one thing in common,
the devil's own temper.
He can let his go...
...but whether I can keep mine bottled
up for the next two years is a question.
I believe you will.
Whatever happens, I'll always
be glad I've known you.
I'll remember that when you're
an admiral. Good night, youngster.
Good night.
- More tea, sir?
- No, you get out.
Yes, sir.
- You sent for me, sir?
- Yes, I've got a job for you this morning.
- Sit down. Had your breakfast?
- Yes, thank you, sir.
I want you to sign the list
of all supplies issued on the voyage.
Certify and sign.
We should raise the island anytime now.
Not a bad voyage so far.
All hands accounted for.
Only six down with scurvy.
Five with scurvy, one with flogging.
Correct, there's your credit.
We're still under canvas.
Mr. Bligh, I can't sign this book.
No such amounts have been issued.
You've signed daybooks with extra kegs
the ship never carried.
- I have, sir.
- And why not? We all do it.
We'd be fools if we didn't
on a lieutenant's pay.
I want to stow away enough
to keep me out of the gutter.
I understand, a captain's prerogative.
Ordinarily, I wouldn't mind.
Why is this case different?
The captains I've served
with didn't starve their men.
They didn't save money by buying up
the stinking meat.
They didn't buy yams
that would sicken a pig.
Silence!
They didn't call their men thieves
and flog them in the bone.
- Impudent scoundrel! Sign that book!
- I refuse...
...and you have no authority.
I haven't?! I'll show you authority.
Lay all hands aft! All hands aft!
Very good, sir.
Company, attend!
Mr. Christian, step forward.
"If any officer or other person
in the fleet...
...shall disobey any lawful command...
...of any of his superior officers,
every such person...
...being convicted of such offense
shall suffer death...
...or other punishment
as shall be inflicted on him...
...by the sentence of a court-martial."
Mr. Christian, you will sign this book.
Mr. Bligh...
...the ship's company will bear witness
that I sign in obedience to your orders.
But remember, sir, I shall demand
a court of inquiry in England.
You mutinous dog.
- Retract that, sir.
- I will repeat it. You're a mutinous dog.
- Mr. Christian.
- Land ho, sir!
Furl away!
MAN:
There she waits, lads!
- What is it, Mr. Fryer?
- Tahiti, you fool.
Oh.
So you'll face me
with a court of inquiry?
We're a long way from England
and what can happen on this ship...
...before we get there
may surprise even you.
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
Milk! It's milk!
Captain, they got cows
here that lays eggs. What a place.
Would you help me up, sir?
I'd like to see the island.
BACCHUS:
What for? All islands are alike.
That's a singularly stupid observation,
sir, and grossly unscientific.
Well, science is one thing
and experience is another.
- See one island, you've seen them all.
- Fiddlesticks.
Well, I'm to be first ashore.
Captain's orders, to begin my dictionary.
I'll get my trade goods.
We can go ashore together.
All right, then.
- I know that man.
- Who is he?
A friend of Captain Cook's
when I was sailing master.
Hitihiti, chief of the island,
priest of the temple. Pipe him aboard.
- Mr. Fryer, dress ship.
- Very good, sir. Dress ship!
[PIPE WHISTLING]
[SPEAKING TAHITIAN]
Bligh.
- Bligh.
- Hitihiti.
[SPEAKING TAHITIAN]
- Bligh, you got fat.
- Oh, well, it is 10 years...
...since we sailed together
with Captain Cook.
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
- I beg your pardon?
- Where Captain Cook?
Uh, Captain Cook is dead.
- Morti?
- Yes, yes, morti.
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
- He was a good man.
- Oh, yes.
- Hail King George.
- King George?
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
Captain Cook say King George come
on next English ship.
His Majesty is extremely
sorry he couldn't come.
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
I beg your pardon?
My hat.
Captain Cook say if King George
don't come, he send hat.
Yes, yes, yes! Of course, the hat.
Mr. Maggs, go to my cabin
and bring me the hat...
- The cocked hat, you fool!
- Yes, sir.
The hat will be here
in one moment.
So we shall require
1000 breadfruit plants.
- Breadfruit? Uru.
- Correct, uru. Uru.
- All we have for you.
- Thank you, thank you.
We shall have to stay here
for several months.
We shall have provision...
[SPEAKING TAHITIAN]
- They're welcome to anything.
- Don't be a fool.
- You'll need those gifts to make friends.
- Him no need gift, my friend.
- Me Hitihiti, you my tayo.
- Tayo?
BLIGH: Chief makes you his friend.
- In my tongue, close friend.
You live home, my home.
Tayo. Friend, the finest
word in any language.
- It shall be the first in my dictionary.
MAGGS: The hat.
Yes, thank you.
With the compliments of His Majesty
King George III of Great Britain.
[SPEAKING TAHITIAN]
- Byam, you come ashore with me.
- Sir?
Permission granted,
mind you report...
...onboard ship every night.
- Very good.
- Byam will live with my family.
- Impossible.
- I can have no favorites aboard my ship.
- Bligh, you are chief on this ship...
...but I am chief on that island.
Byam will come with me, yes?
Perhaps that's best. Permission granted.
By the way, Mr. Morrison,
pipe the ship's company aft.
MORRISON:
Aye, aye, sir. All hands aft.
[PIPE WHISTLING]
Well, we're here. Tahiti at last.
England to Cape Horn,
Africa, New Zealand...
...Van Diemen's Land
and the great South Seas.
I've sailed the Bounty
over 27,000 miles...
...and you think you've come
to an island paradise...
...a tropical grog shop
of feast and song and sleep.
Well, you're wrong!
You're here to labor.
You'll fill this ship with breadfruit trees.
You'll recondition her for sea.
Shore leave permitted
if and when I can spare you.
If you abuse it, you'll answer to me.
Remember, your work is finished when
we drop anchor in Portsmouth Harbor.
Mr. Fryer will have charge
of work ashore.
Very good, sir.
Mr. Christian, you will remain onboard
in charge of reconditioning the ship.
Unfortunately, you will have no shore
leave while we're here at Tahiti.
That's all.
[SINGING]
[CHILDREN SHOUTING]
Hurry, hurry.
What a place.
Hey, when's dinner?
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
[LAUGHING]
Your language is most un-English.
It means exactly what it says.
Here are three pages
on your words meaning "look."
- Plenty kind of look.
- That's the trouble.
There's one for the downcast eyes,
one for the sidelong glance...
...one that invites, one that consents.
A whole language of looks.
Byam, you think too much.
One day, you head go crack.
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
No, no, no, Tehani. I've told you before.
I like my flowers in a bowl.
Now, scat. I'm busy.
What do you call that look, Byam?
The look of a charming girl
who will still be happy...
...when we English invaders go home.
By the way,
what's your word for money?
Money? What is money?
All right, I'll explain. Which would you
choose? The shilling or the nail?
Oh, no, Hitihiti. With one of these
you can buy 20 of these.
- Oh? Where?
- Well, in England.
You see, in England, you must
have money to live with to buy food.
In island of England, no fruit on tree?
- No fish in the sea?
- Oh, yes. Plenty.
No money, no food?
- That's right.
- I stay here.
MAN:
Byam, ahoy!
Sounds like Christian.
- Well, it can't be.
- Maybe so.
Hitihiti, you got him leave!
Byam!
Fletcher!
CHRISTIAN: Ahoy, Robinson Crusoe.
- Fletcher!
I'd given up on seeing you
ashore and Hitihiti never even winked.
When he came aboard wearing that hat,
even the articles of war failed Mr. Bligh.
HITIHITl:
Christian. Christian. Lieutenant.
Thank you
for speaking to the captain.
The sea is good, but the earth
is good also. Be at home.
It's good to be ashore again.
I've been as restless as...
CHRISTIAN: Can you speak Tahitian yet?
BYAM: Like a native.
Why, you little powder monkey!
If you cross my hawse again, I'll
spank your little starboard, understand?
- Yes.
- Yes?
- Well, I didn't know you speak English.
- Yes.
- You must think me a perfect fool.
- Well, does she or doesn't she?
- Yes. She speak English. One word: Yes.
Mr. Byam, your Tahitian dictionary.
Madam.
[BYAM SPEAKING TAHITIAN]
BYAM:
This is Hitihiti's granddaughter.
[BYAM SPEAKING TAHITIAN]
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
- What did she say?
- You must be a king in your country.
What?
If His Majesty could see her...
...as I see her now,
he'd forgive the error.
- Shall I tell her that?
- No, no. Just say thank you.
[BYAM SPEAKING TAHITIAN]
Byam...
...your friend is wise.
He looks, he understand.
You make word,
you understand nothing.
No work today. Go swim, all.
Come along, Fletcher. I'll show you
an island you'll never forget.
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
- You can't imagine what it's...
- Byam.
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
They'd like to come with us,
if you don't object.
- Object?
- I thought not.
[SPEAKING TAHITIAN]
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
Christian?
Aren't they amazing? I never knew
there were such people in the world.
They're simple and kind,
and yet, somehow, they're royal.
Hm? What did you say?
Nothing.
I'm sorry.
I was just thinking...
...what a contrast to the ship.
[HORN BLOWING]
[SPEAKING TAHITIAN]
Tehani wants to race me. Come on!
[LAUGHING]
[SPEAKING TAHITIAN]
- Oh.
- What's wrong?
He comes from the ship.
- Captain Bligh's orders.
- Bligh?
You're to report onboard immediately.
Oh, I am? Byam, I know his game!
He gives me leave and recalls it to devil
me into insubordination. I'll oblige him!
I'll have one day off that ship
if I swing for it! Tell him I refuse!
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
What did she say?
The man will tell Captain Bligh
you can't be found.
Oh, thank you.
I'm sorry I lost my temper.
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
She says you were magnificent,
like a storm at sea.
- Thanks for your kindness.
- You will come again?
That rests with you and the captain.
- You will come again.
- Thank you.
Byam, it's been a day.
Goodbye, Maimiti.
[SPEAKS TAHITIAN]
- Goodbye, all.
- Goodbye, Fletcher.
[DRUMMING]
[SINGING]