(CLOCK TICKING)
(CLOCK CHIMING)
(BELL RINGING)
(CLOCKS TICKING)
(CLOCK CHIMING)
(BELL RINGING)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(BICYCLE BELL RINGS)
Excuse me, Mr. Filby!
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
(CLOCKS TICKING)
(CHAIR SQUEAKS)
(CLOCKS STRIKING AND CHIMING)
(HILLYER SIGHS)
I say...
(CUCKOO CLOCK STRIKES AND CHIMES)
- I say, it's outright rude of him!
- He's merely been detained.
This is such a waste of time!
If he's not coming, I have
more important things to do.
Well, speak up. What is it, woman?
Well, are we or are we
not invited for dinner?
Apparently we are.
- How long has he been gone?
- I'm not certain, sir. Several days.
I've hardly seen him for some time.
He never leaves the lab. He only
comes in and picks at his food.
But he did tell me about dinner,
and left those instructions.
Thank you, Mrs. Watchett.
- What's it say, Filby? What's wrong?
- Nothing, really.
George says that if he's not here
by 8, we're to begin without him.
Oh!
Walter, what time is it?
MRS. WATCHETT:
Dinner is served, gentlemen.
Ah, first sensible thing
I've heard all evening.
This is peculiar. He's usually
prompt, precise and punctual.
Oh! He's making fools of us by not
showing up. It's ungentlemanly.
- To say nothing of a waste of time.
- Huh? Yes. A waste of time.
Ah, one thing I like about
George, best cellar in England.
And Mrs. Watchett is the
finest cook in the world.
Yes, I think I'll drink to that.
(MRS. WATCHETT SCREAMS
THEN TRAY CLATTERS)
- FILBY: Good Lord! What's happened?
- I'm all right.
Some food.
A drink.
- I didn't recognize you.
- Mrs. Watchett.
Can't you speak? What
happened to you?
- Leave him alone.
- It's fine.
- I've got to tell it while I remember.
- Relax. Try to relax.
You've all the time in the world.
You're right, David.
That's exactly what I have.
All the time in the world.
Since we were together
five days ago...
the last day of 1899.
GEORGE: There in that box rests
the result of two years' labor.
I wanted to finish the job
before the new century began.
I barely made it.
- Cheers, gentlemen.
- Marvelous, old boy.
Mm, yes, but what is it?
Well, it has to do with time.
Oh. I've always maintained
that this nation...
needs a reliable timepiece.
Mm, the navy needs one. Heh.
The army needs one
for the artillery.
You couldn't do better, George.
That's why you've been in hiding?
Very clever of you indeed.
I don't think George is
referring to a new timepiece.
No, David.
When I speak of time, I'm referring
to the fourth dimension.
Go on, George.
The fourth dimension
cannot be seen or felt.
If you don't mind, will you refresh
me on the first three dimensions?
Oh, really, Filby. Surely they taught
you something in school. Heh-heh.
Suppose you explain it, doctor.
Huh? Oh, certainly.
Heh.
For example, when I move in a
line, forward or backward...
that's one dimension.
When I move left or
right, two dimensions.
When I move up or down...
three dimensions.
For instance, that box.
That box has three dimensions:
length, breadth and height.
What is the fourth dimension?
Oh, well... That's mere theory.
No one really knows if it exists.
GEORGE: On the contrary.
The fourth dimension is as real
and true as the other three.
In fact, they couldn't
exist without it.
What do you mean?
Let's take that box.
It has the first three dimensions.
- What's inside?
- I'm coming to that.
Let's consider this first.
Why do we ignore the fourth dimension?
Because we can't move within it.
We can move in the other three. Up,
down, forward, sideways, backward.
But when it comes to
time, we are prisoners.
Do you follow me, Bridey?
No.
George, you've given a lucid explanation,
but I'm afraid I don't understand.
There are many things you
don't understand, yes?
Quite a number.
Yet you don't refuse
to believe in them?
- Not if I can see the proof myself.
- Good, Walter.
Gentlemen, all I'm asking you...
is to witness a demonstration
of movement...
within the fourth dimension.
- Doctor, can I have your help?
- Certainly. Ahem.
Ah, it's beautiful!
- Remarkable.
- Very nice, George.
Fascinating.
What is it?
This is only an experimental model.
- To carry a man, I need a larger one.
- To carry a man? Where?
Into the past or into the future.
This is a time machine.
Okay, George, you've had your joke.
Tell us what this contraption is for.
I've already told you.
The larger model can carry
a passenger through time.
Not through space,
but through time.
If you go to the future, won't
you mess things up for us?
The future's already there.
It cannot be changed.
I wonder.
That's the most important
question I hope to answer.
Can man control his destiny? Can he
change the shape of things to come?
If you've gone mad, I forgive you.
- But if you're wasting our time...
- No! You're here as witnesses.
- To see, not to listen.
- To see? What?
The experiment I'm
about to perform.
Let me tell you how it works. The
time traveler sits in the saddle.
In front are the controls.
Let's do this properly. You
can spare a cigar, I trust?
Now, let us imagine
that this cigar...
is the time traveler.
The lever in front of
him controls movement.
Forward pressure sends
it into the future...
backward pressure, into the past.
The harder the pressure,
the faster it travels.
Our little experiment can
be performed only once.
If it succeeds, I lose my model.
That's why I need witnesses.
Go ahead, George.
Ready, gentlemen?
Doctor, lend me your hand.
(RATTLING)
I'll be damned!
It worked.
- Where did it go?
- Go?
Nowhere, in the usual
sense. It's still here.
But it's no longer in the present.
It's traveling through time.
To the future, to be exact.
You expect us to believe that?
Well, you just... Certainly.
- You said it hadn't really moved.
- That's correct.
Then why can't we see it?
Because we're in this room
on December 31, 1899...
but the model is perhaps a
hundred years away by now.
This house may not be
here in a hundred years.
But the time machine occupies
the same space that it did...
a moment before its journey.
If it's occupying the same
space, why can't I feel it?
The space you're putting your
hand through is today's space.
You can't put your hand
into tomorrow's space.
Space doesn't change!
The same space that's here
now should be here forever.
No, Philip, time changes space!
(HILLYER SCOFFS)
This flat ground could've been at
the bottom of the sea long ago.
A million years from now, it could
be the interior of a huge mountain.
If all this is true, what do you
expect to do with such a contraption?
Contraption?
I intend taking a journey
into the future.
(HILLYER SCOFFS)
Or perhaps the doctor
would volunteer to go?
HILLYER: Mm? Hm.
Look here, George...
suppose you do go off and get
lost in the 50th century...
- ...how will you get back?
- That's a risk I'm ready to take.
Oh. Now, look here, George.
I don't know what you
think, but we're not fools!
We're practical businessmen.
What I want to ask you is this:
Even if you had invented a
time machine, what of it?
What's its use? Who'd buy it?
How much would it cost?
Have you thought of the
commercial possibilities?
No, I haven't.
George... There's a war
on in South Africa.
The Boers are putting up a fight. The
country needs inventors like you.
I can put you in touch
with the War Office.
GEORGE: What do you think, David?
Oh, I...
Dr. Hillyer has a
good point, George.
HILLYER:
Ah. That's more sensible. Ha.
I'll see to it right away.
Good Lord! It's time to go.
Yes, I'm sure we all
have plans for tonight.
- Are you all right, George?
- Yes, I'm all right.
HILLYER: Coming, Bridewell?
GEORGE: Thanks for coming.
- Good night.
- Happy New Year.
- Happy new century, George.
- GEORGE: Good night.
MAN: Happy New Year!
(HONKING HORN)
FILBY: George.
I thought I'd better stay.
You shouldn't trouble
yourself. I'm all right.
No, you're not.
You've been behaving oddly
for over a month.
I'll leave, once you tell
me what's on your mind.
I appreciate the gesture, David.
I just want to be left alone.
You've changed, George. Enormously.
I'm sorry.
Will you answer me one
question, honestly?
Yes, I'll try.
Why this preoccupation with time?
Why not?
Don't go simple on me.
The truth is, I don't much care
for the time I was born into.
People aren't dying fast enough.
They call upon science to invent...
new, more efficient weapons
to depopulate the Earth.
And I agree with you.
I agree, but here we are and we
have to make the best of it.
You may have to. I don't.
All right. Take your journey
on your contraption.
What would you become?
A Greek? A Roman?
- A pharaoh?
- I prefer the future.
You're not seriously
saying you can do it?
You saw the experiment, didn't you?
I saw a toy machine vanish.
I'm sure there are any number
of ways of doing that trick.
Any magician could probably do it.
It wasn't a trick!
- Would you like to see the full-scale model?
- No, I would not.
I have no desire to tempt
the laws of Providence.
And I don't think you should.
- It's not for man to trifle with.
- You carry on like Hillyer and Kemp.
There's something to say about
their common-sense attitude.
George, I speak to you as a friend.
More. As a brother.
If that machine can do what
you say it can, destroy it.
Destroy it before it destroys you!
You must have plans for New
Year's Eve. Don't let me keep you.
Mary wasn't well. We thought
we'd stay home with the baby.
Why not come home with me?
You haven't seen Jamey for a while.
I'm sorry, I can't.
What's stopping you?
Well, I just want to see the old
century out by myself, that's all.
Have it your way, George.
George?
Will you promise you'll not
go out of the house tonight?
I promise I won't
walk out the door.
David?
I'm sorry. Please don't think
me unkind or unfriendly.
- Come over to dinner Friday.
- Very well.
- Fine. Bring the others with you.
- As you say, George.
- Happy New Year.
- Happy New Year, David.
- Having supper in tonight, sir?
- I don't think so.
(MAN DRUNKENLY SINGING
"AULD LANG SYNE")
Why don't you go and celebrate?
Thanks, but if you don't need me,
I'll turn in earlier, if I can.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
Oh, Mrs. Watchett, I invited Mr. Filby
and the others to dinner Friday.
- Happy New Year, Mrs. Watchett.
- Happy New Year, sir.
MAN: Happy New Year!
GEORGE: At first, I pushed the
lever forward very slightly...
and the laboratory
grew faint around me.
I stopped.
(DOG BARKING)
No change.
Everything exactly as before.
No! The clock said 6:31 when I
started, and now it was...8:09?
And the candle, shorter by inches.
Yet by my watch, which was with me,
only a few seconds had passed.
It was disconcerting to see the
sun arc in less than a minute.
To see a snail race by.
Flowers flinging wide their
petals to embrace the day.
The hours speeding
across my sundial.
Flowers closing their
eyes for the night.
It was wonderful!
Changes that normally
took hours took seconds.
Dear Mrs. Watchett...
always able to suggest a tie...
but never wearing
anything more stylish...
than what she's worn for years.
Yet I was traveling very slowly.
What if I went faster?
It became intoxicating.
I pushed the lever on
toward even greater speed.
I gained experience in
handling the machine.
I could stop for a day, an hour,
or even a second to observe.
Then go ahead a year or two.
I was able to see the changing
world in a series of glimpses.
Good heavens. That's a dress?
(CHUCKLES)
This was intriguing.
I wondered just how far women
would permit this to go.
I began to grow very
fond of that mannequin.
Maybe because, like
me, she didn't age.
Thirteen years passed.
Fourteen, 15, 16...
Suddenly the light was gone.
What had happened?
In the year 1917, I stopped.
(DOOR CREAKS)
(CLATTERING)
(BELL RINGING)
(CLOCK STRIKING)
(CAR HORN HONKS)
(ENGINE BACKFIRES)
Filby!
Are you going to a
masquerade party?
(GEORGE LAUGHS)
You look rather silly
without your mustache.
- Were you addressing me, sir?
- It's George!
I expected a more
enthusiastic greeting...
You're confusing me with my father.
Yes. There was quite a
resemblance. I'm James Filby.
"Was"?
- Were you a friend of Father's?
- Yes.
Yes, I've been away.
He was killed in the war.
A year ago.
Oh.
I'm so sorry.
- And the gentleman across the street?
- Oh, the inventor chap?
He disappeared around the
turn of the century.
If you're interested in that
house, you can't buy it.
- You can't even get inside.
- Why?
My father was executor of the
estate and refused to liquidate it.
I often chided him on that...
but he believed the owner
would return some day.
People hereabouts think it's
haunted, but, heh-heh...
Who are you, sir?
Just a stranger who
once knew your father.
Have you been at the front?
Front? What front?
Why, the war, of course.
What war?
Good heavens!
You don't know we've been at
war with Germany since 1914?
I thought you'd just
returned from France.
Or perhaps...
Perhaps some tea might
make you feel better.
Won't you come in?
No, thank you.
Are you sure you're all right?
Yes, I'm quite all right.
Then goodbye, sir.
Goodbye, Jamey.
(CAR HORN HONKS)
(CRASHING SOUND)
GEORGE: In 1940, I began to
be buffeted from side to side.
I first thought the machine
had a mechanical defect.
(WHIRRING)
(EXPLOSIONS)
The last time I had stopped
was in 1917, 23 years ago.
The war was still waging, now in
the air with flying machines.
Then I realized the truth.
This was a new war.
Uh, I decided to push on into
time and see the outcome of this.
My house was hit!
The flames shot up.
Instantly, my home was gone.
I was in the open air.
The years rolled by,
everything unfamiliar.
Except the, uh, heh, smile
of my never-aging friend.
(HIGH-PITCHED SOUND)
What was this? Weird sounds
all around. What could it be?
My curiosity compelled me to stop.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(CHATTERING)
At first I wondered if I was
the cause of the panic.
I was soon to find out I wasn't.
Keep it moving! Shove it on!
Come on, into the shelter.
(BELL RINGING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Come on, young man! Come on!
- Filby?
- The name is Mr. Filby.
- Didn't you hear the siren?
- The horrible screeching?
It wasn't constructed for
its aesthetic value...
but to warn young fools
to get into the shelter.
- Now, come along.
- I'm perfectly comfortable here.
I've got to talk to somebody.
This is fantastic!
Your store is magnificent!
The achievements!
- The gigantic strides man has taken!
- Come along, young man!
The mushrooms will be sprouting!
Mushrooms?
You look familiar. Haven't
we met somewhere before?
Indeed we have, Mr. Filby.
Right there. Many years ago.
I was sure of that...
but the exact time escapes me.
It was two wars ago, 1917.
Now I recall. The chap who
inquired about my father...
and the house that used
to stand across the way.
Oh, but no...
No, that's impossible!
You haven't changed.
You're not a day older.
And your clothes!
Don't worry, Filby. It'll
take time to explain, but...
(SIRENS WAILING)
That's the last alert!
Hurry! Hurry!
- Listen, this is important.
- Look!
An atomic satellite, zeroing in.
That's important.
Come on! Come on!
- But I've got to talk to you!
- Come on!
Filby?
Filby!
Hurry! Hide till the all-clear!
But, Filby, I've got
to talk to you!
(EXPLOSION)
GEORGE: The labor of
centuries, gone in an instant.
(EXPLOSION)
Mother Earth, aroused
by man's violence...
responded with volcanic
violence of her own.
(COUGHING)
Only my speed through time saved
me from being encased in stone.
The molten rock cooled.
I prayed...
wondering how many
eons must pass...
before the wind and rain could
wear away the mountain.
Darkness.
Darkness for centuries.
I wondered if there was still
a war being waged above me...
if man would still exist
when I saw the sun again.
The centuries rolled by.
I put my trust in time...
and waited for the
rock to wear down.
I was free again!
Thousands of centuries had passed,
but the Earth stayed green.
There was no winter, no wars.
Had man learned to control
both the elements and himself?
I had to stop and find out.
But I'd stopped too fast.
Magnificent!
Beautiful flowers everywhere!
Natural splendor beyond compare.
The whole landscape a garden
without any weeds or briars.
Trees and vines laden with fruit
of strange shapes and colors.
Nature tamed completely...
and more bountiful than ever!
At last I'd found a paradise.
But it would be no paradise
if it was mine alone.
Unrepaired for centuries.
Maybe unlived-in for as long.
(ECHOING)
Anybody here?
(CHATTERING AND LAUGHING)
So this is man's future: to bask in
the sun, bathe in the streams...
and eat the fruits of the Earth,
work and hardship forgotten.
Well, and why not?
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Don't just sit there! Help her!
Are you all right?
(CHATTERING AND LAUGHING)
GEORGE: Thank you.
- WOMAN: Why did you?
- Why did I what?
Come after me.
Sit down.
I did it to save your life.
That doesn't seem to mean
much to you, or anybody else.
It doesn't.
Twenty of your friends
were watching you drown.
Not one lifted a
finger to save you.
That's a very curious attitude.
A very curious world.
Uh, aren't you interested in who
I am? Where I come from?
Should I be?
Take me to somebody a little
older. Somebody I can talk to.
There is no one older.
Do you mean nobody ages
in this land of yours?
- Well, what's your name?
- Weena.
Weena.
How do you spell it?
- Spell?
- Spell, write. Can't you write?
Look.
Weena.
- What are your people called?
- Eloi.
Aha.
Eloi.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Come. We must go now.
- What's wrong?
- It's getting dark.
(CHATTERING AND LAUGHING)
Hello.
I don't mind telling
you, I'm quite hungry.
I've come a long, long way.
(GEORGE CLEARS THROAT)
In my time, a berry that size...
would've been big news
all over the world.
Excuse me, sir.
Uh, sir?
Perhaps curiosity has died.
Perhaps courtesy too...
but I've come far and I'd
like to know things.
Why?
Because I shall return to my time,
and my people will ask questions.
Such as:
What kind of government
rules your world?
We have no government.
Well, you must have a body of
men who pass and enforce laws.
Laws? There are no laws.
Where do you get food and clothing?
Doesn't anybody work?
No.
Well, where does that come from?
- It grows. It always grows.
- I know, but it must be...
cultivated and planted
and nurtured, um...
Well, unless you...
You have an economy so well-developed
that you can spend all your time...
studying and experimenting?
Is that right?
You ask many questions.
Well, that is the only way man
has learned and developed.
I wish to learn.
I want to learn about
your civilization.
Perhaps, you...
Do you have books?
Books?
- Yes, we have books.
- Wonderful!
I can learn about you from books.
They'll tell me what I want to know.
Could I see the books?
Yes, they do tell me all about you.
What have you done?
Thousands of years of building,
rebuilding, creating and re-creating...
so you can let it crumble to dust!
A million years of sensitive
men dying for their dreams.
For what?
So you can swim and dance...
and play!
You! All of you!
I'm going back! I won't bother to
tell of the useless struggle...
the hopeless future. But at
least I'll die among men!
You're... Aah!
(CHATTERING)
(TWIG SNAPS)
- Weena, what are you doing?
- I came to warn you.
- How do you open that panel?
- No one can. Only the Morlocks.
Who are the Morlocks?
They give us our food and
clothes. We must obey.
Why'd they take my machine?
You've got to tell me!
We mustn't be out in the dark.
Only children are
frightened by the dark.
You are a child, aren't you?
- I'll light a fire.
- Please, let us go.
My machine is inside. I must
find a way to get it out.
- No, you mustn't.
- Help me gather some wood.
Come on.
That's a girl.
Where are you from?
As a matter of fact,
I'm from right here.
That's where my house used to be...
many thousands of years ago.
You see there?
Up to those panels
was my laboratory.
Beyond them was where
my garden used to be.
And right there...
that was my library.
Where I once sat talking
with friends about...
the time machine.
Mm.
You know, Weena...
I'd hoped to learn
such a great deal.
I hoped to take back the knowledge
and advancement man had made.
Instead, I find vegetables.
The human race reduced
to living vegetables.
(WEENA SCREAMS)
They're gone. Are you all right?
- Was that a Morlock?
- Yes.
Don't you worry. The fire
seems to keep them away.
What are you doing? Why did
you put your hand there?
- I never saw it before.
- You...?
No knowledge of fire.
No books.
I'm terribly sorry.
I had no right to be
angry with your people.
No more than if I'd visited the
island of Bali in my own time.
But, you know, Weena...
you were safe inside your
house, yet came out to warn me.
The characteristic which
distinguished man from animals...
was the spirit of self-sacrifice.
And you have that quality.
So do all your people. It just
needs someone to reawaken it.
I'd like to try, if you'll let me.
Will you?
I do not understand...
- ...but I believe you.
- Heh.
That's as good a start as any.
Try to tell me. The Morlocks...
Who or what are they?
Are they animals or people?
Well, what about yourself?
Don't your people ever
speak of the past?
There is no past.
Well, do they ever
wonder about the future?
There is no future.
The past...
man's past...
is mainly a grim
struggle for survival.
But there have been moments when
a few voices have spoken up...
and these rare moments
have made man's past...
a glorious thing.
I refuse to believe
it's dead and gone.
We've had dark ages before.
This is just another one.
All it needs is someone
to show you the way out.
I'm only a mechanic...
but I'm sure there must be
that spark in one of you.
If only I can kindle that spark...
my coming here will have meaning.
GEORGE: My efforts to open
the panel were fruitless.
I had to find another way
to retrieve my machine.
(MACHINES CHUGGING)
Listen.
Do you hear that?
Yes.
Machines?
- No, Morlocks.
- Wait.
Those animals run machines?
They are Morlocks.
- Have you ever seen the machines?
- No, only heard of them.
- Who told you?
- The rings.
- What sort of rings?
- Rings that talk.
Could you show me these rings?
Come, this way.
- These are the talking rings?
- Yes.
They speak?
Of what?
Things no one here understands.
Make it talk.
MAN 1: Now in its 326th year, the
war between the East and West...
has at last come to an end.
There's nothing to fight
with and few left to fight.
The atmosphere has become
so polluted with germs...
that it can no longer be breathed.
There is no place
left that is immune.
The last factory for the manufacture
of oxygen has been destroyed.
Stockpiles are rapidly
diminishing...
and when they are
gone, we must die.
MAN 2:
My name is of no consequence.
You should know that I am the last
who remembers how each of us...
man and woman, made
his own decision.
Some chose to take refuge
in the great caverns...
and find a new way of life
below the Earth's surface.
The rest of us decided to take
our chances in the sunlight...
small as those chances might be.
GEORGE: From the rings I learned
how the human race divided...
and how the world of the
Eloi and the Morlocks began.
By some awful quirk of fate...
the Morlocks became the masters
and the Eloi their servants.
The Morlocks maintained
them and bred them like...
Like cattle...
only to take them below
when they reached maturity.
Which explained why there
were no older people.
I knew I must go below. It was the
only way to reach my machine...
and discover what happened
to the little people.
Don't go!
(MACHINES CHUGGING)
- You won't come back!
- I'll be back.
(SIRENS WAILING)
Weena?
Weena!
Answer me!
Where are you?
What's happening?
What's the matter with you all?
Weena!
Weena?
Weena, stop!
(SIRENS CONTINUE WAILING)
Weena?
(SIRENS STOP)
Stop!
What happens to them?
Don't stand there like fatted cattle!
Will you answer me?
- What is wrong?
- Nothing is wrong. It is all clear.
- What do you mean, all clear?
- All clear.
In the mid-1900s, the bombs, the
people calling out, "All clear!"
No!
That's gone! That's passed!
There are no more flying machines!
No bombs! No more wars!
The rings have told us that story.
But you didn't listen!
You didn't learn!
It was ages ago that men were taught
to hide when the sirens blew...
to run from death, but it's over!
Those men and those who
slaughtered them are dead!
But there is nothing to
fear. It is all clear.
What about the ones who went below?
How will they come back?
They never come back.
- Nobody can bring them back.
- You can try. You can try!
Won't even one of you try?
Well, I'll try!
(MACHINES CHUGGING)
GEORGE: So this was
the destiny of the Eloi.
They were being bred
by the Morlocks...
who had degenerated into the
lowest form of human life:
Cannibalism!
(WHIP CRACKING)
Wake up! Come to your
senses! All of you!
(GEORGE GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
Burn.
Give me something to burn.
It's my last match.
Good, good.
Get up the stairs!
That's the way out!
(GROWLS)
(ALL SCREAM)
The torch!
Get the torch!
(WEENA SCREAMING)
Get up the steps! Hurry up!
Come on, hurry!
Go on, Weena.
(SCREAMING)
(CRASHES)
(COUGHING)
Gather all the deadwood!
All the wood!
That's fine. Come on,
throw it down!
All the deadwood!
Throw it down! Do the
same to the other wells!
All the wood down the wells!
All right, to the river!
Back to the river!
(CHATTERING)
All right, let's go!
GEORGE: Another night was coming,
but this night no Eloi needed to fear.
The underworld of the
Morlocks was gone...
and so was the life of
leisure for the Eloi.
But then what of me?
I was imprisoned in a world...
in which I just did not belong.
Are you sorry?
- Hm? Sorry? Sorry for what?
- That you have to stay?
Yes.
I could tell so much to
the people of my time.
I'd let them know...
about the sorrow and happiness
that the future holds.
Maybe they could learn from it.
Or could they?
- You don't want to stay, do you?
- It isn't that.
It's just that I don't fit here, any
more than you would in my time.
I would love to see your time.
Mm-mm. You wouldn't
be very happy there.
Do you have someone there?
Someone like me?
No one like you.
I have friends who will
miss me, of course.
I'm probably late already.
Women?
No.
There is one woman.
She looks after my house for me.
She's 62 years old and all wrinkled.
How do they wear their hair?
- Who?
- The women of your time.
- Up.
- Up?
Up how?
I don't know. Kind of...
up, like that.
Show me!
Would I be pretty?
Yes, you would. Very pretty.
Oh, Weena.
I wish we could go back to my time.
Or even before that, when
the world was young.
- We could be so very happy.
- MAN: Look!
Look!
GEORGE: My machine!
Come on, Weena!
Weena!
(DOORS SLAM SHUT)
(SOBBING)
(GROWLING)
GEORGE: I was going the wrong
way! Back! I had to go back!
(DOG BARKING)
(BELLS RINGING)
(CLOCKS TICKING)
It's the most ridiculous story
I've ever heard. Preposterous!
George, you always could
tell a good yarn.
You're a truly great
inventor, George.
I think you ought to retire, sir.
Truthfully, George, where
have you been the past week?
Don't ask such questions.
It is not hard for a man to
lose a week now and again.
(GEORGE SIGHS)
I can understand your doubt.
Take it as a lie if you wish.
I scarcely believe it myself,
now that I'm back...
David, there's the
flower Weena gave me.
A present for you. You're
interested in botany.
Try to match that with
any known species!
I don't think I can.
(HILLYER SCOFFS)
- Well, time to go, Bridewell.
- BRIDEWELL: Mm? Oh.
- KEMP: Yes, it is getting late.
- Good night, George.
Good night, George.
Good night.
You look exhausted, George. You
really should get some rest.
Good night. It's grand
having you back.
Goodbye, David.
Thanks for being such a
good friend. Always.
What do you think, Filby?
One thing is certain.
That flower couldn't
bloom in the wintertime.
You don't really
believe that story?
Good night.
Go on, driver.
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
George?
(TIME MACHINE HUMMING AND WHIRRING)
- Mr. Filby, what...?
- He's gone!
Why, look!
I think I understand.
You see the imprint?
This is where it originally stood.
The Morlocks moved it.
They dragged it across the lawn...
right into the sphinx. Right there.
Weena was standing here
when he last saw her.
Right here! The same space
in a different time.
So he dragged his heavy
machine back in here...
scratching the floor...
so he could appear outside
the sphinx again...
and help the Eloi
build a new world.
Build a new world for himself.
- Right where he left her.
- Yes.
It's not like George to
return empty-handed.
To try to rebuild a
civilization without a plan.
He must have taken
something with him.
Nothing.
- Except three books.
- Which three books?
I don't know. Is it important?
Oh, I suppose not.
Only...
which three would you have taken?
Do you think he'll ever return?
One cannot choose but wonder.
You see, he has all the
time in the world.
(English - US - SDH)