(MONKEY SCREECHING)
(ELEPHANT TRUMPETING)
(BIRDS SINGING)
(ANIMAL ROARING)
(CLAMORING)
(SINGING) Bread of heaven
Bread of heaven
(SINGING TUNELESSLY)
In this barren wilderness
(UNINTELLIGIBLE)
Song of praises
I will ever give to thee
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(BLOWING)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(PLAYING THUMB PIANO)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(SINGING) Be the Lord
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
My righteousness
Song of praises
I will ever give to thee...
(ALL CHANTING)
(SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE)
Death of death and hell's...
Song of praises
I will ever give to thee
(CLAMORING)
When I tread the verge of Jordan
(YELLING)
Song of praises
I will ever give to thee
Amen.
Amen
- Hello, Reverend.
- Mr. Allnut.
- Here's your mail.
- Thank you.
Sorry I'm late, but one thing and another
kept me in Limbasi.
You know how it is. Maybe you don't.
- Good morning, Mr. Allnut.
- Good morning, miss.
Ah, splendid, they've come at last.
Huh?
- My rose trees.
- Ah!
- You'll stay for tea?
- Don't mind if I do.
I sure need something in my condition.
I'm in for a going over
when I get back to the mine.
Them Belgians are calling me
all the names they can think of,
but I don't mind being cussed out
in a foreign language.
They won't fire me.
Ain't nobody in Africa except yours truly
can get up a good head of steam
on the old African Queen.
(LAUGHS)
(STOMACH GROWLING)
You take sugar,
I seem to remember, Mr. Allnut?
That's right, miss. Couple of spoonfuls.
And milk?
(STOMACH GROWLS)
That's right, miss.
(STOMACH GROWLING)
- Bread and butter?
- That's right, miss.
- Brother.
- Thank you.
(STOMACH GROWLS)
(CHUCKLES)
Just listen to this stomach of mine.
The way it sounds,
you'd think I had a hyena inside me.
Do have some more
bread and butter, Mr. Allnut.
Thanks, miss. I... I don't mind if I do.
(STOMACH GROWLS)
Excuse me.
Queer thing, ain't it? What I mean is,
what do you suppose makes
a man's stomach carry on like this?
Try a rock cake, Mr. Allnut.
No, thanks, miss.
Herbie Morton's a bishop.
Huh?
- Who's that, dear?
- Dear, surely you remember Herbie.
Blond, a bit younger
than I am, ruddy-faced.
He sang a solo
at the commemoration concert.
Holy, Holy, I think it was.
ROSE: I think I remember.
It was so long ago.
- BROTHER: He's a bishop now.
- Splendid.
Yes, I'd say Herbie was
a bit younger than me,
four or five years. Surprising, really.
He wasn't up to much as a student,
didn't have more than his share
of the social graces.
Then, of course, he married well.
ROSE: Oh.
Yes. That manufacturer's widow.
What was his name, Griggs?
Briggs. That was it. Alfred Briggs.
Soap flakes, I think. Mrs. Alfred Briggs.
Not to take anything away from Herbie.
I'm delighted for him, naturally.
ROSE: Of course.
(STOMACH GROWLS)
Ain't a thing I can do about it.
It was Holy, Holy.
More tea, Mr. Allnut?
Thank you, no, miss.
I reckon I'd better be shoving off
if I'm to get back to the mine
before tomorrow night.
- Don't hurry, Mr. Allnut.
- Do stay for dinner.
ALLNUT: Thanks just the same.
Oh...
I probably won't be coming around
this way for a couple of months.
Really? Well, what about our mail?
Don't look like there's going
to be any mail for a while.
Why not?
- The Germans will hold it up.
- Why, in heaven's name?
- On account of the war.
- War? Where, Mr. Allnut?
- Europe.
- Indeed. Between whom?
Oh, uh...
Germany, England...
- England?
- That's right.
- You really mean war?
(CHUCKLING) Yeah,
that's what they tell me.
Germans claim the British started it,
British claim it was the Germans.
Well, what do you know about it?
What's happened?
Well, let's see. I...
That's all I can remember.
Oh, yes, the French are in it,
and all them little countries.
Austria, Hungary, Belgium, Spain.
I forget who's with who.
- Is that all you can tell us?
- That's all I know.
I'll see what I can find out
when I get to Limbasi.
Well, I'm wondering
what our position will be. Enemy aliens.
What harm could anybody do
the Germans
in this godforsaken place?
God has not forsaken
this place, Mr. Allnut,
as my brother's presence here
bears witness.
- Oh, no offense, miss.
- War.
Yeah. Yeah, looks like it.
Well, I'll be shoving off.
Thanks for the tea.
Take care of yourselves.
- Goodbye. Thank you.
- Goodbye, Mr. Allnut.
Wretched little man. What indifference.
He's a Canadian.
Doesn't he realize he's in this, too?
Shouldn't we perhaps try
to get to Limbasi while we can?
A good shepherd
doesn't desert his flock
when the wolves are prowling.
We must ask the Almighty
to bless the arms of England
and carry her through her hour of trial.
(DRUMS BEATING)
(MAN SHOUTING
IN NATIVE LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE)
(ALL SHOUTING)
Rose, go into the house and stay there.
What's the meaning of this outrage?
How dare you!
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SHOUTING)
ROSE: Samuel!
Samuel!
Dear, here you are.
And without your hat on.
Didn't you hear me calling you?
Yes, but I must get the seeds in now.
It's a bit late. August.
But, dear, you know it doesn't matter
when one plants in Central Africa.
Africa?
Brother, dear, you're not at all well.
- I'll help you off with your things.
- Rose.
(BROTHER GROANING)
(THUD)
Brother. Brother. Dear.
Smite the Amalekites, O Lord.
Smite them, hip and thigh.
Amen.
Cold. Foggy.
Where's Rose?
(INAUDIBLE)
Rose, are you down there in the shop?
I'm here.
Bring me a nice, hot cup of tea.
I'm here, Brother, beside you.
I try so hard, you know, to study.
Hebrew, Greek. I've got no facility.
If I don't pass the examinations,
I shall volunteer as a missionary.
Rose, too.
Not comely among the maidens,
but she, too, can be a servant
in the house of the Lord.
Even for such as she,
God has a goodly purpose.
I'm going to put my books away.
I'm not going to work anymore.
If I don't pass, it'll just mean
that God has other work for me.
Thy will be done.
O Lord, if it be thy will,
let me distinguish myself.
Give me a call here in England at home.
Mother would be so proud.
O Lord, I've tried so hard.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
So they been here, too, eh?
After I left here the other day,
the drums started in the forest.
Pretty soon, my boys was moaning
and rolling their eyes.
I asked them what the trouble was,
and they told me the drums said
the soldiers was rounding up
their people
and marching them off
and burning their villages
so they wouldn't have
no homes to come back to.
Sure enough, when I got to the mine,
everything was a shambles.
My boys took one look
and bolted into the forest.
The way I look at it,
they plan to make soldiers of the natives
and take over all Africa.
Where's the Reverend?
He's in there. He's dead.
Oh.
Well, now, ain't that awful?
If they'd up and shoot a reverend
couldn't do them a bit of harm,
- well, there ain't nobody safe.
- They didn't shoot him, Mr. Allnut,
but they may as well have done.
That's certainly too bad, miss.
That's all I can say.
- When'd he die, miss?
- He died early this morning.
Excuse me, miss. What I mean to say
is, what with the climate and all,
the quicker we get him
under the ground, the better.
If you don't mind my saying so.
You got a spade?
Behind the bungalow.
I expect he'd like to be buried
in the shade.
I'll tell you what.
While I'm digging the grave,
you get your things together,
all the things you want to carry,
and then we can clear out of here
in a hurry.
The Germans might come back anytime.
- Why should they?
- Oh, they'll be back, all right,
looking for the African Queen.
They'd give a lot to get their hands
on her, you bet.
And what's in her, too.
Blasting gelatin, tinned grub,
cylinders of oxygen and hydrogen,
heaps of things them Germans
could use. You can trust them for that.
The Germans.
See, I figure we could go somewheres
behind an island where it's quiet
- and we can talk about what to do.
- I'll get ready.
Fine. I'll be as quick as I can.
Let's go, miss.
Let's go while the going's good.
Pardon me.
Mind taking the tiller, miss? Come on.
- But I can't steer.
- Come on.
A little to starboard, miss.
No, no, the other way.
(SIGHING)
So far, so good.
Here we are, safe and sound,
as you might say.
- The question is, what next?
- Quite.
We got heaps of grub here, miss,
so we're all right as far as that goes.
Two thousand cigarettes.
Two cases of gin.
(LAUGHS) We could stay here
for months if we wanted to.
It's not a bad place to sit out a war,
then, is it, miss?
All the comforts of home,
including running water.
We simply can't remain here
in this backwater
until the war is over, Mr. Allnut.
Can't we, miss? You got the map.
Show me a way out and I'll take it.
The British will certainly
launch an attack.
The only question is,
which way will they come?
Maybe from the sea,
up the railway to Limbasi.
But that would put the Germans
between us and them.
Mightn't our soldiers
come in from British East, Mr. Allnut?
Yeah, they might,
but the war in Europe would be over
before they ever hacked their way
through that forest.
We're in a bit of a fix, miss,
no matter which way you look at it.
There's one thing certain.
They won't come up from the Congo,
not even if they wanted to.
They gotta cross that lake,
and nothing's going to cross that lake
while the Louisa's there.
- The Louisa? What's that?
- A hundred-ton steamer, miss.
The Germans brought her
overland in sections.
She's the boss of the lake
'cause she's got a six-pounder.
A six-pounder? What's that?
A gun, miss.
The biggest gun in Central Africa.
- I see.
- If it wasn't for the Louisa,
there wouldn't be nothing to it.
The Germans wouldn't last a month
if our men could get across the lake,
but all that don't get us
any closer to home, does it, miss?
This river, the Ulanga,
runs into the lake,
doesn't it, Mr. Allnut?
Well, yes, miss, it does,
but if you got any ideas
about going down to the lake
in this launch,
- you better get rid of them.
- Why?
Well, first off, there's Shona.
The Germans have a fort there
overlooking the river.
If we tried to pass under their guns,
they'd blow us right out of the water.
And then after that, miss,
there's the rapids.
A hundred miles of water
like it was coming out of a fire hose.
After that, why,
the river's even got a different name.
It's called the Bora.
That just goes to show you
they didn't even know
it was the same river
- until this fellow Spengler got...
- He got down it, I remember.
Yes, miss, in a dugout canoe.
He had a half a dozen Swahili paddlers.
Map-making, he was.
That was his map you was looking at.
- Mr. Allnut.
- Yes, miss?
What did you say is in these boxes
with the red lines on them?
Well, them, that's blasting gelatin, miss.
Is it dangerous?
Bless you, no, miss.
That's safety stuff, that is.
You can get it wet
and it don't do it any harm.
You set fire to it, and it just burns.
You can hit it with a hammer
and it won't go off.
At least, I don't think it will.
Takes a detonator to set it off.
I'll put it over the side, though,
if it worries you.
No, we may want it.
- Mr. Allnut.
- Yes, miss?
What are these long, round,
torpedo-like things?
Them? Them's oxygen
and hydrogen cylinders, miss.
- Mr. Allnut.
- I'm still right here, miss.
There ain't much of any other place
I could be on a 30-foot boat.
You're a machinist, aren't you? I mean,
wasn't that your position at the mine?
Yes, a kind of a fixer, jack of all trades
and master of none, like they say.
- Could you make a torpedo?
- How's that, miss?
- A torpedo?
(CHUCKLING)
Ask me to make a dreadnought,
and do it up right.
A torpedo, miss...
You don't really know
what you're asking.
You see, there ain't nothing so
complicated as the insides of a torpedo.
It's got gyroscopes, compressed
air chambers, compensating...
But all those things,
those gyroscopes and things,
- they're only to make it go, aren't they?
- Yeah.
Yeah, go and hit what it's aimed at.
Well, we've got the African Queen.
How's that, miss?
If we were to fill those cylinders
with that blasting gelatin
and then fix them so that
they would stick out
over the end of the boat,
and then run the boat
against the side of a ship,
they would go off,
just like a torpedo, wouldn't they?
Yeah, yeah, if they had detonators
in the ends.
We could... What do you call it?
Get a good head of steam up,
and then point the launch toward a ship,
and just before she hits,
we could dive off, couldn't we?
Sure, miss, sure. Absolutely.
There's only one little thing wrong
with your idea.
- There ain't nothing to torpedo.
- Oh, yes, there is.
- There's what?
- Something to torpedo.
- What's that?
- The Louisa.
The Louisa? Now, don't talk silly, miss.
You can't do that. Honest, you can't.
I told you before,
we can't get down the Ulanga.
- Spengler did.
- In a canoe, miss...
- If a German did it, we can, too.
- Not in no launch.
How do you know? You never tried it.
I never tried shooting myself
in the head, neither.
The trouble with you, miss, is you...
You don't know anything about boats.
In other words,
you are refusing to help your country
in her hour of need, Mr. Allnut?
Well, I wouldn't put it that way.
Just how would you put it, Mr. Allnut?
All right, miss, have it your own way,
but don't blame me for what happens.
Very well, then. Let's get started.
- What, now, miss?
- Yes, now.
There ain't two hours
of daylight left, miss.
We can go a long way
in two hours, Mr. Allnut.
Uh...
I'll have to get
the old kettle to boiling and...
Well, do so, Mr. Allnut.
"Could you make a torpedo?
"Well, do so, Mr. Allnut."
A little to starboard, miss. That's right.
Hey, you're doing fine, miss.
It's really quite easy,
isn't it, Mr. Allnut?
- Well, you gotta learn to read the river.
- Read the river?
Yeah. You see that
long thing over there,
looks kind of like a "V"?
That means a snag.
Oh.
Now, this choppy water over here,
that means shallow.
The Queen don't draw much water,
so we can go right over them.
Most boats would
get their bottoms tore up.
And when it's smooth and flat
like that over there,
- does that mean a rock, Mr. Allnut?
- Rock or hippo, miss.
But don't go bumping into no hippo.
Makes them awful mad.
This boat's only big enough
for the two of us.
(LAUGHS)
- What was the matter, Mr. Allnut?
- Feed pump's full of scum and rust.
She gets clogged up.
Kicking her starts her to working again.
I gotta act fast, 'cause one of my boys
dropped a screwdriver
down the safety valve.
What would happen
if you didn't kick her?
(LAUGHING)
Whole boiler would blow up.
But if we're going
downstream, Mr. Allnut,
why do we need the engine at all?
Boat's got to go faster than the water
or you can't steer.
If I was to let the engine die
going down the rapids, we'd be goners.
- Mr. Allnut?
- Yes, miss?
Why don't you dismantle
the safety valve
and remove the screwdriver?
You know, I'm going
to do that one of these days.
The only reason I ain't done it up to now
is that I kind of like kicking her.
She's all I've got.
(SIGHS) It's kind of hot work,
ain't it, miss?
(SIGHS)
I could do with a drink.
Excuse me, miss.
Oh.
- You going to have one, miss?
- No.
- What is it?
- Gin, miss.
- Something the matter, miss?
- No.
How'd you like a nice cup of tea?
I'd like a cup of tea.
Course, it'll taste a little rusty,
but then
we can't have everything, can we?
(CHUCKLES)
There you are.
I'll get this out of the way.
- Sugar, miss?
- Thank you.
Don't mention it.
- Have a bit of supper, miss?
- It's too hot to eat.
- How long you been out here, miss?
- About 10 years.
And what part of England
do you come from?
- The Midlands.
- It sounds pretty, anyway.
Yes, it is. It's very pretty.
Ever get homesick?
It's Sunday afternoons I think of most.
The peace and the quiet.
(CHUCKLING)
On Sunday afternoons,
I was always sleeping one off.
- This is very, very good.
- Yes, it isn't half bad, is it?
- What brought you to Africa, Mr. Allnut?
- The Zambezi Bridge, miss.
A whole boatload of us Canucks
came over to work on it.
Don't know yet
what they wanted a bridge for,
both sides of the river being the same,
(LAUGHING) but why does
a chicken cross the road?
- I beg your pardon?
- Nothing, miss.
Sometimes I wish
I was back rubbing elbows, as they say.
You know, there's nothing
like the jostle and the noise
and the music of a Saturday night
for cheering a fellow up.
The rest of the week
I'd be taking orders from somebody.
Out here, I'm my own boss.
Anyway, I was, until...
You didn't see any crocodiles
in this arm, did you, miss?
Crocodiles? No.
There's no shallows for them.
The current's too swift.
I could do with a bath before I turn in.
I'd like a bath myself.
Well, then, I'll just go up in the bow
and hang off the anchor chain.
You can stay back here in the stern
and do whatever you have to.
Just so long as we don't look,
it won't matter, huh?
Well, how about it, miss?
Very well, Mr. Allnut.
That's the ticket.
- Mr. Allnut.
- ALLNUT: Right here.
- ROSE: I can't get back into the boat.
- I'll give you a hand.
Close your eyes, please, Mr. Allnut.
All right. I'm all right. Thank you.
ROSE: Mr. Allnut!
Hi. Sorry I woke you, miss.
What are you doing?
- I ain't doing nothing, miss.
- Well, get out this instant.
Mr. Allnut.
You may come in out of the rain.
Thank you, miss.
- Oh, miss.
- Yes, Mr. Allnut?
- I'm sorry I gave you such a turn.
- That's quite all right, Mr. Allnut.
- Good night, miss.
- Good night, Mr. Allnut.
- What a frightfully strong smell.
- What smell?
The river. It smells like marigolds.
Stale ones.
It does, huh?
Not a very good smell for a flower.
(LAUGHING)
- They're very pretty, though, marigolds.
- They are, huh?
- Mr. Allnut?
- Yes, miss?
The current's quite
strong here, isn't it?
Yes.
We're getting near the rapids.
- Really? So soon?
- Just around that bend.
Kind of dangerous.
You better let me take over.
Here you are, miss.
- Well, miss?
- Yes, Mr. Allnut?
- How'd you like it?
- Like it?
- White water, rapids?
- I never dreamed.
I don't blame you for being scared, miss,
not one little bit.
Ain't no person in their right mind
ain't scared of white water.
I never dreamed
that any mere physical experience
- could be so stimulating.
- How's that, miss?
I've only known such excitement
a few times before.
A few times
in my dear brother's sermons,
when the spirit was really upon him.
- You mean you want to go on?
- Naturally.
- Miss, you're crazy!
- I beg your pardon?
You know what would have happened
if we'd come up against
one of them rocks?
But we didn't.
I must say, I'm filled with admiration
for your skill, Mr. Allnut.
Do you suppose
after I've practiced steering a bit,
- that someday I might try?
- Miss, let me tell you something.
Them rapids ain't nothing
to what's out in front of us.
On second thoughts,
I wouldn't call them rapids at all.
- I can hardly wait.
- But, miss...
Now that I've had a taste of it,
I don't wonder
you love boating, Mr. Allnut.
Is something the matter, Mr. Allnut?
Tell me.
Nothing. Nothing you'd understand.
I simply can't imagine
what could be the matter.
It's been such a pleasant day.
What is it?
- Yes, Mr. Allnut?
- All this foolish talk about the Louisa,
- going down the river.
- What do you mean?
I mean we ain't going to do
nothing of the sort.
Of course we are. What an absurd idea.
"What an absurd idea.
What an absurd idea."
Lady, you got 10 absurd ideas
for my one.
(SCOFFS)
Just why don't you want
to go on, Mr. Allnut?
- The river and Shona.
- Shona?
You're darn right, Shona.
All it would take would be one bullet
in the blasting gelatin
and we'd be in little bits and pieces.
- Then we'll go by night.
- Oh, no, we won't.
After Shona, there's the rapids.
Nobody in their might rind would
tackle the rapids at night.
But then we'll go in the daylight.
We'll go on the far side
of the river from Shona,
- just as fast as ever we can.
- No, we won't.
- You agreed to go.
- I never did.
I never agreed to nothing.
You are a liar, Mr. Allnut,
and what is worse, you are a coward.
(EXCLAIMS)
Coward yourself.
You ain't no lady. No, miss.
That's what my poor old mother
would say to you.
If my poor old mother were to hear you...
Whose boat is this, anyway?
I asked you on board
'cause I was sorry for you,
on account of you losing
your brother and all.
That's what you get
for feeling sorry for people.
Well, I ain't sorry no more, you crazy,
psalm-singing, skinny old maid!
(SINGING) There was a bold fisherman
Set sail from off Pimlico
And when he got off Pimlico
The winds did begin to blow
And the little boat wibble-wobbled so
That overboard went he
Singing twinkie deedledum
Twinkie deedledee
Was the highly interesting
song that he sung
Twinkie deedledum
Twinkie deedledee...
(MONKEYS SCREECHING)
Oh.
Oh, miss. Have pity, miss.
You don't know what you're doing, miss.
I'll perish without a hair of the dog.
Oh, miss.
It ain't your property!
(GROANS)
What a headache.
(SINGING) There was a bold fisherman
Set sail from off Pimlico
To catch...
(HUMMING TUNE)
But when he got off Pimlico
The one...
It's a great thing
to have a lady aboard with clean habits.
Sets a man a good example.
A man alone,
he gets to living like a hog.
(LAUGHING)
Then, too, with me,
it's always putting things off.
Never do today what you
can put off till tomorrow.
But with you,
business before pleasure, every time.
Do all your personal laundry.
Make yourself spic-and-span,
get all the mending out of the way,
and then, and only then,
sit down for a nice, quiet hour
with the Good Book.
I tell you, it's a model,
like an inspiration.
Why, I ain't had this old engine
so clean in years, inside and out.
(CHUCKLES)
Just look at her, miss.
See how she practically sparkles?
Myself, too.
Guess you haven't never
had a look at me
without my whiskers and all cleaned up.
I'll bet you wouldn't hardly recognize me.
Works that much of a change.
Freshens you up, too.
If I only had some clean clothes like you.
Now, you, why, you could be at high tea.
Say, that's an idea, miss.
How's about a nice little cup of tea?
Now, don't you stir.
I'll be glad to make it for you.
(ANIMAL ROARING)
Uh...
How's the book, miss?
Well, not that I ain't read it.
That is to say,
my poor old mom used to read me
stories out of it.
How's about reading it out loud?
I could sure do with a little
spiritual comfort, myself.
And you call yourself a Christian.
Do you hear me?
Don't you?
Huh?
(ECHOING)
(ANIMALS ROARING)
What you being so mean for, miss?
A man takes a drop too much
once in a while.
It's only human nature.
Nature, Mr. Allnut, is what we are put
in this world to rise above.
Miss.
I'm sorry. I apologize.
What more can a man do
than say he's sorry, huh?
You done paid me back, miss.
You didn't even leave me a drop.
Miss, have a heart. Fair is fair.
You gotta say something.
I don't care what it is,
but you gotta say something.
I'll be honest with you, miss,
I just can't stand no more of this.
I just ain't used to it, that's all.
So you think it was your
nasty drunkenness I minded?
- Well, what else?
- You promised you'd go down the river.
Miss, listen to me and try to understand.
There's death a dozen times over
down the river.
I'm sorry to disappoint you,
but don't blame me. Blame the Ulanga.
- You promised.
- Well, I'm taking my promise back!
All right, miss, you win,
as the crocodiles will be glad to hear.
Down the river we go.
Have some breakfast, Mr. Allnut.
Thanks for asking, and I don't mind
if I do, because it'll be my last.
Or, no. Get up steam.
Breakfast can wait.
(ENGINE CHUGGING)
Waiting for their supper, miss.
Which side of the river is Shona on?
How's that, miss?
Which bank is Shona on?
Over to starboard, miss.
Good. Then the sun will be in their eyes.
Huh?
I say the sun will be in their eyes.
Don't be worried, Mr. Allnut.
Oh, I ain't worried, miss.
Gave myself up for dead
back where we started.
(LAUGHING)
Mr. Allnut.
Better get down, miss.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Come here.
Fire over the ship!
Get down lower, miss.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(GUNS FIRING)
Nothing to do but let her drift, miss.
(ALL CHATTERING)
(SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE)
(MOTOR WHIRRING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Are we going to be all right, Mr. Allnut?
Oh, yes. Everything's all right.
If we can keep the steam up
and the boiler don't bust
and that mend holds.
And we don't pile up on them rocks.
(SCREAMING)
We made it! We made it!
Hip, hip, hooray!
We sure put one over on them
that time, didn't we, miss?
What a curious feeling
to have people shooting at you.
They were that surprised
to see the African Queen,
they didn't start shooting
till we were past.
One knows it's dangerous,
and yet one isn't afraid at all!
They didn't believe
we'd try to go down the gorge!
I suppose it's because the bullets
sound like mosquitoes.
They didn't believe anybody could!
I felt like slapping at them.
Well, we showed them!
Hip, hip, hooray!
Was my handling of the boat all right?
Well, yes, miss.
It was better than all right, miss.
Well, we're running short of fuel.
We better put in someplace.
Well, I guess I better do some pumping.
We'll be swimming pretty soon.
- Let me do that.
- Oh, no, miss.
No, please, let me
while you get the fuel.
Hey, easy does it, miss.
Don't wear yourself out.
Picked up a thorn in my foot.
Must have gone right through
the rubber sole.
Let me.
Thank you, miss.
Do you recognize these flowers,
Mr. Allnut?
Huh?
I've never seen them before.
Well, I can't say as I have, either.
Perhaps no one has.
I don't suppose they even have a name.
Whether they have or not,
they sure are pretty.
Mr. Allnut.
Dear.
Well. Well, now.
This is more like it, breakfast in bed.
Two spoonfuls of sugar is right, isn't it?
Fancy your building the fire and all
while I slept.
Dear, what is your first name?
- Charlie.
That's a nice name. Charlie, Charlie.
Give us a kiss.
Charlie. Charlie.
You know, the more I look at this place,
the prettier it gets.
I expect it's just about
the prettiest place I've ever been to,
and that's saying a lot.
Not that I ain't all for going on
down the river, you understand.
The sooner we blow up
the old Louisa, the better.
What I meant was,
I'd like to come back here someday.
Then you think we can do it?
Do it? Of course we can do it.
Nothing a man can't do
if he believes in himself.
Never say die, that's my motto.
I've had misgivings.
I was beginning to think
that the whole thing was a mistake.
How's that, miss, I mean, Rosie?
I had a moment of weakness.
Oh, now, if you're feeling weak,
a day or two more here
won't make any difference.
Oh, no. We'll go on.
Thank heaven for your strength, Charlie.
(MOTOR CHUGGING)
(IMITATING HIPPOPOTAMUS)
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING)
Oh, no!
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING)
(SCREECHING)
(IMITATING MONKEY)
Charlie.
(RIVER GUSHING)
Hey, Rosie. Listen.
(SCREAMING)
(CLATTERING)
We nearly done it that time,
didn't we, Rosie?
I wonder how much damage we've done.
Let's get the water out and see.
Yeah, better than we could've hoped for.
The skin seems tight enough.
No water coming in.
What was all that clattering
just before we stopped?
That's what we gotta find out, old girl.
How are you going to do that, dear?
I gotta go down underneath
and take a look.
I hope there's no fancy currents
down there.
Well, here goes.
Could you see anything, dear?
Yeah. The shaft's twisted
like a corkscrew
and there's a blade gone off the prop.
We'll have to mend it, then.
(SCOFFS) Mend it? Fat chance.
Why is that, dear?
What should we have to do
before we can go on?
I'll tell you.
I'll tell you what we could do
if we was back in the slip at Limbasi.
We could pull this old tub out
and take the shaft down
and haul it over to the workshop
and forge it straight again.
Then we could write to the makers
for a new prop.
They might even have one in stock,
on account of how
this boat's only 30 years old.
Then while we was waiting, we could
clean her bottom and paint her up.
Then we'd put the new
shaft in and the new prop
and go on our way
as if nothing had happened.
But this ain't Limbasi.
Couldn't you straighten the shaft
without taking the boat up on shore?
I don't know. I might.
Means working underwater.
Could be done, maybe.
If you could get the shaft up on shore,
could you straighten it?
I ain't got no anvil, I
ain't got no hearth,
I ain't got no coal,
I ain't got nothing.
I saw a Masai native working once
using charcoal on a big hollow stone.
He had a boy to fan the charcoal.
Yeah, yeah. I've seen that.
I'd use a bellows myself.
Could make one easy enough.
Well, if you think that would be better.
Well, lots and lots of firewood
on the bank.
Why don't you try it?
(CHUCKLES)
No, no. It ain't no use, Rosie.
I was forgetting the prop.
The blade's gone.
Can't we go on the blades that are left?
No. The prop would be out of balance.
The shaft would be all twisted up
like a corkscrew again.
We'll have to make a new blade, then.
There's lots of iron and stuff
that you could use.
(LAUGHS)
Yeah. Tie it on!
Well, if you think that would do,
but wouldn't it be better to weld it on?
Isn't that the right word, dear?
Weld it on?
(LAUGHING)
You're a one, Rosie. Really, you are.
Well, isn't "weld" the right word, dear?
You know what I mean,
- even if it isn't, don't you?
- Yes.
(COUGHING)
I swallowed half the river that time.
You were down there
an awfully long time. I was scared.
The shaft don't seem
to want to come out. It's stuck, like.
Charlie, let me help you.
How do you mean?
What do you think you're going to do?
- I'm going to go down there, too.
- Rosie, are you cracked?
The currents down there are fierce.
I don't want a drowned woman
on my hands.
What will you be thinking of next?
Well, here goes.
If my old dad had put me to
blacksmithing when I was a kid,
I don't think
I should have ever come to Africa.
I might have...
But then I wouldn't have met you,
Rosie, old girl.
(CHUCKLING) Charlie.
Now.
There.
Yeah, that's about as good
as I can get it.
Didn't take so long, neither.
The blade will be a different thing.
I gotta make that.
It turns right enough,
but that don't mean nothing.
Question is, will she stand up
under a full head of steam?
Well, we'll get the answer out there,
but the Lord help us
if it ain't the right one.
Looks like this old river got tired
of all the running and jumping she did
and decided to lay down
and rest for a while.
This must be where the river
changes her name from Ulanga to Bora.
(SQUAWKING)
Pinch me, Rosie.
Here we are, going down the river
like Antony and Cleopatra
on their barge.
(TRUMPETING)
If it hadn't been for you,
this couldn't be.
- Don't you feel proud of yourself?
- Certainly not.
Look at the way
you kept the engine going.
Look at how you mended the propeller.
It wasn't me at all.
I don't think there's another man alive
who could've done it.
Right you are, Rosie,
'cause no other man alive's got you.
- Oh, Charlie.
- I'll never forget the way you looked
going over the falls.
Head up, chin out,
hair blowing in the wind.
The living picture of a heroine.
Fancy me a heroine.
Charlie, you've lost your mind.
Lost my heart, too.
Shall we drop the anchor, sweetheart?
If the river needs to rest for a while,
I suppose we do, too.
Rosie, I got a feeling that pretty soon
we're going to wish we was
back shooting the rapids.
(GROANING)
This is awful. We gotta get out of here.
(BUZZING)
- We ain't got no steam.
- I'm going in.
- I'm going under the water.
- Yeah, that's it.
- No.
- ROSE: But I'm being eaten alive!
ALLNUT: What's that you said
about being eaten alive?
Look at that.
Get me out of here, Charlie!
I cannot stand it!
(WHIMPERING)
Charlie! Charlie! Charlie!
Golly! Golly! My! Hurry!
(ROSE WHIMPERING)
Charlie!
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
We got away from them.
You can come out now.
I'm ashamed of myself, Charlie,
acting this way,
but I couldn't help it. I was going mad.
Oh...
You're so bitten.
The bites themselves ain't so bad.
It's having them all around you.
I've heard of them driving buffalo
and native cattle stark-staring mad,
so they just run and run
till they fall down dead.
Will it be that way wherever we tie up?
Probably.
What are we going to do, Charlie?
Well, if the river keeps straight
and deep and slow,
there ain't nothing much can hurt us.
I'll let the anchor out a way.
That'll keep us out of trouble.
How much further do you suppose
it is to the lake, Charlie?
Well, not so many miles,
as the crow flies.
No telling how many days.
All depends on how much
winding around this old river does.
(SIGHING)
What a time we've had, Rosie.
(LAUGHS)
What a time.
We'll never lack for stories
to tell our grandchildren, will we?
Nothing but grass and papyrus
as far as you can see.
Which is the main channel?
Don't look like there is one.
What are we going to do, Charlie?
I don't know.
We can't just go round
and round here forever.
We can't just go round and round.
Well, if we get in there and the grass
closes in back of the stern,
there's no going back, Rosie.
If anything happens, we just sit there
till we go off our heads with fever.
I know it.
All right.
You pays your money
and you takes your choice.
- That way.
- Put her over.
(GRUNTING)
We've come along by steam,
we've paddled and pushed
and pulled this old boat
along with the hook.
What we ain't done up to now
is get out and carry her.
Looks like that'll come next.
Hard to breathe, the air is so heavy.
Yeah. You can't tell it from the water,
or the water from the land,
for that matter.
All the channels we've lost,
all the twisting and turning we've done.
We may come out back
where we started, if we come out at all.
We've always followed the current,
what little there is of it.
That don't mean nothing with this river.
This river's crazy, crazy as I am.
- Charlie, Charlie.
- Sorry, old girl.
Well...
The only thing that'll put the roses
back in our cheeks is to
get out of these reeds.
(GRUNTING)
What I said about having to get out
and carry this old boat
was meant to be a joke.
It don't look like a joke now. Well...
(SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMING)
The little beggars.
Pull them off me.
Oh, no, no.
The heads stay in, poison your blood.
Salt. Salt, salt.
(BOTH SHUDDERING)
Your legs.
If there's anything in the world I hate,
it's leeches.
The filthy little devils.
There.
There, dear, there, there.
Fine specimen of a man I am, ain't I?
You're the bravest man that ever lived.
You just overdo, that's all.
What you need is a few hours' sleep.
There. Now, are you all comfortable?
Go to sleep, dear.
When you wake up,
we'll be on our way again.
- Rosie.
- Yes, Charlie.
You want to know the truth, don't you?
Even if we had all our strength, we...
We'd never get her off this mud.
We're finished.
I know it.
But, Rosie, I'm not one bit sorry I came.
What I mean is, it was worth it.
Dear Lord,
we've come to the end of our journey.
In a little while,
we will stand before you.
I pray for you to be merciful.
Judge us not for our weakness,
but for our love.
And open the doors of heaven
for Charlie and me.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROWLING)
Rosie.
Rosie, dear.
Look. We're on the lake.
The rain did it,
just lifted the old Queen up
and carried her over the mud.
We couldn't have been
100 yards from it last night.
Look. Look, Rosie.
Let's build the fire
and get the engine started
and go right out into the middle,
away from these reeds
where we can breathe.
Sure, sure.
We'll be out of here in a jiffy.
(SIGHS)
This air, isn't it wonderful?
Yeah. It's like...
I know you don't approve,
but it's like a shot of gin.
It makes your blood race,
your face numb and your spirit soar.
I'm sorry I poured that gin out, Charlie.
Forget it, Rosie.
And just to show you
there's no hard feelings,
I'll make you another cup of tea.
(SIGHS)
You carry on more over a cup of tea
than I do over a glass of gin.
ROSE: Is it?
Yes, it's the Louisa,
and she's coming right toward us.
She must be doing a good 12 knots.
We've got to make a run for it,
back to the reeds.
She's coming right toward us.
I thought for a minute they'd seen us.
They're going toward that island.
ALLNUT: They'll probably anchor there
for the night and leave in the morning.
Don't you worry, they'll be back again.
You know how the Germans are.
They lays down systems
and then they sticks to them.
Monday, they're one place,
Tuesday, someplace else, and
then Wednesday, they'll be back here.
How long will it take
to get the torpedoes ready?
I don't know.
It depends on the detonators.
We've got to devise something.
I know what you're thinking, Rosie.
You're thinking of taking the Queen
out at night
when the Louisa comes back,
ain't you, old girl?
Well, we ought to manage it.
ALLNUT: There, that ought to work.
When we ram into it,
the ends of these nails
will hit the percussion caps
and shoot the bullets into the gelatin.
ROSE: Charlie, you're wonderful.
CHARLIE: (LAUGHS)
Can't put them in the cylinders yet.
They're pretty tricky.
We'll put them in
when we're ready to start.
It will be dark by then.
Do you think that you can do it
in the dark?
It's a case of have to.
You're quite sure
that they will come back
with the Louisa, aren't you, Charlie?
Mmm-hmm. Dead sure.
Let me see, the lake's 100 miles long,
50 miles wide.
Louisa does about... About 12 knots.
That's 120 miles a day. Yep.
She'll be back here tomorrow.
When she comes,
we'll be ready for her.
Charlie, let's make the Queen
as clean as we can,
scrub her decks and polish her brass.
Sure. She ought to look her best,
representing, as she does,
the Royal Navy.
- You know, Rosie, I've been thinking.
- Yes, Charlie?
Now, there ain't no use
of us both going to do it.
Now that I've had time to study it,
I can plainly see it's a one-man job.
You couldn't be more right,
Charlie dear.
Well now, Rosie,
I'm glad you agree with me.
When the time comes,
I'll put you off on the east shore.
You'll wait there for me
while I attend to the Louisa.
Certainly not.
You're the one to be put ashore.
- Me?
- This whole thing
was my idea, wasn't it?
I'm the logical one to carry it out.
Why, Rosie, I'm surprised at you!
You're a very sensible woman as a rule.
Now, we won't have any more talk
along those lines.
Now, look here, Charlie Allnut,
I can manage this boat
every bit as well as you can
and you know it.
Rosie, you're cracked.
Didn't I steer going down the rapids?
You steer well enough, but you
don't know nothing about the engine.
Suppose she broke down on you
out there? Wouldn't you look foolish?
Now, me,
I'd just walk back from the tiller
and do a thing or two to that old engine.
You know, spit on her, kick her in the
slats and she'd go right to work again.
She knows who's boss, all right,
you bet that old engine does.
- I suppose you're right.
- Well, now, that's all settled.
I'll dive off a second before the crash
and swim over to where
you'll be waiting on the east shore
and we'll be off to Kenya together.
No, I meant it may be necessary
for you to come along.
Come along? What do you mean?
Didn't we just agree
this was a one-man job?
But you convinced me that it isn't,
so now it's settled. We'll go together.
Oh, no, we won't.
You'll wait for me on the east shore.
Who do you think you are,
ordering me about?
I'm the captain, that's who.
And I ain't taking you along.
You'd only be in my way.
I suppose I was in your way
going down the rapids.
Then what you said to me
back there on the river was a lie
about how you never
could have done it alone
and how you'd lost your heart
and everything.
You liar.
Oh, Charlie,
we're having our first quarrel.
Rosie.
It's only that
I just can't bear the thought of...
Well, what I mean is,
suppose something should happen,
not that anything will, but...
Don't you understand, Charlie?
I wouldn't want to go on to Kenya
without you.
Oh, Rosie. All right.
It'll be you at the tiller
and me at the engine,
just like it was from the start.
And there's the Louisa, right on time.
It's blowing up a bit.
We'd better get started, all right?
Charlie. Charlie, I can't steer.
It's hard to steer.
Too much water in the bow.
Screw's out of the water half the time.
We've got to get her nose up
or we'll be in trouble.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Rosie, we're sinking.
Rosie!
Rosie! Rosie! Rosie!
OFFICER: What is your nationality?
French? Belgian? British?
- ALLNUT: Yeah.
- Yes, what?
- ALLNUT: British.
- What were you doing on the island?
Oh...
Fishing.
You are aware that the punishment
for giving false testimony
before this court is death by hanging?
Who cares?
What were you doing on the island?
- I was fishing.
- How did you get there?
I swam.
OFFICER: Do you know
that you are in an area
prohibited to all
but members of the forces
of His Imperial Majesty
Kaiser Wilhelm II?
Who cares?
You are accused of being a spy
in the service
of the British Armed Forces.
Have you anything to say that might lead
this court to believe otherwise?
I told you I was fishing.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
The court sentences you
to death by hanging.
Sentence to be carried out immediately.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Was there a woman with you?
Rosie. Rosie! Rosie! Rosie!
- Charlie!
- Rosie!
Charlie!
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Who's that woman?
- I don't know.
- You just called her by name.
I thought she was somebody else.
I shall hang you twice, I think.
- Charlie, dear.
- Rosie.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Who are you?
Miss Rose Sayer.
English?
Of course.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
- What were you doing on the lake?
- I ain't told him nothing, Rosie.
Silence!
- What were you doing on the lake?
- We were boating.
Last night? In such weather?
We were not responsible
for the weather.
As your fellow prisoner
has already learned,
the penalty for not
answering this court is death.
You mean he... Charlie?
Stop that!
CAPTAIN: Order.
Are they going to hang you, Charlie?
CAPTAIN: Frulein Sayer,
you will come to order
and answer the question of this court.
Very well. Ask your questions.
What were you doing on the lake?
- We came here to sink this ship.
- Rosie!
- And we would have, too, except...
Let's at least have the pleasure
of telling them about it, Charlie.
CAPTAIN: Sink this ship?
Don't you believe her, Your Honor.
She's touched, you know. Fever.
Stop that, Charlie.
We've been through all that.
I'm certainly not going to outlive you,
and that's all there is to it.
And just how, Frulein, did you propose
to sink the Knigin Louise?
With torpedoes.
Torpedoes?
(OFFICER SPEAKS GERMAN)
Will you be so good as to tell us exactly
where and how
you acquired torpedoes?
- Mr. Allnut made them.
- OFFICER: How very interesting.
You don't believe me, do you?
Charlie, tell them
how you made the torpedoes.
Well, I... See, what I did, I...
I took the heads off
two cylinders of oxygen
and I filled them up with live explosive.
You know, about two hundredweight.
That was easy enough.
It was the detonators
that took some doing.
And you know what I used?
Cartridges and nails
and blocks of soft wood.
Then I took the two cylinders
and I put them in the bows
of the African Queen,
right down near the waterline,
so when we rammed you... Poof!
And where is the African Queen?
She sank in the storm.
CAPTAIN: But how did you get
onto the lake?
We came down the Ulanga,
the Bora, you call it down here.
- That's impossible.
- Nevertheless.
But everyone knows
the river is unnavigable.
That may be.
We came down it, though,
didn't we, Charlie?
And in the African Queen.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Would you hang us together, please?
(SPEAKS GERMAN)
- Now, wait a minute. Hey, Captain.
- Yes?
- Will you grant us a last request?
- What is it?
- Marry us.
- What?
We want to get married.
Ship captains can do that, can't they?
- CAPTAIN: Yeah.
- Why, Charlie, what a lovely idea.
What kind of craziness is this?
Come on, Captain,
it'll only take a minute,
and it'll mean such a lot to the lady.
Very well, if you wish it absolutely.
What are the names again?
- Charles.
- Rosie. Rose.
CAPTAIN: Do you, Charles, take this
woman to be your lawful wedded wife?
Yes, sir.
Do you, Rose, take this man
to be your lawful wedded husband?
I do.
By the authority vested in me
by Kaiser Wilhelm II,
I pronounce you man and wife.
Proceed with the execution.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(EXPLOSION)
(ALL SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(SIREN WAILING)
(MEN SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
Hey, what happened?
We did it, Charlie! We did it!
But how?
Well, what do you think?
(LAUGHING)
You all right, Mrs. Allnut?
Wonderful. Simply wonderful.
And you, Mr. Allnut?
Pretty good for an old, married man.
I'm all twisted around, Charlie.
Which way is the east shore?
The way we're swimming, old girl.
(SINGING) There was a bold fisherman
Set sail from off Pimlico
To catch the bold picky
And the gay mackerel
BOTH: (SINGING)
But when he got off Pimlico
The wind did begin to blow...