[music playing]
[clangs]
[machines clinking]
[pants]
[chokes]
[squelching, crunching]
[clicking]
[theme music playing]
2x07 - Ways to Bury A Man
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~
[knocks]
Hey, Jason. Come on.
Jason, come on. Let's go.
[turns doorknob]
Jason?
[door squeaks]
[door closes]
[toilet tank lid scrapes, thunks]
[water splashing]
[breathing heavily]
[gun hammer clicks]
[breathing deeply]
Baby.
Whew.
Lucas: Sugar.
You know, it makes me sick to see an
American classic defaced like that.
Mm.
If it makes you feel any
better, they were aiming for me.
That makes sense.
Lucas: Come inside.
You know there's nothing
on God's green Earth
that would get me to voluntarily
walk into a police station,
but I was getting my fix on in town,
figured I'd drop in, see how
you pulling this shit off.
I mean, a crook posing as a cop
and a car dealership
posing as a cop station?
[chuckles] Hoo.
[groans]
You see Jason this morning?
I thought he had a train to catch.
Yeah, I went to his motel to take
him to the station. He wasn't there.
Maybe he doesn't like saying good-byes.
He wouldn't have left without this.
You know, I-I did see him
last night at the Forge
talking to Proctor's niece.
- Rebecca?
- Yeah.
- When?
- Late.
I'm pretty sure they left together.
What, you think
something happened to him?
Yeah.
I just... I don't know what.
- Lucas: Morning.
- Kai: Sheriff.
What brings you out
our way this morning?
I just came by for a little chat.
Well, do join us.
No. Only be a minute.
- Hey.
- Hi.
You left the Forge
with someone last night.
Late 20s, blond hair.
What seems to be the problem?
Well, he's missing.
There were, uh...
signs of struggle in his motel room.
And what would Rebecca know about that?
That's what I'm here to find out.
Who is this man?
We don't know that yet.
Do you have a name?
So you're gonna try and tell me that
you don't know him?
I don't know him.
I did fuck him, though.
We don't always know the
people we fuck, do we?
So...
you were in his motel room, right?
- For a little bit.
- How long?
I left after he fell asleep.
- Your uncle come pick you up?
- Was there a crime committed?
No, I'm just trying to
make a timeline here.
Why don't you tell me what happened?
- What happened?
- Are you accusing us of something...
- Why would I do that?
- No, indeed, why would you do that?
You have no evidence, no body.
There's not even a name, you say.
It doesn't sound to me
there's a crime committed...
was there?
Are you sure you don't
want anything to eat?
You going along with this?
He said he was leaving town.
I assume he did.
This was your choice.
When I come for him, I come for you.
[footsteps receding]
I have a busy day ahead of me.
I should go.
[speaking Pennsylvania Dutch]
[car beeping]
[beeping stops]
[clicks]
[on CB radio] It's Siobhan, boss.
- Yeah?
- Heard you were in earlier.
Just wondering when you'd be back in.
I'm drawing up the patrol schedule.
I'll be back in an hour.
Copy. See you then.
So you think Proctor killed Jason?
And he wanted me to know it.
Just because the boy
slept with his niece.
That's a new low for Proctor.
[door bursts open]
Fuck this shit. I need
a motherfucking break.
I've been up for the past 72 hours
hacking into every server
I know looking for Rabbit.
Whatever hole that Boris
Karloff motherfucker is in,
it is deep and dark.
- Who died?
- The kid, Jason.
How?
Proctor.
Damn.
I guess we'd better get
out the gloves and shovel.
I'm not burying anyone else this month.
Anyone really gonna
mind if I bury Proctor?
Proctor's got too much juice here.
You can't go after a
man like that head-on
and not expect some major blowback.
Most people are happy with
one psychopath after them.
You really want two?
I'll take my chances.
No, that's the con talking.
I am a con.
Well, you could've
fooled me this morning.
What I'm saying is there's
a lot of ways to bury a man.
Especially when you're
wearing that badge.
[opens car door]
Hey.
- Hey.
- Got a minute?
Uh, I got a patrol.
I was hoping to pick your brain a bit.
What's up?
Hypothetically...
if you were gonna take down
Proctor, how would you do it?
Oh, you're gonna go after Proctor, huh?
What exactly are you
gonna take him down for?
Anything.
Everything.
Yeah, I think I'm gonna need
you to be a little more specific.
- You know what? Forget it.
- Listen, Hood.
Proctor's got his fingers
in everything around here...
prostitution, drugs, extortion.
The problem is, he's
always one step removed.
There's no direct ties,
and he knows exactly
how to walk that line.
So, good luck.
You've been here a long time.
If you were sheriff,
how would you do it?
If I were sheriff.
If I were sheriff...
I'd start by shaking his trees.
- Which trees?
- All of 'em, repeatedly, over and over
till something we can
use falls out of them.
- Something we can use?
- Come on, Hood.
You don't think I'm gonna let
you have all the fun, do you?
All right, let's go find a tree.
[crickets chirping]
Excuse me...
[engine roars]
[grunts]
[engine idling]
Mr. Thompson, do you know who I am?
- Yeah.
- Good, then we can skip an introduction.
George Hunter has engaged the council
in a campaign to oust Alex Longshadow
from the position of chief
with a no-confidence vote.
However, it's in the
interests of numerous parties
that this vote does not pass,
and you, my friend, just
became one of those parties.
[jingles]
- Do you know what these are?
- No.
These are the keys to your daughter's
college dormitory and dorm room.
Cora's doing pretty well.
You must be proud.
[engine revs]
[panting]
So I can count on your cooperation?
Yeah.
Good.
Who's next?
[dishes clattering]
Max, dinner!
Come on, Max. It's not cereal.
Max, I'm not kidding around.
If you don't get over here
right now and eat this,
I'm gonna eat this.
Max? Max?
Max!
Maxie! Max!
Breathe, Max! Max, breathe!
Fuck!
Jesus.
[over phone] You've
reached Gordon Hopewell.
Please leave your name and number.
[phone beeps]
Shit, Dad, it's Max.
He's having an attack and
I don't know what to do.
Can you call me, please?
[over phone] You've
reached Gordon Hopewell.
Please leave your name and number.
[phone beeps]
You've reached Gordon Hopewell.
Please leave your name and number.
[phone beeps]
Fuck.
Man on phone: Emergency Services.
Yeah, um, I need an ambulance.
My brother's having
an attack. Please help.
He has asthma. Can you please hurry?
How we doing?
Siobhan on CB radio: We're good to go.
All right, listen, any illegal activity
will be happening off the east hallway.
That is right behind the dressing areas.
That's where the private
rooms are, all right?
So let's split up when we get inside.
Two stay in front, two hit the back.
Did you copy that?
Siobhan: You're pretty
familiar with the layout.
Don't judge. Let's go.
[engine starts]
[music blaring]
[cheering]
Man: That's my girl!
[overlapping chatter]
Banshee Sheriff's Department!
Banshee Sheriff's!
- Hey!
- I'll hit the lights.
Yeah, music, too.
Hey.
[music stops]
Brock: Banshee Sheriff's Department.
- Everybody stay where you are.
- Siobhan.
Brock: No one's in
trouble. I just need...
dancers, please head to the back.
Patrons, gather up your stuff,
start heading to the front door.
All right, ladies, let's wrap this up.
- Woman: What the fuck?
- Emmett, come get these girls out the front.
- Do you know who owns this place?
- Sure do.
- Then you know it's off-limits
to the cops. - Yeah, not anymore.
You have no idea... [grunts]
[women gasping]
You tell Proctor nothing's
off-limits to me anymore.
Really?
♪ Looking at the time,
waiting on a plane... ♪
What'd you say your name was?
Passion.
- # Staring at the sky, working on a tune... #
- Passion.
All right, Banshee Sheriff...
You two, out the front now.
Picked a bad night, Gordon.
We're busting the
place for prostitution.
Well, that's crack
detective work, Sheriff.
I mean, it's only
Banshee's worst-kept secret.
Wait five minutes and go out
the back. No one will see you.
Oh, what, are you doing me favors now?
Well, fuck you. I don't
need your fucking favors.
- Hey, trust me, asshole. It's not for you.
- Yeah, fuck you.
You ride into town
and this fucking tidal wave of shit
follows you like a fucking plague.
Are you fucking my wife?
- No.
- Bullshit.
Get the fuck out of here, Gordon.
[Gordon groans]
You finished?
[Gordon mumbles]
[groans]
You fuckin'...
[yells] Fuck!
[sighs]
Come on, let's get you out of here.
[grunting]
What is this? Come on!
Come on, get off him!
Come on. Lucas, Lucas.
- Fuckin' piece of shit!
- God, cool off!
Jesus Christ, what is this, huh?
You all right?
You wanna tell me why
I just broke up a fight
between the sheriff and the mayor?
- It's complicated.
- You can talk to me, all right?
- And not just because we're sleep...
- I know, I know.
Woman on intercom: Dr. Valerian to OR1.
Dr. Valerian to OR1.
[sobbing]
It's okay, I'm here.
I'm here.
Emmett: Believe you me,
in a situation like this,
we're just trying our best
to cover all the bases.
I wouldn't take it personally.
Just gonna ask you a couple of
questions. Shouldn't take too long.
Sorry, just to clarify, where did
you say you went to law school?
Did you see somebody pay me
to stick his dick in my ass?
- No.
- No, thank God.
So, what do I know about a
fucking prostitution ring?
All right, so let me just confirm,
your name is Platinum?
Platinumm. Two Ms. Platinumm.
- Platinumm.
- Like, "Mm, she looked good."
Half of them claimed
they didn't know anything
about organized prostitution.
They got paid to dance. That's it.
Jesus Christ.
The smart ones won't even admit
to that until they lawyer up.
We caught some of them in the act.
Well, they say they were acting alone.
- They claim Proctor didn't know anything about it.
- This is fucking ridiculous.
Yes, it is, and that's why
they call it police work.
Hey.
- You okay?
- Hey.
[clicks]
I'm great.
All right, one of the
girls is asking for you.
Excuse me, I'm looking
for my son, Max Hopewell.
Someone downstairs said he was up here.
- Max...
- Hopewell. He has asthma and he...
Are... are you all right?
Never mind.
Where is he?
He's with the doctor now.
Deva, what happened?
- Deva...
- Where were you?
- I was working.
- Bullshit, I called your office!
He could have fucking died, Dad.
- I'm sorry, Deva.
- I don't give a shit if you're sorry.
Jesus fucking Christ, Dad.
Do you even see how fucked up you are?
- It's all right. I just...
- No, it's not all right.
Nothing about this is all right.
We are so fucked. This
whole family is so fucked.
- Deva...
- Get off me!
Gordon, let her go.
She called you.
- Look, tonight was...
- Gordon, you don't have to explain yourself.
Least of all to me.
- Mr. and Mrs. Hopewell?
- Yes.
Dr. Kessler, I'm the resident on duty.
- How is he?
- Max is stable.
He suffered from an acute attack.
How?
We're really good about his meds
and he always has his inhaler nearby.
Nobody did anything wrong.
His condition is deteriorating.
His medicine is no longer as effective.
It looks like you already
talked to Max's pulmonologist
- about leukotriene modifiers...
- Yeah.
- ...beta agonists...
- Yeah, yeah, we thought...
we thought we had more time
before all that was necessary.
You need to talk to his doctor.
I'm gonna go check on
Max. I'll be right back.
Mr. Proctor.
Sheamus, please explain
to me why we're closed.
They came in here,
they busted everybody,
and they took our girls.
That's basically what happened.
Very unfortunate.
Obviously not your fault.
Just give me the arrest warrant.
I'll take it up with my lawyers.
- The warrant?
- Yeah, the arrest warrant.
I'm sure you didn't let a bunch of cops
come in here and shut down my business
without a legal arrest warrant.
They just came through the
front door locked and loaded.
What do you expect me to do?
[grunting]
What I expect you to do
is what I pay you to do.
[grunting]
Keep my club open.
Got that?
[Sheamus coughing]
[Sheamus groans]
Now clean this place up.
[glass thuds]
I want it open by tomorrow
for lunch.
I don't know what we're
gonna do about this.
We're gonna talk to the
insurance company again.
They've gotta be
willing to pay for more.
They say that Max's asthma
has a chronic condition limit,
and if they don't think the
asthma's gonna get any better,
then they're not gonna
approve new treatment.
We're just gonna have to pay
for the treatments ourselves.
Where are we gonna get cash like that?
God damn it, how did I let
things get this screwed up?
You're a good father, Gordon.
Juliet: They're not gonna
say anything about Proctor.
They're more scared of him than you.
And you're not?
Proctor owns this whole town.
He doesn't own me.
How about you?
[grunting]
No one owns me.
Lucas: Okay.
So, what do you got?
[door opens]
[door closes]
So...
I see him three to four times a week.
- He pays you? - Mm-hmm,
but he calls them gifts.
And what would he do if you said no?
He'd get me fired from the
club and I need the money.
So, what do you want to tell me?
If I gave you something on Proctor,
would you put him away?
Could you even put him away?
Depends what it is.
- Would I have to testify?
- Depends what it is.
Well, I won't testify, and
you have to promise me...
- I can't promise you anything until I know what you've got.
- And he can't know it's me.
Listen, I got a jail full
of whores I can do this with.
And I have a...
I have a son.
Fuck.
Listen, if what you've got is
big enough to put Proctor away,
I'll do everything I can
to keep you out of it.
That's as close to a promise
as you're gonna get right now.
No?
There was this guy I used to see.
[sniffles] A client.
He used to drive trucks for
Proctor, running X into Philly.
- Ecstasy?
- He said Proctor has this place where they do it all...
cook it, pack it, and ship it off.
You know his name?
Matt Sharp.
Where do I find him?
Hey.
I'm looking for Matt Sharp.
I'm Sharp.
[laughs] Irony. Nice.
I need to talk to you for a minute.
I'm on the clock, Sheriff.
I don't know if you heard,
but the market's down,
unemployment's at 9%.
You wouldn't want to keep an honest
man from making a buck, would ya?
An honest man, no.
You? Eh, I could give a shit.
Brock: Listen, guys, we just got
a couple of questions for you.
You're gonna want to put that down.
- Are you one of those affirmative action hires?
- Hey.
How do you like sitting in
the front seat versus the back?
Not as good as it'll feel
when I put my boot up your
ass and out your mouth.
- Whoa.
- Hey, we're just messing around.
We didn't mean nothing by it.
Yeah, spic, slope, coon, kike, faggot.
Soon as you put the uniform
on, we dislike you all the same.
Yo, I recognize this dude.
You're that football player, right?
Real big deal in college.
Running back.
Man: Yeah, what happened? Did you quit?
Or did somebody figure out
that a nigger running like he
stole something ain't nothing new?
[laughs]
Brock: Emmett, be cool, all right?
Emmett?
- I'm cool.
- All right.
Don't hold back on my account.
Emmett: A verbal taunt does
not fulfill the protocol
for self-defense, Sheriff,
only a life-threatening act.
And these little men aren't what
I'd consider to be threatening.
Fuck you, O.J.
I do believe I now feel threatened.
I would.
[grunting]
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Don't you fucking move.
Oh!
[grunting]
You okay, Brock?
No!
Emmett, you need a hand?
Oh, fuck.
Emmett!
[choking]
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. Slow down, Sharp.
What do you want, cop?
You're gonna tell me about
Proctor's ecstasy operation.
I don't know what the
fuck you're talking about.
Okay.
[groans]
Let me get you started.
[coughing]
You were a driver.
You did runs from Banshee...
[groans]
...to Philly.
Who told you that?
Well, that's none of your business.
[laughs]
You think I'm gonna roll on
someone like Proctor 'cause of you?
Ah!
Go ahead, arrest me.
At least in jail I got my health.
Yeah, but right now...
♪ I got your arm. ♪
[yells] Stop!
- So tell me how it works.
- Fuck you.
[yells] Okay.
- I was just a driver.
- Yeah, we covered that.
Now, how did it work?
[yells]
It was always at night.
I'd pick up the trucks from the factory,
get 'em loaded, and then drive
from Banshee towards Philly.
And?
[groans]
All right. I'd have an address.
Usually like some parking lot.
I'd leave the truck with the keys
in the cab and then walk away.
- And who took the trucks from there?
- I never saw anyone.
The whole system's rigged with cutouts
so no one knew more than they had to.
But you got your orders
from Proctor, right?
- I never even met him.
- Don't fuck with me, Sharp.
Fuck, I'm not! I told
you, I don't know shit!
I can't argue with that.
[groans]
But you do know where the factory is.
[yells]
Oh, fuck, man.
Near the brick factory on Havershaw.
[taps]
Thanks.
Hey.
We're out.
Well...
look what the parole officer dragged in.
I missed you.
Oh, honey, I know.
But I come bearing gifts.
Your cut from the truck job.
It's hardly retirement money...
- You ain't gonna count it?
- I already know it won't be enough.
Mm, you're telling me.
Enough for what?
I need to do another one.
And I need to stop risking my fine ass
over motherfucking milk money.
- This one's different.
- Oh, this one's different?
Then I'll gather the troops.
It's gotta be just you and me.
Now, we all agreed we were
gonna do this together.
Moonlighting ain't my style.
- I need this, Job.
- Join the motherfucking club.
[whispers] It's not for me.
My son is sick.
Mm.
Who do I have to shoot to get
a motherfucking menu in here?
[trucks beeping]
Emmett: Doesn't look very
secure for a drug lot.
Yeah, that's what someone
wants you to think.
They got cameras covering
the perimeter there, there.
17-gauge wire along the fence line.
It's electrified.
And they got motion sensors in the back.
You can tell all that from here?
Yeah, more or less.
Emmett: Well, we're gonna need
some time to get a warrant.
What do you want to do?
Let's find out who owns the place.
Oh, you mean do some actual
police work. Sounds good.
George: Throughout our history
we have stood behind brave leaders
who protected our culture and traditions
from a world that would see us gone.
Alex Longshadow comes from a
line of great Kinaho chiefs.
No one has done more for their people
than Benjamin Longshadow...
which is why it saddens me
that it has come to this.
Alex simply lacks the
wisdom and experience
to lead the Kinaho tribe
in these complicated times.
That is why it is with a heavy heart
that I call for this
vote of no confidence
in Alex Longshadow as tribal chief.
All in favor, raise
their hand and say, "Aye."
Thompson, you're gonna let
some thug scare you away
from the ideals of your ancestors?
Maybe we were too harsh in our judgment.
Alex is young and ambitious.
Young blood may be just
what this tribe needs.
You have corrupted this
council and shamed yourself
as well as your father.
You gonna adjourn this meeting, or what?
[sighs] What'd you do
to those guys, anyway?
Your father was a man of great wisdom.
He knew, like you now know,
that sometimes the way over a mountain
is through it.
And...
going through the mountain...
well...
that's my specialty.
Be well, Chief Longshadow.
[sighs]
Property report lists the owner of the
warehouse and land as Wildflower, LLC.
Brock: It's probably a shell company.
Proctor's name is nowhere near it.
We'd pretty much have to catch Proctor
in the warehouse personally
cooking up a batch of ecstasy
in order to make the drug charges stick.
Doesn't mean we can't
shut the place down.
Proctor'll have another one
up and running in a week.
You want me to see what I
can find on the shell company?
Uh, yeah. Might as well.
Hey, Emmett...
sorry about what happened yesterday.
You know, the shit at the junkyard.
You know, every time I think
I'm immune to that stuff...
I can only turn the other
cheek for so many times.
But it gave me a chance to be a
good Christian and kick some butt.
And how were you a good Christian?
I forgave them afterwards.
Lucas: Back to square one.
Is there some reason you
need to arrest Proctor today?
Lucas: Proctor does whatever
he wants to whoever he wants.
Every day that list
gets a little bit longer.
Been like that since
before you got here.
That doesn't mean it stays the same way.
[brakes screech]
[air brakes hiss]
Don't you fucking move.
Hands behind your back.
Hands behind your back. Do it!
- Who's left in the warehouse?
- Nobody.
Do you know whose shit you're stealing?
Who says we're stealing it?
[coughs]
Listen, there's a right way
and a wrong way to get Proctor.
So, you can drive this?
Shit, back in the day,
I used to run a big rig
cross-country in 92 hours.
Well, shit's changed
since World War I, Sugar.
You know, I really was hoping
that he'd run your ass over.
Hey.
You sure you want to do this?
Go up against Proctor like this?
You got your issues
with Proctor, I got mine.
This is a war. This
isn't about one battle.
You wanna win this thing?
Just settle in, be patient.
You're right.
[gears grinding]
Damn.
Is he drunk?
[gears grind]
Yeah, it's simple.
- You take care of the cameras?
- Don't insult me, baby.
All right, boys.
Now, this is gonna hurt a little bit.
[all grunt]
[glass shattering]
[electricity crackling]
Whoo! God damn!
Man, that's something you
don't get to do every day.
[laughs]
- Lucas: That gonna be enough?
- That's what the man said.
Look, you gonna give us enough time
to clear our asses outta here?
What, you think we gonna
light a long fuse and run?
This ain't a fuckin'
Road Runner cartoon.
Lucas: Sugar!
Boom, motherfucker.
[grunts]
What happened?
I don't know.
- Are you dialing the right number?
- Yes, I'm dialing the right...
fuck!
Bet you wish you had a long
fuse and a match right about now.
Fuck you, Sugar.
[chuckles]
Maybe it's a loose...
[metal clanging]
Whoo. [groans]
Mm-mm.
[coughs]
Sugar: Damn.
[crashing]
[coughing]
Sugar: Supposed to just blow the lab,
not put a goddamn crater in the Earth.
Now tell me that don't fill you
with a warm, tingling feeling inside.
[debris clattering]
It's a start.
I can't hear a thing.
That's 'cause you old and deaf.
Don't put that shit on me.
- What?
- "What"?
Brock: You know, when
you first got here,
I didn't think you were much of a cop.
Yet you hid it so well.
Oh, I still don't think
you're much of a cop.
But I think you're serious
about getting Proctor,
and this town's been waiting
for somebody to do that
for a long, long time.
And I was hoping it was gonna be me.
But what I'm saying is I
don't mind that it's you.
- That must've hurt.
- Like a prostate exam.
[door closes]
[fire crackling]
[music playing]
.
♪ She's 99 pounds of dynamite ♪
♪ And, oh, what a lovely sight ♪
♪ When she kisses and holds me tight ♪
♪ She's like 99 pounds of dynamite ♪
♪ My baby is good to me ♪
♪ A real package of TNT ♪
♪ When she squeezes with all her might ♪
♪ She's like 99 pounds of dynamite ♪
♪ I want the world to know ♪
♪ I love my baby so ♪
♪ There's no danger if I take it slow ♪
♪ I handle her with
all the care I know ♪
♪ She's 99 pounds of dynamite ♪
♪ She's got the fuse,
I've got the light ♪
♪ Gonna be with my baby tonight ♪
♪ Who is 99 pounds of dynamite ♪
♪ My baby is good to me ♪
♪ A real package of TNT ♪
♪ When she squeezes with all her might ♪
♪ She's like 99 pounds of dynamite ♪
♪ She's 99 pounds of dynamite... ♪
[helicopter blades whirring]
♪ Gonna be with my baby tonight ♪
♪ Who is 99 pounds of dynamite. ♪
[explosion]
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ Addic7ed.com ~