Previously on "weeds"...
my cover business...
what about a bakery?
These will satisfy
your munchies
and give you a long-lasting,
all-body high.
I'm ready to take orders.
Fuck it.
I'll take it all.
Last week's buy,
this week's buy.
My ring, my rover.
You're still short for all
you're gonna want this week.
I'll be back.
I don't like dealing
with things.
I prefer to pretend
they don't exist.
Silas: Megan. Hey, megan.
Megan, can you hear me?
Celia: That deaf girl
down on dewey street.
* little boxes on the hillside *
* little boxes
made of ticky-tacky *
* little boxes on the hillside *
* little boxes all the same *
* there's a green one
and a pink one *
* and a blue one
and a yellow one *
* and they're all made out
of ticky-tacky *
* and they all look
the same *
* and the people in the houses *
* all went to the university *
* where they were put in boxes *
* and they came out
all the same *
* and there's doctors
and lawyers *
* and business executives *
* and they're all made out
of ticky-tacky *
* and they all look
just the same *
Fire! Mom, what are you doing?
There's a fire!
If there's a fire,
i'll run, okay?
Otherwise, i'm gonna bash in
the smoke alarm
with a broom handle.
Andy?
Sorry, pants.
I was trying
to surprise you guys.
Uncle andy!
Hey, guys. Ohhhh!
Yes, i'm diggin' the love.
Oh, i missed you.
How was alaska?
Alaska was so beautiful.
In the summer,
you could party all night.
Then it got dark,
and i met this psycho girl
who tried to bring me up
on charges...
how did you
get in here?
I'll pay for the window.
I didn't want to wake you.
I... uh, i'm joking, i'm joking,
i'm joking, i'm joking!
Oh, hey, you guys want
to help me make breakfast?
Shane, i need you
making the coffee.
Sorry about the grease fire.
That bacon really spits up.
Shane, go get a broom
so i can bash
your uncle andy with it.
Come on, nancy pantsy.
I'm making eggs florentine.
Don't call me "pants."
Pantalones?
Oh, shit. You?
Hey, lupita.
I know you missed me.
How about a hug?
I'm no cleaning up
this mess.
Uncle andy,
did you bring us anything?
Of course!
Look who you're talking to.
Get my duffel in the guest room.
The black one, not the green.
Stay out of the green.
Guest room? Guest room.
Uh, i guess
i could sleep with lupita.
I do love
the fiery latinas.
Ugh.
Know this, lupita.
Until you learn to love me,
i got enough love
for both of us.
How did you and judah emerge
from the same woman?
I know! What family gets blessed
with not one, but two studs?
Everybody gather.
First, young silas,
that's for you.
Oh! Awesome.
So, does it work?
Yeah.
For three weeks.
Then scratch off
the serial number
and get
a new service plan.
Okay. For mama...
shane: What's that?
For your neck, right?
You're always talking about
how your neck hurts.
Take it.
For my neck.
Of course. Thank you.
Lupita.
I'll put it in your bedroom
next to the little one.
What about me?!
Oh, i don't, uh...
oh!
The best for last.
No! No way!
I'll teach him
how to use them.
Shane li,
hand them over.
Andy!
I'll hold on to those
till we're in a better space.
Who's hungry?
Everybody go sit down.
Andy...
how long you
planning on staying?
Don't worry.
I'll help out.
How long?
Just till i figure
some things out.
Like?
I don't know.
My life.
Sure. That.
Good to see you,
pants.
It's good
to be with family.
Come on, let's eat.
Hey, buddy.
Whatcha doing?
Just iming
my girlfriend.
You don't need a credit card
for that, do you?
No. Real girlfriend.
Megan. She's deaf.
Deaf megan.
Is she cute?
Yeah.
She's totally cute.
Oh, yeah.
She doesn't look deaf.
She can't hear anything?
That's what deaf mns. Ea
man, how did you get so smart
at, what, 16?
Took me years to learn
slightly defective chicks
are the way to go.
I once went out with this girl
with a baby arm...
insane in the sack.
Plus, when she grabbed my dick
with her little hand,
it looked gigantic.
So how do you
talk to her?
Uh, we just mostly
haut and stuff.
You should learn braille.
You mean sign language?
[Laughing]
Whatever.
What's this?
Ugh. That's mine.
"Chris died for your sins."
Is that a joke?
Yeah, on me.
At's what happens when you
outsource to fucking malaya.
8-year-olds in a sweatshop
can't spell for shit.
I was trying to jump on board
the red-state-jesus thing...
the fashion of the christ.
I
upend with 3,000 of these.
Totally useless!
If there's one thing
about the christ crowd...
absolutely no
sense of humor.
I should have gone after
the jew market.
Leaat
we can take a joke.
Come on, shane.
Look who's here.
Baby, it's "the early bird
gets the worm," not the weed.
You need to read up
on your bartlett's.
My brother-in-law
took the kids to school,
i thought
i'd get a jump on the day.
You want some oatmeal?
No. Andy made
eggs florentine.
Andy?
When did that fancy-cooking
trouble get back in town?
This morning i woke up,
and there he was.
Mm. Sort of like crotch crabs
only not as treatable, huh?
I forgot you know him.
Been hoping
to forget him.
How did andy
adconrand meet?
I never got a straight answer
out of either of them.
They worked
at circuit city together,
got caught stealing together,
got fired together.
They go way back.
I never should have
let that boy work retail.
You gonna need
to come back later
'cause we ain't got in
everything yet.
I got 17 food orders
to fill.
Ooh! Listen
to betty cracker.
You got bunches
of that crap last time.
You out already?
I've got some, but not enough
for what i need.
My crowd loves
to eat their smoke.
I could hook you up
with a little schwag
if you're really crazy.
Oh, shit.
I've still got the gourmet
fuckup in my kitchen.
I'm never gonna
get anything done.
Oh, fuck. I'm fucked.
Ooh! You got a nasty mouth
when you're stressed.
You got a pen?
Yeah.
I'm gonna give you
a number,
and you say i said
it was okay for you to call.
Who am i calling?
The candyman.
[Laughs]
Wear sporty shoes.
"Megan89"
"Me too. Sore throat."
Bummer.
[Typing]
What are you wearing?
Take it off.
I tried
to spread the word.
I eat here every day,
invited people...
"oh, it's too ethnic."
"Oh, it's too spicy."
"Oh, those people
don't wash their hands."
What the fuck is wrong
with these morons
who wait an hour in line at some
fucking crappy olive garden
and let a treasure like this
go out of business?
I can't take it.
Doug,
why are we here?
Did you taste
the saag aloo?
It's to die for
and then be reincarnated
and to die for again.
Why aren't you eating?
I told you i ate already.
Where?
The olive garden.
I wouldn't take a dump
in the olive garden.
I like the hot
artichoke-spinach dip.
I can't even look at you.
Okay. Enough.
I'm sure the saag aloo
is delicious.
Wow, that's incredible.
Tell me this doesn't
kick your artichoke dip's ass.
Tell me more.
Are your nipples hard?
Come on.
"Like shooting stars."
Whew. "now you."
[Typing]
No, more you.
Are you touching yourself?
"I'm parting the lips
of my blushing vagina."
[Typing]
Yes. Good.
Ah. Oh.
Keep... typing.
Atwh do you think
about this place as the bakery?
I mean, location's pretty good,
kitchen's already set up,
and if you make something
mediocre enough,
you may even make a go
at it legitimately.
Let me think about it.
[Indian accent]
Here you go, mr. Wilson.
20 orders for you.
Let them cool before
you put them in the freezer.
Uh, mr. Advani,
where will you go?
Oh, we just bought an
olive garden franchise close by.
You must come visit.
Fuck agrestic.
Yes, sir. Okay.
Pay when you're ready.
When are my trea
coming in?
I'm having
a little trouble
getting my kitchen
to myself lately.
But i'll let you know.
Hey, lupita.
I was just thinking about you.
It for you.
Wipe your hands.
Podrido, asqueroso,
virgen perro.
Yeah, this is andy.
Awesome.
??????
Yeah. I'll bring the shirts.
Uh, let's say 15 minutes.
Okay.
B-oh, uh,
make it 20. okay.
Hey! Get your original
"chris died" t-shirts
right here. Yeah!
Only $10.
Have your money ready.
That's one-size-fits-all.
It's gonna shrink
a bit.
Oh, yeah.
Uh-huh.
Okay. That's you.
Uncle andy.
What? What? What?
Hang on.
Uncle andy.
Now, remember kids...
chris loves you, so...
what?! What?!
It's the principal.
Shit. We were
just heating up.
Excuse me.
Um, look, kids.
Chris has risen.
Wha... wal...
Have you all seen these?
They are all
over the schl. Oo
And as a christian, i must say
i am deeply, deeply offended.
It's profane.
Has anyone talked
to the principal about this?
Who's chris?
Where's celia? I bet
she'd have something to say.
It's 10 minutes after.
Maybe we should start.
Does anyone know how?
I think the first order of
business should be these shirts.
They're funny.
Excuse me?
I think you're making
way too big a deal about it.
It's a joke.
Oh, we do not joke
about r looujesus christ.
It's a stupid t-shirt.
Hould ignore it.
Only one man
died for my sins, nancy,
and his name wasn't chris.
Well, it sort of was,
wasn't it? Like a nickname?
If we make a big deal, it will
become a full-blown trend.
They're kids.
It'll become cool.
Ah, principal dodge,
have you seen these blasphemes?
Yes.
Are you gonna
do something about them?
I'm about to.
Mrs. Botwin, would you mind
coming into my office
to discuss your son's
t-shirt business?
Shane was selling them?
Yes. With some guy
in a van who sped off.
I'll never talk.
Hey. [laughs]
Hey, what do you
like better...
"jesus say relax,"
or "i'm too sexy for my lord"?
How about "asshole ditched
my 10-year-old"?
I admit it. I panicked.
That guy had a whistle.
They wanted
to suspend him.
For what?
If shane wants
to believe in chris
and they try
to suspend him for it...
whoa, that's freedom
of religion.
That's, like,
the first commandment.
We could nail them on that.
I don't think
"chris" is protected
under freedom
of religion, andy.
In fact, the angry christian
moms i heard from in the pta
were pretty offended
by it.
Well,
that's so intolerant.
I mean,
what would jesus do?
Religious bullshit aside,
you don't want to know
how far i had to crawl
up the principal's ass
just to keep you two
out of trouble.
Not to mention
the unbelievable amount
of shit i'm gonna get
from those hypo-christian
bitch moms tomorrow.
Hey, i was just trying to
pitch in, earn a little money.
I saw an opportunity to help
the family, and i took it.
Really? It was
for the family, huh?
Where's the money?
Don't worry. I'll use it
towards family expenses.
Hello.
I got to i did call. Thanks
my o for getting back to me.
Can you hold on
a second, please?
Go away.
I have to take this call.
Who is it?
None of your business.
Get out of here.
Why? You got a boyfriend?
Isn't it a little soon?
Maybe i should
take my vibrator back.
Fine, angry!
God, keep the vibrator.
Thanks for getting back
to me, um, candyman.
You're the candyman?
Yes. Are you
getting any exercise?
Excuse me?
If you're not committed
to personal fitness,
i can't in good conscience
sell to you.
I wouldn't say
heylia's in the best shape.
Heylia's a lazy fat-fat,
and i'm hoping to put her
into a diabetic coma,
so i have no problem
selling to her.
Why?
Scare her.
Some people never learn
until their life is on the line.
You know what you are?
What am i?
Skinny-fat.
And what are we
gonna do about that?
We're gonna start exercising
right away.
Don't humor me.
I'm very serious.
I used to weigh
314 pounds.
Wow! Congratulations.
The key... exercise.
You know, i'm not buying
for personal use.
Are your customers just a bunch
of fatty mcfat-fats?
Well, they're smokers.
But it stands to reason that
if they eat rather than smoke,
they should be able
to breath easier
should they decide
to exercise.
That's a reasonable
assumption.
And i hope you'll take it
upon yourself to encourage them.
Of course. And i'll take
everything you've got.
Really?
And?
And willi e
a greater effort to exercise
no, no, no, no, no.
And i will exercise.
Yes, you will!
[Laughing]
You dog.
Great. Dumb and dumber
reunited.
Oh, my man.
It's good to see you.
You smell really good.
Get the fuck off me.
What's wrong with you?
Can't a straight man
admire the stink
of another handsome,
straight man?
Not unless you're in prison.
Is that where you been?
Close... alaska.
What about you?
What you been up to?
Same old, same old.
Dealing, growing,
doing a little pilates.
No!
I love that shit, man.
It stretch you out.
It give you power,
make you feel good as hell.
Hot instructor.
Ass like a peach.
You just want to bite that shit.
Nice. Nice.
So, uh, conrad, man, can you
hook me up with a little?
[Laughs softly]
That's a lot of weed.
You got the money?
For that much?
I don't, uh...
great.
Lady saltine sends her little
errand boy but no scratch.
Nancy?
Yeah, she only paid
for the half order
she picked up
this morning.
And that's
the other half?
You got my money,
boy genius?
??????
Fucking kingpin.
What's so funny?
What? Oh, uh,
conrad does pilates.
Okay, where was i?
I'm surrounded.
You're surrounded
by the enemy.
The enemy edges in
closer, closer.
Then when they're just
inches away,
you invoke
the dong-hi defense.
What's that?
You protect your dong
and you swing
like your life depended on it.
Cool!
I need to talk to you,
you fucking perv.
All right.
Go practice that.
What are you talking about?
Did that loony from alaska call?
I'm talking about
what you did to megan today.
Who's megan?
Megan! My girlfriend.
You told her to take her clothes
off when she imed.
Oh! That megan.
Yeah, i did that for you, bro.
You should be
thanking me.
What?!
That girl really digs you.
No shit! She's my fucking
girlfriend!
But you haven't gotten
into her panties yet, have you?
It's none
of your business.
[Laughs]
You know why?
You're afraid to make moves
'cause she's all
handicapped and shit.
That what
you need to learn.
You got to treat them
like everybody else,
and then they pop right open
like a can of pringles.
So...
so... she's ready, man.
You got to go for it.
You gonna
see her tonight?
Yeah.
Well?
Silas, check me out!
You better be right.
Trust me, man.
She's good to go.
Hey, pants.
Please tell me
i didn't hear
that you had cybersex
with a 15-year-old deaf girl.
Absolu not.
I want you out tonight.
Really? 'cause, you know,
i was just cooking dinner.
I want you out now.
I got some
really great recipes
over at my friend conrad's joint
earlier today...
uh, pot roast,
corned-beef hash.
Tonight, i'm gonna galiao it
with a little kedba ziti,
and a big plate of spaghetti
marijuana... uh, i mean...
you sneaky piece of shit.
Oh! Come now,
nancy pants.
Isn't that the pot
calling the kettle black?
What did you do?
Well, i [laughs]
I went to my friend conrad's
to catch up on old times.
You remember conrad?
He's a pot dealer.
He's the one
you're supposed to call
if you ever need
a little puff.
And much to my surprise,
i was handed
a giant bag of weed
and told it was for you.
Where's my stuff?
So i thought, "wow, either
nancy's got a big problem,
or nancy's got
lot a friends."
You've been [laughs]
You've been making friends?
Where's my stuff?!
Don't worry. It's safe.
"Don't worry."
Everything you touch
turns to shit.
I'm family.
We'll work it out.
I really want you
to leave.
Look. The way i see it
is you're in way over
your head here, you know?
You got a house,
you got bills, you're a mommy.
Dealing is
a full-time job.
You need some help,
nancy pants.
Don't call me pants.
Judah called me pants,
t yono
hey, i miss him,
too, nancy.
Whatever you think about me,
judah was my brother,
and i loved him.
And i have your back.
Now, i'm gonna go inside,
and i'm gonna finish
cookdinner for the family.
I'm making stoned crab.
Sorry, i had to get that out.
I was working on them
all the way home.
Hey.
You look hot
in that leotard.
* with the same eyes as me *
* the same fearing frame *
* we can try and disguise
compromise rights *
* and i know
what you're thinking *
* we wear the same dress *
*he s tcolors right *
* is this what suits
our weakened pride? *
* how do i know
'cause you're my blood *
* my blood *
* hey! *
* with the kinks and wires
like me *
* the same fearing frame *
* we can run and hide *
* see the signs call to no one *
* taste with the same tongue *
* swelling up inside *
* we can speak and re-sign
what's yours is mine *
* blood *
* my blood *
* hey! *
* blood *
* my blood *
I have cance
r. * townfolk say
that times are hard *
* i just say, "oh, my lord" *
* coffee's cold *
* and i've been sold
for half a dollar bill *
* every seed that i do sow *
* harvest time,
nothing's grown *
* coffee's cold *
* and i've been sold
for half a dollar bill *
- captions by vitac...
www.vitac.com