[♫ Glenn Frey: The Heat Is On]
Truck looks great.
There must be a fuckin' fortune here.
I know...
Let's not in front of him, alright?
OK, no problem, no problem.
Tell me somethin', fellas,
what's goin' on? Shit.
I been here too long. Talk to me.
Just give us a minute.
I ain't got no more minutes. Check
this out. I want you to see somethin'.
You can't get no cleaner than this.
These are very popular with children.
You know what this is in here?
A federal tax stamp.
You can't get no cleaner than that!
Talk to me! Tell me somethin'.
So go into business yourself
if it's such a great fuckin' deal.
I would, but I ain't from Detroit.
I don't even know nobody in town
that can handle a job this big,
but you all got
all the connections, you know.
Tell me somethin', shit,
I'm a businessman.
- Do what you wanna do.
- It ain't easy to get rid of this shit.
I know, but I'm a businessman,
this is my thing.
I'm doin' business here.
Warm up the truck.
Let's get the fuck outta here.
- That's what I'm talkin' about.
- You're a sharp kid, I like you.
Thank you very much.
I appreciate it.
Cousin, my man, don't dash yet.
This is like two grand to me.
- This doesn't look like $5, 000.
- Let me see that.
The deal's for 5, 000.
That's about 2, 000. Count it yourself.
You know what, this pisses me off.
I told my people it was
supposed to be five grand here,
and look at this shit, they stiffed us.
No, they stiffed you,
'cause I want my money, man.
Son of a bitch, you can't
count on anybody today,
but I tell you what, let's not
fuckin' hassle about it now.
Take the two fucking grand
and on the next score,
I promise I'll make it up to you.
Look, don't jerk me off, all right?
Jerk somebody else off,
this is bullshit.
I need $5,000 dollars,
not 2,000 thing, don't do this to me.
Don't be unreasonable.
You're not dealin' with Johnny Bananas.
- I got you covered.
- I got no idea what Johnny Banana,
but can I have my money...
Look, can I say it slow for you.
I need five thousand dollars!
Read my lips:
Five thousand dollars, is what I need.
This is bullshit here.
I can't do nothin' with that.
If you want to be a fuckin' asshole,
you can take the whole load
and smoke 'em yourself in the park.
- I don't smoke Lucky Strike.
- I got people I gotta answer to.
- I smoke King Size Kent.
- I can't make a price of my...
[siren blares]
Fuck this.
Nice doin' business with you, kid.
Hey, buddy, what you doin' here?
Officers, do you know
what just happened?
You ain't gonna believe this shit.
The truck, it just stopped, man!
It just stopped! You got some
jumper cables, you give me a jump?
Hey... don't I know you
from someplace?
No, that ain't me, I'm from Buffalo.
Both you guys, break out some ID.
Let's get the fuck outta here!
[engine roaring]
[♫ Pointer Sisters: Neutron Dance]
[siren wailing]
Shit! What the fuck?
[cackling]
Oh, shit.
[man] Freeze, asshole!
Foley, we should've known it was you.
[chuckles]
[phones ringing]
Hey, Axel, way to go!
- I don't understand.
- I don't have time, Jeffrey.
Todd's lookin' for you,
he's really pissed.
He said this is your
worst fuck-up ever.
Personally, I don't think that's true.
He's not in there.
Yeah, I can see that, Jeff.
If you'd busted these guys,
maybe he wouldn't have been so mad.
Now I heard you got caught up
haggling for money?
$2,000 wasn't enough money.
If I took it, those guys
woulda known I was a cop.
- Todd's gonna tear you another asshole.
- Don't go anywhere.
I'm not sayin'
you did anything wrong.
If you had busted these guys
it would've worked out better.
That's all I'm sayin'.
Where you goin' now?
I'm gonna go get my shit
and get outta here.
No, big mistake, big mistake.
- Want my advice?
- No.
- You know what I would do?
- No, I don't.
Talk to him.
He'll be right back.
Get away from me or I'm gonna
shoot you. No time for you today.
You know what I would do?
Just lighten up. I'm not listening
to you. I'm not listening.
You're makin' it a lot worse
for yourself.
- [applause, cheering]
- This is great, thank you guys.
Hey, Axel, you got a cigarette?
[sarcastic laugh]
- Did you write that one?
- That's what I'm tryin' to tell you.
Everybody knows
about you and the truck.
Jeffrey, will you listen to me?
I am not listening to you,
I'm ignoring you.
- La-la-la-la-la-la-la!
- Great! Great, real mature.
I am not listening to Jeffrey,
but he's still talking.
- I am not listening to you!
- I really hate when you do that.
- Then stop then.
- It's childish!
- [man] ls that fuckin' Foley in here?
- Oh, shit.
There's Todd, it's show time, OK?
[Axel] I know what you're gonna say...
Where the fuck you come off
goin' undercover without authorization?
What the fuck is this all about?
You wanna play some
fuckin' bullshit cowboy cop,
go do it in somebody else's precinct.
Don't you want to hear
my side of the story?
What's your fuckin' side of the story?
Let's hear your side of the story.
Axel, I'm not takin'
any more of this shit from you.
You know how much this little stunt
is gonna cost this city?
I don't think cost
is the issue here, sir.
I think the issue should be my
blatant disregard for proper procedure.
You damn right, wise-ass!
The mayor called the chief.
The chief called the deputy chief.
The deputy chief just
chewed my ass out!
You see I don't have
any bit of it left, don't you!
Where in the fuck did you get a
truckload of cigarettes from anyway?
From the Dearborn hijack.
The Dearborn hijack?
That bust went down last week.
That truck is supposed to be
in the damn pound!
I tried to tell you.
Jeffrey, this is none
of your fuckin' business.
This is not my locker.
Listen, Axel, no more
of these setups, you understand?
You're a good cop.
You got great potential,
but you don't know every fuckin' thing.
And I'm tired
of takin' the heat for your ass.
One more time
and you're out on the street.
- Do you understand me?
- Let me tell you...
Do you understand me?
Yeah, I understand.
Boss.
The chief ain't chew it all out,
you still got a little ass there.
Don't fuck with me, Axel.
Not now. Go on, go home.
[faint clattering]
Hey!
Hey, man!
- How you doin'?!
- All right.
I see you're still breakin'
in people's houses.
What'd you expect with that lock?
Why didn't you buy a real fuckin' lock?
I don't need no lock, I got my pistol.
I pop a cap in somebody.
I can't afford no electrical bill.
Close my refrigerator.
You got groceries
and shit all inside there.
- Look at you!
- Yeah.
- Yo, man, when you'd get out?
- I walked out six months ago.
You got out six months ago,
and you're just comin' now?
They got me out a year early for,
you know, good time,
and I went out to California
to get some sun.
- I got to show you somethin'.
- I ain't seen you in two years.
Ten thousand Deutsche Marks.
- Deutsche Mark?
- Yeah.
What is that?
They're bearer bonds.
They're bonds. Untraceable.
You stole 'em?
- No. It's not...
- I don't wanna hear it.
I'm sorry I even asked.
- It's just good to see you, man.
- I missed you, man.
- Yeah.
- I missed you.
What were you doin'
in California, anyway'?
- [man] I was workin'.
- Workin' where?
- Guess.
- I don't know, where were you workin'?
- Beverly Hills.
- [laughs]
- What were you doin'?
- You ain't gonna believe this man.
- What?
- I was a security guard.
[♫ Patti LaBelle: New Attitude]
Who the fuck's gonna hire you
as a security guard?
Jenny Summers.
Jenny Summers?!
Oh, man, I haven't seen Jenny
in years! What she up to?
Axel, she's doin' great, right?
She's the manager of this art gallery,
the Hollis Benton Art Gallery
out in Beverly Hills.
It's like a world famous place.
You ever hear of it?
Yeah, I buy all of my art there.
Eight ball, corner pocket,
two cushions.
Fifty bucks you don't make that shot.
- Bullshit.
- A hundred.
You got a bet.
What are you gonna do.
You're just as bright
as you always were.
Twenty, 40, 60, 80, take it.
Have a party.
Pleasure doin' business with you.
[♫ Junior:
Do You Really (Want My Love?)]
What the fuck you gonna do?
[man] Miss, excuse me,
two more Scotch and sodas.
I got a great idea.
I got a great idea!
Let's steal a car.
[laughing]
Are you serious?
I'm a fuckin' police officer,
I can't steal cars no more.
- What's wrong with you?
- So what?
Remember the time
you stole that car, man?
A fuckin' Cadillac.
We had to go and drive it
on the expressway.
You fucking maniac.
I also remember you had to go to jail
behind that shit, too.
That wasn't a jail,
it was a state school.
State school is jail
when you're 15 years old.
Not jail, man, that's like...
That's like day camp compared to jail.
How come you didn't tell on me
when you got caught?
- You didn't tell we were together?
- You don't know?
- No.
It's because I love you, man.
Ah! One more round.
[both laughing]
Hold still, Mike.
I gotta open the door, OK?
Balance yourself.
OK, here we go.
I'm openin' the door now, OK?
Here we go. All right, here we go.
Axel!
[shouting]
Hey, Mikey. Where've you been?
What's up, Zack?
What do you got there, Mikey?
Yeah, what's this, your laundry?
I swear to Christ, Zack,
I was gonna bring 'em back.
- Oh, you get lost?
- No.
I came... I came here to see
my friend, I had 'em with me.
I figured, you know...
What are you doing?
What am I supposed to do here, Mikey?
Zack, there was a whole box
full of those things there,
I took a couple of 'em. I didn't
think anybody was gonna miss 'em.
I figured I'd take 'em...
- Shut up.
- I'm sorry.
- No, shut up.
- Man, please.
- Just shut up, Mikey.
I swear...
[chuckles]
I swear, if you ever
show your face out there again...
- I won't.
- Ever.
- I won't, I promise you.
- Ever!
Man, I'm sorry.
I fucked up, I'm sorry.
- OK.
- I'm sorry.
- Ever. All right.
[grunts]
[gunshots]
[police sirens]
[indistinct radio chatter]
Axel... I thought I told you
to go to the hospital
and get that bump
on your head checked out.
- My head is all right, man.
- It's not a request, Axel.
Boss. Boss.
Can I talk to you for a minute? Look...
I heard a rumor that you're
gonna use Rand on this case,
and between the two of us,
the guy doesn't know the time of day.
Don't mess with me now, Axel.
This is the first time he's
left his desk in 12 years.
At least he's had 12 years.
Anyway, it's a homicide case
and it belongs to Rand.
Now, go to the hospital!
Well, you don't mind if I
ask around a little bit, do you?
Don't do a damn thing!
It's Rand's case.
Your ass is skating
on thin ice as it is.
Hey, look, we're talkin'
about a friend of mine here!
Yes, we are, aren't we?
Now, let's take a close look at that.
One, a hoodlum friend.
Two, a professional hit.
Three, in a cop's apartment.
This whole thing stinks to high heaven.
How you know
it was a professional hit?
I didn't just walk into this town
from the cotton fields!
Whoever killed your friend wasn't
worried about your little narrow ass.
If they were, you'd be lyin'
beside him in that meat wagon.
Just don't do a damn thing.
Stay outta this!
Look, I got some
vacation time comin' to me.
I wanna take my vacation now.
Stay away from this case, Axel.
No, it's just that I feel I need
a little vacation, that's all.
All right, as soon as you're finished
at the hospital, you're on vacation.
Thank you.
But if you decide
to butt into this case,
it'll be the longest vacation
you ever heard of.
[♫ Patti LaBelle: Stir It Up]
[laughing]
Checking in today, sir?
That depends,
is this hotel real expensive?
Not for Beverly Hills.
Can I get your bags for you?
Yeah, that's my bag in the front seat.
I'm sorry, sir, we just have
nothing available tonight.
May I suggest next time
you call for a reservation
you do it at least a week in advance?
Thank you.
- Hi.
- The nerve of some people, huh?
May I help you?
Yes, you have a reservation
for an Axel Foley.
Well, let's see.
I'm sorry, I don't see anything
under that name.
Oh, check Rolling Stone Magazine's
Axel Foley.
That's what it is. [chuckles]
OK.
No, no Rolling Stone, no Axel Foley.
- I'm sorry, sir.
- That's all right.
You guys just probably just
made some mistake with reservations.
Just give me another room,
and I'll go up and go to sleep.
I'm sorry, sir,
but there are no rooms available.
Don't you think I realize
what's going on here, miss?
Who do you think I am?
Don't you think I know if I was some
hot-shot from outta town
that pulled inside here and you guys
made a reservation mistake,
I'd be the first one to get a room,
and I'd be upstairs relaxing right now!
Well, I'm not some
hot-shot from outta town,
I'm a small reporter from
Rolling Stone Magazine,
that's in town to do an exclusive
interview with Michael Jackson
that's gonna be picked up by every
major magazine in the country!
I was gonna call the article "Michael
Jackson ls Sitting On Top Of The World,"
but now I think I
might well just call it,
"Michael Jackson
Can Sit on Top of the World
Just As Long As He Doesn't
Sit in the Beverly Palm Hotel
Because There's No Niggers
Allowed in There!"
Excuse me, sir, it seems that we
do have a last-minute cancellation.
Uh, there is a room available.
It's a suite, but...
I'll only charge
you the single room rate.
Thank you, I'm sorry I got upset.
It's probably from jet lag.
- I'm very tired.
- I understand.
- What's the rate, anyway'?
- That'll be 235 dollars a night, sir.
Fine. Fine.
And that'll be suite 1035.
- Thank you very much.
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
- Here you go.
If Michael calls,
tell him what room I'm in.
Of course, sir.
[♫ Patti LaBelle: Stir It Up]
[laughing]
[chuckling]
- [man] How you are doing today?
- Hi.
I'm fine, my name is Serge,
and how can I help you?
Uh, yeah, I'm looking
for Miss Jenny Summers.
She's very busy today.
Maybe you give me your name.
- My name's Axel Foley.
- And what it's pertaining?
I didn't understand what you said.
Pertaining...
What it's meaning... regarding?
Oh, what's it regarding?
I'm an old acquaintance of hers.
Donny. One moment.
Donny, run and tell Ms. Summers
that Mr. Achmed Foley to see her.
- No, Axel Foley. Axel.
- Achmel, Achwel?
Axel.
Foley's here to see her.
He's a old acquaintance.
- Donny, this is... Cover this up.
- I'm sorry.
Like a breast of a dog
to scrub for the customer.
- It's not sexy. It's animal.
- No, it's not sexy at all.
May I offer you something to drink?
Wine, a cocktail...
- Espresso?
- No, I'm fine, thank you.
I make it myself back there
with the little lemon twist.
- It's good. You should try it.
- No, I'm... I'm fine.
I see you look at this piece.
Yeah, I was wondering how much
something like this went for.
One hundred and thirty thousand dollar.
- Get the fuck outta here!
- No! No, I cannot.
It's serious, because
it's very important piece.
- Have you ever sold one of these?
- Sell it yesterday to a collector.
- Get the fuck outta here!
- No, I'm serious! I sell it myself.
Axel Foley, what on earth
are you doing here?
How you doin'?
I'm fine! Hold a second,
I'll be right down.
Great, excuse me, Serge.
- What are you doing here?
- [Axel] How you doin'?
- Oh, God, it's good to see you.
- Same here.
- How have you been?
- I been... Look at you!
- You like?
- Yes!
- Is it good?
- You gettin' old.
- Fuck you.
- [both laugh]
- What is this?
- A moustache.
- Peach fuzz.
- No, that's man style now.
[laughing]
You have some place
where we can talk real quick?
Well, yeah. Right over there.
- Great.
- Come on.
- I can't believe how you filled out.
- Yeah, I filled out.
No, it looks good though.
Sit down.
I wanna talk to you about Mikey.
Oh, is he in trouble again?
He's dead.
What?
He's dead. He came to Detroit
and somebody killed him.
- I don't believe this.
- [phone ringing]
Look, I can't right now.
I'll be up in a second.
Mikey mentioned that you
helped him get a job.
Yeah...
The guy who owns this gallery
hired him as a favor to me.
Who's this guy?
His name is Victor Maitland.
He was working for Victor
at the gallery's warehouse.
Look, Axel, I can't talk right now,
I have to go upstairs.
That's cool.
I'll call you later on, and we'll
get together later and talk, OK?
Sure.
Be good.
- Hi.
- Oh, hi.
- I have a delivery for Victor Maitland.
- I'll take it right upstairs to him.
Maybe I should give it to him myself.
Well, deliveries are
supposed to be left on my desk.
Yeah, but he has to get
these flowers, it's imperative.
I'm gonna go up myself, all right?
- You're not really supposed to go up.
- Floral delivery is my life.
I have to take it up. Thank you.
- Who let you in here?
- I let myself in.
How you doin'?
I have to ask you some questions
about Michael Tandino.
[Victor] Speak to you later, darling.
And what, may I ask,
is your interest in Mr. Tandino?
He was my best friend.
He came to see me in Detroit
a couple of days ago.
And a couple of hours after he
got there, someone killed him.
Oh, my God! That's terrible!
It's fucked up.
And? What do you wish to know?
He worked for you, didn't he?
Yes, yes, he did. Good gracious.
I'm really sorry to hear this.
Would you like to sit down?
Can I get you anything?
No, I'm all right.
Well, how on earth did this happen?
Detroit is a very violent city,
isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
Well, I do hope the police
have procured some intelligent leads.
Exactly what was it
Mikey did for you here?
I'm sorry, I didn't catch your name.
My name is Foley.
Well, excuse me, Mr. Foley,
if I appear a little rude,
but this sounds like something
for the authorities in Detroit.
So, if you'll forgive me,
I really must get back to work.
Look, all I want to know is what kind...
Gentlemen, would you please
show Mr. Foley to the door?
- Get the fuck off me.
- Hey, take it easy.
Yo, man, get the fuck off me.
Get off me, man! Get off me!
- Get the fuck off me! Get off!
- [door slams]
- [elevator dings]
- [Axel] Get the fuck off me, man.
Get off me!
Get the fuck off me!
You think I'm playin' games, man? Hey!
I'm fuckin' somebody up.
Hey!
- What the fuck is this shit?
- [police siren approaching]
Did you see that shit?
I can describe all of them.
Please move to the side of the car
and put your hands on the hood.
Why, what's with you guys?
You heard what he said, sir.
Do it right now, please.
What kind of shit is this, man?
Hold up, wait a second.
You guys are arrestin' me for gettin'
thrown out of a fuckin' window?!
I got thrown out of a window, man!
Gun, partner!
Sir, you are under arrest.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can, and will be
used against you in a court of law.
You have the right to have an attorney
present during questioning.
Yeah, I understand.
I understand the rights.
I know this is bullshit though.
I got thrown out of a fuckin' window!
- Please get in the car, sir.
- Tell me somethin', what's the charge?
Possession of a concealed weapon,
disturbing the peace.
Disturbing the peace?
I got thrown out of a window!
What's the fuckin' charge for gettin'
pushed out of a movin' car, huh?
Jaywalking'? This is bullshit!
You know, this is the cleanest
and nicest police car
I've ever been in in my life.
This thing's nicer than my apartment.
[Axel] Officers, if we see any like...
movie stars, could y'all stop
and point them out,
I never seen no shit like that.
- That's enough talkin', pal.
- OK, that's cool.
This is nice.
Well, it's about time.
Thought you forgot I was down here.
I was gettin' hungry.
I never been in no cell
that had a phone in it.
Can I stay for awhile,
'cause I ordered some pizza?
Somebody'd eat it.
[indistinct chatter]
Have a seat right over there, please.
I'm Sergeant Taggart and this is
my partner, Detective Rosewood.
You always treat visitors
from out of town like this?
Why didn't you identify yourself as a
police officer when you were arrested?
'Cause I was mindin' my own business.
Where the fuck do you guys get off
arrestin' somebody for gettin'
thrown out of a window?
We have six witnesses
that say you broke in
and started tearin' up the place,
then jumped out the window!
And you guys believed that? What
the fuck are you, cops or doormen?
We're more likely to believe
an important local businessman,
than a foul-mouthed jerk
from out of town!
Foul-mouthed? Fuck you, man.
- Hey, Sarg.
- You watch your mouth.
Don't square off on me
with some bullshit.
- You want to start some static?
- Don't push me!
- Fuck you, man.
- [grunts]
Ta
Yes, sir?
Come here.
[indistinct murmuring]
Sir...
I apologize for striking you.
I have no excuse.
Forget about it.
Detective Foley, I'm Lieutenant Bogomil,
of the Beverly Hills Police Department.
Do you wish to file charges
against Sergeant Taggart?
This is some kind of joke, right?
Do you wish to file charges
against this officer for assault?
Look, where I'm from, cops don't
file charges against other cops.
No, I don't wanna do that.
Well, in Beverly Hills,
we go strictly by the book.
Now, why didn't you inform us
when you came to town?
- I'm on vacation.
- Well, if you're on vacation,
what business did you have
in Victor Maitland's office?
I had to go to the bathroom.
I was walkin' by, it looked like
a nice clean place, so I stopped.
You always take your gun on vacation?
I don't know,
I never been on vacation before.
But in Detroit, cops are required
to carry a firearm at all times.
Well, if you wanna carry a gun,
I suggest you go back there.
I really can't wait to get back there,
if you wanna know the truth.
Is that so?
I just got off the phone
with an Inspector Todd in Detroit.
Does that name ring a bell?
He's my boss.
He tells me you might not
be very welcome back there.
He says that you're
an outstanding young detective.
I find that very difficult to believe.
But it's true, though.
He also says they nearly had
to fire you for insubordination.
I find that very easy to believe.
Now, what are you doing
in Beverly Hills?
I told you, I'm on vacation.
I went to the bathroom,
the next thing I knew six guys
threw me out a window.
Inspector Todd gave me
a message for you, wanna hear it?
I don't think so.
He says if you're out here
investigating the Tandino murder,
you needn't bother coming back.
He tells me that if we inform him
you are working on this case,
he'll have you brought up
on charges and fired.
Now, one last time,
what are you doing...
- I'm on vacation!
- Vacation! Vacation.
Rosewood, take Mr. Foley over to the
courthouse and let him arrange for bail.
Would you follow me, sir?
You know, I gotta hand it to you guys,
if anything you are extremely polite.
Pretty good punch
you got there, Taggart.
[Axel] After you.
After you.
You guys are so sweet, you know that?
Thanks for bailin' me out, Jen.
If I'd known why you'd been arrested,
I wouldn't have come.
[chuckling] Oh, you don't mean that.
No, I don't mean that.
Axel, if it wasn't for Victor Maitland,
I'd be waiting on tables!
It just so happens
that the day Mikey got killed,
he showed up at my apartment
with a bag of German bearer bonds.
I think he stole 'em
from whoever had him killed.
When I mentioned Mikey's name,
Maitland went nuts
and had me thrown out.
Axel, you look like a hoodlum.
You go barging into his office
without an appointment.
You're carrying a gun.
If you barged into my office and
I didn't know you, I'd throw you out.
Is this your car?
Oh, no, in Beverly Hills we just
take whichever car's closest.
I remember you used to drive
that crappy, blue Chevy Nova.
What are you driving now?
- The same crappy, blue Chevy Nova.
- [laughing]
You think it's too late
for me to study art?
Yeah, I do.
Axel, why were you bothering Victor?
You don't think he has anything to do
with Mikey getting killed?
Oh, no. No, I was just pokin' around
I don't think he did nothin'.
Axel, Victor Maitland
is one of the top art dealers
in the United States.
He has been for ten years.
I'm impressed.
- What are you looking back there for?
- The cops, they're following us.
What? Where?
In the back on the right.
The beige Ford.
Can you believe this place?
Axel, how can you afford this?
They're only charging me
the single room rate.
How can you afford that?
Actually I can't afford it. But you know
what they got inside that bathroom?
They got little robes,
with little initials of the hotel on it.
I love this place,
I can't leave this shit.
I'm gonna steal one of them robes.
- You want one?
- No, thanks.
- You want slippers?
- No.
I'm gonna steal them, too.
You should take some of this shit.
Excuse me two seconds.
Hello, room service?
Yes, this is Mr. Axel Foley
in suite 1035. Yeah.
I'd like to order something
from your late supper menu.
But listen, I want you to deliver it to
this beige Ford parked out on Wilshire.
Send down one
bay shrimp salad sandwich, OK?
Right, and is the cold poached
salmon in dill sauce tasty?
OK, send one of those down, all right?
And send down something for dessert.
Thank you very much.
All right, thank you.
You're quite a sport.
How long are you gonna stay?
I'm gonna be in town
until I find out who killed Mikey.
And I'm very seriously considering
going down to that warehouse
where he worked
and checkin' that place out.
Oh, really?
And how are you planning on getting in?
[both chuckling]
- Good evening, sir.
- What the hell is that?
It's late supper, sir,
compliments of Axel Foley.
Foley? How did he know we were here?
'Cause I let you drive.
I need a couple bananas,
how much are they?
Well, the buffet plate is $12.50.
You get peaches, plums,
oranges and bananas.
All I need is a couple of bananas.
Shh. Go ahead, take those bananas.
Thanks.
Forget it, I'm not eatin' that.
Take it back.
- [man] Certainly, sir.
- This really looks great.
Can I get some extra mayo?
- Certainly, sir.
- Thank you.
- [Axel] Ready to go?
' [Jenny] Yeah.
There's the Mercedes.
Will you get rid of that stuff?
[car sputters, stalls]
[Taggart] What the hell are you doing?
[engine turning over]
This the place?
Yeah, but I'm still not sure
I should do this.
OK, you don't have to do anything.
But when you hear glass
and shit breaking,
don't get scared, it's just me
kickin' in the window. Sit tight.
[Jenny laughing]
All right, come on, Axel.
What's happenin', baby?
[laughing] Axel, grow up.
[sniffs]
- You find something?
- Coffee grounds.
$0'?
You know what this stuff is used for?
Yes, some people filter hot water
through it and drink it.
Yeah, I'm gonna take this home
and filter hot water through it
and drink it in the mornin'.
- [laughs]
- [mimics laugh]
[both laughing]
- [whispers] What are we hiding for?
- Shh.
I tell you, I wish you'd been
with me last night.
[man] What happened?
[man 2] I stopped at a joint on the way
home to have a couple of drinks.
- [man] Yeah. Which one?
- [man 2] One of the local joints.
This guy comes in, he sits down
a couple of stools away.
He's got one of them eyes
that's goin' like this.
I didn't know if he was tryin'
to put the make on me, or what.
So I thought I'd take you
over there tonight.
Let him have a little shot at you
before I tore his head off.
[sighs] Come on, let's go,
I wanna get outta here.
Why don't you get off my back.
Come on.
I got it.
- Axel, what the hell's going on?
- I'll tell you later, come on.
- Hurry up
- "Hurry up
- Gimme the key, I'm gonna follow 'em.
- You ever driven a Mercedes before?
No, but a car is a car.
I drive my car everyday.
I'm driving, I've seen your car.
Oh, shit, that's cold.
[car starts]
[brakes squeal]
A banana in your tailpipe!
How could you not notice a man
sticking a banana in your tailpipe?
- He distracted us, sir.
- And how'd he do that?
He sent us a late supper, sir.
See, this waiter comes over...
Billy, he gets the point.
A late supper.
And what did you have, Rosewood?
I think it was a shrimp
salad sandwich, sir.
- A shrimp salad sandwich.
- Yes, sir.
I want you two to go back to the hotel
and wait for Foley to show up.
And if you lose him again,
don't bother calling in. You got that?
- Yes, sir.
"A late supper."
We've got something for you, Billy.
An anti-banana disguise.
It may come in handy.
A little extra protection, Billy.
[chuckling]
Very funny.
[sighs] Come on, Billy, let's go.
Why don't you take the car
and go on home?
- Well, what about you?
- I wanna find out what this place is.
[Jenny] Oh, I can tell you that.
It's a bonded warehouse.
They hold our foreign shipments here
until they clear Customs.
Well, I'm gonna go check it out.
Just take the car and go home, OK?
Damn it, Axel!
I'm not gonna bail you out again.
Go home.
How you doin'? Could you come here
for a second, please?
- Hi, do you have a match?
- There's no smoking in here.
I'm not gonna smoke now,
I'm gonna smoke when I go outside.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
- Is your supervisor here?
- Yeah, he's in the office.
- Can you get him for me?
- What's the problem?
- You security here?
- Yeah.
Then you're the fuokin' problem,
go get your supervisor, please. Now!
- Now!
- OK.
He didn't come back yet.
[sighs]
Well, what do we do now?
We wait.
OK.
- Can I help you'?
- Are you the supervisor here?
Yes, who are you?
I'm Inspector Rafferty,
United States Customs Service.
Has all this stuff
passed through Customs already?
No, this is the bonded area.
Then tell me something.
Answer a question.
How can a black man, dressed like me,
just march into your warehouse,
walk into the bonded area
and start poking around
without anyone askin' me
any questions whatsoever?
Well, I don't know.
Thank you, that's the answer
I was lookin' for.
Just give me your ID numbers,
'cause somebody's gonna lose their job.
This guy gave me a match,
for Christ's sake.
You gave him a match?
Listen to me. I do security checks
all over the nation,
and with the exception of Cleveland,
this place has the worst security
in the nation!
I suggest you call your wives,
'cause we're gonna be here all night.
We're gonna check the background
of each and every crate in this section,
starting with this one, right here!
Wow.
You know, it says here that by the
time the average American is 50,
he's got five pounds
of undigested red meat in his bowels.
Why are you telling me this?
What makes you think
I have any interest in that at all?
Well, you eat a lot of red meat.
Now, the inspector needs
all the information
- on those airway bill numbers.
- All the manifests, too.
That's right, and he needs
the records of all shipments
- due into the same destination.
- Right.
- What's this all about?
- Just do it!
You got some kind of warrant for this?
You know, you have a very big mouth.
Are you hiding something from me?
I bet that's your Porsche that's parked
outside. Isn't that your Porsche?
How would you like for me
to have the IRS come down here
and crawl up your fuckin' ass with
a microscope? 'Cause they'll do it!
I've seen 'em do it!
It's not a pretty sight!
I want you to know somethin', pal.
I want all y'all to know somethin'.
I can have 25 agents down here
in 15 minutes,
to march in here,
snatch up bonds from underneath you
and you guys'll be
out of business permanently
if I don't get some cooperation!
Is that understood?
Don't get upset, we'll give
you everything you need. Right, guys?
- Everything you need.
- That's not my Porsche.
- I don't know whose it is.
- You ain't got nothin' to worry about.
I don't know what you all think I am,
take me for some kind of fool.
Hurry up! Quicker!
You know, I noticed you've been
drinking a lot of coffee lately.
Well, I think that's why you
have a hard time relaxing.
[car door shuts]
Ha-ha-haa!
Jesus Christ!
You almost gave me a heart attack.
What are you guys doin' here so late?
You're a cocky son of a bitch,
aren't you?
Look, if you're still mad about
the banana thing, I'm sorry.
- Just needed a little time to myself.
- Yeah.
Just wish I would've saw the expression
on your face when the car konked out.
Yeah, very funny.
Lieutenant docked us two days' pay.
Get outta here!
- He's not kidding.
- No, he's not kidding.
By the way, thanks for the sandwich.
He meant it as a joke, Billy,
like the bananas.
[Axel] Hey, wait a minute.
I'm a fellow police officer, I know
what it's like to be on a stakeout.
When I sent that food down,
that was from the heart.
Bullshit!
Why are we always arguing, man?
All three of us are cops,
we should be workin' together.
We all had a very rough day today.
What do you say,
we all go get something to drink
and make up and be friends, huh?
Forget it.
OK, fuck it. I'm gonna
get somethin' to drink, all right?
You guys can try to follow me
if you want to do that,
but I lost y'all once today,
which means I can do this shit again.
Why don't we just go get
somethin' to drink together?
- Let's be friends.
- We don't drink on duty.
OK, fine, all right, but listen to me.
I found the perfect place.
I saw it on the way over here.
It's perfect for you guys.
You can go, it's very conservative
and you guys'll love it.
Don't worry, it's nice. Trust me.
[♫ Vanity 6: Nasty Girl]
[woman] Hi, can I get you something?
Yes! I'm havin' a great time.
Can I have a Scotch and soda?
And the brothers... What y'all want,
like, light beers for the fellas.
Two club sodas.
You guys crack me up,
with this "on duty" shit.
Billy! Billy.
You don't have to be embarrassed
if your dick gets hard.
It's a dick, it's supposed to get hard.
That's the whole object of this.
Taggart's dick gets hard, but he won't
let you know, 'cause he's the boss.
Boss's dick got to stay limp, right?
I ain't on duty, so my dick can be hard.
[chuckling] Hey, Taggart, look.
Check that out, I found that
at Maitland's warehouse.
Billy! Bill, here, give her this.
Really, stuff that inside her
little thing and she'll go nuts.
Excuse me.
[Taggart] Billy!
- What do you think?
- Coffee grounds.
- Yeah!
- So?
You guys don't know nothin'
about nothin', do you?
Just got your badges and your guns
and you're on the job, right?
Make sure we get the right drinks.
If I drink club soda, I'll throw up.
Thank you so much.
Thank you very much.
- I think she likes you.
- Think so?
- There's no doubt in my mind.
- [clears throat]
Taggart, see that guy
over there in the black coat?
Black jacket?
- Yeah?
- Well, it's June.
Don't you think it's kind of hot
for a long, black leather coat?
Yeah, a little bit.
Yeah. Look at his partner over there.
They just came in together.
Somethin's gettin' ready to go down.
Why don't you go over there
and cover that guy for me, all right?
[Rosewood] What's going on?
I'm gonna go check out
this asshole at the bar.
Billy over here
is gonna make sure that I behave.
Will somebody tell me what's going on?
No bullshit this time.
Just Sit tight, Billy.
[mimicking drunkenness] Philip!
Hey, man, what's happenin', Phil?
I knew that was you!
He told me it wasn't.
Said you don't come here no more,
but I said, "it's Phil!"
- Get outta here, man.
- I told you it's Philip, you liar!
Hey, Philip, gimme kiss, baby!
- I said get the hell out of here!
- Hew
[music stops abruptly]
Everybody, freeze!
Turn around. Turn around!
- Phil!
- [man] Get your hands on the table!
Phil! What's wrong, man?
What's all the hostility?
- Get back, man.
- What you doin' with all this gun, man?
- I told you to get back.
- You changed, man!
If you don't get back,
I'm gonna blow your fuckin' brains out!
Police, move and I'll kill you.
Don't move! Turn over!
Way to go, Rosewood.
You're some kind of cop, you know that?
Sorry for the disturbance, folks.
Everything's under control.
[cheering, applause]
Taggert!
Would you mind explaining to me
what you and Rosewood
were doing in a strip bar
out of our jurisdiction,
when you were still on duty?
Sir, before you chastise
these two officers,
I think there's something
you should know.
The only reason that they
were at a strip bar
was because they were tailing me
and I went to this place.
Now, these two officers were sitting
outside wondering what I was doing.
I was in havin' a good time,
I'm into things like that.
Anyway, these guys waited outside,
and the only reason
that they came in
was because they saw
two suspicious-looking gentlemen,
with bulges in their jackets,
going into the place.
Well, it turns out that these guys were
gonna commit a robbery, sir.
These men watched them,
waited for them to make their move
and then they foiled the crime.
I did not know what was goin' on.
I was watchin' the show, havin' fun.
I'm still freaked out by it.
They must have a sixth sense or...
I don't know what you teach these
fellows, but they're not regular cops.
They're super cops.
And the only thing missing
on these guys are capes.
Is this what really happened?
No, sir.
Would someone like to tell me
what really happened?
[clears throat] Well...
Foley invited us to this bar...
and we accepted.
We ordered club soda, sir.
Right. And while we were there...
Foley observed the two suspects
casing the establishment.
And before we knew
what was going on...
...he'd already disarmed one of them.
Detective Foley deserves
all the credit for the arrest, sir.
Detective Foley,
we appreciate your assistance.
But in the future, if you want
to practice law enforcement,
I would prefer you did it in Detroit.
I understand, sir. I'm sorry.
But before I go I just want you
two to know something, all right?
The super cop story was working.
OK? It was working
and you guys messed it up.
OK? I'm tryin' to figure
you guys out, but I haven't yet.
But it's cool.
You fuck up a perfectly
good lie and it's all right.
You guys are off the case.
Foster. McCabe. Your turn.
Don't lose him.
Not a chance, sir.
And you two... in my office.
[mouthing] Well? Go on.
Morning, gentlemen.
Some coffee and donuts?
- What?
- Coffee and donuts.
[raps on window]
There he is.
[car door shuts]
Morning, officers.
What you all, the second team?
We're the first team.
Yeah. We're not gonna fall
for a banana in the tailpipe.
[mocking] "You're not going to fall
for the banana in the tailpipe?"
It should be more natural, brother,
it should flow out, like this:
[forcefully] "Look man, I ain't fallin'
for no banana in my tailpipe!"
See, that's more natural for us.
You been hangin' out
with this dude too long.
[chuckling]
I'm sorry, I'm just fuckin' with you.
That's funny to me. Sorry.
So, y'all gonna try and keep up with me?
- No problem.
- Isn't this Victor Maitland's house?
Yeah, I think so.
[sighs]
Well, I seen enough.
Y'all want somethin' to drink?
A beer or somethin'?
I got some stuff in the trunk.
Excuse me.
For a man who claims to be on vacation,
you look a lot like
you're on a stakeout.
Stakeout? No, no, I'm picnicking.
This is like a picnic area.
Well, guys, I been
shootin' the shit long enough.
Time for me to take in some sights.
Excuse me.
[tires screeching]
What the hell's he doing?
[tires squealing]
[laughing]
Can you put this in a good spot?
All this shit happened the last time
I parked here. Thank you.
May I help you?
[effeminate] Yes, I'm looking
for Victor Maitland.
You realize that this is
a members-only club?
Mm-hm, but I have to talk to Victor,
it's very, very important.
Are you sure it's
Victor Maitland you want?
Oh, yes, the grey haired gentleman,
very dark skin, Capricorn. Victor.
Well, why don't you give me
the message and I'll take it to him.
OK, I guess I can do that.
Tell Victor that Ramon,
the fella he met about a week ago,
tell him that Ramon
went to the clinic today
and I found out that I have...
...Herpes symplex ten.
And I think Victor should go check
himself out with his physician
to make sure everything is fine, before
things start fallin' off on the man.
Perhaps you better tell him that.
You know, I think that would be best.
So do I.
Hi, Victor.
I'm back.
Look, cuz, don't even try it, OK?
Why don't you get the hell
outta here, cuz.
Get the fuck away from me.
[mouths]
That's very good, Victor.
Could you teach him to roll over
and sit and do all that shit, too?
- What do you want?
- I want to talk to you.
Last time we met,
I didn't get a chance to talk to you.
- I have nothing to say to you.
- That's cool, I'll do all the talking.
This is a very nice place, Vic.
Hi. I like this, this is nice.
Glad you like it.
I must make you a member.
You know, Victor, I know that you're
into a lot of crooked shit.
And I have a pretty good idea
that you had Mikey killed.
And when I find out for sure...
...I'm gonna fuck you up real bad.
Is that so?
Now, listen to me,
my tough little friend.
I don't know from under
what stone you crawled,
or where you get these
ridiculous ideas about me,
but it seems painfully obvious
you haven't the slightest fucking
idea who you're dealing with.
Now, my advice to you is...
...crawl back to your
little stone in Detroit,
before you get squashed, OK?
Please step away from the table, sir.
Gotta go now, Vic.
- Nice meeting you again.
- Yeah.
[handcuffs clicking]
Catch you later, Vic.
I can't wait.
Don't I know you guys from some place?
You look so familiar.
Detective Foley,
this is becoming very irritating.
Why are you bothering Victor Maitland?
I had a friend named Michael Tandino
that used to work for Victor Maitland.
And Maitland had him killed.
I can't prove that right now,
but when I do,
you'll be the first to know.
Forget what you can prove.
Talk to me.
OK, listen, everybody knows
that Victor Maitland
is a hot-shot art dealer, OK?
But I did some pokin' around and
art's not the only thing that he deals.
I went to his warehouse
and I saw some guys unloading a crate
that was filled
with German bearer bonds.
Now, my friend Michael Tandino
had bonds like this on him,
coincidentally,
when he was killed in Detroit.
Just because Maitland chooses
to invest in the same kind of bonds
your friend had,
doesn't necessarily mean he's a killer.
The man's not an investor,
he's a smuggler, OK?
Be it bonds or drugs or whatever.
The crate that I saw
didn't even pass through Customs.
Maitland is paying someone so his guys
can get the shipments out of Customs
before they get inspected.
Maitland's guys get their hands on it,
they take the drugs
or the bonds out of the crates
and they send it back before
Customs even knows what's going on.
And you witnessed all this?
Everything except for the drugs,
but I found coffee grounds
all over the warehouse.
Coffee grounds?
You said something about that before.
What does that mean?
Drugs are sometimes
packed in coffee grounds.
The scent throws off the dogs.
Very good, lieutenant.
Now what do we do?
Look, Detective Foley, I...
I'm sorry.
I'd really like to help you.
If you'd found the drugs,
that's one thing,
but if your only evidence
is coffee grounds,
we don't have enough
to get a search warrant.
Come on, guys,
I know how we can get around...
We don't get around search warrants
in Beverly Hills.
- Taggart.
- Yes, sir.
I want you to start checking this out.
Start with the LAPD, the FBI
and the Customs Service.
Hey, wait a minute, Taggart.
Look, lieutenant,
Maitland is much smarter than that.
We go and start
snoopin' around his place,
he's gonna close down and get
his shipments from someplace else.
- It'd be a big waste of time.
- Oh, really?
Is that what your extensive experience
leads you to believe?
- Look, I haven't been on your force...
- Sir!
Oh, shit.
- Is this the man?
- Yes, sir.
Is this the gentleman who crashed
through Victor Maitland's window?
Who disabled an unmarked unit
with a banana?
Yes, sir.
Who lured Taggart and Rosemont
into a gross dereliction of duty
at a striptease establishment?
It's Rosewood, sir.
Yes, sir.
Is this the gentleman who ruined the
buffet at the Harrow Club this morning?
[Bogomil] Yes, sir.
I just bet you are the pride
of your department in Detroit.
Lieutenant, I'd like to see you
in your office.
Yes, sir.
[mocking] ls this the man who...
...wrecked the buffet
at the Harrow Club this morning?
[Taggart] Lower your voice,
for Christ's sake.
Why, can the guy hear me
through the wall?
[all] Yes, he can.
Rosewood, take Detective Foley
back to his hotel room,
watch him pack,
and escort him to the city limits.
When you get there,
you can give him his gun back.
The two charges of disturbing the peace
have been dropped against you.
But the chief says if you return
to the city of Beverly Hills,
the charges will be reinstated
and you will be prosecuted
to the limit of the law.
Sir, may I say something?
- [Taggart] Billy...
- What?
Well, he seems to have enough
to follow up...
You wanna tell that to the chief?
- No, sir.
- Then I suggest you get moving.
Come on, Axel.
Right. Let me check on that
tomorrow and get right back to you.
Thank you.
- Hi.
- Victor, hi.
Sit down.
Hope I'm not interrupting you.
Of course not, don't be silly.
Jenny, there's a gentleman
in town from Detroit
who says he's a friend
of Michael Tandino.
He came by the office yesterday
and asked me all sorts of...
...rather odd questions.
Excuse me, darling.
I believe his name is Foley.
Since you were such a good friend of
Michael, I was wondering if you were...
...perhaps familiar with the fellow?
Well, we... grew up
in the same neighborhood.
Really? Have you seen him lately?
He... he came in yesterday.
What, came by here?
Huh.
And?
He told me that... Mikey'd been killed.
Yes. Yes, I know.
- And then?
- That's it.
He left and...
I haven't seen him since.
You wouldn't, by any chance, know
where Foley's staying would you?
I have some information
which just might be helpful for him.
No, I have no idea.
[sighing] Yes
Yes.
Well, I hope I didn't
disturb you too much.
Oh, no, no problem.
- We'll have dinner soon, yes?
- That would be lovely.
Take care.
Hey, Billy,
I read the manifest, all right?
They're expecting
another shipment in today.
- If Bogomil...
- Never mind Bogomil!
This is a chance to blow this case wide
open, the two of us, what do you say?
- Come on.
- Look, Axel...
I wish I could, but I can't!
- Why?
- Because Bogomil would kill me.
Billy...
I'm not going to drive you
to the art gallery, Axel.
It'll just take a couple of minutes!
My friend Jenny'll let us
in Maitland's warehouse.
We can be there when the shipment
comes in and nail 'em!
How can you be sure
if it'll be drugs, or something?
I got a hunch, OK?
It's a technique by which many crimes
outside of Beverly Hills get solved.
Why didn't you tell Bogomil
about this shipment?
Bogomil does everything by the book.
You know what I'm startin' to think?
That everybody
in this goddamn town is a robot.
This thing is very personal to me.
All they asked me to do
was drive you out of town.
Now, I'm gonna screw that up, too.
- [sighs] Boy.
- Billy. I love you.
I just fell in love with you.
Jenny, how you doing?
This is my good buddy, Billy Rosewood.
- This is Jenny Summers.
- Hi.
- Billy's a Beverly Hills cop.
- How do you do?
That's Serge.
Yo, Serge, will you
get my friend an espresso?
You want it with a lemon twist?
Uh... Yeah, sure, if it's no bother.
- No, don't be stupid.
- [chuckling]
Axel, Victor Maitland was here
asking questions about you today.
I'm telling you,
he was acting real weird.
The reason I came down is 'cause
I want to get back inside the warehouse.
- How 'bout I go with you?
- Jenny, come on, now.
You work here with Serge,
in a art gallery. You're not a cop.
Axel, if this has anything
to do with Mikey,
then I want to go
check it out for myself.
I don't have time to stand here
and argue with you.
Wait a second. Let me get my keys...
...and we'll argue on the way.
Billy, your job's just to sit
out here and observe things.
- Don't make a move until I get you.
- I don't see why I can't come in.
You can't go in
'cause you're a cop in this town.
You go in without probable cause,
they're gonna call it an illegal search.
You know that. Or didn't they
teach you that in cop school?
Sit tight. If I find some evidence
I'll come out and get you.
- But you can't just...
- But nothing. Just be cool.
If anything jumps off, I'll come
and I'll get you, all right? OK?
Thank you.
Any chance you're gonna give me that
key and let me go in there by myself?
No chance.
Fuck. Come on.
Looks like they been here already.
- What exactly are you looking for?
- This.
This is a crate from overseas,
hasn't passed through Customs yet.
[Jenny] What is that?
Coffee?
[Axel] Yeah, it's coffee on top.
But this ain't sugar.
- Go get Rosewood.
- Welcome to the party.
Seems we have guests.
How nice.
I do like surprises.
Jeannette.
I just can't tell you how disappointed
I am to find you here.
- Victor, listen I...
- Shut up!
I don't want to hear it.
Take her to the car
and wait for me, OK?
What are you gonna do with him?
I think you should be more worried
about what we're going to do with you.
Jenny, don't worry about me.
We got cocaine and coffee here.
We're gonna get wired
and have a big party.
Thanks for havin' me over Vic,
this is very nice.
You say something?
[sighs]
If somethin' happens to her...
Mm?
I'm all ears.
...I'll kill you.
Really?
That would be a neat trick.
Well, cuz.
Are you still pissed at me?
Oh, no. No.
But I should've taken care of you
in Detroit.
When I popped your little buddy.
[grunting]
[coughing]
Goodbye, Mr. Foley.
Have a nice day.
[gasping] I'll try.
[groans] Damn it.
Oh, boy.
How's that little bump on the head doin'
I gave you in Detroit, huh?
Healed up nice, I hope.
[grunting]
[coughing]
[Axel coughing]
Freeze!
[screams]
Thanks, man.
[tires screeching]
Tell Taggart to check out the warehouse
and act on whatever he finds.
I'll explain it to him later.
DD-6, Sergeant Taggart is here now,
- and he wants to talk to you.
- Shit!
Billy, what the hell is goin' on?
I'm sorry, Sarg, I can't talk now.
What you mean you can't talk now?
Just check out the warehouse and
please don't say anything to Bogomil.
Sorry, sir, he's not
transmitting any more.
- Ah, shit!
- What's the matter?
It's Billy, he's doin' somethin'
dumb again, but I don't know what.
Was he calling from the hotel?
No, sir.
Right now his car is heading north
on Palm Canyon Road.
Hey, we were there this morning.
- [Taggart] What?
- Yeah.
Foley was up there,
looking over Maitland's house.
Do you have the address
of that warehouse?
Yes, sir.
Here. You two check that place out.
Then find me, and let me know
what the hell is goin' on over there.
And don't talk to anybody but me!
[car approaching]
Hold it right there, Foley,
you're under arrest.
Billy, what the hell are you doin' here?
I stole my gun and forced him
to bring me here.
No, he didn't, Sarg. Look, everything
he said about Maitland is right.
Now, he's kidnapped a woman
and he's got her in his house.
Well, let's go in there and get her.
What the fuck you think
I'm tryin' to do here?
You're not doin' anything! We'll have
a search warrant in 20 minutes.
- She'll be dead in 20 minutes.
- Stop workin' on that lock.
I'm gonna open this door and I'm goin'
inside. You wanna stop me? Shoot me.
- Me, too.
- Billy!
You can do what you want,
but I'm going in with Axel.
Goddamn it, Billy,
this is really serious trouble!
If you're lucky, you'll just get fired.
- [door opens]
- [Axel] Got it.
[Taggart] It's my last warning, Foley.
- Billy!
- I'm sorry, Sarg, I've got to.
Shit. Wait a minute.
- [beeping]
- [man] What's that?
Looks like east gate. Punch it up.
Who the hell is that?
Better get Maitland up here.
Where is everybody?
Owensby, is Rosewood back yet?
- No, sir.
- Have you seen Taggart?
He took off about ten minutes ago.
Foley's on the grounds.
Well, how the hell should I know?
Get some people out there right away.
Don't take your eyes off that screen.
I want you to try to locate
Taggart and Rosewood.
Come on.
[grunts]
[Taggart] OK, OK, OK.
[grunting] Shit.
[yelling]
- They must be away from the car, sir.
- I can see that, keep trying.
- DD-13, come in please.
- What's their 20?
- 609 Palm Canyon Road.
- Who lives at that address?
A Victor Maitland, sir.
[gasping] Try again.
Let's go around.
We can do it. Come on.
Ready?
One, two...
[grunting]
[Taggart grunting]
[chuckling]
[machine gunfire]
You all right?
What the fuck am I doin' here?
Drop it!
- Good shot, Billy.
- Let's go.
[machine gunfire]
[all grunting]
- Jesus Christ!
- Yeah, these guys are serious.
I hate machine guns.
Cover me.
You guys go around front,
I'm gonna check the back.
Sir, we have a report of shots fired
at that same location.
609 Palm Canyon Road.
Put out a 998: officers need assistance.
- Undercovers on the scene.
- Sir?
Just do it!
I want all north end units to roll.
South end units stay in their area.
Damn! Let's go.
Undercover officers at location.
Police! You're all under arrest!
You do that again,
I'll shoot you myself.
[spent shells clattering]
You know what I keep thinking about?
You know the end of Butch Cassidy?
Where Redford and Newman
are almost out of ammunition.
And the whole Bolivian Army
is out in front of this little hut.
Billy...
I'm gonna make you pay for this.
[gunshot]
[groaning]
[siren wailing]
- You gonna hang around here?
- Fuck no!
[tires screeching]
- Freeze it!
- Hold it right there.
[Bogomil] Oh, shit.
[Jenny] Axel!
[gasping]
Be careful, old boy, you might hit me.
Freeze!
[body thudding]
Police! You're all under arrest!
Lay down your weapons in front of you
and take two steps back
with your hands up!
Very good.
Great.
[indistinct radio chatter]
[indistinct murmuring]
What the hell's going on here?
Oh, shit.
- What's this man doing here?
- Bleeding, sir.
Rosewood, how come
he isn't wearing cuffs?
Well, he isn't actually in custody, sir.
Well, place him in custody,
or would you like me to do it?
Wouldn't you like to hear
my report first, sir?
You have a report
that explains all this?
Yes, sir.
Well, I will be very glad to hear it.
Well, sir, Ms. Jeannette Summers, the
manager of Mr. Maitland's art gallery,
accidentally discovered large quantities
of a substance
she suspected was cocaine
in the art gallery's warehouse.
She immediately communicated her
discovery to Detective Axel Foley
of the Detroit Police Force.
Detective Foley was,
at the time, cooperating
in a joint Beverly Hills-Detroit
investigation of narcotics trafficking.
Detectives Foley and Rosewood,
responding to Ms. Summers' report,
proceeded to the warehouse,
where Rosewood did, in fact,
discover approximately
80 kilos of cocaine.
Rosewood immediately
called for backup.
And I dispatched our officers
to this location.
Sergeant Taggart here,
was the first to arrive at the scene.
And having probable cause
to believe a felony was in progress,
Sergeant Taggart joined Rosewood,
with Detective Foley
present only as an observer,
and proceeded to enter the grounds.
And in the course
of defending ourselves,
we shot several suspects,
including Mr. Maitland.
You expect me to believe that report?
That's the report I'm filing, sir.
Sergeant Taggart...
Why don't you tell me what happened?
Happened just like
the lieutenant said, chief.
[chuckles] Well, I suppose
congratulations are in order.
Thank you, sir.
That report better be
on my desk in the morning.
Yes, sir, first thing.
You were lyin' your ass off.
[both laughing]
Why don't you go to the hospital
and get your shoulder looked at?
Excuse me, sir.
I was wondering if you could,
like, do me a favor, sir?
- I think your favors are all used up.
- I understand.
It's just that I was hopin'
you could call my Inspector Todd,
my boss back home and straighten
things out, but that's all right.
Guess I'm out of a job.
It's cool, though.
I think I'm gonna stay in Beverly Hills.
I like it here.
I'm gonna start my own
private investigation company.
How's that sound?
I will talk to Inspector Todd
first thing tomorrow.
- Will you, really?
- Yes, you bet.
- Thank you so much, sir.
- You're welcome.
How you doin'? I'm Axel Foley,
checkin' out of suite 1035.
One moment, sir.
I'll get your bill.
- [Taggart clears throat]
- Hey! Guys!
You all didn't have to see me off.
But I'm very moved by the gesture.
Bogomil ordered us
to make sure you got out of town.
You know, that doesn't even matter
to me, Billy. You know what matters?
That you guys came down here.
I'm all choked up on the inside
I got a lump in my throat.
You look a little misty yourself there,
Taggart.
- [man] There you go, sir.
- [Axel] Oh, thank you.
Excuse me. The Beverly Hills Police
Department is picking that up.
Oh, get outta here! Guys!
That's the last straw. That was
the last straw, you guys are too nice.
Sir, do you sell those
Beverly Palm robes down here?
Yes, we do sir,
they're $95 apiece.
Money is no object, put 'em on my tab.
I have to have two of them, though.
Billy, you saved my life, OK?
I don't think I'll ever
be able to repay you.
But as a token of my appreciation,
I want you to have this
fine Beverly Palm robe.
Each time you get out of the shower
and you're dripping wet,
for the rest of your life, I want you
to think about our friendship.
I want you to think about Axel Foley.
I love you, Billy.
- Thanks, Axel.
- [laughs]
Here, let me take this.
You should rest that arm.
Billy, take care of the tab, would you?
- Hey, Taggart.
- Here you are, sir.
This is for you.
No, that's all right.
You keep it as a souvenir.
I already have three of 'em in my bag.
- Here you go.
- Thank you, sir.
- Take it easy.
- You're not gonna say goodbye?
Why, ain't you guys gonna tail me
to the city limits, anyway?
- Yes, we are.
- I figured you would.
I was thinking about stopping off
and getting something to drink, though.
Yeah, we sorta figured you would.
That mean you guys
are gonna join me?
I don't think so, Axel,
we're still on duty.
Well, I don't think one beer's
gonna kill us, Billy.
That's right, listen to Taggart here.
Lighten up, all right?
One drink's not gonna kill us.
[♫ Patti LaBelle: Stir It Up]
[Axel] Hey, guys
If you fall too far behind,
don't be afraid to honk, OK?
Where we goin' anyway'?
Don't worry about it,
just follow my lead.
I know the perfect place.
You guys will love it.
Trust me.