[Man]
Back in the '70s, every cop
wanted out of the city.
But the only cops allowed
to live outside New York
were transit cops.
Because the Transit Authority
was also run
byJersey and Connecticut.
So these guys I knew
at the 3-7...
they started pulling overtime
at subway stations...
and got the city to declare them
"auxiliary transit cops."
They bought some land in Jersey.
Got some cheap loans
from people they knew.
They made themselves a place
where the shit
couldn't touch 'em.
Every precinct
has its "cop bar,"
a private club, all blue.
For the 3-7,
it was the 4 Aces...
just across the river.
[Video Game Noises]
[Tires Screeching]
[Gunshots]
This Armenian guy, he's from
the other side over there.
He tells her that she's dead.
Right? She's gonna be dead
by morning.
- So he drops this box off
at her place, right?
- They call you guys.
- They call Bomb Squad.
- Right. We go in there.
We x-ray it on scene.
- And, uh, we can't see
anything in there.
- [Man] Right.
I cut a little hole in it.
I can see there's something
in there.
[Man]
Uh-huh.
l, uh, I see that there's, uh,
some white fuzz.
There's something pink.
I can't figure out what it is.
- Suddenly I realize
I am looking at a tongue.
- Ah, shit!
A big, fat tongue sticking
out at me. Yes. The guy
put a goat's head in there.
[Man]
This at the end
of the twentieth century.
H.G. Wells, he'd turn over in
his grave to think at the start
of a new millennium...
- [Man] some Iranian guy...
- [Woman] Armenian. Armenian guy.
Some Armenian would be
deliverin' a goat's head to the
door of the woman that he loved.
- Backward culture over there.
- Let me tell you.
We're all backwards, Berta.
- Our machines are all modern
and shit, but our minds?
- Gary.
Our minds are primitive.
Our minds are primitive,
Berta.
- Hey.
- I gotta go home, baby.
All right, wait. I'm just
waitin' on the call, okay?
Come here.
- I gotta pick up the car.
This is not...
- Monica, sit down.
Excuse me.
Do you mind?
- Do you mind?
- Sorry.
Roberta, that's Freddy.
Freddy's cool.
He's got a bad ear.
He'd good people though.
Don't worry about it.
[Video Game]
You have no authority.
Yeah, yeah. Fine.
[TVlndistinct]
It's quiet tonight,
huh, Freddy?
Hmm?
It's quiet.
Everyone's at that
bachelor party across the river.
Oh, yeah.
Whoop-de-doo.
You got any quarters?
Don't look at me, I just
put two more in the meter.
- It's his birthday.
- [Figgis] Oh, yeah?
- He's going for high score.
- Happy Birthday, Freddy.
Happy Birthday.
Let me see what I got.
I wasn't into making
a big deal
after the ten-year thing.
Hey, hey, how you doin'?
Sorry, Freddy. Hey.
[Figgis]
I was wondering if you'd
be able to, uh, come by.
Yeah. 4 Aces.
Where else?
Shit!
Damn it.
Two kinds of people
in this world.
Pinball people
and video game people.
You, Freddy,
you're pinball people.
Always got somethin'
to say, Figgsy.
Come on. Freddy,
Freddy, Freddy.
Freddy! Freddy!
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
It's bedtime, Sheriff.
- You all right to drive?
- Mm-hmm.
- You sure?
- Positive.
- Take it easy, Freddy.
- Take it easy.
[Radio] It was not Lady Luck
thatJim Maloney found
in Atlantic City.
It was the cops.
The 30-year-old native
of the Caribbean island
of Antigua...
was captured in a casino
just days after
an aspiring rap artist...
was fatally beaten
in a Queen's convenience store.
Sources have filled in some
of the blanks for 1010 WINS
saying...
Shit!
[Music, Chattering]
Oh! All right.
Take it easy, take it easy.
I apologize.
Magilla Gorilla,
you fucking ape.
- Mikey, I'm out. I'm gettin' outta here.
- Where're you goin'?
- I love her.
- Yeah! Hell of a party!
- Roger.
- Okay, Superboy.
You're my man, Superboy.
- My man, Roger.
- Keep it up.
You guys take it easy.
Davey, can you dispose
of this legally please?
I don't like
bachelor parties.
See you back
in Jersey.
Oh!
Oh.
Ooh-oof!
Shit!
[Man Groaning]
[Coughing]
Goddamn it!
[Gagging]
[Coughing]
Ah, fuck.!
Shit.!
[Coughing]
You have the fuckin'
wrong stuff here.
Ah, Jesus!
Frankie?
Jesus Christ! What are you
guys doin'? You're giving me
a heart attack over here.
Hey, Superboy,
what'd ya say, kid?
- You all right, Jackie?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Yeah? All right,
I'll see you guys tomorrow, man.
You're like creepers back here.
[Frank]
Thanks, kid.
Be careful driving, huh?
[Radio] Giants leading 10
to 6 as they move to the bottom
of the seventh inning...
in a game characterized
by big rallies.
The Giants scored seven times
in the first inning off...
##[Car Radio... Rap]
- Well, fuck!
- The Yankees lost to the Angels today.
Hey.!
Pull over. N.Y.P.D.
Pull over!
Hey, you hear me?
No!
[Laughing]
[Brakes Squealing]
Fuck! Shit!
Fuckin' cocksucker!
[Screams]
##[Rap Continues]
Freddy?
[Sirens Wailing]
Traffic incident?
Bullshit!
Hey, what's up, man?
These guys were shot
like six times.
Hey, just shut up,
do your fucking job!
- Fucking nurse.
- What've you got?
I got four vials of
crack here and a pipe.
That's it.
Russell, what you're thinking,
swallow it.
The guy saved five babies
out in Redhook, all right?
That's right, black babies.
Mashed potatoes
don't mean gravy.
- I'm on the bridge.
- [Man On Phone] Is Babitch there?
- Yeah. I see him.
- Take care of it.
[Superboy]
Uncle Ray?
Uncle Ray, I saw a gun.
I saw the gun.
He took a shot at me. Tell 'em.
They took a shot at me.
[Man]
Stay here with us.
Tunney didn't even get
the grand jury
for shit like this.
Fuck the G.J.
You're Superboy, huh?
You saved, what?
Six black babies?
Come on, kid, the shit plays!
- Three babies.
- Hey, one at a time, please.
I got P.A. On another channel,
the mayor's office,
assistant D.A.
Press up the yin-yang.
The only reason
they're not here now...
is we got gridlock from
across Bronx to the Palisades.
There's no gun.
You didn't see it, Jack?
You can't find it?
- Flaky.
- Listen, I heard a shot.
I heard a shot, Ray.
- I heard a shot. I saw a gun.
- In my trunk, in the grand union bag.
- I heard a shot, Leo.
- The kid had a
steering wheel lock in his hand.
Your tire blew.
You're fucked up
and you wasted a pair
of shit-bags...
who aren't worth the hair
in the crack of your ass.
So you cool it
with the patty-cake morality.
Because without me, kid,
those stiffs'll put you
in a room...
- Where you will fuck your uncle
and everything he's built.
- Hey, Leo.
The black van's gonna be here
in a minute
and I haven't done shit.!
- What I'm doing is highly...
- Sympathetic.
- [Leo] Yeah, damn right.
- It is.
- Ray, we don't have to do this.
- [Ray] Calm down.
Fuck, Ray!
Ooh, baby!
Hey, we got it.
- Look at that, huh? We got it!
- Yo, yo, yo, yo.
- What the fuck
are you doin', man?
- I found their piece.
- Found their piece?
- Ah, Jesus!
- That wasn't in there.
- What do you mean it wasn't in?
It was underneath the floor mat.
Bullshit, man.
You can't do that!
Shut the fuck up!
Do what?
It was underneath
the fucking floor mat.
What the fuck
are you doing?
Fuck you!
I told you not to do it
like this, Ray.
- We'rejust doin'ourjob,
so let's just calm down.
- I told you!
- [Everyone Shouting]
- [Leo] Take it easy. Hey.!
You boys should take care
of your own business here.
Take my fucking shield
away from me.
- Hey, put it down!
- What? You gonna shoot me?
- Put it down, Chico!
- Chico this, motherfucker!
- Frankie, Help me start it up.
- [Medic] What the fuck you gonna do?
Kiss my ass!
[Shouting]
Fuck!
[Shouting Continues]
Hey, Jack, Jack, Jack.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
[Ray]
Oh, my God.!
Oh, my God! Leo!
Leo! Jesus!
He jumped!
Oh, my God.!
Hejumped.!
- He jumped!
- [Jack] Murray?
Somebody shine a light
down there.
He just hit the water
and... he went down.
- Davis? Where's Davis?
- Oh!
- [Leo] I want aviation, harbor.
I want some illumination now!
- Stupid, fucking kid!
- Oh, my God!
- We got a man over the fucking G.W.!
[Alarm Clock Ringing]
[Ringing Stops]
[Sighs]
How long is the car
gonna take?
Lenny won't know
till the parts guy gets in.
You should take
number two.
What did you tell Lenny
about the accident?
- Chasin' a speeder.
- What?
Sheriff was chasin'
a speeder.
[Laughs]
[Radio]
Our top story on 1010 WINS...
A fatal shootout on the G. W.B.
And a cop's suicide.
Highway Patrol continues
searching the Hudson River
for the body of Officer...
Murray "Superboy"Babitch.
- Babitch leaped off the George
Washington bridge last night...
- Hey, hey, put it out.
- An apparent suicide, after
engaging in a high-speed chase.
- Fuck you, asshole.
There's no way
that guy jumped, man.
- There's no fucking way!
- Controversy swirls around events
on the bridge.
[Man]
Officer, how can you testify...
that Superboy
jumped off that bridge
when you didn't see him jump?
I mean, I'm looking
at your statement right here...
that you filled out
at 0200 hours.
Wait a minute.
I'm gonna object because
we went through this.
[Lawyer]
Now, he's been up all night.
How many times are you gonna ask
the same question?
Let me ask you another
question, brother.
Have you ever been
to Garrison, New Jersey?
- What kind of question is that,
Lieutenant?
- Counselor.
Have you ever been
to Garrison, New Jersey?
- You think those white boys
on that bridge...
- Come on, Lieutenant.
- Please. I object to this!
- What do you think this is, Mod Squad?
- [Lawyer] I'm offended by this.
- [Men Arguing]
All right, all right!
All right, listen.
He doesn't tell us
what we want to know,
he's gonna lose his job.
That's about as simple as
I can make it. He's gonna lose
his fuckin'job. All right?
Do you want that?
What do you take us for?
A bunch of fuckin' morons, huh?
- What is the matter with you?
- With all due respect, I think...
- You be quiet, you be quiet! Shut up!
- I believe...
If you don't mind
my French, all right?
You be quiet.
He's off the force
if he does not start
answering questions.
You want to save your ass?
Start giving us answers.
And I'll tell you
something.
We know anyway.
So do yourself a favor,
and stop fuckin' around.
[E.M.S. Officer]
Yo.! Hey.!
- We gonna talk or what, man?
- When your rep gets here.
- Fuck the rep. I gotta talk to you.
Rueben, can you call
E.M.S. About this guy?
Yeah. Hey, Moe,
Harbor found one
of Superboy's shoes.
What about the socks?
They find them too?
Fuckin' shoe.
Jack Rector's comin' in
tomorrow at 9:00.
- What about Donlan?
- Uh, next week.
- His P.D.A. Attorney says...
- Who's that? Who's his lawyer?
- This guy Sloan.
- Sloan? Ooh, big gun.
Says he's grieving
and all depressed
for his nephew.
Oh, Ray's all grieving
and depressed.
[Laughs]
I'll bet he is.
If Superboy is alive...
he's the fuckin' plague
right about now.
You're not gonna
bring that home.
I mean, you don't shit
where you eat, do you?
I do, Carson.
I live in a house
and in it I shit...
and I eat.
[Beeps]
[Beeping]
It's Grotto.
[Beeps]
[Fast Beeping]
- [Ray] Murray, get down.
- [Jack] It's Freddy's new girl.
Cover yourself.
- Hi. Could you turn
your engine off for me?
- I got the air on.
- You on the job?
- No.
We're comin' from Forest Hills.
I'm John McEnroe.
That's Jimmy Connors.
Is your license in there?
Can you pull it out
for me, please?
- This is a school zone.
- Christ!
Listen, Miss Betts.
You're new, right?
Yes, I'm new here,
but I'm not new on the job.
- I was...
- Freddy!
- A municipal deputy in Elmira.
[Ray]
You see, Officer,
in Garrison...
when the car you're gonna tag
has got a P.D.A. Sticker...
I'd advise you to think
to yourself, "Hey, that's one
of the good guys.
I think I'll go catch me
a bad guy."
If we didn't pull over P.D.,
there wouldn't be
any violations in this town.
The problem in this town
ain't the people that live here.
It's the element that visits.
Is this a new car, Ray?
It's nice.
We didn't recognize it.
Come on, Freddy,
I wanna go home.
Tell this cupcake to heel.
- Okay, that's not necessary.
- Cindy.
- Well, listen, take care, guys.
See you later.
- [Ray] Hey.!
- What happened to you,
Freddy?
- [Chuckles] Fender benders.
She's kinda cute.
[Phone Ringing]
- [Ringing]
- Dispatch. Hi!
Can I call you back?
Bye.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine. I got it.
[Phone Ringing]
Dispatch.
No, no.
That's the next town over.
You called Garrison.
Right. The town
with all the police.
What are you gonna do
with Superboy? You gotta
stash him someplace.
- We lie low.
- [Bell Rings]
Hey, Moe!
Hey, Ray.
- Sorry to hear about your nephew.
- Yeah, he was a good kid.
We were up all night
with it.
[Ray] I know you need
to talk to me.
I'll come in next week
sometime. How's that?
- Jackie here's comin'in
early for you. Tomorrow.
- Hi, Jackie. Moe Tilden.
Yeah, hey.
- Moe Tilden.
- Yeah. Frankie Lagonda.
- [Moe] What house?
- Out of the 3-7.
- You been there long?
- Maybe too long, huh?
- Too long. Right.
- Moe, here, was my classmate
at the academy.
Back in the day...
before he fell in love
with this redhead
at I.A. And transferred.
Is that how it went, Ray?
[Laughing]
So what brings you
to our fair city?
Checkin' up on us?
I heard there was
a way of life out here.
Thought I'd check it out
for myself.
What are we, uh,
like the Amish now?
[Laughing]
See you around.
You fuckin' rat.
[Boys Arguing,
Fighting]
Ah, shit!
[Arguing,
Fighting Continues]
- I thought you gave me a ticket.
- Hmm?
- You the sheriff?
- [Glass Shattering]
- I thought you gave me
a ticket.
- One second.
[Boys Arguing]
Hey, hey, Gordon, that's it.
Knock it off. Let him go.
- [Boy] Asshole.!
- Just let him go. Everyone
go down to the park.
Go on. Go on
before I kick your ass.
Get on!
Sorry.
How long
you been a sheriff?
- Ten years.
- That's great.
I see there's a lot
of city cops here.
- Oh, yeah. A lot of cops.
- Great gig.
Mm-hmm. I like it.
Well, I don't wanna
waste your time.
Let me give you my card.
It's a special unit
in the city.
If you ever wanna talk
about anything,
it's all confidential.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Nice to meet ya.
[Jack]
Ray, that fuck Tilden
shows up here with that grin.
Freddy's new girl
pulls us over.
I mean, someone's talkin;
I say it's Figgis.
I mean,
we got some loose ends.
Freddy's my man.
Unfortunately, he's on
the wrong side of the river.
That don't mean
you can't trust me, Ray...
with anything.
I trust you, Freddy.
I trust you to make sure
the kids don't kill themselves
on prom night.
I trust you to suggest
a good opera record
for my sister at Christmas.
I'm serious.
- [Sighs]
- Freddy, when I leave here
everyday...
I trust you with my town.
Maybe I don't trust you
with anything...
but I trust you
with my home and my family...
and, to me,
that's everything.
- [Knocking At Door]
- ##[Girl Singing]
[Woman]
I'm sorry. Oh.
- Jesus, I'm sorry.
- Oh, it's okay. I heard voices.
I was gonna have the base
call you back anyway.
- Freddy! Look what you found.
- Mm-hmm.
She's gonna be so happy.
Her daddy won it for her
at the fair last year.
- And I left it on top of the car.
- I know. I saw from my window.
It's awful
about Ray's nephew.
Mmm.
What happened
to your nose?
Ah, little accident.
I was chasing a speeder.
[Girl]
Mommy, I need some black.!
Oh, shh.
Look what the sheriff found.
Remember how you were
crying for that today?
Freddy, do you want
some coffee?
Um, no, I'm fine.
Thanks, Liz.
- I got a little bit on me.
- [Liz] Yeah, you got a
little bit on you, didn't you?
Come here. Okay.
All right. You know what?
I have to get something
to clean this off of you.
Okay. We got it off
both hands.
Isn't that nice?
I'm gonna go get
a washcloth. Okay?
All right.
You just draw a rainbow.
Enough with the sparkles.
[Liz]
I'll be right back.
All right?
[Sighs]
Well.
I was gonna call you.
Not you.
One of your guys.
- Why? What's up?
- Oh.!
Someone's
been dumping garbage,
garbage bags.
Uh-huh.
Is that them?
Just one of them.
The rest are mine.
I don't tell Joey,
'cause then he thinks
he's got to deal with it.
Not that he doesn't think
much of the local...
about you guys.
I'll take care of it.
It's okay.
He's got the city
to worry about, right?
Anyway...
[Woman]
What's the point with
the black garbage bag?
[Freddy] It's just I found
your phone bill in a black
garbage bag down the street.
So, what if I said
I didn't know
where it came from?
I'd take your word
for it, Rose.
- Is Ray home?
- No. He's taking care
of our little visitor.
- My garbage gets picked up
every Tuesday.
- All right.
Well, thanks for your time,
Rose.
You tellJoey that he should
come and talk to me...
if he thinks
I got no right.
Rose, I wanna believe you
when you tell me something.
Did you dump these bags or not?
Freddy, this isn't
a law problem. Okay?
You tellJoey Randone
if he does not like my garbage...
well, then, he should stop
soiling my sheets.
You gonna tell Ray
about this?
[Car Horn Honking]
- Hey, Ray.
- What's up, Freddy?
- Decided to give me that ticket?
- No.
- Somebody's been dumping garbage.
- Oh... a felony!
- [Man] What's wrong, Officer?
- Could I see your license
and registration, please?
- I was just asking...
- We just came to get a view of the city.
- [Woman] I don't believe this.
- [Man] lt'll be all right.
They're just a couple over.
I'm checking docs.
- I'll sit.
- [Officer] All right, roger that.
[Brakes Squealing]
- This ass motherfucking pig.
- We came here to watch the view!
- And you pull this?
- Speeding? My ass! Goddamn.
Do you know the meaning
of the word harassment?
That's what this is, you know.
- [Liz] It was Rose, wasn't it?
- [Freddy] Liz...
if you want me to,
I'll talk to 'im.
[Liz Sighs]
Ah, why?
You didn't marry him.
No.
But I'm your friend.
[Sighs]
Freddy, look,
I gotta go.
[Man]
And let me be clear.
It was the system that drove
Murray "Superboy" Babitch
off that bridge.
Murray Babitch was a hero cop.
He deserved a fair hearing,
but he knew this would
not happen, not in this city.
[Man]
Activist Cyril Johns met
the parents of the slain teens...
calling for a human blockade
on the bridge tomorrow.
A drunk cop jumps off a bridge.
That does not erase the murder
of two black children.
Attending the Yankee game,
Mayor Farelli
responded to reports...
- Of cops attempting to plant
evidence on the bridge.
- Shh. Shh.
We are looking into it.
There may have been
some irregularity on the bridge.
- But as I say...
- Your mother's an irregularity.
No more comments, please.
I'm here to enjoy the ball game
with my wife. Thank you.
- [Laughing]
- Oh, that's your boss. Are you kidding?
- You'll never get
another raise in your life.
- Who's gonna tell?
- Diagonal rule.
- Hmm?
Diagonal rule.
Red light, don't fight.
You make a right.
It's more important
than the golden rule.
- If Superboy knew that,
he'd still be alive, Freddy.
- Yo.! Yo, yo.
Freddy, I heard you saved
Ollie the turtle today.
- What happened to your nose?
- Ah, nothing.
I just had a little accident.
Listen, Joey, there's something
we should probably talk about
if you've got some time.
- What?
- Something we should...
If you have a few minutes.
Pretty boyJoey
bettin' against the Bulls.
What is that?
What, are you some kind
of high roller?
- Fuck you, Figgs. I had 12 points.
- Against the 5-time NBA champs?
What kind of bet is that?
You know, you night guys...
you watch way too much Oprah
when you should be catching
your "Z's."
Uh-huh, Figgs, well
at least I'm not the one
sniffin' my money away.
That was your inner child
making that wager, Joey.
Little boyJoey
with the little Met poster
taped above his bed.
Tell you what, Figgs,
why don't you do me a favor.
Come on over here, unzip me,
pull out my inner child
and take a bite, baby.
Bite it hard
and bite it thick.
- Fuck you!
- No, fuck you!
Dumb fuck like that P.D.
How's that make you feel,
Freddy?
I don't care.
Yeah?
You like eatin' doughnuts?
Look, Freddy.
I say it's okay to bejealous.
You saved this girl's life,
right?
From it, from risking yourself
from saving her sorry ass,
you go deaf as a result.
- In one ear.
Then you have to watch
as this girl you saved,
this beauty queen...
marries this cocksucker!
And you, with your ear,
you can't even get
a desk on the force.
You're fucked.
Be jealous, Freddy!
Let it out.
I would.
Purge! Cleanse yourself.
Fucking cleansing.
Del, Del, let me have
another beer.
I gotta go, Freddy.
School's in session.
See you later.
[Figgis]
He bets against the Bulls.
[Ray]
No one wants to get involved
in your personal life, Gary.
Butjust because you're
undercover now, that don't mean
people aren't watchin'you.
[Figgis]
Wh-What's going on here?
This is fucking bullshit.
This is bullshit.
What is this, omerta?
Huh?
Listen, if I.A. 's gonna
fucking hang me by the balls...
it ain't gonna be over
some fucking missing evidence.
[Frank]
Figgsy, you've been a cop
12 years. Six grams missing.
It's not a white socks
violation, babe.
Come on.! You bought that big
ol'house. Maybe you're tryin'
to get out from under.
- Hey! Jack.
- What the fuck's up your ass?
You're telling me you're gettin'
by without gravy, any of you?
[Figgis] Listen to me.
I was putting out Ray's fires
when you were still suckin; ...
on your mama's titties,
sojust back the fuck off,
all right?
So you want to toss me?
What? You can't...
- Sit down, Gary.
- No! Tell me what's going on!
- This is bullshit.!
- Even better, why don't you
get the fuck out?
Fuck you, you fucking child.
Just back the fuck off.
At least I'm not shackin'
with no reekin' whore.
You're supposed to fuck 'em,
Gary, not open up
a methadone clinic.
[Laughing]
- Figgis, get the hell off of me.!
- Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, Figgis, come on.
That's too much now.
Hey, hey, hey.!
- [Ray] Gary.
- [Gary] Fuck you.
You got a problem with me
helpin' a girl in trouble, huh?
- Figgsy.
- You have a problem with that?
- Huh?
- No, you're a fuckin' humanitarian!
- Come here, come here. You think
you're so fuckin' bad, huh?
- Oh, God!
Come on. Come here.
You see this?
Look at Tunney.
You see him?
- That was my fuckin' partner.
That was a cop!
- [Ray] Enough.!
Let go of him, Figgsy.
[Ray]
Go home.
You all right, Jack?
Don't shut me out, Ray!
You found us a sweet
little town. You got us the
low interest, and I'm grateful.
But don't forget who it was
that you came to two years ago
to cover your ass.
Get him outta here, Freddy.
- Come on.
- It's not my fault
that you can't look at him!
You sit in this chair...
with your back to 'im.
You want it to go away,
but I'm still here.
[Figgis]
In for a penny, in for a pound.
Don't shut me out, Ray.
I'll take care of it,
Ray.
It's bullshit.
I'm gettin' the fuck
outta this town!
[Dog Barking]
- [Joey] Open the door.
- [Liz] You wanna play games?
I don't play games.
I want the door op...
I want... I want...
- [Joey] Open it now.!
- [Dog Barking]
- Shut up!
- [Liz]
Why don't you go up the street
and get into bed with Rosie?
- Liz, open the goddamn door now.!
- [Liz] Idiot.!
Open it... now!
Freddy, go home.
Everything is just hunky-dory.
Please go.
- Mind if we check up
on Liz?
- Yes, I do. I mind.
I said I mind, Freddy.
- [Liz]Joey, I've had it, okay?
- I'll get the kit.
Liz, it's Freddy.
[Joey]
Does Ray know?
Freddy, does Ray know?
- Hi, Freddy.
- Are you okay?
Your Uncle Freddy is here
to rescue you again.
[Girl Crying]
[Joey Slams Door]
Liz, maybe you and the baby
need a place to stay.
Let him cool off.
I could take you over
to the Ramada.
Do you want me to do that?
He didn't do anything.
I... hit him with a bottle.
[Crying Continues]
[Record]
D When I lost you, honey d
d Sometimes I think
I lost my guts too d
# Yeah, I wish God
would send you a word #
#Send me something
I'm afraid ##
[Car Horn Honking]
- Freddy?
- [Honking Continues]
- Freddy.!
- [Sirens Wailing]
[Sirens Wailing]
His girlfriend
was in the basement.
- So where is Figgs?
- I called him at the precinct.
He's on his way.
Oh.
[Coughing]
We got no pressure.
I wonder if there's still water
in that tower over there.
[Medic]
Monica, can you hear me?
Oh, my God!
Monica!
Baby, what were
you doin' in there?
Hey! I came back
to see you.
I need...
I needed some...
Wanted...
to see you...
but you weren't there.
I was workin'.
[Gasping]
Monica!
No, baby.
Oh, my God.
[Sobbing]
- The fucker's gettin' payback.
- Who is?
[Figgis]
Ray. Who do you think?
Lenny said it wasn't suspicious.
He said it was electrical.
[Ray]
Figgsy?
Look at me, Figgsy.
Did you call in?
I'm not on till Tuesday.
I'll call in.
Buy you a couple weeks.
[Telephone Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
Dispatch.
Uh-huh.
Well, tell them they can't.
Just because
they're TV people...
it doesn't mean they can
park on your lawn.
[TV Newscaster]
In a cemetery
practically reserved for cops...
you come across the tombstone
of Officer Glenn Tunney.
You may recall his case.
He was murdered in his jail cell
awaiting the grand jury.
Two years later,
deja vu.
Another hero cop,
Murray Babitch is his name,
dubbed "Superboy,"
unwilling to trust the system
that destroyed his friend...
jumps from
the George Washington Bridge.
##[Bagpipes]
- Freddy.
- How ya doin'?
Freddy.
Maybe we should
go up there.
Freddy. Freddy?
I want you to meet
the head of the
Patrolman's Defense Association.
Great.
Vincent.
Vincent Lassaro,
I'd like you to meet
Sheriff Freddy Heflin.
- You did a good job here.
You did a great job.
Real nice.
- Thank you.
- Freddy's a hell of a guy.
- [Vince] Good, great.
He was trying to get
on the force, but he had
this problem with his ear.
- You're not a lip reader, are ya?
- No, no.
It's just this one ear when
I was a kid I had this accident.
You should call me.
I mean, when Ray Donlan
puts his thumb in the air...
It's not the force,
but I got my own people.
Call me.
Is he serious?
Freddy, my boy,
that is how things happen.
See you later.
"Eternal God, our Father,
the Lord of our life and death...
we acknowledge Thee in all
our ways and in all events
which befall us."
What's in the coffin?
His uniform.
"Then in Thy great mercy,
grant us a safe lodging
and a holy rest.
And peace at last
through Jesus Christ,
our Lord."
Amen.
Unto God's gracious mercy
and protection, we commit you.
The Lord bless you
and keep you.
The Lord make His face
to shine upon you,
and be gracious unto you.
The Lord lift up His countenance
upon you and give you peace...
both now and forevermore.
Amen.
[Sighing]
Psst.
Hi, Sheriff.
How you doin'?
This is Detective Carson.
- How's it goin'?
- Come on in. It's your office.
[Carson] That there is
Manny Cardoza and his brother.
They're drug runners.
Hmph. I didn't know
they allowed classical music
in Jersey.
Who's this?
Toy Torillo.
You heard of him?
- Oh, yes.
- [Moe] Hmm.
I don't know how you do it,
Sheriff.
Keeping all these Hessians
in line.
All blue.
Everybody packing.
All together.
One door
down from the next.
The wives borrowing
the sugar.
It's like you're the sheriff
of Copland.
- Hmm.
- [Carson] Look at this.
Hmm.
[Moe]
You see, Sheriff,
I got a sticky problem.
Myjurisdiction ends,
in a sense,
at the George Washington Bridge.
But half the men I watch
live beyond that bridge...
where no one's watching.
I'm watching.
I can see that.
You've got a crime rate here
of about, what?
The lowest
in northern New Jersey.
You got Hoboken
and Jersey City over here.
Newark.
We try to do a good job
with what we have.
With a staff of three?
No, Sheriff.
What you got is a town
that scares the shit
out of certain people.
Lieutenant, I told you,
I'm watching.
I mean, if you look around
you see none of these people
are wearing silk shirts.
Their pools are above ground.
You know?
You raise your family
somewhere decent,
I guess that's a crime now.
[Freddy]
Lieutenant, look around.
This is a town
with a population
of 1,000 people.
- I got news for you.
Not all cops are dirty.
- I'm not saying they are.
[Freddy]
He used to come by,
have drinks with the guys.
He never caused
any problems.
[Moe]
You mind if I sit down?
We buried a suit today.
We buried a suit today!
That doesn't bother you?
- He jumped off the G.W.B.
- Yeah, but his body never hit the water.
That doesn't bother you.
What does?
That I investigate cops?
- Being a man who always pined
to be a cop?
- I am a cop.
Pined to be N.Y.P.D.
Three forced absent,
ten years.
Appeals of hearing tests.
Right?
You may be law enforcement,
and so am l,
but you are not a cop.
Now, I may watch cops.
But tell me if I'm wrong.
Every day out these windows,
so do you.
You watch cops too.
And since we are both
law enforcement,
we share a duty.
Do we not?
If there is a stink,
we must investigate.
We must gather evidence
because evidence
makes us see the truth.
Is this the stink
of a criminal act...
or is it a turd
in a bag?
I'll tell you something,
Sheriff...
I see cops who
lose their way every day...
and I don't like that...
because their ambivalence
is contagious.
They infect those around them.
They're like maggots...
where you find one,
you find a nest...
and I take that
real personally.
I went to the same academy
as our friend there.
Ray? Good man.
I stood by him
at graduation.
He was a beauty.
- He's been good to me.
- Yeah, a real collar man.
To the cop that he was,
to his memory, I am loyal...
but through the fog
of my loyalty, to the men...
the evidence makes me see
and, these days, what I see...
like an island
out of my reach...
I see this beautiful island
shining through this fog...
every house financed
by one of two mob banks.
That's right, Sheriff.
What I see is your town.
No, no you don't see that.
Babitch isn't dead.
You know that and I know that.
Ray got him
off that bridge alive...
before he could talk.
But he wasn't so lucky
the last time when the shit
hit the fan with Tunney.
That boy he took care oflater.
But now what?
What does Ray do now?
That's the $64,000 question.
And that's why I'm here.
That's why I'm here,
Sheriff.
Because you're
on the inside.
And besides the church traffic,
and the cats in the trees...
and all that other bullshit,
okay...
there isn't much here
for you to do
to keep your mind busy.
But I look at you, Sheriff...
and I see a man who's waiting
for something to do.
And here I am.
Here I am saying, "Sheriff...
I got something for you to do."
[Figgis]
#So let's make the most
of this beautiful day #
#Since we're together
we might as well say #
d Would you be mine
Could you be mine d
d Won't you be my neighbor #
You know, Figgsy...
you don't have to sleep
at the station
if you don't want to.
You can stay in my basement
until you find a new place.
[Man]
Let's go.!
It's gonna be a long day,
Poppa!
- Okay, your turn to be a hero.
- [Figgis] Billy heard
they're having a party tonight.
# We had so many
good times #
#And some bad #
- # We shared the happiness #
- I'll take care of it, Phil.
#Shared the sad #
- # We suffered all #
- Hey, Frank, is Ray home?
What, you need us
to turn it down?
- No, I just need to talk to Ray.
- Whoa, come here.
Wait outside there.
- I don't wanna go through this again.
- [Man] It's too fucking bad.
I can't!
I told the boys...
I mean,
they're downstairs now
saying good-bye.
- Ray, how many people you got
at this party? The whole 3-7?
- You got a party downstairs.
Here I am scrambling, cleaning
this thing up for you, and
you're throwing a fuckin' party.
The mayor's gonna suspend
this case.
I'm making it happen tomorrow.!
But sooner or later, Ray,
they gotta find a body in
that river or it will not hold.
Mets, it's
my sister-in-law's kid.!
Didn't you say
he was adopted?
#I'm burnin; I'm burnin'
I'm burning for you #
[Ray] Turn it down.!
- Don't go yet.
- I gotta drive Donna home.
Take her to the train.
Ray, this doesn't make
things very easy for me.
I mean...
This is a pretty big thing
you're having here the day
after. How do you think...
Freddy, what
are you talking about?
This guy came
to see me yesterday,
this Moe Tilden from I.A.
- He brought all these pictures and...
- Freddy.
That guy's had a hard-on
for me for years.
It's a personal thing.
- He is a scumbag.
- All right.
You know how they recruit
at I.A.D.?
They catch you on the take.
And they tell you
you can either do time
or join 'em.
Well, he knows you know
Superboy is...
I told him he was dead, Ray.
I told him he was wrong
about you, but...
I'm the sheriff.
I mean, I'm supposed to know
what's goin' on.
How do you think
this looks?
Go home, Freddy...
and don't think so much.
- Ray, I can't go.
- Freddy...
- Freddy, go home. Go home. Go home.
- I can't go...
[Music, Chattering]
[Man]
Yo, Ross, come over here.
Look at this.
Super.!
It's not Murray.
He's part of a search.
- In Tempe, Arizona.
- Atlanta, Georgia. Atlanta, Georgia.
Murray, Murray.
Listen.
- I want you to have this.
- No, no, Aunt Rose, I'm fine.
Seriously. I gotta go...
Look, Murray, look.
Listen to me.
I want you
to have this.
All right, all right.
You made it for me?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
Hi.
You guys have
another fight?
We were supposed to have
a big talk.
Mmm.
So I sent Caroline
over to my mom's.
And, um...
and Joey called and told me
that he was stuck...
and that he made
some arrest.
I mean, I...
I can't believe him
when he tells me...
anything.
Liz, you wanna
come inside?
[Record]
# I met a little girl
and I settled down #
You can get this on CD,
you know... in stereo.
It wouldn't matter
to me.
All right.
# We got married #
You know, it's a funny thing
when you owe someone your life.
# Then little by little #
# We drifted
from each other's arms #
Why is it
you never got married, Freddy?
#lt was just restlessness #
All the best girls
were taken.
#And it was somethin'more
I guess #
# That tore us apart
and made us weep #
#I'm drivin'a stolen car #
#Down on Eldridge Avenue #
#Each night I wait
to get caught #
#But I never do #
- This is crazy.
- Yes.
All right, take it easy.
All right?
All right, Gabriel,
take it easy.
[Jack]
Murray?
Hey, Murray.!
Ray's outside
waitin'for ya.
- You comin'or what?
- I'm comin', I'm comin'.
That was
a great party, Ray.
You know, Ray,
it's a really great thing
you did.
Makin' a place where everybody
could stick together.
[Murray]
I mean...
you know I know you didn't
have to do this for me.
You could'vejust...
I just...
I wanna let you know
I appreciate it.
I really do.
- Everyone's gone.
- Just us, buddy.
That's it.
I always said to my mom,
"Uncle Ray doesn't like me,
but..."
I always liked you,
Murray.
You just sweat
too much.
- Hey, what's doin'?
- Hey, Superboy.
So what are we gonna do now?
I'm gonna go meet some people?
How does this work?
I've got all my bags packed
and everything, Ray.
Just I'm a little buzzed.
You know, maybe we could
do this tomorrow or something.
I'm really tired, Ray.
- Where's Joey?
- He's working tonight, kid.
Yeah?
Sorry it came out this way,
Murray.
Ah, it's not that bad, Jack.
Yeah, it is, Murray.
[Gunshots]
- Fuck!
- [Joey] What the fuck
is going on here?
What is this?
What are you doin'?
What are you doin', huh?
- Stay outta this.
- What the fuck is this?
Ray, you said P.D.A. Was gonna
set him up with a new life.
You think I'm all that,
Joey?
Ah, fuck it.
Put your files in there.
We're done.
It's over.
- Moe...
- We were shut down by the mayor. Here.
- What the fuck is this?
- Put your files in there.
The case is closed.
Reuben, what are you doin'?
What are you doin'?
- I'm on hold with the
phone company.
- Is that the Garrison file?
Is that a Garrison file?
Give me your Garrison files.
Give me the Garrison files.
- Give me it all. Give me it all.
- All right, all right.
Is that more?
I'll take everything.
The case is closed.
The case is fucking closed!
Closed!
The case is closed, finished,
over!
- Go to lunch.
- L, uh...
Go to lunch!
Go.!
Hey, go to lunch.
Go to lunch!
The case is closed. Everybody,
get the fuck outta here.
Get outta here.!
The case is fucking closed.!
[Radio]
With community leaders
and pundits crying "Cover up,"
Mayor Farelli's suspension
of the Babitch case
is a big gamble...
No one's going to read this.
It's just a bunch of red tape.
- [Groans]
- She's going to fuck up
my insurance claim.
[Cindy]
Don't pull the paper
out of the thing.
- Here's your coffee.
- Okay, Cin, please let's try it his way.
I'm tellin' you,
you don't need
to do this.
It's just a bunch
of bullshit.
[Joey]
What do you want?
Are you gonna help us
or not?
Help you help what?
Help Ray here find him?
Help Ray finish cleaning up
his goddamn pool
with the guy's head?
Is that it?
Huh, Mr. Humanitarian?
You got something
you wanna say to me, Ray?
Or is this about something
a little more personal?
I'm on at 10:00.
I'm outta here.
We all are.
We got another hour.
Hey, come on, Joey.
Instead of taking cop lessons
from a cokehead...
maybe you should be lookin'
at that fire, you know?
My girl over at Chase says Figgs
is missing a few payments.
Where were you that night,
Jack?
I had nothin' to do
with it.
That would be retribution.
And that I leave
to God Almighty.
I'm Gandhi.
[Figgis]
I'm tellin'ya, the mob built
this town for Ray...
so they could own
a fuckin' precinct.
He's a deep and dark
motherfuck.
What you're feelin'
right now, Freddy...
friendless, angry,
nervous, misunderstood...
this is it,
this is the life.
You're lucky your ear
kept you off the force.
You know...
if I saw Liz...
drowning in the water...
If I saw that today...
I wouldn't go in.
I'd stand there,
and I'd think about it.
And that's the best thing
I ever did with my life.
- So?
So you wanna sit around
your whole life wishing
you were on the force?
Or do you wanna bring
the faggot in?
Let him spill.
I wouldn't know where
to begin.
All right.
Brother's in deep shit.
He's down, he's bleeding,
and you gotta get there.
But there's lights, right?
All over the city, red lights.
You go through
the red lights.
Sure, you fire up the roof,
you wail, you go through
the red lights, but that's slow...
fighting your way
through traffic.
The goal is
perpetual motion.
You want greens.
But how do you ensure
the greens?
You can't.
As in life, in traffic.
So what you do
is you leave yourself an out.
At every corner you leave
yourself an alternative.
You move diagonal.
You turn the wheel
when you hit a red light.
You don't drive
down Broadway
to get to Broadway.
If you move diagonal,
you're gonna get
perpetual motion.
That's what you want.
But how does this apply to what
you were saying in there?
It applies, Freddy!
It's just as easy to tail a man
walking in front of him.
Now, you butt heads with these
friends of ours, you're gonna
come at them head-on?
- Okay.
- They got lives, Freddy.
Families.
No.
You move diagonal.
You jag.
[Man] Ah, Christ.!
Where the fuck
are you guys?
[Officer On Radio]
We're on our way...
in 20.
I'm down. But, butJoey,
he's tryin'to hold on...
but this big bastard,
he cut me up.
Stay cool, Tom.
I need your location.
- Agh.! He's a fucking monster.!
- I need your location.!
- I need an assist.
- I can't move.
I think he cut my tendon.
- You got a wife, huh?
Huh? You got a baby?
- [Groans]
Quit!
Tell me you quit.
I'll let you go.
You go home.
Kiss your wife.
Eat your baby's
Fruit Loops and shit.
You thank me, motherfucker,
you're gonna be redeemed.
Re-re-redeemed...
Officer... Randone.
[Sirens Wailing]
[Sirens Wailing,
Tires Screeching]
Shit!
- Motherfucker!
- Shit.
[Siren Wailing]
[People Shouting]
It's the roof, Jack.
You got units sent in.
All right,
I'll check the front.
[Grunting]
Come on, come on.
Son of a bitch!
Agh! Agh!
Please.
[Yelling]
[Grunting, Shouts]
[Joey]
Help.! Help.!
[Joey Groaning,
Shouting]
No! No! No!
[Joey]
No.!
In here!
Joey's in trouble,
Ray.
Ray, let's just break
the fuckin'thing down.
Got it.
[Woman Yelling
In Spanish]
[Yelling Continues]
[Yelling In Spanish
Continues]
[Panting]
His father is serving
a life sentence for murder,
murdering an ex-girlfriend...
- With a sawed-off shotgun back in 1988.
- [Knocking At Door]
- [Knocking Continue]
- The New York Times is quoting
one friend of Royster saying...
that the guy had
an I.Q. Of 160.
[Mouthing Words]
I need your help.
They're tryin'
to kill me.
- Who?
My friends
tried to kill me.
Ray Donlan...
Shit!
Holy shit!
Speak of the devil!
[Panting]
Freddy, forget it.
I don't get this.
This doesn't make
any sense.
Why'd they get Superboy
off the bridge...
bring him back here
and kill him?
[Panting]
Ray had a plan...
and it got
very fucked up.
[Figgis]
You awake, Freddy?
[Figgis Coughing]
Aw, I feel like shit.
Fuckin'allergy
that's killin'me.
Hey.
##[Drumbeats]
##[Drumbeats Continue]
[Minister] In sure and
certain hope of the resurrection
to eternal life...
through our Lord,
Jesus Christ...
we commend to Almighty God
our brotherJoseph...
and we commit his body
to the ground.
The Lord bless him
and keep him.
The Lord make His face
to shine upon him
and be gracious unto him.
The Lord lift up
His countenance upon him,
and give him peace.
[Officer]
Honor Guard, retreat.
[Train Rumbling]
- No, I don't know.
- [Carson] What the hell
are you doing?
- [Freddy] I just, uh...
I got, I got...
- Call you back.
- Excuse me. I'm sorry.
- Moe, I apologize.
He just walked in here.
I'm sorry for rushing in
like this, but you were right.
They tried to kill him
like you said,
but he got away.
Now he's runnin' through
the woods. He's like a scared
animal. He's scared to death.
That motherfucker
should be scared.
His uncle
got this case closed
with one phone call.
Look, I'm sorry it took so long
for me to come around,
but you were right.
I couldn't see the truth.
Like you said, the evidence,
my loyalty, they were confusing.
They never give you
any napkins in this place.
[Moe] What am I
supposed to use?
You want this?
What is this?
You came to me,
to my town...
with all these speeches,
talking to me about
doing the right thing.
I'm doing the right thing.
What's goin' on?
What are you doing?
That was like
two weeks ago.
Two weeks ago?
What about Babitch?
What about him?
Fuck him.
- What about Donlan?
- Fuck him too.
What about
Joey Randone?
He fell off a building.
Don't you read the papers?
Listen, Sheriff,
I'm really sorry...
to have awoken you
from your slumber,
but it's over.
Hands are tied now.
You shut me down.
No, listen to me. You're I.A.
That's why I came to you.
You can do whatever you want.
Remember you came to me, said,
"You wanna be a cop?"
I'm bein' a cop.
- I offered you a chance.
- I'm asking you for some help.
I need to do something.
- I need to do this for myself.
- Listen, you deaf fuck.
I offered you a chance.
When we could have done
something, I offered you
a chance to be a cop...
and you blew it!
You blew it.
You people
are all the same.
That cupcake makes a mess,
we got a case again.
[Sighs]
The mob runs millions in drugs
through their precinct...
and everybody gets
a nice house.
Figgs is right.
The mob owns this town.
[Deputy]
They closed the case, Freddy.
If they don't have...
- The stomach for it...
- They had to. It's circumstantial.
[Cindy]
You don't have anything
either.
All that stuff is illegal.
You stole it.
I know this guy.
He's a corrections officer.
[Sighs]
They took care ofTunney
when he was gonna talk.
Then how come Figgis didn't do
somethin' about it? He was
Ray's right-hand man back then.
Then they tried
to kill Superboy.
They were hiding him,
Freddy.
Then they burned down
Figgsy's house when they think
he might talk.
You don't know that.
We went over every inch
of that house.
Not everything is
a hexagonal conspiracy.
I think you been hangin'
around Figgs too much.
He's the only one getting cash
out of that house,
and he's totally playing you...
just like those assholes
in the city.
And I'm sorry,
but... there's nothing
you can do about this.
Yes, there is.
I can find Superboy
and I can bring him in.
I'm going back upstate.
I want my old job back.
I don't want any part
of this.
of this place.
Come on, Cindy.
- [Door Slams Shut]
- Geez.
Freddy, look, I don't know
about Ray, okay?
But everyone in Garrison
is not a murderer.
No. They just keep
their eyes closed and
their mouths shut just like me.
[Shouting]
##[Carnival]
Hey, Freddy.
[Crowd Cheering]
All right, thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you, sweetheart.
I love you too.
All right,
terrific.
Two in the center?
Uh-uh. No.
Rules are different
for cops.
- I'm losin' my shirt here with you guys.
- So what do I got to do?
- Five out of six in the star.
- Five out of six.
- Hey, Freddy.
- You a cop too?
Yeah, yeah,
I heard ya.
Enjoy your trip
to the big city?
You gotta hit the next five
to win.
[Gunshots]
Shit.!
[Liz]
I just hope you're not trying
to prove anything, Freddy.
I know some of them
are real assholes.
You know.
They think they're high priests
or somethin'. I don't know.
But why would they do all this?
You know, maybe they're doin'
the right thing.
Liz, I saw these pictures
of Ray meeting with these guys.
- You know, like mobsters.
- [Sighs]
- Everyone's houses are financed
by these mob banks.
- Says who? I.A.?
Even you said Joey's death
was no accident.
Joey fell off
a building, Freddy!
Okay?
Now, I don't need this
opened up.
Maybe you do. I don't.
All Joey wanted was a place
for us to live.
Now, who are you
to judge that until
you've walked in his shoes?
Maybe that's what you're tryin'
to do with me.
What're you gonna do,
Freddy?
Huh?
You gonna arrest
the whole town?
You goin' to New York to take
"paint by number" cop lessons?
You know, Ray likes you.
That don't mean
I'm gonna let you fuck him over.
Ray Donlan
gave you this job, Freddy.
You forgot that?
We made your sorry ass!
So now you can do us
a favor, huh?
You could tell us...
[Gun Cocks]
Where Superboy is.
If I knew where he was,
he'd be in the city already.
You're gonna be hurtin',
Freddy.
You're not gonna know when,
you're not gonna know where.
You're gonna be hurtin'.
You mark my words.
I'm watchin' you!
[Door Slams Shut]
[Footsteps]
Hey.
- You got your check.
- Yep.
Thanks to you, Freddy.
Filing out those forms
in such a timely fashion.
Hmm.
- You with Liz?
- Mm-hmm.
Where're ya goin'?
[Chuckles]
I don't know.
My leave came,
so I thought I'd look around
for a new reality. You know?
Anyway,
I'm sure you could use
your privacy, Freddy.
[Sniffs]
No, no.
[Door Slams Shut]
Look all you want,
Freddy.
You're not gonna find
anything.
I took care of it.
That lady cop...
from the Bomb Squad
got you the stuff
to do this with, didn't she?
You didn't know Monica
was gonna be here.
Did you, Figgs?
No.
Monica said...
she was going over
to her friend's house
to watch some pay-per-view.
The thing was on a timer.
I didn't know she was
gonna be here, Freddy.
It's all bullshit.
You, Figgs,
are the bullshit!
Smarten fuckin' up!
You even turned your back
on Tunney
when he needed your help.
Figgs!
I'm gonna find Superboy,
and I'm gonna bring him in.
And for once,
everybody in this town's
gonna tell the truth.
- You gotta find him first,
Freddy!
- I'll find him.
Listen to me. I got a check in
my pocket for $200,000. I got
a chance to start my life again.
I don't give a shit
about this town. I don't
give a shit about that town.
And I don't give a shit
about your fucking justice.
Bein' right is not
a bulletproof vest, Freddy.
Go on, Figgsy!
Go on.!
Run away.!
[Tires Screeching]
[Dog Barking]
Hey, Freddy.
- Ray's not home.
- I know.
I'm lookin'
for your nephew.
I don't know where
he is.
Why the hell would I tell you
if I did?
Rose,
I'm his only chance.
[Gun Trigger Clicks]
Let's go.
You workin' with the feds?
No.
- I.A.?
- No.
You're alone.
Let's go.
- Oh, shit.
- All right. Get down. Get down.
- And stay down.
- Bill, where are you?
- [Radio Crackling]
Bill, if you read,
we're going back
to the station.
You gonna keep me
in here?
in here with cuffs?
- You don't know
what you're doing do you?
- Shut up.
You don't have a clue
as to what the fuck
is going on, do you, Sheriff?
- [Radio Static]
- Bill, do you copy?
- Bill, do you read?
- [Radio Static]
[Chattering]
- It's just club soda, Freddy.
- Finish it.
Hey, Ray.
Hey, Freddy.
I came to tell you
that I found Superboy...
and I'm bringing him in
tomorrow morning...
and I'd like you
to come with me,
I owe you that much.
He's a fugitive,
and he's convinced
you're tryin' to kill him.
Just tell me
where he is, Freddy.
You got him at the station?
Ray, there's gotta be a way
out of this for everyone.
So, I say why don't we all
go in tomorrow together.
Listen to me, Freddy.
You know the difference
between men and boys?
Boys bet everything
on everything.
Boys think every hand
is a royal flush.
You play cards with a man,
he knows his limits.
Freddy,
I invited men...
cops, good men...
to live
in this town.
And these men,
to make a living, they cross
that bridge every day...
to a place where everything
is upside down.
Where the cop is the perp,
and the perp is the victim.
But they play by the rules.
They keep their guns
in their holsters,
and they play by the rules.
The only thing they did
was to get their families out...
before it got
to them.
We made a place
where things make sense...
and you can walk
across the street without fear.
And you come to me with a plan
to set things right.
Everyone in this city
holding hands, singing
"We Are the World."
That's very nice.
But, Freddy, your plan
is the plan of a boy.
You made it on the back
of a matchbook
without thinking!
Without looking
at the cards.
I look at the cards.
I see this town...
destroyed.
Now, that's not
what you want, is it?
I look at this town...
and I don't like
what I see anymore.
Who the fuck
do you think you are?
The sheriff of Garrison,
New Jersey.
Then be the sheriff!
Defend this town!
Protect these men!
Freddy, you got him
at the station?
- Just drop the keys.
- A little too rich for my blood.
Maybe they fell
out of your pocket...
or maybe Cindy's.
Now you go home
and you sleep...
and you wake up
and you guide the traffic
through this town...
and everything will be
the way it was.
[Sighs] I'm taking him in
tomorrow morning at 6:00.
That's in a few hours.
I'd like you to come
with me, Ray.
There's nothing
I can say?
Okay, then 6:00 it is.
Yeah.
No, Lis.
Who was he
supposed to call?
Ray knows
everybody.
What am I supposed to do?
Let him go in alone? What?
You know what?
Okay, fine.
Why don't you
go home?
I mean...
I wanna be here for you,
Freddy, but...
[Sighs]
Lisa's nervous, you know.
She's pregnant.
- I mean...
- So, go on. I'll be fine.
You be careful,
Freddy, huh?
Yeah. You too.
Shut the fuck up!
Would ya, please?
Sh... Fuck!
[Brakes Squealing]
Come on.
Oh, shit!
Get out, you jackass.
I said, get out, buddy.
Oh, Jesus. You guys
don't wanna do this. Jack.
- Don't shit in your pants.
He's not gonna kill ya.
- This is the good one, right?
[Screaming]
Oh, God! Oh, God!
- [Freddy Groaning]
- Move, move, move!
[Groaning]
All right, hit it, Jackie.
Hit it, Jack!
[Screaming]
[Tires Screeching]
[Groaning]
[Shrill Screeching]
In Ear]
[Throbbing]
[Barking Inaudibly]
[Screeching Continues]
[Speaking Inaudibly]
[Speaking Inaudibly,
Gunshot]
[Inaudible]
Jesus Christ!
You fuck!
[Gunshot]
[Inaudible]
Freddy!
[Gunshot]
[Inaudible Mumbling]
I can't hear you,
Ray.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
- [Brakes Squealing]
Hey, hey, hey,
What're you doin'?
Excuse me, Lieutenant.
Come on, guys, it's cool.
Everything's cool.
Everything's cool. Come on.
Come on. Everything's cool.
- Where the hell are you goin'?
- Please move.
Holy shit!
[Figgis]
Guys, guys, guys.
Beat it. Beat it.
Everything's fine.
It's cool.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
- What the fuck?
[Figgis] Come on, Freddy.
Everything's cool.
Everything's fine.
- Wait, wait, wait. Where do
you think you're goin'?
- Call E.M.S. Call E.M.S.
Come on, fellas, back up.
Back up. Back up.
Back up.
- He can't hear.
- Reubens, take him.
- Hey, hey, it's all right.
It's okay. It's okay.
- They blew out his ear.
It's all right.
It's all right!
It's okay.
Come on.
Go on, Freddy.
Come on inside.
Come on.
[Moe]
So Gary Figgis copped a plea.
Gave up the connection between
Ray, the P.D.A. And the mob.
There were a shitload
of indictments.
And the sheriff,
Freddy Heflin...
You know, there's people
on both sides of the river
wish he never recovered.
They cursed the day
he took down Ray Donlan.
But what they don't know,
he figured out.
No one is above the law.
[Reporter #1]
Four cops dead,
and one dead cop resurrected.
In a bizarre twist, Murray
"Superboy"Babitch sits alive
and well in a holding cell...
[Reporter #2]
Sheriff Fred Heflin apprehended
Babitch single-handedly.
[Reporter #3]... he will
be recovering the hearing in his
good ear so that's good news.
[Reporter #4] Files
were seized this morning...
[Reporter #5]
Officer Gary Figgis testified
about mob influence and bribery.
[Reporter #6]
Three months since the shootout
in Garrison, NewJersey...
reputed mob boss Toy Torillo
has been indicted on four counts
of racketeering.
[Reporter #7]
An unidentified corrections
officer was arrested today...
for the murder three years ago
of Officer Glenn Tunney.
[Reporter #8] I understand
Jim Allen is with the mayor.
Do you want to go back to him?