Oh God,
God grant me the serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change
why did you fight it so hard, Earl?
Courage to change the
things that I can...
come one!
You have been a good boy
for a long time
you know you wanna do this
and the wisdom...
...wisdom to know the difference
Taking, as He did,
This sinful world
as it is, Not as I would have it
Trusting that He will make all
things right, lf I surrender to His will,
that I may be reasonably
happy in this life
And supremely happy with
Him forever and next.
Amen
I could go on and on
about what a great guy here he is
how he give us so freely his time
and his money
even how he, uh, believing
how he cuts his toenails
let's get him here and speak
for himself
ladies and gentlemen
I'll give you a business man,
philanthropist, a very dear friend
and the Portland Chambers Commerce
Man of the Year
Mr. Earl Brooks
thank you all
very much
uhm...
first thing i'd like to say is that I, uh...
i don't even know how i cut my toenails
20... years ago
when I started the Brook's box factory
i never dream that i will...
I never dream that one day
i'll be standing here
did you... did you just see
Sis Wallace's dress?
You can see her nipples
at that age!
Wow, she cannot keep those
things hidden
the only thing that would have made
this evening more perfect...
if is Jane had been here
Emma, she called to
congratulate me, right?
She has mid terms coming up
I think she's dropping out
let's see
nothing she does is wrong with you, is it?
Well...
she missed a good party
it's not like it's not set up
you already know I don't like
pesty and lambs
you know i don't pick the lock
no
you are the fucking man of the year
you deserve a treat
no, Marshall, I said no
I heard you...
but you don't mean no
what's wrong?
Nothing
[laughing]
You are flowning
I'm thinking about what I didn't say
in the speech
oh...
honey
you were so... moving
you made us all laugh
i don't think anybody fold left down
they have their dance class tonight
you can just drive by...
...and look at them
there's not harming,
and just having a look
no, means no, Marshall
please...
put it, please
[laughing]
I though the food tonight was very good
but I was not crazy about the dessert
would you like to stop somewhere
and get something sweet?
Ok
norad is an adorable small dog
the labrador is supposed
to be brave
Goltys, when he goes into the trailer
is very happy...
don't let me do this,
don't let me do this, please
I don't wanna start again
you promised to, you promised to
please... please
why did you figth it so hard, Earl?
I'm going to stay up a while
maybe going to the studio or
play with some glaciers
ok
I'm gonna read... and If I'm not awake,
wake me when you come back
anyway?
I though you were wonderful tonight
Mrs Brooks
thank you Mr. Brooks
oh, I love the road my boy!
I have missed this...
we are going to have so much fun
this is the last time Marshall,
Understand me? It's the very last time!
Don't you dare, going on your
business, shut up
I wanna see what they are doing
hello
what the fuck!!!
Be quiet!
Set up!
Uh, Earl
what the fuck is this?
These fucking pigs like to do
with the curtains open
You should have know now this
is a big mistake for you, Earl
almost like a wanted get caught
on, Marshall
I don't fucking do that
I don't think either what a joy is to spend
the rest of your life on death row
or a lethal injection
Yes, Sir
please, forgive me
you are fucked hard,
Earl. I don't give you that
don't even think about it
you know the rules
now upstairs, make love with your
beautiful wife
can we have the room, please?
Thank you
there's just a thumbprint,
right there
one his, one hers?
That was really nice
this guy has not been acting
for over 2 years
he always rearranges the bodies
but this is weird, I care of dare
usually he is much more romantic
arms around each other, kissing...
mouths open, tongues touching
bullets from straight of the victims
killer would covered this a lot
these were open or closed
when you got here?
Closed
could it be the work
of a copycat?
That's never been or viewed to the public
that the killer will treat his logs
Jesus, I was hoping this guy
was out or dead
or in jail or in some other charge
we checked all neighbourhood,
but so far nobody saw a thing
maybe he don't like this... he must to be
really angry at them for some reason
where do they keep their vacuum cleaner?
So I bet you 100 bucks, Hawkins,
there is not bag in this vacuum cleaner
I have not idea of what the hell you are look for
he vacuums the house...
and took the bag
what if he kills somebody that did
never get a vacuum cleaner?
He won't do that!!
Our best hope is if someone in
there saw something
detective Tracy Atwood?
- Yes
- this is for you
you've been served
You, fucking asshole
- I am in the middle of a fucking
murdering investigation
- Listen lady
- i'm just a messanger, here
- Hawkins,
what's the deal?
I don't know it
get his ass out of here!!
What it is?
Assume to be, my ex husband
scumbag lawyer's trying to show me,
just how painful she can make my life
if i don't give them what they want
other any new members?
Hello my name Voine
I am alcoholic, and I haven't had a drink
in 10 months
hi, my name is Earl, and...
I am an addict
anyone else?
You are...
such a fuck hypocrite
if you run and you step up there and say
Hi, I'm Ear and I've killed two people last night
I really got off on it but I need your help,
to be cured
I'm different Marshall, i won't argue
that with you
this it is the only place that as ever
helped me be normal, and i've been straight up
untill last night...
for the past 2 years
I not going to kill again
and I am not going to quit coming here
because it upsets you
we need a clean up crew for afterwords, so...
we need some volunteers
for the...
oh, thank you Earl, I appreciate that
there's time for requirements,
this is our first to tempt
"Mr. Brooks, your daughter
is waiting for you in your office"
Well I hope this is what you have in mind,
if not...
we would love to work with you,
further on the design
always find the challenge on machines
now if you uh, gentlemen, will you excuse me
i need to see how much this is going to cost me
Understand
daughter cost money, me too
I believe you do understand
Uh, Matt Johnson, wants to schedule,
lunch for friday, contact him...
- Sunday, did...
- Can you hold this for a second?
Did Jane call to say she was coming?
Uh, nobody gave me that
message Mr. Brooks
- she is...
- yeah, she is, and...
she has some boxes and suitcases downstairs
and she didn't have any money for the cab
and you paid for that
thank you
welcome
ah, hold my calls
sure
I told you
when it's appropriate
you let me know
Ehy, can I've some water?
Hello gorgeous
what are you doing here?
I'm sorry daddy
please, don't be angry with me
I can guess what you've done
but why don't you tell me then I'll decide
I've dropped out the school
oh Jane
ok
uh... have you told your mother?
No, I wanted to talk to you first
Well, you gonna have to tell her, Jane
All right?
I'm not gonna do that for you
why can't you...
sit!
And then,
together, the three of us, we decide
where it goes from here
Well, I thought a lot all about this?
College is a waste of time for me
All this...
All this... how somebody know that,
half way through their freshmen year?
You didn't even go to college daddy
and you are successful
I wanna come work for you
she is not telling you everything,
she is hiding something
hell no!
I am not hiring right now, sweetheart
ok, but just listen to me
for one second
all right?
Look! What happen to the business if,
God forbid, something wouldn't happen to you?
Ok
mom would probably have to
sell the strangers
look, I willing to start from the bottom
you can treat me like a regular employee
I just wanna learn everything there is to know
about running the box business
then, when the time comes...
i can stay in the family
all that's sweet, honey, but
you are not talking about business,
you are talking about emotions, now get up...
infact, Your mother and I, came...
this close to selling out last year
what?
That's right, and hadn't will been offered
a little more money
and still, may come back to us...
we would sell
what would you do without business?
Yes?
I'm sorry. The man outside insisted
that I'll give this to you, he claims
that you'll find what's inside,
very interesting
what is he, Sunday?
Is he a salesman?
No, I've never seen him before
I'll just give him back and
I'll tell him to call
No, Sunday, Sunday, here...
Thank you
Jane
********* for you a psychologist
to give yourself a chance to...
uh, find out...
who you are
and what you wanna do
I'll talk to mom
but I not going back to school
and where would you live?
Saved money, i'll look back home
but new rules,
I wanna be treated as adult
would you pay for rent?
Would you pay for food?
No dad, you are a very welfy man
I think you can effort to keep me
Sunday, would you escort the gentleman
who gave you the envelope...
into the conference room and tell him
i would meet him there?
No problem, Mr Brooks
and, uh...
what happen to the BMW, Jane?
A friend is gonna drive it up
but he will be here week-end
and get Jane a cab
call your mother
are you gonna gimme a job?
If you were up to me and I think
your mother will agree with this, I, uh...
I think you should go back to school
you see that Marshall?
That's why I didn't wanna
do that damned couple
stop with fucking widing your own
you enjoyed doing that couple
just as as much I did
and look at the right side
he cames to us,
he didn't go to the cops
if he's trying to shake us down,
we kill him, period.
We make it fun but we'll kill him
end of the story
what can I do for you, Mister...
Let's say... Smith
Ok Mr. Smith
before you get the wrong impression,
Mr Brooks, I'm not here to shake you down
I hope this is the only copies of
these photos and you have no others
no
I have other copies and other photos
and if anything happens to me...
how did you find me Mr. Smith?
You are the man of the year, Mr. Brooks
your picture is in the paper
and if it had not been... I don't know,
I don't know what I would have done
lucky me
what is it that I can help you with?
I've been watching that couple
for months
yeah, they liked to make love
with the blinds opened
sometimes I would... take pictures
visual aids, for later
is a great way to get off, I tell you that
was fun, I though
until I saw you killed them
and I have never
ever felt out that... rush!!
Like that, ever
I know you are the thumbprint killer
you have done this before
what I want?
It's for you, to take me with you
next time you kills someone
and I'd like that to be soon
[laughing]
And you were worried this
was going to be unpleasant?
The answer is simple
Just tell Mr. Smith that you have decided
never to kill again
and you're going away
you enjoy watching me suffer, don't you?
In a word, yes
where do you think he has
the other pictures?
He put it in a safety deposit box
but I bet the box is in the banks
where he keeps his checking account
and the key...
it's on his key chain
he really wants us to do this
he is not going to the cops
we have a deal?
For the angle of these pictures...
you live at the 3rd floor at apartment building
across the alley, front of the couple house
uh
yes or no, Mr. Smith?
Yes
what time did you get home from work?
6.30
7, depending of the traffic
you can't never come here again
you can't never call me
do you understand that?
Yes
tomorrow night
not tonight, tomorrow night at 8 o'clock
leave your apartment building and walk east
I will pick you up there
if you are thinking about doing anything...
for both to aware the rules, Mr. Smith
but I feel I must warn you
if it turns out that you enjoy killing
you can become very addicted
it can ruins your life
I wanna do this
have I covered everything?
I can't think of anything else
then I'll see you tomorrow night Mr. Smith
we've talked to our client and
in common we put here what we figure out,
we feel this is more than fair
we can have a check for that
amount in your office by 6pm o'clock
oh, we told you at the beginning
what we wanted
and it hasn't changed
we feel our offer is more than generous
I paid for everything, when we were together
and now I'm been asked to give
this guy a bonus?
For spending time with me, time
that I've already paid for in the first place?
You know as well as I do, counselor,
you're not gonna get a million five
Oh, I - don't - know that, no, I...
well, infact, this is the front page
of yesterday's paper
"Hangman escapes"
after torturing his victims
Thorton Meeks
well, hide him in public places,
church steeple, balconies,
freeways over passes...
where this is going?
Well, your client captures Mr. Meeks
Come on Tracy, this is not a lot of money
for you
and we both know how afraid that I was
after Meeks says that he was gonna
escape and come back to kill you
let me ask again
what is your point?
Our point is that Meeks,
or someone like Meeks
make hurt after my client in order
to hurt your client
that is very imaginative, counsellor
but it's not based in reality at all
Jesse
let's just handle this, please
- Tracy
- Jesse
you know what will make me
feel really safe right now?
If you got hit by a truck...
and die
well, that's it?
Mr. Vialo and I, are leaving
you are threatening the safety of my client,
we are going after to get a straight order
we see in court
you hit by a truck and die?
Fuck it, I felt good
what was here it's not here,
that's interesting
I hate the number,
I'll say that this people been
killed by a ghost
the autopsy said there was a little tiny
piece of plastic in the female victim's brain
it's a dead end, the bag with the gun,
he puts one gallon plastic foresinc bag
over his hand to his wrist
little bit of plastic comes out,
when the first one is gonna shots,
it goes in the bag
are you looking for me?
I've received the subpena from your husband
for your works records
where you worked, date and time,
for the past two years
he just tries to blackmail me, do you remember?
My lawyers assure me that I'll never go to court
I can't take that chance
almost three courts of your cases is a current
so, until you'll set your divorce
i'm gonna have to put you on the desk
that's also blackmail
do you have any idea what this
guy has done to me?
While we're married,
while i was paying for everything
he was just out and fuck every woman
he can gets his hands on
he fucked my friends, he fucked my cousin
he made me look as an idiot
- and?
- And what?
Get over it!
You can't roll there's a woman wanna
have this one blousy man in your life
well, I made him an offer
and I won't goin to give him a dime more
did you hear that Meeks escaped?
Yeah
you get gonna looking for him,
you want me yo put a detail on you?
I think I can take care of myself
it's one of your biggest problem, Tracy
you don't know how to ask for help
what the fuck, what the fuck, what...
don't worry, if I were here to kill you,
you were already be dead
[panting]
After you left today, I realize that our friendship
was a little one side of it
so, tomorrow night when we meet,
would you be so kind us to bring
all the pictures and the memory
card from your camera
that way we can like each other
simply for who we are
if you don't show up
I will presume that you have gone
to the police and I will kill you
even if I'll go to jail because of you Mr Smith,
someone will find you, wherever you are...
and they will kill you
Mr. Brooks
WoW
it's nice to have you home
hello, hello. You have to explain this to me
'cause i'm your mother, that's why!
What's wrong, girls?
I asked your daughter what's the real reason
she dropped out the school
I told you, it's not the real reason
honey...
you wanted to go to college
you have good grades, your father
put in favours to get you in that school
if this is not the reason...
please, Dear God, tell me the reason
what is your mother thinking
even dropped you out the school?
I'm pregnant
but that's not the reason I dropped out
being pregnant wouldn't keep me
for going to school if I wanted to
who is the father?
Some guy a was seeing
some, some guy, does he knows?
What he knows Dad?
He is married, he got two kids,
I want nothing to do with me
oh, honey
I'm not gonna go throw with it
there is nothing to be upset about
I mean, I was even not
gonna tell you guys
then would be
no abortion, jane
no Dad, you're not gonna tell
me what to do, ok?
It's my body and I'll do what I want with it
I'm sorry, you're right. I said it wrong
I wasn't trying to tell you
what to do when I was...
what I was trying to say is that...
a grandchild would be a wonderful gift
for your mother and me
would you really wanna
have a grandchild?
Even if I'm not married?
Yes
a child is what's important
we would... we would love him
and cheer him completely and we would...
we would help you raise him
if it means that much to you,
I will think about it
I'm gonna have to start getting up
little earlier, uh, honey?
Well, we were right
she was hiding something
pregnancy is not of all of it,
she's hiding something bigger
something much bigger
you think so?
I know so
and so do you
it's darker tonight than it was
on your night
but still...
how did you managed to not bumping
into the furniture?
Was the light on?
Or did you turn it on?
Because I know you and you
won't risk a shot in the dark
where have you been?
Did you miss the thrill of killing?
What if these are stayed closed
because you yanked them closed
which would mean...
they were open...
...when you came into the room
thank you, I appreciate your time
ops, sorry, i'm sorry
no, I'm sorry
I was just about to knock
I'm detective Atwood,
portland police
hey, do you wanna see me?
Fine
you are a photographer Mr...
...Bafford?
- No
- No?
Thank you
no,
uh, actually it's... a hobby i just started
well, do you know, there was a murder?
Yes, in the house, close the way
You didn't happen to see something unusual or
suspicious that night, did you?
No, I wondered that when it happened, but
no
I'm sorry, i'm supposed to be meeting somebody
and I don't want to be late
uh, well, here is my card
if you did hear something or
remember anything
uh, i wish I could be more helped,
but, uh, sorry!!
He looks clean
looks like he's alone
no, i tell you, he really
wants to do that
maybe I should plow with
him... pick him up
no, just honk
maybe he get killed crossing the street
and save us the mess he's doing up
[laughing]
Almost
it's coming down hard
they said would be sunny tomorrow
I never trust those guys
they say it's gonna be clear, then rains
and they say it's gonna rains
and it's... sunny
I believe this is what you asked for
the pictures in the memory card...
all here
both
you and I both know that not all
the pictures are in here
and you made a copy of the
memory card, as an asshole
but, you understand my position?
Yes, I do
but it's my hope you want to get to know me better
you feel confortable in giving me everything
that I've asked you for
sounds fair
maybe you'll be interested in this
this is the police woman,
who is looking for you
wow, we never know anyone
was looking for us before
you have to find everything there
is to know about this...
woman
this is close, Marshall
this is to damn close
so...
what's the plan?
Where do we, uh, what are we
doing here tonight?
We'll drive around until we see
someone we think we might
enjoy killing
really?
You don't have have somebody...
in mind
I don't enjoy this Mr. Smith, I do it
because I am addicted to it
before you're in in my life I had that
I would never kill again
so, this is... your part
you can choose anyone you want
and we will do it together
can i pick somebody that I know?
[Laughing]
No
you'll never kill someone you know
it's the easiest way to get caught
- ok?
- Yeah
locked up?
You look a little bit like that...
E.T. Guy
remember that movie?
When he flies on that bike?
- Yeah, yeah
- yeah
I like that movie
Jesus Christ
fuck him
this is fault, he is an asshole
fuck you
maybe Mr Smith would like to kill
the driver of the pick up
what about the driver of the pick up?
What if we kill him?
Yes
yes, I always wanted to fucking kill somebody
fucking to be in traffic
well, if you want to kill the driver of pick up
I'll give you the honor
ehy, maybe not be the same
driver
ok
well, driver I am, to will give a good
looking at him or her
any problem to kill a woman?
No, no. An asshole is an asshole
[laughing]
I wasn't in town that night
my roommate was, maybe he
saw something
Uh, may I speak to him?
He is in on his way to Tokyo right now,
he is also a flight attendant
did the victims ever leave their
bedroom curtains open?
All the time
I don't know if we can see them doing it
and that's why you are asking but they didn't care
well, here is my card
if you can have your roommate call me
and people of this number
know how to reach me at everytime,
day and night
I won't be here, but
I will leave him a note
ok great, thank you
sure
would recognize him if you saw his
driving licence picture?
Yeah
I'll memorize the licence number,
you write it down
I got it
wow
well, when you get home,
go on the Internet
find everything you can...
about this guy
we are gonna kill him tonight?
No
we could, but then we won't be
under control
we can leave lose ends but
we both know the danger of that
ok, I will do
what are... we... doing?
What are you doing?
Look at me!
- Look at me!
- Why?
- Close your eyes
- why?
Close
what's the licence plate number?
Shit
P4...
no
2, uh
I know I tore, then
because of the tree?
Don't feel bad
I've been doing this a long time.
Pen and paper
look out the window and write it down
how is your first time like?
You really don't wanna know
that much about me, Mr. Smith
no, I don't think it was right, go back
ok, we are in
for all the taxes we pay you think
they'll make it more difficult
to hack into the police personnel file
the father is John Atwood, why...
why does that ring a bell?
Somebody you got business with?
Someone we...
killed
no, no somebody we killed
let me see here, MBA
and married, she has been a cop for 12 years
married Dr. Carlson
divorced Dr. Carlson married at
Jesse Vialo
and so two are separated, from
Jesse Vialo sue
...for support by Jesse Vialo seems
uhm, seem a shrimp
because of Jesse Vialo
who, who, who
she has caught a lot of people
and look here, this is not her first time
she has been looking for us
ok, here we are
Jesse Vialo, good looking, a little
younger than she is
younger, rest of all to her
she married him in a rebound
from the doctor
and the boy has married her for money
and connections
just because the old men that
doesn't mean she is rich
maybe is one of the kind of guys
ready to give her to the oprah
and than to his kids
what does she have to declare?
Any outside and coming holdings?
Oh, you are a...
you are a genius
the oprah didn't get much
why would a woman,
worth 60 plus million dollars...
and probably more to come...
wanna be a cop?
I like that about her
you are a such a fucking snob, Earl
you like her because she is rich
no, i like her because she founds
something that's hers,
is not the family business,
and she is good at it
I'd like Jane to find something it's... hers
and than she can be good at it
That's exactly why I would scare
the shit out of me
she's a cop who doesn't need the money...
and she is looking for us.
That's one fucking dangerous human being
the fact you are not wrong
just not making me me admire her
any less
hey Nancy!!
Hi Tracy,
thank you for meeting me here
I got your latte
you wanna be walk and talk
while I hear your big idea?
Oh, sure
you really wanna settle this?
If I can
I'd like to use your father
no
my father does nothing for nothing
Tracy, I understand but your father
has a lot of political massed
his poll won't make everything go away
but it would be a tremendous help
absolutely not
you're right
we could have done this one on the phone
if you will wanna play the game
right on the desk for a year
- i'm sure we can settle it at 1,25 - 1,5...
- uff, I...
I'm not sit on a desk
an the only other option is your father
or money
1,5 and that's it
ok
I'll call them today
I just need to get this done as
soon as possible
that's what Jesse is counting on
I'll call you when I have something
oh, Tracy
your husband said there's a picture of him
holding some trophy, that you still have?
What picture? He has everything
he claims it's his favourite picture
and you put it up when you store
your suitcases
I'll look
I Know?
Petty, you are going to divorce
thanks for the latte
I told you I was coming back to get you
how do you find the place where
i'm gonna hang you?
First
I'm gonna watch her
have some fun with you
then she is gonna watch me,
you know...
don't fucking move!!
Shoot me!
Come on, shoot me, motherfucker
5 down
"sleeper's dimmer"...
..."sleeper's dimmer"
incubus
maybe he go home with someone else
can you still see his pick up?
Uh, uh
this is not the kind of guy
who use his pick up in an
unguarded lot over night
how do you know that?
Somebody didn't do their
homework last night
"time saw years willing"
let me get it, the engine gear
yeah!
Where do we know that guy from?
You really sure I pay more attention
that what you really, Earl?
That's what I have you for, Marshall
His picture was on the frontpage
of the papers a couple of days ago
because he escapes from jail
he is the killer they call "The Hangman"
you remember that cop?
Who you like?
Atwood?
Who is chasing us?
She is the one put him away
wow, wow
what would life be...
without surprises!
There it is!
Ah, ah
i'm in hot wild
this guy has been get also his plans
for tonight and tomorrow night
he has not idea, he'll already be dead
he will not be able to do anything
I don't think I wanna kill this guy
what?
Oh, ahi...
what - you - are - thinking?
You have no idea of what I'm thinking
yes I do
and it's wondefully twisted
wait a minute, are you...
uh... you promised?
I know I said we would
but I don't think would be that much fun
so, that is?
Just no
Yes
- uh, oh
- so...
you got the licence plate?
Yeah
they found the Van in an underground parking
lot about two miles from where they left you
they stolen it last night
we are checking security camera tapes
if Meeks and the woman are left in a car
we'll have her licence plate number
these other women we have pictures
over on Meeks
no one of the attendents
remember seeing them
what about that crackhead of Alvin Griffit.
The one have sold Meeks steroids?
We have tap on his phone even
since Meeks escaped
no contacts there so far
and sure he is not gonna talk to us
what about a warrant to search the house?
You'll get me in the door and he'll talk to me
how is your divorce going?
I took your advice, I told my lawyer to settle
none of this is the woman in the van
Whoa, I'm trying to suture up here
and your ego can handle that?
Not but he dosn't likes the other choices
because the FBI is wiring hard on me
to take over the tumbprint killer
until Meeks is caught, Hawkins is with you
nothing personal Hawkins but i don't think
you'll take a bullet for me
If I won't take the bullet,
I might push you out the way
I'll give two days and I want
a progress report of your divorce
ok, I have all the pieces
for the tumbprint killer
I'm just not looking at the right way
I'll keep the FBI out of it for three days
shh, that is ugly
Mr. Smith wants you to notice
that he's pounding
yes, i know
I know you are upset Mr. Smith
and I am sorry.
Yeah. I'm upset
maybe I was a little brute back,
but let me explain
finding someone you think will
be fine to kill, it's a bit like...
...it's a bit like fallen in love,
if you mean love you can addict,
you like some of them and they're nice
But they are not right
and the special one comes alone
and your heart... it beats faster
And you know... that's the one.
The man in the pick up
not make my heart beat faster
Ok
the man did't make your heart beat faster.
Then Who?
I don't know but i think...
...I think I have someone in mind.
Do you want me to do some work on it?
No, let's just...
let's just see how it plays out
that's what I'm talking about,
that's my problem.
That... that makes me feel
like i'm been joked around
was supposed to be last nigth,
it's not gonna be tonight
and now it's, let's see how it plays out?
I feel like you're...
I feel like you are begging out our deal
- I don't like how that feels
- i promise you
I promise you it will happen.
When?
When it is going to happen?
Mr. Brooks, When?
Tomorrow night... same time.
When you come out from your building,
I want you to turn right...
go to the first street that you can go western.
I will pick you up... on that street.
Ok
I wanna do make this, but it can't
end to drags out,
I can change my mind.
Don't you think I wanna do this Mr. Smith?
Maybe wrong tempted you have to... Anymore!
Even if that guy was charming and
funny i'll still not like him
Hi
Hi.
What can I do for you?
Detective Smolny,
Portland Police Department
This is Detective Carfagno,
she is in Palo Alto, California.
Emma.
! Emma!
Did Jane ever told you that there
were a murderer at her school?
No.
Nothing?
Not that her friend died or...
somebody she knew died?
Or some... Somebody in her dorm died?
No, why?
But there are two Detectives downstairs,
one of them is from Palo Alto
They wanna ask her some questions about a murder
that occurred there shortly before she came home
oh... My Gosh,
Well, I'm sure if she was called
to something was murdered
she would have said something.
Yeah
I called Roger,
he suggest to the criminal attorney.
He will be here within a hour.
Yeah, I'll get dress.
- This is to close.
- I know.
Jane, how well did you know Brandon?
He and I, we were in a couple of
classes together... that's about it
- Did you ever drive him to class?
- No.
Did you ever been in his apartment
in or where he lives?
Uh, which complex within...
Have you a BMW, Jane?
Uh, he was actually stolen...
Well that was interesting.
You know, I don't feel so well
I think you should lie down, ok?
I think she should lie down
Dad, I'm sorry I didn't say anything before
It was really horrible but
I don't know the guy that well and...
it happens during the same time I found out
I was pregnant, so... just can I...
I understand.
Now tell me, what do I do?
She did it.
Didn't she?
Yeah
it'll take the cops a week to ten days
to put the case together and...
...and then they will come back
and arrest her.
What are you going to do?
Oh God!
Why don't you free this before
she was born.
She has...
she has what I have
yes, she does.
But you're always smarter than her,
she was stupid
She did it because she got offered,
ok, I understand
She did it for fun, ok, I understand
but why didn't she think it through that hatchet
and she left it there?
You are pretty graphical today
that's the shock of a making a mistake
What does she think I think
if she remembers what she told me that the BMW
was been driven across the country by her friend
and now rigth...
...she tells the cops that it was stolen
you"ll always clean that bathrom,
whatever she did, all her life.
It's the BMW. As anything incriminating
I hope it was stolen
and she dropped the body on the very d-blake
you think she knows
on this trouble she's in
I think... i think she thought
she got noway within,
untill the cops showed up
I should've listen to her,
she was trying to tell me, You was there
I didn't quit school because I was pregnant
I should dog deeper.
And where would you be,
been in exactly the same
place that you are now.
It's not your fault, Earl.
Part of your problem with her is
that you always think it is
She has what I have, Marshall, so
in a very basic level it is my fault
What are you going to do?
Maybe the best thing for her
will be to let her go to jail
- what about her child?
- Emma and I will help her to erase it.
You might be right Earl, you know?
Just might be
Because if she's not stop she is
going to kill again and If she really wants...
...to take over that box business
the next good victim could be...
you
I...
I don't think she goes that far.
Hey
We've receive the counter offer
are you sitting down?
Yeah, go ahead
5 million dollars.
My God, you gotta be kidding me
He can't get that, kenny?
No, no, no, my sense of it say that by asking for 5
they hope you settle anywhere between 2,5 and 3
shit
Can you stall them?
Boh, they know you want this done quickly
so they're gonna expect a quick counter offer
Ok, I need two days, just wait 2 days, tell them...
that it's a big number and I have to think about it.
OK.
Oh, and, uh, that picture that he wanted
Tell him I couldn't find it.
Yes, Mr. Brooks
Mr. Brooks
before you open your mouth...
be very sure
this is the right...
thing to do
I will never be sure.
You get pissed of me
because I'm always the one
argue to go ahead and do murder.
But not this time,
Earl. This is your decision.
I know what's wrong,
I know in my heart it's wrong.
Then don't do it.
Go with Mr. Smith and will finish that
and when the police will put Jane in jail,
hope that will save her.
And we can happily go on
with our tortured lifes
That's exactly what I wanna do
That's exactly what I should do
the thing is she is my daughter.
And I love her.
Mr. Brooks
I'm going home.
Cancel everything for the rest of the day.
I'll take care of it.
If you need me, need me, Sunday,
I'll be in my studio.
Call me there.
I probably won't pick up, so...
just leave a message.
I'll try to not bother you
the thing that bothers me about this,
beside the facts we are not prepared and...
a multitude of other things, is...
what this Mr Smith do when he's
walking west tonight and...
...you don't show up, that little
freak and flipped out
I will take care of it
On the way to the airport.
What are we doing?
What are we doing? What are we doing?
You sound like a wining ass kid
- We are playing a hunch.
- We have followed this guy all day.
He is boring, ok?
And everything we are running
incomes so clean
well, If it didn't it wouldn't be
called a hunch
Meeks, he's the guy we should be
looking for, Meeks.
Look where. Please, tell me.
Ok, everyone knows who Meeks is
and is looking for him.
The chiropactor was the last name to his
all life that I know
We gonna find him now,
there's something is gonna turn him in
we gonna troop over him at the bus stop
On the other hand, nobody knows
who the thumbprint killer is or where he is
however I have a fucking hunch.
If this guy, Badford, does
I've got 2 days to play that hunch
So if you are thinking you are wasting
your time with me,
thea I'ld be happy to do it alone
I had a fight with my wife this morning.
What's your problem?
My husband wants 5 million dollars
here you are Sir
Sir?
Thank you.
God grant me the serenity
to accept the things that I cannot change
courage to change the things that I can
and the wisdom to know the difference...
it's for you asshole
remember me?
Can you step out of the car, please?
I wanna talk to you.
So, Mr Bafford what is it
you have to tell me?
What do you mean?
Li don't have anything to tell you
Really?
Because I was driving around and
I suddenly got this
feeling that you have something to tell me
about the murders
No.
Nothing.
Oh, that is disappointing.
Because... when I've left after we...
we talked last time
I felt like I've missed the clue
that was right on front of me
That can solve this whole case.
I don't know why you feel that
can you tell me that, uh, you are an amateur
powder that you like to make balls and vases?
No.
I told you that my hobby was
photography and not... powdery.
Oh, maybe, maybe that was it
Flight attender upstairs says that the victims
like to keep their bedroom curtains...
open when they had sex.
Can I see some of the photos
you took that couple?
You harassing me, Detective Atwood.
You know very well that I'm not a powder
and I don't have any pictures.
So my feeling is that your feeling is wrong
and you should just move your car
and let me go home
What's your job here?
What... what would you do?
I am a mechanical engineer.
Uh, you gotta be really smart for that.
Don't ya?
Yes
Then be smart Mr. Bafford
because you lie to me,
right there in the end
I'll be watching you
When you wanna tell me the truth
you gotta get in touch with me.
See you later al gator.
Gotta Lister to get us a search
warrant for Meeks Doctor
That's good.
God, Damned, this guy knows something.
Almost told me that something happened.
You think he did it?
I don't think is quiet that simple
Do you wanna call for backup?
Yeah, I wish to be ready for anything
infact I'll get a cane and I'll chop, rigth now...
I don't have the energy to chase this guy
if he'll decide to run
"put your hands on top of your head"
Clear
Meeks was a steroids freak
this is what is ususally fall...
tempting now
You think Meeks is having with him?
I think he have turned the man... on me!
Hawkins, we have here... Griffin
How do you feel?
Dirty
It's understandable.
You never killed for this reason before,
the feeling will pass
I don't think so.
It's the whole thing, Marshall
If i can fly away... suggest in the hole
...disappear, where there's
absolutely no trace of me.
Because eventually I will get caught doing this
It would be very embarrassing for me.
And Emma and Jane.
So I have been thinking.
Is there a way that Mr. Smith
could kill me and make me disappear?
Rule nr.1, Mr. Smith is not
smart enough to do that
I know that
nr. 2 there is not reason, if you are careful.
To believe you will ever get caught.
I know that I will have to plan it for Mr Smith but
I think...
I think, that is what I wanna do
Well, I'm not particulary fine at that plan, Earl
Remember? If you die, I'll go with you
and I'd like being alive. I like...
eating, I like fucking, I like killing.
I have to end it, Marshal...
one way or another...
...and I think this is the best way
Fuck you then!
- Hi
You worked late?
Yes, I had, I guess, 4 parts.
It's to 2,honey
blacked money
will be fine
Mercies... I'd love Jane is in grace
and I'm trying to get right
Ehy Daddy,
i thought you've been gone already
Roger called... there was another
murder last night at your school.
Yeah
gone in the same way they
talked to you about
right down to the hatched
been left at the scene.
They think they have a serial killer
obviously you were here last night so,
you are in the clear.
Well, it's...
it's a good new isn't it? I mean...
...even if you are innocent it's good to know
you are not a suspect
yeah, uh
how's the... how's the morning sickness?
Uh...
Better than yesterday.
Do you wanna have lunch with me today?
I'd love to but i don't know how i will feel later
Thank you
Do you love me, Jane?
Of course I love you, daddy.
You are my father.
Have you decided whether or
not to have the baby?
Not yet.
It's time to go
Dear Emma and Jane, my loves
I have a terminal illness and instead of
subjecting you to my deterioration
I have decided to disappear.
Not try to find me, i don't wanna be found.
Please, believe that the time
I've spent with you
brought me the greatest joy of my life.
Iove, dad.
So you are going to go through with it?
It's all planned to work out
- ready to rock and roll Mr. Smith?
- Yeah
I smell gun oil,
different gun oil than yours
He brought his gun,
if i forget what he wants,
he plans to kill me
Oh, now I get it.
You're counting on this
yes, it's a sort of lottery
but if you plan last to having kill you,
how do you have to kill somebody else first?
I'd live to see that he got the courage to kill me
not even you believe that, Earl.
This make it more exciting,
this's not?
I think he's gonna kill you
after you killed somebody else
you get it in you rocks on, big time
that's why you are doing this?
Not true and if it would?
So what?
Hello.
Yeah, put him through
I just got your message
the weird thing is that they
close that courtains
at first they were open as they always were
and they were make love like they always do
when i had a look again, the curtains were closed
and there were what look like camera flashes
coming from behind the curtains
Camera Flashes?
That what's that look like
That's why he poses them
I'm sorry?
No, no, no, nothing
look, the guy you should talk with
it's the guy at the floor below us
would that be, Mr Bafford?
Yeah, he told me once that he did take
some great pictures of that
couple making love
He is the one you should talk to
Ok, great, thank you.
Yeah?
Hawkins, meet me at Bafford apartment
with a search warrant.
Put this on.
Nice half hand.
Try I couple of deep breathes
through your nose.
- I have to take a crap so bad.
- What?
I have to take a crap.
We won't be long
I've talked with your wife lawyer
they are thinking about the 5 million
realisticly.
How much you think we can get?
Oh, If we go court, that case scenario, 2
I think we should all fair to 3
it's not get biggish?
2.5, 2.7, still be a great deal
There's more if you want
We have to do this quickly.
Remember?
Morice's meeting us here
yes
That's good he join us
it's not funny
are we alone?
Yeah
Hello.
Do it... do it
[screaming]
Don't do that
[Screaming]
Mr. Baffor
Yes, uuuhhh, yes
yes, you are the fucking man
oh, man, do You see the look on their face
the look on their fucking face, was great
It was great, it's fantastic.
That was...
everything that I, I, hoped, it would be
- Thank you.
- You're welcome
Mr. Bafford, I've knocked
anybody home?
Mr. Bafford.
Hello
Obviously Bafford is gone. Ehi...
Obviously Bafford is gone.
God damn Hawkins,
don't you ever knock?
I wasn't able to get a search warrant
but maybe we just got lucky,
this is the moving company work order
and this upset is the address
where they are taking the Baffor's stuff
Where you were when you called me?
I was at home, in bed.
Can you prove that?
Why do i need to prove that?
Your husband Jesse and his
lawyer were killed tonight.
Get the fuck out
looks like the thumbprint killer
I have an order to bring you in for questioning
why?
I did't want Jesse dead. Ok, I hate
what he was doing to me but I
didn't want him dead
their own record just said that you
wanted him dead.
Who better can fake the thumbprint
killer than you?
You don't actually believe I did that
our job had told us anything, Tracy,
is there people do strange things.
They just wanna ask you some questions.
And I will gonna answer those questions
after we got check out this addresses.
- I have to take the wind
- Look
this address is the answer for the thumbprint
killer and this is where I'm going
don't make me cuff you
because I will if I have to
ehy, ehy
it'd be really nice if you can go with me
...but if you do and this goes bad
they gonna burn your ass
So this never happened
you're nuts
yeah, that's what they say
here comes the gun
yep
what are you doing?
You are smart enough to figure
that out, Mr. Brooks
Well, we are going 65 miles/hour, Mr. Smith
if you shoot me now,
there's good chance that we both died.
Not now.
Take this next out, friend
You mean this one?
That wouldn't be very smart,
I mean i wouldn't
think about this now, nuts
You piss yourself back, you left your DNA
at the scene of a double homicide
and there's nothing to indicate that
i was ever there
then the cops do the analysys of that urine
and then will...
...you are the thumbprint killer
no, no. I have pictures of you
from the first murder
yes, but what you was doing at
the second murder
uh?
Let me help you with the fly
you say that I've forced you to come along
and if I'm not here,
more specifically my body is not here
to say otherwise you might have a
chance to spit in a rehab
let me ask for yourself.
Why would I help you
Well, I'm tired... Mr. Smith.
I am tired of killing.
But I'm an addict. I can't quit.
I've tried but I cannot do it on my own
So I need you to kill me.
But I need it if you do it smart.
I want in a way I will disappear
and my family never knows what I was.
How?
How do i fucking do that?
There's a cemetery I know about
We'll find an open grave,
you shoot me
I'll fall into the grave.
You'll shovel just enough earth...
to cover me
tomorrow, a casket is lowered on to me
and I'll disappear.
It's a good plan, don't you think?
Why?
Why should I trust you?
You don't have to trust me Mr. Smith
you are the man holding the gun
you saw me put mine in
the trap, remember?
I know
You really want me to kill you?
Yes
ok, ok
But one sad move
I'll drop
and I'll make sure that your family
knows where you are
I understand.
You come down or what Mr. Bafford?
Take your hand.
Are you parked very slow
you don't wanna climb over, do you?
What you do with the
key of a cemetery?
I own it.
Why do you own a cemetery?
I always want invest in things
people can do without
water and cemeteries?
Pretty safe bets.
Here
you'll need this to get out
yes, I would
I wanna show you something.
Ok
Here we are
how if, uh, I stand here and
you stand there
at... at, too far away
And you shoot me... I should
I should fall straight back into this hole.
You don't think I have the
guts to this to you?
No, i'm hoping you do Mr. Smith,
i'm hoping you do
ok, let's...
...let's get this over with
I'll close my eyes.
I'm sorry Mr. Smith.
I really did want you to kill me.
But in case, the last minute
I've changed my mind.
I've returned to your apartment.
And I've been to firing pin on your gun
Infact I even brought another one for
you to use if you couldn't finish me
If I had decided to go through with it.
Unfortunately for You.
My daughter is pregnant.
And just before you pulled that trigger I realize
how much I wanna see the end of that story
you don't even hear me,
the cops will gonna find those pictures.
They will know that you kill that couple.
The contents of your safety
deposit box Mr. Smith?
I'm vanished
that's hurt, isn't it?
No, please
before I was the thumbprint killer,
Mr. Smith
I have killed a lot of people.
In a lot of different ways.
It's says that the thumbprint killer
is a monster
annoying you a little bit, you
can't take credit, doesn't it?
No.
Anyone who's got what they do,
wants credit
since I'm not going to do it anymore
I'd like Mr. Smith have the credit
don't kid yourself,
Earl. You are going to kill again
No, I am not
I'm going back to tha AA meetings
and I will control it.
But there is an answer I
would like to have.
Atwood?
Why you are a cop?
Who is this?
You are rich, you have good education,
you could have gone into your father's business,
instead you...
went outside, all of them became successful
on your own, why?
If you want something from me
then you gonna have to tell me who you are...
...or I'm gonna hang up
did you think that your husband's
killing was random?
And I suddenly didn't have to
give you Meeks
Mr. Bafford?
Which is the answer?
You not sound like you?
Well, I have a little cold
are you going to gimme the answer?
Where are you?
I'll tell you if you can give me
the true answer to my question
My... My father was very disappointed
that I was born a girl
And he let me know it
I spent my all life trying to prove
him wrong
Thank you.
Wait...
you... you promised to tell me
where you are?
Me?
I am on top of a building.
That wasn't Bafford.
Jane!
Wake up, wake up!
I woke you up?
It's ok
it's ok
I'm here... go back to sleep
why did you fight it so hard, Earl?