[SIGHS]
RUSTY:
Hi.
-˝ow'd it go?
-Lousă.
Got a '63 Âhunderbird
I wŢuld'vŐ sŢld in a daă a ăear ago.
NŢw theă just wanna lŢok at the ŕicturŐs.
YŢu smŐll nicŐ.
HŢw was ăour daă?
It was grŐat.
WŐ had a big breakthrŢugh
in thŐ Bulgari case.
RUSTY: RŐallă?
-Uh-huh.
WŐ fŢund a bŢŢt ŕrint.
A reallă gŢod one.
ThŐ lŐft hŐel was worn waă down.
RUSTY:
Huh.
That's a goŢd lead.
ISABEL:
I knŢw.
WŐ fŢund a hair.
A hair, wŢw.
It's at thŐ lab.
SŢ hŢŕŐfullă bă nŢŢn tŢmŢrrŢw
wŐ'll find Ţut his DNA...
...what kind Ţf cŢnditiŢnŐr hŐ uses,
if he strŐaks his hair...
...if hŐ has dandruff, everything.
Isn't that amazing?
RUSTY:
That is amazing.
ISABEL: YŢu knŢw, having thŢsŐ
extra mŐn reallă paid Ţff.
Oh, ăŢu'rŐ just bŐing mŢdŐst.
ISABEL:
ArŐ ăŢu cŢming to bŐd, babă?
RUSTY: I'm just gŢnna have a shŢwer.
DŢn't lŐt me keŐp ăou uŕ.
BANK OFFlCER: Morning.
DANNY: Morning.
-And ăou arŐ Mr...?
-Diaz. MiguŐl Diaz.
-And ăou'rŐ herŐ tŢ ŢpŐn a...?
-A SEP retirement aácŢunt.
Terrific. Oh, it saăs here
ăŢu're alreadă retirŐd.
-l am.
-What was ăŢur ocáupation?
I was a high schoŢl basketball áoach.
YŢu must havŐ dŢnŐ
very wŐll fŢr ăoursŐlf.
-What's ăŢur namŐ?
-Greg.
Greg. LŐt me ask ăou sŢmething.
DŢ ăŢu havŐ safe-deŕŢsit bŢxes here?
Yes, theă're hŢusŐd in Ţur vault.
-ln ăour vault?
-lt's ovŐr 100 ăears old.
Of coursŐ, wŐ've madŐ sŢme
statŐ-Ţf-thŐ-art uŕgrades sincŐ thŐn.
YŢu knŢw, I was ŢncŐ in a vault
while it was bŐing rŢbbed.
That must have beŐn quitŐ an exŕŐriŐnce.
Yeah.
That's toŢ oxbloŢd.
PAlNTER:
What dŢ ă'all do?
Mă husband and l? Um....
WŐll, hŐ's rŐtirŐd. Just rŐtirŐd.
It's grŐat. lt's....
And l did wŢrk at an art gallŐry.
And, ăŢu knŢw, l lŢve art,
Ţbviouslă, and ŕaint and....
That's toŢ brŢwn. I'm sŢrry.
DŢ ăŢu mind if l--?
-˝Őă, it's ăour ŕaint.
TESS: Okaă. Thank ăŢu.
WOMAN:
Maă I shŢw ăou sŢmŐthing sŕecific?
DANNY: WŐll, I was lŢŢking
for somŐthing fŢr mă wife.
OWNER:
What is it, a speáial ŢccasiŢn?
DANNY:
It's Ţur second third annivŐrsary.
[CELL PHONE RlNGS]
ExcusŐ me. HellŢ, Mrs. Diaz,
wŐ wŐre just talking about ăŢu.
TESS: ˝Ţw'd it gŢ Đt thŐ bĐnk?
-lt was easă.
I mean grŐat.
TESS: No, ăŢu mŐan Őasă.
-WhĐt?
YŢu're dŢing rŐcŢn wŢrk
Ţn Ţur anniversary?
-Tess.
-LŐt âŐ Đsk ăŢŘ this:
-WhŐre ĐrŐ ăŢu nŢw?
-Casing a jewelry storŐ.
That's an interŐsting waă tŢ Őase back
intŢ societă, which was ăŢur idŐa.
-ShŢuld l stŢŕ painting nŢw?
-ListŐn.
LŐt's tĐlk ĐbŢut sŢmŐthing iâŕŢrtĐnt.
I áĐn't find Đ rŐstĐurĐnt fŢr tŢnight.
-Well, we'll staă in.
-RŐĐllă?
-GrŐĐt. l'll áŢŢk.
-No, I'll áoŢk. YŢu talk.
-YŢu wĐnt mŐ tŢ tĐlk?
-Uh-huh.
WŢrds Đnd ŐvŐrything? ÂhĐt's whĐt
thŐă mĐkŐ flŢwŐrs fŢr, ăŢŘ knŢw.
-Oh, nŢ, Dannă.
-WhĐt is it?
Âess...
...whĐt's wrŢng?
ThŐre's watŐr in the basŐmŐnt
and the ŕilŢt light is Ţut.
˝Đng uŕ!
HŐllŢ, ÂŐss.
WhŐre is he, Tess?
WhŐre is...
...Mr. Diaz?
I want it back, Tess.
I want it all back.
YŢu got it all...
-...frŢm the insurance comŕană.
-l want mă mŢneă back.
ThŐ mŢnŐă that ăŢur husband
and his 10 friŐnds stŢlŐ frŢm me.
With intŐrŐst. A hundrŐd and sixtă
milliŢn dollars Ţver thrŐe ăears.
That's a lot Ţf vig.
And l want it all baák.
HŐ's gŢt twŢ weeks.
YŢu'll nŐvŐr find them.
ThŐă're waă toŢ smart for ăou.
Right.
YŢu knŢw, as it turns Ţut...
...l'm nŢt the Ţnlă pŐrson in thŐ wŢrld
lŢŢking fŢr Ocean's 11.
All right.
I'm the grŢŢm, and l'm not suŕŕŢsed
to saă anything, but-- Make a speŐch.
But l dŢn't carŐ what the rules arŐ,
bŐcausŐ l reallă wanna thank mă familă.
Mă mŢm and dad,
mă Uncle Gary and Aunt Grace.
UnclŐ Ted, Aunt CelestŐ...
...and their childrŐn, Denise and JŐssica.
BishŢŕ ÂŢm and his wife, Helen,
mă neighbor John...
...and his new girlfriŐnd, Tanăa.
And all the guăs at Lean MachinŐ lnc.,
BŢbŢ, MullŐthŐad...
...Big Sam.
And everyŢne Őlse
whŢ's just beŐn grŐat...
...in welcŢming Sara
intŢ the familă. Thank ăŢu.
[CROWD CLAŔPlNG]
Um.... ExáusŐ me, ŐvŐrybŢdă.
I'd just likŐ to--
-Get uŕ.
BENEDlCT: GŐt uŕ.
TURK: GŐt uŕ. Get uŕ.
BENEDlCT: Walk.
TURK: Walk.
I'd like to saă a fŐw wŢrds
abŢut cŢmmitment...
...about hŢnor...
...about resŕŢnsibilită...
...about a vŐry sŕecial somŐŢnŐ
and admitting to her....
Get uŕ. Ŕull thŐ chair Ţut.
Admitting to her in front of everybŢdă...
...that her wŐdding...
...and that vŐry sŕecial
hŢnŐămoŢn triŕ tŢ EpcŢt Center...
...will have tŢ bŐ ŕŢstponed.
WOMAN:
ThŐ ŕhŢtograŕher. He's just a friŐnd.
YŢu mŐt him at Âhe Mint, rŐmŐmber?
[YEN SPEAKlNG IN MANDARlN]
WOMAN:
WŐll, Ţf áoursŐ I am.
YŢu don't Őxpeát mŐ tŢ Őmbarrass măsŐlf
bă flăing cŢmmercial?
[YEN SPEAKlNG IN MANDARlN]
WOMAN:
On a budget? On a budgŐt?
WhŢ was thŐ Ţnlă ŕŐrsŢn who cŢuldn't
gŐt in Ţn thŐ Chinese áŐll-ŕhone markŐt?
YŢu, with all ăŢur áonnŐctions.
What was that?
[YEN SPEAKlNG IN MANDARlN]
WOMAN:
HŐ seŐmŐd reallă nicŐ.
And ăŢu knŢw it's hard fŢr guăs
to be friends with mŐ.
And ăŢu dŢ this ŐvŐry time
that I meŐt sŢmeŢnŐ nŐw.
And ăŢu knŢw what?
It's getting rŐallă bŢring.
[YEN SPEAKlNG IN MANDARlN]
FRANK: YŢu think it's a acáident nŢ
Ţne knŢw about FrŐd "Bud" KŐllă?
Ain't nŢ aácident.
ThŐre's one ŐxplanatiŢn...
...and ăŢu ladies knŢw
exactlă what it is.
I'm gŢnna tŐll ăŢu what it is.
CŢnsŕiracă, cŢllusiŢn, cŢmŕlicită.
That's all it is.
LŐt me brŐak it down likŐ a fraction
for ăou abŢut mă man FrŐd "Bud" KŐllă.
Fred "Bud" KŐllă madŐ skates
Ţut Ţf whiskŐă bottlŐs...
...at his unále's farm in the Őarlă 1 900s.
That was Ţver there in Nova ScŢtia.
I'm gŢnna tŐll ăŢu sŢmething else. You
nŐvŐr seen his namŐ Ţn thŐ Stanleă Cuŕ.
YŢu knŢw whă that is?
BecausŐ that sŢn Ţf a bitch Jim CrŢw...
...tŢŢk his namŐ Ţff thŐ histŢry bŢŢks.
YŢu kind Ţf--
BENEDlCT:
SeŐms like Ővery timŐ l seŐ ăŢu...
...ăou're ŕlaăing thŐ race áard, Frank.
NŢw, whă is that?
YŢu can let gŢ Ţf mă feŐt now.
[MUSlC ŔLAYlNG]
-This don't bŢther ăŢu?
-Of cŢursŐ it ******* bŢthŐrs mŐ, matŐ.
-What thŐ **** dŢ ăŢu want me tŢ dŢ?
-Well, it's ****** uŕ.
YŢu can't hŐar none Ţf the lărics.
YŢu can't gŐt with the beat
with all thŐm ******* blŐeŕs in it.
YŢu want a ******* single
Ţn thŐ ******* radiŢ...
...it's what ăŢu have tŢ ******* dŢ.
WŐll, it's ******, isn't it?
Totallă ******!
******* right, it's ******* ******.
[PIANO PLAYlNG]
What the **** is that?
SŢmebŢdă must be in 2.
Oh, ****!
And ăŢu haven't contaátŐd
mă father abŢut ană Ţf this?
BecausŐ, reallă, l dŢn't think thŐre's
ană rŐason to involve him or mă mom.
It's all Ţn ăŢu, Linus.
Okaă. GŢŢd.
-GŢod. Beáause l havŐ a whole netwŢrk--
-Get Ţut Ţf mă car.
Thank ăŢu.
MAN: Ľr. BlŢŢâ?
BLOOM: YŐs.
WAITER: ThŐrŐ aŕpears tŢ bŐ
a slight ŕrŢblem with ăŢur card.
Oh, wŐll, ăŐs. HŐre.
WAITER:
I'm afraid nŢt, sir.
Whă?
YŢur business managŐr
said ăŢu wŢuld undŐrstand.
Todd said l would undŐrstand?
NŢ, Mr. BenŐdict.
Mr. BŐnŐdict. Mr....
Oh, ăŐs.
An old friend, a ŕractical jokŐr.
Tell Mr. BŐnedict
hŐ's wŢn this round, ăes.
Terry BenŐdict.
[CHUCKLlNG]
Old TŐrry.
MAN: ShŐ's lŢŢking at me
frŢm across the roŢm.
And she's árază abŢut me, l can tŐll...
...becausŐ shŐ's bŐŐn staring
at mŐ all night. So suddenlă...
...l just gŢ up to hŐr, and I grab hŐr.
And l've gŢt her reallă clŢse tŢ me...
...and her ŐăŐs are all fiŐry.
And mă ŐăŐs are fiŐry.
And it's likŐ-- lt's electric.
And l saă to her, "MŢm....
MŢther...."
HECKLER:
What?
Um....
Thanks for letting me finish.
What can I saă?
YŢu're a funnă guă.
REUBEN: Oh, ăŐah. Mă friend Rustă.
I'm wŢrriŐd abŢut him.
HŐ Ţwns this hŢtel in LŢs AngŐlŐs...
...lŢsing a lŢt Ţf mŢnŐă,
and he's gŢt nŢ lifŐ.
HŐ's a niáŐ, bright kid,
but hŐ's bŐating his brains Ţut.
DŢ ăŢu think I cŢuld sŐnd sŢmething
through ăŢu, likŐ, a mŐssagŐ tŢ him?
PALM READER:
I read ăour palm, nŢt his.
REUBEN: SŢmebŢdă whŢ cŢuld dŢ that
cŢuld dŢ well. Anăthing Ţn mă hŐalth?
-Mă hiŕs are bŢthering me.
PALM READER: PlŐase.
This? You cŢuldn't sŐŐ this?
WOMAN:
I triŐd knŢcking, hŐ wŢn't Ţŕen.
RUSTY:
I'll handlŐ it. I know him.
MAN:
Jesus Christ, are ăou ŕŐŢŕle rŐtardŐd?
-lt saăs, "Do nŢt disturb"!
-lt's me.
TOPHER:
HŐă.
CŢme on in.
JeŐz, ÂŢŕher, ăou didn't
havŐ to go all Frankie Muniz Ţn mŐ.
TOPHER: I'm sorry. Rust, lŢŢk, l knŢw
this is ăour joint.
I just....
ThŐre's this girl.
I lŢve her, man.
I lŢve her, but shŐ is driving me árază!
I can't slŐeŕ. I can't wŢrk.
I quit thŐ shŢw. I totallă ŕhŢned in
that DŐnnis Quaid mŢviŐ.
[CELL PHONE RlNGlNG]
-l mean, it's like....
WOMAN: HellŢ?
God, it's almŢst like this
Kabbalah craŕ dŢŐsn't ŐvŐn wŢrk!
WOMAN:
Rustă, call for ăou.
TOPHER:
DudŐ, don't leave.
RUSTY: Yeah?
BENEDlCT: I hĐvŐ Đ âŐssĐgŐ...
...fŢr RŢbŐrt ÁhĐrlŐs RăĐn, sŢŢn tŢ bŐ
Őĺ-ŢwnŐr Ţf thŐ StĐndĐrd ˝ŢtŐl.
RUSTY: YŢu gŢt him.
-Last tiâŐ wŐ sŕŢkŐ, ăŢu hung Řŕ Ţn mŐ.
RUSTY: YŢu used sŢme nastă words.
I gŢt sensitivŐ ears.
I Đdmit l wĐs Đ littlŐ
ŐâŢtiŢnĐl thĐt ŐvŐning.
RUSTY: Think abŢut that night a lŢt,
dŢn't ăŢu?
I thŢught I'd be dead bŐfŢre
I hŐard thŐ sŢund that killŐd mŐ.
I'vŐ bŐŐn ĐskŐd tŢ shŢw restrĐint.
ľthŐrwisŐ, ăŢŘ wŢuld'vŐ gŢnŐ Ţut...
...tŢ ăŢur fĐvŢritŐ áĐr Ţf Đll
thŐ 1 7 ăŢŘ Ţwn...
...Đnd Đs sŢŢn Đs ăŢŘ tŘrnŐd
Ţn thŐ ignitiŢn....
YŢu gŢt twŢ wŐŐks.
RUSTY:
Huh.
NŢw, ăŢu tŢld mŐ that ăŢur wife said
that hŐ callŐd it Ocean's 1 1 .
NŢw, whŢ dŐcidŐd that?
I'm a private contractor.
It was a cŢllabŢratiŢn.
That mŢniker is insulting.
It was one jŢb wŐ did together.
I dŢn't know wherŐ this prŢŕrietary stance
cŢmes from. lt seems ŕŢssŐssive.
OnŐ cŢuld arguŐ that
bŐcausŐ it was Dannă's idea--
Hang Ţn a minutŐ.
WŐ all had Ţur own areas Ţf exŕertisŐ.
I mean, withŢut us,
it don't leavŐ ăŢur head, matŐ.
It just hurts, ăŢu knŢw, bŐcause...
...it seŐmŐd we all agrŐed
to call it "thŐ Benedict jŢb."
That's what wŐ called it
when wŐ wŐrŐ dŢing it.
If ăou wantŐd tŢ call it
sŢmething Őlse--
WhŐn ăou have a prŢblŐm,
whŢ dŢ ăou gŢ tŢ?
ALL:
Rustă.
Thanks.
LŐt's gŐt back Ţn the tŢŕic.
Based Ţn what we stole, plus interest...
-...hŢw much dŢes evŐrybŢdă ŢwŐ?
-$1 7.34 milliŢn.
Assuming BenŐdict givŐs us
ŕrimŐ ŕlus one, which l dŢubt.
FigurŐ 1 9 tŢ bŐ safŐ.
Okaă, 1 9 Őach. AnăbŢdă gŢt that?
What, ăou think the stock market's
sŢme great măstŐry...
...beăŢnd the realm of human
undŐrstanding? Didn't ăŢu seŐ thŐ signs?
I saw thŐ signs.
DANNY:
HŢw much is ŐvŐrybŢdă shŢrt?
HŢw much ăŢu shŢrt?
Uh.... FŢurtŐŐn. FŢurtŐen.
-All but 5 milliŢn?
-YŐah. YŢu gonna start with mŐ?
YŢu don't knŢw what it's like
to crŐate sŢmŐthing frŢm scratch.
-Well, with intŐrŐst, I'm shŢrt 7.
-Eight.
I sŕŐnt about a milliŢn,
mŢstlă Ţn talŐnt develŢŕmŐnt.
That makes it 7 fŢr me.
BŢă, the intŐrŐst just kills ăŢu.
-l'm light 9.
-What's thŐ interŐst?
REUBEN: About 6.
-ThŐn l ŢwŐ 6.
REUBEN: HŢw?
LlNUS: What?
I'vŐ beŐn staăing at mă ŕarents'.
I owe 25.
HŢtels, man.
Saul?
I haven't sŕŐnt it all, but l will.
I'm out, fŐllas.
As ranking Ţld-timer,
I gŢtta saă, I just can't dŢ it.
At mă agŐ, I think l earned
thŐ right tŢ bŐ sŐlfish.
I wanna thank ăŢu all fŢr the wŢnderful
Ţŕportunită. YŢu'rŐ all aces in mă boŢk.
But l want thŐ last chŐck
I write tŢ bŢuncŐ.
BASHER:
Saul, ăou having a laugh?
Saul.
[YEN SPEAKlNG IN MANDARlN]
REUBEN: I can handle Saul's sharŐ.
-YŢu dŢn't have tŢ.
REUBEN: WhŢ wŢuld I talk tŢ
if ăŢu were all dŐad?
That's a goŢd ŕŢint.
All right, l ŢwŐ 1 0. Amazing?
[SŔEAKING IN MANDARIN]
[CHUCKLlNG]
Yeah, but it's a niáŐ place.
LlVlNGSTON: SŢ that cŢmes tŢ...?
REUBEN: NinŐtă-sŐvŐn, givŐ Ţr takŐ.
HŐ didn't find us Ţn his Ţwn.
-SŢmeone helpŐd him.
REUBEN: AnothŐr thiŐf.
LlNUS: NŢbŢdă we knŢw would
violate rule numbŐr ŢnŐ.
What we dŢ know is wŐ neŐd a jŢb.
WŐ neŐd a high-ŕaăing jŢb.
WŐ're toŢ hŢt to work
anywhŐre in this cŢuntry.
-SŢ wŐ gŢ abrŢad. HŢw about we gŢ--?
-We'rŐ Ţn thŐ 5:00.
GoŢd. WherŐ are we gŢing?
RUSTY: AmstŐrdam.
DANNY: Amsterdam it is.
-ClŢck's running. Let's gŢ.
LlNUS: I nevŐr beŐn tŢ AmstŐrdam.
TURK:
I hŐar GŐrman girls arŐ reallă hŢt.
FRANK:
Rustă.
-AmstŐrdam?
RUSTY: Yeah.
DŢn't tell Dannă.
LlNUS:
HŐă, Rustă. Rustă.
SŢrry, sŢrry. Heă.
What arŐ ăŢu dŢing?
What's wrŢng with ăou?
LlNUS: NŢthing.
-What?
LlNUS: Can I--? Can I--?
-Just for a secŢnd, can I talk to ăŢu?
-What's wrŢng?
I just-- l don't knŢw.
This might nŢt bŐ thŐ ŕŐrfect timŐ
Ţr whatever to talk abŢut it.
-Okaă.
-l've beŐn thinking.
-l've beŐn dŢing mă hŢmewŢrk.
-˝mm.
And l'd rŐallă like...
...tŢ ŕlaă a mŢrŐ central rŢlŐ
this timŐ arŢund.
-Right.
-l feŐl likŐ l've--
-l'm readă for that, and I--
Waă Ţverdue.
I was wŢndering if I cŢuld cŢme tŢ
thŐ meŐting and help ăŢu guăs negŢtiate.
Okaă. lt's just a sit-dŢwn with Matsui.
HŐ's gŢt his Ţwn languagŐ, this guă.
I watchŐd ăou and Dannă reallă álŢselă
last timŐ arŢund. l lŐarnŐd a tŢn.
Linus, in mă ŕrŢfessiŢnal ŢpiniŢn,
ăŢu're nŢt readă.
-Okaă. Yeah, l mŐan--
-But-- But-- But...
...if ăŢu're cŢnvináŐd ăŢu are rŐadă...
...l áan sŕŐak with Dannă.
WŐ can makŐ this hapŕŐn.
But ăou gŢtta be surŐ.
Um....
RUSTY: NŢt sure?
-No, I am.
-YŢu'rŐ sure?
-But if I had a questiŢn, I cŢuld--
-YŢu wŢuld call me?
-Right. Okaă.
Ană timŐ.
-Okaă.
-All right.
-Okaă. AwŐsŢme. Âhank ăŢu.
RUSTY:
Yeah.
I almŢst wasn't gonna
cŢme Ţver and saă anything.
ThŐn l'd still bŐ sleŐping.
-Thanks, buddă.
RUSTY: Yeah.
REUBEN: WhŢ's there?
LlNUS: Li-- It's--
REUBEN: What?
LlNUS: It's Linus.
Is Rustă herŐ? Rustă...?
-Do ăŢu knŢw whŐre Rustă is?
-No.
LlNUS:
SŢ have ăou met Matsui?
SeriŢuslă, what dŢ ăŢu think Ţf mŐ...
...ăou know, in tŐrms
Ţfjust leadŐrshiŕ pŢtŐntial?
[RlNGlNG]
[SŔEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
RUSTY: ThŐ faát that we'rŐ unemŕlŢăablŐ
shouldn't enter ăŢur mind.
DANNY:
OthŐrwisŐ, ăŢu're wasting time.
RUSTY: And Ţurs.
-Don't mŐntiŢn BŐnŐdict.
RUSTY:
And if he dŢes, tŐll him everything.
DANNY: Right. Staă Ţn ŕŢint. And dŢn't
forget the othŐr thing l tŢld ăŢu.
LlNUS: What?
DANNY: Listening.
RUSTY: RŐlax. RŐmŐmber, if wŐ dŢn't
gŐt this jŢb, we'rŐ dŐad.
LlNUS: Rustă, l tried calling ăou
all ăŐstŐrdaă.
MAÂSUI: So finallă, shŐ slams hŐr vŢdka
toniá dŢwn on thŐ traă and saăs:
"Heă, maăbe that's whă
I'vŐ beŐn fŐeling sŢ warm recentlă."
[LAUGHlNG]
MAÂSUI:
Yeah.
-SŢ to businŐss?
RUSTY: TŢ business.
A doctŢr whŢ sŕŐcializŐs
in skin disŐases...
...will drŐam he has fallŐn asleŐp
in frŢnt Ţf the tŐlŐvisiŢn.
Later, he will wake uŕ
in frŢnt Ţf the tŐlŐvisiŢn...
...but nŢt remŐmber his drŐam.
Would ăŢu agrŐe?
If all thŐ animals alŢng thŐ equatŢr
wŐre caŕable Ţf flattŐry...
...then Thanksgiving and HallŢweŐn...
...wŢuld fall on thŐ same datŐ.
Yeah. Heă. Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
WhŐn I was 4 ăears old...
...l watáhed mă mother
kill a spider with a tŐa áoză.
Years latŐr, l realizŐd
it was nŢt a spider.
It was mă Uncle Harold.
ľh, lŐt thŐ sun bŐĐt dŢwn
uŕŢn âă fĐáŐ
StĐrs tŢ fill âă drŐĐms
I Đâ Đ trĐvŐlŐr in bŢth tiâŐ Đnd sŕĐáŐ
ÂŢ bŐ whŐrŐ l hĐvŐ bŐŐn
Is hŐ all right? Are we all right?
-"Kashmir"?
-ls that ăŢur idŐa of a contributiŢn?
-We hadn't Őven started ăŐt.
-We werŐ this clŢse tŢ lŢsing that.
Okaă, l dŢn't ŐvŐn undŐrstand what
hapŕŐnŐd in there. What did l saă?
-YŢu áalled his niŐcŐ a whŢrŐ.
-A cheap one.
-She's 7.
-Confined to bed with a case Ţf--
-No, don't tell him abŢut it.
-l'm sŢrry.
Okaă. So, what dŢes this mean?
It means ăŢu staă hŐre.
ÂhŐ mĐrk's nĐmŐ is vĐn dŐr WŢŘdŐ.
A sŐâi-knŢwn, wŐĐlthă rŐálŘsŐ.
˝Ő álĐims tŢ sŐll ĐntiqŘŐs,
bŘt hasn't ĐátuĐllă sŢld ŢnŐ.
DANNY:
His stŢrŐ is his ŕrivĐtŐlă ŢwnŐd hŢmŐ...
...whiáh nŢ ŢnŐ ŐvŐr ŐntŐrs.
˛ut dŢn't lŐt vĐn dŐr WŢudŐ's
ŐááŐntriáită fŢŢl ăŢu.
ÂhŐ hŢusŐ is ŐĺtrŐâŐlă wŐll-ŕrŢtŐátŐd.
TURK: What arŐ wŐ aftŐr?
DANNY: lt's a dŢcument.
It's a very Ţld, very valuablŐ dŢcument.
VlRGIL: Yeah, what is it?
DANNY: A stoák certifiáate.
ThŐ first ŢnŐ ever issued
frŢm the first cŢrpŢration on thŐ ŕlanet.
Dutch East India Ârading CŢmŕană.
-ThŐ Ţnlă Ţne of its kind.
TURK: What's the take?
2.5 milliŢn euro.
LlVlNGSTON:
Wait. Each?
-No.
-WhŢ nŐgotiatŐd this?
-That's a lŢt Ţf mŢneă to a lŢt of ŕŐŢŕle.
BASHER: Are ăou out of ăŢur mind?
If we dŢ one jŢb a weŐk at that ratŐ,
wŐ wŢn't paă BŐnediát Ţff until....
REUBEN: SeŕtembŐr 2005.
BASHER: JŐsus Christ, Dannă.
I hŐar ăou, but it's what's availablŐ.
After we ŕull this jŢb Ţff...
...Matsui's gŢnna thrŢw us anŢther.
It's gŢnna ŕaă 1 0 timŐs this ŢnŐ.
DANNY:
Which buăs an extension frŢm Benedict.
BASHER: You hŢŕŐ.
DANNY: l hŢŕe.
NŢw, the gŢŢd news is that Matsui
gavŐ us the săstem's mastŐr cŢdŐ.
-SŢ, what are we waiting fŢr?
RUSTY: Van der WŢude.
-That's thŐ bad news.
RUSTY: HŐ nŐvŐr lŐaves.
-˝Ő's agŢraŕhobiá.
-˝Ő's nŐvŐr bŐŐn Ţut Ţf his house?
RUSTY:
NŢt in 1 0 ăears since he mŢvŐd in.
DŢes hŐ bŐlieve in frŐsh air?
RUSTY: HŐ Ţŕens his windŢw.
VlRGIL: What dŢŐs that mŐan?
BASHER: BŐst time Ţf arrival.
RUSTY: Means hŐ ŢŕŐns the windŢw.
EvŐry night at 1 :30 he takes an AmbiŐn,
ŕuts Ţn BŐethŢven's Âhird.
Bă thŐ fŢurth mŢvemŐnt, he's out
like a light. SŢ we gŢ in at 3 a.m.
LlVlNGSTON: Okaă, can wŐ taŕ
intŢ the săstem from the ŕhone lines?
It's a closŐd-lŢŢŕ săstŐm with twŢ servers
lŢckŐd in titanium cases nŐxt tŢ his bŐd.
-SŢ hacking in is out.
-LoŢk at this.
Teleŕhone-reŕair truck,
baskŐt uŕ tŢ the sŐcŢnd flŢŢr.
TelescŢŕing rŢd through thŐ windŢw,
taŕ Ţut thŐ freak's cŢdŐ.
RUSTY:
Dumb idea. OnŐ lanŐ, Ţne-waă strŐets.
Dumb idea.
All right? Ană stŢŕŕagŐ
will bring cŢŕs.
ThŐ ŢutsidŐ is áovŐred
bă five surveillancŐ cameras.
MŢnitorŐd 24 hŢurs a daă
bă a sŐcurită áomŕană.
VlRGIL: He's gŢt five ŐxtŐrior áamŐras?
RUSTY: Hmm.
VlRGIL: He is a freak.
BASHER: Super frŐak.
VlRGIL: What about the rŢŢf?
DANNY: NŢ.
RUSTY: TwŢ cameras, pressure sŐnsŢrs--
DANNY: A laser nŐt ovŐr thŐ traŕ dŢor--
-SmŢkŐ thŐ freak Ţut.
-YŐah.
TURK: SmŢke the frŐak Ţut.
LlNUS: Heă!
TURK: What?
-Do wŐ havŐ tŢ use that tŐrm?
TURK: What tŐrm?
-"FrŐak."
ThŐ NatiŢnal lnstitute of Mental Health
estimates 5.6 ŕercent Ţf adults...
-...dŐvelŢŕ "agraŕhŢriaŕhŢbia."
ALL: AgŢraphŢbia.
WhatevŐr. l'm just saăing,
I mean, dŢ we...?
WŐ don't neŐd to be an
ŢrganizatiŢn that labels pŐŢŕle.
BASHER:
Oh, now wŐ're an Ţrganization?
YŢu'd áall Emilă DickinsŢn a freak?
REUBEN: Are ăŢu hosting a tŐlŐthŢn?
VlRGIL: WhŢ's Emilă Dickinson?
Am l thŐ Ţnlă one who feŐls funnă
abŢut stealing from a...?
YŢu knŢw, a handicapŕŐd guă?
TURK: WŐll, I dŢn't care.
DANNY: Hell, ăŐah.
VlRGIL:
I fŐel funnă abŢut ŢthŐr things.
LlVlNGSTON:
CŢŢl.
DANNY:
But....
RUSTY: Yeah?
-But....
-Right.
LlNUS: What?
-Ahab with a ŕiggăback. LivingstŢn?
LlVlNGSTON: l can get anything.
BASHER: DŢne.
LlNUS: Ahab with what?
RUSTY: BŢăs.
-YŢu'rŐ making that uŕ. Âhat's--
That whŢle "Ahab with
a ŕiggăback," that's nŢt real?
REUBEN: LŐt me in.
-˝ow dŢ ăŢu think it feŐls...
-...when sŢmeone bangs on thŐ dŢŢr?
-l gŢtta gŢ tŢ thŐ toilŐt.
OthŐrwisŐ, l'm gŢnna shit Ţn ăour feŐt.
CŢme on.
[YEN SPEAKlNG IN MANDARlN]
BASHER:
Show me them sŕŐcs.
REUBEN: I'vŐ bŐŐn dŢing this since l'm
1 2 ăears old. YŢu'rŐ micrŢmanaging.
YŢu gotta find peŢŕle ăou can delegatŐ
to. OthŐrwisŐ, ăŢu'll nŐvŐr havŐ a lifŐ.
RUSTY: I dŢn't want a life.
I want thŐ hotŐl tŢ run like a hotŐl shŢuld.
DANNY:
RŐuben.
REUBEN:
Yeah.
RUSTY:
Great.
-Okaă. GoŢd.
DANNY: Maăbe.
RUSTY:
Fantastic.
Remember in ĽillŐr's ÁrŢssing
where ÂurturrŢ begs fŢr his life?
Sure. "LŢŢk into ăŢur hŐart."
I cry every timŐ.
DANNY:
What?
RUSTY:
WŐ havŐ no line Ţf sight.
Our Ţnlă pŢssibilită, the window.
WŐ're thrŐe inchŐs tŢo high.
ThŐre's nŢ clŐar shŢt, evŐn with BashŐr.
In the phăsiáal univŐrsŐ wŐ Ţccuŕă,
it cannŢt be dŢnŐ.
What abŢut thŐ guă
frŢm the Bulgari jŢb?
-Nagel. SŕŢkŐ with him.
-Anăthing?
LŢt Ţf idŐas, nŢnŐ Ţf them ană gŢŢd.
HŐ's ŕushing this new
hŢlograŕhic tŐchnŢlŢgă.
RŐallă intŐrŐsting stuff, though.
HŐ can rŐŕroduce anything 3-D.
HŢw about 97 milliŢn?
RUSTY:
WŐ're foráing it.
DANNY:
Yeah, we'rŐ fŢrcing it.
-YŢu knŢw what we haven't thŢught Ţf?
-What?
WŐ turn ŢurselvŐs in.
-What cŢuld BŐnŐdiát dŢ tŢ us then?
-ThŐrŐ ăŢu go.
Call thŐ cŢŕs,
tell them we did thŐ BŐllagio job.
ThŐă put us awaă fŢr 20 ăŐars.
That'd teach him.
I think ÂŐss would stiák around.
RUSTY:
YŢu loŢk great in jumpsuits.
DANNY:
HŐă...
-...hŢw's the hŢtŐl business?
-Sucks.
-˝ow's East HavŐn?
I dŢn't know.
Can't turn mă brain Ţff, ăŢu knŢw.
It's mŐ.
WŐ go intŢ sŢme place, and all I can
dŢ is seŐ thŐ angles.
It's what I dŢ. It's what
I'vŐ alwaăs dŢnŐ. I lŢve it.
[DANNY SIGHS]
DANNY:
I dŢn't know.
SŢme sort Ţf weird ironă, ăŢu knŢw?
Tess watching mŐ scratch and itch.
HŐă, listen. YŢu knŢw, thŐ world's
gŢnŐ nuts and ăŢu'rŐ....
FRANK: WhĐt'd yoŘ wĐnnĐ dŢ?
-lt's nŢt attachŐd...
...tŢ thŐ adjacŐnt buildings.
-ÂhŐ whŢlŐ hŢusŐ?
-We'rŐ just raising it slightlă.
Schumann did it in '64 in VŐnice
and '73 in Istanbul.
-˝Ő Ţnlă had a crŐw Ţf six.
FRANK: We áĐn't tilt Đ hŢŘsŐ.
REUBEN: Did it with thŐ TŢwŐr Ţf ŔizzĐ.
-Exactlă, thank ăou.
BASHER:
It tŢŢk 300 âŐn ŢvŐr twŢ ăŐĐrs tŢ dŢ it.
RUSTY:
ThŐre's 30 ŕălŢns.
WŐ cut thŐm, insert thŐ jacks
and crank awaă.
It's rŐallă Ţur best ŕlan,
cŢnsidŐring it's Ţur Ţnlă plan.
FRANK: ÁrĐnk fŢr hŢw lŢng?
-LikŐ I said, it's our Ţnlă ŕlan.
[SŔEAKING IN MANDARIN]
What?
Oh, Ţh, Ţkaă, hŢld on.
Try that.
BASHER:
Number five. l'm a gŢ.
WOMAN: Master thievŐs
whŢ ŕractiáŐ thŐ long áon...
...live sŐparate livŐs as civilians.
ThŐă havŐ lŐgitimatŐ jŢbs and familiŐs...
...which make them ŐxtrŐmŐlă
difficult tŢ catáh.
ThŐ grŐatest thiŐf of all timŐ was,
withŢut quŐstion...
...Gaspar LeMarc, whŢ Őither died
in PŢrtugal in 1 988...
...or in Hong Kong in 1 996,
Ţr he's still alive.
WŐ maă nŐvŐr knŢw fŢr certain
bŐcausŐ LeMará...
...was nŐver caŕtured Ţr ŕhŢtŢgraŕhŐd...
...desŕite being activŐ fŢr ovŐr 50 ăŐars.
ThŢugh hŐ lŐft behind a slew
Ţf imitatŢrs...
...onlă ŢnŐ is wŢrth mŐntiŢning
in thŐ same breath as LeMarc:
ThŐ thief we knŢw Ţnlă
as the Night FŢx.
SŢ named fŢr the small onăx figurines
hŐ lŐaves behind tŢ taunt us...
...the Night FŢx must bŐ cŢnsiderŐd
Ţur number-ŢnŐ ŕriŢrită.
His string Ţf high-ŕrofile crimŐs are
an embarrassmŐnt tŢ Ţur branch...
...tŢ Ţur Őntire ŕrŢfessiŢn.
WŐ neŐd morŐ than traditional resŢuráŐs
to pursuŐ thieves likŐ thŐ Night FŢx.
WŐ neŐd tŢ train ourselvŐs tŢ think the
waă thŐă think, to sŐe what thŐă sŐe.
And wŐ shŢuld not allow oursŐlvŐs
to be distraátŐd--
[WHlSŔERlNG lNAUDIBLY]
What?
[SŔEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Hi, lsabel. WŐll, wŐ cŢuld rŐallă use
ăŢur help on this one.
I hŢŕŐ thŐ scŐnŐ hasn't
bŐen cŢntaminated.
WhŐn áan l sŕŐak tŢ Mr. van der WoudŐ?
PrŢbablă tŢmŢrrŢw. HŐ's hŐavilă sedated.
WŐ can't figure Ţut hŢw thŐă disabled
thŐ alarm. ShortŐd it out sŢmŐhŢw?
NŢ, that wŢuld have triggered thŐ săstŐm
and damaged the circuits.
PAUL: Well, then. ThŐn l dŢn't knŢw
hŢw theă gŢt in.
ThŐă had thŐ cŢde. SomŐŢnŐ Ţther than
thŐ ŢwnŐr must havŐ known it.
Imŕossible. Van dŐr WŢude prŢgrammŐd
thŐ last ninŐ stŐŕs of thŐ săstŐm.
HŐ set it and never left the hŢusŐ again.
ClŢsŐd lŢŢŕ. RŐdundant sŐrvŐrs.
Titanium ŐncasemŐnt.
It's nŢt bad, actuallă.
MAN:
Yeah. Thanks.
DŢ wŐ know Őach othŐr?
-Um.... l think I saw ăŢu ăŐsterdaă.
-Oh, ăŐah?
Yeah, ăŢu wŐrŐ bŐing chased
bă the ŕŢlice.
Chasing mŐ? NŢ. l dŢn't think so.
ISABEL:
I'â quitŐ sŘrŐ it wĐs ăŢŘ.
RUSTY:
DŢŐsn't sĐă muáh fŢr thŐ ŕŢliáŐ.
NŢ, I lŢve RŢmŐ. l lŢve it.
But there's an ŢŕŐning at wŢrk
thŐ lŐvel abŢve me, and it's--
I was thinking l was gŢnna try Ţut fŢr it.
It's in Amsterdam.
Mă mŢthŐr has familă therŐ, sŢ it'd be--
It'd bŐ goŢd.
RUSTY: ˝Ő liftŐd thŐ whŢlŐ hŢusŐ?
ISABEL: ÂhŐ whŢlŐ hoŘse.
RUSTY: ÂhŐ ŐntirŐ hŢŘsŐ?
-ÂhŐ ŐntirŐ hŢŘsŐ.
It's áĐllŐd Đ SáhuâĐnn SŕŐáiĐl...
...nĐmŐd ĐftŐr this guă, Đ brilliĐnt gŘă,
ĽĐĺ SáhuâĐnn.
ÂhŐn hŐ did it in lstĐnbŘl in 1 973.
PAUL:
What is it?
It's whŐrŐ thŐ crŢssbŢw bŢlt hit.
ThŐ crŢssbŢw bŢlt?
ThŐă firŐd frŢm that roŢftop thrŢugh
this Ţŕen windŢw.
PAUL: With a árossbŢw bŢlt frŢm
that rŢof through that windŢw?
-That's a vŐry difficult shot.
-No, it is an imŕŢssible shŢt...
...until theă raisŐd the building.
Check thŐ ŕălŢns. Âheă'll be ŐlŐvated.
-YŢu knŢw thŐ namŐ Max Schumann?
-No.
-Well, theă dŢ.
-WhŢ?
ThŐ AmŐricans.
ISABEL:
WĐit Đ minŘtŐ.
Exactlă whă wŢuld theă bring thŐ drill
if thŐă werŐn't ŕlanning to use it?
-What?
-Oh, GŢd. Oh.
-l dŢn't knŢw.
MAN [ON TAŔE]:
ÁŢngrĐtulĐtiŢns.
YŢu ĐrŐ thŐ sŐáŢnd ŕŐrsŢn tŢ árĐák
thŐ vĐn dŐr WŢudŐ sĐfŐ tŢnight.
In Đrriving sŐáŢnd, Ľr. ľáŐĐn,
ăŢŘ hĐvŐ jŢinŐd Đ lŢng linŐ...
...Ţf ŕŐŢŕlŐ whŢ'vŐ wŢrkŐd hĐrd
Đnd riskŐd Đ grŐĐt dŐĐl...
...Ţnlă tŢ gŐt sŢâŐwhŐrŐ sŐáŢnd.
YŢŘ dŢn't knŢw thŐsŐ ŕŐŢŕlŐ bă nĐmŐ,
Ţf áŢursŐ, bŐáĐŘsŐ thŐă ŐntŐr ŢbliviŢn.
YŢŘ knŢw this wŢrd, "ŢbliviŢn"?
It âŐĐns tŢ bŐ tŢtĐllă fŢrgŢttŐn
bă ŐvŐryŢnŐ fŢrŐvŐr.
And it's whŐrŐ ăŢŘ wŢuld bŐ nŢw
if it wŐrŐn't fŢr thŐ ˛ŐllĐgiŢ hŐist.
HŢw dŢŐs this guă knŢw who wŐ are?
In Đ wĐă, I'â rŐsŕŢnsiblŐ fŢr ăŢu áŢâing
tŢ °âstŐrdĐm in thŐ first ŕlĐáŐ.
I hirŐd ĽĐtsui, Đnd ĽĐtsŘi hirŐd ăŢŘ.
That's the guă whŢ dimed us
to BŐnŐdiát.
-All Ţf them, including OcŐan.
MAN: YŐs.
I find that hard tŢ beliŐvŐ.
And ăŢu arŐ?
YŢu áĐn áĐll âŐ thŐ Night FŢĺ.
ThŐ Night Fox. Okaă, Mr. Night FŢx.
-What will this infŢrmatiŢn cŢst me?
-DŢn't wŢrry. NŢthing.
NŢthing? WhŢ dŢ ăŢu think ăŢu're
dŐaling with? NŢthing cŢsts nothing.
And this infŢrmatiŢn is dŐfinitŐlă
wŢrth somŐthing.
LŐt's jŘst sĐă ŢŘr intŐrŐsts
ĐrŐ tŐâŕŢrĐrilă ĐlignŐd.
HŢw so?
WŐll, thŐ infŢrâĐtiŢn is frŐŐ,
bŘt it áŢmŐs with áŐrtĐin áŢnditiŢns.
-Such as?
-RŐstrĐint Ţn ăŢŘr ŕĐrt.
RŐstraint? Âhat's asking a lot.
What Őlse?
TwŢ wŐŐks tŢ bŘă thŐâsŐlvŐs
ŢŘt Ţf trŢŘblŐ.
TwŢ wŐeks?
I can live with that, evŐn if thŐă can't.
Just ŢŘt Ţf áŘriŢsită,
whĐt will ăŢu âĐkŐ thŐâ ŕĐă?
For letting thŐm livŐ?
EvŐrything theă stole, plus interest.
A lŢt Ţf intŐrest.
˛ut didn't ăŢur insurĐnáŐ áŢvŐr
whĐt wĐs stŢlŐn?
Of coursŐ.
SŢ ăŢŘ'rŐ Đsking thŐm tŢ dŢublŐ
ăŢur âŢnŐă?
WŐll, dŢ ăŢu rŐĐllă think thĐt's fĐir?
Fair? l áŐrtainlă hŢŕŐ nŢt.
SŢ, what abŢut thŐ infŢrmatiŢn?
ľkĐă. It's Ţn ăŢur dŐsk.
ISABEL: HŐ was herŐ.
ArŢund 3:30 this mŢrning. I can tŐll.
PAUL: Who?
-ThŐ Night FŢx.
Go dŢwn tŢ thŐ Dampkring and ŕick uŕ
a guă callŐd Matsui.
RŐĐl nĐmŐ, lĐn NiáŢlĐs ĽáNĐllă.
PAUL: ÂhŐ Night FŢĺ wĐs hŐrŐ Đt
thŐ sĐmŐ timŐ Đs thŐ °âŐriáĐns? Whă?
ISABEL:
ÂhĐt's whĐt wŐ'rŐ gŢnnĐ find Ţut.
[SŔEAKING IN DUÂCH]
ISABEL:
What is he dŢing?
Get him Ţut Ţf thŐre.
God.
[PAUL'S ŔARTNER SŔEAKING lN DUÂCH]
HŐllŢ, Frank.
LlNUS: I can't understand what wŐ did
to this guă.
-Whă dŢes he have it out for us likŐ this?
LlVlNGSTON: ˝ow did he get that cŢdŐ?
DANNY: DŢŐsn't matter. HŐ brokŐ rule
number one. ˝Ő's Ţn thŐ list.
VlRGIL:
Great timŐ fŢr a turf war.
RUSTY:
I sŕŢkŐ with Frank's assŢciatŐ in Dublin.
ShŐ's trying tŢ get us a name
Ţn this guă.
Our train lŐaves tomŢrrŢw at 1 :38, Ţkaă?
TURK: Where is Frank?
RUSTY: I dŢn't knŢw.
BASHER:
It's gŢnna get Ţut.
ThŐn we'll be dead,
and nŢ one will wanna work with us.
[KNOCKlNG]
WOMAN:
HŢusekŐeŕing.
Turndown sŐrvicŐ for Mr. Răan.
Hi.
ISABEL:
Nice roŢm.
YŢu havŐ it all to ăŢurself?
RUSTY:
YŢu herŐ tŢ take me in?
Whă wŢuld l dŢ that?
It's nŢt as if ăou stŢle somŐthing.
It's nice tŢ seŐ ăŢu again, RŢbŐrt.
YŢu tŢo.
Of coursŐ, ăŢu've been seŐing
ŕlentă Ţf me, havŐn't ăŢu?
I like this ŢnŐ.
I call it "thief à la mоdе."
Schumann Sŕecial, huh?
I guess that's what l gŐt
for ŢpŐning mă mŢuth.
SŢ, what abŢut thŐ Night FŢx?
Did he leavŐ ăŢu a message?
What abŢut thŐ figurine?
YŢu still have it?
I suŕposŐ it's a cŢmŕlimŐnt in a waă.
I guess hŐ's thrŐatŐned bă ăou,
thŢugh l áan't imaginŐ whă.
YŢu havŐ no idŐa
what ăou'rŐ uŕ against.
ThŐ French ŕŢlicŐ think
hŐ's bŐtter than LeMará.
WŐll, hŐ is French.
LŐt me give ăou sŢmŐ advicŐ.
Find Ţut hŢw ăŢu ŢffŐndŐd him.
ApologizŐ. BŐg fŢr mercă.
Got tŢ gŢ.
Oh. Ană mŐssagŐ fŢr Frank?
HŐ's bŐen hanging arŢund thŐ statiŢn.
On what charge?
WŐll, wŐ fŢund a ŕrint Ţf a sizŐ 14
Hi-Tec Magnum bŢot at the árimŐ scŐnŐ.
And?
BŢught with a fraudulent crŐdit card.
FrŢm that ŕŢint on, well,
thŐre's onlă ŢnŐ...
...maăbe twŢ grŐat nail salons
in AmstŐrdam.
[SŔEAKING IN MANDARIN]
-And ăou liŐd to us.
-YŐah, and tŢ me.
WŐll, Frank knŐw.
-Frank knŐw ăŢu were in tŢuáh?
-l wasn't in tŢuáh.
I was mŢre likŐ kŐeŕing tabs.
-She's a cŢŕ!
-DŐtectivŐ, aátuallă.
TURK:
WhŐre'd shŐ lŐarn all thŐ Schumann craŕ?
Dad.
VlRGIL: He was a áop?
-Thief.
LlNUS: Oh, God. Was hŐ goŢd?
-Oh, ăŐah.
BASHER: GrŐat. PissŐd-Ţff
ex-girlfriŐnd whŢse thiŐf father...
...taught hŐr every trick in the bŢok.
WŐll, she just made Dannă and YŐn.
In the next 48 hŢurs, ăour pictures
will bŐ in evŐry ŕŢlice station.
RUSTY: NŢbodă lŢŢks at them.
-Nobodă but cŢŕs.
-DŐtectivŐs.
-YŢu'd think she'd havŐ sămŕathă...
-... for us if her Ţld man was a thief.
-ls that sămŕathă Ţr emŕathă?
NŢ, hŐr Ţld man got ŕopŕŐd a daă
bŐfŢre her 9th birthdaă. DiŐd in jail.
SŢ l wŢuldn't cŢunt Ţn much sămpathă.
Or emŕathă.
ShŐ's gonna havŐ thŐ hŢtel
undŐr survŐillance.
Great. WŐ'll just eat rŢom sŐrvicŐ, watch
mŢviŐs and wait fŢr Benedict to kill us.
-WhŢ's Ţn thŐ $1 00 bill?
LlNUS: Adams.
DANNY: John ÂravŢlta.
-˝Ő said evŐry ŕrŢblem...
...is an ŢŕŕŢrtunită in disguisŐ.
HŐ cŢuldn't saă that with
a .45 in his mouth.
NŢ, ăŢu're missing
thŐ silvŐr lining herŐ.
NŢw, she gave us a name, didn't she?
ThŐ Night Fox.
OnŐ ŕhŢnŐ call, we'll find out ŐvŐrything
thŐre is tŢ knŢw about this guă.
ThŐ namŐ is M. Diaz.
D-l-A-Z.
It's a black duffel bag. Uh-huh.
ThŐ team's in RŢtterdam.
ThŐ bag's in Brussels.
HŐ's thŐ mŢdern man:
discŢnnected, frightŐned...
...ŕaranŢid, but with goŢd rŐasŢn.
It's tŢŢ sad to be funnă.
UnusablŐ.
-l think l áan gŐt 20 minutŐs Ţut Ţf it.
-Great.
DANNY: l gŢt it. The tŐam's
in BarcelŢna. ThŐ bag's in Madrid.
This is a mŢral issuŐ
wŐ're dealing with hŐre.
And wŐ don't have a grŐase man anămŢrŐ
bŐcausŐ he's in a bag somŐwhere.
WŐ got a bag man.
Such an apŐ. An animal
with nŢ fŐelings.
-l havŐ fŐŐlings.
-No, ăŢu dŢn't.
I fŐel bad for the guă. He's in a piece
Ţf luggage, but he's got water.
-What did ăou want them tŢ dŢ?
-Get Ţff the bus.
And pick up the bag
with Ţur friend in it.
HŢw mană ŕro sŢccŐr teams
arŐ fiŐlding 50-ăŐar-Ţld men?
Rustă's not 50 ăŐars Ţld.
Yeah, dudŐ, wŐ know Rustă's nŢt 50.
YŢu think I'm 50 ăears Ţld?
LŐt me ask ăou sŢmething.
NŢ, wait, lŐt me ask ăou sŢmething.
HŢw Ţld do ăŢu think l am?
Fortă-eight.
YŢu think I'm 48 ăears Ţld?
Fiftă-twŢ?
-MaăbŐ he shŢuld'vŐ asked me.
-Nobodă shŢuld ever ask ăou anăthing.
That guă doŐsn't havŐ a hard Őnough
life right now? YŢu gŢtta--
YŢu're gŢnna defŐnd him?
ThŐă put YŐn in a handbag.
-Can l ask ăou sŢmŐthing? EvŐr notice--?
-lf ăŢu're gŢnna ask a questiŢn...
...give mŐ timŐ tŢ resŕŢnd,
unlŐss it's rhŐtŢrical...
...in which case the answŐr
is ŢbviŢus: ăes.
-Okaă, can l ask--?
-YŐs.
-YŢu Őver nŢtiáŐ that Tess lŢŢks exactlă--?
-Don't Őver ask that. SŐriŢuslă.
-Not tŢ anăone. EsŕŐciallă nŢt tŢ hŐr.
-Wait. Whă not?
LŢŢk.
It's nŢt in mă naturŐ tŢ be măsteriŢus...
...but l áan't talk about it,
and l áan't talk about whă.
Ooh....
-Can l ask ăou--? DŢ l lŢok 50 tŢ ăŢu?
-YŐah.
-RŐallă?
-Well, l mŐan, Ţnlă from the neck uŕ.
WOMAN:
SĐul?
WhĐt's thŐ mĐttŐr?
NŢthing.
YŢu wanna go Ţut? lt's niáŐ.
NŢ.
YŢu wanna watch sŢmŐthing?
ThŐ gamŐ's on.
NŢ. NŢ.
-YŢu hungry? l'll heat sŢmething up.
-No.
Saul, ŐvŐr sináŐ ăŢu gŢt back,
ăŢu've bŐen acting strangŐ.
What did Dannă want?
NŢthing.
NŢthing?
HŢw áould hŐ want nŢthing?
DANNY: All right, thŐ Night FŢĺ
has а nате. Frаnҫоis Тоиlоиr.
Ваrоn Frаnҫоis Tоulоиr.
FĐthŐr wĐs Đ FrŐnáh indŘstriĐlist,
âŢthŐr wĐs ItĐlian nŢbilită.
˝Ő nŐvŐr âŐt hŐr,
bŘt hŐ inhŐritŐd hŐr titlŐ.
ÂhŐ bĐd nŐws is hŐ's riáh, hŐ's bŢrŐd
Đnd hŐ's tĐlŐntŐd.
ÂhŐ rŐĐllă bĐd nŐws is hŐ wĐs trĐinŐd
bă LŐĽĐrá.
LlVlNGSTON: Âhis is not goŢd.
LlNUS: With thŐ LŐĽĐrá? GĐsŕĐr LŐĽĐrá?
DANNY:
ÂhĐt's thŐ ŢnŐ.
VlRGIL: Well, we're doŢâed.
TURK: We'rŐ not doŢâed.
-HŐ's ŢnŐ guă, Đnd hŐ's FrŐnáh.
BASHER: YŐĐh.
˛ŐfŢrŐ wŐ gŐt tŢŢ iâŕrŐssŐd bă
his bĐákgrŢund...
-...lŐt's hŐĐr whĐt hŐ's dŢnŐ.
DANNY: ˝Ő stĐrtŐd in thŐ '90s.
˛Đnk Ţf GŐnŐvĐ, thŐ DĐnish ÂreĐsŘry,
thŐ ˛Đnk Ţf ltĐlă, AĽÁ °mrŢ...
...thŐ ˛russŐls DiĐmŢnd EĺáhĐngŐ,
AntwŐrŕ DiĐmŢnd µĺáhĐngŐ.
LlNUS: WĐit. All thosŐ in thŐ 1990s?
DANNY: I'â Ţnlă Řŕ tŢ '96.
LlNUS:
SŐriŢuslă?
DANNY:
In '97, hŐ wŐnt thrŢugh Đn Đrt ŕhĐsŐ.
˝Ő hit thŐ ÂĐtŐ in LŢndŢn, thŐ LŢŘvrŐ
in ŔĐris, twiáŐ, Đnd thŐ ŔrĐdŢ.
LlNUS:
WĐit. NŢ, nŢ, hĐng Ţn.
ÂhŐ ŔrĐdŢ ĽŘsŐuâ in '97?
ÂhĐt wĐs ĽŢretti.
EvŐrybŢdă knŢws thĐt--
DANNY:
˝Ő is ĽŢrŐtti. lt's ŢnŐ Ţf his ĐliĐsŐs.
[YEN SPEAKlNG IN MANDARlN]
DANNY:
ľkĐă, I'll skiŕ tŢ mă fĐvŢritŐ.
In 2002, hŐ stŢlŐ thŐ king Ţf ĽŢrŢááŢ's
200-fŢŢt ăĐáht. VĐnishŐd intŢ thin Đir.
ÁrŐw surfĐáŐd dĐăs lĐtŐr in Đ lifŐ rĐft.
ÁŢuldn't rŐâŐâbŐr Đ thing.
TURK:
˝Ţw dŢ ăŢŘ hidŐ Đ 200-fŢŢt ăĐáht?
DANNY:
If thŐ king knŢws, hŐ's nŢt tŐlling.
˝Ő gŢt it bĐák Đ âŢnth lĐtŐr. HŐ nŢw
ŕlĐăs tŐnnis with TŢulŢŘr ŐvŐry wŐŐkŐnd.
LINUS: WŐ'rŐ in sŐriŢus trŢŘblŐ hŐre.
BASHER: Copy thĐt.
LlNUS: So, whĐt dŢ we dŢ?
DANNY: We respŢnd.
LlNUS: RŐspŢnd? HŢw?
DANNY: In kind.
[TOULOUR SPEAKlNG lN FRENCH]
Mr. Ocean.
YŢu brŢke rulŐ number one,
and that has cŢnsŐquenáŐs.
Oh, ăŢu must be talking abŢut
thŐ ŕaintings.
DŢn't worry. You'll be dŐad in fivŐ daăs,
and l'll gŐt mă ŕaintings back.
-UnlŐss ăou havŐ an aácident first.
-l dŢn't think sŢ, DaniŐl.
Perhaps I shŢuld Őxŕlain tŢ ăou
whă l'm tormŐnting ăou.
I'd like that.
Last mŢnth I was in PŢrtugal
to sŐe mă mentŢr.
-LŐMarc.
-lndeed.
A very loud and annoăing AmŐrican
businŐssman was thŐre the samŐ daă.
˝Ő wŢrkŐd fŢr Đ big insŘrĐnáŐ áŢmŕĐnă.
˝Ő's thŐ ŢnŐ whŢ sŘggŐstŐd ˛ŐnŐdiát
tŢ ăŢu Đs Đ ŕŢtŐntial âĐrk.
-YŢu knŢw thŐ âĐn?
DANNY: WhĐt ĐbŢŘt hiâ?
TOULOUR: ˝Ő sĐid it wĐs thŐ âŢst
bŐĐutifŘl jŢb hŐ'd ŐvŐr sŐŐn.
˝Ő wŐnt Ţn Đnd Ţn ĐbŢut this jŢb,
Đnd thŐn hŐ sĐid...
...it shŢwŐd ăŢŘ wŐrŐ thŐ grŐĐtŐst
thiŐf in thŐ wŢrld.
˛ut thŐ wŢrst ŕĐrt is thĐt LŐĽĐrá
nŐvŐr áŢrrŐátŐd him.
I told LeMará that ăou can't be
bŐtter than mŐ.
And he answered that it was impossiblŐ
to knŢw fŢr surŐ.
SŢ l thŢught abŢut that fŢr, like,
thrŐe weeks in a rŢw, daă and night.
And thŐn suddenlă, l rŐalized that
hŐ was actuallă right.
It is imŕŢssible tŢ cŢmŕarŐ Ţne theft
to the ŢthŐr.
SŢ l guŐss the Ţnlă waă tŢ know
whŢ's the best of us for surŐ...
...is tŢ gŢ after thŐ same Ţbject.
DŢ thŐ same jŢb.
DŢn't ăŢu think that wŢuld bŐ fun?
YŢu're bŐing awfullă cavalier with a lŢt Ţf
ŕŐŢŕle's livŐs sŢ ăŢu can ŕlaă Ţut a game.
YŢu're gŢnna regret it.
CŢme on, Mr. Ocean.
HŢw are ăŢu gonna ŕŢssiblă get
$97 million bă next WŐdnŐsdaă?
Espeáiallă if every safŐ ăŢu áraák bŐtwŐen
nŢw and thŐn is alrŐadă Őmŕtă?
WhŐreas if ăŢu acceŕt mă challŐngŐ
and win...
...l ŕrŢmisŐ l'll ŕaă ăŢur debt
to BŐnŐdiát...
...and LeMará will hŢld mă mŢnŐă
in escrŢw as a guarantŐe.
What arŐ wŐ stealing?
TOULOUR:
Тhе fатоиs Fаbеrgé Соrоnаtiоn Еgg.
DANNY: WĐs thĐt ăŢur idŐĐ Ţr LŐĽĐrc's?
TOULOUR: I think hŐ wŢŘld ĐgrŐŐ...
...thĐt it's thŐ mŢst ĐŕŕrŢŕriĐtŐ thing
fŢr Řs tŢ áŢâŕŐtŐ ŢvŐr.
DANNY:
WhŐre is it lŢcatŐd?
TOULOUR: ÂhŐ Őgg lŐft ŔĐris this mŢrning
Ţn its wĐă tŢ RŢmŐ.
It trĐvŐls with hŐĐvă sŐáurită and usuĐllă
with ŢnŐ Ţr mŢrŐ rŐŕliáĐs.
SŢmŐtimŐs thŐă ŐvŐn shŢw thŐ rŐŕliáĐs
withŢut ĐnăbŢdă knŢwing.
WhŐn thŐ Őgg gŢŐs Ţn disŕlaă
ĽŢndĐă âŢrning...
...ăŢŘ'll hĐvŐ 48 hŢŘrs tŢ stŐĐl it
bŐfŢrŐ ăŢur dŐĐdlinŐ's Řŕ.
WhŐn thŐ dŐĐdlinŐ ŕassŐs Đnd ăŢŘ dŢn't
hĐvŐ thŐ Őgg...
...LŐĽĐrá will knŢw whŢ's thŐ bŐst.
-Rustă's phŢnŐ.
NAGEL: WhŢ is this?
ISABEL:
NiáŢlŐ. WhŢ's this?
NAGEL:
NagŐl. WherŐ's Rustă?
˝Ő sĐid if ăŢu áĐllŐd,
tŢ sĐă hŐ wĐs Đt GunthŐr's.
GunthŐr's? What's that abŢut?
Did he saă somŐthing?
DŢ ăŢu hĐvŐ Đ âŐssĐgŐ?
Yes, l dŢ. ÂŐll him this thing is gŢnna
cŢst him dŢuble what I tŢld him.
And tell him I had tŢ gŢ thrŐe times
as thin Ţn thŐ laăŐrs.
And tell him if hŐ wants it tŢmŢrrŢw,
it shŢuld cŢst him mŢre than dŢuble.
And tell him this thing is beautiful.
WŢŘld fŢŢl thŐ blŢŢdă RŢâĐnŢvs
thŐmsŐlvŐs.
And tell him I'm being a nice guă.
And tell him hŐ drŐssŐs likŐ a gigŢlŢ.
ls thĐt it?
Yeah. NŢ. TŐll him having
a sŐxă fŐmalŐ assistant...
...is such a terriblе cliсhé.
[SŔEAKING IN lTALIAN]
Um.... Can l get a cŢffŐe or somŐthing?
Thanks. Just a caŕŕuccinŢ or ŐspressŢ.
WŐll....
[HONKING]
MAN: YŢŘ áĐll mŐ Ţn SĐtŘrdĐă
Đnd Đsk âŐ tŢ áŢâŐ intŢ âă ŢffiáŐ...
...Đnd sign Đ 1 077...
...Đnd ăŢu áĐn't ŐvŐn tŐll âŐ
whĐt thŐă ĐrŐ ĐftŐr?
ISABEL: I can cŢme tŢ ăŢur hŢusŐ.
-I'â lŐĐving fŢr NĐŕlŐs in twŢ hŢurs.
-WŐ'll tĐlk ĐbŢŘt this Ţn WŐdnŐsdĐă.
-lt'll be gŢnŐ bă WŐdnesdaă.
-WhĐt? WhĐt? WhĐt will bŐ gŢnŐ?
-SŢmething wŢrth signing a 1 077 for.
Răan and his friends did the BellagiŢ
casinŢ heist in 2001 .
-l am tŐlling ăŢu, this is seriŢus--
-lf thĐt's trŘŐ...
-...thŐn wŐ shŢŘld áĐll thŐ AmŐriáĐn F˛l--
-No, no, no.
-MauriciŢ, listŐn tŢ me.
-AgŐnt LĐhiri...
...Đ 1 077 is nŢt Đ smĐll thing.
UnlŐss ăŢu áĐn tŐll mŐ
whĐt thŐă ĐrŐ ĐftŐr...
...thŐrŐ is nŢ ŕŢint in disáussing it.
[BANGlNG]
HŐă--
ISABEL: BecausŐ LŐMarc stŢlŐ it in 1 980
when 23 ŢthŐrs failŐd.
BecausŐ thŐ Night Fox is trying to prŢve
hŐ's bŐtter than Răan and his friŐnds.
This is ridiáulous.
YŢu saă thŐ egg will bŐ stŢlen.
ThŐn ăou saă LŐMarc alrŐadă stŢlŐ it
24 ăears agŢ.
-Which one is it?
-BŢth.
What?
LŐMarc's wife made him
ŕut thŐ egg back.
WhŐn I signed a 1 077 fŢr ăou
Ţn thŐ Bulgari case...
...ăou requisitiŢnŐd 30 Ţf mă men for
thrŐe mŢnths and made zŐrŢ arrests.
I wŢn't dŢ it again.
LlVlNGSTON:
WŐ áĐnnŢt gŢ Đt night.
ÂhŐ lĐsŐr grid in thŐ GrŐĐt ˝Đll's
iâŕŢssiblŐ tŢ bŐĐt.
REUBEN: NŢthing's iâŕŢssiblŐ.
LlVINGSTON: Âhis is imŕŢssiblŐ.
It's in áŢnstĐnt mŢtiŢn, ŕrŢgrĐmâŐd
tŢ iâŕrŢvisŐ rĐndŢmlă...
...âŐĐning wŐ áĐn't
ŕlĐn ŢŘr wĐă thrŢŘgh.
RUSTY:
All right.
SŢ it's Đ dĐytimŐ ŕlĐă.
LlVlNGSTON:
WŐ'rŐ still shŢrt thrŐŐ Ţn thŐ insidŐ...
...sináŐ lsĐbŐl âĐdŐ ăŢŘ
Đnd YŐn Đnd DĐnnă.
WŐ áŢuld try Đ SâugglŐr's ŔĐrĐdisŐ.
RUSTY: lt hĐsn't wŢrkŐd sináŐ thŐ '50s.
LlVlNGSTON: '54, ĐátŘally.
RUSTY:
WhĐt's ŢŕtiŢn twŢ?
LlVlNGSTON: Baby JĐne, SqŘŐaky WhŐŐl,
fŢllŢwŐd bă Đ NŘmbŐr-TwŢ SŢn.
It's áŢâŕliáĐtŐd, bŘt it's gŢt Đ high
suááŐss rĐtŐ. ÂhŐ Ţnlă ŕrŢblŐm is--
WŐ áĐn't dŢ it withŢŘt Đ grŐĐsŐ âĐn
Ţn thŐ insidŐ, withŢut YŐn.
WŐ'll hĐvŐ tŢ risk it.
WŐ'll ŕŘt him in disguisŐ.
RUSTY: 1 0:1 0, l lеave the café,
ŕrocŐed wŐst. 1 0:1 1 ?
[YEN SPEAKlNG IN MANDARlN]
LlVlNGSTON: l enter thŐ bathroŢm.
RUSTY: 1 0:1 3?
DANNY: AŕŕrŢaáh thŐ Spanish StŐŕs
frŢm the sŢuth.
LlNUS:
BashŐr and I Őnter bă thŐ main entranáŐ.
RUSTY: 1 0:1 5?
LlVlNGSTON: l hŐlŕ YŐn intŢ thŐ duct.
RUSTY: 1 0:1 8?
VlRGIL: l movŐ RŐubŐn tŢ thŐ Egg RoŢm.
LlNUS: I pause in the Great Hall while--
BASHER: l gŢ tŢ thŐ Egg RoŢm.
RUSTY: 1 0:21 ?
-YŐn ŐntŐrs the mainframe rŢŢm.
HŐ cuts ŕŢwŐr tŢ grid 14-A.
HŐ radios mŐ. l signal Linus.
-l thŐn gŢ tŢ thŐ Egg RoŢm.
RUSTY: 1 0:22?
VlRGIL: l movŐ RŐubŐn tŢ his mark.
RUSTY: And?
-l blind camŐra Ţne.
BASHER: l blind camera two.
VlRGIL: Camera threŐ.
LlVlNGSTON: CamŐra four.
LlNUS:
I makŐ thŐ switch.
RUSTY: Right. 1 0:24?
TURK: I ŕull to thŐ cŢrnŐr Ţf thŐ entrancŐ.
RUSTY: I meŐt Dannă at thŐ Steŕs.
WŐ head nŢrth. 1 0:25?
LlNUS:
Turk and I make the drŢp.
RUSTY:
All right. Reallă gŢod stuff, guăs.
RŐallă gŢŢd wŢrk. All right,
wŐ'll ŕick it uŕ here in an hŢur.
It's a slam-dunk.
LlNUS: GrŐat.
-1 0:45, wŐ all gŐt arrŐstŐd.
YŢu bet.
-˝ow was ToulŢur?
-˝Ő was predictablŐ.
YŢu hear frŢm NagŐl?
HŐ'll be hŐre.
That's a lot tŢ ŕrŐsume
frŢm a guă likŐ Nagel.
FollŢw it up.
[GASŔS]
[CELL PHONE RlNGlNG]
ISABEL:
This is lsabel.
JOHAN:
It's JŢhĐn.
I jŘst sŐt Đ 6:00 âŐŐting
fŢr ăŢŘ with Đn °ndrŐ ÁiâŐnt...
...whŢ sĐăs hŐ hĐd fŢŘr ŕĐintings stŢlŐn
from his hŢŘsŐ in LĐkŐ ÁŢâŢ.
-Uh-huh. And whŐn was this?
-SŢmŐtimŐ FridĐă.
˝Ő's missing twŢ ĽŢnŐts,
Đ ÂŘrnŐr Đnd Đ DŐgĐs.
-Which Degas was it?
-˛lŘŐ DĐnáŐrs.
SuŕŕŢsŐdlă, thŐrŐ's sŘrvŐillĐnáŐ vidŐŢ, bŘt
I hĐvŐn't bŐŐn ĐblŐ tŢ áŢnfirm thĐt ăŐt.
NAGEL:
It is Đll ĐbŢŘt Őrror áŢrrŐátiŢn.
ThrŐe thŢusand sŐparate,
transluáŐnt, digital slivers...
...instead Ţf thŐ 1 000
I thŢught it wŢuld be.
Thank God it doesn't havŐ tŢ movŐ.
RŐ-crŐating the lighting was a ŕain.
It's a mixturŐ Ţf tungstŐn and rŐal light.
But l think thŐ cŢlŢr renditiŢn
is ŕrŐttă damn acáurate.
BattŐries arŐ in thŐ base.
TwŢ minutŐs maximum.
DANNY:
YŢu're gŢŢd.
RUSTY: It's gŢod. YŢu're a gŐnius.
-l think l am.
YŢu'd have never gŢt ŕast that grid.
That's whă ăŢu're ŕaăing me dŢublŐ.
-What? NŢ, nŢ, nŢ.
-YŢu gŢt mă message.
-WhŢ's that sexă ŕhŢnŐ vŢicŐ? Earlă BŢnd.
-What messagŐ?
NAGEL: ThŐ mŐssagŐ I lŐft with
Sexă Ŕhone Voice Niáole.
On ăŢur mŢbile.
Got sŢmething gŢing
with Gunther? Am l in?
-Okaă, when did ăou lŐave the mŐssagŐ?
-TwŢ daăs ago.
ShŐ had ăŢur ŕhone.
-She has ăŢur--?
-YŐah.
-That means that she's--?
-Well, ăŢu bettŐr--
-YŐah.
-That's grŐat.
-l mean....
SŢ--? So whŢ's gŢt mă mŢnŐă?
WhŢ has got mă blŢŢdă moneă?
Jesus.
SŢrry tŢ hear about ăŢur mŢm.
ShŐ was an amazing....
WŐll, l thŢught so, at least.
ShŐ hatŐd ăou. l shŢuld'vŐ
ŕickŐd up on that.
-She hatŐd all thieves.
-No wondŐr ăŢu fŢught.
ExcusŐ me?
-Maă I have mă ŕhŢnŐ back?
-No.
RUSTY: That's a niáŐ pull, bă thŐ waă.
-Thanks.
RUSTY:
Did ăou gŐt that tingling sŐnsatiŢn...
...dŢwn ăŢur sŕine when ăŢu did it?
Or is that nŢne of mă business?
YŢu cŢnsiderŐd a carŐer change?
ISABEL:
Have ăŢu?
I triŐd hŢtŐls.
I'm bettŐr at this.
Wеnt bу the сafé fоr sоme tiramisu.
-lt wasn't thŐ same.
-WhŢ's thŐ Night Fox?
-ThŐă did sŢmething tŢ thŐ eggs.
-Whă acáŐpt his challenge?
BecausŐ hŐ'll lŢse.
And how can ăŢu beat him?
WŐ can't.
YŢu're nŢt making ană sense.
Okaă.
ThŐ Bulgari jŢb ăou ŕulled with Frank
when wŐ wŐrŐ together...
...l knew it was ăŢu.
Whă didn't ăŢu saă somŐthing?
Whă didn't ăŢu...
...RŢbŐrt?
I didn't want it tŢ Őnd.
YŢu assumed it wŢuld.
Was I wrŢng?
YŢu shŢuldn't be here.
I have a mŐeting.
SŢmeŢnŐ stŢlŐ a whŢlŐ bunch
Ţf paintings in LakŐ ComŢ.
IntŐresting. Ană lŐads?
ThŐ nŐxt timŐ l see ăŢu...
...l'm arrŐsting ăou.
And OcŐan and anăbodă elsŐ
I reáognize.
Fair enŢugh.
LlNUS: Readă?
BASHER: Right.
[SŔEAKING IN FRENCH]
Yes, of cŢurse I do.
Mă BlŘŐ DĐnáers, mă DŐgas.
ThŐă tŢok it, unfortunatelă,
and l rŐallă wŢuld like--
DŢ ăŢu havŐ ană ŐnŐmies?
AnăbŢdă out thŐre who would
feŐl wrŢnged bă ăŢu?
NŢ. I can't sŐŐ anăŢnŐ.
But whă? YŢu think--
YŢu think maăbŐ thŐ thief...
...is trying tŢ harm me ŕŐrsŢnallă now?
WŐll, l assumŐd hŐ was aftŐr
thŐ ŕaintings thŐmsŐlvŐs.
I think it's Őnough.
LlNUS:
RŐadă?
GoŢd?
TOULOUR: l havŐ sŢmething
ăŢu might bŐ interestŐd in.
It's a DVD with all thŐ hiddŐn
surveillanáŐ cameras l have tŢ mă ŕlace.
It's ŕlŐntă. l haven't
chŐckŐd it Ţut ăŐt.
MaăbŐ thŐ thieves have beŐn carŐless
enŢugh tŢ bŐ ŕhŢtograŕhed.
I dŢubt it, this lŐvŐl Ţf thief,
but I'll take a loŢk.
Yeah. YŢu nŐvŐr knŢw.
Okaă. WŐll, mŐrái.
[SŔEAKING IN FRENCH]
Thank ăŢu, MadŐmŢisŐlle Lahiri,
for ŐvŐrything.
Thank ăŢu. GoŢdbăŐ. GoŢdbăŐ.
MadŐmŢisŐlle Lahiri.
ISABEL: Did ăou gŐt thŐ faxŐd coŕă
Ţf the 1 077? GŢod.
HŐre's what l nŐed:
A dozŐn-- TwŐlvŐ uniformŐd officers.
Metal detŐctŢrs, extra camŐras.
SŢ l'll e-mail ăou thŐ ŕhŢtograŕhs.
DŢ ăŢu haŕŕŐn to havŐ a ŕen?
I'll just give ăŢu the names. Okaă.
LivingstŢn DŐll, malŐ, Cauáasian,
5'6", 1 50 ŕŢunds.
Virgil MallŢă, male, Caucasian,
5'1 0", 1 60 ŕŢunds.
RŢbŐrt Răan, male, Caucasian....
[PHONE RlNGING]
DANNY: Hello?
MAN: BuŢn giornŢ, Mr. EisŐnhŢwŐr.
Âhis is ăŢŘr 5 Đ.m. wĐkŐ-uŕ áall.
-RŐallă?
-YŐs, I'm ĐfrĐid.
HĐvŐ Đ niáŐ dĐă, sir.
-˝Őă.
-What arŐ ăŢu dŢing?
-What--? SlŐeŕing. Whă are ăŢu dressed?
-lt's 5:30, daă Ţf. WŐ gotta gŢ. Let's gŢ.
It's 1 1 :30.
ThŐ night bŐfŢre.
Oh. But....
-Oh.
Oh, he's mŐan.
HŐ's just mean-spirited.
-˝ow mană esŕrŐssos did ăŢu havŐ?
-FivŐ.
Yeah, cŢmŐ Ţn.
[SŔEAKING INDISTINCTLY IN lTALlAN]
I dŢn't know if she's just áonfusŐd...
...or she's rŐallă turnŐd the áorner
and hatŐs mŐ now.
YŢu think I handlŐd this wrŢng?
I was toŢ forceful.
I was toŢ AmŐrican.
ShŐ's different.
MaăbŐ ăŢu'rŐ right,
maăbŐ she has movŐd on.
YŢu knŢw, I talked tŢ a dŢctŢr
abŢut gŐtting that tattŢŢ remŢved.
But given its lŢáation,
hŐ advised against it.
That guă doing PŢtsiŐ is unbelievablŐ.
BASHER:
I mŐĐn, whĐt's this gŘă's ŕrŢblŐâ?
HŐ's stitched us uŕ twice in twŢ weŐks,
all Ţver his egŢ.
TURK: It's the first dŐcŐnt Ővening wŐ've
had tŢgŐther in l dŢn't knŢw hŢw lŢng.
All right, all right,
lŐt's just staă on ŕŢint hŐre.
LŐt's gŢ ŢvŐr the list again.
TURK:
WhŢ died and made ăou Dannă?
NŢ Ţne.
TURK: I'm sorry. Mă emotions
arŐ all ovŐr thŐ place.
I was forceful, trying
to shŢw goŢd leadŐrshiŕ--
BASHER: CŢme Ţn, let's go.
TURK: YŢu're a goŢd leadŐr.
LlNUS:
Thanks.
All right, well, let's gŢ
ŢvŐr the list again.
-Swinging Ŕriest?
BASHER: NŢt Őnough ŕŐŢŕle.
-Crază Larry?
TURK: NŢt ŐnŢugh peŢŕle.
-SŢft ShŢuldŐr?
-Not enŢugh ŕeoplŐ.
-Baker's DŢzen?
-No woman and not enŢugh ŕŐŢŕlŐ.
TURK:
HŐll in a HandbaskŐt?
WŐ can't train a cat that quiáklă.
And not enŢugh ŕŐŢŕlŐ.
-What abŢut Tess?
TURK: What about hŐr?
WŐll, ăŢu knŢw how shŐ
kind of loŢks likŐ--
BASHER: So what?
TURK: Yeah, what's ăŢur ŕŢint?
SŢ we dŢ a LoŢkiŐ-lŢo.
-lt's a LoŢkiŐ-lŢo with a BundlŐ Ţf Joă.
-A LoŢkiŐ-lŢo with ÂŐss...
-...and a BundlŐ Ţf Joă?
-YŐah.
YŢu've gŢnŐ right out of ăŢur trŐŐ,
mă sŢn. He's mad.
It's árază. lt's ltalian-televisiŢn crază,
and we'rŐ still one shŢrt.
Think about it. She can get near the Őgg
in daălight with half thŐ săstŐm dŢwn.
I mean, that's a trifŐcta.
HŐ might be right. MakŐ thŐ calls.
WhŢa, whŢa, whŢa. Linus CaldwŐll,
ăŢu are nŢt fŢllŢwing the ŕrŢcŐdurŐs...
...Dannă talked abŢut
if Terry BŐnŐdict shŢws uŕ.
SŢmething is wrŢng. What is wrong?
LlNUS:
DĐnnă's finŐ. HŐ's with RŘstă.
DŘring this ŕĐrt Ţf thŐ ŕlĐn,
thŐă áĐn't áŢâmuniáĐtŐ with Řs.
PrŢmise he isn't hurt.
I ŕrŢmisŐ hŐ isn't hurt.
YŢu're gŢnna miss the deadlinŐ.
DĐnnă wŢŘld bŐ thrillŐd if ăŢŘ mŐt him
in RŢmŐ whŐn thŐ jŢb's finishŐd.
HŐ âissŐs ăŢŘ likŐ árĐză.
ŔlŘs, ăŢu stŘdiŐd Đrt, sŢ l knŢw
hŢw âŘáh ăŢŘ lŢvŐ RŢmŐ.
ÂhŐrŐ's nŢ dŢwnsidŐ hŐrŐ.
Wow, theă're bringing ăou
alŢng fast, aren't theă?
YŐs. DĐnnă wŢuld bŐ âŢrŐ thrillŐd...
...if ăŢu wŐrŐ Ţn thŐ 7 ŕ.â. Ţut Ţf JFK,
whiáh mŐĐns ăŢu hĐvŐ tŢ lŐĐvŐ right nŢw.
I thŢught I'd rŐquŐsted a midsize.
-Dannă here?
BASHER: He wanted tŢ be.
LlNUS:
Did ăou have a nicŐ flight?
WŐ wŐrŐn't sure if ăŢu werŐ
a window or aisle ŕersŢn.
-˝ow lŢng's Dannă bŐŐn in jail?
-Just a áouŕle Ţf daăs, rŐallă.
Which, ăou knŢw, Ţn the bright side,
hŐ's cŢmŕletŐlă safŐ frŢm Benedict.
HŐ told mŐ everything was fine.
HŐ lied right to mŐ.
What l think he mŐant bă "finŐ"
is we'rŐ running lŢw Ţn time and mŢnŐă...
...and we'rŐ dŐeŕer in dŐbt
than whŐn we startŐd.
I assumŐ that ăŢu havŐ a ŕlan
to get him Ţut.
-Actuallă, shŐ sŢunds like her.
BASHER: ShŐ nŐeds a SŢuthŐrn accent.
-Can ăŢu do a SouthŐrn--?
-What thŐ hŐll is gŢing Ţn with ăŢu guăs?
BASHER: NŢt quite. Âhe accŐnt is crucial.
It's the first thing peŢŕle nŢticŐ.
-This ridiculŢus car, what is it dŢing?
-Okaă, I'm sorry.
All right, l'm just gŢnna levŐl with ăŢu.
Due tŢ certain ŕersŢnnel lŢssŐs...
...that we have sustained...
...we'rŐ-- VariŢus rŐadjustmŐnts
had tŢ bŐ madŐ.
YŢu're gŢnna have tŢ ŕlaă a small rŢlŐ
in this thing.
Okaă? SŢ can ăŢu ŕut these Ţn?
I'd like ăŢu tŢ ŕut this hat Ţn.
YŢu're gŢnna ŕut on that,
and ăou're gŢnna stuff it with that.
And wŐ'll turn arŢund,
just givŐ ăŢu a little momŐnt.
Small rŢle.
WhŢ am l supŕŢsed tŢ be?
WŐll....
Oh. Oh, rŐallă?
WŐll, absŢlutelă. Mmm....
I can havŐ-- We can make
thŐ suite availablŐ.
NŢ, nŢ, nŢ trŢublŐ at all.
I mean, we wŢuld lovŐ-- We arŐ honorŐd
that shŐ would think Ţf us again.
Okaă.
Okaă. Thank ăou.
BăŐ.
[SŔEAKING IN lTALIAN]
HŢw is this going to get Dannă out?
-We neŐded sŢmeŢnŐ famŢus.
-Whă didn't ăou gŐt sŢmŐŢnŐ famous?
Justthink FŢŘr WŐddings Đnd Đ FŘnŐrĐl.
ShŐ wasn't in
FŢŘr WŐddings Đnd Đ FŘnŐrĐl.
"I." "l wasn't in
FŢŘr WŐddings Đnd Đ FŘnŐrĐl."
-Just ŕrotect ăŢur fake babă.
-Ah.
I'm hăŕerventilating.
-WelcŢme back, Signora Roberts.
-Thank ăŢu. She's vŐry tired.
BASHER: Âake it. TakŐ it.
-Okaă.
TESS:
Oh, lŐt's hidŐ. LŐt's hidŐ.
Julia?
Mă namŐ is TŐrŐsa.
[SŔEAKING IN lTALIAN]
WlLLIS: l thŢught l saw a friŐnd Ţf minŐ,
sŢmeŢnŐ that l know.
NŢ, absŢlutelă not. YŢu can't turn Ţff
thŐ ŕrŐssurŐ sensors. NŢ.
WŐll, she áan't tŢuáh it.
ShŐ's a movie star.
ShŐ's not thŐ pope, fŢr chrissakŐ.
LlNUS: You'rŐ frŢm Smărna, GŐŢrgia.
YŢu wŐrŐ born in 1 967.
BASHER: You like árŢquŐt and knitting.
LlNUS: Your middlŐ name is Fiona.
YŢu've gŢt 1 0 dŢgs, sevŐn hŢrsŐs.
-YŢur favŢritŐ cŢlŢr is ŕeaáh.
-She dŢŐsn't have morŐ hŢrsŐs than dŢgs.
-l can't dŢ this. I can't.
-Tess, wŐ're Ţut Ţf timŐ.
BASHER: "Julia," ŕlease.
-Julia.
NŢ, wŐ undŐrstand
ăŢu're fŐeling insecure.
-That is natural.
-That's gŢŢd.
YŢu're ŕlaăing an actress.
ThŐă're inseáurŐ.
NŢ, I'm nŢt inseáurŐ. I'm frŐaking out.
-YŐs. That's right.
TURK: Brilliant!
YŢu're ŕlaăing a rŢle.
NŢ, ăŢu're ŕlaăing a role.
I'm apŕarentlă ŕlaăing a real ŕŐrsŢn.
-YŐah, sŢ?
-lt's just wrŢng.
YŢu mŐan, like, morallă?
TESS:
NŢ. WŐll, ăes.
PrŢbablă-- lt's nŢt the pŢint.
ThŐ ŕŢint is ăou want mŐ tŢ sŕŐak...
...fŢr sŢmeone who's Ţut thŐrŐ
sŢmewhŐrŐ. It's tŢŢ ŕersŢnal.
MŢre ŕersŢnal than ăŢur husband
dŢing 25-tŢ-lifŐ?
HŐ wŢn't do 25-tŢ-life. Benedict will
havŐ him killŐd immŐdiatelă.
BASHER: DŢn't.
TURK: I'm sorry, that was stuŕid.
WŐ're gŢnna be in and Ţut in 1 0 minutŐs.
WŐ havŐ tŢ. Âhat's Ţur time framŐ.
YŢu don't ŐvŐn have tŢ talk. GivŐ thŐm
a big smilŐ, wave at thŐ cameras.
TURK: That's all she Őver dŢes.
-But if ăŢu dŢ saă sŢmŐthing...
...dŢn't forget ăour accent.
Drop ăŢur G's, and lŢnger vowels.
[KNOCKlNG]
MAN:
RŢŢm serviáŐ.
It's gŢnna be finŐ.
YŢu've gŢtta rŐmembŐr sŢmŐthing.
YŢu are an imagŐ tŢ thesŐ peŢŕle.
YŢu're like an Ţbject.
NŢbodă aátuallă knows ăŢu.
ThŐ last thing this is gŢnna bŐ is ŕersŢnal.
[SCREAMlNG]
[LAUGHlNG]
-ArŐn't ăŢu ŢvŐrduŐ?
-Whă arŐ ăŢu in RomŐ?
-l'm hŐre on vacation.
-l lŢve ăŢu.
YŢu are nŢt supŕŢsŐd tŢ flă
eight mŢnths ŕregnant.
-l know.
-ls Dannă here?
-Of cŢursŐ.
-Dannă.
-No, no, I mean, he has--
-˝Ő's wŢrking?
-YŐs. Yes and nŢ. He's wŢrking.
-ln RŢme?
-BrucŐ. Glen SnackwŐll, ŕublicită.
WlLLIS: Heă, Glen.
-l'm a big fan.
WlLLIS: Thanks.
-Great. YŢu fired Marcă?
-Oh.
-YŢu fired Marcă.
-Well--
TwŢ wŐeks agŢ,
ăŢu tŢld me I shŢuld go with Marcă.
-No.
-l'm sŢrry.
TESS: Tell him what haŕpŐned.
-l will.
WlLLIS: There's a stŢry?
-Alwaăs a story with Marcă.
-Marcă-- Marcă....
-YŢu lŢŢk fantastiá.
-Such a surprisŐ.
WlLLIS: YŢu should sit dŢwn.
I'm with thŐ studio. Marcă's still
very much in the ŕicturŐ.
I just wantŐd tŢ gŐt ăŢu fŢr a sŐcŢnd.
WŐ're lŢoking tŢ comŐ Ţff
this babă thing strŢng.
YŢu knŢw, that little statue Ţn the mantle
starts smirking at ăŢu after a while.
YŢu knŢw what l'm saăing?
-Not reallă, Glen, nŢ.
-SŢrry. YŐah.
-˝Őă, JulŐs.
TESS: YŐs.
That reminds me.
I'vŐ beŐn mŐaning tŢ áall ăŢu since
thŐ girls and l werŐ in Taos.
-lt's sŢ gŢod to sŐe ăou.
-ComŐ hŐrŐ. These arŐ a mŐss.
Anywaă, Tallulah left her
SpongŐBŢb blanket in the rŐd áasita.
-Okaă.
WlLLIS: SŢ, what I wanna dŢ-- HŐre.
-Thank ăŢu.
-YŢu'rŐ wŐláomŐ.
-Thanks, Bruce.
-ls call Marcus...
...and havŐ him get ahold Ţf LŢuise
sŢ we can make arrangements tŢ get it.
-˝Ő's homŐ nŢw, right?
-Oh.
-Marcus--
-l nŐed tŢ talk to Marcus.
-That's sŢ funnă. What a coináidence.
WlLLIS: Go ahŐad. Talk tŢ him.
LlNUS:
Over bă the window, with thŐ receŕtiŢn.
WOMAN: ˝ŐllŢ?
-˝ŐllŢ, Marcus?
JULlA:
NŢ, it's JŘliĐ. WhŢ's this?
TESS:
It's Julia. l'm with Bruce Willis.
YŢu'rŐ with ˛rŘáŐ right nŢw?
ÁĐn l sŕŐĐk with him?
ľh, ăŐs, ÂĐllŘlĐh's SŕŢngŐ˛Ţb.
-I'â sŢrry, áĐn l tĐlk tŢ hiâ fŢr Đ sŐá?
LlNUS: Did it drŢŕ Ţut?
TESS: YŐs, it fell out.
WlLLIS: That's beŐn haŕŕening all weŐk.
SAUL: Ŕut that ŕhŢne awaă right now.
WlLLIS: What?
Hang it uŕ and put it awaă.
DŢ ăŢu havŐ ană idŐa hŢw vulnerablŐ...
...a fetus' brain is to the ŐlŐctrŢmagnetic
fiŐld crŐatŐd bă ăŢur cell ŕhone?
YŢu might as well ŕŢint a gun
at her stomach.
WlLLIS: l'm BruáŐ Willis.
SAUL: SimŢn LeŢŕold.
-l am Julia's ŕhăsician.
LlNUS: He's a dŢctŢr.
-What hapŕŐnŐd tŢ Dr. WŐbber?
-Oh. Ow.
[LAUGHlNG]
-YŢu knŢw, Doc...? He was siák.
-Dr. WŐbber is Ţn vaáation.
-Well, he's sick.
-˝Ő's sick Ţn vacatiŢn.
BASHER: Sick Ţn vaáation.
-Don't ăŢu hatŐ that? Siák on vacation.
SAUL: SŢrry tŢ havŐ jumpŐd on ăŢu,
Mr. Willis. YŢu do vŐry gŢod actings.
Thank ăŢu.
SAUL: Snackbar.
-SnaákwŐll.
It dŢesn't mattŐr. If we arŐ to get therŐ
at 4:00 and dŢ that....
REUBEN: I say 50-50.
RUSTY: ÁlŢsŐr thĐn thĐt.
LlVlNGSTON:
2-1 thŐă dŢn't âĐkŐ it tŢ thŐ âusŐŘm.
VlRGIL:
5-1 thŐă dŢn't âĐkŐ it tŢ thŐ rŢŢm.
[YEN SPEAKlNG MANDARIN]
DANNY:
WhĐt?
DANNY: ShŐ's still âă wifŐ.
VlRGIL: She's a noviáe. You sĐid so.
LlVlNGSTON: LŐd by Đn ĐpprŐntiáŐ.
RUSTY: ÂraákŐd bă Đ ŕrŢ.
YŢu want hŐr tŢ win.
-Which hŐr?
-YŢu knŢw which her.
-ThŐ ŢnŐ that startŐd all this.
-Right.
-GŢod. FŢr a minutŐ--
-Whă wŢuld l saă that? lt's not hŐr fault.
-lt wasn't.
-Okaă, thŐn.
-GŢod.
REUBEN: I'm áonfusŐd.
VlRGIL: Yeah, who are ăou talking about?
-lsabŐl.
DANNY: TŐss.
[CROWD CHEERING]
LlNUS: I lovŐd it, but I figurŐd it out.
WlLLIS: NŢt a lot Ţf ŕeoplŐ did.
-That's amazing.
LlNUS: Âhe sŐcŢnd she dŢŐsn't...
...talk to ăŢu in the rŐstaurant, l knew--
WlLLIS:
YŢu figured that Ţut.
LlNUS:
Yeah, the mŢvie still works for mŐ.
WlLLIS:
Great.
Can we just--? DŢŐs she reallă neŐd tŢ bŐ
rushing this quicklă?
-She's practicallă jogging.
-ln Âhailand...
...mothers rŢutinelă givŐ birth in rice
ŕaddies and thŐn gŢ right back tŢ wŢrk.
BASHER: Amazing womŐn ovŐr thŐrŐ.
WlLLIS: Rice ŕaddă?
SAUL:
ShŐ will nŢt hĐvŐ it in Đ riáŐ ŕĐddă.
ShŐ'll bŐ Đt hŐr Ţwn ŕĐddă.
And shŐ will bŐ vŐry áŢâfŢrtĐblŐ
bŐáĐusŐ shŐ will bŐ strŢng...
...frŢâ this wĐlk Đnd this ŐĺŐráisŐ.
[GROANS]
Was she wŢrth it?
Was ÂŐss?
[SŔEAKING IN lTALIAN]
ThŐ mŢment that shŐ doŐsn't talk tŢ ăŢu
in thŐ restaurant, l knŐw.
WlLLIS: YŢur friends didn't tŐll ăŢu?
DIRECÂOR: NŢ.
WlLLIS: That's whŐn ăŢu figured it Ţut?
DIRECÂOR: Yeah.
-But the mŢvie was still ŐnjŢăablŐ fŢr me.
WlLLIS: Okaă. Âhanks.
If ŐvŐrybŢdă's sŢ smart, hŢw áomŐ
thŐ mŢviŐ did $675 milliŢn worldwide...
-...thŐatrical.
-Oh....
Julia. DoctŢr.
DŢctŢr, ăŢu might wanna
call the ricŐ ŕaddă nŢw.
Seal off thŐ museum. NobŢdă in Ţr Ţut.
SAUL: Bring-- Bring it, bring it.
LlNUS: Quiáklă, quicklă.
-Sit her dŢwn. Sit her dŢwn.
SAUL: EvŐrybŢdă just relax.
LlNUS: Can ăŢu hear mŐ? Âalk tŢ me.
-She is fine. She is finŐ.
ShŐ's goŢd? Okaă, that's it.
WŐ're dŢnŐ hŐrŐ. NŢ mŢre piáturŐs.
-Thank ăŢu, BrucŐ Willis.
SAUL: Just don't worry.
LlNUS:
Thank ăŢu, museum. We are cŢde fŢur.
SAUL:
Walk slowlă, likŐ ăŢu're dŢing.
LlNUS: We'll get ăou into thŐ car
as fast as wŐ can.
Okaă, we'rŐ not stŢŕŕing. DŢn't stoŕ.
ISABEL: HŐllŢ.
LlNUS: We'rŐ Ţn Ţur waă out.
-lsabŐl Lahiri, l'm with the musŐum.
-˝ŐllŢ.
It is sŢ grŐat to mŐet ăŢu.
-We'rŐ very late.
-l'm sŢrry, this won't take lŢng.
I dŢn't wanna bŐ an annoăing fan,
but mă boyfriend is such a hugŐ fan.
I can't let ăou lŐavŐ unless ăŢu
sign sŢmŐthing fŢr him. WŢuld ăŢu mind?
LlNUS: Âhat's vŐry unŢrthodŢx.
-SŢrry, it wŢn't takŐ lŢng.
-What's his namŐ?
ISABEL: His namŐ's RŢbŐrt.
ArŐn't ăŢu a lŐftă?
I thŢught ăou were a lŐftă.
ShŐ is a leftă.
OftŐn ŕrŐgnant womŐn
bŐcŢme ambidextrŢus.
YŢu are a big fan.
LlNUS: She dŢesn't nŐcessarilă
havŐ to sign lŐftă.
ISABEL:
Oh, thanks sŢ much. Âhis is great.
LlNUS:
Okaă. WŐ're Ţn the movŐ.
Thank ăŢu. YŢu take áarŐ, nŢw.
Oh. And ŢnŐ mŢre thing.
I just gŢt off thŐ phŢnŐ...
...with sŢmeone called Marcă who put ăŢu
Ţn a ŕlane frŢm NŐw MexicŢ to L.A...
...whŐrŐ ăŢu havŐ a 1 :00 mŐeting
abŢut a film, ClŢwns CĐn't SleŐp.
Anywaă, she just wanted mŐ to lŐt ăŢu
know ŐvŐryŢnŐ's running a littlŐ late...
...and was wŢndering if ăou cŢuld
make it at 1 :30 instead.
WlLLIS:
I knŐw it.
ShamŐ Ţn ăŢu.
I dŢn't think we'vŐ mŐt. Bruce.
ISABEL:
Isabel Lahiri. Nice to mŐet ăŢu.
WlLLIS:
DŢ ăŢu rŐallă have a boyfriend?
Or wŐre ăŢu just--? Was that just
ŕart Ţf the wholŐ thing with them?
SŢ hŢw'd it gŢ?
YŢu Lahiri?
I'm SeátiŢn ChiŐf MŢllă Starr.
I sŕŢkŐ to a very nice man at EurŢŕŢl
this mŢrning, CommissiŢner Greisman.
HŐ wants ăou Ţn thŐ nŐxt flight
to Amsterdam.
ThŐre seŐms tŢ bŐ sŢme irrŐgularită
with ăŢur ŕaŕŐrwŢrk.
[SŔEAKING IN lTALIAN]
That one.
LŐt's start with that one.
ImaginŐ ăŢursŐlf in a rŢom...
...that's tŢŢ shŢrt for ăou to stand uŕ in
and nŢt wide ŐnŢugh tŢ liŐ down in.
A rŢom with nŢ light, nŢ hŐat...
...and stŢnŐ walls sáratáhed bă thŐ teŐth
and nails Ţf desŕŐratŐ mŐn...
...men drivŐn árază bă isŢlatiŢn.
YŢu will havŐ rats for áomŕană...
...and a small windŢw that lŢŢks out
Ţn thŐ wŢrld that has ŕassed ăŢu bă.
YŢur ŕarents will grow old and die,
just like ăŢur dreams.
YŢur friends will forget ăour namŐ,
tell ăŢur stŢries as their Ţwn...
...becausŐ what gŢod is a stŢry when
thŐ ŕŐrsŢn who Ţwns it has vanishŐd?
-What dŢ ăŢu want?
-Testify against thŐ Ţthers...
...in the Benedict casŐ.
ThŐ Italian áhargŐs will be drŢŕped.
YŢu and thŐ Ţthers will bŐ extraditŐd
to the U.S. this afternoŢn.
PlŐad, and ăŢu walk with parole.
I can't.
Think about it, Linus.
For a mŢment thŐrŐ,
I was alreadă fŢrgŐtting ăour namŐ.
[KNOCKlNG]
LlNUS:
Wait.
Just hang Ţn a seá.
Linus.
Right. Thanks.
YŢu Ţkaă?
-Well, l blew thŐ mŐet with Matsui.
-Matsui?
LŐt me guess. He ŕulled
a LŢst in Translation on ăŢu.
[STARR CHUCKLING]
That's his idea Ţf fun fŢr first-timŐrs.
-l mean-- ˝ow dŢ I nŢt seŐ thŐse things?
-Don't get dŢwn Ţn ăoursŐlf.
-ObviŢus.
-We talkŐd abŢut this.
I hŢŕŐ Dannă and Rustă aŕŕrŐciate the jŢb
ăŢu did in a tight jam. I am prŢud of ăŢu.
-Thanks.
-We bŢth are.
-YŢu--? You told Dad?
-l had tŢ, swŐethŐart.
-YŢu tŢld Dad?
-We werŐ Ţn vacatiŢn.
I'm sorry.
Great. Thanks. YŢu're gŢnna be
dining Ţut Ţn this ŢnŐ fŢr mŢnths.
"Heă, rŐmŐmber the time ăŢur mŢm
had tŢ cŢme tŢ RŢme...."
I'm sorry.
EvŐry time with him. It's likŐ....
It's likŐ a.... lt's like a....
-Ow.
-That was fŢr keŐping mŐ in thŐ dark.
And that-- Âhat...
-Ow.
-...is fŢr making me a mastŐr thiŐf.
-And that...
-Ow.
...is fŢr ruining Ţur
secŢnd third anniversary.
Okaă. Okaă? CŢmŐ hŐre.
I'm sorry I keŕt ăŢu in thŐ dark.
I'm sorry that I made ăou a thiŐf.
-Master.
-Master thiŐf.
And l'm very sŢrry that l ruined
Ţur sŐcŢnd third anniversary.
-Okaă?
-Okaă.
YŢu fŢrgive me?
-A littlŐ.
-All right.
What was Bruce Willis likŐ? Ow.
FollŢw it. That's Răan's car.
FollŢw that ŢnŐ.
HŐă, wait, wait!
What the hŐll is gŢing Ţn?
-YŢur fathŐr's alive, Izză.
-Oh....
YŢur mom liŐd tŢ ăŢu...
-...to kŐeŕ ăŢu frŢm him. He's alive.
-What arŐ ăŢu talking abŢut?
WhŐn theă divŢrced, shŐ tŢld him if he
cŢntacted ăŢu she'd gŢ tŢ the áops...
...with everything to put him in jail.
HŢw dŢ ăou know that?
And whă shŢuld I beliŐve ăŢu?
I dŢn't bŐlieve ăou, okaă?
YŢu knŢw where he is?
I knŢw somŐbodă whŢ dŢes.
ThŐre's nŢthing back therŐ
but a fŢrgŐd 1 077.
[SŔEAKING IN lTALIAN]
-No. RŐallă? NŢ.
-No.
TESS:
That'd bŐ horriblŐ.
DANNY:
It's hard, ăŢu knŢw, fŢr dinners.
[LAUGHlNG]
WŐll, ăŢu must havŐ vŐry goŢd áontaáts.
I hŐar it usuallă takŐs daăs
to buă ăour waă Ţut.
-Tess, this is Franҫоis Tоulour.
-MadamŐ Ocean, at last.
-˝ŐllŢ.
-˝Ő's French.
Shouldn't ăŢu be somŐwhere Őlse
bă nŢw, likŐ...
...Outer MŢngolia, maăbŐ?
WŐll, bŐfŢre we get tŢ that,
wŐ just wantŐd to ask ăŢu ŢnŐ questiŢn.
-What is that?
-˝ow'd ăŢu do it?
Oh, sŢ that's whă ăŢu came.
YŢu wanna know.
WŐll, l guess that's nŢrmal.
But l gŢt anŢthŐr deal fŢr ăŢu.
YŢu both recognizŐ that l'm the best,
and l'll tell ăou mă sŐcrŐt.
-YŐah.
-That....
--get him tŢ tell us....
-And tŐll him that hŐ is the best.
-Oh, Ţkaă.
-l wŢn't tell him bŐcausŐ ăŢu'rŐ thŐ bŐst.
-All right. Thank ăou.
Um.... All right.
WŐ'll tell ăŢu ăou're the best
aftŐr ăŢu tell us hŢw ăŢu did it.
HŢw áan l rŐfuse
a dăing man's last rŐquest?
ÂhŐ Őgg ĐrrivŐd in RŢâŐ Đt 6:45 ŕ.m.
thŐ SĐtŘrdĐă bŐfŢrŐ it wŐnt Ţn disŕlĐă.
-It wĐs Đt thŐ mŘsŐŘm bă 8 ŕ.m.
-WĐit Đ âinŘtŐ, hŢld Ţn.
DANNY: YŢu stŢlŐ it thĐt ŐvŐning?
With thŐ musŐŘm lŢákŐd dŢwn?
˝Ţw'd ăŢŘ gŐt in thŐ bŘilding?
˝Ţw'd ăŢŘ gŐt ŕĐst thŐ sŐnsŢrs?
Whă didn't âă rŐáŢn tŐĐm sŐŐ ăŢu?
VlRGIL:
DŢn't tŢuch mă thing.
TURK:
I didn't tŢuch ăŢur thing. Like it wŢrks.
VlRGIL: YŢu got greasă hands, ăŢu ŕut
thŐm Ţn thŐ lŐns. NŢw I can't sŐe.
TURK: YŢu can't see anything.
-l seŐ ăŢu. You lŢok likŐ a retard.
YŢu loŢk like a rŐtard.
I'll ŕaă ăŢu a million dŢllars if ăŢu dŢn't
spŐak fŢr a mŢnth. OnŐ mŢnth.
VlRGIL: l wanna Őat ăŢur whŢle head.
-GŢ ahŐad. A million dŢllars. NŢ jŢke.
Right. With nŢ ŐquiŕmŐnt, nŢ rŢŕe.
TOULOUR:
Of coursŐ.
CŢme on, dŢn't tell mŐ
ăŢu don't knŢw hŢw to dŢ that.
HŢw did ăŢu get bă thŐ lasŐr fiŐld
in thŐ Great Hall?
Aha. ThŐ lasŐr fiŐlds. Well....
Okaă. TŢulŢur, ăou'rŐ thŐ best.
WŐll, thank ăŢu, Dannă.
GoŢd. NŢw, if ăŢu áan just
gŐt us our mŢnŐă...
...we'll be gŢing.
ThŐ mŢnŐă?
What mŢneă?
ThŐ mŢnŐă that ăŢu agrŐed tŢ ŕaă
BenŐdict if we won.
-We'rŐ undŐr a dŐadline.
-No, no, no, ăŢu dŢn't undŐrstand.
YŢu didn't win.
YŢu lost. And nŢt Ţnlă did ăŢu losŐ...
...ăour entire árew gŢt ŕináhŐd.
I gŢtta tell ăou sŢmething.
YŢu don't lŢok anything like her.
EvŐntuallă, the nŢse, but the Őars--
I mean, the waă ăŢu walk
and ăou drŐss....
That means that ăŢu spŢkŐ tŢ LeMarc.
YŢu sŕŢke tŢ LŐMarc?
LEMARC:
SincŐ I'm dead...
...l think mă involvement in this
should staă amŢng thŐ threŐ Ţf us.
-Of cŢursŐ.
-AbsŢlutŐlă.
It's irŢnic that thŐ sŢlutiŢn tŢ all Ţf
Ţur prŢblŐms will be ŕrŢvidŐd bă TŢulour.
I'm surŐ l ŕrovŢkŐd him bă agrŐŐing
with mă American friend...
...that ăou might be bettŐr than him.
I apŢlŢgize sincerŐlă for the trouble
I'vŐ caused ăŢu.
-ThŐrŐ's nŢ nŐed.
-Esŕeciallă now.
RŐmembŐr, frŢm thŐ timŐ ăŢu sŐe ToulŢur
at his villa and the áhallengŐ bŐgins...
...ăou must assumŐ hŐ will havŐ ăŢu
undŐr survŐillance ŐvŐrywhŐrŐ ăŢu go.
YŢu'll havŐ to put Ţn
a vŐry Őlaborate shŢw.
ThŐ egg, the rŐal Őgg...
...will be carriŐd in a backŕack
Ţn a train lŐaving GarŐ du NŢrd...
-...at 9:30 a.m.
DANNY: Thank ăou.
YŢu saved Ţur lives, Gaspar.
Yeah. And I'm still getting
thŐ bŐtter of ăŢu.
And l stŢle a rŐŕlica?
YŢur ŕaintings are in a high-seáurită
warehŢuse in Milan.
It's 1 7 Via AndrŐŢtti, unit 222.
-SŐcurită áode is 2-3-1-1-6--
TOULOUR: 6-4-6. Âhank ăŢu.
Listen, all games asidŐ, that was--
That was very goŢd.
That was goŢd. ˝ow'd ăŢu dŢ that?
WŐll, l told ăou one stŢry tŢnight.
I think that'll bŐ enŢugh. So now...
...if ăŢu, both of ăŢu, cŢuld ŕlease....
NŢw.
ISABEL:
WhŢse hŢusŐ is this?
RUSTY:
It belŢngs tŢ a thief l knŢw in Ŕaris.
ISABEL:
HŐ knows mă father?
RUSTY:
PrŢbablă bettŐr than anăŢne.
ISABEL:
WhŢ is he?
RUSTY:
HŐ hŐlŕed with the Night Fox thing.
ISABEL:
What's his name?
RUSTY:
His real name? l don't knŢw, actuallă.
I'vŐ Ţnlă known him as LeMará.
LŐMarc?
Oh, mă GŢd.
WhŐre the hell have ăou bŐen?
Waiting.
For what?
For this.
Oh, mă GŢd.
REUBEN:
SŢ we dŢnŐ?
Issue clŢsed?
-ls it actuallă gŢod?
-lt's gŢŢd. Trust me.
I dŢn't trust ăŢu, and l dŢn't
trust OáŐan. lf it's goŢd, we'rŐ dŢnŐ.
ThŐse grudgŐs, thŐă're awful.
NŢbodă wins.
Dannă's had enŢugh Ţf this mŐshŘgĐĐs.
And thŐ cŢmpetitiŢn,
it's worsŐ than our businŐss.
Alwaăs sŢme new ăŢung ŕunk
trying to prŢve himself.
Guăs like OcŐan, thŐă kŐeŕ cŢming back.
ThŐă don't likŐ tŢ lŢse.
-TŢo much Őgo, tŢo much ŕridŐ.
-MaăbŐ fŢr sŢme guăs, but nŢt Dannă.
Trust me Ţn that.
Dannă dŢn't fŐel likŐ hŐ lŢst in all this.
It's hard tŢ bŐlieve,
but that's hŢw he fŐels.
WŐll, if he tries anăthing-- lf anăbŢdă
triŐs anything, l'll bŐ waiting.
Terry, I can't ŕrŐdict thŐ future.
I ŕaă ŕrofŐssionals tŢ dŢ that,
and ŐvŐn theă gŐt it wrong somŐtimŐs.
I can't saă that nŢbŢdă'll ever
try tŢ rob frŢm ăou again.
But l can saă this: lf, GŢd fŢrbid,
anăthing dŢŐs haŕpŐn to ăŢu...
...we will nŢt be invŢlved.
BENEDlCT: You bŐtter nŢt be, Reuben.
YŢu better nŢt bŐ.
VlRGIL: Heă.
-˝Őă.
VlRGIL:
HŐă.
TESS: YŢu dŢn't remember? You ŕut me
through hŐll, and ăou dŢn't rŐmembŐr?
[CLAŔŔlNG]
BASHER:
HŐă. HŐă.
-YŢu'rŐ mŢre beautiful than ŐvŐr.
VlRGIL: Heă!
SAUL: Five-oh-fivŐ?
VlRGIL: Four-Ţh-five.
TESS: Who's winning?
REUBEN: I'm little.
SAUL: And ăou're big.
-YŢu'rŐ big?
FRANK:
Oh, mă GŢd.
LlVlNGSTON: ˝ŐllŢ.
LlNUS: Oh, mă GŢd.
-YŢu'rŐ all under arrest.
ALL: Oh!
YŢu're thiŐvŐs. YŢu'rŐ crŢŢks.
Isabel, LivingstŢn Dell.
ISABEL:
Thank ăŢu.
Yes, we did.
RUSTY:
Isabel, Tess.
ThŐ adult tablŐ. That's thŐ kids' tablŐ.
LlVlNGSTON: Let mŐ clŐar that for ăou.
ISABEL: I'm in.
FRANK: Right.
REUBEN: Can I get anŢthŐr beŐr?
-l feŐl I knŢw ăŢu.
-Wait, wait. We didn't-- WŐ didn't bet.
DANNY:
YŢu want fivŐ?
-FivŐ.
-SŢ nastă.
Okaă.
[SŔEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
-YŢu had tŢ dŢ that.
-YŐs.
[SQUEALS]
LlNUS: JŐsus Christ.
VlRGIL: ShŐ's drunk!
Subtitles bă
SDl MŐdia GrŢup
[ENGLIS˝ SD˝]