(METAL CLANKING)
(CLANKING CONTINUES)
(FLIES BUZZING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(MUSIC PLAYING INSIDE DINER)
We're not turning around.
He's gone!
He was still moving.
I fucking saw him still moving.
CALEB: We killed people!
What do you mean?
Turn the fucking car around!
He's gone!
What are we supposed to do?
Damn it,
this shit's not worth it for me to leave him there!
HENRY: God damn it! Please, I'm begging you.
He's my fucking brother.
I said this would happen.
Fuck you, Archie!
You can't go anywhere
without your brother.
And I very almost
got my head blown off,
because he's a fucking baby
who can't look after himself.
HENRY: Fuck you!
(GRUNTING)
CALEB: Sit still!
God damn it!
ARCHIE: So then, now,
look what happens to him.
Can't be feeling
responsible for that.
If he was a man who
could look after himself,
he'd be accepting it
right now.
Fuck you. Say that again.
You heard me. You know it.
Fuck you, Archie!
Say that again!
If he was a man,
he wouldn't be crying about it,
he'd be accepting it.
Say that one
more goddamn time.
I said it twice.
One more goddamn time,
Archie.
If I said it again,
I'd say it the exact same way,
and that'd be
three times I said it!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
CALEB: Fuck!
(GROANING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(ARCHIE GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
Let's go.
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on!
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(TRUCK ENGINE STARTING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
Who's this?
CALEB: That's our truck, man.
ARCHIE: What?
What the fuck's he doing?
Jesus, fuck!
Fuck!
ARCHIE: Is he giving up?
He ain't giving up.
ARCHIE: What's he doing?
What's he doing?
He's gonna keep
following us, man.
Okay, okay, okay.
Fuck you. Fuck you.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
He's moving.
HENRY: What's going
on with you, brother?
I said what's
going on, brother?
I want my car back.
HENRY: Yeah,
I can see that.
You ain't
gettin' it back.
ERIC: I want my car back.
If you don't
give it to me now,
I'm gonna get
back in that truck
and I'm gonna stay on you
till you do.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
What makes you think I won't kill you right here?
Huh?
Nothing makes me
think that.
Come on,
just for a little...
(GRUNTING)
(COUGHING)
(GROANING)
MAN: (OVER RADIO)
Area one, all clear. Over.
(SCREECHING)
(GROANING)
(EAGLE SCREECHING)
(GRUNTING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
OVER RADIO)
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Do you need anything?
I'm looking for my car.
It's got three people in it.
MAN: It hasn't stopped here.
They needed petrol.
I haven't got any petrol.
Did you see it?
I haven't seen a car with three people in it.
Do you want to buy something?
I've got tins of stuff and some
auto accessories and other things.
(FLOORBOARDS CREAKING)
(DOG HOWLING)
(SQUEAKING SOUND)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
I'm looking for a car
with three people in it.
Have you seen it?
No.
Anyone else seen it?
I don't know.
Who would know?
Maybe Grandma.
Where's Grandma?
Down there.
I'm looking for my car.
It's got three men in it.
Did it come through here?
What's your name?
Have you seen it?
Do you want something?
Do you want to
sleep with a boy?
I've got a boy here
you can sleep with.
He's smooth like
the inside of your arm.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
COLIN: Stop
fucking whispering.
(WHISPERING)
I need to buy a gun.
Stop fucking whispering.
I'll fucking kill ya.
You understand?
I need a gun.
Fuck!
Fuck this shit!
(GIGGLING)
(DOG BARKING)
Fucking son of a bitch.
Shut up!
(DOG CONTINUES BARKING)
(WHINING)
COLIN: God, no.
(COLIN MUTTERING)
No...
(GRUNTING)
ERIC: Have you got guns?
COLIN: What does it look
like I'm doing up here?
I heard you.
I heard what you need.
Fucking psycho.
Careful.
They're 300 each.
That one's 300. That one's 300.
And that one's 300.
I only take US dollars.
I don't have 300.
They're $300 US.
Can you do
this one for less?
I told you
how much they cost.
I don't have $300 US.
They're 300. You don't have 300,
you can fuck off.
(DOGS BARKING)
(SIGHING)
I'm looking for my car.
Have you seen it?
Tell me your name.
I want to know your name.
Answer my question.
Answer mine.
I'm not gonna say it again.
Okay.
I'll call you "my baby."
My baby.
There was a car
and it had three men in it
and it did what most cars do.
It came in one direction
and left in the other.
That's all I can
tell you about it.
The only detail I can tell you is the
detail that pertains to this place.
I can tell you
what they drank.
what they smelled like.
I can tell you what they said,
if they said anything
and if I heard what
it was that they said.
What did they say?
They didn't say anything.
They didn't stop here.
You must really
love that car, darling.
What a thing to get worked
up about in this day and age.
What is it about the car
that you love so much?
Can you tell me?
What's your name, sweetheart?
Oh, don't be silly.
Now you're just being rude.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANING)
What are you
doing with this car?
It's my brother's car.
Who's your brother?
Where is he?
Where's Henry at?
Who's your brother?
Where is he?
(GROANING)
You tell me where he is,
or I'm gonna kill you.
Where is he?
(ERIC BREATHING HEAVILY)
There's no doctor here.
I'm about the most useful
person in this town.
If that gives you any idea how far
from having a doctor this town is.
Is there a doctor
somewhere else?
Buy something.
I told you what I've got.
I've got tins of things and drinks and stuff.
I have to deal with
this shit all day.
Please.
I'm not joking.
You can say "please" all you like,
but I'm not joking.
Now, pick yourself
something off the shelf.
Pay Benny.
There's a doctor in them hills there.
Head east,
and follow
the road that looks like
It's got a big yellow fridge out the front,
says "Peeples" written on it.
WOMAN: Pull the gun
out of your pants.
I've got a kid in
the car who needs help.
Pull the gun out of your pants
and put it on the ground.
He needs help.
Is this man your friend?
How much do you
want for doing this?
I don't want
your money.
I've gotten pretty good
living without money.
(DOG HOWLING IN DISTANCE)
(DOG PANTING)
(DOG GROWLING)
I have to keep these guys locked
up in here now for the most part,
'cause people
take them for food.
These guys came to me.
And ask me to look after them
while they went away somewhere
or because they had to go somewhere or do something,
and none of them
ever came back.
I guess they've
gone looking for money.
Do you want me to
take a look at your cuts?
No.
Hey.
How ya going?
I'm well.
Um, do you wanna take a chair
while I have a look at you?
(GROANING)
It hurts.
Do you want to
take your hand away?
That doesn't
look too bad.
That looks good.
You just need to keep this clean.
Tell me where
your brother is.
I'll take you to him.
Tell me where
your brother is.
He's gone south
a long way from here.
I'll take you to him,
I promise.
I'm just gonna
get you a T-shirt.
Get up. We're leaving.
Maybe we should ask
what the lady says.
Get up.
(BELL RINGING)
What was that sound?
It's a car coming.
What car?
I don't know.
(BELL RINGING)
That's two cars.
How long till
they're here?
A minute, maybe.
Who is it?
Get your rifle.
DOROTHY: Do you know them?
Go and get your rifle.
Tell me what's going on.
Who are these people?
(GUNSHOT)
Get up. We're leaving.
(CRYING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Get up.
Where are we?
I'm hungry.
(CAR DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
REY: Go and get some food?
You're gonna
start talking to me.
Don't fucking "what" me.
Where are we going?
I can't tell you nothing more
than I already told you.
I don't give a shit what you think you've already told me.
Start fucking
talking to me!
Don't.
Do you even know
where we are?
What?
Where are we?
I don't know.
You don't fucking know?
So, how are you gonna
get to where you're going
if you don't know
where the fuck you are?
(ERIC BREATHING HEAVILY)
Do you even understand
what I just said, half-wit?
We're going to Carloon.
(SIGHING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(WOMAN SPEAKING MANDARIN)
I just asked that lady how to get to Carloon from here.
I was gonna do that anyway
and you would've heard me
and you would've
asked her what I said,
figured out
what I said anyway.
I was gonna tell you anyway.
You wanna know so bad.
But you don't know exactly where
in Carloon we're going exactly,
so, I'm still
in control here.
You don't know exactly where in Carloon we're going,
so you got to
take me with you.
I'm taking you with me
because if I get to Carloon
and your brother's not there,
I'm gonna slit your throat.
What you want with
my brother so bad, hmm?
Who are you?
I'm Rey.
Is that what you mean?
Why are you here?
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Me and my brother came out for the mines.
Like everybody else.
Why's your brother
in Carloon?
That's where
he was gonna go.
Why are you here and your brother's in Carloon?
They had to get going
in a big hurry.
Why?
Why did he have to get
going in a big hurry?
I don't know.
I can't talk about it.
Why did your brother have to
get to Carloon in a big hurry?
I can't talk about it.
You got left here to die
while he was doing it.
It didn't happen like that.
Really?
How did it happen, then?
I can't talk about it no more,
just stop asking about everything.
'Cause I believe in God and I
know Henry believes in God,
and there's no harm Henry
would want to see me come to.
I believe in that.
Yet look at the harm you've come to and where's Henry?
He's waiting for me.
He's not waiting for you.
Yes, he is.
No, he's not.
I'll tell you
what God's given you.
He's put a bullet in you.
And he's abandoned you out here to me,
who feels nothing for you.
I couldn't give a fuck
if you die tomorrow.
God gave you a brother
who's not waiting for you.
He gave you a brother who's not
even thinking about you right now.
Just because you and him came
out of the same woman's hole.
The only thing that
means anything right now
is that I'm here
and he's not.
Your brother
left you to die.
That's what people do.
You don't learn to fight,
your death's gonna come real soon.
(HUMMING)
MAN: (OVER RADIO) This is 5-1.
Passage is called 2-11.
We should be clear
or clearing shortly.
(PANTING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MACHINE GUN FIRING)
(WHIMPERING)
MAN: 4-3-7 Echo.
4-3-7 Echo.
This is K-K. Do you copy?
(GUNSHOT)
Stop shooting!
I just wanted to fight.
I just wanted to fight him.
Let's go.
Come on.
(ENGINE STARTING)
REY: That lady said
it would take about
eight hours to get there,
in the old days.
But it might take
longer now 'cause
a lot of them old roads
ain't there no more.
And all the roads
are bad now anyways
so you can't
drive fast on 'em.
She said about
eight or nine hours.
She wasn't sure if
it was eight or nine.
She seemed a bit
confused about it.
And why would he
still be there?
He had to wait two
weeks for someone.
There's a man there he's got to meet,
it's gonna take two weeks.
You know this?
Or this is what he told you?
Huh?
Your brother
can't be trusted.
Is this something
that you know
or is this something
that he told you?
Both those things.
You work in the mines?
No.
What do you do then?
I was a farmer.
And now I'm here.
Then how come you learned
how to shoot so good?
You was in the army?
When I was a little kid
I grew up on a farm.
We had these neighbors,
real old man and lady, Verna and Clarry,
they's brother and sister.
And they lived on this land
that's all overgrown,
like you couldn't even tell what they farmed,
so overgrown.
And Clarry had
these eight tractors,
and none of them
worked properly,
so every morning
he'd roll each one
down the hill till
he got one of them started
and then use that one to tow all the others back up.
(CHUCKLING)
He did that every day.
And when they died, their family,
who we'd never met before,
came around,
cleared out their house
and they found all this...
They found all this
weird stuff in there.
Like...
Like 50 therm...
Thermionic radio valves.
Like them real old valves
they used in old radios.
And pyramid of pumpkins.
And about 5,000 of these little sticks about this long.
And each wrapped
up in newspaper
and tied up at the ends
with baling twine.
Why are you telling me this?
I just remembered it.
It interested me.
Not everything has
to be about something.
(SIGHING)
I'm tryin' to stop thinking about that little girl who died,
but I can't.
You shouldn't.
But I can't.
You shouldn't stop
thinking about her.
You should never stop thinking
about a life you've taken.
It's the price you
pay for taking it.
(RATTLING)
That's it, sweetheart.
Let's start with
the eyelids.
I want you to roll
over onto your front,
put your hands
behind your back.
And do it slow.
And do it now.
SOLDIER: When are you
gonna say something, cunt?
It's over.
It's over for you.
I know that.
That's good
that you know that.
Do you know it, too?
Oh, I know it, champ.
I told you it.
Do you know it's
over for you, too?
Whatever you think's over for
me was over a long time ago.
I'm asking about you.
(CHUCKLING)
Are you threatening me?
No.
A threat means there's still something left to happen.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
OVER RADIO)
What are you
gonna do with me?
You're going to Sydney.
Why don't you just shoot me?
Why don't you do it?
That's what
everyone else is doing.
Tells Sydney there's a reason to
keep paying us what they pay us.
If we just shot every idiot
we wanted to shoot,
then pretty soon
they'd start to wonder
what the fuck
we're doing out here.
See, personally
I don't care about you.
I don't care if
you get to Sydney and
they let you off or
you bribe your way out
or whatever the fuck they do
down there these days.
I don't give a fuck.
I'm doing this for me.
You're doing
what for you?
You're doing what for you?
I murdered my wife.
I watched him put his fingers
inside her and I killed 'em both.
No one ever came after me.
Ten years ago.
I never had
to explain myself.
I never had to lie to anyone.
I never had to run and hide.
I just buried 'em in
a hole and I went home.
No one ever came after me.
And that hurt me more than getting my heart broken.
Knowing it didn't matter.
Knowing you can do something like
that and no one comes after you.
You do a thing like I did,
that should really mean something.
But it just
doesn't matter anymore.
Well, champ.
Thing you did in Abo town is the
one thing that does matter to us.
Now you can do all the lying and confessing you'd like.
What feeling do you have when
you wake up in the morning?
When your feet
touch the floor?
Or before that,
when you're lying there
thinking about your
feet hitting the floor.
What does that
feel like for you?
Do you know what
I'm talking about?
No, mate. I don't.
No, mate.
I don't know what the fuck you're talking about.
MAN: What the fuck?
(GUNSHOTS)
REY: Phew!
(PANTING)
Is that it?
That was easy.
Do I shoot him again
just to be sure?
No.
That was easy. There
were only three of 'em.
Thought it was gonna
be way more harder.
You tied up?
I snuck up
on these two.
They were just
hanging there.
I came through
the gate here.
I dug a hole out.
Slipped underneath the fence.
Get the truck over there.
Come on, man.
You want me to
drive for a while?
No.
I know I feel
comfortable with someone
when I can just sit,
not talking to them.
Yeah.
I just like sitting there,
not talking.
I just feel comfortable
sittin' there, you know.
I had a pain in
my side real bad.
It's starting to hurt.
I think maybe I gotta
do something with it.
(GROANING)
Don't look bad?
Let's put that
bandage back on.
I think it broke, man.
You got any fuel?
MAN: 50 US.
50 Australian.
MAN: US dollars.
I'm out of US.
MAN: I only take
American money.
What's wrong with
Australian money?
MAN: Either take it
or leave it.
It's paper. It's worthless.
MAN: Yeah, whatever,
mate, I don't care.
It's a piece
of fucking paper!
MAN: Take it or leave it.
How much you need, man?
MAN: 50 US.
Have you got any .38
in there?
Yeah.
Let me get a box of that.
And a box of 9 millimeter
for my friend here.
Thank you kindly.
REY: There's the house.
All them others empty.
They ain't got
people in them anymore.
Are they alone in there?
For now they are.
Until them other people
come, but that ain't
gonna be for
another week or somethin'.
And there's Gordon,
whose house it is, but he's old.
Real old.
Do you know this?
I know it.
We'll go there
in the morning.
There'll be less trouble.
(WOMAN SPEAKING
MANDARIN ON RADIO)
(MAN SPEAKING
(SONG PLAYING ON RADIO)
(HUMMING TO SONG)
(SWITCHES OFF RADIO)
I'm gonna kill him.
I'm going to kill Henry.
Go to sleep.
There's money up there too,
we can take if we want.
Go to sleep.
REY: What you doing?
What you doing?
(WHISPERING)
Just wait there.
They're asleep.
There's two in the back
room. I'll take them.
There's two in the room
on the other side.
If you take them,
we'll bring them into this front room.
Okay? But no shooting.
All right?
Don't say a word.
Slowly lift your
head off the pillow.
What the fuck?
Kick your blanket off.
Both of you get up.
(MUMBLING)
Henry.
Henry, wake up.
Rey?
You gotta get up.
Rey, what the fuck?
You too, Gordon.
You gotta get up.
You both gotta get up outta bed.
What are you doing?
Stop pointing that thing at me.
Don't make me keep saying it.
You got to get up out of bed.
Sit down. Sit.
Sit on your hands.
What's going on in there?
See, Henry?
You gotta get up outta bed.
Rey, who's in there?
He won't get up
outta bed.
Put the gun down, Rey.
You put yours down.
Rey, put the gun down.
I ain't playing.
Why are you doing this?
(MUMBLING)
Why did you leave me there?
Leave you where?
You know where.
On the road, when I was shot.
Rey, we thought
you was dead.
No.
But I wasn't.
But I wasn't dead and you left me there.
Rey, I thought you was dead.
Now put down the fuckin' gun!
REY: You put yours down.
What's going on?
I gotta piss.
Don't you fuckin' move.
I thought you was
my brother, man.
God damn it, Rey! I am your brother.
Now put down the fuckin' gun.
I thought you was my brother.
Rey, if you don't put down the gun I'm gonna shoot you.
All right?
I ain't lyin'.
You was supposed to be my brother, Henry.
You told Pa.
Rey, put down
the goddamn gun!
I thought you was my brother
and you just left me there.
ERIC: What's going on
in there?
(CHOKING)
(CRYING)
What did you do
to my brother?
Huh?
Answer me.
What did you do
to my brother?
I didn't do anything.
Yes, you did.
What did you do to him?
(GUNSHOT)
(RAGGED BREATHING)
(SIGHING)
(GRUNTING)