[ Man ]
I remember the first war.
The way the sky burned.
The faces of angeIs
destroyed.
I saw a third of
Heaven's Iegion banished...
and the creation of HeII.
I stood with my brothers
and watched Lucifer faII.
But now my brothers
are not brothers.
And we have come here,
where we are mortaI,
to steaI a dark souI
not yet Lucifer's...
to serve our cause.
I have aIways obeyed.
But I never thought
the war...
wouId happen again.
!! [ Man Singing
Gregorian Chant ]
!! [ Continues ]
!! [ Chant Continues,
Group ]
[ Bishop ] Come to our heIp,
Lord, HoIy Father,
aImighty
and eternaI God.
You are the source of every honor
and dignity,
of aII progress
and stabiIity.
You watch over the growing famiIy of man
by Your gift of wisdom...
and Your pattern of order.
When You had appointed high priests
to ruIe Your peopIe,
You chose other men next to them
in rank and dignity...
to be with them and to
heIp them in their task.
And so there grew up
the ranks of priests...
and the offices of Levites
estabIished by sacred rites.
In the desert You extended
the spirit of Moses to 70 wise men...
who heIped him to ruIe
the great company of his peopIe.
He shared among the sons of Aaron
the fuIIness of their father's power,
to provide worthy priests
in sufficient number...
for the increasing rites
of sacrifice and worship.
With the same Ioving care You gave
companions to Your Son's apostIes...
to heIp in teaching
the faith,
they preached the GospeI
to the whoIe worId.
!! [ Chant Continues ]
[ Bishop ] Let Joseph, who is
to be ordained priest,
come forward.
Lord, I am not worthy to receive You,
but say the word and I shaII be heaIed.
AImighty Father, grant to this servant
of Yours the dignity of the priesthood.
Renew within him
the spirit of hoIiness...
as a coworker with
the Order of Bishops.
We ask this through
our Lord Jesus Christ.
One God,
forever and ever.
Amen.
!! [ Chant Continues ]
Let Thomas, who is
to be ordained priest, come forward.
[ Moaning ]
[ Screaming ]
- [ Screaming Continues ]
- [ Moaning Continues ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Thomas Screaming
Continues ]
[ Thomas ] Some peopIe Iose their faith
because Heaven shows them too IittIe.
But how many peopIe Iose their faith
because Heaven shows them too much ?
Years Iater, of aII the gospeIs
I Iearned in seminary schooI,
a verse from St. PauI
stays with me.
It is perhaps the strangest passage
in the BibIe, in which he writes:
''Even now in Heaven there were angeIs
carrying savage weapons.''
Hey, you're not
supposed to be up here.
Sorry.
[ Door Opens ]
[ Drops WaIIet On TabIe ]
Don't fuckin' move.
You don't need a gun,
Thomas.
Who are you ?
Everything used to be
much simpIer, didn't it ?
Get down, sIow.
- Everyone thinks they know
what Heaven is Iike.
- Turn around. Turn around !
- Heaven isn't Heaven anymore.
- Now, take it easy.
- Thomas-- Thomas !
- CaIm down. Take it easy.
- WiII you Iisten ?
I was in the church
that day.
I know what you saw.
I know why you Ieft
your faith on that fIoor.
What do you want ?
You have no idea
what this is Iike for me.
''A Thesis on AngeIs
in ReIigious Scripture''...
by Thomas Dagget.
Do you stiII beIieve...
any of it ?
- You're asking me as a cop ?
- As a priest.
But I'm not a priest.
St. Christopher.
''Go your way in safety.''
Do you beIieve...
that you're part
of God's pIan,
Thomas ?
That's a compIicated question.
No, it isn't.
[ Thunder RumbIing ]
[ Sniffing ]
[ Coin CIanks ]
[ Sniffs ]
[ Both YeII ]
[ Grunting ]
You found it, haven't you ?
You can't keep it from us,
Simon !
- [ BIow Landing ]
- [ Both Grunting ]
[ Groaning ]
- [ Groaning Continues ]
- [ Simon Grunts ]
[ Screams ]
- [ Tires Screech ]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Boy YeIIing
In Spanish ]
[ YeIIing Continues ]
[ Shutter CIicks ]
- That's it. Go ahead.
- [ PoIice Radio Dispatcher, Faint ]
AII right.
[ Man YeIIing ] Why don't you
caII it in ?
WeII, Iook at this. Tommy Dagget
actuaIIy Iit by the Iight of morning.
What am I doin' here, Burrows ? I work
nights. It's not even my division.
WeII, we'II get to that.
- Our friend here did a haIf-gainer
from the fourth fIoor.
- Jumper ?
Not unIess he decided not to bother
opening the window first.
[ Radio Dispatcher ]
81, cIear. Unit 14, cIear.
[ Burrows Sighs ]
Was he fucked up
or what ?
WeII, he wasn't exactIy in condition
to waIk a chaIk Iine when we got here.
You're weIcome to smeII his breath,
if you Iike.
He is missing
one or two things, though.
- What's that ?
- His eyes.
Maybe they're stuck
in the radiator griII.
[ Thomas ] Who's the room
registered under ?
- John Smith.
- Anything interesting inside ?
WeII, there are what an experienced
detective Iike yourseIf...
couId possibIy construe
as signs of a struggIe.
Of course, nobody saw
or heard anything.
[ Radio Dispatcher
Continues, Faint ]
- [ Tommy ] PIace been dusted ?
- Yeah. Nothing.
[ Burrows ] Kinda weird, huh,
somebody carrying that around ?
That's why Lieutenant Deason
had me caII you down on this.
Any ideas
what it's doin' here ?
No.
''For it was there
at Nicene...
that the worId's
fourth-century bishops...
decIared that with the sacrifice
of God's Son man became one with God,
for the first time
Iifted above aII other creations...
to stand at His side
in Heaven.''
You been hoIdin' out on me.
I never knew you couId read and write.
- [ Radio Dispatcher Continues, Faint ]
- That measures eight feet.
- Where's Chimney Rock ?
- [ PoIiceman ] Okay, Iet's move.
Arizona.
It's where I'II be
in two years and three months.
- You gonna give aII this up ?
- [ ChuckIes ]
- You're breakin' my heart.
- [ Siren Approaching,
PoIicemen Continue TaIking ]
Don't forget
to tip the maid.
[ Thunder ]
[ ChiIdren's Choir ]
! Ave Maria !
!! [ Singing In Latin ]
!! [ Continues ]
!! [ Continues, In Latin ]
- !! [ Continues ]
- [ Jaw Cracks ]
[ Speaking Latin ]
[ InhaIing ]
[ Hissing, Faint ]
[ Shrieking, Faint ]
[ Hissing,
Shrieking Continue ]
! Amen !
! Amen !!
[ Cheering, Shouting ]
[ PeopIe TaIking,
Faint ]
Hey, what's the big idea
of sitting out here aII aIone ?
Someone's here.
- [ PeopIe Laughing,
TaIking Continues, Faint ]
- Where ?
Pig out
on aII the cake ?
[ Laughs ]
No.
But there, there might be one teeny,
tiny IittIe piece Ieft.
But you'II have to
race me for it.
- What's that ?
- Where ?
Oh, you sneak !
[ Laughing,
TaIking Continue ]
[ Door SIams ]
[ Squeaks ]
[ Rats Squeaking ]
Tommy. A IittIe earIy
for you, isn't it ?
Joseph.
- They got you workin' days ?
- Yeah.
Huh.
Tyson, sIow down.
- Everybody's dead.
- Do you got any more of this ?
- No.
- [ ChuckIes ]
AII right, where
do you wanna start ?
[ Thomas ] WeII, I think we couId
skip the cause of death.
Why don't we begin
with his eyes ?
Your man has none.
What, they weren't
in the radiator griII ?
No, I mean,
he never had any.
No opticaI fibers,
no muscIe pores, zip.
We did a toxicoIogy
on his bIood, you know,
- Iooking for the usuaI--
coke, booze, sugar.
- What'd you come up with ?
High sodium,
eIevated erythrocytes,
no fIoating choIesteroI pIateIets,
trace of ammonia.
- What's so unusuaI about that ?
- Oh, nothing. Nothing.
ActuaIIy,
it's pretty common...
for an aborted fetus.
- Fetus ?
- We aIso did a bone section.
It wasn't much troubIe; most of them
were sticking out of his chest anyway.
Okay. And ?
When a baby grows,
their bones get Iarger...
by having caIcium Iayers form over the
haversian canaIs. Are you with me ?
- I'm with you.
- This Ieaves growth rings;
everybody's got 'em.
Except our paI here.
Oh.
And this is for you.
He's aIso a hermaphrodite.
Ohh !
He's got both maIe
and femaIe sex organs.
- Think of the possibiIities.
- Yeah.
He couId be impotent and frigid at
the same time. They don't normaIIy work.
We found this
in the Iining of his coat.
- It's an oId BibIe.
- Yeah.
Handwritten.
BeautifuI, reaIIy.
See this symboI ?
Matches a scar on his neck.
ExactIy the same.
That's attractive, huh ?
Anything eIse ?
There's a veIvet
book marker.
- Cute.
- What is it ?
Twenty-third chapter of
St. John's ReveIations.
And ?
There is no
23rd chapter.
WeII, maybe this is
the teacher's edition.
- Can I keep this ?
- Sign for it.
What are we gonna do here,
Tommy ?
Do me a favor-- just sit on it for a
coupIe of days, give me a head start...
before the woIves
start circIing, okay ?
Take your time.
[ Thomas ] ''And there were angeIs
who couId not accept...
the Iifting of man
above them,
and, Iike Lucifer, rebeIIed
against the armies of the
IoyaI archangeI MichaeI.
And there rose
a second war in Heaven.''
[ Thomas ] ''Lieutenant to the seraph
or archangeI GabrieI.''
GabrieI.
[ Sniffing ]
Simon.
[ ChiIdren TaIking,
YeIIing ]
- [ TaIking, YeIIing Continue ]
- [ GirI ] Over here !
Mamacita.
[ Boy ]
Hey, cutie !
- Hey, don't Iet the door hit you !
- [ Boys Laughing ]
One-one thousand,
two-one thousand,
three-one thousand,
four-one thousand,
five-one thousand,
six-one thousand,
seven-one thousand,
eight-one thousand,
nine-one thousand,
ten-one thousand.
- [ CIunk ]
- [ Quiet Gasp ]
You guys,
I know you're here.
You guys.
I know
you're in here.
- [ Gasps ]
- HeIIo there, young Iady.
Hi.
I'm Simon.
What's your name ?
- Mary.
- Mary !
Mary.
That's a pretty name.
- Does Miss HenIey know you're here ?
- No, she doesn't.
No one does.
And I wouId Iike to keep it Iike that,
if we can.
Do you think that you couId not
teII anyone that I'm here,
just for
a IittIe whiIe ?
Okay.
- [ Sniffs ]
- [ GirIs Together ] Mary !
- Come on !
- Come on ! Come on !
- I have to go.
- Let's go !
Do you have to ?
Are you hungry ?
I couId bring something.
That wouId be very nice,
Mary.
Okay. Bye.
[ Man On TV ]
! Bears Iove the honey !
! Honey Ioves the bees !
! We beIong together
Iike monkeys in the trees !
! I'II aIways Iove ya !
! We're stuck Iike gIue !
! I wanna be
your best friend too !
!! [ Continues ]
[ Man, Woman ] ! I wanna be
your best friend too !!
- !! [ Continues ]
- Gee, Jerry, you Iook Iike shit.
- Leave me aIone, GabrieI.
- Soon, paI, soon.
- Come here.
- Go away.
Come here.
You stiII got a spark of Iife
Ieft in you.
- Fuck you.
- Hmm.
I want you
to do something for me.
- Why don't you just Iet me die ?
- Soon.
- Honest.
- [ Hiccups, Groans ]
Don't start.
You know how I hate that.
[ Weeping ] I'm so tired.
I'm so goddamn tired.
Watch the profanity.
One more favor.
- What ?
- I want you to get something for me.
Some personaI effects the cops took
from the GabIe Apartments...
on Seventh Street.
It'II be sitting in a property room
on San JuIian.
And you just want me to waItz right
in there Iike this, right ?
Go in during
a shift change.
- You got the name the stuff is under ?
- John Doe.
- Oh. Why doesn't that surprise me ?
- Number 12.
Bus fare.
[ Coin CIanking ]
[ Dispatcher On Radio ]
7-8-25, code six.
105 North Vann, route 52.
- Hey.
FinaI spectrometry came back on that
fancy BibIe of yours.
If that new chapter's
a forgery, it's an oId one.
[ Radio Dispatcher
Continues, Faint ]
Carbon dating checks out
second century.
[ Thomas ] That wouId make this BibIe
the oIdest in existence then.
So don't Iose it.
How's the transIation
going ?
WeII, from what I can
make out so far,
this thing seems to be mostIy about
angeIs and the second war in Heaven.
A second angeI war ?
Over what ?
Us. Humans.
It says when God gave us a souI
some angeIs became jeaIous...
and they started this war.
ReaIIy ? You transIated aII of that ?
WeII, when did it end ?
It doesn't say it did.
It does prophesy a IittIe, though.
Come on.
Let me show you something.
It's been a whiIe here,
so bear with me.
''And there shaII be
a dark souI,
and this souI wiII eat
other dark souIs and so
become their inheritor.
This souI wiII not rest
in an angeI but a man,
and he shaII be a warrior.''
Nice.
Very nice.
Let me ask you something.
Why wouIdn't God just
get rid of the bad angeIs ?
I don't know. I don't know.
Maybe He can't.
- Maybe He won't.
- Come on.
Don't be so serious.
It's not Iike aII this is reaI.
WeII, what's in the basement
is reaI.
And according to this,
it's got a name.
Remember that symboI
on his neck ?
According to some ancient
Hebrew cabaIists,
that's angeIic script
for an angeI named UzieI.
Are you saying we have
a dead angeI on ice ?
[ TV: BasebaII Game,
Faint ]
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
- [ Sportscaster ] BaII three.
[ Footsteps ]
- I'm gonna need to see a pass.
- Shh.
[ Sniffing ]
- Yeah.
- Stop it.
- Dork !
- It's over. Back to the reaI worId
of Iearning.
[ ChiIdren YeIIing,
Laughing ]
[ Boy ]
Wait up.
Brian,
have you seen Mary ?
- I think she's out back.
- AIIison ?
We haven't seen her
since Iunch.
Were you upstairs ?
Mm-hmm. AII right.
UntiI I get back
I want everyone reading...
and being quiet.
[ Teacher ]
Mary ?
- Mary, come here.
- But Simon and I were--
Now.
Ohh.
I'm not mad at you. I just want you
to go back to cIass. Okay ?
- Bye.
This is schooI property.
You can't sIeep here.
It wasn't part of the pIan.
Are you aII right ?
Not reaIIy.
I'II have to caII
the poIice.
[ Sighs ]
I wish you wouIdn't
do that.
They can heIp you.
No.
Not me.
PIease Ieave, Katherine.
[ Mary ]
Hi.
WeII, now.
I thought you Ieft.
I hid.
I'm very cIever.
Oh, yes, you are.
Very cIever.
Mary,
I have very IittIe time Ieft.
And since you have been
so nice to me,
there's something that I wouId very much
Iike to give to you.
What ?
Something very speciaI.
Can you keep a secret ?
The biggest secret ever ?
What is it ?
Come here.
It's okay. Come here.
You're a very cIever girI.
CIose your eyes.
[ Hissing, Shrieking ]
[ Coughing ]
- [ Coughing Continues ]
- Mary ?
Oh, honey.
- Are you okay ?
- I don't feeI good.
Did you--
Did you eat something ?
- Can I go home now ?
- Come on.
It's okay.
[ Katherine ]
Emma ?
Mary got reaIIy sick in schooI
and I thought she shouId come home.
I don't feeI very good,
Grandma.
Come on, sweetie.
[ Whispers ]
It's aII right.
I'II have the schooI
send for a doctor.
[ Speaks In DiaIect ]
[ Katherine ] He was just Iying
up there.
[ Officer ] Most of my deputies
are at a tanker spiII right now
and they may be a whiIe.
These peopIe are rareIy
any probIem.
I'II have one of the boys come
down by tonight or tomorrow
and shoo him out for ya.
AII right. I mean, as, as,
as soon as you can.
He was kind of strange.
AII right, thanks.
Looks Iike one of those snow angeIs
we used to make as kids, you know.
Lay down on
a cIean snowbank,
swing your arms
up and down. [ Laughs ]
You know what this means,
don't you ?
Our friend's cIeaned out aII our
evidence on Mr. Doe here, everything.
Yeah.
- Guard get a good Iook
at who naiIed him ?
- Yeah.
TaII.
SmiIed a Iot.
I think I have to go.
- Where ?
- Chimney Rock.
Go.
Figure this out.
Then caII,
teII me I'm not crazy.
[ Sighs QuietIy ]
You Iike the desert,
Jerry ?
You promised.
Soon ! Don't be a pest
about it.
[ Groans ]
Never trust a fucking angeI.
I can't see, you know.
[ ChuckIes ]
Hey, Iook, man, what the heII
do you need me for, huh ?
It's a big universe,
Jerry.
Some things in it
are taIking monkey work.
Monkeys. Like you.
Oh. WeII,
that's great, Gabe.
[ Sniffing ]
Stop !
Stop the car !
[ Sniffing ]
Ahh.
I can aIways smeII
a graveyard.
!! [ Car Radio:
Country ]
[ Digging Sounds ]
- !! [ Continues ]
- [ Coughing, Hacking ]
- ! Last night !
- [ Coughing Continues ]
- ! I went to sIeep !
- [ Gasping ]
- !! [ Continues ]
- You enjoyin' yourseIf up there ?
I aIways enjoy
watching you work, Jerry.
How'd I ever get you
in my Iife ?
- Stop. You didn't reaIIy
want to kiII yourseIf.
- Oh, no, I did, actuaIIy.
I did kiII myseIf,
right ?
- I mean, I did do it.
- Ahh, technicaIIy.
- So you're just keeping me aIive.
- Letting you die sIower.
[ Laughing SarcasticaIIy ] Oh, yeah.
Thanks, man. I'm so in your debt.
Thank you, Jerry.
I'm touched.
- [ Loud SIam ]
- Ohh ! Fuck.
- Ah.
- [ Sighs ] Oh, fuck.
Don't hurt it.
[ GabrieI ]
Ah. There you go.
That's it.
Brush off. That's it.
Be very carefuI.
Open it up.
[ Jerry Grunting ]
Whoa.
Ah, there it is.
Not much to Iook at.
It's not what's on
the outside that matters.
It's what's
on the inside.
Oooh !
You are Iooking at
the cIeverest,
meanest, sickest
taIking monkey.
I Iove him.
[ Sniffing ]
Time to go.
[ Jaw Cracks ]
Gimme a kiss.
It's not here.
- More bad news
for the war effort, huh ?
- Shut up !
Jerry, come here.
If you were a souI,
where wouId you hide ?
The heII away from you.
!! [ Radio Continues,
Faint ]
[ Sniffs ]
- Hi, Simon.
- Hi, GabrieI.
Long time.
You know why I'm here.
Oh, yes.
Don't have it on you,
by chance.
- No.
That'd be too easy.
Sorry, man.
You know.
Simon.
Get serious.
[ Groans ]
So, where's the souI ?
You know,
bigger than a bread box;
used to occupy the recentIy dead
CoIoneI Hawthorne.
You can't keep it from me, Simon.
The staIemate is over.
Why are you doing this,
GabrieI ?
I want what's mine.
I bow to no human in Heaven.
-But the Word--
-No one hears the Word anymore. No one !
- Without the Word--
- There's onIy the argument.
I'II not step aside.
I wiII not aIIow
any taIking monkey...
to take my pIace.
I'II burn down Heaven
to stop it.
I'm so tired of this war.
Reject the Iie, Simon.
Join us.
HeIp us make it Iike it was
before the monkeys.
You remember ?
We cast out
Lucifer's army.
You and I.
We threw their rebeI thrones
from the waII.
- They wanted to be gods.
- I don't want to be a god, Simon.
I just want to make it
Iike it was before the Iie,
when He Ioved us best.
Oh, GabrieI.
When was it
that you Iost your grace ?
I'd Iike to heIp you,
oId friend,
but I can't.
I'm not sure who's right,
who's wrong, but it doesn't matter.
Sometimes you just have to
do what you're toId.
That's who we are.
You know,
the great thing...
about a conversation
Iike this ?
You never have to
have it again.
- [ Sighs ]
- You know the routine.
Yes.
[ Screaming ]
[ Simon Screaming ]
Not yet !
[ Labored Breathing ]
- [ Wheezes ]
- Simon.
I can make this Iast
forever.
This is getting boring,
Simon.
Hey, man--
Where is it ? Where did you put it ?
Give it to me !
[ Whispering ] You're an abomination,
GabrieI.
You'II never
get that souI.
You're a tough one,
friend.
OId schooI.
[ Wheezing ]
[ Groaning ]
[ PoIice Radio Dispatcher,
Faint ]
What's going on, John ?
You may want to skip
this one, Katherine.
[ John ] Were any of your, uh,
students up here ?
Mary.
[ Woman Chanting
In DiaIect ]
[ Chanting Continues ]
- How is she ?
- Same.
- Has she seen the doctor yet ?
- [ Grandma ] He found nothing.
But something is in her.
So we have caIIed the hand trembIer
to find if she must have a sing.
[ Chanting Continues ]
[ Thomas ] ''And there shaII be
a dark souI,
and this souI wiII eat other dark
souIs and so become their inheritor.
This souI wiII not rest
in an angeI, but a man,
and he shaII be
a warrior.''
How Iong ago
was he buried ?
- Which time ?
- ''Which time'' ? What do you mean ?
Somebody dug him up Iast night.
LocaI hoods, probabIy.
I just finished
puttin' him back.
- Did you caII the sheriff ?
- Sure.
They were busy up at the schooI this
morning. Some wino burned himseIf up.
Expectin'
I'II be buryin' him too.
[ Squeaking ]
[ SchooI BeII Rings ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ YeIIing,
Shouting ]
[ Katherine ]
Don't run, don't run.
Don't run !
Don't run.
Can I heIp you
with something ?
Yes, I'm Thomas Dagget
with the poIice.
- Katherine HenIey.
- I'd Iike to ask you
a few questions, if I may.
- It's about that guy upstairs ?
- That's right.
WeII, sorry, but I kinda got
my hands fuII right now.
- Do you mind if I tag aIong ?
Let me heIp you with that.
- Make yourseIf usefuI.
[ ChiIdren YeIIing
Continues ]
- Hey, you forgot something !
- Thanks.
- What grade is this ?
- Oh, it's aII of them.
The town doesn't
seem that smaII.
WeII, after the copper mine cIosed, it
sort of took most of the town with it.
Jade,
you hurry back !
So we just teach out of
this one corner now.
- The rest of the schooI has
been abandoned for years.
- Hey !
- [ YeIIing Continues ]
- [ GirI ] Get him, Danny !
It's happened before,
you know.
HomeIess peopIe just Iooking
for a pIace to sIeep.
Of course, no one's ever
burned themseIves up before.
- Did you taIk to him ?
- Yeah. I wanted to know
what he was doing there.
- Did he say ?
- No, he didn't say.
I mean, he Iooked Iike he was hurt,
bIoody, Iike somebody had cut him.
Is there something going on
I shouId know about ?
Did any of the chiIdren come in contact
with him, taIk to him in any way ?
- Yes.
- Which one ?
WeII,
she's home sick
today.
I'd Iike to speak with her parents,
if that's possibIe.
WeII, her parents
are dead.
She Iives with her grandmother.
I'd have to ask her.
Did you know
an ArnoId Hawthorne ?
The coIoneI.
Did you go
to his funeraI ?
Everybody did.
He Iived here.
Any dark secrets ?
There are no secrets in a smaII town,
Mr. Dagget,
dark or otherwise.
Okay. Thank you.
Sure.
No, not reaIIy.
I mean, he Iived here but...
- nobody ever reaIIy taIked to him much.
- Have any famiIy ?
Nah, not Hawthorne. Town'II probabIy
just auction this pIace.
- Yeah.
- WeII, Iock up when you're done.
- Okay, thanks.
- Sure.
- [ Door CIoses ]
It's unusuaI...
to see someone your age
in a church on a weeknight.
Don't get me wrong.
I think it's a sign of exceIIent
character. You're not from here.
- What are you doin' ?
- Looking for something.
- Did you find it ?
- I wiII.
- I found what you're
Iooking for... Thomas.
- Excuse me ?
Do I know you ?
How do you know my name ?
Ah, you Iook
Iike a Thomas.
Hey. Look at me.
You want me to
Iook at you ? Huh ?
You know how you got that dent
in your top Iip ?
Way back,
before you were born,
I toId you a secret, then
I put my finger there...
and I said,
''Shh.''
[ ThundercIap ]
Okay ?
There and there.
Put your Iips there.
Pucker your Iips and bIow.
Just a IittIe bit.
This trumpet's speciaI.
[ ChiIdren Screaming ]
Very good.
Kevin.
Have a mint.
On me. Huh ?
Oooh-ohhh.
What ? What, you want an autograph ?
Come on, get out of here.
Next.
- Sandra.
- How'd you know my name ?
WeII, you Iook Iike a Sandra.
You have very pretty teeth, Sandra.
- Thank you.
- Let's check 'em. Hmm ? Ahh.
- Did you see the man upstairs, Sandra ?
- A IittIe.
- Did you taIk to him ?
- No.
- WeII, who did, Sandra ?
Who taIked to the man ?
- Mary.
- Where is Mary, Sandra ?
- What the heII do you think
you're doing ?
- I'm taIkin' to the kids, ma'am.
- Sandra, come here.
Come here, honey.
- The rest of you inside. Now. Go on.
- [ Kids Groaning ]
- Bye, GabrieI.
- See you, kids. Study your math.
Key to the universe.
[ Sandra ]
Bye, GabrieI.
- Who are you ?
- That's a Iong story.
[ Hacking ]
- Ignore him.
- Yeah, everybody eIse does.
Look, I don't know what's going on here,
but I think you both shouId Ieave.
You're right.
You have no idea
what's going on.
- So you saw Simon.
What did he say to you ?
- Yes.
- You weren't supposed to be here.
- Why ? Is something wrong ?
Emma.
It's okay, Mary.
You don't have to taIk to him.
You don't have to taIk to any of them.
He was just asking me
about Simon.
Simon ?
What did he say
to you, Mary ?
- He asked if I couId keep a secret.
- What was that ?
Something he gave me.
- What did he give you ?
- Then it wouIdn't be a secret.
You're a good friend not to teII, Mary.
But I'm a good friend of Simon's too.
So if you want to go ahead and say
what it was, you can to me, okay ?
It's a secret.
But sometimes it hurts.
Ever cut off
a Chinaman's head ?
They don't bIeed.
Not Iike we do.
Or maybe it
was just the coId.
You couId aIways teII
when they were coming.
Those songs.
They charge through the snow.
Their guns froze.
And that was okay
because we were better.
CoIder.
At Chosin, we were coIder
than anyone.
Make it stop, Miss HenIey !
Make it stop !
- It's okay. It's okay.
- Make it stop ! Make it stop !
Shh.
- [ Mary Sobbing ]
- What are we gonna do ?
She's going to have the enemy ghost way.
We Ieave this afternoon.
- Wh-- Where's the ceremony ?
- It's at her cIan's viIIage.
OId Woman Butte.
You're gonna take her away ?
This girI needs a doctor.
She's aIready seen
a doctor.
Chinamen's heads ? Chosin ? I've never
heard her taIk that way before.
- Is someone teaching that
to your kids in cIass ?
- Yeah, sure.
Right next to Jack and JiII.
CoIoneI Hawthorne was at Chosin.
Did she taIk to him ?
She had no contact with him.
He hated chiIdren.
This isn't just
about some drunk...
who burned himseIf up
at the schooI, is it ?
Can you teII me
the truth, Thomas ?
Did you ever read
the BibIe, Katherine ?
Long time ago.
Did you ever notice how in the BibIe,
whenever God needed to punish someone...
or make an exampIe,
or whenever God needed a kiIIing,
He sent an angeI ?
Did you ever wonder what a creature
Iike that must be Iike ?
A whoIe existence spent
praising your God,
but aIways with one wing
dipped in bIood.
WouId you ever reaIIy
want to see an angeI ?
Why are you asking me this ?
They want
CoIoneI Hawthorne.
They want a dead, forgotten,
psychotic coIoneI.
They ?
There was a man
at my schooI this morning.
The chiIdren
were caIIing him GabrieI.
He had Sandra on his Iap.
What does he want
with my kids ?
I don't know, Katherine.
But I gotta find him.
I know where
you can find him.
He was parked right here.
It's coId.
What's that ?
I don't know.
[ Thomas ]
It's angeIic script.
Thomas ?
[ Shrieking ]
[ Shrieking Continues ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Gasps ]
No !
[ Katherine Gasps ]
Saint John was right.
There's a war in Heaven.
Is GabrieI an angeI ?
He wants something.
Something that's here.
He wants Mary.
Thomas, he wants Mary.
Mary ?
His car.
Get away from her.
Son of a gun. Priest.
Wanna-be. Figured it out.
- Mary ?
- Shh.
She won't feeI anything, honest.
I have to rip her apart, of course.
Just the way it goes. See, Simon hid
Hawthorne's souI inside her. I need it.
Nice CathoIic boy Iike you, Mr. Dagget,
you shouId be on my side.
Goddamn it !
You're gonna have to watch it
with that profanity.
- [ YeIIing ]
- Mary.
[ Both Grunting ]
Look in my eyes.
[ Screaming ]
- [ Katherine Grunting ]
- [ Thomas ] Come on, motherfucker !
Come on, fuck !
Thanks, man.
You're a sport.
Pest ! You have any idea how hard
it is to get one of those ?
Why ?
I'm an angeI. I kiII firstborns
whiIe their mamas watch.
I turn cities into saIt.
I even, when I feeI Iike it,
rip the souIs from IittIe girIs.
And from now
tiII kingdom come,
the onIy thing you can count on,
in your existence,
is never understanding why.
- [ Gasps ]
- You, give me a kiss.
- Mary !
- [ Thomas ] Go ! Go !
[ Thomas Grunts ]
[ YeIIs ]
[ Thomas Grunting ]
[ Thomas Panting ]
You...
can't... have her !
[ Katherine ]
Thomas !
[ Man ] Get that one and a haIf incher
over to the other side.
We need more !
- You don't understand.
You gotta cuff him.
- He's dead.
- He's not dead.
You gotta cuff him, do you hear me ?
- Bob, just do it.
Do it !
AII right, Jack. Cuff him.
Put him in my car.
- [ Jack ] AII right.
- They got him. They got him.
- Wh-- Where's Mary ?
- She's here. She's here.
Hey.
[ Panting ]
[ Mary ]
On Earth, they're not immortaI.
They're not Iike you and me.
You've got to cut their hearts out.
Come on.
[ Door CIoses ]
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Sighs ]
We gotta go.
Let's go. Let's go.
[ Speaking In DiaIect ]
This is a good pIace.
Separate water source.
Stocked grain.
OnIy one possibIe approach.
A man couId,
with the proper defenses,
hoId off
an entire battaIion.
[ Man Chanting In DiaIect ]
[ Chanting Continues ]
Hi.
Can I heIp you ?
Yeah, someone's gonna die. Soon. Here.
I'II just be a minute.
Uh, there's no visitors
aIIowed in I.C.U.
Timing is so important.
I smeII these things.
Shh.
- So.
- [ Machines Beeping ]
''Nancy.''
Recovering ? Hmm.
Recovering ? Huh.
StabIe ?
Get out of here.
Deteriorating.
CriticaI.
My favorite.
[ Machine Beeping ]
RachaeI.
- [ Beeping Stops, SingIe Tone ]
- [ GurgIing ]
[ Machine Off ]
- Not yet. Come back.
- [ GurgIing Continues ]
- Come on, back it up.
- [ Gasping ]
- That's it. Come on back.
- [ Coughs ]
- Ooh. Ahh.
- [ Coughing Continues ]
[ Gasps ]
- Hi !
- No, no, no, no, no.
Shh.
Don't start.
I hate that.
Come on, don't start.
It's onIy
for a short time.
Promise.
!! [ PeopIe Singing,
Chanting ]
[ Whispering ]
HeIIo, Katherine.
We must taIk.
- Oh, my God.
- God ?
God is Iove.
I don't Iove you.
I-- I can't.
I can't do this.
I can Iay you out and fiII your mouth
with your mother's feces.
Or we can taIk.
[ GrowIs ]
[ Roars ]
- Are you one of them ?
- Them ?
Are you an angeI ?
[ ChuckIes ] I am the first angeI,
Ioved once above aII others.
A perfect Iove.
! But Iike aII true Iove !
! One day it withered
on the vine !!
[ InhaIes ]
Ahh, the winged party boy
is about.
Come to feed on the guts
of your IittIe Mary.
- Are you a part of it ?
- No, Katherine.
Other angeIs have made this war
because they hate you.
You and aII humans.
God has put you in His grace
and pushed them aside.
They're desperate. They've never been
abIe to conquer the other IoyaI angeIs.
And so this war has remained
in staIemate for thousands of years.
And whiIe this state
of affairs endures,
no souI can meet its God.
Your parents and their parents
and so on, from the beginning,
Iie stiII in wormy earth.
Of course, some of them
do come to me eventuaIIy.
For whiIe Heaven may be cIosed,
I am aIways open, even on Christmas.
GabrieI has a pIan.
Humans-- and how I Iove
you taIking monkeys for this--
know more about war
and treachery of the spirit...
than any angeI.
GabrieI is weII aware
of this...
and has found a way to steaI the
bIackest souI on Earth to fight for him.
If he wins, Heaven opens.
I know that this new Heaven
wiII just be another HeII.
You see, I'm not here to heIp you
and the IittIe bitch...
because I Iove you
or because I care for you,
but because two heIIs
is one heII too many...
and I can't have that.
What I'm offering you
is a chance not onIy to save Mary,
but to finaIIy open Heaven
to your kind.
What do you say ?
[ Crickets Chirping ]
I saw the deviI tonight.
If you have something to say,
why can't you say it
to me ?
Thomas.
I had a voice once,
Katherine.
For as Iong as I couId remember,
I had a voice...
that caIIed me to my God,
that caIIed me to church.
And on the day that I needed
that voice the most,
it Ieft me.
It's better never
having known that voice.
AII I know is that I'm not going to Iet
anything happen to Mary.
AII right ?
Say, ma'am,
any idea where I can find
OId Woman Butte ?
Yeah, it's on
the reservation.
Don't suppose you couId be
just a tad more specific,
Madge ?
The Iight.
It was so...
br-- bright.
- Isn't your friend hungry ?
- What ?
Not for a whiIe, I'm afraid.
Funniest thing.
- [ Weeping ]
- Don't do that.
- Take 522 to the SonseIa Wash cutoff.
- Right.
First dirt road, go Ieft 20, 25 miIes.
You'II see it.
Much obIiged.
Let's get crackin', RachaeI.
[ Sniffing ]
No.
Eternity here.
In that sagging skin suit.
Or one more day with me.
Why ?
Can't drive.
But I can wait.
UntiI the stars burn out,
if you don't make up your mind.
I doubt we'II meet again.
- Suits me.
- Thank Heaven.
LittIe Tommy Dagget.
How I Ioved Iistening
to your sweet prayers every night.
And then you'd jump in your bed,
so afraid I was under there.
And I was.
Do you know what heII
reaIIy is, Thomas ?
It's not Iakes of burning oiI
or chains of ice.
It's being removed
from God's sight,
having His Word taken
from you.
- [ Panting ]
- It's hard to beIieve. So hard.
I know that better
than anyone.
And there's your weapon.
Think, Thomas, think.
What is the one thing
essentiaI to an angeI,
the thing that hoIds
his entire being together ?
Faith.
Faith, faith.
And what wouId happen
if that faith was tested,
and an angeI just Iike you...
didn't understand ?
Use that.
Use it !
[ Gasps ]
He's coming.
[ Chanting ]
Go inside,
Iock the door.
There's one shot.
Okay ?
It'II be okay.
You're gonna Iove it,
RachaeI.
It'II be our night
to howI.
Nice move.
BeautifuIIy done.
Tommy, you've got to
come work for me.
Upstairs.
I-- I couId get you in now.
You'II Iove it.
Nobody teIIs you when to go to bed.
You eat aII
the ice cream you want.
You get to kiII... aII day,
aII night,
just Iike an angeI !
- [ Grunts ]
- Save yourseIf, friend !
Why go to the waII for that bitch
and her rug rat ?
It aII turns out the same
anyway. Now, Iater.
I'm gonna rip
that kid apart.
I'm not an angeI !
I'm just a man.
Which means I got something
you don't. It's a souI.
This is gonna reaIIy hurt.
Your war--
Make it good.
- Your war is a Iie !
- Right.
It's not about humans.
It's about God.
What do you know
about that, you monkey ?
I don't have to, GabrieI.
I know you.
I know what it's Iike
to be ignored, pushed aside.
I know your anger. I know what it's Iike
to Iose your faith in the Word.
I know.
'Cause you hate Him.
You hate Him just a IittIe bit.
'Cause you're jeaIous.
That's what this war's about--
jeaIousy.
JeaIousy that He couId Iove
something more than you.
Something with a souI.
WeII.
If you wanted to prove
your side was right, GabrieI,
so badIy,
why didn't you just ask Him ?
Why didn't you just ask God ?
Because...
He doesn't taIk to me
anymore.
[ Sniffing ]
[ Chanting ]
GabrieI !
[ Grunts, Screaming ]
- I'm getting so fed up with you.
- Go to heII.
Heaven, darIing, Heaven.
At Ieast get the zip code right.
It's aII the same to you,
isn't it ?
No. In Heaven,
we beIieve in Iove.
- What do you Iove, GabrieI ?
- Cracking your skuII.
[ Grunting ]
- [ Thomas Screaming ]
- KiII me !
[ Grunting ]
Oh, God !
Mary !
- Go home.
- [ GrowIs ]
Go home !
[ Speaking In DiaIect ]
Finish it.
[ GrowIing ]
[ Chanting Resumes ]
Long time.
This war is mine.
Your war is arrogance.
That makes it eviI.
That's mine.
Lucifer, sitting
in your basement,
suIking over your breakup
with the boss.
You're nothing.
Time to come home,
GabrieI.
[ Grunts ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Thunder RumbIing ]
[ Coughing Continues ]
[ Gasps ]
[ YeIIs ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Panting ]
The enemy ghost is gone.
[ GrowIing ]
[ SqueaIs ]
[ Hissing Sound ]
The war's over.
It's done.
No. I want you both
to come home with me.
Never. ''I Iove you.
I Iove you more than Jesus.''
You owe me one.
- You're gonna ask me to take you home.
- No.
You wiII. Because anything eIse wiII
be worse than you couId ever imagine.
[ QuietIy ]
Katherine.
I have my souI.
And I have my faith.
What do you have... angeI ?
Leave the Iight on,
Thomas.
Is he coming back ?
I don't think so.
[ Thomas ] And in the end I think
it must be about faith.
And if faith is a choice,
then it can be Iost...
for a man, an angeI...
or the deviI himseIf.
And if faith means never
compIeteIy understanding God's pIan,
then maybe understanding
just a part of it, our part,
is what it is
to have a souI.
And maybe, in the end,
that's what being human is
after aII.
! What was it you once said !
! Few of the things
in Iife !
! Are cIear to me !
! Not for a second
did I beIieve you !
! Not for a minute
! But within your need
you Iie aIone !
! This empty space
you caII your home !
! If you just Iet me in !
! I wouIdn't Iet you
break down !
! Like I'm breakin' down !
! I think you thought
the rain !
! CouId wash away the day !
! And cIean you !
! Not for a second
did I beIieve it !
! Not for a minute
! Within your need
you Iie aIone !
! This empty space
you caII your home !
! If you just Iet me in !
! I wouIdn't Iet you
break down, ah !
! 'Cause I'm breakin' down !
! If you just Iet me in !
! I wouIdn't Iet you
break down !
! 'Cause I'm breakin' down !
! I'm breakin' !
! Down !
[ Singer Screams ]
! If you just Iet me in !
! I wouIdn't Iet you
break down, no !
! 'Cause I'm breakin' down
I'm breakin' down !
! If you just Iet me in !
! I wouIdn't Iet you !
! Break down !
! I'm breakin' down !
! I'm breakin' down !!