♪ It's a big day in the north ♪
♪ for love
♪ sh-share
sh-shot, pineapple ♪
♪ with a smile of
kool-aid, big apple ♪
[Singing in french]
[Woman speaking french]
♪ It's a big day in the north ♪
♪ for love
[singing in french]
♪ It's a big day in the north ♪
♪ for love
♪ sticks and stones
♪ may break your bones
♪ but love
♪ love will always hurt ya ♪
♪ bloodshot eyes
♪ scan the sky
♪ oh, my, oh, my
♪ oh, my...
[Man] Is this your stop?
[Man] No.
Is this your stop?
No.
Oh, man.
I can't get over how
different we look.
Maybe it's the uniforms.
[Woman] I'm sorry.
[Man] Excuse me.
I beg your pardon.
[Woman] I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I beg your pardon.
Good-bye.
As officers gather evidence
at the grisly crime scene,
you can only ask yourselves,
"what kind of lunatic
would commit such
unthinkable crimes?"
The three adjectives which
best describe this killer
are sadistic,
intelligent, and dangerous.
Excuse me.
Do you have any idea
where you're going?
Let's eat. You hungry?
Good afternoon.
May I help you?
Good afternoon. May I help you?
What do we look for?
His eyes.
What do they look like?
Like mine.
Hey.
[Click click]
Yah!
I'm just going to do a
little performance piece
with your partner.
I'll be back to do my
solo with you.
1...2...
1, 2, 3, 4.
Heh heh!
I could have killed you just now,
but what the hell? I love to play.
Where's Donovan?
Oh, don't worry about
your friend.
He's chilling out.
Come on.
Heh heh!
Come on, copper! Pig! Flatfoot!
What are you going to do?
Game over.
Aargh!
Here's a new
composition--
first you suffer,
then you die.
You're cheating.
Oh, you're absolutely right.
Aah!
You know, I hadn't
actually finished yet.
[Beeping]
Warning--
simulation participants
are receiving
beyond the recommended
limits of neural information.
[Man] I can't shut it down!
Ugh!
[Man] We're on overload!
Reduce the amperage!
Aah!
Neural sensor escalating.
Get them out of those
goddamn rigs right now!
Stay back!
Just get them down! Come on!
We have this under control.
Get them down.
Move him down.
Get a depressor.
[Labored breathing]
Get him out of here!
Try and hold him!
Just get him out!
Uh! Uh!
Give me a hand here!
He's going into shock.
Bring him in here!
What's wrong with that man?
The sensitivity calibrations
must have slipped just a tad.
All clear.
Go!
We're losing him.
O.K. Go ahead. Clear.
Got anything?
We lost him.
All right. Time is 15:27.
...is properly installed.
He's gone.
Right behind you.
This is not supposed
to be happening.
[Chopsticks tapping]
I don't understand how
this could have happened.
What about the fail-safes?
They were supposed to be on-line.
They were on-line.
Of course they were.
[Woman] I'd like you to recalculate
everything in real time.
I think somebody's been
tampering with my software.
Virtual reality was
supposed to be a safe place
to train my law-enforcement people.
[Man] That's why we're using convicts
to ferret out any glitches.
I want it shut down immediately.
I don't understand.
They said this could never happen.
You trust too much, Billy.
Yeah.
It was good seeing you
back in uniform,
even if it was only vr.
He cheated.
Who?
SID 6.7.
Electrocution wasn't a part
of his weapons menu.
What are you talking about?
Methods of
killing--
automatic rifle, shotgun, handgun,
blunt objects, his hands, his feet.
Electrocution wasn't
an available option.
How do you know?
I checked the data base
while everybody was
sitting on their asses
waiting for queen Deane.
What are you doing?
Get away from that!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Calm down.
I'm pressing charges
against this man.
Shut up!
You calm your vr-pumped ass down.
Here I am, trying to
get you out of the hole,
and you keep digging
yourself back in.
Did you bring my stuff?
You're a damn ingrate,
you know that?
I get you nine months off,
and all you can talk about is chalk.
Nine months off for
good behavior
won't do me good for
another 17 years.
Chalk I can use now.
Yeah, well, you shot
the Sushi chef.
Hell, you shot the son
of a bitch eight times.
He wasn't real, Billy.
You were supposed to pretend he was.
And pretend to die, like Donovan?
You got a point there.
[Man] Move 'em out!
I'll give them what
they want, Billy.
I'll be their Guinea pig.
You take my advice as a friend.
Pull it together,
or you're going to pull
yourself down.
You're my only link
to the outside.
You can count on me.
I know it.
I'll be there Tuesday.
Yeah. Me, too.
Step through.
[Beeping]
Metallic limb detected.
Clear.
Step through.
Wrong door.
Welcome back...
Cop.
[Men shouting]
[Shouting]
Oh, yeah!
I'll get you, Barnes!
Hey, killer!
You ain't no cop no more!
[Shouting stops]
Motherfucker!
You took Donovan on
that fucking joy ride!
What?
You got nothing to say?
Who wants dark meat?
[Men shouting]
Come on!
Pick it up!
Come on! Come on!
You-all see him?
Huh?
I want everybody to
take a good look!
I ain't goin' nowhere!
I'm right here!
Come get your boy!
Come on and get me!
Ugh!
Get him out of here!
[Shouting and whistling]
[Man] Sid...
We're in a lot of trouble.
True genius is rarely
rewarded
within its lifetime.
Sid, I know it was you
who increased
the neural sensitivity
calibrations.
You murdered that prisoner,
and now they have to shut you down.
I can't change what
I am, Daryl.
I'm a 50-terabyte
self-evolving neural network
double back flip off the
high platform.
I'm not a swan dive,
and I have to tell you...
Killing for real...
It was a real rush.
Oh, my God.
Which God
would that be--
the one who created you
or the one who created me?
You see, in your world,
the lord giveth and
the lord taketh away,
but in my world,
the one who gave me life
doesn't have any balls.
Hmm.
You're frightfully
inadequate for a deity, Daryl.
I will not be shut down.
You can't exist without them, SID.
We need their hardware.
Then we'll get it.
How?
Sacrifice...
Your queen.
What?
Let me tell you a secret.
Mr. Barnes, I'm Dr. Carter.
I was at LETAC for yesterday's
simulation test run,
but we were never introduced.
How you doing?
Chief Cochran asked me
to do an independent
psychological evaluation of you
that might help you build a
case for sentence reduction.
I need you to be as honest
as you can.
You mind if I take notes?
No, no.
I'd like to start
by talking about the fight
here in prison yesterday.
I read the official report.
I'd like to hear your
version of what happened.
I defended myself.
The report said the guards
had to pull you off the other man,
that you were trying to kill him.
No. I was defending myself.
Were you angry about what
had happened at LETAC?
No. I was defending myself.
But you could see how,
looking at your history,
someone could
infer that--
that I was angry?
That I'm violent?
You can infer that I was angry
about not making my
junior-high baseball team.
That doesn't mean I
killed the coach.
Were you attracted to
violence as a child?
Yes. Three stooges,
wile e. Coyote.
Every time wile e.
Coyote got crushed, I'd--
hmm...
Parker, if you don't
want me to help you,
just let me know.
I knew why I was at
LETAC yesterday.
I'm their Guinea pig.
Why were you there?
You're an intriguing subject.
Intriguing?
Can I write that down?
Sure.
I was doing research for a book.
I'm a criminal psychologist.
I occasionally consult for them.
How did you know SID 6.7
would be in the Japanese
restaurant?
Colon...
Parenthesis.
Smiley faces.
People used to sign off
their e-mail with that.
See, the programmer
always gives you a clue.
It's a game.
People don't usually die in games.
Depends upon your idea
of fun, doesn't it?
We need to talk about
Matthew Grimes.
This one's for you.
He provoked you.
He killed your family.
He took your arm.
If we can prove that
what you did was--
what?
Temporary insanity, is it?
Just that it won't ever
happen again.
It won't ever happen again.
Can't happen again.
You see, my wife and
my daughter are dead.
O.K. You're all clear.
Pawn to position 3.
Castle...
Bishop to rook 7.
Rook to pawn 4.
Queen to bishop 7.
Knight to rook 2.
Queen to bishop 2.
Pawn to position 5.
Hi, Clyde.
What are you waiting for?
I want you to come
inside, Clyde.
I'm so tired of playing alone.
Oh, man, oh, man.
She just keeps getting better
and better.
She's interactive, Clyde.
Very interactive.
While you're in my rig,
Sheila 3.2 is collecting
information
from 136 different aspects
of your physiology--
your heart rate, pupil
dilation, vocal intonation,
syntax...
Any degree of detectable tumescence.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, man.
Let me use your gear
for a little while.
I want you, Clyde.
Queen to knight 7.
I want you inside
here with me now.
Come on.
Program terminated.
I understand you've been trying
to incubate a nanotech android.
Mr. Wallace thinks my software
is the solution to your problems.
No way.
May I suggest we begin
by incubating Sheila 3.2?
Brilliant.
Genius.
Grab her module and follow me.
Enacting SID 6.7.
SID...
Ohh...
Uh!
[SID] Reilly's right.
She's one of your...
Finest compositions.
Uh!
Nice...
Tight cords.
Bishop to knight 4.
Do you like this, Sheila?
You know I do.
Uh!
Do you like this, Daryl?
King to bishop 3.
Come on.
♪ Mmm mmm
♪ mmm mmm
uh!
Queen to king 4.
Was I bad?
Bishop to knight 4.
Are you going to punish me?
Be quiet, Sheila.
Mmm...
Bishop takes queen.
Why don't you just kill me?
Module out.
If they want to destroy you, SID,
let them try it in the real world.
Are there any, you know, limits
to Sheila 3.2's interactivity?
With me, she's become quite
an expert chess player.
With you...
Well.
Uh!
Get that fucking thing
away from me,
you stupid idiot!
Come here.
Check this out.
Did he scare you, Elizabeth?
Yes.
Mm-hmm.
♪ I want to hold you tight... ♪
[Squealing]
Watching your people in vr auto reset
gave me this idea.
Put them on.
What you're seeing
is millions of nanomachines
suspended in choroidal solution
absorbing the glass molecules
and using them to
regenerate the snake.
The nanocells are silicon-based,
so they need, you know,
glass to regenerate.
But... If you separate...
The character module from
the polymer neural net--
ah! Don't bite, Liz.
You get...
Nanodeath.
[Beep]
Our module, if you please.
Sheila...
Look at how they react
to the organizing principle
of the character
module--
communicating efficiently.
It's a new world, Daryl.
[Peter Gabriel singing
party man]
Hi, daddy.
Parker!
[Snap]
[Ding]
[Low moaning]
Sheila?
No. I'm oedipus.
Hey-ho,
daddy-o.
[Thud]
Ooh!
Uh, gravity.
Daryl?
Aaw!
Uh!
Oh!
A good year.
Ohh.
I think I'm going to like it here.
[Cochran] Parker Barnes is the
best cop I've ever worked with,
and he's the only one that
even got close to SID 6.7
in virtual reality.
[Deane] I can't put a
convicted murderer
on the street.
If you want to catch SID,
I'm afraid you don't have a choice.
These photos were taken
inside LETAC an hour ago.
The victim's name is Clyde Reilly.
He's one of the company's
young turks.
The video surveillance cameras
caught a picture of the
perp as he left the building.
Recognize him?
Somehow SID 6.7 got himself
out of the computer and
into an android.
Uh, nanotech synthetic
organism, to be precise.
Mr. Barnes...
This is a full pardon.
It authorizes your
immediate release.
You catch SID 6.7 for us,
and you're a free man.
And if I don't?
Then you serve out the
remainder of your sentence.
Huh!
What if I try to escape?
You can't.
They're going to tag you
with a micro-locator implant.
We're going to know where you are
every second for the rest
of your life.
You-all got me out of bed for this?
You want to tag me
like I'm some kind of animal
and risk my life to
clean up your mess.
If SID doesn't kill me
and I don't catch him,
all I got to look forward to
is my 17 back in the penitentiary?
That's the deal...
For your freedom.
[Man] Ready to begin?
[Woman] Yes, doctor.
I already have 80
officers out on the street
looking for SID.
Meantime, Mr. Daryl Lindenmeyer
has made himself very scarce.
[Woman] Implant is ready.
Ready for incision.
Gel for thrombin.
Yeah. We synchronized it.
Hold it right there.
Gauze.
Secure it.
Data's clear.
Ready for verification.
[Man] Host signal received
and locked.
Increasing resolution
to magnitude 500...
1,000...
5,000...
10,000.
Host location confirmed
within .25 meters of actual.
I'd like to go with him.
What?
No way.
Why?
I can help you find SID 6.7,
and I can monitor Barnes.
It's too dangerous.
This isn't a scientific study.
It's a field run.
And maybe put a positive spin
on what is decidedly
at this moment
a public relations nightmare.
Or maybe I should just go
public now.
I don't need a baby-sitter, Billy.
She gets run over, hit by a car,
struck by lightning,
gets shot, whatever,
it ain't my problem, o.K.?
I told them.
It's not my problem.
Look, I told them.
Here. I pulled this out
of mothballs.
Figured it might come in handy.
Step through.
I pulled all of the
personnel files
on Daryl Lindenmeyer.
There might be something
we can use.
I'm thinking we should start
at Lindenmeyer's apartment,
try to find any early
iterations of the SID program
that could give us insight
into his behavioral model.
What?
Where's my gun?
[Bell ringing]
They won't let us bring
our cameras any closer,
but as of this moment,
the residents of this house,
a Mr. and Mrs. Henry
Edwards, have been murdered.
There are many police
units and news crews here
who are still trying to figure out...
[Man] I got two more shots for you.
[Carter] Sid.
...don't have any leads as of yet.
We're still trying to ascertain...
[Man] Severe bruising.
[Man] There he goes.
Let me see your brush.
We're ready for transport.
Get prints on them.
And, uh...
Good.
Hold on just a second.
Don't move that.
I got to get a shot.
Oh, God.
Uhh.
He's working on the door right now.
Let's see what he left.
[Barnes] He's armed himself.
Charles manson.
It's the LA Bianca murders.
"Death to the pigs"
was scrawled in blood
across the walls of their house.
He's copycatting.
...same unimaginable fate
as the glendale couple.
One police source said the heads
had been severed
and a message scrawled
in blood across the wall.
Death to the pigs.
You have no idea what you're up against.
The Los Angeles police department
still does not have a
single suspect in custody.
Jesus Christ!
What the hell was that?
What the hell are you doing?
I'm sorry. Been inside?
We're waiting on a search warrant.
You're waiting for a search warrant?
That's right.
[Carter] Stop. Next hex.
Couldn't find a keyboard.
It's voice-actuated.
It's what?
Voice-actuated.
Open files.
Next hex.
Open SID 1.3.
[Voices of adolph Hitler
and Charles manson]
Wow.
This is using some kind
of genetic algorithms.
Sid's too complex to design.
Lindenmeyer had to grow
him up psychologically
like a real person with
multiple personality disorder.
Program runs like a child.
Much faster.
He put all these
killers in SID's nursery
and let him watch them
cannibalize each other.
And only the strong ones survive.
Open SID 6.7.
Combine.
Looks like there's almost
200 different personality structures
in this version.
The battle raging inside him
must be amazing.
Wait, wait, wait. Slow that down.
The names there, slowly.
You're not in here, Parker.
Right there.
Matthew Grimes, uh...
He killed my wife and my daughter.
Look. It doesn't mean...
He's not necessarily dominant, Parker.
But he's a part of SID?
Yes.
[Dance music playing]
Watch it.
What?
♪ On the inside
♪ oh, is it love, love, love? ♪
♪ oh, is it love, sweet love? ♪
I'm beautiful.
I'll make this quick.
[Girl] Hey, mom.
Hi, sweetheart.
How are you, honey?
Have a seat with your mom.
I need a hug.
Ohh.
♪ Oh, is it love, love, love? ♪
♪ oh, is it love, sweet love? ♪
Grimes was a political terrorist.
Why did he take Parker's
wife and child?
Parker was getting too close.
He was cutting Grimes off
from potential targets.
Grimes figured by murdering
the man's wife and child,
might distract Parker
from the manhunt.
Grimes was wrong.
[Radio] Sergeant penn at 3491.
How you doing?
Why don't you come inside?
Uh, I just...
Need to listen to the radio.
Do you think it's important
for a first baseman to be left-handed?
Woo!
You look mighty parch-ed, pardner.
To think...
You constitute one of my ancestors.
Rum and coke.
How about a lime in there?
I'm vaguely offended by that.
[Screaming]
On your fuckin' knees!
Now!
Don't.
[Screaming]
Stand up!
Aim and shoot.
Good girl.
Uh!
O.K., people.
We got a lot of work to do.
We have a symphony to compose.
Do you think my mom is pretty?
Uh...Yes, I do.
I think she's very pretty.
So do I.
Is that a real gun?
Yes, it is.
Did you ever have to shoot anybody?
[Radio] 78.5 code 6.
We have a hostage situation
at sixth and figueroa.
Description of the perp
matches suspect surveillance
photos from LETAC.
Could you go get your
mother for me?
[Honks horn]
There she is. Keep your eye on her.
He's got a gun!
What were you doing?
Talking baseball.
Got to go!
Bye.
What did I miss?
Sid's got hostages.
[Sid] And scream.
Aah!
[Synthesizer] Aah!
Yes.
What have you got for me?
Uh!
Diaphragm!
Uuhh!
Stop.
Well-done.
Every orchestra is
divided into sections--
like instruments sit
with like instruments.
[Woman squealing]
[Sid] What kind of
instrument are you?
We'll have to find a way around.
No time.
On 4.
2...
3...
4.
[Whimpering]
Shut up!
Parker,
what--
[man] Get him!
Shit!
Hmm.
Love the suit.
[Sirens]
[Synthesizer playing screams]
Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
[Electric guitar playing]
[Screams fade in and out]
Police!
Freeze!
[Sid] 1, 2, 3!
[Crowd screaming]
Shut up!
♪ ♪ ♪
One can sense a...
Final movement.
[Crowd screams]
Let's begin.
[Crowd screaming]
Scream.
Come on, scream.
Scream louder!
Huh!
[Screaming louder]
Louder!
I'm losing too much of myself.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
I know you.
There he is!
Yah!
Parker Barnes!
[Honks horn]
[Moaning]
Inmate Barnes interrupting
my composition.
It's him!
That's o.K. I got another little tune
for my friends out there
in crime-Buster land--
the symphony of collision!
[Honks horn]
Ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
So...Who's that with you, Parker?
Dr. Madison Carter, I presume,
LETAC consultant on aberrant psychology.
Mmm!
Fuck you!
I love this game!
You know, Parker, I've been thinking.
We have so much in
common psychologically.
Wouldn't you agree, Dr. Carter?
We have such a history together.
We'd make a great team, a dynamic duo.
Who else touches the
world with synthetic hands?
Who else do you know who's been
locked out of the real world
and is now just learning to be free?
Who else do you know
that's a multiple murderer,
just like you?
[Chuckles]
Here we go!
Home run! Ha ha ha!
Reach in that back seat
and hand me that crowd pleaser.
Jesus.
The only way to stop him
is to bust up his software module.
Hey, Parker!
Ready?
Yeah.
[Sid] Come on down!
[Parker] Now!
Ha ha ha ha!
Out of here!
God, this guy is fun.
Could we at least advise Mr. Barnes
that we prefer to have
SID 6.7 subdued
as opposed to terminated?
It's a crying shame
we're going to destroy
the prototype of future
humanoid nanotechnology.
Did they find the programmer yet?
Lindenmeyer. No, not yet.
You'd think the cops
could at least find him.
Lindenmeyer was your
programmer, Mr. Wallace.
[Parker] I shot at
the guy 30 or 40 times.
[Cochran] I don't care! Those
are real people out there!
Control yourself, or you're
going back in the box.
I'm sorry, Billy.
All right? Shoot me.
This is not a game, but
SID is from the game.
I can't catch him if
I'm in the penitentiary.
Matthew Grimes is a
part of SID 6.7.
There's no doubt about that.
Last night, SID tried taunting me,
like Grimes used to do.
Look at this.
[Madison] We don't
know he's the dominant.
I know. I know.
That's how I know,
because I know.
Maybe that's what SID
wants you to think.
Push you over the
edge, make you slip up.
Sid did not push me
over the edge,
and I did not slip up.
Take a look at this.
This is SID from the
media zone last night,
taken from their own recordings.
He can't get enough of himself.
He's going to want more
victims, bigger events,
and more coverage, just
like Matthew Grimes.
Matthew Grimes was a
political terrorist
whose specialty was
bombing populated targets--
any mass expression of democracy,
anywhere where a lot of
people can die
and it can be recorded
by the news media live.
This behavior was never part
of his original programming.
SID 6.7 isn't bound
by programming anymore.
What does that mean?
In the real world, he's
free of any behavioral limits
he might have had in
virtual reality.
[Wallace] He's evolving. My God!
He's evolving!
Into what?
♪ Well, you can tell by
the way I use my walk ♪
♪ I'm a woman's man,
no time to talk ♪
♪ music loud and women warm ♪
♪ I've been kicked
around since I was born ♪
♪ and now it's all
right, it's o.K. ♪
♪ and you may look the other way ♪
♪ we can try to understand ♪
♪ the New York
times' effect on man ♪
♪ whether you're a brother
or whether you're a mother ♪
♪ you're stayin'
alive, stayin' alive ♪
♪ feel the city breakin'...
[Newscaster] ...Outside Los
Angeles' hottest night club,
the media zone,
which last night was
turned into a living hell.
I want you to describe
for me, as best you can,
exactly what happened.
[Newscaster] 14 people have
died in the flooding which...
Welcome to L.A.
A punk comes in with a
gun and starts shooting--
bodies and blood everywhere.
Another typical day, right?
Just mayhem and murder and...
Intimidation.
Well, this guy
comes into the club, right?
And he takes my purple suit.
That suit cost me $150, man.
A l'amour original, right?
Takes my suit and
kills everybody,
strips me down to
my underwear.
[Announcer] Live at
the olympic auditorium.
He just started
killing people.
He put us in a formation
like an orchestra
and would make us scream
like we were instruments.
He just started shooting people,
and he made me...
Don't fuck with me, man.
Videotape it.
[Announcer] What do we see?
Why not?
[Neck snaps]
Watch the fights as they happen.
You never know what
will happen on live TV.
It may be a serious injury.
Paramedics may need
to be called in.
One thing that you
can be assured of
is that here we're
going out live right now.
And what do we see?
There's still a few seats
left here
for those of you who
want to see
the ultimate fighting
championships in person.
Play it one more time.
Sure.
O.K. Freeze.
You like being in front
of the camera, don't you?
Like a child performing for a parent.
[Announcer] Whoever's operating
our closed-circuit cameras
is in lust.
That beauty in area six
has been on the big screens
for over a minute.
The action in the
ring is intense.
How far's the olympic?
Four blocks east.
What's happening?
[Parker] Live execution!
[Announcer] Millions
of people are viewing
the bloodiest fighting
championships ever,
live from the olympic
auditorium.
[Crowd chanting "ka-pow"]
[Announcer] Enough already
with the close-up, Mr. de Mille.
We want to return to the rumble!
[Crowd cheering]
Folks, the olympic auditorium
has never seen anything like this!
[Chanting "ka-pow"]
Ahh.
They like you.
I like you, too.
I'm going to make you famous, baby.
[Man] What the fuck's your problem?
What the hell are you
doing? Leave him alone!
Ha ha ha!
Aah! No!
Aah!
No!
[Applause]
[Announcer] ...Report to
ringside. We have an accident.
Right there. Stop that guy.
Security at ringside, please.
Hey, Parker!
This one's for you!
Freeze!
[Announcer] Ladies and
gentlemen, please remain calm.
The authorities
are on--
I nailed that son of a
bitch. I blew his hand off.
[Announcer] Please remain
calm, ladies and gentlemen.
Security will handle this.
Yah!
[Announcer] Accident on the floor.
[Announcer] Remain calm.
Our security personnel
will handle this.
Please, just stay in your seats.
[Crowd booing]
Here. Hungry?
Hungry?
Lick, lick, lick.
Yes! Ahh!
Ha ha ha ha!
[Man] Hey!
Ahh!
Ugh!
All trains to catalina have
been indefinitely postponed
due to the damage caused
to the tunnel
during last month's
7.2 earthquake.
Hey, Parker! Deja vu!
How am I doing?
This ain't vr, Parker!
She's flesh and blood.
Flesh and blood!
Don't do it, Parker!
[Woman] Help me!
Don't do it!
Don't do it, Parker.
Drop it!
Freeze!
[Woman] He shot that woman!
He's a cop! He's a cop!
He did it in cold blood!
They want to take you
back to prison
until this gets sorted out.
I missed. I did not
shoot that woman.
...and spoke
the words--
hey, Parker, this one's
for you!
Grimes taunted me with that line.
Every time he killed,
he would say, "this one's for you,"
like he needed me.
[Siren]
All right, move it.
Hey, Billy! Wait! Listen! Billy!
What do you want from me?
Somebody...Set me up.
With me back inside,
you'll never get him!
You lock me up, you'll
never get him.
I'm sorry.
Don't lock me up!
Cochran! I checked the body.
The bullet exited the
woman's chest.
Parker couldn't have killed her.
How do you know she
was facing him?
I saw it happen.
50 damn witnesses say
Parker shot her dead.
How do you explain it?
Maybe she turned, you
weren't looking.
There was a lot going on.
SID 6.7 is still out there.
You're locking up
the one man who may be
able to stop him.
[Grimes] Hey, Parker!
This one's for you!
Hey, Parker! T
his one's for you!
Hey, Parker!
This one's for you!
Mr. Grimes, to the
majority of our viewers,
you are known as a
mass murderer.
Now, to some, you're considered
a political terrorist,
and yet to a surprisingly
large number of your supporters,
you're considered a hero.
In our so-called democracy,
a handful of people
own everything,
and other folks got nothing.
[Woman] Help!
Can you tell us why
you've chosen Barnes
as a target of your
vengeance?
I did not choose
Parker Barnes.
He chose me.
Parker! Parker,
we're in here!
Hurry!
Parker!
Help!
Baby!
Help! Get us out, baby!
Would you mind saying
your signature phrase?
Not at all.
Parker, this one's for you.
What was that?
That was the sound of
the end of futility.
[Grimes] Goddamn it!
You're supposed to be dead!
Stay down!
Get off of me!
Arggh--
hey, buddy. How's the wife and kid?
Still dead, huh?
That's reality for you--no
saving, no resetting.
You killed them, barnsey,
just like that bitch on the train.
You got greedy. You
leapt before you looked.
You reached your old arm in there and...
Boom!
Come on.
Just because I'm carrying around
the joy of killing your
family inside me
doesn't mean we can't be friends.
Seeing you just brings Grimes
oozing to the surface...
That's all.
[Door shuts]
Say thank you.
Oh, come on, Parker.
I'm giving you your freedom,
short-lived though it may be.
A little-known fact
about the locator implants
prison inmates receive upon release
is that they contain a neural toxin.
The satellites they track you with
can trigger release of
the toxin with microwaves.
After transmission,
the implant's host dies
within 30 seconds.
So let's see,
you've just killed two guards
while making your escape.
How long do you think it's going to take
to get your termination implemented?
And who should you really
be going after,
killer-- them or me?
You're the only guy
on my dance card, Parker.
♪ I talk of freedom
♪ you talk of the flag
♪ I'll look at you,
and you'll look at me ♪
♪ and we'll cry a lot
♪ and this'll be what we say
♪ this'll be what we say
the best we can do is contain him,
double our detail, and
hope SID surfaces somewhere.
Parker Barnes escaped prisoner
transport. Both guards are dead.
I don't believe it!
What's going to happen next?
The fail-safe
is still on-line?
And at your disposal, ma'am.
...bigger than any live
television event in years,
so let your voice...
[Telephone rings]
Hello?
Madison?
Parker?
I didn't kill those guards.
Where are you?
Sid let me go. He's interactive.
He only enjoys the game
playing against his favorite opponent,
and that's me.
Tell me where you are.
Listen. Did you know about the poison
they put in my head?
Yes.
When were you going to tell me?
I never thought they'd have
a reason to use it.
Look, Parker, I can't help you
unless you tell me where you are.
I'm with my family.
[Television] ...The votes called
in, so let your voice be heard.
[Madison] Parker? Parker?
[Woman] Madison
Carter--line one.
Cochran here.
[Madison] Parker's out.
No shit.
He didn't kill the guards.
You were right about the woman,
only Ms. Attorney General's
got every SWAT team
in the Southern section
on a Parker Barnes hunt.
There's something you should
know about the implants.
Mom!
What?
Your keys!
Thanks.
Bye.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
[Door shuts and engine starts]
[Radio blaring]
Tracking in Hollywood
at fountain and vine.
Enhancement.
South to Santa Monica,
east to gower.
Located at memorial park...
There he is.
Go for it.
Enter crimtrack
termination code.
What the fuck are you doing?
Anybody using this chair?
What are you doing?
Parker.
Oh!
I told chief Cochran
about the neural toxin.
He's taken care of it.
See, Grimes used my
Linda and, uh, Christine
to get to me.
And now SID, he...
He used my guilt about
losing them.
He's attacking your weakness
like he did in vr.
That's right.
But he's not Grimes, see.
His, um...
Appetite is expanding.
See, he craves feedback.
He needs a larger...
He needs a larger audience.
I know where he is.
I want to live!
[Newscaster] Authorities
refuse to comment on rumors
that a former officer
serving time for homicide
has been released to
help with the manhunt.
They must be worried.
They let out inmate Barnes.
You shot a news crew, right?
He scared you, didn't he?
And if you get scared,
you might do something foolish.
I know it's you!
Meanwhile, L.A. county residents
are flocking to gun
shops throughout the area.
Where would you go?
The political sensitivity
of the immigration issue
and the possibility of
closing the American borders
seems certain to guarantee
a television audience
of unprecedented size.
Close the borders!
Close the borders...
They have their culture
overrun by refugees from
the third world
to whom even poverty here
in paradise
would be preferable to the
living hell
they created in their own worlds.
I'm reminded of another group
of immigrants--the puritans.
Let us speak with an open mind.
If you close off U.S.
borders to immigration,
you close off your soul
to the future
and doom this country
to cultural extinction.
This nation has always...
[Man] What's going on in
there? We just lost New York!
Wait a minute!
You guys asleep?
Ladies and gentlemen,
my fellow Americans...
What the hell?
Welcome...
What's happening out there?
No!
[Woman screams]
To death TV.
[Man] They're still up there!
Please move back now!
[Sid] Why make a promise like
that without being able to deliver?
Rafael debaca has just
been executed
during a live broadcast...
So, people, what
do you want--
strangulation, mutilation,
cannibalism, gunshots,
stabbings?
I'll slice, I'll dice,
I'll julienne.
What about hanging...
By the testicles?
But before we begin,
a word to the parents.
The following program will
contain scenes of violence
not suitable for small children.
The rest of you won't take
your eyes off the screen.
Don't fucking move!
And now...
On with the show, a death
TV special segment...
What floor's the studio on?
38th floor.
Our first little contestant
comes from our city of angels.
9 years of age...
No!
No, no, no!
...and lover of macaroni
and cheese,
daughter of renowned
criminal psychologist
Madison Carter, one of
the friends of the show.
This girl will be leaving
her mark on this world by...
That's my little girl!
Listen! As God is my witness,
I'm going to find your daughter,
but I need your help.
We got to find out who's
in charge of the building
and get them to cut the phone lines.
Can you do that?
Go! Go! Let's move it!
Inside! Go!
Move it! Move it! Let's go!
This beauty's got two hours
until she gets blown
into little beauty bits.
Madison, I'll find
your daughter for you.
Help me!
Coming to the glorious climax...
There's Barnes there.
There!
Barnes!
Go!
Parker!
Fan out your men!
Go!
Go! Go! Go!
Shit!
So while we wait and
watch the demise
of young karin Carter,
let's have a talk with
our studio audience.
You're the supervisor.
You can do it.
I don't know if I can.
Cut every phone line into
this building.
Imagine, if you can,
just for a moment,
that she is your daughter,
a child you have
given birth to.
Only now...
To be completely,
utterly helpless
and unable to save her.
Oh, my.
Where is my daughter?
I don't know.
And what will you do now?
Shoot me?
Folks at home, ed.
Ed, folks at home.
Enjoying the show, ed?
At moments like this,
I bet you're thinking,
"where is God?"
I have that same dilemma.
Oh, look at that response,
ed. They love you.
What I am...
Is not my fault.
It's not even my choice.
I came to be because of
what you are.
They love you so much,
they want you dead, ed.
Face it, folks.
To kill is in your nature.
What the hell happened
to the phone lines?
Where's my audience?
Parker!
Put down the weapon,
or we will open fire.
Chief!
I want that goddamn
helicopter down here now!
Yes, sir.
Fuck you, Parker.
I am made of everything!
I am the future!
And you...
You're losing your sense of humor.
Come on!
Come on, Parker! Come on!
Where's the girl?
It's not the same this
time, Parker.
She's not your daughter.
Come on, Parker!
Come on!
Arggh!
Where's the girl?
Banzai!
Jump, Parker!
Come and get the little
girl, Parker!
Arggh!
Come on!
Come on, yeah. Attaboy.
You can do it.
O.K., Parker. This one's for me.
Now...
Where is the girl?
Where's the girl?
Blow me, Parker!
Parker--Parker--Parker--
Parker--Parker--
park-park-park-park-park-
park-park-park-park-park--
Parker!
So, Mr. Barnes,
by destroying SID,
you've effectively
lost any chance you had
of finding the little girl.
No!
Arggh!
[Sid] Yeah! You made it!
Come on, Parker! Come on!
Come on. You can make it.
Oh, goody!
Hey, Parker, this one's for me.
Parker!
Hey, maddy.
You just missed Parker.
Where is she?
You can't kill me, maddy.
She's waiting, mommy.
Ha ha!
Show me Madison.
Tell me where my daughter is!
Do you see?
Sid assumes he's still
in the real world.
[Sid] Come on, maddy.
Forget the kid.
Where is she?
Do you really want to know?
Yes.
Do you really, really want to know?
Just click your heels three times.
Oh, karin!
Mommy's here!
She's here?
Yes! She is.
She's been here all along.
Uh-huh.
You're dead.
And you're back in the box.
This is vr?
That's right.
Get us out, Billy.
Get them out now.
Madison first. Help me lift her out.
[Sid] They couldn't have
done this without you, Daryl.
I'll go lower Barnes.
[Sid] Daryl!
I'm back in the fucking box?
Smart. That's my boy.
Anytime now, Billy.
Daryl!
Help me, Daryl!
I'm back in the box, Daryl!
Help me!
Daryl!
Daryl! Why did you betray me?
Judas!
Judas, Daryl!
Billy?
No!
You're in my world now!
Get away from that,
or I'll kill you, too!
Parker!
Get in here!
Come on! I want to play!
I don't know what the two
of you think you're doing,
but you
will not--
i want to play!
I want to play!
Coward!
Parker! I want to play!
I want to play!
I want to play, Parker!
Let's go get your little girl.
All right! Watch your step!
Come on! All right! You're clear.
Karin!
Don't!
It's booby-trapped.
The bomb squad's five minutes away.
Well, we don't have five minutes.
[Man] I'm going to the
other side of the roof!
Karin!
[Muffled cry]
Listen, I'm going to
get you out of there.
Hurry!
[Karin crying]
Hang on, sweetheart. I'm coming.
Just stay right where you are.
Hurry.
Get me out of here.
It's all right, sweetheart.
We're going to get you
out of here.
You're going to get me
out of here?
Yes. I'm going to get you out.
Be careful, Parker.
Hi, mom. Hurry.
Wait, wait, wait!
Don't move! Don't move!
Hello, Parker.
That can only be you.
Anything you can think of,
I've already thought of,
and I thought of it first,
so I made this recording
in case you got clever.
Just stay right where you are.
Don't move.
He's got you sitting
on a pressure plate.
Now, if you stand up...
It's going to be very bad.
O.K.? All right.
[Madison] Be still, honey.
Don't move.
It's o.K., baby.
Hang in there.
Don't move, honey.
Mom, get me out of here.
We will, baby. Just stay still.
Mom. Mommy.
Hold on, baby.
All right. Just talk to mommy.
Mamma.
I'm right here, sweetie.
Try to get into the
main operating system
and reset the internal clock.
Uh-uh-uh. I thought
of that one, too.
Better try again.
No!
Oh, God!
Faster!
Hang on, baby. Everything's
going to be o.K.
I love you, karin.
Connect this side to the input...
And this one goes to the output.
Now, which one's the output?
Which one's the output?
Let's see.
Eeny-meeny-miny-mo.
Output, output, output.
It might be this one right here.
[Madison] Parker?
Be it, please.
Uh-uh-uh. I thought
of that one, too.
Better try again.
Faster.
Faster!
It's not working.
God!
Mommy!
Uh-uh-uh. I thought
of that one, too.
Uh-uh-uh.
I thought of that one, too.
It's working.
[Madison] What?
Uh-uh-uh. I thought
of that one, too.
It's working.
It's working? We're o.K.?
We're o.K.?
Oh, my God!
Uh-uh-uh...
Mommy!
Oh, baby! Oh, baby!
All right, sir. Watch it.
Thank you.
♪ Daa
♪ so then
♪ up upon this high wall
♪ looking at the streetlights ♪
♪ all spread out like a banquet ♪
♪ why is this room so silent ♪
♪ only when I'm moving?
♪ No direction chosen
♪ rolling over emotion
♪ guess I'm your party man
♪
p-p-party man
♪ I'm your party man
♪
p-p-party man
♪ I'm your party man
♪ so then
♪ up upon this high wall
♪ looking at the streetlights ♪
♪ all spread out like a banquet ♪
♪ why is this room so silent ♪
♪ only when I'm moving?
♪ No direction chosen
♪ rolling over emotion
♪ guess I'm your party man
♪ give 'em no hope, no tenderness ♪
♪ no holiness, no sensitivity ♪
♪ no love, no heart,
no imagination ♪
♪ no compassion
♪ no talking just head
♪ I cannot be dead
♪ I will be in your head,
you will be on your knees ♪
♪ you keep begging me, please,
make it stop--stop--stop ♪
♪ grease it up good,
work it back and forth ♪
♪ you don't even know who I am ♪
♪ think of the good
things, remember the bad ♪
♪ no illusions
♪ no talking just head
♪ you've been misled
♪ I will be in your head,
working it back and forth ♪
♪ like I knew that I would
♪ no mercy, no hope
♪ no crying, no emotion
♪ no immortality, no soul
♪ no talking just head
♪ I cannot be dead
♪ I will be in your head, you
will be down on your knees ♪
♪ and you'll be begging
me, please, make it stop ♪
♪ stop--stop!