Okay. Saddle up.  We're moving out.
Sarge, it's not even right.
We just got here Sarge.
But Sarge. I just washed. You said
rest and recreation  were coming up.
Yeah. Well, I talk too much.
We're going on a hike.
Kraut pontoon bridge. A couple engineers
gonna blow it up, and we're their escorts.
Nelson: Where is this bridge Sarge.
Sgt: A town called Chalons.
What? Are they kidding?
Chalons is 4 miles behind the German lines.
Why don't they bomb it?
I don't know. Weather's got 'em
socked in. The planes are grounded.
Let's wait. Maybe it'll clear up.
Sergeant. This is the engineer personnel.
Sgt. Turk, Corporal McQuillan.
Sergeant Sanders.
Hi.
They told me I'd have a platoon.
Well. You were told wrong.
A squad is all we can spare.
Saunders. You'll be responsible
for getting these men in and out.
Sergeant Turk will be in charge
at the bridge. Any questions?
Oh,Yeah. I got a question. How do I get 100 lbs of
high explosive to that bridge and get out without
being picked off by the krauts with this outfit.
Those are your orders Sergeant.
Now a truck will take you as close
to the lines as they can get.
Good luck.
We'll get you to that bridge.
Or die trying.
Everything.
Take off.
Hey. Take it easy will you Caje.
I'm sorry.
This isn't k-rations you know.
Boy. It sure makes me nervous,
slinging this stuff. What happens
if you get hit carrying it?
It can't go off. You can shoot right
into it and nothing could happen.
He's right. Only don't try it. It's a
detonator would set it off, a cap.
They'll go off if they're hit.
But we'll be carrying them.
Works like this.
Forget it McQuillan. You'll get your
chance to shine at the bridge.
The only thing they have to
know about composition C is
how to carry it.
Alright everybody. Gather around here, huh.
Here's where we are right now.
This is the river and this is the bridge at
Chalons. We can expect outpost lines here
and enemy patrols all the way to the river.
Now we're not looking for a fight.
Our mission is to get to the bridge.
We're gonna go in here.
What's so special about this bridge?
How long you been in the war kid?
I came in at Normandy.
Then start acting like it eh.
By blowing up that bridge we're
gonna cut off the German retreat.
Tanks, trucks, guns, so we don't have to fight
them all over again on the other side of the river.
Are the krauts at the bridge yet.
No but they're pulling back fast.
Any more questions?
Caje. Take the point.
Alright.
You follow in the middle right behind Nelson here.
Turk and Shelby, just follow my lead.
Say, Sergeant. I been thinking. A guy  sure
has to know what he's doing when
he's playing around with explosives.
You know, I got some experience with explosives.
Not with composition C.
We used to use dynamite.
Lj: Back home on the farm I used
to help my dad blow stumps.
Turk:  Is that right.
Yeah. But listen Sarge. What I really
wanted to say is I know more about
Get away from me.
But I thought when we got to the bridge I could..
Lookit, stump blower. If and when we get to
that  bridge I don't want you anywhere
around me. Do you understand that?
Now, get back in the file where you belong.
We'll go behind along
the face of the slope.
Alright.
Kraut outpost.
We'll slip up the hill behind them. pass the word.
Es war nur ein Hase.
Are you trying to foul up this mission.
It was a loose rock.
I couldn't help it.
You got loose brains.
A guy with clumsy feet don't belong out here.
Alright. Hold it.
What happened back there was an accident.
It could happen to you, me or anybody else.
From now on you have any complaints
against  the men in this squad,
you make them through me.
I'll do that.
Is Turk always that touchy.
He's one of the best demolition
men this army's got.
He's just worried you won't be
able to get us to that bridge.
Okay. Let's move.
(small engine noise approaching)
Comm mal her.
Was ist es?
Sprengkapseln Eimers.
Amerikaner Sprengkapseln und Eimers.
Wie ist es hier?
Ich weiß nicht.
(German)
Doc.
Littlejohn's hit.
Drag them off to the side. Hide
them in the trees. Their bikes too.
Turk's responsible for this.
He fired the first shot.
Well. What you gonna say now. This wouldn't
have happened if you hadn't fired too soon.
How do you think I'm gonna set those
charges without this primer cord, eh.
Besides, those krauts would be on their way
to report this patrol right now if I hadn't of.
You peek expert, you stump blower.
You had no right sticking your nose in that pack.
Let him alone, he's hurt.
Get outta here.
Look, I said leave him alone.
Boy, you guys are experts.
First of all you try to get rid of the primer cord,
now you're trying to blow up the detonators, huh.
Soldier, you are gonna get court-martialed,
I promise you that. If we get out of this,
you are going to be court martialed.
Is this what you got so hot about.
You had to get off that early shot
and get one of my men hit.
That kraut had to be stopped.
We would have stopped him
soon as Littlejohn took cover.
Maybe, but that's a margin
I can't afford Sergeant.
You know we don't have much
chance to get to that bridge as it is.
If those krauts got away,
we'd have no chance.
Now you listen to me. I'm gonna remind
you just one time. I'm in charge of this
outfit until we get to the bridge.
And if anything happens,
I'll decide what we do about it.
You got it!
(Click)
How ya doing?
OK
Don't be a hero. We got a long ways to go.
I said I'm OK. I wanna be there when
the great master puts on his show.
If you hadn't tangled with him, then
somebody else would. He had good reason.
Thanks. Hey.
Don't forget there Woody. Cause you'll
probably have to come to a court
martial when we get back.
Be a pleasure.
Sergeant?
How is Littlejohn doing?
He's okay.
I been talking with McQuillan Sarge.
He tells me Turk's had a long go at this
demolition business without any relief.
Alright. Come on. Get to it.
Well, he's been on these ulcer
missions since Africa, Sarge.
Sicily, Cilantro, Normandy.
Don't get  me wrong.
I'm not trying to excuse him. I
Thought it might help if you knew
a little bit about him, that's all.
Alright. So I know a little bit about him.
Well. Too much tension and not enough rest
is a tough combination Sarge. You know that.
Guy gets to think his luck's run out on him.
You know, the last time out
he lost a longtime buddy.
Who hasn't?
What makes you think Turk is any different to
me than any other G.I.  I been thrown in with.
This is just another job.
And I'm doing it.
Well. I better get on back.
I understand you've been
blowing up stuff since Africa.
Walton told me you lost a buddy last time out.
C'est La Guerre.
Look Turk. We drew each other.
I didn't ask for this any more than you did.
Alright. You been wrung dry maybe,
but you can better your chances
and ours if you'd slack off a little.
Oh, I got it.
Mother hen is worried about
her little chicks, huh.
You think that a little soft salt will make
me drop my charges  against that
slug happy buddy of yours.
Well you're wrong.
So why don't you stop trying to
understand and just do your job.
Oh, it's not much, but you're
all the protection I have.
And I'd feel a little bit better if you'd at
least take your place up in the line.
(Snap)
Kirby.
They're a little more to the
right up by that high ground.
Those trees will give us some cover.
Say Caje. You've got the language and all.
Do you ever think of staying
over here after the war.
Yeah. Some.
Sure is pretty.
Bang Bang
I think Wilkinson's dead.
Kirby.
Yeah?
You're with me.
Caje. You follow us.
Come on. Give us some cover here.
(German)
(A steady gunfire erupts from the Germans)
Boom
Doc.
Nelson. Take the point. After all
this racket we'll have to clear
out fast. Keep your eyes open.
Doc.
Gonna send you back with Caje and Littlejohn.
If you can't make it all the way,
you hole up and you wait. Got it.
Right.
Get the dead man's packs.
Don't touch those packs.
We'll carry them.
Now let's move out.
Hey Kirby.
What's the trouble.
You're not keeping up.
Wha, I think it's my ankle Sarge.
I must have sprained it or something.
Your ankle... Okay,
let's take a look at it.
Aah, Oo oo
When did it happen?
Well. It's not serious.
I think I had it laced too tight for
one thing, cause it feels better already.
How long you been walking on this?
This happened when you fell
back at the cemetery, didn't it.
Come on Sarge.
I don't want to hold you up.
You're holding us up right now.
What do you think I'm doing back here.
You're so far behind we were losing you.
There's nothing to it.
A little sprain, that's all.
Don't give me that.
Don't you know Doc needed you.
You at least can handle a rifle.
You should have gone back with them.
Okay, come on now. Start back. Try to
catch up with Doc and give him a hand.
I'm not going back.
I'm not gonna quit and
give him the satisfaction.
You're going back.
Your bridge should be right around the bend.
If you brought us the right way.
Krauts.
Should have been here sooner.
I thought we were supposed to get here
before the Germans pulled back this far.
We were, Trigger.
Wasn't that close.
They didn't just get here.
There's more coming.
You still think you can blow the bridge?
Still think you can get me there?
We haven' t had a prayer of
getting at it from this side.
We're gonna have to cross the river.
Billy. Take off your packs.
We'll hide 'em here.
Turk. You stay here and watch the equipment.
McQuillan.
You look up and down the river. Try to
find a boat but keep out of sight.
Billy. You come with me. We're gonna
inspect what's left  of that farmhouse up there.
Now we all meet back here in...30 minutes.
Do any good?
I went down as far as the next bend.
We're out of luck on a boat.
Or are we?
Couldn't find a boat?
Alright. Maybe this will do.
There's a backwash down there
practically surrounded by brush.
We can try it out there.
Then if it works, we'll lash everything
on the top and make it in one trip.
Can I load it up now. Then we'd be
ready to go the minute it gets dark.
Right. Billy.
You go with me up the hill.
We'll pick out a spot for you to dig in.
Y, You want me to stay on this side?
You give us cover. Let's go.
What are you doing?
I'm thinking. I gotta blow a bridge.
Where's McQuillan?
He's down by the river putting that raft together.
What kept you?
Did you have to hold junior's hand
to get him to stay by himself.
(Splash, splash)
(Splash)
(Splash, splash, splash)
(Splash, splash)
(Splash)
(Splash, splash, splash)
(Splash, splash)
He's dead.
Stopped the kraut from getting off a shot.
Where were you? Keeping the krauts
off our necks is the escort's job.
That''s why you're here Saunders.
Looks like you blew it.
Well, not counting junior up on
the hill, that leaves two of us.
I was right.
They didn't send enough men.
Tell me something Turk.
Why do you hate so much.
You can get a lot done with hate.
Let me put it another way.
What are you afraid of.
I'm only afraid of one thing Saunders.
That sometime, someplace, some
jerk is gonna get me killed.
I've come a long way.
When I was seventeen I was
setting charges in open pit mines.
At twenty-one I was blowing oil wells.
I'd hate to cash in now because
some  jerk who's not dry behind
the ears yet, slops up a detail.
You know Saunders, you don't
have to go on with this.
Nobody expected you and one man
to hold off the whole German army
while I blow a bridge.
My orders are to get you to that bridge and back.
And that's what I'm gonna do.
That is unless
unless you call it off.
You got yourself an excuse, Turk.
You lost your assistant.
So, it's your decision.
Do we go?
We go.
Okay Saunders. This is where I take over.
I'm gonna go up ahead and have
a look-see. I'll be back to give
you a hand with the stuff.
Cave over there.
Can you get up? You hear
me Turk? Can you get up?
Come on. Get up.
Up.
Run for it. Get up.
Eh!
Come on.
You can make it.
Now get up and help me.
Hold on!
I knew I'd get it this time. I knew it.
My luck didn't run out.
They took it away from me,
when they gave me you.
You and and your creeps.
Go on. Get out.
Save your own neck.
Turk.
Turk. That bridge is still there.
Don't quit on me now.
Come on Turk. Don't quit on me now.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna blow the bridge.
Not like that you're not.
I'll blow it any way I can.
Now take that mess apart, Saunders.
Don't be stupid. You try to
blow the bridge that way,
The krauts will have it
together before morning.
Turk I haven't got time to take a
correspondence course. And
you're in no shape to do the job.
Just listen to me. Do like I say.
Bust up that ball into three equal parts.
Don't make the charges no bigger than that.
Make about 20 of them.
And get the primer cord.
Cut it in 3 foot lengths.
Put the end of the primer cord
in each one of the charges.
I have the primer cord. 3 foot lengths.
Ah, what next.
Turk.
Turk. 3 foot lengths of
primer cord. Now what's next.
Turk.
Turk what's next.
Now you take the rest of the primer cord.
and lay it out.
That'll be your lead wire.
Then tie the charges on to the lead wire.
About every 4 feet.
And make  sure you press the C2
in tight around the primer cord.
Right.
Then take your main roll of primer cord.
And put it in one of those new zip bags.
Then take your charges and put them in last.
So they'll feed out like a chalk line.
(German voices approaching)
(German)
ja ja , ist der Wein gut
es macht die Nacht schnell gehen
Ich habe meine Cointreau
(clicking noise)
Bring the wire over here.
Now cut it. One at a time though.
(Cough Cough)
Take the plastic box here.
And put those 2 wires on those 2 poles.
Make sure they're tight.
I haven't lost it.
Count to a slow forty.
That'll give you time to get out.
Give me the handle.
This is my job.
My job is to get you back.
You'll never get me back.
I said give me the handle.
No.
Alright. You just relax now, expert.
I'll try to be nice and easy on you.
Just relax.
Don't you mother hen me.
Alright. Hold it now. Here we go.
Here we go.
I'll catch up.
Hans.
Komm mal her.
Es ist Holz.
Ein Floß.
Boom Boom Boom Boom
Huh. Huh.
He's dead. What are we
carrying him for. He's dead.
He can' t be.
He can't be.
He's alive.
Turk.
Don't die on me.
Don't die on me Turk.
You're alive.
You hear me.
I'm gonna get you back alive, Turk.
You're gonna live till I get you back.
You're gonna live, Turk.
Grab a hold.
Turk.
Get out.
What are you gonna do about Kirby?
You listen to me Turk.
You prefer charges against Kirby
and get him court martialed.
And I'm gonna find you.
Get out of here mother hen.
Go back to your chicks.
Chicks huh.
I fought with them ever since Normandy.
They 're good soldiers.
And the reason they're out there
all busted up is because they
tried to get you to the bridge.
Get outta here.
You know something.
I'm gonna put him up for a Silver Star.
Hey Sarge. What'd he say.
He still gonna press charges.
He won't make it stick if he doesn't lie.
He should be careful, you blew  his
bridge for him. Got him back alive.
Come on Sarge. What'd he say.
What'd he say. Was he still mad Sarge.
Alright. Just knock it off. You knock it off.
You guys make me sick.
Go on.
Look at yourselves.
You call yourself a squad?
You're a bunch of goof offs.
Littlejohn, you caused nothing but trouble.
You mind everybody else's business but your own.
Like poking around with that primer
cord and then dropping it on the road.
And from now on you mind your own
business and you follow orders.
Kirby, Kirby.
You're a hot headed showoff, who thinks
of himself first, and everybody else second.
You fly off the handle
every time you turn around.
Now cooling your heels off in some
stockade may be just what you
need so you just better shape up.
Now I've had it.
This squad is gonna shape up.
You been in the front lines so long
you're forgetting you're soldiers.
I'm sick and tired of holding your
hands every time we get into a bind.
Subs by
Jack T.