Bloody rope.
What?
Is it too heavy for you?
Ah!
Come on.
I'm coming.
Got the torch?
Yeah.
Trust me. Come on.
Right, this is the place.
Are you sure?
I told you, there's no-one there.
Okey-doke.
Hurry up.
I love the war, the blackout,
no cars on the street.
It just makes life so easy.
You sure there's no-one here?
Hand it over.
Trust me, mate. This'll do it.
Cor, look at this place.
It's like a bloody museum.
This stuff must be worth a fortune.
No bloody use to us.
We can find the smaller stuff.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Frank?
We got the wrong house.
We thought a friend lived here.
You are thieves.
I heard you break the door.
No. No, you got it wrong, mate.
Tell me your names. If you do not
tell me, I will shoot you where you
stand.
I will start with him.
Frank Morgan.
That's my brother, Terry.
You are...burglars.
We didn't mean anything, mister.
We're sorry. We'll scram.
You will stay exactly where you are.
Do you know what this place is?
Do you know who I am?
No, we just...
Sh-sh! Hm.
This could be the very worst night
of your life
or it could be the best.
It could make you very rich
because it just so happens I am
looking for someone just like you.
What do you mean? Ah!
From now on, you speak
only when you are spoken to.
From now on, you work for me.
Don't you recognise me?
Lydia?
I was afraid you wouldn't.
You been here long?
No, no, not long.
We came on the coach.
Is this erm...
This is James. This is my son.
Well, may we come in?
Well, of course. Yes, erm...
Come on, James. Pick your bag up.
Sit down.
Right.
So, here I am.
Yes, well...
You're looking very well.
I am well.
I don't know what you must think of
me...
...turning up like this.
I was very sorry not to see you at
the funeral.
Oh. Yeah, I wanted to go but they
wouldn't have wanted me there.
I'm sorry. I know how close you and
Daddy were.
My husband's in Tripoli. He's erm...
He's a staff sergeant in the 11th
Hussars.
You married him?
Yes.
I'm Lydia Nicholson now.
Mm.
Erm, I'm sorry you never met him.
You know, you'd like him.
And, er, have you had something to
eat?
No. No, we haven't had anything.
What would you like?
He won't talk to you.
He won't talk to anyone.
He was er...
at Sibford Street School.
Ah, right.
It's a very simple question,
Professor Townsend.
Is it or isn't it going to work?
Well, the question may be simple,
Captain Boothroyd
but I'm afraid the answer is rather
less so.
We need to know. We've got the test
tomorrow
and the actual operation itself is
planned for just one month from now.
Now, we're only going to get one
crack at this. We have to know.
There's nothing wrong with the
machine. It works. Thank you, Hans.
It's not just the machine.
There are all sorts of elements we
need to factor in.
Initial velocity, underbody
turbulence, speed and height,
of course, and then there's the
question of weight.
These are the latest figures,
Professor.
They're reducing the size and
weight.
Mm.
Well, it may make a difference.
I don't know.
And then there's still the question
of the framework. I'm sorry?
These wooden slats that will encase
the central sphere.
That's the problem. They won't hold.
Well, we don't know, of course,
but it's what we believe.
Anyway, tomorrow's tests will tell
us one way or another.
Well, maybe we should cancel the
test.
Absolutely not. There's a whole
world of difference between theory
and practice.
We need to see...
Professor Townsend -
I think you're forgetting the reason
why this unit was set up.
Mr Tizard wants facts, not
assumptions.
He will not continue to support this
project without your assurance that
it will actually work.
And I think I've explained to you,
I cannot give him that...yet.
Well, I hope for your sake that this
test is a success.
You're running out of time.
We all are.
Looks like a bit of a dump.
Just as long as we get paid.
We're doing all right out of this and
when the war ends, we're going to be
well set up.
So what are we going to do this
time? What do you think?
There was just one bomb.
They say it was a thousand pounder.
I don't suppose the pilot knew he'd
targeted a school.
The teachers had heard the plane and
they were leading the children down
when it hit.
38 of them were killed
and six teachers.
When I got there, it was...
Well, you can imagine.
Those tiny bodies.
Some of them six years old.
And nobody crying.
Nobody screaming.
Some of the older children were
searching through the rubble,
"Can I help, Miss?"
James wasn't hurt.
Not even a scratch.
But he hasn't spoken since.
He won't say anything.
He's like this all the time.
I'm not even sure
he knows I'm there.
Does his father know?
I told him about the bomb and that
James wasn't hurt. That's all.
Robert is a wonderful father.
I wasn't wrong about him, you know,
no matter what everyone said.
Why have you come HERE?
What? You want us to go!
No, no, no. No, I didn't say that.
I just, erm, well, we haven't seen
each other for ten years...
We haven't been in touch. All of a
sudden you're here and...
I had nowhere else to go.
Things have been rather difficult
for me.
I have a job.
I'm erm... I'm an OWL operator.
You know, operator, wireless and
line.
It's with the Army
and it's very important work
and, well, having James like this,
it makes it completely impossible.
Well, the MO said maybe what he
needed was a change of scenery.
A bit of fresh air and when he
mentioned the seaside, well,
I thought of you.
I thought, maybe if we could stay
with you just...
just for a few days,
you know, maybe...
Thank you for walking home with me,
Hans. Good night.
Ah, you're home early.
Well...Yes.
I haven't started the tea yet.
Erm... I'll do it.
Oh, will you?
Oh, no, no, no. That's my job.
You sit down. You must be tired.
Did you...
walk home by yourself?
No, Hans came with me.
You were watching.
Hans.
And how is Hans?
Please don't start this again,
Michael. We do this all the time.
Round and round in circles.
You're the one in the circle.
I'll make the tea. And why don't we
go out this evening, the two of us?
We can go to the pub.
Don't patronise me, Evelyn.
I'm already going out.
I'm seeing some friends.
Oh! Hello. I'm Sam.
Is Mr Foyle in? I'm his driver.
James! Oh. I'm sorry.
I... I didn't see him open the door.
That's all right. I'll wait here.
All right.
Are you going to be all right?
Oh, yes.
I'm going to take him down to the
sea.
Well, erm...
get yourself some lunch.
The British Restaurant is as good as
any. I do appreciate this.
See you this evening.
Isn't it absolutely wonderful what
the Russians are doing, sir?
Have you read the papers?
Good old Uncle Joe,
that's what I say.
Her name is Lydia. I'm her godfather.
James is her son.
Thank you. I wasn't going to ask.
Well, of course you weren't.
You haven't mentioned her before.
I haven't seen them for a very long
time. I knew her parents.
Her father was my commanding officer.
They were both killed in the blitz.
Oh, I'm sorry. Well, what are you
going to do with them?
I'm not at all sure but if you keep
quiet about this for the moment, I'd
appreciate it.
I'll keep mum. You know me.
Yeah.
Mr Foyle, morning, sir.
Good morning.
I was expecting you half an hour
ago, sir. Yeah.
Mr Parkins is here, sir. The new
Assistant Commissioner.
He arrived early so I put him in
your office. Thanks.
You must be Detective Chief
Superintendent Foyle.
That's right.
Not a good start, if I may say so.
I don't like being kept waiting.
Well, it's nine o'clock, sir.
We were told to expect you at 11.
No matter. I take it you received my
letter.
I did. This is something about
gambling, isn't it?
From the tone of your voice, I take
it you don't consider it to be a
matter of importance.
Well, it is, I can assure you.
In fact, I've received instructions
at the very highest level.
Er, what instructions exactly?
To crack down, Foyle!
Look, we've got these pontoon
schools everywhere not just in Pall
Mall and Chelsea.
Sometimes £10,000
changes hands in one night.
They're in shipyards, factories,
air-raid shelters
and some workers are losing a
month's wages in one throw.
Marked cards, impossible odds.
What you're talking about here is
nothing short of organised crime.
We do have a sergeant looking into
it. Just one man?
A very capable man.
I don't think it's good enough.
Perhaps you should wait to see the
report.
I take it you're too busy to look
into this matter yourself.
Well, I am as a matter of fact.
Anything you care to share with me?
Well, you're very welcome to see the
file.
Sabotage?
That's right.
And? Well, there's been a fire at
the munitions works.
Another at the docks. Telephone lines
have been brought down
and all by the same people,
as far as we can see.
What makes you think that?
Just a feeling.
A gang of saboteurs working their
way along the coast.
That could be a serious business.
Not quite as serious as the gambling
perhaps but erm...
I should warn you, Foyle.
I've been told about you.
You get results.
You're a good worker. But you're
also insubordinate.
You seem to forget that you're part
of a chain of command that stretches
all the way back to London.
Well, I'm here to remind you that
you're not indispensable.
Well, I'm very pleased to hear it.
I shall be here for a week. I shall
be visiting other stations.
I've booked in to the Regency Hotel.
May I borrow your driver?
Er, please do.
Scared the life out of him.
He choked on a chicken bone...
I need Mr Foyle's driver to take me
to the Regency Hotel. Where is he?
Oh, that's me, sir.
What?
I'm Mr Foyle's driver.
But that's not a police uniform.
Well, no. I was, erm, transferred
from the MTC.
I know it's irregular but what with
the war, there was no-one else.
It's more than irregular. A transfer
from the MTC? It's unheard of.
How long has this been going on for?
About three years.
I don't mind, really!
It's not you I'm thinking of.
It's police procedure.
Would you rather walk, sir?
I'd thank you not to be insolent,
Sergeant. How far is it?
About half an hour. Uphill.
Where's the car?
This way, sir.
Any luck?
Oh, yes, sir.
I've managed to join a game tonight.
Where's that?
They're meeting at a warehouse.
They?
No names yet.
They're a London-based gang.
They run games in the docks.
What games?
Dice. Crown and Anchor.
Looks fair enough on the face of it
but as soon as you start betting on
doubles and triples,
the odds are stacked against you.
Need any help?
I don't think so, sir.
I'll get some names and then I'll
make the arrest. Right.
And get the Assistant Commissioner
off your back. Thank you.
Here it comes.
What happened?
I didn't see. What happened?
Come on, gentlemen, come on.
All right. Come on, last throw of
the evening, I'm in a generous
mood.
I'm offering 4-1 on triples.
3-1 on doubles. Evens all the rest.
Three crowns. Here's a quid.
Doubles on hearts.
Diamonds the same.
Will you take an IOU?
Mr Richards, unless I'm very much
mistaken you're already...
30 bob...
30 shillings down.
Hendry, you know I'm good for it.
What are you betting?
Five bob on spades.
All right. Put him down.
What's all this chat about?
Get on with it.
Young man in a hurry, eh?
All right. Any more bets?
DISAPPOINTED GROANS
Three anchors but no takers. Pay out
on one heart, one crown and one
club.
And, gentlemen, that is the last
throw of the evening.
Thank you very much.
Wait a minute.
One more throw.
You've lost enough.
Look, I've got plenty of money.
Two nicker on crowns.
Frank.
Three crowns?
Let's go, Frank.
This is just for you.
Oh!
Bad luck. Bad luck.
And this is just for me.
That's 35 shillings, Mr Richards.
Yes, of course. Well, I'll make it
up to you. I just need a bit of
time.
How much time?
Riley, let him go.
Mr Richards, you've got 24 hours.
Then we come calling.
Mr Hendry? I was wondering,
when can I get another game?
I don't think I know you.
No. Paul Milner.
I ain't seen you here before.
Well, I haven't been here long.
You from the Smoke?
Why do you want to know?
No reason.
I didn't see you put too much money
on the table.
Oh, well this was just a warm-up.
Pretty lukewarm, if you ask me.
You be here tomorrow night?
Maybe.
All right. I'll see you, then.
Sure.
So, how much did we lose?
I don't know how they do it.
Every bloody time.
Oi, copper.
Oi!
Are you talking to me?
You think we can't see through you?
Asking questions. Sniffing around.
We can smell you.
Hey, you've made a mistake.
Yeah?
It's you who's made a mistake.
Frank.
Get him!
Hey, what are you doing? You get
away from here, you nancies.
It's none of your business.
Yeah?
Come on!
Hit him!
Yeah, you bloody cowards!
Thanks.
Hey, don't mention it, mate.
Come on, Terry.
Hey, wait!
Oh, morning.
I'm sorry. James has wet the bed.
He does it quite often.
Oh, right. Well, is he all right?
Oh, yes, he's fine.
Shall I just take them through?
Yes, put them in there.
Erm, breakfast?
Erm, not just yet, thanks.
Listen, it's not really any of my
business but erm...
it seems to me perhaps you should be
thinking about getting some help.
For me?
No, no, for James.
Well, what help is there?
I've been to doctors. And, well,
they all say the same.
He's still in shock because of what
happened with the bomb.
I'm hoping being here will help.
Erm, how long can we stay here?
Well,
how long were you thinking of?
I don't know. I've got nothing to
get back to in London.
It wasn't my fault, you know.
I fell in love.
Daddy didn't want to see me again.
After James was born,
it was as if I didn't exist.
Well, I don't know.
I wasn't there but erm...
I was with your father in very
difficult circumstances
and the man you're describing is,
frankly, nothing to do with the man I
knew.
Well, it's as you say.
You weren't there.
He hurt me. Well, you all did.
I was in love and I chose a life for
myself with Robert.
You didn't even try to understand.
I wrote to you.
Did you?
You didn't get the letter I wrote to
you? No.
KNOCK AT DOOR
It's your driver.
Yes, erm...
Listen,
these people might be able to help.
Try them.
Melanie Klein and Anna Freud?
Yeah, they've been very helpful for
some children.
They're Germans?
Erm, Jewish refugees, I believe.
You do realise if I wasn't here,
James would have no-one.
He has his father.
He HAD a father.
A wonderful father.
But, erm, I haven't heard from
Robert in a long while and who knows
where he is right now?
I'll see you, then. I've done the
washing up and your lunch is in the
pantry.
Thank you.
I may be home late.
Oh, really? It's a big day. There
was a test last night.
A test? Don't ask me to talk about
it, Michael. You know I can't.
Whatever made you think I was going
to ask you about it? It's nothing to
do with me.
So how much did you lose last night?
What?
I take it that's where you were.
What was it? Chuck-A-Luck?
Pontoon? How much?
A few bob. I've got to have
something to do with my time.
Don't look in my purse.
You've gone through the
housekeeping. I've got my own money.
You got through that weeks ago. The
local shop won't take our credit.
That's all right for you, isn't it?
What with your cushy little number.
"Working late..."
What's that meant to mean? You think
I don't know what's going on?
You think I'm just going to stand
here and put up with it?
What are you going to do, Michael?
Are you going to be cruel to me?
Are you going to start drinking? Are
you going to hurt me?
You've done it all already.
I won't even notice.
Hold still.
Sorry. Does it hurt anywhere else?
Everywhere. You should have had
somebody else with you.
Sam... Well, it could have been a
lot worse.
Are you all right?
Yes, sir, thank you.
First aid training in the MTC. I
always knew it would come in handy.
Are they likely to be back?
I doubt it.
My guess is they'll move the game
further down the coast.
It's a result of a sort. Not the one
the Assistant Commissioner wanted.
Is it my imagination or is the new
Assistant Commissioner worse than
the old one?
That's enough, thank you.
Sir? Yep.
The two lads that helped me, Terry
and Frank, I'd say they're brothers.
The eldest couldn't have been more
than 18 but they had plenty of cash
and they were throwing it away.
Wealthy family?
I don't think so.
They didn't seem the sort.
You know where to find them?
I don't but I'd like to have a go.
Do. If it hadn't been for them, who
knows what would have happened?
Well, if I find them,
I'll thank them.
Maybe if we're lucky, we'll see a
destroyer or a spitfire.
Hey? You'd like that, wouldn't you?
James, you've got to talk to me.
You've got to talk to Mummy because
if you don't tell me what you're
thinking, how can I help you?
I'm so sorry.
God, I have tried so hard...
And it's all gone wrong, hasn't it?
But I'm going to make it
better for you.
That's all that matters.
And one day, you'll understand.
James, huh?
I'm doing it for you.
That's all you need to know.
You have located the building?
Yeah. What do they do there?
Nothing of great consequence, my
friend.
You are concerned?
This stuff we're doing for you...
It is, I am sure, preferable to many
years with hard labour.
We don't want to do it any more.
Hm, it is a little too late for that
now.
I have told you, Frank, I am a
pacifist. I wish harm to no-one.
What I am doing only is to show that
the war is wrong.
Yeah, but it's not you doing it. It's
Terry and me.
And you are being well paid for it.
This time I will pay you double.
It is only because I am pleased with
the work you have done.
Another fire?
No.
This time I have something more
dramatic in mind.
It is very safe
and simple to use.
Now on the face of it, the test was
a complete fiasco.
The wooden cladding shattered on
impact.
As we predicted.
Yes. Well, we don't gain any points
for nay-saying, Hans.
But the steel core held.
Yes.
Were they using our figures? The
back spin was 500 revs per minute.
The package was dropped from 60 feet
at 240 miles per hour.
But then it works.
It works.
Tizard has persuaded the RAF to move
ahead with a full-scale
operational version.
That's wonderful!
Yes, but we're going to have to go
over everything again.
The pilots are going to have to go
in so low that it's almost suicidal
anyway.
Plus the fact that they'll have
6,000 pounds of high explosive
spinning in the middle of their
fuselage.
Now, let's make sure that they don't
blow up before they arrive.
I've brought you some lunch,
darling.
It's a Spam sandwich
and a glass of milk.
I have to go away for a little
while.
You're to wait here for your Uncle
Christopher to come home.
We know AB and CD are parallel.
So, what can anyone tell me about
this angle here at AEF?
Yes, Nicholas?
It's the same as EFD?
Spot on.
Is that meant to be me?
Not very flattering.
Come on, concentrate.
Yes, so if EFD is 45 degrees
and we know that the total
has to add up to a 180 degrees,
therefore, this angle here is...
Yes, Nicholas?
45 degrees.
45 degrees. Well done, well done.
Mr Richards? Yes.
I want to play football.
I wonder if I might have a word?
Bye, sir.
Bye. Do I know who you are?
Bye, see you Tuesday.
I was there last night.
Geometry?
Not my strong suit.
I used to be at St Edmund's.
It's a rescue party depot now.
Requisitioned in '41.
Yes. I know it...
St Jude's is an ambulance station.
And Mill Road closed down as a
short-term rest centre and never
opened again.
They say that truth is the first
casualty of war but it isn't, you
know.
Education is.
You take classes here.
I do what I can. I was teaching when
the war began.
20,000 teachers went into the
forces.
I sometimes think it won't matter
who wins.
Either way we'll have a whole
generation who won't know a thing.
You WERE at the game.
I remember you now.
Have you come to arrest me for
taking part?
No, that's not why I'm here.
Then how can I help you?
I'm looking for two lads that were
at the game.
You might have noticed them. They
were about 18.
Plenty of cash.
I noticed them.
They were hard to miss. They were
losing more than I did.
Their names are Frank and Terry. Do
you know anything more about them?
I don't know their surnames.
I find these dice games aren't
exactly sociable.
True. Do you know
where I might find them?
Would you like to tell me why?
You expecting visitors?
No. Lessons are over for the day.
So, Frank and Terry...
Well, I don't know where they live.
I don't know anything much about
them. They were young.
They have money. I'd seen them a few
times. That's it.
Mr Richards, can I give you some
advice?
Stay away from any further games.
Oh? And why is that?
Well, I've just seen two of Hendry's
men outside.
And, as you say, I can't imagine
they were here to be sociable.
If you owe them money, they will
make you pay, one way or another.
Good night.
Good night, sir.
Ooh, I wonder if you'd noticed that
The Wizard of Oz is playing at the
Palais, sir?
I can't say I have.
I was just thinking...
Right. Thank you.
Lydia?
Where's your mother?
Come on.
A single shot. I heard it clear as
day. It came from the inside.
And this is on the Melton Road?
Yeah, that place there.
It used to be a supply dump or
something.
I think it's an office now.
And what time was this, sir?
Only half an hour ago. I came
straight here.
Well, thank you, sir. I'll make a
report.
Is that all?
Well, I haven't got any men here.
I shouldn't be here except the night
officer is off sick.
Well, you can't have people shooting
each other in the middle of the
night. It's not right.
No, sir. Erm, where can we find you
if we need to ask any more
questions?
I have a shop on the parade. You'll
see my name.
Thank you, Mr Woodridge.
We'll look into it.
No, Frank.
Terry!
I said no.
Why not?
Cutting wires and setting fire to
stuff is one thing.
This is different. This is a bomb!
I know what it is.
Tell him we've had enough.
Look I can't. He'll turn us in.
Then let him. He's a bloody dago,
for God's sake.
What we're doing, it could be
treason.
He's Spanish. They're not in the war.
They're nothing to do with it.
No.
Look, if we don't do what he says,
he'll come after us.
He's got friends. They'll find us.
They'll kill us, Terry.
It's not that. You don't believe
that. You just want the money.
Listen.
We'll make this the last one.
We'll just do this and then we'll
tell him we've got to stop.
Get down.
What is it?
Sh!
Wait. What are they doing?
Come on, Terry. We'll follow them.
Sam.
Sir.
Would you mind coming in a moment,
please?
Look, erm, she's gone.
Gone, sir?
Yes.
Lydia?
With James?
No, he's upstairs.
Well, that's rather strange.
Do you think she's in trouble?
Possible.
Always was a bit wayward. Fell in
love with an insurance salesman and
they eloped.
And the parents are dead now.
Did they ever forgive her?
Well, not a case of forgiveness.
For some reason or another, they
never saw her again and neither did I
until she showed up here.
Where's James's father? North
Africa, evidently, according to her.
He doesn't talk very much, does he?
Well, not least because he was at
the Sibford Street School.
The school that was...
Oh, poor little boy.
Sir, if you want me to look after
him while you're looking for Lydia,
I'm more than happy to. Thank you.
It'll make a nice change from
hanging around outside murders.
Listen, erm, get him some...
tea, cake. That sort of thing.
There's a toy shop on the parade.
Good, good.
Oh, I wonder
if he's seen The Wizard of Oz.
Sergeant Milner, I wonder if you'd
like to look into this?
A shot was heard on the Melton Road.
An elderly gentleman came in last
night.
Where's Mr Foyle?
He's er... He's not in yet.
It's the second time he's been late
this week.
I wouldn't have said that was any of
your business, Sergeant.
I was just making an observation,
Sergeant.
Morning. Someone heard a gunshot
last night, I thought I'd look into
it. Do.
I need to get a search organised for
a 28-year-old woman name of Lydia
Nicholson
or she might be using Lydia Wallace.
What's she done, sir?
Nothing apart from going missing.
She's from Clapton.
Ah, that's my old stamping ground.
She could well have gone back there.
Get a description put in the coach
and railway stations
using this photograph.
She's very attractive.
Yeah.
A gun shot? What time would this
have been?
About nine o'clock.
I can't help you, I'm afraid. I left
at six. Hans?
Ten minutes after you, Professor.
And you are...?
Oh, Hans Lindemann.
And in case you're wondering, I'm
Danish.
Hans was studying under me at
Cambridge when the Germans invaded
Denmark. And I decided to stay.
And were there just the two of you
here last night?
No, I have a secretarial assistant.
Evelyn Richards.
You've just missed her, I'm afraid.
I sent her home.
What sort of work do you do here,
Professor?
We're a branch of the National
Physical Laboratory at Teddington.
We report to the Admiralty in
London.
I can't tell you any more,
I'm afraid.
Our work is classified.
All right.
And yet you have no security.
No Home Guard.
Oh, we keep a low profile, Mr
Milner.
Nobody really knows we're here. So
that's all the security we need.
And there was no sign of any
disturbance this morning when you
arrived?
No, absolutely not.
Everything was as normal.
Look, I know nothing about this
gunshot but I can assure you it
didn't happen here.
Maybe somewhere nearby.
Thank you, we'll have a look.
Ooh, can I just ask, Mr Milner, who
is your superior officer?
Of course. It's Detective Chief
Superintendent Foyle.
Ah, yes, I thought it might be.
I know him well. Please give him my
regards.
Right, let's take a look around.
Search the woods and the side of the
road. Two of you have a look round
the back of the building.
What's that? Over there!
Get Sergeant Milner.
I'll drop this explosive egg on
Hitler's palace.
That night over Germany...
(GERMAN ACCENT) Look, Goering.
I'm sick of this. Half a sausage
between us?
My patience is exhausted.
Bring me an egg!
Now where shall I put it?
Ha, I'll take that fine big egg for
Adolf's breakfast.
Ach, what a fine big egg, at last I
will have the good breakfast.
You're not
really enjoying this, are you?
How about a puzzle?
I've an old blackout book here.
We could try that.
Do we know who he is?
He had no wallet on him.
No identity card, no ration book,
but as a matter of fact I do, sir.
I spoke to him yesterday...
at his house.
His name is Michael Richards.
He was at the dice game.
He lost a fair amount of money.
He may well be in debt because two
of Hendry's men paid him a visit
while I was there.
They saw me and walked off.
It looks like I might have to go
after Hendry after all.
There's a Professor Townsend here at
the Research Centre.
Says he knows you.
Townsend. Mm, that's right.
He also said that he has a
secretarial assistant called
Richards.
Did he?
Well, if he was shot because he owed
money, why here do you think?
Dressed up for something.
A lot smarter than the last time I
saw him.
Foyle, I can't believe we're meeting
under such circumstances.
That's right.
Michael Richards.
This man with the dog,
he must have been mistaken.
Mr Richards may have been killed
nearby
but it certainly wasn't in here.
Right. And who would have been first
here this morning?
I was. I came at seven o'clock.
Oh, right.
You come far?
Mm. Bexhill. I have a room there.
Uh-huh.
Everything was just the way you see
it now.
Right.
Somebody should talk to Evelyn.
She - she needs to be told.
And how long has she been here?
Two years.
An invaluable member of staff.
Very efficient, I mean.
Accurate.
Discreet.
How do you know Professor Townsend,
sir? He's a neighbour.
He said he was attached to the
Admiralty. Involved in something
hush-hush.
It wouldn't surprise me. He taught
physics at Cambridge.
Highly regarded.
Published several books.
I wonder why he was lying to us.
Same reason everybody else does.
I don't know where to begin.
There's not much to tell.
I, I went to bed early.
I was so tired. I've been working
very hard recently.
Michael wasn't in the house
when I got in.
I thought I heard him come in later
but obviously I was wrong.
We sleep in separate rooms.
I might as well be straight with
you.
Things haven't been very easy
between us for some time.
Michael resented my going to work.
He lost his own job when they closed
St Edmund's.
He gave lessons here, didn't he?
Yes, a home school.
Townsend. Is this yours?
No, it's my husband's.
I just type and keep files.
Michael understood more about
Professor Townsend's work than I
ever did.
It was the main reason for the
tension between us.
I was there - and he was here.
So would this be...?
This is his desk.
I can't see why you're asking all
these questions, Mr Foyle.
I know perfectly well who killed my
husband.
He was a compulsive gambler.
He had fallen in with a bad lot
and he owed them money.
He used to steal from the
housekeeping and from my purse.
I know he was afraid of them.
And, erm, why would he have gone to
the research centre last night?
I've no idea.
But you didn't, erm, you didn't part
on very good terms?
No. I suppose I'll have to live with
that.
But he wasn't the man I married.
This was the man I married.
He was young.
An idealist.
He loved his work and he had a
career.
But the war changed all that...
..and the man who was killed,
the man you're telling me about,
in the end I hardly knew him.
All right, then. Here's another one.
It's called A New Deal for Nazis
and what you have to do
is put four cards to form a swastika
inside the frame.
I don't think that's possible,
do you?
Oh, hello, sir.
How's everything?
All present and correct.
I haven't made much progress, I'm
afraid.
I don't suppose there's any news
of...
No. Erm, you'd better get home.
Right.
I thought I'd take James out for a
picnic in Taybury Woods tomorrow.
I baked a cake. Powdered eggs.
That's very kind.
All right, then, James. I'll see you
tomorrow. TTFN.
Thank you.
Michael Richards?
I remember who he is now.
I knew I'd seen him before.
Who is he?
He was that geezer from the game.
Kept on losing.
You were the one who kept on losing.
He couldn't afford it. That's who he
is.
That's who he WAS.
Yeah, I'd say there's money to be
made out of this, Terry,
if we're smart.
What are you talking about?
Well, we saw what we saw, didn't we
in the woods? Yeah.
Well, I reckon they'd pay us plenty
to keep our mouths shut.
So what about the dago?
He's never here. He's in London.
We'll make the money and vamoose.
He'll never find us.
Yeah, and what about this?
We'll get rid of it.
How? Dump it in the sea?
I'm not going in no boat with it.
Rough seas and all the rest.
No. We'll blow it up.
Where?
Taybury Wood. Tomorrow.
And then we'll go and see the boffin
and see what he has to say.
LYDIA: God, I've tried so hard.
It's all gone wrong, hasn't it?
But I'm going to make it better for
you. That's all that matters.
And one day you'll understand.
Four cards?
That's right.
Inside the frame to form a swastika.
Can they overlap? I don't know,
Brookie. It doesn't say.
It doesn't seem do-able to me.
Where did this come from?
The Brighter Blackout Book.
Let's have a look.
No. I don't see it.
Neither do I. I was up all night
thinking about it. Hardly got a wink
of sleep.
Aren't the answers in the back? They
should be but it's missing a page.
Morning.
Morning, sir.
What's going on?
It's a puzzle.
Miss Stewart was just showing it to
me, sir.
Solved it?
We're working on it.
Mm-hm.
Can I go, sir?
Yep, here he is.
Ready?
Now, young man. I hope you like very
slightly burned walnut cake!
Have a good time.
Any news?
Er, nothing so far, sir.
I had her description circulated at
the coach and the train station.
I've been onto the Home Guard.
Er, we did manage to find an address
for her in Clapton
but there's no-one there.
Keep trying.
Sir.
Morning, sir. Good news.
What's that?
Had a tip-off about a dice game
being played at Hythe.
I don't know if it's Hendry but it's
the same game. When?
Lunch time. Are you going to take
anybody with you this time?
Er, yes, sir.
What a good idea.
LYDIA: Dear Uncle Christopher,
everything has been so difficult for
me for so long
and I've often wondered how I can
carry on.
Please forgive me writing to you
like this but I can't take James
with me
so I have decided to leave him with
the one person I can trust,
someone who has always been kind to
me and who will understand what it
is that I have to do.
Goal!
Are you really a 'tec?
Yes, I am.
Can I see your warrant card?
Hm.
How did you find me here?
Your mother told me where you were.
Oh. I thought it would be something
more clever than that.
Oh, sorry to disappoint you.
Are you investigating Mr Richards?
Yes, that's right.
He was shot by gangsters.
Everyone knows that.
You were having a lesson with him,
weren't you, when I came to see him?
Yes. Geometry.
So, how was he?
Mr Richards?
Mm. Was he nervous?
No.
He was usually grumpy but he was all
right.
He had a phone call.
During the lesson?
Yes. It cheered him up.
He was tickety-boo after that.
Right.
Maybe it was the killers.
They tricked him into going to a
meeting and then they done him in.
You've been reading too much Sexton
Blake. I prefer Just William.
Do you play here a lot?
Most days.
We found a piece of shrapnel once.
I hope the war never ends!
Come on. Yep!
This search. You better start
checking the local hospitals,
call the coastguard. See if they
found anybody over the -
You don't think she...
It's worth checking.
Sir.
Thank you.
I feel rather awkward coming to you,
but I felt I should.
Why's that?
It's Michael Richards.
Oh, yeah.
It's just that what's happened
couldn't have come at a worse time
as far as we're concerned.
Well, probably not a very good one
for him either, I wouldn't have
thought.
No, of course not.
It's just that there are things
happening that I can't explain to
you.
I'm not allowed to.
But erm...as you and I have met on
several occasions, I...
I thought you might understand...
Understand what?
Well, that my team and I are on the
brink of something momentous.
I'm not exaggerating when I say that
it could change the course of the
war.
The team being?
Myself and Hans Lindemann, I mean.
Mrs Richards?
She's part of it, yes.
So, you're saying what?
Well, a lot of awkward questions
are the last thing that we need just
now.
Michael Richards was an alcoholic.
He was a violent, unattractive man.
Unintelligent?
Yes.
A great reader of your books,
evidently, according to her.
Look, I've come to tell you that his
death,
in the proximity of where I am
working,
well, it cannot be allowed to get in
the way of what's happening.
Well, it looks as if it already has,
you know.
Do you see anything you like, James?
Shall we go inside?
How about a model plane?
I could sell you a kit for four
shillings
or a made-up one for eight shillings
and ninepence.
We were looking for something less
about the war.
That's not easy, these days.
Er, how about a jigsaw?
Oh, that might be fun.
I have a jigsaw here and it has 200
pieces.
RAF Reconnaissance Planes Beat off
German Fighters.
Well, that's still a bit war-like.
Well, er, what have you in mind?
Have you anything soft and cuddly,
like a teddy bear?
Oh, you won't find any teddy bears
here.
I heard that there were some in
Harrods in London
at ten shillings a time but they'll
have gone long ago.
If you don't mind my saying so, for
a toy shop you don't have many toys.
Well, that's not my fault. All the
toy factories have closed down -
or switched over to war production.
You, as a mother, should know that.
Oh, I'm not his mother. I just don't
want anything to do with the war.
Have you any board games?
Yes, we have board games.
Let's see.
Submarine Hunt, Sky Battle
and Ocean War.
All at two bob.
James?
What's the matter?
What's going on here?
You're Mr Townsend.
I'm Professor Townsend, yes.
Who are you?
I'm Frank.
This is my brother Terry.
What are you doing here?
Well, it just so happens we were
passing the other night, Professor.
And we saw things, didn't we, Terry?
Yeah, that's right.
Seems to me we could have a pretty
story to tell if we went to the
police.
You wouldn't like that, would you?
What do you want?
50 quid. We need to leave Hastings.
We're gonna need living expenses.
50 pounds? I don't have that sort of
money!
Each.
This is madness.
Professor, this is more important.
Say nothing, Hans. Young man, you
are wasting your time.
We're not going to pay you anything.
I think you are.
I'll tell you what, I'll give you
24 hours to think about it.
Talk it over with your friends.
Now there's a lucky throw for you.
I'm paying out on three crowns.
Wish you'd bet more now, don't you?
Who says the odds are with the
house?
I'm paying out more than you lot
earn in a week.
Grab the doors!
Go for it! Scarper!
Go on, get outta here!
No, you don't. No, you don't.
I've got him!
Hold him over there! Hold him!
Nice to see you again, Mr Hendry.
You're talking nonsense, Mr Milner.
I mean, what do you take me for?
I know what you are, Mr Hendry.
Listen to me.
He owed us 35 bob.
Now do I look like someone who's
gonna put a bullet in someone's head
for 35 bob?
I saw your men outside his house.
They saw you too.
They were there to put the wind up
him, that's all.
For 35 bob?
I can't have people welching on me.
It's bad for business.
Word gets around. Five bob, 35 bob.
If you don't pay up, you're going to
get slapped around a bit. I mean,
I got a reputation.
So, you're admitting to conspiracy
to cause actual bodily harm?
I'm admitting to thinking about it
but thinking ain't a crime, is it?
No, but illegal gaming is.
So?
And you attacked an officer in the
course of his duty
so if I offered you evens on a £500
fine and a year in jail... A year?
What do you think?
I think that's a safe bet, sir.
Yeah, I'd say so.
Over here!
I know. I know.
It's not right.
No! You have to use four cards
inside the square.
A swastika.
Only four? Yes.
It can't be done.
I know. It beats the hell out of me.
Hastings Constabulary.
Sergeant Brooke. Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Yeah, I will.
Put those away. I've got to speak to
Mr Foyle.
When they brought her here, they
thought she was going to die.
The doctor says she's come through
the worst.
They said she walked into the sea
with her pockets full of stones.
A mortal sin.
I can't imagine what drove her to
it.
And attempted suicide, I believe, is
a crime.
Is that why you're here?
No, I'm her godfather
and she has a son.
That makes her sin even harder to
forgive.
Where is her child?
He's being looked after.
Come back tomorrow.
She'll be able to speak to you then.
I will, thank you.
James, a picnic in the wood might be
more fun if you would actually talk
to me.
Let's see if we can find somewhere
nice to sit.
Why are you so down in the dumps?
We're out of our depth, Frank.
We should just chuck it.
What and risk someone getting hurt?
Don't tell me you're scared of loud
noises?
I'm scared of getting into more
trouble.
We're getting out of trouble.
That's what all this is about.
When I was your age, my father made
me learn the name of every tree in
the wood.
That's a beech...
Or is it a chestnut?
This over here, this one is an ash.
Over here.
Let's get out of here.
There's someone coming.
What?
These definitely are beeches.
You can tell by the nuts, look.
You've got to warn them.
No, it's too late.
Watch out, there's -
Frank.
Run, Terry.
I have to say, it was the last thing
I was expecting.
Do you realise it's the third time
I've been blown up?
I can't say I was counting.
First of all, there was the pub
and then Jerry dropped a bomb on my
house.
Now this! I was only going for a
walk in the woods.
It seems nowhere's safe these days.
And you saw what?
Two youths.
They were both about 18, I'd say.
One was tall, had dark hair
and HIS name was Terry.
I heard the other one call out to
him.
The other wasn't called Frank by any
chance?
Do you know, I think that might have
been his name.
How did you know?
They're the same men who helped
Milner when he got into trouble the
other night.
That's nice of them (!) Rescue
Milner and then try to kill me.
I wish they'd get their priorities
sorted out.
Are you going to be all right?
Absolutely. I feel tip-top.
Thank you for the whisky.
Pleasure. Where is he?
He's upstairs.
I think you'll find he's completely
changed.
In a way, it's a sort of a miracle.
When the bomb went off, he started
calling for a Mrs Jukes.
Mary Jukes was a teacher who was
killed.
In a way, it sort of unlocked
everything.
Did you find his mother?
I did.
Where?
She's somewhere safe.
Good. All right then, sir.
I'll see you tomorrow and good luck
with James.
Thank you.
I mean...Jimmy.
Ah.
I don't like it here.
Where's my mum? I want to go home!
Well, at least we're finally talking.
What have you done with my mum?
I haven't done anything with your
mum, James. Jimmy!
Everyone calls me Jimmy except her.
Jimmy. She's not very well, I'm
afraid and we're still trying to get
in touch with your father.
I haven't got a father. He's dead!
Not according to your mother.
She's lying. She always lies.
Right...
It looks as if we're going to have to
spend a couple more days together at
least.
Why? I don't like you.
You're a copper.
Yeah, that's right.
Have you ever been to prison?
Their names. I don't know any names.
They're punters.
Mr Hendry, this is now a murder
investigation and I saw your men,
acting under your orders, at the
victim's house just hours before he
was killed.
That had nothing to do with me. You
can't pin that on me.
Frank and Terry Morgan. They're
fishermen.
They've got one of those huts down
the beach. Brothers.
Look...
I'm co-operating with you.
Maybe you can do something for me.
No dice.
How old are you?
I'm 18.
I'm 16.
Where are your parents? You on your
own? Yeah.
Dad's away. Convoy duty.
Mother?
She died.
Well, it seems as if you've got
yourselves in an awful lot of
trouble.
We haven't done nothing.
Haven't you?
How do you account for the money
you've been chucking about at dice
games?
How d'you get your hands on
explosives device which nearly killed
a young woman and child?
What about the murder you're involved
with?
What?
We found this in your hut on the
beach.
It belonged to Michael Richards. You
knew him from the card game.
This is his identity card.
His ration book.
He was shot two nights ago.
What do you know about that?
Look, we looked out for him,
for your oppo, didn't we?
What?
This is what we get in return?
No, I'm very grateful. Which is why
we will do what we can for you but
you've got to tell us the truth.
We can't tell you.
Frank!
Terry, just shut up! No. I've had
enough of it. Frank, please.
I don't even know where to start.
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting,
Mr Foyle.
Can I offer you some refreshment?
A small sherry, perhaps?
We won't, thank you.
Then how can I help you?
You are...
Jose Oliviera de Perez.
Is your sergeant going to write it
down?
I will be very happy to spell it for
you.
No, thank you.
I am a Special Observer for the
Spanish Institute of Political
Studies.
I am attached to the Spanish embassy
but I find it expedient to keep a
house down here by the coast also.
Expedient in that it allows you to
sabotage coastal installations?
That is a very grave accusation, Mr
Foyle.
I wonder what evidence you might
have to support it.
We've arrested two delinquents.
Frank and Terry Morgan.
According to their testimony,
they broke into this house five
weeks ago on the 17th March.
How interesting. I was unaware of
any break-ins.
They claim you discovered them and
that you effectively coerced them
into undertaking several acts of
sabotage on your behalf.
These include a fire at Hythe docks,
a munitions work just outside
Bexhill,
the cutting of telephone wires in
various locations and most recently,
a plan to blow up a research centre
here in Hastings.
And this is your evidence?
The word of, how did you put it, two
delinquents?
They can describe you and this
house.
So can my cleaner. So can many other
people, I am sure.
So, you're denying the charges, sir?
I am neither denying them nor
confirming them, Sergeant Milner.
I think you perhaps failed to hear
when we first spoke.
I am attached to the Spanish embassy
and, as such, I come under their
protection.
I am not required to answer any of
your questions
and, more to the point, this house
is also theirs.
I am sorry to tell you this,
gentlemen, but in effect,
you are on Spanish soil.
Your law does not extend here.
In which instance, therefore, I will
wish you both a very good day,
gentlemen.
Thank you for your time. I only wish
I had more of it to share with you.
I'm sure you will next time.
We will see.
I was going to come back and see you
again, Foyle.
Before or after the Morgans tried to
blackmail you?
I was never very happy about our
attempts to lie about what happened
here
but I persuaded myself that it was
in the national interest.
But there was no crime.
A man was killed.
It was self-defence. More than that.
He was threatening to destroy our
work.
Please just tell me what happened.
I was working late.
There had been a test the previous
evening.
I can't give you any of the details
but I had to type up the results.
Michael wasn't happy about it.
I already told you
he resented my being here -
and that night he decided...I don't
know why.
He'd been drinking.
He came round.
I was astonished to see him
but there was nothing I could do.
Evelyn?
I told him to leave and we argued.
We'd argued before, often, but...
this was different.
He became angry, then violent...
He was always like that.
He was a brute.
He didn't try to hurt me this time.
It was the machine.
It was our work.
I, er, I can't tell you what it
does.
But er, it's taken us months to get
it right.
He tried to destroy it.
I think he was mad.
I'd never seen him like it before.
He picked up a spanner and that's
when I did it.
I knew I had no choice.
Come on.
I shot him to protect our work.
I didn't mean to kill him. I just
wanted to stop him.
You did the right thing.
No. I never hated him.
Despite everything, I...
I never meant to hurt him.
I see.
Where did you get the gun?
It's mine.
I kept it here because...
Well, all these instances of
sabotage.
Bexhill. Hythe.
I thought it might be sensible to
have it on hand, to protect
ourselves if needs be.
And what happened afterwards?
I didn't know what to do.
I telephoned Professor Townsend.
I thought he'd know what to do
and he had to know what had
happened.
He said he'd come straight round.
I didn't even know if he was dead.
I tried to find a pulse...
It was horrible and I was so scared.
And then what?
Well, then I telephoned Lindemann.
I couldn't stand being on my own.
Mrs Richards was very upset
when I arrived.
Lindemann was comforting her but she
was beside herself.
And so what? Then, you decided to,
erm, carry the body out into the
woods
and pretend somebody else had done
it?
What difference did it make?
He had no rights to come here
and, Evelyn, Mrs Richards, she did
the right thing to stop him.
It's all right, Hans. I...
I take full responsibility for the
decision, Foyle.
But I...
I have to say that what was foremost
in our minds was our work here.
If you knew what, what we're doing,
if I could only tell you, I'm...
I'm sure you'd understand.
Are we still pretending that Mrs
Richards here is just a secretary?
The books in your house are yours
not your husband's.
Your desk. Not his. Am I right?
How did you know?
Well, it's just odd for him to keep
a photograph of himself on his desk.
More likely to be one of you,
I'd have thought.
Mrs Richards is erm...
is much more than a secretary.
She, er...
she has an astonishing mind.
I mean this is her work.
The Admiralty are completely
blinkered.
I mean, they wouldn't think of
having a woman involved at this
level.
And so we've...we've always had to
keep up with the pretence.
Well, I'm sorry to have to tell you
that, erm, astonishing or not, er,
there are still one or two questions
for Mrs Richards here so erm...
I'm afraid I'm going to have to ask
you to come with us, Mrs Richards.
Ah, you can't do that! Please. I
thought I'd explained to you.
This work that we're part of...
Will have to wait, I'm afraid.
It can't.
Er, Professor...
It's all right, Hans.
Foyle. Well, that didn't take long.
Afternoon, sir.
This is Captain Boothroyd
from the Admiralty.
I see. Afternoon.
You're holding a Mrs Evelyn Richards
here. Is that right? It is.
I want you to release her
immediately.
Shall we...
talk about this in my office?
Released on whose authority? It's all
right, Assistant Commissioner.
I can assure you this comes right
from the top.
I've been acquainted with all the
facts at the highest level.
The Admiralty has also given me
access to further, restricted
information.
Well, that's kind of them.
It means that I do have the full
picture here.
Mrs Richards was defending the work
of her colleagues against a man who
was drunk and demented.
She has no case to answer.
I'm not asking you to close the
book on this one, Foyle. No need for
that.
At the same time, I see no reason
why Mrs Richards shouldn't remain at
liberty, and at work,
while you tie up the loose ends.
Well, just two problems with that, as
far as I can see. What are they?
Firstly, we'd have to accept she's
telling the truth. She confessed.
I don't see what possible
explanation there could be.
Well, I can think of one or two.
And we'd also have to accept that,
police procedure, British law,
British justice are irrelevant
if any old uniform can turn up here
and decide who can or can't be
detained.
Look, I'm the one making the
decisions here, Mr Foyle.
You can continue your investigation,
if you must,
but I see no reason to keep Mrs
Richards behind bars.
Did they let you go?
Yes.
Then we did it.
We got away with it.
So, this is young James, is it?
Jimmy.
We can look after him for a few
days.
That's a relief. You will find him a
little erm...lively?
Affliction is good for the soul.
Lydia wants to see you now.
Thank you. See you soon.
This way, Jimmy.
Why are you dressed like that?
It's my habit.
You look stupid.
Not as stupid as you'll look when
you're feeling the back of my hand.
I've been so unhappy
and I didn't know what to do.
And after what happened with
James...
well, I felt so useless,
I just couldn't cope any more.
You should have said something.
It was too late.
You should have said something ten
years ago.
I did get that letter you sent me.
You were very kind.
But after what happened with Robert,
I couldn't go back home.
My parents didn't want to see me.
They did.
They'd have taken you back in an
instant. They didn't want to see you
go in the first place.
Are you saying it was my fault?
You never gave them a chance to
accept what had happened.
Go on.
Well, erm...
None of my business.
All too long ago...
but it did seem to me that...
you wanted to be hurt.
They tried to get in touch with you
several times.
You never replied. You never replied
to me.
I was in love.
Is that an excuse?
No, but it explains it
and now it's too late.
You might as well know,
I'm not an OWL operator.
I'm not doing anything for the war
effort.
I have a couple of rooms in Clapton
and I...
earn a living charring and taking in
laundry.
What do you think my parents would
say to that?
The truth is that...
Robert left a few months after James
was born.
I don't... He's not in Africa. I
don't know where he is.
He just shoved off and disappeared.
I have a little money.
What am I to do?
You should, er, stay a little longer.
The sisters have been very kind but
I'm not sure they'd let me...
No, I mean with me,
both of you, for the time being.
Are you sure?
No...
but somebody's got to look after you.
What about your work?
Well, I've got a feeling there's
going to be...less of it from now on.
I'll be back.
Your desk sergeant told me I would
find you here.
I wondered if we could talk.
I feel terrible
about all this business.
I've known you...
I don't know how many years.
And lying to the police!
It's not something I would normally
contemplate.
But you erm...you must understand
what I've been trying to tell you.
My work is classified.
Now I've spoken
with Captain Boothroyd
and he has sought clearance at the
highest level
to enable me to tell you what we've
been working on.
I... I feel I owe it to you.
Too kind.
Very soon, the RAF are going to bomb
a series of dams
in Germany's industrial heartland,
the Ruhr Valley.
Now, if we can knock those dams out,
we will do vast damage to their war
machine.
Factories, power stations, roads,
bridges, farmland.
We'll put them all under hundreds of
millions of gallons of water.
But it's going to need a...
It's going to take
a very special bomb.
A bomb that bounces along
the surface of the water.
Now nothing like this has ever been
attempted before.
The bomb has to be sent spinning
before it's released
and my team have helped to develop a
machine that does precisely that...
..and that was the machine that
Michael Richards would
have destroyed
if Evelyn hadn't stopped him.
And that's why...you protected her?
Well, she was protecting us.
And that's worth...
perverting the course of justice?
I thought so.
Poor decision, Professor,
because, apart from betraying our
friendship,
you've also made yourself an
accessory to premeditated murder.
Evelyn Richards said that she acted
in self-defence.
She lied.
She lied to you and to us.
Lied? Lied about what?
Well, amongst other things...
about what happened.
I didn't know what to do. I
telephoned Professor Townsend.
I thought he'd know what to do and
he had to know what had happened.
He said he'd come straight round.
Then I telephoned Lindemann.
I couldn't stand being on my own.
You live er...less than a mile away
from the research centre.
Yes. Lindemann's rooms are eight
miles away in Bexhill.
Yes, they are.
If she called you first...
how come he was already there when
you arrived?
She...
she must have made a mistake.
If you say so.
Well, I don't get it.
Join the club.
I even got that chap Hendry to have
a go at it.
Well, him being a gambler an' all.
Are you sure you got it right?
Absolutely. It's in the book.
Ready?
Yes, sir.
Still at it.
It's beaten everyone, sir.
Why don't you have a go?
No. It's not quite my sort of thing.
Oh, go on, sir. Help us out. It's
very simple. Is it?
At least, it should be. What you
have to do is make a swastika inside
the frame...using four cards.
Mm. Has anybody got close?
Nowhere near. It's called A New Deal
For The Nazis.
Well, you know,
sometimes it helps to erm...
look behind the cards, maybe.
What do you mean, sir?
Well, I was just thinking about
shapes. You know, but...
No, frankly I don't see it.
If it's foxed you, what hope is
there for the rest of us?
That's enough from you. Come on, this
is getting us nowhere. We're going to
be late. Milner.
Yes, sir. Good luck.
Behind the cards.
Oh!
There it is!
I've got it, I've got it.
I've done it!
Right, this won't take long.
Back soon.
Crafty old fox.
Morning. I've finished my
investigation of the south coast. I
have to get back to London.
I've absolutely no intention of
keeping you.
Well. I'm primarily here to find out
about the De Perez situation.
I'm afraid I can't help you.
He is attached to the embassy,
as he told you,
and, as such, he's beyond our reach.
Spain declared their neutrality back
in September '39.
However, many of their diplomats,
the consular service, the police
and the coast guard
work for the Germans.
I got this from a friend in
Whitehall.
He suggested we pass on what we know
about De Perez to the security
services.
And what will they do?
I doubt they'll do anything.
They know who he is and what he is.
Doubtless they have their own
reasons for keeping him at large.
And so he goes free.
That's marvellous. They all go free.
Who do you mean?
Well, him, Evelyn Richards,
Lindemann. Lindemann?
Lindemann. You're not saying he was
involved, are you?
I am.
What on earth are you suggesting?
On the day he dies,
how does Michael Richards, sir,
in such an extremely good mood as a
result of taking a phone call,
come to be so very angry and violent
so very shortly afterwards?
If he goes to the research centre
with the intention of doing as much
damage as possible,
why does he need his best suit and a
bunch of flowers to do it?
How does a woman with no experience
of firearms
manage to shoot her drunk, violent
husband
so very precisely between the eyes in
such a very premeditated fashion?
I'm suggesting that she made the call
to her husband,
inviting him to the centre with the
prospect of an improvement in their
relationship
where he was shot by Lindemann.
And why would they do this?
Because they're having an affair...
..for which we do have proof.
It's not enough.
Right.
Well, it certainly is for me.
Foyle...
No, with this sort of thing, erm...
virtually condoned for the sake of
the war effort,
a man guilty of coercion and sabotage
can't be touched, while two boys,
guilty of nothing more than slipping
off the rails because of a lack of
parental control,
will get several years with hard
labour.
Assistant Commissioners doing their
very best to undermine me
in front of my staff,
yeah, I'd say I'd had enough.
Look. I know you and I got off to a
bad start, Foyle.
It was my fault
and I apologise for it.
But it's not too late. We can have
another look at Mrs Richards
and I'll tell you what...
You know a young woman.
Lydia Nicholson.
Mmmm. I have here a report concerning
an attempted suicide.
A recommendation to prosecute.
You see?
Justice can sometimes be manipulated
to help the individual.
Well...
Your justice, perhaps. Not mine.
Look. You can't do this...
Damn it.
FOYLE: 'Assistant Commissioner
Parkins,
I have suggested to you that
maintaining the law in a time of war
is all but impossible.
I have now reached the conclusion
that I am no longer up to the task
and it would seem, therefore, that
there can be no useful purpose in me
remaining in my position.'
'I am, therefore, offering you my
resignation, effective as of now.
I remain, sir, your obedient servant,
Christopher Foyle.'
transcript:chocolate
sync:innuit
www.tvsubtitles.net