(PLAINTIVE MUSIC)
Ripped By mstoll
YOUNG MAN:
What did I know about war?
I was 17 years old.
I joined up for the same reason
as everyone else -
for the King
and the Empire.
To do my bit.
They said it'd be
an adventure.
It was the right thing to do.
My brother Bevan and I
signed up to fight Germans.
But here I was
in a little boat
about to invade a country
I'd never heard of.
And now, at dawn
on that first day,
the King, the Empire,
and doing the right thing
seemed a long way off.
(OBJECT ZIPS PAST RAPIDLY NEARBY)
-(SOFT MURMURING)
-(BOAT CREAKS)
Hail Mary, full of Grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God...
- Come on, put a sock in it.
-..pray for us sinners...
...now and at the hour
of our death.
Ugh! (GROANS)
(COUGHS AND GRUNTS)
Steady. Steady.
That's against orders.
They said bayonets only.
Shut up, Tolly.
Now! Forward!
Come on, son, get up!
Come on, you men!
Quickly! This way!
Get off the boat now!
- Go! Go! Go! Follow me!
-Advance with me!
- Advance with me, men!
-Arggh!
C'mon, men!
Keep moving!
Drop your packs, men.
Fix bayonets.
- Move forward!
-(GUNFIRE)
- Get down!
-Where's the 'gentle' slope?
- Get down.
-Drop your packs!
Men, fix bayonets!
- Fix bayonets!
-Fix bayonets!
Alright.
Follow me!
Move behind me!
- Fuck.
-Keep going! Come on!
- Come on.
-Tolly!
What are you doing, Tolly?
Stay with us!
He's dead, Tolly.
We have to leave him. Leave him!
- Onwards!
-With me!
Get to that line
and keep going.
-(GRUNTS AND PANTS)
-Put your bayonet on.
(GUNFIRE)
- You right?
-Yeah, mate.
- Follow me.
-Advance with me, chaps.
Come on, men!
TOLLY: We were told
to move inland
and march on Constantinople.
-(MAN SHOUTS IN TURKISH)
-Yes!
TOLLY: There was no slaughter
on the beach,
just scattered Turkish sentries
firing down on us.
Come on, men!
All you men, keep coming.
Let's go up through here.
- Sergeant?
- It's going well, Captain Taylor.
At least we're moving forward.
That high ground up there -
that's the objective.
Right, sir. Keep moving forward.
Let's go. Come on.
- Move, move, move!
-Come on, son, get up.
- Get up. Son, get up!
-Come on, men, with me!
- Come on, men!
-Get up!
- Come on, lads!
-(BOMB BLASTS DISTANTLY)
TOLLY: It was in the hills,
beyond the beach,
where it all began.
This was bastard country.
Not the sort of place an army
would invade on purpose.
But what did I know?
Come on, men!
Come on, let's pick it up!
Pick it up, men!
Follow me, men!
(GUNSHOT)
(FIRES RIFLE)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(PANTS)
- Ahh!
- Ugh!
-(PANTS)
-(GROANS)
(SCREAMS AND GRUNTS)
(BOTH SCREAM AND GRUNT)
Ahh!
(GROANS)
Allah...
(PRAYS TO ALLAH)
(PANTS ANXIOUSLY)
-(SCREAMS)
-Ahh!
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
-Advance with me!
Advance with me!
(MAN SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
MAN: Number eight platoon,
deploy at 50 yards!
(THEME MUSIC)
(BELL CLANGS)
(DISTANT BOMBING)
MAN: General Hamilton?
- Braith.
-Sir.
The Australians have landed
and they're on the move.
Excellent.
We'll be able to see
what they're capable of.
The first blow
is half the battle, Braithwaite.
Don't forget that.
They're waiting for you inside,
General.
History, Braith.
We're about to write it.
The Greeks and Trojans
will be here forever
and now it's our turn.
Yes, sir.
- Ugh!
-(GUNFIRE)
(MAN SHOUTS)
(GRUNTS)
Cliffy, flank them
from that direction!
Guys, hold your fire!
- Come on!
-(GRUNTS)
Ugh!
Get back! Come on! Come on!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
- Move!
-(SHOUTS)
(MEN SHOUT)
(SHOUTS IN TURKISH)
Jesus, Cliffy.
- Come on, Cliffy!
-Advance in fours and cross the line!
Go! Go! Go! Come on!
(PANTS)
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
-Advance!
Pick it up, men.
-(GUNFIRE)
-Come on, pick it up.
Pick it up.
- Take cover!
-Take cover!
(PANTS)
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
-Fuck! Have you seen Tolly?
- No.
-No.
- TOLLY: Bevan!
-Ugh!
Officer's down at the front!
Bevan. (GRUNTS)
Jeez, Tol, where've you been?
Nowhere.
You gotta stay with us, Tolly.
I promised Mum.
Are you alright?
(GRUNTS)
Bugger this. Who wants to go
back to the beach for a swim?
- There's an idea.
-Should we take a vote?
- Yeah.
-Alright.
All in favour of going to
the beach to swim, say aye.
- MEN: Aye!
-Right. It's unanimous, then.
- Everyone ready?
-Yeah.
And you?
Go!
Come on, gents!
Get down! Get down!
(GRUNTS)
Bev! Wait for me!
It's alright. Alright.
Answer me!
Come on, you bastards! Ugh!
(GRUNTS AND WHIMPERS)
(SERENE MUSIC)
-(BIRDSONG)
-(WATER RUNS)
(FIRES RIFLE)
WOMAN: Mr Tolly.
We've got news.
Bevan's signed up for the war.
Your brother's going to be
a soldier.
Aren't you proud?
GIRL: Tolly!
- BOY: Ah!
-Tolly! (GIGGLES)
- Come here, Celia. (LAUGHS)
-Bevan, stop! Help me!
- Come on. (LAUGHS)
-You can't get me, I'm protected now.
(BEVAN LAUGHS) See ya.
Come on, I'll take you home.
(LAUGHS)
(SOBS)
BEVAN: Tolly!
Come on, Tol!
Tolly!
(COCKS RIFLE)
Come on, Tol!
(BELL CLANGS)
Do we know
if Birdwood's still doing well
with the Anzacs at Gaba Tepe?
What do we have on that?
The landing up there
was highly successful, sir.
I'm aware of that -
things looked fine from out on deck.
But this was two hours ago.
Last report, the Australians and
New Zealanders were moving inland.
Excellent. Now, down south here
with Hunter-Weston.
Do we know what's happening?
Looked like a damn mess
out there to me.
He's on board
the 'Euryalus', sir.
We've no way of knowing.
Well, this can't continue.
I don't want the Hampshire Regiment
wiped out completely.
The Munster Fusiliers -
I want them off V Beach
and re-landed on Y Beach.
Sir, is that sound?
Should we barge into
Hunter-Weston's
invasion plans?
He is executive commander
at Cape Helles.
You think I should not force
his hand, is that it?
Very well. (SIGHS)
Damn shame - they're having
a hellish time of it.
Unlike the colonials, sir.
They have the simple matter
of marching overland.
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
-C Company, forward!
TAYLOR: We're here. We must be.
(WHISTLING AND SHOUTING
CONTINUES)
Are you sure?
'Cause I don't think so.
This is way off.
We're supposed to take
15 minutes to get to here.
Well, it's gonna take two hours,
Captain.
If we're lucky.
Bloody hopeless.
We have to go back.
- We retrace our steps...
-If we do that we'll get caught.
They've got us from both sides.
- There's no other way.
-(WHOOSH)
-Ahh!
-Right!
Make your way fast down
this side as best you can!
Get back to the beach, Sergeant,
report where we're headed.
Recruit as many men
and stretcher bearers as you can
and bring them along down there.
Come on, get moving.
Private, move!
Fall back behind me!
Fall back! Come on!
Quick, men!
The terrain's causing
a lot of confusion, sir.
And the enemy?
He has gun batteries
and machine guns
here, here and here.
We're moving troops to our right
to take this ridge.
So if we keep him to our right
we can move up this valley.
Are we doing that?
I believe some men are moving
for the heights, sir.
- Communications are fragmentary.
-You believe?
We need to know
what's happening up there.
How are you getting
this information?
Wounded men mostly, sir.
They're questioned as soon as
they arrive on the beach.
- Wounded? Many of them?
-Quite a few, I'm afraid.
- The medical staff...
-Well, then.
Casualties means
we've engaged them at least.
This is good.
TOLLY: By mid-morning,
the terrain was doing more damage
than the Turks.
On all the ridges,
hardly anyone
was where
they should have been.
Captain Taylor was doing his best
to follow orders
and all we could do
was follow him.
-(BLOWS WHISTLE)
-(MAN SHOUTS)
One section - Turkish position
100 yards to your front.
One round. Fire.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Get down!
Where the hell did you
come from?
Dunno, sir.
We were told to move inland.
Who's your commanding officer?
Lieutenant Cowper. He's dead.
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
Alright, fall in with these men.
Come on, lads.
Sir! I have orders
from the beach.
So what do we have?
It's in bad order down there, sir.
They seem to focus on the ridge
to our right.
Orders are just to keep on
to occupy the heights.
And these men
are all they could spare?
No, sir,
I ran into them on the way up.
They were lost.
Right, lads,
keep moving with me.
(BIRD CHIRPS)
You signed.
Didn't you?
Mum...
Whatever were you thinking?
It's always the same!
-(WHIMPERS)
-Don't do this to me, Tolly!
- You...
-Mum, please.
- Mum. Mum.
-Damn you, Tolly.
Damn you. No.
Ah! Stop.
TAYLOR: Advance with me.
Advance with me, men!
Johnson, come on, son.
-(GUNFIRE)
-(MAN SPEAKS TURKISH)
(BLOWS WHISTLE) Two section -
100 yards to your front.
Five rounds. Go on!
(MAN SHOUTS IN TURKISH)
Still retreating.
It means their reinforcements
haven't arrived yet.
We have to secure that hill
before they get here.
-(MAN SHOUTS IN TURKISH)
-Bloody good.
Oh, they're scared.
We got 'em on the run. (SNIGGERS)
Hold.
Yes, sir.
Give them a breather,
then we'll proceed.
(MAN SPEAKS TURKISH)
TOLLY: The further we got up
the heights,
the more it felt like war.
A lot of blokes were dead.
The Turks were above us.
I could hear other Anzacs
not too far away
on the ridges to the east.
No-one knew
how this was gonna end.
Lie down.
Senior officers.
Means those reinforcements
aren't far off.
That's the hill we want.
Have the men entrench here
as quickly as possible.
Yes, sir.
You could recognise this hill
on a map?
I think so, yep.
We're obviously way forward
of everyone else.
Get back down to the beach again
on the double.
Tell them we need
urgent reinforcements.
OK.
Alright, one section,
go over to your right-
start entrenching.
Two section over to your left
and start digging.
Ammunition's on its way up.
- And water.
-And water. Get digging!
You four, with me.
TOLLY: I'd only been a fighting soldier
for five hours.
But it felt like a mess to me.
TAYLOR: Senior officer.
300 yards.
Who can take this shot?
I couldn't get him from here, Tolly.
(GRUNTS)
(EXHALES)
(MAN SHOUTS IN TURKISH)
Back! Back!
Back!
-(GRUNTS)
-BEVAN: Come on, Tol!
(MAN SHOUTS) With me!
With me, please!
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(MAN SHOUTS) Move forwards!
Come on, lads!
-(GUNSHOT)
-Ohh!
(GRUNTS AND PANTS)
Where are you,
you sneaky bugger?
(GRUNTS)
(MEN CHATTER)
SERGEANT: Sir.
Back again, Sergeant.
This is hardly your role.
Why aren't you using runners?
Captain Taylor decided we'd have
more certainty this way, sir.
Well done, Sergeant.
Thought you could run faster, is that it?
- That's right, sir.
-(BOMB EXPLODES)
- Well? Come on.
-(SIGHS) May I?
From the beach to this point,
this is the dead end
I pointed out last time.
So Captain Taylor
has moved from down here
up to this hill
where he's digging in.
Who's he with?
How many companies?
It's hard to say, sir.
We lost men to the scrub
and the valleys.
The company structure's
broken down, sir.
We've just been collecting men
the best we can.
What's the size of
Taylor's force, then?
About 60 men.
60?! Be damned!
We need to get more men
up there!
- Right.
-Get back there immediately.
We send what we can, but tell him
he must hold that position.
Yes, sir.
Sixty men.
It puts our troubles
to the right in perspective.
Those heights are critical.
Now we're there, we must hold on.
(HORSE WHINNIES)
(DISTANT SHOUTING)
Company, stand to!
One platoon, five rounds rapid! Fire!
One platoon, fall back!
Fall back!
I thought he'd never ask!
Company, pull back! Pull back!
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(MAN SHOUTS IN TURKISH)
Ahh!
-(TURKISH SOLDIER SHOUTS)
-Ahh!
TAYLOR: Fall back! Fall back!
Company, re-form on me!
Re-form on me!
(GRUNTS)
- They've stopped!
-(ALL PANT)
Oh, they're bastards.
They're Turks.
NCOs, check ammunition
and report back to me!
Do you think
we scared them, sir?
No. He wants to do us
one hill at a time.
(SIGHS)
- Charles Bean?
-Yes.
I watched the landing.
It's a little far north.
Wherever it is, sir,
it's all we've got.
I'm to present myself
to General Bridges.
I believe he's here somewhere, sir.
What do you mean 'somewhere?
Aren't you the landing officer?
Someone said he's gone down
past the beach
to check on communications,
but I can't confirm that.
You're on your own, I'm afraid, sir.
Where's Mr Bartlett?
I was told to expect
two reporters.
He's still on a ship.
He'll be coming later.
- Is this all your luggage?
-Of course.
I'll have your man collect it.
This way, sir.
MAN: Bartlett.
(CHUCKLES) My God! Donald!
Only a damn lieutenant.
I'll have to have a chat with
the Admiral.
And only a reporter.
Where the novel?
I'm far too busy
to write a novel.
Bumped into a chap
looking for you with this.
- From London.
-Ah!
Yes, about time.
I hope it's good news.
(READS) "Under no circumsta..."
Damn.
- What?
-Expenses.
I wanted to rent a yacht.
Sail it up and down the coast,
kit it out with some servants,
of course -
chef...or two.
- Fine idea, don't you think?
-And they knocked you back.
- Quelle surprise.
-Mmm.
Shouldn't you be ashore then?
I was here three years ago -
with the Turks,
when the Bulgarians chased them
out of Europe.
(SNIFFS)
Cholera and shrapnel -
devastating combination.
Spent some time
in Constantinople,
where I got my palm read
by a fortune teller.
- And?
-Apparently I'm all but invincible.
I could've told her that.
(CHUCKLES)
-(GUNFIRE)
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
-(MAN SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
-(PANTS)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(GUNSHOT)
Coward.
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
You alright, son?
Where are you off to?
- You alright?
-I don't know.
- Where's your weapon?
Are you wounded?
- No.
-Alright.
Grab that weapon there and follow me.
Do you understand?
Look at me, lad.
- Yes.
-Yeah? Alright, let's go.
(EXPLOSION)
Ever think we'd be soldiers
in the army together?
I never thought I'd be in a war.
Me too.
This isn't what I figured.
What did you figure?
I don't know.
I didn't think I'd be killing
blokes trying to surrender.
Anyway, they did the same.
- Bastards.
-(BULLET ZIPS NEARBY)
(EXPLOSION)
I'll look after you, but.
Yeah. I know.
You're gonna be my best man.
I can't find Cliffy.
- When did you last see him?
-Uh, back up the hill.
- He was right with us.
-He's gotta be here somewhere.
No, he's gone.
Shit.
Hey, you blokes,
have you seen Cliffy Sutton?
- No.
-No.
Hey, you blokes...
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
-(MAN SHOUTS)
(PANTS)
God, Harry, you're all in.
Sit down.
Thank you. (PANTS)
- Get some of that into you.
-Thank you, sir.
So what's the news?
It's not real good, sir.
What have they got in mind,
Sergeant?
We're to hold that hill.
(INSECTS BUZZ)
- So...
-Don't think about it, Tolly.
He'll turn up.
You know what he's like.
Here, what's happened
to this fella?
There's not a mark on him.
Strange.
Got a...blast injury
or something?
Maybe not.
- Why is he dead?
-Who knows, Tol.
It was his turn.
Grab his arms. Come on.
(GRUNTS) Stop thinking about
Cliffy. Come on.
TOLLY: I couldn't -
me and Cliffy were mates.
He was a simple bloke.
And some of the others
made fun of him,
but he always looked out for me.
Dave came to the war
from university.
He knew a lot of stuff I didn't.
He was a smart bloke,
so I tried hard to believe him.
My brother, Bevan,
was like a bull at a gate.
Oi, you blokes,
you seen Cliffy Sutton?
- No.
-Hey, you - no?
Sure?
TOLLY: He just wanted
to fix things,
even if he didn't know how.
(GUNFIRE)
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
-Reinforcements on their way.
(MAN SHOUTS)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
- Sir.
-Don't salute me, you idiot.
You want to get me shot?
Where are the rest of your men?
- Sir? -And ammunition.
Where's the ammunition?
I wasn't told anything
of ammunition, sir.
We're nearly out.
Your orders were to resupply us.
My...my orders were
to move inland, sir.
Move inland?
And do bloody what?
Isn't anyone thinking?
How are we expected to take...
- Sergeant!
-Right, sir.
- And water!
The Turks will have more
reinforcements on the way.
I'll have to move now
with what I've got.
Get your men into the line.
Stand left.
- Alright, Abdul...
-Move it!
...we know you can take a hill.
Let's see how good you are
at keeping one.
- Follow me!
-(MEN SHOUT) Charge!
Come on! Over, over!
Over! Come on, move it!
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
OFFICER: In two sections!
Cease firing!
One section, to your front,
one round!
Fire!
TAYLOR: Occupy
those fallen pits.
They'll be back!
(MAN SPEAKS TURKISH)
Sir...
Now it's in the timing.
Who gets here first-
that damn Turk up there
or Perceval and his ammunition.
(ALL SING) ♪ Lead, kindly light
♪ Amidst the encircling gloom
♪ Lead Thou me on
♪ The night is dark
♪ And I am far from home
♪ Lead Thou me on
♪ Keep Thou my feet
♪ I do not ask to see
♪ The distant scene
♪ One step enough
♪ For me. ♪
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(MEN CHATTER)
Why are you stretcher bearers
sitting down?
They're exhausted, Sarge.
They just got back
from up in the hills.
On your feet
if you don't mind, gents.
Son, have a look
where I'm pointing.
I need you to make your way
up along this main valley.
All the way to the top
and on the left.
You see where I'm pointing?
Do you understand?
Go.
- Give it to 'em, Sarge.
-Cliffy.
We should take a look
at that shoulder of yours.
Do that later.
PERCEVAL: Have some water, son.
(MAN COUGHS)
- Thanks, cobber.
-Where do you think you're going?
I'm going to Constantinople, mate.
Hunter-Weston's men ashore
consolidating.
Birdwood and his Anzacs in the hills,
gentlemen. (CHUCKLES)
It's the Balkans all over -
the Turk doesn't know
what's hit him.
He has more at his disposal
this time, though, sir.
Hardly matters at all.
He's not a good fighter.
Never has been.
No, indeed.
Strange, the enemy -
phantom till you look 'em in the eyes.
The evil man on the stair.
On the stair?
On. (CHUCKLES)
"As I was going up the stair
"I met a man who wasn't there.
"He wasn't there again today.
"Oh, how I wish he'd go away."
Go away indeed.
The heights today,
Constantinople tomorrow, eh?
- Well, hardly, sir.
-Hyperbole, Braith.
One must learn to think
beyond the obvious.
The obvious is what we have
before us, General.
Perhaps it's best
to deal with that first.
Yes, of course.
Everything in its proper place.
By God, I'll box his ears.
(SPEAKS TURKISH)
-(MEN SHOUT)
-(GUNFIRE)
TAYLOR: Spread out! Spread out!
Platoon, fall back! Fall back!
- Platoon! Platoon!
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
No!
- TAYLOR: Move it, move it!
-(MEN SHOUT)
- Quickly! Fall back! Fall back!
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Now they've got my hill,
they'll keep coming.
(DISTANT BOMBING AND GUNFIRE)
- Where's that ammunition?
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Are our flanks tied in?
Yes, sir.
How many rounds per man?
About 20, sir.
-20?
-Yes, sir.
-(MAN SHOUTS) Come on, men!
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Doesn't look good.
- What?
-Look at him.
He's gonna win the war
all by himself.
What do you mean?
He's a good soldier, Dave.
He knows what he's doing.
No-one on this hill knows
what they're doing, Bev,
if you haven't noticed.
(SIGHS) He's gonna
get us all killed.
He's doing what he's supposed
to be doing.
(SCOFFS) Well, he's enjoying it
a little too much for my liking.
No-one's enjoying it, Dave.
You reckon?
- Ammunition, sir.
-At last.
Distribute to all the men
immediately.
Ohh! (PANTS)
- Hey, cobbers.
-Jeez, Cliffy.
-(OTHERS LAUGH)
-Shit!
- What are you doing?
-I'm winning the war, mate.
What happened to ya?
The bullet, it went in here...
...and come out here.
-(OTHERS LAUGH)
-I never felt a thing.
Quite nice actually -
went down to the beach.
- I even had a swim.
-No, you didn't.
I bloody did. Nah, I didn't.
I wish I did but...
So what've you blokes
been doing?
Sitting on your bony arse
by the looks.
What's wrong, little Tol?
You alright?
- Hey? You OK?
-(OTHERS CHUCKLE)
You're alright. You haven't got
any camel dung?
- No.
-No?
(DISTANT GUNFIRE
AND EXPLOSIONS)
Order the men to stand to -
we're going back up there.
- We're running out of time.
-Yes, sir.
You won't get near,
I reckon.
Have a look where they are.
Maybe we should just
hold them off.
Be buggered, Perceval.
I'm gonna shoot
that bloody Turk.
(MEN CHATTER)
General Birdwood. Welcome, sir.
Gentlemen.
Commander sends his compliments.
We know the situation
on the right.
What we need to know is exactly
what's happening up that valley.
It's confused at the moment, sir.
Has anyone gone up to have
a proper look?
-It's in hand, sir.
-So it should be.
The problem is we don't know
with any precision
what's happening
on our own front.
We're hemmed in on the right.
So, gentlemen,
what we need is a break-out.
I'm sure you can find
a solution.
- Birdy's happy enough.
-I don't know why.
And...he shouldn't be leaving.
(CLEARS THROAT)
General Birdwood, sir.
Godley, thank you so much.
And all the very best to you.
To you too, sir.
(DISTANT EXPLOSION)
One minute -
you're going in one minute!
You are to follow your captain
over that hill.
Do not turn back.
Get your eyes forward, Private.
One minute!
Every second we're here,
the Turks are getting stronger
up there.
I thought you were dead.
I am, Tolly.
Come back to getcha.
You better watch out.
Right, then!
Let's show these Turks what...
-(TURKS SHOUT)
-Oh.
Oh, shit!
(BLOWS WHISTLE) Follow me!
(MEN SHOUT)
Move!
Come on!
(SPEAKS TURKISH)
(GUNFIRE)
But I thought you said
we'd lost that hill.
We did, sir. But we retook it.
- A third time?
-No, sir, it'd be the fourth time.
- Good.
-We've lost it again.
Now the Turks have got control
here, here and here.
And they still hold the heights.
Right. Damn!
So what's Taylor proposing?
Captain Taylor was shot, sir,
just before our last occupation
on this hill here.
So who are you reporting to,
Sergeant?
- Lieutenant Chandler, sir.
- A lieutenant?! What?
Sir, a lot of officers
are gone -
the snipers know their insignia.
So, do you think he can hold?
(SIGHS)
Probably not, sir.
And this is your story too,
Prior?
It is, sir.
We couldn't hold -
they had overwhelming force.
- PERCEVAL: Sir...
-That is all, Sergeant.
Yes, sir.
A broken line, no artillery,
little communication,
severe casualties.
- Birdwood needs to know this.
- WALKER: No.
We need Birdwood back here.
-(PANTS)
-(SOMBRE MUSIC)
(DIGGING SOUND)
CLIFFY: They won't
come at us now.
(SIGHS) They've gotta be
as buggered as we are.
They're probably not, you know.
Yeah, they figure
they're winning.
- Oh, makes a difference.
-Yeah.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Have a look at this.
It's gonna bloody rain now.
(LAUGHTER AND CHATTER)
Good luck, Thomas.
See you when you get back.
- Alright.
-Good luck, Tolly.
See you.
(WOMAN SINGS)
♪ Beautiful dreamer
♪ Wake unto me
♪ Starlight and dewdrops
are waiting for thee
♪ Sounds of the rude world
heard in the day
♪ Lulled by the moonlight
have all passed away
♪ Gone are the cares
of life's busy throng
♪ Beautiful dreamer,
awake unto me
♪ Beautiful dreamer
♪ Awake unto me. ♪
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Company, to the front-
rapid fire!
-(TURKISH SOLDIERS SHOUT)
-Go on!
TOLLY: When I was a little kid,
I was taught
thou shalt not kill.
But once you start...
-(BANG)
-Ugh!
...everything you've been
taught to believe
just disappears.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
No large batteries
out there yet.
Seems they're not
fully prepared.
They'll have them there
soon enough, John.
And they'll open up on you,
no doubt.
And so will I, sir.
- So will I.
-(LAUGHS)
Hunter-Weston'll have to make
another push early.
Quite.
He needs to get off
those damn beaches,
that's what he needs to do now.
Although I'm not sure
about early -
Weston's strictly
a protocol man.
He'll attack at 10:00 or so,
a civilised time.
I rather think the Turks will be
ready for them by then.
But that's no matter,
he knows what he's doing.
He's kept himself
on the 'Euryalus', Braith?
- Yes.
-He hasn't gone ashore?
- No, sir.
-Perhaps he ought to.
Birdwood's on his way ashore
a second time
with his Anzacs -
I applaud that.
Birdy puts himself
in the thick of it.
And is it all going well
for him?
Well, I'm presuming so, John,
in the absence of anything
to the contrary.
Thank you, Peterson.
BRIDGES: General Birdwood,
thanks for coming back, sir.
We're getting some
pretty uncomfortable reports
from the hills.
- Yes?
-Our right flank.
It's not good.
We're pinned down there, can't advance.
And we've lost the heights.
The officers are advising
withdrawal.
Are they?
And what do you recommend?
It galls me to say it, sir,
but our position's critical.
We can't break out.
- Godley?
-The men are exhausted, sir.
Unfortunately we have to
abandon this altogether.
We won't be able to hold
if the Turks attack in the morning.
Which they will,
no bloody doubt.
Walker?
I disagree. Fully.
We've established a line.
We've landed 15,000 men
and they've fought well.
They might have, Walker,
but that's academic.
We don't have the strength
or position
to repel them in the morning
when they come.
- WALKER: Who's to say?
-I'm saying, dammit.
With respect,
your saying means nothing.
What counts is the ability
of our men up there.
- I beg your pardon.
-You're wrong, Bill.
Let me remind you, Walker,
of my seniority.
I'm recommending
disembarkation.
- And if you so much as...
-Enough, gentlemen. Please.
I agree with Walker.
We've come this far,
I don't want to withdraw -
on principle.
- Sir...
-However.
I'll advise the Commander
of your concerns.
PERCEVAL: Make way, Private.
(GROANS)
- Mr Ashmead-Bartlett.
-Yes.
Welcome.
We thought we'd see you earlier.
I've been busy watching
from offshore.
Not as busy as you.
Charles Bean's here?
He arrived earlier today.
But he's gone off the beach.
- The press corps tent's down there.
-Won't be necessary.
I'm just here for a first look,
then back to the ship.
- Fine, sir. Good evening.
-Good evening.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
(MEN COUGH, GROAN
AND CHATTER)
Excuse me. Why haven't these men
been evacuated?
The hospital ships
are all full, sir.
We've been told there's no chance
till sometime tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
And have you been told
by what miracle
more ships will suddenly appear?
- No, sir.
-Because there aren't any.
(SIGHS) I probably
figured that, sir.
It's a damn shame.
How do you do, General?
How do you do, Bartlett?
How did you come ashore?
Take your boat back
and deliver this.
It's of the utmost priority.
Certainly, sir.
So, where are we headed, sir?
I'm not sure.
Let's get back to the 'Queen' -
gotta disembark these poor sods.
Thank you, Bartlett.
How are things with the Anzacs
at Gaba Tepe?
Well, um...I'm not privy
to the details, sir. But...
Yes?
Well, if you're asking me,
preparation time,
troop numbers -
Hamilton needs more of both
if this is going to be a success.
A general, Bartlett,
is like a tenant farmer -
he works with
what he's been given.
Precisely.
But my point remains, sir.
You're welcome
to stay on board tonight.
I'll have more boats
landing again tomorrow.
(QUIETLY) If there is
a tomorrow.
(SOLDIERS SHOUT)
CLIFFY: I hate these bastards!
I hate this bastard place!
I hate the generals.
And I hate you! You bastard!
- They just keep coming!
-Shut up and shoot!
(MEN SHOUT)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Sir Ian.
Sir Ian. Sir Ian?
(GRUNTS) Yes.
Braith. What is it?
It's a matter of
life and death, sir.
You've got to come
and settle it.
(GRUNTS)
What is it?
This from Birdwood.
(READS) "Most serious,
but if we are to re-embark
"it must be done at once."
Re-embark?
Birdwood's generals
want to abandon
the Anzac position altogether?
- When did you get this?
-Thirty minutes ago.
I've given the order for all boats
to stand by to evacuate.
Admiral. Withdrawal?
It can be done.
But it sticks in the craw.
Aye. It does.
Thursby?
It'll take the best part of three days
to get them all off.
And where are the Turks?
On top of them, sir.
Well, then...
...there we are.
To Lieutenant-General Birdwood,
Australia and New Zealand
Army Corps.
Your news is indeed serious.
But there is nothing for you to do
but dig right in
and stick it out.
- Eh, Braith?
-Absolutely, sir.
It will take at least two days
to re-embark you,
which Admiral Thursby
will explain to you.
Down the coast, Hunter-Weston,
despite his heavy losses,
will be advancing tomorrow,
which should divert pressure
from you.
Make a personal appeal
to your men and to Godley's
to make a supreme effort
to hold their ground.
Signed, Ian Hamilton.
P.S. - You have got through
the difficult business...
...and now all you have to do
is dig, dig, dig...
...until you are safe.
So, gentlemen, not quite
the reply we expected.
He's right of course - to go back
is probably more dangerous
than to go forward.
So it's a fait accompli.
Nothing more to be done.
BIRDWOOD: Except get this message
somehow to the line.
We must let the men know
that there'll be no falling back.
WALKER: "Dig, dig, dig
until you are safe."
A strange order from an OC.
Hardly our business, Walker.
I don't question the order, Bill,
I simply note that it's not...
BIRDWOOD: Gentlemen,
I remind you - time is running out.
The Turks are well-advanced.
Utilise whatever communications
we have.
We must start entrenching.
Yes, sir.
-(SOLDIERS SHOUT)
-Hey, hey!
Please, son!
Please, please, please!
Could you just hold his chin
just for a moment?
- Yeah.
-(MAN CHOKES)
Get your fingers
under his jaw there.
Here, push his tongue up.
That's good, son, push hard -
keep his tongue forward
or he'll choke.
That's good.
Try to stop this bleeding.
- It won't stop!
-(GRUNTS)
- Ugh!
-Oh, shit!
-(TOLLY WHIMPERS)
-(MAN CHOKES)
Shit! Here, here,
give me your hand.
Give me your hand. Hold.
BEVAN: Tolly!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
-Ahh!
-Tolly!
Stay there!
I'm alright!
(GRUNTS) And there...
...is day one.
War is such a blasted business.
The first blow
is half the battle, sir.
Don't forget that.
Indeed. Hmm.
- Would you like a whisky, sir?
- Mmm.
- Goodnight, sir.
-Goodnight, Braith.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(SPORADIC GUNFIRE)
TOLLY: That first day
was like a dream,
full of loose ends
and misunderstandings.
Men who landed on the beach
went up into the gullies
and ravines of Gallipoli
and were never seen again.
- Fuck!
- I'd like to go home now.
(PANTS)
TOLLY: I'd heard there'd been
wars here before.
I don't know what it was like
for them.
It didn't matter much.
BEVAN: Tolly!
TOLLY: This was our war now.
There'd be time to think about
the ghosts later.
- Tolly!
-(GUNSHOTS)
I'm alright!
I'm alright.
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(SNIFFS)
We dug in on that hill
in the dark.
And that first day...
...was as far as we ever got.
(PIANO PLAYS HYMN INTRO)
Ripped By mstoll
(WOMAN SINGS
'LEAD, KINDLY LIGHT')