<
Sync:FRM@ËÀ¾¯²ì ¹Ûº£ÎÀ
Rome 201
MORNING, CONSUL.
HOW GOES YOUR DAY?
( grunting )
STOP!
I AM SO PROUD
OF YOU.
OUR NAME IS REDEEMED.
THE REPUBLIC IS SAFE.
IT WAS HORRIBLE,
MOTHER.
HE WOULDN'T DIE.
( shudders )
BUT HE IS DEAD
NOW, EH?
HE TRIED TO SPEAK TO ME.
BUT NO WORDS CAME OUT.
WE MUST BE STRONG NOW.
YES.
THE SENATE WILL LOOK
TO US FOR LEADERSHIP.
THE PEOPLE WILL NEED
A FIRM HAND.
HM?
ARE YOU UP
TO THE TASK?
( sobbing )
DOMINUS.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHOSE CHILD IS THIS?
WHAT DID YOU DO?
LET HIM GO, LET HIM GO!
- ( grunting )
- NO, NO, DON'T!
PLEASE HAVE MERCY.
( sobbing )
I CURSE YOU.
CURSE YOU.
( spits )
I CURSE YOU ALL!
BY ALL THE GODS BELOW.
I CURSE YOU
TO DAMNATION.
( all crying )
( grunts )
Man:
CAESAR IS DEAD!
HE'S DEAD!
( garbled shouting )
Man:
LEAVE IT, FORGET IT.
YOU HEARD WHAT I SAID!
( sobbing )
MOTHER?
LEAVE ME ALONE.
GODS, NOT YOU AS WELL?
CRYING WILL NOT HELP US.
I'M NOT CRYING.
I'M ANGRY.
MAY DIS DEVOUR
THAT BITCH PIG SERVILIA.
WHAT A FOOL I WAS.
IF I'D NOT TOLD HER
OF VORENUS AND HIS WIFE...
LISTEN TO ME.
WE MUST NEVER SPEAK
OF OUR PART IN THIS.
IT MAY BE MISTAKEN
FOR COMPLICITY.
- DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
- ( door opens )
I'LL SEE HER
EATEN BY DOGS.
WE MAY HOPE.
DOMINUS,
TIMON IS HERE.
TIMON, GOOD OF YOU
TO COME.
( panting )
I GRIEVE WITH YOU.
- BAD BUSINESS.
- IT IS.
YOUR MOTHER'S
ALL RIGHT, IS SHE?
SHE'S NOT
RECEIVING VISITORS.
BUT SHE'S WELL ENOUGH.
HAVE YOU MEN WITH YOU?
10. SO, SHE'S
ALL RIGHT, THEN?
AS I SAID.
HOW'S THE CITY?
ALL'S INDOORS.
EVERYWHERE'S DEAD QUIET.
TIMON, THANK YOU
FOR COMING.
I AM SO HAPPY
TO SEE YOU.
I CAME AS SOON
AS I HEARD.
I GRIEVE WITH YOU.
YOU'RE A GOOD FRIEND,
THANK YOU.
ARE THE STREETS SAFE?
CAN WE GET OUT OF THE CITY?
- WE CAN.
- WE SHOULD WAIT A WHILE,
BEFORE TAKING ANY ACTION.
WE DO NOT HAVE A CLEAR VIEW
OF THE POSITION.
- ANTONY MAY WELL--
-  ANTONY WERE ALIVE,
HE WOULD COME TO ME.
OR SEND WORD,
AT LEAST.
I MUST ASSUME
ANTONY IS DEAD.
IT IS QUITE POSSIBLE,
BUT WE CANNOT KNOW
THAT AS YET.
PERHAPS HE'S
FLED THE CITY.
AND LEAVE ME HERE?
NEVER.
PUT ON YOUR
TRAVELING CLOTHES.
- NOTHING FANCY.
- MOTHER, THINK.
YOU HEARD WHAT SERVILIA SAID.
SHE WANTS YOU TO RUN AWAY.
MORE FOOL HER.
LET HER TRY TO FIND ME.
SHE WILL FIND YOU.
YOU HAVE NO TALENT FOR HIDING.
CASTOR, PACK THE MONEY
AND THE HOUSEHOLD GODS.
IMMEDIATELY,
DOMINA.
COME ALONG,
NO TIME TO WASTE.
( panting )
( spits )
ANTONY.
I SWEAR ON THE BLACK STO
THAT I WILL KILL THEM ALL.
BRUTUS AND CASSIUS
AND CASCA AND THE WHOLE
DAMN LOT OF THEM.
EY'RE JUST
SERVILIA'S MINIONS.
THIS IS ALL HER DOING.
I TOLD CAESAR.
I TOLD HIM
THIS WOULD HAPPEN.
I SWEAR, I WILL PISS
ON THEM AS THEY DIE.
THAT I-- I SHOULD
HAVE RUN AND HIDE
FROM THOSE--
THOSE WORMS.
ARE YOU CERTAIN?
ARE YOU CERTAIN SURE
HE'S DEAD?
OH, YEAH.
HE'S DEAD ALL RIGHT.
I WAS THERE,
I SAW HIM.
YOU WERE THERE?
BUT THEN WHY
DIDN'T YOU STOP THEM?
I-I WASN'T THERE.
I WAS--
THEY DELAYED ME
OUTSIDE ON THE STEPS.
BY THE TIME I GOT INSIDE
THE DEED HAD BEEN DONE.
AND THE LICTORS HAD ALL
RUN OFF LIKE RABBITS.
THAT TREACHEROUS
BASTARD VORENUS,
HE MUST HAVE BEEN
PAID OFF.
HE'D LEFT US
BEFORE WE EVEN GOT
TO THE SENATE HOUSE.
HE WAS LURED AWAY.
THE WITCH SERVILIA'S WOMAN
TOLD HIM AN EVIL TALE
ABOUT HIS WIFE.
- OH.
- WHAT DID YOU DO THEN?
WHAT DID I DO?
WHY, NOTHING
I COULD DO.
CAESAR WAS DEAD.
I WAS UNARMED.
WELL I WOULD HAVE...
RIPPED THEM TO PIECES
WITH MY BARE HANDS.
THAT'S EASY
FOR YOU TO SAY.
12 MANGY DOGS
CAN KILL A LION.
WELL, IF YOU SAY SO.
WHAT SHALL WE
DO NOW?
YOU CAN DO AS YOU LIKE.
I WILL GO NORTH...
AND RAISE AN ARMY
OF MONSTERS.
THEN I WILL
COME BACK HERE
AND I WILL CRUCIFY
EVERY LAST ONE OF THOSE
SONS OF BITCHE
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
I MAY "DO AS I LIKE"?
WHY ARE YOU HERE
IF I MAY DO AS I LIKE?
I MEANT NOTHING.
OF COURSE I WANT YOU
TO COME WITH ME.
PLEASE,  YOU'D RATHER
TAKE SOME OTHER LOVER,
I WILL NOT PROTEST.
OH, I MEANT ONLY THAT--
THAT I CANNOT FORCE YOU
TO COME WITH ME.
THAT'S WHERE YOU WER
THESE LAST HOURS, I SUPPOSE?
PUTTING YOUR WHORES INTO--
INTO BAGGAGE CARTS.
I HAVE NO STOMACH
FOR A FIGHT WITH YOU.
NOT NOW, EH?
I DON'T WANT
TO GO NORTH.
THE NORTH IS GHASTLY.
( chuckles )
- WHAT'S YOUR NAME AGAIN?
- TIMON.
TIMON, WE'RE GOING NORTH.
YOU AND YOUR MEN WILL
PROTECT THE FAMILY
UNTIL I CAN GATHER
MY OWN PEOPLE TOGETHER.
- IT'LL COST YOU.
- OF COURSE.
I EXPECT NO PUBLIC
SERVICE FROM A JEW.
WE SHALL BE TAKING
CALPURNIA WITH US, SO WE
MUST LEAVE VIA THE SUBURA.
CALPURNIA?
BUT WHY DO WE NEED
TO TAKE HER?
WE MUST BE SURE
THAT SHE IS SAFE.
WELL, I DON'T SEE HER
RUSHING TO SEE THAT
WE'RE SAFE.
MY DEA WE CANNOT LEAVE
CAESAR'S WIDOW BEHIND.
IT WOULD LOOK ILL WITH
THE PEOPLE, AS IF WE'D
ABANDONED HER.
WHAT A BORE.
( singing in Latin )
( grunts )
FATHER.
FATHER, WAKE ME.
- HUSH.
- WAKE ME.
HUSH NOW,
BE CALM.
I WILL WAKE YOU
IF YOU WILL LET ME GO.
PROMISE ME.
ON THE FIRE OF VESTA,
I PROMISE.
( singing in Latin )
LOVELY.
THANK YOU.
I KNOW I DIDN'T GET US
STARTED OFF ON THE RIGHT FOOT--
KILLING YOUR MAN AND ALL,
AND I'M SORRY FOR THAT.
BUT, VA, I'LL JUST COME
STRAIGHT OUT WITH IT.
I HAVE A QUESTION
TO ASK YOU.
WITH PERMISSION
OF VENUS AND MARS...
I ASK YOU
TO BE MY WIFE.
YOUR WIFE?
MARRIED?
MARRIED.
YOU AND ME.
IF-- IF YOU
WISH IT SO, MASTER.
NO NO NO, I'M NOT
YOUR MASTER ANYMORE.
YORE A FREE WOMAN.
YOU CAN REFUSE ME,
I WON'T BE ANGRY.
WELL, I WON'T BE BEST
PLEASED, BUT YOU KNOW,
I WON'T BEAT YOU
OR ANYTHING.
A MAN LIKE ME
CAN ALWAYS MAKE
GOOD MONEY.
YOU'LL HAVE A ROOF
OVER YOUR HEAD, FOOD.
I'LL BUY YOU ANYTHING
YOU WANT, DRESSES, SHOES.
IS THAT A YES?
YES.
( laughs )
YOU WON'T REGRET IT,
I PROMISE.
DONE.
( sheep bleating )
( woman praying
in Latin )
( praying continues )
THANK YOU, MY DEAR.
VISITORS, DOMINA.
BRING THEM.
( door closes )
( praying sts )
MARK ANTONY,
ATIA.
HOW GOOD OF YOU TO COME,
AND THE CHILDREN.
Antony:
CALPURNIA,
WE GRIEVE WITH YOU.
MY HUSBAND IS GLAD
TO RECEIVE YOU.
YOU'RE THE FIRST
TO PAY RESPECTS.
STRANGE THAT NONE
OF OUR FRIENDS OR
FAMILY HAVE COME.
THEY'RE AFRAID.
YES,
THAT MAY BE SO.
( weeping )
WE ARE GOING TO LEAVE
THE CITY NOW.
IT'S BEST YOU
COME WITH US.
LEAVING?
WHY?
IT IS NOT SAFE.
WELL, THAT'S NO MATTER.
I'M GLAD TO DIE.
MY DEAR LADY...
BUT NOW THAT YOU'RE
HERE TO STAND WITNESS,
WE MUST READ HIS WILL.
HIS WILL?
NO, I'M SORRY.
WE HAVEN'T TIME.
- IT IS THE PROPER FORM.
- WE HAVEN'T TIME.
IT IS THE WILL...
OF A DICTATOR
OF THE ROMAN REPUBLIC.
HAVING MADE DUE
PROVISION WITH THE
WELL-BEING AND SECURITY
OF MY HONEST AND DUTIFUL
WIFE, CALPURNIA, ET CETERA,
I LEAVE THE SUM OF
75 DENARII TO EVERY
ENROLLED CITIZEN--
OH, RIDICULOUS.
WHAT A WASTE.
MY NAME
AND THE REMAINDER
OF MY ESTATE
WITH ALL LEGAL
OBLIGATIONS AND BENEFITS,
ALL PROPERTY, GOLD,
SILVER
AND OTHER MONIES,
I LEAVE TO GAIUS OCTAVIAN,
WHO IS HENCEFORTH
TO BE REGARDED
FOR ALL INTENTS AND
PURPOSES AS MY LAWFUL SON
AND SOLE HEIR.
OCTAVIAN?
MY OCTAVIAN?
WHAT ELSE?
HE STIPULATES THAT THE
SLAVE KNOWN AS POSCA--
THAT IS I-- AM TO BE
GIVEN MY LIBERTY
WITH AN APPROPRIATE
STIPEND.
I GIVE YOU JOY
OF YOUR FREEDOM.
WHATLSE?
THERE ARE NO FURTHER
BEQUESTS.
I SEE.
WELL,
CONGRATULATIONS, BOY.
THANK YOU, POSCA.
( door opens )
OCTAVIAN GETS EVERYTHING?
ALL OF IT?
HE'LL GET NOTHING.
IT'S ALL WAX FOR SAPING.
IT'S A WILL.
IT-- IT'S HIS BY LAW.
THE LAW IS NOW BRUTUS
AND HIS MINIONS.
CAESAR'S LAND AND MONEY
WILL GO TO THEM.
THAT IS SO.
THEY WILL DECLARE HIS DEATH
A RIGHTFUL TYRANNICIDE,
HIS WILL AND ALL HIS ACTS
BECOME NULL AND VOID,
HIS PROPERTY WILL BE
INTESTATE.
- THEY CANNOT TAKE THE NAME.
- Antony: OH NO.
THAT'S ALL YOURS.
MUCH GOOD
MAY IT DO YOU.
- AWAY NOW.
- ( sighs )
I MAY HAVE TO TAKE
CALPURNIA ALONG BY FORCE,
SO DON'T BE ALARMED
IF SHE MAKES A CLAMOR.
HEY, SEND
FOR YOUR MISTRESS.
TELL HER WE'RE LEAVING.
MOTHER, I MUST STAY
IN ROME.
- EH?
- I MUST STAY IN ROME.
I AM CAESAR'S SON.
I MUST PROTECT MY STATUS
AND RIGHTS.
THERE'S BLOOD.
A PROPER LITTLE SPARTAN.
YOU SHALL HAVE TO
STAY ALSO, MOTHER.
THE FAMILY MUST
APPEAR UNITED.
OH MY STRANGE, BRAVE, POMPOUS
LITTLE BOY, WE'RE GOING NORTH.
I'M HEAD OF THE FAMILY.
STRICTLY SPEAKING, IT IS
FOR ME TO SAY WHERE WE GO.
I KNOW YOU'RE ONLY TRYING
TO BE MANLY, THAT'S LOVELY.
BUT NOW IS NOT THE TIME.
WE ARE GOING AND THERE'S
AN END ON IT.
ANTONY LISTEN, BRUTUS
IS IN A LEGAL BIND.
I THINK WE CAN FORCE HIM
INTO MAKING A DEAL WITH US.
GO ON.
BRUTUS MUST DECLARE CAESAR
A TYRANT OR ELSE THE ACT
OF KILLING CAESAR IS MURDER.
BUT ALL THE ACTS OF
A TYRANT ARE UNLAWFUL,
INCLUDING THOSE APPOINTING
BRUTUS AS PRAETOR,
CASSIUS AS PROCONSUL,
- AND SO FORTH.
- AND THEN SO?
IF BRUTUS HONORS
THE LAW,
HE LOSES ALL RANK
AND POSITION.
IT'S LAWYERS' PRATTLE.
I DON'T THINK SO.
IF YOU OFFER THEM AMNESTY
- IN RETURN--
- AMNESTY?
I'M GONNA EAT
THEIR LIVERS.
AMNESTY?
YOU'RE NOT FOLLOWING ME.
ENOUGH! YOU THINK YOU KNOW
BETTER THAN ANTONY?
- BUT YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
- JUNO'S CUNT, MUST I SLAP YOU?
IF THE WILL STANDS,
AND IT MIGHT,
YOU ARE MOTHER TO
THE RICHEST MAN IN ROME.
IF THE WILL IS BROKEN,
SERVILIA HAS THAT HONOR.
NO.
WHERE IS THIS
DAMN WOMAN?
WHEN I GIVE YOU THE NOD,
I WANT YOU TO HELP ME
SEIZE THE OLD LADY
AND GET HER GETSIDE QUICK.
SHE TRUSTS YOU, NAY?
- SIR, WILL ALL RESPECT...
- WHAT?
WITH ALL RESPECT,
UNTIL THE WILL IS RATIFIED,
I AM BOUND TO SERVE
THE HOUSE OF CAESAR.
WITH THAT IN MIND,
I MUST BEG YOU NOT TO TAKE
MY MISTRESS BY FORCE.
- WITH ALL RESPECT.
- RESPECT?
YOU IMPUDENT TOAD.
YOU'LL DO AS I SAY,
AND I WILL DO AS I PLEASE
WITH YOUR DAMN MISTRESS.
ANTONY?
WE'RE STAYING.
( sheep bleating )
NO THANK YOU, MASTER.
YOU'VE GOT TO STOP
CALLING ME THAT.
WHAT SHALL I
CALL YOU THEN?
ANYTHING YOU WANT.
UM, HUSBAND?
HONEY?
( horse whinnies )
CAESAR IS DEAD!
HA!
CAESAR IS DEAD.
- ( horse whinnies )
- CAESAR IS DEAD!
( grunts )
DON'T WOY.
IF HE COMES BACK,
BA HE COMES BACK.
( grunting )
( distant shouting )
( door opens )
THERE.
SEE HOW FINE SHE LOOKS?
SHE'LL BE
WELL RESPECTED.
A WOMAN FROM
GOOD PEOPLE.
HELLO, CHILDREN.
IMMORTALS!
IMMORTALS, I SAY.
YOU NOBLEMEN HAVE
CARVED YOUR NAMES
DEEP IN THE
ETERNAL STONE.
THAT IS VERY HIGH
PRAISE INDEED.
I WOULD EMBRACE YOU ALL
BUT I'M DESOLATED
THAT YOU DID NOT ENLIST ME
IN YOUR COHORT OF HEROES.
TO WIELD THE
LIBERATORS' KNIFE--
WHAT JOY YOU
HAVE DENIED ME.
OH, FORGIVE US.
BUT WE RATHER THOUGHT
YOU'D PREFER NOT TO KNOW.
IT IS DONE.
I CANNOT SHARE
IN YOUR GLORY.
I CAN ONLY APPLAUD.
( chuckles )
NOW TELL ME,
IS THE CITY SECURE?
Cassius:
WE HAVE 2,000
MEN UNDER ARMS.
CAESAR'S PEOPLE
HAVE FLED.
THE CITY IS OURS.
EXCELLENT, AND MARK ANTONY,
THE DOG, IS DEAD I HOPE?
- HE IS NOT.
- MARK ANTONY IS ALIVE?
AN ERROR!
I THINK,
A DEEP ERROR.
WE ARE SENATORS,
NOT HIRED THUGS.
KILL HIM YOURSELF
IF YOU WANT IT SO.
WELL, WELL YOU
KNOW BEST WHAT IS
THE RIGHT THING TO DO.
I-I MUST GO.
I'M AWAY TO THE COUNTRY.
ANOTHER TEDIOUS LAWSUIT.
I JUST WANTED TO SALUTE YOU
BEFORE I LEFT.
IMMORTAL LIBERATORS.
( door closes )
FRIEND CICERO.
WHY SO PALE?
BROTHER?
VORENUS?
- LEGIONARY PULLO,
SECOND SENTRY, FIRST COHORT.
- WHAT'S HAPPENED?
FIRST COHORT.
BROTHER VORENUS,
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
SHE'S MOTHER
TO THE BOY LUCIUS.
I WAS...
GOING TO KILL HER.
I HAD THE KNIFE
IN MY HAND.
SHE DID IT HERSELF.
MISERIA.
- WHERE ARE THE CHILDREN?
- GONE.
GONE WHERE?
I CURSED THEM.
I CURSED THEM
TO HADES.
vi
GET SOME WATER.
BROTHER VORENUS?
- BROTHER VORENUS?
- HUH?
COME SIT DOWN.
LET'S GET YOU
CLEANED UP, EH?
CONSUL ANTONY,
I AM HERE
STRICTLY AS AN
IMPARTIAL ARBITER.
I KNEW NOTHING OF
THIS DISTURBING ACT.
OH?
I WAS AS SURPRISED AND--
AND SHOCKED AS YOU WERE.
AS BRUTUS CAN CONFIRM.
UH, CICERO KNEW NOTHING.
YOU HAVE LOST A GOOD
FRIEND AND PATRON TODAY.
WE ARE SORRY.
IF THAT MONKEY REMAINS
I SHALL HAVE TO EN HIS NECK.
HE TRIED TO
KILL ME THIS MORNING.
HIS PRESENCE IS AN INSULT.
YOU'RE MISTAKEN.
NO ONE TRIED TO KILL YOU.
IT WAS MY EXPRESS ORDER
THAT YOU BE SPARED.
AM I, CASSIUS?
MISTAKEN?
WE DO APOLOGIZE IF
THIS MAN'S BEEN OVERZEALOUS.
MM.
GO, QUINTUS.
Servilia:
TELL US, ANTONY...
TO WHAT DO WE OWE
THIS UNEXPECTED PLEASURE?
LISTEN.
WHY SO QUIET?
A TYRANT IS DEAD.
SURELY THE PEOPLE
SHOULD BE HAPPY.
WHERE IS THE CHEERING THRONG
AT YOUR DOOR?
WHERE ARE THE JOYOUS CRIES
OF LIBERTY? HM?
THE PEOPLE FEAR CHANGE.
A SOMBER MOOD
IS ONLY NATURAL.
WHEN THEY REALIZE
THEY ARE FREE FROM TYRANNY,
THE PEOPLE WILL BE GLAD.
THE PEOPLE LOVED CAESAR.
AND THEY WILL HATE YOU
FOR WHAT YOU'VE DONE.
THEY LOVED HIM ONCE.
AS I DID.
OH, SOME HAVE TURNED
AGAINST HIM, NO DOUBT.
IT CANNOT BE DENIED HE WAS
SOMETHING OF A TYRANT.
BUT A GREAT MANY PEOPLE WILL
WORSHIP CAESAR UNTIL THEY DIE.
A GREAT MANY.
AND THOSE PEOPLE
ARE MINE NOW.
WE DO NOT NEED
SUCH PEOPLE.
OUR MEN-AT-ARMS
HAVE SECURED THE CITY.
WE'VE RECEIVED
REPRESENTATIVES FROM
ALL THE BEST ELEMENTS.
THE SENATE IS WITH US,
THE KNIGHTS ARE WITH US.
THE PONTIFFS, THE URBAN
COHORTS, THE LICTORS' GUILD.
MM, THE LICTORS' GUILD,
VERY GOOD.
ONLY RALLY THE BAKERS
AND THE FLUTPLAYERS,
AND YOU CAN PUT ON
A FESTIVAL.
BEST WAIT TILL AFTER
THE ELECTIONS, THOUGH.
WHAT ELECTIONS?
SURELY YOU'VE THOUGHT
THIS THROUGH?
IF CAESAR WAS,
AS YOU INSIST, A TYRANT,
THEN ALL HIS ACTS
AND APPOINTMENTS
ARE NULLIFIED.
I AM NO LONGER CONSUL,
YOU'RE NO LONGER PRAETOR,
YOU'RE NO LONGER PROCONSUL.
ELECTIONS WILL
HAVE TO BE HELD.
THAT IS SO.
MESSY THINGS,
ELECTIONS.
YOU SPOKE OF HELPING US?
I DID.
ALL THOSE TH LOVED CAESAR,
BUT HATE TYRANNY...
I MAY BE ABLE TO BRING
TO YOUR SIDE.
WHY WOULD YOU DO THAT?
NEITHER OF US
CAN WIN OUTRIGHT.
NOT WITHOUT MUCH BLOOD
SPILLED TO PROVE THE ISSUE.
I WANT NO MORE BLOOD.
I WANT PEACE
AND STABILITY.
HOW?
FIRST,
A GENERAL AMNESTY.
CAESAR IS NOT DECLARED TYRANT,
NOR YOU DECLARED KILLERS.
ALL CAESAR'S ACTS
AND HIS WILL
SHALL STAND.
WE SHALL ALL
KEEP OUR POSTS.
IT WL BE AS IF
HE WERE STRUCK BY LIGHTNING.
A NATURAL DEATH.
GO ON.
THEN A SHOW OF UNITY.
A PUBLIC FUNERAL FOR CAESAR,
LED BY YOU AND I
TOGETHER.
WE SHALL MOURN THE MAN
AND BURN THE TYRANT.
AND THEN,
I SHALL SERVE OUT
THE REST
OF MY TERM AS CONSUL,
AND THEN RETIRE QUIETLY
TO THE PROVINCES
WHERE I WILL PLOUGH
MY FIELDS
AND FUCK MY SLAVES.
JUST LIKE OLD
NCINNATUS.
AND THE REPUBLIC SHALL
ROLL ON WITHOUT ME.
I SWEAR
ON THE BLACK STONE,
I AM DONE WITH POLITICS.
OH, YOU PEOPLE
PLAY TOO ROUGH
FOR A SIMPLE SOLDIER
LIKE ME.
KNIVES
IN THE SENATE HOUSE.
DIDN'T THINK
YOU HAD IT IN YOU.
AND IF WE DO NOT WISH
TO BE RECONCILED WITH YOU?
WELL, IF WE CANNOT BE FRIENDS,
THEN WE SHALL BE ENEMIES.
AND I WILL DO MY VERY BEST
TO ANNIHILATE YOU.
PERHAPS YOU WOULD GIVE US
SOME TIME TO TALK THIS OVER?
HM.
YOU CAN TALK ALL YOU LIKE.
I SHALL WAIT OUTSIDE.
( door opens )
( door closes )
YOU TRIED TO KILL HIM
DESPITE EVERYTHING I SAID?
FORGIVE ME.
YOUR SCRUPLES DO YOU CREDIT,
BUT WITHOUT YOUR KNOWLEDGE
HIS DEATH COULD NOT HAVE
DISHONORED YOU--
TO THE CONTRARY,
I WILL BE TWICE DISHONORED--
A KILLER AND A FOOL.
IS YOUR HONOR WORTH MORE
THAN THE REPUBLIC?
IT IS NOT TOO LATE.
HE'S HERE,
IN YOUR HANDS.
I'M SIMPLY STATING
THE FACTS.
I DO NOT URGE
YOU TO ANY
PARTICULAR CRSE
OF ACTION.
NOR WILL I TAKE THE
COURSE YOU DO NOT URGE.
BROTHER.
IT IS THE ONLY
RATIONAL THING TO DO.
HE'S BROKEN
NO CAPITAL LAW.
AND HE OFFERS A TRUCE
WHICH WILL PRESERVE
THE PUBLIC ORDER.
WE HAVE NO RIGHT
TO TAKE HIS LIFE.
DAMN THE LAW IN HIS CASE.
HE'S TOO DANGEROUS TO LIVE.
YOU EXAGGERATE HIM.
HE IS A VULGAR BEAST.
WITHOUT CAESAR HE WILL
DESTROY HIMSELF SOON ENOUGH.
- HE IS--
- HE IS A GUEST IN MY HOUSE.
HE IS NOT IN THE HOUSE.
HE IS ON THE STREET.
YOU TOO,OTHER?
( men chattering )
CONSUL ANTONY...
WE SHALL BE FRIENDS.
FRIENDS, EH?
( exhales )
( door closes )
( gasps )
MY GOD.
THERE.
THAT'S BETTER.
- I SHOULDN'T HAVE DONE IT.
- WHAT'S THAT?
I CURSED MY
OWN CHILDREN, PULLO.
IT WASN'T THEIR FAULT.
DON'T WORRY,
THEY'LL BE BACK.
YOU CAN LIFT
THE CURSE THEN,
NO TROUBLE.
YOU DIDN'T KILL
AN ANIMAL ON IT,
DID YOU?
- NO.
- THERE YOU GO THEN.
THE CURSE ISN'T SEALED.
AND WHEN THEY COME BACK,
YOU CAN LIFT IT.
NO HARM DONE.
WHAT IF THEY DON'T
COME BACK?
WHERE ELSE
THEY GONNA GO?
COURSE THEY'RE
COMING BACK.
TOMORROW,
AT THE FOURTH HOUR,
A FUNERAL SERVICE
WILL BE HELD FOR
GAIUS JULIUS CAESAR.
UNDER TERMS OF TRU
AND IN THE SPIRIT OF UNITY
AND FORGIVENESS,
EULOGIES WILL BE DELIVERED
BY PRAETOR
MARCUS JUNIUS BRUNUS
AND CONSUL
MARK ANTONY.
NO PROSTITUTES, ACTORS
OR UNCLEAN
TRADESMEN MAY ATTEND.
I AM COME TO PAY
MY RESPECTS TO YOUR HUSBAND.
( spits )
I UNDERSTAND
YOU ARE GRIEVING.
( spits )
SHOW HER
WHAT SHE'S DONE.
SO VORENUS WENT HOME
TO CONFRONT HIS WIFE
AND CAESAR WENT TO THE SENATE
ALONE AND UNPROTECTED.
BASTARDS.
WHAT I DON'T UNDERSTAND
IS HOW THEY KNEW
ABOUT NIOBE AND ALL THAT
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
YOU AND I WERE THE ONLY
ONES THAT KNEW THE TRUTH.
I TOLD MY SISTER.
AND SHE TOLD SERVILIA.
MY SISTER WAS--
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THE JUG IS BROKEN,
I CANNOT MEND IT
WITH REGRET.
I ASK FOR YOUR
FORGIVENESS.
OF COURSE.
I CAN'T EXPECT A YOUNG LAD
LIKE YOURSELF TO BE--
TO BE--
ANYWAY,
IT'S DONE,
AS YOU SAY.
YOU SHOULD NOT REPEAT
WHAT I HAVE TOLD YOU.
IT'S NOT THAT I'M ASHAMED,
THOUGH I AM.
IT'S ONLY THAT
IT WILL NOT LOOK GOOD
WITH THE PEOPLE.
IT'S FORGOTTEN ALREADY.
SORRY ABOUT YOUR UNCLE.
I AM MADE HIS SON
BY WILL.
OH.
CONGRATULATIONS.
YOU'LL BE WANTING
VENGEANCE, THEN?
AT SOME POINT.
I'LL BE UP FOR
THE DUTY, OF COURSE.
( praying in Latin )
OH COME ON, GET UP.
HAVE YOU FORGOTTEN
WHAT DAY IT IS?
OH,
WHAT DAY IS IT?
DON'T PLAY WITH ME.
I'M NOT UP FOR IT TODAY.
AH.
RELAX.
IT'S GONNA BE MY DAY.
I CAN FEEL IT.
I DON'T THINK
I'VE EVER FUCKED A WOMAN
IN A FUNERAL DRESS
BEFORE.
NOR SHALL YOU NOW.
THAT'S A SHAME.
IT'LL HAVE TO BE
MERULA THEN.
COME HERE, OLD GIRL.
JUMP ON.
- SHE'D EAT YOU ALIVE.
- HM.
COME ON, THIS IS
NO MORNING FOR FOOLERY.
JUST GET UP.
OH COME HERE.
STOP FOOLING AROUND
AND JUSTET UP!
I AM NOT RISING
FROM THIS BED
UNTIL I'VE FUCKED
SOMEONE.
FINE, FINE. MERULA,
FETCH THAT GERMAN SLUT
FROM THE KITCHEN.
COME ON,
GET IT RIGHT THIS TIME
OR YOU'LL BE NEXT
FOR THE "KING OF GOATS"
OVER THERE.
UNDERTAKER'S HERE.
WE'RE READY TO GO.
WE MUST WAIT
FOR THE CHILDREN.
THEY'LL BE BACK,
BROTHER.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE DONE IT.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE
CURSED THEM.
THEY'LL BE BACK.
I'M SURE OF IT.
SOONER OR LATER.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE DONE IT.
I SHOULDN'T
HAVE DONE IT.
HEY,EY, HEY.
HEY.
WE'VE GOT TO SEND
NIOBE ON HER WAY NOW.
WE CAN'T LEAVE IT
ANY LONGER, CAN WE?
ELSE THEM BELOW
WILL BE VEXED.
PLEASE.
( women chanting
in Latin )
( chanting continues )
( people cheering )
- ( crowd clamoring )
- ( fire roaring )
GRAIN MONITOR?
WHY ON GAIA'S EARTH WOULD
I WANT TO BE GRAIN MONITOR?
IT WOULD GIVE YOU
REASON TO LEAVE THE CITY
WITH DIGNITY.
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF LEAVING THE CITY.
A TOUR OF THE ASIAN
SUPPLY PORTS
WOULD BE THE MOST
NATURAL THING IN THE WORLD.
NOBODY COULD
POSSIBLY ACCUSE YOU
OF RUNNING AWAY.
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF LEAVING THE CITY!
SERVILIA, MY DEAR...
SORRY ABOUT ALL THIS.
( sighs )
GOT A BIT CARRIED AWAY.
YOU GA
AN EXCELLENT SPEECH,
INCIDENTALLY.
IT WAS PERHAPS
A TOUCH TOO CEREBRAL
FOR THAT AUDIENCE,
BUT...
HAVE YOU BEEN OFFERED
ANY REFRESHMENT?
AH, SOME WATER
WILL BE LOVELY.
THANK YOU.
PLEASE, SPEAK SENSE
TO YOUR SON.
HIM AND HIS FRIENDS
MUST LEAVE THE CITY.
I CANNOT ANSWER
FOR THEIR SAFETY.
DO NOT LOOK SO PLEASED
WITH YOURSELF.
YOU'RE A LIAR
AND A BREAKER OF OATHS,
AND YOU'VE ROUSED YOUR RABBLE,
NOTHING MORE.
A PANTOMIME ACTOR MIGHT HAVE
DONE WHAT YOU DID TODAY.
LUCKY THEN IT WAS ME
THAT DID IT, EH?
ELSE YOU WOULD NOW BE
ON YOUR KNEES SUCKING
PANTOMIME COCK.
I HAVE NO WISH TO ABUSE
OR HUMILIATE YOU.
I ONLY WISH YOU GONE.
WE'RE GOING NOWHERE.
HM. NO, NOT YOU,
AT LEAST.
THE MEN SHALL LEAVE.
YOU WILL STAY HERE
IN THE CITY WITH ME
AS MY GUEST.
( laughs )
HOSTAGE, YOU MEAN.
AS YOU LIKE.
YOU MAY WISH AS YOU WILL.
WE YET HAVE ALL
THE SENATE BEHIND US
AND ALL THE MEN
OF QUALITY.
AND I HAVE
AN ANGRY MOB...
THAT WILL ROAST AND EAT
YOUR "MEN OF QUALITY"
IN THE ASHES OF
THE SENATE HOUSE!
( cup crashes )
CHILDREN?
ELDEST?
VORENA?
THEY'RE NOT HE.
NEVER MIND.
JUST HAVE TO BE PATIENT.
HOW ABOUT YOU MAKE US
A NICE POT OF PORRIDGE?
WE'LL ALL FEEL BETTER
WITH SOME FOOD INSIDE US.
( metal clanging )
- VORENA?
- ANYONE HERE?
( clattering )
( screaming )
I'M SORRY, I'M SORRY.
I WAS ONLY TAKING BACK
THINGS I LENT.
HUSH, IT DOESN'T MATTER.
DO YOU KNOW WHERE THE
CHILDREN HAVE RUN TO?
I SWEAR,
ONLY THINGS I LENT.
DO YOU KNOW WHERE
THE CHILDREN ARE?
SPEAK!
ERASTES' FOREMEN
TOOK THEM.
( whispering )
PORCA JUNO.
I'M VERY SORRY
FOR YOUR LOSS.
( horse whinnies )
AYE, AYE, AYE, RIGHT.
THE PLACE IS FUCKING
PACKED, YEAH?
TAKES ME HALF AN HOUR TO
FIGHT MY WAY TO THE FRONT
AND UP STEPS BRUTUS.
HA! RIGHT?
AND HE GOES,
"BLAH, BLAH, BLAH.
THE LAW THIS
AND THE REPUBLIC THAT.
AND THE 12 BLOODY TABLES."
I COULDN'T UNDERSTAND
HALF OF IT.
YEAH, YEAH,
THEN WHAT HAPPENED?
THEN, ANTONY'S UP.
BUT HE GIVES BRUTUS A HUG.
HE STARTS TALKING
ALL CALM AND GENTLE
LIKE HE'S NOT BOTHERED.
AND I'M THINKING,
"BOLLOCKS TO THIS. WE'LL BE
AWAY FOR A BEVY."
BUT THEN...
HE PULLS OUT
CAESAR'S TOGA,
ALL COVERED IN BLOOD.
EVERYONE GOES,
"WHOA!"
DISGUSTING.
FUCKING DIGNITY, THAT MAN.
BUT NOW, ANTONY'S STALKING
UP AND DOWN WITH THE TOGA
AND HE'S CRYING ABOUT
"WHAT A GOOD MAN WAS CAESAR"
AND HOW MUCH HE LOVES HIM
AND WHAT A GREAT LEADER
WE'VE LOST
UNTIL THE CROWD--
HALF OF THEM ARE CRYING--
THEY'RE SOBBING
LIKE BABIES.
AND THEN WHAT DOES HE DO?
HE TAKES THE BLOODY TOGA...
AND THROWS IT INTO THE CROWD.
WHOOSH!
THE WHOLE FUCKING PLACE
WENTP LIKE A TAR BARREL.
THE WHOLE
FUCKING CRD WENT MAD.
BRUTUS AND THEM
ARE LUCKY TO BE ALIVE.
IF THEY ARE.
IT'S DISGRACE.
NO FUCKING RESPECT.
- YEAH, WEYE PEOPLE GET
ANGRY, DON'T THEY?
- NO EXCUSE.
IT'S A CONSULAR
FUCKING FUNERAL, ISN'T IT?
SUPPOSED TO SHOW
SOME FUCKING RESPECT.
NOT RUN AROUND
LOOTING AND BURNING.
ANIMALS.
THAT ANTONY'S
A CUNT, TOO.
MARK ME, NOW.
ANYONE OF YOU CUNNIES
JOIN IN THIS DISGRACE,
YOU'LL BE DISJOINTED
QUICK AS PAN.
WE OBSERVE
THE FUCKING DECENCIES.
- RIGHT?
- All: RIGHT.
( rocks sizzling )
AH, FUCKING SLAVES
AND FOREIGNERS TO BLAME.
( rocks sizzling )
SEND THEM BACK TO BITHYNIA,
OR WHEREVER THE FUCK
YOU COME FROM.
ROME FOR
FUCKING ROMANS, EH?
( sighs )
- ( whip snaps )
- ( woman screaming )
FLAVIO?
TELL THOSE DAMN SCURRAS
TO SHUT THAT UP!
THEY WANT TO FIGHT,
TAKE IT OUTSIDE.
( screaming continues )
Man:
KEEP YOUR HANDS ABOVE IT!
FLAVIO!
( man screams )
FUCKING USELESS.
YOU HAVE MY CHILDREN.
EH? WHAT THE FUCK
YOU TALKING ABOUT?
YOU HAVE MY CHILDREN.
SOMEONE'S MISLED YOU,
FRIEND.
WHERE ARE THEY?
I DON'T KNOW.
( sobbing )
WHERE ARE THEY?
FLAVIO!
FLAVIO'S NOT COMING.
panting )
( chuckles )
HERE WE ARE THEN.
WHERE ARE THEY?
WHERE ARE MY CHILDREN?
WILL YOU HAVE
A LITTLE WINE WITH ME?
NO? WELL...
KISS MY ASS.
TELL HIM.
IF THEY'RE NOT HARMED,
YOU MAY YET LIVE.
( laughs )
YOU THINK SO?
TELL HIM.
NOTHING LIKE A GOOD
FALERNIAN GRAPE, IS THERE?
YOU'RE NOT A BAD SORT
OF MAN, VORENUS.
YOU JUST HAVE
TOO MUCH ANGER IN YOU.
TELL HIM!
TOOK YOUR CHILDREN IN PAYMENT
FOR YOUR MANY SLIGHTS TO ME.
I FUCKED THEM
THEN I KILLED THEM.
AND THEN I THREW THEM
IN THE RIVER.