President: This summer marks
the 100th anniversary
of the start of the First World War.
And the beginning of a period that saw two
of the deadliest conflicts in our history.
It's a chance to remember those who died.
For their brothers, for their country
and for the freedom we enjoy today.
And its a chance to honor
the courage and bravery of all
those who stepped forward and
answered the call to serve.
Men like my Grandfather who marched through
France as a member of Patton's army.
Women like my Grandmother who worked on
a bomber assembly line while he was gone.
So as we listen to the stories of
the leaders like Roosevelt and Churchill,
let's also remember
the citizens whose names
will never appear on
monuments or in textbooks.
Men and Women who stood
firm in the face of evil
and in the years since have taken
their rightful place in history.
May their sacrifice never be forgotten.
_
[Intense orchestral music]
♪ ♪
[Gas hissing]
_
[Gasping]
[Coughs]
[Crickets chirping]
[Dramatic orchestral music]
♪ ♪
[Symphonic techno music]
Sync and corrections by awaqeded
www.addic7ed.com
Narrator: Over a 30-year period,
from 1914 to 1945
more than 100 million people will die
in the bloodiest conflict
the world has ever seen.
But it all began
in the slums of Vienna.
[Thunder booming]
At age 25, Adolf Hitler is a poor loner,
an aspiring artist,
struggling to survive.
Both his parents are dead...
[Thunder booming]
Leaving Hitler truly alone in the world.
He was a lost soul.
He wanted to be an artist,
but he couldn't get into the art school,
and he ended up living in a flophouse.
Narrator: Left without
any means of support,
his only way to make money is
selling paintings around town
for next to nothing.
Hitler didn't have a plan
B when he was rejected.
He just didn't know what to do.
So he started to drift.
He had very little money.
He was living in a hand-to-mouth existence.
He had no clear aim in life at all.
He was, in a sense, waiting
for something to happen.
Narrator: Before long,
a chance event 450 miles away
will change everything.
June 28, 1914.
[Explosion]
An assassin takes down the
Archduke of Austria-Hungary.
The murder ignites a deadly conflict
that quickly erupts into war.
From the tangle of alliances
two sides emerge.
Britain, France, and Russia
become known as the Allies,
while Austria-Hungary,
Germany, and the Ottoman Empire
form the Central Powers.
Filled with a patriotic sense of urgency,
men on both sides rush to join the fight.
For Hitler, it's the opportunity
he's been waiting for.
He quickly rushes to enlist.
He tried out for the Austrian army.
He failed the physical.
He wasn't considered strong
enough to carry a rifle.
Narrator: Rejected by his own country,
Hitler turns to the German army
who's accepting almost anyone
as they worked to build
the largest fighting force
in the world.
[Bells tolling]
Germany has finally given Hitler
what he's always wanted:
A place to belong.
I think that the decision
to enter the military
for most people is not a decision to serve.
It may be in a very general sense,
but it's more often
because something else is motivating you.
Zwei!
Drei!
Vier!
Narrator: Throughout August of 1914,
Hitler trains as a
Private in the German army.
Well, the German army was considered
to be the finest army in the world.
It was a massive force...
well equipped, well trained,
and very well led,
and Hitler was swept away.
Being part of the German army
was something that Hitler deeply loved.
Narrator: The structure of
training transforms Hitler
into a devout German soldier.
Hitler joins 1 1/2 million Germans
marching towards the French border
and the unified Allied forces.
In the history of warfare,
armies this large have never met in combat.
6,000 miles away,
America has nothing to
do with the war in Europe.
They're in their own war
with Pancho Villa.
[Hooves rumbling]
[Gunshots]
The Mexican Revolutionary
is carrying out violent
attacks on U.S. citizens
along the southwestern border.
But he goes too far.
[Gunshots ricocheting]
Villa and his men seize
an American mining train,
brutally killing 16 innocent Americans,
leaving the U.S. military no choice
but to take action.
Nearly 5,000 American troops
cross the Mexican border
to take down Villa.
But fighting a guerrilla
force with a traditional army
is next to impossible.
[Gunshot]
One army Captain is determined
to find a different way.
His name is George S. Patton.
Patton's ancestors fought
in the Revolutionary War;
they fought in the Civil War.
He grew up wanting to be a military hero.
He has a reputation for being smart, tough,
and for being ruthless.
And he has another quality that's essential
in military leadership.
He understands the power of technology,
and he doesn't want to fight
with cavalry and with horses.
He's looking for new technology
that will change the
nature of the battlefield.
So the car is fairly new.
If you strap a gun to a car,
you've got a new instrument of warfare.
Narrator: What Patton doesn't know
is that he's about to
revolutionize warfare.
I think Patton knew only one direction,
and that was forward.
He had a lot of charisma.
He was a very colorful leader.
I thought he was very egotistical,
and that's fine as long
as you translate that
into good leadership.
But maybe a little bit over the top.
Narrator: Almost immediately,
Patton is able to put
his plan into action...
[Motor rumbling]
And he launches a surprise
raid on Pancho Villa's camp.
Faster!
Got 'em on the run. Go!
Get down!
[Gunfire]
Let's go, let's go!
Narrator: The bandits are no match
for Patton and his mobile army,
and by the end of the fight,
three of villa's men have been killed,
including his second-in-command.
The first use of motorized warfare
by the United States army
is a huge success,
and for Patton,
it's the first step in
his rise to greatness.
Half a world away,
two massive armies collide
on the battlefield...
In the first major war
with modern technology.
When you look at World War I,
it's about machine guns, and, you know,
all of these sorts of
new killing mechanisms.
It's the beginning of the
20th century as a tech era.
This is not men on horseback anymore.
This is a motorized war.
Narrator: The advanced
weaponry turns the conflict
into a slaughter.
230 men are killed each hour...
one death every 15 seconds.
Really the machine gun probably
did more than anything else.
They found if they dug
even shallow trenches
and used machine guns,
a small number of troops
could stop a large attacking force.
And then both sides
started to dig trenches.
And so they were locked along
this line, the Western front,
which was this extraordinarily
complex set of trenches
that didn't move very much either way.
[Explosion]
Narrator: The trenches cover 25,000 miles.
Laid end to end,
they would circle the globe.
The area between the trenches is so deadly,
it's known...
As no-man's-land.
Among the German soldiers
stationed in the trenches
along the Western front
is Adolf Hitler.
But even after months on the front lines,
Hitler's still seen as an outcast.
Hitler was regarded by the other troops
as something of a loner,
something of a rather
peculiar eccentric person
who kept to himself.
Narrator: But what
Hitler lacks in popularity
he makes up for in blind ambition.
Runner!
Command wants this taken
to the 3rd Battalion.
- Now!
- Yes, sir.
Hitler's role as a messenger
was actually considered
perhaps the most dangerous task
in trench warfare...
running from trench to trench,
exposing himself to enemy fire.
The mortality rate for messengers
was quite significant.
Pull back!
[Grunts]
[Gunfire]
[Explosion]
[High-pitched ringing]
[Dramatic string music]
♪ ♪
The Germans are retreating,
and Adolf Hitler has been injured,
and he has this encounter
with a Private Henry Tandey,
a British Private.
[Music swells]
Tandey has Adolf Hitler in his sights,
and even though he's a trained soldier,
he can't bring himself to pull the trigger.
If Tandey had pulled the trigger,
Adolf Hitler would have died on
the battlefields in World War I,
and the whole course of human
history would have been changed.
It's one of the great what-ifs in history.
Narrator: The World Wars have begun
with Britain, France, and Russia
squaring off against Germany
and the Central Powers.
[Gunfire]
Modern weaponry is causing mass devastation
on the battlefields,
and tens of thousands of soldiers
are now living in overcrowded trenches.
Very soon after the war began,
both sides realized, "we can entrench,
and the other side can't move us out.
"They can move us backwards a little bit
but only at horrendous cost."
And the result of this,
the war just bogged down in
the muds of northern France.
Narrator: But in London,
one man is convinced he
can break the stalemate.
He comes up to the barman and says...
Narrator: Born into one of the
wealthiest families in Britain,
he's risen through the
ranks at unusual speed...
To become the head of the British Navy.
His name is Winston Churchill.
Churchill had the most
enormous self-confidence,
and it's easy to see why that was the case.
He was the son of Lord Randolph Churchill,
who was a brilliant politician.
And so Churchill, from a very young man,
saw himself, almost by divine right,
as playing a leading role in politics.
Narrator: Churchill forms a bold plan
that he's certain will
change the Allies' fortunes.
He even at that point
considered himself a strategist,
and he looked for ways to break
the stalemate in Western Europe
rather than just to get more
armies and more artillery,
and it actually was fairly thoughtful.
What if we could send a fleet
to the south into the Black Sea?
Resupply the Russians?
Well, yes, exactly.
There's no way.
Well, yes, there is.
Through Gallipoli.
Gallipoli? No.
This is our way in.
With all due respect, we are
here to provide information...
this is what we are doing.
A lot of people Churchill worked with
thought he was a man of contradictions,
a Maverick, a loose cannon.
He was known as someone to watch.
His friends would say someone to watch
because he's very talented,
and his enemies would say someone to watch
because he was dangerous.
Narrator: The Gallipoli peninsula
is heavily guarded by the Central Powers.
Churchill's plan is to blast
through the narrow strait,
Pushing through to Russia and
allowing the Allies to launch
an overwhelming attack from the east,
opening up a second front against Germany.
If it's successful,
the Allies will be able
to turn the tide of the war
and crush the Central Powers.
More than 100 warships set sail
for what will be the
largest amphibious invasion
the world has ever seen.
[Pensive orchestral music]
♪ ♪
People often ask me, "what's the most
difficult decision you've ever made?"
It's always the decision
of sending men into battle,
and the worst part of it all
is the night that the battle begins,
because you know you've
just launched something,
and you know that within a few hours
you will start getting
calls from the battlefield,
from your commanders out in the field,
that will tell you how
many young men have died.
[Telephone rings]
Yes?
They're halfway up the straits.
They should have broken through by now.
They'll make it.
Four ships sunk.
Another burning.
Losses were to be expected.
The fleet is requesting
permission to turn back.
They are to press on at all costs.
This is war.
Gallipoli I don't think
could ever have worked.
The troops who stormed ashore
were met by a hail of machine
gun fire and artillery,
and the casualties were appalling.
Narrator: The invasion
is a devastating failure.
56,000 Allied troops are killed
and nearly 200,000 are
reported injured or missing.
Almost no ground is gained...
And the supply route to Russia
remains closed off.
I think Churchill's
credibility after Gallipoli
was certainly called into question.
Warfare is not a science.
The one thing you do know
when you commit to warfare is,
it's gonna be horrible.
Narrator: The public is
outraged by the carnage.
Someone will have to take the blame.
It's over.
The plan was sound.
Excuse me?
All we needed to do was
keep pushing forward.
I'm afraid your services
as First Lord of the Admiralty
are no longer required.
I'll expect your letter of
resignation in the morning.
When Churchill was let go,
he thought his career was over, finished.
And that wasn't melodrama on his part,
and he could be melodramatic.
It appeared that it would be finished.
It's hard to imagine Churchill
being humbled by something like Gallipoli,
but he was chastened.
He thought, "never again.
"The next time, if there's a next time"...
and it didn't look like there would be...
"I'll do it right."
Narrator: Defeated and humiliated,
Churchill's career is all but ruined.
He's offered a desk job
which he turns down.
He knows if he's ever
going to redeem himself,
he needs a new path.
So Churchill does the unthinkable.
He enlists in the British army...
And heads straight for the front lines.
While Winston Churchill
looks for redemption,
Germany looks to capitalize
on its victory at Gallipoli,
devising a plan to
eliminate the Russian threat
once and for all.
The Germans load a secret weapon
onto a heavily guarded
train headed for Russia.
[Dramatic orchestral music]
♪ ♪
It's a weapon that promises
to destroy their enemies
from the inside out.
[Whistle blowing]
That weapon is Vladimir Lenin.
Lenin is the leader of Russia's
Communist Revolutionaries
hell-bent on toppling the Russian Czar.
For the past ten years,
he's been in exile in Switzerland
until Germany sends him home on a train
along with over $10 million
to fund his revolution.
The Germans decided
that they would take this enormous gamble
and bring Lenin back to Russia
to bring about a revolution
to get Russia out the war.
That's about as radical
a step as you can take.
Narrator: When Lenin gets to Moscow,
he's greeted by an old friend.
Six times he's been exiled to Siberia,
and six times he's escaped.
His name is Joseph Stalin.
Comrade.
Let me show you to your new place.
Narrator: Reunited,
the two play right into Germany's plan
as they begin to plot an armed rebellion.
Over the next few months,
Lenin and Stalin recruit
a massive workers' militia.
Using the $10 million
from the German government,
they quietly amass a
stockpile of weapons...
Until they are ready to make their move.
I've arranged to take the train stations
and the telephone communications.
And the palace guard?
Many of our sources
say they are sympathetic to our cause.
Our timing has to be perfect.
Narrator: The Communists
storm the Winter Palace,
toppling the Russian Czar.
The Soviet union is born.
This is just the beginning, comrade.
Narrator: Just days later,
Lenin signs a decree that
takes Russia out of the war.
The German plan works,
bringing them one step closer to victory.
Narrator: Europe is at war,
and in a bold move, the Central Powers
have ended the fighting
on the eastern front,
sending exiled revolutionary
Vladimir Lenin back to Russia
where he seized control of the country
and took the Russian army out of the fight.
Germany can turn its
attention to the other Allies,
and one of the countries
now forced to fend off
a new wave of German soldiers
is Italy.
Italy joined the fight in 1915
and now must face the full
might of the German army
for the first time.
Tens of thousands of troops
are rushed to defend the
Italian border in the alps.
Among them
is a sharpshooter named Benito Mussolini.
Before the war, Mussolini
is an antiwar activist.
He's a journalist. He's
pretty much a pacifist.
[Gunshot]
Narrator: The time spent
defending Italy's border
makes Mussolini hungry to
return Italy to greatness.
[Gunshot]
Mussolini becomes a very different person
than he was before the war.
His whole attitude toward his nation
and his role in it changes.
He develops this hyper
sense of nationalism,
this real pride in his country.
Narrator: The horrors of war
have transformed Mussolini
into a ruthless killing machine.
A trait he'll take back with him to Rome.
[Gunshot]
600 miles to the north in Belgium,
the British army digs in...
[Gunfire]
Since the beginning of the war,
nearly 400,000 British
soldiers have been killed
just to be replaced by new arrivals.
Among the new recruits
is a man battling back
from the biggest failure of his life...
Winston Churchill.
Churchill took responsibility
for everything he ever did in his life.
He never passed the buck.
He was humbled, humiliated by Gallipoli,
and he had to do something,
and he put himself in harm's way
and volunteered to go to the trenches.
It was a very dangerous thing to do.
[Explosion]
- Move!
- Go!
[Explosions, gunfire]
Sir,
2nd Platoon lost this main trench.
Get me the Mortar Team
from the West Reserve now.
You get the hell scared
out of you first of all.
The first time I got shot at, um, was,
"hey, this isn't a game. This is for real.
This guy really missed me,
and he killed somebody else.
But tomorrow he'll try to kill me."
[Gunshot]
As we say in the military,
that opens your nostrils.
Narrator: With British
casualties escalating,
Churchill is quickly promoted
and discovers he has what it takes
to lead men into battle.
For a man of Churchill's ambition,
it's the first step towards redemption.
In his heart, what
Churchill always wanted to be
was the great warrior, the great hero.
Here he was commanding a mere 800 men,
whereas he dreamed of directing
the battle destinies of millions.
Narrator: The fight seems unending...
Mail!
Narrator: Until Germany
unleashes a secret weapon.
Incoming!
[Explosion, gas hissing]
Gas!
Move! Move!
Out of the way!
Go!
[All coughing]
Go, go, go, go!
The fight between the
Central and Allied powers
has become the bloodiest
war in human history.
By 1917,
nearly 7 million British, French,
and German soldiers have been killed.
- Gas!
- Go.
[All coughing]
It was a war of attrition.
You had to kill as many
of the enemy as you could
so you could possibly advance.
Chemical warfare just enabled that
in a very horrific way.
For a way to alter the course of the war.
So they look to the one country
that could finally tip
the scales in their favor.
Until now, President Woodrow Wilson
has kept America out of the war.
Wilson recognized that the American people
did not want to get involved in a war,
particularly if it's a war
far away involving people
and for causes that we
had nothing to do with.
Frankly, the American
people did not see themselves
at immediate risk.
Narrator: But with hostilities escalating,
a peaceful solution seems
less and less likely,
and Wilson's advisors urge him
to begin preparing military forces.
Among them is the 35-year-old
Assistant Secretary of the Navy
Franklin Delano Roosevelt.
Mr. President, I recommend
an immediate allocation
of more funds to our naval resources
if we want to maintain
military preparedness.
Wilson found himself being
drawn closer and closer to war.
In the spring of 1915,
the British liner the lusitania was sunk,
and on board were over a hundred Americans.
Now, this was a big deal.
Until this time, it
had been a European war.
But now in this European war,
Americans were getting killed.
Narrator: American resentment
grows against Germany,
and on February 26, 1917,
it to finally reaches a boiling point.
Mr. President, I think you
should look at this right away.
Narrator: The United States intercepts
a secret telegram from Germany
intended for the Mexican government
containing a shocking proposal.
The Germans are offering to fund
a Mexican invasion of the United States
that would allow the country
to reclaim the border states
of Arizona, New Mexico, and Texas.
The German ploy was,
preoccupy America with a war with Mexico,
and therefore you keep them out of Europe.
Well, this incensed a lot of Americans,
and rightfully so.
Narrator: The U.S. government
releases the contents
of the secret message,
and almost instantly,
anti-German protests
erupt all across America.
The Zimmermann telegram
was one of the stupidest things
the German government ever did.
Texas didn't care about the war in Europe.
Now all of a sudden,
the Germans are trying
to return Texas to Mexico?
Enough with Germany.
They need to be taught a lesson.
Narrator: President Wilson
signs the declaration of war
in April of 1917.
Germany's plan to keep
America out of Europe
completely backfires.
The Americans may finally be ready for war,
but their military isn't.
The U.S. has a standing army
of only 100,000 men
while the German army has 4 1/2 million.
The United States hurries
to build its military,
and those few with fighting
experience are rushed to France.
George S. Patton
has been presented with a huge challenge...
To command a Battalion of American men
using the latest form
of military innovation...
The tank.
Some American Generals were
really resisting the tank
because they didn't want to
get rid of the horse cavalry.
George Patton understood the
power of the new technology
of mobile and armed warfare,
and he invested a lot in that.
Narrator: The tank is already
being used on the Western front
but with little success.
It runs out of gas too quickly,
gets stuck in the mud too easily,
and its sheer size
makes it difficult to incorporate
in military maneuvers.
But where others see an
insurmountable challenge,
Patton sees a chance
to prove that his tanks
can break the stalemate.
I think innovation comes between the ears.
It's not about the gizmo.
It's about how you think about
using technology and so forth.
You have to give credit
to the people like Patton
that experienced World War I, that had been
thinking about how to employ new things.
Narrator: Patton knows the stakes are high.
[Explosion]
But with his Battalion of tanks,
he's determined to win the war...
[Explosion]
Or die trying.
Narrator: The global war rages in Europe...
[Gunfire]
As the Allies fight to hold their ground
against Germany and the Central Powers...
in the sprawling system of trenches.
Things are ugly in World War I.
Europe was staggered, exhausted,
many cities in rubble.
Starvation and disease were widespread.
You know, the Red Cross
couldn't even keep up
with what was going on.
If you were the Allies in Europe,
you needed the reinforcements...
The new energy, the new blood.
To aid in the fight, the Allies
recruit a new country to their side.
Following their long-awaited
entry into the war,
America is ready to make its presence felt.
Their first major offensive
is an attack on the Western front
hoping to force the Central Powers
out of their trenches
and drive them out of France.
They're armed with a
secret weapon of their own:
A Battalion of lightweight tanks
under the command of
Colonel George S. Patton.
In a column.
We're gonna go down the main road.
Don't let anyone know we're coming.
- We move at dawn.
- Yes, sir!
Patton is testing his new strategy.
He's leading this new
form of weaponry, the tank.
So it's an important battle for him
to prove that tanks are
valuable on the battlefield
and also to establish himself
as an important military leader.
Narrator: For Patton,
everything in his career
has led up to this moment.
George Patton had grown up to be a soldier.
It was his identity.
And so in the first World
War, he is in his element.
[Engines roaring]
[Distant explosions]
Narrator: The night before
the planned invasion,
Patton can't sleep.
Tanks are still unproven in warfare,
and Patton knows he can't
leave anything to chance.
[Explosion, flare hissing]
He slips out of the
trenches totally unprotected,
deep into the heart
of no-man's-land.
He's scouting a route
to ensure his machines
won't get stuck in the mud.
I think when you look at
someone like George Patton,
he used intelligence well
but I think the best thing he did was,
he turned intelligence
into action, very quickly.
George Patton's tendency was for action.
Because he was aggressive,
for him it worked very, very well.
Narrator: On September 12, 1918,
Patton and his forces
sweep onto the battlefield
from every angle...
[Explosions, gunfire]
And the Germans hit back
with everything they've got.
But all of Patton's
intelligence is paying off...
And his Tank Brigade begins
to break down the German line.
Soldier!
- Get on the left flank now!
- Yes, sir.
General, Charlie Company's advancing.
- Take position on the Ridge.
- Yes, sir.
Keep moving! Keep moving!
Lieutenant George S. Patton,
1st Tank Brigade.
Brigadier General Douglas MacArthur,
42nd Infantry.
General, sir, they need you at the front.
All right, boys!
Let's move up!
Patton and MacArthur.
Here they are in Saint-Mihiel,
and they meet on the
battlefield for the first time
in the midst of artillery
shells all around them.
You have these two men
who are going to play
such an important role
in shaping the future of the 20th century,
and they have no idea what
history has in store for them.
Narrator: MacArthur is from
a long line of military men.
His father was awarded the
Congressional Medal of Honor
in the American Civil War.
No less is expected of his son.
Douglas MacArthur would lead attacks
walking out into
no-man's-land with a swagger.
He was embodied with not
only tremendous ability
but also tremendous self-confidence.
Watch the right flank!
From an early age,
he was different.
He was special.
I don't want to say "anointed".
But he may have thought he was.
Narrator: The two West Point graduates
will be allies and rivals for decades.
I don't think there's any question
that a leader who has experienced war
and what it means to be in battle.
If you're a military commander,
that experience is invaluable.
How you try to ensure that
in the midst of all of that chaos
and the killing that's going on,
that you keep your eye on the mission
that has to be accomplished,
that's not easy to do.
[explosions, gunfire]
Narrator: The two men
lead the Allies to victory
as the German line crumbles.
And for the first time,
the Central Powers are on the run.
Just 240 miles away,
years of trench warfare have
transformed Adolf Hitler
from a directionless loner
to a hardened soldier.
[Gas hissing, indistinct shouting]
Hitler has escaped death twice...
[Shouting indistinctly]
Narrator: And it's left him a changed man.
[Coughing]
[Gasping]
[Gunshot]
Hitler didn't feel at this
time during the First World War
that he was a man of destiny at all.
[Gunshot]
What he did feel was a sense of belonging
and a sense of commitment,
and that, I think, made him braver
than he might otherwise have been.
He felt he was fighting in
a really important cause,
the cause of Germany.
[Gunshot]
Narrator: Hitler's ideology
takes root on the front lines.
He begins to believe
in Germany's superiority
over the Allies
and is now certain he can withstand
anything the Allied forces throw his way.
Gas!
[Intense percussive music]
♪ ♪
Narrator: The gas attacks are endless.
To Hitler, they've become almost routine.
But this time it's different.
The Allies hit the Germans
with a deadly new form of chemical warfare:
Mustard gas.
It lingers in the trenches for days.
And attacks both the
respiratory system and the skin.
Mustard gas affects the
central nervous system.
It creates mustard-colored
blisters on the skin.
It blinds people.
It strips away the mucous membranes.
It's incredibly painful and debilitating,
and since it had no odor,
by the time you realized
that you had inhaled it,
and it was on your skin, it was too late.
[Coughing]
Narrator: After three years of bloody war,
the stalemate in Europe has been broken.
The United States has
joined the fighting...
Giving Allied armies a needed boost...
Fire!
Pull back!
Narrator: And driving the Germans
back to their original defensive line
in northern France.
But the German army remains powerful,
meaning the Allies have to act fast.
[Explosions]
Brigadier General Douglas MacArthur
is seeking every tactical advantage.
Military leaders are human beings
that are remarkably different
in personality and background.
Every so often,
someone crosses the constellation
of military leaders
a little bit like a shooting star,
and Douglas MacArthur did that.
Narrator: MacArthur learns
of a surveillance photograph
of German trenches along
the Western front...
[Camera shutter clicking]
That reveals an undetected
gap in the German line.
Where others see an unbreakable defense,
MacArthur knows he can
exploit that weakness.
Intelligence is essential,
and the more you can get, the better.
But at the end of the day,
it's your instinct as a senior person.
The reason we're wearing stars
or have these elevated positions is,
we have demonstrated over the years
our ability to have an instinct that works.
Narrator: MacArthur is determined
to break through the line
and surround the Germans
in their trenches...
Supported by George S. Patton
and his Battalion of tanks.
In the fall of 1918...
Come on! Come on!
Narrator: The Allies
launch an all-out attack
in what will come to be known...
Fire!
Narrator: As the 100 days offensive.
Boosted by MacArthur's men.
And Patton's tanks...
Get a move... move! Move!
Narrator: The Allied armies
become the most dominant fighting force
the war has ever seen.
Press forward!
Both of 'em had big egos,
but there's no doubt that both of them
were brilliant on the battlefield.
Go on, keep advancing!
MacArthur was an extraordinarily talented
and effective military leader.
Fire!
Patton, for what he was asked to do,
which was trying to
break out of the trenches,
there was probably nobody better.
Move! Move!
On, come on! Move!
[Gunfire]
Incoming!
[Explosion]
Move! Move! Move!
[Gunfire]
Narrator: The Allies relentlessly attack
the German line from every direction.
[Gunshot]
[Explosions, gunfire]
Move! Move! Move! Move!
Come on! Come on!
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
[Dramatic orchestral music]
Narrator: After months of fighting,
the Allies finally break through...
[Gunshot]
Putting the mighty German army on the run.
[Indistinct shouting]
[Grunting]
Narrator: Finally, with no other option,
tens of thousands of German soldiers...
Do it now!
Narrator: Lay down their guns...
Hands up!
Narrator: And surrender.
You look at the great leaders.
These were men who understood
the most important resource
they had available to them
to fight a war...
not the weapons, not the planes,
not the tanks.
It's the soldiers who get it done,
and leadership is all about
inspiring your soldiers
to achieve a decisive win.
Narrator: After four years
of continuous fighting
and 37 million casualties,
the two sides agree to a cease fire.
When the world is shaking
and rearranging itself
as it does after a great
events, like the end of a war.
There are a whole range
of different emotions.
The first is exhilaration,
a very personal feeling,
exhilaration at being part of an event
that is changing the world,
and there's never much time to look back.
There's always a lot to look forward to.
Narrator: While most of the world
celebrates the end of the fighting,
some deep in the heart of Germany
refuse to accept defeat.
Hitler was wounded in the gas attack
at the very end of the war,
and he was then hospitalized,
temporarily blinded.
That our people will be losing the war
against the Western armies...
While he was in hospital,
he was then told that Germany
had lost the First World War,
and that's a crucial turning point
in Hitler's life.
In Hitler's worldview,
it was always, um,
dead or alive,
win or total defeat.
For him, surrender was something un-German.
You are a coward,
somehow, if you surrender.
[Tense music]
♪ ♪
Hitler took the surrender personally...
A personal destructive blow to himself.
He also took it as a mission,
a mission in life
to avenge and rectify the surrender.
Narrator: After four long and bloody years
and 37 million casualties,
the United States and the Allies
have finally claimed victory,
forcing Germany to surrender.
But while the fighting has stopped,
the pressure is now on the Allied leaders
to come to an agreement
preventing war from
ever breaking out again.
As negotiations to secure the peace
get underway in France,
massive crowds greet the world leaders...
[Cheers and applause]
Including United States President
Woodrow Wilson.
Woodrow Wilson was the first
President of the United States
to spend anywhere near six months
outside this country,
and he felt that for
him to send anyone else
to negotiate the peace,
it would not have been as well done.
Wilson said, "Whatever happens
with the settlement of this war,
"if it goes well, give me credit.
If it doesn't, blame me."
Narrator: The leaders gather
at the Palace of Versailles.
But one country not invited
to the table is Germany.
Gentlemen, please, please sit down.
If we can start by considering the points
before we discuss any of
the individual ideas...
The main thing
that Woodrow Wilson wanted
to accomplish at Versailles
was defanging Germany,
not allowing them to develop
a huge war machine again.
This was what the victors
all wanted to see happen.
Narrator: But as negotiations get underway,
Wilson quickly realizes
that each country has come to the table
with their own agenda.
There were these national leaders
who had different views of what they wanted
out of the Paris peace conference.
They had led their countries
through this brutal, bloody, long war,
and Wilson waltzes in with the Americans
just at the end.
So they had to listen to him,
and Wilson could be kind of persuasive...
but not that persuasive.
Narrator: As negotiations
drag on for months,
the talks fall apart,
and one Allied nation
feels completely cut
out of the negotiations.
Japan entered the war in 1914,
contributing thousands of troops
and millions of dollars to the war effort.
They come to Versailles with one goal:
To be treated equally.
But Allied leaders completely ignore Japan
throughout the proceedings,
and for Japan,
it's the ultimate insult.
The Japanese, who'd
been on the winning side,
get this slap at the peace conference.
So the Japanese became alienated
from the United States and
from the Western powers,
and it was a fairly
straight line from there
to the belief that,
"if we're gonna get any respect,
it's going to be by fighting
are way to respect.
Narrator: The attention shifts
from Wilson's plan for a lasting peace
to a plan focused on punishing Germany,
forcing them to pay
for the devastation they've caused.
The reparations that
were demanded of Germany
were astronomical.
It was a matter of,
"we're gonna squeeze as much
out of Germany as we can."
Well, there were some on the American side
who said, "we are making
the next war inevitable."
Wilson worked against that.
Wilson wanted a somewhat
more reasonable peace,
and he wanted the Germans
to feel that they had a stake
in the continuation of
the Versailles system.
The problem with the treaty
as it was finalized was,
Germany had no stake in that system.
It had every interest in
overturning the system.
Narrator: Despite Wilson's best efforts,
he is unable to convince the other Allies
to buy into his plan for peace.
After six months of intense negotiations,
the Allies finally have a treaty.
But the final agreement
is far from the fair and equitable plan
Wilson had originally hoped for.
The losers, Germany principally,
they were there.
They didn't get to speak.
They weren't asked to contribute.
They were basically...
they had a gun put at
their heads figuratively...
almost literally...
and said, "you're gonna
sign on the dotted line."
It was very much a Victor's peace.
The victors dictated
the terms of the peace.
They made out like bandits.
Narrator: Europe is finally at peace.
But while most of the world celebrates,
Germany is ordered to pay the Allies
over 80 Billion dollars.
The modern equivalent
of nearly 1/2 a trillion dollars,
a debt they won't pay off until 2010.
As a result,
the government quickly goes bankrupt,
leaving millions of Germans impoverished.
The economic devastation
completely transforms the
country and its people.
Germany immediately is struggling
with a question of survival.
For ordinary Germans,
the war did not end in November 1918.
For ordinary Germans the
battle for survival,
the daily struggle for food,
the effort to find shoes and clothing
stretched on into the 1920s.
Narrator: As the anger
and starvation spread,
tensions rise throughout the country.
[Indistinct shouting]
Germany is in a state of near Civil War.
The left and the right
are fighting with each
other in the streets.
Paramilitary groups clash.
Germany is a country
divided against itself.
When World War I came to an end,
this is not a treaty.
This is an armistice that'll
probably last 20 years...
Meaning we have not really
defeated the German spirit.
We have not really solved this problem.
Narrator: With the fighting stopped,
the treaty for peace
is signed at Versailles.
[Cheers and applause]
And for the first time in over four years,
Europe is at peace.
While celebrations erupt around the world,
Germany is in a state of unrest,
and many are convinced
that the peace won't hold.
Among them is Winston Churchill.
Having just returned to
England from the front lines,
he sets out to reestablish
his political career,
narrowly winning reelection
to his old seat in parliament.
There were a lot of doubts about Churchill.
He seemed erratic in his judgments.
His decision in respect
to the Gallipoli campaign
had disastrous consequences.
But it was in war that he proved
his leadership credentials,
and that's what transformed him.
Narrator: Churchill returns to government
convinced the German
threat hasn't gone away.
[Whistle blowing intermittently]
After leading his troops
to victory in France,
Brigadier General Douglas MacArthur
is given one of the most
prestigious positions
in the armed forces...
- Will you be late again?
- No, sir!
Superintendent of the Military
Academy at West Point.
Where he immediately gets to work
preparing American soldiers for combat
in case the peace fails.
240 miles away
at his tank academy in
Camp Meade, Maryland,
Colonel George S. Patton...
Ready!
Narrator: Is also training
the next generation of American soldiers.
Aim!
Narrator: And like MacArthur,
he's betting the cease-fire won't last.
[Gunshots]
- Fire!
- [Gunshots]
Fire!
- Fire!
- [Gunshots]
[Bells tolling]
Narrator: In Italy,
one man sees the end of fighting
as an opportunity.
Benito Mussolini returns to his job
as a newspaper journalist.
But the country he fought to protect
is now in disarray.
The Italians came out of
the war on the winning side
but failed to gain the territory
they had expected to gain,
and there's a sense of outrage about this
amongst Italian nationalists,
a sense almost that Italy has lost the war
despite being on the winning side.
Narrator: Mussolini uses his newspaper
to convey his view of a new Italy,
that under a strong leader
the country can regain
the glory of the Roman empire.
He believes he can be that leader...
The man who returns Italy to greatness.
He soon brings his
anti-government views...
to a new medium...
radio.
We have actually been at war
since we lifted the flag of our revolution
which was then defended by a handful of men
against the masonic, democratic,
capitalistic world.
Mussolini was a man of strong words.
He liked the idea of overthrowing
existing institutions.
He favored the use of violence to do this.
Narrator: To make his vision a reality,
Mussolini forms a band of
disgruntled former soldiers
called the Blackshirts
who terrorize his political opponents
and begin preparing
for an armed revolution.
In a matter of months,
Mussolini has launched a movement
that is about to change the fate of Italy.
Lance Corporal Adolf Hitler.
Sir.
Sit down.
- So you're looking for work.
- Yes, sir.
I am ready for duty.
I understand.
Unfortunately, I have nothing.
Nothing?
There is no work.
The war is over.
There has to be something.
After all I've done,
after all I've given...
There is a new political group in town:
The German Workers' party.
We need to find out more about them
and what their intentions are.
- Yes, sir.
- Try to not stand out.
The Versailles Treaty caused
the economic conditions
which gave rise to extremism.
You find in history that
when an economy is terrible,
it gives rise to all kinds
of different extremist organizations.
Narrator: Hitler is assigned to infiltrate
the German Workers' party,
one of many anti-government organizations
that have formed in the wake of the treaty.
[Door creaks]
For months, he attends secret meetings
held at undisclosed locations
throughout the country.
They signed away our army.
The Versailles Treaty is not my treaty.
It was as if nothing had happened,
as if we are forgotten.
Narrator: But Hitler soon realizes
they are radical nationalists
intensely loyal to the fatherland,
and many of them harbor extremist views
of German superiority.
Views that are no different from his own.
There was never really an effort
to deal with all the damage
that had occurred during World War I.
The failure to do that
I think is what ultimately
produced the seeds
for Hitler and Nazism.
Germany as a whole is dead.
It has nothing left in its heart.
There are riots on the streets.
There is no Germany left to fight for.
Germany must break apart.
It is only through this
that we can survive.
No Germany?
Yes, there's nothing left to fight for.
"There's nothing left to fight for"
are the famous last words of every turncoat
in the history of warfare.
The weak among us turn to such excuses
and abandon our pride and hope
when it is only unity
that separates the
victors from the defeated.
Clearly you have stopped fighting.
But we are still fighting
Germany's great war, our war,
for what we deserve:
A united Germany,
a strong, proud Germany.
Germany is a sleeping giant,
and once we rid our nation
of the spineless frauds among us
and alongside the criminals of Versailles,
we will once again know greatness.
[Applause]
Narrator: After four years of war,
a tenuous peace holds.
[Birds cawing]
But anger and resentment are spreading...
and shots are about to be fired again.
[Applause]
Adolf Hitler leaves the German army
to fully devote himself
to the anti-government Workers Party.
Our Germany is dead,
and you have conspired...
Narrator: His popularity and fiery rhetoric
make him stand out in the group.
You have bled her with your corruption.
Narrator: And he's promoted
to the head of propaganda.
We will call ourselves the
National Socialist Party!
[Cheers and applause]
Narrator: Under Hitler's leadership,
membership in the National Socialist Party
quickly expands
as Hitler experiences his
first taste of real power.
There are many reports from fairly early on
about Hitler's charisma as a speaker,
and he gradually came to realize
that he was indeed a powerful speaker...
far more powerful than
anyone else around...
and began to use that as an asset.
Narrator: To cast all
Germany under his spell,
Hitler needs an image
that will burn into the minds of millions.
Nowadays we'd call it a logo of course.
It was designed personally by Hitler,
and it may be that he put
some of his artistic impulses into this.
The essential part of it
ultimately went back to India,
but it was taken up as a symbol
of racism and anti-semitism
combined with the red
background for socialism
and the red, white, and black colors
for the old Kaiser Reich.
Narrator: While Hitler is still in
the early stages of his revolution,
Benito Mussolini has already
amassed an army of followers
and is ready to take Italy by force.
For seven days in October of 1922
in a massive show of his popularity.
Mussolini leads a march of
30,000 Blackshirts into Rome.
With the people behind him,
Mussolini and the Blackshirts
storm the Royal Palace,
forcing the King of Italy to hand
over control of the government.
Mussolini came to power in Italy in 1922.
His successful march on Rome
was eased by the process of
expanding ego and adulation
by the people around Mussolini
and then eventually most
of the public opinion
in the country.
This is a dangerous process.
Narrator: In just months,
Mussolini has been transformed
from newspaper journalist
to the most powerful man in Italy.
600 miles to the north,
Adolf Hitler is watching
everything Mussolini has done,
and he wants that same
ultimate power for himself.
So he amasses an army of his own.
Hitler does seem early to have been
very impressed by Mussolini
and indeed by the march on Rome.
His rise to power was modeled on what
the Italian Fascists had done in Italy.
On November 8, 1923,
Hitler leads the Nazis
into a Munich beer hall
where top government officials are meeting.
[Indistinct chatter]
[Gunshots]
Germany is dead,
and you have conspired to kill her!
You have crushed her
with your incompetence.
You have bled her with your corruption.
[Gun cocking]
You have profaned her by consorting
with degenerate peoples.
No more!
The revolution has begun!
Join us now
as we give birth to a new Germany!
You watch him, and you
think of how Adolf Hitler
was able to do that,
to get other people to follow him.
I think it was partly because
he could persuade people that
that was a good thing to do
and partly because people
were intimidated by him.
Narrator: After storming the beer hall,
Hitler leads the Nazis into the streets
to take the city by force.
But unlike in Italy,
the German police are prepared.
Halt!
Ready!
[Guns cocking]
Aim!
Join us!
The National Socialist Party
has taken over the government!
[Gunshot]
[Gunfire]
[Dramatic music]
♪ ♪
Narrator: Unlike Mussolini,
Hitler's attempt to
seize power is a failure,
and he's arrested and charged with treason.
He spends his time in prison
plotting his next move.
[Speaking indistinctly]
[Typewriter clicking]
[Typewriter dings]
Narrator: To gain followers
and to spread his message,
Hitler creates a manifesto...
The heart of which is a radical plan
for world domination.
What we must fight for
is to safeguard the existence...
And the reproduction of
our race and our people.
Narrator: Coming up on The World Wars...
The fighting may have stopped,
but the war isn't over.
[Camera shutter clicking]
Out of a great global depression
a new generation of leader emerges.
We must reverse the Treaty of Versailles.
Let these chains be burst asunder.
[Applause]
Narrator: While some are
desperate to maintain the peace...
None of these people, General,
want me putting money towards the next war.
Narrator: Others rise from the ashes,
looking to re-ignite a great global war.
Hitler is far more dangerous
than anything we've ever faced before!
Bomb every city,
every town,
every village.
We will annihilate them.
Narrator: And as the
fighting breaks out again...
It's not a request! It's a damned order.
Narrator: The fate of mankind
hangs in the balance.
[Gunfire]
It is time to end America's threat
once and for all.
Sync and corrections by awaqeded
www.addic7ed.com