Tom?
Are they coming to help
or to finish the job?
In the jeep... now.
We don't know who blew up that plane.
- (GUNFIRE)
- CHANDLER: There's your answer.
- (ENGINE STARTS)
- Go, go, go!
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
Weapons?!
In the bag.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GRUNTS)
(GUN COCKS)
Look out!
(TIRES SCREECH)
(GRUNTS) (GLASS SHATTERS)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
KARA: Copy.
25 nautical miles off the coast
in vicinity of 2.60
north by 106.94 east.
I just got off the phone
with the Vietnamese.
Eight of their own security team
were gunned down outside a nightclub.
We put the James in Vietnam
to send a message.
Peng just sent one right back to us.
Captain Chandler's plane will be in
secure airspace in less than four hours.
We'll get a better read on
Peng when we talk to him.
(DOOR CLOSES)
The James is safely off
the Vietnamese coast.
They're at EMCON, awaiting
further instructions from us.
Still no word from any
of the missing sailors?
No, sir.
SLATTERY: Who the hell
is in charge here?
Damn it.
My man needs a doctor.
The dressing isn't
stopping the bleeding.
At least let me take a
look at it. (GRUNTS)
Hey, hey, hey. If we're hostages,
you don't want to lose one.
- (GRUNTS)
- Hey, get your hands off her!
(GRUNTS)
I want to talk to the man in charge!
(MEN SHOUTING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE)
Hang in there, Mason.
Hang in there, buddy. We're
gonna get you some help.
Does anyone speak English?
Our man needs help.
- (GRUNTS)
- He needs help!
Don't just stand there!
RIOS: I can help him if you
give me some damn equipment.
(LABORED BREATHING)
SLATTERY: Hang in there, buddy.
RIOS: Just give me some equipment!
Hang in there.
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com
CHANDLER: I say again, this is Zephyr.
Alpha Team, come in.
Anyone from Alpha Team, this is Zephyr.
Are you sure this is
on the right channel?
It's the right channel, and
it's been clear all week.
- Alpha Team, Zephyr... come in.
- We've been operating on EHF.
It's completely secure.
If they're not answering,
it's because Peng took
them out, that mother f...
Hey! You need me to drive?
I'll be fine, sir.
Let's just get out of this hellhole.
(CHEERING)
Hey, no comms in the area.
Phones are still down.
Radios are still FUBAR.
Nothing I can do.
Let's get out of here.
(WOMAN SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
Thank you. That's very sweet of you.
We have to get back to
our ship. Thank you.
We're sticking out like sore thumbs.
We got to get a change of clothes
before we get to the pier.
OOD, any contact on radar or visual?
- No, sir.
- Anything?
No, and local frequencies are clear.
They all had radios,
and not one of them had
a chance to contact us.
- Must've been a very quick hit.
- You were right.
We should've warned them earlier.
It was a tough call.
Okay.
St. Louis said stay offshore,
but they didn't say
we had to sit here with
our thumbs up our asses.
You want to find those three boats?
They disappeared around that bay
one hour before the attack.
If we chase them, we could be
out of position for a rescue.
If our people are on those boats,
we still have a chance to catch them.
OOD, head 1-8-5 toward Do Son.
OOD: Left full rudder...
Steady course 1-8-5.
Damn it. I can't see
shit without my glasses.
I need clamps.
I need clamps! Clamps!
Rags and gauze are not enough.
(LABORED BREATHING)
Green got away.
M-Maybe Burk did, too.
No doubt.
Probably back on the James right now.
They had EMPs.
That's how they cut off the comms.
I know, son. I know.
(DOOR OPENS)
(MAN SHOUTS IN JAPANESE)
(MEN SHOUTING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE)
What are they doing?
Are they taking him?
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
No, no, no, no!
Stop! Stop! No, no!
This man can't be moved!
This man can't be moved! Put him back!
- No! No!
- (GRUNTS)
You son of a bitch!
(MEN SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE)
(LOCK CLINKS)
Maybe they've got a doctor for him.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
BURK: They're looking for us.
I count eight.
They want us alive, right?
That gives us the advantage.
We need a couple of them alive...
if we're gonna find out
where our people are.
Sir?
Shackleton and Hayward are
scheduled to dock in Okinawa
in less than three hours.
I suggest we refuel them immediately
and deploy them to Hai Phong.
Refuel, yes, but we still
might need those ships
to investigate the mutations in Japan.
Let's not forget why we
sent Chandler to Asia
in the first place.
I don't think it's prudent
to send anybody else into the region
till we have a better sense
of the situation, sir.
Uh, Mr. President, someone
took 13 of our people.
Now, I don't care if it's Peng,
the Vietnamese, or pirates.
The James is sitting out
there without its X.O.,
without its C.O.... On its own.
Once the James comes off EMCON,
we're going to need to have
full communication capability.
Audio noise we can deal with.
We're not getting any video.
Val was working on it before she left,
but see what you can figure out.
Okay.
And if you're right,
Alex, if it is Peng,
this could be a trap to get our
only three west-Pac destroyers
in one place.
MICHENER: I agree.
We wait till we hear
from Captain Chandler.
Meantime, nothing leaves this room.
- Understood?
- Yes.
CHANDLER: What makes you
think this friend of yours
will be willing to help us?
She was a pilot for
Doctors Without Borders,
one of the best I've ever seen.
When the plague hit, she
couldn't get out of China,
but she still risked getting infected
to run aid to isolated regions.
Before Peng emerged,
I used my contacts to help her
target the hardest-hit areas.
We smuggled food, fuel,
other provisions.
Once Peng took power and
you delivered the cure,
I slipped into a more diplomatic role.
Jesse did not.
(ELECTRONIC MUSIC BLARING)
Uh, she's a bit paranoid
about new people.
Why don't you hang here?
Let me talk to her first.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
SASHA: Jesse?
Jesse?!
(SIGHS)
You want to do the honors?
Yes, sir.
♪ We all fall down ♪
♪ Ring around the Rosie ♪
♪ Pocketful of posies ♪
♪ Ashes, ashes ♪
♪ We all fall down ♪
♪ Ring around the Rosie ♪
♪ Pocketful of posies ♪
♪ Ashes, ashes ♪ Jesse?
♪ We all fall down ♪
Jesse?
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(AUSTRALIAN ACCENT) Oh, hey, Sasha.
(GRUNTS) Jesus, Jesse!
Who are these? Your goons?
Come to finish the job for Peng?
What are you talking about?
You don't know?
I don't have a clue.
Guangzhou... That little hellhole
no one was supposed to know about.
We show up... It's crawling with PLA.
If you had told me Peng
was moving his missiles,
we wouldn't have walked into a trap!
I didn't have any idea about
Peng moving anything!
Well, it was bad luck for us,
or someone told them we were coming.
'Cause Lau Hu was there waiting.
My brother, all my
friends... Mowed down.
Jesse, I didn't know
anything about that.
You have to believe me.
Believe you?
You already got a deluxe
suite in Peng's mansion.
Or have you moved into the master?
CHANDLER: Hey.
Do you know who I am?
I came here to stop Peng
from hoarding the cure.
Now, he just tried to kill me...
All of us, actually.
I think anyone I'm with at
this point is fair game.
And his MSS are 10 minutes behind us.
I'm very sorry about your friends.
I've lost too many myself.
And as far as I'm concerned,
Peng's been pissing all
over their graves,
but your cover's blown now.
So we should all probably go.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
We need the helo.
(SIGHS)
God damn it.
Let's go.
- Sonar?
- Nothing yet, sir.
And we are clear of land.
WOMAN: We've got something on radar.
- Sonar has it, as well.
- Is it a ship?
It's broadcasting a commercial radar
and identifying it as a
fishing vessel on the AIS,
but it's not one of the three
ships we tracked coming in.
Sonar, give me a set of cans.
Got some engine noise.
That's the same ship that ID'd itself
as the Chinese Class B fishing vessel.
Yes, sir. I believe so, sir.
You can change your call sign,
but not the way your engine rattles.
Gator, tell the OOD to get us closer.
- GATOR: Roger.
- Any sign of those other two ships?
- No, sir.
- It's been five hours.
They could be long gone by now.
Who are they?
I don't think they're Vietnamese.
SLATTERY: Seems like a hodgepodge.
Heard some Thai, some Chinese.
Chinese writing on the
side of the freighter.
You all right, kid?
(CHUCKLING) Yeah, just seasick.
This boat's a lot
rockier than the James.
Hey.
Bend your knees, hold them to
your chest, close your eyes.
Every 60 seconds, open
them again for a 5 count.
Do it again.
4:32.
Been at sea, what?
Figure three hours?
I got us at 12 to 14
knots, holding steady.
Direction?
Based on the roll of the ship,
if the wind's held east,
south, southeast, don't you think?
Away from China.
Away from Vietnam.
Where are they taking us?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(BOAT BEEPS, ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(MEN SHOUTING IN FILIPINO)
All eight are coming.
Let's leave two alive.
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS)
BURK: It's on, Danny boy!
I just killed one!
- (GROANS)
- Now I've got two.
That makes four.
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SPEAKS THAI)
I don't speak that language, douchebag.
(GRUNTS)
Damn it. That's seven.
(GROANS)
Just tell me that last
one is still breathing.
(GRUNTS)
I hold that vessel at 1.3 nautical miles
north-northwest of our current position.
OOD, all full ahead.
Bring her around. Intercept that boat.
We're gonna board it,
and we're gonna find out
where our people are.
(OOD SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Fishing vessel six kilometers southeast
of the Do Son peninsula,
this is U.S. Navy Warship 1-5-1,
two kilometers off your port bow,
hailing you on channel 1-6.
Over.
(STATIC)
Fishing vessel six kilometers
southeast of the...
They're on the move
and increasing speed.
North-northwest, headed 3-4-0.
OOD, adjust course... 3-4-0.
You stay on his ass.
(OOD SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
Hey, can you put out the cigarette?
Are you afraid of lung cancer?
We got bigger problems, right?
MSS 10 minutes behind us?
Could be.
Or not.
I mean, Peng did try to kill us, too,
if it's any consolation.
You're quiet.
Processing.
I know that look.
You're not processing.
You're brooding.
You have to understand, Mr. President,
people have been doing things
a certain way to survive.
Now you want to change all that.
These ration cards are becoming
a very inflammatory issue.
I know it's an adjustment, but
if you've learned one thing
from all this, it's that the
American people are resilient.
BEATTY: They are resilient. (SIGHS)
You do realize that his honeymoon period
- is coming to an end.
- The people support him.
People have a very short memory,
and you got to know that
out there on the street,
it's Chandler and Dr.
Scott who get the credit.
CASTILLO: My wife was
at the market today.
Guy comes into the store,
wants to buy six boxes of cereal.
He's got enough money,
but his rations for the week
say he can only have one.
Then he looks up on the shelves
and sees 300 boxes sitting there.
Half that cereal's going to go stale.
These guys.
They kept their regions together
by their own grit and
mettle for almost a year.
From where they sit,
if the cure would've landed
there instead of here,
one of them would be calling
the shots right now.
That's preposterous.
Beatty was a senator,
and Castillo owned a limousine company.
And Michener was a lowly
cabinet Secretary.
Approved by Congress, which
makes him the president.
He's unelected.
And let's not forget, he's an immune.
MICHENER: I know your constituents
don't want to hear it,
but it's an issue of
hoarding versus sharing.
If this guy has more than he needs,
he needs to be sending it to
places without the resources.
(SIGHS) We're doing what
we can, Mr. President,
but you're asking people to
change their core beliefs
about how our society should function.
- (DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
- Rationing is just not in the American DNA.
I hear what you're saying, gentlemen.
Captain Chandler's plane
is supposed to be over clear air space,
but we cannot reach the plane.
We tried Sasha Cooper and our
security team in Hong Kong.
We cannot raise them, either.
When are they due to
land in Pearl Harbor?
5 1/2 hours.
Our ships are refueling
in Okinawa as we speak.
Let's not go there yet.
Just keep trying the plane.
Yes, ma'am.
- Hold your horses, Alex.
- You may not want to admit it,
but he's got problems here at home.
How he handles this issue abroad...
It's gonna have to be with strength.
I understand your concerns, gentlemen,
but you're gonna have to be patient.
The course has been decided.
CAMERON: Where's that boat?
GATOR: Still 60 miles south-southwest.
I hold that vessel at 30 knots.
Stay on them.
30 knots? That's no fishing vessel.
They're headed for Cat Ba Pass.
That's too narrow for us.
If we come around this island here,
we might be able to cut
them off at daybreak.
OOD, left full rudder.
We'll intercept them on the other side.
Left full rudder!
Peng's got patrols all
over these waters.
This is how she keeps it off the radar.
Once we get to Kowloon,
I have a van stashed on the other side.
Let's hope for your
sake it's still there.
- For your sake, too.
- Doesn't bother me.
I got nothing to live for.
Well, hey, we've all lost
pretty much everything.
And if you really want to hurt Peng,
this should be the only
thing that matters to you.
- (MAN SPEAKING CHINESE)
- Hey!
(SPEAKS CHINESE)
Back at the apartment,
you asked me to wait in the hall.
You were trying to get to her
first to keep her quiet.
It wasn't just food
and fuel before Peng.
It was cure.
And it was well after Peng...
While you were working as a diplomat.
(SIGHS)
I stopped a few weeks ago
when I thought it might
be getting too hot.
She's been pissed at me ever since.
Does Rivera know? The president?
No, of course not.
I would never jeopardize them like that.
Always got to do things your own way.
Sasha knows best.
They needed deniability,
and it's not like I even
could've told them anyway.
You know there's no secure comms
from Hong Kong to the States.
You do realize that may
be why my people got hit.
You think Vietnam was retribution
for what I've been doing with Jesse?
My plane, too.
If Peng knew anything about this,
he would've strung me out by my
balls the second he found out.
Like you said, he plays the long game...
and he was gonna kill you
as soon as I took off.
I'm sorry about your people, Tom...
but I promise you
there is something much
bigger going on here
than me and that girl smuggling
cure across the borders.
(GRUNTS)
(SPITS)
(GROANS)
Are we even sure he's Vietnamese?
This blade's got some other
kind of writing on it.
CAMERON: We're coming into open water.
Tell me we have eyes on that boat.
I'm picking them up now.
I hold them bearing
2-7-0 at 6,000 yards.
They're threading the islands.
Charted depth here is 14 feet.
Damn it.
Bare steerage, OOD.
All ahead... 1/3 for 3 knots.
Lost them again.
They're gone.
(SIGHS)
CHANDLER: So, I hear
you're quite a pilot.
How long till we meet
this helo of yours?
You're getting a little impatient.
I had other plans for myself today.
WOLF: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's this?
JESSE: Welcome to Hong Kong.
(BRAKES SQUEAL)
I've never seen a checkpoint here.
It's for us.
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
Eat.
Eat! Eat!
Filet mignon and apricots?
When they took me to
the bathroom before,
I could see the rest of their crew.
They were eating beans out of a can.
(RAY VOMITS)
Sorry, guys.
We got to get him some fluids.
He needs water. Water.
Yeah, a little clean-up
wouldn't hurt, either.
Water. Huh?
(SPEAKS JAPANESE)
- JETER: What are you doing?
- (GUNS COCK)
- Hey, hey!
- (INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
- What are you doing?
- Leave this kid alone.
He's a kid! He just wants water!
Leave him alone! He's just a kid!
TOSHIRO: We take your
man to get fresh air.
Now... you eat.
(SPEAKS CHINESE)
(MEN SPEAKING CHINESE)
(GRUNTING)
Get down!
Jesus, Sasha. I said get down.
And I heard you.
(GRUNTS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
Just a bunch of random stuff.
I can't figure out where they're from.
How are you doing?
I'm fine. It's him I'm worried about.
(LABORED BREATHING)
Get medieval on his ass.
I'll wait.
(GASPING)
He's going into shock. Hey! Hey!
Stay with me! Stay with me!
He's... losing... blood.
He said you're losing blood.
What? You speak English?
He won't like that.
Who the hell is he talking about?
Who? Who won't like that?
Who do you work for?!
Who sent you, huh?!
(SCOFFS)
Damn it!
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION IN DISTANCE)
Headed south now, I think.
Feels like we're just
turning in circles.
They don't want us to know where we are.
Unless they're not taking us anywhere.
Unless they're keeping us here.
(BRAKES SQUEAL, ENGINE SHUTS OFF)
Sit tight, kids. Be back in a jiff.
(DOOR CLOSES)
We left a lot of bodies back there.
How long till MSS is on our trail?
Checkpoints send reports
every half hour.
When Peng doesn't hear from them,
he'll send reinforcements.
This is an irradiated zone.
There's a nuclear power
plant six miles inland.
And there was a leak?
More of a meltdown.
Few months back.
No one could sustain
the safety protocols.
So this is where she keeps her helo?
Takes nine minutes to get in there.
Gives us 11 minutes to
get the bird in the air
before the radiation kills us.
11 minutes?
More or less.
Sir, I'm on the phone with Pearl Harbor.
They can't find the plane
anywhere on their radar.
It's not answering their
radio calls, either.
Mr. President, there's an
incoming call from Hong Kong.
It's President Peng.
President Peng.
Mr. President, I understand
it is very late there,
so I am sorry to add to
your troubles in Vietnam.
No. No.
Do you have some news for us?
I'm afraid I do.
It seems that Captain Chandler's plane
had some very serious engine trouble
as it tried to take
off from our airport.
Unfortunately, the plane went down.
Plane went down?
Are there any survivors?
We are searching the waters now...
but we are not hopeful.
We walked right into this.
It is certainly suspicious,
Mr. President,
with what happened in Vietnam.
As I have told you,
there are many rogue elements
operating in the region.
We suspected pirates at first,
but your pilot radioed
in with engine trouble.
We are sending the transmission now
between your pilot and
our air traffic control.
Yes. Obviously, we'd very much
like to hear that recording.
I assure you we will conduct
a thorough investigation
and keep you fully informed.
Well, we appreciate
that, President Peng,
and we will speak soon.
(RECEIVER CLICKS)
You're not buying that, are you?
I'm not jumping to any conclusions,
and neither should anyone in this room.
Let's hear that transmission.
WOLF: You stole a Chinese army helo?
We're in China. What did you expect?
What's the range on this thing?
About 600 miles.
Just enough to get us to Hai Phong.
Depending on the winds.
You okay? Just a bit nauseous.
Might be a good idea we get out of here.
JESSE: All right, buckle up.
- Grenade launchers?
- Can't be too careful.
(ENGINE SPUTTERS) Shit.
Oh, you're bloody kidding me.
Hot start?
Get the battery and the
alligator clips out of the car.
You can't jump a 28-volt
battery with 12 volts.
There's an old pickup on the
other side of the generator.
We can use that.
(COUGHING)
MSS is coming.
- You need a daisy chain?
- Yeah.
I'll buy you some time.
- (TIRES SCREECH)
- We're clear!
(ENGINE SPUTTERS)
My turbines still aren't
spinning fast enough.
(ELECTRICITY ZAPS)
Can't hold them off much longer!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
- Try it now!
(ENGINE STARTS)
JESSE: I've got the generator online.
Pull the pins and get
your asses in here.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(TIRES SCREECH, MEN SPEAK INDISTINCTLY)
You all right?
You don't happen to have
a Geiger counter on you?
Feels like it was last week
we were standing under that arch...
spreading the cure.
(CLEARS THROAT)
It's possible Peng's lying.
You heard the transmission
from the cockpit.
(SIGHS)
Our Air Force captain
confirmed the voices.
(SIGHS)
GATOR: We're currently 16
miles out of position, sir.
Damn it.
OOD, any visual?
- OOD: Negative, sir.
- Anything?
There's no sign of them or our people.
We need to return to
position for a rescue.
Never should've gone
to that stupid party.
All the senior leadership
off ship at the same time.
We were on a diplomatic mission.
Cameron is more than capable.
Burk and Green will find them,
and they'll find us.
Flares starboard side...
Green, red, green,
bearing 3-5-0, but they're
at least 10 miles out.
That's our sequence, and
they're on the move.
TAO, give me full radar and
sonar sweeps of the area.
OOD, make course along that bearing.
Right standard rudder,
steady course 3-5-0.
You better be right about that ship,
'cause we're running low on fuel
and in the next 10 minutes,
we're gonna be in the drink.
SOP says they'll be within a
20-mile radius of Hai Phong.
We got to be within radio range by now.
Don't bother. It's busted.
Suitable extraction points
would be here, here, and here,
but it's gonna take at least 20
minutes to close the distance.
Hey, Burky, where the hell are they?
They should be closer to shore.
New surface contact bearing
0-4-0 at one nautical mile
heading 2-4-5 at 35 knots.
Bridge, TAO.
AIS signals confirmed.
Hostile vessel is back.
All fire stations manned,
ready to engage on your mark.
Birds with five inch, sir.
Negative, TAO. We do not fire.
There could be hostages onboard.
Recommend adjusting course to intercept.
Cut them off before
they get to our people.
Agreed. OOD, make course 0-2-0.
- All engines ahead flank.
- OOD: Aye, sir.
- Helm, right standard rudder.
- They're going towards those islands,
closing in on our people.
CCS, override all safeties.
Enable battle short. We'll cut them off.
(ALARM BLARING)
Time to rethink your travel plans.
Tell me your radar works, at least.
- Don't touch that.
- Sasha.
Your ship will identify us as Chinese.
They'll think we're
trying to attack them.
You don't think I know that?
- There has to be another way.
- One problem at a time.
Are you two sleeping together?
Turn it on.
Unknown aircraft approaching from 0-8-0.
110 knots.
Sir, we have incoming.
Appears to be a Chinese helo.
We got the James.
She's 10 miles out, due west-southwest.
SASHA: What are you doing?
Saying hello.
Aircraft just changed her squawk.
1-2-0-9. 1-2-0-9?
Does that mean something to you?
- ALISHA: No, no. That can't be.
- What is it?
I-It's the CNO.
That's his birthday... December 9th.
He'd sometimes use that as his ID tag.
CNO? Here? On a Chinese helicopter?
30 seconds before we lose the contact.
Hail our guys on that boat.
Let them know they got trouble.
(GROANS)
DANNY: Hang in there, buddy!
We're almost home.
Distress warning, 1:00.
I'm guessing red's not good.
No.
Looks like two of our boys
down there on a speedboat.
They're being pursued!
We need to help. Keep moving.
We're running on fumes. We need to land.
I said keep going!
Oh, heads up!
Heads up!
Get us in closer.
Cover fire!
BURK: They're gaining on us!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Yes! Yes!
(MAN SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE)
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com