- Previously on The Tudors.
- [Henry VIII]:The King
of France
has demonstrated
his aggressive policies.
He has our Ambassador
murdered in cold blood.
These are all
just causes for war!
- As a humanist I have
an abhorrence of war.
- As a King,
I'm forced to disagree.
Why is Henry V remembered?
Because he won the battle
of Agincourt.
That victory made him immortal.
- He has no right to any
of this. I'm a direct
descendent of Edward II.
This is my crown and my court.
Not his crown or his court.
- Treason your Grace.
- What if your Majesty
could gain more power
by peaceful means?
- Which is...?
- Treaty of universal
and perpetual peace.
- The Treaty is entirely
new in the history of Europe.
- [Queen]: You have not answered
my nephew's letters.
He advises you not to heed
everything Wolsey tells you.
- You are not my Minister.
You are not my Chancellor.
But my wife.
- About the other
matter we discussed.
- Which other matter?
- I saved your Master's arse.
Now I want my reward.
And you can
arrange it.
- [Queen]: I cannot give
the King a living son.
The King blames me,
he thinks it all my fault
and now he does not
come to my bed.
- It says if a man marries
his brother's wife
they die childless.
But you have a child.
- But not a son.
- I am with child.
tdIt is his Majesty's.
- There is to be a summit
between King Francis
and King Henry near Calais.
That means you will both have
the opportunity to meet
the King of England.
[Laughing]
Mary and Anne Boleyn.
- Pope Alexander
is desperately ill.
I can assure the support
of the French cardinals,
you will
be elected Pope.
- It's time. My father planned
to assassinate Richard III.
He would come before him with a
knife secreted about his person.
Your Majesty.
[Yelping]
[Laughing]
- [King]: I can't wait for
the summit. We'll change
the world forever.
You and I will be immortal.
- You think you know a story.óRk:
But you only know how it ends.
To get to the heart
of the story,
You have to go back
to the beginning.
***
mVñT//($F(6÷a
- Halt.
- There it is!
Val D'Or...
The Valley of Gold.
- What if the French don't show?
- Oh, they'll show.
They'll just be
fashionably late.
Your Majesty, look!
There they are.
- Au pas!
- What's the plan?
- I was to ride down aloneí]|k
and meet the King.
- It's a trap.
What if they mean to lure you
down there to kill you?
- All of you!
On pain of death!
Stay!
- The King!
- Cousin.
Bienvenue en France.
- After you.
- Mais non.
After you.
- How do you like my beard?
- You almost look French,
you know?
[Laughter, voices & music]
- Hear ye! Hear ye!
I, Henry, by the Grace of God,
King of England, Ireland and
France, do hereby--
- Stop.
I cannot be that
while you are here,
for I would be a liar.
During this summit I am simply
Henry, King of England.
- J'apprécie
énormément.
- And I am just...
François,
King of France
and Burgundy.
[Applause]
- Your Majesties, may I ask
you each to place a hand
upon the Holy Bible,
and swear before God
and these Princes
and Lords here gathered,
that you will be true,
viiSrtuous, and loving
toach  eother.
- I so swear.
- Moi aussi.
I swear too.
Of course.
[Trumpets]
[Applause]
- Princess Mary, may I introduce
Prince Henri Philippe,
your future husband.
- Are you the Dauphin of France?
- Oui.
- Then I want to kiss you.
- Maman! Maman!
- Mon Dieu!
- Mary.
- I have got to get
one of these.
- The Palace of Illusions.
What do you think?
- It's incredible,
your Majesty.
- It's only painted canvas.
- But real wine!
- Don't drink too
much of it Charles!
[Fencing]
- And now I have a gift for you.
- Ah!
[Applause]
- You embarrass me, brother.
- Oh no.
And all I can give you
in return is this pastry.
[Chirping & reactions
of surprise]
- Très amusant.
***
- What are you thinking,
Charles?
- I'm thinking that,
while I'm here,
I should behave like
the King of France.
- Which means?
- Which means...
I shall slip readily
into the gardens of others
and drink water
from many fountains.
- Do you see that
young woman over there?
Dressed in purple and gold?
- Yes.
Her name is Mary Boleyn,
the daughter of your Ambassador,
with her sister Anne.
I call Mary my English mare
because I ride her so often.
- Ha!
- Ah! Gentlemen.
Monsieur.
- Hurry! Hurry!
We need 2 more barrels!
[Chattering voices]
- Excellence.
- Papa.
- King Henry
noticed you today.
He wants to see you.
- Wait!
I must go and tell Anne.
Anne.
[Whispering]: The King...
[Angelic male singing]
- * Lo li lo lay *
* Lo li lo lay *
* The falcon hath borne *
* My maid away *
- What's your name, boy?
- Thomas Tallis,
your Majesty.
- Tallis.
Good voice.
[Sighing]
Take a sovereign for your song.
- Thank you, your Majesty.
[Chattering continues]
- Ah, Boleyn.
- What of Buckingham?
- In my presence he has railed
against your Eminence,
calling you
a necromancer, a pimp,
accusing you of using
evil ways to maintain
your hold over the King.
- And what did Lord Buckingham
say about the King?
- He told me he has a greater
claim to the throne,
and that as his Majesty
has no male heirs,
and will have none,
that he, Buckingham,
will succeed to the throne.
But he also told me once
that he has considered
bringing that eventuality
forward more quickly.
- In what way?
- By assassinating his Majesty.
- You did well to come to me.
But I must warn you,
say nothing of this to anyone.
[Cheering and yelling]
- Bravo.
- You see that,
brother?
In most things,
we French excel you.
We have the
greatest painters,
the greatest musicians
and the greatest poets.
Most of whom, by the way,
live at my court, Dieu merci.
The greatest
philosophical minds,
engineers, architects.
And of course,
we have the most
beautiful women.
You won't deny that,
will you?
Even our wrestlers
are better than yours!
- Are you sure?
- What?
- I said are you sure?
All your wrestlers
are better than mine?
Do you want to prove it?
- What are
you suggesting?
- I am challenging you to
a wrestling match, brother.
- Non, David.
- You're a coward.
- Merde!
French honour is at stake.
I accept your challenge.
Parce que tel est
notre bon plaisir.
Let's do it now.
- Groom!
- Alors ça commence!
- Your Majesty...
- No.
- Your Majesties...
Gentlemen...
The rules are as follows:
the first man to throw
his opponent
to the ground
shall be declared the winner.
Are you content?
- Yes.
- Then fight on!
- What bet will you lay?
- Go, Henry.
- 2 Kings, 2 Queens and a Fool.
- Who's the Fool?
- I don't know yet,
but it's a full house.
- Come on, your Majesty!
- Henry's gonna win.
- Whatever happens,
he's not gonna win.
- Go, Henry!
- Come on!
- Yes!
- Ha! Ha!
- I want a re-match!
I want a re-match!!
Are you afraid?
Are you afraid of a re-match?
- Are you calling me afraid? Of
what am I supposed to be afraid?
- Of me!
- Let's have it then...
- I'm not going to sign
the treaty!
- Ha! Ha! Ha!
- I'm not gonna sign it!
Go and tell them!
- Alright if that's what--
- I said...
Go and tell them!
- Alright!
If you want the wod rlto think
that the King of England is
easily changeable, shallow,
intemperate, incapable
of keeping his word
then of course,
I will go tell them.
After all, I am merely your
Majesty's humble servant.
Rns|
- Lady Mary.
- Your Majesty.
- I've heard
a lot about you.
You've been at the French
court for 2 years.
Tell me...
What French graces
have you learned?
- With your Majesty's
permission?
- Granted.
7"]
- Ah!
[Choir]
- And now I ask his gracious
Majesty, the King of England,
to also sign, in good faith,
the Treaty of Universal
and Perpetual Peace.
"J0
[Applause]
[Choir continues]
[Screaming]
32M6EA
- Leave.
Forget about the French.
The Queen's nephew's
been electd.e
Now he's not only Charles V,
the King of Spain,
he's also
the Holy Roman Emperor!
His dominions are vast,
his wealth extraordinary.
And he's only 20 years old.
You will make arrangements
to visit him at Aachen.
Personally.
It may suit us better to do
business with him,
than with the French.
- Yes, Majesty.
- Sir Thomas Boleyn, your Grace.
- Your Grace I--
- What did you thinks|
of that performance?
- I...
- Don't be stupid!
You're not stupid. The King's
performance! At the summit!
How did it strike you?
- Personally, I would have
wished to seen a greater
more powerful man upon
the throne of England.
Someone whose very presence
would have made the French
sit up and come to heel.
- I have the way
and the means
to crush the usurper
of my throne
as one would crush
a revolting spider.
I will
make him wish
that he had entered the Church
after all and left the affairs
of the state to those
who are born to rule!
If you betray
me Boleyn,
I'll feed
your body to my dogs.
- Now...
What have you
discovered here?
- I have it on
good authority...
that the Duke of Buckingham
is raising an army.
He says it's
to protect him while
he tours his Welsh estates
where he's not popular.
He's also been borrowing
large sums of money.
- Buckingham.
Invite him to court,
for the New Year.
But don't say anything
to alarm him.
tq
How are your children?
- They're well,
thank you, your Majesty.
I encourage them all
at their studies.
Even the girls.
- Always the idealist.
- At some point,
I imagine,
it will be considered
ordinary enough,
and nothing strange
for a girl to be educated.
- I've received a gift.
From the Duke of Urbino.
It's a book called
The Prince, by a Florentine,
Niccolo Machiavelli.
- Yes I know it.
It's about
political opportunity.
[Chuckling]
- It's true...
It's not like your book, Utopia.
It's less... utopian.
Nevertheless he asks
an important question
whether it is better for a King
to be feared...
Or loved.
Buckingham is going
to try and kill me.
[Crackling fire]
- Your Eminence.
- Lady Blount.
You are full term?
- In a little while.
- Are you well?
- As can be expected.
Have you some message
from his Majesty?
- No. None.
But from your husband.
- My husband?
- Yes, I have spoken
to him.
He finds that he is...
Reconciled to your condition.
- Then he won't send me
to a nunnery?
- He will be
made an Earl
and be given estates.
- And my child?
- That is for the King to decide
whether he will
recognize the child.
I'm afraid I can offer you
no more comfort than that.
- Will you tell the King
of my love for him?
***
- My Lord, I hereby pledge
my allegiance to you
and your house
and do swear to serve you,
even unto death.
- We thank you from
the bottom of our heart.
And in due course, you will find
your loyalties richly
and properly rewarded.
- I thought
I should tell you.
I am being sent to meet
the new Holy Roman Emperor.
The King has asked me
to draw up a new treaty,
uniting us
against the French.
- You must be
very disappointed.
- I am very realistic.
- Then I am disappointed.
- Our dreams were
very unrealistic.
- Maybe so.
But I will continue
to dream them,
even if I am alone in doing so.
I fear his
Majesty no longer...
Trusts or cares for me
as he once did.
- Thomas, let me give
you a little advice.
If you want to keep
the love of a Prince,
this is what you must do:
you must be prepared
to give him the thing you most
care for in all the world.
- The thing I care for most
is my integrity.
What is it you care for most in
the world, your Eminence?
***
- [Lord]: Make way for the great
Duke of Buckingham!
- His Grace,
the Duke of Norfolk.
- Your Grace.
- I hope your majesty will
accept this humble gift
for the New Year.
- We are very grateful
to your Grace.
Your generosity
overwhelms me.
As always.
[Woman screaming]
- [Nurse]: Lie down.
Get some minions.
- His Grace,
the Duke of Buckingham.
(Z
- Your Grace.
- Your Majesty.
It...
Has some words engraved on it.
- Give it to me.
"With humble,
true heart".
Your Grace
overwhelms me.
Your words touch me.
They are the greatest gift;
greater than any riches.
***
[Screaming]
- [Nurse]: Push. Breathe.
It's coming.
[Screaming and baby crying]
[Ticking]
- "With true and humble heart."
- There!
Hold your Grace!
- What do you want?
- Your Grace is arrested
on suspicion of treason.
çI am ordered
by|0 the King's Majesty
to take you to the Tower.
- You take my advice, gentlemen,
you let us pass.
- [Knivert]: By no means.
And if any of your men
should strike
against his Majesty's servants
in pursuit of their duties,
that is treason too, as
your Grace should know.
- Your Grace?
- You are only new men.
You don't know anything.
If I'm accused of treason,
I should be judged
by a jury of my peers,
not by the dogs of butchers.
There's no Lord in England
who'll ever find against me!
[Neighing]
- Form them up!
- I have instituted
a Court of High Steward
to judge
Buckingham's case.
20 peers will be
appointed to the court.
Norfolk will be
first among them.
- Your Majesty, if I may...
- What?
- I believe
it could be dangerous
to find the Duke
guilty of treason.
- Even if he is?
- Even if he is.
On the other hand,
he could be found guilty
of some lesser offence,
heavily fined
and banished from court.
In that way
45i[he would be
disgraced but his friends
and allies would have
little cause or occasion
to rise against you.
- And that would be
the best outcome?
- I believe it would, yes.
- And you would see to it that
the court came to that decision?
- I have every confidence.
- As I have in your Eminence.
[Applause]
Wolsey will set up the court.
Norfolk will head it.
I want you to remind his Grace
of his responsibilities.
- 40-30!
Chase to full, gentlemen.
s|- Bull!
- Mary?
- Does the King still
call for you at night?
- No papa.
- [Norfolk]: Even though
the King is your Godfather
when you approach him...
- Your Grace.
- What do you want?
- Only to pass on
his Majesty's love.
He appreciates
the role you will play at
my Lord Buckingham's trial.
And for all the care
you have for
his Majesty's well being.
He also sends you this.
- This is my father's ring.
He was executed by his Majesty's
father, did you know that?
- His Majesty thought
you might like to wear it.
Is this your son?
- Yes it is. He is going to be
received by his godfather.
The King.
- Your Grace should have a care
for his inheritance.
It would be terrible, for
example, if some action of yours
were to deprive him
of a father, a title and a ring.
Your Grace.
- Your Grace
has been accused
of treason and of imagining
and plotting the death
of the King's Majesty.
This court of High Steward,
after reviewing all the evidence
against your Grace...
finds your Grace...
guilty of the charges
against you.
[Reaction from crowd]
- No.
- And so... sentences your Grace
to death,
at his Majesty's pleasure.
- This is your doing!
You butcher's dog!
It's all... your doing!
[Screaming]
Bastards!
***
[Ticking]
- Your Majesty.
[Neighing]
- What!? Yes!
Woo! Ha!
***
[Murmur of voices from crowd]
- God bless you, sir.
- Take this your Grace.
[Reciting of prayer]
- Do you forgive me?
- Your Grace must lie down.
[Audience shouting]
- When you stretch out
your arms, I will strike!
Stretch out your arms.
[Baby crying]
- I have a son.
I have a son.
Thank God.
[Cackling]
- Come on you coward.
- I have a son!
Ha! Ha!
I have a son, God!
Can you hear me?
I have a son!
[Fireworks screaming
& trumpets piping]
[Cheering & applause]
- Your Majesty
is to be congratulated
on such a happy event.
- Thank you, your Eminence.
The Lady is upstairs.
- Henry, congratulations.
- Thank you Charles.
I always knew
it wasn't my fault.
- No.
- His Majesty has decided
to recognize his son.
He will be known for
the present as Henry Fitzroy.
He will have his own
establishment at Durham House,
with a chaplain, officer
and a retinue
befitting his station.
- Thank you.
- You should write
and thank his Majesty.
I only do his bidding.
- The Queen!
The Queen!!
[Fireworks continue]
@?@A"
- To my son!
[Cheering]
[Prayer]
- What was your deal
with Wolsey?
- In return for England not
going to war with France,
I promised him
the French vote.
- The fact is, Wolsey
has gone to Aachen to
meet the new Emperor.
He obviously means to break
the Treaty with your King.
- In which case...
We are no longer obliged to
deliver our side of the bargain.
[Reciting latin prayer]
Corpus Domini nostri
Jesu Christi.
- In any case,
we don't want an English Pope.
We
had one once.
He was insane.
Never again.
The Pope must
be an Italian.
That is God's will.
- Your Holiness must swallow it.
- Push it!
[Taking last breath]
[Church bells ringing]
u,k(
[Choir singing]
- My Lady, full of Grace,
I pray you, I beseech you.
In all humility
for the love I bear for you
and for your son Jesus Christ.
I pray you...
Give me a child.
A son to fill my empty womb.
I beg you...
- In a few weeks
the court will quit
Whitehall for Hampton Court.
There's been
an incident
of the Sweating
Sickness in the city.
You know how afraid
the King is of any illness.
- How is the King?
I was sorry to hear of
Cardinal Orsini's
election as Pope.
You are perpetually
sorry, More.
- I wasn't simply being polite.
- Oh, really?
- I was not.
As long as there is such blatant
corruption in the Church,
that heretic Luther
will continue to gain followers.
I know that if your Eminence
had been elected, you
would have wkedor
tirelessly to cleanse the Church
of all its evil practices.
- Perhaps you think
too highly of me, Thomas.
Perhaps, you think too highly
of the whole human race.
- Lady Blount.
- Mr. More.
- The Queen!
- My Lady.
- Uncle.
- Anne.
- Sweet Anne.
- Yes, Papa.
- You know why you are here?
- No, Papa.
In Paris,
no one explained.
- Good. It's better
that way.
- What's happened?
- His Majesty is tiring
of his French alliance.
It seems he is also
tiring of your sister.
He no longer
invites her to his bed.
- Poor Mary.
- Poor us!
When she was his mistress
all our fortunes were made.
Now most likely
they will fall.
Unless...
- Even if he had me,
who is to say he would keep me?
It's not just Mary.
They say that all
his liaisons are soon over.
He blows hot, he blows cold.
- Perhaps you could imagine a
way to keep his interest more...
Prolonged?
I daresay you learned
things in France?
How to play
his passions.
There's something deep
and dangerous in you, Anne.
Those eyes of yours are like
dark hooks for the soul.
- How was your meeting
with the Emperor?
- Good. Productive.
He makes no secret of his
antipathy for the French.
He wants to go to wa
for an alliance
with your Majesty.
- And in return for
our alliance?
- There will be a joint
invasion of France
for the overthrow
of King Francis.
- And I shall claim the crown
***
and once more truly be King of
England, Ireland, and France,
just like my forefathers.
Your Eminence, has built
the most beautiful palace.
- Thank you,
your Majesty.
- Probably the finest
house in England.
I have nothing
to compare with it.
Nothing to show more fair.
- Your Majesty,
it is yours.
- With the furnishings?
[Laughing]
Come on!