Previously on "Vikings":
Why do you not go home?
By staying you've given me time
to raise a large army.
Thorvard: Your lands are
lost, invaded by Jarl Borg.
Your family has fled
only the gods know where.
I must find my family.
If I can be of help
to king Horik
Then I'm happy to stay.
Then so be it.
Your friends will be leaving
at first light.
Ealdorman Werferth:
Their forces have divided,
Four of their ships
have sailed away.
- (arrow strikes)
- Aghhh! Ugh!
Bishop Edmund:
Here is your destiny, apostate!
King Ecbert:
Wait! Cut him down.
Jarl Borg: I'm happy that
Ragnar Lothbrok has returned.
I will kill him!
(cheers erupt)
Rollo: We have no chance
at defeating Jarl Borg.
Ragnar:
Then we find more men.
Rollo: There are no more to find.
I have tried.
It has been a long time.
Hello, Ragnar.
♪♪
♪ More, give me more ♪
♪ give me more ♪
♪ if I had a heart
I could love you ♪
♪ if I had a voice I would sing ♪
♪ after the night
when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see
what tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I... ♪
♪ if I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪♪
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
(warriors chatter,
horses snort and whinny)
(door creaks open)
(chickens cluck)
(sheep bleat)
Lagertha, you're the last person
I expected to see here.
You and your warriors
are as welcome to us
As spring after the hardest
and most bitter winter.
Rollo, my son and I
are only too glad
To come to Ragnar's aid.
(laughs)
Freya and all the gods, Bjorn,
You're a big bastard now.
Thank you, Uncle.
Still can't grow a beard,
though.
(emotional exhale)
Everything is new now.
Torstein:
Good to see you, Bjorn.
Yes...
Yes. (giggles)
You stayed true to your path.
Siggy!
Floki: You see him, Helga?
He's all grown up!
Bjorn:
I missed you so much.
Floki: You look stronger
than your father.
Come, what have they been
feeding you?!
You look like
you've been eating a cow a day.
Bjorn:
You are the one to talk.
Aslaug:
I am grateful to see you.
Lagertha:
Thank you, princess Aslaug.
(sigurd coos softly)
Bjorn:
Princess.
My sons: Ubbe and Hvitserk.
I am pleased to see you.
I always knew that, some day,
I would meet some more
of Ragnar's sons.
Ubbe:
How did you know?
And you have a baby?
May I?
Aslaug: His name is
Sigurd snake-in-the-eye.
After your father?
And after his own father.
(low hum of chatter,
goats bleat)
Ragnar: Enough with the
pleasantries, let's make a plan.
Lagertha:
So?
Torstein: Even with your
additional forces, Lagertha,
We cannot attack Kattegat
and hope to succeed.
Jarl Borg is well dug in.
Lagertha:
What do you propose?
Rollo: We want to drive
Jarl Borg out of Kattegat.
He has no idea
we have been reinforced.
Torstein: And what would
make him leave Kattegat
Where he can winter in safety?
Rollo: The one thing
that would threaten
His whole existence there.
Floki:
And what would that be?
Food.
A few of us will go
into the town
And destroy the winter
grain stores.
Floki: I will do it! I will go.
Ragnar:
No. My son and I shall go.
We'll only need a few men.
(loud buzz of chatter,
carts rattle)
Woman: Don't think
we will be long now.
Man: Seems to me the
case is quite clear.
Encompass everything else
we've discussed... Yes, yes.
(door groans and shuts heavily)
King Ecbert:
Thank you.
I cannot see your face.
Young woman: I am ex-wife
of Christ: A nun.
I cannot show my face
to any man.
Well,
I am not "any man."
I am King Ecbert
And you will show me your face
Or I will be unable to judge
Whether or not
you're telling me the truth.
(crowd murmurs)
Who did this to you?
My husband.
He claimed
I had been unfaithful.
And were you...
Unfaithful?
(whispering) no.
Hmm... What do pagans say
of such cases?
(crutch taps lightly)
Athelstan:
If she was a free woman,
They would believe her word,
And make judgment
on her behalf.
King Ecbert: But surely her
husband has every right over her?
Surely she belongs to him,
to do with as he sees fit.
Not according to the pagans.
Then pagan laws are superior
to ours?
Not in every case, sire.
Woman, I find it unlawful
and disagreeable
That your husband should make
false claims against you.
He has provided no evidence
of your cupidity.
Therefore, I dismiss his demand
to have you branded in public.
Thank you.
Oh, thank you, lord.
Oh, well, don't thank me.
Thank this pagan.
(crowd murmurs quietly)
♪♪
(foliage rustles underfoot)
(splashing through stream)
Ragnar: Olrik, Erik, sneak
through the water to the docks.
Once there,
create a... distraction,
Something that will
lead the guards away.
My son and I shall do the rest.
Guard 1:
Not long till sunrise.
Guard 2:
It's been long in coming.
Ragnar:
Don't fear death.
If it comes, embrace it
As if you're lying down
next to a beautiful woman.
Bjorn: May the fates
be kind, Olrik.
(exhales nervously)
(sighs heavily)
Ever since you were
eight years old,
All I heard was,
"father, father,
I want to come with you,
I'm ready.
Father, I want to fight."
Well, here we are.
(preparatory breaths)
(footsteps squelch in the mud)
Guard 1:
You're right.
Guard 2:
On the South side.
Guard 3:
Look what we have to eat.
(water ripples quietly)
(water splashes)
Erik:
Now!
(horn bellows,
banging on barrel)
(dogs barking)
Guard:
Hey! Over there!
(horn bellows)
Guard 2: Take your weapons!
Go! This way!
Guard 3:
Move!
Man 3: Where are they?!
Can you see them!
(horn bellows, dogs barking)
Ragnar:
(clucking)
(axe strikes head,
body thuds on the ground)
(horn bellows, dogs barking)
(banging)
Erik:
(whispers) split up.
(dogs barking)
(horn bellows loudly)
Guard 1:
Stop!
(dogs barking)
Erik:
Ungh!
Erik: (gasping in pain)
guards: (laugh cruelly)
(pained screams fill the air)
Guard 1:
Now!
(fighting grunts,
weapons clank)
Olrik:
Yah! Ungh!
Aghhhhhhhhh!
(struggling grunts)
Guard:
(gurgled scream)
(groans in pain)
Olrik:
(panting)
Guard:
(muffled gasps)
(knife slashes)
(grunting with effort)
(feet shuffling)
Guard 1:
This way!
Bring the dogs!
(dogs bark)
Guard 2: I can't see anyone!
Get more men!
(rustling) there!
(flint sparks)
bjorn: Ragnar.
Olrik:
It's me.
Bjorn: Olrik, come quick! Help.
Guard 1: Come on!
Olrik: (grunts in pain)
How bad is it?
I'm fine, don't worry about me.
(flame catches, blowing)
Guard: Over here!
Something is over here!
(dogs barking)
Guard 2:
Do you see them?!
Bjorn:
Take it.
Guard:
Where'd they go?
Ragnar:
Watch out!
Ungh!
Guards:
Over there! There! There!
Ragnar:
Quickly!
Olrik: (grunts in pain)
bjorn: Wait! Come, come.
(flames crackle)
(fire roars)
Guard:
The grain!
Wife: What are you
thinking of doing?
Jarl Borg: I'm thinking
of hunting down the men
who despoiled and destroyed
our winter supplies.
Wife:
This is a disgusting place.
I don't want
to be left alone here.
I am with child!
(horses snort)
Jarl Borg:
Let's go.
(horses whinny)
men: Ho! Yah!
(horses whinny,
shields clatter)
Man:
Go on!
(dogs bark, water rushes)
(whimpering)
(hooves thud softly)
(horses snort)
(birds chirp)
(hooves thud, horse snorts)
Jarl Borg:
Come on.
(horses whinny)
(horses snort)
(foliage rustles underfoot)
(taps stick,
body thuds heavily)
(horn bellows loudly)
(foliage rustles,
weapons clank lightly)
(shields and weapons thud
and clank)
(chicken clucks, fire crackles)
(battle cries build
to a deafening roar)
(warriors shouting and grunting,
weapons clashing)
(weapons and shields clank
and batter)
(warriors shout, weapons clank)
(fighting grunts)
Yah!
(shields crash) Agghhh!
(fighting grunts and shouts,
trading blows)
(distorted dull thud)
(fierce battle cry)
(hard blows, fighting grunts)
(aggressive fighting grunts)
(fierce battle cry,
weapons clash)
Keep the shield-wall!
Lagertha:
Ungh! Aggghhhh!
Borg's man: Yahhhh!
Lagertha: Ungh!
(fierce battle cry)
Yah!
Agh!
(vicious attack yell,
shields clank)
(forceful grunt, weapons clash)
Arrgghhh!
Yah! Ungh!
Yah!
(warriors shouting and grunting,
weapons battering)
(axe strikes) Agghhh!
Agh!
♪♪
(horn bellows)
(warriors shout,
shields clatter)
Brace! Brace!
Be ready!
Stay on your feet!
Jarl Borg: Go!
Warriors: (vicious attack cries)
(shields crash, warriors thud)
Bjorn:
Agghhh! Oof!
(rushing grunt)
(weapons clank)
Ragnar:
Get up! Get up!
Aghhh! Oof! Ungh!
(axe strikes,
warrior screams in agony)
Aghhhhh! Oof!
(grunts)
(fighting grunts)
Rollo:
Torstein!
Agghhhh!
(hard blow)
(fighting grunts,
fierce battle cries)
(weapons clang and bash,
fighting grunts)
(fighting grunts)
- Warrior: Aggghhhhhhhh!
- Rollo: Ungh!
Rollo:
I'm with you, brother!
- Rollo: Yah!
- Warrior: Agghhh! Ungh!
(war axes striking,
warrior grunting in pain)
(hacking)
(fighting grunts and screams)
Yah! Ungh!
Ragnar!
(weapons clank,
fighting grunts)
(sword slashing)
(fighting grunts)
(grunts)
Oof! Ungh!
(attack grunt)
(vicious axe blows)
- Jarl Borg: Retreat!
- Warrior: Follow Jarl Borg!
- Warrior: Retreat! Go!
- Shield-Maiden: Quickly!
Shield-Maiden:
Make for the horses!
(warrior gurgles,
horses whinny)
Warrior:
They're running!
Jarl Borg:
Hold on!
(jumping grunt)
- Jarl Borg: Go!
- Warrior: Come on!
(horses whinny
as they gallop away)
(panting)
Rollo:
You fought well today, bjorn.
Bjorn:
Thank you, Uncle.
You have a lot to learn.
Let's go.
(low hum of chatter,
goats bleat)
Man 1: Ragnar Lothbrok!
He's back!
- Woman: Look!
- Man: Ragnar! He's home!
- Man: (delighted laugh)
- Woman: Come on! Come on!
(exclamations of delight)
Ragnar! Ragnar!
- Elisef: Floki!
- Floki: Elisef!
We are so glad to see you all.
We've been to hell and back.
Now it's time to celebrate.
Boy:
Uncle!
(excited buzz of chatter)
- How are you?
- I'm alright.
Girl:
Lagertha!
Girl 2:
She's back! We've missed you!
Man:
Lagertha!
Girl: We've missed you so much!
How was it?
(townsfolk chatter excitedly)
(low hum of chatter,
birds chirp)
(townsfolk chatter,
hammering nearby)
(chickens cluck, sheep bleat)
Woman:
Yes, quite well!
Man: We could do some
more... Some more trade.
- Man 1: Here, will you try some?
- Man 2: They're all the same.
(townsfolk chatter)
My lord Aethelwulf.
I heard the pagans captured you
when they raided Lindisfarne.
Is that where you're from,
Northumbria?
Athelstan:
Yes.
My father is making plans
to visit
The king of Northumbria.
Perhaps we will take you
with us.
What for?
Father Cuthbert is dead,
The monks are gone,
the monastery is burned.
What is left for me there?
Aethelwulf: Perhaps you've lost
interest in your heavenly father?
Is it true you're a pagan now?
We are christians here.
My father served at the court
of the emperor charlemagne,
The most devout of men.
If I were you,
I would not forget to attend
high mass...
That is,
if you value your soul.
(bell tolls)
Baker: Bread! No stone in this bread!
Best bread you can buy! Bread!
(townsfolk chatter)
- Man: Fine, we'll take one.
- Woman: Introduce them!
(bell ringing grows louder)
(bell tolls loudly)
(quietly)
Mary, mother of Jesus.
I just wanted to thank you.
(bell tolls)
That's...
I'm glad.
No woman should be treated
like that,
Especially not a christian.
(square buzzes with chatter)
Woman: Another one on the
way for her and her boys.
(square buzzes with chatter)
(exhales held breath and sighs)
Rollo: On this day, we
offer a sacrifice to Odin,
The mighty one,
Townsfolk:
(cheer)
(jeering)
Rollo:
Release him from his bonds.
I know he will want
to die well.
Man 1: (murmurs loudly)
man 2: (laughs)
(blade rings)
Kneel.
In the presence of the gods,
and in their honor,
I offer this sacrifice.
Ragnar:
Stop!
(confused murmurs)
Father?
(fire crackles)
(footsteps crunch)
In the presence of the gods,
and in their honor,
I offer this sacrifice.
(axe slices, cheers erupt)
(invigorating grunt)
(music, laughter, and chatter
fill the air)
♪♪
Ragnar:
I love two women.
Both of them
have given me children.
Seer: And you suppose you
must choose between them?
Ragnar:
No. I don't want to choose.
I would like
to have both of them.
Seer:
(chuckles) I see.
You know, of course,
the story of the marriage
Between Njord and Skadi?
Skadi was a giantess.
Her father was killed.
She strode to Askard
to get justice
And the gods asked her
if she wanted gold
For the death of her father.
"I'll settle for a husband,"
she said,
"and a bellyful of laughter."
Ragnar: This is going
to be a long story.
Seer: If you are
hundreds of years old,
Then it's a very quick story.
Ragnar:
Hmm.
Seer:
The gods conferred and agreed
That skadi could choose
a husband from among them,
But they made one condition:
That she chose him by his feet.
His feet?
Seer: Yes. And skadi
lost no time in choosing
The most shapely pair of feet,
Believing they would naturally
belong to Balder,
The most handsome of the gods.
Ragnar:
But they didn't?
Seer: No. They belonged
to the God Njord,
The lord of seafarers
and sea harvests.
His skin was old and weathered.
Ragnar:
What are you talking about?
I don't want to make a choice
between them,
But if I did,
Are you saying
that I should decide
Based on the appearance
of their feet?
Seer: Neither their
feet nor their faces.
You should examine their hearts,
their livers,
And every other organ.
In any case,
it makes no difference.
You are only fooling yourself,
Ragnar Lothbrok,
If you think the choice
is yours to make.
(wind howls)
Bishop Edmund:
Accipite et bibite ex eo omes
Hic est enim calix
sanguinis mei...
Qui pro vobis et effundetur.
(footsteps scuff)
Corpus christi.
Sanguinis christi.
(monks chant in Latin)
Et pro multis in remissionem
peccatorum...
Me sterium fide.
Corpus christi.
(Latin prayers
and chanting merge)
Corpus christi.
(crutch clunks lightly)
Bishop Edmund:
Corpus christi.
Sanguinis christi.
(rain begins pouring heavily,
townsfolk cry out)
Woman: Quickly! Quickly!
Man: Come along!
- Bjorn: Oh!
- Hvitserk: I got you!
Bjorn:
Agh!
You have to be stronger
than that!
(laughing)
Hvitserk, when you grow bigger,
I'll teach you to hunt.
Ubbe! Whoa!
Ragnar: It is good to see
them playing together.
Bjorn:
Agh! You have to pull!
- Aslaug: For you.
- Ragnar: Mmm...
They are all my children.
Bjorn:
What are you boys doing?
(loud thunderclap,
Ragnar sighs, amused)
Bjorn:
There! You have it!
I am going to bear you
another son.
I know.
Bjorn:
What are you doing, huh?
But I am fearful
of the prophecy.
Hvitserk:
Caught you there!
(thunder rumbles)
What are you going to do
about Lagertha?
What do you mean
what am I going to do?
Bjorn: Stronger than this!
(boys laugh)
It is her decision.
I've never had a choice
whether she comes or goes.
I will not tell her to go away,
If she does not want to.
Then, if you like,
I shall go away!
Oh, stop!
No doubt you prefer her
because she is a Shield-Maiden.
A warrior.
In that way,
she is more like you.
Bjorn:
What are you going to do?
Bjorn and hvitserk:
(laughing)
I don't want either of you
to leave.
I want you both to stay.
I want to believe you love me.
Then believe me!
Hmm?
(thunder rumbles loudly)
(rain patters loudly,
thunder rolls)
(knocking)
(fire crackles,
door creaks open)
Thank you.
I came to talk to...
Rollo:
We all know why you're here.
(rain patters loudly)
(thunder rolls)
(door creaks shut)
(sighs heavily)
I was wondering-you were
wondering what I was going to do.
Yes.
Regarding my son.
I don't know what to do.
Then he should stay.
You both should stay.
Your wife would not be happy.
I imagine not.
(rain patters loudly)
Siggy: I think Ragnar is
still in love with Lagertha.
Are you?
In a way, yes.
And yet, it seems to be
another rollo
Who still loves her.
I am like a snake
which has shed its skin.
The pattern is just the same,
but the snake is new.
And this new rollo
does not love Lagertha,
Or suffer from desires for her.
(loud thunderclap,
thunder rumbles)
Does that answer your question?
Athelstan:
(shallow breaths)
Please, lord, hear my prayer.
I am weak.
Make me strong.
Come into me again, lord.
Ravish me.
Open my eyes, lord,
to the truth.
To your presence.
Why don't you show yourself
to me?
Let me be filled again, lord,
by the holy spirit.
(ominous whispers)
(object clatters)
(loud whoosh, frightened gasp)
(vicious growl,
athelstan gasps in fear)
(panicked breaths)
(barrel clatters)
(vicious growl)
(gasps in horror) you devil!
(shaky breaths)
(calming breaths)
(ominous whispers)
You devil!
I think he's ***.
Just assume that
we shall find him guilty
And confiscate his land.
Men:
Yes! Yes!
But, on this occasion,
I believe he should
keep his land...
(murmurs of concern)
And the accusers
should give him...
Three sheep?
(crowd laughs)
All in favor, say baaaaah.
Crowd: Baaaaaaah. (banging)
Man:
Ragnar!
Ragnar:
Quiet! Thorvard.
Thorvard:
My lord Ragnar.
I hope you bring better news
than the last.
My lord, after you left,
The Saxons treacherously
attacked
King Horik's camp at Wessex.
There was a terrible slaughter.
A great many warriors perished.
The king and his son only just
escaped with their lives.
What about athelstan?
What happened to athelstan?
My lord, I don't know
of whom you speak.
Why has it taken so long
for me to hear this news?
My lord, bad news travels
a great deal slower
Than good news.
(worried murmurs)
Man 1:
Make way, make way.
Man 2:
It's Lagertha.
Man 1: Make way, make way.
Ragnar: (whispers) we
shall speak later.
Thank you.
What is wrong?
I have something important
to say.
Should it be said in private?
No. I want to say it
before everyone.
(townsfolk whisper)
Lagertha:
I have come to a decision.
More than anything
in the world,
To stay here with his father.
And who can blame him?
If you had a father
like Ragnar Lothbrok,
Would you not want to stay?
(murmurs of agreement)
I happily give my permission
to my beloved and only son
To remain here with his father
and his half brothers.
As for me...
I must go back to my husband.
I have a duty;
I am a responsible person.
(upset murmurs)
But I leave my son
in your good hands.
(fire crackles, quiet murmurs)
Look after him, Ragnar.
He's all I have left.
(townsfolk murmur quietly)
(loud chatter resumes)
(horse snorts)
Aslaug:
Lagertha.
(sighs heavily)
Thank you.
There are no possible words
to describe
What you have done for us.
I will always be in your debt.
The debt is already paid.
The future is open.
Trust in the gods.
Live for each moment.
(horse whinnies)
Don't take any more shit!
Lagertha:
Who do you think I am?!
(hooves thud)
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
(sighs)