[panting]
[wind howling]
[panting, grunting]
[ Zager & Evans:
In The Year 2525]
In the year 2525
If man is still alive
If woman can survive
They may find
In the year 3535
Ain't gonna need
To tell the truth
Tell no lies
Everything you think,
do, and say
Is in the pill
You took today
In the year 4545
Ain't gonna need your teeth,
Won't need your eyes
You won't find a thing
to chew
Nobody's gonna look at you
In the year 5555
Your arms are hanging limp
at your sides
Your legs got nothing to do
Some machine is doing that
for you
In the year 6565
Ain't gonna need no husband,
Won't need no wife
You'll pick your son,
Pick your daughter too
From the bottom of
a long glass tube
Whoooa
[grunting, panting]
The tunnel is clear.
[groaning]
[rats squeaking]
[man] All right, let's go.
Move it!
Come on, move, man. Move.
Let's go.
Pick up your positions.
Anderson, on that tree line.
[man] Come on,
we gotta get these...
[man] Go!
[indistinct shouting]
[man] Move out!
[man] Nicky, I got a letter
from your mother.
All right, boys, let's do it.
We don't got all day.
Welcome home.
Ain't Buckingham Palace,
but looks like something.
Roof, bed to sleep on.
Garraty, how the fuck are ya?
Ladies and gentlemen, this is
Garraty. Don't feed him.
He fuckin' bites.
Find a bed.
Unpack your kit.
Yeah. Hey, hey,
welcome, welcome.
Bunch of fucking clowns.
Gentlemen, we chow
at 1700 hours.
That's it. That's my bit.
The illustrious Lieutenant
Hollowborn. Sir.
Men, I'm Lieutenant Hollowborn .
I don't give a fuck
what you did before.
There's no dope smoking
in this platoon.
You settle in,
get some chow, get some rest.
We open our first tunnel
tomorrow.
You have any problems,
talk to Sergeant Heaney.
Or me, or whatever.
First tunnel tomorrow?
Great.
Three months off the boat
and I'm already in this
hellhole.
That's my stuff.
- What's your name, white bread?
- Miller.
It's early to get
your ass whipped.
Fuck this shit.
[man] Uh, you're on my bunk.
- Yeah. You wanna trade?
- No.
Goddamn it.
[rock plays on radio]
You look in the Bible
at the Battle of Jericho.
Joshua is ordered by Yahweh
to slay every man, woman,
child, cattle
and slave of his enemy. That's
how you win a fucking war.
You want the prisoner hung?
That fucking gook murdered five
of my men. I want him hung.
I understand, lieutenant,
but he's still a soldier.
He's not a soldier.
He's not in uniform.
I want him hung.
Yes, sir.
Corporal.
[Hollowborn] Platoon, form up.
Witness the execution.
[man] You heard him.
[Hollowborn] Let's go. Let's go.
[man shouting]
[Heaney] This man
is a VC sniper.
He's killed at least five
of our brothers.
We show no mercy.
We take no prisoners.
- [cracking]
- [laughter]
[man] Best gook's a dead gook.
[man 2] They're sick.
- They're sick.
- Garraty, cut him down.
[Garraty] All right.
Where I come from,
that's murder.
You got a problem with the Army,
or with me, asshole?
I believe I've got
a problem with you, sir.
Good.
[man] You one of the new guys?
How long you been here?
A while.
- Heard about the tunnels?
- Yeah.
- Ever been in one?
- A few.
Well, shit.
Welcome to the camp.
- Porterson.
- Johnson.
[Porterson] All right.
Thanks.
Johnson, right?
Miller. Bob Miller.
And you are...?
- Porterson.
Right.
Man, I just cannot
get used to this food.
My mom's the best cook.
Her brisket
is out of this world.
Every Friday night,
we have the best Shabbat dinner.
Me, her, the entire
neighborhood.
I can't wait to get back.
She's sick, my mom.
Every week I'm away, it breaks
her heart more and more.
If I lose her
before I get back...
- Gary, right?
- Yeah.
Miller.
People like Miller
got no business being here.
- I know.
- Blabbermouths.
Nothing they say
is ever worth hearing.
Talking too much out here
can get you hurt, get other
people killed.
Take a look at them,
for example.
Battle-hardened vets, they come
in, eat their chow and leave.
Then you got enlisted types who
think this is a fucking game.
Then there's guys like Miller.
Future KIA.
Someone who talks a lot because
he's scared shitless to be here.
Well, I hope this
makes you feel better.
[grunting]
You wanna play God,
you son of a bitch?
Is that what you
wanna do, play God?
Ah!
It ain't about God or the devil,
Harris. It's about survival.
All right.
[grunting]
Charlie's gonna kill you
just for fucking being here.
He doesn't care
if you're a nice guy.
[groaning]
[indistinct chatter]
Same old shit.
Verano, come here.
- Sarge?
- What's wrong with the food?
Just tastes bad, sergeant.
I know. Where you from?
- Michigan.
- Yeah?
My wife's folks have a place in
Charlevoix. Know where that is?
- Yeah. Really?
- It's around the lake.
It's beautiful.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Yeah.
You ever get scared out there?
Let me tell you the
only thing you need to know.
This place is
all about survival.
It's not black and white.
It's all grey.
The sooner you realize that,
the better chance you've got
of packing your shit
together one day
and doing that
duffle bag drag
back to the world.
- Understand?
- Yeah.
All right.
Now finish your meal.
[man] Over here. Over here.
[indistinct chatter]
[soft rock plays]
- All right, going for three?
- Going for three.
You beat me twice. I think
you're trying to hustle me, boy.
- Show me the queen.
- Here we go.
- The queen, you got it?
- Got it.
Look at this beautiful
black queen.
- Lookin' at her?
- Yeah.
Keep your eye on her, boy. Come
on. You ready? Where's she at?
You got her, right?
Keep your eyes open, boy.
All you've gotta think about
is that beautiful, black,
- thick queen. Where's she at?
- She's right there.
- You sure?
- Positive.
- Damn, boy. Look at that.
- [both laugh]
You're getting hustled,
Verano.
Stop corrupting Terence.
Nobody's corrupting.
Am I corrupting you?
- No.
- Trying to learn something.
- OK.
- Damn this thing.
Big, heavy ass.
Come on, split six.
- Six?
- Yep. Come on.
- You ready?
- I'm ready.
Let's go.
Where you at, boy?
- Where's she at?
- She's right there.
- You sure?
- I'm positive.
Uh-oh. Shame, boy.
Come on, pay up.
- Big fucking surprise.
- All good. You'll win next
time.
Better save your cigarettes,
Terence.
[Lidford] Ain't got nothing
to do with you.
What you reading
over there, man?
Romans, Chapter 11.
You hear that?
Got a southern belle out here.
Flip that on to Jeremiah 29:11.
- Oh, yeah?
- Uh-huh.
- Where'd you find this?
- Chicago.
- What you know about the Bible?
- I'm about to learn you.
Yeah, OK.
"'For I know the thoughts
that I think toward you,'
said the Lord,
'Thoughts of peace
and not of evil,
to give you
an expected end.
Then shall you
call upon me...'"
"'Then shall you call
upon me and I will listen,
and I will call you
from the nations
from which you were banished,
and I will bring you out of
the exile
- in which I carried you.'"
- That's right.
[laughs] What the hell's
that supposed to mean?
Tell him what it mean, Harris.
If you have faith, God will save
you from this horrible shit.
- Mm-hm.
- You got faith?
- Yeah, I do.
- God's gonna save you
from this shit?
- I believe that.
- Well, that's good.
Because while men are cutting
off other men's heads
for trophies
and hanging ears
around their neck,
it's good to know that Harris
is going to be saved.
- This isn't the end, man.
- This is the end.
Ain't nobody trying to
hear that jive-ass shit.
- You're fucking up my high.
- That book is a high.
- Here we go.
- That book's a high.
Got men believing they're
gonna get swept out of here.
Shut the fuck up.
How about that?
Got to you, huh?
- I'll kick your ass, man.
- Don't you fucking touch me!
- Yeah.
- Do something, nigga.
- You fucking hoodies.
- Go take a shower, bitch.
Yeah.
Come on, boy. Come on.
Put your money up, boy.
Show me the queen.
- Ready?
- I'm ready.
[man] Fucking small-minded,
ghetto hoodies. Fantasy land.
- What's your name? Gil...
- Graybridge.
Graybridge.
Where you from, Graybridge?
Let me ask you a question.
Do you believe in God?
I believe in God.
Let me ask you a question.
When was the last time
Red Sox won the Series?
I don't know.
Fifty-some years ago, I guess.
That answer your question?
I tell you what.
A greater franchise has never
existed. This is our year.
- Year. Year of the franchise.
- What the fuck are you smoking?
- No, listen. You like burgers?
- Everybody likes burgers.
Right, everybody likes burgers,
but check it out.
In California,
this guy started up a franchise.
That's the magic word.
Burgers, fries, shakes,
speed, like that.
You just find a plot of land,
he fronts the dough. It's easy
as pie.
It's the American dream.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Which American dream?
This fucking American dream?
I don't know, man. This don't
seem like no dream to me.
No, you're missing it. I'm
talking about when I get back.
I'm gonna be my own boss.
I'm gonna be an entrepreneur.
- I'm gonna...
- You're gonna...
Me too, Graybridge.
Me too. I'm gonna...
I'm gonna get a girl.
I'm gonna get a boat.
I'm gonna get a little house
on Lake Winnipesaukee.
It's gonna be fucking great.
I'm serious.
But meantime,
this is what we've got right
here. Right fucking here.
There's a forest full
of chinky-eyed motherfuckers,
and they got their vision of the
gook dream, whatever that is.
They'll slit your
fucking throat to get it.
- You're missing it...
- Oh yeah? Tell me.
Burger joints.
They're the wave of the future.
That sounds good.
How about some fucking water?
Yeah. Sure.
Fucking war.
What the fuck, man?!
Did you piss in this?
- Nah, nah.
- Fuck! Thank you.
You're a real winner.
[Lidford] This is serious shit,
boy, all right? Pay attention.
There's power to the way a man
smokes a cigarette, all right?
- Right-handed?
- Yeah.
All right.
Relax your shoulders.
Look forward. Inhale.
- [coughing] Shit!
- You all right?
Heading to the tunnels tomorrow.
I wouldn't be smoking.
The VC don't give a damn
about no cigarette smoke.
When you're underground in a
confined space, the VC can smell
anything on you:
Your aftershave,
cigarette smoke in your uniform.
They can even tell what brand.
If that happens, you're as good
as dead.
Bullshit, Johnson.
Bullshit, all right?
My mom would kill me
if she saw me doing this.
I wouldn't worry about your mom
killing you tomorrow, Verano.
My parents have a house
on Lake Michigan.
And at night, me and my sister,
we'd sneak out and go down
to the beach.
We'd run up the sand dune and
lay there and look at the stars.
We'd talk about
all kinds of shit.
She'd talk about girl stuff
and I'd talk about baseball.
We'd spend hours up there.
I remember one time... [laughs]
...we fell asleep up there
and we got in so much trouble.
I woke up to my fucking dog
licking me in my face.
I don't know, man.
I'd do anything
to see my family right now.
My sister and my dog
and my parents.
What about your folks?
It must have been pretty tough
on you, your mom and your dad.
You don't know shit about
my mom and my dad.
Sorry.
Why you asking all these
stupid-ass questions, anyway?
- Get the fuck off my bunk, man.
- I didn't mean anything. Sorry.
[Porterson]
None of that shit matters.
Where you've been,
where you're from.
Right now you're in Vietnam.
It matters what you do
on that field.
Oh, shit.
Got a blow a kiss to my girl.
Oh, yeah. The moon
is nice and bright out there.
- Who you out there kissing?
- Oh, it's a concept
me and my girl came up with:
the satellite of love.
I send a kiss up every night
and she takes one down from
the moon.
- It's nice.
- Yeah.
Let me ask you something.
What happened with you
and Hollowborn today?
We had to talk
a couple things out.
- Did you get to say anything?
- Not much.
Yeah, maybe next time you'll
keep your mouth shut, huh?
Hero. John Wayne.
Thanks for the headset, Verano.
Oh, man!
Would you eat here?
[laughs] Yeah, it looks good.
Hey. Thanks.
[indistinct chatter]
[Harris] I heard about
these tunnels.
I had an uncle who died
here last year.
Your uncle obviously
didn't have an M-60.
They say they stretch
for hundreds of miles.
No one knows where
they start or where they end.
This is a really bad
place to be.
- This is it. You ready?
- I was born ready.
- You nervous?
- Not at all.
Just follow my lead.
- You got it.
- [imitating] You got it.
You just love following the
white man, don't you, boy?
Saddle up, motherfuckers.
We're moving out.
- Corporal Green, take point.
- Yes, sir.
Garraty, get that 60, in front
of me. Johnson, bring up the
rear. Let's go. Fall in.
[Hollowborn] RTO, you do not
leave my side.
Let's go. Let's go.
[man] Right away.
[whistles]
Check it out, man.
- Heaney.
- Yes, sir.
Secure the perimeter.
Verano, Lidford, Green,
give me a perimeter.
We found this tunnel before
sundown, and I'm not clearing
a tunnel at night.
OK, this is what it's all
about.
I'm using a stick,
whereas a knife
might set off a trap.
And these holes are full of
them.
Volunteers.
- Got it, sir.
- I'll go first.
Garraty, Johnson, Porterson.
I ain't got a lot of cock,
but I've got a lot of balls.
Harris, take the 60.
- Fucking John Wayne.
- Fucking A.
Hey, Garraty,
five bucks for a dead gook.
All right.
Later, fuckers.
- [gunshot]
- Shit.
- What the fuck, man?
- I'll get him.
Watch your fucking six.
[gasping]
[gunshot]
[man] Shot in the stomach!
Coming up!
Porterson, give me a hand.
[gasping]
I need another compress!
[Porterson] I'm right here.
I gotcha. I gotcha.
You hold on, man.
Garraty, look at me.
Look at me. I'm right here.
You're going to make it.
Just hang in there.
Hold on.
Garraty? Look at me. Look at me.
- Shit!
- Clear him. Porterson,
give me grenades.
- Give me grenades.
- Yes, sir.
[Hollowborn] Blow it. Blow it
and get the fuck out of there!
[man] Come on!
[Hollowborn] Come on!
- Come on!
- Get him out!
[man] Get the fuck out!
[man] Eyes on that treeline.
How many VC did
you see down there?
I saw two VC, lieutenant.
All right, get some
CS gas down there.
Harris?
I'm gonna take Garraty
back to base camp. Heaney.
I want them to gather
as much intel as is left.
Dave, Bob,
you're going with me.
Yes, Sir.
Miller, leave the radio with me.
[man] Still on that treeline.
[Hollowborn] Come on,
let's get him up.
- [man] Porterson, you ready?
- Ready.
[Porterson] We've got one!
Got one VC coming up!
- Got him?
- Coming up.
Over here.
- His fucking leg.
- Grab it.
- [Porterson] Got another one.
- [man] Got another one.
Lidford, give me a knife
and a flashlight.
We're going back down.
- [man] Hook it up.
- [man #2] I got it.
- [man] All set.
- [man #2] Back down.
[man] Let's get this hooked up.
- The radio's on.
- Here you go.
Keep your eyes peeled.
[metal scraping]
[panting]
It's a dead end.
There's nothing down here.
[speaking Vietnamese]
[panting]
[Johnson] I'm gonna go up
and check the surrounding area,
see if I can find
Sergeant Heaney,
let him know this section's
clear. Cover the rear.
Right behind you.
[gagging]
[Porterson] Johnson!
Johnson! Johnson!
[gagging]
[panting]
Alpha Bravo, come in. Over.
Check the tension.
- It's loose.
- Shit!
Harris, Lidford,
stay here in case they come
back.
Green, Verano, come with me.
We're gonna check that out.
Yes, sir.
[vomiting]
- Jesus Christ.
- Fucking Christ.
We need to get to
Harris and Lidford.
- What about Porterson?
- We're gonna leave him here?
We'll come back.
We need to get back.
What about Porterson?
[grunting]
[coughing]
[grunts]
What the fuck, man? Where the
fuck is everybody else?
- Johnson's dead.
- What the fuck you mean
he's dead?
What you think
he means he's dead?
He's got a fucking hole in the
neck the size of a baseball
- and blood coming out his eyes!
- Hey!
- Calm the fuck down.
- We get the picture.
- What about Porterson?
- We didn't see him.
- What now?
- Harris, get on the radio.
Try to get a hold of the
lieutenant. Lidford,
I need you to cover him.
Verano, you also. Corporal,
stay. I'm going in.
- I'm going with you.
- Sure about that?
Fuck that.
Fuck "Corporal, stay here."
Charlie Six to Alpha One, over.
We're sitting fucking ducks
for Charlie right now.
I think you understand that,
sergeant.
Yes, I do.
Charlie Six to Alpha One, over.
- Fuck this!
- Come on!
[Harris] Charlie Six to Alpha
One, over.
[Green] We're supposed to stick
around like a bunch of ducks
waiting for Charlie
to come to us? Fuck that.
[Heaney] Hold tight.
Hold tight.
[Green] Good luck,
fuckers.
- [Lidford] Get that working.
- I'm trying.
Get that shit working!
Make the fucking shit work!
Make the shit work!
Make it work!
That's not gonna help, OK?
It's dead, man. It's dead.
Shh.
What's wrong?
The tunnel splits
in two different directions.
We need to split up.
Porterson is down here
someplace,
If we don't find him, someone
else will. We need to split up.
We stay together,
and stay quiet.
[speaking Vietnamese]
[panting]
[crashing]
Ah!
- Sarge? Oh, my God!
- [Green] Heaney.
- [Verano] Oh, my God!
- Fuck.
- Sarge? Oh, my God. [sobbing]
- Sarge?
[Verano] I wanna go home!
Oh, fuck.
[sobbing] Oh, fuck!
- Get away from the hole.
- I'm not fucking leaving him!
- Look at me, sarge.
- Get the fuck away
from the hole.
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
- [gunshots]
- [screaming]
- How long have they been gone?
- Way too long. Way too long.
Just keep some cover, all right?
Keep your eyes open.
Shh. You hear that?
Over there.
They're coming.
[gunfire]
Lidford, get in the hole!
Motherfuckers, come on!
Come on, motherfuckers!
Fuck you!
Come on, piece of shit.
Ah! Shit!
Come on,
get your ass down now!
[Harris] Let's go!
[speaking Vietnamese]
[screaming]
I've been here over a year now,
and I can't get used to it.
- How many deaths have you seen?
- I don't want to talk
about that.
I don't want
to talk about that.
Where are you from?
- Do you have any family?
- You're cool with me.
I don't want
to talk about that.
[gunfire]
Come on, Graybridge!
- Stay there!
- What the fuck is going on?
Ah! Ah!
[Green] Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck.
Porterson?
It's Harris.
Harris?
- Oh, fuck.
- Green. Green.
it's OK. We took heavy fire
up top. Lidford's been shot.
He's losing blood.
We've gotta get
his ass out of here now.
There are VC all over us
down this way.
- [gasping]
- Green, where's your team?
- Ah!
- Is that too tight?
- [groaning]
- Green, where's your team?
I'm gonna fucking die out here,
man. I'm gonna die in this
fucking hole.
Hey. Don't get stupid on me.
You're not gonna die.
We're going this way.
Get your shit together.
Let's go.
Ah!
[screaming]
Fuck. Lidford!
Put your head down!
Fuck! Jim, put your
fucking head down!
Fuck!
Jim?
[screaming]
Ah! Oh!
[shouts]
[panting, straining]
Keep moving.
What are you doing?
- I'm done.
- What?
I ain't going no more, Harris.
Put that cigarette out.
Those commie gook motherfuckers
want me, I'm gonna be here,
but I'm not moving another
foot in this goddamn tunnel!
Shut your damn mouth! Shut up!
I'm not going anywhere!
[shouting]
Ah!
I got two.
Hotel One, Hotel One,
this is Zebra Three.
This is Zebra Three.
I need air support immediately.
Ah!
Oh, fuck it, we're overrun.
Hotel One, this is Zebra Three.
I need an air strike at my
position.
position. Zebra Three, out.
Go! Come on, Miller!
I believe. I believe. I believe.
Come on. Come on.
Graybridge!
Jesus? I believe. I believe.
[panting]
Ah!
[gasping]
[gunfire]
Ah! [screaming]
- [screaming]
- Ah! Ah!
[yelling]
[speaking Vietnamese]
[shouting, gunfire]
[screaming]
[man] Get out of there!
[grunting]
[screams]
Ah!
[grunting]
Oh!
[panting]
[coughing]
[gunfire]
[grunts]
[coughing]
[panting, coughing]
[gasping]
[panting]
[grunting]
Shit.
[panting]
Don't... shoot.
No.
[speaking Vietnamese]
[panting]
[water bubbling]
[gasping, straining]
[panting]
[insects chirping]
[clanking]
Porterson.
Easy.
Easy now.
OK. OK.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm not gonna hurt anyone.
[speaking Vietnamese]
I just want to go through.
Look, I'm not a killer. I don't
want to use this, all right?
Do you speak English?
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Look, look, look,
I'm your friend, right? Right?
I'm your friend.
I'm not gonna use this.
Hey, little girl. Hey, sweetie,
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm not gonna hurt anyone.
I just want to go home.
I just want to go home, please.
Please, I'll put it away.
See? I'll put it away.
Look. See? See?
See? I'm not gonna
hurt your children.
Just let me go through here.
I want go up. All right?
Please, please! I'm not gonna
hurt your children, all right?
I couldn't do that! I just want
to go through here and get up!
[planes passing overhead]
I just want to get out of here.
Get those kids out of here!
Go! Go!
Just go!
You gotta go through there!
You have to get outta here now!
You have to go!
I'm not gonna do anything to
you! You have to go now!
I don't want to die down here!
You don't want to die down here!
Get out!
- No!
- Go! Just go!
Go! Just go! Get out, please!
[bomb whistling]
[plane passing overhead]
[woman screams]
[screaming]
[coughing]
- [woman sobbing]
- [grunting]
[grunting]
We dig now, OK? Dig.
Give me that.
OK.
There it is. There it is.
Easy.
Come on.
Please, God.
[grunting]
Ah, shit!
Come on!
We're almost there.
[coughing]
[ Caitlin Tortorici:
Breathe In]