- Thirty thousand.
- From the Russians?
No, from the French.
From the Russians we capture
more than that every day.
[People Shouting,
Chattering]
Mr. Postman.
War is war and schnapps is schnapps,
and business must go on.
You didn't leave
the mail yet this morning.
Ah, I'm sorry, Mr. Meyer.
Hello, Himmelstoss.
Anything for us today?
- No, no, Master Peter.
- Oh, there must be something.
Here, here you go,
young lad. [Laughing]
There. This is
the last mail I deliver anyhow.
- What?
- Tomorrow I change uniforms.
- You're going in the army?
- Yes, I was called.
I'm a sergeant
in the reserves, you know.
I'll be called myself,
if it doesn't end in a few months.
- It will, though.
- I'm sure you're right, Mr. Meyer.
[Shouting, Chattering
Continue]
真 [Band Playing]
- 真 [Continues]
- [Shouting Continues]
[Speaking, Inaudible]
...defending our country,
our fatherland.
Now, my beloved class,
this is what we must do:
Strike with all our power.
Give every ounce of strength...
to win victory
before the end of the year.
It is with reluctance that
I bring this subject up again.
You are the life
of the fatherland, you boys.
You are the iron men
of Germany.
You are the gay heroes
who will repulse the enemy...
when you are called upon
to do so.
It is not for me to suggest
that any of you...
should stand up and offer
to defend his country.
But I wonder if such a thing
is going through your heads.
I know that
in one of the schools,
the boys have risen up
in the classroom...
and enlisted in a mass.
But, of course, if such a thing
should happen here,
you would not blame me
for a feeling of pride.
Perhaps some will say...
that you should not
be allowed to go yet,
that you are too young, that you
have homes, mothers, fathers,
that you should not be
torn away.
Are your fathers so forgetful
of their fatherland...
that they would let it perish
rather than you?
Are your mothers so weak
that they cannot send a son...
to defend the land
which gave them birth?
And after all,
is a little experience...
such a bad thing
for a boy?
Is the honor of wearing
a uniform...
something from which
we should run?
And if our young ladies
glory in those who wear it,
is that anything
to be ashamed of?
I know you have never desired
the adulation of heroes.
That has not been
part of my teaching.
We have sought
to make ourselves worthy,
and let a claim come
when it would.
But to be
foremost in battle...
is a virtue
not to be despised.
I believe it will be
a quick war,
that there will be
few losses.
But if losses there must be,
then let us remember
the Latin phrase...
which must have come
to the lips of many a Roman...
when he stood embattled
in a foreign land:
"Dulce et decorum est
pro patria mori."
"Sweet and fitting it is
to die for the fatherland."
Some of you
may have ambitions.
I know of one young man who has
great promise as a writer,
and he has written the first act
of a tragedy...
which would be a credit
to one of the masters.
And he is dreaming,
I suppose,
of following in the footsteps
of Goethe and Schiller,
and I hope he will.
But now our country calls.
The fatherland needs leaders.
Personal ambition
must be thrown aside...
in the one great sacrifice
for our country.
Here is a glorious beginning
to your lives.
The field of honor
calls you.
Why are we here?
You, Kropp,
what has kept you back?
You, Mueller, you know
how much you are needed?
Ah, I see you look
at your leader.
And I, too, look to you,
Paul Baumer,
and I wonder
what you are going to do.
- I'll go.
- I want to go.
- Count on me.
- Me too.
- I'm ready.
- I'm not gonna stay home!
- [All Shouting]
Follow me!
Enlist now!
- No more classes!
- [Others] No more classes!
- Don't be a quitter!
- Come on, Behn!
Stick together.
That's what we've got to do.
- Let's all stick together.
- Come on, Behn.
All right.
- I'll go.
- That's the way!
Let's go!
Hey! Let's sing!
Come on!
真 [All Singing,
Unintelligible]
真 [Continues]
[Men Shouting]
[Chattering]
[Shouting Continues]
- Keep in line there, soldiers.
- [Laughing]
- Anything you say, General.
- [All Laughing]
Detail, halt!
Left face!
Get into uniform, ready
to report. Fall out!
[All Chattering,
Shouting]
I betcha a place like this
gets you in good condition.
You have to be
for the long marches.
I'm gonna get
in the cavalry and ride.
No cavalry for me.
Infantry's where
you see the fighting.
Where are all the guns?
That's what I want to know.
Oh, you don't get a gun
for a long while yet.
If I'm gonna bump off the enemy,
I gotta have some practice. Ow!
Bayonet drill.
That's what I want.
Ah!
You won a medal
that time, Mueller.
You wait. In about a month
I'll be covered with 'em.
Say, keep your boots
out of my face!
Why, it's an honor to have
those boots in your face.
They're the best pair in the army!
My uncle gave 'em to me.
Just look at that
special imported leather.
Put 'em anyplace you like,
except in my face.
Not even a kitchen maid'll
look at me in this!
Attention!
Well, for the love of...
It's Himmelstoss!
- So it is.
- And all dressed up.
Hello, Himmie. You didn't think
you'd see me again so soon, did you?
- You see my rank?
- Sure.
Fall back, then!
- Himmelstoss, we certainly are
glad to see you.
- What did you say?
- I was going to say...
- Never mind!
- What's the matter with you?
- When you address your
superior officer, say "sir"!
- Where'd he get such a nice uniform?
- Any mail for us, Himmie?
- Quiet!
- My dear fellow, you're shouting.
Ah, come on, Himmelstoss. We know ya.
Take off the false whiskers.
- I believe you mean it!
- You'll find out that I mean it.
- But only three days ago
you were our postman.
- Silence!
Come back here!
Line up!
Line up! Get in
some kind of a line!
All of you!
Line up, I say!
[Laughing]
Hmm.
What a pretty sight
that is!
Have you never heard
of standing in line?
You make
a fine mess of it.
Well, I'll have
to teach you.
We'll spend the whole
day on it, huh?
You may be stupid,
but I'm used to that.
And then there'll be
plenty of other things too.
Oh, I'll not neglect you.
Hmm. You're not much
to begin with,
but I'll do my best.
I see that we have come here
with a slight misunderstanding,
and we'll correct that,
too, won't we, huh?
And the first thing to do is to
forget everything you ever knew.
Everything you ever learned,
forget! See?
Forget what you've been and what
you think you're going to be.
You're going to be soldiers,
and that's all!
I'll take the mother's milk out of you!
I'll make you hard-boiled!
I'll make soldiers out of you
or kill you!
Now... salute!
A-ten-hut!
Detachment... lie down!
Down!
Head down!
Keep your head down,
Baumer!
Detachment... get up!
Now sing!
真 [All Singing Feebly,
Unintelligibly]
Do you call that
singing?
Detachment, halt!
So... we have
no spirit, huh?
We are in no mood
for recreation.
Work is what we want.
Good!
Then we'll go back
to work!
Detachment,
lie down!
Keep your head down!
Now sing!
真 [All Singing In German,
Spirited]
真 [Continues]
Men... halt!
Order, arms!
Inspection at 3:00.
Dismissed!
[Chattering]
Oh, that swine!
That means we get no time off.
It will take four hours
to get ready for inspection.
- I'd like to know what's in his mind.
- He hasn't got any!
I'm gonna cut him open
sometime and find out!
He's too thick-skinned.
He won't cut.
This is the fourth time he's made me
disappoint that poor girl.
Arms!
Order, arms!
Left shoulder, arms!
Squad right.
To the right, march!
Left, left, left, left.
Follow right, march!
Squad, left march!
Forward... march!
Detachment...
halt!
Present arms!
Himmelstoss.
Excellent work.
They're going up front tomorrow.
- I recommend leave till midnight.
- Very good, sir.
[Shouting Orders,
Unintelligible]
Left, left, left.
Detachment...
lie down!
Crawl forward!
[All Chattering]
He spoiled our leave.
I'll never forgive him for that.
- The rat!
- Leave till midnight. Hmm!
Lt'll take till midnight
to dry our clothes.
There goes
the filthy ape now.
While we slave over this mud,
he goes off to have a few drinks!
Someday I'm going to take
one smack at him... just one.
Me too. That's gonna be
my life's work from now on.
Why only one?
I'm gonna take several.
I might even kick him while
he's down. I feel mean.
What are you doing?
You're not going
to desert, are you?
What?
[Laughing]
Listen. I've got an idea.
真 [Singing,
Unintelligible]
[Laughing]
Crawl forward!
Lie down!
[Laughing]
[Himmelstoss
Laughing]
Lie down! Crawl forward!
[Continues Laughing]
Oh! What?
[Laughing]
[Himmelstoss
Yelling, Screaming]
[Continues Screaming]
Ow! Ow!
真 [Whistling]
[Boys Whispering]
- [Men Shouting]
- [Distant Gunfire]
[Explosions]
- [Explosion]
- [Man] Cover!
- [Shouting]
- [Shell Whistling]
[Shouting]
- [All Chattering]
- Paul, you all right?
Behn! Behn!
Behn!
Come on!
Behn, come on!
You fool! Behn!
Get up!
Come on.
[Shouting Continues]
[Men Shouting]
- 真 [Concertina]
- Sounds like
more replacements coming in.
Yeah. Tjaden must have
gone home for that wood.
There's some more,
fresh from the turnip patch.
[Paul]
I suppose this is where we bunk.
That's me,
"I. Westhus,"
and this is
where I live.
- I didn't know!
- Well, you know now!
Yes. Yes, of course.
- It's all right.
- [Soldier] Here's a bunk, Paul.
- When did we eat last?
- Don't remind me.
- I was fine until you spoke.
- Where are we anyway?
I don't know. The name on
the railroad station's been shot off.
There must be something
to eat somewhere.
I'll tell you
what I'll do.
I'll ask those fellas.
Sorry to disturb you,
Mr. Westhus.
Oh. Meet Detering.
A better farmer never lived.
- And Mr. Tjaden.
- Sit down.
You see, we haven't eaten
since breakfast.
We thought maybe you could tell us
what we ought to do about it.
Eat without
further delay.
[Detering,
Tjaden Laughing]
Well, what's funny
about that?
This is a bad town
to bring an appetite to, soldier.
We've been here since yesterday morning,
living on baled hay and razor blades.
We're willing to buy our food.
Where's the canteen?
[Laughing] The only canteen in these
regions is out looking for supplies.
- Ever hear of Katczinsky?
- Who?
Katczinsky.
He's uncanny.
If there's any food within
25 miles, he'll be the one to get it.
- Hey!
- [Grunts]
[Grunts]
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hup!
- Hup!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
[Chattering]
Attention!
[Laughing]
- What is this?
- Volunteers for the future
generals' staff.
Sometime I'm gonna take
one of you volunteers apart...
and find out what makes you
leave school and join the army.
At ease. This is
no parade ground.
- Hungry?
- [All Shouting] Yes.
Wait! Wait a minute!
That's no invitation.
- Can you pay?
- Yeah, sure.
- I have some money.
No, not money.
That's just pieces of paper.
Have you got any
cigarettes, cigars,
- or soap, cognac...
- Yeah, yeah.
- Yeah.
- Chewing tobacco?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Kat!
Are you crazy?
There ain't enough here for us.
I wish you three
would get bumped off.
I'm tired of feeding ya
for nothing.
- Bring everything you got.
- [All Chattering]
- [Boy #1] I'm so hungry...
- [Boy #2] I'd be glad to give you...
- Come on!
- Is this enough, sir?
- Kat!
- Hmm?
- You've got the wiring detail tonight.
- Where?
- Past the graveyard.
- With this bunch?
It's quiet tonight.
You can teach 'em a couple of things.
Thanks. I'd rather
do it alone.
- These babes get killed off too fast.
- Well, the lorry's waiting.
Last night
I was too hungry to sleep,
and tonight, when I get the wrinkles out
of my gut, they think up wiring duty.
Well, here's
your chance, heroes.
For the fatherland!
Come on, get your stuff
and let's get out of here.
- Is that any way to drive?
- Let him drive any way he wants.
Suppose he breaks your arm.
You get sent home, don't you?
A lot better than havin'
a hole in your guts.
If there's any of you left,
I'll pick you up in the morning.
Well, if that ride you gave us
didn't kill us, nothing will.
- And be on time. I don't
want to miss my breakfast.
- [Laughing]
- Huh?
- You better wait for your army, Papa.
Here, here.
Don't be so backward.
Listen, children. All we got to do
is to string a little wire.
We pick it up at the dump
and carry it to where we need it.
Now, you're gonna see some shell fire,
and you're gonna be scared, see?
[Shell Whistling,
Explosion]
It's all right, boy.
Get up.
Here. Never mind.
It's happened to better men than you,
and it's happened to me.
When we come back, I'll get you all
some nice clean underwear. [Chuckles]
That kind of shell you don't have to
pay much attention to.
Those big fellas just make
a lot of noise and land about
five miles behind the line.
The things we've got to watch
out for are the light ones.
They don't give you
much warning.
They go
"waa-aa-aah zing."
And when you hear that,
down!
Mother Earth.
Press yourselves
down upon her.
Bury yourselves
deep into her.
Just keep your eyes on me.
When you see me flop,
you flop,
only try to beat me to it.
[Explosion]
Shh-shh. Now listen.
I'll show you
how it's done.
Give me a couple of those.
That's to kill the noise.
Tjaden.
[Explosion]
[Machine Gun Fire,
Explosions]
See that?
- What's that mean?
- Bombardment.
[Screaming, Crying]
[Screaming]
My eyes!
I'm blind!
I can't see! God!
- [Explosions Continue]
- My eyes! I can't see!
[Continues Screaming]
- [Screaming] I can't see!
- It's Behn! It's Behn!
[Machine Gun Fire]
- I'll go get him...
- You'll get killed!
[Shouting]
- Let me...
- Lay down and stay there!
He's dead.
- He's dead!
- Why did you risk your life
bringin' him in?
But it's Behn!
- My friend.
- He's a corpse, no matter who it is.
Now, don't any of you
ever do that again.
Put him over there.
- [All] Mind the wire.
- [Kat] Mind the wire.
All right, come on.
Get your packs and fall in. Hurry up!
Come on. Hurry up.
Make it snappy.
Get your packs
and fall in.
Kat, what are we doing?
What's happening?
You heard him.
Orders to march.
- But where to, for the love of...
- Another party.
And this one is gonna
last a long time.
Come on.
Here we go.
Company, attention!
Shoulder arms!
March right, march!
- [Explosions]
- Take your hands off that!
- Queen takes it!
- Well, if you think
that's a queen, look again.
Ah, it's a jack.
- Yeah.
- Honest, these cards all look alike.
[Laughing]
It's too noisy!
I can't play.
- I suppose your delicate nerves
can't stand it.
- Get up!
That's Oscar.
The son of a...
Look at that!
Don't be so snooty.
You may wish you had this back.
About two more days
of this...
and this rat-bitten end of
a piece of bread's gonna taste
like a hunk of fruitcake.
It wouldn't... It wouldn't last
two more days, would it?
Didn't I tell you
this was gonna be a bad one?
I don't mind
the days so much.
It's keeping up
all night...
Ah, two more days
makes a week, kid.
Then you can say
you've been under fire!
You're not scared, are you?
No. I was just asking.
That's all.
- Wanna play some more?
- Do you?
- Sure.
- All right. My deal.
You better get your boot back
before Oscar eats that!
- [Laughing]
- The kid's all right.
[Explosions Continue]
[Soldier Groaning]
Behn!
Behn.
[Kat] Yeah, yeah.
Let him sleep. He's dreamin'.
Oh, God.
Can't you see it's Behn?
He didn't want
to come to war!
No, no.
It isn't Behn.
[Shouting]
It isn't Behn!
It's Kemmerick!
It's me!
Shut up, will you?
It's bad enough in here as it is.
[Paul]
Every...
Everything's all right,
Franz. You're dreaming.
You're just
dreaming, I guess.
- Attention!
- At ease.
The barrage
is gettin' worse.
The men in two more
dugouts gone.
[Explosions Continue]
However, we'll do our best to get
some food up here by evening.
[Whimpering, Moaning]
[Screaming]
Stop! Stop!
[All Shouting]
[Kemmerick]
Let me out!
- What did you do that for?
- Shut up! Grab him.
- No.
- Now hold him.
[Sobbing]
You all right now?
I think so.
I couldn't hold out
much longer.
[Screaming]
[Paul Shouting]
- Oh, God, it's Franz!
- Get him over there!
No, he's been hit in the stomach.
He can't have anything to drink.
Get a stretcher.
Where'd they get you,
Kemmerick?
Oh.
- Here it is, sir.
- Take his head.
All right. Take him out.
- Is it serious, sir?
- I'm not sure.
- Tell the others he's all right.
- Yes, sir.
If we're going to fight,
why don't we fight?
Why don't we go over?
You could go crazy
staying here.
Let's do something!
- Let's go after 'em!
- Sit down!
If that cook of ours had any guts,
he'd try to bring something through.
He's so far behind the lines
he can't hear the shooting!
- Here's Kat. Get anything?
- Any luck?
- We'll have to split this up among us.
- Something to eat!
[All Shouting]
We need butter too.
Yes. And dessert.
And a feather bed to sleep on.
- Rats!
Get out of the way!
[All Shouting]
[Explosions Cease]
What's that?
- [Whistle Blowing]
- Come on! Grab your rifles!
[All Shouting]
Come on!
[Whistle Blowing]
- [Soldier #1] Here they come.
- [Soldier #2] Get your grenades here.
Hurry up.
Come on, hurry up.
[Distant Rumbling]
[Shells Whistling,
Exploding]
[Shouting]
[Shouting Continues]
[All Shouting]
Let's go!
Back to your own lines!
[Gunfire, Explosions
Continue]
真 [Singing Together
In German]
- Fill it up.
- And hurry up.
I've got other things to do.
I've been waiting for this
for three weeks.
When they all
get here.
What do you want?
Beans, you homely-lookin'
son of a frog's leg.
- What do you think I want?
- [Man] We're hungry.
[All Shouting]
Shut up! I'll feed you
when you're all here.
- We're all here now.
- Only half the company's here.
Get the rest.
- Wake 'em up.
- [All Laughing]
I wish I could
wake 'em up.
There's 80
of us left.
The rest is in dressing stations
or pushin' up daisies.
Eighty?
And I cooked for 150!
All right. We'll have enough
for once. Come on. Dish out!
You mean you've
cooked beans for 150...
and you've got bread
for 150...
and sausage for 150,
and tobacco for 150?
Everything! It's all wrong.
I should have been notified.
What a feast!
- Everyone gets two issues.
- [All Shouting]
- Get back in line! Get back in line!
- Oh, no!
That won't do.
I can't give 80 men
what's meant for 150.
[All Grumbling]
Listen.
You drew rations
for the 2nd Company, didn't ya?
Yeah.
All right.
We're the 2nd Company.
- [Approving Shouts]
- I've got my orders.
- Kat's right.
- We're the 2nd Company.
And if only half of us get back,
that's our good luck.
- Come on. Dish it out.
- [Men Shouting] Come on!
- No!
- [All] Hey!
You're the yellowest baboon
that ever drew a cook wagon,
and you're scared...
it shows.
All we want to hear out of you
is one more little yip,
and we'll cut ya up
and eat ya raw.
Why, you keep your kitchen
so far back of the lines,
we never get anything to eat
until it's cold and we're asleep!
Now, you low-down rat,
get out...
- or we wreck the joint!
- [Approving Shouts]
- Come on! Give us...
- Attention!
At ease.
What's goin' on here?
He's cooked for 150, sir,
and he only wants to give us half.
- Looks pretty good.
- Yes, sir.
- Serve the whole issue.
The men can use it.
- Yes, sir.
- And bring me a plate too.
All right. Take it all.
Take everything.
Give 'em honey.
Give 'em what they want.
- Fill it up!
[All Chattering]
- Don't mind me.
- Oh, that's all right. Don't mention it.
You know...
I could do with
some more beans.
Go help yourself.
There's more over there.
[Groaning]
- It's too far.
- [Kat Chuckling]
- I wonder, when are we
going back to the front?
- Tomorrow.
It's enough to take away
a man's appetite.
You know, if they're gonna
march us in again tomorrow,
we ought to go see
how Kemmerick is.
- That's a good idea.
- Let's do that.
- How far is the dressing station?
- About two miles.
- We could take his things to him.
- Good.
It seemed rotten to think of a thing
like that happening to him,
a nice fellow
like Kemmerick.
Ah, the French certainly deserve
to be punished for starting this war.
Everybody says
it's somebody else.
Well, how do they
start a war?
Well, one country
offends another.
How could one country
offend another?
You mean there's a mountain
over in Germany gets mad
at a field over in France?
- [All Laughing]
- Well, stupid,
one people offends another.
Oh, if that's it,
I shouldn't be here at all.
I don't feel offended.
It don't apply
to tramps like you.
Good. Then I can be
going home right away.
- Ah, you just try it.
- [Kat] Yeah. You wanna get shot?
- The kaiser and me...
- [Jeering, Snickering]
Me and the kaiser felt
just alike about this war.
We didn't either of us
want any war, so I'm going home.
- He's there already.
- Somebody must have wanted it.
Maybe it was
the English.
No, I don't want
to shoot any Englishmen.
I never saw one
till I came up here.
And I suppose most of them never saw
a German till they came up here.
- No, I'm sure they weren't
asked about it.
- No.
Well...
it must be doing
somebody some good.
- Not me and the kaiser.
- I think maybe the kaiser wanted a war.
You leave us
out of this!
I don't see that.
The kaiser's got
everything he needs.
Well, he never
had a war before.
Every full-grown emperor
needs one war to make him famous.
- Why, that's history.
- Yeah, generals too. They need war.
- And manufacturers. They get rich.
- [Murmurs Of Agreement]
I think it's more
a kind of fever.
Nobody wants it
in particular,
and then all at once,
there it is.
We didn't want it.
The English didn't want it.
And here we are fighting.
I'll tell you how
it should all be done.
Whenever there's
a big war comin' on,
- you should rope off a big field...
- And sell tickets.
Yeah. And...
And on the big day,
you should take all the kings
and their cabinets and their generals,
put them in the center
dressed in their underpants,
and let 'em fight it out
with clubs.
- The best country wins.
- [All Groan, Murmur]
Well, now that Kat's settled everything,
let's go see Kemmerick.
- Something interesting
might happen on the way.
- Might cheer him up.
Boys, me and the kaiser want you
back in time to march tomorrow.
Don't forget.
- We'll be back.
- Give the boy my regards.
[Soldiers Chattering]
There he is.
- Hello, Kemmerick.
- How are ya?
- How's it going?
How are things going?
Are they looking after you all right?
How are they treating you?
Franz?
[Groaning]
They're robbers here.
Robbers.
They stole my watch!
I always told you, nobody
should carry as good a watch as that.
- They took it while I was under ether!
- Franz, you'll get it back.
Do you feel all right?
- Just look at my hand.
- That's because you lost so much blood.
- Just eat decently
and you'll get well again.
- Oh, no.
You must eat. That's the main thing.
It looks good too.
I have such a terrible pain
in my foot.
Every toe
on my right foot hurts.
Well, how can your foot hurt
when your leg's been...
[Hysterically]
I know what you mean!
I know!
I know now!
They cut my leg off.
Why didn't they tell me?
Why... Why didn't they tell me?
- Franz! Franz!
- Now I can't walk anymore!
You must be thankful that you've
come off with only that.
I wanted to be
a forester once.
You can yet. They make artificial legs
that are wonderful.
And you're through too.
You can go home. Think of that.
We brought your things
for you. See?
Put 'em under the bed.
That's a marvelous pair
of boots.
Look at that leather!
What comfort.
I was just thinking.
If you're not going to be using these,
Franz, why don't you leave 'em with us?
What good are they to you?
I can use 'em.
My boots give me blister
after blister...
Well, we'll be going,
Franz.
Oh, don't go. Stay just
a little while longer.
- I'll come right back.
- We'll be coming soon again, Franz.
- I know you'll be feeling better.
- Bye.
- Good-bye, Franz.
[Albert]
You think he'll last till after mess?
- I don't think...
- Done for.
[Paul] Boys, you go along.
I'll see you later.
[Soldiers]
Good-bye. All right, Paul.
I'm sorry, Paul.
I wouldn't touch a thing
of his if he could use it.
I'd go barefoot over barbed wire
for him if it'd do him any good.
Only... Only why should
some orderly get those boots?
I understand, Mueller.
We're all alike out here.
And good boots
are scarce.
Tell the doctor to come,
please.
Doctor, the man in the next bed
would like to see you, sir.
I've done everything I can for him.
There's no helping him.
Poor little fella.
He says next time,
Franz.
Do you think
I'll ever get well?
Why, of course.
- Do you really think so?
- Sure, once you get over the operation.
I don't think so.
Franz! Don't talk nonsense.
Why, you'll be as good as new.
They fix up worse things
than that.
Perhaps you'll go
to the convalescent home...
in Klosterberg
among the villagers.
Then you can look out of the
windows, across the fields...
to the two trees
on the horizon.
The loveliest time of the year
now when the corn ripens.