[Firearm Cocking]
- Oh, man.
- Man, what's takin' you so long?
- It's cold as a motherfucker out here.
- I had to get the last stop.
- Quiet, punk.
- Come on, man. I'm freezin'
my fuckin' nuts out here.
- Mush, mother, mush!
- [Laughing]
?? [Radio]
- Ant, Juanita give you
some of that pussy yet?
- Oh, get out of here, man.
What? Man, I thought we was
homies, man. I'm just askin'.
Why you gotta be askin' me
all that? I mean...
Look, I'm just
lookin' out for you.
All I'm sayin', man, fine as she is,
she should be giving you something.
I bet you ain't even
smelled the pussy, eh?
You two realize that soon we're
gonna be out of school, right?
- Ohh, sure.
- After four long years of that shit.
I can't fuckin' wait to get out.
That's all I been thinkin' about, man.
You know? I just been thinkin' about
what I'm gonna do afterwards, right?
You know, I can dig
some travelling.
You sound like
you rich or somethin'.
Hear this nigger?
He ain't even got a fuckin' job!
- I know.
- You better take your ass
off to college, man.
I'm tellin' you.
Uncle Sam grab your ass like
they gonna do this stupid motherfucker.
- Oh, bullshit, Skip, man.
Ain't nobody gonna grab me.
- Jose.
A recruiter can see your
dumb ass a mile away. Look at you.
You a recruiter's dream.
You a 1-A.
A one-way ticket to motherfuckin'
Vietnam if I ever saw one.
That's why I'm goin' to Hunter College.
You goddamn right.
I ain't fightin'
no white man's war. Shit.
Them Vietcongs, chongs, whatever
the fuck, ain't done shit to me.
I don't even know
them motherfuckers, man.
I ain't afraid
of no war.
What the fuck
you been smokin'?
Y'all might think
I'm crazy, but...
I just wanna do somethin'
that's different.
Yeah, well, gettin' your fuckin' head
blown off is different.
Ha-ha! Hey, man, turn that shit down.
And slow this motherfucker down.
- Ain't nobody
in a hurry to go to school.
- Man, leave that shit up.
?? [Radio Continues]
[Skip]
You know I fucked Monica, right? Her
mama came in, caught us the other day.
- Came in, seen my dick,
jumped in the bed too.
- Later, you chump suckers.
- [Skip] Oh, fuck you.
- Yo' mama.
- Jivin' around. Get your
dumb ass back in the truck.
- For you, Anthony, right here.
Close this motherfuckin' door.
It's cold as hell out here.
Get your nasty ass in.
Oh, hey.
How you doin'?
You up kinda early.
Um, I heard your truck.
Seems like you hear my truck
every mornin'.
Well, uh, morning is
the best time to study, so...
You should, uh, try workin' on
your first boyfriend.
I'm too busy studyin'
to be worryin' about boys.
Your sister up?
- Uh, Sleeping Beauty?
- Yeah.
Look, uh, tell her
I said hey. See ya.
- Mornin', Anthony.
- Oh, hey.
- I thought you were sleeping.
- You woke me up.
- Uh, so you goin' to school today?
- Mmm.
I could lay in bed
all mornin'.
Ohh. See, now...
Now that'd be real nice.
- Don't even think about it.
- Well, look, uh...
I'm gonna get on out of here.
I'll talk to you later.
- Okay.
- See ya.
? Keep on pushin'?
- ? Keep on pushin'?
- [Man Calling, Indistinct]
- I'll be down there later on.
- ? You got to keep on pushin'?
? Mmm?
? I can't stop now...??
Hard shoe. Come here,
hard shoe. Come here, man.
- What's up? What's up?
- Listen, I want you to tell
Kirby I want 645.
- Straight now. Listen, and,
uh... We've been rollin' here.
- Straight.
- Come on, man. I ain't got time.
Let me get the money.
- I want you to be back here...
- Tonight with my money,
you little motherfucker.
- Man, straighten your hat out.
What's goin' on, baby?
All right, Cat Daddy. All right.
- Hey, Anthony. How you doin'?
- Hey.
You know you brought me luck the other
day, so look, ten of that's for you.
- [Man] See? Now that's how it go.
- Hey, now.
- I'm gonna use the same number too.
- Don't forget me, man.
- What's goin' on?
Hey, what's goin' on?
- ? She belongs to my baby?
- Hey there, Jellybean. What's goin' on?
- ?? [Singing Continues]
?? [Saxophone, R&B]
[Billiard Balls Clacking]
All right.
Hey, what's goin' on?
How you feelin'? Kirby back there?
[Men Murmuring,
Indistinct]
- Get that shot. Get that shot.
- All right, thanks, youngblood.
Hey, Peanut. What's goin' on?
What's up there?
[Buzzer]
Blood.
- Come on, come on,
- Kirby's back there
in the back, man.
- Put that in Brooklyn and get hold
of that fuckin' Spyder.
- Yeah.
- Hey, kid.
- [Man] Aw, man, take...
[Indistinct]
- Here's the numbers.
- [Radio Broadcast, Indistinct]
- Cash.
- [Phone Ringing]
- Here it is.
- [Popeye On TV, Indistinct]
- [Man] We got five.
- [Olive Oyl] Hubba, hubba!
- Whoo!
- Ain't you supposed to be
duck huntin' with your daddy?
Oh, yeah. We gonna go
next weekend.
- Oh, shit.
- Oh, man, Kirby.
Made me
miss my shot.
[Kirby] You know these
motherfuckers down South.
I wonder if half the time they
believe what they be sayin'.
What's a nigger
gonna do?
We got blood in this land from slaves.
Been to war. Spilt our blood.
Shit, I been to war.
I spilt blood.
[Anthony] Ha! That's right.
Tell 'em, Kirby.
You over there
fightin' in Korea.
That's how I got this plastic-ass leg.
Nicky, fix me a drink.
[Kirby]
Ko-motherfuckin'-rea.
Damn! Mmm!
- ? Never gonna give you up??
- [Kirby] That's why I had
to leave that whole thing.
'Cause if I'd have still been there,
I'd have killed me a motherfucker.
[Nicky] Man, shit ain't gonna change.
What make you think shit gonna change?
Nigger, what's your little narrow ass
doin' up in here, man?
Leave that boy alone
and let him shoot.
Aw, Kirby, man, you know he too
goddam young to be up in here, man.
He can outshoot you.
Oh, shit.
Oh, I know you out your
motherfuckin' mind, man.
- [Chuckles]
- Put your money where your mouth is.
I take your money.
Rack 'em, boy.
- ? Uh-huh, uh-uh?
- Watch this.
? I got the feelin'?
? Baby, baby
I got the feelin'?
- [Anthony] Yes!
- ? You don't know?
- [Muttering]
- You got my two dollars?
- Game ain't over yet, man.
- ? What you do to me??
[Anthony]
Got the eight ball, corner pocket.
Oh, man! Damn!
[Slams Cue Stick]
Come on.
Don't run out of here without
payin' me after that boy whup you.
Yeah, at least I will
run out of this, motherfucker.
People that owe me money don't pay me,
I can take care of them.
Man, will you get the fuck off
my motherfuckin' table, please?
Chicken-haired
motherfucker.
Ain't no goddam business
bein' here in the first place.
Ooh, missed it
by that much.
- [Anthony] Cleanup time.
- Hey now, you don't never play with me.
Eight ball,
corner pocket.
Oh! Yes! Game.
[Claps Hands,
Chuckles]
Hey, that's
a good game, Cowboy.
You're a lucky motherfucker,
you know that?
Aw. [Laughing] I wouldn't say
luck, but you know.
- Just know how to play a little bit.
- Here's the money.
Give that to Kirby.
All right.
Wait.
This is two dollars.
See, uh, you bet me, so that means,
uh, you owe me some money too.
Man, fuck you.
Why you gotta cheat?
Who the fuck you think
you talkin' to, man?
You know what? I'm gonna tell
everybody around here...
when it comes to playin' pool,
Cowboy likes to cheat.
- Nigger, I'll kick your
little monkey ass, man.
- Oh, man.
Shut your motherfuckin'
mouth, man.
I oughta cut you.
Little motherfucker.
Yeah.
It hurt, don't it?
[Laughing]
What the fuck?
What the fuck are you doin'?
- [Kirby Muttering]
- [Cowboy] Get the fuck off of me, man.
- Kirby, what the fuck you doin', man?
- What the fuck are you doin'?
- Get out of here. Get on out of here!
- You a bad motherfucker!
- And don't you come back in here
unless you come correct.
- [Cowboy] Fuck you!
[Door Slamming]
[Muttering]
- You all right, kid?
- Oh, yeah. Just a little cut, you know?
It's all right.
Yep. You do a real good job
for me with them numbers.
Well, you know, I try.
But, uh, you better be cool.
Don't let your mom and pop find out.
Oh, no way.
I won't do that.
It's for you.
Oh, man. Whoa!
Oh-ho!
Hey, thanks, Kirby.
Ain't nothin' to thank me for.
You earned it.
Ohh. Twenties.
Hey, kid. You wanna
take a little run with me?
Yeah. I'll take
a little run with you.
[Horns Honking]
- [Radio]
You want to be one of the boys?
- Say, Kirby, where we goin'?
- The marines are looking
for a few good men.
- Like I told you.
- Just a little run.
- A run. Okay.
All right.
- Wanna drive, kid?
- Who, me?
No, not "me."
You, motherfucker.
- Well, Kirby, I don't have
my licence yet.
- Oh, shit.
- Fuck the dumb shit.
You wanna drive or what?
- Yeah. L-I'll drive. Yeah.
[Horn Honking]
- Pull over here.
- All right.
Come on.
[Anthony] What you call her?
Nellie? Come on, Nellie.
[Kirby] I call this bitch
whatever I want to.
[Siren Wailing]
Listen here.
Keep that motre runnin'.
- I'll just be a minute, hear?
- Yeah, all right.
?? [Radio Plays]
[Stations Changing]
?? [Upbeat]
- [Kirby] I told you
to stop messin' with my gold.
- [Man] Wait a minute!
How many times
I gotta tell you?
[Woman Screaming]
I ain't no motherfuckin'
play toy! I'll kick your ass.
Get the fuck up.
You get the fuck up
off of Spyder!
- Whoa.
- You got more heart than your
punk-ass old man. Come here.
- [Men Yelling]
- Oh, man! Kirby!
Oh! What the...
Give me my fuckin' leg!
You stupid son-of-a-bitch.
You grabbed the wrong leg, you
stupid cocksucker. Come here.
- Get on back in here now, Spyder.
- [Kirby] You asshole.
- I want my motherfuckin'
money, hear? Now!
- Easy, Kirby. Easy, man.
Dumb son of a... Give me my fuckin' leg,
you stupid cocksucker.
I'll fuck you up!
[Man]
Get on back down there.
? I got
15 miles to go now?
- Come on. Come on!
- ? I can hear my baby callin' my name?
- Floor this motherfucker.
- ?? [Music Continues, Indistinct]
Floor it.
? Now I'll be so glad
to see my baby?
? And hold her in my arms
one more time?
? Huh
Now when I kiss her lips?
- ? I'll turn a backward flip?
- [Kirby] You did good, kid.
You almost as good
a getaway driver as me.
- Uh, thanks.
- ? Just keep on walkin'?
- Say, uh, so you were
a getaway driver, huh?
- ? Walk on...??
[Coughing]
Son of a bitch.
- What? What's wrong?
- I oughta go back there
and kill that bastard.
- Why? What happened?
- Motherfucker made me lose
a whole pack of cigarettes.
A pack of cigarettes?
I thought maybe you should be worried
about your leg or somethin'.
- Well, that's just funny to you, huh?
- No, no, it's not funny.
I tell you what. The next time a
motherfucker grabs me by the wrong leg,
I'm gonna use it to kick his ass
between his shoulder blades.
- [Both Laughing]
- Hey, man, you really did that sucker.
Yeah, everybody in town
know I got one leg, and that
motherfucker grab the wrong one.
Me and Kirby, baby.
Yeah.
[Laughter]
This is wonderful news,
Edward.
- Thank you.
- [Mother] All right, all right.
You see, Anthony?
You be thankful you can go to City
College on the financial aid programme.
Yeah, in four years,
you can be just like me.
Just like you.
[Laughing]
You can graduate and maybe even
go to graduate school too.
Well, I'll tell y'all one thing.
My mama sure would've been proud.
Never would've believed
I got two college graduates.
You think about what
you're gonna major in, baby?
Uh, the Marine Corps.
Dad, could you pass the salt?
What'd you say?
Ahem. Thanks.
I said the, uh, Marine Corps.
I'm... I'm joinin'.
- Marine Corps?
- Yeah.
[Brother]
Now that's original.
What you talkin' about,
Anthony?
I'm talkin' about
I wanna do somethin' else.
I don't wanna go
to college.
I'm sick of school.
I mean... I don't know why everybody
got this strange look on their face.
It's my life.
Yeah.
It's your life.
Looks like to me you're tryin'
to ruin it, baby.
You're an idiot.
You know that?
Man, I don't wanna go to college.
I'm just not ready for no college.
You always said the marines and fightin'
over in Korea made a man out of you.
I figure I be, you know,
livin' my own life.
I'll talk to your mama.
[Kids Chattering]
? When your baby and you
are tight?
? And everything is right
and you is mellow?
Here you go.
Drink some wine.
? You keep everything
all right?
? And you know that
you're the only fellow?
? Ain't that a groove?
? Ain't that a groove
Ah?
- ? Ain't that a groove?
- [Retching]
- Told your little ass
you couldn't drink with me.
- ? Ain't that a groove?
- ? Now lookee here, fella?
- Yeah. Whoa!
? Girls like to be
in the mood?
- ? Whenever they think
their man is yellow?
- Whoo!
- ? Hit me, baby?
- Yeah!
- ? You'll fight real hard...??
- Say, Skeeter, I still can't
believe you graduated, man.
- [Laughing]
- Man, shut up.
Glad we out of school, man.
I'm sick of these stupid-ass brothers.
I'm 'bout to get
my pimp thing on started.
You know I got so many ho's now, man,
I gotta get an assistant pimp...
just to keepin' track of 'em,
you know, make sure they
on the right streets and shit.
Say, Skippy, why... why you
always talkin' 'bout this pimp
stuff, man? What's happenin'?
'Cause it's real, man. I'm a pimp.
Pimpin' run in my family.
My great-great-granddaddy
was a slave, and he was a pimp.
He used to have ho's pick his cotton
in the field. He didn't have to do shit.
- Ha!
- You better be careful, man.
- You're gonna catch
something, Skip. Watch.
- That's all right, motherfucker.
I was born by the pussy;
I'll die by the pussy.
Don't worry about what the fuck I do.
Hey, Skip, you believe
in superstition?
Hell, no.
Well, you should, man.
Your stupid-ass jinxed me.
- What the fuck you talkin' 'bout?
- Uncle Sam, man.
- Dropped a motherfuckin' 1-A on me.
- [Laughing]
- I told you, didn't I?
Didn't I tell you?
- Hey, when did that happen?
- Last week, Anthony, man.
- Yeah, right, mother. Pass the joint.
- Anthony, man.
- What?
You know that, uh,
that me and Marisol, we tight, man.
Yeah, man, y'all are...
Y'all pretty down.
[Jose]
You would say I love her?
I could say
that you love her, man.
- I'm thinkin' about marrying her, man.
- Oh, wait a minute.
- Hey, don't do that shit.
- Hey, man, now you might be
goin' a little too fast now.
Hey, I love her, man, and did you see
how she looks today at that party, man?
- [Anthony]
Aw, she looks good enough to marry.
- I'm glad to hear you want me.
- What you over here
talkin' about, Anthony?
- Why you standin' over here?
- Shut up, Skippy.
- Shut up.
Anthony, I know you ain't gonna
stay over here talkin' to Skip
while my song's playin'.
Mmm. Not if they expect
to be with us tonight.
- Look, we're gonna
have to cut on out, bro.
- Uh, yeah.
- Man, where y'all goin'?
- Uh, we gonna go hang on out.
- Look it. Have some chicken.
- I thought we was hangin', man.
- Have some chicken, man.
- I told you 'bout them
broads, old punk-ass.
And anyway, Skip,
Brenda lookin' for you.
I don't give a fuck. You tell her I'm
at where I at and I'll be where I be.
Motherfuckin' pimp. I gotta go every ho
want me to be, I be confused.
Motherfucker. Tell her don't make me
hurt my hand again.
? If you want a do-right
all-day?
? Woman?
- [Backup]? Woman?
- ? You gotta be a do-right?
? Do-right?
- ? All-night man??
- Jose.
I love you.
I love you, too, mama.
If you give my pussy away
to somebody else when I'm gone,
I'm gonna come back
and blow that motherfucker up.
I got this itch
I need to be scratched.
S-S-S-S-So you're sayin'
that y-your, your mama...
is workin'
the night shift tonight?
Mm-hmm. And you know
what else?
You can scratch it
all night long if you want to.
- You know I'm the nigger.
I'm the nigger. You know I'm the nigger.
- Mm-hmm.
You swear Big Bertha
won't get off work early?
She's not gonna
get off from work early.
- You scared?
- No, I ain't scared. I just don't want...
You act like you're scared.
Come on. Shut up.
- Wh-Where Delilah at?
- She in her room. Come on!
- ? Say it loud?
- [Backup Singers]
? I'm black and I'm proud?
- Get out.
- ? Say it loud?
- Go to your own room.
- ? I'm black and I'm proud?
- ? Say it loud, Oh?
- ? I'm black and I'm proud??
? Once upon a time
I almost lost my mind?
? I was lonely?
Mmm.
? So lonely??
[Gasping]
Oh, Juanita.
Look, it's okay.
It's all right.
It's okay.
Okay. Okay.
- Let me get your bra.
- Okay.
Ow. Just unhook it.
Just unhook the...
- I can't.
- I'll get it. I'll do it.
- Okay. Okay.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Don't peek. Don't look at...
Don't look at me. Okay.
Okay.
- Oh!
- What?
That's not it.
Up, up, up, up. Higher. Ow.
That's too high.
Wait. Down, down.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Right there? Okay.
- Okay. Okay.
- All right.
Uh, wait.
Okay.
Easy. Ow!
Ah!
[Gasping]
[Headboard Banging]
[Banging Continues,
Anthony Grunting]
[Juanita Gasping]
- Oh, brother!
- [Anthony] Oh! Oh, shit.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
[Shuddering]
Oh, shit.
- Okay.
- [Gasping] Baby.
You know, Marisol and Jose
going down to city hall tomorrow.
Oh, yeah?
What for?
To get married.
- Is that right?
- What you think about that?
Nothin', I guess.
So I guess you don't want me to
wait for you either.
[Sighs] Look, Juanita,
I didn't say that.
So you gonna marry me
when you get back?
I mean, if you ain't
got somebody else.
I don't want nobody else.
Juanita, have you
ever thought maybe...
maybe I might get hurt out there
and never come back?
You know, I don't want you
waitin' for nothin'.
You not scared
of losing me?
I didn't say that either.
I'm scared
of losin' you.
So do you think we could probably
do it one more time before I go?
Uh-huh.
[Juanita Gasping,
Headboard Banging]
Oh, no.
- It's Ma!
- Shh! But it's just 6:30!
- She just pulled up.
- Well, go stall her. And close my door!
Oh, shoot!
- I shouldn't have never messed
around with you in the first place.
- Right.
- You know Bertha gonna kill us.
- Wait a minute.
- Nuh-uh, ain't gonna wait
a minute. Would you move?
- Wait a minute!
[Delilah] Come on.
Let me help you with them packages.
- [Bertha] Delilah!
- I got it.
Girl, you got my good groceries
all on the ground.
Pick those up!
[Banging]
Since I work, the least you girls
could do is keep this place clean.
You know I'm gonna
wait for you, Anthony.
Juanita, I gotta go.
I gotta go,
Juanita.
- [Tyres Squealing]
- [Man] Nigger, get out of my yard!
Fuck you!
[Tyres Squealing,
Dog Barking]
Shut up!
[Radio Transmission]
What's your status? Over.
[Gunfire]
[Soldiers Yelling, Indistinct]
Move it!
Shit.
Head for the rally point!
Get back to the rally point!
- [Explosion]
- Get the fuck outta here!
Go!
Forward!
Let's go! Pick it up!
Pick it up! Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Move! Move! Let's go!
- [Gunfire]
- Load 'em up! Load 'em up!
[Gunfire]
Oh, fuck!
I'm out of ammo!
- Devaughn! Cover me!
- Stay down!
[Gunfire]
- I got him. Hurry up!
- [Mortar Whistling]
- [Screaming]
- Don't check out on us, Martin.
- You're all right.
You're gonna be all right.
- I got him!
- Cover fire!
- [Gunfire]
- You'll be all right.
- Goddamn it! They got us pinned down!
We'll never make
the rally point!
Dugan!
You think it's time we get these
fucking dinks off our asses? Huh?
- Relax.
- Fuck you! Fuck you,
fuck you, fuck you!
- [Yelling]
- Radio, up!
God don't like dinks.
- How's he doin', Curtis?
- Hey, man, thanks.
- Thanks for not leavin' me, man.
- Shh.
- Where the fuck is that radio?
Get that radio up here!
- [Anthony] No, no, no, no.
- [Soldier]
Radio comin' around! Radio comin'!
- Get that cover fire, Ferguson.
- You wanna die, boy?
- [Soldier] Lieutenant, arty freak.
Sir, sir! Lieutenant!
Arty freak!
- Over here!
- Hammerhead, hammerhead.
Recon Cobra.
Emergency fire mission. Over.
- [Groaning]
- Hold on, brother. Come on.
Come on, come on. You gonna make it,
dude. You only got a little longer.
- You gonna make it.
- [Lt. Dugan]
Grid five, seven, one-niner.
- Tell Mama...
- [Radio Operator] Three, eight.
No, no. I don't...
[Indistinct]
[Mortar Whistling,
Explosion]
Gooks in the bush. Request
firecracker salvo. Will adjust.
How copy?
Over.
[Radio Transmission]
Roger. Solid copy. Firecracker shot out.
[Soldier]
Incoming!
Down! Down!
Down!
Curtis, get down!
Out-fucking-standing job.
Saddle up. Let's get to the rally point,
take that whirlybird home.
- We got some beer to drink.
- We goin' to the rally point now?
The mission's been compromised.
We're goin' to site 37.
It ain't compromised
no more.
They're dead.
Now this is Sneaky Pete.
Reconnaissance.
Some of them dead gooks,
they could have important
intelligence papers on their bodies.
All right.
- Move 'em out.
- Move out!
[Radio Operator]
Hammerhead, Hammerhead, Cobra
on site of your mission now.
I count ten... say again, ten...
Number-Victor-Alpha Kilo-lndia-Alpha.
- How copy? Over.
- [Radio] I copy, one-zero. Good job.
- [Static]
- Hammerhead, Cobra.
Solid copy. "Good job."
Cobra out.
Aw, shit, man!
What you doin'? He already dead.
Motherfucker.
[Laughing]
Looks like we nailed us
an officer.
You lucky bastard.
You get back to C.P., you
name your own price, sir.
No way, D'Ambrosio.
I'm keepin' this one.
Been lookin' for one of these
since Cleon and I got here in '66.
Ain't that right, Cleon?
[Laughing]
I walked
right by that guy.
Ah, you gotta keep
your eyes open.
Oh, man, what the fuck?
Ahem. You hungry
or somethin', Cleon?
Just like you, sir.
I'm collectin' me
a souvenir.
Mm-hmm.
Saddle up.
We're movin' out.
That's all he's gonna say?
You ain't got nothin' to tell this
fuckin' shit, man? Fuck.
- Man, that nigger Cleon crazy.
- Yeah.
- Did you see that shit?
- I saw it.
- Nigger, did you see that shit?
- Yes.
I heard that nigger supposed to be
a preacher's son and shit.
He cuttin' off motherfucker's
heads for souvenirs and shit.
You know, if you hadn't flunked out of
Hunter College, pimp daddy Skippy,
you would've missed all this good shit
down in Vietnam.
Kiss my ass, nigger. You the reason why
I'm in this motherfucker anyway.
You didn't tell me
'bout this recon shit.
That's 'cause you didn't ask
me when you were writin' me.
- Shit, I figured it was better
than bein' a grunt.
- It is.
Ant. Motherfucker,
we out in the woods all day.
Them motherfuckin' gooks jumpin' out
like Indians every five minutes, man.
- Nigger ain't made for this shit.
- You thought this was a skate.
Nigger, ain't nothin' wrong
with no skate.
You could just call me
a skatin' motherfucker.
I skate my ass right out of here,
they give me a chance to.
- Ain't no shitbirds on my squad.
- Man, what you jivin' about?
[Young Woman
Speaking Vietnamese]
- [Anthony Muttering]
- [Women Chattering]
Hey. Hey.
Hey! To the Bronx.
Yeah, uh,
to the young blood who couldn't be
with us today.
- Lance Corporal Martin.
- To Lance Corporal Martin.
Yes.
Yo, Ant, man. What they been puttin'
in your head out here, man?
I mean, you done got into this shit a
little bit too deep, don't you think?
You in recon now, Skip.
You in deep too.
Man, fuck this shit, man.
- Oh, come on, man.
- Man, this ain't our war, man.
Shit, our black ass should be back
in the Bronx where we belong.
Joe-ass got lucky. They sent him home,
gettin' wounded and shit.
Heard he wounded his hand
pretty bad, man.
Shit, that's all right, though.
He got out of this shit.
I rather be home with a fucked-up hand
up in some pussy than to be out here...
healthier than
a motherfucker without it.
- Shit.
- Same old Skip. Boy, you ain't changed.
That's right.
You heard from Juanita?
She used to write me a lot
during my first tour.
[Soldier Shouting]
We got a package for ya!
Turns out, man, before I left,
fucked around and got her pregnant.
- Man, you bullshittin'.
- No, I ain't.
- No shit?
- Dead serious, man.
Got a little girl back at home.
Oh, man, that's groovy, man. That's
groovy. I can dig it. That's cool.
Hey, dig, man, I know
you got a picture, man.
- Let me see her picture. Shit.
- Can't even look at her, man.
Man, what the fuck
you mean, bro?
That's your little girl, man.
That's your baby.
You know how I survived
26 months in the bush?
Because I don't think about the world,
Skip. That shit don't exist to me.
I don't give a fuck about anything
or anyone in it,
because the minute I do, I'm a dead man
out here, and you remember that shit.
We'll talk about the world
when we get back.
Yeah, whatever, man.
I'm gonna go get high.
I mean real high. And I'm gonna
get my dick sucked too.
[Speaking Vietnamese]
[Skip Continues In Vietnamese]
Big dick. Big.
Very, very big.
Can you handle it?
"Hey there, Kirby. What's happenin'
back in the world?
If you hadn't heard,
doin' my second tour.
- Fire in the hole!
We spend most of our time
livin' in the bush.
[Letter Continues]
Kind of numb to everything out here.
Tryin' to keep
my head clear.
Our lieutenant is this crazy
white boy named Dugan from Ohio.
- He's good at gettin' us
out of crazy situations.
- Look out.
[Soldiers Yelling]
We got this one wild-ass
brother out here named Cleon.
Gook fuck.
His daddy's this big-time
preacher, but you'd never know
from his crazy son.
Now you're good.
Now Jesus loves you.
He's from Mount Vernon.
Oh, yeah. You won't believe it,
but Skip volunteered
for my unit.
I don't think he's
cut out for recon.
He's always gettin' high and shit,
tryin' to keep his mind off things.
Me, I'm just tryin' to take it
one day at a time and do what's right,
whatever that is.
See you when I get
back to the Bronx.
Anthony."
[Coughing]
[Radio Transmission,
Indistinct]
That fuckin' shit stinks.
I don't wanna pull rank, Cleon, but if
you don't get rid of that fuckin' head...
I don't hear nobody else
complainin' but you.
Well, maybe you should
listen to your team.
Medical advice, Cleon:
You dump that shit.
Hey, Doc, shut the fuck up.
You don't know shit.
Fuck you, man. It stinks like
a sack full of assholes.
Ain't a one of us got as much as
a splinter in his finger
since I cut this head off.
This head is our
good-luck charm.
Nah, this here's
our good-luck charm.
If you don't mind, Sergeant, l...
My vote is to get rid of it.
Man, Cleon, you need to get the
fuck on with that bullshit, man.
That head smell like shit.
Bottom line,
Staff Sergeant:
You either get rid of that
fuckin' head A.S.A. fuckin' P.,
or I'm gonna have your ass
court-martialled when we get
back to the rear.
We clear?
- Cobra, Cobra, Delta six. Over.
- Delta six, Delta six, Cobra.
Copy. Over.
- [Radio] Cobra, Delta six.
X-G Charlie, Michael...
- We're in a world of shit now.
I just buried our luck.
Listen up. Change of mission.
A patrol from 25...
has found a shitload of weapons
in a vill about a klik
and a half to our whisky.
Platoon commander wants us
to interrogate on the spot.
Betancourt, you're the closest one in
the area that speaks that gook shit.
So that's where we're headin'.
All right, saddle up. We're movin' out.
- So now where's D'Ambrosio?
- He went to go take a shit.
- When?
- When Cleon was diggin' the hole.
- Why the hell didn't you go with him?
- You know how he is.
- He don't like nobody around
when he's shittin'.
- Oh, man.
Grab his shit.
Let's find him.
Aww.
Fuck! Doc.
- 360!
- D'Ambrosio, what'd they do?
- You'll be all right.
Doc's gonna take care of you, okay?
- Yeah.
This morphine is all
I can do for him right now.
Here, Doc. You can use mine
if that's not enough.
Are you crazy? Another one
of those would kill him right now.
What the fuck
you got there, Curtis?
Somethin' about
"Black men, go home."
"This isn't your war."
You get rid of that cocksucking
commie bullshit right now.
- Yeah. Right.
- Hey, Curtis.
- Apply some pressure here.
- We gotta hump this man
back to the rally point.
Oh, shit.
Save me, Curtis.
Look, Adam, you don't
worry 'bout nothin'.
We're a team,
okay, brother?
- We gonna take care of you.
- Please.
Yeah. It's not much longer.
We're almost there.
Kill me.
Kill me!
I would do it for you.
I would do it
for you, Curtis.
Buttermilk 17.
Cobra, over.
[Radio] Cobra. Buttermilk 17. Inbound
your buzz. Contact on your visual.
- Shh.
- [Dugan] Buttermilk 17. Cobra.
- Hey, you gonna be all right.
- [Dugan's Transmission
Continues, Indistinct]
The medevac will be here
in a minute.
- [Radio Transmission, Indistinct]
- Do it.
You think
I don't mean it?
I can't go home like this.
- [Skip] Hey, what's he saying?
- He's delirious, man.
- Please.
- [Radio] Uh, Cobra, Buttermilk.
- Hooking direct to your 12. Stand by.
- Cobra standing by. Over.
Shh-shh-shh.
[Radio] Uh, Cobra, Buttermilk 17.
On your visual. Pop smoke. Over.
Buttermilk 17, Cobra.
Smoke. Over.
Pop the smoke.
Get that man ready for medevac!
[Transmission Continues,
Indistinct]
- When'd he go?
- A few minutes ago.
It's better to check out
than to go home all fucked up.
[Helicopter Approaching]
No shit.
[Metal Clattering]
Oh, shit!
Get down!
- [Shuddering]
- Fuckin' assholes!
- Stay down! Stay down!
- I'm gonna get these motherfuckers!
[Dugan]
Return fire! Fire!
[Yelling, Indistinct]
Get these motherfuckers!
- Skip! Return some fire!
- Shoot them motherfuckers!
Mission aborted! We get the fuck
out of Dodge, back to the rally point!
Ferguson! Get some
fuckin' rounds goin'!
- [Soldier Yelling In Vietnamese]
- Skip! Cover me!
- [Cleon] Dugan!
- [Anthony] Dugan, wait!
Dugan! Dugan!
[Yelling,
Indistinct]
[Screaming]
[Soldier Yelling,
Indistinct]
Skip! Snap out of
that shit. Go!
- Fuck this, man. Let's bug out, Cleon!
- Cobra, move the fuck out!
- Get up! Come on!
- Move it! Move it!
Move! Get up!
Get up! Come on!
- What are you doin'?
- What is this, man?
- Slow down, man. Say!
- Fuckin' grunts!
- Get a special shot for Skip.
My man's goin' home today.
- Count of three: 1-2-3.
- Snap it.
- All right. Good. Now come on now.
Skip, come on now.
- Let's see a dap, man.
- Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh.
He say, "Uh."
He say, "Fi-ive."
- Ah. All right. Whoo!
- Get one like this. Get one like this.
One, two. Come on now.
Everybody, come on. Get closer.
- Aw, man!
- This is Cobra, baby.
- Recon Cobra!
It's Cobra. Hey, hey!
Whoo!
- Team Cobra, ready? [Grunting]
- [Growling]
? Come on?
? Come along, Come on and get up
and get down too?
- ? Ah, get down, get up?
- Say, h-h-hold on a sec.
- Keep the metre running.
- ? Ah, get down, get up
and move your feet?
- ? Ah, come on and?
- ? Rise, rise, rise, shake your getup??
Straighten up there,
marine.
He a friend of yours?
He a friend of yours,
I'll give you a discount, marine.
Nah, man.
Oh, shit.
Man, look who's back in
the motherfuckin' world.
- Dig this motherfucker right here, man.
- [People Chattering]
Look at you, man. That's a mackin'
outfit if I've ever seen one.
Look with all these stripes and shit.
What, you a captain now?
- Nah, nah, brother.
- Look, man, you wear that
motherfucker for about a month,
this nigger get
all the pussy, man.
Check this
motherfucker out, man.
- Need somethin', Cowboy?
- Well, look mi... Yeah, you go
get me some squares, man.
- Right on.
- I gotta take care
a couple of things, baby.
I'll get back with you, all right?
You stay up now, all right?
What's happenin', blood?
Hey, man, I'm back!
My nigger!
- Hey, Luther!
- Yeah?
Tell your sister I'm gonna be
over there later on!
Hey, fuck you!
Man, the neighbourhood
is changin'.
Aw, it's still
a good place.
- White people movin' out, though.
- [Chuckling]
Oh, dig. I saw Juanita
the other day, man.
Man, she finer
than a motherfucker.
Is that right?
You need to go check her out, man.
Go see your little daughter.
- Remember them big-ass ears
you had when you was young?
- [Chuckling]
She got 'em, just like you.
That's how I know it was yours.
So what's up with Joe, man?
Is he, uh... Is he workin' or what?
Aw, post office, you know.
Three-quarter gig, part-time.
He gotta do what he gotta do.
He got mouths to feed, you know.
What about you, man?
How you doin'?
- Who, me?
- Yeah.
I'm cool, baby. I'm Skippy, baby.
I'm still pimpin'.
Need any money
or anything, you know?
Man, I got over like a fat rat
when I got out, man.
Dig. I got my school money comin'
from the government once a month.
I got my veteran's cheque
comin' once a month.
I got my 50% medical cheque comin'
to me for the rest of my life.
I ain't gotta do a goddam thing else
but go to the mailbox, you dig?
Hey, man, how the hell you pull a 50%
medical? Nigger, you ain't disabled.
Man, some shit got
into me over there, man.
What?
All I know is
my blood cells all fucked up.
Some nights I wake up
in cold sweats and shit.
Don't look at me like that, man.
It ain't the heroin.
Heroin ain't never did nothin' to me.
Lot of vets comin' down with this shit.
- And they don't know what it is?
- Square biz.
Damn.
Look, man, you wanna come on
in the crib or somethin', man?
Nah, man. I'm cool, baby.
Hey, I'm gonna split.
But you here, baby. You home.
We got plenty of time do our thing.
You know what I'm sayin'?
- Brother.
- Go see your mama.
- Right on. I'm gonna check her out.
With her fine ass. I been takin'
care of your mama while you been gone.
Boy, I kick your head in.
Don't talk like that.
[Smacking Lips]
Mm.
You all right?
Yeah.
Well, can't you look me
in my eyes?
I ain't seen you
in four years.
What'd you do over there?
What was it like?
Look, uh, I'd rather not
talk about that right now.
Well, Anthony, you're gonna
have to tell us something.
You know, a lot of them boys went over
there and got hooked on drugs and stuff.
Look. I was in
a special unit out there,
and bad habits could have
cost us our lives.
That's what I'm talkin' about,
them bad habits.
Now, if you picked up
some of them things,
there's a lot of places
you can go and get help.
No bad habits, Ma,
'cept a little killin'.
For my country,
of course.
Hey, let me give you some more of
these collards. Baby, this sure is good.
[Mr Curtis Chuckles,
Clears Throat]
- All right.
- Oh, shit. Look who's back.
Look at this motherfuckin' man.
- Hey, what's happenin', youngblood?
- What's goin' on, Cool Breeze?
- Long time no see.
- All right now, Pops. What's happenin'?
[Pops] Hey, young fella.
[Laughing]
Hey there. What's goin' on, blood?
Ain't seen you in a long time, man.
- Hey.
- All right. Cheers. Cheers.
- My man! Drink!
- All right. How you feel?
All right.
Hey, what's goin' on? Hey, I got
next game, and you know that's my table.
[Man]
You call that a break?
Hold up there, now.
It's my shot.
Say, chump. Don't I know you
from somewhere?
Ha-ha! My man!
Joe, what's happenin'?
- Oh, man!
- Ahh! Ha-ha! Look at you!
- How you doin', man?
- Good, man.
- Jesus Christ, man!
I can't believe it's you.
- What's goin' on, man?
- You cool, man!
- I heard you got wounded out there.
Yeah, man.
I was in demolitions,
and my fuckin' hand
gets blown off, man.
- Oh, man. Shit!
- Yeah, man.
Hey, motherfuckers taught me everything
there is to know about explosives, man.
That right?
Check you out, papi.
- You got all those kids now.
- Oh, man. Hey.
You gotta check out Kirby, man.
- He's over in the back room.
- Yeah, let's go on back.
He's still back here, huh?
- All right. Dig it.
- Hey,  abre la puerta! Hey! Hey!
Doin' all right. You know, Kirby just
all hangin' in there, you know?
- Who the fuck is it?
- It's me.
Blood!
What's up, blood?
- Hey, Nicky. What's happenin', man?
- Skin! Kirby back there, man.
That boy looked at me.
He said, "Kirby,
when she pulled off them drawers,
I thought I'd never stop seein' hair!"
[Laughing]
- [Chuckling]
- What's happenin', Cap'n?
Who the fuck is that that?
- Youngblood?
- Yeah, it's me!
Youngblood!
Come on, boy! [Laughing]
- How ya doin'?
- Oh, boy.
- Come on in the back here, boy.
- All right.
Mm!
Man, I been everywhere
lookin' for a gig.
Motherfuckers forget about you gettin'
your ass almost blowed off...
or whatever the fuck.
Yeah. Look, uh, Kirby, uh...
[Sniffles] I was thinkin', man,
maybe, uh, come back and work for you.
What? Work for me?
Yeah. You know, runnin' numbers,
like we used to do.
Shh! Fuckin' pigs
run me outta business.
How the pigs run you outta business,
man? You had 'em on the payroll.
Pigs are greedy.
And you gotta remember,
I'm dealin' with the N.Y.P.D.,
greediest, most corrupt pigs
on the face of the Earth.
So I got
the fuck out.
I told that motherfucker I'd rather
eat cat shit with a knittin' needle.
I wasn't gonna bust my ass sendin'
some cop kids to college. Shit.
I dig it.
This place ain't never
made much money.
So... I'm just hustlin'
here and there.
Tryin' to get over
just like everybody else.
- [Sighs]
- It's gonna be all right, kid.
Here's to gettin' over.
- [Glasses Clinking]
- I hope, man. I hope.
- You afraid of blood?
- That's all I've been around
for the past three years.
"Anthony Curtis."
You related to Tony?
The actor?
N-No. Not... Oh!
No. The act...
No, no, no, no.
- Different colour, right?
- Yeah, he's a white cat. Yeah.
Yeah, and his name was Schwartz.
Schwartz, not Curtis.
- [Laughs] Okay.
- You know anything about butchering?
Uh... I'm a fast learner.
Here, put that on.
Here. Take this.