BLAlR: Welcome, Colonel Lee.
Welcome to my home.
Make yourself comfortable
there, colonel.
Allow me to get to the point, sir.
l have been authorized by
President Lincoln himself. . .
. ..with the full blessing
of the War Department...
. ..to offer you full command of the Army
with the rank of major general.
This Army being raised to quell this,
uh, rebellion and to preserve the Union.
l assume this Army is to be used
to invade those areas. . .
. ..to eliminate the rebellion by force.
Yes, sir, the Federal government
has been challenged by these rebels. . .
. ..who have been most effective in changing
the sentiments of state legislatures...
. ..challenging our Constitution
and challenging our central government.
The attack on Fort Sumter
cannot be ignored.
General, my home is right there
across the Potomac.
Why, you can see Arlington House
from your front door.
My family is spread all
over this part of Virginia.
lf you invade the South, your enemy
territory will be right across that river.
Well, sir, there is no great outcry
for secession in, uh, Virginia.
lt's not a foregone conclusion that
Virginia or Tennessee or Arkansas...
. ..or Kentucky will join the rebellion.
My friend, may l humbly submit that
you're mistaken about Virginia.
As you know, the legislature is
convening in Richmond this very day...
. ..to discuss the very issue of secession.
Now, perhaps you know their mind
better than they themselves.
And l regret to say the president's
hasty calling up of 75,000 volunteers. . .
. ..to subdue the rebellion
in the cotton states. . .
. ..has done nothing to ameliorate
the crisis. lt has only deepened it.
l trust you're not being
too hasty yourself, colonel.
This is a great opportunity
for you to serve your country.
My country, Mr. Blair?
l never thought l'd see the day
the president of the United States. . .
. ..would raise an army
to invade his own country.
No, Mr. Blair, l cannot lead it.
l will not lead it. No.
l'm sorry to hear you say that, sir.
l fear you're making
a most dreadful mistake.
Sir, please convey my deep sense of
honor and gratitude to the president...
. ..but l must decline his offer.
Please tell him.
Please be clear. l have
never taken my duties lightly. . .
. ..but l have no greater duty
than to my home, to Virginia.
Thank you, sir.
[SOLDlER SHOUTlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
JACKSON: Gentlemen, if you are going
to succeed at this institution...
. ..you have one common goal:
To learn your lessons.
lf you are placing
your energies elsewhere...
. ..you will not succeed either with me
or in your careers as military officers.
l had hoped you'd see that with a
proper grasp of the artillery principles...
. .. l've laid before you today,
you would learn to apply. . .
. ..these principles with great
effectiveness in your field experiences.
But since you seem unable
to grasp these principles...
. .. l'm forced to conclude l must repeat
this lesson tomorrow, word for word.
Word for word.
[CROWD SHOUTlNG NEARBY]
CROWD [CHANTlNG]:
Secession! Secession! Secession!
Hoist it! Hoist it up!
Major, listen to them.
The leaders of our intellectual future...
. ..screaming for the destruction
of our nation!
Sir, President Lincoln is raising
the troops.
l ....
l will not stay in a place where my
students dishonor their country's flag.
Major, l'm leaving
for Pennsylvania tomorrow.
War is the sum of all evils.
But if l know myself,
all l am and all l have. ..
. ..is at the service of my
home, my country.
Your country, Thomas?
Your country, my country. lt's all one.
All one, Thomas. All one.
So that in the midst of the searching
of souls and the gnashing of teeth. . .
. ..the delegates of this convention...
. ..harried by the actions of a belligerent
usurper and the radicals of his party. ..
. ..have stumbled into secession.
Now God knows, l and many
in this room have resisted it.
But how could there be union
with a section of the country. . .
. ..that wants to impose
its will through coercion?
Now that Virginia confronts the armed
might of the United States. . .
. ..we Virginians have determined
that not one spot of her sacred soil...
. ..be polluted by the foot of an invader.
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
God bless Virginia!
Now, in the memory of that great
Virginian, George Washington.. .
. ..who was first in the hearts
of his countrymen and calling also. . .
. ..upon the memory of his own gallant
father, General Light-Horse Harry Lee. . .
. ..this convention now calls upon
Robert Edward Lee to take command. . .
. ..of the armed forces of
the Citizen Army of Virginia.
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
Mr. President, gentlemen
of the convention...
. .. l'm profoundly impressed
by the solemnity of the occasion...
. ..for which l must say
l was not prepared.
l accept the position assigned me
by your partiality.
l would have much preferred had
your choice fallen on an abler man.
But trusting to Almighty God,
an approving conscience...
. ..and the aid of my fellow citizens...
. .. l devote myself to the service
of my native state. . .
. ..in whose behalf alone will l
ever again draw my sword.
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
[PLAYlNG PlANO]
We must not fear the final result of this
war, but many a loved one will fall...
. ..and many a heart throb
with anguish. . .
. ..before we can breathe the exhilarating
atmosphere of freedom. . .
. ..and feel the sweet assurance
of safety and peace once more.
There's nothing in this life more dear
to me than my children...
. ..except perhaps the memory
of your wonderful father.
When you go to Richmond,
and wherever this war takes you. . .
. ..you must not fear for us.
We will be with you wherever you go.
Surely goodness and mercy have
followed me all the days of my life.
Now be on your way,
and God be with you.
Y'all be coming on back, you hear?
We'll be back, Martha.
[MARCHlNG BAND
PLAYlNG UPBEAT MUSlC]
Mr. Wilkes, sir.
Would you be kind enough
as to autograph my playbill?
l was never much interested
in Shakespeare. ..
-Mm-hm.
-. . .until l saw you play Richard l l l.
"A horse! A horse!
My kingdom for a horse!"
Was ever woman in this humor wooed?
Was ever woman in this humor won?
[CHUCKLES]
Say, uh, haven't l seen you someplace?
WOMAN:
Why, of course you have.
This here is Mr. Wilkes Booth,
the finest actor in all of Richmond.
All the world's a stage...
. ..and we but its poor players.
What better role than a soldier's
in defense of his home...
. ..his honor.. .
. ..and his beloved?
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
Good morning, major.
This just arrived for you.
Cadet Norris, return to the lnstitute.
My compliments to Colonel Smith.
l will be at his office
within the half-hour.
Sir.
"You are ordered to report with the
corps of cadets to camp instruction...
. ..to begin training and organization
of the Provisional Army...
. ..for the defense of the
Commonwealth of Virginia."
My esposita.
Come, before l leave, we must sit...
. ..read together, the verse.
Here.
Yes, here. Corinthians--
Second Corinthians, chapter five.
l have been thinking about this verse.
"For we know that if our earthly house
of this Tabernacle were dissolved...
. ..we have a building of God.
A house not made with hands,
eternal in the heavens."
O, Almighty God. . .
. ..grant that if it be thy will...
. ..thou wilt still avert the threatening
danger and bring us peace.
Keep her whom l love in
thy protected care.
And bring us all at last to
the joy of thy eternal kingdom.
[MARCHlNG BAND PLAYlNG
UPBEAT MUSlC]
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
MAN 1 :
Give them hell, sir!
MAN 2:
Yeah, give them hell, men!
PASTOR: "The Lord is my light.
My salvation. Whom shall l fear?
The Lord is the strength in my life.
Of whom shall l be afraid?
When the wicked, even mine
enemies and my foes...
...came upon me to eat up my flesh,
they stumbled and fell.
Though unhost should encamp against
me, my heart shall not fear.
Though war should rise up against me.
ln this will l be comforted."
REVEREND JENKlNS:
Secession is inexcusable.
Southerners and Northerners
can still work together.
Slavery will eventually die
of natural causes.
But the breakup of the Union
will inaugurate wars. . .
. ..of a hundred generations in America...
. ..only to repeat the bloody
history of Europe.
lf Virginia adheres
to the United States, l adhere.
Her determination must control mine.
This is my understanding of patriotism.
And though l love the Union,
l love Virginia more.
Private Jenkins, because of the high
regard with which l hold your father...
. ..you are free to do as you please. You may
return to his new home in Pennsylvania.
lt is your decision.
But, if you decide to stay with us.. .
. ..you may never again leave. lf you do,
you'll be treated as a deserter.
Colonel Jackson, sir. Father.
l am a soldier in the 4th Virginia.
And in the 4th Virginia l will stay.
And if needs be, die.
-Then l will take my leave.
-No, sir.
lt is l who will leave the two of you to
have some time together on your own.
You may have this room
for as long as you require it.
Thank you.
Farewell, colonel.
May we meet again in happier times.
And if not in this troubled world
may we meet in. . . .
ln heaven.
HARMAN:
This train was on its way to Washington.
lts livestock's been requisitioned
by the Confederate government.
There's enough damn beef in here
to keep us fed for quite a while.
And as many steeds as would
damn well meet our current needs.
With your permission, sir, we've made
a selection of the more promising horses.
There's some damn fine ones here.
JACKSON:
Mr. Harman, l fear you are a wicked man.
-This animal looks fit for the duty.
-Then he's yours, sir.
That small horse over there,
has he been assigned?
Well, it's a well-rounded sorrel, sir,
but too small for you.
You'll have your feet
dragging in the dust.
l was thinking of my wife, Anna.
He would make a fine present for her.
HARMAN: Well, that it would, sir.
Shall l arrange for the purchase?
Leave the bill of the sale
at my headquarters.
l will buy them both.
The Confederate Treasury is honored, sir.
And may you both sit well in the saddle.
What shall l call you?
-Good morning, sir.
-Reverend Pendleton.
-How goes it with the artillery today?
-You're just in time for a christening.
The men have decided to name the
howitzers: Matthew, Mark, Luke and John.
l'm sure your men will spread the gospel
wherever they encounter the enemy.
Has my son proven a worthy adjutant?
l'm certain Captain Pendleton will prove
himself deserving of the family name.
ALL:
Break! Guard! Charge!
As if you could ever get close enough
to stick a man with this.
You can give me your bayonet
if you have no further use for it.
What you gonna do with two of them?
You never heard of spare parts?
Pogue, your only hope is that some Yank
puts you out of your misery.
Captain White.
How fare the scholars
of Washington College?
Are they making their transition
from books to bullets?
A few more days of drill, and my boys
will surpass the cadets of VMl .
Drill, Professor White, drill and drill.
Remember Alexander in Anatolia.
Caesar in Gaul. Napoleon in lberia.
We march by day,
and read Xenophon by night.
-We will be your Greek phalanx.
-Then you must begin with the bayonet.
The bayonet must be for a Virginian
what the sarissa was for a Macedonian.
lf the Yankees dare set foot in Virginia,
we must show them the bayonet.
Train with the bayonet
and we shall keep our freedom.
WHlTE:
Yes, sir.
Sir.
Harman has a detachment ready to take
your sorrel to Mrs. Jackson in Lexington.
The horse you chose
is waiting at headquarters.
l've decided to keep
this little sorrel for myself.
l prefer his gait
to that of the larger horse.
Unlike the other, he has an even temper.
He will need it where we are going.
Yes, l will keep it.
And Mrs. Jackson?
What should we send her, sir?
lnstruct Harman
to make another selection.
My complete admiration in his choice
of livestock, if not in his choice of words.
The man's vocabulary
is extremely repulsive.
Yes, sir.
-Will that be all, sir?
-Language is blasphemous...
. ..but he is a good quartermaster,
a good quartermaster. You understand me?
-Yes, sir.
-That's all.
Hyah!
SOLDlER 1 :
Blue, gray, green, even red uniforms.
How are we to know who the enemy is?
SOLDlER 2: You dang fool, you just shoot
at the man that's shooting at you!
l thought we was gonna be trained.
l could have done this walking
on my own back in Staunton.
l never seen you walk in your life when
you didn't have to. Nor me, neither.
What man in his senses
would cross his street...
. ..when he could just be
sitting on his front porch?
l done more walking this week than in
my life and my daddy's life put together.
Who'll give us fresh shoes when these
are but tatters and old bits of laces?
You'll excuse me, gentlemen.
Lieutenant Colonel Stuart
reporting for duty.
Colonel Stuart.
-That's an impeccable hat, sir.
-Thank you, sir.
-Colonel Stuart. You use tobacco?
-No, sir. Not in any form.
Neither do l. l find l like it too much.
Sit down.
l understand from your record that
you are West Point, class of '54.
Served since in the cavalry,
Ft. Clark, Texas.
Operations against Apache, Comanche.
Fought with Longstreet and Ewell, sir.
Nasty business. Merciless climate.
Glad to be home, sir.
The Apache were defending their
homes, as we will be defending ours.
lf we fight as well as the Apache,
l pity the Yankee invader.
Colonel Stuart, if l had my way,
we would show no quarter to the enemy.
No more than the redskins showed your
troopers. The black flag, sir.
lf the North triumphs, it is not alone
the destruction of our property.
lt is the prelude to anarchy, infidelity...
. ..the loss of free
and responsible government.
lt is the triumph of commerce.
The banks, factories.
We should meet the invader on
the verge of just defense...
. ..and raise the black flag. No quarter to
the violators of our homes and firesides.
Our political leadership is too timid
to face the reality of this coming war.
They should look to the Bible.
lt is full of such wars.
Only the black flag will bring the North
to its senses and rapidly end the war.
Well, colonel.
One way or the other, the South
will give them a warm reception.
You'll be in charge of the cavalry
in the Harper's Ferry district.
Your experience and your zeal
will be invaluable.
Thank you, sir.
And, colonel...
. ..know that l will tell my men always
to gallop toward the enemy. . .
. ..but trot away.
"Trot."
[CHATTERlNG]
The ratification vote for secession is in.
Reporting from all the counties
of Virginia, the vote is 4-to-1 in favor.
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
And l'm proud to report that the vote
in the Shenandoah Valley. . .
. ..is 31 30 in favor, 1 0 against!
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
ln my own Rockbridge County, only one
person voted against leaving the Union.
MAN:
Probably the village idiot!
[ALL LAUGHlNG]
SOLDlER 1 :
Order!
-Parade, rest!
-Parade.
Men of the valley.
Citizen soldiers.
l am here at the order of General Robert
E. Lee, commanding all Virginia forces.
On April 1 5 of this year
of our Lord, 1 861 ...
. ..Simon Cameron, the secretary of war
of the United States. . .
. ..sent a telegram to our governor to
raise three regiments of infantry. ..
. ..to be sent to assist in suppressing
the Southern Confederacy.
Governor Letcher's answer is well
known to you, but perhaps not his words.
His wire to Washington stated:
"You have chosen to inaugurate civil war.
Having done so, we will meet you
in a spirit as determined. . .
. ..as the Lincoln administration
has exhibited toward the South."
Two days later the Virginia legislature
were voting for secession.
Just as we would not send any of our
soldiers to march in other states...
. ..and tyrannize other people. ..
. ..so will we never allow the armies
of others to march into our state.. .
. ..and tyrannize our people.
Like many of you, indeed most of you,
l've always been a Union man.
lt is not with joy or with a light heart
that many have welcomed secession.
Had our neighbors to the North practiced
a less bellicose form of persuasion. ..
. ..this day might not have come.
But that day has been thrust upon us...
. ..like it was thrust upon our ancestors.
The Lincoln administration required
us to raise three regiments.
Tell them we have done so.
Soldiers! Commanding
General Johnston's orders:
"General Beauregard is being attacked
at Manassas Junction...
. ..by overwhelming forces."
We have been ordered to cross
the Blue Ridge to his assistance.
Every moment now is precious. ..
. ..and the general hopes his soldiers
will step out and keep closed ranks.
Well, this march is a forced march
to save our country.
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
You must get some rest, sir.
l'll rest easier when Pendleton and
the artillery make it up this mountain.
They'll make better time tomorrow, sir.
lt'll all be downhill.
You'll trust me to wait for the guns, sir?
Dr. McGuire.
You're an excellent practitioner,
and l believe l will take your prescription.
[GRUNTS]
SOLDlER 1 : No fires, no tents.
Just like l always dreamed it'd be.
You suppose the Virginia legislature was
gonna buy you your own personal tent?
That's fine for now.
You'll be humming a different tune when
it's raining, you're all covered in frost...
. ..or you need me to dig you
out of a snowdrift.
So damn dark the bats
run into each other.
Old Hickory's just getting us
fit for the fighting.
Old Hickory, Old Jack, Old Blue Light.
How many names you got
for the old man, anyway?
Them VMl boys come up
with the choice one.
They calls him "Tom Fool" when
he's looking the other way.
l'll be a fool if l listened
to you all livelong night.
SOLDlER 2: Old Tom Fool. That name
ought to stick to him like a tick on a mule.
That's it! Step lively! Two at a time!
As quick as you can.
No dilly, no dally.
One foot forward, then the other.
Nothing pretty, nothing fancy.
lnto the train. Do it lovely,
do it ugly, all the same to me.
-Colonel Jackson.
-Colonel Trimble.
-l understand you're a train man.
-Baltimore and Ohio.
Spent most of my life building lines,
and the past six months tearing them up.
No use in leaving them in fine
fettle with a meddling Yankee.
lf you'll excuse me, sir.
Got to move these men where they'll
do the most damage to the enemy.
Excuse me, ladies.
Now that's the finest dressed man
in the whole Confederate Army.
TRlMBLE:
ln you go! Up and over!
Through the brush and in the clover.
Crowd on in. Move it over.
[GUNFlRE NEARBY]
[SOLDlER SPEAKlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
PENDLETON:
That's General Bee's brigade!
lnform General Bee the
1 st Virginians are on the field.
Ask him, can he hold long enough
for me to deploy my men?
Yes, sir! l'll ask him!
They may not hold, gentlemen.
We must assume they cannot.
-Mr. Smith.
-Sir?
lnstruct lmboden and Stanard to position
their batteries in the center of the crest.
l want the 4th and the 27th
regiments stationed as support.
l want the 5th Regiment
posted to their right. . .
. ..the 2nd and 33rd to the left.
Understood?
-Yes, sir.
-Mm-hm.
[SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG]
Counter battery fire!
Eight hundred yards!
-Shell! Five-second fuse!
-Fire!
Counter battery fire. Eight hundred yards.
Shell, five inch. Five-second fuse.
-Fire one!
-Two!
-Three!
-Five, fire!
Get primed!
Fire!
[SOLDlERS SCREAMlNG]
General! Our line on Matthew's Hill
has broken. They are beating us back.
Then we must give them the bayonet!
1 st Brigade, move up to a position just
below the crest of the hill. And stay low!
-Sir.
-Hyah!
Rally, men! Rally!
Look!
There is Jackson, standing like a stone wall.
Let us determine to die here today
and we will conquer.
Rally behind the Virginians!
[SOLDlERS CHEERlNG]
Fix bayonets.
-Fix bayonets!
-Fix!
SOLDlER:
Fire!
Fill in there--!
lnstruct the men to lay down!
Hug the ground!
-Lie down, men!
-Privates! First rank, lie down!
Second rank, kneel!
They are coming, boys.
Wait till they get close before you shoot.
Hold your lines!
[SCREAMlNG]
Halt!
Hold your fire!
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
[SHOUTS]
Fire! Reload!
SOLDlER 1 : Rise up!
SOLDlER 2: Quickly, boys!
Rise up!
Quickly, men! Quickly!
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
Reload! Reload, men!
Come on, boys!
Quick and we can whip them!
-Easy, men. We have no orders to advance!
-Get back in the ranks!
Steady, men. Steady!
Damn it.
Charge!
lt's Cummings' boys.
-What are they doing?
-Easy, Mr. Pendleton. Easy.
Good to have your dander up,
but discipline wins the day.
SOLDlER: About-face! About-face, men!
Aim! Fire!
For God's sakes, forward!
General, sir, the day is going against us.
lf you think so, sir, you had better
not say anything about it.
Rise up, rise up!
Rise up, Virginia!
Stand up, you men! Stand up, you free men!
We're gonna charge them.
We're gonna drive them to Washington!
Stand up, Virginia!
1 st Brigade...
. ..reserve your fire...
. ..till they come within 50 yards. . .
. ..then fire!
And give them the bayonet!
And when you charge...
. ..yell like Furies!
-Ready! Aim!
-Aim!
-Fire!
Charge bayonets!
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
Charge!
Press on! Press on!
SOLDlER:
l surrender! l surrender!
[SOLDlER PLAYlNG BUGLE]
[THUNDER CRASHlNG]
SMlTH:
General?
How is it you can keep so serene. . .
. ..and stay so utterly insensible...
. ..with a storm of shells and bullets
raining about your head?
Captain Smith...
. ..my religious belief teaches me
to feel as safe in battle as in bed.
God has fixed the time for my death,
l do not concern myself with that...
. ..but to be always ready,
whenever it may overtake me.
That is the way all men should live.
Then all men would be equally brave.
Preliminary reports for the brigade, sir.
One hundred and eleven dead.
Three hundred seventy-three
wounded or missing.
And if l may ask, sir, how's your hand?
Just a spent bullet. No more than
a scratch really, Mr. Pendleton.
l'm more than pleased with the part
performed by the brigade during the action.
Through the blessing of God. . .
. ..they met the thus far victorious enemy
and turned the fortunes of the day.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Tomorrow's a new day.
-Evening, general.
-Evening, sir.
JACKSON:
Oh, Mr. Pendleton?
Thank you for the report.
l will never forget these men.
Which is it tonight, John?
Hamlet? Richard Ill? Or the Scottish play?
The schedule's posted.
l'm relieved to see
you've prepared for your role.
l admit, my concentration has been impaired
by the distractions of this war.
Mm.
Then think "winter of our discontent."
And what a glorious summer it will be. . .
. ..when the South is free
of these meddling Yankees.
Sometimes when l'm up on that stage...
. ..brandishing the prop sword
or threatening with the mock word...
. .. l wonder if it's more farce
than tragedy.
More posturing than art.
Harrison.
As we recite and declaim,
others march and die.
Down in Mississippi. . .
. ..when all the other boys went
hunting or fishing, l was reading books.. .
. ..learning Shakespeare sonnets by heart.
My daddy said art
was the hardest thing.
That everything else seems
more important at the time. . .
. ..but that we needed it more than air.
More than food, even.
So now it's politics instead of hunting.
Same old thing.
Gotta stay concentrated
on what really matters.
Shakespeare matters.
Acting matters.
Gentlemen, new orders
from the War Department.
The Confederate Army's been reorganized
into three districts.
That of the Potomac will remain
under General Beauregard.
The Aquia under General Holmes.
Um, l've been promoted
to major general. . .
. ..commanding all forces in and around
the Shenandoah Valley.
The entire army together will now be known
as the Army of Northern Virginia.
Although l am being transferred
to Winchester...
. ..the brigade must remain here
at Centreville.
Begging your pardon, sir. ..
. ..but the men would prefer
remaining under your command.
That's right, sir.
Couldn't the entire brigade be transferred
with you to the Valley?
Gentlemen, such a degree
of public respect, confidence...
. ..as puts it in one's power to serve
his country must be accepted and prized.
But apart from that. . .
. ..promotion among men is only
a temptation and a trouble.
Had this not come to me as an order,
l should instantly have declined it. . .
. ..continued in command
of my brave old brigade.
Sir, may we hope. ..
. ..that a formal entreaty
to the authorities in Richmond. . .
. ..may effect a transfer
of the entire brigade to the Valley?
Hear, hear.
l'll not stop you
from making such a request.
But for now, we must prepare ourselves.
We shall all have our labors to perform...
. ..but with the help
of an ever-kindly heavenly father. . .
. .. l trust he will enable us
to accomplish them.
SOLDlER:
Forward!
Rest!
Throughout the broad extent
of the country...
. ..through which you have marched. . .
. ..by your respect for the rights
and property of others. ..
. ..you have always shown you are soldiers,
not only to defend. . .
. ..but able and willing
both to defend and protect.
You've already won...
. ..a brilliant reputation throughout the Army
of the whole Confederacy.
And l trust in the future
by your deeds in the field...
. ..and by the assistance of the same kind
providence who has favored our cause...
. ..you will win more victories and add
luster to the reputation you now enjoy.
You already gained a proud position. . .
. ..in the future history of this. . .
. ..our second war of independence.
l shall look with anxiety
to your future movements...
. ..and l trust whenever l shall hear
of the 1 st Brigade. . .
. ..on the field of battle. . .
. ..it will be of still nobler deeds achieved
and higher reputation won.
ln the Army of the Shenandoah,
you were the 1 st Brigade.
ln the Army of the Potomac,
ln the 2nd Corps of this Army,
you are the 1 st Brigade.
You are the 1 st Brigade
in the affections of your general.
And l hope by your future deeds and bearing
you will be handed down to posterity. . .
. ..as the 1 st Brigade. . .
. ..in this, our second war of independence.
Farewell!
[ALL CHEERlNG]
SOLDlERS [CHANTlNG]:
Jackson! Jackson! Jackson! Jackson!
Jackson! Jackson! Jackson!
CHAMBERLAlN: The universe itself
is subject to rules, to law.
The super-abounding life lavished
on this world of ours.. .
. ..is proof. . .
. ..that the play of infinite freedom.. .
. ..is here to help work out
the will of infinite law.
The nature of the universe demonstrates. . .
. ..that freedom can only exist...
. ..as part of law.
STUDENT:
Pardon me, Professor Chamberlain. . .
. ..but how does the study of philosophy
intersect with real life?
lf freedom can only exist as a part of law. . .
. ..how can we continue to tolerate slavery
protected by law?
Lawrence, l know.
How?
l've noticed the way you've been looking
into the children's room each night.
Blue.
Why blue uniforms? lt should be red.
-Like the English, the color of blood.
-Are you angry with me?
Lawrence, my darling Lawrence.
Do you remember when you were
thinking of being a missionary?
And you wrote me saying
that you wished your little wife...
. ..was willing for you to take
whatever course you thought best...
. ..and was ready to help you
in it with all her heart?
"Little wife."
How could l ever have called you that?
Your spirit is vaster than oceans.
Then you wrote back.
And l have never forgotten
what you said.
You said, "Well, dear, she is willing. . .
. ..and she feels that you know better
about the matter than she does."
But now. . .
. .. l never think l know better than you.
l couldn't bear for you to feel that you
must forever remain at a stand. . .
. ..just because you're married.
l always want to help you on
in your excelsior striving.
But l had a dream about you, Lawrence.
Last night.
While you were away,
offering your services to the governor.
l saw you in my dream.
There were boys in blue marching past.
Some of the boys that we know.
And there you were. . .
. ..riding ahead of them
on a great, white horse.
Fanny, my love, l felt l had to go.
l offered the governor my services,
wherever he wanted to place me.
l thought he'd probably order me
to an officer.
-Speeches, administration.
-Oh.
Lawrence...
. .. l know you.
When you do a thing, you do it à l'outrance.
-So? He gave you a commission, didn't he?
-They need serving officers.
Five new regiments are being formed now.
Maine has already sent 1 5.
How could l refuse?
Poor Lawrence, damn you,
you'll be good at it too.
You'll be good at soldiering just like
you're good at everything else. So go.
Go do your duty to your country's flag...
. ..go on and get your medals for bravery,
go and get yourself killed.
That poem of Lovelace.
That beautiful, horrible, damnable,
lovely, sad poem.
l think that you recited it in my dream.
Lovelace. "Off to the English Civil War"?
l would not dare presume
to quote it now.
Tell me not, sweet, l am unkind
That from the nunnery
Of thy chaste breast and quiet mind
To warlike arms l fly.
True, a new mistress now l serve
The first foe in the field
And with a sterner faith embrace
The sword, a horse, a shield.
Yet this inconstancy is such
As thou too shalt adore.
l could not love thee, dear, so much
Loved l not honor more.
You will be wounded.
You will be changed by the horrors of it.
But you will come home.
l believe that, my love.
You will come home.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Come in.
You must be Mr. Lewis.
Ha, ha.
There's some that calls me Uncle Jim.
Some calls me Big Jim.
Some folks just calls me Jim.
l don't suppose you've heard
any of the names l get called?
l heard Stonewall once.
That name properly belongs
to the 1 st Virginia Brigade, not to me.
-They were the ones who earned it.
-Some folks says otherwise.
Folks say men can't fight without
nobody up front to lead them on.
-l'm told you're a first-rate cook.
-Ha, ha. Yes, sir.
They wasn't lying, told you that.
Whatever you likes to eat, l can cook it.
Pan-fry, griddle, boil, bake. Roasted.
And l understand you're from Lexington.
You come highly recommended to me, Jim.
Lexington is my home, general.
Same as yours.
lf l could do my share
in defending my home...
. .. l'd be doing the same as you.
l heard it was Napoleon hisself said:
"An army can't march
but on its stomach."
Well. . . .
lf you love your country...
. ..fear the Lord...
. ..and have no trouble getting up at
4:00 in the morning, the job is yours.
Yous got yourself a deal, general.
Sir.
My darling esposita.
Welcome to Winchester.
Thomas. Oh.
-Come in out of the cold.
-Why, thank you.
-l have been thinking, Thomas...
-Mm.
. ..that it may have been a blessing. . .
. ..that the Battle of Manassas
was fought on my birthday.
Why is that?
ln our old age, you will never forget it.
l will forget my own
before l ever forget yours.
[WHlSPERlNG]
Oh, Anna.
Anna.
[WHlSPERlNG]
What is it, Tom?
What?
Everything in this life seems so fragile.
So temporary.
[lN NORMAL VOlCE]
When we are separated, l fear...
. .. l will never see you again.
l fear we may never have a child.
l fear l may lose you
if we dare to have a child.
l know l should trust in the Lord. . .
. ..but then l see the face
of my dear mama. . .
. ..of my first wife, dead and cold.
With our dead darling.
Dead before he could draw
his first breath in this world.
And l am afraid.
And l am afraid to feel happiness.
Afraid to hope for it again.
l am afraid of God's judgment.
[lN NORMAL VOlCE]
We serve a loving God, Thomas.
We are in each other's arms.
We are together,
and we are happy together.
And is our love not proof of his?
We must not fear, Thomas.
We will survive this war.
And we will have a child.
So help us, God.
[MARCHlNG BAND PLAYlNG
UPBEAT MUSlC]
-Major Gilmore, stop that damn drumming!
-Quiet!
-Stop that damn drumming!
This is a hell of a regiment.
Men of the 20th Maine Regiment
of Volunteers. . .
. ..this is your commanding officer,
Colonel Adelbert Ames.
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
Quiet! Quiet!
You do not cheer an officer.
You salute him.
20th Maine, l commend you
for the enthusiasm...
. ..that has made you volunteer
for service in Lincoln's Army.
l can see that many of you
are strong and fit.
We Maine men know that
life in the woods of Maine...
. ..toughens the muscles
and stretches the sinews.
l've no doubt many of you
have become good shots by hunting deer.
But tough muscles and skillful shooting
are not enough to make a soldier.
That requires discipline.
Major Gilmore tells me you are in the habit
of holding discussions with your officers.
That will cease from now.
An officer's orders are to be obeyed
instantly and without question.
This regiment must learn
to move as one man.
Otherwise we will all be killed.
-See if you can teach them to march.
-Yes, sir.
Colonel Chamberlain.
Come with me.
When l say, "20th Maine, attention". . .
. ..you bring your feet together.
Governor Washburn
and Adjutant General Hodgson. . .
. ..have sent me
an impressive report about you.
They say you will master
any assignment you're given.
l shall certainly try, sir.
l, uh, understand you were in
the Battle of Bull Run.
Wounded too. lt taught me the need
for discipline and proper procedure.
Take the act of shooting, for example.
When you're hunting in the Maine woods
there's no difficulty in loading a rifle.
But in the panic of war,
men act foolishly.
ln Bull Run l saw a soldier forget
to remove his ramrod from the barrel.
When he fired,
out it flew with a dismal twang.
He lost the means of firing again
and was killed soon after by a Rebel bullet.
Sergeant Tom Chamberlain
reporting for duty, sir.
Tom, what on earth--?
What are you doing?
l signed up, Lawrence, l'm in this regiment.
l'm coming with you.
Did Father approve?
How will he run the farm?
Once he heard you were colonel,
he couldn't say no.
Besides, you know him,
he'll be all right. They both will.
l'm giving them one less thing to cuss at.
Mama said so many prayers for the both
of us, we got nothing to worry about.
Well, l guess l have one more responsibility.
l have to look after you.
Me?
Lawrence, Mama told me
to watch after you.
Just remember, lads, even a tin cup
is a great weight after 20 mile.
Your precarious pegs won't last
if you turn yourselves into pack mules.
And only one leg to a pant, if you please.
You'll soon be at the worn end of it...
. ..where your formal attire will be
your shirt collar and boots.
ln the U.S. Army we have
the School of the Soldier. . .
. ..in which the soldier is trained
and by numbers drilled.
Loading a musket
is done in nine movements. . .
. ..performed over and over
until they become automatic. ..
. ..or, as we call it, loading in nine times.
Aah! l see. Sergeant Chamberlain.
Loading in nine times. Demonstrate this.
Assume the musket has just been fired.
One, reach into cartridge box
and withdraw cartridge.
Two, place cartridge between teeth.
Three, tear paper open.
Four, pour powder into barrel
and charge cartridge.
Five, withdraw the ramrod.
Six, ram the ball home.
Seven, return ramrod.
Eight, half-cock the hammer...
. ..remove old cap. ..
. ..and put a new cap on the cone.
Nine, shoulder arms.
All right, you have the idea.
But this must be done without thinking
and much, much faster.
Here.
One, two, three, four...
. ..five...
. ..six...
. ..seven...
. ..eight...
. ..nine.
Practice until you can do it
as fast as that.
lt may save your lives. Colonel.
Line of battle consists of two lines of men,
one behind the other. ..
. ..so that while one line fires,
the other reloads.
Behind them is a line of, uh, file closers.
Lieutenants and sergeants.
But two lines make a regiment
unwieldy on the move...
. ..so we need to switch to column of fours.
We need to be able to change from
column of fours to line of battle. . .
. ..and back again quickly.
lt is not difficult to move from line of battle
into column of fours.
lt is harder to move from
column of fours into line of battle...
...and if we're called to make that move,
it will be when we're under fire.
You understand how important it is that
these moves are learned so thoroughly...
...that the men can perform them
in their sleep.
Company. . .
. ..halt!
Company, front!
Order arms!
Well done, colonel. That's a beginning.
But that move must be practiced
and practiced and practiced.
Another month and we'll be ready.
But we leave for Washington tomorrow.
Shoulder arms!
Company, forward march!
[SOLDlER PLAYlNG DRUM]
Gentlemen, it's only September.
Too soon for winter camp.
We have the momentum.
l propose we advance our army
north into Maryland...
. ..because there the farms are plentiful
and nearly untouched.
And with a fall harvest,
we could feed our troops very well indeed.
And there is one other consideration.
Maryland is being held in the Union
by force.
Our arrival may be viewed as a liberation.
We might receive some hospitality.
Might even receive a number of volunteers
for service in the Army.
General, might this not be considered
an invasion?
l don't believe so, general. No, sir.
With the Federal invasion of Virginia. . .
. ..the Confederacy proved
who's the aggressor here.
We did not bring this war...
. ..and we fight now only to free the South
of Federal occupation.
As l've said many times. . .
. ..if Washington will end their side
of the fighting and recall their armies...
. ..this war will be over.
But in the meantime...
. ..we must show the enemy
that they cannot win.
Cannot win.
Now, by moving into Maryland, we'd be
in a position to push into Pennsylvania.
And so far, gentlemen,
the bloody fields are Southern fields.
lf we threaten the Northern cities...
. ..if we threaten to bring the blood
into the North. . .
. ..there'll be pressure on Lincoln
to end this war.
Amen.
Our presence, just the threat,
could be sufficient.
LONGSTREET:
General Lee...
. ..we'd be cutting ourselves off from
our base of supplies, communications.
We'd be vulnerable from the rear, sir.
General Longstreet, you marched
into Mexico with General Scott?
Yes, sir.
LEE: Did not General Scott cut himself off
from his supplies and communication?
And by so doing,
did he not bring a rapid end to that war?
And did he not accomplish all of that
in a foreign land?
Well, this is not a foreign land.
The citizens will see we're not coming
to vandalize as the Yankees did to us.
We've come to end the war quickly. . .
. ..and without any need
to conquer or subdue anyone.
We proved our superiority
on the battlefield.
That superiority may be
all we need, gentlemen.
All we need.
-General Lee?
-Yes.
Pleased to hear we're finally
taking the war to the enemy.
Let them feel the scourge
of this war that they began.
Yes, sir.
SOLDlERS [SlNGlNG]:
His torch is at thy temple door
Maryland, my Maryland
Avenge the patriotic gore
That flecked the streets of Baltimore
And be the battle queen of yore
Maryland, my Maryland
Morning to you, sir.
Colonel Ames sent me to get you.
-Said you might be needing a drop of this.
-Ah. Thank you. ...
Kilrain, sir. Sergeant Kilrain.
Glad to be of service.
You know, colonel, uh...
. ..the boys. . . .
We've been watching you, sir,
that we have.
You've learned fast.
Becoming a pleasure to serve under you.
Yes, well, ahem....
Are you a, uh, veteran, sergeant?
Aye, sir. l suppose you could say that.
Did me duty in the regular Army
for a while.
Did the great long walk with General Scott,
down south of the Rio Grande.
Uh, some men you fought with are on
the other side. Almost all of their generals.
Oh, it gets worse than generals, colonel.
Some of the lads that l left lreland with
are on the other side as well. lmagine that.
We left together to escape a tyranny...
. ..and end up shooting at one another
in the land of the free.
l, too, have friends
on the other side, sergeant.
And enemies.
Yes, sir.
No shortage of enemies, that's for sure.
We're ordered to remain in place.
The army is spreading out
a couple miles up.
The enemy is dug in
behind a small creek.
Antietam Creek,
just this side of Sharpsburg.
We may be put into the battle
at any time.
For now, get the men to step it up,
finish breakfast and wait for orders.
-Got that?
-Certainly, colonel.
[GUNFlRE NEARBY]
Whose guns are those?
Has the attack begun?
Likely it's the first feeling-out,
probing, testing of strength.
lt's a game to the artillery boys. . .
. ..letting you know they can hit you
when the time comes.
Lawrence. Lawrence, lookie here.
This is what we've been eating
every day.
But you know what?
l've gained some weight.
Hard to believe a man could
gain some weight on a diet of worms.
[CHUCKLES]
Well, best eat up, sergeant.
We're moving out.
Good morning, sir.
The Yankees are coming thick and fast
in the woods before us.
We're making it hot for them.
We must hold this ridge. We must.
So pour it to them, Reverend.
Sir.
ROB:
Sir, it's me, Rob.
My dear son. How are you, boy?
l'm well, sir.
l congratulate you for being
in the fight and unhurt.
May God keep you so.
And remember, son, we must do
all we can to drive these people back.
Yes, sir. We'll do our best, sir.
SOLDlER:
Fire!
[SOLDlERS SCREAMlNG]
Mr. Pendleton, ride to General Hood,
ask him can he maintain his position?
Yes, sir, can he maintain his position?
Hyah, hyah!
Fire!
Reload!
lt's good to be sergeant, isn't it?
To shoot a sergeant,
you have to fire through two men.
A sergeant never fires his weapon
until the men in front of him are killed. . .
. ..and then only unless
you want to show off.
Move the men into this field
and wait for further orders.
We're part of the reserve.
-Battalion, forward!
-Forward!
[SOLDlER PLAYlNG BUGLE]
March!
[BOTH SHOUTlNG]
Compliments from General Jackson.
He wants to know,
can you maintain position?
Tell General Jackson
unless l get reinforcements. . .
. .. l must be forced back.
But l'm going on while l can.
Yes, sir. Reinforcements. Yes, sir.
[SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG AND GRUNTlNG]
-Load!
Take aim!
Fire!
Forward, men, forward!
[SOLDlERS SCREAMlNG]
-General McClellan, sir.
-General Hancock.
Had you heard that General Richardson
had been wounded?
l heard he'd been wounded.
l'm sorry to tell you it is serious
and you will assume his command.
Yes, sir. Of course, sir.
l'm honored to accept the command.
l'm sure you will perform this duty. ..
. ..with the skill and courage
you have shown already.
We are on the move now, and we will drive
the Rebels into the river before the sun sets.
Hold this position against
any assault by the enemy.
Reply from General Hood:
"Tell Jackson unless l get reinforcements,
l must be forced back."
-But he will go on while he can.
-Good, good.
General McLaws, advance your--
Captain Morrison.
l think it advisable
you keep your distance from me.
lt would not do for Anna to lose both
a husband and a brother on the same day.
Battalion, halt!
The battle may be moving our way.
Keep them ready.
Yes, sir.
Courtesy of a lady admirer in Sharpsburg.
Think we can hold out
against another attack?
l think they have done their worst.
l think there's little danger
of our line being broken.
We won't be needed today, colonel.
The 5th Corps was not
needed today, gentlemen.
Not according to the judgment
of our commanding general.
The battle has been extremely costly.
The enemy has been checked,
at great loss to both sides.
From what we can observe so far,
we've gained little.
lt's possible the fight
will resume tomorrow.
He that created us
gave us such strong argument. . .
. ..starting before and after,
gave us not capabilities...
. ..and divine reason
to fust inside of us unused.
Now, whether it be bestial oblivion,
or some craven scruple. . .
. ..of thinking too precisely
on the event. ..
. ..a thought which, quartered,
hath but one part one wisdom...
. ..and ever three parts coward...
. .. l do not know why yet l live to say
"This thing's to do"...
. ..sith l have cause and will and strength
and means to do it.
Examples gross as earth exhort me:
Witness this army
of such mass and charge...
...led by a delicate and tender prince...
...whose spirit
with divine ambition puffed...
...makes mouths at the invisible event...
...exposing what is mortal and unsure...
...to all that death and danger dare,
even for an egg-shell.
Rightly to be great
is not to stir without great argument...
...but greatly to find quarrel in a straw
when honor's at the stake.
How stand l then...
...that have a father killed...
...a mother stained...
...excitements of my reason
and my blood...
...and let all sleep?
While, to my shame, l see...
. ..the imminent death of 20,000 men.. .
. ..that, for a fantasy or trick of fame...
. ..go to their graves like beds,
fight for a plot. . .
. ..whereon the numbers
cannot try the cause...
. ..which is not tomb enough or continent
to hide the slain?
O, from this time forth...
. ..my thoughts be bloody. . .
. ..or be nothing worth.
He's mad. Did you see this?
lt's nothing less than a call
for a slave uprising.
Darling, l hardly ever get to see you.
Can't we put away the paper
this one evening?
lt'll put you in the foulest mood.
lt always does.
Well, here. Read it for yourself.
Lincoln plans a general emancipation
on New Year's Day. . .
. ..for all slaves
from states still in rebellion.
Yet another page from the Constitution
torn to shreds.
But this is harmless, John.
See, it says right here:
"An emancipation of all slaves
from the states still in rebellion."
But can't you see?
Those are the very states where the
president has no authority and no power.
Why, yes. You're quite right.
l hadn't considered it in that light.
Now, can we fold up the paper
into a nice little square. . .
. ..so that l can cut it up
into a hundred little pieces. . .
. ..and throw it into the street?
[CHUCKLES]
Hmm.
Boyo, another round, if you please.
[BAND PLAYlNG SOMBER MUSlC]
Now, it says here in Blackmantle's
Art of Punning...
. ..that "punning is an art of harmonious
jingling upon words...
. ..which, passing in at the ears
and falling upon the diaphragm...
. ..excites a titillary motion
in those parts. . .
[BOTH LAUGHlNG]
. ..and this, being conveyed by the
animal spirits into the muscles of the face.. .
. ..raises the cockles of the heart."
All right, then. ls everyone ready?
-Sure, why not?
-Yes, sir.
Counties of England.
Who has the most dogs?
Bark-shire.
-Ha, ha.
-Well done.
And from where did
the first hermaphrodites come from?
Oh. Um, Middlesex.
Yeah. And from whence
the first circus tumblers came?
Circus tumblers?
Somerset.
-Oh, Lord.
-Somerset.
Well, l can see you've all learned
rule number six:
Never speak well of another punster
and never laugh at his puns.
[LAUGH lNG]
Somerset.
The Rebel sharpshooters
was in the house.
That's what made them Yankees
shell it so.
-Where was this?
-Outside Winchester.
Them Yankees been through that town
more times than there is flies on a mule.
Mm.
Where's your master now?
l ain't got no master no more.
Now he my boss.
See, l was sold at auction
over in Fredericksburg once...
. ..and he bought me for $1 200.
Then the war come,
that didn't set right with him...
. ..so he gave me my freedom papers.
Now he pays me wages.
-No, sir.
-Thirty dollars a month.
What he pay you for?
l can do anything l turn my hands to.
Then them Yankees come
and burned down his house...
. ..and the next thing you know,
the man who's paying me wages. ..
. ..is in the Confederate Army.
And so am l.
[BOTH LAUGHlNG]
-Man, that's good!
-Let's do this thing right here.
Hey, come on. Check it.
No, no, no. Gentlemen.
Stay where you are.
Greetings.
General.
[SPEAKlNG lN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
How is our fine Prussian officer
this evening?
l would've thought General Stuart
would've had you at least. . .
. ..20 miles behind enemy lines...
. ..creating havoc and bewilderment
in Washington.
[LAUGH lNG]
l would certainly prefer such a mission.
But tonight. . .
. ..tonight, general,
l come bringing you a present.
General Jackson.. .
. .. l am greatly pleased to bring
this present from General Stuart.
The general has gone to great lengths
to secure for you this.
Would you like for me
to open that for you, sir?
Thank you.
General.
This is some fine material. Look here.
That's gold braid.
You may tell General Stuart
that l deeply appreciate this gift.
Please assure the general...
. .. l will treat it with the utmost of care.. .
. ..and see that no harm comes to it.
Mr. Pendleton, will you kindly
place that uniform in my tent.
-And keep it neatly folded.
-Sir.
No, general, no.
You do not understand.
General Stuart was most insistent.
He says now that you are
a leutnant general...
. ..corps commander,
you deserve a new uniform.
He was most insistent you try it on.
He will certainly ask, "How was the fit?"
Please, general.
Try it on.
[CHUCKLES]
General, that's some mighty fine coat.
Ha, ha.
[ALL CHUCKLlNG]
[SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG]
That is the sweetest music l ever heard.
Ah, gentlemen.
Excuse us, General Burnside...
. ..General Hancock has information
you may find useful.
Yes, General Hancock, a pleasure.
Sumner, come.
We have visitors.
Sir, General Hancock reports the river
can be forded the short way upstream.
There'll be no difficulty crossing. With
your permission, we can move right away.
General Hancock, l appreciate your efforts
at reconnaissance...
. ..but this possibility has been
considered and rejected.
The pontoons will be here any time.
We'll cross with not only the men
but also the wagons and supplies.
lt would be foolhardy to send the men
without the wagons, the big guns--
Excuse me, am l correct
in my observation...
. ..that there's little force opposing us
across the river?
Yes, you're absolutely correct.
For once we seem to have caught
Lee by surprise.
Then, sir, if l may suggest,
isn't it possible Lee is moving this way?
Certainly he's aware of our intentions.
lf we could occupy the town with infantry...
. ..it would make our job much easier
when the bridges do arrive.
Yes, but that's risky. Those men
could be cut off. ln this weather?
lt snows one day, melts the next.
The river could rise unexpectedly.
lt will be best, l assure you, if we wait
until the entire Army can cross together.
General Burnside, if we don't cross
the river soon...
. ..General Lee will make every effort
to stop us.
He will not let us move
toward Richmond unopposed.
Where are General Jackson's forces now?
Shouldn't we attempt to occupy
Fredericksburg. . .
. ..and possibly the Heights beyond now,
while we have it for the taking?
Please allow me, sir, to at least send
General Hancock's division across the river.
Surely they can carry
enough supplies with them...
. ..and the artillery from this side can protect
them against any advance by Lee.
Gentlemen, we will cross this river
when the bridges arrive and not before.
l do not have the luxury of deviating
from the larger plan.
The president approved my strategy,
and l shall stick to it.
Once this Army is across the river,
we will advance on Richmond in force.
We must not allow him. ..
. ..the luxury of attacking us as divided and
separated units as he's done in the past.
And l will not make the same mistake
as my predecessors.
So no, General Hancock.
You will stay on this side
until the pontoons are in place. . .
. ..and the entire Army crosses together.
An irresistible, impregnable force.
TAYLOR: Did you know George Washington
spent his boyhood not far from here?
And across that river, he's supposed
to have thrown that silver dollar...
. ..and cut down that cherry tree.
That may be so, Mr. Taylor, but it has
an even greater significance for me.
lt's where l met my wife.
That's something these Yankees
do not understand, will never understand.
You see these rivers and valleys
and streams...
. ..and fields, even towns?
They're just markings on a map to those
people in the war office in Washington.
But to us, my goodness,
they're birthplaces and burial grounds.
They're battlefields
where our ancestors fought...
. ..places where you and l learned
to walk, to talk and to pray.
Places where we made friendships
and, oh, yes, fell in love.
And they're the incarnation
of all our memories, Mr. Taylor. . .
. ..and all that we are.
All that we are.
-What place is this?
-Chancellor's Crossing.
We're another two hours or so
from Fredericksburg.
We'll rest here for a short time.
Yes, sir. l'll see what
the good folks can provide.
The general be fixing to eat
something warm?
No, no, Jim.
We gotta ride on straight
through to General Lee.
Don't want to get all warmed up
just to feel the cold all over again.
[CHUCKLES]
You never seem to mind the cold much.
Oh. l minds it. l just don't shows it.
Now, Little Sorrel,
l know this corn look poorly...
. ..but it sure beats no corn at all.
You heard from your family lately?
Ain't heared much for some time.
Yankee mail used to move
quicker than Secesh mail.
Lord, from where you sit
you can see the great distance...
. ..that separates our Southern men
from their wives and children.
We pray that you watch over our families.
Lord, l ask you to watch over
Jim Lewis' family...
. ..over his friends, his loved ones,
wherever they may be.
Lord, l know you sees
into the hearts of all men...
. ..just like you sees into the heart
of old Jim Lewis.
And, Lord, l know there's
no lying or deceitfulness. . .
. ..can hide from you.
You find the truth. ..
. ..in the bottom of the deepest pit
of darkness.
There be no hiding from your truth
and your ever-watchful eye.
Amen.
How is it, Lord?
Can you explain something
to this old Virginia man?
How is it a good Christian man. . .
. ..like some folks l know...
. ..can tolerate their black brothers
in bondage?
How is it, Lord, they don't just...
. ..break them chains?
How is it, Lord?
My heart is open and aching.
And l wants to know.
Lord, speak to us.
Speak to your children.
Speak to Jim Lewis and Thomas Jackson,
your humble and obedient servants.
Speak to all of us.
Our hearts are open.
Lord, you show us the way,
we will follow.
Amen.
[SlGHS]
-Jim?
-Yeah.
What is the status of your family?
About half is free, half slave.
That's counting all the cousins and such.
You must know that there are
some officers in this Army. . .
. ..who are of the opinion that...
. ..we should be enlisting Negroes
as a condition for freedom.
That's what they says around the camp.
Your people will be free,
one way or another.
The question is,
if the Southern government will have. . .
. ..the good sense to do it first and soon.
And in so doing seal a bond
of enduring friendship between us.
That's what they says, general.
God's plan is a great mystery.
lt will be revealed to us.
That's all the fodder you get tonight.
We's going to a country where there's
nothing more for an animal to eat...
. ..than there is what's in the palm
of my hand. Ha, ha.
General Lee, fine day, sir.
We got batteries all along that hill,
covering our front to the river.
Strong anchor on the north.
Tomorrow, guns will be positioned
in those trees to the south.
We'll be able to cover the entire
open ground, all of it.
General, they gonna come at us here?
Colonel Alexander...
. ..Federal troops amassed across that river
are watching us prepare for them.
lf l were General Burnside,
l wouldn't attack here.
l'd move back upstream,
come across from above us.
Burnside is not a man
with the luxury of flexibility.
He's being pushed from behind
by loud voices in Washington. . .
. ..by newspapers
who demand quick action.
But we're here,
and so he will attack us here.
We got batteries pointing from all angles.
They cross that canal,
that'll slow them down.
We shall hit them from all sides.
No, sir, a chicken couldn't live
on that field.
General Lee, sir.
General Jackson sends his respects. . .
. ..and advises his corps will deploy
to the south of this position. . .
. ..by tomorrow, as you instructed.
Well, what are his men made of?
He's 1 50 miles away.
To General Jackson,
dawn begins the minute after midnight.
General Hood, l've often wondered
how it is that.. .
. ..Texas men, the most independent-minded
in this Army of irascibles. . .
. ..have agreed to serve under
a Kentuckian.
l have often wondered the same.
General Gregg, have you settled your
differences with General Jackson?
No, General Hill, l have not.
Have you?
No, sir.
JACKSON:
Tell me, general...
. ..do you expect to live
until the end of this war?
Oh. l do not know. . .
. ..but l'm inclined to think l will.
l expect l will be wounded.
And you, general?
l do not expect to live to see
the end of this war.
Nor can l say that without victory
l would desire to do so.
-Get up.
Sir?
Yes, Mr. Pendleton, you may enter.
Forgive me, general.
There's a letter for you.
Courier was running a little slow today,
but l thought you'd want to see it.
Yes, thank you.
Good night, sir.
ANNA:
My own dear father:
As my mother's letter
has been cut short by my arrival...
...l think it but justice
that I should continue it.
l know that you are rejoiced
to hear of my coming.
And l hope that God has sent me
to radiate your pathway through life.
l am a very tiny little thing.
l weigh only eight and a half pounds...
...and Aunt Harriet says l am
the express image of my darling papa.
My mother is very comfortable
this morning.
Your loving daughter.
Thank you, Lord.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
They've occupied all the buildings
along the riverfront.
We will be lining up those pontoon
bridges through a hail of lead.
Once across, the Rebs are sure
to make us pay for every block.
Beyond the town is the canal
which cuts across this open field.. .
. ..a field we'll have to cross to reach
their entrenchments on Marye's Heights. ..
. ..another difficult obstacle
in the face of artillery fire.
Down to our left we could burst through.. .
. ..turn Jackson's lines, push him back,
trap Longstreet on top of the hill.. .
. ..surround him.
lt's possible.
Turn Jackson's lines?
No, general, we'll meet them head on.
And it will be a bloody mess.
We'll march up to that hill there. ..
. ..and we'll eat their artillery fire
all the way across this field.
We'll be able to look
at ourselves and say:
"We're good soldiers.
We did what we were told."
lf we're not successful, we can say it was
a good plan, but there were contingencies.
You can go back to your hometown...
. ..and tell the families of your men
they died doing their duty.
The Rebs have fortified
the high ground up the river.
And anyway, there are strong currents
and obstacles to a crossing there.
Below Fredericksburg,
the river is too wide.
And our earliest forces are
clear down to Port Royal.
Fredericksburg is now
the only place we can cross.
lf Burnside doesn't cross here,
he might as well resign.
That wily gray fox has outmaneuvered
our command again.
And there's going to be hell to pay.
MAN:
Hurry up! Let's go!
BARKSDALE:
Pick your targets, boys!
Commence firing!
[SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG]
Them Yankees is coming, sure as Jesus.
They got two pontoons across that river.
We got to get you and them children
out of here.
Stop fussing with me. Get your family
ready. We'll leave together.
Miss Jane, us done talked this over,
and we decided to stay here.. .
. ..and look after the house.
No use saying no more.
Martha, l won't leave you to the mercy
of those blue devils.
Miss Jane, you know they ain't gonna be
bothering us colored folks.
lf we go with you, there won't be any food
left in the pantry when we come back.
And we need to eat, same as you.
-Pastor Lacy, we must run to our lines.
LACY: There's no time.
The streets are raining iron.
To the basement.
[SHOUTS]
Anybody hurt?
Sam?
Easy.
Sam!
Can you get up? Easy! Easy!
Fall back, Mississippi!
Fall back!
[KNOCKlNG ON DOOR]
JOHN:
Mother? Are you here?
Oh, praise be! lt's Master John!
-We're down here in the cellar!
JOHN: The door is blocked!
l'll go around to the side!
Children, y'all stay right here.
Mama'll be back.
Come out!
There's an ambulance out front.
The enemy is crossing the river. Hurry!
-No! Martha, l won't leave without you.
-l done told you, l'm staying.
Off with you then.
Come on, Martha.
Stay in the basement!
Hyah.
[SHOUTlNG]
Get the bayonets!
May God be with them.
May he strengthen their hearts
and their arms for the coming struggle.
Give them the victory.
[CHATTERlNG]
Can l be of service
to you fine Northern gentlemen?
ls this your master's place?
This is my place.
Children!
Sorry to have to bother you, ma'am.
Come on, let's go.
Go back inside. Hurry up.
Put a stop to this at once!
Where are the officers?
Drop that, soldier. Now!
Get a message to Couch, to Hancock.
This will not be tolerated!
This is an army, not a rabble!
Well, General Jackson,
you are a most gallant sight this morning.
Thank you, General Stuart,
your gift is much appreciated.
General Longstreet, show us
where your troops are positioned.
Yes, sir. We're anchored on the north
by Anderson's division...
. ..up on the bend in the river
and Ransom's division...
. ..along and below the ridge
of Marye's Heights...
. ..with Cobb's brigade dug in down
on the road behind that stone wall.
Now, to their right, is General McLaws...
. ..and further down in the woods
and to the right, Pickett and Hood.
General Hood is my right flank.
He's connected in those heavy trees
over there with General Jackson's left.
Up here on the Heights,
we have the Washington artillery. ..
. ..Colonel Alexander's batteries
and support.
lt's a strong line, general.
Very well.
General Jackson, would you please extend
the line for us?
Um, General A.P. Hill is on the left,
adjoining General Hood.
Position is supported by General Taliaferro
and General Early.
Now to the right flank and behind
is D.H. Hill.
We've built a road behind our lines
running the entire length.
We can move troops as is necessary.
lf the enemy penetrates our lines
at any point...
. ..the reserves, Taliaferro and Early,
can move rapidly to a new position.
lf the enemy attempts to cut our center. ..
. ..or if General Pickett is pressed,
we can change positions, sir.
Good, very good.
General Stuart, are you in a strong position
for protecting. . .
. ..General Jackson's flank?
STUART:
Oh, yes, sir.
We're covering the enemy from the river,
as far out as our own lines.
lf the Yankees move down river or
threaten to turn General Jackson's line. ..
. ..we can block their advance
until the line is moved.
Very well. Gentlemen,
these deployments are sound.
The rest is in God's hands.
BOTH:
Amen.
CHAMBERLAlN:
ln the Roman civil war...
...Julius Caesar knew he had
to march on Rome itself...
...which no legion was permitted to do.
Marcus Lucanus left us a chronicle
of what happened.
How swiftly Caesar had surmounted
the icy Alps...
...and in his mind conceived
immense upheavals, coming war.
When he reached the little Rubicon,
clearly through the murky night...
...appeared a mighty image
of his country in distress...
. ..grief in her face. ..
. ..her white hair streaming
from her tower-crowned head.
With tresses torn and shoulders bare,
she stood before him and sighing, said:
"Where further do you march? Where
do you take my standards, warriors?
lf lawfully you come, if as citizens,
this far only is allowed."
Trembling struck his limbs.
And weakness checked his progress,
holding his feet at the river's edge.
At last he speaks.
Oh, thunderer. . .
. ..surveying great Rome's walls
from the Tarpeian rock.
Oh, Phrygian, house gods of lulus. . .
. ..clan and mysteries of Quirinus
who was carried off to heaven.
Oh, Jupiter of Latium, seated
in lofty Alba and hearths of Vesta.
Oh, Rome, equal to the highest deity,
favor my plans.
Not with impious weapons
do l pursue you.
Here am l, Caesar...
...conqueror of land and sea,
your own soldier everywhere...
...now too if l am permitted.
The man who makes me your enemy,
it is he will be the guilty one.
He broke the barriers of war
and through the swollen river...
...swiftly took his standards.
When Caesar crossed the flood
and reached the opposite bank...
...from Hesperia's forbidden fields,
he took his stand and said:
"Here, l abandoned peace
and desecrated law.
Fortune, it is you l follow.
Farewell to treaties.
From now on, war is our judge."
Hail Caesar.
We who are about to die salute you.
General Zook!
Move your brigade forward!
SOLDlER:
Double quick, forward march!
[BAND PLAYlNG lRlSH JlG]
[MARCHlNG BAND
PLAYlNG UPBEAT MUSlC]
Steady, boys, steady.
You'll soon be forward.
ls that to be
General Meagher's position?
He's enjoying the privilege of an officer.
Protecting the rear.
He's got a lame knee, for pity's sake.
Fair enough.
Someone's got to keep Burnside company.
Quiet in the ranks!
Shoulder arms!
[SOLDlER PLAYlNG BUGLE]
Colonel.
20th Maine to the front.
Battalion! Shoulder arms!
SOLDlER:
Shoulder arms!
Left face!
High-file right...
. ..march!
Come on, boys! Show them the cold steel!
lrish brigade, move out!
lrish brigade, at the double-quick. ..
. ..forward march!
Front and center!
Double column, boys! Form up!
[SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG]
Forward!
Keep moving!
That's the lrish.
What are those boys doing fighting in blue?
Don't they know we're fighting
for our independence?
Did they learn nothing
at the hands of the English?
They're Reb lrishmen. They're our brothers.
They've been misled to their fates.
Do your duty!
Steady, men! Steady!
Men, do your duty!
Battalion, halt!
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
Load them up, boys, load them up!
Keep loading, boys!
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
Load! Load! Load!
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
Fall back! Fall back, men!
Now move! Move!
Fall back! Now!
Go to hell! Go to hell and damnation!
Move, boys!
Lie down here!
Lie down and load!
Load!
Load and fire!
Quickly!
Blaze away, lads! Do it, boys!
Fire, boys.
Fire!
Keep firing, men! Keep firing!
[SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
Fall back!
Fall back, lads!
Every man for himself!
Fall back, men!
[SHOUTlNG]
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
-Caldwell's brigade, forward! Now!
-Yes, sir!
At the double-quick! March!
[SOLDlER PLAYlNG DRUM]
-General Armistead.
-Afternoon, General Pickett.
-See that last charge by Meagher's brigade?
-Those fellas deserved a better fate.
Their bravery is worthy of a better cause.
My heart stood still as l watched it.
ARMlSTEAD: l would not have believed
that mortal men. . .
. ..could march into the face
of such destruction.
LEE:
General Longstreet...
. ..those people committing more
fresh divisions at your lines.. .
. ..their mounting numbers
may overwhelm our defense.
Sir, if they put every man they have
on the field to approach me. . .
. ..give me plenty of ammunition,
l'll kill them all before they reach my line.
Nevertheless,
we must be prudent, general.
We must never ignore the unknown
or the unpredictable.
Yes, sir. l'll take the necessary measures.
Orders!
Send orders to Ransom's Tar Heels
to advance his division...
. ..and to Kershaw to bring up his brigade
to support Cobb at the wall.
Yes, sir! Hyah, hyah!
Forward, men!
[SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG]
General Griffin, sir.
There goes my first brigade to hell.
All right, get them ready.
20th Maine, fix bayonets!
Officers of the 3rd Brigade
will dismount.
Shoulder arms!
All right, men, move them out!
Forward march!
[SOLDlER PLAYlNG DRUM]
Load! Five-second fuse!
She burst! The barrel burst!
SOLDlER: Stretcher!
-General Lee, you all right, sir?
-Sergeant! Call for the surgeon! Quickly!
-Here l go. Help me up, boys.
lt's not yet our time, gentlemen.
Not yet our time.
General Kemper. General Kemper.
You are ordered by General Longstreet to
proceed to your left in support of McLaws.
Take two regiments of your brigade into
the sunken road behind the stone wall.
Yes, sir. At once.
Do your duty, general.
My horse. We go to where the fight is.
Commanding general has
called us into battle.
We move at once.
[SOLDlERS CHEERlNG]
lf we can whip the enemy here today. ..
. .. l tell you, from what l know. . .
. ..the Confederacy is surely established.
Men of Virginia. . .
. ..you who have fought
on so many hard-won fields. . .
. ..today your country calls upon you
one more time. . .
. ..to stand between her and the enemy.
And l know that you will do your duty!
[SOLDlERS CHEERlNG]
Brigade, halt! Form by battalion!
Pass them forward.
Just load and pass them forward!
Fire!
20th Maine. . .
. ..halt!
AMES: lt is not difficult to move from
line of battle into column of fours.
lt is much harder to move from
column of fours into line of battle...
...and if we're called to make that move,
it will be when we are under fire.
You understand how important it is that
these moves are learned so thoroughly...
...that the men can perform them
in their sleep.
[SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG]
Seems a terrible long distance
up that hill.
lt'll be shortened by those in the front.
Begging your pardon, sir.
The only thing that'll be shortened
by those in front is their lives.
God help us now.
-Colonel, take care of the right wing.
-Yes, sir. l'll watch them, sir.
Hail Caesar.
We who are about to die salute you.
20th Maine!
-Forward!
-March!
By the right of companies,
to the front! March!
Right of companies to the front! March!
Form a line, boys! Form a line!
Form up a line! Form up a line!
Dress to the colors!
Come on, boys!
Come on, boys.
Dress to the colors!
[SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG]
Keep your line, men. Keep your line.
Close that gap!
Dress to the colors!
At the double-quick, men!
Double-quick, boys! Come on, boys!
Keep it tight, boys! Keep it tight!
Turn right, boys! Right!
Turn to the right!
Keep it tight, men! Keep it tight, men!
Come on, boys!
At the double-quick, boys!
Forward, men. Keep moving!
Battalion, halt!
-Battalion, halt!
Watch your line!
Dress to the colors!
Ready! Fire!
Reload, boys! Reload quickly!
Hold your line! Hold your line!
Two, three, four...
-. . .five, six, seven...
SOLDlER: Dress right! Dress right!
. ..eight.
-Steady! Steady!
-Fire!
Load them! Let's go!
Keep firing! Keep firing!
Battalion, fight by fire!
Thattaway, boys, fire away!
Pour it into them!
Close the gap, boys!
Fill this hole now!
All right, pour it into them, boys!
Steady now! Pour it into them!
Dress that line down there!
-Sir?
-What is it?!
Request permission
to return to the rear, sir.
Permission granted. Permission granted.
All right, then, boys. Pour it.
No, no, Patrick, me boy.
Just reload and shoot.
Pour it into them, boys!
Pour it in to them!
Fill that line in!
Fill this hole now!
Dress to the right!
Fire!
Pour it into them, boys!
Pour it into them!
Fire!
-Fall back, men!
-Fall back! Fall back!
Fall back, boys!
-What did you do that for?
-You'll thank me in the morning.
Oh, Mother. Oh, Mother, help me. . . .
lt's all right, Casey, l got you. Don't worry
about a thing. l'll get you home.
SOLDlER:
Quickly, men. Reload quickly!
lt is well that war is so terrible...
. ..for we should grow too fond of it.
Yes, sir?
We're requisitioning your house
for use as a hospital.
Come on inside out the cold.
You there.
You wounded?
Truly sorry, old fella--
Damn.
[BREATHlNG HEAVlLY]
-General Hancock, sir.
-Surgeon.
This man is Major Sidney Willard
of the 35th Massachusetts.
This way, sir.
Prepare to lift. Lift.
He's been shot twice in the chest, general.
There's nothing l can do.
[SlGHS]
-ls there whiskey in this house?
-Yes, sir.
Drink this, sir.
l love them people
you done chased from this house.
l's known them most all my life.
The Beales is good people.
Mr. General?
l was born a slave.
And l wants to die free.
Lord knows l wants to die free,
and l wants my children to be free.
Heaven help me.
May God bless you all.
[GASPS]
Damn it, Tom,
you scared me half to death.
You? Lawrence, l thought
you was with the beyond.
[LAUGH lNG]
[GROANlNG]
Mother?
l was able to secure the aid
of a good spyglass. . .
. ..and could ascertain beyond all doubt
that our house is still standing.
Oh.
Oh, l pray to God
for Martha and her dear ones.
LUCY:
But, Mother...
. ..it is a pitiful sight on the fields
below Marye's Heights.
l should feel rancor in my heart
for those invaders...
. ..but all l feel for them is sorrow.
Dear Lucy. . .
. ..when you were
but a child in petticoats...
. .. l believe the year was 1 847. . .
. ..there was a great famine in lreland.
Those fields below the Heights
were covered...
. ..with the finest crop of corn
ever raised in this section.
The greater part of it was sent
as a donation to the starving lrish.
l cannot help thinking...
. ..but that it helped to feed
the poor victims of the lrish brigade...
. ..who fell on this very field today.
General Gregg.
General Jackson.
l wish to apologize...
. ..for the differences we had.
The doctor tells me
you have not long to live.
l ask you to dismiss this matter
from your mind. . .
. ..and turn your thoughts to God.. .
. ..and the world to which you go.
General. ..
. ..you know that l'm not a believer.
Well, then l will believe
for the both of us.
How horrible is war.
Horrible, yes.. .
. ..but we have been invaded.
Lord, what can we do?
Kill them, sir.
Kill every last man of them.
Gentlemen.
[GROANlNG]
Oh, what l wouldn't give
for a cup of Rio just now.
[GUNFlRE]
20th Maine! Return fire!
-Return fire!
Oh.
Patrick.
l hope you don't mind.
l know you're in heaven,
but you got work yet to do down here. ..
. ..in this poor pitiless world.
-Colonel Chamberlain.
-Mm.
Your orders are to withdraw.
Withdraw to the city.
Colonel.
We are ordered to form a picket line and
cover the Army's retreat across the river.
Colonel Chamberlain, did you hear me?
Yes, sir. We are to retreat, sir.
Captain Spear.
-Form the regiment. We're moving out.
-Yes, sir.
Morning, general.
General Jackson would like to report the
enemy is no longer in front of his position.
Go on, Mr. Pendleton.
General, the enemy has withdrawn
back across the river.
The pontoon bridges are gone, sir,
cut loose from their banks.
Major, summon General Longstreet.
l wanna know what's down below us here
and l do not wish to wait for the fog to lift.
Yes, sir.
Captain Pendleton,
you may return to General Jackson.
Express my appreciation
for his diligence.. .
. ..and remind him we do not wish
to give the enemy. . .
. ..an opportunity by exposing our troops
to those guns on Stafford Heights.
When the fog lifts, any advance will surely
receive a concentration of his artillery fire.
Yes, sir.
And, captain, l'm told you received
a wound to your thigh.
l trust it's not serious.
Thank you for asking, general.
lt's just a flesh wound.
Nothing serious at all.
MAN:
Yankees.
Everywhere.
Where y'all been? Can't find my own house.
Gone! Gone!
What y'all done with my house?
Where is it? Can y'all tell me that?
Well, can you? Can you?
20th Maine, halt!
You had a hard chance, colonel.
-l'm glad to see you out of there.
-lt was chance, general.
Not much intelligent design there.
God knows it wasn't l
that put you in there.
That was the trouble.
You should have put us in, sir.
We were handed in piecemeal,
on toasting forks.
ALL [SlNGlNG]:
Steal away
Steal away to Jesus
Steal away home
l ain't got long
To stay here
What you gonna do
now that your master's dead?
Done already told you he my boss. . .
. ..not my master.
Well, one way or the other, he gone now.
Ain't much left for me here in Virginny.
My brother done run off with the Yankees.
He in Chambersburg now.
Up north in Pennsylvania.
You planning on heading up that way?
Once l gets this body
up to his kin in Winchester. . .
. .. l sees the way things is.
Well, it's good for you
your boss got killed in the wintertime.
That's a long way to be
carrying a man in a pine box.
White folks be killing one another
for a while yet.
They're still plenty mad,
and plenty of them.
But this here Rebel. . .
. ..give me my freedom papers.
He already with Jesus.
l'm just taking him home.
Amen.
"Men of the Army. ..
. ..although you were not successful
in the recent battle. . .
. ..the attempt was not an error,
nor the failure other than an accident.
No soldiers in the annals of war
fought more bravely.
Condoling with the mourners
for the dead. ..
. ..and sympathizing
with the severely wounded.. .
. .. l congratulate the Army
that the numbers of casualties. . .
-. . .have been comparatively so small."
-Compared to what?
The Scots at Culloden?
The English at Bunker Hill?
The French at Waterloo?
"--the thanks of the nation."
Signed: Abraham Lincoln.
Battalion!
Dismissed!
At this Christmas season,
when the good fairies are in the air.. .
. ..we can hardly wonder
at the sudden miracle. . .
. ..that has shown us
the Fredericksburg affair in its true light.. .
. ..and given us occasion for national joy
instead of national sorrow.
[PLAYlNG PlANO]
General Jackson?
Do you know
what these decorations signify?
[SlGHS]
l was wondering if someone
would tell me.
-This is Santa's sled.
-l see.
And this is stuff made of candy.
This is a gingerbread snowflake.
And this is a paper chain of angels.
Did you make this angel?
lt's lovely.
-How old are you, Jane?
-l'm 5 years old.
-How old are you?
-l'm 38.
My father is 38. He's a soldier like you.
l haven't seen him for more than a year.
l've not met your father, but l'm told
he's a very good man, very brave man.
l'm sure he misses you
as much as l miss my daughter.
When did you last see your daughter?
l've never seen her.
She was born just days ago.
l want to see her more than anything
in this world.
l want to see her as much as
your father wants to see you.
You see that star at the top of the tree?
The star of Bethlehem.
The star that showed the wise men
where they could find the baby Jesus.
Mother says that star will show Daddy
how to find his way back home.
Well, your mother's very wise,
very good person.
Your daddy will come home.
All the daddies will come home.
Oh, my.
[SOBBlNG]
Gentlemen, let us lift our glasses
to our Southern women. . .
. ..without whose bravery and fortitude...
. ..without whose love,
without whose endurance and sacrifice. ..
. ..not a man among us
can stay the course.. .
. ..or defend the cause.
CROWD:
Hear, hear.
Now it's time for a carol.
Come up. Everybody must sing.
-Carols are my favorite.
-l can't sing.
Of course you can sing, Mr. Jackson.
You can breathe, can't you?
Just let your breath flow gently over
your vocal chords and nature does the rest.
[PLAYlNG "SlLENT NlGHT" ON PlANO]
ALL [SlNGlNG]:
Silent night.
Holy night
CHAMBERLAlN:
Dearest Fanny:
The bugle has just sounded,
3rd Brigade extinguish lights.
lt makes me happy to think of you
and my dear little ones at home...
...all nestled together.
l know that it is all well and bright with her
whose sweet face shines in my heart.
Come and let me kiss your dear lips,
precious wife.
Let our hearts worship together God's loVe,
and wisdom, and mercy.
Yes, all is well, well with us, darling...
...well if we can only meet at last,
as l pray God we may.
Hey, Billy Yank.
-That's a mighty nice song.
-l'm pleased you find it so agreeable.
l'd like it even more if l had some coffee
to wash it down.
-Want some baccy?
-Sure, Johnny.
Have you got a lame horse?
What do you be wanting to trade
for a lame horse?
Would you take General Burnside?
[LAUGH lNG]
No. l guess l'll keep the horsehide.
Come on, get your baccy.
Mr. Smith, are you aware that the Bible
gives models of official battle reports?
-No, sir.
-Nevertheless, there are such.
Consider the narrative of Joshua's battles
with the Amalekites.
lt has clearness and modesty, brevity.
And it traces the victory to the right source,
the blessing of God.
Has it helped you with your reports, sir?
Anybody home?
Afternoon, General Jackson.
[CHUCKLES]
What's this?
[LAUGH lNG]
-New recruits.
-Ha, ha.
JANE:
My mama helped me make these.
Mm? That's fine.
-Left, right. Left, right.
-Child, that hat is a bit too large for you.
However. . .
. ..there.
l believe that suits a young girl
better than an old soldier.
JANE:
Mama's baking some biscuits.
You know, l was thinking of walking over
to the big house for a nice hot cup of tea.
And l would very much like the company
of one beautiful little lady.
Yes, General Jackson,
a hot cup of chamomile.
Uh, Mr. Smith, you may continue
writing the reports.
Consult first and second Samuel.. .
. ..and first and second Kings.
They will be of help to you.
Shall we go?
Do you prefer butter biscuits
or sugar cookies?
Oh, my. l know your mother's biscuits
are first-rate.
[CHUCKLES]
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
CROWD:
Whoo!
[CROWD LAUGH lNG]
CROWD:
Whoo!
Coward.
lt's a fine thing for you
to call me a coward. ..
. ..when you spend all my salary
on stockings.
CROWD:
Whoo!
The first lady must look good
if her husband looks like a baboon.
[PLAYlNG DRUM]
You must be the missing "link-oln."
[MAN PLAYlNG DRUM]
l begin to wonder
who runs the White House.
[MAN PLAYlNG DRUM]
[CROWD LAUGH lNG]
And that's the long and the short of it.
And now, my gallant friends...
. ..my own dear beau will sing
a verse of his original creation. ..
. ..and invites you to all join in
on the chorus.
"The Bonnie Blue Flag!"
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
[SlNGlNG]
We are a band of brothers
And native to the soil
Fighting for our liberty with....
And when our rights were threatened
The cry rose near and far
Hurrah for the Bonnie Blue Flag
That bears a single star
ALL [SlNGlNG]: Hurrah, Hurrah
For Southern rights, hurrah
Hurrah for the Bonnie Blue Flag
That bears a single star
We owe you Texas boys a debt of gratitude
for putting on these shows.
Colonel Patton, any man who can't handle
a guitar or a fiddle...
. ..ain't fit to carry a musket.
[SlNGlNG]
But now, when Northern treachery
Attempts our rights to mar
We hoist on high the Bonnie Blue Flag
That bears a single star
ALL [SlNGlNG]: Hurrah, Hurrah
For Southern rights, hurrah
Hurrah for the Bonnie Blue Flag
That bears a single star
Then here's to our Confederacy
Strong we are and braVe
Like patriots of old we'll fight
Our heritage to saVe
And rather than submit to shame
To die we would prefer
So cheer for the Bonnie Blue Flag
That bears a single star
ALL [SlNGlNG]: Hurrah, hurrah
For Southern rights, hurrah
Hurrah for the Bonnie Blue Flag
That bears a single star
Hurrah, hurrah
For Southern rights, hurrah
Hurrah for the Bonnie Blue Flag
That bears a single star
[CROWD CHEERlNG]
SOLDlER:
Attention, battalions.
Halt.
-Sergeant, keep these men here for now.
-Yes, sir.
Sir.
The men have rounded up three deserters.
Establish the courts-martial.
Have them arraigned.
See they're given a fair hearing.
Uh, yes, sir.
Yes?
Well, l thought that you should know, sir.
They all belong to the Stonewall brigade.
[SlGHS]
Do your duty, soldier.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Pendleton, if they are innocent,
these men will go free.
But if they are found guilty of desertion. ..
. ..the courts-martial condemns them
to death. lt must be so.
Yes, sir.
Of course, sir.
l'm not done yet.
Sandie.
lf the Republicans lose their little war,
they are voted out in the next election. ..
. ..and they return to their homes
in New York or Massachusetts or lllinois. . .
. ..fat with their war profits.
lf we lose, we lose our country.
We lose our independence.
We lose it all.
Our soldiers are brave.
They have endured hardships none of them
could ever have imagined.
Desertion is not a solitary crime.
lt's a crime against the tens of thousands
of veterans. . .
. ..who are huddled together
in the harsh cold of this winter.
Against all those who have sacrificed.
Against all those who have fallen.
Against all the women and the children
we have left alone to fend for themselves.
l regard the crime of desertion as a sin
against the Army of the Lord.
Duty is ours.
The consequences are God's.
JENKlNS:
l am a soldier in the 4th Virginia.
And in the 4th Virginia l will stay.
And if needs be, die.
The courts-martial of the Army
of Northern Virginia. . .
. ..has found you guilty of desertion
and sentences you to death. . .
. ..by firing squad.
Lieutenant, do your duty.
Detail, ready!
Aim.
Fire!
Recover, arm!
Morning, Lawrence.
-Any mail?
-No.
But l did manage to get my hands
on a New York Tribune.
-What are they saying about us now?
-Well, not much about us.
l mean, that is, this Army here
in Stoneman's Switch.
Sure are kicking up a fuss about
Lincoln's Emancipation Proclamation.
Oh. Says here that enlistments are down
and desertions are up.
-Any grumbling among the men?
-Well, not in our regiment.
A few wonder out loud why they should be
risking their lives for the darkies.
Well, Tom, you know my position.
l signed up to preserve the Union.
The president did the right thing.
What's the use of uniting the country
by force and leaving slavery in place?
lt sure riled up those Johnny Rebs.
They'll think Lincoln incited the slaves
to rise against them.
Why shouldn't they?
Freeing the slaves wasn't a war aim
when this began, but war changes things.
-lt sorts things out.
-Well, l don't know, Lawrence.
Not everybody feels the way we do
about the darkies.
Especially when it comes to fighting
and dying.
Tom.
Do me a favor.
Don't call me Lawrence
and don't call Negroes "darkies."
That's a patronizing expression
from which we must free ourselves.
Come outside. l want to, uh--
l want to show you something.
[SlGHS]
All these thousands of men.
Many of them not much more than boys.
Each one of them some mother's son.
Some sister's brother.
Some daughter's father.
Each one of them a whole person,
loved and cherished in some home far away.
Many of them will never return.
An army is power.
lts entire purpose is to coerce others.
Now, this kind of power cannot be used
carelessly or recklessly.
This kind of power can do great harm.
We have seen more suffering
than any man should ever see. . .
. ..and if there is going to be an end to it,
it must be an end that justifies the cost.
Now, somewhere out there
is the Confederate Army.
They claim they are fighting
for their independence, for their freedom.
Now, l cannot question their integrity.
l believe they are wrong,
but l cannot question it.
But l do question a system that defends
its own freedom while it denies it to others.
To an entire race of men.
l will admit it, Tom, war is a scourge.
But so is slavery.
lt is the systematic coercion
of one group of men over another.
lt has been around since
the book of Genesis.
lt exists in every corner of the world.
But that's no excuse for us
to tolerate it here.. .
. ..when we find it right before
our very eyes, in our own country.
As God is my witness, there is no one
l hold in my heart dearer than you.
But if your life or mine is part of the price
to end this curse and free the Negro. . .
. ..then let God's will be done.
CORBlN: Oh, my, general,
we do appreciate the gift.
Where do you get all these lemons?
lt's a kind providence
that provides kindly.
Miss Corbin, the Yankees have not
succeeded in cutting our rail lines...
. ..to the South.
Here is to the sultry, balmy South.
And, Miss Corbin,
here's to your engagement.
May Sandie Pendleton prove to be
as fine a husband as he is a soldier.
Hear, hear.
Mm.
BOTH:
That's good, it's not too sweet.
May l have some more?
Sure.
[MlMlCKlNG HORSE]
Mrs. Corbin.
Thank you for your many kindnesses.
Our cause and our country
are in your debt.
l only regret, general,
that we could not do more.
You'll come visit us again
when this cruel war is over?
l should like to say goodbye to your
daughter. l shall miss her very much.
Certainly, general.
She's not feeling very well today.
All of the children have come down
with the fever. Please, come in.
Well, now.
What's this?
How can l play with my friend
if she insists on staying in bed?
Jane.
Will you place this angel on your tree
next Christmas?
Mm-hm.
Bless you, child.
Mrs. Corbin, l must return to my men.
My physician, Doctor McGuire,
will attend to her.
-l will send him directly.
-Bless you, general.
Fresh meat. What a change.
Yeah. A live steer around these parts
is as rare as a peacock in a poultry pen.
[SOLDlERS LAUGHlNG]
lt was scarlet fever.
The children are all right. They'll be fine.
Except--
l'm so sorry, sir.
The little girl, Jane.
She did not survive. She died, sir.
No, Sandie.
[CRYlNG]
What is it?
He's never cried before.
Not for all the blood and all the death,
not for his young students from VMl ...
. ..not for his friends. . .
. ..not for anyone.
Not so, Sandie.
l think he is crying for them all.
[MARCHlNG BAND
PLAYlNG UPBEAT MUSlC]
[CHEERlNG]
[lNAUDlBLE DlALOGUE]
She's too pretty to look like me.
Nonsense, Thomas.
She is very like you.
She rises early and she loves
to be held in my arms.
[CHUCKLES]
l have never seen you look so well,
Thomas.
You are handsomer than ever.
And grant that this child
now to be baptized therein...
. ..may receive the fullness of thy grace...
. ..and ever remain the number
of thy faithful children.
Through Jesus Christ, our Lord. Amen.
CROWD:
Amen.
[BABY CRYlNG]
What is the Christian name of the child?
-Julia Laura.
LACY: Julia Laura.
l baptize thee in the name of the Father. . .
. ..and of the Son. . .
. ..and of the Holy Ghost.
Amen.
CROWD:
[CHUCKLES]
He won't agree.
[SCOFFS]
Mr. Minnis.
Would you tell him that you were sent
to take General Lee's photograph. ..
. ..but that General Lee declined unless
General Jackson's was taken first.
Certainly, Captain Pendleton.
No photographs.
Sir, l was sent from Richmond
to take a photograph of General Lee. ..
. ..but the general decided that
he did not want his photograph taken. . .
. ..until l had taken your photograph first.
Sir, General Lee was most insistent
on the importance of your photograph.
l cannot refuse General Lee's request.
Where do you wish me to stand?
Mr. Booth is here the entire month.
He's playing in Hamlet,
Katherine and Petruchio...
...The Merchant of Venice,
Richard llI and Macbeth.
Which is your favorite, Mr. President?
l think nothing equals Macbeth.
l have read it many times.
-l am curious to see Mr. Booth's rendition.
-lndeed?
l am told Booth does
the death scene spectacularly.
Very physical.
Wilder than his brother Edwin.
That is one reproach l have
of Shakespeare's heroes.
What reproach is that, dear?
They all make long speeches
when they are killed.
[BOTH LAUGHlNG]
They do indeed.
ls this a dagger which l see before me. . .
. ..handle towards my hand?
Come, let me clutch thee.
l have thee not, yet l see thee still.
Art thou not, fatal vision,
sensible to feeling as to sight?
Or art thou but a dagger of the mind. . .
. ..a false creation. . .
. ..proceeding from
the heat-oppressed brain?
l see thee yet. . .
. ..in form as palpable as this
which now l draw.
Thou marshall'st me
the way that l was going. ..
. ..and such an instrument l was to use.
Mine eyes are made the fools
o' the other senses.
l see thee still. . .
. ..and on thy blade and dudgeon...
. ..gouts of blood,
which was not so before.
lt is the bloody business which informs
thus to mine eyes.
Whiles l threat...
. ..he lives.
Words to the heat of deeds too cold
breath gives.
l go, and it is done.
The bell invites me.
Hear it not, Duncan. . .
. ..for it is a knell
that summons thee to heaven...
. ..or to hell.
Well, Mr. Booth, another triumph.
The president and Mrs. Lincoln
wish to see you.
[CHUCKLES]
You may tell that tyrant...
. ..that destroyer of civil liberties. . .
. ..that warmonger...
. ..that l am indisposed. Huh?
Better still, tell him nothing.
Tell him l'd already gone.
Golly gee, Booth.
An endorsement from
the president of the United States.
Could be a big thing for your career.
LEE:
General, from what we've observed. . .
. ..Hooker has moved five corps,
maybe 70,000 men.
They're digging in around
Chancellor's mansion.
Sedgwick has another 40,000
spread out along the Stafford Heights. . .
. ..on the north bank of the Rappahannock
in front of General Early at Fredericksburg.
Now, there's possibly 30,000 more
back along the river north of here. . .
. ..that we've not yet located.
We're not in a position of strength here.
We owe a great deal to the unexplainable,
the mystery of General Hooker. . .
. ..who's allowed us to maneuver freely...
. ..between two parts of an army
that's more than twice our strength.
We do not yet understand his plan.
He may still plan a move
toward Gordonsville. . .
. ..move around below us,
cut us off from Richmond.
And there's still Sedgwick on the river.
Now Sedgwick shows no signs of moving,
but that could change.
They're anchored against the river. . .
. ..and their lines continue
down below Chancellorsville. . .
. ..then curves along here.
We've observed their lines curving out
in these open clearings. . .
. ..then extending on out to the west.
Then what, general?
Do you know where their right flank is?
JACKSON: No. Not yet.
LEE: We must know. We must know.
lf he marches in that direction,
he could threaten our flank.. .
. ..or be going toward Gordonsville
before we can react.
Out here, in the west,
along this turnpike, here...
. ..their right flank's in the air.
lt's the one place they're not digging in.
They're not expecting any pressure there.
-Who's on their flank?
-1 1 th Corps. Oliver Howard.
Mm-hm. Were there any roads
farther down below the turnpike?
Yes, sir. lndeed there are, good roads.
That's Catherine's Furnace here
and there's a road here.
-There's a road over this way.
-Then, we must hit them there.
Then attack the flank.
They will have nowhere to go.
They'll have to go back across the river
or we will destroy them.
We're too close to their lines.
They'll observe our movements.
There must be another road farther down.
Now, is there someone we know?
Someone we can trust who knows the area?
Captain Pendleton.
Find Reverend Lacy for me.
LACY:
l'm, uh, here, sir.
This is my chaplain,
the Reverend Tucker Lacy.
He has family in this area.
General Lee.
Reverend, it would be very helpful
if you could find us a safe route...
-. . .around the enemy.
-Well, sir, uh, there, l know a family.
The Wellfords. Uh, l suggest a visit to them.
We may find ourselves a guide.
Please go at once, Mr. Lacy. Find someone
who might show us how we might proceed.
Yes, sir.
Then it has been decided, general.
This mission will be yours.
l would not have it any other way.
Where is General Jackson, Jim?
He done gone to see his officers, sir.
How come that you know so much
about what the general is thinking, Jim?
None of us do.
The general never tells me nothing, sir.
But the way l knows is this:
The general say his prayers twice a day...
. ..morning and night.
But if he gets out of bed in the night
two or three times to pray...
. .. l just packs the haversack.
l know there's a move on hand
and hell to pay in the morning.
[LAUGH lNG]
"Hell to pay in the morning."
Very amusing.
-Amusing.
-Yeah.
Yeah.
Wait.
There is another road.
lt's a road that runs
well below the Federal lines.
The Wellford boy explained it to me.
He knows the route.
He will march with us to where
this road rejoins the turnpike. . .
. ..then we turn to the east
and attack their right flank.
lt is a greater distance, perhaps 1 2 or
1 3 miles, but the boys can do it.
They have never let us down.
Farewell, general.
How many troops will you require?
Five, general, my whole corps.
And what will you leave me?
Well, the divisions
of Anderson and McLaws.
You leave me 1 2,000 men
against Hooker's 70,000.
lf Hooker pushes out of his trenches.. .
. ..he could destroy not only the plan
but possibly the Army.
And there's still Sedgwick
along the river.
How long will he sit staring at Marye's Hill?
How long?
We've divided the Army before.
We must retain the advantage of
surprise, we must outflank the flankers.
We must beat them at their own game.
Take your entire corps,
General Jackson, and destroy the enemy.
God be with you.
Boys, my days are numbered.
My time has come.
You can laugh, but my time has come.
l got a 20-dollar gold piece l carried
through the war and a silver watch. . .
. ..my daddy sent to me
through the lines.
Take them off of me when l'm dead.
Give them to my captain to give to my
daddy when he gets back home.
Here's my clothes and my blanket.
Anybody who wishes can have them.
My rations l do not wish at all. My gun
and cartridge box l expect to die with.
-Mr. Smith.
-Sir.
Your instructions to the ranks: There is
to be no noise, l want no talking.
Stragglers will be bayoneted,
let the men know.
No muskets are to be loaded until we
deploy for battle. Secrecy, Mr. Smith.
Everything depends upon
the element of surprise.
Sir, l'll convey the orders. No stragglers.
-Reverend.
-May we bow our heads.
Dear Lord, heavenly Father,
you who know all things.
We face again a mighty
foe, a vast host.
An enemy more than twice our number.
But you have taught us
to fear not, to trust in you.
When the Philistines came before them,
the people of lsrael feared Goliath.
Their Army was in terror.
No one had the courage to stand
against the mighty warrior.
Then you brought forth David,
a mere boy.
And Saul armed David with his armor...
...and he put a helmet
of brass upon his head.
Also he armed him with a coat of mail.
And DaVid girded his sword upon
his armor and he assayed to go.
General Rodes, deploy your men on
either side of the turnpike, brigade front.
How soon will
General Colston's men be up?
We're right behind, general.
JACKSON:
General Lee...
...l hope as soon as
practicable to attack...
...l trust that an ever kind providence
will bless us with great success.
Take this to General Lee.
Well, General Rodes...
. ..it appears the Virginia Military
lnstitute will be heard from today.
Deploy your brigade.
Two hours of daylight left.
Are you ready, General Rodes?
You may move forward.
[ALL SHOUTlNG]
SOLDlER 1 :
Fall back!
SOLDlER 2:
They're coming! Get your muskets!
-Shoulder to shoulder! Let's go, let's go!
-Fall back!
Aim, fire!
Pull back and save yourself!
Fall back!
Fire! Fall back!
lnto the trees, men! Fall back!
SOLDlER 3:
lnto the trees!
Form a line! Form a line!
Form a line!
-Run! Run!
-Charge!
Press on!
Hold up right here! Aim! Fire!
Push on!
Fire!
Hell, that's hot. l knew
you'd be all right, you dang fool.
Oh, God.
Regroup!
-Stop running!
-Move into line!
Stay together!
My God! Give them the bayonet!
-Stop running!
Stop running, soldier!
Stop running! Rally with me, men!
-Rally with me!
-Stop! Rally around the general!
We have stopped, sir. Can't see.
The lines are tangled.
We're mixed in with Rodes' men.
lt's confusion, sir.
We need Hill to come up.
Hill's men can move on by us.
Tell General Colston
he must re-form his men.
Now l will strongly urge General Hill
to push forward hard.
We must not stop. Let General Colston
know they will run if we press them.
Yes, sir.
General Hill, you must keep the men
moving. We must keep the pressure up.
We have broken their flank. We can
crush them now if we can cut them off.
We must not give them time
to get organized.
General, take your division forward.
Press on north, move toward the river,
toward the United States ford.
-We must not let them escape.
-lt's late in the day, general.
-We don't know the ground.
-Boswell!
You will ride with General Hill. You will find
a way through the woods to the northeast.
You will find the rear
of the enemy's position.
Yes, sir.
We will cut them off, general!
They're digging in. Must be Federal.
Sound carries at night,
they could be a ways off.
General, sir, we are beyond our lines.
This is no place for you, sir.
You're right.
lt cannot go the way l'd hoped.
lt will have to be tomorrow.
Gentlemen, let us return to the road.
Stop firing! You're firing
at your own men!
Hold it!
Hold your fire!
These are your own men here!
lt's a lie! Pour into them, boys!
Cease fire! Cease fire!
General Hill, they're our men!
What have they done?
Who is this?
Oh, God, general! Are you hurt badly?
l'm afraid l am, in my shoulder.
And here.
-Get a litter. We need a litter. Move!
SOLDlER: Yes, sir.
-We must leave here, general.
-Here, take this. lt'll help, sir.
l will try to keep this from
the knowledge of the troops.
Thank you, general.
The Yankees have set up a battery not a
hundred yards. We must get away!
Ready? Lift! Careful now.
Move out. Ready, lift.
Fire!
General. Lie quiet, or you
will most certainly be killed.
Let's go. Lift!
Move! Ready? Lift!
Doctor, good to see you.
l am hurt badly.
l fear l am dying.
Sir, l want you to drink this.
lt's whiskey and morphine.
Your right hand is minor.
The ball lodged under the skin.
lt's these other wounds.
l need to examine your arm.
And l'll administer chloroform
to make it painless.
lf l should find that the condition
warrants amputation...
. ..may l proceed at once?
l have complete faith
in you, Dr. McGuire.
You must do to me whatever
you think necessary.
Breathe deeply, general.
What an infinite blessing.
Blessing.
[ALL CHEERlNG]
Doesn't seem right that General Jackson
isn't here to see this.
No, major. lt does not seem right at all.
But it is the will of God.
He's lost his left arm. l've lost my right.
General?
How you feeling, sir?
Do not concern yourself about me.
But tell me, how are we faring?
General, the enemy's gone
across the river.
We secured the high ground
around Chancellorsville.
General Stuart did well by you, sir.
And the Stonewall brigade...
. ..right in the middle of it, sir.
"Remember Jackson," they shouted.
l heard that all day.
They were fighting for Stonewall.
Well, isn't that just like them.
They are a noble set of men.
That name, Stonewall, belongs
to the brigade, not to me.
l have the ball.
Dr. McGuire allowed me to keep the
musket ball he took from your hand.
lt was a round, smooth bore.
lt had to be one of ours.
l heard. They thought l was asleep.
lt could not be helped.
There's no blame in war.
We must all forgive.
Watch your step.
Mrs. Jackson.
So am--?
Am l allowed to visit my husband
before he is buried?
Buried? He's--
Oh, my. No, no, no.
This is the body of Frank Paxton.
General Paxton is moving his body
back to Lexington.
Well, l knew Mr. Paxton.
General Paxton, he's our neighbor.
His wife, she cried when he left.
l suppose she knew
something like this would happen.
Thank you.
l had to remove your husband's
left arm, patch his right hand.
He's healing well, l'm very pleased.
But there is a new problem.
l do believe he is developing pneumonia.
-May l see him, doctor?
-Well, certainly, certainly. Um, he's weak.
l've given him some medicine
to help him sleep.
He's in some pain and the medication
makes him drift away. He's in and out.
[KNOCKlNG ON DOOR]
General, l have a treat for you.
Something you may have been missing.
Another medicine?
Very well, doctor.
No, it's not mine, actually.
But it may do you some good.
Oh, oh, oh, so sweet. Too much sugar.
Always the problem with
my esposita's lemonade.
l'm so glad to see you looking so bright.
No, no. You must be cheerful.
Let's not have a long face.
You know l like cheerfulness
and brightness in a sickroom.
Esposita.
My esposita.
l know you would gladly
give your life for me. . .
. ..but l am perfectly resigned.
Do not be sad.
l hope l may yet recover.
Pray for me.
But in your prayers, never forget to
use the petition, "Thy will be done."
l'm so glad you're here.
Your lemonade is delicious.
[CHUCKLES]
-lt's not too sweet.
-Too much sugar.
l never told you that.
MAN: O, Caesar--
-Hence! Wilt thou lift up Olympus?
Great Caesar--
Doth not Brutus bootless kneel?
Speak, hands, for me!
[GROANlNG]
Et tu, Brute!
[CROWD GASPlNG]
Then fall, Caesar.
Liberty! Freedom!
Tyranny is dead!
-Hello, Mrs. Chamberlain.
-Hello.
-Thank you for staying.
-Thank you.
Come, you must meet the other actors.
Mr. Harrison, Mr. Booth, may l present
Colonel Chamberlain and his wife.
May l congratulate you, all of you,
on a most moving interpretation.
This is only a play.
We've heard about you, colonel. . .
. ..and how you stood on the bridge
of the Rappahannock like Horatius. . .
. ..as hundreds fled in panic round you.
How can our playing compare to what
you have seen, what you have done?
Well, remember, gentlemen,
l am not a soldier by nature.
l am a teacher of rhetoric...
. ..and my master, as yours,
is Shakespeare.
And, uh, did you enjoy the play,
Mrs. Chamberlain?
Oh. Very much.
Mr. Booth, tell me something.
Do you regard yourself as the hero
or the villain of Shakespeare's play?
Well, ha, ha. . . .
Well, an actor must always regard himself
as a hero, Mrs. Chamberlain...
. ..even if that role be no more than
a simple soldier who only speaks one line.
Yes. lt's for the audience to decide
who is a hero and who is villain.
We merely play the parts allotted to us.
How do you think of us,
Mrs. Chamberlain...
. ..Cinna and Brutus,
as heroes or villains?
Well. . .
. ..noblest Roman of them all. . .
. ..you cannot be villains
in Shakespeare's eyes. . .
. ..though Dante makes you
the worst villains in the world. . .
. ..after Judas lscariot.
No, you are not villains to Shakespeare. . .
. ..but l wonder, are you heroes?
-Oh. l speak too much. l'm sorry.
-No, no, no.
My beloved husband has been given
a few days' furlough here. . .
. ..and everything about these days
delights me utterly.
Do not expect me to speak intelligently
about your play or anything else.
My eyes, my heart, my whole being
is dancing uncontrollably with joy. ..
. ..at being together
with the man that l love.
Thank you for enriching my stay here
with those immortal words. Thank you.
Come, Fanny. We must leave the players
to rest after their exertions.
Good evening.
What a Caesar, Harrison.
What a Caesar.
Too young for Caesar. Henry V.
Yes, Henry V.
With that voice shouting,
"Once more into the breach!"
Oh, yes. Henry V.
Teacher, not a soldier.
And a better actor than either of us.
But he's chosen the right role
in the right play.
He'll be applauded
long after we're forgotten.
All we can do, Harrison,
is like l said to Mrs. Chamberlain.
All we can do is play the roles
allotted to us.
Well, if a teacher of rhetoric can
become a soldier, so can an actor.
l've known for some time
l could not go on like this.
And now. ...
lf the Yankee cause can sway
a man like that.. .
. ..then we need every man
we can muster.
Booth, l'm quitting the stage.
l have to go.
l loathe, l detest his cause.
But were l to be killed
by a man like that. . .
. .. l'd regard it an honor.
Yes, sir.
An honor.
You were always inclined
to melodrama, Harrison.
What makes you think you'll be
a better soldier than an actor?
Stay here.
Your place is here.
Why should we think what we do
is any less than what soldiers do?
We may be mere actors.. .
. ..but think of the words
we help to keep alive.
Who will remember the names of.. .
. ..Queen Elizabeth's generals,
and politicians?
Who will ever forget. . .
. ..the name...
. ..Shakespeare?
ls that my sweet darling angel?
[JULlA BABBLlNG]
My Julia.
ls it certain, doctor?
[SlGHS]
Does he know?
l have not told him.
Then l will.
He must know.
He must be prepared.
JOSEPH & ANNA [SlNGlNG]:
Guard us, guide us
Keep us, feed us
For we have no help but thee
Yet possessing every blessing
lf our God our father be
My darling...
. ..today is Sunday.
Do you know that the doctor says
you must very soon be in heaven?
Do you not feel willing to acquiesce in
God's allotment if he wills you to go today?
l prefer it.
Well. . .
. ..by the time this day closes. . .
. ..you will be with the blessed
Savior in his glory.
[SOBBlNG]
l ....
l will be an infinite gainer
to be translated.
General Lee.
What is the news, Reverend?
General Lee, l must report
that his case appears hopeless.
His wounds are healing,
but he's dying of pneumonia.
Surely General Jackson must recover.
God will not take him from us, not now
that we need him so very much.
Will you see him, sir?
No, sir, l won't. No, sir.
When you return,
l trust you'll find him better.
And when the occasion offers, tell him
that l prayed for him last night.. .
. ..as l never prayed,
l believe, for myself.
Please tell him.
Sir.
Push up that column.
Move up that column.
Pendleton, take charge of that line.
Where's Smith?
Tell him. Push up that column.
Move the batteries to the center
of the crest. There's no time to waste.
General Stuart, no quarter to the
violators of our homes and hearths.
General Lee, we must take
the war to the enemy.
[SOBBlNG]
You are the 1 st Brigade.
Advance, my brave boys.
Press on.
Let us cross over the river. . .
. ..and rest under the shade of the trees.
[SOLDlER PLAYlNG DRUM]
[English - US - SDH]