From the Halls of Montezuma
To the shores of Tripoli
We fight
our country's battles
On the land as on the sea
Admiration of the nation
We're the finest ever seen
And we glory in the title
Of United States Marines
From the Halls
of Montezuma
To the shores of Tripoli
We fight
our country's battles
On the land as on the sea
Admiration of the nation
We're the finest ever seen
And we glory in the title
Of United States Marines
[Intercom Buzzes]
Officer: Colonel Gilfillan
will address the men.
Aye, aye, sir.
Boatswain:
Now hear this.
Gilfillan: Marines,
Company B, First Battalion,
this is Colonel Gilfillan.
We're gonna be landing on
a Jap-held island before long.
A couple of things
I've said to you before
I think are worth repeating.
When you hit that beach,
there's gonna be a lot of
noise and smoke and confusion.
You're gonna have
to keep your eyes
on your squad leaders
and platoon leaders.
I don't want any lost
little lambs runnin' around.
You know where lambs end up.
And let's get it straight,
this is a big island.
There's a lot about it
we don't know yet,
and a lot
we're gonna have to find out
from theJaps themselves.
We used to say that the only
good Jap was a dead Jap.
I'll remind you
that that's changed.
From here on in,
a good Jap is also a Jap
prisoner who tells us things.
Now, this is an order.
Whenever possible,
you will take prisoners.
I say again,
Some of us were together
at Guadalcanal
and again at Tarawa.
I was proud to be with you.
I know it will be
the same after this.
Believe me,
this trip is necessary.
All hands, good luck.
I'll see you on the beach.
Wouldn't you know,
I'd get a stinkin' cold.
What's the matter,
Whitney?
I don't like the dreams
I've been having.
Ah, don't let it
worry you.
I've landed
on 2 Jap islands,
and I'm still here.
Yeah, but this guy
I'm a replacement for,
where's he?
Got a half inch
of whiskey.
It's all I got left
in the world.
- You want it?
- I don't drink.
You will.
Gonna make
some more
the first
minute I get.
No, thanks,
I don't drink.
Okay,just take this
ashore for me.
Come on.
What is it?
It's a gazintuh.
This goes into that.
It's a still!
Shh!
Just get it ashore.
Watch out for
Sergeant Zelenko.
But I don't drink.
Yeah, I know.
You told me, but I do.
Boatswain: Now hear this.
Now hear this.
All troops lay below
and prepare to debark.
[Rattling]
Hey, you, Whitney.
What are you carrying,
a still?
Sergeant, I don't--
Now, look, pal,
we've a war to fight.
Yeah, and you're
gonna fight it sober.
Sergeant, I don't drink.
Come with me.
Now, listen to me...
you new men...
step up here.
Don't let Slattery
give you a snow job
and get you into trouble.
He's got no more sense than
a setting hen in a hurricane.
That's why
he's been a private
longer than any man
in the Marine Corps...
and he'll die
a private.
Don't have nothin'
to do with him.
Except when things
get tough,
stick to him
like plaster.
The best fighting man
I know.
But before and after,
he's a no-good,
money-burnin',
gin-drinkin'
horsehead.
Now, let's get moving.
Got a lot of coal to dig.
Hey, Zelenko!
Where's Lieutenant Anderson?
Coffman, you shouldn't
worry so much.
He'll be here.
Yeah, but he said he'd meet us
on the deck, like always.
Take your pack off and
loosen your leggings.
Did he ever miss
a train before?
Conroy: hey,
where's the lieutenant?
Pharmacist's mate:
I don't know.
Lieutenant, I--
I can't make it.
I'm sick.
You gotta
scratch me out.
[Crying]
Please, Lieutenant...
you've gotta get me out
of this landing.
I can't get away with it
anymore after...
Tarawa, the Canal.
Call me a psycho,
court-martial me.
I don't care!
The war's comin' out
of my ears! I'm sick!
Anderson, Thinking:
So am I.
Do you hear me,
Lieutenant?
Do you hear me?
Anderson: I hear you.
Anderson: Both of us had it
comin' out of our ears.
So what do I tell him,
think of ice cream sodas,
Fourth ofJuly?
There are no bands
playing here.
The first time I saw him
he was just as scared...
a hundred years ago.
Greetings, on this first day
of the new term.
Oh, I see we have a transfer
from Clinton High School.
Mr. Conroy, have you
ever had chemistry before?
Conroy.
Well, speak up.
Are you tongue-tied?
I--I--
He s-s-stutters.
[Laughing]
Quiet.
I apologize, Mr. Conroy.
You may sit down.
All right, Conroy,
repeat slowly after me,
hope is the mother
of all men.
Hope...is the mother...
Uh, h-h-hope
is t-t-the--
Now, wait a minute.
Read that top line,
will ya?
The top one.
Uh...
S-S-September...
23rd...
1 940.
There you are.
You see?
You don't stutter as much
when you read.
No, not--
not much.
Now, Stuart,
listen to me.
Stuttering is a matter
of conflict and fear.
Maybe in your case,
fear of failure.
Now we may not be able
to cure all of it,
but I'm sure we'll be able
to fix that stuttering.
After all, we've got
a whole year to try.
So let's get started.
Now, close your eyes and
pretend that you're all alone,
and you see words
in your mind--
The words, hope is
the mother of all men.
Now, close your eyes
and read what you see.
Uh...
hope...
is...the...
mother...
of...all...
men.
It worked.
Good. Now,
let's try it again.
Uh, hope...
is the mother...
of all men.
Swell.
Mr. Principal,
members of the faculty,
honored guests...
fellow graduates of
the class of 1 941 --
Hope...
Hope is the mother
of all men.
And as we leave
these hallowed halls,
we must, each one of us,
fearlessly hold on
to the belief
in the promise
of the future.
There is no limit
to our achievement.
What are you thinking,
Lieutenant, that I'm a coward?
Is that
what you're thinking?!
Thinking of
dear old school days.
That's a laugh!
No! I was thinking
you handled fear once,
you can
handle it again.
Mr. Conroy, have you
ever had chemistry before?
Boatswain:
now hear this.
Now hear this.
All hands go to
debarkation stations.
Okay, Lieutenant.
Let's walk.
I want to tell you men
who've never been
in combat before
that it's okay to be scared.
We're all scared.
But if anybody feels
like vomiting, do it now.
What's holdin' us up?
Let's get rollin'.
How many landings
you gotta make to learn
we circle out here until
they're ready for us?
I'm in a hurry to get home,
that's all.
You and Pretty Boy
buddies, are ya?
Sure. We kinda
look after each other.
He's tough.
He's a nice fellow,
but he is tough.
Something the matter,
Lieutenant?
Get out of here.
Hey, Doc, you better
talk to Anderson.
He's in some kind
of pain.
Did he ask for me?
No.
Then let me alone.
But, Doc, I--
If he needs me,
he'll ask for me.
Now, look, Doc,
I'm an old friend of his.
Let me alone,
I told you.
Doc: I'd do anything
for Anderson,
but it ain't up to me.
I ought to be on my farm
where I belong,
working with cows.
It's easy to figure
right and wrong with cows.
That's a honey of a pipe,
Lieutenant.
Say, thanks a lot.
Forget it, Doc.
The principal of
my old school sent it to me.
I don't smoke pipes.
Hey, uh...
you did a fine job getting
that plasma into me at Tarawa.
Forget it, sir.
The medical brass say I'll
be out of here pretty soon.
Hey, that's fine,
Lieutenant.
Yeah.
Sit down.
Go ahead,
it's all right.
There's an old witch
of a nurse out there
with an ear like radar and
a tongue like a fire bell.
Heh heh.
You know what
psychological migraine is?
A lot of pain
in the head,
no functional
disorder.
Heh heh, for a guy
who was a manure spreader
in South Dakota 3 years ago,
you're pretty hep.
Well, I always wanted
to be a doctor.
You know where
a migraine comes from?
I ain't that hep,
Lieutenant.
It comes from being scared
too many times
and wanting to run away...
and not running away.
I got it.
What do the doctors say?
I haven't told them.
I'm not going to.
I want you to see
that I'm supplied
with enough of these
to keep me going.
If the lieutenant will
excuse the expression,
the lieutenant
is a 5-star fool.
You have a chance to
go back to the states,
don't you want to live?
The gentleman on
the middle aisle says no.
Oh...
that's
no explanation.
What about
the future?
your teaching?
Heh.
Yeah, I used to get
a bang standing up there,
pretending to know
all the answers.
But now?
Teach high school boys
the bright new world
of science after this?
Oh, Doc, you can have
the future for peanuts.
Listen, if you think
the future--
I had 44 men
in my platoon
when I started out
on the Canal.
Now I've got
37 replacements.
I believe in nothing
but the survivors.
Listen,
about the future, you--
Pigeon Lane, Slattery,
Pretty Boy, Coffman,
Conroy, Zelenko,
and you,
you're all I've got left
in the world.
I want to stay out here
till I'm dead...
or till we're all dead.
Now, how about
these painkillers?
It ain't gonna
help you very much.
They're only temporary.
Ha, so am I.
Listen, about this
psychological migraine,
I know
that it's something
you've got to
beat down by yourself
without medicine.
Yes or no, Doc?
If you don't solve
your own problems,
you're gonna be like
a full-grown man
hangin' on to your
mama's apron strings.
Yes or no?
Is that an order?
No.
Okay, I'll do it.
Thanks.
Yeah, but you're wrong
about the future.
Well, I was a farmer.
If we didn't believe
in the future,
we'd never grow wheat
to make the bread.
Oh, beat it, Doc.
I'm tired.
Oh, sorry. I--
So long.
Oh, hello, Doc.
What's the matter,
you sick?
No, I came to see
the lieutenant.
Anderson: Hi, Coffman.
Come on in.
Coffman: Lieutenant, I--
I brought you a book.
Oh, thanks.
Thanks very much.
Uh, Lieutenant, I--
I just dropped by
to thank you.
For what?
For pullin' me out of
the drink at Tarawa.
I pulled no one out
of the drink at Tarawa.
[Buzz]
But, Lieutenant,
they told me that you--
Forget it, Coffman,
in this war,
everybody's
a lifesaver.
But, Lieutenant,
a man saves your life,
it's only decent
to thank him.
Forget it.
What is this,
a clambake?
The old witch, huh?
Heh.
I see
the lieutenant's
been complaining
about me again.
Oh, no.
No, no, no.
He spoke
very highly of you.
You're a liar. Oh!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh.
What's the matter,
Doc?
You nervous?
You dropped your pipe.
Oh, thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Doc: did I do
the right thing?
Shouldn't I have told
the doctors?
How can he go on
fighting this war
with his head in a vise?
I feed him the pills, and
he keeps gettin' the pain.
Doc!
Yes, sir!
Yes, sir?
Check the men's packs?
Yes, sir.
Okay, that's all.
We're approaching
the line of departure.
Get down!
Pansy baker!
This is pansy baker 2.
Over.
Our naval gunfire's
comin' in okay.
There isn't
a Jap home today.
[Speaking Japanese ]
We're on the beach.
No resistance.
Moving up to the ridge.
Over and out.
We're moving up!
Let's get to that ridge!
Let's go!
[Speaking Japanese]
Ute!
Coffman,
get me the C.P.
Pansy baker!
Get out of this hole!
Spread out!
You want me
to get killed?
Somebody's
got to get killed.
Zelenko said to stick
to you like plaster.
Joe, they got us pinned down
here at the ridge. Over.
Seaman:
What's in front of you? Over.
2 pillboxes, maybe
half dozen machine guns.
We need tanks.
Need 'em bad. Over and out.
About time you got here!
Hey!
Get behind those tanks!
Come on, come on, open up!
Spray the whole hill.
It's lousy with Nips!
My squad's dug in,
Lieutenant.
Everyone's
in position.
Okay, nobody gets
trigger-happy tonight...
and keep the gab down.
Yes, sir.
[Flare Gun Fires]
See anything?
What are you writing?
I'll show it to you
some other time.
If you can see to write,
your eyes are better
than mine.
Get up there.
[Flare Gun Fires]
Man, am I jittery.
See anything?
It's me, Anderson.
Do you see anything?
Everything...
nothing.
Anderson: We never had
that problem in chemistry.
You don't have to worry
about me anymore.
They can kill me,
but they can't eat me.
The rules of warfare,
you know.
Good.
Let me know if you
see anything, huh?
Japanese Soldier:
Down with marines!
How long is this
thing gonna last?
We've been here
all week already.
Pretty Boy: You're crazy.
It's only 3 days.
Monday, Tuesday...
Wednesday, and Thursday.
You're both wrong.
It's 4 days.
What difference--
4 days, a week?
If we only set long enough
so I can warm up my mash
and get the still goin'.
At night, when you can't
have a fire goin',
we stay put.
Ahh, the marines
never get a break.
Hey, what's the range
in your meat can there?
It depends.
See if you can get me
the flagship, will you?
Shall I ask
for the admiral?
No, the chef.
I want to give him
the recipe for this.
I cannot be selfish.
I must share it
with the navy.
Japanese Soldier:
Marines, you die!
Oh, you said it, pal.
You can't trust 'em.
What's the joke?
My bein' here.
Heh heh,
well, some joke.
Yes, it is.
I was fightin' in L.A.
In January 1 942...
and a marine colonel
asked me
if I'd put on
an exhibition for them.
So I did.
I was walking around camp,
the general comes up to me,
and he says, "" Hey, you know,
we can use a fighter like you
to teach our fellas
how to box.""
I said, "" Me?""
He said, ""Sure.""
He says, ""You can box,
get all the fighting you want.""
So I joined.
I haven't boxed since,
but...
boy, I got all the fighting
I want.
Japanese Soldier:
Down with the marines!
I wonder what he's got
against the marines?
Japanese Soldier:
Death to marines!
Why don't we go out
and get those monkeys?
Zelenko: You'd love
to get killed, maybe?
I'm just in a hurry
to get home, that's all.
What are they gonna do
when you get home,
give you a big parade?
Listen, my folks
is important people
in California.
I live my whole life
in a 2-story house
with 5 bathrooms.
You can only use
one at a time.
Japanese Soldier:
Down with marines!
Oh, I'd like to get
my hands on thatJap.
Stop bein'
such a hotshot.
Knock it off.
Pretty Boy: I ain't
gonna be a nobody.
They ain't gonna forget
Pretty Boy Duncanon.
Riley?
Riley. I want you
to go into town
and find your father.
How many times
I gotta tell you...
stop playing
with that pistol.
You'll kill me
with that someday.
I will, if you
don't stop nagging me.
You've never
been any good
since your mother died.
This letter come
for your father.
Get him. You'll find him
in a saloon somewhere.
Letter's from Hawaii.
Your sister
was married last week.
Okay. Okay for her.
To a Jap.
You're a liar!
A liar!
Read it yourself.
Ain't no one
in this family
ever been any good.
You keep your mouth
shut about this,
or they'll ride us
out of town
on a 2x4.
They can't. They won't.
I won't let 'em!
I ain't gonna
be a nobody.
Someday, I'm gonna be
the biggest man
around here.
I'll have my own gang.
They'll do whatever
I tell 'em.
Anybody dare talk
about me or my sister,
and they'll cut
his tongue out.
I gotta learn how
to do things smart.
Gotta learn.
Gotta learn with this.
Brother, did I learn.
Don't you say
I'm gonna be a nobody.
Don't you ever
say it again.
Man: Cut the gab,
will you?
Think you're big.
Get down!
I want my Luger!
Get my Luger!
Why don't you leave
the kid alone?
He gets on my nerves.
Big talk. Big wind.
He saved my life.
His life's
worth saving, too.
Pretends he's something
he's not.
I know that.
You all know that.
What you don't know
is why.
It's because
he hates what he is.
How you doing, kid?
Oh, look, now,
I didn't mean
to hit you like that,
but I can't
let you get killed.
I need you, Pretty Boy.
You're my manager.
I want my Luger.
I'll get it for you
in the morning, okay?
Oh, leave me alone.
Where are we going,
Slattery?
See that nice range
of juicy hills?
Well, what's so special
about them?
They've ordered us
to take them
before lunch.
Oh.
[Rockets Firing]
Let's go.
Get outta there.
Come on,
get outta there.
Move.
What are they
throwing at us?
Just get going,
that's all. Move it.
Move it, move it!
What is it,
Lieutenant?
Move it, that's all.
Move it!
Hurry up.
Get yourselves in here.
Lieutenant,
company passed word
for us to pull back
to the ridge and dig in.
Zelenko, pull your squad
back to the ridge
and dig in pronto.
Anderson:
get back of that ridge!
You don't need a special
invite for this one.
Whitney, move out!
Anderson:
come on. Take cover.
Doc.
How many got it?
Enough.
How many
of the old bunch?
None.
Come on. Come on, Doc.
Give me some.
I gave you some
this morning.
I've still got my
head on, haven't I?
Yeah, you got it,
but you won't--
I want to run like crazy,
and I'm still here.
Give 'em to me.
Don't worry about
the apron strings, Doc.
I told you
I'm not going home.
Lieutenant,
the company passed
the word down
for us to dig in.
The navy's gonna
plaster the hills
with everything
they've got.
We're convinced that's where
the rockets are coming from.
What's the matter, Doc?
Nothing's
the matter.
Dickerman asked
for this pencil.
Here,
give it to him.
Come on, scram!
Doc, let's have them.
Let's have them.
Here.
[Planes Fly Past]
There's the navy.
They'll wipe us out
before the navy gets it.
I gotta get the C.P.
You think this stuffll
really do the trick,
Lieutenant?
Oh, the Nips
don't have rockets.
They're just
kidding around.
If we don't get out of here,
we're gonna get ki--
Coffman?
Coffman!
Doc! Doc! It's Coffman!
I was
just talking to him.
I was just--
shut up.
Talking to him
a minute--
He kept
pestering everybody.
All he wanted to know
was who pulled him
out of the drink at Tarawa.
You should have told him,
Lieutenant.
You know how to work
that radio?
Yes, sir.
Then get back
and work it
and connect me
with the C.P.
Cover him up.
It's Coffman.
Give Whitney a hand,
will you?
[Crying]
Okay, okay.
I don't understand it.
I was talking to him just
a couple of minutes ago.
I was getting
to know him real well.
Give me his bayonet.
First dead pal, huh?
Well, you're now a member
of a great universal
fraternity.
Congratulations.
Pansy baker...
Pansy baker 2.
Come in. Come in.
So I pulled him
out of the drink.
I gave him--
I gave him
6 more months to live.
For what?
This is Andy!
Was it you who said the Nips
don't have any rockets?
All right, we learned
that the hard way.
Don't waste time saying
we should have known.
Question is,
where are the rockets?
Where?
Sir, if my memory
serves me right,
the rocket is
a high-angle fire weapon
designed primarily to fire
over mountains and ridges.
Therefore, my guess
is that the rockets
are located on the reverse
slopes of the hill.
Sergeant Dickerman,
for your private information,
I'm well aware of what
the rocket is designed for.
For hours we've been pounding
those reverse slopes
with everything we've got.
So far we haven't
touched them.
Why? Where are they?!
Does the colonel
have a theory?
I sent out a patrol
instructed to take prisoners.
They killed Nips
and no prisoners.
When are these men
going to understand
the importance
of liveJaps?
You can't teach men
to hate and kill, Colonel,
then suddenly
teach them not to kill.
We teach them
to follow orders.
Colonel, may I suggest
that with the right kind
of indoctrination--
Sergeant Dickerman,
you're what's known
as a combat
correspondent.
Yes, sir.
And since this is
your first combat,
I suggest you
correspond.
Don't worry yourself
about things
that don't concern you.
Sir, I'm concerned
about everything.
This war is as much
mine as yours.
We did get one Nip,
Colonel.
Charlie company found him
wandering around
about an hour ago.
What's the scoop on him?
I passed the word on
to regiment, sir,
and they said for us
to work him over.
SergeantJohnson's outside
questioning him now.
See what he's found out.
Now, rockets
or no rockets,
we've been ordered
to secure these hills.
It's 025 5 now.
We jump off at 1 200.
That's exactly 9 hours
and 5 minutes from now.
Any comments?
If we try to take
those hills, Colonel,
the whole battalion
will be wiped out.
Unless we find a way to
wipe out the rockets first.
The general made this
our baby,
and we're gonna see
that it's well-diapered,
or you--
He'll be right in,
sir.
Johnson.
Yes, sir.
Well, any resemblance
of your present attire
to a marine uniform is--
You're impossible!
Yes, sir.
The colonel knows
it's a mistake
to let war interfere
with one's personal comfort.
Get rid of that
cigarette holder.
The colonel knows it's
the only way I enjoy smoking.
What about the Nip?
The Nip was in a cave
cut off by our artillery
from his own forces,
bypassed by us.
Rather unpopular, I think.
Last night he tried to make
contact with his blokes,
but ran into
Charlie Company.
He says the men he left
behind--1 0 of them--
Have been commanded to hold on
and fight to the death,
but they're
pretty well gone now,
and he rather guesses they'll
be willing to surrender.
Where's the cave?
The approximate position--
may I, sir?--
Is-- Is here.
What about the rockets?
He knows nothing
about them,
but he thinks
maybe his friends do.
I've persuaded him
to guide a patrol for us.
What do you think, Mac?
Why, I rather think we
ought to take him up on it.
I didn't ask you.
Well, why not? I'm
an expert on theJapanese.
That's the only reason
you're not in the brig.
Well?
Sir, to me it don't
look kosher.
He's persuaded the Nip
to guide us to the cave,
but remember
what happened
1 2 August
on Guadalcanal.
Remember Colonel Goettge's
patrol?
He was informed someJaps
wanted to surrender, too.
So he went out
to bring them in.
25 marines
went with him.
Only 3 came back.
Colonel,
it's an ambush.
It's a dead certainty,
and I mean dead.
Joe?
Well, it's
a big risk.
What else is
there to do?
Frank?
Maybe we invest
6 men.
Maybe we save
600.
Lieutenant Butterfield?
In my opinion, sir,
they sent this Nip over
to suck us in.
The lieutenant
doesn't make sense.
Sergeant, you're
way off base.
Sergeant, this war isn't
gonna last forever, and--
It's a nice
thought, sir.
Colonel?
There may be an ambush.
I don't know.
But this Nip
isn't in on it.
He's tired,
and he's hungry,
and, well, he wants
to live and go home,
like the rest of us.
Stinkin' cold!
It'll take us
about 2, 2 1 /2 hours
to get in there.
Anybody got a match?
Sir, if there's
gonna be a patrol,
I'd like to--
Joe, you got some experienced
scouts in your company.
Yes, sir. That's why I
asked Lieutenant Anderson
to come over.
Anderson?
Well, it's
the same old question...
gambling
the lives of a few
against the lives
of many.
I want you to take out
a small patrol.
Use this Jap
as a guide,
and Johnson here'll
go along to interpret.
Hello.
Sir.
Now, I want prisoners.
You understand me?
No ""yes, buts...""
and ""howevers.""
Aye, sir.
McCreavy, bring
that Nip in here.
Can you fire
an M-1 ?
I shot expert, sir.
Take this writer
along with you.
He's pining to get
his head blown off.
I suppose
I'll be the villain
of your great
American war novel.
Well, sir--
Don't tell me.
Jump off
as soon as possible.
You've got 8 hours
and 5 5 minutes.
I'll lay a harassing fire
on the cave area.
Let me know when
you want it lifted.
Yes, sir. Uh...
do I have to take
the sergeant along?
Up to you.
Oh, take him along,
Lieutenant.
It isn't every patrol
that has its own
private historian.
Here's your Nip,
Anderson.
Shimpai shinai de.
Old Willie here
doesn't look
like a decoy,
now, does he?
[Rocket Approaching]
[Explosion]
[Cough]
Well, if that's
all, Colonel,
I'll be
seeing you.
That's all.
Okay,Johnson.
Iko!
Dickerman,
let's go.
Anderson.
Yes, sir?
Don't cut your corners
too sharp.
Good luck.
Thank you, sir.
And, uh...
I hope your cold
gets better.
Pansy baker. Pansy baker.
This is Andy. Over.
Ask Willie
where the cave is.
[Japanese]
Pansy baker,
this is Andy. Over.
We've reached the cave
area. Going in. Over.
He says it's up
ahead, Lieutenant,
around that bend.
Out.
Okay.
It's now 0530.
6 1 /2 hours to go.
Okay,Johnson...
we'll walk.
Let's walk.
Koko desu.
Yosi. Lieutenant.
This is
the place.
Okay.
Tell Willie
to call 'em out.
Minna dete kuru yo
ni ittenasai.
Ha.
Go on up
with him.
Willie: Oi!
- Okay.
- Oi!
[Willie Shouting In Japanese]
Tell 'em we've got
food and a doctor here.
We'll take
good care of'em.
[Speaking Japanese]
[Japanese]
Dete koi!
[Speaking Japanese]
Well, I guess I was
right about Willie.
Keep your eyes
on him.
Tabako mo shokudo
takusan aruzo.
Tell him
to shut up!
He's only offering them the
hospitality of the house.
Zelenko.
Come on!
My eyes...
[Cursing In Japanese]
[Return Fire]
Oh, my eyes.
[Sobbing]
My eyes!
Zelenko's hit.
One of'em's
still movin'!
I'll finish him!
Lieutenant!
Prisoners!
Remember?
Yeah, I know.
Lieutenant!
- [Machine Gun Fires]
- [Japanese Soldier Gasps]
Hold your fire!
Japanese soldier: Oi!
He says there
are 5 left.
Zembu heitai da.
All
enlisted men.
Utsu no shoko
no kangae da yo.
The ambush was
their officer's idea.
Ima kosan shitai ga,
dete kitara,
Korosu no ga
osoroshi kara.
They'd like
to surrender now,
but they're afraid
to come out.
They're sure
we'll kill 'em all.
Lieutenant,
let me go up there
and parley
with the fellows.
No!
Okay.
No prisoners then.
All right.
Go ahead.
Okay.
KeepJohnson covered.
He's gonna try
to talk them out.
That guy's
a screwball.
He's trying to
get himself killed.
Stand by!
Watakushi no namae
wa Johnson desu.
Omaye no tameni tabako to
mizu wa motte kita.
Soko ni nannin oru ka ne?
Gonin orimasu.
Anshin shiro kosan
shita no ho ga ii desho?
I'm going in!
Slattery,
where are you going?
I'm gonna pick up
that samurai sword.
Stay where you are.
Samurai swords are worth
a very pretty drop.
Tomare!
I've persuaded
3 out of 5 to come out.
[Gunshot]
Number 4 has decided to join
the 47 heavenly warriors.
[Gunshot]
So has number 5,
and there's a wounded
officer down here
who wants some help.
Iko.
Keep 'em covered.
If you just keep pointing me
in the right direction,
I'll be able to make it--
Sit down
and stay down.
Good boy.
Doc, come with me.
I want you to check
that wounded Nip,
see if we can
get him back alive.
Dickerman, watch Zelenko.
Lane, you and Slattery
frisk the Nips for grenades.
On the double.
We want to
get out of here quick.
Good goin',Johnson.
See that the men
search 'em, will ya?
Yes, sir.
Please, tobacco,
give me.
Oh, no tobacco,
Always treat a human being
like a human being, old pal.
You'll be surprised
what happens.
What do you
think, Doc?
We don't
have much time.
I don't know.
I speak
English.
My name is Captain
Ishio Makino.
It is my misfortune
that I'm still alive.
Well, that's
all right, Captain.
We don't mind.
You understand
you'll be
treated decently?
I wish only to die.
I know you do,
but first
we'd like to ask you
a few questions.
I only know
that I've--
I have disgraced
my family.
To them I'm now dead.
Now look, Captain,
you're
an educated man.
I was never educated
to become a prisoner,
and I will speak
to you no more.
If I give him
some plasma,
I think
he can make it.
Well, we haven't
got the time.
[Artillery Fire]
[Explosion]
In the cave, quick!
Run those Nips
back up here!
Get him inside.
Look at that,
our own artillery.
What are they trying
to do, kill us?
Those areJap
90 mm mortars.
Probably got an observer
up on one
of those ridges.
Come on. Better give him
the plasma, Doc.
We're stuck here
for a while anyway.
How am I gonna see?
I want to take
a look around.
Oh.
Someone tell me
where we are now.
We're up
in the Nip cave.
Boy, we'll never
get out of here.
Omae no namae wa nanda?
Why don't you
spit in it, Doc?
Knock it off.
[Explosions]
Hey, where's
the lieutenant?
Johnson.
Talk to him, will ya?
The old duffer's scared.
The captain must have
talked the whole family
into ""hari-kiri,""
but this one was
too shell-shocked
to have gone
through with it.
Whitney.
Omae wa dare da?
Oh, you're right.
He's too frightened
to know anything.
Yeah.
Have Doc
take a look at him.
Well, we've got 5,
maybe 1 0 minutes
so start working
on the Nips.
If we get any dope
on the rockets,
we can radio back.
Oh. Here's a map
I took off the captain.
Okay.
Duncanon,
search the dead.
Lane, you can
give him a hand.
I want all diaries
and maps.
Step on it. Let's go.
How's he doin'?
I don't know.
Whitney,
you set up here.
We're going to have to wait
till those mortars lift,
if they don't
take too long.
Picked up
your carbine
and your radio,
Lieutenant.
Mm-hmm.
And that's not all.
Now find a spot
where that radio will work...
without getting
your head blown off.
Johnson: Lieutenant,
I think I got something.
Slattery:
Pansy baker. Pansy baker.
What's up?
Take a look at this map.
Now, according
to Colonel Gilfillan,
the rockets are coming
from the general direction
of these hills.
Here's a sugar cane field
next to them.
Fukado.
This man was in
an infantry company
ticked off
to defend that field.
He didn't see any rockets,
but he did see a couple
of hundred coolie carts,
and they all had
grooved wheels.
So what?
Coolie carts seldom have
grooved wheels.
What does that suggest
to you, Lieutenant?
I don't know.
A railroad, I suppose.
Well, what would a railroad
be doing in this wilderness?
Look, if you've got
any ideas, spill them.
We've no time
for guessing games.
Well, it could be a railroad
carrying rocket shells.
Mm-hmm...
or sugar cane.
Slattery: I've got
the company, Lieutenant.
Hold them.
All right.
See if you can get
some confirmation
on your wacky idea
while I pass
the word on.
This is Andy.
Find target area 2-7-4,
Love and Mike.
West of hills.
Sugar cane field.
Oi, honto
no koto ie.
Tobacco, sir.
I tell very good truth
for tobacco.
Oh, you speak
English, huh?
Oh, very good English,
sir.
You see, before war,
I am Tokyo guide
for American.
I am called Romeo.
I buy everything
for Americans:
kimono, painting, girl.
I am very good man.
Well, Romeo,
how long have you
been on this island?
Maybe a year
before you come.
What's your work?
I tell truth.
I am truck driver.
This is a big
sugar cane field here.
Did you ever truck
things up there?
What things?
Maybe I have tobacco
for later, huh, sir?
Yeah.
A whole pack.
Oh, I be very good
to American.
I buy kimono,
painting--
Yeah. What did you
carry in the trucks?
Concrete.
Small rail. Big rail.
Little rail.
Little engine also.
What did they do
with them?
I no know.
The mortars have lifted.
Let's get out of here,
on the double.
Slattery, take the point.
Whitney, you cover
the left flank.
Dickerman,
stick with Zelenko.
Doc, you nursemaid grandpa.
Conroy, go with Slattery.
Lane, you bring up
the rear.
Duncanon, you cover
the right flank.
Johnson, get those
Nips of yours
to make a litter
for the officer.
- Hurry it up.
- What did they say
about the sugar cane field,
Lieutenant?
Wrong spot.
They say they've
blasted that field
from beer
to breakfast.
The rockets
are still coming in.
Okay.
We'll start back
on a first leg
of 67 degrees
till we hit
Susana Creek.
6 hours left.
We got to get back
in 3.
Where you going?
I forgot my sword
and pistol.
There's no time
for souvenirs.
You've got your orders.
Get going!
Yes, sir.
All right,
let's walk.
Would have brought
a pretty drop.
This looks like
the best place to cross.
Conroy,
you get over first.
Look around.
We'll cover you.
Slattery, you get the B.A.R.s
into position.
Have the rest stand fast.
Hurry it up.
Conroy's going across.
Cover him.
Hold fast.
Conroy's going across.
Cover him.
Hold fast.
Okay, now.
You're rear guard...
and don't cross
till I signal.
Anderson:
hold it up.
Hold it up.
Anderson:
Snipers! Take cover!
All right, into that gully.
Let's go!
Lane. Lane, you stay here
with the prisoners.
Doc, Dickerman,
up on the road.
Keep your eye out
for the flank.
The rest of us'll get after
those snipers. Let's go.
Zelenko, you nuts?
Lane, watch Zelenko.
Keep him with you.
Aah!
Hyah!
Water.
Water,
please.
Water.
Give him some water,
Pidge.
Fresh out.
Well,
go get him some.
Who is it?
Pidge?
They all gotta die.
Pretty Boy,
are you nuts?
After all we've
gone through
to get
these prisoners?
They all gotta die!
Get back. Pidge!
Okay, Tojo.
You're first!
No, Pretty Boy.
Don't make me
shoot you.
Pidge!
Bugs and lice!
They'll save the lives
of our own men, you fool!
Pidge!
They all gotta die!
What are you trying
to do, Pretty Boy?
He wants to kill
the prisoners, Pidge.
Oh, don't, Pretty Boy.
Don't.
I can't let you
do that.
They stink.
They crawl.
They all
gotta die.
Now, don't do it,
Pretty Boy.
I don't like them
any more than you do,
but we've got
to follow orders.
Come on.
Drop your gun.
Sit down over there.
What'd you do,
you crazy punk?
What'd you do?
You dope! Why did you
pull the rifle?
Pretty Boy.
Kill 'em for me,
will ya?
Doc!
They ain't gonna
drive me out of town.
I'll-- I'll cut
their tongues out.
I didn't mean it,
Pretty Boy.
You--you pulled
the rifle.
It-it-it
was an accident.
Kill them for me,
Pidge.
You're my friend.
I-I'm a big shot
in my town.
Don't you forget it.
You shouldn't have
pulled the rifle!
Pidge.
I don't want to die.
Come on, men.
Hurry it up.
Conroy, you and Whitney
pull in Doc and that writer.
They're down on the road.
And snap it up. We're late.
Come on.
Who else got it?
I killed him.
What?
I murdered him.
No. He didn't do it,
Lieutenant.
I heard it.
Pretty Boy
blew his top.
He wanted to kill
the prisoners.
Pidge did it
in the line of duty.
I'm a murderer.
He pulled
my rifle.
All right! Shut up!
Is that the way
it happened?
Yes, sir.
Sir, he was just
a mixed-up kid. I...
I could've
straightened him out
if I'd only had
a little more time.
He was gonna be
my fight manager.
For a bunch
of crummyJaps.
Take it easy.
I liked Pretty Boy, too,
but he disobeyed orders.
It happens sometimes.
Not often,
but it happens.
Slattery,
you and Johnson bury him.
I'm sorry to hurry, Lane,
but we gotta get
out of here fast.
I'll bury him myself.
You won't lose any time,
Lieutenant.
Doc: Now I can go back
to being a farmer.
Dickerman:
sure you can.
Fine corpsman I am.
Hey, I-I ain't
supposed to be
on the receiving end.
Take it easy,
Doc. Don't talk.
You like Anderson?
Yeah.
I've known him
from the beginning.
He is the best.
I'll take your
word for it,
but relax now,
will ya?
Okay. I'm okay.
Men like Anderson
gotta live and go home,
tell them what it's like.
Please, Doc, huh?
I am a corpsman, right?
Right. Then I know
my condition.
Well, will you talk
to him about it,
sometime?
You speak his language,
being a writer.
Sure. Yeah.
I...
I put down on paper
something I've been trying
to tell the lieutenant.
It ain't finished,
but will you
take a look at it?
Maybe fix it up?
You know what I mean.
Being a writer, you know.
Okay, but pipe down
now, huh?
Pipe.
It's Doc.
How bad is it?
He'll be okay, I think.
Hold it.
Doc, what are you
trying to pull?
You can't--
Dead?
Yeah. Why not?
Bury him quick.
We gotta get out
of here fast.
What happened?
Will someone tell me
what happened?
It's poor old Doc.
What's the matter
with you guys?
Get on with it!
We gotta walk.
Someone get the dead men's
personal effects.
Someone take a compass
reading of this place.
We'll have to notify
the graves registration.
And someone take
their weapons and ammo.
My patrol has just been
reported in, sir.
[Explosions]
Yes, Colonel.
I know what time it is.
Aye, aye, sir.
[Explosions]
Between this stinking cold
and those stinking rockets,
I'm gonna end up
a mental case!
Well, where's that patrol?
It was reported in
1 0 minutes ago.
Anderson,
what's the scoop?
We got 4 prisoners
for you
and a shell-shocked
old man.
These are their
effects.
I lost 2 men.
One of them
was a corpsman...
C.E. "" Doc"" Jones.
Anything
on the rockets?
No, sir.
We've bombed and shelled
every inch of those
reverse slopes,
and they're still
comin'.
McCreavy, start
interrogating thoseJaps.
And don't forget time, time,
time is the essence.
All we got
are 90 minutes.
All right, sir.
Paskowicz. Davis.
Colonel,
I'd like to get back
to my men
as soon as possible.
No. Work with Mac
and that fantasticJohnson.
You know the prisoners.
Yes, sir.Johnson's
already at work.
Anderson.
Yes, sir?
Thanks.
That was a good job.
Thank you, sir.
Johnson:
You must put your mind
on different thoughts,
captain.
When the war's over,
you can go back
and rebuild your country.
You've much to live for.
You'll live well.
Sergeant, you seem
to have forgotten
that for generations
my people think
not of living well
but of dying well.
Have you not studied
our philosophy,
military science,
our judo wrestling?
Do you not remember
that we always
take the obvious
and reverse it?
So, reverse
the role of life.
To us, it is death
that is desirable.
It is the source
of our strength.
Do not say to me
that I have
anything to live for.
And now, Sergeant,
I believe I know what
information you are seeking.
Will you help us?
Go... bring
commissioned officer.
Well,
I'm the expert here,
but this is no time
to stand on pride.
How's it going,
Johnson?
Oh, pretty good, sir.
Lieutenant,
the captain just told me
he's willing to talk...
but to an officer.
Good.
[Coughing]
Take care
of this mess.
The boys
are aiming better.
What's happened
to him?
He's committed hara-kiri.
And with your knife,
SergeantJohnson.
I thought I'd lost it.
It never occurred to me
someone had taken it.
Makino:
Sir, is custom to finish hara-kiri
with gun. Please.
Sorry. The situation
doesn't allow
for peacetime
customs.
Get a corpsman.
I'm afraid
it's too late.
He's dead.
Take his body outside.
Your negligence
cost us a prisoner.
Take it easy, Mac.
It could have happened
to any one of us.
Forget it.
Lieutenant.
Yeah.
I have Pretty Boy's and
Doc's personal effects here.
What should I do
with them?
Go through them.
Hey, uh, put this on
for me, will you?
Sure.
Well, I guess
it's up to us
to pay off
this stinkin' business.
You're the big brain.
What do we do first?
Well, let's start
working on Romeo.
He's one of those
know-it-all types
that if we flatter
the wig off him,
he'll chatter
like a gooney bird
at mating time.
Okay. Here,
I'll finish it.
Say, Lieutenant.
Yeah?
What do I do
about this stuff?
What's that?
Doc's and Pretty Boy's--
Oh. Oh, yeah.
Well, check it
and see if there's anything
embarrassing to their families,
and we'll send it on.
Okay,Johnson.
Let's get rolling.
Nomura:
Watanabe, kiotsukero.
Romeo.
Yes, sir.
We're looking
for a man
who can handle
important matters.
Yes, sir. In Tokyo I buy--
One who can speak
English well.
Oh, make speak
greatly.
A man who'd be
in charge
of a big Japanese
prisoner of war camp.
I a good man.
Yeah. But we've
got to trust you,
understand?
Yes, sir. You trust me.
You see, if we can
trust you, we can--
Lieutenant,
I found something
in Pretty Boy's stuff
that I--
I told you what you're
supposed to do with it.
- Yes, sir, but--
- Later.
Lieutenant, you've got
to look at what I found.
Look, Dickerman, will you
please not interrupt?
Will you just take
a look at it, sir?
Hold it
till I get back.
Okay.
All right.
What've you got?
CallJohnson.
Dickerman:
Johnson.
Take over, will you?
This is a Jap overlay.
It shows one of their
positions in the hills.
What's this symbol
mean?
It means fire.
Where did you get this?
In this case. I found it
in Pretty Boy's stuff.
The question is,
did Pretty Boy
find it in the cave?
He might have had it
for months.
I'll find out.
Andy, the colonel sent me
to take over the interrogation,
but he said if you're
doing all right
just to keep going.
No, I'll stick with it.
All right.
[Rocket Whistling]
Ha. Need a torch
to keep them lit
out here.
Yeah, it is
from the cave.
Belonged
to his sergeant.
Okay. Butterfield, fit
this overlay to the map
I took off Makino,
will you?
That's a good idea,
but it'll take hours.
Well, give it a whirl
anyway, huh?
5 5 minutes to go.
Oh, yakky doc,
yakky doc.
Come on, baby.
Start pouring,
yakky doc.
Oh, give with that
first pretty drop, huh?
I ain't got all day.
Oh, sweetheart,
oh, make old Slattery
happy.
Come on, let's see some
of that angel juice.
[Incoming Rocket]
Andy...
Don't be scared.
I'm not frightened.
You know it, Andy.
[Panting]
It doesn't hurt me,
you know.
Boy,
that was close!
You don't count
the close ones.
Aw, come on, baby,
start pourin'!
That thing's
never gonna pour.
You've done everything
but sing to it.
Sitting
in O'Reilly's bar
Listening to the tales
of blood and thunder
Came a thought
into my mind
Why not love
O'Reilly's daughter?
Fiddly-I-e,
fiddly-I-o
Fiddly-I-e
for the one-eyed Reilly
Rub a dub dub,
kiss and hug
love on
I grabbed that sea witch
by the hair--
Corpsman!
I think I got it.
Andy.
Oh, where is he?
Get him for me,
will you, Pigeon?
He's gotta know.
Hope...
is the mother...
of all men.
We must...
hold... on
to that belief.
Andy!
It's too late,
Mac.
He got the count.
Come on, Bill.
What's holding you up?
Andy, all I got
on this overlay
is 3 little wiggles.
And there's 3 little wiggles
just like them on this map.
Mm-hmm.
Now all I got to do
is find them.
Would y'all
like to try it?
Okay. Go ahead.
Now if we only knew
where to start with it.
Forward slope,
reverse slope,
east flank,
west flank...
well, here's
where we were
when the rockets
first hit us.
The Nips probably
stuck them
on the reverse slope,
so try it in there, huh?
Reverse slope.
Check.
Man, what a job. I'll be
here the rest of the war.
Well,
just keep pushin'.
Johnson, you better get
back to friend Romeo.
Okay.
Come on, come on.
[Spanish Accent]
Lieutenant Anderson?
Yeah?
You got
an old Nip to go?
Yeah, he's in there.
First door.
Yes, sir.
Texas?
Yes.
How did you know?
How could I miss?
My uncle's got a big
business in El Paso.
Yeah. Well,
that explains it.
I come for
the old Nip.
Come on, old sport.
I'm gonna take you
to a nice, quiet place.
Hey, come on, pops.
I ain't got all day.
[Speaking Japanese]
Matsuoda-san.
[Both Speaking Japanese]
Get over there.
[To Himself]
Matsuoda-san.
Hold it, chum.
Lieutenant.
Did he get it?
No, sir.
Just knocked cold.
Lieutenant,
it's important
that we keep
the old man with us.
Okay. Take him
to the aid station.
Let me know as soon
as he comes around.
[Coughing]
What's the story
on it?
The old man
didn't want to be
taken away
from Nomura.
He begged him
to interfere.
Nomura kicked him
to shut him up.
Did he say anything
of value to us?
Yes, sir. He called
Nomura Matsuoda,
which must be
his real name.
Nomura is Matsuoda.
Ah, good for grandpa.
Okay, now let's get
acquainted with Matsuoda.
Let's first find out
from Romeo
why Matsuoda's
lying, sir.
Right.
Nomura!
Romeo...
who is this man?
Oh, yes, sir.
He is Nomura.
Private
in naval battalion,
like me.
What was his job?
He do many things.
Did he mix
cement?
Oh, yes.
Tell him to hold
out his hands.
Te o dase.
His hands are soft.
You're lying!
Now stand up
and tell us the truth!
Kiotsuke!
We know that his name
is Matsuoda.
Now, who is he?
He is officer.
He are a big man.
Very big
in allJapan.
Of course.
Big general maybe, huh?
Navy captain?
Air force colonel?
Oh, no. He are
a major in army.
But in Japan,
I know his name.
I make gamble
money on him.
He is big... very big
baseball player.
What team?
Meiji University.
But surely you're not
interested in baseball.
I am.
Come on,Johnson.
Let's go.
Oh, Lieutenant
Anderson.
Yeah.
We brought
the old man around.
Good. You get
back to him.
Yes, sir.
Talk to him.
I'll handle our major.
Right. But, Lieutenant,
if I may make a suggestion:
tear down his ego. He's
rolling in pride and vanity.
Okay.
Meiji University
teaches engineering,
doesn't it?
Japanese universities
teach everything.
What kind of
an engineer are you?
Railroad.
I have 3 university
degrees.
Uh-huh. And in spite
of your 3 university
degrees,
your rank and your name,
you're a coward.
You hide
in a private's uniform.
Lieutenant,
you're a fool.
All right.
What's your story?
You'll know the story
when you see
the number of dead you have
through my efforts.
You're a liar!
You probably got to be
a major because your
family had influence!
I became a major
because I planned a big--
Lieutenant...
you seem to know
Japanese psychology.
But I'm smart, too.
I know you know.
I say no more.
The rule of war states
I give only my name and rank.
Major Kenji Matsuoda.
No more.
This is important,
Lieutenant.
Dickerman, tell the colonel
we stumbled onto something.
One of the Nip privates
is a major. Hurry it up.
Yes, sir.
What did you
find out?
The old man told me that
Matsuoda lived with him
and his son a year ago
on their plantation.
He treated them well,
but after a while
he moved them out, and
the army built a tunnel
from the house
for wolf-tails.
What are wolf-tails?
Rockets. Lieutenant,
don't you remember
what I said to you in the
cave about grooved wheels?
They're using that tunnel
to transport rockets.
Yeah, you're right.
That's why we couldn't
see the rail line from the air.
Where's the house?
He said it's on
a sugar plantation.
Wait a minute. There was
that sugar cane field
you found
on Captain Makino's map.
That's right.
Where are they? Let me
take a look at this, Bill.
Let's see.
There it is,
and there's the house.
But how can we be sure
it's his house?
He says that when he stands
in front of his house,
there's water on his left.
Here we are...water.
It's a lake.
It's in front of and to one
side of the ranch house.
And on the right
some hills and woods.
Here we are. Hills
and woods to the right.
And he says that in front
of his house there's a hill
some distance away with a road
on the other side.
There's the hill.
There's the road. Right.
Bill, those rockets
are somewhere near
that ranch house.
Now work the overlay
around there, quick!
Right.
Boy, this climate is sure
death on a man's pleasures.
All right, Anderson.
Let's have a look at that Nip.
It's no use, Colonel.
I've been at him.
He won't talk.
What have we got
here?
Found a Jap overlay.
If we match it right,
the rockets'll
be pinpointed.
That'll take all day.
We've got 45 minutes.
Will you wipe
my forehead?
Wasn't there
a General Sherman or somebody
who once made
a vulgar comment on war?
Yeah. He said ""war is hell.""
And what did he know about it?
That eight-ball
never left the states.
Colonel, if we don't
get it in time,
can't we postpone
h-hour?
With 20,000 men
jumping off in 41 minutes?
Anderson, I want
a crack at that Nip.
- Get him out here.
- Aye, sir.
Butterfield:
still not
gettin'
anywhere.
You're doing your best.
Stay with it.
[Coughing]
Major Matsuoda.
If you didn't want
to live,
you wouldn't be wearing
that disguise.
Now, you're gonna answer
my questions, Major Matsuoda.
You will not find
rockets.
They will fall on you
like rain.
You Americans do not learn
very good from Japan.
You should learn
to accept your fate
to die well.
We die well.
As Captain Makino said,
we all die well.
Wait a minute.
He's told us
something.
Die well...
while I was talking
to Captain Makino,
there was something
he said.
I wish I could remember
his exact words.
Dickerman,
you were there.
Yeah. I got it right here.
Where do you want me to start?
Where he talked
about judo.
"" Have you not studied
our philosophy,
""our military science,
our judo wrestling?
"" Do you not remember
that we always take the obvious
and reverse it, so we reverse
the role of life--""
That's right. They
reverse the obvious.
Don't you see,
theJaps thought
that we'd figure
they'd put the rockets
on the reverse slope.
So instead,
they dug a tunnel
to the forward slope.
It's that easy.
Get him outta here.
Will it work?
I'll find out
in a hurry.
I've got it!
There are your
rockets, Colonel.
Seal the mouth of the tunnel
on the forward slope,
and there'll be
no more rockets.
Butterfield, get that stuff
over to my map.
Locate the exact position.
Get the air liaison officer
and find out what planes
he's got to shellack those hills
in the next 30 minutes.
Any planes at all-- Piper Cubs,
kiddy cars, slow boats to China.
The stinkin' time!
Dickerman. Anderson.
Yes, sir.
You people
have done...
Thanks.
Johnson, I told you
to get rid of that--
Yeah, I remember.
That's the only way
you enjoy smoking.
You see? Give him time.
He'll learn.
Try and contact
second platoon,
Baker Company.
Yes, sir.
Hey, uh,Johnson,
tell me something, will you?
Yeah.
How'd you ever get
to be a sergeant?
Oh, straight from
civilian life, sir.
Yeah, but how in the name
of green apples
did they ever pass you
through boot camp?
Pass me, sir?
I taught there.
[Coughing]
Maybe you got an in
with the angels, too.
So start prayin' those rockets
are stopped in time.
Good luck,
Lieutenant.
Right.
Good luck, Dickerman.
Good-bye.
Oh, by the way,
for your book...
it's, uh,
Randolph Johnson.
Second Platoon,
Baker Company ready, sir.
Okay. Thank you.
Lieutenant,
I'd like to go back
to your platoon with
you for a while.
Well, it's your book,
your neck. Hello, who's this?
Oh, Slattery, tell the men
we found the rockets.
Pass the word along they won't
have to start without me.
I'll be right there.
Let's go.
Yes, sir.
Why do you writers
take such chances?
You could hang around
the officers' bars
and pick up the greatest
stories of the war.
I got something that
Doc asked me to show--
Lay off.
I don't want to talk
about Doc.
Lieutenant, I--
Did you and Conroy
take care of Zelenko?
Yes, sir. They're going to fly
him out tonight. But, sir--
Okay. I want you to take
his place.
From now on,
you're a squad leader.
And you will be as long
as you stay sober.
Yes, sir.
You take over the squad.
Conroy'll be your assistant.
You'll have to get me
another assistant.
Why, what's the matter?
Don't you like con--
What's the matter?
What is it?
All the way, Lieutenant.
It's Conroy.
Conroy?
[Whispers]
That hit him
6 feet deep.
I'll talk to him.
Aw, let him alone.
Lieutenant?
Beat it.
I have a paper
addressed to you, sir.
Tear it up.
It's from Doc.
Yeah, Doc.
I told Doc I believed
in nothing but 7 guys.
Now one's blind.
4 are dead.
And the rest of us
are gonna get it, too.
TheJaps have got
the right idea...
kill yourself.
His last words
to me were...
""I put down on paper
something I've been
""trying to tell
the lieutenant.
""It ain't finished, but
will you take a look at it?
Maybe fix it up?
I mean, being a writer...""
I tried. It didn't
need any fixing.
Tear it up.
I don't want to hear it.
Well, you're
gonna hear it
whether you want to
or not, Lieutenant.
From pharmacist's mate
second class
C.E "" Doc"" Jones
to Lieutenant Anderson.
Sir...
I ask the lieutenant's
permission
to read this to the men
of our platoon.
Doc wrote this.
Wanted you men to hear it.
""We all ask ourselves
the question
""why it is that some of us
are killed while others remain.
""The only answer is our faith
""in the wisdom
of the supreme being.
""If he has chosen us to live,
there must be a reason.
""I've tried to reckon out why.
"" Perhaps he has saved us because
we are needed as witnesses
""to remind each other
and our folks
""and folks everywhere
""that war is too full of horror
for human beings.
"" Let us never forget that
some of what we went through
""and our losses came
because our country was weak.
"" Now we are part of the world,
and the world is part of us.
""If any part suffers,
all suffer.
""If any part loses freedom,
all will lose it.
""We, the survivors
of the Second Marine Platoon,
""Company B, First Battalion,
hereby swear
""that if any of us
return home,
""we will not forget what we saw
and what we suffered.
""We must keep
our country strong,
""courageous,
and wise in spirit
""and be unafraid
in the knowledge
""that we are on God's side.
We must...""
he never finished it.
Our Father
who art in heaven...
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done,
on Earth as it is
in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread
and forgive us our debts
as we forgive our debtors.
Lead us not
into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For Thine is the kingdom,
and the power
and the glory forever.
- We're movin' out!
- Amen.
2 minutes to go!
They'll never be
stopped in time.
[Rockets Whistling]
What good
was the patrol?
Doc, Pretty Boy?
What for?
They got 'em, Lieutenant!
They got the rockets!
That's right.
Hey, we did it, Lieutenant!
We did it!
Come on, men!
Give 'em hell!
[Men Yelling]
From the Halls
of Montezuma
To the shores of Tripoli
We fight our country's
battles
On the land
as on the sea
Admiration of a nation
We're the finest ever seen
And we glory in the title
Of United States Marines
The United States Marines