The latest ceasefire came too late
to save these villages...
Today President Clinton voiced concerns
at the deteriorating situation in Sarajevo...
When people ask me, good listeners,
why do I hate all the Tutsi,
I say, "Read our history."
The Tutsi were collaborators
for the Belgian colonists.
They stole our Hutu land,
they whipped us.
Now they have come back,
these Tutsi rebels.
They are cockroaches.
They are murderers.
Rwanda is our Hutu land.
We are the majority.
They are a minority of traitors
and invaders.
We will squash the infestation.
We will wipe out the RPF rebels.
This is RTLM, Hutu Power Radio.
Stay alert.
Watch your neighbors.
- Mr. Rusesabagina, thank you.
- Good to see you, sir.
Thank you.
These are for you, sir.
They're fresh from Havana.
Wonderful. Next time you are there,
tell Fidel that I said hello.
Good to see you gentlemen.
That is a fine cigar, sir.
This is a Cohiba cigar.
- Each one is worth 10,000 francs.
- 10,000 francs?
Yes, yes. But it is worth
more to me than 10,000 francs.
What do you mean, sir?
If I give a businessman 10,000 francs,
what does that matter to him?
He is rich.
But if I give him a Cohiba cigar
straight from Havana, Cuba...
Hey, that is style, Dube.
Style.
Cohiba... a fantastic cigar.
The best, eh?
So, you're going to join us
at the rally today?
I will try my best, George,
but these days I have no time
for rallies and politics.
Politics is power, Paul.
Hutu power.
And money.
It's time for you
to join your people.
Thank you, George.
But time is also money.
I need six extra cases
of beer today,
along with the regular order.
- Business is good at the hotel.
- It is very good.
I'm always glad
to see you, Paul.
Put that back! Put that back!
That's not beer!
- You, clean this up.
- Yes, sir. Come on.
Paul, don't worry
about the Carlsberg.
I'll give you Heineken,
and I won't charge you extra.
Thank you.
A bargain buy from China...
ten cents each.
You know, I'll get at least fifty.
At least.
George Rutaganda is a bad man.
I've heard him on the radio
telling the Hutus to kill all the Tutsis.
Rutaganda and his people,
they are fools, Dube.
Their time is soon over.
Anyway, this is business.
- Oh, no. It's the Interhamwe.
- Do as they say. Pull over.
No, no, sit up, Dube. Sit up.
Smile, Dube. Don't attract
attention to yourself.
Some of these men are my neighbors.
They know that I'm Tutsi.
Just smile as if
they are friends, Dube.
- I know this man!
- Are you a Tutsi?
What are you doing here?
No, no. Hutu power.
Hutu power, Hutu power!
Okay. Yes!
Get out of here.
There's water coming from the box.
Park here.
We'll go in the front.
Gregoire, please help with this water.
Gregoire!
Deal with this right away.
- We were hoping to go see the gorilla.
- You must contact our safari desk.
Dube, this is the lobby.
- What's going on?
- I am sorry, sir. It is an emergency.
Oh, shit! Oh, sorry, sir.
Ten alive, twelve are dead.
All right.
But save the shells.
Fill them with...
...a stuffing.
The good meat and something local.
- Cassava?
- And... the fish.
- And tipali.
- Yes.
We'll call it "fresh lobster
in a cassava and tipali crust."
Dube.
Style, sir.
Yes, sir.
The problem is, General Bizimungu,
I have information
that the Interhamwe militia
will not heed the peace agreement.
Colonel, the U.N. Need not worry
about the Interhamwe.
We will control them.
- General.
- Paul.
This scotch is exceptional.
It is our most popular single malt.
I knew you'd like it.
Colonel Oliver,
it is a pleasure to see you, sir.
Good to see you, Paul.
General, let me recommend
the lobster for lunch today.
It is spectacular...
straight off the plane.
Fresh lobster in Kigali.
You do us proud, Paul.
Thank you.
I left a little something for you
at the coat check.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
I need flour.
Give me two bags of flour.
Okay, the plates are ready.
Here they come.
Good afternoon, ladies.
Elizabeth, please put these
in the general's briefcase.
Yes, sir.
This is RTLM, Hutu Power Radio.
I have a message for our president.
Beware. Do not trust
the Tutsi rebels.
Do not shake the hand
that will stab you.
They will treat you...
... reporting from Kigali, Rwanda,
where tensions are high
as the deadline for the U.N. -brokered
peace agreement approaches.
Hello, Mr. Paul.
Hello, Jeremiah.
Hello, sir.
- Good to see you, Paul.
- Odette.
See you soon.
So your brother
and the girls are here.
Yes.
One, two, three...
Oh, Carine!
Okay, Anais, let me see.
Your turn.
One, two, three...
Who is the winner?
Oh, it doesn't matter.
I have chocolates.
Who wants chocolates?
Hey, Papa, watch this.
Oh, my goodness. Well, here,
chocolates, chocolates. Who wants?
Say thank you to your Uncle Paul.
- Please, not before dinner.
- Not before dinner, Mama says.
- Thank you.
- Okay, okay.
Let's go in.
Things are very slow at the shop.
How are things at the hotel?
Very busy.
Many people visiting the gorillas.
A lot of foreign press arriving
for the peace acc...
- What?
- There are soldiers.
- Where?
- On the street.
I'll go see what's happening.
It's all right.
- We know you are Tutsi.
- Please, sir, this is my husband.
- He's just a gardener.
- He's been spying for the rebels.
- No, we do not know any rebels.
- You will come with us!
No, we are telling the truth.
We do not know any...
- What is it?
- Shut up!
Tatiana, go back in the house.
You must go back.
- You mustn't be out here.
- It's Victor.
No, Captain, you see...
It's not me. It's not me.
Captain, Captain.
Why are you taking him away?
Please, please.
- I know, I know, but it's not me.
- You Tutsi fuckers.
No! No!
We must do something.
- Do what?
- Call someone.
I'm not going. I'm not going.
No!
Get him in the truck. Now!
We must do something.
Please help him!
Oh, Victor!
Victor!
There is nothing we can do.
- You must stay the night, Thomas.
- Yes.
No!
Why would they arrest Victor?
He has no politics.
- He's a gardener.
- Who knows, Tatsi?
Who knows?
Someone who didn't like him
denounced him as a rebel spy.
Happens all the time now.
Maybe you could call
one of your contacts in the army.
It wouldn't help.
You could ask as a favor.
No, I could not.
Tatsi, all day long I work
to please this officer,
that diplomat, some tourist,
to store up favors
so if there is a time
when we need help,
I have powerful people
I can call upon.
But Victor was a good neighbor.
He is not family.
Family is all that matters.
Please, please,
leave these things to my good judgment.
This assignment is bullshit.
Come on. A few days in a nice hotel,
no one shooting at us?
Gentlemen, welcome
to the Mille Collines.
I am Paul Rusesabagina,
the house manager.
- How you doing?
- Nice to meet you.
Anything that you need,
please find me.
- Thank you.
- Certainly.
So, what is the actual difference
between a Hutu and a Tutsi?
According to the Belgian colonists,
the Tutsis are taller and more elegant.
It was the Belgians
that created the division.
How?
They picked people,
those with thinner noses, lighter skin.
They used to measure
the width of people's noses.
The Belgians used the Tutsis
to run the country.
Then when they left,
they left the power to the Hutus,
and of course the Hutus
took revenge
on the elite Tutsis
for years of repression.
Am I telling the truth, Paul?
Yes, unfortunately.
Please take this to the general.
Benedict is our finest journalist
in Kigali, an expert on the subject.
So what are you, Paul?
I am Hutu.
Gentlemen.
- More champagne?
- More champagne would be nice.
Excuse me, honey.
Can I ask you a personal question?
- Are you a Hutu or a Tutsi?
- I am Tutsi.
- And your friend? Tutsi?
- No, I am Hutu.
They could be twins.
Get the camera.
The general's going to give us an interview.
Okay.
I'm in room 22. I'd love
to finish up this conversation.
Senior U.N. Officers claim that
the Rwandan army is secretly training
and arming the Hutu militia
called the Interhamwe.
I put this claim to the head
of the armed forces, General Bizimungu.
No. No, we have not been
training the militia.
The U.N. Are mistaken
in this accusation.
Do you support your president's
agreement to make peace with the rebels?
The president has
the full support of the army.
That peace agreement will
be signed today in Tanzania
between Tutsi rebel forces
and President Habyarimana.
This is a great day for Rwanda
and for all of Africa.
Negotiation has replaced confrontation...
Paul, have a drink.
Friendship has replaced fear.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a live feed
to the signing
of the peace agreement.
To our president.
May he find peace.
May we all find peace.
Let us all dedicate ourselves
to nurturing this hard-earned accord.
To peace!
Peace!
- Look me up if you come over.
- Yes, it is a beautiful city.
I am planning on returning there as...
Forgive me.
- Thank you. Bye.
- Thomas.
- Hello, Fedens.
- Paul.
Well, this is a surprise.
Forgive us, Paul.
We must talk.
Yes, what's wrong?
I have it from a very
reliable source, Paul.
Who?
Thank you, Sullivan.
My assistant,
the Hutu Power man.
He says that we must get out now,
that soon it'll be very bad.
Give me this man's name.
Please, Paul, even though
he is Interhamwe, he's a friend.
He wants your job, Thomas.
He said that
there is a signal.
It is "Cut the tall trees."
And when they hear this signal,
the militia are to go to war.
Paul, please, let us
take Tatiana with us.
You are Hutu.
You will be safe.
Fedens, I know you
have heard many things.
And I know
what we have seen, Thomas.
But please, the United Nations
are here now.
The world press are watching.
The peace has been signed.
Let this process work...
What was that?
Power cuts.
We are running on generators.
Fedens...
Please, don't worry.
Tomorrow you will come by the house
and we will discuss this with Tatiana.
All right?
- Good night, Paul.
- Yes. Kiss the girls for me.
Shit!
Stay in your houses.
Stay in your house.
Everybody stay in your house!
Tatiana?
- Paul!
- Tatiana!
- What is going on here?
- Our house has been burned.
- Didn't you hear the news?
- What news?
They are saying President Habyarimana
has been murdered.
Tutsi rebels have killed him.
Nonsense. Why would the rebels kill
the president when he agreed to peace?
Everyone, please,
out of this room. Please.
Jean Baptiste, find them seats
in the other room.
Odette, please.
- Did you meet with Thomas and Fedens?
- Yes. I told them to go home.
- Go and call them, Tatsi.
- I've tried. Our phones, they do not work.
- Why do the neighbors run to us?
- You are the only Hutu they can trust.
You are a Tutsi.
They are scared, Paul.
I am scared.
These are probably rumors
started by agitators.
We must remain calm
for the children, Tatsi. We must.
Forgive me, Paul.
Elys says that Roger has gone.
Gone? Gone where?
- He was afraid for his friend Simon, Mama.
- Where has he gone, Elys?
He went next door.
Wait. Paul!
Tatiana, no. You have to
stay here with the children.
- Stay in the house. No!
- Please.
Paul, please, what is wrong?
Tell me, what is wrong?
- Oh, my son! Where are you hurt?
- Is he okay? Oh, my baby!
Talk to me.
Where are you hurt?
Paul?
Oh, Tatsi.
Odette, Odette!
Oh, no.
I'm okay.
Get his clothes off.
Tatsi, please get some water.
- He's hurt.
- Please, let's get his clothes off.
- He's covered in blood.
- Lay back, son.
He went next door
to the Chirangas.
Where is he hurt?
Look here, Odette, look here.
Stay still, Roger.
Keep him still, Paul.
- I can't find the wound.
- What happened to you?
- Tell your mother.
- Talk to me.
Tell your mother
what happened, Roger.
Roger, you're okay.
Do not worry, he is not cut.
He is not hurt.
This is not his blood, Paul.
You are not hurt.
My darling, it's okay.
It's okay.
You are safe.
Look at your mother.
Come here, Elys.
- Where did the blood come from?
- Please, please!
- You are safe.
- You are out, Roger.
You are safe, you are safe, Roger.
You are safe, Roger.
It's okay.
I love you so much.
I love you.
Oh, son.
Paul.
Listen to me, good people of Rwanda.
Terrible news...
- It is true.
- Horrible news...
Our great president
is murdered by the Tutsi cockroaches.
Oh, my God!
They tricked him to sign
their phony peace agreement.
Then they shot his plane
from the sky.
It is time to clear the brush,
good Hutus of Rwanda.
We must cut the tall trees.
Cut the tall trees now!
The soldiers are here!
- Let us go to work, loyal Hutus.
- No, no.
Everyone, stay calm.
Stay calm and be quiet.
Find these traitors.
Let none of them escape.
Split up.
Everybody out.
- You two, check the back.
- Go.
- You, go and find him.
- Yes, sir.
I better go have a word with them.
Go around the back.
Make sure no one comes out.
Yes, sir!
Who's in charge here?
You.
- Can I help you, sir?
- Everybody out! Out!
- Let me see your identity card.
- Grab your things. Go!
I am a good friend
of General Bizimungu.
Get out!
Get out of here!
Everybody, out!
Get out, get out!
You work at the Hotel Diplomat?
No, I work at the Mille Collines.
I used to work at the Diplomat.
We want to use that hotel.
All the room keys are in the safe.
You must open it.
Let's go.
- Paul!
- Sir, I cannot leave my family.
I must take them with me.
It is not safe here.
There are Tutsi spies everywhere.
I cannot take all these people.
No, no, sir,
you do not have to.
We have our car
and our van.
- Captain Kaliso, come on.
- Roger.
- Let's go!
- Come on. Hurry! Go around, go around.
We found him.
Let's go. Let's go!
- Can I go with you?
- Yes, of course, Jeremiah. Hurry.
Oh, Jesus, no!
Oh, it's Simon, Papa!
Don't look, don't look, don't look.
Don't look, Tatiana.
- The safe is in the manager's office.
- You two, go with him.
Look at this. Beer.
I've got them.
Get down, all of you!
Sir, sir. Here, I have them.
I have them. I've got them.
Traitor!
These are Tutsi cockroaches!
Let me explain, sir.
Please wait.
Shoot them.
Please, I don't use guns.
I don't.
It's easy.
Shoot them, or you die first.
Sir, what could I pay you
not to do this?
You wanna pay me?
Why not?
Look at them.
These are not rebels.
Soon they will be worthless to you.
Why not take some money for your work?
- How much?
- You name a price.
10,000 francs for each.
- Sir, I don't have that much.
- Okay.
Wait, wait! Here.
It's 1,000 U.S.
And here.
50,000 francs for my wife and children.
- Take them.
- Go, go, go.
Go, go, go.
- Have you any money?
- Nothing.
- Paul, don't let them die.
- Get in the van.
Sir, I have more money actually.
And let them give you something.
Some money, whatever they have.
All right?
Here you are.
Give me everything you have.
Here, Paul, it's all I have.
Here you are. See?
This is enough for one cockroach.
Pick one.
Sir...
I will give you 100,000 francs
for all of them.
- Give me it.
- I don't have it here.
At the Mille Collines
I can get it for you.
You'll run into the hotel
and hide behind the U.N.
Sir, I swear.
100,000 francs.
I will get you the money.
You keep them outside.
Please, sir. Please.
- Let's go.
- Okay. Everyone in the van.
Come on now. Hurry.
Go with my soldiers. And hurry back
if you want to keep these cockroaches.
The soldiers are here.
Where is the car?
There is nothing I can do.
Excuse me, sir! Please, could you...
Here's the money.
100,000 francs as promised.
Now please, let them go, sir.
Take the money.
We will get them later.
- You can go.
- Thank you.
Traitor.
Thank you, Paul.
Do you understand, Dube?
Because I can't wait for Paul.
- You must tell him when he comes...
- Here he is, sir.
Paul, I have to go.
The staff of Kivu Lodge have fled.
I have to close up there.
You are in charge now.
It's okay, it's okay.
There were no survivors in last night's
plane crash in Kigali, Rwanda.
Everyone, please move to the side.
Clear the door.
Come, Tatsi.
Andre, I need two suites.
- Paul, please, where is my passport?
- Yes, I understand.
- I need to get hold of my embassy.
- If you give me one moment, please.
- Odette, Jean Baptiste, take this room.
- What about our neighbors?
What will they do?
- Dube.
- Yes, sir?
Please... put these "guests"
in two staff rooms.
Right away, sir.
No, no, no. Please, it's old.
Have the fruit.
It's all right, Roger.
It's all right. We're here.
- Ah, Joseph.
- Your suit, sir.
This mess is unacceptable.
Call housekeeping, get them
up here right away. Thank you.
- I'm trying Thomas and Fedens.
- All right.
Operator, I need a line.
I need a line now. Please. Hello?
You did not reach them?
No. No answer.
It is a very tense situation,
and I just want to assure the families
of those who are there that we are
doing everything we possibly can
to try to ensure
the safety of our citizens there.
Can you at least tell us,
is the airport actually open?
We are calling the airport.
We are calling the embassy.
We are trying to get as much
information for you as we can.
- And yes, your passport, yes.
- And my passport.
Antoinette will take care
of this for you.
Dube, where is Gregoire?
Sir, he has moved
into the Presidential Suite.
Mr. Manager.
What do you think
you are doing, Gregoire?
Who is it?
It's okay, darling.
What do you want?
You had better get out of this room
and back downstairs right away.
- I don't have to listen to you anymore.
- Yes, you do.
I am in charge. Now get out
of this room right now.
Mr. Manager, do you notice
the smell of cockroaches?
If I were to leave this room,
I'm sure I could find it.
And I know people
who can cleanse it.
But maybe it doesn't bother you.
Why is that?
Are you used to the smell?
Well, not me.
I need a clean room
to escape it.
Please move into the hotel.
Everyone, keep moving.
My house has been burned.
I have nowhere to go.
Yes, I understand this, Your Honor.
But we are operating
at capacity as it is.
I can give you one room,
but you will have to share it. I'm sorry.
- There's no way we can share.
- I am sorry. Forgive me.
There are eight of us.
- Yes?
- Paul, I need your help.
Yes, Madame Archer.
They're Tutsi children
from the St. Francis orphanage.
Okay, come on, let's go.
- I have only one room.
- That'll do.
Come.
- Otto, please.
- Excuse me.
Corporal, take that lady's bag, please,
and quickly.
- Have to go get the rest of them.
- The rest of them?
There are another ten.
I'll be back soon.
Madame Archer.
I have a favor to ask of you.
My brother-in-law and his family,
they live near the St. Francis.
On O'Clare, 20.
Can you please get them
and bring them here to me?
- Sure.
- And I have a photo.
Please, keep moving!
- Thanks, Paul.
- Thank you.
Please move into the hotel!
Come on, kids, don't be afraid.
- Take them around the back.
- Everyone, keep moving!
Has he spoken to you yet?
No.
Is your face still hurting?
It's all right.
The neighbors asked me
to thank you for your kindness.
I shouldn't have brought them here.
The first thing they told me
when I received my appointment
was to never, never lower
the tone of the hotel.
"Maintain the Mille Collines' dignity
at all times, Paul."
Soon all of this will be over.
What if I lose my job, Tatsi?
Oh, my God!
- Where are you going?
- I'll be right back.
Take care of them.
How, sir?
Bathe them, feed them.
Put them to bed.
I will send you some help.
Okay, babies.
We have heard reports
of reprisal massacres.
Will the U.N. Intervene
to stop the bloodshed?
We're here as peacekeepers,
not as peacemakers.
My orders are
not to intervene.
- Excuse me.
- Thank you, Colonel.
Here. Over here.
Listen, I got us a car,
but we gotta move now.
We're not allowed
to do that, Jack.
David, the shit's going down outside
these walls. We gotta cover it.
We're not leaving the hotel grounds
unless we have an armored car.
- That's the ground rules.
- The ground rules?
Where do you think we are,
fucking Wimbledon?
We cover the story from here
until we get the proper vehicles, Jack.
Shoot some "B" roll of the refugees.
Let's go.
Colonel, I have no way
to protect these people.
And I have more refugees
than I have room for as it is.
I was given 20 orphans today
by the Red Cross.
This is not a refugee camp.
Can you not take them with you
to your facilities?
No, I can't do that, Paul.
I'm sorry.
I'm overwhelmed
at my refugee camp.
I'm under attack, constant attack.
As soon as we can stabilize
this situation, then I'll take 'em.
... and stop the Tutsi cockroaches
who try to run from justice.
The Tutsi cockroach judge
called Makesa is hiding at 4...
- ... Kabulla and his cockroaches...
- Turn that radio off.
Watch out for him. He...
And get back to work.
We have a hotel to run.
There's no work here anyway.
The boss has left.
I am your boss!
Sir, there's a call from the Mille Collines
in Rwanda on line one.
Yes? Who am I speaking to?
Yes, sir, Paul Rusesabagina,
the house manager.
I met you on your last visit here,
Mr. Tillens.
Ah, yes. Paul, I remember.
How are things there?
The situation is difficult, sir.
Some of our directors believe
we should close the Mille Collines
until this unrest is over.
I'm not sure about that, Paul.
What do you think?
Sir, that would be
very bad for our reputation.
The Mille Collines is an oasis of calm
for all our loyal customers.
What would they think
if Sabena deserted them now?
I assure you, the United Nations
have everything under control, sir.
Very well, Paul.
Very well.
But if this thing gets worse,
we must close.
If there is anything
I can do, please call.
Sir, yes, there is one thing I'm going
to be needing from you right away.
Let me tell you, it was an embarrassment
for me to have to ask for this.
Most of us in this room have known each
other and worked together for many years.
Is it really necessary
for me to get a letter from Belgium
for you to perform your duties?
In fact, forget this letter.
If you don't want to work for me and would
rather be out there, then leave now.
Please, everyone, back to work.
Paul, thank you for coming.
The air conditioner's on the blink. Is
there any way you can have a look at it?
- I'm just on a deadline.
- Certainly.
Fred, let me know when you
get the satellite feed. Thanks.
Mr. Fleming, I brought you
some tea as well, sir.
Thank you, Paul.
You're an oasis in the desert.
... the elements of
the government and army
are following the example of what
happened to the Americans in Somalia.
I think they intend to intimidate us,
try to attack us, and...
hope that the West
will pull all its troops out.
- Do you think they'll succeed?
- No, they won't.
The U.N.'s here to stay.
What about
the outbreak of violence
since the shooting down
of the president's plane?
What the hell
do you think you're doing?
I'm responsible
for the safety of this crew.
What is this?
- Where did you get this?
- Half a mile down the road.
Fred, it's David.
I've got incredible footage.
It's a massacre.
Dead bodies, machetes.
If I get this through right away,
can you make the evening news?
Yeah.
You have to lead with this.
I point at you, you do a shot.
And you'll get a total double
and see if all the drinking...
- Excuse me, Mr. Daglish.
- Hey, Paul.
Listen, sorry about earlier.
If I'd known you were in there,
I wouldn't have...
I am glad that you have shot this footage
and that the world will see it.
It is the only way we have
a chance that people might intervene.
Yeah, and if no one intervenes,
is it still a good thing to show?
How can they not intervene
when they witness such atrocities?
I think if people see this footage...
...they'll say, "Oh, my God,
that's horrible,"
and then go on
eating their dinners.
What the hell do I know?
Listen, you wanna just relax?
I have more work to do.
I thank you for your offer.
Please enjoy your evening,
Mr. Daglish.
- Help! Please help us! Please!
- Sir! Sir!
We've got trouble at the gate.
Can we have some
medical assistance here, please?
That group, come with me.
Move out of the area.
- Here, get up, get up.
- Right, fall back, everybody.
Benedict, what is happening?
They're killing everyone.
The lady...
The Interhamwe have surrounded
the whole town.
Come on!
Cover the road. Now.
Stand your ground.
Hold the line.
Do not shoot!
- Lieutenant, guard this gate.
- Yes, sir.
You two, take up positions
behind those sandbags.
They murdered my men.
I lost ten Belgian U.N. Soldiers.
They were protecting
the lady prime minister.
- She is dead?
- Yeah, she's dead.
The Europeans are putting together
an intervention force.
They'll be here in a few days.
I understand that, Colonel, but there is
simply no place for me to put all of them.
What can I do?
I'll put two more men on the gate,
two of my best lieutenants.
- All right.
I understand. Thank you.
Madame Archer.
Hello.
- We were expecting you five days ago.
- I'm sorry.
My brother and his family,
did you find them?
I made it to the house,
but it was empty.
- Empty?
- It had been ransacked.
As I left, an old woman,
she waved to me.
I went to the house. She has
the two little girls. They're safe.
Okay.
But...
My brother and his wife...
did the old lady know of them?
My brother is dead.
They would never leave their children.
Perhaps they could not make it
home, Tatiana. They are hiding.
Please, can you return
and bring the girls back here to us?
I can't. There are
Interhamwe roadblocks everywhere.
When I reached the orphanage...
...the Interhamwe were there.
They'd already started
killing children.
They made me watch.
There was one girl,
she had her little sister
wrapped on her back.
As they were about to chop her,
she cried out to me.
"Please don't let them kill me.
I promise I won't be Tutsi anymore."
Please, I can't.
They're targeting Tutsi children, Paul,
to wipe out the next generation.
I've nowhere to take
the orphans, Paul.
Don't worry. There will be
an intervention force coming soon.
We will get the orphans out then.
They're here!
They're here! We are safe!
Soldiers have arrived!
- Wow, look, it's the French!
- Yes!
Thank goodness!
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
Well done.
About time, gentlemen.
Thank you for saving our lives.
It's okay, Roger.
Jean Baptiste, our prayers
have been answered. Thank God.
Yes, finally!
See, it's okay.
We can do nothing
from our side.
Sweetheart, I told you
we'd be safe.
See? I told you. Yeah.
So, Colonel, what can I get for you?
Something strong.
- Scotch?
- Yeah.
Congratulations, Colonel.
You have performed a minor miracle.
- Congratulations, huh?
- Yes, sir.
You should spit in my face.
Excuse me, Colonel?
You're dirt.
We think you're dirt, Paul.
Who is "we"?
The West, all the superpowers,
everything you believe in, Paul.
They think you're dirt,
they think you're dung. You're worthless.
I'm afraid I don't understand
what you are saying, sir.
Come on, don't bullshit me, Paul.
You're the smartest man here.
You got them all eating
out of your hands.
You could own this freakin' hotel,
except for one thing...
you're black.
You're not even a nigger.
You're an African.
They're not gonna stay, Paul.
They're not gonna stop this slaughter.
Please.
Got it.
- Hello.
- Hello, Daddy.
Elys, take Diane in the other room.
What is it?
All the whites are leaving.
They are being evacuated.
But... what about us?
We have been abandoned.
But the soldiers
will stop the killers.
Listen. Listen to me, Tatsi. Listen.
I said all the whites are leaving...
the French, the Italians,
even the U.N. Belgian soldiers,
all of them!
Who is left?
I don't know.
Colonel Oliver said he has 300
U.N. Peacekeepers for the whole country.
The most he can spare
for the hotel are four men.
And they are not allowed to shoot.
I am a fool.
No. No, no.
They told me
I was one of them, and I...
Wine, chocolates, cigars, style...
I swallowed it.
I swallowed all of it.
And they handed me their shit.
I have no history.
I have no memory.
I'm a fool, Tatsi.
You are no fool.
I know who you are.
News Service Africa.
A United Nations source reports
that the U.S. And British representatives
on the Security Council
will lobby for the removal
of all U.N. Peacekeepers
from Rwanda.
Please, Jack.
Please don't go.
Wait, he's British.
Take out your passport.
Jack, please don't leave me.
Can we talk?
Just one second.
Please, Jack. Please.
They'll put me on the street.
They'll chop me.
Here. Now just take...
- Take this.
- No, no...
Just take the money.
Please, just take the money.
You must go. You must.
Please, they are waiting.
- Paul!
- They are waiting.
Paul.
He won't put you out.
Here, give her anything she wants.
- Anything. Just charge it.
- This is not necessary.
- They're gonna kill us here.
- Let him go.
We have to let him go.
Don't do that, please.
Jesus Christ, I'm so ashamed.
Wait! Wait!
Hold the buses!
Peter!
Thank you for being here.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
- No Rwandans.
- What?
Foreign nationals only.
Sorry, Father, those were the orders.
- But you can't leave the children behind.
- Sorry, Father, we have our orders.
- You can't leave them!
- We can do no more.
Father, it is of no use.
These men are not here...
They are not here to help us.
Please, there is nothing we can do.
Get your people on the bus.
I will take care of the others.
It is of no use, Father.
Please, hurry.
No, no, no.
No, no, no. No.
To the hotel.
Sir, please, don't touch the camera.
We have the right to film.
- No filming.
- Go to the hotel.
Go inside.
Go inside the hotel,
all of you.
Yes, you can stay, yes.
We will take care of you.
Go into the hotel.
No!
Go to the hotel.
Go inside. Go inside the hotel.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Sir.
- Come, Dube.
- Please, everyone inside.
- Please, people, let's go inside.
Out of the rain, please.
Come, sister, come.
Paul.
I want you to go.
Go where?
You take the children.
You go get the girls.
- Your card says Hutu...
- What are you saying?
Please, please.
You pay money at the roadblocks.
I want you to go.
No, Tatiana, no.
I will never leave you.
Oh, Tatsi.
Let us sleep, my wife.
Let us sleep.
Get up. Get up.
Get up, get up, get up.
- Are you the manager?
- Yes, sir. What's the matter?
Everyone must leave the hotel now.
- Why?
- Papa, what's wrong?
It's an order.
I need some time...
20, 30 minutes... to take a shower.
- Sir, people are still sleeping.
- I don't care.
Please, let me get you some beers.
You and your boys.
And I'll be down right away, all right?
As quick as I can.
- Ten minutes.
- Yes, sir, ten minutes.
- Get out of the way.
- Quick, children, quickly.
- Roger's not here.
- Where is he? Where's Roger?
Under the bed.
Roger. It's Papa.
They've gone.
They've gone, they've gone.
Come, come. Come on.
Oh, my darling.
It's okay, sweetie. It's okay.
Come on, it's okay. It's okay.
- Go to the roof, Tatiana.
- The roof?
Yes, yes,
go to the roof right now.
Yes, good day.
General Bizimungu, please.
He is where?
No, that is unacceptable.
Who would order such a thing?
Yes, did you find the general?
Gentlemen, please have some beer.
Get me the guest list.
Yes, sir.
Yes?
Sorry, sir, but I have a call
from Paul in Kigali. He says it's urgent.
Paul, are you all right?
We have a big problem, sir.
What?
The Hutu army have come.
They've ordered us...
all of us... out of the hotel.
Why are they doing this?
I think they will kill us all.
Kill?
What do you mean... all?
How many?
We have 100 staff
and now more than 800 guests.
- 800?!
- Yes, sir.
There are now 800 Tutsi
and Hutu refugees.
I do not have much time left, sir.
I want to thank you
for everything that you
have done for me and my family,
and please thank all
of my friends at Sabena.
Paul, wait.
I'm gonna put you on hold.
Stay by the phone.
- Where are your papers?
- We don't have any papers, sir.
We don't have any papers.
They got burnt in the house.
Louis, get on to the U.N.
Tell them what's happening.
Did you need something, sir?
Mary, call the prime minister's office.
Tell them I must speak with him now.
Okay.
Paul, are you there?
Yes, sir.
Who can I call to stop this?
The French.
They supply the Hutu army.
Do everything you can to buy time.
I'll call you right back.