[helicopter thwacking]
- [explosions]
- [incoming rockets]
[quietly] Move it! Move it!
- Hang on, Junior! Take it easy!
- Come on! Come on!
[men shouting]
Move it!
[men yelling indistinctly]
- Come on! Come on!
- [rapid gunfire nearby]
[man] Through here! Through here!
[men shouting]
[yelling]
[incoming rocket]
[shouting in foreign language]
Gotta cross this! Let's go!
[men shouting indistinctly]
[rapid gunfire]
[shouts in foreign language]
Let's go!
[incoming mortar]
- Keep it moving!
- [approaching helicopters]
Move it!
- Come on!
- [incoming mortar]
[shouting]
[gasping]
- Come on, soldier!
- [grunting]
[incoming rocket]
[rapid gunfire]
[screaming]
[yelling]
- [man] Choppers!
- [man 2] Quickly! Go!
[rapid gunfire]
[yelling]
- Let's go!
- [men shouting indistinctly]
Behind you!
Come on! Get in! Get in!
- Let's go! Let's get outta here!
- Go, go, go!
Wait!
[shouting]
- [man] Get in!
- [man 2] Oh, my God!
- Over here!
- [indistinct shouting]
[rapid gunfire continues]
Get up! Get up!
Let's go! Let's go!
Get your ass up in the air!
Get out the way, damn it!
All right, we're ready! Let's go!
Move it! Move it!
[gunfire continues]
[men screaming]
Come on! Keep going!
Move it!
[rapid gunfire]
- Hurry up, godammit!
- Give me your hand!
Take off! Take off! Go! Go! Go!
[shouting]
Move it!
Aah!
He won't try that shit again!
Griffin, get him out of here!
- [rapid gunfire]
- [grunting]
God...!
[Grunts]
[screaming]
[screaming continues]
[shouting]
[woman on TV] ...American servicemen
missing in action. Bill?
[male reporter] Thanks, Jane.
Preparations for a high-/eve/ meeting
with the Vietnamese continue today
as a senate delegation made ready
to leave for Ho Chi Minh City.
The primary purpose of the talks
is to determine whether or not
American servicemen are still being
held as prisoners of war in Vietnam.
In recent months, American veterans'
organizations have increased demands
for information regarding
some 2,500 American servicemen
who did not return home
from the war in Vietnam.
The fate of these Missing In Action
Americans still remains uncertain today.
Reported sightings of foreign
prisoners being held in Vietnam
have resulted in greater efforts to
resolve the MIA issue once and for all.
Senator Maxwell Porter, head
of the US delegation to Vietnam,
expressed guarded optimism
that talks would result
in shedding some light
on this unresolved issue.
But we're cautioned,
however, that progress
would probably
be slow and painstaking.
[man] You give off bad vibes, Shocker!
[dramatic music, effects on TV]
[man 2] Spider-Man, we meet again!
Sooner than I expected!
[Spider-Man] I love reunions!
[man] Here's one, Iceman!
Looks like I'll have to settle
with the wall-crawler
before I do anything else!
And I know just how I'm going to do it!
[Spider-Man] Leaving?
Was it something I said?
[man] Puny insect! My vibro-shock
power lets me vibrate out of any trap!
- The next reunion will be your last!
- [dramatic music, effects continue]
[chains rattling]
[chaotic chatter]
[indistinct shouting]
[shouting]
Over there!
Listen to me!
One of you for one of mine!
- [incoming bomb]
- [shouting]
- [rapid gunfire]
- [chaotic shouting]
[man] Shocker returns
with even more vibro-shock power!
[Spider-Man] Spider friends...
---Q0 for it!
Let's visit a maximum-security prison!
[alarm blaring on TV]
It's the Shocker! He's making a break!
[man] Spider-Man put me in that hole
and now I'm gonna get even!
[man on TV] As you may recall,
he masterminded an escape of Americans
from a Vietnamese prison camp and has
maintained that the camp in which
he was held was not
the only one in Vietnam.
Though he has never been able
to offer any proof of his allegations,
Braddock has been one of the most
outspoken proponents of the theory
that American prisoners are
still being held in Vietnam today.
Braddock has, however,
refused all recent offers
to speak to servicemen 's organizations
on the subject of MIAs
and has completely withdrawn
from any public discussion
of the MIA controversy.
The American delegation had hoped
that Braddock's presence at the talks
would increase their ability
to negotiate.
This is Braddock.
I'll go.
The Vietnamese government
will never buy it.
The people in these photos
could be damn near anybody.
Including American MIAs.
Now, listen, even our own experts agree
that that's only a 50-50 chance.
You can imagine
what their people are gonna say.
We're gonna need something
a hell of a lot stronger than that
if we're gonna make
an impression on 'em.
Isn't that why Colonel Braddock
is along? As irrefutable evidence?
Some piece of irrefutable evidence.
Just look at the way
the son of a bitch is dressed.
Who am I trying to impress, Senator?
[shouting command]
Senator Porter, I am General Tran.
Welcome to the
People's Republic of Vietnam.
It's a pleasure, General.
I'd like to introduce you to
Ann Fitzgerald, State Department.
- Miss Fitzgerald, welcome.
- Thank you.
Colonel James Braddock.
Ah, Colonel Braddock,
I've heard much about you.
Welcome to the
People's Republic of Vietnam.
Colonel!
Excuse me.
You're a goddamn embarrassment,
Braddock.
That's why I'm here, Senator.
Something I've been wondering.
What made you change your mind?
I mean, we must've asked you 20 times.
I've got my reasons.
[shouting in foreign language]
[grunting]
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
- So nice to have you with us.
- [reporters chattering]
Senator Porter, we all know that
Colonel Braddock was brought here
only in an attempt
to embarrass my government.
That's not true, General.
But I believe that once
the real reason
for his extended imprisonment
is revealed,
the world will take
quite a different view of him.
Miss Fitzgerald.
- [man] Colonel Braddock...
- [reporters chattering]
- General!
- Can we get through here?
- Excuse me, General, sir...
- [overlapping chatter]
[speaks foreign language]
[Tran speaks foreign language]
[woman] These people were eyewitnesses
to some of the war crimes
committed by Colonel Braddock
against the people of Vietnam.
[speaks foreign language]
[woman] Innocent women, children
and old men were his victims.
[speaks foreign language]
[woman] You have their sworn statements
in front of you.
[speaks foreign language]
[low chatter in foreign language]
What did he say?
He said he understands and it's OK.
Colonel Braddock...
is it not true that during the war
there was a price on your head
of 5,000 American dollars?
It was more like $20,000.
What?
Why don't you tell us
why there was a price on my head?
For your war crimes, of course.
- For killing assholes like you.
- [overlapping chatter]
- Colonel!
- [chaotic chatter]
[yells in foreign language]
The atrocities,
as documented in front of you,
were the real reasons
why Colonel Braddock was held here!
He was not a prisoner of war,
but a common criminal!
- [soft piano music plays]
- [low chatter]
Been
Thanks.
I see you've come up in the world.
You got out
of this country once, Colonel.
You might not be so lucky this time.
[sighing] Tran is up in arms about
your behavior this afternoon.
Porter called Washington
trying to get you recalled.
And the President is outraged...
publicly.
Ah, Miss Fitzgerald,
you look lovely tonight.
Uh, Colonel Braddock, there is a
question I've been wanting to ask you.
Is it true that you let
ten of your men die in prison
all because you alone refused
to admit your war crimes?
You are the most undiplomatic man
I have ever met.
I'm not running for office. Besides,
you don't know anything about me.
Oh. Well, let's see.
James Thomas Braddock, 38 years old.
Colonel in the Army Special Forces.
Retired.
Prisoner of war for eight months.
Missing in action for seven years,
escaping last year.
And you are now in Saigon
at the request of the President
to see if there are
any more Braddocks in Vietnam.
Like I said,
you don't know anything about me.
How about a nightcap?
Yeah, sure.
See you in a few minutes, huh?
[chuckles]
The champagne's getting warm.
Oh, yeah.
Been quite a day.
Yeah. It should be quite a night, too.
Now, look, Braddock, just because...
- Just what do you think you're doing?
- What does it look like?
[signing]
Would you mind?
I'm a little on the shy side.
I don't believe this.
Look, Braddock, I invited you up here
for a nightcap, not...
Jim!
What the hell is this?
I'm gonna take a look around Saigon.
See how it's changed since the war.
We are not supposed to leave
the hotel without an escort.
Jim, do you hear me?
I won't be gone long.
I'm supposed to be keeping you
out of trouble.
[sighing] Shit.
Braddock, don't.
How are you gonna
get out of here, anyway?
FIY-
[whispers] Bastard.
- [glass breaking]
- [laughter nearby]
[chattering in foreign language]
[speaking foreign language]
[chatter in foreign language]
[grunting]
[Grunts]
[gasping]
[whispering] Keep your eyes shut...
...and listen very carefully.
The answer you give me...
...will decide whether you live or die.
- And I'll know if you're lying
- [gasping]
Now, where are the American MIAs?
I don't know. [whimpering]
Don't do it!
There is a camp.
- Delta region.
- Where?
Dong Ha. Dong Ha.
Eight kilometers from the coast.
[grunts] No, don't! Don't! Spare me!
I gave you the information. I gave it.
That's all I know. Don't...
If you move...
...I'll kill you.
[grunting]
[gasping]
[men shouting in foreign language]
[shouting in foreign language]
[sirens wailing]
[chatter in foreign language]
[speaking foreign language]
[whispers in foreign language]
[woman weeping nearby]
[speaking foreign language]
[crackling]
[indistinct chatter below]
[shouting in foreign language]
[speaking foreign language]
I suppose he's been here
with you all night?
That's right.
How very convenient.
Yes, isn't it?
You...
You leave tomorrow...
...or you'll not leave at all.
I wish you didn't have to go.
Nothing I can do here.
Jim, why Bangkok?
I have to look up a friend.
An old army buddy.
[signing]
Be careful.
[chatter in foreign language]
[woman on PA] Flight 320 from Ho Chi
Minh City, arriving at Gate Six.
[woman on PA speaking foreign language]
Flight 210 to Singapore
now boarding at Gate Three.
[overlapping chatter]
[tires squealing]
[horn honking]
[dance music playing]
Do you need a nice girl, sir?
It's ten dollars.
It's awfully cheap.
[low chatter]
- Buy me a drink, handsome?
- Not tonight.
[speaks angrily in foreign language]
Do you speak English?
You bet.
- I'm looking for a friend.
- Isn't everybody?
He must be a good friend.
His name's Tucker. Jack Tucker.
I think... maybe I have heard of him.
- Where can I find him?
- What do you want him for?
Wrong answer.
He's probably at Madame Pearl's
whorehouse down the road.
Thanks.
Come back soon.
[starting engine]
Taxi! Taxi!
Patpong Road.
[gasping, choking]
[people screaming]
[choking]
[gasping]
Sam Song Hotel.
[dance music plays]
J' She sits alone waiting for suggestions
J' He's so nervous,
avoiding all the questions
J' His lips are dry...
- Where's Madame Pearl?
- She's over there.
J' If you want my body
and you think I'm sexy
J' Come on, honey, let it show
I'm looking for Jack Tucker.
Is he around?
He'll be here... in a moment.
[clattering]
- [music stops]
- Thanks.
How's it going, Tuck?
Braddock.
- What the hell are you doing here?
- I wanna rent your boat.
Oh, shit. We'd better talk later.
It's important. How much?
Five grand.
- Four grand!
- I didn't hear ya!
Two!
- Did you say one thousand?
- No.
Yeah, a thousand bucks.
That's what I thought you said.
Come on.
What the hell do you need
my boat for, anyway?
We're going back to Nam
to rescue some MIAs.
Oh, shit, Braddock. You're crazy.
[cackling]
You said "we."
You said "we're going back."
You owe me, Tuck. I need your help.
Yeah, I owe you.
More than once.
All right, you bastard.
I'll take you in.
But I'm not going ashore.
OK?
OK.
[chatter in foreign language]
Getting in is no problem.
I've been smuggling cigarettes
and booze for years.
My new Southern Belle's one of the
fastest boats in the water around here.
There she is.
What the hell is that?
Like my daddy always said,
don't believe everything you see.
Discourages pirates.
I'll show you something back here.
They're Detroit diesels.
Turbocharged, 650 horsepower.
We can hit 21 knots if we have to.
M-16s, grenades, C-4, LAW.
You're playing for keeps.
What the hell do you need
an assault raft for?
The camp's in the delta.
A raft is the easiest way in.
How come you never mention
getting out?
If we can hit the camp without raising
an alarm, we'll go back the way we came.
- That's nice. And if not?
- We'll think of something.
Great. Look, you wanna do me a favor?
Next time I ask you something
about the mission,
you don't tell me nothing, OK?
I'd rather not know.
- There is something else.
- What?
We could use a long-range chopper
as a backup.
Now how in hell are we supposed
to manage that?
We'll think of something.
[signing]
Gentlemen,
I can help you with everything,
even the M-16s, but not the raft.
Bullshit, Carlos.
We both know you got one.
Got one? Sure, I got one.
I got the only one in all Thailand.
But have you got the money?
That's the question.
Let's see the sucker first,
then we'll talk money.
There she is. Yang!
Quite a unique weapon, eh?
She can run 60 miles an hour,
and, with her mufflers on,
no one can hear you coming.
Yeah, too bad a single bullet'll
put her out of commission.
Yang.
It's Kevlar.
Very expensive.
Same material your bulletproof vests
are made out of.
It will stop anything,
short of a grenade.
How much?
Twenty thousand American dollars...
for the raft.
The rifles and ammunition...
...I throw in, free.
Five.
Don't be ridiculous.
There is nothing like her
in all of Southeast Asia.
- Seven.
- Seventeen!
Fifteen. No less.
Ten.
Deal.
- [dance music playing]
- So, if I get this helicopter of yours,
are you willing to pay?
I didn't figure it was free.
- OK, then. What about the marking? US?
- It doesn't matter.
Just make sure I can count on the pilot.
Look around, my friend.
In this place, you can count on
people doing anything for money.
[arguing in foreign language]
[arguing continues]
- [screaming]
- [grunting]
[grunting]
[yelling]
[people screaming]
[chaotic yelling, chatter]
[shouting in foreign language]
[all screaming]
[woman sobbing]
[shouting in foreign language]
[speaks foreign language]
[shouting, sobbing]
Braddock! Hey, hop in!
Come on, we're leaving early.
Get dressed.
AW... Shit.
[groaning]
[rapid gunfire]
[people screaming]
Mike, cast off!
[revving]
[squealing]
[rapid gunfire]
[speaking foreign language]
[boat engine starting]
[grunting]
[growling]
[Grunts]
[straining]
You shouldn't have hurt
those people in Bangkok.
[gasping] Fortunes of war.
Yeah.
[gasping]
[groaning]
Fortunes of war.
Well, there she is... Vietnam.
Pearl of the Orient.
If I'm not back in 12 hours,
get the hell outta here.
You're crazy, Braddock.
Maybe.
What happens if you have to fight
and navigate at the same time?
I'll figure something out.
You already have. You son of a bitch!
Goddammit! You knew there was no way
in hell I'd let you go in there alone
once we got here, didn't you?
Let's get one thing straight!
I'm only here to operate the damn raft!
That's it. Period!
I'm not getting outta
the goddamn thing for any reason!
Give us 14 hours!
If I don't make it back,
the Belle 's yours.
[gasping] Come on, Tuck.
No. You promised me
I wouldn't have to get off the raft.
What do we need that for, anyway?
We're coming back on the raft.
If we're lucky. If not, I don't think
our guys are gonna be in much condition
to swim out to the boat.
Tuck.
[men chattering in foreign language]
[chatter continues]
[grunting]
[calling out]
Aah! [yells]
[grunting]
Aah!
Sorry. Won't happen again.
- Do we run or fight?
- We don't have a choice now.
The camp is about one klick
north of here.
I'll go the rest of the way on foot.
Thanks for coming this far.
- Did I have a choice?
- Yeah, you did.
[hushed] Watch your ass!
[wire snapping]
[men speaking foreign language]
[men chattering]
[bugs chirping]
[faint chatter]
[chatter continues]
[buttons beeping]
[speaking foreign language]
[rapid gunfire]
[yelling]
Sergeant Dinh, Black Panther Rangers.
- You are after the Americans?
- Yeah. Where are they?
They moved less than three hours ago,
somewhere further inland.
Do you know which road they took?
There is only one road
that connects with Highway One.
It follows the river all the way.
- You are going after them?
- Yeah.
Thank you. Thank you.
[speaking foreign language]
[all chattering in foreign language]
[whispers] Tuck!
- Tuck!
- Braddock?
- Where's our people?
- They've been moved.
- Shit!
- Let's go!
[starting engine]
[shouting in foreign language]
There it is!
[yelling]
[all yelling]
[revving]
Aah!
[laughing]
Braddock?
Is it safe?
[sharp inhale]
[inhaling]
Holy Christ.
You guys are going home.
[panting] We're going home?
Damn right!
Give me your hand.
We're going home!
[Braddock] Come on!
Get to the Jeep!
Get in! Come on!
Get in!
OK, Braddock!
- How far to the coast?
- About six klicks.
Pray the boat's still there.
Take 'em to the river! I'll catch up.
[Tuck] Out you 90-
Keep it goin'!
[approaching vehicles]
[all yelling]
[shouting in foreign language]
Two klicks to the coast.
Can you make it?
We'll make it.
Come on!
Come on! Come on!
[Tuck] Come on! Move it!
Come on! The boat!
Keep moving there! Keep goin' now!
- [men shouting]
- [incoming mortar]
Keep moving! Come on!
[yelling]
[rapid gunfire]
Come on!
[incoming bomb]
Patrol boat!
[rapid gunfire]
Get back! Go back to the shore!
I'll see you in hell!
Tuck!
Take it down!
[grunting]
[rapid gunfire]
Aah!
Hurry up! [grunting]
[rapid gunfire]
- Where to?
- Saigon.
Oh, shit!
If I knew it would be like this,
I wouldn't rent you the helicopter
for a million bucks!
My government is extremely gratified
to be able to put this issue to rest,
once and for all.
[screaming, chaotic chatter]
In conclusion, then...
[indistinct shouting]
...we categorically deny...
[overlapping shouts]
...that there are any living MIAs
in the People's Republic of Vietnam.
[men shouting]
[yelling outside]
[overlapping shouts, chatter]
[inaudible dialogue]
[cheering, shouting]
English - US - SDH