[Man] Welcome to the
oven, aka Camp Carolina:
our home away from home
in this godforsaken country.
What I can't convey,
via this video journal
is the incredible heat
and the local smells.
Oh, my God, it stinks.
[chuckles]
Yo, Mustangs!
Yo!
On 3, give me a smile!
1, 2, 3!
[shutter clicks]
But let me introduce myself.
My name is Angel Salazar.
Private Salazar.
I'm that poor Latino filmmaker
that did not get into USC.
Hey! Papi Chulo, what's
goin' on over here, man?
Ai! Qué chulo!
Enter McCoy.
Hace calor!
I'm tryin' to make a video.
Oh, yeah? Tryin' to make--
You know what just happened
to your video? Yeah?
Just got a whole hell of a
lot sexier, baby. [laughs]
Yes, it did. Sexy is here.
Making a video of me
making a video of you.
Yeah, yeah. You're making a
video of me making a video of you.
Uh-huh. Why is that?
Getting it all down
because this might be the last
video that either of us makes.
Is that so?
Mm-hmm.
Well, I'll tell you what.
Let's make a deal, then.
You and me. Seriously.
All right.
If I die in this war, I want you
to get all my videos, all right?
Okay. And if you die in this war,
I'll get your videos,
your camera,
and your girlfriend's
phone number.
My girlfriend's number?
Yeah, your girlfriend's
phone number.
What's Mrs. McCoy going
to be saying about that?
This is my brother.
Come on, man.
All right, that's a deal.
Who do you think I am?
That's a deal. You know
what I like about you, Sally?
Yeah?
Besides absolutely nothing?
Absolutely nothing. And your
sweet and sunny disposition.
No, no, no. It's not about
sunny disposition, McCoy.
It's about
telling it how it is.
Oh, is that what it's about?
It's about telling it
how it is.
You want to hear telling it--
Hey, hey! Hey!
Over here, over here.
Please.
Focus on what's beautiful.
Thank you.
Do you want to hear me
telling it how it is?
Y'all want to hear
What do you all think's
gonna be the first casualty
of this entire conflict, huh?
[Man] You.
That's right!
It's not going to be
Rush or Flake
or "Don't ask, don't tell"
over here.
You know what it's gonna be?
[Men] What?
Do you know what it's
going to be? Talk to me!
You know what it's gonna be?
What's it gonna be?
It's gonna be the truth.
[groaning]
Come on, now. Just
tellin' it like it is.
You suck! What are you talking about?
Ah, here endeth the lesson.
[laughs] That was some sad,
depressing stuff right there.
All right, let me finish.
Let me finish.
All right. So I joined up
to get the money for college,
and a better chance
at film school. Yeah.
I mean, I'm going to be a combat
vet, for chrissakes, right?
And with this awesome war film
in hand, they got to take me.
Oh, yeah.
So while I'm over here,
I'm gonna be shootin'
whatev-- [squeaks]
...whatever the fuck goes on.
[laughing]
Which so far-- Get--
Which so far
is basically nothing.
Now, our squad mans
a checkpoint outside Samarra.
It's all day long
in the boiling hot sun,
wearing 120 pounds of gear,
checking out cars for
weapons and bombs and shit?
This deployment is
unspeakably underwhelming.
The only insurgent
we found so far
is one big fuckin' rat we
chased out of here last night.
Oh, that rat died.
So, get-- Get off.
'Cause I fucked it
to death.
So don't be expecting
any Hollywood action flick.
It's not going
to be smash cuts,
no adrenaline-pumping
soundtrack,
no logical narrative to
help you make sense of it.
Basically, here,
shit happens.
[Woman speaking French]
[Boy]
You want soda?
No. No.
I scored some
for one M.R.E.
Just go.
Go on. Get out
of here. Go on.
Jesus.
He doesn't let up.
[candy clicking]
[Woman narrating]
[American soldier] As you
see, we set up road signs.
They're vividly colored,
highly visible,
and impossible to miss.
They're written
in English and Arabic,
and they inform
every single driver
that they're entering
a checkpoint.
[Woman, in French]
[speaks Arabic]
Get out of the car.
[Arabic continues]
Come up over here.
Quickly.
Let's go, people.
[Arabic]
Go, quick!
Get in line here.
Right there.
That's it, that's it.
Let's go, people.
Yell out.
[Arabic continues]
Arms up.
Arms down. Tell him
to open the trunk.
Open the trunk.
[Arabic]
Let's go, people.
Come on.
Come on, move.
[Arabic]
Don't go in. It's open, it's
open. Take your hands out of there.
[Arabic]
Is he afraid of the dog?
Afraid of the dog?
Who gives a fuck?
Fuck him.
Come over here.
Come on, stay in line.
Eyes front.
Sally?
All right, Blix.
The car is yours.
Good. Come here.
Come back, come back here.
In there. In there.
In there. Okay.
Up here, up here.
In. In. In, in, in.
In. In, in, in, boy.
Come on. I need you
in there. In there.
Come on, boy. Wait.
Up here. Up here.
In there. In there. Up
here. Up here. Come on.
Good boy, Kevin.
Good boy.
All right, come here.
Back through here.
[Angel] It's all clear. All right.
Tell them they can go in
the car and drive off slowly.
[Arabic]
[Woman speaking French]
[Angel] That's Gabe
Blix. He's from Virginia.
He doesn't talk a lot 'cause he's
got his nose in a book all the time.
Yo, Gabe, what you
readin' over there?
I'm reading a book,
Salazar.
All right.
What's it about?
It's about-- Dude, no,
seriously. What are you doing?
What are you doing right
now? Who are you? I'm--
I want to get your opinion.
Okay, if you have that camera,
then you're part of the media,
and we're under strict orders
not to speak with you, yeah?
Don't call me media, asshole!
Come on, just tell me what
you're reading. Tell me about it.
Dude, no. You're gonna make some, kinda
like commie rendition of our mission--
Hey! No, no, no, no, no.
This is about the truth, bro.
This is about what's going
down. This is the truth 24/7.
This camera, it never
lies. Yeah, the--
Dude, that is bullshit.
Okay?
'Cause that's all
that camera ever does.
Just show me
the title of the book.
"Appoin--" Really?
All right. So, you know,
what's it got to say
about Samarra? Nothing.
Nothing.
No, nothing.
It's about this, like, guy,
he's this country club guy,
and he gets really drunk
on Christmas Eve,
and he throws his drink
in his boss' face.
And everybody in the whole
city that he lives in,
like right outside
of Philadelphia--
Okay, but what's it
got to do with Samarra?
It-- Nothing. The opening
makes reference to Samarra,
but besides that, you know, it's
just like, classic cover situation
What? Don't judge a book by its cover.
Right.
Basically.
All right. So, uh--
Whoa, when's the appointment?
You don't want to know.
I do want to know!
Dude, you don't-- This is about books!
I don't have anything about books.
This is literary.
This is good.
The appointment, uh-- Do you want
me to just read you the introduction?
Perfect. Perfect.
Give me something good.
Okay, let me find it.
The introduction's
actually not by John O'Hara.
It's by W. Somerset Maugham.
Perfect.
And-- You have no idea
who that is, do you?
Not at all.
Didn't think so. Okay.
It's called Death Speaks.
Oh, wait, it's spooky?
All right. Read that
right into the camera. Go.
All right."There was
a merchant in Baghdad,
who sent his servant
to market to buy--"
All right, Gabe, wait.
Before you start reading that,
once you get into it, think
about what you're gonna say,
and then put some like,
you know, some heart behind it.
Go!
"There was a merchant in Baghdad
who sent his servant to market
"to buy provisions,
and in a little while,
"the servant came back,
white and trembling,
"and said, 'Master, just now,
when I was
in the marketplace'--"
Yeah, this is a little bit
boring, bro. This is like--
I need to-- Dude, I don't
even want to do this.
Hey!
Yeah.
I got reading, too.
Okay. All right, kid.
I win. Get out of here.
Come on, go.
Emshe, emshe.
[talking] Find your
mother. Go find your mother.
No.
[chuckles]
I don't need any hajji
slave, all right?
I get you anything.
You want soda?
No. I don't want any
fuckin' soda. [chuckles]
Hey, hey. Sally, Sally!
Ain't you supposed to be saying
"action" on me, or something like that?
All right. Here we go.
I'm Master Sergeant James--
[Men]
Ohh!
It stands for M.R.E.:
"Meals Refusing to Excrete."
What you doin', Sally?
God damn, man! That's shit.
You're asking for this.
Hey, hey, Sally!
Come on, now.
All right, you ready?
I'm Master Sergeant James
Sweet-- Over here.
Hey.
What's he lookin' at?
Boy! Get out of here. Hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Full security. Full security.
Hey, Ishta! Ishta!
Ish-motherfuckin'-ta.
Hey, hey. Hey!
Get over here, Blake.
Oh, oh!
Don't be givin' your
fuckin' food, man. No. No.
Ishta. Ishta.
Go. Go.
[sighs]
What the fuck is
wrong with you, man?
Stay away from anything
and everything
these little midget Ali Babas
give you, all right?
Yo, why not, Master Sergeant?
Why not?
See, my black ass has been over here
for three goddamn tours, all right?
I don't trust
anybody over here. Shit.
How long have you been
over here, Flake?
Just a couple months.
Just a couple of months.
Shit. Got ourselves
a goddamn virgin here.
Oh!
No, I'm not a virgin
Yeah, all right.
[Angel] I bet.
And what'd you do before that?
I just hung out, you know?
Fucking around.
Gettin' drunk.
Tried to stay out
of jail.
Sally, come on over here.
Look at this miserable fuck.
This one?
Yeah.
Got him. Probably suckin'
dick for beer money,
if it wasn't for the Army.
Oh.
Look, you're right. I was
suckin' dick for beer money.
This here is the cream of
the Army recruits, right here.
[Angel] Ouch.
[Sweet] "Cream" is no joke.
You're so goddamn white, boy, you
wouldn't wear yourself after Labor Day.
[chuckles]
All right, tell me, Flynny.
Tell me. Like, what was it? You either
had to serve time here or stateside?
Something like that.
Yeah.
Well, you want to get
your ass back in one piece?
I most definitely do.
Well, good.
Stop lookin' to get
yourself killed, then.
You chow down on anything these
little motherfuckin' ragheads give you,
it's like swallowin'
an IED
I wa-- It's a date.
Look at this.
Do you think I want
to eat this?
I wasn't going to eat this.
I was trying to be friendly.
They don't want
to be your friend, slick.
They want to piss on your back and
tell you that it's raining, all right?
Look, trust me. You eat that
shit, and next thing you know,
you gonna be
spittin' up blood.
Hey, look alive,
soldier. All right?
We get back to the house, get yourself
a little kitty kitty, how 'bout that?
[Angel] Woof-woof!
How can you arrange that?
Look alive, look alive! This right
here is my motherfuckin' Caucasian.
He's mine too!
You're my motherfuckin' ese.
I am your ese?
That's right. Come on.
Yo, Master Sergeant.
What?
We swept by this place
yesterday, right?
Hell, yeah. Bet your ass we're
gonna do it again tomorrow.
Because when
the sun goes down,
these motherfuckin' hajjis
come out their ratholes
and resow their IED's in different
and more surprising places
than the day before,
and you can bet your ass
that these smilin',
soccer-playin' shitbirds
ain't nothin' but
their eyes and ears.
[Woman speaking French]
Slow down! Slow down.
Slow it down. Hey! Stop!
Stop the fucking car!
Stop! Stop the goddamn car!
Sally, we got one! Stop!
Stop the god--
Sal!
What the fuck?
Jesus Christ. Holy shit.
[Woman speaking French]
[screaming in Arabic]
Get back!
You got to get back.
Ishta, ishta.
Back 'em up, Sally.
Let's go. Come on.
Ishta, ishta.
Move back from the car!
[Men speaking Arabic]
[Woman speaking Arabic]
[Arabic]
[Sally] Say hello to
B.B. Rush and Reno Flake.
Flake is your average grunt, completely
in touch with his primal self,
He's one of our
latest recruits
from way down on the bottom
of the gumbo barrel.
Boy, he discovered
his soul mate: B.B. Rush.
The guy's dumber than
shit, but he's loyal.
Now, they only want
two things here:
to fuck or to fight.
And yesterday, Flake blew
away his first civilian.
Yo, Flake,
what you readin'?
Oh, yeah?
You been gettin' any?
Mm.
No.
All right.
I have.
All right, fine.
Yo, Flake.
How do you feel about
that hajji you smoked?
Well--
[mumbling]
All I know is, the only language
these sand niggers understand is force.
And I'm just the cat
to make the introductions.
Fuckin' Roger that, man.
Oh, but the truth be told?
Truth be told, Flake.
Truth be told. Truth is, it wasn't
everything it's cracked up to be.
I mean, I thought my first
kill shot would blow my mind,
[imitates shot]
but--
It was nothing.
It was like guttin' catfish.
Yo. Sarge, you waved
that guy to stop, right,
that hajji retard?
Oh, yeah. This guy, uh--
Yeah, but the problem is that
most of these fuckin' people,
you know, when you put
your hand up?
They don't know that
that means to stop.
You know, most of these Iraqis
think that you're wavin' hello.
[Rush] But they fuckin' know what
it means now. All I know is...
these cats screamed
their heads off,
screamed his little,
lady lungs out,
you screamed your beaucoup
brains off-- Ha ha.
And that car just kept comin',
right across that trigger line.
What the fuck else am I
supposed to do but light 'em up?
Light 'em the fuck up.
You did your job.
All right.
But, you know, Flake,
you're not gonna win
many hearts and minds
pumping pregnant women
full of lead, though, right?
That's true, Sally.
Come on. Salazar.
I mean, what do you want me to do?
Get all teary-eyed and say I'm sorry?
[Salazar chuckles]
[chuckles]
"I'm so sorry."
[Rush laughing]
My life's been
changed forever?
My life's been changed
forever, fuck.
Waxing hajjis is like
stomping cockroaches.
I've been there. I've done
that, and it makes me thirsty.
So how about
a nice, cold beer?
[grunts]
[Rush]
God damn!
[Sally] So Flake--
It's the next fuckin' shipment.
Flake, there's no remorse, now
that you know that she's pregnant?
Now that you know that she had
a child in her womb over there?
Nothin'?
You really have
no remorse.
I don't know what the fuck
I'm supposed to--
How am I supposed to--
You have no second thoughts.
I have second thoughts.
Let me tell you something:
you have a kid, you have
a wife that's pregnant--
Hold up. Hold up. No, no, no, hold
up. You'll have second thoughts.
You can't afford remorse, okay?
You get remorse, you get weak. I'm
not saying you didn't do a good job.
You get weak, you die.
As simple as that.
He did his fuckin' job.
What are you saying?
You have a kid,
you have a pregnant wife, you
become more of a human being.
If you have a kid, you're gonna be
even more on your fuckin' plan then.
Because you can't afford-- I'm
not saying you're not on your plan.
...not to go home
without diapers.
What the hell
is wrong with you?
How do we know that
her-- the fuckin'... Hey!
How do we know if the bun
in her fuckin' oven... Hey!
At ease the shit, all right? Look,
point in fact, he did his job.
Rules of engagement states
if they cross the trigger line,
he kills 'em.
That's fuckin' right!
Hey! Get the fuck
away from him!
Sarge, how the fuck am I
supposed to see in there? How?
Have a fucking heart.
Get in your fucking rack!
Enough.
Everybody go to bed,
all right?
Does anybody have
a fucking problem with that?
Enough.
Shut the fucking camera off!
[Cameraman]
All right, all right.
Ten-hut!
Okay, guys. You've all
done a tremendous job,
and I wanna personally thank
each and every one of you.
Colonel Ford, permission
to speak, sir?
Go ahead.
Thank you.
We just wanted to thank you
for your kind words, and, also,
there have been some rumors circulating
about a possible follow-up mission.
No, no, no. I haven't heard
anything about that.
But it does look like we have to keep
up the work here just a little longer.
Longer, sir?
How much longer?
As long as it takes, Private!
That's what you're here for!
Now buck the fuck up!
Yes, sir!
I just got orders.
Second Battalion of 727
is pinned down in Baghdad.
They can't replace us
till someone replaces them.
So half a company will have to
temporarily remain here in Samarra
to man the checkpoints and
keep a lid on insurgent traffic.
You know what it's like? I swear
to God, it's like that Clerks movie.
You know, where the guy
has to work on his day off,
and all kinds
of crazy shit happens,
and all he keeps thinking is,
Oh, man, I'm not even
supposed to be here today.
None of us are supposed
to be here. Fuck, man!
We're just asking
to get waxed.
Dude, all I'm saying is,
they just keep saying,
"All right.
You're going home tomorrow."
And the next day,
it's the same shit.
You're going home tomorrow.
Fuckin' on and on,
week after week.
"You're going home tomorrow."
And we're still here, man.
We're like sitting ducks.
Take care of this,
Sergeant.
Fuckin' Sally, get
that camera out of my face!
What the fuck is your problem?
What are you bitching about?
What, because they
extended our deployment?
Big fuckin' surprise!
Welcome to the goddamn Army!
We all want to fuckin'
go home! We can't.
So stand the fuck up
and be a fucking man about it!
Drive on with
a fuckin' hard-on! Yeah?
[mumbles in affirmation]
Let's go!
Coming here is one step closer
to that appointment.
What'd you say, Gabe?
I said, every fucking day here
is one step closer
to that appointment.
What?
That book, the one that I read to
you, the one that was so boring,
you should check it out.
"Death speaks.
"There was a merchant
in Baghdad
"who sent his servant
to market to buy provisions.
"And in a little while,
the servant came back
"white and trembling,
and said,
"'Master, just now,
when I was in the marketplace,
"'I was jostled
by women in the crowd,
"'and when I turned, I saw
it was Death that jostled me.
"'She looked at me
and made a threatening gesture.
"'Now, lend me your horse,
"'and I will ride away from
the city and avoid my fate.
"I will go to Samarra.
There, Death will not find me.'
"The merchant lent him his
horse, and the servant mounted it,
"and he dug his spurs
in his flanks,
"and as fast as the horse
could gallop, he went.
"Then the merchant
went down to the marketplace,
"and he saw me
standing in the crowd,
"and he came to me and said,
"'Why did you make a
threatening gesture to my servant
"when you saw him
this morning?'
"'That was not
a threatening gesture,' I said.
"'It was only
a startled surprise.
"'I was astonished
to see him in Baghdad,
for I had an appointment
with him tonight in Samarra.'"
[chuckling]
¶ [Middle Eastern]
[chattering]
[chuckles]
[Man]
You awake? Wake up.
Runnin' over there.
[breathing heavily,
speaks Arabic]
White chocolate?
No.
Milk chocolate?
Absolutely not.
And dark chocolate.
Dark chocolate.
Those would be
your three wishes
if you found a magic lamp under
one of these fuckin' rocks.
And speaking of
dark chocolate, Salazar.
Hi.
[laughs]
[speaking Arabic]
[laughing]
[radio static]
Oh, man. Oh, man.
[radio static continues]
[mutters]
[spits] Ew! It's no good. Dude.
Fuck that!
Give me back my shit!
Snowflake, goddamn it, man!
That's my last one! Fuck!
Jesus! Guys, guys, do
not make a fucking move!
Goddamn it! What the fuck
is behind your eyes?
My brain, Sergeant.
You know what I think?
Hey, Flake, get over here.
Stand right here.
Look alive, Soldier.
Sal, are you getting all this?
[Sal] I'm getting all of
it. Ask me what I think.
What do you think,
Master Sergeant?
I can't help but think
that Rush ain't gonna make it.
Now, are you listening to
me, Soldier? Yes, Sergeant.
But are you hearing me?
I'm hearing you, Sergeant.
Goddamn it, boy.
You're so dog ugly,
a bullet to your face
would be an improvement.
[laughing]
Now listen up--
Fuck off, Sally. ...as I
educate your boots on the ground.
This ground, this very
terrain that you are at present
brainlessly bobbing
your fat ass over--
Are you listening to me, Rush?
Yes, Sergeant.
But are you hearing me?
I'm hearing you, Sergeant.
Then slow the fuck down!
Reconnoiter.
Recon the area.
Take a look around.
Now answer me this:
Did you or did you not
check out this furniture
here yesterday?
No, Sergeant.
Why not?
Because it wasn't here
yesterday.
That's exactly my point.
So stay the fuck away from it!
Now, look, we came here
in one piece,
and you can bet your ass
we're gonna leave here
in one piece, all right?
Roger that, Sergeant.
Look alive, Soldier.
All right. Come on.
Let's get our asses
out of here.
[grunts] Goddamn it, Rush! [laughing]
Shut up!
Fuck!
[groaning] Oh, fuck! [coughing]
[Man speaking Arabic]
[groaning]
[coughing]
[Arabic continues]
Oh, fuck!
And this shit hole is nothing
but a fuckin' deathtrap.
Oh!
We need to get
the fuck outta here.
Yeah.
Nuke it and pave it
over, you know?
Pave the whole
fucking thing, man.
Vaporize every last sand
nigger. Goddamn right.
Sweet's the only guy-- the only
guy that ever gave a shit about us,
and they torched him--
they fucking torched him!
Hey, man, if they had
fuckin' sent us home
when they was
supposed to, huh?
Sweetness'd be alive, right?
Partying with us right now.
They're fucking killing
us off one by one.
That's why they took out
the Twin Towers.
Trying to fucking kill us.
No. No, Sally.
To get our attention.
Attention for what?
Jesus Christ, Sally.
Don't you fuckin' get it?
Man, they don't wanna kill us over
there in the good old U.S. of A.
I mean, shit, they do,
but they can't.
It's too fuckin' hard
right now.
Man, they wanna kill us here.
On their turf, in their
fuckin' shit hole country!
Yeah. Where every
turn is the wrong turn.
Every single one of them knew where
that fucking IED was! Goddamn right!
You don't see them
stepping on it? Do you? No!
They just sit
in their fucking backyard,
drinking their fucking tea,
waiting for one of us
poor motherfuckers
to light up their day.
Come on, boys.
Well, guess what. That ain't
gonna happen no more!
Hell, no! There's gonna be one big
fuckin' bitch of a preemptive strike!
Yeah! We're gonna be torching
every last Johnny-fucking-jihad!
Later. And there ain't
gonna be nothing left
but scorched fuckin' earth!
[grunts]
Get down!
[all shouting at once]
Go, go, go, go! Inside,
inside! [shouting]
Move!
Down!
We got one! We got one!
[shouting continues]
Down! Clear!
Down!
Get down!
[girl screams]
Get down! Get down!
Get down!
This is the guy!
Let's go! Let's go!
We're clear!
Come on, people! Let's go!
Come on!
Check the back! Check the back! Clear!
Move, move, move!
What are you doing?
Oh. Oh, hi.
Uh, well, we're looking
for evidence right now.
Evidence of what?
Evidence of anything
that's gonna help us, uh,
fight the war.
Clear!
Can read that?
Well, no, of course not.
Can have this paper?
No, you can't have...
This is Iraqi, okay?
Iraqi? You mean Arabic?
Arabic. That's right.
This is really important stuff.
So how do you know it's important?
Well, we're gonna find out
if it's important,
'cause I've got people
who can translate this for me.
And, um...
But they're not here right now.
So you guys have to step out.
So how do you know it's evidence?
We're gonna find out
if it's evidence, all right?
Jonesy, let's get these people
out of here. Thank you for coming.
Okay, people, let's go!
Let's go!
Move! Move it! Move it!
Okay, okay, okay. Okay.
Is this the guy? Yeah,
this is him! Grab him!
[all shouting at once]
Bring him out!
Get down! I won't shoot
you! [Girl screaming]
[shouting continues]
Up against the wall. Hands against
the wall. I got him, I got him.
[speaking Arabic]
He's clear.
On your knees!
[groaning]
Sit down. Give me the
bag. Give me the bag.
I'm bagging him.
Well, he looks
pretty harmless.
Why are using a hood?
[whimpering]
Why are using a hood? Because once
he's bagged, he's like a blind chicken.
He can't run if he can't see.
He can't breathe with that on.
Are you sure he can breathe?
No-- Yes, he can breathe.
Can't you hear him breathing
right now? [gasping]
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure he can breathe.
[speaking Arabic]
She says his back is broken.
The old man's back is broken!
Get off me!
She said the old man's
back is broken!
Can you understand that?
No-- All right. Well...
I'm not carrying
that bag of shit.
Let's go!
Everybody out!
Let's go, let's go,
let's go! 1, 2--
[all shouting at once]
Let's go!
Move, move, move!
Move, move!
Get back!
[rifle cocks]
[both sobbing]
[speaking Arabic]
[sobbing continues]
[Woman speaking French]
Good boy.
[dog whining]
[Man]
Uh, we're good.
Right here.
It's okay, it's okay.
Arms up. Arms up.
That's it.
Arms-- Arms up.
Arms up. Up. Arms.
Arms.
Arms!
Mmm.
[chuckling]
Yella.
[laughing]
[Man laughing]
Hoo!
¶ [rock]
[Sally] All the way from Camp Carolina,
it's the first episode
of Drug Poker, baby.
I got an idea. Why don't you
turn off the fucking camera?
Do you guys know how big
high-stakes poker is on TV? So what?
When I sell my show and you guys
become stars, you can all thank me then.
How about that?
Okay, yeah, we'll do that.
Why don't you play the
game right now? I'm playing.
[Rush]
You can't afford us.
There's no way.
Sally? Come on, shithead.
Are you in or out?
All right, all right, all right.
Don't fuck around.
I...am...
Wow. I'm out.
You are so out.
Out again.
What do you know?
I was out.
Show me them. Show me them.
I got two cards. And she's doing
the Pledge of Allegiance, I think.
[laughing, chattering]
What you got there, Reno?
What's you say?
"She's doing The Pledge
of Allegiance!"
Reno's doing-- doing
all right. All right.
Mr. Blix?
Um, she's my favorite.
I like her.
Oh, that is a solid choice.
She looks like a nice girl.
Not bad for Mrs. Blix.
Mr. Mactastic? Um, is it wrong to
fall in love with the king of clubs?
[laughing]
If you don't ask
and you don't tell.
There you go.
All right,
out of the cards.
All right.
What's happening right now?
Blix, what do you need?
Blix needs, uh...
Blix needs three, although it's very
hard to say good-bye to the 8 of clubs.
Oh, yes, I'm sure it is.
No, check her out.
Freakie boy.
One.
Are the cards thirsty or
something? I want four.
Ooh.
I'm thirsty.
[laughing]
What?
Did you just say you need four?
Yeah. What's the big fucking deal?
No, it's just--
it's perfect Rush strategy.
Do you even have
an ace, dude?
I have an ace,
and I boned her.
[laughter]
We gotta go back
to that house.
What are you talking about?
What house?
That house we raided last week.
I didn't see any orders
about that.
Dude, we're going to Farah's.
Farah's house. That's right. [grunting]
What are you guys talking about?
That's not... We just...
There's nothing
in that house.
How can you say that
that tasty skank is nothing?
Come on, dude. We're gonna take
some initiative and go to that house.
She's a spoil of war.
That's right.
Oh, I forgot.
That's exactly right.
Okay, you guys
are fucking crazy.
Come on. They're drunk.
Dude, we're all drunk.
Turn that fucking thing
off.
No, keep that
fucking thing on.
Fuck off! This is off the record,
so turn the fucking camera off!
Back off. All right,
all right. Keep it on!
Fuck off!
Guys, relax.
Let's just play the game. You guys are
really drunk, as I was saying before.
So I actually think maybe... I'm
seeing things clearer than you.
No, you're not seeing
anything clearer, Flake.
Flake, you haven't seen anything
clear in, like, four months.
Stop it!
Who doesn't see clear?
How the fuck am I
supposed to see clearly?
[chuckles]
I mean,
what are we doing here?
"What are we doing here?" Yeah,
what the fuck are we doing here?
You know
what we're doing here.
We're helping the new
Iraqi government survive.
Knuckleheads.
And what the fuck
do you think
is so important about that?
I think there's a lot
important about that.
Enlighten me.
We're, you know-- We're--
What?
We're just doing our job.
We're not-- We're not
supposed to think about it.
We're supposed to follow
orders. We're soldiers. Amen.
Yeah.
Welcome to the fucking Army.
But these people
don't want us here.
Yes, they do. No, they don't.
They want us dead and gone.
And when those fucking beltway clerks
finally find that out, we're gonna be both.
So, in the meantime,
Rush and me
and...Gabriel... I have
to say shut the fuck up.
Get away from me,
because I'm not doing...
You're such a pussy! I'm not a pussy because
I don't wanna break through the door...
Oh, no, the door's
already broken down.
The door's already broken down.
The father's locked up.
What's the problem? Nothing
to worry about. Let's do it.
Sounds like the perfect
cap on the evening. I agree.
Yeah, perfect cap on the evening.
I'm gonna go wake up Sarge.
I'm gonna ask him what the SOP is on
a gang rape. You're not gonna say shit!
Don't wake up Sarge for this.
I'm not gonna say shit?
No, you're not gonna say shit. You
know why Sarge is finding out shit?
Why?
Because nothing's gonna happen,
because you guys couldn't even get
outside the wire if you wanted to.
Get your fucking hands off me!
Hey! Hey! Cut it out. Cut it out.
That's bullshit!
Sit down, sit down.
If you can find your chair.
Got it.
All right. Can we
play the fucking game?
Jesus Christ, Gabe!
What do you think, Sally?
I-- I think I'm gonna be going for
this little-- this little jaunt.
Yeah, you are, baby!
[laughing]
Sally's got a set of balls.
What about you, McCoy?
Are you serious?
Come on, dude. Come with.
Get your fucking hand off me.
No, fuck him.
Pussy boy doesn't want to go.
Dude, let me
tell you something.
First of all, y'all
are drunk. Thank you.
Probably high doing all
sorts of fucking drugs
or whatever the hell
you're doing.
You're fucked-up.
But?
If I go, it's to make sure you don't get
your asses killed. That's right. When we go.
We are not
gonna get killed!
"Hello, honey.
"I don't have much time,
but I have to send you this.
"First, I want you to know
that I love you very much.
"I miss you more every day
"and can't wait to touch
your beautiful face.
"I was looking
at the pictures
"you just sent me
of you and the boys.
"I'm wishing to God
I was there instead of here.
"The guys have been
drinking all day,
"and it looks like they're
going out looking for trouble.
"I can't stop them,
"but I'm going to make sure
"they don't
get themselves hurt.
"You just can't go outside
and blow off steam here.
"It's too dangerous.
"Anyway, I love you.
Lawyer."
[sighs]
I knew he was doing
raids outside the wire,
but he hadn't done
too many in a while,
and I-I'd built up
a sense of security
in knowing this.
I live for his phone calls
and his chats online, you know?
They help me not
to worry so much.
But today is--
...is different.
[sobbing]
Oh, my--
Um, I'm scared. I'm--
I'm scared to death for him.
I rigged a mini-cam
to my helmet
so I can record
tonight's follies
without the guys
knowing about it.
I don't want 'em
getting camera-shy.
[sighs]
So what are you
gonna do?
I don't know, man.
I'm gonna--
...go with them and try to
talk some sense into them.
Dude, they're going to get
about 20 feet outside there,
they'll get scared
of the dark,
and come right back here.
And what about Sally?
Sa-- Man, you know,
Sally-- What's he doing?
He's gonna go out there, come
running back to base camp,
turn on his camcorder and give a
firsthand account of what he saw.
It's sick.
It's fuckin' sick.
It's a pretty juicy
story, though, isn't it?
"Our band of brothers
losing their moral compass
and trying to wreak vengeance
on a 15-year-old girl.
It's unbelievable.
Yeah.
Ride the cable news chain all
the way up to 60 fucking Minutes.
Hey.
Hey, Rush. What's up, man?
What the fuck
are you two doing?
Just talking, you know.
Smoking.
Oh. Thought you quit.
Uh, no. No, I--
I never quit.
[laughs]
Oh, shit!
Temper, temper!
Hot damn. The fuckin'
pussy's on the rag again.
Jesus Christ!
[chuckles]
Hey, man. Where's your gear?
Rush, dude. Come on.
Let's think about this.
I mean seriously.
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Fuck that, dude. Fuck that.
Shut up, man.
I'm all thunk out, okay?
My fuck stick needs some
pussy. Like right now.
Okay? Whackin' off in a sock just
ain't cuttin' it no more, man.
This fucking baby
is hurtin'!
It's like all red, and sore,
and chapped and shit, man.
And there is nothing like
some sweet hajji ass
that is going to get this
plumbing right back into alignment.
You can't be fucking serious.
I am dead serious, dude.
So get your fuckin'
gear on, and let's go!
Go on! Get your fuckin'
shit on! McCord--
McCord, this is fuckin'--
And you! You, you!
Get your fuckin' hands
off me! Shut the fuck up!
Shut up! Just shut up!
You listen to me like you never
listened before in your life.
If I hear you breathing
one word
about anything
that goes on here tonight,
so help me God, I will cut
your fucking tongue out.
And I'll feed it to
that fucking dog of yours.
You get me?
Do you get me, Blix?
Yeah.
Good boy.
Now why don't you get
the fuck out of here?
Go read some Shakespeare.
[McCoy]
[Flake]
I'm talking about the
girl, man. The girl?
I'm talking about fucking
with a 15-year-old girl.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
You're all discombobulated.
You got to lay off
that hajji juice,
'cause that is
some sneaky shit.
I don't touch that fucking
shit, you know that.
Really? What the fuck
are you doing up here?
You're supposed to be
at the rear. Excuse me?
You giving me
an order, Private Flake?
That's right, Corporal.
Get to the fuckin' rear!
Fuck off me!
[laughing]
Fuck you!
Fuck off, bitch.
[Sally] McCoy! McCoy,
you're not going to go in?
Fuck it!
McCoy, come on!
What's your excuse, Sally? Huh?
Excuse for what?
Excuse for wanting
to take a part of this, huh?
McCoy, I'm a fly on the wall. I got
to get a record of what's happening.
That's right, you're the
fly on the fuckin' wall. Yes!
Actually, Sally, I think
you're a fuckin' jackal!
Ripping meat off
a fucking carcass!
That's what you are.
Can I quote you on that one?
Sure, Sally, quote away.
You know what? I got another quote
for you. You ready? What? What?
Take a look around you at all your
greedy, media buddies-- You dick.
...who sold their soul for
a talk show and a book deal!
'Cause that's what you are! This is my
free pass into film school, right now.
Really? Well done, Sally.
[Women screaming]
Take it all down,
cry for cry,
and scream for scream--
go ahead!
Thanks for your permission,
there, dick.
Oh, look out there, Mac.
I don't want you tripping
over your goddamn soapbox.
Fuck it.
Fuck you!
[shouting, screaming]
Flake! Flake.
Flake,
enough's enough, man.
Enough's enough.
You've had your fun.
Let's get out of here.
We're just gettin' started.
We just got here. What
the fuck's your problem, McCoy?
You shouldn't be here,
Flake, and you know it.
We're just here, man.
We're here,
and we are gonna fuckin'
find these-- [crying]
weapons-- we're searching
for evidence--
We're looking for weapons
of mass destruction!
Weapons of mass destruction.
That's right.
I don't give a shit
what anybody says.
They're here, and
we're going to find them.
Flake, there is nothing
here, and you know it!
What are you fucking-- We ripped
this place apart last week.
There's nothing here!
They're just like weeds, McCoy.
You rip 'em up, they're all
back the next day, aren't they?
She's a 15-year-old girl, man.
She's a 15-year-old girl.
We're going to accomplish this
mission. Please don't do this.
We are going to conquer that.
It's inhuman to rape.
She's a fine cunt, just like
everybody else in this fucking country.
I'm not doin' it, man.
You fuckin' candy ass!
Well, you're not doin' it!
Shut the fuck up.
Are you not
supporting the troops?
What? Are you not supporting the troops?
No.
[laughing]
Oops. Did I just blow
your fuckin' head off?
Don't.
Where are your balls, McCoy?
Man, I thought you had a
pair. What are they, at home?
Inside your wife's
sandy hajj pussy?
[McCoy] God! [laughing]
Fuck you!
[Flake]
Thought you had a pair.
How about you, Rush?
Where are your balls?
They're almost
in her ass, sir.
Almost in her ass.
What about you, Sally?
Get it up!
"I can't hear you, sir."
They're right here. I can't
hear you. I can't hear you!
They're right here!
Where are your balls?
Good!
All right.
[whispering in Arabic]
All right, motherfucker.
Hitch a ride outside.
Take the faggot watch. [Rush] Yeah,
take the faggot watch, you pussy!
Bunch of fuckin' assholes.
Fuck you.
What do you think
of that, huh?
Ooh, did you like that?
Did you miss me, huh?
[Rush laughing, groaning]
Oh, it's go time for you.
You ready?
Huh?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
So, you ready?
Here you go, here you go.
Come here, Salazar. Come
here. Take her fucking hand.
Take her fucking hand!
Rush. Rush.
[pleading in Arabic]
Rush, hold on!
Wait. Wait for Flake. Hold
on, Rush. Wait for Flake.
This is his idea. He gets
the cherry. Come on, wait up.
What? You got a problem
with sloppy seconds?
[screaming]
[automatic weapons burst]
Holy shit!
[laughs]
He tried to use
this on me.
Motherfuck.
[laughs]
Those motherfuckers! What
the fuck do you think I did?
I fuckin' killed them all.
I killed them all.
[Rush laughs hysterically]
Every fuckin' one of them.
They're fuckin'
all gone, baby.
They're all fuckin' gone.
[laughing]
All right.
Sally, come on over here, baby.
It's showtime. Take the
fuckin' hand. Here we go.
[Arabic]
[laughing]
Oh. You ready? You ready for
the ride of your life, bitch?
[screaming]
Shut the fuck up! Don't
you fuckin' make a sound!
Give it to her!
[Rush hooting, laughing]
Aah!
[Flake grunts]
God!
What happened?
What happened in there?
Talk to me!
Tell them-- No! Fuck!
What are you talking about?
McCoy!
What's up, Rush?
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
What are you telling Blix? Nothing.
Just shooting
the breeze, man.
the breeze, huh?
Get the fuck off him, Rush.
Back off!
Back off, Blix!
I'll cut you like a pig!
Sit down.
Okay, okay.
Get the fuck off me! If you
fuckin' move, I'll snap it.
It'll be real quick.
Piece of shit.
I want you to listen
to me real careful, Mac.
Listen to what?
Have you ever
been to Vegas?
What?
Are you fucking deaf, McCoy?
Am I speaking too softly
for you? No, I hear you.
All right. So you're tuned
in on my frequency, right?
Yes. Good. Now let me ask you again.
Have you ever
been to Vegas?
Yes, I've been
to fucking Vegas.
Good. Now what
do they say?
Uh-- What do they say
about what happens there?
It stays there.
I'm sorry. What was that?
"What happens in Vegas,
stays in Vegas."
That's right.
That's right, Big Mac.
Now I want you to think
about our little trip tonight,
like it was a trip to Vegas. Okay.
You read me, soldier?
Yes, I read you.
Do you fuckin' read me?
Yes, I hear you!
[sniffs deeply]
[coughs]
Sometimes, man--
I swear to God.
For a college boy, you can
be real fucking stupid.
Where's Flake, Rush?
What the fuck
do you care, hairball?
Huh?
For your information, our boy
Flake is inside right now.
Sleeping like
a little baby.
You know what
that's like, right, Blix?
Right after you've been
sucked and fucked?
Hey, Mac, man.
Where were you?
What do you mean,
where was I?
I mean, what the fuck
happened to you?
I went outside.
I was on watch.
[scoffs] Flake stuck a gun
in my face. You remember that?
That's right, that's right.
You were on watch.
Did you see anything?
Ah. No, I didn't
see anything.
Well, that's good. That's good,
because you were on watch, right?
Yeah, I was on watch, so--
I mean, it was kind of
dark out there, too.
Yeah, it was
pitch dark, actually.
Yeah.
What about the fire?
Did you see the fire?
Fire?
It was a big fuckin' fire.
You didn't see that?
No, I didn't see it.
I had my back
to the house,
just looking around,
so I guess I must have
missed the fire.
That's good.
That's good, man.
And what about
the insurgents?
Insurgents?
Yeah, man.
We had to hightail it
out of there.
They were
like, all over the place.
And really pissed.
Mm.
That must have been one of
those Sunni-Shiite things.
Right.
You know, I mean--
We don't want to get caught
in a civil war crossfire.
So the, uh, insurgents
set the fire.
Yeah, it must have been.
Because you know,
when they're not trying
to kill us,
[chuckles]
Yeah, they're torchi''
each other.
[Arabic]
And when did you start
having these dreams?
A couple nights.
I couldn't sleep.
I don't want to sleep.
Can you remember anything?
Anything that happened
that could have
triggered them?
Yeah, after Sweet died?
And I was shooting it
when it happened.
He got blown apart.
I got it all on tape.
His arm landed
right in front of me.
Have you looked
at the video?
Couple of times,
but then I stop,
but it kept going, going over
and over again in my head.
That's when I began
hating everyone.
Every hajji out there.
I couldn't stand the sight of
them, and I got angry all the time.
And then I couldn't sleep,
and every time I did,
I'd have the same dream
of her body burning.
Her body?
No. No.
No, his body.
Sweet's body.
It gets mixed up
in my head.
And you videoed it.
Yeah. It's part of my diary
of my experiences here.
I'm going to use it
to get into film school.
Is this part
of your experience?
What, talking to you?
Yeah.
Talking to me.
I can't do it anymore.
Everything
you shouldn't see,
just because you're watching it
doesn't mean you're not a part of it.
That's what everyone does, you know?
They just watch, and they do nothing.
[weeping] Or they make a
video for people to watch,
and they do nothing!
[sobbing]
Got to tell someone.
It's driving me crazy.
Dad, if something happened,
something really,
really horrible,
and you knew who
was responsible,
isn't it your duty
to say something?
What did you do?
I didn't do anything.
I didn't do a damn thing.
A couple of my buddies--
Members of your squad?
Yes, sir.
I hope you realize how serious
this situation could be.
Yes, I do realize.
We don't need another
Abu Ghraib.
I understand that,
sir, but--
I mean, if your brothers
screwed up,
that behavior reflects
on the whole Corps.
There was a crime, sir. I
think charges should be brought.
Son, listen to me.
Do you know the first thing
to come into question
in a court martial
in a thing like this
will be your sanity.
My sanity?
That's right! Your sanity,
for bringing charges like this.
[sighs]
I don't care.
Here I am, Mama, in
beautiful, downtown Samarra,
getting you
a homecoming present.
I've been shooting
some unbelievable stuff.
I can't show it to anybody, because
I'd get in a lot of trouble here.
But when I get back,
everyone's going to see this.
The truth about
what's going down here.
24 times a second,
24/7--
[horn honking]
Get off! Rush! Rush!
Fuck. Sally, where
the fuck did you go?
[man calling goats]
[Arabic]
[Man]
Mount up!
[Male reporter] The body being
loaded into this military ambulance
is believed to be that of the U.S.
soldier missing since last Friday.
That's according to Iraq Defense
Ministry Secretary, Abdul Aziz.
This Bedouin encampment
where the body was discovered
just moments ago is outside
the Samarra base camp
where the soldier
was kidnapped.
The Pentagon has not yet
issued a statement
on the identity of the body,
but senior sources tell us it
could be the body of Angel Salazar,
who went missing last Friday.
Iraqi Defense Ministry
spokesmen have said
the details are
very disturbing.
There are signs of
torture and decapitation.
[speaking Arabic]
[Arabic]
Allahu Akbhar! Allahu
Akbhar! Allahu Akbhar!
[choking, screaming]
[chanting continues]
Private Flake,
what kind of a soldier
was your fallen friend,
Angel Salazar?
[quacks]
And take your time.
What the fuck?
What do you think I was
doing? I was taking my time.
Jesus Christ, Snowflake.
Don't get a fuckin'
hard-on, man, all right?
I'm trying to make this
official and everything.
All right?
All right.
Uh, Private,
how-how would you
summarize
your buddy?
I mean, you know,
if you take all of
his...his parts,
and you like stack them,
one on top of one another,
right, what would--
What would--
What would be the one
word that would-- [quacks]
...be the sum of those parts? Generous?
Generous.
He was a generous spic.
That's a very good word.
And how
was he generous?
He was a...
dedicated reporter.
He used that camera.
This camera right here?
To record his-- our--
war stories.
Stories that will
last on into history.
Long after
you and me are gone.
He was like our
very own Private...Ryan.
[snickers]
Hey-up!
[laughing]
Semper fi, brother.
Semper fuckin' fi,
fuck Marines.
[chuckles]
Okay.
What would be, Private,
your last memory
of our brother Salazar?
I--
...just can't
talk about it.
I understand.
This is hard.
But I can talk
about my brother.
And the life lessons
that he taught me.
Well, lay it on me.
[quacks]
My brother, Vegas Flake.
[laughs]
Really, you have a
brother named Vegas? Yep.
I have a brother named
Vegas. Reno and Vegas.
Daddy was a gambler,
and he named his
two favorite sons
after his two
favorite places.
Hmm.
Called us his wild cards.
[snickers]
That's nice.
Yeah, I thought so.
I do, too.
Vegas was a Teamster.
Mm-hmm.
And the head of his local,
Mike Dancer,
he's a troublemaker.
He'd run for president
of the U.T.,
and lost, now the bitter prick
Dancer's contesting the election.
Got ahold of some
ballot boxes
that my brother Vegas
had rigged,
and he's blowing his whistle
to federal prosecutors.
Nothing but a fucking rat.
Word comes down.
He's got to go.
So, what happened?
A fucking embarrassment.
A bunch of clowns who need a road
map to find their own assholes
drive out to his house
one night.
Knock on the door.
And are they, like,
locked and loaded?
Yeah! Yeah, they are
locked and loaded.
[laughs] So? So.
Dancer opens the door.
He's there, big as life
in his shorts and T-shirt,
holding his fucking
newspaper?
And what do you think
our Wild Bunch did?
They just blasted
the shit out of him, right?
Wrong. They asked him
for a job.
A job.
Yeah, that's right.
A job. They're too
chickenshit to shoot him.
He's the head of a local.
Since they're not getting paid
for not killing him--
and what the fuck are they
doing on his doorstep anyway--
[chuckles]
they ask him for a job.
They really asked him
for a job?
Yeah, he says to 'em, too.
He's like,
"Come by the office in the morning.
I'll see what I can do for you."
They get in the car,
drive to the nearest bar.
Fucking embarrassment.
Right, I don't get it.
Listen on, my man.
Clyde, the mastermind
of this group,
sees my brother--
Vegas.
...playing pool.
Invites him in the back room,
says Dancer's going down.
Vegas has got his own
beef with Dancer, right?
Contract for 20,000? My brother
says he'll do it for ten.
What about the other
guys, says Clyde.
What about the other guys,
says my brother.
I-I-- I still
don't get it, though.
They drive back out
to Dancer's.
Opens the door.
Oh, shit.
Shorts, T-shirt.
Vegas shoots him in the face.
Steps over the body,
goes upstairs,
kills the wife and kids,
in and out, five minutes.
End of story.
Wow. Um--
[clears throat]
All right. So, uh,
All right.
[chuckling]
Great story.
All right. Private,
what would you say
would be the lesson
that we have
learned here today?
Uh, the lesson is that,
when you're on a mission,
a deadly mission--
Deadly mission.
It's all about having
the right mix of guys.
And in that mix, there's
got to be the wild card.
Vegas was the wild card.
And so am I.
Mm-hmm.
You got that right.
And what has become
of the wild card, Vegas?
He's dead.
He died in prison.
Jesus.
He got caught?
Took about, what, 24 hours.
Cops come knocking
on Clyde's door,
they flip him,
go to the bar,
find Vegas--
Only takes one fucking rat
to bring the whole house down.
Jesus, dude. What are you
looking at me for?
I'm sorry.
You know, my mom always told
me it was impolite to stare.
Come on, dude.
I mean, what about
the other guys?
[chuckles]
What about the other guys?
Well, McCoy didn't
see nothing.
And Angel--
Well, kind of
lost his head.
[electronically altered]
I am making this video
to expose a situation
that happened to my squad
that I think people
should know about.
I'm hiding my identity
from the public
because I'm afraid
that the F.B.I.,
and the Department
of Defense,
and even the Insurgents
can trace my I.D.
and find me.
They already got
one of my guys,
and I'm not going
to take any chances.
But this needs to be said.
For legal reasons,
and for my personal safety,
I cannot reveal
the time or the place
or the soldiers involved,
but believe me, everything
I'm about to tell you,
everything is absolutely true.
When I was stationed
in the Middle East,
two men from my squad
raped and killed
a 15-year-old girl,
killed her little sister,
killed her mother,
and killed her grandfather
and no one has done
a thing about it.
I'm posting this
on the Internet
in hopes that someone
from my squad,
anyone, will see it,
and will help me, please,
bring this forward, and
bring this out into the light.
Did you see the woman
being raped?
Yeir. Well, uh,
not really.
Rush was holding her down
when I went outside.
Well, to do what?
To get away.
I didn't think they were
actually going to do it.
How did you know her?
Flake put a gun in my face
and told me to go on watch.
How did you know her?
She would go in and out
of our checkpoint every day.
Rush would take a little
extra time with her.
Said he was just
being thorough.
And why did you
make this assumption
that she was a girl
and not a woman?
Because she was
younger than that.
She didn't look that old,
so I just assumed that she--
Wasn't she an insurgent,
resisting arrest?
[chuckles]
Uh, no. No.
She was just a girl.
She was scared to death.
How do you know
she wasn't scared to death
because she was an insurgent
resisting arrest?
Because, um,
Flake said that we were
going to get this girl
and "have a little fun."
Oh, that's new.
When did he say that?
He said it when we were
playing poker one night.
I thought he was
just kidding around.
Did you see Flake
rape her?
No, I told you.
I went outside.
So what did you see?
I didn't see him ra--
I heard some shots.
I heard some screams.
Then what happened?
Then I went up the stairs,
and I saw Salazar, and he
told me what happened inside.
You didn't actually
see him shoot her.
No, but Flake had a gun
pointed at her head--
So did Salazar and Rush
have guns?
Yes, sir. Rush had a gun.
Did you have a gun?
Yes, sir, I did. Couldn't
Rush have shot her?
No! I--
Couldn't you have shot her?
I didn't shoot the girl.
But when you saw her,
she was still alive.
I told you. I didn't
go back inside.
Salazar said-- We're not
interested in what Salazar said.
We're interested in
what you saw.
Flake shot her
in the face!
So you believed
she was dead.
Yes! I believed
But you didn't
see him shoot her.
No, but I didn't know--
And you didn't
see him rape her.
No, but that's
not the point!
What is the point?
Isn't your testimony that you
were outside keeping watch?
I didn't know what to do.
I didn't want to see it,
and I didn't want
to be a part of it.
Why don't you believe me?
This is the scene
of one of the most
shocking crimes
alleged to have been
carried out
by American
soldiers in Iraq.
According to evidence
at the hearing,
one July evening,
four U.S. soldiers
came to this house here.
According to Lawyer McCoy's
statement,
Reno Flake and B.B. Rush
repeatedly raped
a 15-year-old girl.
In another room,
the girl's grandfather,
mother, and little sister
were shot dead.
This man, Private Reno Flake,
is accused of committing
all the murders.
His accomplice,
B.B. Rush, was taken--
[Rush]
We were securing the area.
We checked everyone
and everything.
And that girl went in
and out of our checkpoint
again and again.
So, yeah, I checked
her thoroughly.
Every fucking time, because there
was something fishy about her.
"Fishy"? What exactly do you
mean by fishy, Specialist Rush?
Fishy, fishy, like
she was up to something.
And I'll deal you
one more card.
It's angel faces
like hers
that are going to walk right up to
you and give you a great big smile,
and then blow you
the fuck apart.
And sure as shit,
the next day,
the very
next fucking day,
one of my best buddies
got torched on a path that
she just walked right over.
Didn't miss a beat.
So don't you dare sit there
for one second and think
that she didn't know where
that fuckin' IED was planted.
[Flake chuckles]
You know, I went back
to the house because
I knew they were hiding
weapons and shit?
I mean, hell,
that old man,
broken back, tried to
shoot me with an AK-47.
You know-- Hey--
It really
pisses me off, sir,
when I think of everything
we've done for these
sand niggers?
Got rid of Saddam,
planted democracy,
giving up our lives to keep them
safe from their own insurgents,
and I'm not looking
for a thank-you, but--
I want them to stop
trying to kill us!
Mm-hmm. Did you
find these weapons
before or after
you raped the girl?
Raped?
I mean--
That hajji bitch
was all over me.
What, bombing and shooting them is okay,
but fucking them
isn't.
I mean,
who-- who says--
Do you say?
Who says their pussies
aren't better
than their
hearts and minds?
Would you answer
the question, Pratt?
This is bullshit.
Just a, you know--
It's
a dog and pony show
for the folks
back home, right?
I'm just one of those
bad apples, huh?
Soldiers
like B.B. Rush and I?
We're keeping the Arab
scum off your doorstep.
We shouldn't be in here
answering this crap.
Let me tell you
something, sir.
We should be out,
doing our job,
boots on the ground,
finding the bad guys,
putting two in the heart
and one in the head,
keeping America safe
and making sure
the motherfucker's dead.
You prosecute
guys like us.
You're just aiding
the terrorists.
A quick death...
is too good
for this brainwashed,
racist Nazi fuck.
This stormtrooper needs
to be stripped naked
and strung up by his feet.
Then, what's left
of the family--
you know,
the ones he didn't shoot
or set on fire--
the family of that
poor little girl
should be given
baseball bats,
white-hot branding irons,
blow torches,
dull knives, pliers,
and, of course, rocks,
and be told
to go to town!
This is the same monster
immortalized in every
fucking movie about Vietnam.
"Let's do the whole
fucking village!"
You don't see the My Lai
massacre in the movies
because the truths
of that fascist orgy
are just too hellish for even
liberal Hollywood to cop to.
Oh, but that doesn't
stop them
making another movie
about 9/11
because an American life
is worth so much more
than a Vietnamese,
a Palestinian,
a Lebanese,
or an Iraqi life
because we
are the uber race.
Sieg heil, motherfucker!
[Man]
Oh. Okay. Okay, that's great.
[giggling]
All right. All right, now--
Hey, McCoy--
Woman!
...I'm not
getting your faces.
Come on, I want you
to turn toward me.
Come on, come on.
Look in the lens here.
All right, all right,
all right.
Hurry up.
Take your picture.
ALl right, here we go.
Ready? Come on. Face me.
Here we go.
Come on, Judy, look at me.
Here we go. 1, 2--
No, I got to go
fix my face.
Your-- What?
Your face is fine.
It's just--
I'll fix my lipstick.
It's perfectly fine.
You look great! Judy!
Okay.
How about a war story?
Yeah, how about not?
Oh, yeah.
Come on.
There are no war stories.
Tell us a war story.
You don't want to hear
a war story.
Sure we do. Tell us
what you did out there.
Did you kill
anybody?
Come on!
Let's hear one.
Do you want to hear
a war story?
Absolutely.
Do you really want
to hear a war story?
Very much so.
Absolutely.
All right. Here's
a war story for you.
Uh...
when I first went over there,
to Afghanistan,
I was, uh, I was all amped up
to kill for my country.
I was ready to just kick
some ass, you know?
Get some licks in for what
they did to the Towers.
Just be a big fucking
war hero.
[clapping] Right on! Yeah!
I get over to Iraq,
and man, it's just--
it's just a totally
different story.
You grow up really,
really fast over there
because everything you see,
everywhere you look
is just death,
and it's suffering.
And the killing
that I did do,
it made me sick to my stomach
because of these smells
and these sounds
and these images.
I have these-- these
snapshots in my brain
that are burned
in there forever,
and I don't know what the fuck
I'm going to do about them.
And what was I doing there?
What was I
doing in a country
that's done nothing
to me?
Just following orders?
Bullshit. Bull shit.
You better have a really
good fucking reason
for one of your buddies
to die in your arms,
to be blown up
right in front of you.
A really good
fucking reason.
And I saw some shit
there, man. I just--
I just don't know how
I'm going to live with.
I went on a raid
in Samarra.
And two men from my unit
raped and killed
a 15-year-old girl
and burned her body.
And I didn't do
anything to stop it.
[soft voice]
Oh, no.
No, no.
This is a celebration
for a war hero.
Come on, come on.
Celebration!
To Lawyer McCoy!
Come on, come on.
And I'm going
to get my picture here.
Okay. Okay. Okay, McCoy.
Here we go.
Look at the camera.
Come on, Judy.
Look at us here.
Here we go.
1, 2, 3--
[shutter clicks]
Subtitles extracted by LeapinLar