# #  [ Suspenseful ]
[ Heavy Machinery
Rumbling Nearby ]
[ Steam Whistle Blowing ]
Here come the wolves.
[ Rumbling of door opening]
[ Footsteps & Workers Chattering ]
Uh-oh.  Bottleneck.
Mr. Roosevelt should hear of this.
I'm sorry.  Hope you didn't
hurt yourself.
My friend
says he's sorry.
Okay.
That shows what a blonde can do
to hold up national defense.
Nice, pleasant guy.
Man !
Gee,
a hundred bucks.
[ Whistles ]
So that's what they look like.
Where'd he go ?
I don't know.
Uh--
I wonder
what his name is.
I saw it on the envelope.
Uh... Fry.  That's it.  Fry.
Fry.
How do you
know my name ?
What do you care
how I know your name ?
I saw it on one of the
envelopes you dropped.
Here's something
that belongs to you.
[ Siren Wailing ]
The paint shop ! It'll go up like dynamite !
Here.  Take this one.
What about me ?  Don't I get to play too ?
You get another.
Right !
So I see these two kids. And I
yell at them:  "The sprinklers are busted...
The whole shootin' match will go up."
And they run right in,
the both of them.
And the last thing I saw
when I looked back...
was one kid give the extinguisher
to the other kid,
and then it was just like
all hell comes up.
That's all I see.
-Was there anybody else around ?
No.  Just the two kids:
the poor kid with the extinguisher
and the one who give it to him.
Thank you, Rogers.
We appreciate all you've done.
We needn't keep you any longer now.
Better go and take care of those hands.
Who've
you got next ?
There's a fellow Barry Kane waiting.
-Send Barry Kane in.
Barry Kane !
All right.  Just take it easy. We only
want to ask you a couple of questions.
A matter of a routine checkup.
-Well, I want to do anything I can to help.
Sure.  Now, suppose you tell us
where you were when the fire started.
Well, I was one of the first to rush in.
The sprinkler systems weren't working.
[ Investigator ]
Who else was with you ?
There was just myself, a fellow
named Fry, and my friend...
Ken Mason.
[ Investigator ]  Go on.
-Fry handed me an extinguisher,
and I started running toward the fire.
I gave it to Ken.
[ Inhales ]  And then he...
Okay.  Take it easy.
That's all.
Just stick around for a while.
We may need you.
Send for Fry.
Get hold of a fellow called Fry.
What'd they do, ask you
a lot of questions ?
Hardly any.  Gee, it's
awful tough going,
seeing it happen
in front of you.
Yeah, it is tough.  Ken Mason
was your pal, too, wasn't he ?
Yeah.
Was he married ?
-No.  He was living with his mother.
Must be pretty tough on her.
Sorry, fellows.
I'll see you later.
[ Door unlatching ]
[ Door latching-
Radio #  in background]
Hello, Mrs. Mason.
They...they wouldn't
let me see him.
It's awful hard to believe.
It happened so quick.
Why, only this morning...
-Please !
Please don't talk about it now.
[ Sighs ]
Anything I can do ?
Could I get you something ?
No....No, thank you...
Not now.
Maybe some brandy ?
How is the poor dear soul ?
If you mean Mrs. Mason,
she's feeling bad.
Ah, well.
She's every reason to.
Do you know what ?  They wouldn't
even let her see him.
Her only son.
-Yes, I know.
I told her to insist on seeing him.
I told her I would, and she
as good as told me to get out !
Me !  That was only tryin' to help.
The poor dear soul.
I think you can help,
if you'll get some brandy.
You come with me, young man.
I have a little in the house.
[ Doorbell Buzzes ]
Sorry to bother you, Mrs. Mason,
but we're looking for Barry Kane.
Do you know him ?  He isn't
here right now, is he ?
They told us at the plant we might
be able to find him here.
Well...what do you
want to see him about ?
He's in pretty bad trouble, lady.
-What is it ?  I'd like to know.
He was mixed up with
that fire at the factory.
I...I don't understand.
[ Second Man ] There are a lot of things
we don't understand either.
But how is Barry
involved in it ?
That fire extinguisher.  Seems it
wasn't just an accident.
It turns out that the extinguisher
Barry Kane handed your son...
was filled with gasoline.
-Oh !
[ Second Man ]You ought'a be able to help us.
Give us a lead on this guy, Kane.
Yeah.  That's why we want to look around.
-Well...
Why...
I can't talk about it now.  I...
Yeah.  Sorry, but,
you see, there was a...
I wouldn't give her too much of that.
It often makes people weepy.
I know it affects me...
-Yes, I've got to hurry back.
Thank you very much.
Try some of this, Mrs. Mason.
It'll make you feel better.
There were two
detectives just here.
They were looking for you.
-For me ?
I guess they wanted to ask
more questions.  I said I'd help.
Here.  Try this.
-No.  That wasn't it.
They wanted to arrest you.
They said that the fire extinguisher
that you handed to Kenneth...
was filled with gasoline.
That you killed him!
That I killed...
Why, are they crazy ?  Why would
I want to do a thing...
Ken was my best friend !  Haven't they
talked to Fry about the extinguisher ?
They said that there was
no such man employed at the plant as Fry.
Why, I saw him !
I saw him twice !
Ken saw him too !
He was with us at the fire.
He handed me the extinguisher.
Ken said, "Don't I get to play too ?"
He was kidding.
I handed it to him.
Fry was right there with us,
I'm sure !
Why, he must have known
there was gasoline in it.
He must have known !  He stood
right there with us and watched, that...
[ Glass being put on table ]
Please go.
Don't you believe me ?
Do you think I had
something to do with this ?
I didn't tell the police
anything....
Oh, I don't know !
It's all so confused...
and so terrible.
I don't know what they're talking about !
Why don't they get this fellow Fry ?
You'd better go.
All right.  I'll go.
I've got to find Fry,
or, Ken won't be the last one
to die.
[ Doorbell Buzzes ]
[ Neighbor ] I saw him
go in the back way.
[ Dorbell Buzzes ]
[ Truck engine approaching ]
# [ Whistling: "Fifth Symphony"
By Beethoven ]
Catchy.
What ?  That tune
you're whistling.
# [ Imitating Tune ]
Oh, I didn't even know I was whistling.
-You must be pretty happy.
- Easy to see there's nothin' on your mind.
[ Truck Rattles ]
Oops.  That must have been Junior.
Felt like him.
Junior ?
-Yeah, that rock.
I know every one from
Los Angeles to Reno.
Tough job, driving a truck.
Got any other hot news tonight ?
I never realized
how tough it was before.
The tough part, you can take that.
It's the monotony that gets you.
I been thinking I'm gonna get out
of this trucking game.
-Why don't you ?
One of the neighbors told my wife
it's stylish to eat three meals a day.
- You married ?
- Nope.
Go ahead and whistle.
[ Rattling Sound ]
That thing bother you ?
-What's doin' it ?
Here.  Stick this wad of
paper in there, will you ?
It's a pretty good thing to have
around, one of these extinguishers.
I wouldn't be without one.
Now, take the other day...
A big lettuce truck turns over
right down here.
The gasoline catches, and she
goes up like a matchbox.
A friend of the driver's
gets caught in her.
If the driver hadn't had an extinguisher,
his pal would have been fried alive,
right in front of his eyes.
I didn't see it happen.
I never see anything happen.
I don't even hear about anything,
except when my wife tells me
what she sees at the moving pictures.
That's the way she spends the money:
moving pictures and new hats.
Buys a hat so she can go to the
picture show...so she can take it off.
No, sir.  I haven't got
anything to whistle about.
Where are you from, bud ?
Uh, Los Angeles.
-Tough.  You work down there ?
Yeah.  Well, I did.
-What doin' ?
I was workin' in an airplane factory.
-They say that's pretty good.
I was wondering why
you weren't in the army.
-Yeah.
They're particular about the fellows
they hire in those defense plants.
Well...That's no more than right.
They gotta be careful they don't get blown up.
-Yeah.
-I understand if a fellow
had any police record, no job.
Is that right ?
-Oh, I don't know.
Hey, buddy.  Hold the wheel a while, will you,
while I animate this thing.
I'm a nicotine addict.
Hey, watch it, bud !  Stay on
this side of the white line.
Where do you wanna get off
when we get to Springville ?
Oh, it doesn't matter.
Drop me in the middle of town.
The minute you get to Springville,
you're in the middle of the town.
The next minute,
the place is just a memory.
Whole town
isn't a block long.
You're goin' to one of those big ranches
outside, aren't you ?
- Yeah.
- I'd be glad to drop you off
at whatever one you want.
[ Echo of Footsteps From Factory]
That's it !
Deep Springs Ranch.
Hey !  Say, that's
a whale of a big place.
Got a chance of a job there ?
Yeah.
I think so.
You ought to like it.   Nice climate.
[ Siren Wailing ]
The police !  Maybe
something's happened !
I'd like to talk with you...out here !
-Yeah.  Sure, officer !
Stay here a minute, buddy,
I'll be right back.
[ Door squeaking open ]
[ Truck idling]
Hey, bud !
Come on, everything's fixed.
Good night, officer.
Can you imagine
a thing like that ?
Cop chase, sirens, the whole works !
Just because one of my taillights went out !
That's a trucking game
for you in a nutshell.
[ Radio ]
Calling all highway patrolmen:
Be on lookout
for a man named Barry Kane.
Last seen on Highway 99.
He has dark brown hair,
blue eyes,
height about six feet two,
no hat, around 25 years old.
Calling all highway patrolmen.
[ Motorcycle engine revving ]
# #  [ Gentle Western ]
[ Truck brakes sqeak
then engine revs ]
[ Cattle lowing ]
How do you do ?  Is, uh...
Mr. Frank Fry here ?
No, this is
Mr. Tobin's ranch.
Oh.  Uh, could I
speak to Mr. Tobin ?
Well, I'll see.
Just a minute.
You wait here, please.
There.
We've got the ball.
Throw it to me !
-A young man to see you, sir.
Where is Daddy's girl ?
[ Laughs ]
What did you say, Adele ?
Who wants to see me ?
-A young man, sir.  He came
to ask for a Mr. Fry.
Oh.
[ Child chatters ]
Well.  Have him come out here,
will you ?
Yes, sir.
-Throw me the ball !
Throw me the ball !
Here comes your granddaddy!
Mr. Tobin will see you.  Follow me, please.
-Thank you.
[ Child Chattering ]
[ Tobin ] Want the ball ?
[ Tobin Laughs ]
How do you do ?
I'm Charles Tobin.
This is my daughter,
Mrs. Brown.
How do you do ?
Well, I'm not gonna ask you to excuse
the informality of this costume.
We're all informal out here
at Deep Springs Ranch,
That's one of the rules of the place.
-I see.
[ Child chattering ]
Want me to take Suzy with me ?
No, Suzy isn't gonna
disturb us at all.
You just let her play right here.
I'll see she doesn't fall in the pool.
All right.
[ Tobin laughs ]
Well, shall we sit out here ?
-Yes, sir.
It seems a shame to go indoors
on a beautiful day !
-Yes, it does.
-Now, you wanted to see me
about something ?
Yes, sir.  I'm looking for a man
named Fry.  Frank Fry.
I met him up in Los Angeles.
I understand he lives here.
Oh, no.  No.
Fry, huh ?
Frank Fry ?
I'm afraid I don't know
anybody by that name.
Wait a minute.
Fry.
I've heard that name
somewhere.
I just don't seem
to be able to place it.
Uh-huh.
Uh, there used to be
a fellow...
with a name something like that,
worked around here.
No.  No.
It wasn't Fry.
Well, I'm afraid you
found the wrong address.
Well, it couldn't be one of the cowhands
or somebody who's working ?
No, I know the names
of all my men.
Wait a minute....
My next door neighbor...
Well, 'next door neighbor'...
He lives 20 miles from here !
But he may know your friend!
I'll telephone him.
Oh, no, please don't.
No, no !  You look as though
you've had a hard journey.
Just too bad if you came
all this way for nothing !
Now, if you'll just wait a minute,
we can find out.
Will you see that Suzy
doesn't fall into the pool ?
Yes, sir! [ Laughs ]
-Thank you.
[ Suzy Chattering ]
Hey !  Come here !
Come over here !
Oh, so you're a ball player,
are you ?  Throw me the ball.
Let me have it.
Come on.  Throw me the ball.
That's fine !
Throw me the other one.
Come on !
Throw it to me.
Give me the ball.
That's fine.  Fine !
Now, I'll throw it back.
Where are you goin' ?
Uh-oh.  Don't do that.
Leave those where they are.
Leave them right there.
[ Echo of Footsteps From Factory ]
Wanna be a good girl ?
Put these back where you found them.
No, no, Suzy.
The gentleman says put them
back where you found them.
The gentleman knows that you must be
careful with letters that don't belong to you.
Probably I'm prejudiced,
but it seems to me...
that Suzy is a pretty cute
young lady.
[ Laughs ]
Yeah, she's great.
Where's Frank Fry ?
Well, really, you must do something
about that memory of yours.
It wasn't a minute ago that you
read a telegram that Fry sent me,
and it said that he was
on his way to Soda City.
Do you remember that ?
-Where's Soda City ?
Well, I haven't given it much thought,
but I wouldn't imagine...
there'd be an overabundance
of Soda Cities on the map.
I suppose there's some
way of finding out !
[ Radio ]...last minute headlines:
Los Angeles-A fire at Stewart Aircraft Works
in which one man was killed,
many injured and half a million
dollars worth of damage caused,
has been definitely
set-down to sabotage.
Police have traced the incendiary blaze
to Barry Kane, former aircraft emp...
[  Clicks Radio  Off ]
Don't want any more of that.
I Think you'd be rather bored with
the descriptions of yourself.
Or maybe you never get tired
of them....  Well, I am by this time.
I've been listening to
those reports all morning.
-Alright, you knew me.  What about it ?
Oh, quite a lot about it, Mr. Kane.
You ought to know that.
You've become too famous
to remain so modest.
Tell me one thing.
Why are you covering up Frank Fry ?
What's a man like you in this for ?
Young man, I don't know what
you're talking about.
-I think maybe you do !
Frank Fry is a saboteur who
doesn't mind killing Americans for money.
You must watch yourself,
Mr. Kane !
I'm telling you this for your own benefit, but...
you have the makings of an outstanding bore.
You can't get away with this, Tobin, even if
I don't stop you, others will.
A man like you can't last
in a country like this.
Very pretty speech.
Youthful, passionate, idealistic.
You see, I've already
sent for the police.
You can't bluff me.
You're hooked, and you know it.
Must I remind you that YOU are
the fugitive from justice and not I ?
I'm a prominent citizen,
widely respected.
You are an obscure
young workman...
wanted for the committing of an
extremely unpopular crime.
Now, which of us do you think
the police will believe ?
Hmm ?
[ Laughs ]
Oh, you must think me
a very poor host, Mr. Kane.
Now, don't you feel that a long,
cold drink is indicated ?
Well, I guess I found out everything
you're gonna tell me.
I'll have to go on now and
do the rest by myself.
-You mean you wish to leave us ?
Adele, Adele !
Mr. Kane is going !
I'm sorry.
You'll stop, please.
What does that shoot ?  Water ?
-Bullets, I'm afraid.
You shouldn't be so anxious to leave us.
You'll hurt our feelings.
You make it very hard for me
to refuse your invitations.
- Suzy, come on.
- No, no, Suzy !  Come here.
Hello, Suzy.
You know where we're going ?
For a piggyback ride.
You like piggyback rides ?
[ Tobin ] Dick, Joe !  Get after him !
Hurry up !  Get him !
Get after him !  Hurry up !
# # [ Intense Western ]
Go on, get going.
You can't take me away like this.
Don't tell us what we can't do, chum.
Go on, get started !
You gotta get him !
Just because he's got a big ranch...
and a fancy pool and a lovely house,
doesn't mean he's a nice guy !
Find out the things he's been doing !
-Sure.  We know all about that.
Just come on along.
-The baby had the letters, I tell ya !
Oh, Suzy would be only
too glad to cooperate,
but it'll be quite a few months
before she'll be of any assistance.
[ Baby Fussing ]
No, no, Suzy.
Those are not for Suzy.
Those are for the gentleman.
All right, let's go.
Where are we goin' ?
We're gonna let you get an
idea of the county jail.
You won't find it
the best in the West.
But it won't hurt you 'til they come up
from Los Angeles for you.
You can't hold me without a warrant.
-Chum...
Do I have to keep askin' you
not to tell us what we can't do ?
I'm tryin' to explain ! Gimme a break !
There isn't time !
Time's the one thing
you don't need to worry about.
You'll have it to burn.
You'll have 20 years,
if you get the right lawyer.
If you don't, you'll
have all the time there is.
- What's wrong, Mac, what's holding us up ?
- Truck ahead blockin' the whole road.
Looks like they're changin' a tire.
Got a cigarette ?
Sure.  All you want.
Hiya, bud !
Hey, what's the matter ?
# # [ Suspenseful  ]
[ Water Rushing ]
He went
behind those rocks !
[ Man Shouting ]  Not over here !
There he goes !
There he is !
# # [ Violins-Redemptive ]
[ Thunder ]
[ Dog Barking ]
Hello there.
Hello.  I got caught in this storm.
I'm pretty wet, I'm afraid.
Maybe you'd like to come
inside and get dry.
Did you leave your car down on the road ?
Why don't you bring it and put it in the shed ?
It won't do it any good
standing in the rain.
-I don't have any car.
You might say
I'm traveling by thumb.
By thumb ?
Yeah, I'm a hitchhiker.
Oh, I see.
I've always thought that was the best way
to learn about this country,
and the surest test
of the American heart.
Yes, I guess it is.
-Go to the fire and dry your clothes ?
Thanks.
-They'd dry more quickly if you
put on something of mine.
Oh, no, thanks !
This is fine.
We could do with another log
on the fire.  Would you ?
Why, sure.
You must stay until this blows over.
It won't detain you long.
These autumn storms are short.
They yield to none in wetness,
but they are short.
-Yes, I...
[ Log Bangs on Floor]
I should have warned you.
Those logs are heavier than you'd think.
I drop them constantly.
Yes, they are heavy.
I guess I was too smart trying
to pick it up with one hand.
Good job it didn't land on your foot.
That often happens to me.
You're lucky.
Yeah.
I'm lucky.
Oh, I was forgetting.
My name is Philip Martin.
Oh, I'm Barry K...
Mason.
I'm glad you found yourself near here,
Mr. Mason, when the storm came.
It's a pleasant thing to have
a guest sharing the fire when
the rain is beating on the roof.
- You live here alone, do you sir ?
- Yes, except I don't think of it in that way.
You see, sounds are my lights
and my colors.
My music, for example.
I compose a little.
And there is nobody to tell me that the
results are anything but brilliant,
so I live in a comfortable
glow of self-appreciation.
[ # ]
I prefer playing the works
of other composers.
Undoubtedly,
you'd prefer listening to them.
I used to play the triangle in our
high school band.  Of course,
that was a long time ago.
Oh, that's too bad.
It's unfortunate when you get
out of practice on the triangle.
The piano is a boon to me.
The piano can't know
that you're blind,
so it doesn't embarrass you by trying
to make things easier for you.
It does you the compliment
to trust you.
Delius, the British composer,
was blind too...
That's our only resemblance.
[ # ] This is his
'Summer Night on the River.'
[ Crunch ]
A very interesting effect:
obbligato on an apple.
Oh, I apologize, Mr. Mason.
I forgot how hungry you
must be after your long walk.
Just a moment.
I'll get something.
Oh, no.  Thanks.
This is fine.  I...
I like apples.
So do I.  We'll save them
for dessert.
It was all ready,
you see.
All I needed was a reminder
that I was hungry too.
Are you dry enough ?
-Just about, sir.
It stopped raining.
[ Rumble ]
Is that a car coming ?
Two cars, I think.
[ Dog Barks ]
Excuse me.
One car is my niece's.  I'd know
the sound of that motor anywhere.
The other is a stranger to me.
-A couple of men in it.
The girl's pointing down the road.
They must have asked her where to go.
This is an easy country to lose
your way in.  That's one of its charms.
The car is moving, they're starting-off
down the road now.
The girl's coming up the path.
-That's my niece, she's been staying with me.
She comes from New York to spend
a month with me every year.
It's one of my greatest pleasures.
Unhappily for me, she can't stay longer.
After a month,
she finds the quiet deafening.
Oh, Uncle Philip...
Hello, old boy.
Uncle Philip, what do you
think happened ?  Oh.
You didn't know we had a guest.  You
turned your back, and see what happens !
My niece, Patricia Martin...
Mr. Mason.
How do you do ?
-How do you do ?
Uncle Philip, there was a car full
of detectives down the road.
They wanted to know
the way to town.
They're searching for a man that
got away from them. It was on all the radios.
They said he was really dangerous criminal...
My dear, the police
are always on the alarmist side.
- But they said this man is really dangerous !
- I'm sure they did.
How could they be heroes
if he were harmless ?
Would you mind not having any
further quotations from the police ?
Their remarks are always so expected.
They kill conversation.
You've probably seen the face
of my niece before, Mr. Mason.
Why, yes.  I was wondering
where I'd seen...
As a matter of fact, you've seen her
practically everywhere.
I'm told that billboards she adorns
would reach across the continent...
if placed end to end.
I can't imagine who's going to
place them end to end,
nor why they should consider
it the thing to do.
Uncle Philip never has been enthusiastic
over my career as a model.
Oh, well, relatives are like that.
My, aren't you two mean,
going ahead and eating without me !
I'm starving.  Would you pass
me one of those plates, please, Mr. Mason ?
- Oh !
- What's the matter, Pat ?
Have you just seen his handcuffs ?
I heard them as
soon as he came in.
Uncle Philip, he must be the man
they're looking for.
Yes, very probably.  But you should
have given him to the police !
Are you frightened, Pat ?
Is that what makes you so cruel ?
But you've got to !
He's a dangerous man.
Oh, Pat, come on,
Mr. Mason may be many things,
but he's certainly
not dangerous.
In fact, I'm not at all
convinced that he's guilty.
Uncle Philip, it's your duty as
an American citizen !
It is my duty
as an American Citizen...
to believe a man innocent
until he's been proved guilty.
Don't tell me about my duty.
It makes you sound so stuffy.
Besides, I have my own ideas
about my duties as a citizen.
They sometimes involve
disregarding the law.
But what are you
going to do with him ?
I'm going to turn him over
to you, my dear.
And you're going to drive him
down to Tim, the blacksmith,
and have those preposterous contraptions
removed from his wrists.
Oh, how could I do
a thing like that ?
'Cause you know I can see
a great deal farther than you can.
I can see intangible things.
For example, innocence.
Will you go with my niece, Mr. Mason ?
-Oh, yes, sir.
Uh, if you don't mind ?
What'll I tell the blacksmith ?
Tell him Mr. Mason
is my friend...and my guest.
He won't ask
any other questions.
Go ahead, Pat.
Go with her, Barry.
Barry, I know, is your name.
Your voice explained to me
that "Mason" isn't.
But as I told you before, names are
of such little importance.
I...I don't know how to
thank you, Mr. Martin.
Go ahead, Barry.
Go ahead.
And do the things...
I wish I could do.
Good luck, Barry,
and for heaven's sake...
get back in practice
on that triangle !
Is the blacksmith's shop very far ?
-Not very...right along here.
And, uh, is he...
is he really all right ?
He and my uncle
are great friends.
-Oh.
I guess he's all right, then.
You needn't worry.
He's all right.
He's a darling blacksmith, only
I'm not sure how much experience
he's had with handcuffs.
Do you mind if I see them ?
What do they do to get them off ? I...
I can't quite see.
Could you hold them nearer ?
Now I feel better.
-I'll bet you do.
I'll bet this makes you feel great,
doesn't it ?
The blacksmith shop is two miles back.
We're on our way to the police.
Your uncle's certainly
gonna be proud of you !
The world isn't full of kind old gentlemen
like my uncle; you're gonna find that out !
Even my uncle wouldn't have
been so kind if he'd known more.
All right, go ahead. What'd I do ?
I'd be kinda happy to know.
If it had been any other crime...
if a man had stolen because he was starving,
even committed murder to defend himself,
maybe I wouldn't tell the police.
But there's only one reason
why a man commits sabotage.
That's worse than murder.
-Surprise !  I agree with every word.
Please don't talk to me.
-That'll be my pleasure.
Well !  I'll see
that she doesn't !
[ Tires squeal  to a stop ]
[ Exhales ]
Never try driving
this way; it hurts.
I'm stopping
the first car I see !
[ Sighs ]
[ Engine Revs Faster ]
[ Hood Release Pops ]
[ Clicking against fan blade ]
[ Grinding ]
# # [ Suspenseful ]
Help !
Come on.  I can't get
along without you.
Let me go !  Help !
Help !
Get the police !
My, they must be
terribly in love.
[ Motorcycle engines slowing then stopping ]
Looks as though this car
has been overheated.
Fan's broken.
I'm cold.
Yeah, I know. And you're hungry.
-Now mostly I'm cold.
Look, if you'd stop trying to be
a hero and decide to be on my side,
maybe we could do something
about your being cold.
Build a fire ?
No, I wasn't exactly
thinking of that.
Well, I didn't want to insult you
by not even trying.
What do you want
to turn me in for ?
Haven't you got your picture
stuck-up in enough places now ?
I just want to do my duty.
That's hard for you to understand.
Why won't you believe I'm all right ?
You don't make sense.
If you hadn't done it, you would
have gone to the police.
It's a question of time !
It'd take weeks to convince them.
If they're as dumb as you are,
it'll take me months !
Do you think we're very far
from Soda City ?
I don't know.
We'll ask at the next town.
If there's a next town.
Anyway, I don't believe
that part about Tobin.
You don't believe it because he's got
a big ranch and a beautiful pool...
No.  It's just hard to believe
that about any American.
Well, you believe it
about me !
Well, you're different.
You look like a saboteur.
You have a saboteur's
disposition.
Don't tell me you've
decided to be on my side.
No, I'm cold.
Say, aren't you wasting
your very valuable time,
sitting up here
admiring the scenery ?
Hey, look at that.
Looks like
we've got company.
What do you suppose
all that's doing way up here ?
They aren't moving very fast,
are they ?
You know what
we can do ?
Oh, no, you won't.
Sorry, I can't take a chance.
[ Muffled ]  You're right.
I'll kill you the first
opportunity I get.
Let go of me !
Let me go !
-Ouch !
Help !  Help !
Won't you give me one break ?
Won't you wait 'til we get to Soda City ?
All right.
I'm sorry I've got to
leave you here alone,
but I told you what I've got
to do, and I'm going to do it !
There's only one thing I want
to warn you about...Snakes.
There are a lot out here.
There's only five or six poisonous kinds.
But there are a lot of the
long, squirmy, slippery, slimy ones.
- Barry !
- I'm coming up in the world, now
I'm better than the snakes.
Barry, please !
Are you with me ?
Yes, yes !
What made you
change your mind ?
I can't turn you in if I'm stuck out there.
-Oh, so that's it, go back with the reptiles.
Let me go !
-Who's there ?
You've got no right here !
Stop it and get off !
Now, now, Major.
Ah ! stowaways !
In the middle of this desert sea,
we acquired two more vagabonds.
Bedouins like ourselves, eh, Esmeralda ?
-Why, they're just a couple of kids !
Uh, our car broke down, a way back,
and we've walked for miles.
So we just sort of hopped on.
We didn't want to wake you at this hour.
Broke down, eh ?
We didn't pass no wrecks
on the highway.
- The whole thing sounds like a pack of lies.
-See,  we were off on a side road.
I know.  A moonlight night
and a parked car.  That's nice.
- Oh, no, really...
- Esmeralda !  Everywhere
you search for sex.
Get your eyes out of the mud
and look up at the stars.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
My name is Bones.  I'm also
known as the Human Skeleton.
- How do you do ?
- And this is Esmeralda,
our bearded lady.
Naturally, we're very proud to have
her as a member of our group.
You poor kids must be tired.
Come on in and sit down, have a little rest.
We're trying to get to Soda City,
a couple hundred miles north, I think.
Well, then, you won't get there 'til morning,
so make yourselves comfortable.
You must meet
our other co-worker:
Titania,
our little human mountain.
A very great lady, indeed.
- How do you do ?
- [ Woman ] What's goes on there ?
[ Esmeralda ] Oh, did we wake you, honey ?
-Oh, I was awake.
I wish you'd tell Minnie to do something
about that insomnia of hers.
I've been tossing and turning.
I wish you'd tell Marigold to shut
her silly old face.
Are you girls not speaking
to each-other again ?  Dear, dear!
Marigold's mad because I got
her beau away from her back
in the last town we played.
Kindly tell Minnie
I heard that last remark.
That I wouldn't have the gentleman
in question as a gift.  Nothing
but a common novelty seeker !
Girls !  Girls ! What
will our guests think ?
Hey, he's cute !
You hear that ?
There she goes again.
[ Esmeralda ] Stop your squabbling.
They're tired.
- They've been walking for miles !
- Nobody gave you a lift ?
The normal are normally coldhearted.
-Stop gabbing and get these tramps off !
A cold heart.
I won't take no insults.
Get 'em off.
Aw, Major, honey...
-Don't "honey" me !  I've got a contract.
It provides for safe transportation and
don't say nothing about picking-up hoboes !
[ Sirens Wailing ]
That's the police.
They must be looking for somebody.
Who could they want ?
Me, I guess.
Oh !
They came for you.
He has handcuffs on.
What do they want you for ?
- For something somebody else did.
[ Major Laughs ]
I don't believe he's done anything wrong !
I'll go to bat for him anytime.
I've always told Minnie she'd get
mixed up with the police if she wasn't careful.
They're starting to search
at the front.
Well, what are you waiting for ?
Hand them over to the police.
He's perfectly right.
He's a little stinker.
Seems like a terrible thing to do,
but it would be terrible, too,
if we got into trouble.
Alright, Bones, call the cops !
-Just a minute, Major.
In this situation I find
a parallel for the present
world predicament.
We stand defeated
at the outset.
You, Esmeralda, have sympathy,
yet you're willing to remain passive,
and let the inevitable happen.
I have a belief, and yet I'm tempted
to let myself be overridden by force.
The rest of you, with the exception
of this malignant jerk,
are ignorant of the facts
and, therefore, confused.
Thank heaven we're still
members of a democracy.
We'll put the matter to a vote !
- [ Major ] I'm against voting !
- Fascist !
You know how we stand so far.
The twins, as usual, are on opposite sides.
And so their votes pair.
Titania's on both sides at once
and, therefore, neutral.
The major is for delivering
these young people to the police,
and I, frankly,
am against it.
Esmeralda, the decision
is up to you.
I don't want any trouble
any more than anybody else,
but while you've been talking,
I've been looking at something--
something pretty fine too.
I've been looking at that little girl there,
standing beside that poor young man.
Never a word.
Never a question.
Takin' everything he's had to take,
stringin' along with him, whatever happens
And I've been thinking,
it's the good people that stick
when anybody's in trouble,
and there aren't many
good people in the world.
I think that we, all of us,
know that better than most.
Well, it isn't something you see
every day of the week.
- So I vote...
- We don't give them up. Good girl, Esmeralda !
This is subversive !  I won't stand for it !
Oh, no, you don't, Cuddles !
You'll abide by the will of the majority.
Back in your places and pretend to be asleep.
That's all you have to do!
Here, you sit down here.
Come on, young man, we've got to hide you.
Turn all the lights off.
Here.  Take off your coat and put this on.
Come on,
wake up in there !
Hey, what is this ?  Halloween ?
-Police !
Oh. is that so ?  Haven't you got
anything better to do...
than waking up law-abiding citizens
in the middle of the night ?
We're lookin' for a man
and his woman companion.
He's got dark hair, between
the ages of 20 and 25.
The dame's supposed to be good-lookin'.
Have you seen him ?
Now, where would I see anybody
as normal as that ?
Who's this ?
Doesn't look like one of your troupe.
[ Esmeralda ] Sure, she's one of us.
She's our little snake charmer.
Right now, she's sitting on a box of snakes
so they don't get lonesome.
Can you imagine that ?
A good-lookin' gal too.
Well, I guess you can
all go back to sleep now.
A snake charmer !
Well, well.  You never
can tell about women.
It's all right.
You can come out now.
Wait, Justice, come back !
-Sit down here !  We're on our way.
I don't know how I can thank you, sir.
-It's all right, my boy.
Gives you a good feeling
when you can help somebody.
You've got a right to know what this is about.
-It's all right.
If that little girl of yours  can trust you,
I guess we can.
The baby !
She's had a tough time.
Poor little girl.
She's worn out.
-I'll take care of her.
Come on.  Let's go.
[ Crying ]
-Better let the snakes get some sleep.
They have to look good tomorrow.
I'm sorry.
What for ?
-For being such a dope...I was scared.
You'd have been a dope
if you hadn't been scared.
You're tired;
that's all that's the matter with you.
Get some sleep.
You'll be fine.
[ Sighs ] I can go to sleep, all right.
I'm so tired.
[ Sniffles ]
I want to tell you
something.
I believe you.
Do you, Pat ?
You didn't, you know.
It's a free country.  A girl can change
her mind, can't she ?
Sure, she can.
Thank you, Pat.
They made me so ashamed.
They're so nice
and trusting.
They're
wonderful people,
all except that
nasty little major
and that...
mean twin.
I don't suppose
you can really blame
the fat lady though,
when a woman has lost
her figure that way.
# #  [ Hopeful ]
# #  [ Ominous ]
Welcome to Soda City.
The heart
of the bicarbonate belt.
Well, we might as well
do the town.
There's nothing here.
Come on.
I suppose we are a little late.
Sorry, darling.  I knew I shouldn't
have brought you here.
I'm not complaining.
This is great, isn't it ?
The solution to all my problems.
I was counting
on this place.
A dump like this,
5,000 miles from nowhere.
[ She Sighs ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
Look at this.
It's been in use.
Let's go around
to the window.
[ Ringing Continues ]
Careful !
Don't cut yourself.
[ Ringing Continues ]
Hello ?  Hello ?
Hung up.
-What sort of phone is that ?
It's a field telephone.
Well, a room with a view.
What do you suppose
they cut that for ?
-I don't know.
Say, look.
Tripod.
Looks like it's
the right height.
Yeah.
Something else
goes with this.
There !
That's it.
[ Pat ] See anything ?
-Not yet.
[ Barry ]
Uh-oh.
Let me see !
Why, that's a...  Why, Barry !
-Yeah.
Better put this away.  Take that.
- Say !  The wood.
- What about it ?
You wouldn't burn that in the stove.
-Why not ?
The smoke would show.
[ Door Shuts ]
That's a car.
You better hide.
No, not here.
Hey...What do you think you're
doin' around here?
I, uh...I was wonderin' when you'd get here.
-Where you from ?
What are you stickin'
around here for ?
Excuse me.
Funny, you knowin' about
this place.  I don't quite get it.
You might have thought it over
more carefully.
Your coming here
doesn't help us a bit.
[ Old Man ] The heat's on this guy
and he shows up here!
Tobin sent me !
-The old man must be off his nut
sending him up here.
Be a little more careful, Neilson.
Your criticisms in front of other people.
- Yeah.  Don't talk that way about the old guy.
- I'll watch out for myself.
Me too.  Don't forget about me.
That's why Tobin sent me here.
He said you'd know
how to take care of me.
I guess that makes it
pretty clear, Neilson.
I don't know.  A guy walks in, out of the
desert, and right away I get orders.
It ain't so clear to me.
I'm a little better than a stranger,
if you'll remember my press clippings !
Yes.  Mister, uh...Kane has done
pretty well down south.
His accomplishments can't be disregarded.
At least I hope not.
A man that has served as well as he has
is entitled, at least, to recognition.
I'm entitled to more than that,
to protection too !  You guys have
got to take care of me.
I'm sure the firm will do its best.
They're quite loyal to their employees.
Neilson will see to it that the firm's
record is maintained.
You've  got it easy,
you guys from back East.
You give orders.
You do that, all right.
The big boys
with the desk jobs.
All you gotta do is reach for a telephone,
sit back in a big leather chair,
and us guys out here
have gotta take the rap.
You know, I think I'll go back East
and work for a while.
You're not a very good
example of loyalty to the firm.
[ Neilson ] Yeah ?  Well, I'm gettin'
just a little bit tired.  See ?
So am I !  I'm getting a little bit
tired of all this talk, let's get goin' !
The trip up here was no pushover.
I had to hoof it most of the way.
I got no place to hide you out.
That ain't in my line.
That ain't your line, huh ?
What about you ?  You don't
seem so interested either !
I suppose you're just the big brains !
Or maybe you take a chance just for laughs !
Maybe it doesn't work that way.
Maybe I'm the only guy that
sticks his neck out !
Well, get this !
I pulled a big job,
and they're after me !
And you guys have gotta take care of me,
or you're gonna have some trouble
on your hands !
I've gotta get out of this part of the country !
The ground's burning up under my feet !
I've gotta get back East !
It's more crowded and a guy
doesn't stand out, like here !
Take it easy.
Hang onto your nerve.
I've been hanging on to my nerve !
I've been hanging on long enough !
I understand your difficulties,
I'm sorry about all the talk,
but in this business...
we always have to make sure.
I think I know him now.
I'm driving back East, you know,
you'd better come with me.
-All right.
Let's get goin'.
Get all the things together.
After we leave,
I want this place cleaned up.
You won't be coming back here.
Why not ?
You think they got
the place spotted ?
I'm making sure.
You'll have to find another
place and store all this stuff.
It's not gonna be easy.
-It's your job.  If you can't handle it,
I'll have to get someone else.
All right.
I'll handle it.
You'll need
some clothes.
Size 42?
What'll we do about these ?
How did you manage
to break them ?
On an automobile fan.
I think that's very bright of you.
I think we can even take care of that.
But let's get started
now.
[ Thud ]
Did you hear
something ?
Where does that lead to ?
-Just another room.
The way out.
You see, we figure that Kane and the other
fellows are probably headin' for New York.
If there's anything I can do.
-We sure appreciate that.
Why, anyone would have done the same thing.
-That's right.
This war sure makes a difference.
Everybody wants to get in and pitch.
Now, if you'll give me your address
in New York, Miss Martin,
we can contact you
back there.
Or maybe you could wire me
about which plane you're taking...
We may want
to get a hold of you fast.
I can do that when I
get back to my uncle.
-Okay, Miss Martin, just keep in touch.
I'm glad we came this way.
It adds a few miles, to our trip...
but somehow, I've become
a little sentimental.
I want to take
a last look at it.
Beautiful, isn't it ?
A great monument to man's unceasing industry...
and to his stubborn
faith in the future.
You'll be moving along soon.
Are you carrying any cameras
or firearms at all ?
Nothing at all, officer.
-You, sir ?
No, sir.
They must get a lot of power
from this dam.
I think it supplies about 75%
for the Los Angeles district,
naturally, including most of the power
for the defense plants there.
-Do you think there's a...
-Do you know Tobin very well ?
No.  I met him just that once at his ranch.
-Did he have the child with him ?
His grandchild ?  Yes.  He seemed to be
very fond of her.
Yes.  That's one of the things
I like about old Tobin:
his love for that little girl.
Evidence of a good heart.
I have children too, you know ?
-Oh ?
Two boys.  Nice little fellows.
Aged two and four.
The four-year-old
is naughty at times.
He's quite a problem.
We get him a new toy and within
half-an-hour it's smashed to bits.
And then, sometimes,
after it's all over,
he seems almost sorry.
Sometimes I wish my younger child
had been a girl.
In fact, my wife and I often argue
over a little idiosyncrasy I have.
I don't want his hair cut short
until he's much older.
Do you think it'd be bad for him ?
-Well, I don't know, it might be.
When I was a child,
I had long golden curls.
People used to stop
on the street to admire me.
Things are different nowadays.
If you gave the kid a haircut,
it might save him a lot of grief.
Ah, we're on our way.
[ Singing together--to Tune of: Tchaikovsky
Piano Concerto No. 1 (Tonight We Love) ]
# We love #
# While the moon #
# Beams down in dream light #
# Tonight #
# We touch the stars #
# Love is ours #
# Like winds that sigh #
# Embrace the sky #
# Tonight we love #
# In the glow #
# That blows so softly #
# I know #
Drive to 401...instead of the office.
-Okay.
Anything wrong ?
-Funny, I've just called the office.
They've disconnected the phone.
Same old phone company...
Should've paid the bill !
-This is no time for jokes !
The police.  They're watching the office.
The disconnected phone, that's our signal.
Think they're watching for me ?
-I don't know.
Who'd know you
were in New York ?
Well, yeah,
I guess you're right.
How about Brooklyn tomorrow ?
Do you want me on the job ?
When are you gonna learn
to keep your mouth shut ?
Sorry.  I...I thought
he was in on it.
Shut up.
It's all right.  I'm good at keeping secrets.
Let's go.
[ Clerk ]  Mr. Freeman....
Hi, Mr. Freeman.
-Hello.
#  [ Dance Band Nearby ]
Ah, pleased to see you !  Have a good trip ?
Yes.  Thank you, Robert.
-Madam is upstairs, she's waiting anxiously.
Oh, thank you, Robert.
We'll go right up.
This way.
Who was that ?
# [ Band Continues ] #
Hey, is this a hotel ?
What's the festivity ?
It's for a very worthy cause.  Mrs. Sutton
often gives her house over to charity affairs.
She's a very generous woman, but she
isn't going to be pleased to see us
on a night like this.
[ Knocking on Door ]
[ Woman ]  Idiots, all of you.
Stupid, inefficient idiots.
Everything is left to me.  I have to
hover over all you like an old hen.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Sutton.
-The guests expect me to put in an appearance.
After all, as you say, they want
something for their $25 !
I will not have
my benevolence abused.
My life, my position,
they're...important to me.
I'll do my best, Mrs. Sutton.
-I just wish your best were a little better.
Oh.  Mr. Freeman,
I'm glad you've come at this time.
I was just telling Edward...
Is this the young man ?
Must you bring him here  as well?
I certainly can't furnish him with sanctuary.
This house is full of guests,
important people !
Don't you understand my position ?
The police are already watching your office.
Thank goodness they'll never come here.
But a little more of your stupid behavior,
and even the respectability
of my house won't shield you.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Sutton,  we can't
leave any loose ends.
All right, all right !  But for heaven's sake,
stop playing the conspirator !
Now tell me all you know
about the girl, or ask him.
Why didn't you tell me
about the young lady
back in Soda City ?
Well, I...I didn't think
it was important.
She was just a girl, like anybody else.
She picked me up.  She was pretty.
I guess it was kind of risky.
Well, there you are.
I'm so sorry to have exposed
you to any risk.
What's she doing here ?
You're surprised to see me again.
-How did you get here ?
It doesn't matter.  There was
no reason to bring her at all !
You see, I just learned on the
telephone at the gas station...
that she was most indiscreet
after she left you at Soda City.
She went to the local sheriff; who,
fortunately, happened to be a
particularly good friend of ours.
Don't waste time in explanations.
You've got to get the girl
out of this house.
I will not have my benevolence abused !
So you played smart. That's great.
That's a big help to all of us.
No, I wasn't smart at all.
I haven't been smart for four days.
Even when I went to the sheriff, I hesitated.
I hated to do anything that
might get you into trouble.
Yeah, I sympathize.  The mistake
I made was not leaving you with the snakes !
You might have learned to rattle.
I was right about you.
Good evening, Mr. Kane.
I didn't know you were a bookworm.
You must let me choose something
appropriate for you. Something not
too difficult for you to understand.
Let me see.
Here we are.
This'll do admirably.
Remarkable work.
Somehow prophetic.
Why are you here, Charles ?
And, what's all this nonsense about books ?
I am a refugee.
I have at last joined that
revolting group of world travelers.
One ultimately turns into the thing
one despises most.
And whom have I to thank for it ?
You, Mr. Freeman.
The girl was allowed to escape
unobserved.  She left Mr. Kane and
went straight to her uncle.
That charming old man
went to the police.
As a result, a whole hoard
of officers came to my house.
Luckily, I was leaving
when they arrived.
And the others...
the very loyal ones...
Well, they're paying for their loyalty.
How appalling !
Your charming house.
I'm so sorry, Charles.
Rather lucky.  You might have
been sorrier.
And you might have been a little more
efficient in this matter,  Mr. Freeman.
What good is it to insult me ?
We're in trouble now.
So the most important thing is to
make sure of everyone around us.
Mr. Kane.  I'm just not sure.
I want to know that he's all right.
[ Tobin ]  All right ?
What an understatement!
He's much more than that !
He's noble and fine and pure.
And so, he pays the penalty that the noble
and the fine and the pure must pay
in this world:
he's misjudged by everyone.
Why, even the police have a
completely erroneous impression of him.
I can assure you that,
contrary to what is supposed,
and to what he may have told you,
that young man is certainly not one
of his country's enemies.
[ Mrs. Sutton ]  Charles, you're joking !
-I mean exactly what I say.
Mr. Kane is definitely no part
of our little organization.
Your protege.  Well, you've done splendidly.
You bring him here, you idiot !
What in heaven's name
are we going to do with him ?
That's a very appropriate question.
Not much we can do with him.
I made the mistake once of
turning him over to the police.
That's even more impossible at the moment.
I'm afraid there's only
one thing we can do.
You see, the new law threatens all of...
us...with the death penalty.
So I'm afraid we'll have to apply
the ancient axiom:  a tooth for a tooth.
A Kane for a Tobin.
Please don't discuss things
of that sort here.
It's rather nauseating and quite out of place.
Oh, Charles, I'm frightened.
We must take all precaution.
-Of course, we must also continue
with our work.
It's too risky now.  We're abandoning
the dam.  We must remain inactive for a while.
Inactive ?  You are utterly mistaken.
Once we do that, our organization is finished.
We must carry on at all cost.
- What about tomorrow's work ?
Tomorrow's work ?  You can't
abandon that after all your preparations.
-But Charles,  the risk !
Is great !  I know that.
Unfortunately, we will have
to carry out our orders.
I'm leaving for the Caribbean now.
My position here is more impossible
than all of yours.
I'm rather looking forward
to Central America.
Havana will be very gay this season.
You know, somehow I've suddenly
had enough of this country.
The war has made it grim.
You're leaving us here to face
everything, and you'll be on a boat...
sailing along...it all sounds idyllic.
Oh, Charles, Charles,
It's...This whole thing...It's impossible !
It's...panicky.
-I'm deeply sorry.
Ah, there you are, darling !
How unbecoming for a hostess
to hide herself away.
Am I intruding ?  I'm so sorry, but I just
must kidnap Henrietta.  She'll be back.
I've had some trouble with these people.
They're doing the catering.  And making a
rather horrid mess of everything!
Our boy will appear any minute
with the caviar !  I assure you !
[ Tobin ]  Don't be a fool !
Get to the house phone.
How'd you get here ?
-They met me at the airport.
I thought they were the police.
Wait a minute.  No use
trying the way I came in.
Let's walk right out through
the front door !  Might as well !
Yes, sir !  We'll watch the back exit.
They won't get out.
# [ Dance Band ]
No good.  See the one on the other side ?
He's one of them.  We'll never get out that way !
What can they do ?
Plenty.  They'd grab us.
We wouldn't have a chance.
These people would see them.
If anyone had a question,
we're gate crashers.
[ Exhales ]  Barry, this is awful !
It's like a bad dream.  All these people.
Isn't there anyone we can trust ?
Sure.  All of them.
Only which one ?
Excuse me.  Uh, this may
sound sort of crazy.
I don't even know
how to start.
But this whole house is a hotbed
of spies and saboteurs.
I'm not being silly.  I assure you,
even our hostess, Mrs. Sutton...
What's the matter
with you, sir ?  You're drunk.
You're not even dressed.
What'd he say ?
He thinks I'm drunk.
[ Guest ] When I read in the papers
what those Japs are doing...
[ Man Snapping Fingers ]  Beat it out !
Eight to the bar.
Yeah, man.  Stay in there and pitch.
#  [ Swing ]
Pardon me.  Did you pay $25
to get in here tonight ?
No, not exactly. The boss gave
me a ticket.  Why ?
I need your help.  We're in the middle
of the biggest fifth columnists in this country.
Are you kiddin' ?  What's the gag ?
-No.  I'm on the level.
Aw, you're kiddin' ?  We got a wagon to join,
The guy's tryin' to rib me.
Aw, sling him your curve.
Beat it out, son; beat it out!
Excuse me, sir.  I'd like to talk to you
about something very important.
What is it, Mr. Kane ?
You know it's hopeless.
Why don't you join Mr. Tobin
upstairs in a little supper ?
I'll show you the way.
Barry, before they get to us, stop
the music and tell them !
Tell them all !
This is the Sutton mansion.  I'm just
a guy from Glendale, California,
wanted by the police.
They'll grab me as soon
as I open my mouth.
What are you gonna do ?  We can't
just stand here.  I know where we'll be safe.
[ # ]
Barry, I'm scared.
It's so unreal, all these people dancing
and having a good time.
And when you try to warn them,
they laugh at you.
They think you're drunk. That grey-haired
man you spoke to seemed like such
an honest citizen.
Mmm, just a friend of the family.  I guess
the room's well sprinkled with them.
They're so smart.
That's what frightens me.
Yeah, they're smart,
because they're ruthless.
It's easy to win when you
forget about the rules.
[ Sighs ] A man named Fry drops
a wallet in California,
and we wind up here,
you and me.
That's the only good part:
I'm with you.
I wish it were somewhere else...
the North Pole...I wouldn't care.
We might wind up there too, chasing
Fry over an old glacier !
[ Chuckles ]
Fry.  He seems so small now.
I'd forgotten about him.
So had I.
We can't just go on dancing
like it's Saturday night
at the Palladium.
We can't just wait
'til they get us.
What do you think
they'll really do ?
Well, right now, they're probably haggling
over the price with Murder, Incorporated.
Oh, Barry, please !
-Sorry, Pat,  I hate to be out of it now,
there's still so much to do.
If staying alive was ever important.
You heard what they said...
Something about a job they're going
to do tomorrow in Brooklyn.
The navy yard.
-One of us has got to get out of here.
Maybe if I start something,
you can make a break for it.
What about you ?
-You can't worry about me, we've
gotta take a chance.
[ Sighs ] Oh, Barry, why couldn't I have
met you a hundred years ago ?
On a beach somewhere.
Bathing suits looked awfully funny
a hundred years ago.
I'll bet you'd look
beautiful though.
Afraid we're not behaving
very well.
What's the difference ?
We weren't invited anyway.
Pat, this moment
belongs to me.
No matter what happens,
they can never take it away
from me.
Oh, pardon me.
Do you mind ?
Oh, excuse me. Would you, uh...
Would you care to dance ?
Why, yes.  Certainly.
Oh, you're really
a much better dancer.
Thanks.  Who was the man
you were dancing with ?
I have no idea.
I never saw him before.
No, I mean the man
that just left you.
I know.  That's who I'm
talking about.  I never
saw him before in my life.
Oh, what a pity.
That was lovely.  I hope
you will ask me again.
Oh, thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Well, young man, you seem to
be enjoying yourself.
Charming party, isn't it ?
Where is she ?
-Your young lady ?  I thought
you were taking care of her.
Perhaps she has a headache
and is lying down somewhere.
Would you like to come with me
and look for her ?
Hold on.
Ladies and Gentlemen.
Ladies and Gentlemen !
Your attention, please.
I...I have something
to tell you.
Something you ought to know about
this house and about your hostess.
Sir, before you go on, take a look
at the curtain on the balcony.
I'm...uh, not much
of a...public speaker,
Ladies and Gentlemen,
and, uh...
some of you are probably wondering
how I can tell you anything
about your hostess...
that you, uh...
you don't already know...
her graciousness,
her kindness,
her many charities.
Well, I want to tell you that you
have a big surprise coming,
Ladies and Gentlemen.
Tonight, in this house, for the benefit
of this great cause...
for which she's already done so much,
our hostess, Mrs. Sutton, is
putting up for auction...
one of her most
treasured possessions,
one of the famous Sutton jewels.
Mrs. Sutton, would you
kindly step forward ?
Thank you.
- Mr. Kane, the young lady
is asking to see you.
Are you sure ?
-I wouldn't keep her waiting
if I were you, sir.
Yes.  Uh...
Will someone please, uh,
uh...Admiral ?
Would you take over for me, please ?
I'm wanted on the phone.
Delighted, sir.
-Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, I will
entertain your bids for this
beautiful bracelet...
which has been donated
by our hostess, Mrs. Sutton.
What am I bid ?
-[ Man ] One thousand dollars.
$1,000. has been bid.
Do I have any more ?
[ Guest ] Fifteen hundred.
-$1,500. has been bid.
Do I hear..?
[ Guest ] 1,750.
-$1,750. has been bid...
[ Man ] Two thousand.
[ Admiral ]  $2,000. has been bid...
Where is she ?
You seem to have a soft spot
for that young lady.
You can't afford to make
yourself that vulnerable...
not when you're out trying
to...save your country.
Why is it you sneer every time
you refer to this country.  You've
done well here, I don't get it.
No, you wouldn't. You're one
of the ardent believers...
a good American...
all the millions like you, people
who plod along without
asking questions.
I hate to use the word stupid,
but it seems to be the only
one that applies...
the great masses,
the moron millions.
Well, there are a few of us who are
unwilling to just troop along;
a few who are clever enough to see
that there's much more to be done...
than just live small,
complacent lives;
a few of us in America, who
desire a more...profitable
type of government.
When you think about it,
Mr. Kane,
the competence of totalitarian
nations is much higher than ours.
They get things done.
Yeah.  They get things done.
They bomb cities, sink ships,
torture and murder...
so you and your friends can eat
off a gold plate.  It's
a great philosophy.
I neither intend to be bombed
nor sunk, Mr. Kane.
That's why I'm leaving now.
And if things don't go right for you...
If, uh, WE should win...
then I'll come back.
Perhaps I can get
what I want then: Power.
Yes.  I want that as much as you
want your comfort or your job...
or...that girl.
We all have different
tastes, as you can see.
Only I'm willing to back my tastes
...with the necessary force.
You certainly make it sound
smooth and easy.
Well, that's a trick.
I know the results of
that power you believe in.
It killed my friend, and it's
killing thousands like him.
That's what
you're aiming at.
And it doesn't bother you,
I can see that.
Because you
really hate all people.
Let me tell you something.
The last four or five days
I've learned a lot.
I've met guys like you,
and I've met others--
people that are helpful and
eager to do the right thing,
people that get a kick out of
helping each other fight the bad guys.
Love and hate.
The world's choosing up sides.
I know who I'm with.
There are a lot of people on my side...
millions of us in every country.
And we're not soft;
we're plenty strong.
And we'll fight standing up on
our two feet, and we'll win !
Remember that, Mr. Tobin, We'll win,
no matter what you guys do.
We'll win if it takes from now
until the cows come home !
Mr. Kane, I think we've discussed
the rights of man sufficiently.
[ Yawning ] I'm feeling a little tired.
You must be too.
Robert, do you think you can
arrange for Mr. Kane to sleep
somewhere tonight ?
Yes, sir.
Certainly, sir.
That's enough, Robert.
-Very good, sir.
Think you can take care of this ?
-Yes, sir.
Will that be all, sir ?
-Yes, thank you.
#  [ Continues ]
It doesn't matter what
arrangements we've made,
to what trouble we've gone.
This whole job hangs
on one thing: timing.
If the section of the slipway goes up
before the actual launching,
then all our efforts have been wasted.
If you blow her too late,
then you just scare the crowd.
Timing, timing, timing.
That button must not be pressed
until the ship starts to move.
What arrangements
have been made for getting out of there ?
As soon as the cables are unhooked,
this truck goes.
We got it fixed at the gate.
Who's handling the camera
near the slipway ?
-I am.
The wires to the explosives were
laid last night.  All I have to do is
to hook them up to the camera.
Too bad we have to
lose a good camera.
Well, everything seems to be taken
care of.  I'll be waiting for you
at the newsreel office.
Good luck.
- Have they gone ?
- Yes.
How is she ?
-Okay.  She's having her breakfast.
Any trouble keeping her quiet ?
-No.  I made a deal with her.
You see, she got tired of
having that adhesive tape
over her eyes and mouth.
Well, I hope you get rid
of her soon.
I promised to take my kid sister
to the Philharmonic.
Give me the key.
-There it is.
I'm sorry we couldn't keep
you at the house,
but Mrs. Sutton has a limited
number of guest rooms,
and I suppose Mr. Kane
was first in line.
Where am I ?
-Oh, that's a trade secret.
I only hope it isn't too high
for you here.
Mr. Kane's quarters are nearer
the ground, but he's being
well looked after...
and, like you, is probably
enjoying a hearty breakfast.
[ Alarm Ringing ]
[ All Shouting ]
[ Alarm Continues ]
[ Man ] Somebody get the fire hose !
Whose place is that ?
-That's Mrs. Sutton's  house.
Oh.  Who's she ?
-Some rich dame.
Saw something in the paper about
her doing things for charity.
Right here, somewhere....
Here.
[ Man ]  What about tomorrow's work ?
[ Tobin ]  Tomorrow's work ?
Can't abandon that after
all your preparations.
[ Mrs. Sutton ]  But, Charles, the risk--
-Is great !  I know that.
Unfortunately, we will
have to carry out our orders.
- What's the time ?
- 10:50.
Thanks.
Brooklyn Navy Yard, quick !
[ Door Opening ]
How much ?
Fifteen.
Got change ?
Yes.
[ Radio Announcer ]  Courtesy of the
Navy Department, we take you
to the navy yard,
where we will endeavor to
bring you a description...
of the launching ceremony
of the Navy's Capitol Ship,
the  U.S.S. Alaska.
And so without further ado, we
switch you now to the
Brooklyn Navy Yard.
Here we are.  A rather windy autumn
day, but a pretty good day
for a launching.
I guess, any day is a good day
for a launching in these times.
Our microphones are
located in several key spots.
So, we will be able to bring you...
What's holding us up ?
Traffic, buddy.
What do you think ?
[ Radio Continues... ]
Here.  I'll walk.
Okay.
[ Radio Announcer ]
The main speaker
is about to begin.
Ladies and Gentlemen, I am now
turning you over to Bill Donnan,
located on the actual platform.
Go ahead, Bill.
This is Bill Donnan.  We're located
right below the hull of the great ship.
It towers over us like some
enormous monster.  This platform
on which...
Take me to the guy in charge !
Okay.  I'll take care of this.
What do you want ?
Something's gonna happen...Sabotage!
Where'd you get your information ?
I can't go into that now,
there isn't time !
What can I do?  We gotta have
a little more than that to go on.
Better  come into the office
and tell the chief.
-There isn't time !
What do you expect me to do?
-Take me to the guy in charge
of the launching.
You gotta go through
the office first.
Towley, 1050.
[ Radio Announcer ]  Crowded
at the moment with all kinds of navy
officers and personnel.
I can see in the group to
my left, Rear Admiral Pierce
and Mrs. Pierce.
It is Mrs. Pierce who will
perform the actual
bottle breaking today.
She is shaking hands with
a great many people down
there, right now.
Just a second, Ladies and Gentlemen...
I see Rear Admiral Pierce
moving toward the microphone.
Yes.  I think he's going
to begin his speech now.
We'll switch you over
to the speaker's microphone.
[ Admiral ]  The launching of a ship
in time of war...
is always a solemn occasion.
Today, when our fleet is
fighting on all the seven seas,
this ceremony
gains magnitude...
for it represents for the
American People a victory....
Where'd that guy go ?
-I don't know. He just
stepped outside.
[ Admiral On Radio ]
...by the strong hands
of American workmen.
- Let us rejoice, then, at this
moment.  Let us be confident...
[ Piling Crashes ]
...work together
to show the world
what Americans can do.
Our American soldiers...
are freely giving their lives so
that we in this country can live
in decency, security and peace.
This is Bill Donnan again,
Ladies and Gentlemen...
You've just heard
Rear Admiral Pierce speaking
from the Brooklyn Navy Yard.
His speech is being received
with great applause...
Shut the back doors !  Quick !
I can handle this !  Be ready to
pull out as soon as she goes.
[ Radio Announcer ] A Naval officer is
handing her a bottle of champagne that
is tied to the ship above her...
[ Door Slams ]
[ Bell Clanging ]
The crowd is tense.
It is indeed a solemn occasion.
I switch you over to our microphone
near the bow of the ship...
so that you may hear
the actual launching.
Now I can see that Mrs. Pierce
is moving towards the bow of the ship.
I'll switch you over now to Mrs. Pierce.
[ Mrs. Pierce ]In the name of the people
of the United States,
I christen thee Alaska.
[ Bottle Breaking ]
# [ Band:  "Columbia,
The Gem Of The Ocean" ]
[ Explosion ]
[ Ship's Whistle Blaring ]
[ People Yelling ]
[Truck Starting and Moving Out ]
[ Truck Horn ]
What's the trouble ?
-Don't know.  An explosion somewhere.
[ City Traffic Sounds ]
[ Brakes Sqealing ]
[Truck Door Slamming]
[ Whispers ]  George !
Everything okay ?
-No.  Give us a hand.  We got a guy.
[ Truck Door Opening ]
[ Multiple Footsteps Down Hall ]
[ Simultaneous Gunshots ]
Better scatter. Go down  through the
iron door into the music hall.
We'll go this way.
[ Door Sliding Open ]
[ People Laughing ]
[ Actress ]  You must go at once,
before Henry catches you here !
[ Actor ] See here, I thought you wanted
to make the old boy jealous.
[ Actress ] Not anymore.  He's threatened
to kill you on sight.
[ Audience Laughs ]
[ Actor ]  Oh, I say, you don't think
he'd go that far, do you ?
[ Actress ] Oh, will you go before it's too
late ?  Before he shoots you to death?
- [ Audience Laughing ]
-[ Actor ]  Are you trying to tell me
old Henry's got a gun ?  A real gun ?
[ Actress ]  Oh !
[ Older Actor ] What do you think this is ?
...I've caught you,
you rat in the grass !
- [ Gunshots ]
- [ Actress ]  Stop that !
Run, Wilbur !
Run, before he gets your range !
I think I got it now.
Get out before I shoot again !
[ Gunshot ]
[ Actress ]
Run !  Quick !
[ Gunshot ]
[ Actor ]  Never touched me !
[ Older Actor ]
I'll get you this time.
[ Moviegoer ] My husband !  He's shot !
I'll kill the rat
if it's the last thing I do !
[ Gunshot ]
He was only kidding.
I swear !
And I'm only kidding too !
[ Gunshots ]
Get outta here !
[ Actress ]  He's gone mad !  Mad !
- [ Older Actor ]  Get out !  Get out !
-[ Gunshots ]
[ Actress ]  Not that way !
He'll kill you !
[ Actor ] Murder !  Help !
[ Actress ]  Run !  Run !
- [ Actress ]  Run for your life !
-[ Gunshots ]
[ Moviegoers Yelling ]
There he goes !  He's the one you're after !
You're the one we're after.  Come on !
-I tell you he's the one you're after,
he'll get away !
Come on !
Grab a cab and go after him, and
don't lose him...
It's our only chance !
Taxi !
Downtown.
-Whereabouts ?
Anywhere.  Just
keep goin' downtown.
#  [Tense ]
May I have change
for the telephone ?
-Yes, ma'am.
[ Cash Register Rings ]
There you are.
[Coin Drops]
[Dialing Operator ]
Operator ?  Give me the F.B.I.
headquarters, please.
Federal Bureau
of Investigation.
Hold on,
I'll put you through.
Make sure he doesn't
leave by the next boat.
Talk to him.  Follow him !
Keep him there
until our men come along.
The girl thinks she's traced Fry to
Bedloe Island.  She's crazy!
He'd never go there !
Where did you pick up Schultz last month?
-In that museum, that modern art place.
And Renaldo ?  You caught him
looking at the fish in the
aquarium, didn't you?
Yeah, but the statue's a
dead end.  That's why he's smart!
You better get going!
Let me take him along in any case,just
to make sure the girl
hasn't made a mistake.
Burke, you're one of the most obstinate
men I've ever met !  Get going.
-Come On!
[ Clears Throat ]
Pardon me.  Could you tell me
which is Brooklyn ?
I've seen you before, haven't I ?
Sure.
On that boat comin' over.
What'd you ask me ?
About Brooklyn, I was wondering
where it was...
I've heard so much about it!
Over there.
Where are you from ?
-New York.
What are you handin' me ?
-Oh, no.  You see, I work
in a store downtown.
And I never get
a chance to get out.
I just sit around all day,
and I never see anything.
So I said to myself:   the first
vacation I get, I'm going to see
the Statue of Liberty.
This must be a big
moment for you, huh ?
Oh, it is...and it means
so much to us now !
Why, I was just reading
in this booklet...
Did you know this statue
was given to us by the French ?
You know what they
had written on it ?
"Give me your tired, your poor,
your huddled masses...
"yearning to breathe free;
"the wretched refuse
of your teeming shore.
Send these: the homeless,
tempest-tossed to me."
And just look at the French!
Isn't it sad ?
-Yeah.  Very sad.
Oh, it's such a beautiful statue.
I could just sit up here all day
thinking about it...couldn't you ?
Some other day, maybe,
not right now.
Right now I gotta
catch that boat back.
You comin' ?
Well, there's another boat
in 15 minutes.
Couldn't we wait ?
All the people have gone, and
we'd be alone...just you and me.
Sounds cozy.
But I...I haven't got the time.
Oh, on a nice autumn day like this,
you couldn't spare 15 minutes for me ?
I don't like autumn.
You're not being very
nice to a lonely girl.
You look as though you
might be lonely too.
Yeah.
I gotta catch that boat.
Fifteen minutes shouldn't make
such a big difference, Mr. Fry!
Who are ya ?
Come on.  Quit stalling.
I think I told you...
a working girl on her day off.
Don't chide me !
What are you doin' here ?
It's rather a long story, Mr. Fry.
It all started with
an unknown blonde,
...an aircraft worker at a
factory in Glendale, California.
I get it.
Little Miss Liberty,
carryin' the torch.
Why'd you follow me ?
-Why do you think ?
Take a look down there. If you can't
figure it out for yourself...
they're coming for you!
#  [Tense ]
[ Visitors Chattering ]
Do you see him in this bunch ?
-No.
Barnes, you stay here and watch
this end.  The rest of you fellows,
come with me.
You two, watch that side.
I'm going up.
Barry !
Pat, where is he ?
He started down !
Are you sure ?
[ Clatter ]
He's up here !  Come on !
Come on, Fry !
I'll get your sleeve.
[ Ship's Horn ]
Don't you go over !  If you slip,
that'll be three gone !
Quick !  Get a rope.
- Can you get a grip
with your feet ?
- I can't.
Kane, I'm
getting a rope !
- They're getting a rope.  Hold on, Fry.
- I'll clear you.
I swear I will.
I'll clear you.
- Hurry-up with the rope !
Tell them quick.
The sleeve.
Sleeve !
Kane !
[ Woman Screams ]
[ Ship's Horns ]
#  #  [Triumphal]