In the last century before the birth
of the new faith called Christianity:::
which was destined to overthrow
the pagan tyranny of Rome
and bring about a new society:::
the Roman Republic stood at the very
centre of the civilised world:
'Of all things fairest, ''
sang the poet:::
'first among cities and home
of the gods is golden Rome: ''
Yet, even at the zenith
of her pride and power:::
the Republic lay fatally stricken
with a disease called::: human slavery:
The age of the dictator
was at hand:::
waiting in the shadows
for the event to bring it forth:
In that same century:::
in the conquered
Greek province of Thrace:::
an illiterate slave woman
added to her master's wealth:::
by giving birth to a son
whom she named Spartacus:
A proud, rebellious son:::
who was sold to living death
in the mines of Libya:::
before his thirteenth birthday:
There, under whip and chain and sun:::
he lived out his youth
and his young manhood:::
dreaming the death of slavery 2,000
years before it finally would die:
Back to work!
Get up, Spartacus, you Thracian dog!
Come on, get up!
Aaah!
My ankle, my ankle!
My ankle!
Guard, guard.
Spartacus again?
Well, this time he dies:
Back to work, all of you.
- Welcome, Lentulus Batiatus.
- Welcome, indeed, my dear captain.
Oh, eleven miles
through this disastrous heat...
and the cost of hiring
an escort... ruinous.
Even so, I warrant you have
nothing fit to sell me.
I've wasted my time and my money.
- Tell me the truth.
- We have a few you
might be interested in.
These? Carrion!
The buzzards are late:
This one's not bad.
He's a Gaul.
I don't like Gauls.
Hairy.
Can he come down unassisted?
[ Captain ]
Come down, you!
Come down!
- Be good enough
to show me the... teeth.
- Open your mouth!
Thank you.
Yes... as the teeth go,
so go the bones.
This mouth is
really impermissible.
- The fellow's made of chalk.
- We have many others!
The sun's over there.
I have to pay these people.
- Who's that?
- This one's a Thracian.
- I'm making an example of him.
- How?
Starve him to death.
It's the only thing impresses slaves.
What a pity.
He reacts.
Good muscle tone.
Can I see his teeth?
Open your mouth, Spartacus!
You smell like a rhinoceros.
Captain, you asked him
to open his mouth.
- He doesn't obey you?
- His teeth are the best thing
about him:
- He hamstrung a guard with them
not more than an hour ago:
- Marvellous!
I wish I'd been here:
I'll take him:
Let's look at some of the others:
Come along!
In spite of sickness and death...
we will profit 1 1 ,000 sesterces!
Including your commission,
of course.
Oh, no, sir.
Without my commission.
Marcellus, there they are.
They're a dirty-looking lot,
but the best I could find.
No one else could have made
so fine a choice.
[ Whistle ]
[ Batiatus ] Slaves...
you have arrived at the gladiatorial
school of Lentulus Batiatus:
You'll be trained by experts
to fight in pairs to the death:
You won't fight
to the death here:
That will be after you've been sold...
and then for ladies
and gentlemen of quality...
for those who appreciate
a fine kill.
A gladiator's like a stallion:
He must be pampered.
You'll be oiled, bathed...
shaved, massaged,
taught to use your heads:
A good body with a dull brain:::
is as cheap as life itself!
You'll be given
your ceremonial caudas.
Marcellus, please.
There.
Be proud of them.
On special occasions,
those who please me...
will even be given
the companionship of a young lady.
Approximately half our graduates...
live for five, ten, ten years.
Some even attain freedom:::
and become trainers themselves.
Marcellus.
I congratulate you.
And may fortune smile
on most of you.
[ Whistle ]
Marcellus, watch the second
from the right.
He's a Thracian. They were going
to kill him for hamstringing a guard.
- We'll break him of that.
- Don't overdue it. He has quality.
Aaah!
Next.
[ Groan ]
I like you.
I want you to be my friend.
I want to be your friend.
All I ask
is that you get along with me.
What's your name, slave?
Spartacus.
I feel you don't like me.
Give him your sword.
Take it!
I have a feeling
you want to kill me.
This is the only chance
you'll ever get.
Kill me!
Don't be afraid, slave.
You have that sword.
I only have this piece of wood!
Are you going to disobey me?
[ Chuckle ]
Take his sword:
You're not as stupid
as I thought.
You might even be intelligent.
That's dangerous for slaves:
You just remember:::
from now on everything you do
I'll be watching.
You did the right thing.
Every once in a while...
Marcellus likes to kill
a man as an example.
I think he's picked you.
Better watch him.
- How long have you been here?
- Six months.
I wish he'd pick me.
I want one chance at that pig
before they carry me out!
Quiet!
No talking down there:
Dionysius, you'll
get us in trouble...
just like in the mines.
What's your name?
You don't want to know my name.
I don't want to know your name!
Just a friendly question.
Gladiators don't make friends.
If we're ever matched
in the arena together...
I'll have to kill you.
Helena...
with Galino.
Patricia...
Crixus.
Priscilla...
David.
Claudia...
Pharox.
Varinia...
- Dionysius.
- No, no. Spartacus.
Spartacus.
Felicia:::
I've never had a woman.
[ Batiatus ] You have one now,
Spartacus. You must take her.
- Go away.
- What will she think of you?
Indeed, what will I think of you?
- Go away.
- Come, come. Be generous.
We must learn
to share our pleasures.
I'm not an animal!
You're not trying to escape,
by any chance?
Direct your courage
to the girl, Spartacus:
I'm not an animal!
- I'm not an animal:
- Neither am I.
What's your name?
Varinia.
You'll have to take her
out of here, Marcellus.
You may not be an animal:::
but this sorry show
gives me little hope:::
that you'll ever be a man.
[ Marcellus ]
First rule:::you get
an instant kill on the red:
Here... here.
Always remember,
go for the red first.
If you don't,
your opponent will.
In the blue,
you get a cripple.
Here...
here... here... and here.
Second rule...
go for the cripple
before the slow kill.
Here's a slow kill
on the yellow.
Here... here... and here.
Remember...
a slow kill may have enough left
to kill you before he dies.
With a cripple,
you know you've got him...
if you keep your distance
and wear him down:
The rest is all right
for a public spectacle in Rome:::
but here at Capua we expect
more than simple butchery:::
and we get it.
Spartacus, why are you
looking at that girl?
Varinia! Stand still:
Since all he can do
is look at girls...
all right, slave,
go ahead and look.
I said, look!
No. No, this one
goes to the Spaniard.
Have a good night's rest,
Spartacus.
[ Marcellus ]
In there:
[ Laughter ]
[ Door Closes, Locks ]
Woman!
I've warned you
about this kind of thing.
All right, bring them in.
No talking!
Move along.
[ Whispering ]
Did they hurt you?
No.
That's a kill.
One... two...
three... four... five.
three... four.
We have visitors,
tremendous visitors!
Two simply enormous Roman lords
on the hill.
How easily impressed
you are, Ramon.
Just 'cause they're Romans,
I guess they're enormous.
Tell them to wait for me
when they arrive.
- Master, you don't understand!
- How enormous
do these Roman lords get?
One of them is
Marcus Licinius Crassus.
What?
Wait a minute.
Crassus here?
My red toga with the acorns.
Chairs in the atrium.
Second-best wine.
No, the best,
but small goblets.
Gracchus! You know
how Crassus loathes him.
- Take him away.
- I can't lift it.
Use your imagination!
Cover him.
Tell Marcellus
to get the men ready.
Crassus has expensive taste.
He'll want a show.
Forgive me, Gracchus.
Marcus Licinius Crassus...
Most Noble Radiance...
first general of the Republic...
father and defender of Rome,
honour my house.
Bless it with your presence.
Wine! Sweetmeats!
Can't you see that
Their Honours are exhausted?
Have the goodness to sit.
Is anything wrong, Your Nobility?
No.
Welcome to the Lady Claudia Maria...
former wife
of Lucius Caius Marius...
whose recent execution
touched us all deeply.
Honour to the Lady Helena...
daughter of the late
Septimus Optimus Glabrus...
whose fame shall live on forever...
in the person of his son,
your brother.
Marcus Publius Glabrus...
hero of the Eastern Wars.
How very much he knows.
Allow me to bring you up-to-date.
We're here to celebrate the marriage
of my brother to the Lady Claudia.
A mating of eagles!
Your Sanctity!
Fan His Magnitude.
He sweats.
My young friends desire
a private showing of two pairs.
Two pairs.
Oh, yes.
- I have something
that would please them.
- Two pairs to the death.
To the death, Your Ladyship?
Surely you don't think
we came all the way to Capua...
for gymnastics?
But I beg Your Honours.
We train the finest
gladiators in all Italy.
We can give you a display
of swordsmanship which is better
than you can see in Rome.
When they're sold, their new masters
may do with them as they wish.
But here, no, we never fight
them to the death.
Crassus.
Today is an exception.
But the ill feeling it would spread
through the whole school.
Then the cost.
Oh, the cost!
Name your price.
25,000 sesterces.
Arrange it.
Are you serious, sir?
Arrange it immediately.
Of course, we shall want
to choose them ourselves.
- You do have a certain... variety?
- Inexhaustible.
Spartacus, there's going to be
a fight to the death.
- To the death?
- How do you know?
I heard Marcellus
tell one of his guards.
- Who fights?
- I don't know.
To the death.
What if they matched you and me?
They won't.
What if they did?
Would you fight?
I'd have to. So would you.
Would you try to kill me?
Yes, I'd kill.
I'd try to stay--
I'd try to stay alive
and so would you.
[ Marcellus ]
All gladiators up to the training area:
Some visitors want to admire you:
Form a line in front of me.
Would Your Excellencies care
to make your selection now?
Claudia.
Oh, they're magnificent.
For you, Lady Helena...
may I suggest... Praxus?
A veritable tiger:
I don't like him.
- I prefer that one.
- Which one?
- No, no.
- David?
Oh, Crixus, yes:
Ah, Marcellus:::
Crixus for the short sword.
Ah!
Have you ever seen such a pair
of shoulders? Dionysius!
I admit he's small,
but he's very compact:::
and extremely strong.
In fact, he looks--
He looks smaller here
than he does in the arena.
Optical.
- Give me that one.
- Oh, Galino.
Yes, yes: Galino:
You have a shrewd eye:
Your Pulchritude,
if I many permit myself the--
Galino.
Practically every man
in this school...
is an expert
with a Thracian sword...
but the trident is something
very rare these days.
May I suggest...
the Ethiopian.
There are very few Ethiopians
in the country.
Ethiopians are recognized
as masters of the trident.
I'll take him.
Draba? Oh, no:
For you I want the best:
- I do think the Ethiopian--
- I want the most beautiful.
I'll take the big black one.
Draba.
Only one man
in the entire school...
stands a chance with the Thracian knife
against the trident.
There.
- Over there, Lady Helena.
- He's impertinent!
I'll take him:
[ Batiatus ]
And he's a coward to boot:
Have him flogged!
Over there, Lady Helena.
The beast of Libya.
I prefer the coward.
Spartacus.
If both men are down
and refuse to fight...
your trainer will slit their throats:
We want no tricks:
Tricks, madam?
At the school of Batiatus?
You heard the instruction,
Marcellus? Remember it:
I feel sorry for the
poor things in this heat.
Don't put them
in those suffocating tunics.
Let them wear just enough
for modesty.
Whatever they wear, Lady,
they'll bless your name.
[ Marcellus ]
Back, the rest of you!
Our choosing has bored you?
No, most exciting.
I tingle.
Do let's get out of the sun.
May I conduct Your Magnificences
to the gallery?
[ Crassus ]
Ah-ha! An eavesdropper.
- Oh, the gods!
- [ Laughter ]
How far from Rome must I go
to avoid that cunning face?
Don't talk about Gracchus.
He's so hateful.
For Gracchus, hatred of the patrician
class is a profession...
and not such a bad one, either.
How else can one become master
of the mob and first senator of Rome?
Crassus, it's so boring.
I believe that girl smells
of perfume.
Whatever it is,
it smells most delectable:
You can't keep slaves from stealing
unless you chain them.
When a slave's as pretty as she is,
she doesn't have to steal:
An arrangement is made:
If her ankles are good...
you can be sure
an arrangement was made!
- Oh, master!
- A catastrophe!
I've been anointed!
Why, you trollop!
You did that on purpose.
It was an accident.
Come here, girl.
Don't be frightened.
- What country are you from?
- Britannia.
How long have you been a slave?
Since I was thirteen.
You have a certain... education.
My first master had me tutored
for his children:
I like her.
She has spirit.
I'll buy her.
Buy her, Your Magnificence?
I have spent quite
a lot of money on her:
I've no doubt of it.
2,000 sesterces.
She'll be waiting at your litter:
No, I don't want her feet
spoiled by walking.
Send her to Rome with your steward
the next time he has to go there:
He leaves tomorrow,
and the girl with him:
More wine, and thank your gods!
You provoke me, Crassus.
- I shan't be nice to you any more!
- Why distress me so much?
You're horribly rich...
yet you're the only one
of my brother's friends...
who hasn't given him
a wedding present:
Ah!
I was saving it
for a more suitable moment.
Here.
Give it to him, child.
What is it?
As from this moment, your husband
is commander of the garrison of Rome.
Wonderful!
[ Clapping ] Ahh!
I don't know how I shall
ever be able to repay you.
Time will solve that mystery.
- The garrison of Rome.
- Yes:
The only power in Rome strong enough
to checkmate Gracchus and his senate.
You are clever!
Open up.
Through that door.
[ Giggling ]
You will have
to watch him, Claudia.
Father almost disinherited him
because of slave girls.
[ Claudia ] The marriage contract
absolutely forbids a harem:
[ Glabrus ]
What about your litter bearers?
Every one of them is under twenty:::
and taller than they should be:
[ Crassus ] She sets
rather a high standard for you:
[ Batiatus ]
Your pleasure, Your Highness:
[ Crassus ]
To you, my dear:::
shall go the honour
of starting this poetic drama:
[ Marcellus ]
Open up!
First pair!
Crixus and Galino!
[ Marcellus ] Those who are
about to die salute you:
[ Whistle ]
[ Swords Clashing ]
[ Thud ]
Aaah!
[ Applause ]
Crixus.
Next pair!
Those who are about to die salute you.
[ Whistle ]
[ Claudia ]
Your Thracian's doing well.
How were you able to get my appointment
without Gracchus knowing?
I fought fire with oil.
I purchased the senate behind his back.
I still think
the trident's going to win.
[ Claudia ]
Why doesn't he kill him?
[ Helena ] Kill him:
[ Claudia ]
What's the matter now?
- Kill him!
- Kill him, you imbecile! Kill him!
- Kill... oh!
He'll hang there till he rots.
[ Marcellus ]
Take a last look, Spartacus:
She's going to Rome.
She's been sold.
She's been sold?
No talking
in the kitchen, slave.
Aaah!
[ Whistle ]
There's trouble in the mess hall.
- They killed Marcellus
and maybe the other two.
- Call out the guard!
- [ Whistle ]
- Move, move!
On second thoughts,
I'll deliver the girl personally.
Ride to Capua. Call out the garrison.
I don't trust this lot.
- I hold you responsible.
- Yes, sir.
Ho!
[ Shouting ]
Aaah!
Around Capua,
they ravished the countryside...
forcing other slaves to join them.
Looting, robbing,
burning everything...
while they make their camp
in the escarpments of Vesuvius.
Each day swells their numbers.
The situation lies in the hands...
of this august body.
Where's the mighty Crassus?
- Out of the city.
- At least you're here.
No need to fear for Rome
as long as Glabrus is with us.
Let me add... over 1 00
estates have been burned...
among them, gentlemen, my own...
burned to the ground
and three million sesterces lost.
I propose the immediate recall
of Pompey and his legions from Spain.
I could raise 500 men
and bring the lot of them in.
Don't make a fool of yourself.
Why... call back the legions...
when the garrison of Rome
has nothing to do...
- but to defend us from sausage makers?
- [ Laughter ]
Let's send Glabrus
against these scoundrels!
Give 'em a taste of Roman steel.
[ Applause ]
I protest.
I most strongly protest.
There are more slaves
in Rome than Romans.
With the garrison absent,
what's to prevent them from rising too?
I did not say the whole garrison.
Six cohorts will
more than do the job.
The rest can stay in Rome
to save you from your... housemaids.
[ Laughter ]
Will you accept
such a charge, Glabrus?
I accept the charge of the senate...
if the senate truly charges me.
The garrison of Rome stands ready.
Slave hunting's a dirty business.
It takes a brave commander
to consent to it.
I propose we turn
the city out tomorrow...
in tribute to Glabrus
as he marches through:
And:::
for temporary command
of the garrison during his absence:::
I propose Caius Julius Caesar:
[ Applause ]
You don't look very happy
over the new job.
It's not a serious disturbance.
Glabrus will be back.
Maybe.
At least it gives me a chance...
to separate Glabrus
from Crassus for a while.
You know, this republic of ours...
is something like a rich widow.
Most Romans love her
as their mother.
But Crassus dreams of marrying
the old girl, to put it politely.
Hail Glabrus!
- God be with you, Glabrus.
- And with you too.
I hope he returns
to such applause.
Oh, one fat one, Fimbria!
Keep the change.
Give it to your wife.
- May the gods adore you.
- Only through your prayers.
Let's make an old-fashioned sacrifice
for Glabrus' success, hmm?
I thought you
had reservations about the gods.
Privately I believe in none.
Neither do you.
Publicly I believe in them all.
Greetings,
Marcus Clodius Flavius!
Is Marcus Glabrus in attendance?
- He awaits you in the atrium, sir.
- Excellent.
- What have we here?
- A gift from the governor of Sicily.
Antoninus...
Sicilian, age 26...
singer of songs.
For whom did you practise
this wondrous talent?
For the children of my master...
whom I also taught the classics.
Classics, indeed.
What position have we, I wonder...
for a boy of such varied gifts?
You shall be my body servant.
Instruct him.
All of you, come with me.
Are you on guard duty?
My dear Crassus,
congratulate me.
Or better still,
let us congratulate each other.
I congratulate us.
Tomorrow I lead six cohorts
of the garrison...
against the slaves on Vesuvius.
The whole city is
turning out to see us off.
Great merciful bloodstained gods!
Your pardon.
I always address heaven
in moments of triumph.
Did Gracchus have something
to do with this brilliant affair?
Yes, he proposed it.
Rather decently, too.
And you? Do you think
I made you commander...
to control some
rock patch on Vesuvius?
It was to control
the streets of Rome!
I only take six cohorts.
The rest remain.
Under whose command?
- Under Caesar's.
- Oh, excellent, excellent!
Finding Gracchus in control
of the mob and the senate...
you felt compelled to hand over
the garrison to him also:
I see.
I'll refuse,
withdraw from the expedition.
One of the disadvantages
of being a patrician...
is that occasionally
you're obliged to act like one.
You've pledged to go,
and go you must.
If Gracchus should decide
to move against you--
He won't!
Has no need to.
He has, with your assistance,
immobilized me altogether.
Your legions are in camp
outside the city walls?
My legions?
Do you truly believe I'd order
my legions to enter Rome?
You can... if you have to.
Are you not aware
of Rome's most ancient law...
that no general may enter the city
at the head of his armed legions?
- Sulla did.
- Sulla? To the infamy of his name!
To the utter damnation
of his line!
No, my young friend.
One day I shall cleanse this Rome
which my fathers bequeathed me.
I shall restore all the traditions
that made her great.
It follows that I cannot come
to power or defend myself...
by an act which betrays
the most sacred tradition of all.
I shall not bring my legions
within these walls.
I shall not violate Rome...
at the moment of possessing her.
Go.
Prepare your troops at once.
March out of Rome tonight,
but the tribute is impossible.
We've already been made
to look a fool.
Let's not add
the trappings of a clown.
Leave by unfrequented streets...
without fanfare,
without even a drum!
Sneak out.
As you wish.
And for heaven's sake,
my young friend...
see to it that you don't
have to sneak back again.
Farewell.
[ Shouting ]
[ Faint Shouting ]
A-ha-ha!
Come on, fat boy!
[ Shouting And Cheering ]
Hey, Spartacus!
Spartacus!
Noble Romans.
Fighting each other like animals!
Your new masters,
betting to see who'll die first.
[ Cheering And Laughing ]
Drop your swords.
- No! No!
I want to see their blood
here where Draba died!
When I fight matched pairs,
they fight to the death.
I made myself a promise, Crixus.
I swore that
if I ever got out of this place...
I'd die before I'd watch
two men fight to the death again.
Draba made that promise too.
He kept it.
So will I.
Go on. Get out!
What are we, Crixus?
What are we becoming?
Romans?
Have we learned nothing?
We look for wine
when we should be hunting bread.
- When you've got wine,
you don't need bread!
- [ Laughter ]
You can't just be a gang
of drunken raiders.
- What else can we be?
- Gladiators!
An army of gladiators.
There's never been
an army like that.
One gladiator's worth
any two Roman soldiers.
We beat the Roman guards, but a Roman
army's different. They fight different.
We can beat anything
they send against us if we want to.
- It takes a big army:
- We'll have a big army.
Once we're on the march, we'll free
every slave in every town and village.
Can anybody get a bigger army?
Once we cross the Alps,
we're safe!
Nobody can cross the Alps. Every pass
is defended by its own legion.
There's only one way
to get out of this country.
The sea.
What good is the sea
if you have no ships?
The Cilician pirates have ships.
They're at war with Rome.
Every Roman galley that sails
out of Brundusium pays tribute.
They've got the biggest
fleet in the world.
I was a galley slave. Give them
enough gold, they'll take you anywhere.
- We haven't got enough gold.
- Take every Roman we capture
and warm his back a little.
- We'll have gold all right.
- Spartacus is right!
Let's hire these pirates
and march straight to Brundusium!
[ Cheering ]
Come join us.
All of you, come join us.
Come on and join us!
[ Cheering ]
Come on!
Hey!
Back to Vesuvius!
Come on!
Varinia.
I thought
I'd never see you again.
Everything's so different.
The last time I saw you, you--
you were waiting in the arena to--
I-- I thought
you were in Rome.
How'd you escape?
I--
I jumped out of the cart...
and Batiatus was so fat--
I flew out of the cart...
and Batiatus was so fat...
he couldn't catch me.
He couldn't catch up with me.
Do you realize...
nobody can ever sell you again?
Nobody can sell you.
- Or give you away.
- Nobody can ever make you
stay with anyone.
- Nobody can make you.
Oh, I love you, Spartacus.
I love you.
I still can't believe it.
Forbid me...
ever to leave you.
I do forbid you.
I forbid you.
[ Batiatus ]
It was funny at the time:
How good you are to me,
if I may say so.
- You may.
- Thank you.
Don't just eye those birds.
Eat them.
There's no need to be
on your best behaviour.
May I remind you...
you've been good to me
in the past.
- I've been good to you? Oh, ho, ho.
- Oh, yes.
You've sold me slaves
at an extremely reasonable price.
And you arranged gladiatorial
jousts at cost, practically.
You are both ethical
in business...
and certainly
farsighted socially.
Zenobia's put on weight
since I last saw her.
- Hasn't she? I like it.
- So do I.
You and I have a tendency
towards corpulence.
Corpulence makes a man reasonable,
pleasant and phlegmatic.
Have you noticed the nastiest
of tyrants are invariably thin?
In spite of your vices...
you are the most generous Roman
of our time.
Vices?
[ Chuckle ] Ladies.
Ladies! Since when are they a vice?
Perhaps I used the wrong word.
An eccentricity, a foible.
I hope I pronounced that word.
It's well-known that even your groom
and butler are women.
I'm the most virtuous man in Rome.
I keep these women out
of my respect for Roman morality:
That morality, which has made
Rome strong enough to steal...
two-thirds of the world
from its rightful owners...
founded on the sanctity
of Roman marriage and family.
I happen to like women:
I have a promiscuous nature:::
and unlike these aristocrats,
I will not take a marriage vow:::
which my nature will
prevent me from keeping.
You have too great a respect
for the purity of womankind.
Exactly.
It must be tantalizing
to be surrounded by so much purity.
It is.
Let's mix business with pleasure:
How may I help?
Great Gracchus,
I find it difficult to hate...
but there's one man
I can't think of without fuming.
- Who's that?
- Crassus.
- You've grown very ambitious
in your hatred.
- Do you blame me?
There I was, better than
a millionaire in the morning...
and a penniless refugee
by nightfall...
with nothing but rags
and my flesh.
All because Crassus decides
to break his journey at Capua...
with a couple of capricious,
over-painted nymphs!
These two daughters of Venus
had to taunt the gladiators...
force them to fight to the death,
and before I knew what had happened...
- revolution on my hands!
- What...
revenge have you in mind?
I sold Crassus
this woman, Varinia.
- Whom?
- Varinia: May the gods give her wings:
There was no contract,
but she was clearly his slave...
as soon as the deal was made.
Now she's off with Spartacus
killing people in their beds.
And Crassus,
no mention of money!
You never offered me
this woman. Why not?
Well... she's not
remotely your type, Gracchus.
- She is very thin and--
- Look around you.
- You'll see women of all sizes.
- Well, yes.
500 sesterces
deposit on Varinia.
Since he hasn't paid:::
this gives me first call
when she's caught:
May the gods adore you!
Why would you want a woman
you've never seen?
To annoy Crassus, of course,
and help you.
Fetch a stool, Antoninus.
In here with it.
That will do.
Do you steal, Antoninus?
No, master.
Do you lie?
Not if I can avoid it.
Have you...
ever dishonoured the gods?
No, master.
Do you refrain
from these vices...
out of respect
for the moral virtues?
Yes, master.
Do you eat oysters?
When I have them, master.
Do you eat snails?
No, master.
Do you consider the eating
of oysters to be moral...
and the eating of snails
to be immoral?
No, master.
Of course not.
It is all a matter
of taste, isn't it?
Yes, master.
And taste is not
the same as appetite...
and therefore not a question
of morals, is it?
Hmm?
It could be argued so, master.
That will do.
My robe, Antoninus.
My taste includes...
both snails and oysters.
Antoninus, look.
Across the river.
There is something
you must see.
There, boy, is Rome.
The might, the majesty...
the terror of Rome.
There is the power:::
that bestrides the known world
like a colossus:
No man can withstand Rome.
No nation can withstand her.
How much less...
a boy!
Hmm?
[ Chuckle ]
There's only one way to deal
with Rome, Antoninus.
You must serve her.
You must abase yourself
before her.
You must grovel at her feet.
You must... love her.
Isn't that so, Antoninus?
Antoninus!
Antoninus?
Take your time!
- How are they coming?
- Good. Give me another
thousand like them...
- and we can march on Rome.
- Come on, once again.
Here on Vesuvius,
we're safe from attack...
while we organize
ourselves into an army.
It may take six months,
a year.
Once we're strong, we're gonna fight
our way south to the sea.
We're going to arrange for ships
with the Cilician pirates.
The sea will be our road home.
If you agree, you may join us.
If you don't agree, go back
before your escape is discovered.
Too many women.
What's wrong with women?
Where would you be now,
you lout...
if some woman hadn't fought
all the pains of hell...
to get you
into this accursed world?
I can handle a knife
in the dark as well as anyone.
I can cast spells
and brew poisons.
I have made the death shrouds
for seven Roman masters.
- I want to see Spartacus.
- All right, grandmother. I'm Spartacus.
Stay with us. We'll need a million
Roman shrouds before we're through.
- Where do you come from?
- Most of us come
from the estate of Lillius.
- What kind of work did you do there?
- 1 6 years a carpenter.
Good.
We can use carpenters.
- What kind of work did you do?
- Chief steward.
You'll help with the food supplies.
Report to Patullus.
What kind of work did you do?
Singer of songs.
Singer of songs?
But what work did you do?
That's my work.
I also juggle.
Juggle.
What else do you do?
I can do feats of magic.
Magic?
Maybe he can make
the Romans disappear.
I'll need one volunteer,
man or woman.
How about you?
You, sir?
Here we have
a likely subject.
You'll notice there is
nothing in my hand, true?
- How many fingers do you see?
- Three.
- Three!
I make a bowl.
My hand is upside down...
and I ask you to blow at it.
Not hard enough.
Hard!
Thank you.
[ Chirping ]
Would you like to try?
Hit it against the rock, gently.
[ Chirping ]
Poet, I haven't had
an egg in days.
You haven't?
- Here.
- Thank you.
I'm not going
to let mine get away.
- Sing us a song.
- Sing us a song, Antoninus.
Sing, Antoninus.
[ Antoninus ]
When the blazing sun
hangs low in the western sky:::
when the wind dies away
on the mountain:::
when the song of
the meadowlark turns still...
when the field locust
clicks no more in the field...
and the sea foam sleeps
like a maiden at rest:::
and twilight touches the shape
of the wondering earth:::
I turn home:
Through blue shadows
and purple woods:::
I turn home:
I turn to the place
that I was born:::
to the mother who bore me
and the father who taught me:::
long ago, long ago:::
long ago:
Alone am I now, lost and alone
in a far, wide, wondering world:
Yet still
when the blazing sun hangs low:::
when the wind dies away
and the sea foam sleeps:::
and twilight touches
the wondering earth...
I turn home:
Where'd you learn that song?
My father taught it to me.
I was wrong about you, poet.
You won't learn to kill.
- You'll teach us songs:
- I came here to fight.
Anyone can learn to fight.
I joined to fight!
What's your name?
Antoninus.
There's a time for fighting,
and a time for singing.
Now you teach us to sing.
Sing, Antoninus.
When the blazing sun
hangs low in the western sky--
You like him, don't you?
Who wants to fight?
An animal can learn to fight.
But to sing beautiful things...
and make people believe them--
Hmm.
What are you thinking about?
I'm free.
And what do I know?
I don't even know how to read.
You know things
that can't be taught.
I know nothing.
Nothing!
And I want to know.
I want to--
I want to know.
Know what?
Everything.
Why a star falls
and a bird doesn't.
Where the sun goes at night.
Why the moon changes shape.
I want to know
where the wind comes from.
The wind begins in a cave.
Far to the north,
a young god sleeps in that cave.
He dreams of a girl,
and he sighs...
and the night wind
stirs with his breath.
I want to know all about you.
Every line...
every curve.
I want to know
every part of you.
Every beat of your heart.
Go on about the city
of Metapontum.
What garrisons
will we find there?
There are two legions
in the garrison.
Some have been sent south--
Set the litter down there:
Well, where is
this slave general?
Dionysius, get the litter bearers
out of the rain.
Give them food,
a bed and their freedom.
- [ Dionysius ] All right, follow me:
- We'll pay you for them:
We have no slaves in this camp.
Tigranes Levantus at your service.
My credentials.
Come in.
''To the general of the Italian
slaves called Spartacus...
''from Ibar M'hali,
Cilician governor of Delos.
''Greetings. Word has been
received that you wish...
''to embark your armies
on the Cilician ships...
''from the Italian port
of Brundusium.
- ''Receive my agent, Tigranes--
- Levantus.
''Who bargains in my name.
May Isis and Serapis bring victory
to your cause. The governor of Delos.''
- What are Isis and Serapis?
- Gods of the East.
- Why should they want us to win?
- Because...
they favour Cilicia, and Cilicia,
like you, fights against the Romans.
[ Chuckle ]
Would you like some wine?
I drink only after the bargain
has been concluded...
never before.
How many ships
do these Cilicians have?
500 at least.
But no deal is too small,
I assure you.
- We'll need them all:
- All?
What is the price?
Price...
is 1 00,000 sesterces per ship.
For 500 ships, that would be...
50 million sesterces.
- You... have such a sum?
- We will have.
See for yourself.
[ Chuckle ] Beautiful.
- When will the ships be ready?
- Beautiful.
I love to see such beauty.
When will the ships be ready?
Ah, my friend...
when will you be ready?
How long will it
take you to cross...
one-third the length of Italy...
fighting a major battle
in every town?
One year?
Two years?
If we're not in Brundusium
seven months from now...
- we'll never be there.
- Hmm.
What if we assemble the ships:::
and there is no longer
a slave army to board them?
We'll give you a chest
of treasure now...
the rest
when we get to Brundusium.
- This one?
- Yes:
Done! Seven months from now,
the ships will be assembled.
- Arrange to have the chest loaded.
- And now:::
with your permission, I should like
to have the wine you offered me.
- Will you join me?
- I will.
Excellent workmanship.
It came from the estate
of a wealthy nobleman.
I've heard... that you are
of noble birth yourself.
I'm the son and grandson
of slaves.
I knew that
when I saw you couldn't read.
Of course, it pleases Roman vanity
to think that you are noble.
They shrink from the idea
of fighting mere slaves...
especially a man like Crassus:
- You know him?
- I entertained him one afternoon.
- You?
- In the arena.
Excellent wine.
May I--
- May I ask you something?
- You can ask.
Surely you know you're
going to lose, don't you?
You have no chance:
At this very moment, six cohorts
of the garrison of Rome:::
are approaching this position:
What are you going to do?
We'll decide that
when they get here.
Let me put it differently.
If you looked
into a magic crystal...
and you saw your army destroyed,
and yourself dead...
if you saw that in the future,
as I'm sure you're seeing it now...
would you continue to fight?
Yes.
Knowing that you must lose?
Knowing we can't.
All men lose when they die,
and all men die.
But a slave and a free man
lose different things.
They both lose life.
When a free man dies,
he loses the pleasure of life.
A slave loses his pain.
Death is the only freedom
a slave knows.
That's why
he's not afraid of it.
That's why we'll win.
Spartacus,
that pirate was right.
The garrison of Rome,
they're setting up camp.
- How many are there?
- About six cohorts.
- Where?
- At the mouth of the valley:::
against the cliffs:
- Strong camp?
- They've built no stockade:
No stockade? Are you sure?
- I'm very sure.
- This campaign is great sport for them.
The Romans are having a picnic.
- Did they see you?
- No! We were hidden:
Maybe we ought to join
this Roman picnic.
Form your men.
Six cohorts.
A lot of arms and weapons...
to build our army with.
Crixus always wanted
to march on Rome.
Now he doesn't have to.
Rome's come to us.
[ Shouting ]
Half this way!
The rest over there.
Stand up...
- the way a noble Roman should!
- That's Roman pride for you!
[ Laughter ]
That's better.
What's your name?
Marcus Glabrus.
Glabrus:
- Commander of the garrison of Rome!
- Commander?
He was commanding it
on his belly, playing dead!
You disappoint me,
Marcus Glabrus.
Playing dead.
You afraid to die?
It's easy to die.
Haven't you seen enough
gladiators in the arena...
to see how easy it is to die?
Of course you have.
Why--
What are you going to do to me?
I don't know.
What should we do with him?
Let's have a matched pair,
him and me.
I'll not fight like a gladiator!
[ Booing ]
You keep staring at this.
Do you recognize this baton?
- Yes!
- You should!
It was in your tent.
The symbol of the senate.
All the power of Rome!
That's the power of Rome!
Take that back to your senate.
Tell them you
and that broken stick...
is all that's left
of the garrison of Rome!
Tell them we want
nothing from Rome...
nothing... except our freedom!
All we want is to get out
of this damn country!
We're marching south to the sea.
And we'll smash every army
they send against us.
Put him on a horse!
[ Cheering ]