NARRATOR: In the dark
days at the dawn...
of the 16th century,
the conquering hordes
of the Turkish Sultan...
spread terror
throughout the civilized world.
The Ottoman Empire swept
east across Asia Minor,
south across the Mediterranean,
north across the Crimea.
Triumphant, the Turkish Sultan
turned west to the Ukraine.
Turkish spearheads threatened
the frontiers of Poland.
The fate of Europe
hung in the balance...
on the vast fertile plains...
known as the Steppes.
Your Highness,
the Turks have broken our lines.
Call out the reserves.
We have yet to hear
from our allies.
The Cossacks.
The whole army's probably
lying drunk in the mud.
The Cossacks will be here.
- We can't wait, Sire.
Zaporozhtzi.
( ALL YELLING )...
(MAN SCREAMS)...
( GUNSHOTS)
Cutthroats, animals.
Devils with scalp locks.
But there are no such fighters
in the world.
( ALL CHATTERING )
Prince Grigory will toast victory
at the Royal Pavilion...
with the Cossack Colonel.
Tell your Prince,
the hetman of the Zaporozhtzi
only drinks with kings.
My Colonel,
have a drink for me
with Prince Grigory.
And you will represent me
at the Royal Pavilion,
Taras Bulba.
Follow me.
Never set foot under a Polish roof.
Not even a tent.
Colonel Manfred, we
will speak here.
It will spare us
both embarrassment.
I give you a toast to our common
triumph over the infidels.
I'll drink to that.
Gold.
Too bad we're fighting
on the same side, huh?
You fight well, Cossack.
How are you known?
Armed guards behind my back.
( COSSACKS LAUGHING )
Your name?
Taras Bulba.
Colonel of the
Oumansky Cossacks.
Well, Taras Bulba,
Colonel of the
Oumansky Cossacks,
His Majesty is pleased
by the results of our alliance.
So pleased he has decided
to do you the honor...
of integrating all Cossack troops
into the Polish-lmperial Army.
Do you see this scalp lock?
That means you're speaking
to the Zaporozhtzi.
Do you know what
Zaporozhtzi means?
The Cossack Brotherhood.
Free men.
We fought with you
to rid this land of the Turks...
because this is our land.
Now take your Polish
honor back to Poland...
and leave us alone.
Leave us alone, Pole.
Colonel Manfred, the
Cossack is right.
Honor has nothing to do with this.
We need the Ukraine
as a buffer against the East...
and we need your grain.
We are here and we intend to stay.
That is why His lmperial Majesty
is dispersing the Cossack troops...
before you can turn
your horses against us.
That is why we held
back our reserves...
till you had won the battle for us.
Zaporozhtzi!
Holy Father,
blessed archangel,
what have we done?
What is your will?
I've led you to dishonor,
defeat and death.
No.
Devil take you, Mykola.
You are our hetman.
You did not lead us to defeat.
We trusted the Poles.
That...
was our mistake.
Before the moon changes,
I'm going to have a son.
He may already be born.
And I will kiss the
Devil before my son...
wears the Polish collar.
So,
start again,
burn our farms,
take to the forests,
live in the hills.
Kubenko in the south.
Tymoshevsky in the east.
The scalp lock is forbidden.
There's my pledge.
It may take years,
it may take a whole generation,
but the Cossack Brotherhood
will rise again,
with fire and sword...
and repay the Pole
measure for measure.
And take...
the Steppes back...
for our own.
And may God help us.
Zaporozhtzi,
pray to your archangel.
NARRATOR:
With the burning of their farms,
the Cossacks scattered
across their beloved Steppes.
There, in the ancient hills,
Taras Bulba 's vision
was to take root...
and grow like the sons he bore,
steeled from birth for the day
when the Cossack Brotherhood...
would drive the Polish conquerors
from their homeland...
and take back the
Steppes for their own.
(BABY CCYING )...
( CCYING )
There, Andrei,
there's your lesson.
Armor plate can stop a saber.
If you want to kill a man in armor,
what you need is this.
(BABY CCYING )
Why don't Cossacks wear armor?
This is our armor, boy.
Faith.
And a good saber arm.
TARAS: Ostap, watch your brother.
He rides like a Cossack,
fights like a Cossack.
And soon, we'll teach him
to drink like a Cossack.
MEN: Taras Zaporozhtzi!
(MEN SINGING )...
(SINGING ) When you
see a Cossack...
with him is a Cossack
We the brotherhood we are one
MEN: Hi, Zaporozhtzi!
Hi, Zaporozhtzi!
We the brotherhood we are one
Hey!
TARAS: Turn to your left
then turn to your right
And faces shine
brighter than the sun
MEN: Hi, Zaporozhtzi!
Hi, Zaporozhtzi!
Faces shine brighter than the sun
Hey!
TARAS: When you say Cossack
you're saying brother
Cossack and brother
mean the same
MEN: Hi, Zaporozhtzi!
Hi, Zaporozhtzi!
Cossack and brother
mean the same!
Hey!
We are the Cossacks
Men that no one on earth can tame
MEN: Hi, Zaporozhtzi!
Hi, Zaporozhtzi!
Men that no one on earth can tame
Taras?
In the holy name, are you mad?
A Cossack scalp lock?
- Don't chatter, magpie.
You make the barber nervous.
You'll be hanged on sight.
The more you talk,
the more you show
your ignorance.
The scalp lock is the latest fashion...
imported from the
court at Warsaw,
His Polish Majesty
has forgiven us our sins.
Royal pardon to all Cossacks.
( GRUNTS)
Watch what you're doing.
Shave me when you're
through with papa.
I want a scalp lock.
How's that?
A scalp lock!
You'll wear a scalp lock
when you've earned it, boy.
In battle.
You don't need a scalp
lock to study Latin.
Latin?
The Poles have opened
the Kiev Academy to all Cossacks,
and the sons of Taras Bulba
will be the first ones there.
Right, Father Mikhail?
The devil we are!
The King is spitting in our eye.
He's saying the Cossacks...
aren't worth worrying
about anymore.
What the devil are
you doing up there?
I am repairing the weathercock...
so that you can tell
which way the wind blows.
Papa, what can we
learn from the Poles?
Father Mikhail has taught us...
everything that a
Cossack should know.
A Cossack?
- Yes.
What do you know?
Pots and pans.
Petticoats and apron strings.
That's what you know.
A Cossack should
be fighting Poles,
that's what I know.
Send me to Kiev with a saber,
I'll teach them what I know.
But I won't go to learn to be a Pole.
Uh-huh.
You think you are
ready to fight me, boy?
Anytime you say, Papa.
- Uh-huh.
(LAUGHING )
All right, Papa.
Come on.
So we go,
the sons of Taras Bulba,
to learn to be Poles.
I don't know why we go, Papa,
but I follow your orders...
until the day comes
that I can throw you in the well.
And...
that day will come.
So...
You don't know why you're going.
So you say you want
to fight the Poles.
When you come home,
when you've learned
everything the Poles know...
and all there is to
know about the Poles,
then you'll be ready to fight them,
and not before.
And that day will come.
That day will come.
(URGING OXEN)
Pigs, lepers and Cossacks
around the back.
(EX CLAIMING )...
(STUDENTS LAUGHING )...
( GROANS)
Follow me.
Andrei Bulba.
Ostap Bulba.
We have opened our
schools to you...
in the hope that we may yet raise
a generation of civilized Cossacks,
worthy to be counted among
the subjects of the Polish crown.
Let it be clear from the start,
we will not tolerate the barbaric...
behavior to which
you are accustomed.
You will remove your tunics
and prostrate yourselves.
Brother Bartholomew.
( CHORAL SINGING )
I thought we came here to study.
Papa said we should
learn everything...
there is to know about the Poles.
But she's the governor's daughter.
She'd spit on a Cossack.
Amo,
amas,
amat.
I love,
thou lovest,
he loves.
STUDENTS: (SINGING )
Rise ye shepherds...
on this winter's night
In the skies...
one wondrous star shines bright
Angel voices bid ye rise
Oh come ye all where Jesus lies
Oh come and greet your Lord!
Come, ye shepherds
Ye have traveled far
Ye have been guided
By his holy star
Gently, gently dawn is creeping
In the manger he is sleeping
Come and greet your Lord
Rise, ye shepherds...
on this winter's night
In the skies
one wondrous star shines bright
Angel voices bid ye rise
Oh come ye all where Jesus lies
Oh come and greet your Lord
Oh, Natalia,
your brother and I...
would like to share
a toast with you.
DRIVER: Whoa, there!
(WOMEN GIGGLING )...
(LAUGHING )
Do you think it's funny
to run people down?
I'm sorry.
You look so funny
when you get angry.
It's hard to look angry
with mud on your face.
(BELL TOLLING )
That's the Academy bell.
You will be late.
They will whip you.
( CHUCKLES SHYLY)...
I'll return this.
- Oh, it doesn't matter.
Tomorrow.
No.
Please.
I won't be here tomorrow.
But I can easily get another one,
at the Thieves' Market.
Joseph.
Andrei...
Andrei, come on.
Come on, Andrei, the
gates are closed.
The Thieves' Market.
- What did you say?
The gates are closed.
Veni.
Vidi.
Vici.
I came.
I saw.
I conquered.
Make yourselves presentable.
Then report to the Abbot.
Ostap Bulba, you're dismissed.
Go to your studies.
I'm sure that'll be
more painful for you...
than any flogging.
Do you know why I have decided...
to punish you and
not your brother?
It's the Machiavellian theory
of statesmanship you taught us.
Divide your enemy and conquer.
Ostap was born a Cossack,
he will die a Cossack.
But you distress me, Andrei.
You have a fine mind.
It distresses you
to find a Cossack can think?
On the contrary,
you gave me hope for
the Cossack kind.
To raise yourself out of ignorance
and barbarism.
There's a real challenge
for a restless spirit.
Must you waste yourself
hating all Poles?
Not all Poles.
It's not so much that
I hate Poles, sir.
I love the Steppes.
But the Steppes are Poland.
The past is dead.
The wheel of history
moves forward...
and no one can turn it
back single-handed.
Not even you, Andrei Bulba.
Well, it's a challenge
for a restless spirit.
Remove your cassock
and prostrate yourself.
Brother Bartholomew.
( ALL CHATTERING )...
(SINGING ) They tell of a star
That shines just by day
Just by day
The wishing star
Can only be seen
When two lovers kiss
So they say
You make a wish
On a summer night
And dream till dawn
When the sun is bright
Then kiss your love
And look up above
If you see a star in the blue
The wishing star
Is shining for you
And you know your wish
will come true
Tomorrow?
Where?
After vespers. At the cathedral.
(WHISPERING ) Are
you out of your mind?
Yes.
And she loves me.
And as soon as we can get out
of this monk's trap...
she's going to be my wife.
Do you know what Papa
would do to her?
He'll throw her to the pigs for slop.
Andrei, she's a Pole.
Don't let her make a fool of you.
This Cossack
dishonored my sister.
We cannot allow him...
to disgrace any more
Polish families.
Gentlemen, I'll need
your assistance.
I'm not going to kill you, Cossack,
but I'm going to make sure...
you never molest
another Polish woman...
as long as you live.
Stand him up.
MAN: Stop the Cossacks!
Brother Bartholomew!
- Brother Bartholomew!
STUDENTS: Open the door!
Open the door!
They killed Captain Alex.
The stables. We'll need horses.
- I'll find Natalia. Saddle three.
Thank you, Lieutenant,
for coming here.
It was considerate of you.
Please wait.
My son is dead.
Your brother killed by
your Cossack lover.
Tell your servant to
pack your belongings.
I'll arrange for an escort
to take you out of the city.
You cannot stay here after tonight.
You'll be taken to Dubno.
There you will serve
as maid in waiting...
until you have been trained...
in the responsibilities
of your birth.
Alert the patrol...
and apprehend my
daughter as well.
(WHISPERING ) Natalia!
Go back!
Go back, Andrei! Go back!
Go back! Go back!
Go back!
(DISTANT BARKING )
SHILO: Strangers.
Strangers.
Look at the way they ride.
(LAUGHING HEARTILY)
Turn around, son. Turn around.
Don't move, son. Don't move.
Let's take a look at you.
What is this, a skirt?
My sons in skirts.
Let's see if you can run to the well
without tripping over your dress.
Papa, the only reason
I'd run to the well
is to throw you in.
How do you ride?
Sidesaddle?
Papa, please don't make fun of us.
And why not?
Because if you do,
Papa, I'll hit you.
Uh-huh.
You want to fight?
Anytime you say, Papa.
Fists?
- What else?
So you think you're tough enough
to push the old cock off the roost.
(EX CLAIMS)...
(BOTH GRUNTING )
Andrei, Taras.
Look at them.
Two years they haven't
seen each other.
What do they do? Try
to kill each other.
Well, you've learned
to fight a little.
I'll say that for you.
What about you?
(BOTH LAUGHING )
Andrei, you're hurt.
Come.
Sit.
So,
who stuck you?
- A Pole.
Did you kill him?
My little brother did.
What did you fight about?
A woman.
- A woman!
How do you like that?
Did you see the way he fought me?
With a sword hole in his shoulder.
MEN: (SINGING )
If we drink we will die
And if we don't drink we will die
So we might as well
say what the hell
And let our glasses clink!
Whatever your name
you'll be dying just the same
So as long as we are going to die
It is better if we drink
Whatever your name is...
To Andrei and Ostap,
sons of Taras.
What's the Latin for vodka?
The Romans didn't drink vodka.
That's why the Roman Empire fell.
Scholars.
(SINGING ) Some men are lovers
They work under covers
And from lady's bed to lady's bed
they leap...
( ALL LAUGHING )
But I want to drink
to the man nobody drinks to
The fellow who gets into bed...
and goes to sleep...
( ALL LAUGHING )
ALL: (SINGING ) If
we drink we will die
And if we don't drink we will die
So we might as well
say what the hell
And let our glasses clink
TARAS: Go back.
Make room.
Andrei!
Ostap!
Take these horses
with your father's blessing.
Kneel.
I am the oldest living Cossack,
but I refuse to die
sitting on an oven.
Now, you two start some fighting...
and give an old Cossack a chance
to die the way he should.
Welcome to the
Cossack Brotherhood.
God ride with you.
( ALL CHEERING )...
( GUNSHOTS)
We're looking for Taras Bulba,
Colonel of the
Oumansky Cossacks.
Filipenko! Korzh!
You sons of the devil.
Shilo.
- Filipenko.
What more can a man want?
My sons and my friends.
My old partners
and my future partners in battle.
So these are your young pups, eh?
Not bad, not bad.
Taras, you've done a good job, eh?
(FILIPENKO LAUGHS)
Nice pair, but too small for me.
I'd have to carry this
horse on my back.
I'd like to see that.
- With you on his back.
( ALL LAUGHING )
MAN: Let's go.
( ALL CHEERING )...
Come on.
- Come on, Korzh.
( ALL SHOUTING
ENCOURAGINGLY)
Who else can carry a horse
on their back all the night?
Who else but an
idiot would want to?
( ALL LAUGHING )...
( ALL CHEERING )
The time is at hand...
when Cossacks will have
something better to do...
than carry horses
around the house.
Lift your scalp locks
out of the soup, Cossacks.
Pull your sabers out of the bread.
The hetman has raised...
the golden standard
of the archangel.
The Zaporozhtzi are called to arms.
We are marching to war!
( ALL CHEERING )...
( GLASSES SMASHING )
Women, more glasses.
More vodka.
May God ride with the Zaporozhtzi!
( ALL CHEERING )
Hey! When do we march?
Every hairy-tongued Cossack
with powder in his flask...
will assemble at Chigirin...
on the road to Dubno...
by the first day of
Holy Easter Week.
( ALL CHEERING )
You can whet your blade,
Stepan Kanevsky,
and prepare to die
like a Cossack should.
( ALL CHEERING )
Who... Who... Who are we fighting?
Or doesn't it matter?
Not a devil of a lot.
( ALL LAUGHING )
Who is there to fight
except the Poles?
MEN: Right. The Poles.
FILIPENKO: Not this time.
The King of Poland...
wants an army of 10,000 Cossacks
under the Cossack standard,
led by Cossack officers,
at full pay and booty,
to march to the Baltic wars.
And after the war?
We bury our dead,
clean our sabers,
count our booty, and get drunk.
What the devil is he talking about?
You don't argue with
an old pirate like Filipenko.
This...
we will settle with
our hetman, Mykola.
( ALL SHOUTING IN AGREEMENT)
Why must you always
be so particular...
about whose booty you take?
Because the Cossacks fought
for the Poles once before,
or have you forgotten?
And do you remember, puppy?
You weren't even littered yet.
I'd rather be pulling
the Turk's nose...
if I had my choice.
The plunder is richer
and I like the smell of harem girls.
But they say these
Baltic princes have...
slop pots of gold, too,
and their women have hips
like Percherons.
(MEN LAUGHING )
And what's going to be left
of the Steppes when we get back?
( GLASS SMASHING )
Questions! Questions!
Is that what the Poles taught you?
I'll tell you what
the Poles taught me.
That a Cossack is an
ignorant barbarian...
good enough to kiss
a Pole's foot...
or fight a Pole's war,
but not good enough
to walk Polish streets.
Or raise his eyes
to a Polish woman.
Or rule his own land.
A Cossack does not question
the word of a hetman.
Will you fight or not?
That is the only question.
Not for the Poles.
(MEN SHOUTING IN AGREEMENT)
Devil's blood, Taras, it looks like
you've raised a coward for a son.
No man on earth can say
a Cossack is a coward.
That can only be proven
by the will of God.
Tell him you didn't mean it.
It's only a word. You
can't die over a word.
Taras, stop them.
There are words men must die for.
We will ride to the gorge at dawn.
The starting mark will
be of your choice.
Take your positions.
Let the will of God be done.
(KORZH URGES HORSE)...
His shoulder, Papa.
- Return to your place, Cossack.
Your arm, boy.
Let the will of God be done.
(URGES HORSE)...
(HORSE NEIGHING )
Burn this in your memory.
The man who died
was a great Cossack,
and never forget it.
Was I wrong?
The hetman has called
us to the standard.
Now,
tomorrow you raise
your companies...
and meet on the march to Chigirin.
Tonight, ride to the village...
and drink Korzh's soul to hell.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING )
Flaming flatbread, Cossacks.
Was I wrong?
- You were both wrong.
And you were both right.
Now, we ride to join Mykola
on the road to Dubno...
and I swear it will all be settled.
( ALL CHEERING )...
( GRUNTING )...
( GRUNTS)...
( ALL CHEERING )
Come on, Andrei.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)...
( ALL CHEERING )...
( GIGGLING )