"we have shared the incommunicable
experience of war.
"we have felt, we still feel,
the passion of life to its top."
our hearts were touched with fire."
oliver wendell holmes.
[explosions]
By the summer of 1861,
wilmer mclean had had enough.
[explosion]
two great armies were
converging on his farm,
and what would be
the first major battle
of the civil war--
bull run, or manassas,
as the confederates
called it--
would soon rage across
the aging virginian's farm,
a union shell going so far
as to explode
in the summer kitchen.
now mclean moved his family
away from manassas,
far south and west
of richmond,
out of harm's way,
he prayed,
to a dusty
little crossroads
called appomattox courthouse.
and it was there
in his living room,
3 1/2 years later,
that lee
surrendered to grant.
and wilmer mclean
could rightfully say,
"the war began
in my front yard
and ended
in my front parlor."
the civil war was fought
in 10,000 places
from valverde,
new mexico,
and tullahoma, tennessee,
to st. albans, vermont,
and fernandina on
the florida coast.
more than 3 million
americans fought in it,
and over 600,000 men,
2% of the population,
died in it.
american homes
became headquarters.
american churches
and schoolhouses
sheltered the dying...
and huge foraging armies
swept across american farms
and burned
american towns.
americans slaughtered
one another wholesale here,
in america,
in their own corn fields
and peach orchards,
along familiar roads,
and by waters with
old american names.
in two days at shiloh,
on the banks
of the tennessee,
more american men fell
than in all previous
american wars combined.
at cold harbor,
7,000 americans fell
in 20 minutes.
men who had
never strayed 20 miles
from their
own front doors
now found themselves
soldiers in great armies,
fighting epic battles
hundreds of miles from home.
they knew
they were making history,
and it was the greatest
adventure of their lives.
the war made some rich,
ruined others,
and changed forever
the lives of all
who lived through it...
a lackluster clerk
from galena, illinois,
a failure in everything
except marriage and war,
who, in 3 years, would
be head of the union army
and in 7, president
of the united states;
an eccentric student of
theology and military tactics,
a hypochondriac
who rode into battle
with one hand raised
"to keep," he said,
"the blood balanced;"
a college professor
from maine,
who, on a little hill
in pennsylvania,
ordered an unlikely
textbook maneuver
that saved the union army
and possibly
the union itself...
two ordinary soldiers--
one from providence,
rhode island,
the other from
columbia, tennessee,
who each served 4 years
and together seemed to
have been everywhere
during the war and lived
to tell the tale...
the courtly,
unknowable aristocrat,
who disapproved
of secession and slavery,
yet went on
to defend them both
at the head of one
of the greatest armies
of all time;
the runaway boy who
"stole himself" from slavery,
recruited two regiments
of black soldiers,
and helped transform
the civil war
into a struggle for
the freedom for all americans.
and then there was
the rough man from illinois,
who would rise to be
the greatest president
the country has ever seen.
between 1861 and 1865,
americans made war
on each other
and killed each other
in great numbers,
if only to become
the kind of country
that could
no longer conceive
how that was possible.
what began
as a bitter dispute
over union
and states' rights
ended as a struggle
over the meaning
of freedom in america.
at gettysburg in 1863,
abraham lincoln said
perhaps more than he knew.
the war was about
"a new birth of freedom."
man: 1938--
75th anniversary of
the battle of gettysburg.
spoke to the remaining
few civil war veterans.
veterans of the blue
and the gray...
on behalf of the people
of the united states,
i accept this monument
in the spirit of
brotherhood and peace.
year after year,
the nation remembered.
in 1930, veterans
of the union army
marched in
cincinnati, ohio,
4 years later,
in new york city.
they and the surviving
veterans of the confederacy
were the last link
with the terrible conflict
that tore america apart
from 1861 to 1865.
the last civil war veteran
would die in 1959,
of long-ago battles,
only history and legends.
any understanding
of this nation
has to be based,
and i mean really based,
on an understanding
of the civil war.
i believe that firmly.
it defined us.
the revolution
did what it did.
our involvement
in european wars,
beginning with
the first world war,
did what it did,
but the civil war
defined us as what we are,
and it opened us
to being what we became,
uh, good and bad things.
and it--
it is very necessary
if you're
going to understand
the american character
in the 20th century
to learn about this
enormous catastrophe
of the mid-19th century.
it was the--
the crossroads
of our being,
and it was a hell
of a crossroads.
for me, the picture
of the civil war
as a historic
phenomenon...
is not
on the battlefield.
it's not about weapons.
it's not about soldiers,
except to the extent
that weapons
and soldiers
at that crucial moment
joined a discussion
about something higher,
about humanity,
about human dignity,
about human freedom.
"whence shall we expect
the approach of danger?
"shall some transatlantic
giant step the earth
"and crush us at a blow?
"never.
"all the armies
of europe and asia
"could not by force
take a drink
"from the ohio river
"or make a track
on the blue ridge
"in the trial of
a thousand years.
"if destruction
be our lot,
"we must ourselves be
its author and finisher.
"as a nation of free men,
we will live forever...
or die by suicide."
abraham lincoln, 1837.
in 1861,
most of the nation's
31 million people
lived peaceably on farms
and in small towns.
at sharpsburg, maryland,
a german pacifist sect,
the dunkards,
made their home in
a sea of wheat and corn.
in gettysburg, pennsylvania,
population 2,400,
young men studied
latin and mathematics
at the small college there.
steamboats
filled with cotton
came and went at vicksburg
on the mississippi.
in washington, d.c.,
senator jefferson davis
reviewed plans
for remodeling the capitol.
in richmond,
the 900 employees
of the tredegar iron works
turned out gun carriages
and cannon
for the u.s. government.
at west point
on the hudson,
officers trained
and friendships
were formed
they thought would last
a lifetime.
"in thinking of america,
"i sometimes find myself
"admiring her
bright blue sky,
"her grand old woods,
"her fertile fields,
"her beautiful rivers,
her mighty lakes
and star-crowned
mountains..."
"but my rapture
is soon checked.
"when i remember
that all is cursed
"with
the infernal spirit
"of slaveholding
and wrong,
"that with the waters
of her noblest rivers,
"the tears
of my brethren
"are borne to the ocean,
"disregarded
and forgotten,
"that her
most fertile fields
"drink daily
of the warm blood
"of my outraged sisters,
i am filled with
unutterable loathing."
frederick douglass.
?? we are ??
?? climbing ??
?? jacob's ladder ??
?? hallelujah ??
?? we are ??
?? climbing ??
?? climb?? jacob's ??
?? j?? ?? jacob's ladder ?? ??
?? soldiers ??
?? of the ??
?? cross ??
?? people ??
?? climbing ??
?
?? climbing ?? we will ?
?? we will
?? people ??ly make it ??
?? keep on ??
?? climbing ?? ?? we will ???
?? we will
surely make it ??ng ??
?? soldiers ??
?? of the ??
?? cross ??
"no day ever dawns
for the slave,"
a freed
black man wrote,
"nor is it looked for.
"for the slave,
it is all night.
all night forever."
one white mississippian
was more blunt--
"i'd rather be dead,"
he said,
on one of these
big plantations."
a slave
entered the world
in a one-room,
dirt-floored shack.
drafty in winter,
reeking in summer,
slave cabins bred
pneumonia, typhus, cholera,
lockjaw, tuberculosis.
the child who survived
to be sent to the fields at 12
was likely to have
rotten teeth, worms,
dysentery, malaria.
fewer than 4 out of 100
lived to be 60.
[singing]
work began at sunrise
and continued as long
as there was light--
14 hours sometimes,
unless there was
a full moon,
when it went on
still longer.
on the auction block,
blacks were made
to jump and dance
to jump and dance ??
to demonstrate
their sprightliness
and stripped to show how little
whipping they needed.
buyers poked
and prodded them,
examined their feet,
eyes, and teeth...
"precisely,"
one ex-slave recalled,
"as a jockey
examines a horse."
a slave could expect
to be sold
at least once
in his lifetime,
maybe two times,
maybe more.
since slave marriages
had no legal status,
preachers changed
the wedding vows to read,
"until death or distance
do you part."
"you know
what i'd rather do?"
"if i thought..."
"that i'd ever be
a slave again,
"i'd take a gun
and just end it all
right away
"because you're
nothing but a dog.
you're not a thing
but a dog."
[chorussingingjacob's ladder]
?? children ??
?? do you ??
?? want your freedom? ??
some slaves
refused to work.
some ran away.
?? do you
want your freedom? ??
still,
blacks struggled
to hold
their families together,
created their own culture
under the worst
of conditions...
and yearned to be free.
?? do you ??
?? want your freedom? ??
?? soldiers ??
?? of the ??
?? cross ??
if there was a single event
that caused the war,
it was the establishment
of the united states
in independence
from great britain
with slavery still
a part of its heritage.
it was because
we failed to do
the thing
we really have
a genius for,
which is compromise.
americans like to
think of themselves
as uncompromising.
our true genius
is for compromise--
our whole government's
founded on it,
and it failed.
"there was never
a moment in our history
"when slavery was not
a sleeping serpent.
"it lay coiled up
under the table
"during
the deliberations
"of the constitutional
convention.
"owing
to the cotton gin,
"it was more
than half awake.
"thereafter, slavery
was on everyone's mind,
though not always
on his tongue."
john jay chapman.
by the time the nation
was founded,
??
by the time the nation
was founded,? climbing
slavery was dying
in the north.
there were doubts
in the south, too,
but few could conceive
of any alternative.
thomas jefferson of virginia
said maintaining slavery
was like holding a wolf
by the ears.
you didn't like it,
but you didn't dare
let it go.
then in 1793,
a northerner, eli whitney,
taught the south
how to make slavery pay.
whitney's engine,
or gin,
made it easier to separate
cotton from its seed.
where before it had taken
one slave 10 hours
to produce a single
pound of lint,
the cotton gin could crank out
a thousand pounds a day.
production soared...
and with it,
the demand for slaves.
by 1860,
the last year of peace,
one out of every 7 americans
belonged to another
american.
4 million men, women,
and children were slaves.
[horn blowing]
in boston in 1831,
claiming "that which
is not just is not law,"
william lloyd garrison
began publishing
a militant, antislavery
newspaper,the liberator.
he called for complete
and immediate abolition.
"i am in earnest.
"i will not equivocate.
"i will not excuse.
"i will not retreat
a single inch,
and i will be heard."
he was heard,
and his message
was clear--
slavery was sin...
and those who maintained it,
criminals.
the abolition movement grew,
inspired by
passionate leaders--
harriet tubman,
called "moses" by the slaves
who followed her north
to freedom;
wendell phillips,
named "the golden trumpet"
of abolitionism for his oratory;
and frederick douglass,
the son of a slave
and a white man.
"i appear
this evening
"as a thief
and robber.
"i stole this head,
these limbs,
"this body
from my master
and ran off
with them."
douglass was so eloquent
that skeptics charged
he could never
have been a slave.
in part
to prove them wrong,
he wrote an autobiography,
purchased his freedom with $600
obtained from english admirers,
and returned
to the struggle.
"the abolitionists
would raise the negroes
"to a social
and political equality
with the whites.
"and, that being effected,
we would soon see
"the present condition
of the two races reversed.
"they and their
northern allies
would be the masters,
and we the slaves."
john c. calhoun.
southerners worried
about the growing political
as well as economic
power of the north.
northerners were increasingly
hostile to slavery.
still, most southerners
refused to acknowledge
even the possibility
of changing their way of life.
"on the north bank
of the ohio,
"everything is
activity, industry.
"labor is honored.
there are no slaves.
"pass
to the south bank
"and the scene
changes so suddenly
"that you think
yourself
"on the other side
of the world.
the enterprising
spirit is gone."
alexis
de tocqueville.
"we are separated
because of incompatibility
of temper.
"we are divorced
north from south
because we hated
each other so."
mary chesnut.
on the clear, moonlit night
of november 7, 1837,
a mob surrounded a warehouse
at alton, illinois,
intent on destroying
an antislavery newspaper
run by the reverend
elijah p. lovejoy.
when one of the mob moved
to set the building on fire,
lovejoy,
armed with a pistol,
came out to stop him.
[gunshot]
the slavery men
shot him dead
and dumped his printing press
into the mississippi.
the news stunned
the nation--
a white man had been killed
over black slavery.
protest meetings were held
throughout the north.
one abolitionist wrote that
"thousands
of our citizens
"who lately believed they had
nothing to do with slavery
now begin to discover
their error."
in hudson, ohio,
a clergyman told
a church gathering,
"the question
now before us
"is no longer,
can slaves be made free,
"but, arewefree,
or are we slaves
under mob law?"
in the back of the church,
a strange, gaunt man
rose to his feet
and raised his right hand.
"here, before god,
in the presence
of these witnesses,
"i consecrate
my life
to the destruction
of slavery."
john brown.
in 1846, a lawyer
from springfield, illinois,
was elected to congress.
he was born in kentucky,
the son of a farmer
who could barely
sign his name.
he became a legislator at 24,
a prosperous attorney,
and after
a turbulent courtship,
the husband
of miss mary todd,
the daughter of a slave-holding
kentucky banker.
for abraham lincoln,
the declaration
of independence
was to be taken literally--
all men had
the right to rise
as far as talent
would take them,
just as he had.
but he called
for its restriction,
not immediate abolition.
by mid-century,
the country was deeply divided.
southerners feared the north
might forbid slavery.
northerners feared slavery
might move west.
as each new state
was added to the union,
it threatened to upset
the delicate
equilibrium of power.
"there are
grave doubts
"at the hugeness
of the land,
"and whether
one government
can comprehend
the whole."
henry adams.
now events accelerated.
in 1852,
harriet beecher stowe
published
uncle tom's cabin.
its portrayal
of slavery's cruelty
moved readers
as nothing else had.
queen victoria
wept over it.
more than
1.5 million copies
were in print worldwide.
in 1854,
congress allowed settlers
in the kansas
and nebraska territories
to decide for themselves
whether or not
to permit slavery.
kansas exploded.
5,000 proslavery men
invaded the territory.
in the next 3 months,
200 men died
in "bleeding kansas."
the killing would not stop
for 10 years.
in 1857,
the supreme court
refused to free a slave,
dred scott,
even though he had lived
for many years
on free soil.
chief justice
roger b. taney said
a black man
had no rights
a white man
was bound to respect.
"as a nation, we
began by declaring
"that all men
are created equal.
"we now practically
read it--
"all men
are created equal,
except negroes.
"soon it will read--
"all men
are created equal,
"except negroes
and foreigners
"and catholics.
"when it comes
to this,
"i should prefer
emigrating
"to some country
"where they make
no pretense
of loving liberty--
"to russia,
for instance,
"where despotism
can be taken pure
"and without
the base alloy
of hypocrisy."
abraham lincoln.
violence reached
the floor
of the united states senate,
where congressman
preston brooks
of south carolina
savagely beat abolitionist
senator charles sumner
with his cane.
southern sympathizers
sent brooks new canes.
members began carrying
knives and pistols
into the chamber.
meanwhile, the nation's
chief executive,
james buchanan,
did nothing.
"a house divided
against itself
cannot stand.
"i believe
this government
cannot endure,
"permanently
half slave
and half free.
"i do not expect
the union
to be dissolved.
"i do not
expect the house
to fall.
"but i do expect
it will cease
to be divided.
"it will become
all one thing
or all
the other."
on sunday evening,
october 16, 1859,
the radical abolitionist
john brown
led 5 blacks
and 13 whites
into harpers ferry,
virginia.
he brought along
a wagonload of guns
to arm the slaves
he was sure
would rally to him.
once they had, he planned
to lead them southward
along the crest
of the appalachians
and destroy slavery.
brown was an inept
businessman
who had failed 20 times
in 6 states
and defaulted
on his debts.
yet he believed himself
god's agent on earth.
in 1856,
at pottawatomie creek
in kansas,
he and his sons
had hacked 5
proslavery men to death
with broadswords,
all in the name
of defeating satan
and his legions.
quietly seized the armory,
arsenal, and engine house,
and took up hostages,
including george washington's
great grandnephew.
after that,
nothing went right.
the first person killed
was the town
baggage master,
a free black.
the slaves
did not rise up;
angry townspeople did.
the first of brown's
followers to fall
was dangerfield newby,
a former slave.
someone in the crowd
cut off his ears
as souvenirs.
on tuesday morning,
federal troops arrived
from washington,
led by a u.s. army colonel,
robert e. lee.
lee's men stormed
the engine house,
and 9 more
of brown's men were killed,
including two of his sons.
brown, severely wounded,
was turned over
to virginia
to be tried for treason.
"in firing his gun,
"john brown
has merely told
"what time
of day it is.
it is high noon,
thank god."
william lloyd
garrison.
"an undivided south
says,let him hang."
albany, georgia
patriot.
virginia found
brown guilty
and sentenced him
to death.
among the troops
at the scene of his hanging
were cadets from
the virginia military institute
led by
an eccentric professor,
thomas j. jackson.
also there was a private
in the richmond grays,
a young actor named
john wilkes booth.
"december 2, 1859...
"old john brown
has been executed
for treason
"against a state.
"we cannot object,
"even though
he agreed with us
"in thinking
slavery wrong.
"that cannot excuse
violence, bloodshed,
and treason.
"it could avail him
nothing
that he might think
himself right."
abraham lincoln.
ralph waldo emerson
likened brown to christ.
nathaniel hawthorne
declared,
"no man ever more
justly hanged."
and herman melville
called him,
"the meteor of the war."
brown had said nothing
from the gallows,
but he did hand
one of his guards a note.
"i, john brown,
am now quite certain
"that the crimes
of this guilty land
will never be purged away
but with blood."
"his zeal in
the cause of freedom
"was infinitely
superior to mine.
"mine was as
the taper light;
"his was as
the burning sun.
"i could live
for the slave.
john brown
could die for him."
john brown,
john brown...
very important person
in history--
important, though,
for only one episode.
failure in everything
in life,
except he becomes
the single most
important factor,
in my opinion,
in bringing on the war.
the militia system
in the south,
which had been
a joke before this,
before them,
becomes
a viable instrument,
as the southern militias
begin to take a true form
and the south
begins to worry
about northerners
agitating the blacks
to murder them
in their beds.
it was the beginning
of the confederate army.
"for dissolution
of the union
"is becoming
more general.
"men are now
beginning to talk
of it seriously
"who 12 months ago
"hardly
permitted themselves
to think of it.
the crisis
is not far ahead."
alexander stephens.
the country
was coming apart.
in the presidential
election of 1860,
buchanan happily
stepped aside,
but not before his ruling
democratic party
was fatally split
over the issue of slavery.
the republicans,
a new party,
saw their chance
and nominated
abraham lincoln,
his platform pledged only
to halt slavery's
further spread.
"on that point,
hold firm
"as with a chain
of steel.
"those who deny
freedom to others
"deserve it
not for themselves,
"and under a just god
cannot long retain it."
radical abolitionists
in the north complained
that lincoln's
opposition to slavery
did not go far enough.
but to most people
in the south,
the prospect
of lincoln's election
posed a lethal threat.
the 1860 campaign
had become a referendum
on the southern
way of life.
on november 6, 1860,
abraham lincoln
won the presidency
with only 40%
of the vote.
he did not even appear
on the ballot
in 10 southern states.
"the election
of mr. lincoln
"is undoubtedly
the greatest evil
"that has ever
befallen this country.
"but the mischief
is done.
"and the only relief
for the american people
"is to shorten sail,
"send down the top masts,
and prepare
for a hurricane."
richmond whig.
in the south,
lincoln was burned
in effigy.
now the south carolina
legislature
called for a convention
to consider seceding
from the union.
southerners
would have told you
they were fighting
for self-government.
they believed
the gathering
of power in washington
was against them.
when they entered
into that federation,
they certainly would never
have entered into it
if they hadn't believed
it would be possible
to get out.
and when the time came
that they wanted
to get out,
they thought
they had every right.
the southerners saw
the election of lincoln
as a sign
that the union
was about to be
radicalized
and that they
were about to be
taken in directions
they did not care to go.
the abolitionist
aspect of it
was very strong,
and they figured
they were about to lose
what they called
their property
and faced ruin.
yet many southerners
thought secession
was madness.
"south carolina,"
one southern
politician wrote,
"is too small
for a republic
and too large
for an insane asylum."
"november 19, 1860.
"a most gloomy day
in wall street.
"everything
at a deadlock.
"first-class paper
not negotiable.
stocks falling."
george templeton strong.
in new york, emotions
were no less explosive,
and george templeton strong,
a conservative lawyer
who distrusted lincoln,
began to keep track
of events in his diary.
"the bird of our country
is a debilitated chicken,
"disguised
in eagle feathers.
"we have never
been a nation.
"we are only an aggregate
of communities,
ready to fall apart
at the first
serious shock."
when abraham lincoln
was elected president,
there were 33 states
in the union,
and a 34th, free kansas,
was about to join.
by the time
of his inauguration
5 months later,
just 27 states
would remain.
the suddenness
of secession
took everyone
by surprise.
[bell tolling]
south carolina led the way
on december 20.
a bell in charleston
tolled the succession
of departing states--
mississippi
on january 9...
florida on the 10th...
then alabama, georgia,
louisiana.
in texas,
governor sam houston
was deposed when he tried
to stop his state
from joining
the confederacy.
"let me tell you
what is coming.
"after the sacrifice
of countless millions
of treasure
"and hundreds
of thousands of lives,
"you may win
southern independence,
"but i doubt it.
"the north is determined
to preserve this union.
"they are not a fiery,
impulsive people
as you are,
"for they live
in colder climates.
"but when they
begin to move
in a given direction,
"they move
with the steady momentum
and perseverance
of a mighty avalanche."
texas left anyway.
even virginia,
the most populous
southern state,
birthplace
of 7 presidents,
seemed sure to follow.
"all the indications are
"that this treasonable
inflammation,
"secessionitis,
"keeps on making
steady progress,
week by week.
"if disunion becomes
an established fact,
"we have one
consolation--
"the self-amputated
members
"were diseased
beyond immediate cure,
and their virus
will infect our system
no longer."
george templeton strong.
the charlestonmercury.
"the tea has been
thrown overboard.
the revolution of 1860
has been initiated."
after south carolina
seceded,
the handful
of federal troops
still stationed
in charleston
withdrew to fort sumter,
far out in the harbor.
their commander,
major robert anderson,
said he
had moved his men
in order to prevent
the effusion of blood.
they were quickly surrounded
by rebel batteries.
"thank god
we have a country
at last,
"to live for,
to pray for,
and, if need be,
to die for."
lucius quintus lamar.
on february 18,
a few minutes after noon,
jefferson davis
stood on the steps
of the alabama statehouse
at montgomery
and took the oath of office
as president
of the provisional
confederate states of america.
the crowds cheered, wept,
farewellwell
to the star-spangled banner
anddixie,
a minstrel tune written
by a northerner.
he was brittle, nervous,
often unable to sleep,
and partly blind
in one eye.
accustomed
to being obeyed,
he scorned the bargaining
that made
democratic government work.
sam houston said
he was as cold as a lizard
and ambitious
as lucifer.
like lincoln,
he was a kentuckian,
the son
of an itinerant farmer.
but he had been
educated at west point,
fought in mexico,
and served
as secretary of war.
as senator
from mississippi,
he resisted secession
as long as he could.
but when his state
withdrew from the union,
he headed home
to his plantation, brierfield,
south of vicksburg.
he and his wife varina
were there,
clipping roses
in the garden,
when word came that
he had been elected president.
"reading that telegram,
he looked so grieved
"that i feared some evil
had befallen our family.
"after a few minutes,
he told me,
as a man might speak
of a sentence of death."
"upon my head
were showered smiles,
plaudits, and flowers,
but beyond them,
i saw troubles
innumerable."
jefferson davis.
the confederate constitution
was almost identical
to the united states
constitution,
but it gave the president
a line-item veto,
a 6-year term,
and it outlawed
international slave trading.
the confederate cabinet
met for the first time
in a hotel room.
a sheet of stationery
pinned to the door
marked the president's
office.
"where will i find
the state department?"
a visitor asked robert toombs,
secretary of state.
"in my hat, sir,
and the archives
in my coat pocket."
"our new government
is founded
upon the great truth
that the negro
is not equal
to the white man."
vice president
alexander stephens.
"god forgive us,
"but ours
is a monstrous system.
"like the patriarchs
of old,
"our men live
all in one house
"with their wives
and their concubines,
"and the mulattoes
one sees in every family
"exactly resemble
the white children.
"all the time,
"they seem to think
themselves patterns,
models of husbands
and fathers."
mary chesnut.
mary chesnut
and her husband james,
a former united states
senator from south carolina,
moved among
the highest circles
of the confederacy
and were close
to jefferson davis
and his wife.
mary was subject
to depressions and nightmares,
for which she sometimes
took opium.
now she, too,
began to keep a diary.
"this journal
"itended to be
entirely objective.
my subjective days
are over."
"the impression
produced by the size
of his extremities
"and by his flapping
and wide-projecting ears
"may be removed
by the appearance
"of kindliness,
sagacity.
"the nose itself,
a prominent organ,
"stands out
from the face
"with an inquiring,
anxious air,
"as though
it were sniffing
"for some good thing
in the wind.
"the eyes, dark, full,
and deeply set,
are penetrating,
"but full of
an expression
which almost amounts
to tenderness."
william russell,
thelondon times.
two days after
jefferson davis left home,
abraham lincoln set out
from springfield, illinois,
forhiscapital.
"here i have lived
a quarter of a century
"and passed from a young
to an old man.
"here my children
have been born
"and one is buried.
"i now leave,
not knowing when
"or whether ever
i may return,
"with the task before me
greater than that
"which rested upon
washington.
"without the assistance
of that divine being
"who ever attended him,
i cannot succeed.
"with that assistance,
i cannot fail.
"to his care
commending you,
"as i hope
in your prayers
"you will commend me,
i bid you an
affectionate farewell."
en route to washington,
the president's train
stopped at cleveland,
buffalo, albany,
and new york.
in philadelphia,
warned of plots to kill him,
lincoln declared he would
rather be assassinated
than see a single star
removed from
the american flag.
two days later,
he reluctantly
canceled plans
for a grand arrival
in washington
and slipped into the capital
by train at dawn,
wrapped in a shawl
and protected
by two armed guards.
inauguration day
in washington
was cloudy and cold.
a large, tense crowd
gathered
beneath
the unfinished dome.
cannon guarded
the capitol grounds.
sharp shooters
lined the roof.
lincoln promised not
to interfere with slavery,
but he denied the right
of any state to secede,
vowed to defend
federal installations,
and spoke directly
to the south.
"in your hands,
my dissatisfied countrymen,
"and not in mine,
"is the momentous issue
of civil war.
"the government
will not assail you.
"you can have
no conflict
"without being
yourselves the aggressors.
"we are not enemies,
but friends.
"we must not be enemies.
"though passion
may have strained,
"it must not break
our bonds of affection.
"the mystic chords
of memory,
"stretching
from every battlefield
"and patriot grave
"to every living heart
and hearthstone
"all over
this broad land,
"will yet swell the chorus
of the union,
"when again touched,
as surely they will be,
by the better angels
of our nature."
"i do not pretend
to go to sleep.
"how can i?
"if anderson does
not accept terms
at 4:00,
"the orders are
he shall
be fired upon.
"i count 4--
st. michael chimes.
i begin to hope."
"the heavy booming
of a cannon--
"i sprang out of bed
and on my knees,
prostrate,
i prayed as i have
never prayed before."
the civil war began
at 4:30 a.m.
on the 12th
of april, 1861.
general pierre gustave
toutant beauregard
ordered his
confederate gunners
to open fire
on fort sumter,
at that hour,
only a dark shape
out in charleston harbor.
confederate commander
beauregard was a gunner,
so skilled as
an artillery student
at west point
that his instructor
kept him on
as an assistant
for another year.
that instructor
was major robert anderson,
union commander
inside fort sumter.
"all the pent-up hatred
of the past months
"and years is voiced
in the thunder
"of these cannon.
"and the people seem
almost beside themselves
"in the exultation
of a freedom
they deem already won."
the signal to fire
the first shot
was given by a civilian,
edmund ruffin,
a virginia farmer
and editor
who had preached
secession for 20 years.
"of course," he said,
"i was delighted
to perform the service."
[explosions]
34 hours later,
a white flag over the fort
ended the bombardment.
the only casualty
had been a confederate horse.
it was a bloodless opening
to the bloodiest war
in american history.
"the first gun that
was fired at fort sumter
"sounded the death knell
of slavery.
"they who fired it
"were the greatest
practical abolitionists
this nation
has produced."
"april 13.
"so civil war
is inaugurated at last.
god defend the right."
14 april.
montgomerydaily advertiser.
"the intelligence
that fort sumter
"has surrendered
to the confederate
forces yesterday
"sent a thrill of joy
to the heart
sometime poet and journalist
for the brooklynstandard,
of the south.lynstandard,d
"the face
of every southern man
was brighter,
"his step lighter,
and his bearing prouder
than it had been
before."
jubilant volunteers
marched past faneuil hall,
eager to avenge
fort sumter.
in baltimore,
anti-lincoln men
rampaged through the streets.
in richmond, a mob
marched on the statehouse,
tore down
the stars and stripes,
and raised
the stars and bars.
there was no longer any doubt
that virginia would secede.
100,000 people
crowded union square,
where the sumter flag
now flew.
walt whitman,
was stunned by the news.
"all the past
we leave behind
with sumter," he said.
"woe to those
who began this war
if they were not
in bitter earnest."
mary chesnut.
"father and i
were husking out corn
"when william corry
came across the field.
he was excited
and said,
"jonathan,
the rebels have fired
"upon fort sumter.
father got white
and couldn't say a word."
theodore f. upson.
"april 15.
events multiply.
"the president is out
with a proclamation
"calling
for 75,000 volunteers.
"it is said 200,000 more
will be called
within a few days."
on the day sumter fell,
the regular army
of the united states
consisted of fewer
than 17,000 men,
most of whom
were stationed
in the far west.
only two of its generals
had ever commanded
an army in the field,
and both were
long past their prime.
winfield scott,
the hero of the mexican war,
"old fuss and feathers,"
was too fat
even to mount a horse.
"we was treated as good
as company could be
"at every station.
"we got kisses
from the girls
at a good many places,
and we returned
the same to them."
hercules stanard.
"i've got the best
suit of clothes
i ever had
in my life."
in the north,
they came by hundreds
and by thousands...
from boston,
massachusetts...
from detroit
and ann arbor, michigan...
and portsmouth,
new hampshire, in the rain.
whole towns signed up.
the 10th michigan
volunteer infantry
was made up
of flint boys.
their commander
was the mayor,
their regimental doctor,
the man who had been
taking care of them
since they were young.
the 6th new york contained
so many bowery toughs,
it was said a man
had to have done
time in prison
just to get into
the regiment.
the elite 7th,
on the other hand,
set out for washington
with sandwiches
from delmonico's
and 1,000
velvet-covered campstools
on which to sit
and eat them.
oh his way to war,
lieutenant george
armstrong custer,
just 22 and less than
a month out of west point,
where he graduated
at the bottom of his class,
stopped in new york
to have himself fitted out
with a splendid
new uniform...
then went
to a photographer.
in pawtuxet, rhode island,
19-year-old
elisha hunt rhodes
left his job
as a harness maker's clerk
and signed on
as a private
in the 2nd
rhode island volunteers.
he would
have joined earlier,
but his widowed mother
begged him to stay home.
"we drilled
all day and night.
"standing before
a long mirror,
"i put many hours
of weary work
"and soon thought myself
quite a soldier.
"i was elected
first sergeant,
"much to my surprise.
"just what
a first sergeant's
duties might be,
i had no idea."
after two weeks
of drilling,
the 2nd rhode island
moved out.
"today we have orders
to pack up
"and be ready to leave
for washington.
"my knapsack was so heavy
"that i could scarcely
stagger under the load.
"at the wharf,
an immense crowd
had gathered,
"and we went
on board our steamer
with mingled feelings
of joy and sorrow."
in baton rouge,
william tecumseh sherman
resigned as superintendent
of the louisiana
military academy
and headed north.
"you politicians,"
he told his brother,
senator john sherman
of ohio,
"have got things
in a hell of a fix,
"and you may get them out
as best you can.
i will have no more
to do with it."
but when sumter fell,
he put his uniform back on
and reluctantly
went to war.
"you might as well
attempt to put out
"the flames of
a burning house
with a squirt gun.
"i think this
is to be a long war,
"very long,
much longer than any
politician thinks."
"there are
but two parties now--
"traitors and patriots--
and i want hereafter
to be ranked
with the latter."
ulysses s. grant.
39-year-old
ulysses s. grant
was working
in his father's harness shop,
having failed
as a peacetime soldier
and considered
by some a drunk.
now he signed on
as a mustering officer,
handling the flood
of volunteers
at $4.20 a day.
"new orleans, 1861.
"i feel that i would like
to shoot a yankee,
"and yet i know that this
would not be in harmony
with the spirit
of christianity."
william nugent.
"so impatient
did i become
for starting
"that i felt
like 1,000 pins
were pricking me
"in every part
of my body,
"and i started off
a week in advance
of my brothers."
"i found mobile
boiling over
with enthusiasm.
"the young merchants
had dropped their ledgers
and were forming
and drilling companies
by night and day."
"every day,
regiments marched by.
"charleston is crowded
with soldiers.
"these new ones
are running in fairly.
"they fear the war
will be over
"before they get sight
of the fun.
"every man from every
little country precinct
wants a place
in the picture."
the confederate
government,
its capital
now in richmond,
called for 100,000
volunteers.
so many southerners
volunteered
that a third of them
had to be sent home.
they came from catahoula
and baton rouge,
louisiana...
greenville, mississippi,
moonsville, alabama,
the odds against a southern
victory were long.
tennessee
joined the confederacy.
so did arkansas
and north carolina.
in memphis,
nathan bedford forrest,
a blacksmith's son who had
made himself a millionaire
selling land,
cotton, and slaves,
put up posters
calling on anyone
who wanted to kill yankees
to come and ride with him.
the clinch rifles
from augusta, georgia,
started out in may 1861.
only the drummer boy
would survive.
there were nearly
21 million people
in the north,
just 9 million
in the confederacy,
and 4 million of them
were slaves,
whom their masters
did not dare arm.
the value of all
the manufactured goods
produced in
all the confederate states
added up to less than 1/4
of those produced
in new york state alone.
but none of this mattered
to the men who joined
the tallapoosa thrashers
and chickasaw desperados
and cherokee
lincoln killers.
"the histories
of the lost cause
"are all written out
by big bugs--
"generals
and renowned historians.
"well,
i have as much right
as any man
to write a history."
sam watkins.
one of the first
to answer the southern call
was 21-year-old sam watkins
of columbia, tenssee.
he joined company "h"
of the 1st tennessee
at nashville.
like most rebel soldiers,
he owned no slaves.
"and place everything
aboard the cars.
"we went bowling along
at 30 miles an hour
"as fast as steam
could carry us.
"at every town
and station,
"citizens and ladies
were waving
their handkerchiefs
"and hurrahing
for jeff davis
"and the southern
confederacy.
"it's worth soldiering
to receive
such a welcome as this."
"if the president
of the united states
would tell me
"that a great battle
was to be fought
"for the liberty
or slavery
of the country
"and asked
my judgment
"as to the ability
of a commander,
"i would say with
my dying breath,
let it be
robert e. lee."
general
winfield scott.
"i can anticipate
no greater calamity
for the country
"than a dissolution
of the union.
"it would be
an accumulation
"of all the evils
we complain of.
"and i am willing
to sacrifice
everything but honor
for its preservation."
robert e. lee.
the most promising officer
in the regular army
was robert e. lee
of virginia.
on april 18,
4 days after sumter,
lee was summoned
to blair house
at lincoln's behest
and offered field command
of the entire union army.
lee said he would
think about it.
virginia had voted to secede
the day before.
that night,
he paced anxiously
in the gardens around
his arlington mansion
across the potomac.
at midnight,
saturday the 20th,
lee wrote his letter
of resignation
from the united states army.
on the 21st,
the governor of virginia
asked lee to take command
of the state militia.
when lee had to choose
between the nation
and virginia,
there was never any doubt
about what his choice
would be.
he went with his state,
and he said,
"i can't draw my sword
against my native state"--
or, as he often said,
"my country."
lincoln had lost
his best soldier.
"not by one word
or look
"can we detect any change
"in the demeanor
of the negro servants.
"they make no sign.
"are they stupid?
"or wiser than we are?
silent and strong,
biding their time?"
mary chesnut.
both sides thought
it would be a 90-day war,
and both sides
agreed it was to be
a white man's fight.
blacks who tried to sign up
were turned away.
"april 19.
"there has been
a serious disturbance
in baltimore.
"regiments
from massachusetts
assailed by a mob
that was repulsed
by shot and steel."
"it's a notable
coincidence
"that the first blood
in this great struggle
"is drawn
by massachusetts men
on the anniversary
of lexington."
"we are in washington,
and what a city.
"mud, pigs,
negroes, palaces,
shanties everywhere.
"as we passed
the white house,
"i had my first view
of abraham lincoln.
"he looks like
a good, honest man.
"and i trust that,
with god's help,
"he can
bring our country
safely out
of its peril."
elisha hunt rhodes.
the rhode islanders
set up their bunks
at the patent office.
new yorkers slept
on the carpeted floor
of the house chamber.
massachusetts men
camped in the rotunda
and cooked their bacon
on furnaces
in the basement.
overhead, the capitol dome
remained incomplete.
despite the war,
lincoln insisted
that the work go on.
"i take it as a sign,"
he said,
"that the union
will continue."
"the first thing
in the morning is drill.
"then drill,
then drill again.
"then drill, drill,
a little more drill,
then drill.
"then lastly, drill.
"between drills,
we drill
"and sometimes stop
to eat a little
and have a roll call."
"outskirts of baltimore.
my dear william,
"i can now march
20 and 25 miles a day,
"live on short rations
"of hardtack,
raw, rancid bacon,
"green roasting ears
and cold water,
"sleep out in the rain
and heavy dew
"with nothing
but an army coat
over me,
and enjoy myself
capitally."
edward
hastings ripley.
there was
a confederate veteran--
a young country boy--
on guard duty.
he's walking his post
in the woods.
and there was an owl,
unknown to him,
in a tree nearby,
and the owl said,
"who
and the boy, trembling
with fear, said,
"it's me, sir,
john albert,
a friend of yours."
in may, union troops crossed
the potomac by torchlight
and took the heights
of arlington.
robert e. lee's house
would be occupied
by union troops
for the rest of the war.
in late june,
the new general
in charge of the union army,
irvin mcdowell,
outlined plans
for attacking
the confederates
in virginia,
but he did not yet
want to fight.
"this is not an army,"
he warned the president.
"you are green, it is true,"
lincoln answered,
"but they are green also.
you are all green alike."
to preserve
the constitution,
lincoln had for 3 months
gone beyond it--
waging war without
congressional consent,
seizing northern
telegraph offices,
suspending
habeas corpus.
to keep the border states
from seceding,
lincoln sent troops
to occupy baltimore
and clapped the mayor
and 19 secessionist legislators
in jail without trial.
chief justice taney ruled
that the president
had exceeded his power.
lincoln simply
ignored him.
"more rogues
than honest men
find shelter under
habeas corpus," he said,
and even contemplated
arresting the chief justice.
a very mysterious man,
he's got
so many sides to him.
the curious thing
about lincoln to me
is that he could
remove himself
from himself
as if he were looking
at himself.
it's a very strange,
very eerie thing
and highly intelligent.
such a simple thing
to say,
but lincoln's been
so smothered with stories
of his compassion,
that people forget
what a highly
intelligent man he was,
and almost
everything he did--
almost everything he did
was calculated for effect.
?? people ??
?? climbing ??
?? surely
make it... ??
"teach the rebels
and traitors
"that the price
they are to pay
"for the attempt
to abolish this government
must be the abolition
of slavery."
frederick douglass.
?
?? we will make it ?
?? soldiers ??
?? of the ??
?? cross ??
from the start of the war,
slaves fled
their plantations
for the union lines,
but lincoln's policy
was clear.
despite pressure
from the abolitionists,
he insisted he was
making war on secession,
not slavery,
and ordered the army
to return fugitives
to their owners.
but now, an unlikely figure
helped to change men's minds.
general benjamin butler
was a massachusetts politician
with crossed eyes
and mixed motives
who had once backed
jefferson davis
for president
of the united states.
"returning slaves only
aided the enemy,"
butler argued,
and he got permission
to hold fugitive slaves
as contraband of war
and employ them as laborers
in the union army.
"major cary
of virginia
"asked if i did not
feel myself bound
"by my constitutional
obligations
"to deliver up fugitives
under the fugitive slave act.
"to this i replied
that the fugitive
slave act
"did not affect
a foreign country,
"which virginia
claimed to be,
"and she must reckon it
one of the infelicities
of her position
that insofar, at least,
she was taken at her word."
general benjamin butler.
the trickle of runaways
coming into northern lines
now swelled to a flood.
one ex-slave who had
recently bought his freedom
told a union soldier,
"if i had known you gun men
was a-comin',
i'd have saved my money."
[explosions]
war was breaking out
all across the country.
there were engagements
at big bethel, virginia,
and booneville, missouri.
skirmishes from maryland
to new mexico territory.
at phillipi,
in western virginia,
a young union general
george mcclellan
won a small,
highly publicized victory
over a tiny
confederate force.
but still, there had been
no decisive battle.
"july 9.
our battle summer.
"may it be our first
and our last so-called.
after all,
we've not had any
of the horrors of war."
mary chesnut.
"july 16. it begins
to look warlike,
"and we
shall probably
have a chance
"a visit upon
the sacred soil
"of virginia
very soon.
"i hope we shall
be successful
and give
the rebels
a good pounding."
elisha hunt rhodes.
on july 16th,
the volunteer union army
of 37,000 men
marched into virginia.
their aim--to cut
the railroad at manassas,
then move on at last
to richmond.
washington star--
"the scene from
the hills was grand.
"regiment after
regiment was seen
coming along the road
"and across
the long bridge,
"their arms
gleaming in the sun.
"cheer after cheer
was heard as regiment
greeted regiment.
"with martial music
and sharp, clear orders
of commanding officers,
it made a combination
of sounds very pleasant
to the ear
of a union man."
to stop
the union invasion,
22,000 confederate troops
had moved north
from richmond
commanded by
general beauregard,
who knew in advance
the federals were coming.
rose greenhow,
a prominent socialite
in washington
and a confederate spy,
had alerted him.
now beauregard
made his headquarters
in wilmer mclean's
farmhouse.
the confederates formed
a meandering 8-mile line
along one side
of bull run creek.
they were less than
25 miles from washington,
and there they waited.
hundreds of washingtonians
in holiday mood
rode out to manassas
hoping to see
a real battle.
some brought
field glasses,
picnic baskets,
bottles of champagne.
"we saw carriages
which contained civilians
"who'd driven out
from washington
to witness the operations.
"a connecticut boy said,
there's our senator,
"and some of our men
recognized other
members of congress.
"we thought
it wasn't a bad idea
"to have the great men
from washington
come out to
see us thrash the rebs."
private james tinkham.
on the morning
of the 21st,
mcdowell sent his men
across bull run.
they smashed into the left side
of the confederate line,
driving the rebels from
one position after another.
the civilian onlookers
waved hats
and fluttered handkerchiefs.
it was not yet noon,
and all was going
just as they wanted.
"on reaching a clearing
"separated from
our left flank
by a rail fence,
"we were saluted
by a volley musketry
"which was fired
so high
"that all the bullets
went over our heads.
"my first sensation
was astonishment
"at the peculiar
whir of the bullets,
"and that the regiment
immediately laid down
without waiting
for orders."
"we fired
a volley and saw
the rebels running.
"the boys were
saying constantly
in great glee,
"we've
whipped them.
"we'll hang
jeff davis to
a sour apple tree.
they're running.
the war's over."
an onlooker remembered that
the advancing union army
looked like
a bristling monster
lifting himself
by a slow, wavy motion
up the laborious ascent.
union victory
seemed so sure
that on one part
of the battlefield
men stopped
to gather souvenirs.
but holding a hill
at the center
of the southern line
was a virginia brigade led
by general thomas jackson.
while other southern
commands wavered,
jackson's held firm.
one confederate officer,
trying to rally
his own frightened men,
shouted, "look! there's jackson
with his virginians,
standing like
a stone wall."
the name stuck.
he had
the strange combination
of religious fanaticism
and a glory in battle.
he loved battle.
his eyes would
light up.
because of the way
his eyes would
light up in battle.
he was totally fearless,
had no thought
whatsoever of danger
at any time
when the battle was on,
and he could define
what he wanted to do.
he said, "once you
get them running,
"you stay right
on top of them,
"and that way
a small force
can defeat a large one
every time."
he knew
perfectly well that
a reputation for victory
would roll and build.
it was the turning point.
at 4:00, beauregard
ordered a counterattack.
jackson urged his men
to yell like furies.
the rebel yell
first heard that day
would echo
from 1,000 battlefields.
confederate reinforcements
began to arrive.
the first cane
on horseback.
more arrived by train,
something new in war.
the northern army
fell apart.
the retreat
soon became a rout,
as union guns
became entangled
with the carriages
of fleeing spectators.
"we tried to tell them
that there was no danger,
"called on them to stop,
implored them to stand.
"we called them cowards.
"put out our
heavy revolvers
and threatened to shoot,
but all in vain."
"along the shady
little valley
"through which
our road lay,
"the surgeons
had been plying
"their vocation
all the morning
upon the wounded.
"tables
about breast-high
had been erected,
"upon which
screaming victims
"were having legs
and arms cut off.
"the surgeons and
their assistants,
"stripped
to the waist
"and all bespattered
with blood,
"stood around,
some holding
the poor fellas,
"while others, armed
with long, bloody
knives and saws,
"with frightful
rapidity,
throwing the mangled
limbs on a pile nearby.
as soon as removed."
lieutenant colonel
w.w. blackford,
1st cavalry,
virginia.
"what a horrible
sight it was--
"here a man,
"grasping his gun
firmly in his hands,
stone dead,
"several with
distorted features,
all horribly dirty.
"many were
terribly wounded,
some with legs shot off,
"others with arms gone.
"some so badly wounded
"they could not
drag themselves away,
slowly bleeding to death.
"we stopped many times
to give some a drink,
"and soon saw enough
to satisfy us
with the horrors of war."
lieutenant josiah favill.
"i struggled on,
clinging to my gun
and cartridge box.
"many times,
i sat down
in the mud,
"determined to go
no further
"and willing to die
and end my misery,
"but soon a friend
would pass
"and urge me to make
another effort,
"and i would stagger
a mile further.
"at daylight,
we could see
"the spires
of washington,
"and a welcome
sight it was.
"the loss
of regiment in this
disastrous affair
was 93 killed,
wounded, or missing."
there is a congressman,
i believe from alabama--
i've forgotten
where from--
who said there would
be no war,
and he offered to
wipe up all blood
that would be shed
with a pocket handkerchief.
that was his prediction.
i've always said,
someone could get a ph.d.
by calculating how many
pocket handkerchiefs
it would take
to wipe up all the blood
that was shed.
it would be
many handkerchiefs.
from the confederate
white house in richmond,
jefferson davis rejoiced.
"my fellow citizens,
"your little army,
"derided for
its want of arms,
"derided
for its lack
"of all
the essential
material of war,
"has met the grand
army of the enemy,
"routed it
at every point,
"and it now
flies inglorious
in retreat
"before our
victorious columns.
"we have
taught them a lesson
in their invasion
of the sacred soil
of virginia."
"today will be known
as black monday.
"we are utterly
and disgracefully
routed, beaten,
whipped by secessionists."
george templeton strong.
london times.
"the inmates
of the white house
"are in a state
of utmost trepidation
"and mr. lincoln
in despair.
"why beauregard does not
attack washington,
i know not,
nor can i well guess."
it was remembered
as the great skedaddle.
for days,
discouraged troops
straggled back
into washington.
"i saw
a steady stream of men,
"covered with mud,
soaked through with rain,
"who were pouring irregularly
up pennsylvania avenue
toward the capitol.
"a dense stream of vapor
rose from the multitude.
"i asked a pale young man
"who looked exhausted
to death
"whether the whole army
had been defeated.
"that's more
than i know,he said.
i know i'm going home.
i've had
enough of fighting
to last my lifetime."
the north was appalled
at the 5,000 casualties.
both sides now knew
it would be no
90 days war.
two days later,
canny real estate speculators
bought up the battlefield
to make a second kind
of killing--
as a tourist attraction.
"what upon earth
is the matter with
the american people?
"do they really covet
the world's ridicule
"as well as their own
social and political ruin?
"the national edifice
is on fire.
"every man who can
carry a bucket of water
"or remove a brick
is wanted.
"yet government leaders
persistently refuse
"to receive
as soldiers the slaves,
"the very class of men
which has a deeper interest
"in the defeat
and humiliation
"of the rebels
than all others.
"such is the pride,
the stupid
prejudice, and folly
that rules the hour."
frederick douglass.
"little
did i conceive
"of the greatness
of the defeat,
"the magnitude
of the disaster
"which had
entailed upon
the united states.
"so short-lived has been
the american union
"that men
who saw it rise
may live
to see it fall."
william russell,
london times.
"washington. august.
"i found no preparations
whatever for defense.
"not a regiment
was properly encamped,
"not a single avenue
or approach guarded.
"all was chaos,
and the streets,
hotels, and barrooms
"were filled
with drunken officers
"and men absent
from their regiments
without leave.
perfect pandemonium."
george mcclellan.
5 days after
the disaster at bull run,
a new general took over
the army of the potomac.
george brinton mcclellan,
only 34,
seemed just
what the north needed.
he brought with him
to the demoralized capital
what one aide called
"an indescribable air
of success."
he replaced inept officers
with regulars.
he laid out tidy camps
around washington
to accommodate
the 10,000 new volunteers
arriving each week,
drilled them
8 hours a day,
and staged grand reviews
to boost morale.
"all the attention
was upon the young general
"with the calm eye,
with the satisfied air,
"who moved around
followed by an immense staff
"to the clanking
of sabers
and the acclamation
of the spectators."
regis de trobiand.
"i find myself in
a new and strange
position here--
"president, cabinet,
general scott,
"and all
deferring to me.
"by some strange
piece of magic,
"i seem to have become
the power of the land.
"i almost think
that were i to win
"some small
success now,
"i could
become dictator,
"or anything else
that might please me.
"but nothing
of that kind
would please me.
"therefore, i won't
be a dictator.
admirable
self-denial."
the newspapers called him
young napoleon,
and he could not help seeing
the resemblance himself.
but 100,000
untrained volunteers
had become an army.
mcclellan's army.
his men, who loved him
for have made them
proud of themselves,
called him little mac.
his specialty
is preparing
troops to fight,
and he did that superbly.
mcclellan
trained that army.
whatever the army
of the potomac did
in the after years
is largely due
to the training
mcclellan gave them
in that first year.
with lincoln,
mcclellan and his staff
devised a 3-pronged attack
on the confederacy.
one army would
drive into virginia
and take richmond.
another would secure
kentucky and tennessee,
then push into the heartland
of the confederacy
and occupy mississippi,
alabama, and georgia.
meanwhile, the navy would
clear the mississippi,
surround
the confederacy by sea,
and choke off supplies.
the war would be fought
along a 1,000-mile front.
that fall,
lincoln elevated mcclellan
to general in chief,
replacing the aging
winfield scott.
"i can do it all,"
mcclellan said.
but he did nothing.
as summer
turned to autumn,
it became
increasingly clear
that having made
a magnificent army,
george mcclellan had
no immediate plans
to lead it anywhere.
"as we approached
the brow of the hill,
"my heart kept getting
higher and higher,
"until it felt
it was in my throat.
"i would have given
anything then
"to have been back
in illinois,
"but i kept right on.
"when the valley below
was in full view, i halted.
"the enemy's troops
were gone.
"my heart
resumed its place,
"and it occurred
to me at once
"that he had been
as much afraid of me
"as i of him.
"this was a view
of the question
i had never taken before,
but it was one
i never forgot afterwards."
general ulysses s. grant.
in september,
ulysses s. grant
took paducah, kentucky,
a strategic city
at the mouth of the tennessee,
but two months later,
his undisciplined recruits
were almost destroyed,
looting a captured
rebel camp
instead of preparing
for a counterattack.
grant was returned
to desk duty.
in november,
william tecumseh sherman
was relieved as
union commander in kentucky
when he insisted that
at least 200,000 men
would be needed
to suppress the rebellion
in the west.
no one believed him.
he grew melancholic,
prone to fits
of anxiety and rage.
"sherman," mcclellan said,
"is gone in the head."
december found him at home
in the care of his wife,
contemplating suicide.
no. no one thought
it would last long.
no one on either side
thought it would last long.
those few individuals
who said that it would,
tecumseh sherman,
for instance,
were actually judged
to be insane
for making predictions
about casualties,
which were actually low.
in november,
a union warship
stopped a british steamer
at gunpoint
and arrested two confederate
diplomats found on board.
britain's prime minister,
lord palmerston,
was outraged, demanded
their immediate release,
and dispatched
11,000 troops to canada.
"one war at a time,"
lincoln said,
and quietly let
the two confederates go.
by december,
optimists on both sides
were disappointed.
the confederacy showed
no signs of imminent collapse.
the north would not
abandon its efforts
to reunite
the nation by force.
by the end of the year,
there were 700,000 men
in the union army.
no one knew how many
confederates there were.
"december 31st.
"poor old 1861 just going.
"it has been a gloomy year
of trouble and disaster.
"i should be glad
of its departure
were it not that 1862
is likely to be no better."
george templeton strong.
a week before
the battle of bull run,
sullivan ballou,
a major in the 2nd
rhode island volunteers,
wrote home to his wife
in smithfield.
"july 14, 1861.
washington, d.c.
"dear sarah,
"the indications
are very strong
"that we shall
move in a few days,
perhaps tomorrow,
"and lest i should not
be able to write you again,
"i feel impelled
to write a few lines
"that may fall
under your eye
when i'm no more.
"i have no misgivings about
or lack of confidence
"in the cause in which
i am engaged,
"and my courage
does not halt or falter.
"i know how
american civilization
"now leans
upon the triumph
of the government,
"and how great
a debt we owe
"to those who went
before us
"through the blood
and suffering
of the revolution,
"and i am willing,
perfectly willing,
"to lay down
all joys in this life
"to help maintain
this government
"and to pay that debt.
"sarah, my love for you
is deathless.
"it seems to bind me
with mighty cables
"that nothing but
omnipotence can break,
"and yet my love
of country
"comes over me
like a strong wind,
"and bears me irresistibly
with all those chains
to the battlefield.
"the memory of all
the blissful moments
i have enjoyed with you
"come crowding over me,
"and i feel
most deeply grateful
to god and you
"that i've enjoyed them
for so long.
"and how hard it is
for me to give them up
"and burn to ashes
the hopes of future years,
"when, god willing,
we might still have
lived and loved together,
"and see our boys
grown up to honorable
manhood around us.
"if i do not return,
my dear sarah,
"never forget
how much i loved you,
"nor that when
my last breath escapes me
on the battlefield,
"it will whisper your name.
"forgive my many faults
"and the many pains
i have caused you.
"how thoughtless,
how foolish i have
sometimes been.
"but, oh, sarah,
"if the dead can
come back to this earth
"and flit unseen
around those they love,
"i shall always be
with you
"in the brightest day
and the darkest night.
"always.
"and when the soft breeze
fans your cheek,
"it shall be my breath.
"or the cool air
at your throbbing temple,
"it shall be
my spirit passing by.
"sarah, do not
mourn me dead.
"think i am gone
"and wait for me,
for we shall meet again."
sullivan ballou
was killed a week later
at the first battle
of bull run.