[Crickets chirping]
[People chattering faintly]
[Ship's horn blows]
[Woman singing in Vietnamese]
[Explosion]
FOWLER: I can 't say what made
me fall in love with Vietnam...
that a woman 's voice
can drug you...
that everything
is so intense.
The colors...
the taste...
even the rain.
Nothing like the filthy rain
in London.
[Distant gunfire]
They say whatever
you 're looking for...
you will find here.
They say
you come to Vietnam...
and you understand a lot
in a few minutes...
but the rest
has got to be lived.
The smell...that's the first
thing that hits you...
promising everything
in exchange for your soul.
And the heat.
Your shirt
is straightaway a rag.
You can hardly remember
your name...
or what you came
to escape from.
But at night,
there's a breeze.
The river is beautiful.
You could be forgiven for
thinking there was no war...
that the gunshots
were fireworks...
that only pleasure matters.
A pipe of opium...
or the touch of a girl...
who might tell you
she loves you.
[Thud, splash]
And then
something happens...
as you knew it would.
And nothing can ever
be the same again.
Monsieur Fowler,
thank you for coming in.
I'm sorry to ask you
at this hour.
Well, I know
about as much as you do.
He's an American.
He's about thirty.
He works for
the Economic Aid Mission...
and I like him.
He's a very good chap.
Serious. Not like
those noisy bastards...
down at the Continental.
He's a quiet American.
Yes, a very quiet American.
He's dead, isn't he?
Not guilty. I just put
two and two together.
He was killed by a knife.
Can you identify him?
Yes.
He was... a friend.
To tell you the truth,
I'm not completely sorry.
These Americans are causing
a lot of trouble to us.
But still,
a murder is a murder.
Anything to help us?
[Woman singing in Vietnamese]
No... nothing at all.
Please.
[Bell ringing]
[Thunder]
[Woman talking indistinctly]
[Door opens]
[Door closes]
[Opens door]
[Closes door]
Pyle...
est mort.
Assassinated.
How?
He was stabbed.
Pyle est mort.
Yes.
He was in love with me.
Yes, he was.
I'm so sorry, Phuong.
I go to my mother's.
I must think.
[Car horn honks]
FOWLER: I met Pyle
where you meet everybody...
at the Hotel Continental.
I'm there
every morning at 11 i 00.
I'm English. I have habits.
I drink tea.
I'm a reporter, so I listen.
I have a lover.
I like to watch her arrive
with her friends...
at the milk bar.
And there was Alden Pyle...
a face with no history
and no problems.
The face we all had once.
- I'm Alden Pyle.
- I'm Thomas Fowler.
The "London Times."
You've done your homework.
I've read your articles.
May I join you?
Please.
And what brings you
to Saigon, Mr. Pyle?
I'm with
the Economic Aid Mission.
I'm on the medical side.
My specialty is eye disease.
Do you know trachoma?
It's very common here.
It's actually very easy
to treat and prevent.
You staying at the hotel?
No, I just dropped by...
for a cup of tea
on the way to the office.
PYLE: This is really
a stroke of luck for me.
You're one of
the few correspondents...
who has a reputation of actually
going out into the field.
Not anymore. And besides...
I have never thought of myself
as a correspondent.
I am just a reporter.
I offer no point of view,
I take no action...
I don't get involved.
I just report what I see.
But you must have an opinion.
Even an opinion
is a form of action.
Still, I'd appreciate it
if you could...
FOWLER: Pyle was hungry for
everything I could tell him...
about Vietnam and her fight
for independence.
Why were the French
losing the war?
And why were
the Communists winning?
Then he saw Phuong.
I should've realized how saving
a country and saving a woman.
would be the same thing
to someone like Pyle.
PYLE: We've got
to contain Communism...
or what they call Communism.
FOWLER: What could be done,
what should be done...
what he thought,
what he'd read.
He made me remember
there was a time...
when I had wanted
to make a difference.
PYLE: to watch liberty
snuffed out?
FOWLER: "Liberty"
is a very western word.
How do you define it
for the Vietnamese?
By giving people
the freedom to choose.
OK, you give them
the freedom to choose...
they vote,
and they elect Ho Chi Minh.
Things are more complicated
than they seem.
[Explosion]
- What was that?
- A grenade.
[Whistle blowing]
Sounded like a car backfiring.
A week here,
and you'll know the difference.
It's been a genuine pleasure
meeting you.
Maybe we could
eat dinner sometime.
- I look forward to it.
- Great.
Good morning.
[Man talking indistinctly]
Morning, Hinh.
Anything new?
HINH:
Corruption, mendacity.
I said "new."
There is a rumor
that the Communists...
are planning an attack
in the north, at Phat Diem.
One of your contacts?
Yes, sir.
Oh... and a telegram.
- From the London office.
- Mr. Stemins.
He says the paper has conducted
a review of the foreign desk.
He wants you based in London.
Christ.
I thought
you liked London, sir.
I do, but I like it
just where it is.
I don't want
to bloody go there.
For what, a desk job?
They probably think
it's cheaper...
to let the wire services
cover Vietnam.
How many stories
have we given them?
This year?
- Yes.
- Three.
No shit.
Maybe I should go up there.
HINH: Where, sir?
Phat Diem.
It's not an easy place to get
into with the Communist attack.
Send a cable to Stemins.
"Understand your
current concern. Stop.
"Am working on a story
of major proportions. Stop.
"Suggest I remain in Saigon
until completed. Stop.
"Fowler."
Which story is that, sir?
I don't know...
but I'm sure
that you know someone...
who can get me in there.
[Ominous music playing]
[Woman singing in French
on radio]
Ah!
[Giggles]
Today our anniversary.
Did you forget?
Can it be?
Two years already?
- Yes.
- Heh heh. Yes.
Ah! Be careful with me.
I'm old and fragile.
Not so old.
Not so fragile.
Tom!
Thomas.
Thomas. Hello.
Hello again.
I'm here with some friends.
Care to join us?
Phuong, this is Mr. Pyle.
- Alden, please.
- Enchanté.
Delighted to meet you, too.
Please excuse my bad French.
You know Joe Tunney
from the American Legation.
I know Joe. Overthrown
any small countries recently?
Fowler sees
conspiracies everywhere.
Is it true the Communists
are attacking Phat Diem?
How the fuck should I know?
We only report victories.
One of our medical teams
wasn't allowed past Nam Dinh.
I was thinking
of going up there.
PYLE: It's a Catholic town,
isn't it?
Pretty strong
against the Communists.
- You got a date tonight?
- Bill.
She's got a date every night.
You got your piece of ass,
I want mine.
Pyle, fellas...
let's go to the House
of 500 Girls.
Oh, no. Thanks.
I was planning on taking
Mr. Fowler...
We've already got a table
at the Arc En Ciel.
BILL: That's great.
You go eat
at the L'Arc En Ciel...
and I'll get eaten next door.
- Sounds like a plan.
- Yeah.
Come on, Bill. Walk with me.
Gents.
[People chattering]
FOWLER:
Seems like a nice young man.
What does he do?
Something with medical aid.
PYLE: Where are we going?
Go get us a table,
and I'll rescue our Mr. Pyle.
- Merci, monsieur.
- Thank you.
[Woman singing in Vietnamese]
[Women shouting]
PYLE:
I'm just dropping him off.
I'm not staying.
No, no, no.
Please, please, please.
No, come on.
Pyle, let's get out of here.
No, no, no. Let me go.
Put your arm around this one.
If they think you've chosen one,
they'll let you go.
- Put your arm around her.
- Excusez-moi!
BILL:
Who wants to be with me?
Good night, Granger!
[Woman singing in French]
Miss Phuong, I'm so sorry.
Please forgive us
for keeping you waiting.
I forgive you.
We had to make sure
that Bill Granger got home.
Home! Ha ha ha!
- Monsieur, a ticket?
- Sorry?
Tickets for the taxi dancers.
With the girls here,
you buy a ticket for a dance.
PHUONG: Buy a ticket,
maybe I dance with you.
PYLE: There you are.
Shall we?
[Song ends]
[New song begins]
Phong is a very beautiful name.
Phuong.
It means "phoenix."
Oh.
I thought it meant "flower"...
like the ones in your hair.
Do you like my hair?
This is traditional style.
It's very nice.
Do you know Vietnamese?
Yeah, sure. Try me.
When you dance,
don't try to lead.
When...
No, I don't...
[Laughs]
I only know two words.
I know...
beer and hair cut.
- Mr. Fowler?
- Hello.
May I?
Of course.
Thanks.
Haven't seen you
for a long time.
I'm away a lot.
Yes.
Who's he? Y our friend?
His name is Pyle.
He's with the American
Economic Mission.
He's from Boston, in America.
He's a very bad dancer.
Yes.
[Song ends]
He is married?
Not that I know of, no.
This is Miss Hei,
Phuong's sister.
Alden Pyle.
Very happy to meet you.
Your father is a businessman?
No. He's a professor.
My sister
is very good dancer, yes?
She's too good for me.
She's my only sister.
He's cute, the American.
And money, too.
Sometimes you're as vulgar
as the French you hate so much.
Your sister's
a very pretty girl.
My sister is the most
beautiful girl in Saigon.
I don't doubt that at all.
Mr. Fowler's a very lucky man.
MISS HEI:
My father was very sad.
He had no grandchildren.
Would you like a drink?
No, thank you.
My friends.
So pleased to have met you.
I hope we meet again soon.
Perhaps you could arrange.
When I get back
from the north.
You are going north?
Yes.
Then you must have dinner
with me and my sister...
while Mr. Fowler is gone,
to cheer her up.
Thank you.
I'd like that very much.
What a nice woman.
An absolute saint.
She used to work in office...
import/export.
- Really?
- She knows shorthand.
- Does she?
- Maybe you need someone.
Maybe we could
work something out.
[New song begins]
Please forgive me for dancing
with Miss Phuong so many times.
That's all right.
I like watching her dance.
She's a very good dancer.
She should be.
She used to do it for a living.
What do you mean?
She was a taxi dancer,
a hostess...
here at the Arc En Ciel.
I thought you said
she came from a good family.
She did, but the father died...
so the sisters
had to earn a living.
Oh. That's too bad.
What?
Isn't that just a step up from
the girls across the street?
Good God, no.
Took me six months...
to get her to go out on a date.
Oh.
[Explosion]
Grenade.
A grenade. [Laughs]
[Whistle blowing]
So, are you married?
- Yes, I am.
- Hmm.
Bonsoir, mademoiselle.
But not to her.
FOWLER: There's something
I haven't told you.
I got a telegram
from the paper...
asking me to go back
to London.
So, when you go?
I've cabled them, asking them
to let me stay, but...
if they stop paying me,
I'm not sure how we'll live.
I come with you to London.
I'd marry you if I could.
You know that?
Yes.
That's what
I always tell my sister.
Do you think your wife
will give divorce?
I doubt it.
FOWLER:
When did everything change?
Maybe there isn't one moment.
A cable from London
calling me home...
or watching them
dancing together...
or what followed
between us...she and l...
through the long night.
[People shouting]
I was never brave...
but there I was,
heading north...
the fear of losing Phuong
more terrifying...
than the fear of any bullet.
The Communists attacked
four days ago.
We pushed them back
only yesterday.
We think there is 300
in this village.
But you will not see them.
FOWLER:
It's getting worse, isn't it?
How long can you keep going?
A few months maybe.
My men are counting bullets.
[Crickets chirping]
[Birds twittering]
Silence.
[Speaking French]
[Engine rumbling]
[Gunshot]
No, no, no, no!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Pyle?
[Soldier speaks French]
What the hell
are you doing here?
PYLE: They wouldn't let my
trachoma team out of Nam Dinh...
so I figured I'd see
what was going on for myself.
FOWLER:
You're lucky to get here alive!
[Radio chattering]
It wasn't that hard
after I hired a boat.
Wasn't that expensive.
I just bought it.
You are mad.
- I'm mad?
- Yes.
Have you ever seen anyone
with trachoma?
I suppose I have.
It's not that easy
to remain uninvolved.
Here.
FOWLER: "Not that easy
to remain uninvolved. "
I had hidden for so long
behind a typewriter.
What we found there...
what we saw in Phat Diem...
what did that do...
to his zeal...
to my detachment?
The dead are not involved.
The dead have no zeal.
They are lying in wait.
You see them...
all their tenderness...
and then they haunt you.
Communists?
Clearly. This is not the work
of French soldiers.
FOWLER: It doesn 't make sense.
The Communists
don't kill townspeople.
It is not in their interest.
SOLDIER:
Maybe another faction.
There are so many of them.
Each with their own army.
[Ominous music playing]
What's that book
you're always reading?
York Harding...
"Dangers to Democracy."
- An American?
- Yeah.
He was out here
a couple of years back.
Was he here long?
I don't know.
I heard him lecture once.
Joe actually met him.
He put forward the idea
of a third force...
to run Vietnam...
not the Communists
and not the French.
Not the Americans?
No, we're not colonialists.
Something that could
really help these people.
SOLDIER:
You have a gun, either of you?
No.
They shall attack
again tonight.
You don't want
to be taken alive.
Believe me.
Shoot yourselves.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
Stay inside that bunker!
[Man shouting in French]
Do you want something to eat?
No, thank you.
Come on.
You didn't come up
to check your medical team.
Joe Tunney sent you, right?
A little intelligence work.
I've never been very good
at keeping secrets.
There is another reason
why I came up here.
[Bomb whistling]
It's you.
Me?
Yep.
You said that
you might be coming up here.
Yeah.
[Cow moos]
[Explosions]
Um...
The thing is,
it's about Phuong.
Well, I guess it started...
that night when we were
at the L'Arc En Ciel...
and I was dancing with her.
Ha ha! I didn't think
you ever got close enough.
And then I had dinner
with her and her sister...
[Bomb whistles]
last Saturday and...
just when I was sitting there
looking at her...
it all just
became so clear to me.
I see.
Look, Tom,
none of this was planned.
There's no way...
I never ever used to believe
in love at first sight.
But after seeing all those girls
in that awful place...
and thinking that Phuong could
very easily become one of them...
I want to protect her.
And what did she say when
you offered her your protection?
- I haven't told her yet.
- You haven't told her?
No. I didn't think
it would be right.
I wanted to speak
with you first.
[Men shouting]
Look, if you two
had been married...
that'd be a completely
different situation.
I could never marry her.
Oh, shit.
My wife would never
give me a divorce.
She's a Catholic.
[Bombs whistling]
It's getting closer.
They're walking it in.
[Bombs exploding]
[Men talking]
PYLE: Dear Thomas...
I guess I'll be back
in Saigon ahead of you...
and I wanted
to reassure you...
that I won 't go to see Phuong
until after you return.
If you can make
the next transport out...
you should be back
by the end of the week.
I can check in
with your assistant...
to see if you made it.
If so...
I'll come around
to see you both on Friday...
say, 5i 00?
Anyone due to go out
to Hong Kong?
Someone from Reuters,
I believe.
Type this up, will you...
and ask him to cable it
to London for me.
Your big story?
Yes. Massacre at Phat Diem.
Nobody did it, of course.
Not the French,
not the Communists...
but there are rumors.
What's going on?
I forgot.
- What?
- It's a rally.
A new political party.
Bloody hell.
I think I better leave
your car here, sir.
We can walk.
[Music playing]
[Crowd cheering]
Isn't that Colonel Thé?
General Thé.
- Who made him a general?
- He did.
He broke away from the French
and formed his own army.
- Hello.
- Hi.
You have a dog.
- Come in.
- Thanks.
[Whistles] Come on.
Is Phuong...?
She's gone to see her sister.
Oh.
Would you like a whiskey?
Just a soda, thanks.
Does he have to do that?
Huh? Duke, come here.
You called him "Duke"?
Yeah. Found this guy
on the street.
Didn't I?
Who could turn their back
on a mug like that?
I saw you and Joe Tunney
at the parade.
Go sit.
Did you go on to the rally?
Thanks. Yeah, I did.
It was really something else.
I thought only
American politicians...
went in for that nonsense.
All that was missing
was the ticker tape.
They sure didn't forget
the brass band.
He's a pretty impressive guy,
that General Thé.
It doesn't trouble you
that he's a complete egomaniac?
Look, I don't want to talk
about Phuong behind her back.
I thought she was going
to be here.
Her sister told me
about her predicament.
What predicament is that?
I think you know.
No.
You can't marry her,
and by living with you...
she can never have a proper
marriage to a Vietnamese man.
She doesn't need
a proper marriage...
with a Vietnamese man.
She's with me.
[Door opens]
There she is.
FOWLER: Hello, Phuong.
- My sister is out.
- Oh.
- Hello.
- It's very nice to see you.
Actually, it's you that Mr. Pyle
has come to visit, Phuong.
Why don't we all sit down?
Unless of course
you want me to leave.
No, no, no,
that wouldn't be right.
We shall sit down, then.
Fire away.
Phuong...
ever since I met you
and danced with you...
and talked with you...
I haven't been able to get you
out of my thoughts...
for more than a moment.
And...
I've fallen in love with you.
You fall in love with me?
Please,
believe me when I say...
I've never behaved
like this before.
I apologize.
It is abrupt
and ill-mannered, but...
I'm in love with you.
Shouldn't you be on one knee?
Phuong, I'm not a rich man...
but I do have assets...
- Let's toss for her.
- What can you offer her?
Oh, Christ.
I don't expect you
to love me right away.
You can always make love
to the chauffeur...
while he's at the office.
You have no right
to insult her!
Will you shut
your bloody dog up?
Come with me right now.
Tell him to bugger off
and take his dog with him.
[Dog growls]
No.
She said no.
Yes.
Sit down, have a scotch.
No. I should go.
I'm so sorry. I apologize.
- Do you want to smoke a pipe?
- A pipe?
Opium.
No. Why would I do that?
[Whistles]
FOWLER: "I know
before we married...
"you warned me
your beliefs meant...
"that there could
never be a divorce.
"All the same,
that's what I'm asking for now.
"The fact is,
I love someone very much.
"I want you
to feel affection...
"act before
you have time to think...
"and just cable me
and tell me you agree. "
I've just asked my wife
for a divorce.
Your sister...
Was she really out?
I told you.
I thought perhaps
she sent you back...
so that you could meet Pyle.
He's very young.
That's not so important.
[Louis Armstrong
singing on record player]
HINH: Good news.
They printed your story.
Got a cable from Stemins.
This got me
a month's reprieve.
HINH: Page ten...
"French break Communist siege."
They didn't use much, did they?
Nothing here about
the villagers that were killed.
What did the French paper say?
Headlines... blaming it
on the Communists, of course.
Well, a month is a month.
What else can you tell me
about this General Thé?
He set himself up against both
the French and the Communists.
Do you think
he'd give me an interview...
if I went up the holy mountain?
Difficult to say.
Perhaps if he thought
he could get his message across.
The problem would be
getting it past the censor.
No, the real problem
would be to get close...
to the Cambodian border
and back before dark.
The Communists control
that road at night.
So many Europeans
have been killed out there.
[Speaking Vietnamese]
I am Thomas Fowler
of the "London Times"...
and I'm here
to interview General Thé.
[Speaking Vietnamese]
Thomas Fowler
of the "London Times."
I'm here to see General Thé.
[Shouts in Vietnamese]
[Shouting in Vietnamese]
FOWLER:
September, October, November.
I'd seen Pyle only once...
since he'd asked Phuong
to marry him...
at the Continental.
He'd been polite, of course.
How was I? How was Phuong?
He'd been busy, he said,
out of the city...
working on
his medical program.
PYLE: Thomas!
Somehow I wasn't
surprised to see him.
Thomas!
I was surprised
to be pleased to see him.
What brings you out
to these parts?
I was hoping
to interview the general...
but they've thrown me
out of the place.
What's your excuse this time?
Heh heh heh.
This is a test run for us.
The French,
in a typically French way...
have been very uncooperative...
but General Thé was good enough
to let us set up camp here.
I'll get him to let you in.
C'est bon. C'est bon.
PYLE: Joe Tunney's
running aid programs...
with some of the businesspeople
close to Thé.
- Mr. Muoi?
- Mr. Pyle.
- Hello, how are you?
- Good.
PYLE:
His name is Thomas Fowler.
He's looking for an interview
with the general.
[Firing]
My name is Mr. Muoi.
The general
only has a few moments.
FOWLER: May I first
ask you a question?
Please.
What is your relationship
to the general?
MUOI: I'm a businessman
and a patriot.
Many of the supplies and aid
that you see here...
are the result of my efforts.
Shall we begin
with the first question?
FOWLER: You say
you've broken away...
from the French and Vietnamese
forces with which you served.
Do any ties remain?
[Muoi translating]
[Speaking Vietnamese]
MUOI:
The French are colonialists.
Not to be trusted.
[Thé speaking Vietnamese]
MUOI: It will take an
independent Vietnamese leader...
to rule our country.
How does the general
expect to launch...
a successful campaign
against the larger forces...
of the Communists and the French
with so few men and supplies?
And who is providing
the means...
for the general
to achieve this victory?
[Muoi translating]
[Speaking Vietnamese]
Has he been fighting his war
in the north?
There was a massacre
at Phat Diem.
Were your forces present?
[Speaking Vietnamese]
[Shouts]
Regrettably, the general
has just recalled...
that he has another urgent
appointment, so, please...
Thank you.
That was quick.
FOWLER: Things didn't go
entirely according to plan.
Watch yourself with Joe.
I think he's up to something
with General Thé.
Can I get a ride
back to Saigon with you?
There's something wrong
with my car.
Yes, of course you can.
Hello.
Some kind soul
has had mine cleaned.
I heard a rumor that
you've been recalled to London.
Really?
Who told you that?
Phuong's sister.
[Engine rattling]
- Shit.
- What is it?
We're out of petrol.
Some bugger up in the mountains
must have siphoned it off.
[Engine stops]
FOWLER: They might have
some spare petrol...
in that watch tower.
[Car door opens]
[Birds squawking]
Hello!
Is anybody there?
FOWLER:
It looks like it's deserted.
I'll go in and have a look.
[Opens door]
Hello?
Is anyone there?
Excusez-moi.
My car down below
has run out of gas.
Do you have any gas to sell?
No.
Is everything OK?
FOWLER: Yes... come up.
My friend and I will have
to stay here until morning.
It's not allowed.
My friend.
Oh. Hey...
[Speaking French]
OK? Go easy.
Whoa...whoa.
[Pyle speaking French]
It's OK.
Please, lower your guns.
Please lower them.
He's a friend.
What are you thinking?
I was wondering what
she was doing right now.
This morning,
she met her friends...
for elevenses at La Fontaine.
Ice cream
and the latest gossip.
On her way home...
she stopped at the market
for fresh fish for dinner.
And now she's flipping through
the pages of magazines...
looking at photographs...
of the royal family
and film stars...
and listening to Bach's
"Well-Tempered Clavier."
I just got her started on Bach.
Have you had
a lot of women, Thomas?
You start out
by being promiscuous...
and end up
like your grandfather...
faithful to one woman.
I know I'm not essential
to Phuong...
but believe me when I tell you
that if I were to lose her...
for me...
it would be
the beginning of death.
[Distant gunfire]
Somebody's had it.
There are 30 or 40 of these
towers between here and Saigon.
They only hit
one or two a night...
so our odds aren't too bad.
[Speaking Vietnamese]
So, what do you think the...
they'd do if
the Communists attacked?
These two?
They'd fire a shot and run.
Why should they die for us?
Or the French?
- What's that?
- What?
I thought
I saw something move.
[Female soldier
speaking Vietnamese]
FOWLER:
Christ, they're here!
[Female soldier
speaking Vietnamese]
FOWLER: As far as
I can make out...
she's told them
to give us up... or else.
[Female soldier
speaking Vietnamese]
[Male soldier
Stop! Give me that!
Shh.
Come on, Thomas.
[Groans]
- What is it?
- I twisted my ankle.
[Men scream]
Unh.
[Panting and grunting]
Unh!
I'm gonna head up the road
to the next watch tower.
See if I can't find
a French patrol.
Sit tight.
I'll be right back.
[Panting]
[Woman singing faintly
in Vietnamese]
[Dance music playing]
- Hey!
May I introduce myself?
Thomas Fowler.
[Phuong laughs]
Thomas. Thomas.
I found a patrol.
If I had died...
you could've had her.
[People chattering]
FOWLER: And I think you should
inform your sources...
that General Thé
has a lot more men...
than the hundred
at their last count.
He's a story
we should take seriously.
HINH: Never underestimate
a patriot, sir.
FOWLER: What do you know
about this Muoi chap?
Would he have the means
to finance Thé's army?
Muoi?
He owns a bicycle factory.
I think Joe Tunney's
plotting with both he and Thé...
and it's more than just
foreign aid programs.
I'll see what
I can find out, sir.
[Jazz music playing]
Things are under control
at the office.
Try to get some rest.
Thank you, Hinh.
[Laughs]
Mmm! Ahh!
I miss you!
Ow. Ow.
Are you all right?
I'm all in one piece.
- You got a letter.
- A letter?
- From London.
- Yes?
- I fetch it for you?
- No.
Give me a kiss.
Give me one. Mmm.
Mmm.
I will get it.
PHUONG: You look afraid.
I'd better
have a brandy and soda.
[Knock on door]
Hello.
[Jazz music ends]
Pyle. Come in.
Thought I'd drop by
and see how you're doing.
Very well, thanks.
Good. How 's that leg?
I expect my tennis game
will suffer...
but it wasn't much
to begin with.
Thank you.
I'm glad you dropped by.
We have to thank Mr. Pyle,
Phuong, for saving my life.
Thank you.
How 's your sister doing?
Sister?
Yes. Alden got her a job
with Americans.
Oh, yes?
She likes it very much.
Thank you.
PYLE: Good. I'm very glad
to hear that.
Since you're both here...
now is as good a time
as any to tell you...
that I have received
a letter from my wife...
and she has more or less agreed
to give me a divorce.
[Laughs]
Ow!
[Chuckling]
That's wonderful.
Come sit.
No, thank you.
I've got plans.
Thank you for dropping by.
All right, bye.
- Bye, Phuong.
- Good-bye.
[Door closes]
[Hinh speaking Vietnamese]
Sir, l...
I trusted you, Thomas.
Always a mistake when
there's a woman involved.
Couldn't you have won
without lying?
What is it, anyway?
My sister read the letter
from your wife.
I show it to her...
because I was so proud,
so happy.
How could you treat her
like this?
"Dear Thomas,
you always picked up women...
"like you picked up mud
on your shoes."
I'm sorry, Phuong.
Why did you lie to her?
Obviously because
I wanted to keep her.
That's not love.
See, he doesn't even deny
he's a liar.
"Have you ever stopped
to think...
"how sad and lonely
this girl will be in England...
"especially when you decide
to leave her?"
Shut up, for Christ's sake.
"I don't believe in divorce.
"My religion forbids it,
and so the answer is no... no."
I was taught never to read
other people's letters.
I was taught not to tell lies.
PYLE: Come on, Phuong.
[Speaking Vietnamese]
I don't speak Vietnamese.
Get lost.
[Footsteps]
You were right about Muoi.
He does have connections.
Can we discuss this
some other time?
Crates from overseas have been
moving through his factory...
bypassing French customs.
My sources have been unable
to determine what they contain.
He's probably got
someone on the take.
He's an exporter,
not an importer.
Yes, well,
we'll do that tomorrow, OK?
A shipment just came in
this afternoon.
It could be gone
by the morning.
[Person hammering metal]
[Man speaking Vietnamese]
[Door opens]
What are you doing here?
I'm looking for Monsieur Muoi.
He's not here.
He invited me
to visit him here.
I'm a British journalist.
A friend of General Thé.
Where is Monsieur Muoi?
FOWLER: What is this
"diolacton"?
HINH: We must leave
immediately.
Crazy British,
they drink too much.
Go home. Rest.
He's a nobody.
He's a no-one.
What are you doing?
Trying to save your life.
Go!
Phuong?
- Good morning.
- Can I help you?
I think you've done
quite enough already!
Where's Pyle?
Alden? He's not in the office
this morning.
He does a lot
of his work at home.
- I know what he does at home.
- What do you mean?
Ask her. She fixed him up
with my girl.
Now, Fowler, we can't
have scenes in the office.
I know I am behaving badly...
but I have every intention
of behaving badly.
As a matter of fact, this is
exactly the kind of situation...
where one should behave badly.
Could we please
just lower our voice...
Why don't you bugger off!
Thomas, there is a lady here.
This lady and I
know each other quite well.
She tried to get
her rake off from me...
but now she's getting
one from Pyle.
We have a lot
of work to do, Thomas.
If Pyle phones,
tell him I called.
It would be polite
to return the visit.
How did he get in here?
[Sobbing]
This is Boston?
PYLE:
No, that's Niagara Falls.
So is that.
This is Boston.
That's Fanueil Hall.
I can't wait to take you
to my country.
My friend from school...
she go to airport
with her boyfriend.
He said he take her
to France...
but in the airport he disappear,
leave her there.
So many girls
with French boyfriend.
No one to marry them.
That'll never happen to you.
I promise.
- Hi.
- Have a nice Christmas?
- One long party.
Did Phuong forget something?
Heard you came by the legation.
Yes.
Who's this?
It's a bodyguard.
We all have them now.
FOWLER:
Are you married yet?
No, I figured I'd wait until
we got home and do it properly.
You don't mind
living here improperly?
It's hard to talk to you if
you're going to be so cynical.
It'd be good to do it
with my parents there.
I had a cable from head office.
They want me back.
Oh, that's, uh...
So it's good that Phuong
went off with you.
If I'd had to leave,
she might've ended up...
as another piece of ass
for someone like Granger.
At least I know
you'll treat her right.
Does this mean that
we can still be friends?
I don't see why not.
So, what is diolacton, anyway?
You know about that?
Shouldn't I?
Diolacton
is a milk-based plastic.
It's used for the frames
in the eyeglasses.
Are you still in touch
with General Thé?
- We keep the channels open.
- And Muoi?
He's been helpful in getting
our supplies through customs.
The French have started
to charge us...
You asked me for advice once.
Here it is.
Leave the bloody third force
to Joe, forget York Harding...
and go home with Phuong.
And would you shut the door
on the way out, please?
FOWLER: Morning, Larry.
What is it today?
Ah, you know,
some cockamamie assignment.
- Hey, we should go.
- You think so?
Joe Tunney said to be
out of here by 10 to 11:00.
It's five of now.
- What is it, anyway?
- I'm not sure.
Is it a demonstration?
I don't know,
but if Joe Tunney says...
[Car horn honks]
[Explosion]
[People screaming]
[People shouting]
[Speaks Vietnamese]
My friend is in there!
[Dramatic music playing]
[Siren wailing]
[Dripping]
HINH:
Did you cut your hand, sir?
Yes.
How is it down there?
HINH: Thirty dead.
Probably twenty more
by morning.
They've started arresting
Communist sympathizers.
There was a woman...
with a baby.
She covered it with her hat.
[Sirens wailing,
whistles blowing]
This man... he died...
right in front of his family.
Pyle...
Did you see him?
He spoke Vietnamese.
Vietnamese.
Like it was his, you know,
native language.
Larry! Larry!
Come over here! Get this!
Move it! Right here!
Right here!
On this side!
No, over here! No!
Get this! Right here!
No, no, no!
[Speaking Vietnamese]
[Both speaking Vietnamese]
Understand?
Go make yourself useful
somewhere else!
PYLE: Diolacton
is a milk-based plastic.
We use it for the frames
in the eyeglasses.
Muoi's been very helpful
in helping us...
get all of our supplies
through customs.
FOWLER: "Casein Plastics.
"Made from milk protein."
PYLE: York Harding...
"Dangers to Democracy."
He put forward the idea
of a third force...
"Used in the manufacture...
"of imitation
tortoiseshell and jade.
"Trade name, diolacton.
"Also used as a plasticizer
in explosive compounds."
PYLE: Joe Tunney 's
running aid programs...
with some of the businesspeople
close to Thé.
FOWLER: Muoi.
MUOI: The French
are colonialists...
not to be trusted.
FOWLER: And Thé.
MUOI: It will take
an independent...
Vietnamese leader
to rule our country.
FOWLER: The Americans
have been supplying them...
with materials to make bombs.
TUNNE Yi Fowler sees
conspiracies everywhere.
I have some contacts who would
like to speak to your friend.
Joe Tunney?
Pyle?
They feel he can give them...
important information
about all this.
You're saying Pyle is OSS?
I believe the new name is CIA.
Anyone can speak to him.
HINH: It's not so easy.
He's followed by protectors.
But if you ask
to meet with him...
man to man,
he would come alone.
[Siren passes outside]
These contacts,
are they Communists?
Officially, no.
Unofficially, yes.
I don't know.
Suppose you invite him
to dinner...
at the Vieux Moulin,
say, between 9:00, 9:30.
It's quiet near there.
My friends can speak to him
undisturbed.
Maybe he's engaged.
At 6:30...
my contacts will have
someone in the street...
outside your apartment.
All you have to do...
if you decide
to invite him to dinner...
go to the window
and open a book.
What will they do to him?
I promise you my contact
will act as gently...
as the situation allows.
[Carriage rolling]
Sooner or later, Mr. Fowler...
one has to take sides
if one is to remain human.
FOWLER: Pyle...
I need to speak to you...
about what happened
this morning...
in the Place Garnier.
[Men speaking indistinctly]
Phuong.
A letter for you.
[Men speaking Vietnamese inside]
Thank you.
Just give me a few minutes,
all right?
[Speaking Vietnamese]
[Door closes]
[Knock on door]
[Knock knock knock]
[Panting]
Come in.
I got your message.
So I see.
Lie down, lie down.
I'd love a drink.
I've only got hard liquor,
and you're probably on duty.
As a matter of fact,
I've noticed...
you're rarely off-duty
these days.
Whiskey would be fine.
People change.
Or maybe they never were
what we thought they were.
Hmm?
Who of us is, Thomas?
I suppose you want to talk
about General Thé.
FOWLER: Yes. And Mr. Muoi...
and diolacton.
We met with Thé this afternoon.
FOWLER: He's in Saigon?
Come to see how
his explosives worked?
His original target
was a military parade.
I don't mind telling you that
we were pretty tough on him.
Did you tell him you wouldn't
support him anymore?
We told him that if
he steps out of line again...
He tried to kill you
on the road to Saigon.
No. He tried to kill you.
And you knew?
I suspected
he might try something...
or one of his officers might,
so I tagged along.
You're a fool if you think
you can control General Thé.
In a war, you use
the tools you've got...
and right now
he's the best we have.
And in the meantime,
even more people must die.
Last year, the U.S. government
gave $210 million...
in military assistance
to the French in Indochina.
If we are going
to stop Communism...
and underwrite a third way...
we need to give the people
a leader who they admire.
Tomorrow morning,
when Congress...
reads the reports
and sees the photographs...
of the Communist atrocities
in the square...
they are going
to give us that support.
The French aren't going
to stop the Communists.
They haven't got
the brains or the guts.
How did I fit into all this?
Am I part of your cover?
Or a source of information?
Or did you have your eye
on Phuong all the time?
PYLE: You and Phuong...
I never planned
for any of that to happen.
Believe me,
it would have been easier...
if I never met
either one of you.
But you did,
and you lied to us.
PYLE: What do you want me
to tell you, Thomas?
That I take no action,
I have no opinion?
Tell me that you don't mean
any of this...
tell me you were
only obeying orders or...
that after what you saw
in the square... those children...
who did nothing
and hurt no one...
tell me that you were
so confused and horrified...
at how brutal and insane
these actions are...
tell me how
your love for Phuong...
has caused you
to have some doubts.
But it is because of Phuong
that I am even more determined.
Let's look at Phuong...
this beauty...
this daughter of a professor.
Taxi dancer, mistress
of an older European man.
That pretty well describes
the whole country, doesn't it?
Look, we are here to save
Vietnam from all of that.
What happened in the square
today makes me sick.
But in the long run,
I'm going to save lives.
It's you, isn't it?
Joe Tunney,
the staff at the legation...
Mr. Muoi, General Thé...
they all take their fucking
orders from you, Pyle.
York Harding prattles on
about a third force...
in that book you carry around.
You've actually gone out
and made one.
I don't think you see
the big picture, Thomas.
No, I do not see
the big picture.
FOWLER:
Do you know this poem?
"I walk down the street,
and I don't give a damn.
"The people, they stare,
and they ask who I am."
PYLE: "And if by chance
I should run over a cat...
"I can pay for the damage
if ever so bad."
We can disagree and remain
friends, can't we, Thomas?
Yes.
Look, I'm sorry.
Let's have dinner and
put this mess behind us.
9:00, Vieux Moulin, OK?
That sounds great.
I miss our conversations.
Vieux Moulin it is.
All right, then.
I'll tell Phuong that she can
have dinner with her sister.
I'll get her
to meet me here afterward.
Look, if...
if you can't make it,
come straight here.
I'll wait for you.
All right.
I'll see you soon, Thomas.
[Door closes]
[Accordion music playing]
[Dramatic music playing]
Walk.
[Chair squeaks]
I need to talk to somebody
who speaks English.
It's my son's birthday tonight.
[Shouting in Vietnamese]
We need to ask you
some questions.
I'm from the American Legation.
I'm just trying
to help people see.
[Dog barking]
The thing is,
I got a cable from my wife.
My boy has polio.
They don't know
if he's going to make it.
I don't care if he's crippled.
I just don't want him to die.
[Woman singing in Vietnamese]
[Groans]
[Wheezing]
[Removes knife]
[Gasping]
[Groaning]
I'm sorry.
I've got to get some air.
Throw him in the river.
MAN ON RADIO: ... and at least
2,000 people were killed...
and scores of others injured.
In the wake of last week's...
devastating bomb blast
in Saigon...
French officials
report that...
[Knock on door]
Phuong?
I'm sorry to bother you,
but would you mind...
to come downstairs
with me for a moment?
What do you want?
There's something
I would like to show you.
It seems Monsieur Pyle came
to see you the night he died.
So what, Vigot?
You said he did not.
By the way...
we found Pyle's dog.
They cut his throat.
[Rubbing floor]
You see here?
Pyle's dog.
Had cement between its toes.
This was poured on
the afternoon of his murder.
FOWLER:
So what does that prove?
Monsieur Bertrand of
the Vieux Moulin told me...
that night you asked for
a table for one, not two.
I have nothing more to add
to my original statement.
Nothing?
You know I didn't kill him.
There's a war on.
People are dying every day.
[Ballroom music playing]
Ask another girl.
I don't want another girl.
Will you come back now, Phuong?
- Will you come back to me?
- To London?
No. Not to London.
Then I don't come back.
Please, I...
I can't take you to London...
because I'm not going.
I'm not leaving you.
Never.
Will you come back to me?
Will you take down my hair?
Yes.
Do you miss him?
I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry?
I don't know.
I just feel that...
I ought to apologize
to someone.
Not to me.
Never to me.
FOWLER: They say
you come to Vietnam...
and understand a lot
in a few minutes.
The rest has got to be lived.
They say whatever it was
you were looking for...
you will find here.
They say there is a ghost
in every house...
and if you can
make peace with him...
he will stay quiet.
[Woman singing in Vietnamese]