Finish work!
Go to hut.
Yeah, that figures.
If the new prisoners see us
digging graves, they may run.
No time for jokes. Finish work!
Dig, dig.
How about putting us
on sick list?
Have a heart, captain.
Put us in hospital.
You no sick. You never sick.
Why you always play sick, Shears?
Don't want one of these
over my head, I guess.
Captain Kanematsu...
...how about a butt?
I give you butt this morning.
Both of you.
That's what I mean.
I want to return the favour.
When a man gives a gift
from the goodness of his heart...
...like you gave me that butt,
I remember it from the heart.
That's why...
...l want you to keep this lighter.
Think I stole it?
It belonged to that English kid
we just buried.
He gave it to me
for a favour I'd done him.
Before I pass on,
I want to do the same for you.
You funny man, Shears.
You go on sick list. Him too.
One of these days Colonel Saito
will catch you bribing him...
...then where'll we be?
Before that happens
we'll be far away from here, chum.
Far away.
Okay, let's knock off.
Here lies....
I forgot who we just buried.
Thomson.
Ah, yes.
Here lies Corporal Herbert Thomson...
...serial number zero-one-two-
three-four-five-six-seven.
Valiant member of the King's Own
or the Queen's Own or something...
...who died of beri-beri
in the year of our Lord, 1 943...
...for the greater glory of....
-What did he die for?
-Come off it.
No need to mock the grave.
I don't mock the grave or the man.
May he rest in peace.
He found little of it
while he was alive.
"A" Company, mark time!
Mark time!
Halt.
Into line, left turn.
Stand easy.
We're going to be
busy gravediggers, Weaver.
Well done, well done.
That colonel doesn't know
what he's in for.
You going to tell him the truth?
Of course not.
You're neither an officer
nor a gentleman.
My name is Nicholson.
I am Colonel Saito.
In the name of His lmperial Majesty...
...l welcome you.
I am the commanding officer
of this camp...
...which is Camp 1 6...
...along the great railroad...
...which will soon connect
Bangkok with Rangoon.
You British prisoners
have been chosen...
...to build a bridge
across the River Kwai.
It will be pleasant work,
requiring skill.
And officers will work as well as men.
The Japanese Army cannot
have idle mouths to feed.
If you work hard,
you will be treated well.
But if you do not work hard...
...you will be punished.
A word to you about escape.
There is no barbed wire.
No stockade.
No watchtower.
They are not necessary.
We are an island in the jungle.
Escape is impossible.
You would die.
Today you rest.
Tomorrow you'll begin.
Let me remind you of
General Yamashita's motto:
" Be happy in your work."
Be happy in your work.
Dismissed.
Battalion, stand at ease.
Fall out, Major Hughes.
Battalion, stand easy.
Hughes, get the men to their quarters.
See who's sick.
I'm going to have a word
with this fellow.
I heard your remarks just now, sir.
My men will carry on in the way
one expects of a British soldier.
My officers and I
will be responsible for their conduct.
You may have overlooked the fact
that the use of officers for labour...
...is expressly forbidden
by the Geneva Convention.
Is that so?
I have a copy of the convention...
...and would be glad to
let you glance through it.
That will not be necessary.
Sit down, please.
Yes, sir.
I'm going to have a word with Clipton.
Clipton, don't let me interrupt.
-How's the arm?
-Nearly healed.
Sir, this is Commander Shears
of the United States Navy.
How do you do, sir?
We found him and an Australian.
All that's left of the
prisoners who built the camp.
U.S. Navy? Out here?
I am sort of landlocked.
-You lost your ship?
-The Houston.
I made it ashore, but I got separated
from the other survivors.
And your group here?
Mostly Aussies. Some lime--
Some British.
Indians, Burmese, Siamese.
And what happened to them?
They died...
...of malaria, dysentery,
beri-beri, gangrene.
Other causes of death:
Famine, overwork, bullet wounds,
snakebites...
...Saito.
Then there were some
who just got tired of living.
Has Clipton seen you?
Just about to. Come over here,
you can shave later.
All right.
You'll stay with the officers.
We'll find some decent clothing.
Don't bother about me.
I'm not anxious to
get off the sick list.
Besides, this is working kit.
It's the fashion here.
The officers in your party
did manual labour?
I think you could call it that.
I raised that very point
with Colonel what's-his-name.
Saito.
-I think he understands now.
-Is that so?
Yes. I must say he seems
quite a reasonable type.
Well, I must be pushing on.
There's an officer's meeting at 7.
-Give me a list of your requirements.
-Yes, sir.
Anything we can do.
Thank you, sir.
-What is it?
-Never mind.
Go on, say it.
I can think of a lot of things
to call Saito...
...but reasonable, that's a new one.
Perhaps Col. Nicholson
defines the word differently.
Any other points?
-By your leave, sir?
-Jennings?
About the escape committee.
I've spoken with Cmd. Shears--
There won't be any escape committee.
I don't understand, sir.
Lt. Jennings has a plan.
Yes, yes, I'm sure Jennings
has a plan, but escape?
Where? lnto this jungle?
That fellow, Saito, is right.
No need for barbed wire here.
One chance in 1 00 of survival.
I'm sure a man of Cmdr. Shears'
experience will back me up on that.
I'd say that the odds against a
successful escape are 1 00 to one.
But may I add another word?
Please.
The odds against survival in this camp
are even worse.
You've seen the graveyard.
They're your real odds.
To give up hope of escape...
...to stop thinking about it
means accepting a death sentence.
Why haven't you tried to escape,
commander?
I'm biding my time. Waiting for
the right moment, the right company.
I understand how you feel.
Of course, it's the duty of a
captured soldier to attempt escape.
But my men and I are
involved in a curious legal point...
...of which you are unaware.
In Singapore we were ordered to
surrender by command headquarters.
Ordered, mind you.
Therefore, in our case, escape might
well be an infraction of military law.
Interesting point, sir.
I'm sorry, sir,
I didn't quite follow you.
You intend to uphold the letter
of the law, no matter what it costs?
Without law, commander,
there is no civilization.
That's just my point.
Here, there is no civilization.
Then we have the opportunity
to introduce it.
I suggest we drop
the subject of escape.
Is there anything else?
I think we're
clear on the program.
I want everything to go off smoothly
starting tomorrow morning.
And remember this:
Our men must always feel they are
still commanded by us...
...and not by the Japanese.
So long as they have that idea,
they'll be soldiers and not slaves.
Are you with me there, commander?
I hope they can
remain soldiers, colonel.
As for me, I'm just a slave.
A living slave.
Queer bird. Even for an Ameri--
He's been in isolation too long,
poor chap.
Cut off from his unit.
It should be a lesson to all of us.
English prisoners!
Notice I do not say English soldiers.
From the moment you surrendered,
you ceased to be soldiers.
You will finish the bridge
by the twelfth day of May.
You will work under the direction
of a Japanese engineer.
Time is short. All men will work.
Your officers will work beside you.
This is only just...
...for it is they
who betrayed you by surrender.
Your shame is their dishonour.
It is they who told you...
...better to live like a coolie
then die like a hero.
It is they who brought you here,
not l.
Therefore, they will join you
in useful labour.
That is all.
Officer prisoners, collect your tools.
Bradley, back in your place.
I must call your attention,
Colonel Saito...
...to Article 27
of the Geneva Convention.
" Belligerents may employ
prisoners of war...
...who are fit,
other than officers--"
Give me the book.
By all means.
You read English, I take it?
-Do you read Japanese?
-I'm sorry, no.
If it's a matter of translation,
I'm sure it can be arranged.
You see, the Code states that--
Stand fast in the ranks.
You speak to me of Code?
What " Code"?
The coward's code!
What do you know
of the soldier's code?
Of bushido? Nothing!
You are unworthy of command!
If you refuse to abide by the laws
of the civilized world...
...we must consider ourselves
absolved from our duty to obey you.
My officers will not do manual labour.
We shall see.
All enlisted prisoners to work.
Sergeant Major! Take the men to work.
Battalion, take up tools.
Move to the left in columnar route.
Left turn!
"A" Company, by the right,
quick march.
Eyes right.
Eyes front.
Quick march, eyes right.
" C" Company, by the right.
What's he up to?
Looks like he doesn't
want any witnesses.
Now, you will be reasonable.
You will order your officers to work.
No.
I will count three.
If by the third count...
...you and your officers
are not on the way to work...
...l will give the order to fire.
He's going to do it.
Believe me,
he's really going to do it.
One.
I warn you, Colonel....
Two.
Stop!
Colonel Saito,
I've seen and heard everything.
So has every man in the hospital.
They're too many witnesses.
You can't call it a mass escape.
Most of those men can't walk.
Is this your soldier's code?
Murdering unarmed men?
You see, Jennings, there are
advantages to being on the sick list.
I'll say this for the old man.
He's got guts.
" Into the valley of death
rode the 600."
How's that, sir?
That kind of guts.
Also the kind they had in 1 91 4...
...when officers fought
with only a swagger stick.
-I see what you mean.
-You don't see what I mean at all.
The kind of guts
that can get us all killed.
Excuse me, sir,
I'd like to go along too.
Arm's almost healed, sir,
really it is.
What about him?
He didn't order us not to escape,
he suggested.
Listen, when a man like your colonel
suggests something, it's an order.
Here we go again.
Colonel Saito says all officers
to punishment hut.
Tell them to go.
Not you.
Come.
Leave him alone!
They're going to put him in the oven.
For he's a jolly good fellow
And so say all of us
Timber!
One, two, three, four.
No, no, no!
Let go!
You wish to see me?
I've tried to see you for three days.
It's about the colonel.
He's been shut up in that hut--
I could have you shot.
Those prisoners who tried to escape,
they were in your charge.
I knew nothing about the escape.
It does not matter.
One must respect those who tried.
For a brief moment,
between escape and death...
...they were soldiers again.
But it is insane to try and escape.
Two soldiers shot
and the third drowned.
To what end?
It was an escape from reality.
There is your reality.
This shows the position work
should have reached by noon today.
And this shows the position
of actual progress.
Because of your colonel's stubbornness,
we are far behind schedule.
That is not all.
Enlisted prisoners sabotaged the work.
Yes, I have seen it.
I could have them all shot.
Then who would build your bridge?
Besides, are you sure it's sabotage?
The men don't work well
without their own officers.
My officers will direct them.
Your officers will work beside them.
That's for Nicholson to decide.
As he said,
it's against the rules.
Do not speak to me of rules.
This is war!
This is not a game of cricket.
He's mad, your colonel...
...quite mad.
Sit down, please.
I have decided to allow you
one visit to your colonel.
Thank you.
Tell him that if his officers
will not work...
...l'll be forced
to close the hospital...
...and your patients will
work in their place.
Many will die,
and he will be responsible.
Go and speak to him.
You have five minutes.
Doc's going to see the old man.
Sir....
It's Clipton, sir.
I brought you a few things.
-How are the men?
-Fine, sir, fine.
We scraped together a little meat
and a coconut.
And the officers?
Not so good.
They're still in detention.
And Lieutenant Jennings....
Jennings is dead.
-What?
-Killed, attempting to escape.
Also two others,
Corporal Weaver and the American.
Jennings. Poor, brave lad.
I warned him, didn't l, Clipton?
Look, sir, we haven't much time.
I'm going to clean you up a little
while I talk.
I've got something to tell you.
I've just had a word with Saito.
That man is the worst commanding
officer I've ever come across.
Actually, I think he's mad.
Carry on.
Blackmail!
I know, sir, but he means it.
I'm sure he does.
It's a question of face, pure and
simple. And he can't give in.
It's still blackmail.
Sir, you can't stand
much more of this.
Wouldn't the officers be better off
working than suffocating in that hole?
The men are doing a wonderful job.
They're going as slow as they dare.
But Saito's cut their food rations...
...and if he makes
the sick men work....
Well, they're going to die.
That's all there is to it.
Yes, Clipton, I understand. Truly.
But don't you see?
It's a matter of principle.
If we give in now,
there'll be no end to it. No.
Sir, we're lost in the jungle,
a thousand miles from anywhere.
We're under a man who'll stop at
nothing to get his way. Principle!
No one will ever know or care
what happens to us.
Give in, sir. Please!
I'm adamant.
I will not have an officer
from my battalion working as a coolie.
-Time.
-All right.
Please thank those concerned.
Everybody in the hospital
contributed one piece.
Reynolds stole the coconut.
We'll be able to get you
food sometimes.
We've bribed one of your guards.
Goodbye, sir. And good luck.
Many thanks.
Did you say that American
was killed?
Yes, sir. Shot and drowned.
It's insane to plan escapes.
Three men killed, and to what end?
Time!
Here is where we must win through.
Doc just looked at us and shook
his head. Whatever that means.
Means only one thing,
the colonel won't give in.
Well?
It's like this.
Colonel Nicholson
won't give in to force.
It's a question of principle.
As medical officer, I protest
the way he's being treated.
It's a wonder he's still alive.
Should a tragedy occur,
it would be tantamount to murder.
He is responsible.
Not l.
You sick?
Are they both mad?
Or am I going mad?
Or is it the sun?
Attention!
Battalion, attention.
English prisoners.
Let us ask the question...
...why does the bridge not progress?
You know why,
because your officers are lazy!
They think themselves too good
to share your burden.
This is not just.
Therefore, you are not happy
in your work.
Therefore, the bridge
does not progress.
But there is another cause.
I do not hide the truth.
With deep shame and regret...
...l admit to you the failure...
...of a member of the Japanese staff.
I refer to Lieutenant Miura.
He is a bad engineer.
He is unworthy of command.
Therefore, I have removed him
from his post.
Tomorrow we begin again.
I shall be in personal command.
Today we rest.
All work and no play
make Jack a dull boy!
As token of regard
for your efforts in the future...
...l give presents to you all.
Let us be happy in our work.
Company, dismissed.
Battalion, dismissed.
Hey, take a look at this.
Red Cross! He's given us our--
Hey, he's given us
our own Red Cross parcels.
"Tomorrow we begin again."
Hey, Harry, look!
They're letting the old man out.
Most likely going to give him
another pasting.
Good evening, colonel.
Do you mind sitting over here?
I am having rather a late supper.
English corned beef.
No, thank you.
Produce of Scotland.
I prefer it to sake.
I spent three years in London,
you know.
I studied at the London Polytechnic.
Cheers!
Sorry.
Later, perhaps?
Perhaps.
I was not a good artist.
My father disapproved.
He felt I belonged in the army.
So I changed from art to engineering.
I must tell you, Colonel Saito.
I intend to make a full report
of your activities.
I do not think you
quite realize my position.
-I must carry out my orders.
-Oh, quite, quite.
My orders are to complete the bridge
by the 1 2th day of May.
-I have only 1 2 weeks more.
-No doubt.
Therefore, I am compelled
to use all available personnel.
No officers, except
for administration.
But officers are working
along the entire railway.
You know it. I know it.
I'm not responsible
for other officers.
Personally, I'm appalled.
Let's not get excited.
Will you have a cigar?
No. Thank you.
When I said all officers must work...
...naturally, I never meant you,
the commanding officer.
My orders were only intended
for officers below--
No officers will do manual labour.
Please! I was about to say:
I've thought the matter over
and have decided...
...to put majors and above
on administrative duties...
...leaving only junior officers
to work.
No. The Convention's
quite clear on that point.
Do you know what will happen to me
if the bridge is not ready in time?
I haven't the foggiest.
I'd have to kill myself.
What would you do if you were me?
I suppose if I were you...
...l'd have to kill myself.
Cheers.
I warn you, colonel...
...if I am to die,
others will die before me.
Do you understand?
Clipton did mention that.
That won't solve your problem.
I'm sure we can
arrive at a solution.
Please sit down.
Now. Tell me, colonel...
...do you agree that the first job
of an officer is command?
-Of course.
-Good.
Now.
Take this bridge of yours.
It's quite an enormous undertaking.
Frankly, I doubt whether
your Lieutenant what's-his-name...
Miura.
...is capable of tackling
a job of such importance.
On the other hand, I have officers,
Reeves and Hughes for instance...
...who have built bridges
all over lndia.
The men respect them.
It's essential for an officer
to have that respect.
If it's gone, he ceases to command.
What then?
Demoralization and chaos.
A poor commander I would be if
I allowed that to happen.
Perhaps you are not aware that
the bridge is now under my command.
Really? And may I ask, are you
satisfied with the work?
-I am not!
-You've proved my point.
I hate the British!
You are defeated
but you have no shame.
You are stubborn
but have no pride.
You endure
but you have no courage.
I hate the British!
Pointless, going on like this.
Stay there!
Stand down. Stand down!
Battalion, attention!
Battalion, stand at ease.
Please....
Do you know what is
the date today, colonel?
I've lost count.
It's the anniversary of
our great victory...
...over Russia in 1 905.
Throughout East Asia
we are celebrating this date.
In honour of this occasion...
...l have given your troops
a day of rest.
Many thanks.
I am declaring a general amnesty.
You and your officers may
return to your quarters.
As part of this amnesty...
...it will not be necessary
for officers to do manual labour.
He's done it!
Somebody deserves a medal, sir.
How many men in your party?
I don't really know, sir.
-You don't know?
-Twelve, usually.
One of the men took sick
this morning, sir.
It took three or four
to help him to the hospital.
And-- He took terrible sick, sir.
A corporal should know
how many men he has under him.
Oh, yes, sir.
Have you a nervous affliction?
Stop making those faces.
It may be funny to you,
but it's not military behaviour.
No, sir.
We must put a stop
to these demonstrations.
-I say, Reeves?
-Yes, sir?
Ever built a bridge
over a stream like the Kwai?
Yes, sir, half a dozen of them
in Madras, Bengal....
If this were your bridge...
...how would you get it under way?
Get it under way, sir?
First of all,
I wouldn't build it here.
Oh, why not?
I was trying to tell you...
...the Japanese couldn't have
picked a worse location.
You see those piles?
They're sinking.
We could drive those logs
forever and they wouldn't hold.
Where would you build it?
Further downstream, sir.
Across those narrows.
Then we'd have solid bedrock
on both banks.
Hughes, if this were your bridge,
how would you use the men?
Not the way they're doing it.
It's chaos, as you can see.
Uncoordinated activity.
No teamwork.
Some parties are working
against each other.
Yes.
I say, gentlemen, we have
a problem on our hands.
Thanks to the Japanese,
we command a rabble.
There's no order, no discipline.
-Our task is to rebuild the battalion.
-Yes, sir.
Which isn't going to be easy.
Fortunately, we have
the means at hand. The bridge.
-The bridge, sir?
-The bridge.
We'll teach them a lesson in Western
efficiency that'll put them to shame.
Show what a British
soldier is capable of.
Yes. I see your point, sir.
I know how difficult
it's going to be here...
...where you can't find what you need.
-There's the challenge.
-I beg your pardon, sir.
You really want them
to build the bridge?
You're not usually
so slow in the uptake.
I know our men.
You've got to keep them occupied.
If there weren't any work,
we'd invent some.
-That we would, sir.
-So we're lucky.
But it's going to be a proper bridge.
Here again I know the men.
It's essential that they
take pride in their job.
-Right, men?
-Yes, sir.
Reeves, you're
the key man here as engineer.
Tell me what you want and we'll
get it. Can we make a go of it?
-We'll do out best, sir.
-Fine.
We must draw up our plans...
...then arrange a conference
with Saito...
...and set him straight.
That takes care of all
the procedural matters.
Oh, yes.
The next point is unpleasant
for all concerned, I'm afraid.
Sorry to say, the position
of the bridge was fixed hastily...
...and, I have to add, incorrectly.
Incorrectly?
Unfortunately, yes.
Our engineer has made
a study of the site...
...and decided that the river bottom
there is too soft.
Too soft?
Mud! All the work
has been useless.
-Reeves, will you carry on?
-Yes, sir.
Those piles of yours could be hammered
below water level before they'd hold.
It would collapse
under the first train.
The pressure and soil resistance
figures in tons per square inch.
Reeves, before you get too involved....
Colonel, could we have a cup of tea?
I take it we all agree
that if we're to avoid disaster...
...we build a new bridge, at the site
picked by Reeves, 400 yards downstream.
Let's proceed to the next point.
I decided to alter
the work quota of our men.
-Alter?
-I've increased it.
From 1 .5 yards of earth moved
to two.
I'm sure it will
meet with your approval.
Hughes has all the facts.
Would you take over?
I've done a time study
of the entire project.
You see, the available forces
have been badly distributed.
I'd urge we revise the
organization of the working parties.
Just a moment. Colonel, it would save
time if we could work during dinner.
Would it be possible
to have dinner?
Of course.
-Carry on.
-Yes, sir.
If we increase the squads
and specialize their functions...
...l'm certain the total daily output
can be increased by 30º/0 .
Now, Colonel Saito,
I have one more point....
Now, there's another important
decision that can't be postponed.
As the British
will work on the bridge...
...only a few will be available
for railway work.
I must ask you to lend us some of your
men to reinforce the railway gang...
...so the final stretch of track can
be completed as quickly as possible.
I have already given the order.
We must fix the daily work quota
for your men.
I thought to set it at 1 .5 yards
so as not to overtire them...
...but isn't it best
to be the same as ours?
That would also create a healthy
competitive spirit.
I have already given the order.
We'll try to surpass that,
won't we, Hughes?
I think that completes
the agenda for tonight.
Thank you, Colonel Saito,
for your kind attention.
Are there any other questions?
One question.
Can you finish the bridge in time?
Frankly, the consensus of opinion
is that it's impossible.
But we'll certainly give it a go.
Don't forget we wasted a month
through an unfortunate disagreement...
...for which I was not to blame.
Is there anything else?
No.
Thank you. The meeting is closed.
-Good night.
I hope these Japanese appreciate
what we're doing for them.
For now I'm not concerned
with their appreciation.
-Good night, Clipton.
-Good night, sir.
By the way, I meant to tell you...
...there are trees here
similar to elm.
And the elm piles of London Bridge
lasted 600 years.
-Six hundred years, Reeves?
-Yes, sir.
Six hundred years.
That would be quite something.
I'm looking for an American
named Commander Shears.
-Yes, down on the beach.
-Oh, thank you very much.
Kiss!
Too many eyes.
You give me powders, pills, baths,
injections, enemas....
All I need is love.
It's true.
All you really need is love.
Why are you so sure
you'll get a medical discharge?
Because I'm a civilian
at heart, lover.
And I always follow my heart.
Kiss.
How's that, commander?
Don't call me commander.
It's unromantic.
You're an officer yourself.
How'd you like it
if I called you Lieutenant Lover?
Let's be democratic.
Just call me "sir."
Yes, sir.
Brass ahoy.
He wants you. He's all yours.
-I'm going for a swim.
-Don't leave me!
-Commander Shears?
-Yes.
My name's Warden.
-How do you do?
-Sorry to intrude--
That's okay, major.
I'm used to it.
Like a martini?
That's very kind.
I think not.
Mind if I have one?
How did you get that?
Where there's a hospital,
there's alcohol.
Yes, of course. Jolly good.
Well, I'll be as brief as possible.
I belong to a rather rum group
called Force 31 6.
Our headquarters is in
the Botanical Gardens.
-Protecting rare plants from the enemy?
-Not quite.
-Sure you won't have one?
-No, thanks.
We have an interest
in that railway you worked on.
You could give us no end
of valuable information.
Well, I'm leaving
for the States in a few days...
...and I told your people
everything I know.
But you could help us
in a rather special sense.
I know it's a terrible imposition, but
could you possibly come out and see us?
If you want to go over
the whole thing again.
Very kind.
Lord Louis'll be grateful.
-Who?
-Mountbatten.
We're one of his special pigeons.
Shall we say this evening, then?
About 8. I'll send a car.
This evening? Out of the question.
Tomorrow morning then?
About 1 0?
-Okay, 1 0:00.
-Thanks very much.
-Cheerio.
Good luck.
Thanks.
You're sorry, but
you're going to stand me up tonight.
You couldn't be more wrong.
General salute!
Present arms!
-May I see your pass, please?
-Oh, yes.
Major Warden's bungalow
is at the end of the path.
Good show, Jenkins. Good show!
Come along, Thomson.
Use your knife, man.
On your feet!
Away to the debriefing room.
Come on, move yourselves!
Move quickly!
Very clumsy, Joyce, very clumsy.
Always use your knife
immediately, Joyce.
You see, he's gained the initiative.
Wait a minute!
I'm terribly sorry, sir.
-You're sorry?
-So am l.
-I thought you were the enemy.
-I'm American, if that's what you mean.
-That'll be all, Joyce.
-Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
-What can I do for you?
-I'm going to see Major Warden.
I'll show you the way. He'll finish
his lecture any moment now.
-That's the end of his lecture.
-Thunderous ovation.
He believes in keeping our training
as close to real life as possible.
-Major Warden, sir?
-Yes?
Good of you to come.
-They took care of you?
-They certainly have.
Thank you, staff.
Well, come along, then.
Col. Green is looking forward
to meeting you.
-Fascinating place, isn't it?
-Didn't know it was a commando school.
We're trying to discourage the use of
that word. Such a melodramatic air.
What do you do here?
Sabotage, demolition,
that line of country.
We're using P.E., plastic explosives.
It's wonderful.
That pop was made
with a lump half this size.
It's twice as powerful as gelignite
at half the weight.
It's quite harmless
until it's detonated.
Thanks for telling me.
It's completely waterproof
and actually plastic.
You can do what you like with it.
This is my place.
Go ahead.