He said,
that the day he climbed from
out of the mountain of bodies,
he was already dead
All my men are dead
I am the only one left
That is because you have a good life
I pretended to be dead
My men, over 1600 strong
Fought for 3 days and nights
All gone
The Kui Army bastards just stood the rear and watched.
Watching my men die one by one
All dead ...
He said, he met a woman that day
and spent a night in an abandoned run-down house
He wasn't sure if it was the bowl of gruel, or the woman
that made him feel
that he was still alive
Where can I get some rice to eat?
Go wait in front of the old house on the main street
He said
That on the first day he met me
The sky was ashen, just like his mood
But I remember vividly, that it was a clear day
Glaring to the eye
After you've eaten, come and work to repay your lives
After you've eaten, come and work
Food!
Come, eat!
You fight well ... follow me!
I'll bring you to see big brother!
What work is it?
Robbery!
Steal army provisions!
He later said, that we were foolishly brave
to dare to steal from troops
I replied, that there was no food within a 100 mile radius
When you're about to die from starvation,
I doesn't matter who's provisions they are
Charge out!
Kill!
Quick! Kill the leader!
That day, not only did he save me
He also taught me
[?] When beating a snake, you must beat it 7 inches,
To catch a thief, you must first catch the king
Brother WuYang
Look
It was from 'that' person
That's what Generals wear
Brother WuYang is a General
What are you thinking about?
My home
They're back ...
Don't be impatient, come, we have food!
Tonight we're going to have a feast!
Why are you alone?
I ran away from home
By your accent, you are from YangZhou?
You picked up on it?
How did you pick that I had a YangZhou accent?
Have you heard of the YangZhou market?
That’s where they pick out the prettiest girls,
teach them the arts
And after they've grown up,
sell them to rich men as wives, right?
But ...
When I was 15
and about to be sold
A childhood friend
stole me back
He even killed someone
and took me to hide
in the mountains as a felon.
He didn't realize that you'd changed,
and thought that he was saving you
He is a good person
Rest in peace!
Big Brother's rules
Leave an empty place at the table
with a full cup, to honor the dead.
Were you a commander in the army?
It's in the past now
Why did you leave?
Come, drink!
We were Imperial troops,
and had agreed to join up to eliminate the enemy
The Kui Army promised but did not deliver
And we could not suppress the enemy
So all of my men died
The world is big, but not bigger
than the bond between brothers-in-arms
Right?
Without comrades
Life is not worth living
WuYang
Time to eat
Will the new people in the village, stay?
With rice to eat, who will leave?
Yes, there's one named Pang,
who is quite impressive
Whether he will leave, I do not know
Doesn't it look nice?
I got it from a body
Do you know what this is?
No idea
A protection charm
Was that night real?
I stayed there waiting
I thought it was but a dream
If you'd already run away,
why did you come back?
I've run away many times
It seems a good idea,
but each time I come back
Why do you come back?
One's fate should be decided by oneself
Hide here
... why are you taking our food
You want to hit me with your rod?
-Hit me! Hit me!
-Don't move! Don't move!
Stop!
How old are you?  You'd hit a grandmother?
Don't move, I'll shoot!  People will die!
I'm not afraid of you
I'm serious, I'll shoot.  I'm serious ...
I'm not afraid!  You kill me!
You
Nobody move
Why aren't you looking at me?
Did you think that by raiding our supply cart,
the provisions would be all yours?
I'm giving you a chance today
[?] report yourselves to the imperial government
Leave!
If we only had guns, we'd fight them
It'd still be suicide
Living like this, I'd rather die
Being a bandit is a dog's life; always on the run
Why don't we join the army?
In the army, we'd get paid
With the money we can buy food for our families
In the army we'd have weapons.
With weapons, no-one would dare attack us.
The village would have true peace
We are bandits
Would the government accept us?
The Kui Army is a big military power
They won't even bother with our little band
But ChenGong needs manpower
His Lu Army is constantly being harassed by the Kui Army
And he wants to be a major military power
If we side with him, it would be perfect timing
ErHu, grasp this opportunity
And let today's events, never happen again
Fine
Bandits
We have to be the best!
In the past you were a Qing soldier
Now you want us to join the army?
You have no loyalty
Why should we trust you?
Swear a blood oath
Today, Pang ChingYun
Cao ErHu
Jiang WuYang
Swear an oath, to be blood brothers
[?] In each other we entrust, to save from danger
[?] Together in prosperity or difficulty
[?] If an outsider disrupts our brotherhood
[?] By our oath, they must die
[?] If a brother disrupts our brotherhood
[?] With the heaven and earth as our witness
[?]
[?] Together in one heart
He later told me,
He didn't believe in blood oaths
I asked what he did believe in
He said that he believed in Brother ErHu
and me
Wait, take these shoes
Be careful on the road
Mother won't be able to see you again
Mum, I'm leaving
Brother ErHu
Shi JiMiao has taken a group of men
He only said one thing
That he'd rather die than join the army
I heard
You led a battalion of men to suppress the enemy in HeChuan
But they all perished
You disappeared for 2 months, and you have the audacity to return?
Lord Chen
At the battle of HeChuan
Lord Jiang sent the Kui Army to guard my left wing
He Kui, fearing the enemy, retreated 30 Li
This is how my battalion of men all died
The whole army perished
And you were the only survivor?
I didn't die
So that I could come back to see you, Lord Jiang
How many men do you have?
Eight Hundred
Give me another 800
And within 15 days, I will take SongCheng
A soldier should not tell lies
10 days
I will take SongCheng in 10 days
Fine
I ...
I will give you another 1500 soldiers
But there will be no pay
That's not necessary
After I take the city, I want half of everything
Pang ChingYun
Your banner is [Deer Mountain]
Well call them the Mountain Army then
Thank you, my lords
You're taking a gamble
With the lives of 800 men
War has always been a gamble
I won't gamble
These 1500 soldiers are ChenGong's foundation
If they go
ChenGong will lose all power in the Imperial court
So when will you make your move?
My soldiers
Will only serve to make your force look more threatening
This is your only chance for victory
Otherwise
The Kui Army will forever have you under their feet
Big Brother
They're all faulty
Over there are 200 guns
It will be a difficult battle
There is only one way to win
A blind charge, to destroy their artillery
A battle of ruthlessness
Comrades
Tell him, who is the fiercest?
We're the fiercest!
Our armies are separated by 300 paces
Their guns have a range of 200 paces
Arrows have a range of 100 paces
We need 200 men in the frontline to charge
Followed by 200 archers
When they fire, don't stop.  Continue the charge
Follow it through to the end
To let the archers gain that 100 paces
Many men will die
I'll go!
Who will go with me?
The families for those who go will be paid extra
Those who die, 2 pieces, those who live 3 pieces!
Go make your fortunes
[?]
Come
Damn it, I'll go!
Me too!
Include me, I'll go ...
Me too ...
I'll go ... Me too ...
Defeat SongCheng!
Seize gold, seize food, seize land!
[?], the victor has already been decided
We are merciful, surrender and we will spare your lives
Kill!
Fire!
They're almost all dead, why aren't we going yet?
Don't you ever forget
On the battlefield, there can only be one commander
Kill!
Release the arrows!
Release!
Brother!
Ready!
Blindfold the horses
Charge!
Save Big Brother!
Big Brother!
Don't pull it out!
Hold steady
We're really going to die here!
We made a blood oath
We pray not to be born together, but to die together!
Well said
Even in death we need to take something with us
Everyone we kill counts!
Charge out!
Kill!
Insane!
Those 800 men have thrown 5000 soldiers into chaos
We can fight!
We desperately need this victory!
On me! Charge!
WuYang!
Lord Li
Pang ChingYun can be considered a blessing
Pang ChingYun, it seems we have a destiny together
Seems you've found yourself a treasure there
With the SongCheng battle, you've made name for yourself
Pang ChingYun
I'll put another 5 battalions under your command.
How about it?
[?] It's like adding flowers to a bouquet
-Lun DaShan
-Present
From now you are responsible for transferring funds
Thank you, Sir
Pang ChingYun
There's an old friend from the Kui Army waiting for you
He Kui
Present
My Lord
General Pang
Long time no see
As you already know each other,
you should continue to cooperate together
You conquer the cities, and he'll defend them
With him here, how'll we split it?
Lord Li
Lord Chen
I trust you're agreeable with this?
I'm scared that he'll be too slow to keep up
First we'll take SuZhou, then Nanjing
How about it?
What are they laughing at?
Nanjing is the enemies heart
To break Nanjing, you must take SuZhou first
If the war ends, they have nothing to gain
They won't let us fight SuZhou
Can they do anything if we do go and fight?
Inserting the Kui Army
was so that they could keep an eye on us
Come quick, they're back!
XiaoWu
XiaoWu ....
XiaoWu's shoes ....
XiaoWu ...
XiaoQi
XiaoQi, my son!
We were no longer bandits
He said, that bandits only kill for their own
But we, were risking ourselves for others
I'm willing to be this kind of person
You've lost weight
Big Brother said, that this time we'll be back in 3 years
I know that you don't like it here
Once I'm done fighting, I'll take you somewhere nice to spend our days
Where's Big Brother?
He's just outside the village
He said that he won't come in
We set out early tomorrow morning
Remember
All's fair in war
Begin!
Kill!
We're here to take over defense of the city
And let our comrades indulge themselves for 3 days
Seize money, seize food, seize land!
Come out, the battle is over
Come out
Come on out
Don't be afraid
You haven't eaten, right?
Are you hungry?
What are you doing?  Miss!
Are you going to watch?
GouZi, I'm leaving
Brother Pang
Move!
What is it?
Why are you holding me?
Move!
What is it?
Harming the innocent, will be punished on the spot!
Brother ErHu!
Big Brother, what happened?
Rape of a girl
Looting the city for 3 days, these are the rules
From today, this sort of thing cannot occur in our ranks
We've always done this
We were bandits, now we're soldiers
If we don't change, we won't accomplish anything
If we continue to do this
We'll be just like those Kui Army bastards
Rules must start somewhere.  That day is now
We've just finished killing their family members
Now that we're here
You want protect them?
Who will fight for you in the future?
Big Brother
Listen to me
Look at them
They get it
You don't need to kill them, right?
What are you doing?
Hurry up an admit your mistake!
Big Brother, we were wrong.  We won't do it again!