[Galloping Hoofbeats]
[Horses Whinnying]
[Man Shouting Commands]
[Shouting]
[Man]
Lord, yonder!
Whoa!
Make way!
l"d speak with Targutai.
Lord,
the Mongol Chief!
Let him approach!
By whose leave
do you cross my lands?
A chief's lands are those
his men can hold with arms,
Temüjin.
The Merkit Chief
comes to dispute them?
Were we alone, it would
be easier, Targutai.
Your blood brother
speaks in riddles.
Targutai is not
so wanting in wit
as he would let believe.
[Targutai]
Nor courage, Mongol, should
you seek to challenge it.
[Jamuga]
Would two lonely hunters
challenge a Merkit force...
under Chief Targutai
himself?
[Targutai]
Such humbleness
sits ill a Mongol.
Targutai is not deceived.
But I seek no dispute.
This journey is
an occasion ofjoy.
I am taking for myself
a third wife.
A Tartar woman,
Temüjin.
I share your taste
in women, Targutai,
but not in blood.
Farewell,
Tartar woman.
For much less, my father
would have slain him.
The thought came
to me, but-
But you feared
the Mongol dog!
Not so, woman.
Targutai fears no man!
I put violence from me
lest I imperil you.
Would a Mongol dare touch
Kumlek"s daughter?
You know ill
the son of Yessugai.
An insolent pig.
[Shouts]
[Shouting]
Let the guards
spread out.
As ChiefTargutai orders.
Come on!
[Shouting Commands]
I suspect Temüjin had men
concealed nearby, and was
seeking to provoke me.
By such tricks does he live
since the death
of his father Yessugai.
His clans
are scattered.
Thanks to my father.
Your father Kumlek did well
to destroy the old Mongol Chief.
His tribe is now of
no more consequence than lice...
on a fat gelding.
Yet still you dare
not brave Temüjin!
Bring me to drink!
And make haste, vermin!
Tempting.
Tempting but unwise,
my brother. Listen to me.
There are moments for wisdom,
Jamuga, then I listen to you.
There are moments for action,
then I listen to my blood.
I feel this Tartar woman
is for me.
My blood says,
"Take her."
[Goats Bleating]
[Men Jeer]
[Men Laughing]
Not even the mighty Kasar
bends iron
forged by Sorgan.
There"s a secret
in the dipping of it.
[Shouting
Encouragement]
[Grunting]
Our little brother
exercises himself.
[Grunting]
So there"s a secret
in the dipping of it,
eh, Sorgan?
Come, Kasar.
There is sport more suited
to your strength.
Put on your armor.
A raid?
A raid.
Yes, a sport worthy
of a man, eh, Sorgan?
[Men Laughing]
Nugal, take this
to the tanner.
Share the meat
among you.
I greet you,
my Mother.
Falconer!
You return empty-handed
from the chase, my son?
Not so.
A fine gazelle.
Now we seek
bigger game, Hunlun.
How many Merkits
did you observe?
Thirty. No more.
We"ll take twice that number.
Call Borgurchi and Subaya.
A small caravan.
With one flight
of arrows.
No man bends his bow
until so ordered.
I want Targutai"s woman
unharmed.
Targutai!
We attack
the Merkit Chief himself?
This troubles you?
The Merkits are numerous
and close!
The Tartars are
more numerous.
And the woman I take
from the Merkit"s Chief
is a Tartar woman.
This raid may reap us
more grief than spoils,
Temüjin.
True!
Aye!
What says Jamuga?
Aye, what says
Jamuga?
Well, what says Jamuga?
I follow
my blood brother,
and so do we all.
Are you women
that you tremble before
a force half your number?
You fear the Merkits" revenge.
I seek it!
Let him who shrinks from it
say so and be gone.
There is no room in my tents
for those who fear...
or question my orders.
[Borgurchi]
None question your orders.
They offer counsel, brother.
Would they fear
to follow Temüjin who is
without equal in battle?
Jamuga of
the silver tongue.
We attack as planned.
[Shouts]
Lord!
Whoa!
That jackal, Temüjin!
To arms!
Guard the carts!
The Mongol!
[Shouting]
Lord, they"re on us
from all sides!
Your horse!
Mount!
We flee!
From a pack
of lice?
Make haste, woman,
lest I leave you!
Go, my gallant suitor!
Bowmen!
Targutai!
Greetings!
[Whinnying]
Why such haste,
ChiefTargutai?
Do you spurn the hospitality
of my lands?
Arise, valiant one!
Come out from under there!
It"s all over!
Come on, get out
from under there!
On, brave suitor!
Would you desert
your bride unkissed?
Make haste, craven!
The Tartar wench awaits you.
What would the Tartar woman
have me do with her hero?
What does the jackal do
with a rabbit, Mongol?
Return to your people,
Targutai,
and speak well of
the Mongols" generosity.
[Yells]
Take this in memory
of your Tartar woman.
[Jamuga]
Away, Targutai!
The wounded beast is more
dangerous than the whole.
Better that you had slain him.
I have no fear ofTargutai,
wounded or whole.
Here"s the one
I must fear.
You say well, Mongol.
I am Bortai,
daughter of Kumlek!
Chief of all the Tartars!
Slayer of my father.
And of you
and all your mangy tribe
before this moon has waned.
What say you
of my prize, Jamuga?
Richer than you dreamed,
my brother.
Borgurchi, we march!
[Shouting Commands]
My Mother.
See to the sharing
of the booty.
All?
Place her tent
next to mine.
Ahh!
A fair prize, my son,
if my eyes see well.
Fairer than you know,
my Mother.
She is the daughter
of Kumlek.
Kumlek"s daughter!
Spawn of evil!
Let your slaves
have their sport with her!
I will not have her within our tents.
I say who stays
in our tents.
This woman
is for my pleasure.
You will take pleasure...
with the offspring
of your father"s slayer?
She will bring woe to you,
my son.
And to your people!
Stay, my Mother!
There will be feasting...
and rejoicing!
Rejoicing?
The memory of your father
is heavy in my heart.
And for me
there is no rejoicing.
?? [Guitar, Drums]
?? [Melancholy Song
In Native Language]
?? [Singing Continues]
?? [Song Ends]
?? [Lively Music]
[Shouts In Native Language]
Dance!
No! No!
Let"s see
the Tartar woman dance!
Huh?
[Cheering]
[Cheering Continues]
I do not dance
for jackals.
No?
But for Temüjin
you"ll dance!
Dance,
Tartar woman.
Dance for Temüjin!
Know this, woman.
I take you for wife.
Is Temüjin so wanting
for a woman that he will
quench his fire with ice?
You had no love for Targutai.
This l"d swear.
So I must be overwhelmed
by Temüjin, flattered
by his drunken ardor,
returning
kiss for kiss.
The least of my slaves
will give you more pleasure,
Mongol.
Guard!
Lord?
Take this captive
to her tent.
Come.
[Panther Snarls]
Woman!
[Whispering]
Jamuga.
Jamuga!
[Gasps]
Lord, my mistress
wishes to speak with you.
Bortai? Where is she?
A captive in her tent,
my Lord,
else she would
have come to you.
Come.
What mischief do you want
of me, woman?
Mischief?
Temüjin did not think
it mischief...
until I refused him.
You I would not refuse,
Jamuga.
Suppose, having taken
your favors,
I refuse the favor
you seek?
Then I would reveal
your betrayal to Temüjin.
Horses for me and
my slave woman, and safe
conduct out of this camp.
Is that so much?
I am tempted, woman.
Tempted above all
to let you go from here,
for you will bring sorrow
between me and him,
and disaster upon his people!
Let me go, then,
Jamuga.
He"s dearer to me
than life.
I cannot betray him,
even for his good.
Better to betray him for his good
than be thought a traitor...
without profit.
What are you saying,
woman?
That I will cry out
and call your beloved Temüjin!
[Men Shouting]
Back!
[Snarling]
Hyah!
Out, Mongol! Out!
Out!
Out, Mongol!
Targutai!
[Man Shouts]
- Temüjin!
- [Man Shouts]
Mongol!
[Dog Barks]
Why is this carcass
lying here?
It is an omen, my son.
What woman"s talk
is this, my Mother?
Rid us of this carrion!
And what of your dead?
Those who died needlessly
for this cursed child
of Kumlek"s!
Jalair!
Lord?
Let two men guard this woman
in her tent.
If ill befalls her, they shall die
the slow death.
Chepei!
If the outpost guards still live,
bring them before me.
You would punish
your outposts...
after deserting us
and leaving Jamuga
to defend the camp?
Greetings, Temüjin.
Ah! To drink.
I could drain
ten brood mares dry.
Where is Jamuga?
I am here,
my brother.
What of the Merkits?
Routed
and well-bloodied.
But Subaya was wounded,
half his men slain.
Men we shall miss when
the Tartars descend upon us.
Leave the Tartars to me.
[Man]
As with the Merkits?
I dealt gently
with this oaf.
If others would speak,
let it be now!
Lord, the outposts.
Ah! So you had
the guard last night.
Yes, Lord.
The Merkits
fell upon us unawares.
You were fortunate
to have escaped death.
Truly fortunate, Lord.
We had drunk much.
Hang them.
Come.
Let all pay heed.
I have taken
the Tartar woman for a wife.
My son,
this you cannot do!
There"ll be an end of talk
on her account.
Bring meat and drink.
Jamuga!
Miserable fools!
They fear what will befall
when Kumlek strikes.
Who shall blame them?
For less cause, tribes
have slain their chiefs.
And you stand
with them?
Where is your faith,
my brother?
I was to bring
under my standard
all the tribes of the Gobi.
None would dare
stand against me.
Was not that once
your dream for me, Jamuga?
And still is.
But the time
is not yet ripe.
So I share the fear
that Kumlek"s daughter
will bring disaster.
Or lead me to achieve
what I have too long put off:
the destruction
of the Tartars.
How so, my brother?
With the forces
of Wang Khan.
Could it be that
this woman has touched
your wits as well?
Sharpened them,
more likely.
Were not my father and
Wang Khan blood brothers
as you and I?
I have a blood claim on him
l"ve never made,
even in my early trials.
Because the young Temüjin
had pride,
and knew that Wang Khan
would not lift a finger,
save in his own interest.
I go to him now
not as a beggar,
but as an ally with gifts...
and grave intelligence.
Kumlek, I learn, is preparing
to attack Wang"s city of Urga.
That lie
will not deceive him.
He"ll send spies
to test my report.
We"ll waylay them.
Their failure to return
will confirm my warning.
It could succeed...
if Wang does not
take counsel of his Shaman.
It is said he places
much reliance
in soothsayers.
What venture
is without hazard?
But not without retreat,
as this is.
If Wang discovers your deceit,
we"ll never leave the city.
This is a hazard
I run alone.
You"ll remain here,
making all ready for
moving camp on my return.
And the woman?
I leave her here, Jamuga,
in your trust.
You are troubled?
There"s something
I would tell.
Concerning her?
She used her wiles
on me last night
to gain her freedom.
What took you
to her tent?
That is a poor thought
between us, Temüjin.
Her slave came to me.
I divined the reason,
but went nonetheless
to learn her intent.
There is no limit
to her perfidy!
She is a woman,
Jamuga.
Much woman.
Should her perfidy be less
than that of other women?
I take her with me.
Jalair.
Yes, Lord?
Take three men and
make camp to the north.
If any man comes
riding hard from Urga,
question him on his purpose.
Torture him until
he speaks true.
If he goes to spy on
the Tartars, slay him.
And send word to me
at all speed.
As you command.
[Shouting]
Chepei.
Proceed to make camp
at the water hole.
You"ll find more ease
this night than last.
For me there is no ease
while you live, Mongol.
Your future promises
much discomfort.
Why is no tent
put up for me?
Because you"ll share mine.
I will sleep outside.
You, bring my fur robe.
Tend to your men.
You"ll have no further need
for furs. Come drink.
By night, my warmth,
and for adornment by day...
I shall heap precious stones
on you and rare ornaments.
I want no more
your stolen treasure than
your vile warmth, Mongol!
Those furs are mine!
The dowry for my marriage
with the man you slew!
[Groans]
I have taken you for wife, Bortai,
and I take your dowry.
Tomorrow in Urga,
I make gift of it to Wang Khan.
[Chepei]
Lord, the woman!
[All Laughing]
You"re beautiful
in your wrath.
Were Wang younger and
more nimble at dodging swords,
I might give you to him
and keep the furs.
For they, too, are beautiful.
I shall keep you, Bortai.
I shall keep you,
and responding to my passion,
your hatred
will kindle into love.
Before that day dawns,
Mongol,
the vultures will have
feasted on your heart!
Who goes?
Temüjin,
Chief of the Mongols!
Taleek!
To the palace!
[Vendor]
You doubt thejuiciness
thereof?
Ahh.
Temüjin salutes you,
O Khan!
Temüjin!
My eyes are rejoiced
by the sight of you, my son!
Your welcome touches me.
My heart is reminded
of your father Yessugai.
My blood brother
so treacherously poisoned
by the Tartar Kumlek.
What say you, O Khan?
Is a daughter
a fair exchange...
for a father?
Be it fair exchange
or no,
she"s a fair daughter
whoever"s she be.
What means, Temüjin?
This is Bortai,
daughter of Kumlek.
Daughter of
the Tartar?
I had thought to bring
her to you as a gift,
but I could not do you
this ill service,
for her nature is as ugly
as her body fair.
[Chuckles]
I bring you instead
a gift of equal beauty...
that will give you
endless pleasure
without endless trouble.
Ahh!
A regal gift indeed,
Temüjin!
A regal gift!
Come.
Let there be music and a feast...
befitting Temüjin,
Chief of the Mongols!
?? [Dance Music]
?? [Cymbals]
?? [Music Continues]
A woman of Samarkand.
I recognize her
by the, uh-
There are no finer dancers
under the heavens.
And without compare
in the arts of love.
After them,
all other women are like the
second pressing of the grape.
[Wang Chuckling]
?? [Music Continues]
?? [Stops]
Had I made captive
such a one, O Khan,
she would have made
a worthy gift.
?? [Music Begins]
Does not their skill
excite your admiration?
Or even envy?
It seems your Tartar woman
does not share our delight
in these dancers.
Forgive her, O Khan.
But lacking the talents
of these women,
the sight of them
is irksome to her.
[Gong Struck]
?? [Music Continues]
?? [Stops]
Chepei!
To the woman"s
quarters!
I beg forgiveness
for her, O Khan.
With such gestures
does the Tartar woman
prove her love.
You see, she would"ve made
a poor gift.
Wine.
Temüjin spoke earlier
of grave intelligence.
May we not
hear it now?
Yes! Yes!
Let"s hear it now.
Be gone! Be gone!
The Tartars and the Merkits
are joining forces
to attack us.
You are surprised,
as I was.
Yet we both have cause to know
the perfidy of Kumlek...
and the Merkit,
Targutai"s, ambition.
True.
For long l"ve nursed
revenge against Kumlek.
When I heard
his daughter was to be
the Merkit"s bride,
I struck,
waylaying them.
Targutai, I slew.
And with his dying oath,
he swore he"d be avenged:
that soon Kumlek
would rule the Gobi.
A vain boast in death.
And so I took it, until
the woman, in her wrath,
spat out like threats.
I forthwith sent spies
to Tartar territory,
and learned the news...
which brought me here
in haste.
What say you of this, Shaman?
lfTemüjin"s spies
reported truly-
Let the Khan send out
his own spies.
What think you
of that, Shaman?
So grave a question
demands a surer answer.
Let a sheep be slaughtered,
and the shoulder blade
brought hither.
The spirits shall speak.
Gods of fire
and gods of water,
gods of air
and gods of thunder,
show thy message
in the blade bones...
burning hot before my eyes.
Through the vapors,
from the heavens,
make the truth arise, arise!
[Chanting]
[Chanting Continues]
[Sizzling]
Light!
It is even as Temüjin
relates, O Khan!
The Tartars prepare
to attack your city.
Alas, there is no peace!
Even for him who seeks
only to enjoy
his hard-won riches.
This yet can be, O Khan,
and your peaceful city
spared all strife...
by destroying the Tartars
in their camp.
Send swiftly and in secret
to your clans to mobilize,
and join with me in wiping out
the Tartars and the Merkits.
Thus my father
will be avenged,
and much stock and grazing land
added to our own.
Temüjin speaks wisely,
O Khan.
So let it be, then.
I depart with
the first light.
You will get word from me
naming the day and the place...
for the meeting
of our forces.
Halt.
Well, Shaman,
what brings you out
at this early hour?
The rising sun never finds
a servant of the heavens
sleeping.
I come to speed you
on your journey, Temüjin,
and wish you well.
I would speak further,
but, uh-
Chepei, wait outside.
And guard the woman.
I value your good wishes,
Shaman,
for all your doubt
of my report last night.
The spirits
confirmed your report.
And who am l-
humble servant of
the eternal heavens-
Who am I to doubt the spirits
when they have spoken
in the prescribed manner?
The Khan grows idle
and full of years.
Soon his petty chiefs
will fight among themselves
to take his place.
Then other tribes
will fall on us
like jackals.
The moment is ripe
for a young Khan
of bold cunning.
I wish you well,
Temüjin Khan.
I wish you well, Shaman.
Your tents burn well.
Chepei, leave the packhorses,
disperse,
and at nightfall
go singly into camp.
l"ll await you here.
Lord, as you command.
[Shouts Command]
Tartars!
Farewell, Mongol!
[Shouts]
Tie him.
The Mongol!
[Shouting]
[Groaning]
Temüjin!
Jamuga.
Ambushed.
I know.
Tell me of the battle.
Kumlek and his Tartar dogs
revel in our tents
at this hour!
Bortai with him.
Our losses?
This needs more care
than I can give it.
Our losses-
Are they great?
A few.
The tents were ready
as you ordered.
Thus much was saved
by our retreat.
Nor were we long pursued.
It is you he seeks.
An eagerness we share.
I came with scouts
to warn you,
but too late.
Tartars fell upon us, and
I alone escaped... afoot.
Your place
is with our people.
They are secure
under Borgurchi
in the western gorges.
Your perils are greater.
Coming upon the signs
of ambush, I sought you
among the dead,
and then recalled
this cave of our youth.
The place of our blood rite...
and much dreaming.
Temüjin
will yet conquer!
First we must get you
to your people.
We need horses.
I will seek them
in the camp.
Guard yourself well,
my brother.
What venture is
without hazard?
[Laughing]
[Drunken Chatter,
Laughter]
Mongol!
Mongol I am,
Tartar!
Mongol General
come freely to speak
to your great Chief Kumlek.
March, Mongol!
Come, little one.
Come!
[Men Laughing]
Lord,
a Mongol General.
Jamuga, seeking
to serve you, Lord.
Jamuga?
I have deserted
Temüjin.
His folly in abducting the great
Tartar Chief's daughter has
aroused his people against him.
He is unfit to lead.
Was he captured?
I made him captive,
Lord.
You lie! I came openly
into the camp, and sought
to be brought to you!
Ah.
I will speak with you
more in daylight.
Take him away.
The man lies, my Father.
He would die the slow death
before betraying
his blood brother.
Hmm.
[Chuckling]
Before we march tomorrow,
he shall be put to the test.
But tonight,
back to your tent,
my daughter.
Come, little Mongol.
[Man Laughs]
[Woman Screams]
So, you would betray
your blood brother!
The lie chokes you,
eh, Mongol?
What is there in this
Temüjin that makes you
love him thus?
Untie him.
Put him in a tent
and guard him well.
[Gagging]
Follow.
Do not return
without Temüjin.
[Whistling]
Hyah!
Temüjin, fools!
Temüjin!
[Captain]
The Mongol Chief!
Seize him!
He served you well,
your beloved blood brother.
You lie!
Look, Mongol.
[Captain]
I, myself, heard him
betray you to Kumlek.
I salute you, Temüjin!
[Whip Cracks]
[Crowd Cheering]
Behold, Tartars!
I bring you Temüjin,
son of Yessugai.
Gaze upon him,
Chief of the Mongols.
[Jeering]
To drink! Wine!
When the beasts have been
watered, do likewise
for the Mongol.
You thirst,
Mongol?
[Crowd Laughs]
[Laughing]
Loose him!
I grieve.
He grieves!
Already the Mongol whelp whines!
I grieve that I cannot
salute you as I would.
I am bereft of spit!
Stay.
Tell us, Mongol,
in like circumstance,
what punishment
would you decree?
What else, my wife,
but the slow death?
So be it, Temüjin.
The slow death.
Joint by joint, from the toe
and fingertip upwards
shall you be cut to pieces.
[Kumlek]
And each carrion piece,
hour by hour and day by day,
shall be cast to the dogs
before your very eyes...
until they, too, shall be
plucked out as morsels
for the vultures!
[Laughing]
Away with him!
You do well, Kumlek.
For while I have fingers
to grasp a sword
and eyes to see,
your treacherous head
is not safe on your shoulders,
nor your daughter in her bed!
Away, I said!
[Crowd Jeering]
Music! Music.
The bear! Bring the bear.
I am weary, my father.
?? [Dance]
[Laughter]
More wine.
[Laughing]
Set yourself alight, Juggler.
Give us some real sport!
Bortai.
[Whispering]
He has suffered much.
Deny not the heart.
Bring food,
and lead him to the horses.
[Laughing]
Let us see if the Mongol sleeps.
Let us!
Yes!
Bring the bear.
We"ll have sport
with Temüjin!
[Laughter]
[Laughing]
The bear!
Make haste with the bear!
We"ll tie him with Temüjin.
[Laughter Continues]
Guards!
The Mongol"s gone!
Up, you dog!
Where is he?
Here, Lord.
Fool!
Rouse the guards!
Search the camp!
Where are your men?
[Shouting]
Guards! Guards! Guards!
You are lost, Mongol.
This will spare you
much agony.
[Hoofbeats]
He cannot go far!
Search the reeds!
Over there!
[Arrow Whistles]
Temüjin!
Lord, we believed
you slain.
Death comes not easy
to Temüjin.
Believing me slain,
whom did you acknowledge
as Chief?
Who else but
your blood brother could
lead us in our adversity?
His joy will be great.
[Shouts Command]
Ho! Give greetings
to Temüjin!
Our leader has returned.
Temüjin lives!
[Cheering]
Temüjin!
Temüjin, my brother.
I have returned, Jamuga.
My son!
My son, a miracle
has been wrought!
You live!
You didn"t suckle me
to be slain by Tartars,
my Mother,
but to destroy them.
Here. Burn these foul rags!
[Groans]
Oh, my son. Oh.
Small wonderJamuga
thought you dead.
Jamuga erred.
Temüjin!
Stay, my son.
Kasar, fetch my healing leaves
and ointments.
I see no betrayal there.
But this, the blackest
kind of treachery,
can thus masquerade
as brother"s love.
Speak then! Deny it!
I will not.
To deny it would give
substance to your thought.
This shame
l"d spare you!
Curb that silver tongue!
Speak straight!
Did you betray me to the Tartars?
No!
Hunlun, my mother.
Come tend my wound.
[Hunlun]
I come.
This he shall pay for
tenfold.
We march against
the Tartar.
With Wang Khan?
With the legions of Wang Khan,
and the Mongol clans I gather.
What folly do I hear?
We march against Kumlek.
Jamuga, depart tonight
for Urga.
Let Wang Khan know
I await his forces...
in the hills of Kerulon
at the full moon.
My brother,
I know your plan.
But I doubt if-
Kasar, go you with Jamuga.
Your brawn may serve
to complement his wit
in case of trouble.
Let us be on our way, Kasar.
Come, my Mother.
Work your healing on this.
Would that I could cure
the madness that possesses you.
Is that your woman"s way
of saying...
you oppose my plan to seize
this chance for power?
Can you speak thus to me,
your mother?
Did I not hold our tribe together,
and raise you with but one thought:
to regain your father"s power
and avenge his death?
Now you"d thwart me
and let our vengeance cool
still longer.
You lie, my son.
You seek no vengeance
for your father.
No, not even for yourself.
You seek this Tartar woman!
My compact with
Wang Khan calls for-
Wang Khan?
He will betray you
into disaster,
or rob you of your spoils
in victory.
Were you not blinded by lust
for this woman, you would see-
Lust?
You, too, are blind,
my Mother.
Blinded by your hatred
for her.
Daughter of Kumlek?
Even were you right
about Wang Khan, yet would
I venture this unaided.
For I will have Bortai,
though I and all of us
go down to destruction.
For good or ill,
she is my destiny.
Envoys ofTemüjin,
Chief of the Mongols.
[Shouts]
[Sighs]
Precious musk ofTonking, Lord.
Oh, no! The scent of musk
fits ill the celestial signs.
Ah, bring civet.
Lord, two Mongol emissaries
seek audience.
Mongols? Bring them to me.
My hat and beads.
Be gone, be gone.
We bring greetings,
O Khan, from our Chief,
Temüjin.
He lives?
Approach, Jamuga.
Word reached me
that he was slain by Kumlek.
A Tartar lie, O Khan.
They tried in vain
to hold him captive.
My heart rejoices.
My Shaman!
My presence is desired,
O Khan?
Ah, my Shaman!
Always at hand.
Jamuga and Kasar bring word
ofTemüjin"s escape from Kumlek.
A miracle indeed!
What say you, Shaman?
My heart rejoices.
We come to name the day
and place where Temüjin
will await your forces.
Speak!
The slaves, their tongues
have been cut out.
Speak freely.
The hills of Kerulon
at the full moon.
Ah, all is well.
I have-
These envoys must be weary,
O Khan.
Oh, true.
Rest and refresh yourselves.
We"ll talk again
in the cool of the day.
But, Jamuga-
We accept your hospitality,
O Khan.
I like not this tale
ofTemüjin"s
miraculous escape.
I catch the scent
of treachery here.
Treachery?
Treachery.
How say you, Shaman?
I have long thought
on this, O Khan.
Were the Mongol"s
secret purpose to trick us
into war with Kumlek,
he would not act otherwise.
To what end?
To fatten on our flesh,
O Khan.
Remember, they say
that when Temüjin was born,
a clot of blood was found
in his clenched fingers.
A certain augury
of greatness.
Beware, O Khan, beware...
lest the Mongol"s greatness
be achieved at your expense.
What say the spirits,
Shaman?
I was consulting them
when these emissaries arrived.
The signs are yet unclear,
and time presses.
With your leave, I will,
myself, look further
into Temüjin"s designs...
before our forces
are committed.
My faithful Shaman.
Should ill befall you-
Jamuga is much beloved
ofTemüjin.
Hold him, O Khan,
the young bull also,
as hostages
to my safe return.
Well, if our brother
did not await-
Shh.
[Claps Hands]
The slaves are at
the command of the
Khan"s honored guests.
Remember your father
Yessugai.
What?
Touch no meat nor drink.
Poison?
Maybe.
There"s something afoot.
Then why stay?
Why not return?
If there is treachery,
we must penetrate it.
To do so, we must stay-
listening, not shouting our suspicions.
Sit down.
Whatever we learn will
serve our brother naught
while we remain here.
I say he should be warned!
They would have stopped us
had we refused to stay.
None would stop me-
Shh, shh.
What?
[Grunting]
Wait!
We"ll need more than brawn
for this enemy, Kasar.
All is well, Shaman.
Should they escape-
They shall not escape,
Shaman.
The dead never escape.
And beneath
the cloak of darkness,
who shall know what befell?
[Speaking Native
Language]
I do not see what use
this will be.
Pry it loose!
Come.
Between the bars.
Thus!
Ah!
[Grunting]
At last, a purpose
worthy of these muscles!
Go first, Jamuga.
And cease henceforth
to twit me for my brawn.
Henceforth, l"ll
proclaim it far and wide!
Yeah.
My brawn
now holds me captive.
Take my hand.
I think- I think-
The Mongol!
After him!
Wherefore such haste,
Mongol?
For want of a thrush,
we eat starling!
Seeking Temüjin,
we find his blood brother.
Tie him
on the horse.
The full moon is long since high.
He promises much,
this whelp of Yessugai.
[Hoofbeats]
If we"ve aroused
our clans for naught-
Lord, for close on a day"s
march distant, there"s no sign
of Wang Khan"s forces.
Ah.
You"ve traveled far.
Refresh yourself.
He let himself
be tricked by Wang.
My vassal chiefs tremble.
Will you meet
Kumlek"s men alone?
You assured us Wang Khan"s
forces would unite with us!
But for the promise
of Wang Khan"s alliance,
would we have been fools enough
to gather our tribes?
Your plan is but-
You will yet share
Temüjin"s triumph!
[Animal Howling]
Eternal skies,
Yessugai my father,
hear me.
Summon the spirits of heaven
to my aid.
Send me men!
Men!
This day I have long awaited.
And now I am beset by
weaklings and traitors.
And victory is slipping
from my grasp.
Spirits of heaven,
Yessugai my father,
do not desert me
in this fateful hour.
Let not treachery prevail!
Lord?
Lord, an envoy
from Wang Khan.
Temüjin.
I bring you ill tidings,
I doubt it not.
Secure in his city,
Wang Khan waits word...
of your destruction
at the Tartar"s hands.
You rode two days
to bring me such news?
To give you warning,
and a plan to thwart
the old man"s treachery.
And the plan?
Seize Urga!
And bleed my strength in
siege of Wang Khan"s city?
There will be no siege
and no battle.
I, myself,
will open the gates,
and taken by surprise,
the city will fall
like a ripe plum.
The time has come,
Temüjin Khan,
if you would tread the path
of power and riches.
And the young Khan
will know how to reward
a humble servitor.
What of my brothers,
Jamuga and Kasar?
Wang holds them captive.
Strike camp.
We ride on Urga.
[Shouting]
We ride!
Sorgan.
Keep this Shaman
always in your sight.
If he leaves our ranks,
slay him.
Ho there. Stand!
Hold. The Shaman
of your Khan.
l"ve come with
the Mongol Chief for
audience with the Khan.
Open.
Our news awaits.
The gates.
Bow!
Come on!
[Sighs]
Ah, my Shaman!
What word bring you?
The spirits grow impatient
for your coming, O Khan.
[Screams]
You are avenged, Temüjin Khan!
Temüjin, beware the viper.
He anticipated
my vengeance, traitor.
Not I, Temüjin, not I.
He spoke poisoned words
against you.
To confound him
for your advantage!
He wished me to abandon you
to Kumlek and-
And...
my brothers?
Kasar-
My... humble servitor!
[Groans]
[Shouting]
Ho! Hear me!
[Shouting Continues]
[Crashes]
Hear me! Hear me!
Wang Khan is slain!
Urga is ours!
[Cheering]
[Crashes]
Lord, Wang"s generals
swear allegiance.
[Temüjin]
Let all take heed.
I, Temüjin,
Chief of all Mongols...
and henceforth ruler
over the possessions
of Wang Khan,
make known to all men present
and afar off:
Those who oppose me
shall be destroyed:
those who submit
shall be spared:
and those who
freely unite with me...
shall profit richly
for I march against the Tartars.
The Khan!
[Cheering]
[Water Dripping]
No torment moves him.
The man is iron!
I care not!
You will make him talk,
or every torment he has had
shall be your lot!
Make fire.
For three days now
your men have worked on him.
Is not your pleasure
satisfied, my Father?
He sickens me.
But he shall talk!
l"ll know the whereabouts
ofTemüjin-
Then let me talk with him
as I have asked you.
I know the nature
of this man.
No torture will persuade him
like a woman"s gentleness.
My eagerness is no less
than your own to know
the whereabouts ofTemüjin.
Do with him what you will,
but make him talk!
Captain!
Let him be brought
to my tent.
You have slept long.
Drink.
You have suffered much.
But you will spare me
further suffering if-
If it is in my power.
Let us speak low.
Three of my father"s guard
watch this tent.
The hand is gentler,
the koumiss sweeter,
but no more potent than
the water to make me speak.
I ask nothing
but to know he lives.
I am well rested.
Call your guards.
You cannot trust me,
yet I aided his escape.
And you will aid mine
if I tell you-
Nothing! Only that he lives.
Is he recovered?
Tell me, Mongol!
Guard!
Go! Go!
But you-
Fool.
For this betrayal, my father
would tear my heart out
with his own foul hand.
I chance this gladly
just to know Temüjin lives.
To reach his arms,
l"d cast Kumlek to his fate...
and betray my people
into Mongol bondage.
Do you not understand,
Jamuga?
You said once you loved him
more than life.
I am consumed
with want of him.
I can take you to him.
Where is he?
No, no. Do not tell me.
I will find a way.
It must be soon.
A danger threatens
he must know of.
I was hastening to warn him
when your men captured me.
It must be tonight.
If he should die-
He will not die.
The peril is chiefly
to his enterprise.
His life is charmed,
for destiny has marked him.
Tell me ofTemüjin.
I know of him only that on
a sudden, my hatred for him
could not withstand my love.
He has a quality of spirit
that commands love,
and makes men
greater than themselves.
Lacking this spirit,
I found fulfillment
in our brotherhood,
and strove to inspire him
to the greatness
he knew not yet was in him.
That was the purpose
of my life.
"Was,"Jamuga?
He has found greater
inspiration, Bortai.
We must go to him.
I must find a way!
Bortai!
Temüjin!
Ah, my brother!
No, Temüjin, no!
Die, traitor, die!
Temüjin, beloved.
Ten men will guard you
with their lives.
I go to avenge my father.
[Shouts Commands]
[Shouting]
[Shouts]
Mongol dog!
Hyah!
He comes!
My heart is glad
that he lives to rejoice
in your triumph.
Open your heart to him,
Temüjin.
His love and loyalty for you
are no less than my own.
Let there be brotherhood
between us as before, Jamuga.
Though your tongue
calls me brother,
your heart denies me,
Temüjin,
for the worm of distrust
has entered into it.
The past shall be
forgotten, Jamuga.
The worm buries deep
but never dies.
Temüjin would be uneasy by day,
and by night sleep fearfully.
Let"s hear no more of this.
I have made great conquests.
I shall need
your wisdom henceforth.
You have no need of me
henceforth, my brother,
for you have found
your destiny.
Far greater conquests
will be yours, Temüjin,
and men will call you Genghis Khan,
the perfect warrior.
Jamuga of the silver tongue.
I have ill repaid your love,
my brother.
Ask now any favor of me,
and that I take my oath
to grant you.
Grant that I may die swiftly.
No!
Jamuga!
That is the favor I ask,
my brother.
I hold you to your oath.
As in the sacred ritual
of our ancestors, let my dying
be without bloodshed,
so that in
the eternal heavens...
my spirit may forever counsel
and protect the Great Khan.
So be it, my brother.
[Jamuga Narrating]
And the Great Khan
made such conquests...
as were undreamed of
by mortal men.
Tribes of the Gobi flocked
to his standard,
and the farthest reaches
of the desert trembled
under the hooves ofhis hordes.
At the feet ofhis Tartar woman,
he laid all the riches
of Cathay.
For 100 years,
the children of their loins
ruled half the world.