'This film is dedicated to prisoners of war.
'Their unbroken spirit is the symbol of a moral victory
'for which no bells have pealed.
'And which will not be remembered
'with the battle names on regimental colours.
'It was a war in which no decorations could be given,
'but to have come out of it
'with a whole spirit is its highest honour.
'These are a few of those men
'captured in the summer of 1940.
'They were the men who stood on the Dial,
'the Somme, and the La Basi Canal,
'who fought at Calais, April, St Valery,
'and the vital perimeter around the beaches of Dunkirk,
'the men who held on until the German armour thundered past their lines.
'220 miles they marched into captivity,
'through that blazing, dusty June, through France, through Belgium,
'through Holland, to the Rhine.'
Ahh...
Beer isn't what it used to be.
I hope the French beer isn't what it used to be, either.
Remember the last time, Ted?
Yeah, I remember something better than beer, too.
That stunner! Ooh, she was a smasher.
I can see her hair now, blacker than coal.
And that savoury piece in Lille!
Ooh, boy! She taught me a thing or two.
Pity you kept it to yourself.
It's proud we should be married to a couple of Don Juans.
Don't believe a girl ever looked at him twice. Poor old dear.
- Steady, you looked twice, didn't you?
- You caught me off me guard.
I was low following the flu.
Wonder what made you marry me.
You don't know? That wicked tenor voice you have.
- Leave them. Me and Ted will clear later.
- Any more for any more?
- No, thank you.
- It's nearly 12. We've got to be at the depot at 7am.
- Come on home.
- We'll have 'em both back before you can turn round.
War will be over by Christmas.
War will be over by Christmas? Where have I heard that before?
It's a shame we got to close the business.
It's just a habit we've got into, fighting the same war every 20 years.
- Nasty habit, too.
- Good night, Flo.
Good night.
See you in the morning.
All right.
She's a proper worrier.
Shame she never had kids.
And her always wanting them so much.
They'd have took her mind off things.
Well, it's too late now, I suppose.
Are you sorry Glad and Mary are grown up?
Well, I am and I'm not, in a manner of speaking.
What about starting all over again, old girl?
No, thank you, Ted.
I'm too old for that kind of war work.
HE CHUCKLES
DRAMATIC PIANO MUSIC
- Thanks, Stephen. I liked that a lot.
- The boy definitely shows promise.
- Nearly 1 o'clock.
- May I cadge a lift?
- Yes, of course.
Come on, Carol. Put your bonnet on.
- Cheerio. See you before you embark.
- Righty-o, Robert.
- Goodbye, Stephen, darling. Take care of yourself.
- Good night.
Well, wait for me.
(Stephen...)
Come on, Carol!
All right, Robert!
(Caroline...)
Caroline! Caroline!
CAR DRIVES AWAY
Stephen...
Caroline!
You left your scarf.
I know.
I had to come back.
Robert. What about him?
I wanted to tell you.
It's all over with Robert.
I think he understands.
I told him three weeks ago.
We met three weeks ago.
I wasn't sure until tonight.
Caroline.
You've only 48 hours before you go to France.
It's nothing and it's everything.
Everything.
I hope you know how to get a special licence.
TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS
HUBBUB
- And don't forget to write, David.
- Yes, Mum.
Let us know if there's anything you want.
Thank you, Mrs McDougall. Will you write to me, Elspeth?
- Yes, David, I will.
- You see, I...
WHISTLE BLOWS
Yes, David?
- Goodbye, David.
- Goodbye, David, my boy.
Goodbye, Mother.
Take care of yourself, David.
- Yes, Mrs McDougall. Elspeth, you see, I...
- Me too, David.
What did you say?
I love you.
Elspeth. Elspeth, will you marry me?
Yes, David!
TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS
CHURCH BELLS TOLL
Macht schnell! Los, los, schnell!
MAN COUNTS IN GERMAN
Mehr Tempo!
Herr Major, dass die Offiziere von den Mannschaften getrennt werden.
What's he talking about?
Sorry. I've no idea.
Can I be of any help?
Do you speak German? Good.
Herr Major hat Sie nicht verstanden. Kann ich ubersetzen, was Sie zu sagen wunschen?
Ja, gut. Erklaren Sie, dass die Offiziere von den Mannschaften getrennt werden.
He says the officers must be separated from the men.
But we must keep the wounded with us.
We've only got one MO among the lot of us.
Der Herr Major bittet, dass wir auf jeden Fall unsere Verwundeten bei uns behalten koennen.
Wir haben nur einen Arzt fuer uns alle.
Nun gut. Dann koennen Sie vorlaeufig zusammen bleiben bis Sie ins Lager transportiert werden.
- He says they may stay with us till we reach the camp.
- Thank you.
- A lot of them will remain automatically on the orderlies' train.
- That's right.
Well, come on, lads. In we go.
- How's tricks, Evans?
- Mustn't grumble, sir.
- You'll feel better with a gasper.
- Thank you, sir.
HE COUGHS
I don't know that you ought to smoke with that chest.
Oh, it's nothing. Wound's practically healed.
It's a pretty bad show all around.
I take it you fellows feel the same as I do.
We mustn't let the Jerries see we're down.
Take the Jerries to get me down? It's them ruddy cobbles.
What can I do for my feet, sir?
Do what I do. Try to forget 'em.
I can't take 'em off, can I?
How are you, Lennox? Eyes hurting you a bit?
A wee bit, sir.
We'll get the Jerries to give you some proper treatment As soon as we reach camp.
- Thank you, sir.
- How about you?
Mustn't grumble.
- You OK?
- Not too bad.
- How's the arm?
- Feels better now, sir.
Good boy. All right, lads.
It won't be long now.
Then you'll be able to have a real rest.
Thanks for the help just now.
Useful man to know. Perfect German.
Dalrymple's my name. 31st Lancers.
Geoffrey Mitchell, 5th Oxfordshire light infantry.
Oh, where did the Jerries pick you up?
Thionville.
- Oh, really? I didn't know the 5th were anywhere near there.
- Yes.
Oh!
GUNFIRE
EXPLOSIONS
TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS
GERMAN SOLDIERS BARK ORDERS
March to attention!
MEN START WHISTLING
ALL WHISTLE TUNE TOGETHER
CLOCK CHIMES HOUR
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon. Do sit down, won't you?
Thank you.
My name's Celia Mitchell.
I've heard my husband may be a prisoner of war...
Captain Geoffrey Mitchell.
Maybe. Didn't the war office notify you, Mrs Mitchell?
Well, no, you see, I don't expect he put me down as next of kin.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
Your husband's regiment?
5th Oxford light infantry.
General index. Give me particulars of Captain Geoffrey Mitchell,
5th Oxfordshire light infantry, will you?
I'd like to send him parcels.
I suppose I can do that.
Oh, yes, certainly.
Flag 27. Prisoner of war number 1376.
Thank you.
Hello, Mummy!
Hello, darling. Have you had a lovely day with Grandpa?
Will Father ever come back to us, Grandpa,
even when the war's over?
Well, would you be glad if he did?
No. He used to make Mummy cry.
He is a prisoner.
- Hello, Desmond.
- Hello, Mummy.
Janet, I'll leave you in charge.
Well?
He didn't put me down as next of kin.
Well, that seems to be the final gesture, doesn't it, my dear?
It was only logical, I suppose.
Poor Geoffrey.
Poor Geoffrey?
Well, I for one don't intend to shed any tears over him.
- Father?
- Hmm?
I'm going to write to him.
- You are?
- Yes.
Can't do any harm or good.
They must be glad of any news of home.
I don't suppose Geoffrey ever betrayed the faintest interest in his home.
I can tell him how the children are getting on.
I can see Geoffrey regaling his fellow prisoners
with news of the children he's scarcely ever seen.
You're afraid, aren't you, Father?
Certainly. I'm afraid that you may let yourself be carried away
by sentimentality and suggest patching things up with him.
Don't worry.
But we said so many hard, cruel things to each other.
I'd like to wipe out the memory of them.
And then if we should happen to meet when the war's over,
it won't be as enemies.
Here. Go easy with the soap.
Sorry, old boy.
We may make it last two days more if we're very careful.
After that, we've got to make do with godliness.
I say, Padre, what are you smoking? Sauerkraut?
Fag ends of fag ends of fag ends.
Lucky fellow. I'm down to Mr Middleton's specials.
Not a cough in a contest.
I hear there's a bush around here that's not too bad in a pipe.
Had a marvellous dream last night.
Anybody I know?
Eggs and bacon.
Tomato ketchup this time.
We must have lost a shocking lot of stuff.
There's nothing to stop 'em.
He's bound to invade before the end of summer, that's the end of us.
- Steady. What about the home fleet?
- What about the Luftwaffe?!
Well, of all the damn defeatists!
- Well, if you prefer to be a ruddy halfwit.
- What about the RAF?
Hitler can't stage an invasion
until he's got control of the air,
- and I don't see the boys handing him that on a plate.
- Hear, hear!
You can't judge Hitler by ordinary standards.
If he thinks he'll invade, he'll invade.
My old woman makes the kids pay a penny a week for the Red Cross.
I'm writing to her to stop that caper.
Red ruddy Cross!
Bloody sausage we ever get out of it!
It's only two months.
Don't forget, there were only a few hundred prisoners here before.
Now there are tens of thousands.
It's a big job.
Yeah. Don't let's kid ourselves.
Nobody worries about us anymore.
We've been written off.
You're a pessimist.
How do you spell "sufficient"?
Same as the Sergeant Major's blessing, two "F"s and one "C".
Writing about the grub.
Muck, I call it.
Bit of the old woman's cooking is what I'd like now.
What a sucker I was joining the ruddy army.
Picturing meself cutting loose with some rowdy old French dames.
Here I am shut up in this place till I'll be past it.
You ought to have joined the Navy and let the world see you.
Now, son, there's no use you blowing off.
Take things as you find them, that's always been my motto.
The way I look at it is...
Hark at you! Drip, drip, drip. You're worse than a woman.
Knock it, sonny. I was swinging a rifle
when your nappies was on the line.
Swinging a lead, more like it.
Here, if you want a clip on the ear, my lad, you've come to the right person.
Ohh!
- That cigarette. Let me see it.
- What do you mean see it?
It's a Player's. Where did you get it?
Saved it up. What's it to you?
- I had three Player's left. You stole it!
- Ah, go chase yourself.
- Hand it over!
- Pipe down, you little Welshman.
- Give it back!
You did pinch that fag, you young basket.
Yes, I did. So what?
- Just this.
- Ooh!
Been asking for it, sonny.
I'm a man of peace, and peace is what I'm going to have plenty of in here.
Blimey. They'll have to have you at the peace conference.
- How are you today, Jessup?
- Mustn't grumble, sir.
- Manage to get any sleep?
- Not so as you'd notice.
We'll soon get you out of here.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
Morning, Lennox.
Oh, good morning, sir.
Got some good news for you, David.
Yes, Padre?
Yes, my lad. You'll be rejoining the rest of us tomorrow.
Oh, that's fine, sir.
And I'll be able to take this bandage off?
Not yet, I'm afraid.
You'll have to wait till the optic nerve is completely healthy again.
They'll send you to the eye hospital for an operation.
So you'll have to be a very patient patient, my boy.
I'll do my best, sir.
That's right.
I'm sorry, mate. I'll give you a packet of 20
when the Red Cross parcels come.
Losing my temper over a fag.
I shouldn't have left them loafing about.
You know, you wouldn't be a bad lad,
if you got rid of some of your nasty habits.
Nark it. Leave all that reforming stuff to the padre.
What's your job in Civvy Street?
Only suckers work.
- Oh, a wide boy, eh?
- You bet.
Me and Ted's in the building business.
What about learning the trade when we get home?
I'll be home long before you two mugs.
I'm going to scarper.
You got out of tougher spots than this, eh?
- Sure.
- Got a plan?
Dozens of 'em. For instance...
You know, I can't make up me mind
whether to turn this into a brigantine or a schooner.
GIRL GIGGLES
I wonder how Jane's getting on these days?
Who is Jane?
Your girl?
No, no, the Jane, the strip in the Mirror.
Oh, yes, the strip in the Mirror.
I suppose a highbrow like you wouldn't read the Daily Mirror.
Oh, I don't know. Why highbrow?
I mean, perfect German and all that sort of thing.
Spent much time in Germany?
Yes, as a matter of fact, I have.
Come to think of it, it's funny that
- none of the rest of your chaps got caught with you.
- Yes.
Did you have a company?
Yes, machine gun company.
Machine gun company?!
You see, I...
I think I'll turn it up. Wound's hurting a bit.
All I have to do is stow away in one of them garbage bins or something, why, it's as easy as...
If you're planning an escape, Mathews,
may I give you a piece of advice?
Individual escapes hardly ever succeed.
These things have to be planned and coordinated by a whole group.
All the same, sir, I'm going to have a go at it if you have no objections.
Well, good luck to you.
Good luck. Two-faced bleeder.
I don't know what it is, but there's something phony about that bloke.
Always sucking up with the German MO or Commandant.
Look, men!
That settles it.
But they have machine gun companies in the German army.
- You seriously think he's a traitor?
- He speaks German as well as any German.
Why shouldn't he be a German planted here as a stool pigeon?
- That would account for a lot of things.
- We're always talking about home. He never does.
- I hate to believe it.
- Come in.
May I report something, sir?
Go ahead.
Well, it's rather confidential, sir.
It's about somebody we think's a fifth columnist.
- An officer?
- A matter of fact, sir, it is.
Captain Mitchell, sir.
- There you are.
- He overheard me planning a breakout
- and went and talked to one of the German guards.
- Thank you.
- Keep your mouth shut for the time being.
- Very good, sir.
There's only one thing to do with a rat. String him up!
Here, wait a bit. Man's innocent till he's proved guilty.
Don't let us behave like a bunch of Nazis.
Come on.
Oh, Mitchell, you didn't destroy your identity card, did you?
No, why?
Oh, just check up. Have a look at it?
Do you mind duplicating your signature?
You can't do it, you swine, your name isn't Mitchell!
- Come on, what are we waiting for? Let's get it over with!
- Stop it!
If you have anything to say, you better say it quick.
It's a long story, and...
..you wouldn't believe a word of it.
- You're dead right, we wouldn't!
- Shut up! Go on, spill it.
I'm not a German. I'm a Czech.
A Czech in British uniform? That's bloody likely!
I'm in charge here. Shut up, and that's an order!
Come on.
I escaped from a German concentration camp.
I got through to France, and I took this uniform
and the identity card from Mitchell's dead body.
It was my only chance if the Germans caught up with me.
If that's the truth, why didn't you tell us?
Would you have believed me any more than you do now?
Besides, I have more to fear from the stool pigeons than you have.
You've no proof of your story.
None. How could I have?
How do you come to speak such perfect English and German?
My father was at the Czech embassy in London after the last war.
I spent my childhood there.
German is a sort of second language in Czechoslovakia.
I became professor of English at Prague University.
I'm not much of a soldier, I'm afraid.
What were you talking about to that guard just now?
Oh, I was trying to get a chess set for David Lennox.
- PA:
- 'Achtung! Achtung!
'All British prisoners will parade at once.'
- You may get proof of my story after all.
- How?
The civilian. His name's Forster.
- Gestapo.
- How do you know?
He ran the concentration camp I was in.
You think he'll recognise you?
Well, if he does, he'll do your job for you.
- 'Achtung! Achtung!'
- Come on.
'All British prisoners will parade at once.'
HE GREETS HIM IN GERMAN
Right turn!
Stand your men at ease, please.
Stand at ease!
Gentlemen, I present to you Herr Forster, the foreign office.
Gentlemen. For the time being, all communications
between Germany and England are at a standstill.
Your letters, therefore, cannot leave this country.
To keep you informed, however,
our news bulletins will be broadcast to you in English.
And as you cannot hope to receive news from home,
arrangements have been made for you
to broadcast messages to your next of kin.
GRUMBLING
Will all those who wish to avail themselves
of Herr Forster's offer, take three paces forward!
You are the senior British officer?
- Yes.
- Are your men afraid that this is some sort of propaganda trick?
- Well, it's just possible.
- As you wish.
Your name?
- Mitchell.
- Mitchell?
You are the officer acting as hospital interpreter.
Yes.
I understand you speak almost perfect German.
That's rather unusual for an Englishman.
- Is it?
- I wonder why your face seems familiar.
I have many friends in England.
Possibly we met there.
Possibly.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Do you wish to continue this conversation?
- No.
- Prisoners cannot be required to answer any questions
other than relating to name, rank, and number.
Quite, quite.
The matter is of no importance.
You may dismiss the parade.
Parade, turn!
- PA:
- 'This is today's official war communique
'issued by the German high command.
'The Battle of Britain has entered upon a new and final stage.
'Annihilation of England's towns and cities
'by the all-conquering Luftwaffe.
'Last night, just before sunset,
'the air-raid sirens sounded their ominous wailing notes
'to the 9 million inhabitants of Greater London.
'All night, an endless stream of bombers roared above the city
'discharging their loads of high-explosive
'and incendiary bombs.
'Anti-aircraft opposition was negligible,
'for the British do not possess the guns to defend their homeland.
'And this attack will continue every night from dusk till dawn
'until the nerve centre and capital city of the British Empire
'is reduced to a vast pile of rubble, dust, and ashes.
'The words of our great battle hymn have come true at last.
'Wir fahren gegen England!
'We march against England!'
GERMAN BATTLE HYMN PLAYS
Come on, boys. Let's give 'em our great battle hymn!
# Roll out the barrel
# We'll have a barrel of fun
# We've got the blues on the run
# Zing, boom, terrara
# Sing out a song of good cheer
# Now's the time to roll the barrel
# Cos the gang's all here... #
Come on!
# Roll out the barrel
# We'll have a barrel of fun
# We've got the blues on the run
# Zing, boom, terrara
# Sing out a song of good cheer
# Now's the time to roll the barrel
# For the gang's all here! #
You should have come to see me before this, Mrs Evans.
Nothing wrong, is there?
No, but you're not exactly robust.
I had the flu last year, but nothing since.
And you're over 40, aren't you?
Only just.
Well, we needn't make any decision yet.
Decision?
I may have to suggest an operation.
I see.
Thank you, Doctor.
I was at Finn's the night before last.
Miracle none of us copped it.
The guvnor was just standing around.
This one's on the house, he said. And lummy, it was.
- Well, dear?
- Everything's all right.
Waste of time and money it was, making me come and see the doctor.
Your dad wanted to make quite sure, you know.
Yes, of course.
I always felt I'd failed him,
but never a word of reproach.
There's kind he is, all through.
But now, now I won't fail him.
- I know I won't.
- Of course you won't, dear.
PLAYS SIMPLE ROMANTIC MELODY
Stephen wrote that for me.
My application's been approved, Carol.
Staff job, west Africa.
I was going to ask you for a photograph,
but perhaps I'm better without it.
Look, Robert, ever since Beryl's been living here with me,
I've seen how crazy she is about you.
Why don't you and she...
Beryl and I might have made a go of it
if I hadn't met you first.
I'm sorry, Robert.
I did treat you shabbily.
No, you didn't. I realise now you were never more than just fond of me.
You'd have realised it, too, even if Stephen hadn't turned up.
I always will be fond of you.
As long as you're happy. That's what matters.
That's sweet of you.
My dear...
I'm sorry.
I'm not.
But it's got to be goodbye, Robert.
Goodbye.
Last Christmas, I had my first concert.
It's there I met Caroline.
Last Christmas, I was in Dachau concentration camp.
Christmas eve, a new batch of prisoners came in.
One of them brought me news of my family.
They'd been caught giving food to a Polish Jew.
They were taken out and shot.
My father, my mother...
All of them.
Only 36 shopping days to Christmas.
Christmas. Parked around a blazing fire
with a great bowl of hot rum punch.
Looks like it's snowing again. That should raise the temperature.
What binds me is living by courtesy of Jerry.
Can't see any future in it, really.
They say the first seven years are the hardest.
If the next six are like this...
The Red Cross parcels are bound to arrive soon.
- You've been saying that for exactly four months.
- I've been meaning it!
All I can think about is food.
Roast turkey, mince pies, Christmas...
Oh, shut up!
Das ist alles.
Well, lad, it's me again.
Yes, padre.
David, they can't operate.
Not...ever?
No, David.
I won't ever see again?
I don't believe it. It's that German doctor.
- When I get back to Scotland...
- No.
David, it's no use. You've got to face it.
I'll not need this anymore.
You feel now there's nothing left to live for,
and that feeling will go on for a long time,
but then you'll begin to remember the things that are left.
You'll begin to realise that this darkness of yours is not absolute.
David, the things that make life worthwhile for all of us...
kindness, affection, companionship...
The loss of your sight can never rob you of those things, David.
We're your friends here.
We offer you our help and understanding.
And waiting to welcome you home
when all this is over, are your own folk who love you.
I'll be all right.
HE SOBS
18, 20, play 21s.
- What's for tea?
- Fancy cakes. Just fancy you've had 'em.
Good job we haven't got any brass monkeys in here,
we'd have the RSPCA down on us, and no error.
Can't you do anything with this ruddy stove?
Isn't there anything else to burn?
All right.
I never said a word, did I?
Go on, burn the ruddy thing.
It's enough for a brew-up.
They've come! Hundreds and hundreds of 'em!
All right, I'll bite. Hundreds of what?
Red Cross parcels, ruddy mountains of 'em!
ALL SHOUT AND CHEER
The Red Cross parcels are here!
ALL: Hooray!
Red Cross parcels are here!
MEN SING: # O come all ye faithful
# Joyful and triumphant
# O come ye, O come ye
# To Bethlehem
# Come and behold him
# Born the king of angels
# O come let us adore him
# Christ the Lord
# Sing choirs of angels... #
OC Sports, you. OC Music, Stephen Harley.
- Anything else I haven't covered?
- No. Extraordinary, isn't it?
We seem to have specialists on every subject.
Aren't you an expert on anything?
Only racing, I'm afraid.
I had thought of starting a little bookmaking business.
Why not? Anyway, our money will be safe. You can't welsh on us.
THEY LAUGH
OK, number four shift.
- How far?
- About three feet.
Good. By the way, doc, I put you down OC Entertainment.
- Fine.
- What about me? I've had masses of experience backstage.
What sort of experience?
No need to make low insinuendos, old man.
Come on, fellows! Here it is!
Mail from home!
- Baker!
- Here!
- Macdonald!
My father's been thrown through the dispensary window.
What, by an angry patient?
No, a bomb.
Well, well, they've requisitioned the church hall.
- I say, that's serious.
- What is?
Veronica. She sweats all night.
Well, surely she can do something about it,
- with all these advertisements.
- Don't be a halfwit.
Veronica's a filly and is getting ready for the flat.
Oh, sorry, old boy. I thought she was a popsy getting ready for the...
My kids have been evacuated to the country.
My girl joined the land army. She'll wait for me
- till the cows come home.
- One way of putting it!
Listen to this. "Dear Daddy, today is your birthday.
"I hope it will be your last."
Hello, David.
- I didn't notice. Shall I read your letter for you?
- Thank you.
It's signed...Elspeth.
"Dearest David,
"your mother says I am silly to worry about it,
"but it seems queer not a word from you yet.
"Do please send me a line when you get this.
"The three of us had a little party on your birthday.
"Wouldn't it be wonderful, darling,
"if you were home again for your next?
"I miss you all the time.
"Your loving Elspeth.
"PS, I'm going to join the Wrens."
Will you do me a favour?
I'd like to answer it at once.
Yes, of course.
Here's a form.
I've got a pencil. Ready when you are.
My dearest Elspeth,
I am dictating this letter because my wound
is not quite better yet.
I've been thinking things over.
And this is to ask if you will release me
from our engagement.
I realise now I don't feel the way
I...I fancied I did about you.
So it's best to make a definite break.
Yours, David.
David, why not tell her the truth?
It is the truth.
About your eyes, I mean.
Why not let her decide when she knows?
Will you please send that letter?
- Look, David...
- Please!
All right, David.
Ted, it's it! It's it!
- It's it!
- Brought it from Littlewoods?
Wonderful news, man, wonderful.
It's Dillith. There's a baby coming.
Good old Di! I reckon that's the best Christmas present you ever had.
I can see her now, the way she smiles with her eyes.
Aye, indeed. It's lovely to...
How do I look for a godfather?
Ah, yes! That's it, man.
You and Flo. It goes without saying.
And what's the matter?
Got the same chit from the income tax as me, old boy?
Well, don't worry. They can't put us in jag.
We've had it.
What wouldn't I give to see Queen's Park play Rangers this year.
Never mind, padre. They'll be playing over here one day.
'All British prisoners will parade at once.'
- Hello! What's cooking?
- Forster's on the warpath. They're searching the camp.
Forster again.
'Achtung! Achtung!
'All British prisoners will parade at once.'
Raus, raus!
'Achtung! Achtung!
'All British prisoners will parade at once.'
HE SPEAKS GERMAN
Parade! Halt.
Gentlemen, we have discovered your tunnel.
Since you have thus abused the amenities accorded you,
and pending reconsideration of the camp's security measures,
all these amenities will be removed until further notice.
I've given instructions, therefore, to confiscate all books,
writing material, music, all tables and chairs,
bedding, mirrors, knives, and shaving equipment.
You may dismiss the parade.
Parade! Dismissed.
I shall have to grow a beard after all.
I don't know whether to have a two-pronged affair
- or a natty little imperial.
- Wonder how long they'll keep it up.
Not more than a month, I should think.
- I'll keep on nagging the commandant.
- Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Good afternoon.
I hope this slight setback won't prevent you from trying again.
But I must add,
a moat will be dug around the whole perimeter,
which, as you know, makes tunnelling impossible.
Captain Mitchell, who speaks such excellent German...
THEY CONVERSE IN GERMAN
What's he want this time?
Wants to know why I haven't written a single letter home.
Why should you? Mitchell may have had nobody particular to write to.
But he had. This came today.
It's from his wife.
You must answer, or she'll make enquiries.
That'll be fatal.
Seems a pretty cruel fraud.
You're wearing a dead man's shoes. You've got to get used to them.
My handwriting. She'd know it wasn't her husband.
Yes, takes a bit of figuring out.
Alibi for using your left hand. That's what you need.
I can't see much point in this,
now the blighters have taken away the football.
Well, anyway, it's good exercise.
Think so? I suppose next week they'll give us back the football
and take away the goalposts.
Come on, it's your turn now.
Ready?
Look out!
- Good morning, Mrs Mitchell.
- Thank you.
I've mastered the boiler and the power plant.
I won't be defeated by a miserable wireless set.
I've heard from Geoffrey.
Really?
Is he well?
I don't know what to make of it.
He seems to have changed.
Good. Any change in Geoffrey could only be for the better.
Well, the change seems to include his handwriting.
Hurt his hand. He's using his left.
Listen to this.
"It is a world cut off completely from the real world.
"Time stands still here.
"The future is remote. The present empty.
"Even the past begins to seem unreal.
"But a man must have something to hold onto.
"He must forge lengths to keep him sane.
"Will you write to me again, Celia,
"as though I were a stranger?
"Somebody who knows nothing of your life and your home.
"Even of yourself."
Changed?! Why, he's even learned to write grammatically.
Write to him as though he were a stranger...
KNOCKING
Robert!
Come back to be briefed.
Sort of a hush-hush job.
Thought you wouldn't mind if I just called in
to say hail and farewell.
Of course not. Come in.
You look ill, Carol.
I'm all right.
I ran into Beryl in an odd sort of mood.
- I gather she isn't living with you any longer.
- No.
No, she left soon after you went away.
Heard from Stephen yet?
Oh, yes, I've heard from Stephen.
- What's he say?
- That our marriage is all washed up.
What?!
He got a letter accusing me of having an affair with you.
Carol, I... But who?
Beryl.
Ahh... I see.
And he actually believed it?
Yes.
I'll write back myself and tell him the whole thing's
a deliberate, malicious lie.
What for?
What for?! You don't want Stephen to go on thinking this, do you?
I don't care what he thinks now.
Carol, you mustn't take it like that.
Stephen's a prisoner of war.
If you were in his place, would you pay attention to a poison pen letter?
I don't know.
I'd never been in love before.
I thought being in love meant that you trusted each other completely.
All the things he said,
I believed every word.
Killed my love for him.
Caroline, my darling, I can't bear to see you cry.
Don't forget to drop us a line, dear, if there's anything you want.
I've tried to get used to it,
but I still can't believe it.
We were so much in love.
- Ah, it's a mystery to me.
- He has a right to change his mind, I suppose.
Could it be that he doesn't think it's fair to make Elspeth wait on and on?
Do you think it might be that?
No. I don't think David's the kind
to make that sort of sacrifice for that sort of reason.
- Goodbye, my darling.
- Goodbye.
'The photograph I'm sending makes me look absurdly young,
'but I'm no longer young.
'The one of Janet, that funny expression's only shyness,
'not a stomach ache.
'I can see her now through the window
'telling her grandpapa how to plant tomatoes.
'I'm worried about her teeth.
'Father thinks she should wear one of those wire things.
'And that hulking boy is Desmond. Nine years old yesterday.
'The village is livelier than it's ever been.
'We have a large contingent of evacuees
'and a lot of other visitors that come and go.
'Everything's changed and yet nothing's changed.
'There's the whistle of the 4:35.
'Half an hour late as usual.
'Mrs Trusket still serves her homemade toffee.
'Where she manages to get the sugar from, I can't imagine.
'And there's still cricket on Saturday afternoon.'
Oh, what a kick in the pants that turned out to be.
Five times more officers than other ranks
and they have to knock the stuffing out of us.
It was a mistake having long-on too close to the wire.
If he has to run back to take a catch, he's had it.
Do you know what the Jerries want for a new ball? 500 cigarettes.
- Sheer blackmail.
- Oh, I think it's worth it if this marvellous weather continues.
I wonder if they've been having an early spring at home.
"The apple trees are in full blossom already,
"making the orchard look like a sheet of fleecy snow.
"And 10-Acre Meadow is all white, too.
"Because this year,
"that's where the ewes are pastured with their lambs.
"Soon the garden will be filled with the scent
"and colour of the May.
"And beyond the river,
"you can see the first vivid green of the larches
"in the bluebell wood."
- Ted?
- Yeah?
Remember that redhead I told you about?
Let's see, is that your own true dream girl lovey pie
or cheerio, toots?
No! It's my steady.
She says the works manager's fallen for her.
Says he's a key man.
Sounds like one of them backdoor key men to me.
You and your pin-up girls.
My pinup's Tessie O'Shea, with a rawlplug.
- Yeah, but in my experience...
- Your experience?
Cor blimey, one sniff of a barmaid's apron,
and you'd be on your knees, sonny boy.
That's all you know. Teach you a thing or two.
What's the matter, Ted? Bad news?
Ted?
Blimey, I never saw that one.
Hey, my old woman's gone on the buses.
- Oh, you'll be walking the kids when you get home.
- If we get home.
It's a firm stand I'm going to take.
The rest of them you can eat,
but not Lili Marleen.
She's got such a trusting look in her eye.
Besides, next winter I shall use her as a hot water bottle.
I've had a letter, Dai.
Amazing. Perhaps there's one for me
with news of the baby.
No letter for you.
There is news.
Flo's all right?
Not Ann-Marie?
She's OK. Letter's from her.
"It's a baby girl. She's doing nice.
"Dillith..."
You'll have it sooner or later.
Seems that doctor warned her about it being dangerous,
because of her age.
She wouldn't be put off.
Flo was with her at the end.
It was all over quite quick.
Flo's going to look after the baby until you get back.
The play's the thing.
Wherein I'll catch the conscience of the king.
Well, what happens in the end?
Do they bump the dirty old basket off?
Well, there's a sort of all-round massacre,
and Hamlet gets killed himself.
First class gangster stuff. The old boy certainly knew his onion.
You wait till we get to Richard III.
There's a murder on practically every page.
You're getting pretty hot at this Braille business.
Och, it's easy. But I'm still terrible clumsy with my hands.
Oh, I don't know about that. That tobacco pouch you made was smashing.
I've got sort of used to it now.
And, well, you've all been so...
You get on with your reading. I want to know what happens next.
Right.
'Celia, your letter has arrived with the photographs.
'They're in front of me as I write.
'You ask me to describe our life here
'so that you may picture it in your imagination.
'From where I sit, I can hear the sound of a piano.
'It is my friend Stephen Harley.
'I wish you could hear this music,
'for it describes our life here
'better than I could ever do with words.
'It tells of men emerging from the twilight.
'Turning their faces inwards from the wire.
'Creating in miniature a world of their own.
'It tells of men who have come to terms with the present
'and find it far from empty.
'Men who no longer lie down to fate but face it.
'And find their own ways of beating it.'
THEY SING HYMN
GENTLE CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS
RAUCOUS LAUGHTER
HOOTING AND WOLF-WHISTLES
'All this goes to make up the picture of our life here,
'made bearable only by the letters and parcels
'we receive from home.
'They keep our bodies and our faith alive.
'And that is true not only of us
'here in our little wired enclosed cinder patch,
'but also of the scores of other camps throughout Germany.
'Great sprawling towns of 20,000 men
'or hamlets of a few hundred, each a little piece of England.'
'The months pass and my thoughts are constantly of you, Celia.
'Summer gives place to autumn, autumn to winter.
'Another Christmas come and gone.
'Another batch of prisoners to swell our numbers.
'They don't make the housing problem any easier.
'But they bring us eagerly awaited news of the outside world.
'A little while ago there was a rumour
'that some of us were to be repatriated.
'I allowed myself to dream that these letters of ours
'could come to life.
'I could see with my own eyes your home, the children,
'yourself.
'But the commission never came.
'Were we forgotten?
'Or was it just one more reprisal?'
Being they are prisoners,
this practice must come to rest.
Orders.
Finally, the recent operations at Dieppe,
as a reprisal for such an unwarranted action,
all British prisoners of war of cellblock 27
will, until further notice, remain manacled
from dawn until dusk.
You may dismiss the parade.
HE SHOUTS ORDERS
Cigarette?
Thanks.
It's easy. Sardine key.
Turn to the right.
Turn to the left.
Bob's your uncle.
All part of the Red Cross service.
THEY LAUGH
'Our third winter is approaching,
'bringing with it a new enemy.
'It's not the duration but the indefiniteness.
'For if a man knew the length of his sentence,
'he could plan accordingly.
'Afterwards in our memories,
'we shall relive only the sunny days
'or pleasant scenes,
'the freedom of mind and the comradeship.
'We shall forget the wet days, the wet weeks.
'Those days when it seemed an effort to do nothing
'and our bunks were the only release.
'Deep down in the hearts of all of us,
'there dwells a lonely ache,
'a desperate yearning for those we love
'and a fear, fear of becoming forgotten men.
'Write to me again soon, Celia.
'You could never know how great the comfort is
'that your letters bring to me.
'They're more than comfort.
'They give me strength and hope and happiness.
'You will never know how much they mean to me.'
'Oh, my dear, I am so terribly moved by the way you write.
'Is it too late to recapture the happiness of our first years together?'
'I have no place in your past or your future, Celia.
'You must think of your husband as dead.
'This is goodbye.'
'I understand. Don't be afraid.
'I'll help you back.
'I'll give you back your strength,
'the strength you've given to me writing to me through these dark years.
'I'll wait for you.'
DISTANT DRONE OF PLANES
PLANES APPROACH
Fortresses.
They'll soon be able to see the Channel.
They'll be home in time for tea.
That's exactly 157 you owe me.
Cut you through the pack. Double or quits.
Not on your life. I've got my old age to think of.
Bloodsucker.
Oh, well, bang goes my gratuity.
Cheap enough to pass the time.
Funny how much you learn about time when you're killing it.
Such as what?
I've got a theory that everything that counts is done by busy people.
When you've got too little time, it's extraordinary what you can do with it.
And when you've got all the time in the world,
like us, you don't do a damn thing.
I say, you're becoming quite a philosopher in your old age.
Why not? The war hasn't exactly chosen us to be heroes.
I know exactly what I'm going to do with my time right now.
I'm going to climb into my bunk
and do absolutely nothing till supper.
They're talking about Teran for the derby this year.
It'll be the fourth derby I've missed.
Four derbies. That's a hell of a lot of time.
With nothing up or down on the book to show for it.
Planting leeks again this year, Dai?
I was thinking of trying some asparagus.
Asparagus? That takes seven years, cock.
Aye.
I don't give it more than another year myself.
Another year?
Gwyneth will be four.
Flo's hair has gone all white, she says.
Everything's changing.
Do you think we'll be able to pick it up?
The business and everything?
Search me. We're not as young as we were, Dai.
No, Ted, we're not as young as we were.
Surely they'll invade soon.
Yeah, that's what you said last year.
And the year before.
What's there, mate, holiday list?
Yeah, it's got you down for August, 1949.
I wrote that for Caroline.
Somehow it expressed what I felt when I first met her.
It was after a concert.
There weren't any taxis.
We walked back across the park.
After a bit, it began to rain.
I put my coat over her shoulders.
You're still in love with her, aren't you?
I've tried to shut her out of my thoughts completely.
But I can't. I long for her all the time.
I'm a bigger fool than you are.
Falling in love with a photograph. A dream.
And a home in a strange land.
Achtung!
Oh, carry on.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Oh, please, do carry on.
Each time I visit this camp,
I'm intrigued as to where we met before.
But now I think I know the answer.
Your name wasn't always Geoffrey Mitchell.
Your identification photograph is being sent
to Gestapo headquarters in Berlin.
They have a large collection of photographs there.
It will be interesting to make comparisons.
I suppose it had to come.
They always catch up with you in the end.
Repatriation, fellas! Repatriation!
THEY ALL SCOFF
Great news, gentlemen, great news! Repatriation!
And this time it's the real McCoy.
The thing that makes me mouth water, real live girls.
- All lining up waiting for me.
- Girls, what are they?
Bipeds, old boy, furnished with two of practically everything!
A mixed German and Swiss medical commission
will examine all those whose names are down for repatriation.
Apparently it's a rush job, so anybody who gets his ticket
will leave in a week's time.
MEN CHEER So you've got a chance.
Yes.
But we must have positive evidence to justify repatriation.
Of course.
Ah. Anything else, Corporal?
Well, sir, every time I breathe,
I can feel me liver knocking up against me kidneys.
- Come here.
- Yes, sir.
Cough, please.
Cough? Blimey, do you want me to bring up my appendix?
Ja.
You have passed.
Thank you, sir.
Matthews.
I wonder if you'll get through.
Hello, Evans. You'll soon be seeing your youngster.
Yes, indeed. I'm sorry to hear about you and Captain Grayson, sir.
Oh, well, the flat racing season's over.
That Swiss fellow had the nerve to congratulate me on my fitness.
Ha ha! Well?
- I got my ticket, all right.
- Fine.
You have passed.
Suits me, sir.
Captain Mitchell.
Ah.
You need not strip, Captain Mitchell.
I regret your case is deferred
until the next board in six months' time.
Morris.
And once it's discovered he's not Mitchell, he's sunk. We've got to do something for him.
Yes, but what?
- Excuse me, sir. Can we put up a scheme to you?
- Sure. Sit down.
- What's it all about?
- We know the spot Captain Mitchell's in.
- We thought we'd fix a stunt to get him out of here.
- What's the scheme?
There's a list for repatriation in the commandant's office.
- We thought if we could get it, alter the names...
- Stage a break-in, sir.
Here, hold on. We aren't professional burglars.
Well, yes, sir, as a matter of fact... well, I was.
Were you really? Well, how awfully interesting.
Commandant's office. Only one wire to cut.
Yes, but what about the perimeter lights?
- They put them out when there's an air raid.
- And they've been as regular as clockwork.
I believe we've got something!
- Suppose we do get the list. What then?
- I can type.
Scratch out one name and type Mitchell's on instead.
Just a minute. Don't you see, the chap whose name goes off has to stay behind.
Well, uh, my name begins with M, sir.
You'd really give up your ticket home?
Why not?
But I thought all the girls were lining up for you to come home?
Well, so they are. But they'll wait.
You are a sportsman.
Gentleman, we'll have a smack at it.
Now, as I see it, the drill is this...
DISTANT SINGING
# My eyes are dim, I cannot see
# I have not brought my specs with me... #
Shh, shhh!
PLANES APPROACH
Here come the boys. Bang on the dot.
- What do you mean?
- Well, just another raid, old boy.
All right, chaps, light up and sing out.
THEY CONTINUE SINGING
Well, they had better start.
I know. God bless the RAF.
Here he is.
Good boy. Look out!
All clear.
THEY CHAT IN GERMAN
THEY LAUGH
That's the lock you've got to pick.
Good, there's a typewriter.
Get down!
- Type on the floor.
- OK.
It's tougher than I thought.
Let me try.
- Must be a bit out of practice.
- I'll say.
Einrichtung, einrichtung...
Good, this is it.
Sing, you so-and-sos, sing!
- That'll do.
- Come on.
- That'll fool 'em.
- Should do.
- Let's split up and get back to our own huts.
- OK, sir.
DOG GROWLS
GUNSHOTS
- What's going on?
- You're not supposed to know.
The boys were putting your name on the repatriation list.
GUNSHOTS
DOG HOWLS
GUNFIRE CONTINUES
MUSIC AND SINGING
You will all remain here until the other huts have been checked!
Permission to go home, sir?
Yes, provided you put a fiver on Teran at the derby for me.
- It's you that ought to be going home.
- Oh, don't you believe it.
I'm a social parasite.
The sort we're fighting to get rid of.
That's right. I've got to stay here and exterminate him.
Go slow with the popsies, old boy.
Don't forget to save a couple of blondes for your Uncle Jim.
- That's a promise.
- Course, I was forgetting.
You're one of those one-woman blokes, aren't you?
Yes, that's my trouble.
Sorry, then. Always putting my foot in it.
Tell the girls round Hammersmith that I'll be home soon
and I've got plenty saved up to give them a treat with.
- Yeah, you bet.
- I'll keep a job warm for him.
- Horsfall, Evans, and Mathews.
- Unlimited.
Hello, Mathews. Feeling all right?
Yes, it's all right, sir. I was a sissy passing out like that.
I can never thank you for what you've done.
Forget it. Just keep your head down on the parade and Bob's your uncle.
- Thanks.
- Don't worry, sir. You'll get through all right.
We'll be right behind you, sir.
One other thing. What about the German MO?
He's certain to be on parade,
and he's likely to remember that Mitchell's name wasn't on the list.
I know. I've thought of that.
I'm going to start up a conversation while they're calling the names.
He only speaks about a dozen words in English.
You leave it to me.
Hello, David, my boy.
Goodbye and good luck.
Goodbye, sir, and thank you all.
See you again before you know where you are.
- Yes.
- Come on, David.
Don't forget. We've got a bridge date tonight.
Don't forget the cigarettes you owe me.
Play you double or quits tonight.
Ambrose.
Anderson.
Burns.
There are a lot of things I'd like to say, but...
but I can't.
Go on. Off you go.
Goodbye. Good luck.
- So long, old boy.
- Good luck.
Keep out of the German MO's eyeline.
Grant.
Harley.
Hunt.
Horsfall.
Jackson.
Jessop.
How soon do you think the war will end now, Doctor?
Six months or one year.
By then, you'll be speaking fluent English.
You think I've made good progression?
Oh, terrific. Yes, you Germans certainly have a gift for languages.
- You think so?
- Of course. Yes.
After the war, they might make me headmaster of Oxford University.
THEY LAUGH
Mitchell.
Mitre.
THEY LAUGH
Achtung. March!
"LAND OF HOPE AND GLORY" PLAYS
I'm sorry, madam, but you can't go in.
I must. It's my husband. Please.
Excuse me.
What's happened to the iron gate, Mother?
It went for salvage two years ago.
I'll miss the squeaking of that old gate.
Have there been any other changes?
No. I kept your room exactly as it was
the day you went off to France.
Same old smell.
Like soap and furniture polish.
You come in here for a minute and I'll get you something to eat.
David.
Elspeth.
That last letter.
Your mother showed me.
Telling the truth about your eyes.
So that was the reason.
The reason for what?
For breaking our engagement.
But you can't go on being engaged
when you're not in love any longer.
You can't go on breaking a person's heart
to satisfy your own stupid pride.
I'm not prepared to discuss the matter.
Neither am I. David...
Why did you have to make me so dreadfully unhappy?
Caroline!
But...but what are you...
There were some things I left behind.
Caretaker let me in.
I had no idea.
I'll go now.
Caroline.
Yes, Stephen?
Are you all right?
Why are you crying?
Because I'm a fool.
Are you unhappy with Robert?
I'm not with Robert.
Oh, Stephen.
Why did you have to believe that letter?
It wasn't true? It wasn't true?!
No. Not then.
Go on.
When I got your letter, it was as if
all I'd ever believed in didn't exist anymore.
I didn't care what happened.
He was in love with you?
- Yes.
- And you?
No.
Let me go now. Please.
Listen, Caroline.
There, everything seemed so... so out of proportion.
I think I was mad for a bit.
You see, I loved you so desperately.
Still do.
- Always shall.
- Stephen...
Thanks, mate.
Thanks.
Well, this is it, Dai.
- Yes.
- How do you feel?
Empty. Empty inside.
Me too, like it wasn't me standing here at all.
Come on, Dai. Let's get weaving.
KNOCKING
Hello, old girl.
Hello, Ted.
Journey all right?
I was seasick.
Stomach always was your weakness.
Suits you.
Oh, Ted.
There, there.
I can't leave Dai out in the cold like that.
- Oh, Dai.
- Hello, Flo.
Oh, it's lovely to see you. Come on in.
- Where is she?
- In here.
- Hello, Gwyneth.
- Hello.
- Do you know who I am?
- Yes. You're my daddy, aren't you?
That's it. Look.
I made this in the prison camp for you.
- Can she shut her eyes?
- No, she can't.
- My doll can.
- She's lovely.
So that's settled.
Captain Hasek reports to duty to Czech headquarters.
There was something I wanted to ask, sir.
- About Mrs Mitchell.
- Oh, yes. Very awkward, of course.
Don't worry, Captain Hasek. We've got that matter in hand.
I wanted to suggest, sir, as it's my responsibility,
that if the notification of her husband's death
could be delayed until I've seen Mrs Mitchell myself.
She'll have to be told through the usual channels.
- Yes, sir, but in a case like this...
- War Office will look after it.
Of course, if you'd like to see her off your own bat, there's nothing to stop you.
I see. Thank you, sir.
Looks like rain.
My dear. It's no good going on hoping.
You must face up to it.
That he won't come back?
That he won't come back.
Grandpa. It's starting to rain.
Come help me put the chairs in the summer house.
Oh, come on.
DOORBELL RINGS
Oh...
I'm sorry. I was expecting someone else.
Mrs Mitchell, I came to see you.
I have some news for you, of your husband.
Oh.
Come in, please.
What?
Your husband is dead.
Dead?
He was killed four years ago
in the fighting at Saint-Ardennie.
I heard from him. From the prison camp.
Your husband was never in that prison camp.
He was never a prisoner of war.
But...the letters...
I wrote those letters.
- You?
- Yes.
But I...
I took these from your husband's body.
I took his name, his uniform, his identity.
For four years, I've been Geoffrey Mitchell.
But why?
To save my life. The Germans were after me.
- The letters?
- Later in the camp, I had to write.
They suspected me.
If I hadn't answered your letters, they'd have been on to me.
You had to answer my letters.
I understand that. You...
You even had to go on writing.
I understand that, too.
Why did you have to write the way you did?
I believed every word you said.
At first, I had to make you tell me
as much as possible about yourself.
I was fighting for my life.
And then...
..I got your other letters.
Photos of the children.
Glimpses of things lost to me forever and...
It was as if you were offering me a new world.
It was easy out there to delude oneself.
And I believed a wonderful thing had happened.
My husband had left me.
And those letters made me believe he was mine again,
that everything would be as I'd hoped it would be.
I planned for the day he'd come home again...
..for a new life together.
What a fool I was.
You were still in love with him?
How I can tell now?
I know there's no excuse for what I did, but...
Will you go now, please?
You must believe that I meant what I wrote.
Your letters came to be my life.
You see, I fell in love with you.
It was a dream then. Now it's reality.
SHE SOBS
'I allowed myself to dream
'that these letters of ours could come to life.
'That I could see with my own eyes your home,
'the children, yourself.'
Celia, you're wanted on the telephone.
Who is it?
Captain Hasek.
INAUDIBLE OVER MUSIC