[Surf Crashing]
[Seagulls Squawking]
- [Man Shouting In German]
- [Crowd Cheering]
[Man] The army has recruited the Spanish
colonial army of Morocco.
[Crowd Shouting In Foreign Language]
[Man] This is an announcement
from your government.
There has been a military uprising.
- [Man Speaking Foreign Language]
- [Airplane Engines Roaring]
[Man #1]
One, two. One, two. One, two.
[Man #2]
Surrender.
- [Man #3] Ready.
- Surrender.
[Man #3]
Aim. Firel
- [Gunshot]
- [Airplane Engine Roaring]
[Church Bells Tolling]
- [Birds Chirping]
- [Horn Honking]
[Man Narrating]
I was a war baby.
But luckily for me, I haven't had to fight...
in any of the 165 wars
that have occurred in my lifetime.
My father wasn't so lucky.
When he was a young man...
everyone in Spain had
to take sides and take up arms.
The decision may have taken a second...
but the consequences
lasted the rest of his life.
He never talked about the war...
until I was asked to write a book
about a dead priest-
Josemaría Escrivá.
And then he began to talk and talk and talk.
And that's how I went looking for a saint
and found my father instead.
I think it was Oscar Wilde who wrote...
"Every saint has a past...
and every sinner has a future. "
Josemaría!
It's the Father. Quick!
Quick! Get the doctor!
[Wind Howling]
[Man]
In June of 1976...
the nun was at the point of death...
diagnosed with a multiple
calcific lipomatosis tumor, causing pain...
attaining a mass the size of an orange
on the left shoulder.
Cured in a sudden and lasting way...
after the Servant of God,
Josemaría Escrivá...
had been invoked.
[Phone Ringing]
- [Ringing]
- [Machine Clicks, Beeps]
[Man]
You have reached Judge Manolo Torres.
- Leave a message.
- [Beeps]
Dad? It's- It's me, Robert.
Your son.
I'm in Rome.
I'm doing a book on Josemaría Escrivá.
I'm- I'm coming to Madrid, Dad...
and, you know, I-I want
to talk to you about him.
Are you there?
Please, Dad, pick up the phone.
Okay. Well, I'll call you when I arrive.
[Machine Clicks]
And why this interest in Escrivá?
The uproar in the press about his possible
canonization turned my publisher on.
You know, and curiously, he-
he came from the same town as my father.
Ah, yes, of course.
How is the judge, Roberto?
To be honest, l-
[Clears Throat]
We haven't spoken in...
eight years.
So I moved to London permanently,
and since then-
Well, he's not very forgiving,
my father.
Eight years, huh?
- Children?
- No.
I don't quite see myself as a father.
[Chuckles]
Your father is a product of difficult times.
You should try to understand him.
Well, I do, Monsignor. I do.
God bless you in your quest.
- And give my regards to, uh-
- To Leila.
Leila.
- Good-bye.
- [Robert] Are you sure?
- Yes.
That's Josemaría Escrivá in the middle.
And that's me on the right.
And on the left, your father.
Here's another one. At the seminary.
- [Phone Rings]
- [Line Clicks]
[Manolo]
Hello.
Dad. I'm in Madrid.
Been a long time.
Listen. I'm close to the apartment,
and I wanted to come see you.
Why would you write a book about him?
That's what I wanted to talk to you about.
Leave it alone, Roberto.
Well, I found out that you were
in the seminary with him...
and you never told me
that you wanted to be a priest.
- Don't you think that's weird?
- Yes, I thought so too.
That's why I left after a year, Roberto.
Why? Was it because of the civil war?
- [Gasps]
- [Line Clicks]
[Dial Tone]
[Woman]
Hello. London University.
Dr. Leila Azoulay, please.
Which department?
Mathematical Physics.
Good timing.
I was just about to call you.
How's Spain?
I love Spain.
How's your father?
Tell me.
He doesn't want me to do
this Josemaría Escrivá thing.
At least you two spoke. That's progress, no?
He knows something about Josemaría, damn it.
I know he does. Why can't he just tell me?
I could wrangle the weekend away.
Want me to come out?
[Hinges Squeak]
[Woman Screams]
[Grunting]
[Sighs, Panting]
Gun.
No!
Damn it.
[Groans]
[Groaning]
[Keys Jingling]
[Lock Clicks]
[Clears Throat]
I was nine
when Josemaría's path crossed mine.
A long time ago.
Roberto, you've often told me
that I was a terrible father.
What I've never told you
is that I agree with you.
- Manolo! Manolo!
- There's so much I haven't
told you that you need to know.
- So if you want to hear about the past...
- Manolo!
- I'll tell you.
- But I warn you, there be dragons.
- Manolo! Manolo!
Are you okay? Manolo!
- Manolo!
- [Shouts]
[Gasps]
You got me.
- I got you, Josemaría.
- I was a little terror like most boys.
- I'm gonna get you.
- Josemaría was no saint either.
There was one day he almost killed me.
[Horse Whinnying]
[Woman Shrieks]
Good driving, boy. Come on!
[Yelling]
[Woman Shrieking]
[Chattering]
Feels like a Taurus, Manolo.
Faster!
[Screams]
Stop!
- Manolo, are you all right?
- Are you mad?
Josemaría, I'll speak to your father.
He should give you a beating.
I hate this backwater.
I've half a mind to sell up
and go back to Madrid, I promise.
- Can I drive again, Papa?
- No, Manolo. Enough.
[Children Chattering, Laughing]
[Barking]
[Woman]
Here is the first one.
See?
There are many kinds of dragons
you will have to face.
She scares me.
Don't be scared, Manolo.
How many dragons are there, Abileyza?
Many, Josemaría.
But what matters is how you face them,
as you shall see.
[Manolo Narrating]
Josemaría's nanny talked about dragons...
as if they really existed.
A quarter of a century passed
before I realized she was right.
But things happened in Josemaría's life...
that meant he understood this before I did.
[Woman Sobbing]
Why?
No!
[Sobbing Continues]
My baby! Why?
[Manolo Narrating]
Josemaría lost three sisters.
I lost a baby brother.
In those days, death was part of life.
[Josemaría]
Mama?
Do you hate God now?
No, dearest.
I... love him very much.
Will you hate him when he takes me away?
Come here.
I'm sorry about your sister.
[Manolo Narrating]
Josemaría's father owned a chocolate factory.
The manager was a strange, old guy-
Honorio.
We know we like what's here.
We know that we want what's here.
But what is here exactly?
Just sit this on your tongue...
for five seconds.
Hmm? Now, chew...
three times.
Manolo, you taste what?
Almond.
Almond?
Cinnamon.
Cinnamon?
Don't scoff.
Yes. Cinnamon.
All right, off you go.
Josemaría, you stay here.
I scolded Manolo for mocking
what he can't experience...
not because he couldn't experience it.
Ah, now, look at this.
Ugly, isn't it?
Just a poor, ordinary little bean.
Yet, patience...
skill, hard work and love...
can unleash the divine flavors
hidden within.
There.
Do you understand the lesson?
But not everyone has a taste
for the divine, you know.
And why is that, I wonder?
Manolo!
Manolo! Wait for me!
Stop! Manolo!
[Manolo Narrating]
My favorite trick in those days...
was stealing Josemaría's dad's chocolates.
But then his dad went bankrupt
and lost the chocolate factory.
And I wasn't allowed to play
with Josemaría anymore.
My dad thought poverty was contagious.
- He said that Josemaría wasn't one of us.
- [Father] One!
- [Groans]
- Two!
- And my dad could be quite persuasive.
- Three!
[Groans]
My dad had more money...
more cars, more houses.
But Josemaría had more dad.
A seed of envy began to grow in me.
In a child's heart, many seeds are planted.
You never quite know what will grow.
Hmm. I'm sure he didn't see us.
[Door Squeaks]
[Wind Howling]
[Manolo Narrating]
Around that time, Josemaría changed.
I'll tell you the story as he told it to me.
One cold winter night...
Josemaría saw footprints
in the snow outside his house.
He followed them.
And then he saw someone.
And he felt that God was calling him.
It wasn't unusual in those days...
for a young man to want to become a priest.
Like it or not, most young men were celibate.
At least as a priest...
you got paid for it.
The priesthood was a career option.
But for Josemaría, it was a sacred calling.
[Church Bells Tolling]
[Women Chattering]
- [Woman #1] You are incorrigible.
- [Woman #2 Chuckles]
Do you know what you're taking on, Son?
Yes, Papa.
No one to love.
Human love, I mean.
No family of your own.
- No sons.
- I know, papi.
And... is this the wisest time
to become a priest?
Probably not.
Is your father still selling
underpants, Josemaría?
[Josemaría]
Backstabber.
Hey, careerist.
- [Man] Fight! Fight!
- [Manolo] You vain little pig!
[Men Chanting]
Fight! Fight!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight! Fight!
[Whistle Blows]
What lesson do you draw from this?
[Clears Throat]
To control my temper.
Bravo.
Torres, what did you call Seminarian Escrivá?
[Clears Throat]
A vain little... pig.
And you- what did you call Torres?
A backstabbing careerist.
Sorry, Monsignor. I can't stand his type.
That sums him up, eh?
What, his father is rich, so he thinks
he can act like a pain in the ass?
That's not the summing up
I had in mind, Escrivá.
Yet, isn't someone else his Father?
And yours?
Remember, the withholding of forgiveness...
is the one thing, as our Lord made clear...
that will not be forgiven.
So...
do you think that two hotheads,
a hypocrite and a loser...
can be good priests?
Well, I think it's possible.
I really do.
[Manolo Narrating]
Well, he was wrong about me.
[Crowd Yelling]
[Shouting, Indistinct]
No, no, no, no! Get away!
- [Whistle Blows]
- Your job is to clear this scum away...
- and let my factory get back to work.
- What can we do?
That's your job! Scum!
- Go!
- But they're just trying
to feed their families, Papa.
- What?
- The workers.
Scum!
Manolo, when push comes to shove...
a man has only one duty...
and that is to choose the winning side.
Eh?
- Come on.
- [Whistle Blows]
[Man On P.A. Speaking Spanish]
- Hi.
- Good to see you.
- You too.
- [Horn Honking]
- Nice car.
[Leila]
Where did you get all this?
They're my dad's files from the '50s.
There's more at the hotel.
- He actually sent this stuff to you?
- Yeah.
You are making progress.
What's the reason for the change?
I don't know.
I'm almost scared to find out.
"Foundation for the Sick."
God, such a different world.
[Manolo Narrating] Josemaría wrote to me
once a year until he died.
I never wrote back,
but he kept writing anyway.
In his letters he told me
the turns his life was taking.
Honorio.
[Honorio Gasping]
Josemaría.
Oh, look at you.
Give me your hand.
How's my old employer?
Papa died four years ago, Honorio.
Ah.
I said my first Mass for him.
Do you- you remember...
[Labored Breathing]
The chocolate bean?
Of course.
It was a great lesson.
[Laughing, Coughing]
[Gasping]
I'm sorry. That won't work.
Why not?
Because...
I'm Jewish.
You know, the love of my life is Jewish.
Once I thought of conversion...
but I couldn't dishonor my father.
Honoring our parents is the sweetest precept
of all, Honorio, and very dear to God.
- But Jesus Christ-
- Then he won't turn his back on me...
when I stand before him, will he?
What I know for sure is that...
he loves you very much.
Thank you.
I was afraid of dying here alone.
[Breathing Heavily]
Please pray with me, Father.
- [Saying Prayer In Hebrew]
- And you shall love the Lord your God...
with all your heart...
and with all your mind...
and with all your soul.
Our Father...
who art in heaven...
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done on earth...
as it is in heaven.
Good night, Father.
- [Josemaría] Lord, open my eyes.
- [Scribbling]
I am such a blind donkey.
For so long I have felt you
guiding me, but to what?
[Scribbling Continues]
Do you have a purpose
for your donkey, Lord...
but I'm too blind to see it?
You were there tonight, Lord.
I felt you there.
Please be with me now.
Please show me.
[Honorio's Voice]
Ah, now, look at this.
Just a poor, ordinary little bean.
Patience, skill...
hard work and love...
can unleash the divine flavors hidden within.
Do you understand the lesson?
[Chuckling]
[Squeaking]
Yes.
Yes, I see.
Everyone and everything.
Everyone and everything...
for your glory.
Your arms open to all.
One by one.
- Thank you, Lord.
- [Birds Chirping]
So this group of red-blooded
young men are prepared...
to offer themselves completely to God...
in, uh, apostolic work, including celibacy?
Yes, Vicar.
That was the choice I gave them
and one they accepted.
- Really?
- Yes.
[Birds Chirping, Tweeting]
How many?
Uh...
three.
Three.
[Laughs]
[Vicar's Voice] My worry
is that this calling may be delusional.
[Chattering]
[Man]
And this work is to include women?
Yes, Your Excellency.
They will live separately,
but our work will include them...
and will also be open to married people.
[Sighs]
Living in the same institution?
It's not an institution or a movement.
It's just a family of individuals.
And no, married couples will live at home.
[Sighs]
It all seems rather...
Protestant-
that God is to be found in the...
well, vanities of daily life.
Hmm?
Outside holy orders.
No vows. Hmm?
No... habits.
Well, Jesus spent most
of his life working in a shop...
in Nazareth.
God's world is so full of, uh-
[Church Bells Tolling]
[People Chattering In Distance]
God's world is so full of goodness.
If we do them for love,
each daily task can give him glory.
Small but regular acts of love
between husbands and wives...
between friends, between strangers...
each revealing the beauty of his creation.
And you want to open
a new residence in Valencia, huh?
Yes. And one day in New York, Paris...
London and-and... Tokyo.
[Laughs]
It's a long way to Tokyo.
And, uh...
no money yet to speak of.
Well, I can't provide any.
No, I didn't come to ask for that.
I ask merely for your permission-
for me and for the work.
And you shall have them.
Father Escrivá...
I offer you a job as my secretary.
In time this will lead to a career...
that might grant you the influence
that you would need...
to realize this- this dream of yours.
So, what do you say?
I said no, thank you.
Santi.
Now, it won't be easy, I know.
But I'll always see that there's a roof
over your heads and food on the table.
No? Huh?
- Josemaría-
- Actually...
I have an idea.
[Children]
Pecunia in arboribus non crescit.
Crescit. Good. Okay. Agustin.
Pec- Pec-
- Pecunia.
- I can't do it, sir.
- [Other Children Laugh]
- Yes, you can. Shh, shh. Yes, you can.
You will learn, and I will learn to teach it.
[Coughing]
Oh, no. Damn it!
Stay here.
- [Water Running]
- [Man Coughs]
[Groans]
I'm sorry, Father.
Sorry. But I can't-
The smell. I can't.
- [Laughing]
- [Coughing]
[Coughing Continues]
How's your Latin?
Go.
[Man] No.
Go on. Go.
- Go, go, go. Go.
- [Laughing]
- [Dog Barking]
- [Crowd Chattering]
- [Horn Honking]
- [Manolo] Union scum.
Drive through them!
Don't. Thugs.
How can you do this?
You know my father's ill.
Then God is just.
- [Yelling]
- [Whistle Blows]
Damn unions.
I've always said they're going to kill him.
[Woman]
It's a stroke. The doctor just left.
[Manolo]
No. No.
Papa.
[Wheezing]
[Nurse]
He can't speak.
What? What did the doctor say?
That it's God's will.
Get out of here.
Manolo, please.
Get out!
[Wheezing]
Papa.
Papa?
## [Piano]
Thank you.
Good afternoon, brother.
Brother?
Uh, Josemaría.
I know who you are, Josemaría.
[Clears Throat]
I heard your sad news, Manolo.
You have been in my prayers.
Thank you.
But I don't need your brand of sympathy-
however sincere.
Manolo,
whatever struggles you are experiencing-
- Struggles?
- Well, whatever doubts you may be having.
Doubts. Struggles.
Josemaría, I blundered into the seminary
in deference to my mother.
I left because I wasn't priest material.
As you know.
Well, maybe not, but it doesn't mean
you're not saint material.
[Chuckles]
You know...
my recurring nightmare
is that I was partly to blame for you leaving.
No, Josemaría.
Unlike you,
I chose to live in the real world.
But I appreciate your concern.
It's not concern, Manolo.
It's love.
Our Lord said love,
and love is what he meant.
And it's what we owe each other. No?
Josemaría, the truth is...
we are born alone and we die alone.
All we have in between
is a battle I intend to win.
The rest is, frankly, sentimental drivel.
- ## [Resumes]
- Well, I will leave you.
Call on me.
I'll come, I promise.
Josemaría. You don't give up, do you?
It may help you to find some meaning
for your suffering, Manolo.
Suffering has no meaning. It's meaningless.
If you can show me otherwise,
I'll kiss your ass.
That's my promise.
I know what it is to be angry at life.
Please be careful
where that leads you, Manolo.
Sheep.
[Manolo Narrating] Around the time
that Josemaría got a call from God...
I also got a call-
from an old friend of my father's.
Ah, Torres.
- Good morning.
## [Soldiers Singing In Spanish]
- Well?
- A spy?
Yes. You.
But I expected something more.
With the king gone,
Spain has lost its center of gravity.
Which we will now re-create,
by force if needs be.
[Man #2]
And other means.
But our government's elected. It's popular.
Its time is over.
[Man #1]
The government is a rotten biscuit.
- Tap it and see the maggots emerge.
- Maggots?
Socialists who want a socialist state.
Stalinists who want a Stalinist state.
Anarchists who want no state at all.
Manolo, we want to create a new Spain.
- [Man #1] A united Spain.
- Cleansed with blood if necessary.
[Man #1]
Resurrected, great and as it once was-
- ordered, vigorous.
- [Man #2] And admired.
- [Pounding On Table]
- [Speaking German]
## [Singing In Spanish]
[Manolo Narrating]
They called us fascists.
- We called them communists.
- ## [March]
Really, the world was much
more complicated than that.
But many preferred to see it
in those simple terms.
Three years later,
half a million people were dead-
most of them civilians.
But even in times like these...
some people are more interested
in hats and shoes.
[Mother]
I thought you were going to buy new shoes.
Uh, yes, I was, but, uh,
something else came up.
- What was that?
- No. L- I met an old lady who-
- Who needed a hat.
- [Man #2] And some breakfast?
- [Man #1] Yes, and some lunch.
- Thank you.
[Chuckling]
Sit down, please, Pedro, Isidoro.
Well, uh-
- So?
- [Clears Throat]
This group that keeps you from your homes-
what is it called?
We don't have a name, Mama.
We just refer to it as God's work.
Latin would sound better.
Uh, Opus Dei.
##[Radio... Guitar]
[Volume Increases]
##[Folk Chorus Singing In Spanish]
Well, your donkey may lack funds...
but the work has found its name.
[Chuckling]
What's next?
##[Chorus Singing In Spanish]
[Chattering, Cheering]
Vamos.
Está bien.
[Manolo Narrating]
A communist strike killed my father.
Now it was my turn to strike.
##[Continues]
- [Man Grunting]
- Get out of the car!
- Come here, scum!
- [Man Shouts]
- Put the hood on him!
- Please! No!
[Muffled Shouting]
Yeah, we'll show you how just God is.
- In the boss's car.
- [Muffled Screaming]
Let's go!
[Car Doors Open, Close]
[Whimpering]
Where's your gun?
This is not a game.
He killed your father.
Ah, damn it.
The bastard's shitting his pants.
- [Whimpering]
- Do it.
[Muffled Screaming]
Do it, damn it.
[Engine Starts]
Pedro.
- [Laughs] You're crazy.
- No, I'm not.
You're crazy.
He'll hate the whole idea.
Well, let's ask him.
Ask me?
This. We're gonna put them up
all over Madrid.
Look.
[Pedro]
Not me, Father. Not me.
- A crusade?
- Yes, Father.
Using the cross to incite hatred and anger-
that's Christian?
Well, maybe not.
But, Father, the government
is openly attacking the church.
No, it isn't.
It's trying to modernize Spain.
Come on, Pedro.
If we don't do something,
we are just cowards.
- Or worse- traitors.
- Traitors.
- Traitors?
- Yes, Paco. Traitors.
That's what people are saying.
Standing by while the church gets attacked-
how is that being a good Catholic?
Pedro, is it understandable
to want to protect the church?
Yes, Father, but-
Juan, is it understandable
to want social justice?
Yes, of course.
Good. So the question is,
how do we achieve both?
[Mother]
By feeding the hungry.
And lunch is ready, so sit down now.
So we just let the matter drop?
No.
Look, I'm not going
to tell you what to think.
God gave each of you a brain
and reason and a conscience.
Why? So that you can
come to conclusions on your own...
and take personal responsibility for them.
But before rushing to act-
before trying to change the world-
first think about changing yourselves.
We're building something vital here together.
Now- especially now-
we have to be sowers of peace and joy.
And lunch, Mama.
- Father!
- [Loud Clatter]
They've started killing priests.
- What?
- It's in the newspaper.
[Paco]
Oh, my God.
- Where?
- Here in Madrid.
Let me see.
So, what do we do now, Father?
Exactly what I just said, Juan.
Please.
Bless us, O Lord, and these thy gifts...
which we are about to receive...
from your bounty, through Christ our Lord.
- Amen.
- [Others] Amen.
[Crowd Shouting]
[Shouting, Cheering]
[Bell Clanging]
[Man]
Oh, what have we here?
Found a cockroach.
Hey, watch where you're going.
How about we squash it, eh?
- [Muttering]
- Let's squash him.
[Man]
Well, well, well.
- Priest.
- What have we got here?
- A little priest?
- Oh, yeah.
- Whoa!
- Look there.
- I'm sorry.
- What's he carrying?
So, what have we got there? Huh?
- Come on. Show us.
- No, no. Please. Please.
Give me the packet,
or I stick you with this.
[Woman]
Stab the parasite.
I'm not a parasite.
I have to work for a living,
just like all of you.
Work for a living?
You know what working for a living is?
That's enough!
- That's enough!
- [Shouting, Muttering]
Please! Get on the next one.
- Relax.
- [All Muttering]
- Relax, old man.
- Please.
See you later, priest.
- I'm on your side.
- Fascist.
- [Muttering, Laughing]
- Come on.
- We'll get you next time.
- Yeah.
[Whistle Blows]
They've got a thing
against enemies of their class.
- Can't say I blame them.
- No. I know.
All part of creating
this new, more civilized Spain.
Exactly.
And how will uncivilized behavior
accomplish that?
Can't make an omelet without breaking eggs.
No. Life is not an omelet.
And people are not eggs.
Okay. Hey, if I was you...
I'd stop wandering about
in that costume of yours.
It won't protect you anymore.
I don't wear this for protection.
You got balls for a bourgeois ass.
[Boy]
One, two. One, two.
Thank you, Father.
One, two. Halt.
[Cheering, Singing]
[Manolo Narrating]
From their palaces, the bishops said...
"The meek shall inherit the earth."
Ready!
Aim! Fire!
- [Lmitating Gunshots]
- [Groans]
- [Man] Hey!
- [Children Laughing]
But the meek were tired of waiting.
- [Groans]
- [Children Laughing]
They took the bishops and their palaces.
He was lucky it was only a rock.
Hello?
Juan? Paco?
Happy birthday!
[All Exclaiming, Laughing]
It's not my birthday.
Please. Come on.
Josemaría...
as your brother, I have been chosen...
to ask you to celebrate
our second year together...
by removing your shoes.
- [All Laughing]
- Yes, Father!
- Take them off.
- Take off your shoes.
- Shoes off. Come on, Father.
- No.
- Yes.
- The shoes.
- Take them off.
[All Chuckling]
- Behold a simple shoe.
- [All Murmur]
But is it what it seems?
- Yes.
No. It is, in fact, a hole.
[All Laughing]
A hole masquerading as a shoe.
Oh!
And a hole surrounded by leather.
[Laughing Continues]
Shh! Shh!
But also a testament
to 20 kilometers a day...
seven days a week...
rain and shine.
- Yes!
- Thank you.
And in pity for this innocent shoe...
we have also pooled together for-
- Ta-da!
- [All Cheering]
- [Man] What nice shoes.
- Try them on.
- [Gunshot]
- [Pedro] Get down! Get down!
[Mother]
Santiago, get down!
- Santi!
- God!
[Gunshots]
Get down!
[Gunshots Continue Outside]
[Male Announcer]
This is an announcement
from your government.
There has been a military uprising.
The army has recruited
the Spanish colonial army of Morocco.
All able-bodied Spaniards
who love their country-
[Clock Ticking]
[Manolo Narrating]
It's remarkably easy to join a war.
[Shouting, Cheering]
I wormed my way into a communist brigade.
- ## [Singing In Spanish]
- So far, I was enjoying being a spy.
There's something inspiring
about the common purpose...
even when it's not yours.
I can't describe that ecstasy
of belonging to a crowd-
even when it's the enemy.
There's no better feeling.
Well, apart from one.
Cat got your tongue, comrade?
## [Singing Continues]
[Crowd Applauding, Cheering]
[Microphone Feedback]
[Man]
So many young people-
what do you know of suffering and death?
How they will taunt you- "Is it worth it?"
They will ask again and again,
"Is it worth it?"
And what will fill your hearts
with the answer "Yes"? Yes!
- Hatred of oppression? Of tyranny?
- [Crowd] Yes!
- Hatred of those who treat us like animals-
- [Crowd Cheering]
Denying our hopes and stifling our lives?
Yes!
But more.
It will be faith-
faith that a new world will be
born from the blood of the old.
[Cheering]
And comradeship, my brothers and sisters.
And courage-
courage to burst from our cages...
and set ourselves free to live noble...
as the eagle hovering
above his mountain peak.
- Or die in the attempt!
- [Cheering]
##[Orchestra On P.A.]
- ##[Chorus Singing..."The Internationale"]
- Thanks.
- Name and country.
- Régis. France.
- Jan. South Africa.
- Name and country.
- Petofi, lldiko. Hungary, sir.
There are no "sirs" in the Iron Brigade,
lldiko.
Peasants, factory workers...
some like me- escaped convicts.
We are what we are, but we are all equal.
But still fighting to be free-
as we all wish to be!
[Cheering]
Lldiko Petofi.
Yes, sir.
- Oriol.
- Yes, Oriol.
"Yes, Oriol."
- Jealous?
- No.
What is your name?
Manolo.
[Man On P.A.]
Viva la República!
[All]
Vival [Cheering]
[Man Groaning]
[Whistle Blows]
Go, go, go!
[Man Shouts]
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Come on!
[Man Shouts]
Take cover! Move!
[All Shouting]
Fire! Fire! Fire!
[Groans]
Lldi- Ildi- Ildiko!
[Whimpering]
Stop. Go back. Face them.
Thank the bastards for testing your bravery.
Go!
Go! Go. Go.
- Torres.
- Yeah.
Look after her.
[Man]
Forward!
Oh, God. I'm such a coward.
Me too.
I don't feel right about this.
You read the newspapers.
They don't exactly like priests out there,
Father.
Then don't call me Father
when I am dressed like this.
Call me Mariano.
- [Doorbell Buzzing]
- That's Vargas.
Come on, Father. I mean, Mariano.
[Isidoro]
Come on. The car is here.
Father, they'll be safe. Don't worry.