We are here.
Cup: (Over radio)
At 8,000 feet.
This is it, boys.
Phil: (Over radio)
You got it, Zamp?
Louie: Roger.
You hit this one,
drinks are on me.
Louie: I ain't going
to a bar with you, handsome.
You confuse all the broads.
- (Chuckles)
- (Wolf-whistles)
Get your cameras, boys.
I'm gonna light it up like Christmas.
(Over radio)
Pilot to bombardier, your ship.
Bombardier to pilot.
Roger.
Bombardier to crew,
bomb bay doors open.
Harry: Bay doors open!
Damn flak.
- (Explosion)
- Argh!
Oh, boy!
Come on.
Come on, Zamp.
Louie: There you are.
Louie: Bombs away.
Bombardier to pilot, your ship.
Phil: (Over radio)
Roger.
Okay.
Here we go.
(Chuckling)
Yeah, just like Christmas.
(Mechanical whirring)
Louie: Bomb bay doors are stuck.
Uh-oh.
- Louie: Zero, inbound, 10 o'clock, level.
- Phil: All right.
Cup: (Over radio)
Here they come, boys.
Call them out.
(Rapid gunfire)
(Aircraft approaching)
Phil: (Over radio)
Gotta get those doors closed, zamp.
Louie: Roger.
Get them, get them, get them, Mitchell.
Harry: (Over radio)
Coming in high at nine o'clock.
(Gunfire)
Glassman: Coming level to three.
Clarence: Take 'em out, Mitchell.
(Bullets ricocheting)
(Man shouting indistinctly)
(Men shouting indistinctly)
(Strains)
Mac: Low, he's going low.
(Aircraft approaching)
Douglas: Brooks, he's going down.
He's coming to your side.
Louie: Glassman!
Glassman!
Okay, okay.
(Screaming)
I know, I know. I know.
Let me take a look at you.
I know, buddy, I know.
Just be brave now, all right?
You're still good looking.
You're still very handsome.
- (Groans)
- You make me sick!
Yeah!
- (Groans)
- I know.
You got it, buddy.
You got it. I'm right here.
- I want to go home.
- You will, Harry.
You will. All right?
You think about home. Okay?
(Men shouting indistinctly)
Oh, boy.
Lambert: Louie?
(Panting)
Louie: Lambert.
Here, take this. All right? Take this.
It's okay. Take this.
Louie: Pillsbury?
(Rapid gunfire)
Cup: (Over radio)
Nice work, boys.
Everything's shot
up back there, Phil.
We got no hydraulics but
we're still flying.
We got no flaps, Phil.
So basically we got no brakes.
How far to base?
I don't know. Five hours.
If we make it that far.
The runway is over 6,000 feet,
but we're gonna need at least 10
if we got no brakes.
Priest: God created two great lights.
The greater light
to rule over the day,
and the lesser light
to rule over the night.
Now these things,
light and dark, day and night,
are separated from each other.
God created each in its place.
He did not create a
battle between them.
He said, "I have created
both of these things."
You must live through the night.
Don't battle with it.
(Speaking in Italian)
Priest: For God said,
"the night also is mine."
He sent his son,
Jesus, not to do battle.
Not to wage war
on the sins of man,
but to forgive them.
Forgive the sin.
Smile on the sinner.
Accept the darkness.
Live through the night.
Love thine enemy.
(Dog barking)
Officer Collier: Zamperini!
Hey!
Boy 1: Is that garlic I smell?
What are you doing, wop?
Boy 1: Hey, why don't you go back to Italy?
You and your greasy wop family.
(Boy 1 chuckles)
- Boy 3: Get him up.
- Boy 1: Get up.
Hey! Hey!
Boy 2: Get off him!
(Grunts)
Boy 1: Stay down. Dumb dago.
- Boy 1: Hey! Hey!
- Get him off me!
Jesus.
Officer Collier: Hey!
- Boy 2: Shit.
- Boy 1: Go, go, go.
Only reason you're not in reform school now
is because of the respect
we have for your parents.
Everybody in town
wants you put away.
(Doorbell rings)
Sorry, Louise. He was fighting again.
(Speaking in Italian)
And, uh, we found this.
He painted the bottle.
It's liquor.
(Speaking in Italian)
(Anthony scolding in Italian)
- (Smacking)
- (Groans)
(Louise praying in Italian)
Woman: What do you think?
He's kinda cute, right?
(Women speaking indistinctly)
Man: Come on, Jimmy, pick it up!
Go, go, go!
Girl: Come on, Pete!
Go! Go! Go!
Man: Come on, pass him!
Man: Is someone down there?
Man: Who's down there?
(Breathing heavily)
Louie: This is so dumb.
Since when were you so smart?
Come on. Faster.
Why?
No one's chasing me.
I'm chasing you.
(Panting)
I can't do this, Pete.
I'm not like you.
I'm nothing.
Just let me be nothing.
What are you talking about?
I can't make a track team.
- I don't even know why you want me to.
- Yes, you can.
If you can take it, you can make it.
What?
All right.
You train and you fight
way harder than
those other guys.
And you win.
You get out from under them.
Or you keep going
the way you're going
and you end up as
a bum in the streets.
(Sighs) You can do this, Lou.
Just gotta believe you can.
I don't believe.
(Sighs)
I do.
Come on.
(Commanding in Italian)
(Gunshot fires)
Pete: Come on!
You dumb dago!
(Panting)
(Spectators cheering)
Come on, Louie!
Male radio announcer:
Boy, oh, boy, can that guy fly.
They're calling him
the torrance tornado.
(Cheering and applauding)
(Cheering)
(Bell ringing)
This kid zamperini runs like his
feet never touch the ground.
(All panting)
(Groaning)
(Bell ringing)
Come on!
Keep going!
(Cheering in Italian)
Come on, Louie!
Come on, come on, come on!
Male radio announcer:
The torrance tornado smoked the mile
in 4 minutes, 21.3 seconds.
Zamperini is now officially the fastest
high school runner
in American history.
Folks, this kid is on his
way to the Olympics!
Why would I come?
You're not going to win.
Sure.
I know that. It's all right.
Four years' time, next Olympics,
that's when I show them.
This is just the tryouts for me.
- Tokyo.
Smart kid.
- Take care of yourself, all right?
- Mmm-hmm.
Go have a little fun, too, huh?
Say hi to those pretty
German broads for me.
You know it.
Come here.
Thanks, Pete.
For everything.
(Train whistle blowing)
Go on.
(Sighs)
(Crowd cheering)
Pete: Louie.
A moment of pain is
worth a lifetime of glory.
You remember that.
Gear is down.
All right, here we go.
Still coming in pretty hot. 110.
Almost.
Still too fast.
Come on.
(Brakes screeching)
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
(Panting)
Okay.
Flat tire.
(Laughs)
(All laughing and
cheering ecstatically)
Gunner: Thank you, God.
Now you're praying?
I was busy before.
My mother does that sometimes.
Yeah. A lot of people do this.
He say anything back?
- Yeah.
- What?
He says my bombardier is a dope.
(Chuckles)
- Really?
- (Laughs)
All right, buddy.
Now!
(Horn honking)
Man: Come on, Louie!
Keep on, buddy.
Keep pushing.
- (Horn honking)
- Whoa!
Yeah?
Huh?
Oh, boy! (Laughs)
4:12. Getting close.
I hope you're not that fast in the sack.
Oh, boy.
(Distant car horn blaring)
- Wrap it up, speedy.
- Huh?
- We got a mission.
Not a combat mission. Rescue.
B-24 en route to
kanton never made it
so looks like those boys ditched.
A lot of ocean.
Yeah.
And, uh, they got
us some new crew.
We get a new plane?
(Chuckling)
This is just like sitting in a living
room trying to fly the house.
They've been taking parts
off this for other planes.
We're lucky it's still got an engine.
Lieutenant says it's airworthy.
It's been certified, he says.
By Helen Keller.
Lot of ocean.
Phil: (Over radio) Yeah.
- Mitchell.
- Yeah.
You're up.
So a duck walks into a bar, right?
Or, waddles, if you will.
- So, he walks into the bar...
- Uh-huh.
He says to the bartender,
"can I have a crème de menthe?"
(Rumbling)
Hang on, there.
Number one is out.
Other engines are
burning more fuel.
Phil: Gotta feather it.
Hey, uh...
- (Mouthing) What's his name?
- I don't know.
Cup: Engineer?
Can you come up to the cockpit
and feather the engine?
- What's going on, guys?
- Co-pilot to radio. Send to base.
- Which one?
- Phil: The left.
We need more on the right.
Cup: That's all we got on the right.
We need more on the right!
That's all we got on the right.
Cup: Damn it!
Phil: Left engines are both gone.
That's everything on the right, Phil.
Okay.
(Engine sputtering)
Hey, Phil?
Phil: Yeah?
Is this a...
Prepare to crash.
Mac: Waist gunner!
Get the rations box.
Cup: Tie the guns down.
Who's on the raft?
Mac: Glassman!
Cup: Send mayday.
Man: Is everyone in position?
- Cup: Anyone on the rafts?
- Yeah.
I got it!
Phil: Mayday, mayday, mayday!
This isgreen hornet.
We are going down.
Mayday, mayday, mayday!
Okay.
Phil: Everybody brace.
Brace!
(Spectators cheering wildly)
(Slow drumroll playing)
(Wild cheering continues)
(Ceremonial song playing)
Olympics radio announcer:
In an astounding performance,
negro American
Jesse Owens from Ohio state
has won four gold medals
in the 100 meter, the 200 meter
the long jump and
the 400 meter relay.
Next up, the 5,000 meter
with America's record-breaking
don lash leading the American team.
Along with newcomer Louie zamperini.
(All cheering excitedly)
Fertig!
(Gunshot fires)
And already,
three sections of runners have formed
with America's don lash and the Finnish
salminen and höckert ahead of the pack.
The Finns always the favorite
in this long-haul event.
In the second group
is America's Louie zamperini.
The Finns, höckert,
lehtinen and salminen have set the pace
and they are not letting up.
And zamperini is fading, too,
dropping further back.
(Speaking in Italian)
And into the 8th lap
it's the Finns still in the lead,
with salminen in first place.
Come on, Louie.
Pete: Come on, Louie.
(Bell ringing)
Olympics radio announcer:
And we start the last lap.
The Finns seem to be in control.
It doesn't look like don lash is gonna
bring home the medal for the usa.
There seems to be
some movement back in the pack.
Yes, that's zamperini
overtaking Norway's Rolf Hansen.
(Indistinct)
He seems to have
some gas in reserve.
- He really is making up some time.
- (Laughs)
Höckert and lehtinen
will be one and two.
But look at that zamperini!
He's got don lash in his sights.
The great don lash is not gonna be
the first American, folks.
It's high school kid zamperini
pushing past the record-breakers
on this field!
I have not seen that!
(Spectators cheering wildly)
That final lap, folks,
the record for that was 69.2 seconds.
Zamperini just did it in 56 seconds.
That record is going to hold for a while,
let me tell you.
(Gasping)
(Grunting)
(Metal creaks)
(Air hissing)
(Gasping)
All right, Phil.
Okay, buddy.
On three.
Two. Three.
(All grunting)
Okay.
All right, here we go.
Glassman didn't make it.
Cup didn't make it.
Don't think about it, Mac.
We're gonna die.
No, we're not, Mac.
They don't know where we are.
They'll find us.
They'll never see us.
Tell him to shut up.
- Shut up, Mac.
- We're gonna die out here.
Come on, Mac, shut up.
Hey, Mac, chocolate.
One square at night,
one square in the morning.
All right?
Mac?
Two or three sips a day, yeah?
We gotta make it last.
Phil: Zamp?
- Zamp?
- Yeah, yeah?
Yeah, Phil?
I'm glad it's you.
Yeah, I'm glad it's me, too.
(Thudding)
Mac: What was that?
(Thudding continues)
(Gasps)
(Aircraft hovering)
Mac! Mac! Mac, come on!
Get the dye, Mac. Get the dye.
- Hey!
(Flare gun fires)
Hey!
Louie: Hey!
Mac: Hey!
Down here!
Hey!
Turn around!
Mac: You son of a bitch!
Louie: What did you do, Mac?
Huh?
- It doesn't matter.
- It doesn't matter?
It doesn't matter?
It doesn't matter.
(Exhales deeply)
(Sobbing)
(Squawking)
Louie: Jesus!
(Screeching)
Louie: Get it, Mac! Get it.
(Groans)
(Louie and Mac groaning)
I don't think I can do it.
We gotta try.
(All coughing)
We had to try.
You know what?
Maybe the fish
won't be so picky.
Phil: Oh, boy.
Louie: Yeah?
Phil: I got one. Yeah.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- (Laughing)
Attaboy, Phil!
(Phil laughing)
Here, here, here.
Damn it.
Phil: Okay.
Come here, Mac.
Come on.
Okay.
Buon appetito.
Mmm.
Good?
(Moans)
This is how the Japanese eat fish.
Raw.
If you ask me, it's not
food until you cook it.
Little lemon,
little garlic...
When we get home, come around my house.
Mama will cook for ya.
You remember that
story inlife magazine
about Eddie rickenbacker?
Him and his crew ran out
of fuel over the pacific.
They were drifting
in rafts for 24 days.
Twenty-four days.
They made it, right?
Yeah.
Most of them lost their minds.
But they made it.
We gotta keep talking.
Gotta keep our minds sharp.
Hey, I'll tell you what
else you're gonna love.
Mama's gnocchi.
- Italians.
- Louie: Nobody... (Laughs)
Nobody a-make-a gnocchi like her.
(Chuckles)
Louie: So light.
Like clouds.
First, she makes the dough
out of very fine flour.
So fine, it's like talcum powder.
Then she uses lots of eggs, like, maybe 12.
(Imitating breaking eggs)
And then she
beats them up, Mac.
(Louie imitates whirring)
Beats them up.
And she drizzles them over.
Mmm.
(Sighs)
Phil: (Singing) Thou me on
the night is dark
and I am far from home
lead thou me on
Louie: Do you think
God made the stars, Phil?
Phil: Yes, I do.
Louie: So you think there's
some kind of a grand plan?
Why did we live
and the others didn't?
Why are we here now?
Phil: Here's the plan.
You go on living the best you can.
You try to have
some fun along the way.
Then one day it's over.
You'll wake up
and there's an angel
sitting at the edge of your bed.
Angel says,
"okay,
"you can ask me
all those dumb questions now
"because I got all the answers."
That's what you believe?
Yeah.
That's what I believe.
(Panting)
Phil: Our father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
If you get me through this,
if you answer my prayers
I swear I'll dedicate
my whole life to you.
I'll do whatever you want.
Please.
(Thunder rumbling)
(Rain pattering)
Mac.
Here we go.
- Here we go. Here we go. Here we go.
- All right, all right.
(Straining)
You got it?
(Panting)
Jeez.
(Moans)
Just a scratch.
How is it?
Stinks.
That's the bandage,
not you.
We beat rickenbacker's record
four days ago.
You're keeping count?
Yeah.
(Aircraft whirring overhead)
(Weakly) Hey. Hey.
Hey.
(Winces)
(Flare gun fires)
(Weakly) Hey!
Phil: Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
Hey!
(Voice breaking) Hey!
(Rapid gunshots)
(Gasps)
- Get out, boys. Get out!
- Phil: I can't!
Louie: Come on!
(Muffled gunfire)
(Gasping)
Louie: Mac?
Mac: Still here.
Still here.
Phil?
Phil: If the japs are this bad,
we might even win this damn war.
(Sighs heavily)
Shit.
Phil.
Here.
(Air hissing)
(Grunting)
Mac.
Did you see that surprise Mac attack?
Came down on that thing
like a goddamn dive bomber.
Damn sharks were scared shit.
(Chuckles)
He saved your skinny ass.
1937. Baseball mvp.
Kid from Detroit.
Gehringer.
Hey, Mac, get in the game.
Louie: Mac?
- Mac?
- Still here.
Still here.
What are you gonna make
for breakfast, zamp?
It's your call.
Your mother's gnocchi.
Gnocchi for breakfast?
Why not?
Am I gonna die?
Maybe, Mac.
You think tonight?
Maybe.
Yes, sir.
I think tonight.
So you got your dough...
And you roll it out.
Just rolling it out.
Good, no lumps.
(Voice fades)
Phil?
(Weakly) Hmm?
I got good news...
And bad news.
(Guard shouting in Japanese)
Phil?
Phil: Zamp?
You okay?
Phil: Land feels funny.
Funny.
Yeah.
(Door opens)
(Guard shouting in Japanese)
(Phil grunting violently)
(Groaning continues)
(Shouting) Stop!
Stop it.
Please, stop it.
(Shouting in Japanese)
(Speaking in Japanese)
Colonel would like to know
disposition of troops in Hawaii.
I don't know.
Japanese translator: Speak up!
I wouldn't know.
I haven't been there in...
(Colonel continues
speaking in Japanese)
Japanese translator: Is this you?
Japanese translator:
You are famous olympic athlete.
(Colonel speaking in Japanese)
Colonel would like to know
location of radar in e-class, b-24.
We used the old one. D-class.
- You bombardier?
- Yes.
(Translating to Japanese)
What happened to the marines
from makin island?
How you work
the norden bombsight?
You just twist two knobs.
What happened to the marines?
Draw norden bombsight.
They were beheaded.
(Commanding in Japanese)
(Ordering in Japanese)
(Louie whispering)
Fuck!
(Screaming)
(Shouting in Japanese)
(Speaking in Japanese)
Take off clothes.
Japanese translator: Kneel down.
Kneel down?
Japanese translator: Kneel down!
(Shouting in Japanese)
(Sobbing)
(Men commanding in Japanese)
No, no! No, no!
Phil?
- Phil?
- Zamp!
Zamp!
Louie: This is Tokyo, right?
Must be.
I was supposed to race here
for the Olympics...
Before they got canceled.
Tinker: Yeah?
Louie: I always wanted to come to Tokyo.
Careful what you wish for, fella.
(Shouting in Japanese)
Soldier. Soldier.
Officer.
Soldier.
Good evening, old prisoners.
Welcome, new hands.
This is omori detention camp.
I am corporal watanabe.
You are enemies of Japan.
You will be treated accordingly.
Look at me.
Look me in the eye.
(Grunts)
(Breathing heavily)
Look at me!
(Groans)
Don't look at me.
New prisoners, you are not dismissed.
You will stand a quarantine.
We cannot have
disease in the barracks.
(Commanding in Japanese)
- Evening, chaps.
- Evening, sir.
Tom Miller, your barrack commander.
Let's get you settled
into your bunks, shall we?
You're up top.
305,
you're here next
to sleeping beauty.
Take a pew.
307, you're in here.
You are?
Frank tinker.
Tinker, you're up top.
I see you met the bird.
Why do you call him "the bird"?
Because he listens.
And if he heard the names
we'd like to call him, he'd kill us.
Miller: Apparently he grew up wealthy.
Wanted to be an officer.
Expected to be, too.
And was denied,
which obviously hasn't
gone down too well.
Fitzgerald: Of course,
none of this explains his erratic behavior.
Commander Fitzgerald.
Zamperini, sir.
They were looking for answers.
Miller: Didn't get any though, did they?
Not one bit.
You should get some shut-eye.
Yes, sir.
(Officer commanding in Japanese)
Fitzgerald: Infirmary, turning right!
Dismissed!
Officers, turning right!
(Officer keeping count in Japanese)
(All keeping count in Japanese)
There is much
talent in omori camp.
We have an opera singer.
Who is the opera singer?
We have a chef from Sydney, Australia.
And we have an olympic athlete.
Who is the olympic athlete?
(Gun fires)
(Cheering in Japanese)
Don't get up.
(Panting)
You fail.
You are nothing.
(Cane strikes)
(Louie groans)
(Man whistling)
Sir?
He's tracing so we can return it
before the japs find out.
He's got most of
the war mapped out.
(Whispers)
We've invaded the Marshall Islands.
The us have invaded
the Marshall Islands.
Allies are gaining ground.
(Conversing in Japanese)
You know, I gotta say...
- Please don't.
- For a bunch of guys who don't eat anything
we sure do shit a lot.
(Both chuckling)
Oh, yeah.
I think that one is mine.
(Flies buzzing)
(Officers conversing in Japanese)
(Spits)
(Shouting in Japanese)
(Speaks in Japanese)
You like saipan?
- (Grunts)
- (Groans)
(Whimpering)
I'm gonna kill him.
Then they shoot you.
I don't give a damn.
Let them shoot me.
That's not how we beat them.
We beat them by making it
to the end of the war alive.
That's how we do it.
That's our revenge.
If I can take it,
I can make it.
Precisely.
My brother Pete
used to say that.
He used to think
that I could do anything.
He used to think that
I was better than I am.
Who says you're not?
(Distant explosions)
We're getting closer.
(Speaking in Japanese)
(Grunts)
(Whimpers)
(Breathing heavily)
Why do you make me hit you?
Hmm?
Radio Tokyo man 1:You are dead.
In America, they say zamperini dead.
They tell your family you died in war.
Nbc radio tell America
famous olympic runner zamperini is dead.
Radio Tokyo man 2:
You want to tell family you're not dead?
Watanabe: These gentlemen,
they're from radio Tokyo.
Radio Tokyo man 2:
We have program go all over world.
It is namepostman calls.
"Hello, mother.
"Your son is calling you.
"Mother, I love you.
"I'm alive and well."
(Speaks in Japanese)
(Indistinct conversations)
I'm only saying my own words.
Of course.
(Elevator bell dings)
Hello, America.
(Speaking in Japanese)
This isthe postman calls.
Today the postman calls
for Mrs. Louise zamperini
of torrance, California.
Louie zamperini is not
missing, and not dead
as erroneously announced
by your government.
He is safe and sound with us.
So keep listening, Mrs. zamperini...
And don't mention it.
The pleasure is all ours.
Hello, mother and father,
sisters and friends.
This is your Louie talking.
And the first time in two years
that you will have heard my voice.
I am uninjured
and in good health.
I am now interned in
a Tokyo prisoner of war camp
being treated as well as can be
expected under wartime conditions.
I hope Pete is still able to pay you
his weekly visits from San Diego.
Dad...
Keep my guns in good condition
so we can go
hunting when I get home.
(Sobbing)
Get some good rabbits
for mom's gnocchi sauce.
I wish you all a merry Christmas
and a happy new year.
(Voice breaks)
Your loving son, Louie.
(Indistinct chatter)
You were good.
Very good.
You can speak on radio again.
I can't say this.
Why not?
Because it's not true.
What it says about America,
I can't say that.
They say that.
American like you.
They live here.
Very comfortable.
Good food.
Radio Tokyo man 2: They have lovely food.
You want to go back to camp?
You make broadcast.
(Sighs)
You are like me.
We are both strong.
I saw it in your eyes...
The first day.
I thought...
This man will be my friend.
But...
Enemy of Japan.
You do not listen.
You do not do
what is asked of you.
It is necessary to have respect.
No respect...
No order.
This man must be taught respect.
All other prisoners will
teach him this lesson.
Each prisoner...
Will punch this man in his face.
(Shouting in Japanese)
Sir...
We cannot do that.
(Watanabe commands in Japanese)
(Phil groans)
(Watanabe continues
shouting in Japanese)
Louie: Do it.
Do it, sir. Come on.
Just get it over with.
Punch him in the face.
Come on.
Watanabe: Punch him!
Next!
Louie: Go on.
Come on, come on.
Next!
Okay. Come on, come on, sir.
Come on.
- Hit hard!
- Come on!
Hit me!
Next!
Come on, tink, hit me good. Go on.
(Louie groans)
Watanabe: Next!
Louie: Come on.
(Louie continues groaning)
Watanabe: Next!
Watanabe: Hit hard!
(Speaking in Japanese)
Watanabe: Harder!
Watanabe: Next!
Next!
(Speaking in Japanese)
(Guard keeping count in Japanese)
(All keeping count in Japanese)
(Men laughing)
(Hooting and whistling)
Tinker: (As stepsister 1) Cinderella!
Miller: (As stepsister 2) Cinderella!
Ah, cinderella!
- Where is that naughty little maggot?
- (Laughter continues)
Have you seen her, fella?
Ah, there you are,
you lazy little girl.
How am I supposed to get ready for the ball
with you sitting there doing nothing?
Miller: (As stepsister 2)
That's as useful to us
as our morning dance routines.
(Laughter)
Tinker: (As stepsister 1) Fix my dress
so I can catch the eye
of the dreamy prince hillenbrand.
You couldn't catch the eye of a prince
if it fell in your lap.
Come, cinders, fix my hair.
Tinker: (As stepsister 1) Fix my dress!
Miller: (As stepsister 2) Fix my hair!
Tinker: (As stepsister 1) Dress!
Miller: (As stepsister 2) Hair, hair, hair!
Tinker: (As stepsister 1)
Are you speaking kraut now?
Fitzgerald: (As cinderella)
Enough! Enough!
You guys make me do
all these stupid, impossible things
with no food and no rest!
You lock me up
in a rabbit hutch.
I've had enough!
(Whispering) I have good news.
I have had a promotion.
That's the good news.
The bad news?
I say goodbye to my friends.
I leave omori tomorrow.
Blackie: (As old lady)
Nothing in this life is hopeless, cinders.
If you keep your
head and your heart
you can do anything!
(Men jeering and hooting)
Fear not, dear child...
I am your fairy godmother.
You may congratulate me.
Mmm.
(Men applauding)
And there he goes.
Just like that.
Miller: I have got...
Four kings.
And there you go.
The baron's been beaten, tinker.
- Tinker: Oh, yeah?
- Sugar for us tonight.
(Indistinct chattering continues)
(Exhales)
(Alarm sirens blaring)
(Men shouting)
(Distant explosions)
(Gunfire)
(Shouting)
Fitzgerald: Got it, Miller?
Miller: Send another bucket!
We're helping the japs now?
Might as well let it burn.
Pass it down!
There you go.
(Explosions continue)
Tinker: B-29s, boys!
Won't be long now.
I wouldn't get too excited.
If the allies win,
the japs issue kill-all orders.
I overheard them.
We win, we're dead.
Tinker: Well, what are we
supposed to be praying for?
(Shrill whistle)
Down! Get down!
(Gasps)
Grab your gear.
They're moving us out.
- To where?
- I don't know.
Some new camp.
Tokyo ritz.
Some place the
allies can't find us.
(Guard ordering in Japanese)
(Sobbing)
(Guards ordering in Japanese)
(Guard continues
ordering in Japanese)
(Door slams shut)
(Guard ordering in Japanese)
This is naoetsu prison camp.
I am sergeant watanabe,
your commanding officer.
You are enemies of Japan.
You will be treated...
Accordingly.
You will help the Japanese
by working on the coal barges.
Anyone who will not work...
Will be executed.
Why don't you
look me in the eye?
Clift: You boys can sleep here.
You two over there.
This is the end, mates.
No one knows you're here.
It's best if you
just resign to your fate.
(Groans)
(Screaming)
(Ordering in Japanese)
(Commanding in Japanese)
Your president Roosevelt
is dead.
(Sobbing)
(Officers ordering in Japanese)
(Groaning)
(Ordering in Japanese)
Louie?
Are you all right?
(Officer commanding in Japanese)
(Panting)
(Officer shouting in Japanese)
(Speaking in Japanese)
Pick up!
Watanabe: Lift it.
Lift it!
Over your head.
If he drops it
shoot him.
(Breath wavering)
(Officers ordering in Japanese)
Come on, Louie.
Come on, boy.
(Grunts)
(Yelling)
(Laughing)
(Yells)
(Breathing heavily)
Don't look at me.
(Voice breaks) Don't look at me.
(Watanabe speaking in Japanese)
Don't look at me!
(Breathing heavily)
(Commanding in Japanese)
(Shouting in Japanese)
(Guard commanding in Japanese)
(Officer speaking in Japanese)
Fitzgerald: (Translating)
"Prisoners of naoetsu...
"The war has come
to a point of cessation.
(Officer continues in Japanese)
Fitzgerald: "Today...
"In the spirit of the new future
of our great nations,
"we invite all prisoners
to bathe in the hokura river."
(Officer commanding in Japanese)
This is it.
We're dead.
(Guard ordering in Japanese)
(Guard continues ordering)
(Distant engine droning)
Tinker: That's our boys!
That's our boys!
Miller: They've seen us!
It's over!
The war is over!
(All cheering)
(Talking indistinctly)
(People cheering)
Pete: Louie!
You made it.
Oh, God, look at you.
(Both laughing)
Oh, mama.
(People cheering and applauding)
(Cheering continues)