The promises of the Fuhrer about
peace and prosperity are destroyed,
and left nothing but destruction.
The nastiness Hitler brought with his S.S.
are a shame to the German army.
In the officers choir
there is widespread disgust,
about the atrocities of the Nazis.
The murder of civilians,
The torture and starvation
of prisoners.
The mass execution of Jews.
My duty as an officer,
is no longer to save my country,
but to save human lives.
I cannot find one general in a position
to confront Hitler with the courage to do it.
Von Stauffenberg, sir,
the General will be here in 4 hours.
Thank you.
I'll need to see him when he arrives.
I found myself surrounded by men
unwilling -- or unable -- to face the truth:
Hiltler is not only the arch-enemy
of the whole world,
but the arch-enemy of Germany.
A change must be made.
Colonel, my orders are to advance
to Sidi Mansour and hold it -- that what we'll do.
The British are moving-up from the south,
Patton is closing-in on the coast,
you know we should've left two days ago.
- No, Colonel, we keep fighting.
Until the final victory.
North Africa is lost, and you're gonna need those men
a year from now to defend Berlin.
We can save Germany,
or the Fuhrer, not both.
It's just that sort of talk,
that had you sent here, Colonel.
What I said was much worse.
General,
I'm just trying to get these men
out of here alive.
What would you have me doing?
You tell Command we're low on water.
We have to reroute [...] with the 21st Panzer.
At least then we'll have a chance.
And records will show we didn't have
enough water to reach Sidi Mansour?
I can guarantee it.
See it as done.
General.
Sit.
Hitler's leaving!
- Now?  - Yes! The fuse...
Colonel Brandt.
On regards to Colonel Stieff.
Thank you.
So we do not get thirsty on the way.
This is Tresckow.
He has landed.
This is General Tresckow.
Connect me with Operations, Colonel Brandt.
Colonel, Tresckow.
I'm glad you arrived safely.
I'm hate to trouble you, but it seems
you have the wrong bottles for Colonel Stieff.
You do still have the package?
Oh, no, as it happens I've been called
to Berlin unexpectedly.
I can be at your office first-thing
tomorrow's morning to pick it up.
Sorry for the inconvenience, Colonel.
Yes, thank you.
Do you think he knows?
There is only one way to find out.
We've been discovered.
- What makes you think that?
Oster has been arrested.
The Gestapo came for him last night.
The Gestapo could've arrested
him for anything.
What do you think went wrong?
- We don't know.
The fuse, temperature, altitude, who knows.
The damn thing didn't go off.
General Tresckow to see
Colonel Brandt.
The Colonel is expecting you, sir.
At ease.
You'll forgive me, General. This round-up is
having me writing reports all day.
Round-up?
Dissidents.
Another plot against the Fuhrer.
Who are these people?
You'd be surprised.
Is this what you've come for?
Perhaps we should open it.
I beg your pardon?
Well, you have come a long way,
you must be thirsty.
You know, I wonder how the Fuhrer,
who does not partaked,
would feel about a soldier
who did so on duty.
Colonel Brandt.
I took you for an honest soldier, General.
And I, you.
We are still in business.
Find a replacement for Oster.
There's no one we can trust,
not in Berlin.
Then stop looking in Berlin.
Frau von Stauffenberg.
Perhaps, before you go in, we could
have a word together in my office.
I will see my husband now.
His right hand has been
amputated above the wrist.
He's missing the fourth and fifth fingers
on the left hand.
We couldn't save the left eye.
Colonel.
Are you ready, sir?
I'm a soldier, I serve my country.
But this is not my country.
When I was lying there,
bleeding to death, thinking:
If I die now, I leave nothing
to my children, but shame.
I know now there's only
one way to serve Germany.
And doing so,
I'll be a traitor.
I accept that.
Just tell me,
can these men see it through?
We need to reorganize,
reconsider our strategy,
recruit new men.
That's why we want you.
You understand what will happen
to my wife and children
if these men can't see it through?
Come and hear what
they have to say.
You know where to find us.
Enough. I'm not gonna listen to another word
of this. You had your chance, you failed.
Your so-called simple solution
didn't work.
Our only option now is
to confront Hilter openly.
It's a military operation.
It's not a military operation!
it's a political organization,
and one that's giving it's military-arm
too much control.
In any military exercise, you have
to expect a certain measure of deviation.
A "measure"?
What about total, complete, utter failure?
Gentlemen, I think it's time
we face the fact, that...
The allies are coming, sooner or later.
I say, we sit back,
and let them wipe-out the Nazis.
And ask every living soul in Europe
to pay the price? Use your head.
Carl, please.
- I'm sorry, Ludwig. I've held my tounge too long.
We must confront Hitler now.
Force him out!
And then what?
I beg your pardon?
When Hilter is gone, then what?
I'm sorry, who is this man?
Colonel Stauffenberg is Oster's replacement.
He's been transferred to my office,
at the War Ministry.
How is your uncle?
- He's well, sir. He sends his regards.
Speaks very highly of you.
- And of you, General.
'Cause on of the things that made Oster
such a great organizer,
was that he kept his opinions
to himself.
I'm simply asking what you intend to do
when Hitler is gone.
You don't really believe you could
just walk into the Reichskanzlerei,
and command the Army to end the war?
Yes, we do.
You're in presence of men who would've
been Hitler's inner circle.
Instead, we refused, Colonel.
The people know we put our principles
above personal gain.
We have the respect of the people...
... and the army.
Then you don't need me.
Gentlemen.
Those men are confusing respect
with popularity.
The Army sworn an oath,
an oath that won't just die with Hitler.
What are you gonna do? How are you gonna deal
with Goebbels, Himmler and the S.S.?
They will wipe you out!
- It doesn't matter!
It only matters that we act, now,
before we lose the war.
Otherwise, this will always
be Hitler's Germany,
And we have to show the world,
that not all of us were like him.
That is not enough for me.
There has to be a chance of success.
Then find a way.
Papa! Papa! Papa is home!
Papa is here!
I thought we agreed I'd come see you
in Bamberg.
The children couldn't wait.
The children?
Valkyrie.
We have already considered Valkyrie,
it isn't suitable.
Not as it's currently written, but the Colonel has
an idea I think we should consider.
Excuse me, what is Valkyrie?
- Operation Valkyrie.
The reserve army has thousands of men,
all over Berlin.
Valkyrie is Hitler's contingency plan to
mobilize those men during a national emergency.
The sole purpose of the order is to protect
Hitler's government if he is cut-off or killed.
And what use is this to us?
Valkyrie is designed to contain
civil unrest.
But what if the S.S. was staging a coup?
State Security is trying to overthrow Hitler,
how would High Command respond?
We would have no choice -
we will declare a military state of emergency.
Exactly - and initiate Valkyrie.
- Hitler's own reserve army using Hitler's own plan.
We will have no choice but
to cease power in Berlin,
to prevent the S.S. take-over.
They'll think they're fighting for Hilter government,
not against it.
While we quietly put
a new government in place.
But only if he's dead.
That's what you're saying, isn't it?
How else you're gonna convince people
the S.S. are trying to seize power?
We have to kill Hitler.
- I'm disappointed in you, Colonel.
I thought a man of your background would
suggest a more honorable approach.
Your plan has a few minor obstacles, Colonel.
Firstly, Valkyrie would've to be rewritten
to exclude the S.S.!
And I'll need your help
to get a copy.
Rewriting an order is one thing.
Distributing it is another.
In this case, we'd be willfully circulating
written evidence of high treason.
Evidence requiring Hitler's signature.
Well, we can all draw straws
for the job.
And what about Fromm?
- Fromm? Who is Fromm?
He's the commander of the reserve army.
I can put the reserve troops on alert,
but only Fromm can initiate Valkyrie.
Can you get to him?
We're running out of time.
Can you get to Fromm?
He is a careerist pig.
But one who has gone as far as he can go
in Hitler's army.
There's no secret
he's not happy about it.
Offer him a key position
in the new regime.
Make him see the light.
Reich War Ministry - Berlin
Colonel Stauffenberg for General Fromm.
Colonel Stauffenberg, sir. Welcome back to the
War Ministry. It's an honor, sir.
I'd send you to the front, whether I didn't think
you'd surrender just to be Montgomery's whore!
The General will see you now.
What is it you want?
I wanted to introduce our new man,
Colonel Stauffenberg.
Ah! From Africa!
I'd offer you my hand,
but I might not get it back.
I'd say the General has lost more
important things this morning.
It's about time they put somebody
with balls into this office.
Please sit, Colonel.
And you, Olbricht, if you must.
They tell me you're critical of the war, Colonel,
not that you don't seem to have good reasons.
I am critical of indecision, General.
In the field?
- In Berlin.
So that's why you're here, I take it...
to make decisions.
- I've already made my decision.
I'm here to help others make theirs.
They say when there's no clear option,
the best thing is to do nothing.
We're at war, we must act.
Sometimes rushingly.
And what rush action
did you have in mind, Colonel?
That would be a decision for
the supreme military commander, sir.
A supreme commander?
Second only to the Chancellor.
If I was that man...
... this war would be going quite differently.
Well, we were thinking the same thing.
I don't need to remind you
that we've all sworn an oath to the Fuhrer.
Having said that, I'm going to forget
this conversation ever took place.
In the strict understanding that such talk
never occurs again under this roof.
Is that clear? - Yes, sir.
You can tell your friends, Colonel,
that I always come down on the right side.
And as long as the Fuhrer is alive,
you know what side that is.
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler.
You realize how close
I am to Hitler?
With one word, I can
make you disappear.
My associates don't know we've been talking,
if that's what you're afraid of.
When the S.S. catch you, they will
pull you apart, like warm bread.
It'll be a crime just to
have known you then.
I warn you, don't try
to contact me again.
Maybe, if you [...] when I first approached you,
you might have been keeping your oath.
Now you're just as guilty as me.
- And you think that makes me a sympathizer?
Give a man a choice of betraying
his fellow officer or his Fuhrer,
and you think his actions
will show you his heart?
It is not that simple.
- Yes. Yes it is.
For the last time,
don't push me to make a decision.
I don't have a choice.
It's clear now.
Without you, there is no hope of success.
You nothing but rats,
jumping from a sinking ship!
What makes you think
you'll be any different?
you're stronger than the people?
The Reich? The very momentum of history?
- This is going to happen. Action is inevitable,
as are the consequences.
When they'll come for me, I'll do everything
I can to hide what you knew and when you knew it.
But don't delude yourself.
You were invloved in a crime against
your country long before you met me.
And there may still be time
to redeem yourself.
Only God can judge us now.
Hitler had Operation Valkyrie designed to
completely secure his government in 6 hours.
I'm rewriting the order so we can seize control
of the government in 3.
As written, your order spreads reserve troops
across all of Germany's 19 military districts,
including occupied cities like
Paris, Vienna and Prague.
This is a waste of resources,
since all these districts
follow orders from Berlin without question.
If you take Berlin, you take Germany.
I'm rewriting Valkyrie to direct the majority of our
strongest units to focus entirely on Berlin.
We'll surround the government quarter,
occupy all S.S. and police barracks.
Once we have control of the government,
we'll shut-down all concentration camps.
Any officers who resist will be arrested,
or shot.
I've been transferred to the front.
It doesn't matter.
You knew these orders better than anyone.
That's why I'm putting you in-charge
of the military wing of the operation.
Beck agrees.
- Why not Olbricht?
No, it's your plan.
It's you.
One more thing: you need to be absolutely certain
no conflicting orders get out after the flash.
It is not enough to kill Hitler.
You need to isolate his chain of command
and cut them off from the outside world immediately.
Yes, I've already considered that, I...
think I have just the man who can help.
- Who is he?
Perhaps it's better I don't say.
You know, God promised to Abraham
he would not destroy Sodom
if he could find just
10 righteous men.
I have a feeling that for Germany,
it may come down to one.
Let us begin.
The Fuhrer, Adolf Hitler,
is dead.
Heil Hiltler, General.
Would you excuse us, please?
You play the part of bureaucrat beautifully.
- It's the only time I get to relax.
You've been promoted Chief of Staff
for the reserve army.
Excuse me?
- Congratulations.
I am busy with other things.
Unfortunately, your nocturnal activities don't
count as service to the Reich.
I'll refuse the promotion.
- You'll do no such thing.
Tresckow may have left you incharge of the operation,
but in this world I still outrank you.
You will accept the promotion.
You'll have real access to Hitler,
his advisers, his schedule.
We need this.
I've looked through your changes to Valkyrie.
I approve.
I'll need you to get Hitler to sign it.
Now, there's a man here,
to interview as your adjutant.
He comes highly recommended.
Close the door.
Be seated.
Do you know how this war
will end, Lieutenant?
The portrait will be un-hung,
and the man will be hung.
I'm engaged in high treason,
with all means available to me.
Can I count you in?
For anything, sir. Anything at all.
Come, children.
Colonel Brandt, operations.
Colonel Stauffenberg, I'd like to review
your presentation to the Fuhrer.
Strictly routine.
Sir, the contents of the Colonel's bag
are for the Fuhrer's eyes only.
I am the Fuhrer's eyes, Lieutenant.
The Colonel is a member of my staff at the
War Ministry. He doesn't answer to you.
They're waiting.
This way.
My Fuhrer, may I present Colonel Stauffenberg,
our new chief of staff for the reserve army.
Heil, My Fuhrer.
[...] an honor it is to meet an officer who has
sacrificed so much for Germany.
And if only more of my men
were like you.
Let this man stand as an example to all of you.
He is the ideal German officer.
My Fuhrer...
Colonel Stauffenberg was asked
to come here today to brief us
on mobilizing troops of the reserve army,
to repel the invasion.
Invasion?
Normandy, my Fuhrer.
Oh, yes.
Normandy.
That will not be necessary.
Reich-Marshall Goering assures me
that everything completely under control.
Thank you Colonel.
My Fuhrer, if I may, I have an amended copy
of Operation Valkyrie for your approval.
You know your Wagner, Colonel.
The Valkyrie, handmaidens of the gods.
Choosing who will live
and who will die.
Sparing the most heroic
from an agonizing death.
One cannot understand National-Socialism,
if one does not understand Wagner.
I am sure, whatever changes
you've made, are for the best.
You're dismissed. Send your men home.
And Fromm...
Have some fresh tea
brought in, will you?
I don't know what you're brewing up,
and I don't want to know,
But when the music stops,
I'd be [...] if Keitel found himself without a chair.
Any problem on Earth
can be solved,
by the careful application
of high explosives.
The trick is not to be around
when they go off.
Two 975 gram packs of plastic,
enough explosive to cripple a panzer.
Your detonators,
your fuses.
British time pencils.
This acid capsule is your trigger.
When you're ready to arm, attach the detonator
to the buttom of the time pencil...
... like so.
Insert the entire device into either end
of the plastic,
crush the acid capsule,
and you're live.
When the acid eats through them while
holding back the firing pin...
Well, you'll want to be very far away.
For you.
- How much time will we have?
Theoretically, there's a 30-minute delay,
but with the kind of heat
you can expect at the Wolves' Lair,
I'd give you 10, 15 minutes tops.
That's hardly precise...
This is state-of-the-art. You can
have small, or precise, not both.
Might this just be a little too small?
No. Hitler's bunker will magnify the blast.
It is constructed of reinforced concrete.
Steel door, no windows.
The air pressure generated by just one
of these explosives in a space like that
will kill everyone instantly.
The second charge will be entirely redundant.
If, by some miracle, Hitler does survive,
what then?
We still initiate Valkyrie.
At that point, there'll be no turning back.
But we'll have an advantage.
We have an inside-man
at the Wolf's Lair.
After the flash, he'll cut off
communication with the outside world.
While Hitler's inner circle
is struggling to regroup
we'll have the momentum we need
to seize control in Berlin.
Himmler is expected to be in the
meeting as well. Don't proceed,
unless you can get them both.
What?
Don't proceed unless you're confident
you can get both Himmler and Hitler.
This is Goerdeler, isn't it?
Yeah, I'll hold off,
if the decision is unanimous,
but I want another man on the committee.
Not a politician.
- Who?
Him.
Him?
Fine. But remember,
this is a military operation.
Nothing ever goes
according to plan.
I'll take the children to Bamberg.
If I fail...
... they'll come for you,
all of you.
I know.
Gentlemen, good morning.
Hitler has scheduled a military briefing
for today, at 1 o'clock.
Stauffenberg will start once once everyone is present.
- They're here.
Before arming the explosives,
Stauffenberg will call for authorization to proceed.
After the flash, his inside man
will sever all communications.
Assuming Fromm refuses to join us,
Olbricht will take command
of the reserve army,
and initiate Valkyrie.
Then you'll notify all district commanders,
that the S.S. is attempting to seize power.
The reserve army will arrest all S.S.,
Gestapo, and Nazi officials.
By then, Stauffenberg would've return to Berlin
and taken command of the reserve army.
Witzleben and I will assume the roles of
Commander of the Armed Forces
and Head of State.
With Berlin secured, Dr. Goerdeler
will address the nation as our new Chancellor.
Then, God willing... we can negotiate
a truce with the Allies,
and save Europe from total destruction.
This will identify you as a member of the operation.
Nobody gets in or out of the perimeter without one.
Gentlemen.
This is the most important day of your lives.
Long live Sacred Germany.
-Captain.
- What is it?
An order from General Olbricht's office.
It's calling the reserve army
for some sort of a stand-by action
in all the military districts,
including Berlin.
Looks like a drill of some kind.
Send it [...].
Sir.
Stand-by action. What the hell for?
- The order doesn't say.
Assemble the men.
This better not be a drill.
Deutschland Guard Battalion - Berlin
The men are assembled
and waiting for the orders.
What do you suppose this
is really all about?
Your man?
He is now.
Colonel.
Attention!
Gentlemen, our first order of business,
General Fromm will present his plans
for the reallocation of troops,
from the reserve army
in the Eastern front.
Fellas, as you know, last night
the Russians launched  a new offensive
against Army Group North Ukraine,
in the South Poland section.
General Harper was brought in to replace Model
and bring a swift end to this confrontation.
Himmler is not here.
... transfer 3 divisions to fortify
General Harper's troops.
Now, these divisions will stick
to a mobile defense plan
rather then holding
any one particular...
Operator.
Direct me to War Ministry,
General Olbricht's office.
One moment, please.
- Himmler's not at the briefing.
I'm ready to arm,
permission to proceed.
Hold [...]
Stauffenberg says Himmler is not at the briefing.
He wants to proceed.
Call Beck.
- Beck.
- Himmler is not at the briefing.
Himmler is not at the briefing.
... ready, diminished reserves.
No.
They say no.
What do you say?
I say do it.
Attention!
Whatever it was, Colonel,
I hope it was important.
Colonel, your bag.
This had been a drill,
you're dismissed!
How dare you put reserve army in stand-by
without my knowledge?
[...] cost me my commission.
And what, in God's name, made you think
you even had the authority?
It was only a drill with an exercise.
- Oh, don't lie, Olbricht! Not to me.
We both know it wasn't a drill.
- General, if I may...
No, you may not, Colonel.
You may not do anything.
Because not only have you proved
to me you can't deliver,
you've painted a target
on my back.
If I so much as sense you're trying
to move the reserve army again,
I will personally
have you both arrested.
Do I make myself abundantly clear?
- Yes, sir.
Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler.
I'll hear you say it, Colonel.
Heil Hitler!
The point of replacing Hitler,
is to negotiate a truce with the Allies.
The Allies, I suspect,
would be more amenable to a truce
if we offer it to them before
they get to fucking Berlin!
There's no point in killing Hitler
unless you kill Himmler too.
Why remove a madman,
just to have a lunatic take his place?
Today's failure had nothing to do
with Himmler, and you know it.
This is a military operation in the hands
of a politician, nothing more.
What are you suggesting?
- I'm not suggesting anything!
I'm stating the facts as I see them!
You don't have the courage to kill Hitler,
so you're making the task impossible.
Nothing seems to stop you and your henchmen
from trying it on your own.
My only regret is that I waited for you
to find your backbone!
I don't think I'm alone when
I say your judgement is in question!
I'd like to call a vote.
- Carl...
I propose that we relieve
Colonel Stauffenberg.
Carl, can I have a word
with you in private?
No, but if you think you have
something to say, say it.
Very well. I've heard from
the chief of police this evening...
... that Himmler has issued
a warrant for your arrest.
You have to leave Germany,
tonight.
When we succeed with
the central solution,
you'll return as Chancellor.
Disappear, Carl.
Avoid contact with anyone.
Good luck, Colonel.
No more indecision. From now on,
Stauffenberg has full discretion.
I can't issue the alert again,
unless we follow through.
I'll do my job.
You just take Berlin.
Hold on, sir. I'm trying to connect you right no.
- Thank you.
Hello.
- Hello? Hello?
[...]
- Hello?
I'm sorry, sir. There's bombing in Ebingen.
We've been disconnected.
Ebingen is a long way from Bamberg.
I'm sure your family is safe.
Thank you.
Welcome, Colonel.
- Do you have a place where I can change, Major?
Please follow me.
At least put the reserve army on stand-by alert.
- Not until I've heard from Stauffenberg,
Not until I'm sure...
- That's not what he...
Noted, Colonel, thank you.
The meeting has been
moved up to 12:30.
Mussolini is arriving
on the afternoon train.
The Fuhrer wants to have lunch with him.
- Yes, sir.
Will Mussolini be joining us
at the briefing, sir?
I only wish he were.
Then some ambitious officer
might take the opportunity
to shoot that dago bastard!
Excuse me, General. I'm expecting
an important call.
Could you please have someone
come and get me?
Even if I'm with the Fuhrer.
Of course, Colonel.
- Thank you, sir.
Colonel.
Major Freyend speaking.
Colonel?
They insist you hurry.
The briefing's about to begin.
- One moment please, Major.
10 minutes: 2 for the walk,
1 for the checkpoint,
... 1 for the bunker,
6 to get out.
Plenty of time.
Excuse me, Colonel.
Sir, the Fuhrer's at the briefing!
The Colonel's changing, Major.
You understand, this can be difficult.
- Of course.
Plenty of time.
Get the car.
Sir?
- I have everything I need. Get the car.
I can manage this.
Where're they going?
- It's too hot.
The briefing has been moved
to the conference hut.
Major, my injury has
left me hard of hearing.
Would you place me as close to
the Fuhrer as possible?
I'll see what I can do.
Not only have they been
advancing from the east,
but they're coming down on the
northern and the southern France as well.
As you can see,
my Fuhrer,
if the enemy continues at this rate, the
situation in the east Prussian sector is critical.
Lack of supplies is continuing
to weaken our main units,
and reserves are severely depleated.
My Fuhrer, you remember
Colonel Stauffenberg?
As you're all aware, in the past 2 days alone,
the 10th Army has given up Ancona,
and the 14th Division
has been pushed out of [...].
Army Group Center has already
lost 28 of their 40 divisions.
That is a total of
almost 350,000 men.
Since the Red Army first attacked,
nearly a month ago,
our troops have already been
pushed back to the Polish border.
Conference hut.
... pounded with the loss of the 4th Army
in Minsk, threatens the entire eastern...
Yes, sir.
... from Army Group North Ukraine,
as well as the Romanian army...
... further losses. Unless we can
quickly dispatch new blocking divisions,
at vital points along the German right, Army Group...
- Colonel, there's a telephone call for you.
... (can be swallowed by the enemy),
in less than a fortnight,
and we run the risk of losing all the ground
we have managed to gain in the last 3 years.
Our spear...
General Fellgiebel, sir. He says it's urgent.
Yes, General. This is Stauffenberg.
Russian air-activity has proven just as
impregnable as their ground force...
My Fuhrer...
... In some areas they outnumber us...
... the Italian front, I further propose...
One thing is certain: the Red Army
will continue an aggressive push west,
even at the expense of...
... In order to rebuild,
at this...
... already southwest of Luneburg,
and closing on Army Group...
It will be a catastrophe...
Get in.
Drive.
I have orders from
the Fuhrer, drive.
Drive, drive!
Back to work!
Give me the War Ministry, General Olbricht.
Olbricht! The call is urgent!
General Olbricht's office.
- They're calling from the Wolf's Lair...
... with an urgent ... General Olbricht...
- ... happened ... the Fuhrer...
Fellgiebel? Fellgiebel!
- Sever all communications!
Sir?
- Just do it!
What did he say?
- I can't be sure...
Well, get him back on the line.
Sir, the bomb did go off,
that much was clear.
Fellgiebel's next step will be
to sever all communications.
Sorry, Colonel, no one gets in or out.
- We have an order from the Fuhrer.
We have to get to the airfield immediately.
Open the gate.
Very sorry, sir, but my orders are...
- I just gave you an order, Sergeant!
Sir. Sir!
Excuse me!
Colonel Stauffenberg
for Field Marshal Keitel.
Colonel Stauffenberg was explicit.
We initiate Valyrie, regardless...
Only Fromm can initiate, you know that.
Then tell him Hitler is dead,
or arrest him, but do it now!
Sir, you have to give the order
to initiate Valkyrie. This is our only...
I'm not doing anything
until I hear from Fellgiebel!
Get him back
on the phone now.
Every second we stand here arguing
is a second lost!
The risk is too great.
What about Stauffenberg?
What about his risk?
He did his part, and now
you're abandoning him!
Field Marshal, sir, Stauffenberg here.
A Sergeant...
Kolbe, sir.
- What? - Kolbe.
Kolbe, won't let me pass the main gate.
Yes, sir, I explained that.
Perhaps you can make
him understand, sir.
Everything's fine now, sir. Thank you.
Open the gate!
At least put the reserve army in alert!
- When Stauffenberg returns.
When he gives me confirmation that Hiltler is dead.
Then we'll proceed.
Where are you going?
- The same place as you are.
Lunch.
Another stand-by alert.
Send it through,
and keep me informed.
Sir,
another stand-by order.
In ancient Greece you
would've been killed for this.
Lucky for you,
we evolved.
Assemble the men.
Quiet, isn't it?
I'll see where our driver is.
This is von Haeften. The Colonel and I are at the airfield,
there's no car, there's no one here...
You mean to tell me the alert
has only just gone out?!
This is Stauffenberg.
Give me General Olbricht.
What's this?
Explain this!
- Someone had to do something, while you were...
We don't know that Hitler is not alive!
- This is about Germany, for God's sake, not you!
General Olbricht's office.
Colonel Stauffenberg. For you, sir.
This is Olbricht. - It's been 3 hours Olbricht.
What, the hell, have you been doing?
We've had no confirmation
that Hitler was dead.
Damn it!
I saw the explosion myself.
We are committed.
- Dear God...
Now where is Fromm?
Is he with us?
No one has spoken to him yet.
You listen to me.
Nevermind Germany. Nevermind Europe.
Your life is at stake now,
and if you want to live to the night,
you'll do exactly as I say.
The second you hang-up the phone,
initiate Valkyrie in Fromm's name.
Give him the choice to join us or place him
under immidiate arrest, do you understand?
Yes. - I'll be in Fromm's office in 15 minutes.
Be there when I arrive.
Call Beck and the others,
tell them it's time.
Put me though to communications.
This is General Olbricht,
calling on behalf of General Fromm,
commander of the reserve army.
The Fuhrer, Adolf Hitler, is dead.
A group of radicals in the S.S. are attempting
to seize control of the government.
Initiate Operation Valkyrie.
You have the orders,
pass them along.
Battalion.
Attention!
Fuhrer...
Our Fuhrer, Adolf Hitler...
is dead.
Who told you
the Fuhrer was dead?
General Fellgiebel,
at the Wolf's Lair.
There's no use calling.
All communication lines are down.
Yes, get me the Wolf's Lair.
- One moment, sir.
Wolf's Lair. - Yes, General Fromm
for Field Marshal Keitel, urgent.
Keitel.
- Yes, I'm sorry to disturb you, sir,
but I wonder if you could tell me what's happening?
Most incredible rumors are circulating in Berlin.
I don't know what you mean...
There's a talk that the Fuhrer
has been assassinated.
Another failed attempt.
The Fuhrer was never in danger.
By the way, where's your man
Stauffenberg?
Stauffenberg? On his way
back to Berlin, I would think.
Let me know when he arrives.
I'd like a word with him.
The Fuhrer's fine.
- That is a lie.
Adolf Hitler's dead,
Operation Valkyrie is in effect.
Only I can initiate Valkyrie.
- You did.
This is treason!
Right now, the reserve army is
assuming control of Berlin.
Are you with us or not?
- Do you realize what you've done?
The Fuhrer is alive!
I delivered the bomb myself.
I saw the blast. he is dead.
Are you with us?
I don't believe this is happening.
This is some kind of...
Are you with us or not?
Colonel, if what you say is true,
you should shoot yourself immediately!
The rest of you are under arrest!
- No, General. You are.
I don't know where you
think this is going.
Get me operations.
This is Colonel Stauffenberg. Seal off
the War Ministry per Operation Valkyrie.
No one gets in or out without autorization
from General Olbricht's office.
General Beck...
You're not wearing your uniform, sir.
They should be see in us
a movement of the people.
Colonel Stauffenberg?
- Yes...
The chief has guaranteed
the full support of the Berlin police.
You will have no interference from my men.
You have my word.
Thank you.
Colonel Stauffenberg, sir.
We are reporting for duty.
Thank you for coming.
Gentlemen,
in 3 hours I want confirmation
that the government quarter's ours,
and S.S. Command has been cleared
of every living soul.
You all know what must to be done.
By night fall I want to know
that Hitler's Germany
has seen his last sunrise.
Yes, sir, all replacments
have been authorized.
In fact, Field Marshal Witzleben
has been appointed
commander in chief
of the armed forces.
That's exactly why
he's been appointed...
If he was a member of the party,
he'd be locked-up as a suspect.
Yes, sir, I understand.
But this is an emergency.
Commanding officer
at the 11th district...
I need a decision, Major.
Tell your men that acts of vengeance
will not be tolerated.
Could I speak with commanding officer in Hanover?
- We represent a different form of government...
I'd be careful who you said that to.
Loyalty to the party isn't what it used to be...
Yes, Paris, France.
Not since they murdered
the Fuhrer...
Thank you...
- You made the right decision.
District 13 is ours.
By order of Field Marshal von Witzleben
you're under arrest for crimes against the state.
This is Stauffenberg,
I'm trying to connect with Major General Todt.
I've already spoken 413 battalion,
you'll have no trouble getting...
Yes, sir,
this is Colonel Stauffenberg...
... The order explaining everything
will be in your hands shortly...
... No, these are you orders...
... Excellent!
My wife is in Bamberg with my children.
Would you please try trace them with the phone?
Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
General Schroedler has issued the Valkyrie orders
and had sealed our headquarters.
Good. Check on the radio stations every 20 minutes,
until we have confirmation they're ours.
With all due respect, sir,
you can't believe everything you hear...
That is S.S. propaganda, he's dead. Only the commander
of the Home Army is authorized to give orders.
General.
Hello, Christian...
Our men in the Transport Office have secured
the railway communications network,
But there are repeater stations, telephones...
- Yes, I give you my word.
... Broadcast outposts... We need more men!
- Give my best to your family.
He's with us.
Mertz, call Potsdam, tell them place
all available units under our control.
You have your men,
now get control on the radio.
We have control on
the government quarter!
We don't have Berlin yet.
What is it now, Sergeant?
- An arrest order, sir.
One from Colonel Stauffenberg
in the War Ministry,
to arrest Reich Minister Goebbels,
The other is from the Wolf's Lair,
to arrest Colonel Stauffenberg...
Send them both through.
Our job is not to interpret the orders.
Our job is to pass them along, regardless.
Yes, but...
That will be all, Sergeant!
... You are all going to pay for this!
New arrest orders, sir.
For Stauffenberg and Goebbels.
Do we arrest them both?
I would hate to find out
I'm being taken advantage of.
Do you really think it's a coup?
Of that I'm sure.
What I can't say, is
which side we are.
Come with me.
District 4: Dresden and Leipzig...
District 12: Wiesbaden...
District 5...
... No trouble bringing reinforcements,
and I rely on you to see it gets started...
I just spoke with Colonel [...],
they've arrested 1200 S.S.
and Gestapo officials in Paris.
Not a single shot fired.
Early reports from Vienna are good.
I'm waiting on a word from Prague...
This is incredible...
I am ready to be connected.
Minister Goebbels?
What can I do for you, Major?
My battalion has a order to block
every government quarter,
and place you under arrest.
Are you a dedicated
National Socialist, Major?
Yes, sir.
Major Remer here...
Hello?
Do you recognize my voice?
Yes, my Fuhrer...
- Then listen to me very carefully.
I want these traitors taken alive.
- Yes, my Fuhrer.
You heard what he said.
The Fuhrer wants the traitors taken alive.
Yes, sir.
It's a coup, alright.
We can't afford to remain neutral
any longer.
You have to make a decision.
When it's over, we better wake-up
on the right side.
Very well...
Send through all communications
from the Wolf's Lair,
stop all communications
from Stauffenberg.
Release these men!
But... they're part of the coup...
I've just been on the phone
with Hiltler itself.
We are the coup, you idiot!
We've been duped!
We've lost contact with District 11.
The switchboard is overloaded.
Give it 10 minutes and try again.
Give me General Bieler, District 11.
... We still need a... I don't want to leave any ...
- Keep trying.
Where is General Fromm?
General Fromm is no longer in command.
I am.
Beck? What are you doing here?
What is going on?
The Fuhrer is dead.
The S.S. were staging a coup,
we've initiated Operation Valkyrie
to crush the uprising
and save Hitler's Germany.
You will present the order
to your troops.
I will do no such thing,
until I speak to General Fromm.
You will follow your orders,
or you're under arrest.
This is treason.
I will take no part.
The Fuhrer is not dead.
The Fuhrer is not dead!
- Stop him!  - The Fuhrer is not dead...
I sworn an oath! This is treason!
You all sworn an oath!
Listen to what I have to say!
You are all making a terrible mistake!
The Fuhrer is not dead!
Please track my wife again...
Bamberg, please...
Get your hands off!
Sir...
"... Over 215 enemy tanks have been annahilated
in the past week alone."
"The Airforce engaged a low-flying offensive
on enemy concentrations..."
Lieutenant! I can't get through
to General Goerlock.
Send a runner down to his office,
bring him here.
Yes, thank you.
Yes, this is Stauffenberg. I was speaking
to the General 5 minutes ago.
He told me he'll return my call...
I trust everything in your district
is under control?
And the General knows I'm waiting?
I'm ordering you to put him
on the phone immediately.
... the army gave their oath to a liar, Hans...
- Hello?
... One who has broken his own oath to
the people a hundred times over...  - Hello?
Hans, listen to me!..
This operation has been terminated!
Stand down!
"Today, an attempt was made
on the Fuhrer's life."
"The Fuhrer himself suffered no major injuries
beyond light burns and bruises."
"He resumed his work immediately."
"Those seriously wounded include General [...],
Colonel Brandt and staff-officer Berger..."
Send the following orders to all
reserve army commanders:
"Broadcast incorrect. The Fuhrer is dead..."
"Operation Valkyrie is
still in effect."
"... Reich Marshal Goering, and has scheduled
to receive Mussolini..."
"... Long live our Fuhrer, Adolf Hitler, whom
the Almighty God has so visibly blessed today."
I saw the blast.
I saw the blast...
"Today, an attempt was made
on the Fuhrer's life."
"The Fuhrer himself suffered no major injuries
beyond light burns and bruises."
I'm sorry...
- "... resumed his work immediately. Those seriously..."
"Stay tuned for the Fuhrer's address
to the German people."
My family?
- Our lines have been cut...
I'm sorry...
Go.
It alright, go...
General, sir, we have to
get you out of here.
Get back.
Stop.
- Stand down!
I said stop!
- I said stand down!
Hold your fire.
Colonel Stauffenberg.
By orders of the Fuhrer,
you're under arrest.
If you have any last messages to your
wives and children, I will hear them now.
Very well.
A court-martial convened my me,
in the Fuhrer absence,
will pronounce the sentence.
Beck, you're under arrest.
Colonel Mertz von Quirnheim,
General Olbricht, Lieutenant Haeften,
and the Colonel, whose name I will not mention,
are condemned to death.
General, my orders are
to take these men alive.
Noted, Major.
I'd like a pistol, please.
for personal reasons.
Get on with it.
- With all due respect, sir...
That will be all, Major!
Killing us won't hide
your involvement.
My involvement? I don't know
what you're talking about.
You knew, and did nothing.
- You're as guilty as any of us.
Spare me, Lieutenant.
No one will be spared.
I thinking of earlier times...
This is an outrage that
has never before been [...] ...
A Field Marshal and a General declare,
that they could do things better
than he, who is the Fuhrer of us all!
You'll protest to having said this?
Yes.
"My fellow Germans:
I speak to you tonight for two reasons."
"First, so that you can hear my voice,
and know that I am unhurt."
"Second, so you may know
the details of a crime"
"without parallel in German history."
"A small clique of ambitious, dishonorable officers
had conspired to eliminate me."
"Expect for a few bruises and burns"
"I was completely untouched."
"I see in this the hand of Providence"
"directing me to complete my work."
Look to me in the eye...
They'll remember you.
Olbricht!
Men, ready!
And we have to show the world,
that not all of us were like him.
Safe! Stand.
Fire! Stand.
Stauffenberg!
The people know we put our principles
above personal gain.
Men, Ready!
Aim!
Safe! Stand.
You may hand us over to the executioner,
but in 3-months time,
the disgusted and [...] people
will bring you to book,
and drag you alive through
the dirt in the streets.
Take him away!
Men, Ready!
Aim!
Long live Sacred Germany!
- Fire!
Stand.
Credit to:
Sync & Sub Jopie123
re-sync to 25fps by:
npdv.indoheroes [at] yahoo.com
Corrections by UV-IL