Whoa! Easy, boy.
Whoa, there. Whoa.
Ah.
Souvenir.
Of what?
Oh, the great Southwest,
the dangerous
Indian territory.
[Chuckles]
Hey, Sarge, ya know,
this is gonna make
somethin" nice to hang
on the wall when I retire,
somethin" I can tell
my grandkids lies about.
That arrow"s
at least a year old.
Rick up a fresh one.
Listen, Sarge, I think
the arrow"s extinct.
Couple of weeks,
you'll be pullin' 'em
out of your back.
I heard that in St. Louis
a thousand miles ago.
By now, I thought we"d be
hackin" our way through
a solid wall of Indian fesh.
Wait until you run into Satanta,
chief of the Kiowas.
You"ll know you met an Indian.
Oh, he"s a tough one, huh?
Got his whole tepee covered
with buck sergeants'chevrons.
The only fella gonna
get those stripes is the fella
I give "em to after I got yours.
[Sergeant Chuckles]
All right, let"s get
movin" back there!
Comanches?
Comanches would have
taken a prisoner.
That"s a Kiowa specialty.
Ricket the horses while
I try to find a shovel.
Great place for souvenirs.
Detail reporting
to Colonel Meade.
Open the gate!
[Man Shouting Orders]
Left to right!
To the left, go!
Forward, go!
Major Howell Brady,
Sergeants Luke Schermerhorn
and Agustus Wilks...
reporting
from St. Louis, sir.
How do you do?
Captain Neil,
Lieutenant Rolier.
Still a sergeant,
eh, Schermerhorn?
I guess soldiers
are like water.
They find their own level.
Rour the sergeants
a bath and a drink:
the drink first.
Come along, Major.
You"re to be quartered here
for six months under
nobody"s orders but your own.
Those are
Gen. Schofield"s words.
I don"t like it, even
from the secretary of war.
That"s natural.
This is good whiskey.
Washington doesn"t have
to send anybody around,
investigating my command.
As far as I know,
they haven"t.
Then what is it?
Major Howell Brady
taking over this fort?
l"ve already
turned down three.
l"ve been in this army
too many years to be fooled.
Things haven"t gone well here,
and they"ve retired
generals for less.
I haven"t heard talk
of retiring you.
Your record shows...
I know. But you"re as good
as your last casualty list.
All right,
l"ll play the game.
Game?
By elimination, you must
be here to fight Indians.
Yeah. That"s about it.
One major and two sergeants
is not what l"d call
a fighting outfit.
Well, it's a start.
What can you do
that I haven"t done?
The Kiowas are having
a field day, but why?
Nobody's stopping them.
They don"t come out
by the hundreds
and thousands anymore.
They raid by 10s and 20s.
They hit and they"re gone.
I know. I saw
some of their work
a few miles back.
Family named McMurdo.
At least they"re buried
under a cross.
Crude, but a cross.
How can I stop this
with only one command?
You might break it up
into companies
or platoons,
send "em riding
in all directions.
That"s what the Kiowas want.
They"d cut us to ribbons.
The only hope for law
is to keep this command intact.
When it"s gone, the Kiowas rule.
They seem
to be ruling now.
If you"re here
to fight Indians, Major,
there"s a lot of work waiting.
I hear you have Seminoles
in this territory.
Yeah, a small tribe up by Golden.
At least they"re peaceful.
You know their chief,
Maygro?
Not personally,
but I fought against
his father in Florida.
- What"s your opinion of them?
- For eight years in Florida,
they held back almost every
regiment of the army, marines,
the navy and 50,000 militia.
All that
with just 400 warriors.
Incredible, wasn't it?
Heh. Expensive too.
The government had to scatter
them all over the country so
there wouldn"t be another war.
Now they"re a poor
tribe of vagabonds
living in sod huts...
and trying to raise
a few scrawny sheep.
But they
can still fight.
Fight who?
Kiowas.
You couldn"t get
a Seminole Indian to fight
for his sister"s virtue.
Why not?
They"ve laid down
their guns for good.
The Kiowas run
through their village
Just for sport.
Could you get me
three fresh horses
and $500?
Anything, Major.
l"ll have you quartered
within the hour.
Well, don"t bother
with anything elaborate.
l"ll move Mrs. Corwin
out of Capt. Corwin"s house.
He was killed recently.
Rlease don"t inconvenience
anyone for me.
There's room for the woman
at my place.
You"re the C.O.
By the way,
there"s a birthday party
at my house tonight.
That hardly gives me time
to buy a present.
Don"t bother.
You"ve already given me one:
the funniest story
of the year.
Seminoles fighting Kiowas.
[Laughing]
Happy birthday, Colonel.
Thank you, Major.
Excuse me.
Certainly.
So I told him he had to be
in full uniform at all times.
[Laughing]
The colonel"s special blend.
Major Howell Brady,
ma"am.
I came to dance,
if you"d do me
the honor.
We were holding
a conversation, Major.
You should try
holding a girl
sometime, Captain.
I have a feeling that patience
is not one of your
stronger virtues, Major.
[Chuckles]
Consider the life span
of the average human,
then subtract
all the minutes we waste
in meaningless formalities.
Criminal.
There"s little enough time
for small pleasures as it is.
As I live and breathe,
a philosopher.
[Chuckles]
A... a realist.
Well, whatever you are,
l"m glad someone
finally asked me to dance.
Is there something
about you I should know?
l"m Mrs. Corwin.
l"m, uh, sorry about having
taken over your house.
The fortunes of war, Major.
Besides, any man
who"s held every rank
from private to major,
won a field commission,
been breveted twice
for exceptional gallantry...
and won the Congressional
Medal of Honor,
there just isn"t enough
that we can do for him.
Who told you all that?
Col. Meade, and not
without a little envy.
Oh, ah, l"m taking
a room in his house.
Yes, so I heard.
And he who gossips
will be out chasing Kiowas
in the morning.
[Chuckles]
They should be anyway.
Don"t you go, Major.
We"ve lost too many
good dancers already.
[Orchestra Stops,
Crowd Applauds]
l"m even more sorry
about your husband.
When did it happen?
About six months ago
on a scouting party.
He must"ve been
quite a man...
for his memory to have
kept you single
on the frontier this long.
They"ve been proposing to me
by platoons lately.
Bad training.
There are times when
the individual soldier...
is much more effective
than the unit.
You"re an exponent of
the one-man frontal attack.
Yes, but I believe
in cautious
reconnoitering first.
Better be careful, Major.
You"re revealing
your position to the enemy.
Enjoy your waltz, Major?
Were we waltzing?
It was more like
a musical fencing match.
I couldn"t get
past her guard.
Nobody ever does.
She"s a greater threat
to this post than the Kiowas.
- Something oughta be done.
- You"ll have to go
to the end of the line.
Not him.
He doesn"t waste his time
on meaningless formalities.
Major Brady, perhaps you"d
tell our younger officers...
of your experiences
fighting the Cheyenne.
They look
about as friendly
as the Cheyenne.
A later dance,
Mrs. Corwin?
The Captain"s Quadrille.
Write "Elaine" on your card.
Thank you.
I thought you were
above firting.
Was I?
I hear he came
from St. Louis
and Washington.
He"s still
Just another soldier.
Well, tell me,
what"s he doing here?
Trying to get Seminoles
to fight Kiowas.
Why, Colonel,
you"re jealous of him.
[Whooping, Shouting]
[Whooping,
Shouting Continue]
Hey.
I always knew you were
a brave man, Major,
but goin" in through
the colonel"s back door
ain"t recommended,
even for heroes.
That"s
Capt. Corwin"s widow.
Oh. l"m sorry.
I always figured
that Corwin was
too ornery to die.
Them Kiowas ain"t choosy
about who they kill.
You knew him?
Yeah, I knew him.
It"d take more
than a few Indians
to keep me away from that.
We"re ridin" in a noose.
I know.
Care to pick a number?
At least five,
or they"d be afraid.
Not 10,
or they"d have cut loose.
Seven.
Lucky seven.
We"ll have
to fight our way out.
Yeah.
Rrobably try to catch us
at that other rise.
Tell Wilks to keep
his eyes front.
He don"t
even know they"re up there.
He's got barroom eyes.
When we reach that rim,
we"ll go into a run.
Come over it shooting.
l"ll take the left.
You and Wilks
take the right.
[Laughing] How about
them fellas tellin" us
it was dangerous...
for just the three of us
to ride in this country?
They call this Coffin Rim.
It"s not famous for the births
that have happened here.
l"ll bet you a dollar
there ain"t an Indian
within 10 miles.
You got a bet.
How"re we gonna prove it?
Easy. Four Kiowas have
got you in their sights now.
Don"t look up!
Are you serious?
When we hit that ridge,
you do as I do...
if you want to live long enough
for another promotion.
Yes, sir.
Uh, you fellas
is lucky I was along.
You"re right. I just
made an easy dollar.
Wilks and I will do
some cleaning up.
You contact the Seminoles
and tell them what I said.
l"ll do what I can.
All right.
Schermerhorn,
I hate to bring this up,
but don"t you think
I oughta hold the dollar?
Just in case.
Uh-uh. If anything happens,
l"m gonna need some
gambling money where l"m going.
Well, that Schermerhorn.
That feller could charm
the Rocky Mountains into
goin" south for the winter.
Rsst!
My father, Chief Maygro,
said to give you
some food while he talks.
Rabbit, eh?
We call it Texas buffalo.
Say, you talk English
real good.
Why shouldn"t I?
I went to school
in San Antonio.
[Wilks]
What's your name, honey?
Avis. It means bird.
And do not speak
of putting salt on my tail.
[Laughing]
Some fella already
beat me to it, huh?
Uh, my name is Wilks.
Sergeant Wilks.
And this fella here...
I forget his name.
Anyway, he"s married
and got 16 kids.
You make him
sound interesting.
[Clears Throat]
Uh, you like
this life out here?
I hate it.
Would you like to spend
your life in a mud hut
with corn husks for beds...
and rabbit
for food every day?
Well, uh, I might
if you was with me.
I won"t be.
l"m going someplace.
Any particular place?
Anywhere. It couldn"t
be worse than this.
Maybe you and I could
work something out.
What I want,
you don"t have.
[Luke Laughing]
Oh, try me.
Good food and clothes
and a decent place to live?
Well, that sure
lets out enlisted men.
What"s your father
think about all this?
My father will not
let me leave.
He won't? How come?
He says there"s only one way
to get the things I want.
He could be right.
I don't care.
I know what I want.
l"m going to get it.
Wait a minute.
There"s a lot to be said
for bein" a nice girl.
Weren"t you just suggesting
we could work something out?
I didn"t mean...
Who are you to tell me
what is nice and what isn"t?
When I get the chance,
I will leave and
I will do what I want.
Then you want us
to help you fight the Kiowa?
That"s right, Maygro.
You Seminoles.
We are Kanyuksa Indians
from Florida.
Among our people,
"Seminole" is not a good word.
All right, Kanyuksa.
We number 300,
maybe 25 men
who could fight.
That"s more than enough.
I try to understand...
We have to fight the Kiowas
on their own terms.
A small, fast-moving,
hard-hitting force,
one that knows the country,
understands the language,
has endurance and doesn"t
ask any luxuries.
Why should we do this
for you?
For six months" service,
the government will give you
land of your own.
Like this?
No, this will be
green land...
with water and cattle,
trees to build houses with.
Where is this land?
The whole
Santa Media Valley.
But to get it,
we must fight.
Yeah.
That is one thing
we cannot do.
Aw! We make foolish journey
to come here.
Why don"t you
ask your people?
I am the law
of the Kanyuksas.
I say no.
You afraid, Maygro?
Come.
We speak with others.
Tell us, how will
our families eat
when men are gone?
The army will send
supplies every month.
Meantime,
$500 until the first
supply train comes.
We have put down
our guns for good.
Fighting will only lose us
the peace we find.
Reace?
You mean hunger!
Let me die fighting,
not from peaceful
starvation!
Rino, you"re too young
to remember what war did
to the Kanyuksa.
When you have to fight,
you fight!
Even a snake
or gopher knows that.
Are we to sit around...
and watch the Kiowas
run through our camp
for sport?
The young men have the heart,
but we have no weapons!
If I had a gun,
I would show them...
that the Kanyuksa have at least
as much courage as gopher!
Rino, sit down!
When elders speak,
you listen. Sit down!
I am your leader.
When we were
driven from Florida,
we pledged to keep peace.
We knew it would be hard.
You want new leader,
say so.
Then as long as I am
Maygro, your leader,
I do what I think best.
You"re less than women!
l"m ashamed that
I talked to you as equals,
as men of courage!
Major!
[Shouting, Whooping]
[Luke]
Kiowas!
Well, at least you got
six more horses.
I never saw gun
shoot like that.
Fifteen times without reloading.
It"s a Henry repeating rife.
This is the weapon you"ll have.
Makes one man equal to 30.
You teach
strong lesson.
I always said whoever called
the Kanyuksas "Seminoles"
was right.
That"s all they ever were:
Seminoles, cowards,
and renegades.
Avis, this is no time
for such talk.
You might yet turn out
to be men.
- No one will give you anything
unless you fight for it.
- Quiet. We will go with Major.
I know,
and I am going with you.
You will stay in village
where you belong
with the rest of the women.
Try and keep me there.
Hey, Schermerhorn,
you captured
the wrong Indians.
Them ain"t fighters:
they"re sheep eaters.
l"m beginnin" to feel a little foolish.
You got the face
to go with it.
I guess you"re right.
Colonel, this is Maygro...
Who said these Seminoles
were to be quartered?
The orders,
some of the fine print.
You don"t pull
sleeping quarters
out of the air.
Give "em a gun and a horse
and they"ll be gone
by tomorrow morning.
The Kanyuksas will...
l"m talking
to the major!
Go on, Maygro.
The Kanyuksas will not go.
They will fight well
for land and food promised.
What land?
What food?
The Santa Media Valley,
and a wagon train to
their families every month.
I need all the supplies
I have!
The supplies will
be ready at the nearest
army railhead monthly.
You just furnish
the transportation.
Where are you going?
To Major Brady"s house
to stay with my father.
That would not be good.
They put me in a tent
worse than the hut
I came from.
If you would marry me,
I would build a house for us.
What will you build?
Ajackal hut?
Made of handsome sod
and magnificent mud?
No, Rino. Never.
A house is good because of
how you live in it,
not how it is made.
That is not for me!
Hello.
l"m Mrs. Corwin.
Elaine Corwin.
My name is Avis.
Your dress
is very pretty.
Thank you.
Coming from another woman,
that"s the highest compliment.
Did it cost much?
No. I made it myself.
You can"t buy ready-made
dresses out here.
Someday l"ll have
a dress prettier than that.
l"ll show you how to make one
with my patterns.
If I had the cloth,
I could sew it myself.
I might have some cloth too.
Thank you,
but l"ll get my own.
Afternoon, Mrs. Corwin.
Hello, Major.
You"re about to have a new
resident in your house.
Oh, homesick already?
As far as l"m concerned,
one house is the same
as another on an army post.
l"m disappointed.
l"m fattered
by your disappointment.
And l"m properly
put in my place.
About my new resident...
It"s Avis.
I understand
she"s moving in.
I guess she wants
to be near her father.
Uh-uh.
She"s dying to have
a dress like mine,
probably so her father
will realize
how pretty she is.
Or Rino.
Or you.
She has a kind
of untamed charm.
They say that a wild plant
never lives very long indoors.
I'm gonna be too busy
to conduct social experiments.
Speaking of experiments,
the talk is that you"ll
never train the Seminoles.
The only thing that talk
ever trained is a parrot.
By the way, they don"t like
to be called Seminoles.
Oh?
Suppose we discuss it later?
Be all right?
Very well.
Well, your men are ready.
I gave "em each a horse
and a Henry repeater.
These guns will speak
their own answer
to the colonel.
Just load "em up on Sunday,
and they"ll shoot all week.
For you.
Well, you can"t see
through the paper,
you know.
Oh.
There"s enough
material for a dress,
pattern, needles, thread.
If you need any more help,
I can"t give it to you.
Thank you.
Hope it"ll give you
something to do.
She told you,
didn"t she?
Yeah.
l"ll be a better woman
than she is.
What do you do
with your old losers, Major?
All right, now, keep
your elbow on your knee.
The stock dug
into your shoulder.
That"s it.
Just like that.
Rick your targets
carefully,
every shot.
All right, Luke.
Take a steady grip
and squeeze.
Don"t pull the trigger,
or you"ll jerk the barrel
off the target.
Keep this little ball
Just underneath what you"re
aimin" at, like this.
[Gunshots]
All right, one at a time.
Maygro, you lead off.
[Gunshots]
Ha!
[Chuckling]
All right, Rino.
[Gunshots]
[Brady Chuckling]
l"m not sure
this is such a good idea.
What?
Leaving the fort after dark.
Could get mighty dangerous
out here.
Everything"s dangerous
in this country.
I know.
I mean, danger doesn"t stop
at the walls of the fort.
I know that too.
Why, even in your own home.
Once I walked
into my living room,
and there was a rattler.
Gave me quite a start.
Once I walked into a room...
and there was one of the most
beautiful women l"ve ever seen.
Gave me quite a start.
Anyway, if I didn"t get
outside once in a while,
l"d go crazy.
Sometimes the fort seems
Just like a prison.
Why do you stay on?
Oh, it isn"t easy for
a woman to pull up roots
and start traveling.
Colonel Meade
wouldn"t have anything
to do with it, would he?
Why do you ask that?
Because he"s entirely
too paternal for a man
who isn"t the fatherly type.
l"m very fond
ofjack as a friend.
Nothing more,
and he knows it.
A smart officer prepares
for a long campaign.
He"d have the same luck
with me that he"s having
with the Kiowas.
That seems to be true
for everybody.
Something tells me
that you"ll do
a little better.
With you?
I was thinking
about the Kiowas.
Oh.
I don"t know.
Their raids aren"t haphazard.
There"s a plan behind them.
l"m sorry
I even mentioned it.
All right, pick a subject.
Something far away,
something like
Washington or St. Louis.
Oh, the buildings
hem you in and the noise
wears you down.
l"ve had
a warehouseful of quiet.
Tell me about the parties
and the dresses...
and the crystal
and the silver.
And the colds and bad food
and the empty conversation?
Oh, sounds wonderful.
To be sitting with a cold
in a noisy restaurant
in Washington...
listening
to bad conversation,
l"d give all the love
that"s in me.
Now or when you get there?
l... I don"t know what
made me say that.
Don"t you?
Do your plans really
include a return
to the East?
I don"t know, except...
Well, then why don"t
we talk about it...
when you really know
where you"re going?
All right, Wilks,
take over.
Yes, sir.
Now, you all know
how to sit on a horse.
l"m gonna show you
how to jump a horse!
Now pay attention.
[Luke Laughing]
Rino,
follow me over.
When the time comes,
you"ll have to dig"em
faster and deeper.
Man should not
fight in hole.
He should stand erect.
And get his head shot off?
In case of a sudden attack,
this is what we"ll use
these trenches for. Ready?
[Men Shouting]
[Horses Whinny]
Think we had enough?
Even the army don"t
work this hard.
That"s
why we"re out here. Come on.
He"s training those Seminoles
like a cross between Kentucky
frontiersmen and rustlers.
Digging holes,
firing dismounted,
charging four at a time.
To fight Indians, you"ve got
to give "em a spectacle.
Stun "em, make noise.
l"d like to be looking on
when Brady"s bunch meets
its first party of Kiowas.
Those lads
aren"t interested
in playing games.
It"ll take him a month
to round up
his Seminoles again.
One way or another,
l"d like to see it.
A toast...
to the memory
of Brady"s bunch.
[Knocking]
Oh, hello, Major.
Looking for the colonel?
No, he"s in his office.
I made sure of that.
May I come in?
Oh, of course.
Would you like
a cup of tea?
No, thank you.
Oh, um, how"s your army
coming along?
If maneuvers mean anything,
we"re unbeatable.
We"ll know shortly.
I leave in a day or so.
Oh, so soon?
Mm-hmm.
Elaine, l-I don"t know
how long this will take
or how well it"ll come out.
What an alarming
lack of confidence.
It isn"t like you.
I have my moments.
Sometimes when
we play make-believe,
we get overconfident.
Worse, we lose sight
of what's make-believe
and what's real.
Are we talking
about the same thing?
I think we are.
If we ever get
the Kiowas in line,
I can just about pick
my next assignment.
l"ve had enough
of this special frontier duty
to warrant it.
You"re very fortunate,
Major.
I thought I might ask
for a tour of duty
in Washington,
the A.G. office
or something like that.
Where the buildings
hem you in and the noise
wears you down.
When a man has nothing
but time on his hands,
no one to share it with,
he concentrates
on noise and cold.
He has to blame
his loneliness on something.
Elaine, l... l-l"m not doing
a very good job of this,
but l"m trying
to tell you l...
l"m in love with you.
I know.
I wish you hadn"t.
The other night,
that was one thing.
l"m sorry for it.
This is different.
No, it"s worse.
l-I don"t understand.
It"s really very simple.
l"m not in love with you.
You haven"t given
yourself time
to think about it.
I don"t have to think
about it. I know.
I don"t believe that.
You and your supreme ego, Major.
Can"t you stand being rejected?
As much as you can
stand being a woman.
Don"t worry. l"m a woman.
l"m beginning to wonder.
l"m genuinely impressed,
Major,
but l"m afraid
nothing"s changed.
You"re so wrong
about that.
l"m sorry I troubled you.
[Door Closes]
They hide out
somewhere in the northeast.
Raids have been in this area.
There are certain ridges
and canyons they have
to take to reach this spot.
Suppose we stake
this one out.
Spread out.
Thanks for volunteering
to be bait, Rino.
I must make myself
as strong a man as you
so Avis will notice me.
My blood is slowin"
down to a walk.
Stop complainin".
We"re makin" a hero out of ya.
Well, l"ll trade my medals
for a piece of that fire.
Go up and join "em, then.
I think I will.
All right, go on.
On second thought,
I think l"ll stay
right where I am.
[Horse Whinnies]
Wait until we"re sure.
The last second.
These make good graves
for later.
You better dig it
a little wider, Wilks.
Ah! Aw, you can
bury me sideways.
[Chuckling]
Luke, come here.
[Faint Hoofbeats
Approaching]
Get "em ready.
Tell "em not to mistake me
for a Kiowa.
[Hoofbeats Louder]
[Shouting War Whoops]
[Whooping Continues]
[Gunfire Stops]
Lesson grows stronger.
[Hoofbeats Approaching]
Here comes
some more of"em.
[Horses Whinny]
[Wilks]
Major Brady!
I almost killed ya!
He got away!
Who got away?
I don"t know,
but he wasn"t an Indian.
I better get me
a pair of them eyeglasses.
Oh, forget it.
Got a match?
Yeah, I think so.
This could have been picked up
by some Kiowa off Corwin"s body.
I hope so.
The man who carried it
was white.
Corwin"s dead.
He went on a scouting trip
with a corporal and a private.
I found their bodies burned
and tied to a wagon wheel.
There are his papers.
Must be some other
white man fighting
with the Indians.
Could be almost anyone.
There are a lot
of renegades out there.
But your job is the Indians.
I know my job, Colonel.
I guess this belongs
to Mrs. Corwin.
l"ll see that she gets it.
Uh, Brady.
It"s difficult to prove
that your men killed as
many raiders as you claim.
But let's assume you're
truthful. Congratulations.
[Door Closes]
Where did you find it?
I won it. First prize
in a free-for-all.
The man who carried it
was white.
Was he tall
and dark-haired?
I didn"t get
a good look at him, but...
l"d say that"s
a pretty fair description
of almost anyone.
Do you think he"s alive?
It"s only a feeling,
woman"s intuition.
I was hoping
that he had died.
He went on
that scouting expedition
to desert.
He wanted me
to go with him.
Meade found his body.
Burned. Who could say
it was him?
I saw his papers.
Meade showed them to me.
The whole idea"s
pretty farfetched.
Roger was
a very farfetched man.
He cultivated
the friendship of some
infuential Mexicans...
that didn"t like
the Guadalupe Treaty,
that lost them
their lands in Texas.
They offered him
a small fortune to start
the Indians fighting again.
To get Mexico
back in the war?
I don"t know.
l-I think so.
Why didn"t you
turn him in?
I didn"t think
that he was serious.
It would have been
a very difficult
thing to prove.
Then when I heard he was dead,
there didn"t seem
to be any point to it.
Quite a man you married.
Sure, I married him.
I was in love with him.
But you can"t hate him
any more than I do now.
Yet you insist
on remaining tied to him.
You lock the gate
on your emotions, refuse
to fall in love again,
all because you"re living
in wedlock with a ghost.
Apparently more than a ghost.
That"s all he is.
A body was identified
by Col. Meade.
That sets you free legally
in any court.
There are other things
besides legal freedom.
l"ve the feeling
that he"s still alive.
And now this.
This saber doesn"t
prove anything.
It could"ve been found!
It doesn"t prove
that he"s dead either.
Luke, you, uh...
You didn"t like Capt. Corwin
very much, did you?
I took more kindly
to scorpions.
Why?
Never did warm to these
galvanized Yankees,
but Corwin was
the sourest pickle
in the barrel.
Fought for
the Confederacy, huh?
He never stopped fightin".
He joined us
Just to get even.
I never saw one man
could hate
a Yankee so hard.
Enough to stand by and see
a lot of"em slaughtered?
He wouldn"t be standin" by.
He"d be helpin" out.
?? [Orchestra]
Good evening, Major.
Good evening, Captain.
These dances sure
break up the monotony
on the post.
You should try
chasing Kiowas for that.
?? [Chanting]
Those savages know we"re
having a dance in here?
Rrobably.
If I were commanding
this post, they"d
show respect for rank.
I think they"ve earned
their celebration...
much more than your rank
has earned you
any respect, Captain.
?? [Chanting Continues]
Made from the cloth
you gave me.
No. I never
gave you any cloth
as beautiful as that.
I was going to wait here
until you came out,
so you would see it.
Did you wear it
especially
for the celebration?
I did not make this dress
for an Indian celebration.
l"m not a savage.
Did I do
as I said I would?
Hmm?
Did I make myself
a better woman
for you to look at...
than the woman
who cried on your shoulder?
Avis, I doubt that
anywhere in the world...
there"s a woman better
to look at than you.
Thank you.
Take everything you need.
You won"t see
a quartermaster for weeks.
That"s as good
as gettin" two weeks away
from your mother-in-law.
Brady.
l... I just wanted
to wish you luck.
That"d mean bringing
your husband back,
if it is your husband.
I know.
If it"s me personally
you"re wishing luck,
it"d mean
bringing him back dead.
Yes.
You don"t give a man
a very comfortable choice,
do you?
l"m being honest
for the first time
in my life.
It isn"t easy for me
either.
But l"m the one who has
to make the decision.
Boy, I never thought
l"d end up one of them
female "personators.
Ha-ha!
He don"t seem to mind!
Hey, he"s prettier
than me!
[Whooping]
Here they come!
Boy, are they gonna
get a surprise.
Take their rifes
and let "em go.
Keep that one here.
I wanna talk to him.
Speak English?
Know any Kiowa words,
Maygro?
I can speak with him.
Ask him if there"s
a white man riding with "em.
[Speaking Kiowa Language]
He just say, "Kill me."
Ask him again.
[Kiowa Language]
All right, let him go.
Major, he understand
only torture.
I don"t.
I said let him go.
[Kiowa Language]
He say kill him.
He thinks
we shoot him in back.
Give him an escort.
Tell him we"ll
keep after his people...
until they stop
fighting.
[Kiowa Language]
Yes, sir. A Kiowa a day
keeps me rollin" in pay.
[Laughing]
Twenty a month. That"s
about 65 cents a Kiowa.
l"m gonna run a special:
two for a quarter.
We"ve done all right.
Two raidin" parties a day.
That"s pretty good huntin".
It"s just fair.
It"s a new record
for this territory.
Unless we find
their leaders,
it will take us
the rest of our lives
to wipe out the Kiowas.
The Kiowa talked.
I don"t believe in torture.
He would have
killed himself anyway.
He not return
to tribe disgraced.
We"re trying to bring
law into this territory.
Yet, one life for many.
Rino!
There is a white man.
Corwin.
He was officer in your army.
He lead Kiowa raids.
Where does he hide out?
Many place.
He move every day.
He has heard of us.
What"d I tell ya?
Any outfit Agustus Wilks joins
becomes immortal overnight.
He worries.
When war parties
do not come back,
people and their chief Satanta
ask questions.
Anything else?
He know, to rule this land,
he must destroy fort.
When was that
scheduled for?
Not for long time.
But because of us,
and doubt spread
among his tribes,
he will be forced
to do it soon.
Any day.
The fort isn"t easy
to defend...
with a hill
looking down on it.
They had to build it
where the fresh water was.
Let"s go back
and get us a drink.
Did you learn
anything about...
Yeah.
He"s...
He"s still alive?
Still alive.
What"s your claim
this time, Major?
Twenty raiding parties.
Would you like
to see the bodies?
That"s a nice,
round number.
l"m too tired to play
word games today.
You"ll get my written report
in the morning.
Should be stirring stuff.
Is it true you do not send
supplies to my people?
That door"s to knock on!
Before I cut you
in two, tell me!
You enlisted in this army
as a scout. l"m a colonel!
There are limits
to the liberties
you can take with me!
Tell me!
Did you send
the supplies?
No.
We kept our word!
Why you not keep your word?
I gave you no word!
But I did,
through an authority
higher than yours.
What are my people to eat?
Dirt?
The supplies
haven"t arrived
from the Army depot.
When they do, l"ll let
you know. Until then, get
out of my office, Maygro!
You can"t
treat him like that.
He"s a chief!
Of what?
A worthless band
of vagabonds?
Now, if there"s
nothing else, Major...
There"s a lot else, Colonel!
Capt. Corwin is alive
and directing
the Indian raids.
Who told you that?
A Kiowa.
Huh.
Just before he died.
All right, he lied.
But let"s assume
it"s true.
Then someday
we"ll find him.
Maybe he"ll find you first.
What do you mean?
He plans to destroy
this fort.
Good. We"ll be
waiting for him.
Just remember
where you heard it first.
About these supplies:
You"ve got more
than you need.
l"m not authorized
to issue them to you.
Wars are won by initiative,
not authorization.
I never cared much
for debates, Major,
especially
with junior officers.
All right, Meade,
fight your own private war.
But before you"re through,
you"ll need more
than those eagles.
Brady!
Brady, they've gone!
Maygro?
And all the men.
They just rode out.
You must get them back.
What for? To save your
precious Capt. Corwin?
There are other things
to consider: the women
and children in this fort.
l"ve never seen
my father so angry.
Why didn"t you go too?
I told my father
I would not go.
I told him we were
gonna be married.
Married?
I had to tell him something.
That"s just another promise
he"ll think l"ve broken.
l"ll tell him
the truth someday.
Thanks.
I stayed
because I want you
to go after them.
You need them,
but they need you more.
They"ve known
hunger before,
but this time
their hunger
will have a purpose.
Bring them back, Brady.
I wasn"t sure I liked you
the first time I saw you.
Now?
I can stand you.
Not enough to have you
give me away in marriage.
Won"t help to catch up
with Maygro unless we"ve got
more than words to offer him.
Supplies from the
quartermaster warehouse?
Yeah.
Biggest wagonload
of everything you can find.
Findin"s gonna be easy.
Gettin" it out will be the job.
You can turn it down
if you want.
Well, l"ve had a pretty good
career in the army.
Not as good as yours, Luke,
but it wasn"t bad.
l"ll let you
wear my stripes
while we do it.
I always knowed
l"d get to wear
them stripes someday.
Use the back gate.
Be sure to watch out
for the O.D.
How much time
we got left, Luke?
Two more minutes before
the officer of the day
will be making his rounds.
Maybe he"ll
be late tonight.
Capt. Neil is never late.
Capt. Neil!
We"ll never drink all that!
Two of"em
is for the horses.
He"ll be here any second!
I never drink
without a chaser.
Oh-oh.
Firin" squad,
here we come.
Start thinkin"
what you"re gonna say
at the court-martial.
Anybody in there?
No, sir.
We go on.
Just a few more
minutes, Maygro.
We wait too long now.
[Wagon Approaches]
Good work!
Did you have
any trouble?
Trouble? Ha! Aw, no,
we didn"t have no trouble,
Major. We was just...
By the orders of Col. Meade,
you"re under arrest.
Any move to resist
would save a tiresome
court-martial.
Don"t get drunk with power.
I still outrank you.
Temporarily.
What"s the charge?
What do you think?
Somebody made the mistake
of dropping his pay book.
The major didn"t have
nothin" to do with that.
This room is off-limits
to prisoners.
So we took
a few supplies.
You can do anything
you want with your men
and supplies, but not mine.
The secretary of war
can"t protect you now.
The supplies
will be replaced.
In the meantime,
they must be officially
listed as stolen.
Meade,
this isn"t West Roint:
it"s Indian country.
No regulations
ever stopped an Indian.
My first duty
is to this command.
What good were they
doing sitting here?
That"s my concern.
The concern
of every dead settler
from here to Arkansas.
You"ve been waitin" for me
to make a mistake like this.
You're the type.
Capt. Neil is waiting.
You"ll be under guard
in your quarters.
You plan to run
the Seminoles by yourself?
Yes.
l"m gonna run"em
out of this fort.
Even you can"t carry
petty jealousy that far.
Until the army replaces me,
l"m still commanding!
And using your rank
to make a personal war!
Out here
the U.S. Army is the law!
I'm not gonna see it handed
over to a band of rabble!
Even if they do the job better?
Even if they can
do the job better.
With them leaving
and Brady under guard,
that"s the last
of Brady"s bunch.
Good evening,
Mrs. Corwin.
Good evening.
We have only
a few moments before
we are discovered.
We need horses and guns.
They are going
out the back gate now.
How"d you get in?
Mrs. Corwin.
Let"s go.
You two stay here.
You can"t get rid of us.
We know too much.
l-It"d be desertion.
If we accomplish something,
they might be good to us, but...
It"s service
above and beyond
the call of duty.
All right, you enlisted.
You shouldn"t be here.
Get going!
l"m not leaving!
Don"t be crazy!
l"m staying here to prove
that you"ll all come back.
You don"t know what
they might do to you.
She made up her mind.
It"s the only thing
I can do to help.
All right.
There"s no doubt the Kiowas
are gathering to get ready
for the attack on the fort.
How many you think?
About every brave
who can ride a horse.
You can"t hide
that many Indians.
You can decoy your opposition
by sending out small parties
to strike at everything.
That"ll keep the colonel
running in every direction.
Would Corwin know to do this?
He"s a professional soldier,
isn"t he?
Then when Meade"s patrols
are out, he"ll hit the fort
with a big attack.
You told Meade
about this?
Yeah, I told him.
What is our job?
We"ll break up into
scouting parties to see
if Corwin uses this plan.
Let the raiding parties
go out, then trail "em
to the main force.
That way we"ll know
where it is.
Remember, if any of us
are seen or heard,
the fat"s in the fire.
Let"s go.
Who"s gonna play
hide-and-go-seek this time?
l"ll take this bunch.
All here.
We move fast,
Satanta.
Make sure horse
do not stumble.
Kiowas ride over you.
That"s the spirit.
When the attack starts,
we keep going until
everyone inside the fort
is killed.
My tribe take big chance.
It"s no chance:
it"s a certainty.
You make mistake,
you make no more.
Stop worrying. just start
counting the loot.
Well, I saw it.
How"d it look?
Biggest war party
in local history headin"
in this direction.
Them Kiowas sure
been breedin" fast.
Was Corwin with them?
It"s Corwin.
I got a glimpse
of Satanta too.
That fella with all
them sergeants" stripes
on his tepee?
Better warn Meade.
Listen, Meade would rather
have you in irons...
than beat the Kiowas.
He"ll have his chance
to do both. Mount up.
Back to give yourself up?
Where are all the men?
Out on patrol.
How soon will
those patrols return?
They just went out.
What difference does it make?
Drop your sidearms
on the foor.
How many men are here?
He said drop your sidearm.
You"re under arrest.
Twenty? Forty?
Fifty?
Twenty.
Think you can put my whole
detachment under arrest?
Just you.
You"ll need even me.
In a half hour,
every Kiowa...
in this territory"s gonna
be climbing these walls.
I don"t believe that.
You oughta have
more faith, Colonel.
Rut it on the table.
You"re adding one charge
after another! l"ll see you
in front of a firing squad!
You won"t live
to see anything
if we don"t get moving.
Rile up
all your ammunition.
Set your artillery up
on the north wall.
Rut your women
and children
in the powder magazine.
- l"ll give the orders!
- By that time, the Kiowas
will be finishing your meal!
You lost your rank
when you deserted!
That"s
for a court-martial to decide!
l"ll make sure of that!
Open the gate!
[Horses Approaching]
Sir, we sighted
a full force of Kiowas
heading toward the fort.
Very well.
[Door Closes]
Major, take charge
of your bunch.
l"ll handle the troops
that are left.
Is that all the ammunition
you could find?
That"s all, sir.
We"ll need 20 times that.
Not with these old pieces.
Six rounds
and they"ll blow up.
What good is artillery here?
What good"s a fort with a hill
lookin" down its throat?
Nobody will be able
to move inside this compound.
You"re overdramatizing things.
Aw, there"s one
in every fort.
Get that man"s name!
Come on, boy!
Get him inside.
Inside, ladies.
That"s it.
Brady, it can"t be
this bad.
Your husband and every
Kiowa in this territory
are dropping in on us.
That"s right,
spread it out.
As fast as you can.
l"d rather stay out here.
I want to see him
for myself.
You"ll be tortured
if you"re caught.
He wouldn"t let them.
Once those Kiowas get inside,
nothing will stop them.
Where"s Avis?
She"s in
the quartermaster warehouse,
held as a prisoner.
l"d better get her.
Brady!
Oh, Rino, l"m so glad
to see you!
I am glad too, Avis.
Rut her
in the powder magazine.
No!
Go with Rino!
But why
the powder magazine?
If necessary, we"d both
rather see you die that way.
Avis, you must do
as the major says.
Yes.
It is time I listened
to other people.
Go on.
[Faint Hoofbeats Approaching]
[Gunfire]
[Shouting War Whoops]
[Horses Whinny]
One of those guns is out!
The other ain"t got
far to go!
[Shouting War Whoops]
[Gunfire Continues]
[Whooping Continues]
[Whooping, Gunfire Continue]
[Ricochet]
[Crying]
[Whooping Continues]
Brady, never
have I been so wrong...
and somebody else
so right.
I owe you more
than I can say.
Luke, get every man you can.
Try to drive the Kiowas
out through the gate.
Wilks, get the colonel
into his office.
[Gunfire Continues]
Maygro! Rino!
You men come with me!
Right here!
[Gunfire Continues]
[Gunshot]
[Whooping Continues]
[Gunfire Stops]
Oh, Brady.
Good luck, Major.
Take care
of the Seminoles, sir.
Don"t worry about them.
You just take care of Elaine.
You"ve made
the word "Seminole"
an honorable one.
The days will be long
till you return.
We"ll be back someday.
[Officer]
Troops! Atten-shun!