MAN (over phone):
I'm telling you, this company
is poised to make a killing
at only $13 a share.
I don't care if
it's 13 cents
a share, I'm not buying, Danny.
I'm out of the game.
(chuckles)
I've tasted freedom, man.
The city's poison.
The only green I care about now
is the kale I'm growing.
(laughter over phone)
Laugh it up, Danny.
You laugh it up from
your smog-filled city office.
I'm in God's country,
I'm doing God's work.
And he's looking out for me.
I bet he is.
Just visit, dude.
That's all I'm saying.
I will, I promise.
I love kale.
Oh!
(coughs)
Hey, what's wrong?
Too much fresh air?
Oh, God, I don't know.
Just smells like a dead animal,
that's all.
What the hell is that?
Oh, God. Oh, God!
(gears grinding)
How do you stop this thing?
(engine stops)
What? What? What's going on?
Hey, Chip, what's going on?
(screams)
I just killed a dead guy!
(indistinct chatter)
(camera shutter clicking)
BOOTH:
Okay, just think of it
as an investment for our future.
For Parker, for Christine.
Asteroid mining?
Yeah, asteroid mining.
I did my
research, okay?
The head of the
Jet Propulsion Lab
says it's possible,
and the two guys
who sent the rover
to Mars, they agree.
The microgravity technologies
required to do so
don't even exist, Booth.
You know what?
There was a time
when radios and-and railroads,
they didn't exist,
but people, they got rich.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
Like a schoolteacher.
Every time I have a good idea...
Anyway, just look at the bones.
Why did the farmer
run over the remains?
He was an investment banker
trying to get back to nature.
I'm guessing the tractor
didn't handle like his Beemer.
Well, according to
the shallow grave here,
shish kebob,
he was definitely murdered.
The presence of
Nicrophorus americanus,
along with some of its larvae,
suggest the murder took place
five days ago.
Right. You believe
in asteroid mining?
Are you kidding me? It's
the only way that the species
is gonna survive.
Did you hear that?
I am a visionary.
You're gonna be
an asteroid miner?
Yeah.
I didn't ask that.
Don't want to know.
Please explain the difficulty to him
of retrieving
a 500-ton asteroid.
No. Not my place.
HODGINS: No, no, no.
No, you just put it
in a lunar orbit
and send some guys up there.
I think it's really
simple, actually.
Is she looking at me
like an angry schoolteacher?
Oh, yeah, yeah. She does that a lot.
BRENNAN: We're here to work.
These bones have been
heavily scavenged.
The three-cornered
puncture marks indicate coyotes.
Oh, do you think
they ran off with the head?
We've got techs searching
the area for it.
Flattened anterior and posterior
sides of the victim's
femoral neck indicate
a Hispanic male.
Well, it's tough to get
an I.D. without the head.
Easier than capturing
an asteroid.
Hey. I am on your side, man.
I need all
of the remains
and the aerator
brought back to the lab.
BOOTH:
Right.
BOOTH: Look, they just need
$2.6 billion in seed money.
I mean, that's like
a sports team almost
when you think about it.
Plus, the platinum alone,
it's worth about $50 billion.
Why do you care what I think?
Why? Because
my platinum is your platinum,
and your platinum
is my platinum.
$2,500 is a lot for you,
and there are no guarantees.
Well, there never are.
I mean, look at us.
Huh? No one ever thought
that we would pay off.
(chuckles)
Bringing back that much platinum
could cause the bottom to drop
out of the platinum market.
I'm sorry, are you trying
to be supportive?
I thought I was.
I was discussing this
as if it's reasonable.
Dr. Brennan!
Yes?
I've got a surprise for you.
Wait till you see this.
FBI. Get your hand out
(customers exclaim)
of the bag, get on the ground now.
Okay.
Now. Now!
Okay, okay, okay.
Take it easy.
No problems.
Smith & Wesson 1911, right?
A man of tradition, I see.
That's a very cool gun.
It's gonna be
the last thing you see
if you don't shut your mouth.
Booth, what are you doing?
What do you mean what am
I doing? He's all bloody.
Do you really think he's got a
bouquet of flowers in that bag?
He's right. I-I don't have
a bouquet of flowers...
Shut up. Put your head
on the ground. Slide the bag
very easily
across the floor.
Don't do anything stupid.
Here.
(customers scream)
It's your victim's skull.
Hi, I'm your new intern.
Hi.
♪ Bones 8x17 ♪
The Fact in the Fiction
Original Air Date on February 25, 2013
♪ Main Title Theme ♪ The Crystal Method
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
Why wasn't I notified
about the new intern?
Have you read
all your e-mails, Dr. Brennan?
Well, only the ones
with a subject line
pertaining to a specific case.
Well, I suggest you read
the ones with the subject line
"Personnel."
Is there a problem
with Dr. Wells?
He brought a skull
into the diner in a satchel.
He's enthusiastic.
He tracked the skull
to a coyote den six miles
from the crime scene.
Well, that is enthusiastic, but...
He hasn't learned
our protocols yet.
I think you'll find him
a quick study though.
Based on what?
Dr. Wells has a PhD in physics,
a masters in both astronomy
and wildlife ecology,
and he's two credits short
of a masters
in forensic anthropology.
Well, how was I supposed
to know that?
Well, perhaps
you should read the e-mails
with the subject line
"Intern Résumés."
He's also passed the bar.
It's like getting five interns
for the price of one.
Except that he brought me
the skull in a bag
made of recycled plastic,
which produces condensation,
which could have severely
compromised crucial evidence.
Which is why I rushed
the skull to you
at the diner, Dr. Brennan.
You see, condensation starts
after three hours.
I got you the skull
in an hour and 45 minutes.
That's simple physics.
And the plastic
was recycled so...
good for the environment.
HODGINS: Can we please
de-spike this dude
so I can start picking
through his clothing?
All in good time,
Dr. Hodgins.
What should I do now?
Tell Dr. Brennan
what you've deduced so far.
Induced, actually.
Going from the specific
to the general,
lack of cut marks
on the gonial angle
of the mandible, underside
of chin and cervical vertebrae
leave me no reason to suspect
that this skull was removed
by anything
other than the coyotes.
So... not a zombie?
Zombies have to be beheaded
or they eat your brains.
BRENNAN: There are
no such things as zombies
or vampires or ghosts.
The first law
of thermodynamics states
that energy is neither
created nor destroyed.
So when we die,
all that energy has
to go somewhere, right?
I believe
that if we die
with an abundance
of this power,
it can become
forever imprinted
on the immediate environment.
And that imprint, that's our ghost?
Mm-hmm.
Can we keep him?
I haven't decided yet.
There appears to be
a strange glow emanating
from the victim's inferior
nasal conchae.
HODGINS:
Ooh, ghosty.
SWEETS:
The guy literally
fought off coyotes
to get the skull back.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
Coyotes, they just run away
if you yell at them.
I know, but still, to face
a pack of wild animals alone...
I'm sure you'd just bore them
to death with your shrinky talk.
A-And I'm sure you could just
break their hearts
with your mean, mean words.
Wow.
Yeah, wow.
So, the brother is the victim's
only family that you found?
So far. Okay,
Hodgins found traces
of glow-in-the-dark auto paint
in the victim's nose.
It's rare stuff apparently,
and he traced it back
to the brother's auto body shop.
You know, driving
a glow-in-the-dark car seems
like an excellent safety
feature, doesn't it?
Don't say stuff like that
when we get there, okay?
Look, the guy's brother is dead.
I know. I'm just... telling you.
And... I'm not wrong.
Oh, God. Yes.
That's my little
brother Benji.
Benjamin.
He's dead?
Yes, sir.
We're sorry
for your loss.
Who did this?
BOOTH: Well, we're not sure yet.
He worked here, right?
Yeah.
Why didn't you report him missing?
Benji was in college.
Finals coming up,
I gave him a week off
to hole up and study.
First one ever
in our family to go to college.
Is there any other family
we should notify, Mr. Garcia?
No.
It's just me and Benji. Mom died
four years ago, Dad took off
when we were little kids.
What happened to my brother?
Well, his remains
are still being examined.
Oh, God. That's bad.
You find his truck?
BOOTH: Why would
the truck be the first thing
you bring up?
If somebody killed Benji,
it had to be for his truck.
Tricked-out '59 El Camino.
SWEETS:
You think someone
would kill for a pickup truck?
I'll tell
you who hated
that truck.
Courtney.
SWEETS:
Who's Courtney?
His ex-girlfriend.
They broke up
a week ago.
WELLS:
Okay, given the choice,
would you rather have your brain
in a beetle's body
or a beetle's brain
in your body?
Okay, all right,
I'll bite.
If my brain were
in a beetle's body,
then I would be King
of the Beetles,
just like I'm King
of the Lab.
There, what does
that answer tell you?
It tells me you not only feel
like you belong here,
but that this
is your domain
and you love it.
You're a very happy man.
Ah, I can't argue
with any of that.
Contusion on the occipital bone,
roughly 20 millimeters
in diameter.
Staining suggests that
the trauma occurred
around the time of death.
Dr. Brennan prefers we use terms
like "conked on the noggin."
The beetle question also told me
that you're mischievous
and disruptive
by spirit
and willing to lie
for humorous effect.
That conk wasn't enough to kill.
What else did
that beetle question tell you?
You got picked on a lot
in high school, didn't you?
I didn't kill Benji.
Uh, that man was
the love of my life.
So it was Benji
who broke up with you?
Seriously?
Look at me.
I am the one who dumped him.
I thought you said
he was the love of your life.
Yeah. Too bad it wasn't
a reciprocal relationship.
Oh, right.
So there was another woman.
Again, please,
look at me. You really think
that Benji could get a woman
hotter than me? I mean...
(scoffs)
I couldn't compete
with his truck though.
Ever since he saw
that old photo
of his dad posing
with an El Camino,
he decided that he needed
to restore one just like it.
So, what did he do
the rest of the time?
His experiments,
which I did not resent.
Why?
They were
scientific experiments.
Benji was...
(sighs)
wicked smart.
Except when it came
to the stupid truck.
I know some scientists,
and they are specific
about their branch of science.
Time travel.
What?
SWEETS: Benji was into...
time travel? Not time-share,
like condos,
but traveling...
through time?
Yeah. He wanted to be
the first to do it.
Okay, so...
Benji wanted
to be a time traveler,
but you were
mad at him because of a truck?
Duh.
One was gonna make us
a lot of money,
the other was just a stupid truck.
And when was
the last time
you talked to Benji?
Last Saturday night.
We argued.
About the truck?
Courtney, that
was the night
that he was killed.
Did he say anything that could
lead to his killer?
He said he was too busy.
With his truck.
Of course.
His truck.
Would you choose
a truck over this?
Okay, seriously,
but is she crazy enough
to kill someone?
SWEETS:
She seems to display some of
the symptoms of Intermittent
Explosive Disorder.
What does that mean,
she gets mad?
I.E.D. is usually
characterized
by sporadic episodes
of extreme aggression,
violence and
destructive behavior.
Sweets, could she kill him?
If she was at the mercy
of her own anger, yeah.
Yeah.
What are you eating, Dr. Wells?
String cheese.
Do you want
some string cheese?
Eating in the lab
is strictly prohibited.
Whenever I'm working
on a conundrum,
I always eat string cheese.
It started when I was
in grade school
and I was getting ready
for the science fair.
Which I won.
I don't care.
Thought-controlled
prosthetic limbs
and the elimination
of artifact distraction
from E.E.G. signal processing.
I'm pretty sure
you care about that.
I was 13 years old.
We are concerned
with these bones, now.
Nothing more.
Right.
The, uh, cheese made me
think of calcium,
which is important for bone
growth, and that brought
my attention to the scoliosis
from which the victim suffered.
I also found incomplete
perimortem fractures
to the right anterolateral
tibia and fibula.
You got to admit,
I'm pretty impressive.
Until recently
on the isle of Vanuatu,
you could be cannibalized
for disobeying
your tribal chief.
And you could have been forced
to give your child
to my clan to settle
this petty conflict.
You're familiar
with the Vanuatu?
My knowledge is vast.
Which is why I'm here, right?
So, don't try to cherry-pick
facts to win an argument.
Then let's deal with our tribe.
You have not yet
found cause of death.
Finish rearticulating
these bones as ordered
or you will be banished.
Double mocha latte.
Oh, God's perfect food.
I thought that was pizza.
Well, you need something
to wash it down with.
Did you find anything
in Benji's clothes?
Well, a couple of strawberry
seeds in his shoe tread.
Were there any strawberries
on the farm
where he was buried?
No,
but they are grown
pretty much everywhere else.
So it doesn't help much
in determining
what he was doing
on the night
of his death.
Well, how about you?
Well, Courtney's alibi
checked out.
She was hating on a DJ
at a club.
So, I looked into Benji's
hard drive.
It's filled
with headache-inducing
theories on time travel.
Awesome.
Wow.
Time dilation.
Relativistic velocities.
This kid was pretty smart.
He was trying
to go back, not forward.
What difference
does that make?
I mean, this
is all crazy.
Not really.
See, Einstein tells us
that traveling into the future
is theoretically possible,
but visiting the past,
now that gets into causality
and everything
starts falling apart.
Do you think he really thought
that he could do it?
Oh, man, wouldn't you want to?
I would go back
to April 19, 2004.
The moment I first met you.
You had a rubber band
on your wrist,
and a spider on your shoulder.
(laughs)
That's right. What about you?
If you could go back,
what moment would you choose?
I would choose that one.
I would choose that...
I would choose that same moment.
You had to take a minute
to think about that.
Are you sure?
Yes, I am... I'm sure.
Give me this.
One other thing that I found.
Benji was spending
a lot of time
on the Collindale
University server.
Which is very weird, because
he wasn't a student there.
He was logged in as
Professor Scott Hunter.
Hunter. He's a
theoretical physicist.
You know, a lot of Benji's math
was pretty sophisticated.
I wonder if they were
working together on that.
On time travel?
Yeah, theoretical physicists
can be pretty weird.
I'll tell Booth
to look into Hunter.
You sure you didn't want to go
back to some other time?
Nope.
That time.
Yeah, okay.
(chuckles)
Okay.
SWEETS: People become obsessed
with time travel
either because they're missing
something or they're running
away from something.
Well, according to his brother,
Benji had a pretty
rough childhood.
I mean, come on, why would
anyone want to revisit that?
Because that's
where he felt that he lost
a part of himself.
I think he wanted
to go back
to stop his dad from leaving.
What, he was trying to save his
family from falling apart?
Yes. Exactly.
Look, everyone at some point
has wanted to go back.
I... I wish I could,
to see the Finleys again.
The couple
that adopted me.
They saved my life, and I was...
a kid, I...
I gave them a rough time,
I don't know.
I just wish I could go back
and let them know
how much I appreciate them.
They know.
Um, you said
you found something?
Yeah.
This guy, uh,
Professor Hunter,
might be someone else
who's looking for a do-over.
Taught physics at Collindale
till two years ago,
when he was fired
for electrocuting a student.
He was also
supposed to meet Benji
the night he was killed.
WELLS:
Dr. Brennan, given the choice,
would you rather be run over
by one steamroller
or by 1,000 mopeds?
Why would you ask
such a preposterous question?
Dr. George did
psychological experiments
at Cambridge on bias
and judgment formation....
I don't like psychology.
And I'm not the one
we're studying here.
Sorry.
Would that be one moped
1,000 times,
or 1,000 mopeds at once?
It doesn't matter.
You'd choose the steamroller.
By the time it had
run over your legs,
you'd already
be dead from shock.
It fits in with your
hyper-rational outlook.
Please don't pretend
to know how my mind works.
You shy away from randomness,
and that prevents you
from casting a wide net.
Are you saying
that I'm narrow-minded?
Your words, not mine.
That's interesting.
There appears to be
microfracturing
to the anterior
and posterior aspects
of right sternal ribs
nine and ten.
As well as the anterior aspect
of the right
vertebral ribs 11 and 12.
So whatever created
this damage also created
some pretty horrific damage
to the liver as well.
Which would have certainly
caused his death.
Didn't Agent Booth
say that the professor
that Benji was working with
once electrocuted a student?
If a current passed through
the thoracic region
with enough voltage,
it could certainly
have created
the fracturing on the bone.
No wide net needed.
BRENNAN:
Professor Hunter got fired
for electrocuting a student.
Losing university resources
could drive Hunter
to start working
with outsiders such as Benji.
Experiment that goes wrong,
Benji gets electrocuted.
And knowing that he
could be convicted
of negligent homicide,
Hunter decides to,
what, dump the body.
You're casting a wide net.
Huh?
By positing various motives.
I don't do that, apparently.
Rather be run over
by a steamroller.
What?
You want to be run
over by a steamroller?
Yes.
Instead of a thousand
mopeds, of course.
I'm-I'm... what am I
hearing right now?
Am I having a stroke?
Dr. Wells
defined me, with ease.
I don't like that.
Even if he's correct.
I'd love to help
you here, Bones,
but I really
have absolutely
no idea what you're
talking about.
It's fine, Booth.
Maybe Dr. Wells is right.
Maybe I'm narrow-minded.
(mouths)
No.
No. What?
BRENNAN: Odd for a professor
of theoretical physics
to be working with someone
without a degree.
Benjamin read an
article I had written.
He knew I was
conducting experiments
in time travel and
wanted to help.
So, what, he just show up
at your doorstep one day?
Basically, yes.
It was about a year ago.
We've been working
together ever since.
Including the night
that he died.
We've pinpointed time of death.
You think I killed Benjamin?
Well, I mean,
accidents do happen,
but you know that all too well,
now, don't you, Professor?
This is ludicrous.
You can't be serious.
Sometimes these accidents
are just so big,
you just try to cover them up,
isn't that right?
We need to see
your lab, Professor.
HUNTER:
At-at least put on a gown.
You're contaminating
the entire facility.
Please, Dr. Brennan,
from one scientist
to another.
That's for my
metamaterial experiment.
Please don't touch that.
Whoa.
BOOTH: Oh. Exposed wiring.
You seem to make a habit
out of being
negligent, Professor.
BRENNAN:
This is a
240-volt battery.
If Benji came into contact
with these wires,
it could have
created the fracturing
we found on his ribs.
(electricity crackles)
Professor was cooking with some
serious fire
with these batteries.
240 volts to the chest
could definitely be responsible
for Benji's death,
but was it enough
to crack his ribs?
Well, that's what we're
here to find out,
my brother from another mother.
See, this ordnance gel
has been calibrated
to absolutely replicate
human tissue, so we can see
if the ribs crack
when they're electrocuted.
You certainly
love your job, huh?
See, I always get
bored so easily,
which is why keep accumulating
all these degrees.
Which explains your hope
that time travel exists,
because that would
not be boring.
Yeah, well,
I would not go back, though.
I'd keep my past
in the past.
Whoa, it's like
you're hiding something.
No, it's just,
what's done is done.
There's so much more money
to be made in the future.
I wouldn't go that far forward.
Just, like, five years.
Vernor Vinge's
theory of exponential
accelerating change, huh?
Exactly, and that
pretty much guarantees
some pretty sweet
technological advances.
So, you would travel
to the future,
steal their technology,
then bring it back here
to the present
and make a fortune?
Well, there's no legal precedent
for time travel,
so I wouldn't exactly
say I was stealing.
Well, being
that we are
evidence-based here,
I think you should
keep that one to yourself.
Okay. Ready?
Yeah.
Zip up.
Put this on.
Thank you.
Okay.
Ready?
Fire in the hole!
Technically, it's not a fire
until the amps make sure the...
WELLS:
Maybe, uh,
next time, protective
eyewear, I think?
Yeah.
Yeah. Maybe?
Fair enough.
(clears throat)
Wow. We just hit this
guy with enough current
to take down an elephant.
Still no fracturing of the ribs.
Yeah.
Meaning that Benji was not
killed by electrocution.
WELLS: Thought. Have
you considered
hydrostatic shock?
You're talking about doing
another experiment, aren't you?
Perhaps I am your brother
from another mother.
(laughs)
So, the professor said
that there was a call made
to Benji's cell phone
on Saturday night,
and there was, but
the caller used a
disposable cell.
Benji was at the professor's
place in Silver Spring
when he got the call.
The FBI
said the victim borrowed cash
from Professor Hunter,
and withdrew cash
from two ATMs.
One here,
and the second here,
farther outside the city.
So, Benji was leaving town,
and collecting money as he went.
The body was
found here
in Brookmont.
So, why was Benji at an ATM
up in North Bethesda?
Cam,
if time travel existed,
and you could make one trip,
what would it be?
You mean, like,
have tea with Jesus,
or strangle Hitler
in his crib?
Or redo something
from your own life
when you were happiest.
(laughs):
What is it?
I can't.
Oh, come on!
Do you remember your ex-husband?
Oh, my God! Birimbau?
I am sorry.
I would do the
same thing.
The same guy, I mean.
Oh, my God.
Would you tell your
significant other the truth,
or would you...?
Oh, I would tell him that...
I wanted to have tea with Jesus.
Oh.
Excuse me?
Hi.
I ran a spectroscopic analysis
of the strawberry seeds and soil
found in the sole
of Benji's shoe. Could you...?
Yes, yes.
Now, the shoe soil is
very deficient in calcium.
But his body was found in soil
extremely rich in calcium.
So, the body was moved
after he was killed?
Yeah, he was killed
in serpentine soil.
It's very rare, but there are
some deposits here in Rockville.
That is a
strawberry farm near Rockville.
Tell Booth.
HODGINS: Cam,
I actually came in here
to ask you for a gun.
Okay.
HODGINS:
I wanted to shoot the gun.
Well, I am the one
authorized to shoot the gun.
My only question is, why?
The microfracturing on
the victim's ribs did not occur
due to electrical shock,
but the waves in the gel made me
think of hydrostatic shock.
See, the high rate of speed at
which a bullet enters the body
causes displacement in
the liquids surrounding it.
So we believe that if the victim
was shot just below
the rib cage,
this expansion could have
created the microfracturing.
Okay.
Fire in the hole!
That's my...
That's my line.
Ah.
It worked.
SAROYAN:
The victim was shot.
Wow. It is good to have
a physicist
in the house.
What?
I... It's...
(crickets chirping)
BRENNAN: The house
is completely boarded up.
Doesn't look like anyone's
lived here for quite some time.
Really? Then why is there
a light on in the barn?
All right, enough.
Can you keep that down?
Oh, easy. Easy, easy.
Yeah. Looks like
someone broke in.
Well, looks like
Benji's truck.
I think it's more
of a car, to be honest with you.
Booth?
Yeah.
BOOTH: That's a lot of blood
for one person.
Benji may have
also been killed here.
Rugged nuchal area
on the cranium,
as well
as the convoluted sutures,
suggest the victim
was an Hispanic male.
Like Benji.
Victim appears
to have suffered
projectile trauma to the
inferior right thoracic region.
Like Benji.
Texturing of the
sternal rib ends
indicates an age
of mid-to-late 40s
Bones, I mean,
you're describing Benji,
but 20 years older.
The victim suffered a
single gunshot wound
to the inferior right
thoracic region.
Huh.
And judging by the marbling
and skin slippage,
I'd say he's been dead
about six days?
Double huh.
I'm sorry.
Why the double huh, Dr. Wells?
Because
I believe that our two victims
may be the same person.
Excuse me?
WELLS: Quantum physics
tells us
that out there somewhere
is a world 20 years
ahead of this one, right?
Theoretically.
Now, assuming that Benji
is a time traveler
from the future...
Big assumption.
When he transports himself
back here,
he changes the course
of his destiny in this time.
So, when younger Benji
gets shot, future Benji
must then take a bullet
to satisfy the variable
of causality.
Is this necessary?
You said that you believe
time travel is impossible.
Just because
something is
theoretically impossible
doesn't mean
that it's not possible.
I believe
that is exactly what it means.
Well, of course you do,
because your mind stops working
when it hears
the word impossible,
where mine just keeps going
and exploring.
If you believe that the
two victims are the same person,
you don't belong in this lab.
Of course I don't believe that.
That's absurd.
Excellent. Moving on.
But I do embrace
the impossible probability
as a reality.
I mean, what serious
scientist wouldn't?
I found a contusion
on the frontal bone,
roughly 20 millimeters
in diameter.
Which suggests
this man was struck
on the head around
time of death.
Just like... our first victim.
I believe
that warrants a triple huh.
BOOTH:
This guy-- he is a jackass.
Okay? He's gonna be gone
when this case is over.
Maybe Dr. Wells has a point, though.
(scoffs)
Just because we can't travel
through time right now
doesn't mean that we
can't do it in the future.
Okay, well, then, why aren't
these future-seeing people here,
and they're not
rewriting the past,
or betting
on football games then?
Okay, I don't have
all the answers.
I'm just trying to
cast a wider net.
Okay, well, here's
where I'm casting mine.
So, these guys--
they met at a remote place.
There were burner cells
that were involved.
There was cash
that we never found.
Suggesting an illegal
transaction that ends in death.
But the only thing
I don't understand is,
why the killer took Benji's body
and buried it in another farm.
Well, clearly,
we need a wider net.
Hmm. This guy Wells--
did he mention anything
about the asteroid mining?
(sighs)
What?
Booth.
I'm just curious.
(phone ringing)
Really?
Yeah.
Brennan.
Sorry to interrupt your lunch,
but I found something on the
second victim's right patella.
Oh, a comminuted fracture.
Right. I placed the bone
under a microscope,
and at 40 times
magnification,
I found evidence
of slight remodeling.
So, he was probably
walking or limping
on this injury
for several few days.
That is a severe break.
The man must have been
in immense pain.
Right. Yet, instead
of going to a hospital,
he was hanging out in a barn?
See, I'm thinking,
he didn't go to the hospital
because he couldn't.
He couldn't jeopardize
anybody knowing
that he was from the future.
Or perhaps there is
a more logical explanation.
The victim suffered
from a minor case of scoliosis.
Just like Benji.
Right. And Scoliosis is
a hereditary disease,
which suggests that both
victims might be related.
Sorry to disappoint you,
Dr. Wells.
DNA results confirm that our
second victim is Benji's father.
Sounds reasonable.
GARCIA: First you tell me
my little brother's dead.
Now you're telling me
my father's dead, too?
I'm sorry for your loss.
Yeah.
Thanks.
I can't believe this.
You told Agent Booth
that your father left
when you and Benji were young.
Were you aware that, um,
Benji's been in contact
with your dad?
No. Benji would have told me.
It must have been
a one-time thing.
How can you be so sure of that?
'Cause Benji thought
our dad was dead.
Why would he think that?
Benji was little
when Felix left.
Rather than tell him
his dad was a deadbeat junkie,
Mom and I decided
to tell him that Felix was dead.
When was the last time
you saw your father?
Years ago.
And that was fine with me.
Now, if your father
was still an addict,
do you think
that could explain why
he reached out to Benji
last Saturday night?
Had to be.
That son of a bitch
was probably in trouble
with one of his dealers.
He needed Benji
to bail him out.
WELLS:
The bullet that entered Felix
nicked the sternal end
of the inferior tenth,
and then, went on
to lodge itself
into the superior margin
of the 11th rib.
There could be two shooters.
Or the victims were
on the ground,
and the killer just
stood over them and shot.
Which would also explain the
damage to both of their skulls.
This is a pretty
easy explanation. Sorry.
I realize that you might
think that I'm crazy
like Yoshiro Nakamatsu
or Tycho Brahe,
but without them,
we wouldn't have the laws
of planetary motion
or the simple taxi meter.
(sighs) It's not crazy that I'm worried
about, actually.
It's arrogance.
We're a team here,
and you can be traded.
Wherever I go I'm always
the smartest person,
and it always creates problems.
Well, maybe you should try
being less of a douche.
Could you please rotate
both sets of remains
90 degrees to the left?
Yes.
But you can't.
Hmm. Well,
you were wrong
about the skull damage.
They were both hit
with the other's head.
Oh, my God.
I really hate to
say this, but
you are actually right.
In this position, the trajectory
of both bullet wounds now...
lines up.
It does. Perfect.
Do I look humble?
I'm trying to be less
of a douche.
BOOTH:
Ford's Theatre, 1865. Yep.
But you said that time travel
was impossible.
It is impossible.
I'm saying if it isn't, okay?
Then, like, a movie
or something.
You'd... stop Lincoln
from being shot?
Yeah, I would.
I mean, he deserved to...
know that everything
turned out pretty well. I mean,
I could do it. Even if it
meant that, you know, I had to
put a bullet in, uh,
Booth's head.
But then you might not
have been...
Yeah, I know, Bones,
but it's impossible.
Al right, what about you? If you
could travel through time,
where would you go?
I'm already there.
Here.
What? Here?
The difference
between past and future
is nowhere to be found
in the laws of physics.
Everything I want or need
is here.
Right now.
Wow. Right here?
Mm-hmm.
Right now?
(phone rings)
(groans)
Booth.
Right.
Yeah, okay,
and you're sure?
Yeah, I-I'll be right down.
Looks like we got
Felix Garcia's drug dealer.
According to Alex, the father
had been using for years.
He must've had
multiple dealers.
Yeah, but here's
the kicker, okay?
The dealer also works
at Alex's body shop.
So he has a connection
to both victims.
Must not be a very good dealer
if he has to work a second job.
Yeah, well,
killing your customer?
That's bad for business, too.
BOOTH: So, how long have you been
dealing heroin, Sidney?
I don't do that.
I got busted in 2009
and got off with probation.
I took it as a sign
and I retired.
Right. You know what this is?
Looks like a tactical baton.
Found it in the trunk of your car.
I don't know, man.
I go to some pretty
sketchy neighborhoods.
You use it recently?
Nope.
Maybe on the kneecap
of a Felix Garcia?
Nope.
Do you even know a Felix Garcia?
No, okay. Let me
fill you in, okay?
He owed you money
for heroin.
He didn't pay you,
so what do you do?
You whacked him
in the kneecap with this.
He ran and he hid, and he got
his son Benji to pay you off,
but you shot them both.
No.
Which part?
You have an alibi
for last Saturday night?
Mm... no.
You're gonna need a lawyer, pal.
Why do I need a lawyer?
I think I'm doing pretty great
on my own.
WELLS:
The two striations
on Felix's knee
are one millimeter apart,
and they correspond precisely
with the millimeter-sized divot
at the end
of Jouron's baton.
But if we hope to convict him,
we need to tie his baton
to perimortem damage.
Benji Garcia
sustained this other injury
at or very near time of death.
Can you tie this to
his baton as well?
What are your thoughts
on asteroid mining, Dr. Wells?
Well, uh,
it'll definitely happen.
Robotic technologies
have advanced to the point
where they can be
self-repairing, and...
near-Earth asteroids
like 4660 Nereus
are practical candidates for
strip and magnetic extraction.
Financially speaking,
the key is to invest early.
If my minor in economics
is worth anything, yes.
No striations.
The baton
was not used
to inflict this damage.
So we're looking
for another weapon.
WELLS: Look at the compression and
the bending around the breaks.
What kind of weapon
could come down
with this kind of force
at a 45-degree angle?
SWEETS:
So, Jouron busted
Felix's kneecap.
Yeah, I mean, days
before either murder.
Okay, so, tell me again why you
want to talk to Alex Garcia.
When I asked him when he last
saw his father, he stood up.
That means something.
Yeah, it means he's got
a cramp in his leg.
Or it means he was fleeing
the question. Symbolically.
If so, he's hiding
something.
Mr. Garcia,
we got a warrant here
to look through
Sidney Jouron's locker.
Were you aware
that he deals drugs?
He used to.
I gave him a job here as part
of his early release.
I'll open his locker for you.
SWEETS: Uh, so,
I've been thinking
about you and your father...
(cries out)
Okay, that cannot
be a coincidence.
There's something going on
with his dad.
I haven't seen my dad in years.
These doors here,
what angle do they-they
come down on?
45 degrees. Why?
45 degrees.
What's that got
to do with my dad?
You slammed your brother's leg
in the car door, didn't you?
After he was dead.
You're saying I killed him?
I loved my brother.
Why would I do that?
We're gonna find traces of blood
in the seat, aren't we, Alex?
SWEETS:
I can see it all happen.
Your dad got his drugs
from Sidney.
He didn't pay his debts.
Sid busts up his leg,
so he comes to you two guys
for help.
Now, Benji thought your dad
was dead so, unlike you,
he was thrilled
to see him.
Benji was gonna give
your dad the money,
so you followed him to the barn.
You didn't want to shoot Benji,
but he stepped in the way.
To protect his father.
He was gonna give the old man
his college money.
I couldn't let him do that.
I never meant for...
All he ever wanted
was to go back in time
and to meet his old man.
He got his wish.
And look what happened.
BRENNAN (over computer):
The extensive amount
of fracture lines are indicative
of a weapon
with a circular cross-section.
Hey. Usually when we catch
a bad guy, we go home.
Oh, yeah, I'm just trying
to commit to memory everything
that I learned
from Dr. Brennan.
Uh, take my advice--
get a notebook.
Oh, it's okay. I have
a photographic memory.
Okay. (chuckles)
Good night.
See you.
We caught the murderer,
Dr. Wells. You can go home.
Yeah, see, I'm just
a little concerned
that we may have caught him
because of good luck.
There's no such thing as good luck.
Well,
as I understand it,
if Agent Booth hadn't brought
Dr. Sweets along
and they hadn't seen Alex Garcia
get clunked on the head,
then we never would've
caught the guy.
That's not luck; that's teamwork.
It's the fact
that you don't believe in luck
that doesn't
let you see the role
that it played
in this investigation.
Nonsense. We've been working
together a long time.
And since you have a degree
in complicated systems
and imaginary numbers,
you know that what appears
to be synchronicity--
luck-- is nothing more
than a sophisticated array
of cause and effect.
I, uh...
I don't have a degree
in complicated systems.
Oh, well, we all have
our areas of weakness.
Good night, Dr. Wells.
Are you saying
that I'm lacking?
BOOTH (laughing):
That's funny.
Well, I didn't tell you
that to make you laugh.
Well... (chuckles)
I confess that in a moment
of weakness,
I took the opportunity
to make...
Dr. Wells feel bad
about himself.
He deserves it.
Trust me.
It's probably the first time
he's met someone
that's smarter than him.
You're referring to me?
Yes.
I have another confession.
Mm-hmm?
It's possible that...
I'm not smarter than he is.
(clears throat)
Really?
He saw the merit in your
get rich scheme before I did.
Ah, the asteroid mining. Yes!
Yes.
I invested $10,000.
Yeah, but wait a second.
I didn't put any money
into that at all.
Why not?
Because you're the smarter one.
I'm going
to point out that if I'd
trusted you from the beginning,
I would've invested
in the asteroids
and I would've been
ahead of Dr. Wells.
Right, so...
(clears throat)
logically speaking,
that makes me the smarter one.
No argument there?
I'm thinking.
Ah, I hear nothing but asteroids.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
What that mean?