Previously on:
So, what have you
been up to?
I started a new
software company
with my old partner
Billy Stanhope.
You really think we can finally
build the electric suitcase?
Yes. We have the technology now.
Something you should know.
It's about your ex-wife.
What, Bridget?
Yeah. I'm, uh...
kind of sleeping with her.
What?
Wait! Hey!
Morning.
It's 2:00 p.m.
So?
It's Saturday; I slept in.
It's Sunday.
Really?
That's disturbing.
So what did you do last night
that you had to sleep all day?
One thing at a time.
I'm still trying to figure out
what happened to Saturday.
Jake, you're gonna graduate
high school in a few days.
Don't you think it's time
to start getting
your life together?
I will if you will.
What?
I will certainly
consider that, Father.
This is serious.
You will never amount to
anything if you sleep all day.
WALDEN:
Morning.
I'm sorry, I was distracted
by the naked billionaire
that just woke up.
Shut up and eat
your damn cereal.
♪ Men, men, men, men, manly men,
men, men ♪
♪ Ah. ♪
♪ Men. ♪
♪ Two and a Half Men 9x24 ♪
Oh Look! Al-Qaeda!
Original Air Date on May 14, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Man, I did not think Jeremy
was ever gonna stop talking.
Yeah.
That guy really puts the "dict"
in "valedictorian."
Thinks he's so great just
'cause he's going to Harvard.
Where is Harvard anyway?
Dude, didn't you learn
anything in high school?
It's the capital of Connecticut.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Harvard, Connecticut.
What'd you think
was the capital of Connecticut?
"C."
(laughs)
You're an idiot.
I don't know why
I hang out with you.
'Cause you're gay.
Well, what does that make you?
Attractive.
So are your parents giving you
a hard time about your "future"?
Oh, yeah.
Both my mom and my dad.
I'm sick of hearing it.
Yeah. "If you're not going to
college, you need to get a job""
Where do they
get this stuff?
Beats me.
So what are we gonna do?
About what?
Our future.
Oh.
I could go for
some frozen yogurt.
Good idea, man.
Let's go.
Should we take
our robes off?
No, no, leave them on.
They'll attract smart chicks.
Come on, Judith.
He's your son too.
I have videotape of him
shooting out of your body.
Yes, I've talked to him
about his lack of plans,
but it's like talking to a wall.
A very good-natured,
but dense wall.
Of course I'm concerned,
but what do you want me to do?
No, I'm not gonna ask Walden
to give him a job.
Because it would
be an imposition.
Yes, more of an imposition
than me living there for free.
Okay, okay, if it'll get you
to shut up, I'll ask him.
She's never
gonna shut up.
Okay, okay.
Good-bye, Judith.
(scoffs)
I am so thankful
I have you in my life.
What about my son?
What about him?
You're gonna ask Walden for a
job for Jake, but not Eldridge?
Of course not.
I was just gonna hold Eldridge
back to sweeten the deal.
BILLY:
I have a question.
What?
Why didn't you order
adjustable chairs?
I did.
Mine's adjustable.
Well, wait.
How'd you do that?
This lever right here.
I don't have a lever.
Hmm?
Well, that's too bad,
you being so short and all.
You did this to get back at me.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
For sleeping with your ex-wife.
Do you really think
that I am so petty
that I would pay a chair
manufacturer an extra $480
to remove the adjustable
height feature?
That is crazy talk.
How's everything down there
at the Lollipop Guild?
Hey, guys.
Am I interrupting?
Hey, Alan.
Just thought
I'd bring you by
a little office-warming
dieffenbachia.
Ah, thank you.
Looks like you got the place
up and running.
We're getting there.
Electric Suitcase, Inc.
Very, very impressive.
(laughs)
What can I do for you?
Oh, nothing. I just came
to drop off my gift
and wish you well.
Okay.
Okay, well, I'll get out
of your hair.
Uh, nice to see
you again.
Yep. Always thrill.
Oh, there is one thing.
Here we go.
Um, you know Jake
just graduated high school.
Oh, hey, I'm sorry I couldn't
make it to the ceremony.
Oh, don't be silly.
No one expected you to.
You know what?
Here...
why don't you give this
to him for me.
Ooh, a hundred dollars.
I will make sure he gets this.
What? I-I don't
even know the kid.
Oh, of course not.
(laughs)
Um, anyway, I was
just wondering, um,
since you've started
this exciting venture
and obviously you're hiring,
that there might be
an opportunity here for Jake.
He's not going to college?
Not unless he's
delivering pizzas.
Uh, probably true,
but he has a good heart,
and I'm afraid if I
can't find him a decent job,
he might have to sell it.
Okay, listen, Alan, I'm sorry.
I-I like Jake,
but I just don't think
we have anything for him here.
Oh, oh, okay.
I understand.
You know, he's just my kid.
Our future. But, um,
but thanks anyway.
Oh, wait, wait.
Hold it, hold it.
Yeah? Yeah?
Does he know anything
about computers at all?
Not per se,
but he is eager to learn.
He's like a sponge when it comes
to soaking up information.
No, he isn't.
Will you at least give me
the sponge part?
Yeah, if you lay him
on a wet spot,
he might absorb liquid.
Why are you being
such a jerk, man?
Let's give
the boy a shot.
Billy,
I've seen this kid spend
an entire afternoon
smoking dope and trying
to lick his own nipples.
Who amongst us
hasn't... done...
Look, we will...
we will take him on, okay?
Billy...
He'll be my responsibility.
Oh, thank you so much.
You will not regret it.
Yes, you will.
I will send him right over.
Oh, one more thing,
uh, my girlfriend's son
needs a job too,
but you're gonna love him,
he's...
blonde. Bye.
Okay, I'm telling you
right now,
this is a bad idea.
How did you do that?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Okay, fellas...
this is the heart and soul
of The Electric Suitcase.
300 state of the art,
high bandwidth servers
all working
in tandem.
Cool.
Awesome.
Any questions so far?
Uh, yeah.
Is there a cafeteria
or do we order in?
There's a cafeteria
on the 14th floor.
Oh. Cool.
I got a question.
Yes?
Do they have donuts?
Was I lying?
I don't know if I have donuts.
That's okay.
It's not a deal-breaker.
Glad to hear it.
Uh, okay, guys...
all you have to do
between now
and 8:00 tomorrow morning,
is watch the lights
on these servers, all right?
If a green goes to red,
it means the drive
is about to fail
so all you do...
you pop it out
and you replace it
with a fresh one
from right here.
Got it. No problem.
All right.
Oh, and there's no smoking dope
in this building.
No, sir.
Absolutely not.
Not inside the building.
Or outside the building.
How about the roof?
No.
What about before
we come to work?
No!
What about brownies?
There's no pot, period!
No brownies, no God, no roof,
no outside, no inside.
No problem.
All right.
Good.
Oh, and we just want
to take this opportunity
to thank you both for
this great opportunity.
'Cause let's face it,
it is an opportunity.
And it's great.
Opportunity.
Remember, this is on you.
Oh, and on a personal note,
thank you
for the graduation money.
It's my pleasure.
A kid my age can always
use an extra 50 bucks.
You know,
I kind of like this whole
"working for a living" thing.
It feels good, you know?
Responsible, grownup.
Absolutely.
All right, we have
successfully downloaded
40,000 hours of porn.
That's a lot to watch
two minutes at a time.
I just hope Billy
and Walden don't notice
that we're using
their hard drives.
Don't worry. I've labeled
every movie "personal."
Oh. Good thinking.
Oh, red light. I got it.
Nicely done.
We got this job nailed, my man.
Yeah.
And the best part is,
we are in on the ground floor
of the company.
(beeps)
Oh, another one.
Allow me.
Maybe they'll give us
stock options and we'll be rich.
What exactly is a stock option?
It's a call option on the
common stock of a company,
issued as a form
of cash compensation.
If the company stock rises,
the holder of the option
generally experiences
a direct financial benefit.
Where'd you learn that?
Wikipedia.
It's not just for term papers.
The point is,
we're gonna be rich.
(beeps)
Oh, another one.
Cool. So we'll have
our own planes
and yachts and chicks.
And tons of pot.
Chicks with pot.
Chicks with pot in bikinis.
Naked chicks with pot.
On a yacht.
I like that a lot.
Uh-oh.
That's not good.
Yeah. Why are they all
going bad at the same time?
I don't know.
It's like there's
some sort of virus.
Like the kind you get
when you download too much...
Uh-oh.
Maybe we should call Billy!
No, we can do this!
Okay, we can't do this.
Call Billy!
Hello?
Billy, it's Jake.
(hissing)
I just want to start once again
by saying how grateful we are
for this opportunity.
It's great.
How did this happen?
Oh, I... I don't know.
Well, faulty wiring
or, uh, cheap hardware...
Definitely not
a porn virus.
Shut up.
How could you guys do this?
I went out on a limb for you.
I believed in you.
Well, thank you.
It was... it was a
wonderful opportunity.
Oh, great opportunity.
So, when do we get paid?
(chuckles wryly)
Okay.
Yeah, you can't.
I know their parents.
Hey. What are you guys
doing here?
I thought your shift
didn't end till 8:00 a.m.
Well, we got done early.
Oh. Everything go okay?
I was kind of worried
you might burn the whole place
down or something.
Well, it wasn't "or something."
How am I supposed to find jobs
in the next 24 hours?
Beats me.
It's like our parents
are clueless
about how bad
the economy is.
Yeah.
You know what,
instead of working
for someone else,
we should start
our own business.
I like that.
We could find some
adventure capitalists
and become, um--
what do you call--
entrepraneers.
Yeah. It's not like we
don't have our own good idea.
We have great ideas.
Hey, maybe we can put other
food on a stick and sell it.
Yeah. Pizza on a stick.
Pizza sticks.
Pie.
Pie sticks.
Fish.
Yeah, what are we
going to call those?
Fish-sicles!
Genius!
Yeah.
MAN:
Excuse me.
Did I hear you guys say
you're looking for jobs?
Yeah.
Why?
Maybe it's me.
I'm an idiot magnet.
ALAN:
Hey.
Yup.
Hi.
How you doing?
Not so good.
Yeah, yeah, we heard,
and we're so, so sorry.
So, so very sorry.
Yeah, well, thank God
the files are backed up
and insurance will cover
most of the damage.
That's great news!
Yes. Phew!
(laughing)
You do realize that
your children are not normal.
Well, yeah, but, you know,
what's normal?
And-and in Jake's defense,
he never would have done
anything like this
unless, uh, you know.
(chuckling nervously)
"You know" what, Alan?
Well, I didn't want to,
you know, say anything
but, uh, but clearly there's
a bad influence involved here.
I mean, I don't want
to point any fingers,
but, uh, his name rhymes
with "smeldridge."
(Lyndsey scoffs)
Oh, my God.
You-you can't be serious.
My son had never been in trouble
in his life
until he met your son.
Never been in trouble?
He tried
to counterfeit money
with a computer
and an inkjet printer.
The government dropped
the charges.
Only because
there's no such thing
as a $25 bill.
LYNDSEY:
Yeah? Yeah? Well,
well, what about when Jake stole
your brother's Mercedes
and lost it in Topanga Canyon?
He didn't steal it.
He borrowed it.
And he was only driving it
because my brother was drunk
and someone had to take
his hooker home.
In Topanga Canyon,
which is where she lived.
You are always making excuses
for him.
And you don't excuse Eldridge?
LYNDSEY: Hey, he went through
a very rough divorce.
ALAN:
And Jake didn't?
LYNDSEY: Well, at least your
wife traded up.
Wh-what is that supposed
to mean?
Really?
That was too subtle for you?
Hey, everybody, good news.
You don't have to worry
about us finding work.
You-you got a job?
Yeah. It's not
just a job though.
It's an adventure.
What?
We're gonna be
all we can be.
Oh, oh, no-no, you didn't.
We didn't what?
Join the Army.
Yeah, we joined the Army.
How'd you know?
You need to listen to me.
They are not normal.
Uh, hiya.
Hi.
Looking for a new career?
Um, I'm 44 years old.
That's okay.
Today's Army is all-inclusive.
You can be as old and as gay
as you want.
Uh, well,
that's-that's good to know.
Um, uh, but I-I actually wanted
to talk to you
about my son, Jake Harper.
Harper. Harper.
Oh, yeah,
wants to be a drone pilot.
Yeah, he told me.
He thinks it's like
a video game.
Oh, it is.
It's exactly like a video game.
Except we blow up real people.
Yeah, actually, that's what
I wanted to talk to you about.
Um,
I love my son,
uh, but more importantly,
I love my country,
uh, which is why
I don't think my son
should have access
to flying bombs.
Or really any kind of weapon.
I mean, between you and me,
I've seen him try to pick up
spilled food with a fork
and stab himself in the leg.
And not just once.
I understand your concern,
but our training is unsurpassed.
We take boys
and turn them into men.
I know you think that...
...but you don't know him
like I do.
He's 18, right?
Yeah.
Not currently on probation
or under indictment?
No.
Is this his signature?
Yeah.
Then if he passes the physical,
he's signed, stamped,
and off to camp.
I see.
Oh, look, al-Qaeda!
It's just a copy!
Hey, guys, you like video games?
Congratulations, Jake.
I know I'm only your stepdad,
but I'm real proud of you.
Thanks, Herb.
Were you ever in the Army?
Well, the KISS Army.
But I don't think
that really counts.
You think Mom's ever gonna
stop crying
before I go?
(sobbing quietly)
My guess is no.
Don't worry, Mom.
I'll be fine.
I'm a grown man now.
No, you're not.
You're my bigheaded baby.
(sobbing)
(piano playing
"Pop! Goes the Weasel")
So, Berta,
are you gonna miss me?
Nah, why should I miss you?
You're just an extra
toilet to clean.
That is, when you
hit the toilet.
(piano playing
"Pop! Goes the Weasel")
Don't worry, Grandma.
I'll make you proud of me.
I've always been proud
of you, darling.
In my own way.
(piano playing
"Pop! Goes the Weasel")
Thanks for everything.
Come here.
(piano playing
"Pop! Goes the Weasel")
Look at
the bright side, Dad.
You won't have
to buy me clothes anymore.
They're gonna give me
a dress uniform,
a work uniform, and even one
for when I'm tired.
What?
Yeah, they call 'em "fatigues."
I don't know why they just
wouldn't call 'em pajamas.
Oh, my son, my son.
(piano playing
"Pop! Goes the Weasel")
You be a good boy,
and you do what you're told,
and promise me
you'll be careful.
Don't worry about me.
Worry about
our nation's enemies.
I am worried.
♪ Men. ♪
DRILL SERGEANT:
Come on, you lazy pukes!
Move it! Move it! Move it!
When do we start flying
the robot planes?
(grunting)
(straining):
I don't know.
Maybe after lunch.
No, we're going
on a five-mile run after lunch.
No, I'm gonna skip that.
I want to take a nap.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==