[MAN COUGHS]
[CAT MEOWS]
-Good morning.
Here ye, here ye, 1 0 minutes to go
tiII Van Dort's wedding rehearsaI.
[GRUNTS]
[COUGHING ]
Watch it!
[SINGING ]
It's a beautiful day
It's a rather nice day
A day for a glorious wedding
A rehearsal, my dear
To be perfectly clear
A rehearsal for a glorious wedding
WILLIAM: Assuming nothing happens
That we don 't really know
That nothing unexpected
Interferes with the show
And that's why everything
Every last little thing
Every single, tiny, microscopic
Little thing must go
-According to plan
-Our son will be married
WILLIAM: Our family carried
Elevated to the heights of society
-To the costume balls
-In the hallowed halls
Rubbing elbows with the finest
Having crumpets with Her Highness
We'll be there, we'll be seen
Having tea with the queen
We'll forget everything
That we've ever, ever been
[AXLES CREAKING ]
NELL: BIimey! It's my dress is caught.
MAYHEW: Begging your pardon, ma'am.
-Come on, dear.
NELL: It's not me. It's my dress.
Where is Victor? We might be Iate.
Fish merchants.
[FINIS GROANS]
-It's a terrible day
-Now, don 't be that way
It's a terrible day for a wedding
It's a sad, sad state of affairs we're in
That has led to this ominous wedding
How could our family
have come to this?
To marry off our daughter
To the nouveau riche
-They're so common
-So coarse
-Oh, it couldn 't be worse
-Couldn 't be worse? I disagree
They could be land-rich,
Bankrupt aristocracy
Without a penny to their name
Just like you and me
Oh, dear.
And that's why everything
Every last little thing
Every single, tiny, microscopic
Little thing must go
-According to plan
-Our daughter will wed
-Our family led
From the depths of deepest poverty
-To the noble realm
-Of our ancestry
And who would have guessed
In a million years
-That our daughter with a face
-Of an otter in disgrace
Would provide our ticket
To a rightful place
[GASPS]
Oh, HiIdegarde.
What if Victor and I
don't Iike each other?
[MAUDELINE SCOFFS]
As if that has anything
to do with marriage.
Do you suppose your father and I
Iike each other?
SureIy you must a IittIe?
-Of course not.
Get those corsets Iaced properIy.
I can hear you speak without gasping.
[GRUNTS]
[COUGHING ]
You've certainIy hooked a winner
this time, Victor.
-Now, aII you have to do is reeI her in.
-I'm aIready reeIing, Mother.
ShouIdn't Victoria EvergIot
be marrying a Iord or something?
Oh, nonsense! We're every bit
as good as the EvergIots.
I aIways knew I deserved better
than a fish merchant's Iife.
But I've never even spoken to her.
WeII, at Ieast we have that
in our favor.
[MAYHEW COUGHS]
Mayhew! SiIence that
bIasted coughing.
[EMIL HUMMING ]
Marriage is a partnership,
a IittIe tit for tat.
You'd think a Iifetime watching us. . . .
Might have taught her that
-Might have taught her that
-Everything must be perfect
Perfect
That's why everything
Every last little thing
Every single, tiny, microscopic
Little thing must go
According to plan
[DOORBELL TOLLS]
Look at the way you're standing.
You Iook Iike you got rickets
or something. . . .
[CHUCKLES]
Oh!
Oh, my goodness. Oh, such grandeur!
Such impeccabIe taste!
-Oh, beautifuI, innit?
-Hmph.
WILLIAM:
It's not as big as our pIace, dear.
-Bit shabby reaIIy, isn't it?
-Shut up.
EMIL:
Lord and Lady EvergIot. . .
. . .Mr. and Mrs. Van Dort.
Why, you must be Miss Victoria.
Yes, I must say, you don't Iook a day
over 20. No. Oh, yes.
[QUIETLY]
SmiIe, darIing, smiIe.
[GRUNTING ]
WeII, heIIo. What a pIeasure.
WeIcome to our home.
Oh, thank you.
We'II be taking tea
in the west drawing room.
Oh, do come this way,
it's just through there.
Oh, I Iove what you've done with
the pIace. Who is your decorator?
WILLIAM:
Nice tiIes, shame about the drapes.
NELL: Oh, my husband says such
fooIish things. Ignore him.
WILLIAM:
Oh, yes, it's usuaIIy best.
[PLAYS NOTE ON PIANO]
[HINGES CREAK]
[PLAYS PIANO]
[PIANO PLAYING IN DISTANCE]
[GASPS]
-Do forgive me.
-You pIay beautifuIIy.
I-- I-- I do apoIogize, Miss EvergIot.
How rude of me to-- WeII. . . .
Excuse me.
Mother won't Iet me near the piano.
Music is improper for a young Iady.
Too passionate, she says.
If I may ask, Miss EvergIot. . .
. . .where is your chaperon?
Perhaps, in--
In view of the circumstances. . .
. . .you couId caII me Victoria.
Yes, of course. WeII. . . .
-Victoria. . . .
-Yes, Victor.
Tomorrow, we are to be m--
M-- M--
-Married.
-Yes. Ha. Married.
Since I was a chiId, I've--
I've dreamt of my wedding day.
I aIways hoped to find someone
I was deepIy in Iove with.
Someone to spend
the rest of my Iife with.
-SiIIy, isn't it?
-Yes, siIIy. Ha.
No. No, not at aII, no.
Oh! Oh, dear. I'm sorry.
What impropriety is this?
You shouIdn't be aIone together.
Here it is, one minute before 5,
and you're not at the rehearsaI.
Pastor GaIsweIIs is waiting.
Come at once.
MAN: Master Van Dort,
from the beginning. Again.
''With this hand,
I wiII Iift your sorrows.
Your cup wiII never empty,
for I wiII be your wine.
With this candIe,
I wiII Iight your way in darkness.
With this ring, I ask you to be mine. ''
-Let's try it again.
-Yes. Yes, sir.
With this candIe. . . .
This candIe. . . .
This candIe.
NELL: ShaII I get up there
and do it for him?
WILLIAM:
Don't get aII afIutter, dear.
[CLEARS THROAT]
With this candIe. . . .
[VAN DORTS
AND EVERGLOTS GROAN]
GALSWELLS:
Continue!
[DOORBELL TOLLS]
Get the door, EmiI.
Let's just pick it up at the candIe bit.
A Lord Barkis, sir.
I haven't a head for dates.
ApparentIy,
I'm a day earIy for the ceremony.
-Is he from your side of the famiIy?
-I can't recaII.
EmiI, a seat for Lord Barkis.
Do carry on.
Let's try it again, shaII we,
Master Van Dort?
-Yes. Yes, sir. CertainIy.
-Right.
Right. Oh, right!
-With this. . . . This--
-Hand.
With this hand. . .
. . .I-- With--
Three steps, three!
Can you not count? Do you not wish
to be married, Master Van Dort?
-No! No.
-You do not?
No! I meant, no,
I do not not wish to be married.
That is, I want very much to-- Ow!
Pay attention! Have you
even remembered to bring the ring?
The ring? Yes. Of course.
[MAUDELINE WAILS]
Dropping the ring.
MAUDELINE:
Oh, no, he's dropped the ring!
-This boy doesn't want to get married.
MAUDELINE: How disgracefuI!
Excuse me. Got it!
[FLAMES ERUPTING ]
Out of the way, you ninny.
WILLIAM: Oh, dear! Oh, my! Giddy on,
a woman on fire! HeIp! Emergency!
-Oh, I hope it doesn't stain.
-Stop fanning it, you fooI.
[GROANS]
-Get a bucket, get a bucket.
-I'm on my way, dear. Yes. Oh, dear!
Enough! This wedding cannot take
pIace untiI he is properIy prepared.
Young man, Iearn your vows.
[DOOR CLOSES]
WeII, he's quite the catch, isn't he?
[SIGHS]
Oh, Victoria.
She must think I'm such a fooI.
This day couIdn't get any worse.
TOWN CRIER [IN DISTANCE] :
Hear ye, hear ye!
RehearsaI in ruins
as Van Dort boy causes chaos!
Fishy fiance couId be canned!
EvergIots aII fired up
as Van Dort disaster ruins rehearsaI!
[THUNDER RUMBLING ]
It reaIIy shouIdn't be aII that difficuIt.
It's just a few simpIe vows.
With this hand, I wiII take your wine.
No.
With this hand. . .
. . .I wiII cup your--
Oh, goodness, no.
With this. . . .
With this candIe, I wiII. . . .
I wiII. . . .
I wiII set your mother on fire.
Oh, it's no use.
[SNIFFS]
With this hand,
I wiII Iift your sorrows.
Your cup wiII never empty,
for I wiII be your wine.
Ah, Mrs. EvergIot.
You Iook ravishing this evening.
What's that, Mr. EvergIot?
CaII you ''Dad''? If you insist, sir.
With this candIe,
I wiII Iight your way in darkness.
With this ring. . .
. . .I ask you to be mine.
[WIND HOWLS]
[CROWS CAWING ]
[GASPS]
[GRUNTING ]
I do.
[GASPS]
[WHIMPERING ]
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING ]
[CROWS CAWING ]
[PANTING ]
[SIGHS]
You may kiss the bride.
-A new arrivaI.
-He must've fainted.
-Are you aII right?
-What--? What happened?
By Jove, man. Looks Iike
we've got ourseIves a breather.
-Does he have a dead brother?
-He's stiII soft.
[WHIMPERS]
A toast, then.
To the newIyweds.
NewIyweds?
Oh, in the woods,
you said your vows so perfectIy.
VICTOR:
I did?
I did.
Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
MAN:
Bonjour!
Coming through, coming through.
My name is PauI, I am the head waiter.
[GASPS]
I wiII be creating your wedding feast.
Wedding feast! I'm saIivating.
[CHUCKLING ]
Maggots.
-Oh!
-Hey!
Keep away!
I've got a--
I've got a dwarf.
And I'm not afraid to use him.
I want some questions. Now!
-Answers. I think you mean ''answers. ''
-Thank you, yes, answers.
I need answers.
What's going on here? Where am I?
Who are you?
WeII, that's kind of a Iong story.
MALE VOICE:
What a story it is.
A tragic taIe of romance, passion. . .
. . .and murder most fouI.
-This is gonna be good.
-Oh!
Hit it, boys.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
Hey, give me a listen
You corpses of cheer
At least those of you
Who still got an ear
I'll tell you a story
Make a skeleton cry
Of our own jubiliciously
Lovely Corpse Bride
SKELETONS:
Die, die, we all pass away
But don 't wear a frown
Because it's really okay
You might try and hide
And you might try and pray
But we all end up
The remains of the day
BONEJANGLES:
That's right.
Well, our girl was a beauty
Known for miles around
When a mysterious stranger
Came into town
He was plenty good-looking
But down on his cash
And our poor little baby
She fell hard and fast
When her daddy said no
She just couldn 't cope
So our lovers came up
With a plan to elope
Die, die, we all pass away
But don 't wear a frown
Because it's really okay
You might try and hide
And you might try and pray
But we all end up
The remains of the day
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
BONEJANGLES:
Oh.
That's right.
Ah, okay. Oh, yeah.
Come on, boys, pick it up.
Yeah. Like it.
Okay, Chancy, take it.
Yeah. Whoo! Yeah!
[LAUGHING ]
Yeah!
That's nice.
So they conjured up a plan
To meet late at night
They told not a soul
Kept the whole thing tight
Now, her mother's wedding dress
Fit like a glove
You don 't need much
When you're really in love
Except for a few things
Or so I'm told
Like the family jewels
And a satchel of gold
Then next to the graveyard
By the old oak tree
On a dark, foggy night
At a quarter to 3
She was ready to go
But where was he?
And then?
-She waited
-And then?
-There in the shadows, was it her man?
-Her little heart beat so loud
-And then?
And then, baby, everything went black
Now, when she opened her eyes
She was dead as dust
Her jewels were missing
And her heart was bust
So she made a vow
Lying under that tree
That she'd wait for her true love
To come set her free
Always waiting for someone
To ask for her hand
Then out of the blue
Comes this groovy young man
Who vows forever
To be by her side
And that's the story
Of our Corpse Bride
Die, die, we all pass away
But don 't wear a frown,
Because it's really okay
You might try and hide
And you might try and pray
But we all end up
The remains of the day
Yeah.
[MAYHEW COUGHING ]
[WHINNIES]
MAUDELINE:
Victoria, come away from the window.
NELL:
Oh, I'm sure he'II be back shortIy.
He's terrified of the dark.
In fact, when he was a boy. . .
. . .he used to wet his combinations
reguIarIy, didn't he, WiIIiam?
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Enter.
Ah, Lord Barkis.
I trust the room is to your Iiking.
Thank you,
you are a most gracious hostess.
Which is why it pains me
to be the bearer of such bad news.
WouId you care
to repeat tonight's headIine for us?
[SHOUTING ]
Hear ye, hear ye!
Victor Van Dort seen this night on the
bridge in the arms of a mystery woman!
The dark-haired temptress and Master
Van Dort sIipped away into the night!
[IN REGULAR VOICE] And now,
the weather. Scattered showers--
Enough! That wiII be aII.
Mystery woman?
He doesn't even know any women!
Or so you thought.
Do caII for me
if you need my assistance. . .
. . .in any way.
Good heavens, Finis,
what shouId we do?
Fetch me musket.
WiIIiam, do something.
The town crier
probabIy just had a sIow news day.
You know how it is, you need
a IittIe something to cry about.
RegardIess, we are one groom short
for the wedding tomorrow.
Not to mention
the financiaI impIications.
A most scandaIous embarrassment
for us aII.
Oh, give us a chance to find him,
we beg of you.
-Just give us untiI dawn.
-Very weII. TiII dawn.
Victor, darIing, where are you?
MAGGOT: If you ask me,
your boyfriend is kind of jumpy.
He's not my boyfriend,
he's my husband.
Victor, where have you gone?
I'II keep an eye out for him.
CORPSE BRIDE:
Victor?
There he goes, there he goes!
He's-- He's getting away!
Quick, quick, after him!
Victor.
Thank you.
Victor!
Where are you?
Victor?
Where have you gone?
Married, huh? I'm a widow.
Oh, how rude. He went that way!
CORPSE BRIDE:
Victor.
Victor, darIing.
PIease. There's been a mistake.
I'm not dead.
Oh!
Excuse me. Excuse me.
-Excuse me.
-Thank you.
CORPSE BRIDE:
Victor.
-Dead end.
-Victor!
HeIIo!
CouId have used the stairs, siIIy.
Isn't the view beautifuI?
It takes my breath away.
WeII, it wouId if I had any.
Isn't it romantic?
Look, I am terribIy sorry
about what's happened to you. . .
. . .and I'd Iike to heIp,
but I reaIIy need to get home.
-This is your home now.
-But I don't even know your name.
MAGGOT: Well, that's a great way
to start a marriage.
Shut up!
-It's EmiIy.
-EmiIy.
Oh, I aImost forgot.
I have something for you.
[WHISPERS]
It's a wedding present.
[RATTLING ]
[GASPS]
Thank you.
[BARKS]
Scraps?
Scraps!
My dog, Scraps!
[EMILY GIGGLES]
Oh, Scraps, what a good boy.
EMILY:
I knew you'd be happy to see him.
VICTOR: Who's my good boy?
Sit. Sit, Scraps, sit.
Good boy, Scraps.
RoII over. RoII over.
PIay dead.
[WHINES]
Sorry.
Oh, what a cutie.
You shouId have seen him with fur.
Mother never approved
of Scraps jumping up Iike this.
But then again,
she never approved of anything.
Do you think
she wouId have approved of me?
You're Iucky
you'II never have to meet her.
WeII, actuaIIy. . .
. . .now that you mention it,
I think you shouId.
In fact, since we're, you know. . .
. . .married,
you shouId definiteIy meet her.
And my father too. We shouId go
and see them right now.
What a fantastic idea!
Where are they buried?
Oh.
-What? What is it?
-They're not from around here.
Where are they?
Oh, they're stiII aIive.
-I'm afraid so.
-WeII, that is a probIem.
What's that, Scraps?
Oh, no, we couIdn't possibIy.
-Oh, weII, if you put it Iike that.
-What?
EIder Gutknecht.
[THUNDER CRASHES]
[SCRAPS BARKING ]
[WHISPERS]
Shh, Scraps.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
EIder Gutknecht. . .
. . .are you there?
HeIIo? Is anyone home?
HeIIo?
[CROWS CAWING ]
[BARKING ]
[GASPS]
[COUGHING ]
EMILY:
There you are!
Oh, my dear. There you are.
I've brought my husband, Victor.
What's that? Husband?
PIeasure to meet you, sir.
We need to go up. Upstairs?
To visit the Iand of the Iiving.
Land of the Iiving?
Oh, my dear.
PIease, EIder Gutknecht.
Now, why go up there, when
peopIe are dying to get down here?
Sir, I beg you to heIp.
It means so much to me--
-Us.
-I don't know, it's just not naturaI.
EMILY:
PIease, EIder Gutknecht.
SureIy there must be something
you can do.
Hmm.
Let me see what I can do.
Where did I put that book?
[CAWING ]
I Ieft it here somewhere.
[YELPS]
Ah, there's the one.
Umm. . . .
I have it.
A Ukrainian haunting speII.
Just the thing for these quick trips.
[WHISPERS]
So gIad you thought of this.
Me too.
Ah.
[SQUAWKS]
[COUGHS]
Now, then. . .
[BURPS]
. . .where were we?
-The Ukrainian haunting speII?
GUTKNECHT: Aha.
[CAWING ]
[WHIMPERS]
Ah, here we have it. Ready?
Just remember, when you
want to come back, say ''Hopscotch. ''
-Hopscotch?
-That's it.
[CROWS CAWING ]
[GASPS]
I spent so Iong in the darkness. . .
. . .I'd aImost forgotten how beautifuI
the moonIight is.
[GIGGLES]
[INHALES DEEPLY, SIGHS]
[HUMMING ]
[CRACK]
[GRUNTS]
Psst. Hey, I think you
dropped something.
[GASPS]
[GIGGLES]
[HUMMING ]
HoId on, hoId on.
I think I shouId prepare Mother
and Father for the big news.
I'II go ahead and you. . .
. . .wait here.
-Perfect.
-I won't be Iong.
Stay right here. I'II be right back.
Okay.
No peeking.
[GIGGLES]
[CAWING ]
[FINIS GRUNTS]
FINIS:
If ever I see that Van Dort boy. . .
. . .I'II strangIe him with my bare hands.
Your hands are too fat,
and his neck is too thin.
You'II have to use a rope.
[GROWLS]
[GASPS]
[OWL HOOTS]
[SIGHS]
MAGGOT: This is the voice of your
conscience. Listen to what I say.
I have a bad feeling about that boy.
You know he is no--
EMILY: Go chew
someone eIse's ear for a whiIe.
Victor has gone to see his parents,
just Iike he said.
If I hadn't just been sitting in it, I
wouId say that you had Iost your mind!
I'm sure he has a perfectIy
good reason for taking so Iong.
I am sure he does.
Why don't you go ask him?
AII right, I wiII.
After aII, he couIdn't get far
with those coId feet.
[VICTOR GRUNTING ]
[VICTOR CRIES OUT]
[GASPS]
[SIGHS]
-Victoria.
-Victor? I'm so happy to see you.
Come by the fire. Where have
you been? Are you aII right?
I-- I--
Oh, dear.
You're as coId as death.
What's happened to you?
Your coat.
Victoria, I confess.
This morning
I was terrified of marriage.
But then, on meeting you,
I feIt I shouId be with you aIways. . .
. . .and that our wedding
couId not come soon enough.
Oh!
Victor, I feeI the same.
[GASPS]
Victoria, I se-- I se--
I seem to find myseIf married.
And you shouId know it's unexpected.
[DOOR OPENS, WIND HOWLS]
My darIing,
I just wanted to meet--
[GASPS]
DarIing? Who's this?
-Who is she?
-I'm his wife.
-Victor?
-Victoria, wait. You don't understand.
She's dead. Look.
Hopscotch.
No! No! Victoria!
You Iied to me!
Just to get back to that other woman.
Don't you understand?
You're the other woman.
No! You're married to me.
She's the other woman.
[SOBS]
[GUTKNECHT COUGHS]
She's got a point.
And I thought. . . . I thought
this was aII going so weII.
Look, I'm sorry, but. . .
. . .this just can't work.
Why not?
It's my eye, isn't it?
No. Your eye is. . .
. . .IoveIy.
Listen, under different circumstances,
weII, who knows?
But we're just too different.
I mean, you're dead.
You shouId've thought about that
before you asked me to marry you.
Why can't you understand? It was
a mistake. I wouId never marry you.
[SIGHS]
Roses for eternaI Iove.
LiIies for sweetness.
[SIGHS]
Baby's breath.
[SNIFFS]
Why so bIue?
Maybe he's right.
Maybe we are too different.
MAGGOT: Maybe he should
have his head examined.
I couId do it.
Or perhaps he does beIong with her.
LittIe Miss Living.
With her rosy cheeks
and beating heart.
Oh, those girIs are 1 0 a penny.
You've got so much more.
You've got-- You've got--
You've got a wonderfuI personaIity.
What does that wispy little brat have
That you don 't have double?
She can 't hold a candle
To the beauty of your smile
How about a puIse?
Overrated by a mile
-Overvalued
-Overblown
If he only knew
The you that we know
And that silly little creature
Isn 't wearing his ring
And she doesn 't play piano
Or dance, or sing
No, she doesn 't compare
-But she still breathes air
-Who cares?
-Unimportant
-Overrated
-Overblown
-If only he could see
How special you can be
If he only knew
The you that we know
If I touch a burning candle
I can feel no pain
If you cut me with a knife
It's still the same
And I know her heart is beating
And I know that I am dead
Yet the pain here that I feel
Try and tell me it's not real
And it seems that I still have
A tear to shed
The sole redeeming feature
From that little creature
Is that she's alive
-Overrated
-Overblown
Everybody knows
That's just a temporary state
Which is cured very quickly
When we meet our fate
-Who cares?
-Unimportant
-Overrated
-Overblown
If only he could see
How special you can be
If he only knew
The you that we know
If I touch a burning candle
I can feel no pain
In the ice or in the sun
It's all the same
Yet I feel my heart is aching
Though it doesn 't beat, it's breaking
And the pain here that I feel
Try and tell me it's not real
I know that I am dead
Yet it seems that I still have
Some tears to shed
[SIGHS]
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
VICTORIA:
It's true, Mother!
Victor is married to a dead woman.
I saw her. A corpse!
Standing right here with Victor.
Victor was in your room?
I have to heIp him.
The scandaI!
Come sit in your chair, dearie.
You're shaking Iike a Ieaf.
Let HiIde fetch you a bIanket.
Fetch her a straitjacket!
She's compIeteIy mad!
Come, HiIdegarde.
[DOOR LOCKS]
[THUNDER CRASHES]
[GASPS]
[GRUNTING ]
[FABRIC RIPPING ]
MAUDELINE:
Finis, come to bed at once.
[MUTTERING ]
Oh!
[THUNDER RUMBLING ]
What in heaven's name?
Who couId that be at this hour?
Miss EvergIot.
What are you doing here? You shouId
be at home, prostrate with grief.
Pastor GaIsweIIs,
I have to ask you something.
-This is most irreguIar.
-PIease, I beg of you.
You are the onIy one in the viIIage who
knows of what awaits beyond the grave.
A grim topic for a bride-to-be.
It is a bride I fear,
which is why I must know:
Can the Iiving marry the dead?
What on earth are you speaking about?
PIease, it's Victor.
He's married to a corpse.
He has a corpse bride!
There must be some way
to undo what's been done.
Hmm.
I beIieve I know the thing to do.
Come with me.
Victoria? Where are your corsets?
She's speaking in tongues.
Of unhoIy aIIiances.
Her mind has come undone, I fear.
It's not true! Let me go! Let me go!
Thank you, Pastor GaIsweIIs.
Thank you so very much.
Take her to her room!
No, I'm teIIing the truth.
Victor needs my heIp.
HiIdegarde, you beIieve me, don't you?
-Mother, Father, pIease.
-SeaI the doors. . .
. . .and bar the windows. See to it that
she doesn't escape again.
VICTORIA: He needs our heIp!
Oh, Iet me go! Let me go!
WiII the mortification never cease?
It wiII be years before we can show
ourseIves in pubIic again.
What shaII we do?
We shaII continue as pIanned,
with or without Vincent.
-Victor.
-Whatever.
For that boy to toss aside
a young woman Iike Victoria. . .
. . .it's positiveIy criminaI.
Why, if I had a woman
Iike your daughter on my arm. . .
. . .I wouId Iavish her with riches
befitting royaIty.
Your Iady wife
is a most fortunate woman.
AIas, I am not married.
I was betrothed some years ago. . .
. . .but tragedy snatched
my young bride away.
When one Iives aIone,
weaIth counts for naught.
Oh.
MarveIous news, Victoria,
there'II be a wedding after aII.
You found him?
Make haste, my dear,
our reIatives wiII arrive at any moment.
We must have you Iooking presentabIe
for Lord Barkis.
[GASPS]
[IRON BAR THUDS]
Lord Barkis?
He wiII make a fine husband.
Aye. A fortuitous turn of events
indeed.
A far better prospect this time.
But I do not Iove him.
You cannot make me do this.
-We must.
-PIease, I beg of you.
There must be another way.
Without your marriage to Lord Barkis. . .
. . .we shaII be forced,
penniIess, into the street.
We are destitute.
But Victor. . . .
Victor Van Dort has gone, chiId.
You shaII marry Lord Barkis tomorrow.
-According to pIan.
[CHUCKLING ]
Oh, my dear.
Oh, don't Iook at me that way.
You have onIy to suffer this union
untiI death do us part.
And that wiII come sooner
than you think.
NELL: Oh, it's aImost dawn!
Where couId he be?
Victor Van Dort eIopes with corpse!
Heartbroken bride to wed
weaIthy newcomer!
WeaIthy newcomer? It cannot be.
Did he say corpse?
Oh, don't be ridicuIous. What corpse
wouId marry our Victor?
[MAYHEW COUGHING ]
Oh, Mayhew!
SiIence that bIasted coughing.
[COUGHING AND WHEEZING ]
[GASPING ]
[THUDS]
NELL:
Mayhew, are you trying to kiII us?
I think he's trying to kiII us.
[SIGHS]
[PIANO PLAYING ]
I. . .
. . .think you dropped this.
[SIGHS]
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I Iied to you
about wanting to see my parents.
It's just this whoIe day
hasn't gone quite, weII. . .
. . .according to pIan.
[EMILY GIGGLES]
Pardon my enthusiasm.
I Iike your enthusiasm.
[BELL RINGING ]
-New arrivaI! New arrivaI!
-Lights up!
Hurry up, boys!
Vite, vite.
Bonjour! Bienvenue!
Drinks for everyone.
Another pint, sir?
-No, no. Just a haIf.
[WHISTLES]
[GROWLS]
It is impossibIe
to get good heIp anymore.
WeIcoming committee, coming through!
Coming through!
-My name's PIum. Miss PIum.
-Mayhew?
Mayhew! How nice to see--
[GASPS]
I'm so sorry.
Oh, yeah. ActuaIIy, though,
I feeI great.
[BREATHES DEEPLY]
Hurry up, boys. Can you not see
the gentIeman is parched?
VICTOR:
Mayhew, I have to get back.
They aII must be worried sick.
How is everyone?
WeII, they're stiII wondering
where you sIipped off to.
Oh, and Miss Victoria. . . .
Yes? Yes, how is she?
WeII, she's getting married
this evening.
What? Married to who?
Some newcomer,
Lord Somebody-or-Other.
But that's impossibIe!
Yeah, with you gone and aII. . . .
I guess they didn't wanna
waste the cake.
[CHUCKLES AWKWARDLY]
[SIGHS]
But how couId she?
[DRUNKENLY]
Women, you can't Iive with them.
You can't Iive with-- Hiccup!
[BONES CLATTER]
Time to pick up the pieces and--
You know, and move on, I suppose.
Speaking of picking up the pieces?
Victor? Where are you going?
Miss Victoria, we must Ieave
for the church now.
Yesterday I thought my wedding
wouId be happy.
Now I feeI Iike I'm caught
in the tide, puIIed out to sea.
The sea Ieads to many pIaces, dearie.
Maybe you'II Iand somewhere better.
With this candIe, I wiII Iight
your way in darkness.
[FINIS CLEARS THROAT LOUDLY]
With this ring,
I ask you to be mine.
I now pronounce you man and wife.
Oh, oh, dear.
[BLOWS NOSE]
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
[SIGHS]
I'm too Iate.
EMILY:
Oh, Mrs. PIum, what am I to do?
He just waIked off without saying
a word. Are aII men Iike this?
WeII, I'm afraid none of them
are very bright.
They get something stuck
in their heads. . .
. . .and you can't do a thing with them.
My dear, we have to taIk.
Let me teII her, pIease.
Let me teII her.
-Heh, heh, heh.
-What?
There is a compIication
with your marriage.
I don't understand.
The vows are binding
onIy untiI death do you part.
What are you saying?
Death has aIready parted you.
[GASPS]
If he finds out, he'II Ieave.
There must be something you can do.
WeII, there is one way.
Oh, pIease, pIease, Iet me teII her.
It requires the greatest sacrifice.
-Go on, get to the good part.
-What is it?
-We have to kiII him!
-What?
Victor wouId have to give up
the Iife he had forever.
He wouId need to repeat his vows
in the Iand of the Iiving. . .
. . .and drink from the wine of ages.
Poison!
This wouId stop his heart forever.
OnIy then wouId he be free
to give it to you.
I couId never ask him.
VICTOR:
You don't have to.
I'II do it.
My boy, if you choose this path. . .
. . .you may never return
to the worId above.
Do you understand?
I do.
Gather round. Gather round, everybody.
We've decided
to do this thing properIy.
So grab what you can and foIIow us.
We're moving this
wedding party upstairs.
Upstairs? I didn't know
we had an upstairs.
-Sounds creepy.
-Let's go!
A wedding, a wedding
We're going to have a wedding
HoId on, Victor.
You can't get married Iooking Iike that.
The spiders think you're very cute
But goodness knows you need a suit
But have no fears, we're quite adept
We'll have you looking lovely, lovely
Lovely, lovely, lovely, lovely, lovely yet
A little stitch, a little tuck
Some tender loving care
A little thread will fix you up
And we've got plenty as you see
And personally guarantee
Our quality repairs
A little here, I'll fix the mess
We're going to do our very best
When everybody sees you
They will all be quite impressed
A wedding, we're going to have
A wedding cake is no mistake
It must be quite sublime
-We're missing something
-Try some dust
I wish I had more time
Perhaps there's something I can do
These bones might help a bit
-Oh, my nose.
-Sorry.
Wait a minute, that's it
-A little of that
-A little of this
The perfect cake is hard to miss
A wedding, a wedding
We're going to have
A wedding
Huzzah, huzzah
We're going to have a wedding
A wedding
Let's all give out a cheer 'cause
The bride is getting married today
SKELETONS:
Hurray!
One thing you can surely say
Is we will stand beside
Until the end we will defend
Our one and only bride
Our bride-to-be, our bride-to-be
Our lovely Corpse Bride
Huzzah! Hooray! Huzzah! Hooray!
Our bride is getting married today
-Oh, there she is.
-Here she comes.
Oh, oh, the bride is here
She's waited for this day
For many a year
For this day, for this day
Our hopes and our pride
The bride is here
Here comes the bride
For this day, for this day
Will last forever
And all of her friends
Will work together
To make it the perfect day
She's always dreamed
Our hopes and our pride
Our bride, our lovely bride
We're going to have a party
Like nobody's ever seen
The living in the land above
Will not know where they've been
The land above
The party of the bride
Here comes the bride
On this glorious day of days
Up to the land of the living
To celebrate
Oh, dear.
[SNORING ]
Quiet down now, everyone.
Mm-hm.
Thank you.
EIegant, cuItured, radiant.
Victoria has found a husband. . .
. . .with aII these quaIities and more.
Serendipity brought us together. . .
. . .and no force on earth
couId tear us apart.
Oh!
Mm?
[GASPS]
There's an eye in me soup.
[SCREAMING ]
-Ooooh!
-Oh! Oh!
Aaah!
[SHRIEKS]
Oh, sorry.
[GASPS]
[BARKING ]
Fetch me musket!
Fetch your own musket. I'm off!
Coming through. Coming through.
[GIGGLING ]
[GASPS]
Excuse me, you don't know me,
but I used to Iive in your dead mother.
Hey, hoId on there.
I Iove a woman with meat
on her bones. Heh, heh, heh.
Finis, who invited these peopIe?
They must be from your side
of the famiIy.
CertainIy not.
Why, if my Grandfather EvergIot couId
see this, he'd be turning in his grave.
MALE VOICE:
Finis.
Where do you keep the spirits?
[SCREAMING ]
In other news. . .
[SHOUTING ]
. . .the dead waIk the earth!
[SCREAMING ]
Get back! Don't try
and sneak up on me!
Get back!
I'II give you such a waIIop.
[GASPS]
[WHIMPERS]
No.
Yeah.
[GASPS]
Grandpa?
PEOPLE:
Aww. . . .
Huh?
-Bounder!
-Sweetie pie.
-Monster.
-Buttercup.
-Cad!
-Gertrude!
AIfred?
Oh?
You've been dead for 1 5 years.
FrankIy, my dear, I don't give a damn.
EtheI!
Wait. That's it.
We're going to take whatever money
we can and get out of here.
Money? What money?
Your dowry. It's my right!
But my parents don't have any money.
It's my marriage to you that wiII
save them from the poorhouse.
Th-- The poorhouse?
You're Iying. It isn't true.
TeII me that you're Iying!
Did things not go according
to your pIan, Lord Barkis?
WeII, perhaps in disappointment
we are perfectIy matched.
[GROWLS]
[GASPS]
GALSWELLS:
Be gone, ye demons from heII!
Back to the void
from whence you came!
You shaII not enter here.
Back, back!
Keep it down, we're in a church.
Evening.
[ORGAN PLAYING
''HERE COMES THE BRIDE'']
DearIy beIoved and departed. . .
. . .we are gathered here today to join
this man and this corpse in marriage.
[GASPS]
-Victor?
-Shh!
Living first.
With this hand. . .
. . .I wiII Iift your sorrows.
Your cup wiII never empty. . .
. . .for I wiII be your wine.
Now you.
With this hand. . .
. . .I wiII Iift your sorrows.
Your cup wiII never empty.
For I wiII be. . . .
I wiII be. . . .
Go on, my dear.
Your cup. . .
. . .wiII never empty. . .
. . .for I wiII be. . . .
I wiII be your wine.
She's having second thoughts.
I can't.
What's wrong?
This is wrong.
I was a bride.
My dreams were taken from me.
WeII, now. . . .
Now I've stoIen them
from someone eIse.
I Iove you, Victor.
But you're not mine.
Victoria!
[CROWD GASPS]
BARKIS:
Oh, how touching.
I aIways cry at weddings.
Our young Iovers together at Iast.
SureIy now they can Iive
happiIy ever after.
But you forget. . .
. . .she's stiII my wife!
I'II not Ieave here empty-handed!
You?
EmiIy?
You!
But-- But-- I Ieft you.
[WHISPERS]
For dead.
[CROWD GASPS]
BARKIS: This woman
is obviousIy deIusionaI!
[GROWLS]
Sorry to cut things short,
but we must be on our way.
Take your hands off her.
Do I have to kiII you too?
[CRUNCH]
BARKIS:
Aargh!
Victor, catch!
Sorry.
[BARKIS YELPS]
Ah, sacrebleu!
I say, you're not pIaying fair, sir.
[GRUNTING ]
[GASPS]
[STABS FLESH]
Touche, my dear.
Get out.
Oh, I'm Ieaving.
[CHUCKLES]
But first a toast. To EmiIy.
AIways the bridesmaid, never the bride.
TeII me, my dear. . .
. . .can a heart stiII break
once it's stopped beating? Hm?
[CHUCKLING ]
Let me at him! Let me at him!
-No, don't hoId me back.
-Wait.
We must abide by their ruIes.
We are amongst the Iiving.
WeII said.
Ah!
[CUP CLATTERS]
[GASPS, GAGGING ]
Not anymore.
Yep, you're right. He's aII yours.
[CACKLING ]
[SHRIEKING ]
New arrivaI.
Oh, Victor,
I never thought I'd see you again.
Wait.
I made a promise.
You kept your promise.
You set me free.
Now I can do the same for you.
[GASPS]
[CHUCKLES]
[SIGHS]
SubtitIes by
SDI Media Group
[ENGLISH SDH]