♪ TONIGHT I GOTTA CUT LOOSE
FOOTLOOSE ♪
♪ KICK OFF YOUR SUNDAY SHOES
♪ PLEASE, LOUISE
♪ PULL ME OFF OF MY KNEES
♪ JACK, GET BACK
♪ COME ON, BEFORE WE CRACK
♪ LOSE YOUR BLUES
♪ EVERYBODY CUT FOOTLOOSE
♪ YOU'RE PLAYIN' SO COOL
♪ OBEYIN' EVERY RULE
♪ DIG WAY DOWN
IN YOUR HEART ♪
♪ YOU'RE BURNIN'
YEARNIN' FOR SOME ♪
♪ SOMEBODY TO TELL YOU
♪ LIFE AIN'T PASSIN' YOU BY
♪ I'M TRYIN' TO TELL YOU
♪ IT WILL
IF YOU DON'T EVEN TRY ♪
♪ YOU CAN FLY
IF YOU'D ONLY ♪
♪ CUT LOOSE, FOOTLOOSE
♪ KICK OFF YOUR SUNDAY SHOES
♪ OOH-WEE, MARIE
♪ SHAKE IT
SHAKE IT FOR ME ♪
♪ OH, MILO
♪ COME ON
COME ON, LET'S GO ♪
♪ LOSE YOUR BLUES
♪ EVERYBODY CUT FOOTLOOSE
♪ OH, OH, OH
♪ CUT FOOTLOOSE
CUT FOOTLOOSE ♪
♪ OH, OH, OH
♪ YOU GOT TO TURN IT AROUND
♪ AND PUT YOUR FEET
ON THE GROUND ♪
♪ NOW TAKE A HOLD
OF YOUR SOUL ♪
♪ OH, OH, OH
♪ I'M TURNIN' IT LOOSE
FOOTLOOSE ♪
[Man]
AND HE IS TESTING US.
EVERY, EVERY DAY,
OUR LORD IS TESTING US.
IF HE WASN'T TESTING US,
HOW WOULD YOU ACCOUNT...
FOR THE SORRY STATE
OF OUR SOCIETY?
FOR THE CRIMES...
THAT PLAGUE THE BIG CITIES
OF THIS COUNTRY?
WHEN HE COULD SWEEP THIS PESTILENCE
FROM THE FACE OF THE EARTH...
WITH ONE MIGHTY GESTURE
OF HIS HAND.
IF OUR LORD
WASN'T TESTING US,
HOW WOULD YOU ACCOUNT FOR
THE PROLIFERATION THESE DAYS...
OF THIS OBSCENE...
ROCK AND ROLL MUSIC,
WITH ITS GOSPEL
OF EASY SEXUALITY...
AND RELAXED MORALITY?
IF OUR LORD
WASN'T TESTING US,
WHY, HE COULD TAKE ALL THESE
PORNOGRAPHIC BOOKS AND ALBUMS...
AND TURN THEM INTO ONE BIG
FIERY CINDER LIKE THAT!
BUT HOW WOULD THAT
MAKE US STRONGER FOR HIM?
ONE OF THESE DAYS,
MY LORD IS GONNA COME TO ME...
AND ASK ME FOR AN EXPLANATION FOR THE
LIVES OF EACH AND EVERY ONE OF YOU.
AND WHAT AM I GONNA TELL HIM
ON THAT DAY?
THAT I WAS BUSY?
THAT I WAS TIRED?
THAT I WAS BORED?
NO! I CAN NEVER LET UP!
I WELCOME HIS TEST.
I WELCOME THIS CHALLENGE
OF MY LORD SO THAT ONE DAY...
I CAN DELIVER ALL OF YOU
UNTO HIS HANDS.
AND WHEN THAT DAY DAWNS, I DON'T
WANNA HAVE TO DO ANY EXPLAINING.
I DON'T WANT TO BE MISSING...
FROM YOUR LIVES.
PRAISE THE LORD
IN SINGING.
♪ [Organ]
HYMN NUMBER THREE-NINE-SEVEN.
"WHAT A FRIEND WE HAVE
IN JESUS."
♪ WHAT A FRIEND
WE HAVE IN JESUS ♪
♪ ALL OUR SINS
AND GRIEFS TO BEAR ♪
I WILL. YOU HAVE A GOOD WEEK.
WE'LL SEE YOU.
BYE-BYE.
[Reverend]
MRS. MacCORMACK,
YOUR SISTER
HAS US SO EXCITED
ABOUT YOU COMING.
OH, THANK YOU.
DID YOU MEET MY WIFE VI?
NO. HOW DO YOU DO?
HOW NICE TO MEET YOU.
THANK YOU.
THIS IS MY SON REN.
WELCOME.
HELLO, REN.
WOULD YOU EXCUSE ME?
HI.
[Chattering]
DADDY?
OH, ARIEL, WILL YOU COME
AND MEET THE MacCORMACKS?
- THE STUNNING NEW GENTLEMAN.
- THIS IS, UH, MRS. MacCORMACK.
- AND HER SON. IS IT REN?
- REN.
- [All Giggling]
- REN'S GONNA BE NEW
AT THE HIGH SCHOOL TOMORROW.
- HI.
DADDY. ME, EDNA, WENDY JO
AND RUSTY ARE GOING DOWN FOR
A SODA AT THE HI-SPOT, OKAY?
[Edna]
HOW YOU DOING?
[Ren] HI.
SEE YA.
ARIEL, REMEMBER YOU HAVE
SCHOOL TOMORROW.
[Ariel]
I'LL BE HOME FOR SUPPER.
GOD, IS HE EXCELLENT!
WHAT, THE NEW KID?
OH, HE'S ALL RIGHT.
WHAT, ARE YOU BLIND?
HE'S GORGEOUS.
SO, HAVE YOU SEEN
THE NEW HIGH SCHOOL?
UH, NO.
[Girl]
OH, MY GOD. I ALMOST FORGOT.
CINDY ADAMS HAD HER BABY.
[Girls Scream, Chattering]
WHO TOLD YOU?
YESTERDAY.
MY MOTHER SPOKE TO HER MOTHER.
IS SHE COMING BACK
FOR GRADUATION?
I DON'T FEEL
A BIT SORRY FOR HER.
YOU CAN'T BUY A DIAPHRAGM
THROUGH THE MAIL.
I'M SERIOUS.
WELL, DID SHE DECIDE
WHO THE FATHER WAS?
THERE'S NO QUESTION.
IT WAS DUANE CAPPS.
DUANE CAPPS.
NO, WAIT A MINUTE.
I'VE BEEN GOING
WITH DUANE CAPPS.
- HE NEVER HAD THE TIME.
- WELL, HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE,
WENDY JO?
AH, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
MOVING UP BEHIND US,
YOU'LL NOTICE
THE INCREDIBLE BARF-MOBILE.
CRAP!
COME ON.
[Indistinct Yelling]
HI, GIRLS.
GOIN' MY WAY?
ARE YOU LONELY
IN YOUR CAR?
YOU WANNA RACE?
YOU GOT A RACE!
- WHAT, THAT PIECE OF JUNK?
- COME ON! STEP ON IT!
♪ WELL, SHE'D LIKE YOU TO THINK
SHE WAS BORN YESTERDAY ♪
♪ WITH HER INNOCENT LOOKS
AND HER LITTLE TOWN WAYS ♪
♪ WHEN SHE SMILES AT ME
SHE'S GOT ANGELS IN HER EYES ♪
- AW, NO GUTS, HUH?
- ♪ BUT I'VE SEEN HOW SHE MOVES
♪ AND THIS GIRL REALLY COOKS
SHE TAUGHT ME SOME TRICKS ♪
IN BACK OF US, BUDDY.
♪ THAT YOU CAN'T
LEARN IN BOOKS ♪
YA CHICKEN!
- TAKE THIS!
- COME ON. I'LL TAKE
YOU ALL ON, GIRL!
[Yelling Indistinct]
COME ON, CHUCK!
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- COME ON!
- EDNA, SLOW DOWN, OKAY, PLEASE.
- THROW IT, HONEY. THROW IT.
- ARIEL, STOP IT!
- COME ON. I'LL GO SLOW.
COME ON.
YOU CAN DO IT.
[Girls Yelling]
♪ OVER AND OVER
I NEVER GET MY FILL ♪
[Screaming]
WILL YOU STOP IT? NOW!
ARIEL, STOP SHOWING OFF!
IT'S NOT FUNNY!
YOU'RE GONNA KILL YOURSELF!
♪ BUT SHE'LL NEVER SAY NO
WHEN THE MOTOR IS RUNNING ♪
- ♪ THIS GIRL DON'T SIT STILL
- BE CAREFUL!
HE'S TESTING US!
- ♪ SHE KNOWS WHAT SHE LIKES
- ARIEL, WATCH OUT.
THERE'S A TRUCK!
♪ I GOT WHAT SHE NEEDS
WHOO ♪
- ♪ AND ONE OF THESE NIGHTS
- [Laughing]
- GET IN THE CAR NOW!
- ♪ WE'LL COVER SOME GROUND
- [Chuck]
SHIT! GET IN THE TRUCK, ARIEL!
- GET INTO THE CAR!
[Yelling, Indistinct]
- ARIEL, BE CAREFUL!
- ♪ THIS GIRL GETS AROUND
[Horn Honks]
- COME ON! GET IN!
- [Horn Honking]
- GET IN!
- [Girls Screaming]
- [Horn Honks]
♪ YEAH, SHE KNOWS
WHAT SHE LIKES ♪
- ♪ I GOT WHAT SHE NEEDS
- JESUS, HE SHOULD NEVER
HAVE LET HER DONE THAT.
♪ BABY, ONE OF THESE NIGHTS
♪ WE'LL BOTH MAKE OUR MOVES
[Both Laughing]
♪ YEAH, WE'LL COVER
SOME GROUND ♪
SO, HAVE YOU MET
ANY OF YOUR TEACHERS?
NO, I HAVEN'T HAD A CHANCE.
REVEREND, THEY'VE ONLY
BEEN HERE EIGHT HOURS.
NOW I TOOK CARE
OF ALL THAT LAST WEEK.
REGISTERED HIM AND EVERYTHING.
I MADE YOU SOME OF THOSE
TOLL HOUSE SQUARES I PROMISED.
YOU TASTE ONE OF THESE,
YOU'LL BURN YOUR RECIPE.
REVEREND, WE HAVE
A LITTLE PROBLEM.
I HEARD THAT THE ENGLISH TEACHER
OVER AT THE SCHOOL IS PLANNING
TO TEACH THAT BOOK.
SLAUGHTERHOUSE FIVE.
ISN'T THAT AN AWFUL NAME?
OH, YEAH,
IT'S A GREAT BOOK.
SLAUGHTERHOUSE FIVE?
YEAH, IT'S--
IT'S A CLASSIC.
DO YOU READ MUCH?
MAYBE IN ANOTHER TOWN
IT'S A CLASSIC.
- IN ANY TOWN.
- TOM SAWYER IS A CLASSIC.
NO, THAT'S FINE, ETHEL.
THANKS.
ETHEL, HONEY, HERE
HAVE SOME MORE HAM.
NO, NO.
YOU SURE REN
DOESN'T WANT SOMETHING?
I DON'T THINK SO.
WE'RE BOTH A LITTLE TIRED
FROM THE MOVE.
[Girl]
I THINK I'M GONNA
TAKE REN A POTATO.
[Father]
AMY, COME BACK
AND SIT DOWN.
I'M SURE YOUR COUSIN'S FINE.
THROWS A SHOCK TO THE SYSTEM,
MOVING OUT HERE
FROM THE BIG CITY.
BUT WHAT IF HE'S STARVING?
AMY, YOU ARE SO LAME.
SAR-- AMY! EAT!
OH, I CAN'T SIT STILL.
I'M SO EXCITED YOU'RE BOTH HERE!
ETHEL, YOU SURE
YOU'RE NOT TOO TIRED?
NO, REN DID MOST
OF THE DRIVING.
IF YOU ASK ME,
REN IS A TOTAL FOX.
[Ethel] AMY!
[Father]
WHERE DID YOU HEAR THAT?
ETHEL, YOU SEE HOW TELEVISION
AND THOSE KINDS OF BOOKS
INFLUENCE CHILDREN?
YOU SEE?
[Horn Honks]
[Man]
HEY!
[Horn Honks]
[Wendy Jo]
WHAT THE HELL'S YOUR PROBLEM?
CHUCK CRANSTON,
ARE YOU CRAZY?
YOU'RE SICK!
HEY, ARIEL,
HERE'S YOUR SWEATER.
ARE YOU
OUT OF YOUR MIND?
I COULD KILL YOU!
YOU ALMOST DID, EDNA.
THAT'S WHAT YOU GET
FOR SNIFFING SPRAY STARCH.
AFTER HE GRADUATED,
THEY DRAINED HIS BRAIN.
- HEY, EDNA, YOU GETTIN' FRIES?
- IF I AM, YOU CAN'T HAVE ANY.
- WENDY JO! WENDY JO!
- YES?
- BRING ME EDNA'S FRIES.
- OH, SURE.
HEY, WHERE YOU GOING?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
SMUGGLED TAPES.
YOU BE CAREFUL WITH THAT.
YOUR DADDY HEARS YOU PLAYING IT,
HE'LL BUST YOUR BUTT.
♪ [Dance]
♪ DANCIN' IN THE SHEETS
♪ I CAUGHT YOU SMILIN'
I KNOW I'VE SEEN YOU
HERE BEFORE ♪
♪ HOW COME YOU'RE HIDIN'
HEY, DON'T YOU WANNA
HIT THE FLOOR ♪
HE PUT HIS HANDS
ALL OVER HER.
♪ THE PLACE IS CROWDED OR MAYBE
YOU DON'T LIKE THE BEAT ♪
♪ I GOT A TWO-TRACK
PLAYIN' IN MY HEAD ♪
♪ SO LET ME TAKE YOU
SOMEWHERE ELSE INSTEAD ♪
♪ DANCIN' IN THE SHEETS
♪ GRAB YOUR COAT
AND WAVE GOOD-BYE
TO YOUR FRIENDS ♪
♪ I WANNA TAKE YOU
WHERE THE NIGHT NEVER ENDS ♪
♪ I FEEL THE NEED TO SWEEP YOU
OFF OF YOUR FEET ♪
♪ YOU AND ME WE SHOULD BE
DANCIN' IN THE SHEETS ♪
♪ DANCIN' IN THE SHEETS
- ♪ [Off]
- [Video Game Noises]
[Indistinct Murmuring]
YOUR MOTHER DIDN'T THINK
YOU HAD ANY MONEY WITH YOU.
[Train Whistle Blows
In Distance]
♪ [Humming]
[Knock On Door]
REN?
YEAH, MOM.
YOU ABOUT READY TO GO?
UH-HUH.
YOU GONNA
WEAR THAT TIE?
YEAH.
I THINK YOU MIGHT WANNA
DRESS DOWN FOR NOW.
I LIKE THE TIE.
SEPTEMBER, WHEN YOU'RE
OFF TO COLLEGE, YOU CAN
DRESS LIKE DAVID BOWIE.
COME ON. LET'S GO.
[Radio]
♪ I'M LIKE A LASER
SIX-STRING RAZOR ♪
♪ I'VE GOT A MOUTH
LIKE AN ALLIGATOR ♪
♪ I WANT IT LOUDER
MORE POWER ♪
♪ I'M GONNA ROCK IT
TILL IT STRIKES THE HOUR ♪
♪ BANG YOUR HEAD
♪ METAL HEALTH
WILL DRIVE YOU MAD ♪
♪ [Radio Off]
[Students Chattering]
WHY DON'T YOU COMB
YOUR HAIR?
SHIT, MISTER,
WHERE YOU GOIN'?
[Stammers]
SON OF A BITCH,
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO LOOK.
SORRY.
HEY, WHERE'D YOU LEARN
HOW TO DRIVE, ANYWAY?
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO
STAY ON THE RIGHT SIDE.
HEY, I LIKE THAT HAT, MAN.
THEY SELL MEN'S CLOTHES
WHERE YOU GOT THAT?
[Boy]
WILLARD, COME ON.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
REN.
YEAH?
MY NAME'S WILLARD.
HEWITT.
GOOD TO MEET YA.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL SEE YOU AROUND.
WILLARD, I SWEAR,
ONE OF THESE DAYS--
HEY, THAT TIE
IS FABULOUS.
I MEAN IT, IT'S FABULOUS.
DON'T LET ANYONE TELL YOU
ANY DIFFERENT.
ARIEL.
- RIGHT?
- VERY GOOD.
WHOO! GIRL, YOU ARE ON!
MM-HMM.
CHICAGO?
WOW, MAN, MUST BE WILD.
LIKE THE NAKED CITY.
UH, ONE FISH.
I'LL TELL YOU, MAN.
YOU'RE GONNA BOUNCE OFF
THE GODDAMN WALLS HERE.
SO WHAT DO YOU DO THERE?
SAME THING YOU DO HERE.
WHAT DO YOU DO HERE?
LOT OF THIS.
YEAH, THAT TOO.
OH, I TELL YOU, MAN,
THERE WAS THIS PLACE...
CALLED THE BLUE HEAVEN.
YEAH?
THAT WAS GREAT.
I HAD TO STEAL I.D.s
TO GET IN THIS PLACE.
IT WAS INCREDIBLE.
IT WAS LIKE A HUGE
UNDERGROUND CIRCUS, YOU KNOW.
HOT PINK NEON
CLIMBING UP THE WALLS.
ASTRO MUSIC AND GIRLS.
MILLIONS OF GIRLS.
LIKE, FROM
THE UNIVERSITY MOSTLY.
IF WE COULD GET ONE OF THEM
TO DANCE, JUST ONE,
THEN THAT WAS IT.
WE'D GET OUT ON THE FLOOR
AND REALLY START TO SMOKE.
WE'D START CUTTIN' IN ON EACH
OTHER, AND THESE GIRLS WOULD
STOP WHAT THEY WERE DOING.
THEY'D LOOK--
THEY'D LOOK.
THEY'D LOOK HOW?
YOU KNOW, THEY'D START
TO WARM UP A LITTLE.
RIGHT? PRETTY SOON,
THEY'D START BUYIN' US BEER.
THEY WERE BUYIN'
YOU GUYS BEERS? OH, SHIT.
OH, YEAH. OH, YEAH.
OH, WAIT.
THERE WAS THIS ONE.
[Laughs]
THIS WAS THE BEST.
GINGER.
NOW LISTEN.
WE STARTED DANCING.
SLOW DANCING.
LIKE WE WERE STUCK
TO EACH OTHER.
NOW, EVENTUALLY IT'S OBVIOUS
TO ME THAT SHE WANTS TO
DO MORE THAN DANCE.
ALL RIGHT?
SO, WE LEFT THE PLACE.
ON THE WAY TO THE CAR,
SHE'S ALREADY GOT HER TONGUE
IN MY EAR.
ALL RIGHT?
WE GET TO THE CAR.
SHE SAYS WE CAN'T GO BACK
TO HER PLACE 'CAUSE OF
HER ROOMMATE, RIGHT?
SHE SAYS,
"HEY, THAT'S NO PROBLEM."
SHE'S GOT
THESE SEATS IN THE CAR
THAT RECLINE BACK.
ALL THE WAY BACK.
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING.
ALL THE WAY?
WOULD I SHIT YOU?
ALL RIGHT?
SHE RIPS MY SHIRT OPEN.
SHE'S CLAWIN' MY CHEST.
SHE-- SHE'S BITIN' MY NECK,
AND I'M-- I'M TRYIN'
TO GET OVER THE STICK SHIFT.
'CAUSE WE'RE GOIN' LIKE
A FREAKIN' FREIGHT TRAIN NOW.
ALL OF A SUDDEN,
SHE STARTS SCREAMIN'
AT THE TOP OF HER LUNGS,
"OH, GOD! OH, GOD!
DON'T STOP! DON'T STOP!
MAKE GINGER POP!"
- AH, SHIT. REALLY?
- NO.
YEAH, BUT WE DID DANCE.
SO-- WE DANCED OUR ASSES OFF.
WILLARD!
WILLARD, HOW COULD YOU LET
OUR NEW STUDENT EAT THIS FOOD?
DON'T EAT THIS. UH-UH.
NOW WE HAVE SOME DELICIOUS
HOMEMADE FOOD OVER THERE.
COME ON OVER.
IT'S SO GOOD.
YEAH, COME ON.
COME ON, WILLARD.
OH, CHICKEN. MM!
HI.
COME ON. COME ON.
GOOD BOY. COME ON.
BRING YOUR FRIEND.
YOU WON'T GET
ANY OF THAT HERE.
WHAT'S THAT?
DANCIN'.
THERE'S NO DANCIN'. RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHY?
IT'S ILLEGAL.
- JUMP BACK.
- IT'S TRUE.
[Willard] HAS BEEN FOR
ABOUT FIVE OR SIX YEARS.
WHY?
GO AHEAD. TELL HIM.
STARTED WHEN A BUNCH OF KIDS
GOT KILLED IN A CAR WRECK.
WHOLE TOWN WENT BANANAS,
BLAMING IT ON THE MUSIC
AND THE LIQUOR AND DANCING.
NOW THEY'RE JUST CONVINCED
IT'S ALL A SIN.
WHO'S CONVINCED?
WHOLE DAMN TOWN.
SO, YOU REALLY CAN'T
DANCE HERE, MAN.
I CAN'T BELIEVE THAT.
IT'S TRUE.
THIS ISN'T
THE ONLY PLACE EITHER.
YOU'D BE SURPRISED.
PLACES UPSTATE
YOU CAN'T DANCE.
PLACES IN KANSAS AND ARKANSAS.
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
MY COUSIN LIVES IN MONTANA,
AND YOU CAN'T DANCE
WHERE SHE LIVES EITHER.
YEAH? SHE EVER
GET BUSTED FOR BOPPIN'?
I DON'T KNOW.
NEVER ASKED HER.
YOU RICH?
NO. NO, WHY?
[Engine Starts]
♪ [Radio: Rock]
I DON'T THINK I EVER
BOUGHT A TAPE BEFORE.
GET SERIOUS.
THIS PLACE IS TOO WEIRD.
DON'T YOU EVER LISTEN
TO THE RADIO?
NO. WE GOT ONE RADIO
AT HOME, BUT IT'S NEVER ON.
YOU LIKE MEN AT WORK?
WHICH MEN?
MEN AT WORK.
WHERE DO THEY WORK?
NO, THEY DON'T.
THEY'RE A MUSIC GROUP.
WHAT DO THEY CALL THEMSELVES?
OH, NO.
WHAT ABOUT THE POLICE?
WHAT ABOUT 'EM?
HAVE YOU HEARD THEM?
WHAT, IN CONCERT?
NO, BUT I'VE SEEN THEM.
NO, BEHIND YOU.
WHAT?
[Siren Wailing]
[Ren]
OH, SHIT.
- WANNA STEP OUT OF THE CAR?
- COULD YOU TELL ME
WHAT THE PROBLEM IS?
WILL YOU JUST STEP OUT
OF THE CAR, PLEASE?
HEY, JIM, THESE PLATES
ARE ILLINOIS STATE.
SO?
SO, YOU GOT A LICENSE?
- CATCH.
- HEY, I JUST BOUGHT THAT.
HEY. PLAYIN' IT
KIND OF LOUD, WEREN'T YOU?
IS THERE A LAW
AGAINST LOUD MUSIC?
HEY, LET'S WATCH
THAT ATTITUDE, BOY.
THIS WAY, I DON'T
HAVE TO TAKE YOU IN.
TWENTY-FIVE DOLLARS.
THEY WOULDN'T EVEN
LET ME OFF WITH A WARNING.
YOU CAN'T TALK TO OUR POLICE
THE WAY YOU TALK TO
THOSE BIG CITY POLICE.
- BUT I WASN'T DOING ANYTHING.
- YEAH, SURE.
SARAH, HUSH. REN, THERE WAS
THIS BUNCH OF KIDS SNUCK OVER
THE STATE LINE...
A YEAR OR SO AGO
TO SEE SOME ROCK-AND-ROLL GROUP,
AND THEY WERE STOPPED
ON THEIR WAY BACK INTO TOWN
BY THE POLICE.
THEY WERE ON CHURCH
AND SCHOOL PROBATION FOR WEEKS.
SO, YOU BETTER WATCH YOUR STEP
AROUND HERE, YOUNG MAN.
♪ [Orchestral]
[Typewriter Keys
Clacking]
DADDY?
HMM?
I'M SORRY ABOUT THE OTHER NIGHT
AT THE DRIVE-IN.
I MEAN, ABOUT THE MUSIC.
I WAS SURPRISED.
YEAH.
[Typewriter Keys
Continue Clacking]
DADDY?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT CAME OVER ME.
YOU KNOW, I CAN'T ALWAYS
BE WITH YOU, ARIEL.
I CAN'T ALWAYS
LOOK OUT FOR YOU.
WHAT'S THE MUSIC?
OH, IT'S, UH, UM,
I THINK IT'S HAYDN.
CHAMBER PIECES.
AND THAT KIND
OF MUSIC'S OKAY?
WELL, IT'S UPLIFTING.
IT DOESN'T CONFUSE
PEOPLE'S MINDS AND BODIES.
I DON'T--
WHAT?
I SEE.
COULD YOU TELL YOUR MOTHER
TO GO ON TO BED?
I STILL HAVE A LOT
OF WORK TO DO HERE.
I WILL.
DADDY?
WHAT IS IT?
GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT, HONEY.
[Students Chattering]
HEY, CHUCK! WHOO!
[Boy]
I'LL CATCH YOU LATER.
HERE. GRAB MY BOOKS.
LET ME IN.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
[Horn Honks]
HEY, YOU THE NEW KID?
I'M TALKIN' TO YOU.
WHERE'D YOUR TIE GO?
I THOUGHT ONLY PANSIES
WORE NECKTIES.
OH, YEAH? SEE THAT?
I THOUGHT ONLY ASSHOLES
USED THE WORD PANSY.
WHOO! HE GOT YOU
ON THAT ONE, CHUCK.
SHUT UP!
[Chuck]
SON OF A BITCH
IS GONNA PAY FOR THAT.
EITHER YOU GOT
JUMBO COCONUT BALLS,
OR YOU'RE REALLY PRETTY STUPID.
WHO IS THAT DOUCHE BAG?
HE'S JUST A LITTLE WEASEL,
BUT YOU GOTTA WATCH YOUR BACK.
CAN YOU OPERATE
A PALLET JACK?
UH-UH.
HOW ABOUT A BAG CLOSER?
WHERE YOU FROM?
CHICAGO.
YOU'RE NOT STUPID,
ARE YOU?
HEY, YOU TRYING
TO PISS ME OFF?
WELL, BOY, A LOT OF FOLKS
ARE GONNA GIVE YOU PROBLEMS
RIGHT OFF,
BECAUSE, YOU SEE,
YOU'RE AN OUTSIDER.
YOU'RE DANGEROUS.
THEY'RE ALWAYS GONNA
WORRY ABOUT YOU.
SCREW 'EM. AND THIS IS ONLY
ONE LITTLE CORNER OF THE WORLD.
START THURSDAY?
- SOUNDS OKAY.
- YES!
[Man Talking, Indistinct]
HARD WORK,
BUT YOU'LL GET USED TO IT.
[Grunts]
OH, HI, ARIEL.
CHUCK CRANSTON
WANTS TO SEE YOU.
MEET HIM OVER AT THE BACK
OF HIS DADDY'S FIELD TOMORROW.
5:30.
SO, WHAT HAPPENS TOMORROW
AT 5:30?
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
SHOW UP TO FIND OUT.
- IF I DON'T?
- PEOPLE WILL KNOW
YOU'RE SCARED.
ANYWAY,
CHUCK WILL FIND YOU.
YOU WANT THAT?
[Man]
HEY, REN, WE'RE BACKING UP
IN HERE. WHERE ARE YOU?
HEY! HEY, YO, YO, YO!
HOW COME HE SENT YOU?
I VOLUNTEERED.
HEY, MacCORMACK,
WHERE THE HELL ARE YOU?
YOU KNOW HER?
[Grunts]
AND SO SHE TELLS ME THAT--
THAT I PISSED
CHUCK OFF, RIGHT?
SO, HE WANTS TO SEE ME,
AND SHE WALKS AWAY.
HE FIGURED YOU WERE GONNA
CHICKEN AND NEVER--
OOH, IMPRESSIVE!
NO. KIND OF OUT OF IT.
I HAD TO GO
TO WORK LAST YEAR.
WELL, YOU'RE STILL MOVIN'.
OOH, YOU'D BETTER WATCH THAT.
ARIEL'S GONNA TELL HER POP,
AND YOU'RE GONNA BURN.
YEAH, WHAT'S HER STORY?
IS SHE REALLY TOUGH, OR WHAT?
NAW. SHE'S JUST TRYING TO
MAKE PEOPLE FORGET
SHE'S THE PREACHER'S KID.
[Grunts]
IS THAT WHY SHE HANGS OUT
WITH CHUCK?
MAYBE. PEOPLE THINK
SHE'S A HELL-RAISER.
- IS SHE?
- I THINK SHE'S BEEN
KISSED A LOT.
♪ [Radio: Dance]
[Chuck Making Siren Noises]
OH, CHUCK!
YOU'D NEVER THINK
YOUR DADDY'S A FIRE CHIEF.
YOU'D NEVER GUESS
YOUR DADDY'S A MINISTER.
RED BOOTS.
MY DADDY HATES ME
WEARING THESE BOOTS.
AND YOU LOVE THAT,
DON'T YA? HUH?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WHEN I GO AWAY TO COLLEGE?
WHY DO YOU WANNA
DO THAT, HONEY?
JUST 'CAUSE.
CUT OUT FOR MORE
THAN THIS SMALL TOWN.
YOU'RE AS SMALL TOWN
AS THEY COME.
♪ [Radio: Indistinct]
A CHICKEN RACE
WITH TRACTORS?
HOW HARD COULD IT BE, RIGHT?
JUST LIKE A CAR.
IT'S EASY.
JUST LIKE
DRIVING A SPORTS CAR.
NOTHIN' COULD BE SIMPLER.
OH HELL, REN,
JUST REMEMBER TO STAY CALM.
CALM. "CALM," HE SAYS.
I'VE NEVER DRIVEN
A TRACTOR BEFORE.
IT'S EASY. LOOK.
THIS IS YOUR CLUTCH.
THERE'S YOUR GAS.
YOU GOT YOUR
CLUTCH DOWN HERE.
YOUR GAS AND YOUR BRAKE.
YOU START OFF,
YOU SHIFT IT INTO HIGH.
SHIFT IT INTO HIGH.
PUT IT IN THIRD,
AND ONCE YOU GET GOING,
SLAM IT INTO FOURTH.
PUT IT INTO FOURTH.
THAT'S YOUR EMERGENCY BRAKE.
THESE OPERATE YOUR BUCKET.
DON'T MESS
WITH THE BUCKETS.
I'LL BET HE'S SCARED SHITLESS.
HE TURNS OUT IN TEN SECONDS.
WHOA! HEY, CHUCK,
YOU SURE YOU'RE UP FOR THIS?
WELL, WHOSE SIDE YOU ON,
ANYWAY, HONEY?
YOU HAD A LOT TO SMOKE.
DON'T TELL ME
I HAD ENOUGH TO SMOKE.
I DIDN'T SAY YOU HAD ENOUGH
TO SMOKE. I SAID YOU HAD
A LOT TO SMOKE.
WELL, DON'T TELL ME THAT,
EITHER.
WHY DON'T YOU GO TELL DOGFACE
WE'RE READY TO GO?
[Boy]
YEAH, ALL RIGHT.
LET'S DO IT.
[Boy #2]
OKAY, I'LL CATCH YOU LATER.
COME ON, MAN.
THIS RACE IS ALREADY WON.
[Chattering,
Yelling]
REN, JUST REMEMBER HE'S
CHICKENSHIT. JUST HANG IN THERE.
YOU'RE GONNA BE GREAT.
JUST HOPE TO GOD HE PULLS OUT.
'CAUSE THEN I WANNA
SPLIT HIS FACE OPEN.
COOL IT, TARZAN!
LET'S GET HIM, REN!
GIVE 'IM HELL, REN.
WE'RE WITH YA.
HOW DID I GET MYSELF
INTO THIS?
HEY, HEY, WOODY.
WOODY, COME HERE.
LISTEN, UH,
HAS ANYBODY EVER DIED
DOING THIS?
JUST ONCE.
HEY, REN. HEY, SPORT.
WHEN THIS HAT FLIES IN THE AIR,
YOU BETTER HAVE
YOUR BUTT IN GEAR.
[All Yelling At Once]
♪ [Rock]
[Engine Starts]
YEOW!
♪ WHERE HAVE ALL
THE GOOD MEN GONE
AND WHERE ARE ALL THE GODS ♪
- ♪ WHERE'S
THE STREETWISE HERCULES ♪
- COME ON, REN!
- ♪ TO FIGHT THE RISING ODDS
- GO! GO!
♪ ISN'T THERE A WHITE KNIGHT
UPON A FIERY STEED ♪
♪ LATE AT NIGHT
I TOSS AND I TURN ♪
- ♪ AND I DREAM OF WHAT I NEED
- LET'S SEE WHAT YOU'RE MADE OF!
♪ I NEED A HERO
I'M HOLDING OUT FOR A HERO ♪
- COME ON, YOU SUCKER!
- ♪ TILL THE END OF THE NIGHT
- ♪ HE'S GOTTA BE STRONG
AND HE'S GOTTA BE FAST ♪
- COME ON, CHUCK, MOVE IT!
♪ AND HE'S GOTTA
BE FRESH FROM THE FIGHT ♪
♪ I NEED A HERO
♪ I'M HOLDING OUT FOR A HERO
TILL THE MORNING LIGHT ♪
- YOU WANNA GO UP? THERE YOU GO.
- ♪ HE'S GOTTA BE SURE
AND HE'S GOTTA BE SOON ♪
♪ AND HE'S GOTTA
BE LARGER THAN LIFE
LARGER THAN LIFE ♪
OH, YOU WANNA GO DOWN?
GO DOWN, HUH?
KICK HIS ASS!
COME ON!
[Chuck Yelling, Indistinct]
- ♪ SOMEWHERE AFTER MIDNIGHT
IN MY WILDEST FANTASY ♪
- THAT'S IT JUMP, YOU CHICKEN!
- SIT BACK DOWN!
- ♪ SOMEWHERE JUST
BEYOND MY REACH ♪
♪ THERE'S SOMEONE
REACHING BACK FOR ME ♪
♪ RACING ON THE THUNDER
- ♪ AND RISING WITH THE HEAT
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING, HUH?
- ♪ IT'S GONNA TAKE A SUPER MAN
- STUPID IDIOT!
- ♪ TO SWEEP ME OFF MY FEET
- GET OFF!
- TURN OUT!
- ♪ YEAH
- OH, SHIT!
- ♪ I NEED A HERO
♪ I'M HOLDING OUT FOR A HERO
TILL THE END OF THE NIGHT ♪
- ♪ HE'S GOTTA BE STRONG
AND HE'S GOTTA BE FAST ♪
- ALL RIGHT!
♪ AND HE'S GOTTA BE FRESH
FROM THE FIGHT ♪
♪ I NEED A HERO
♪ I'M HOLDING OUT FOR A HERO
TILL THE MORNING LIGHT ♪
WHOO!
♪ HE'S GOTTA BE SURE
AND HE'S GOTTA BE SOON ♪
♪ AND HE'S GOTTA
BE LARGER THAN LIFE ♪
[All Cheering]
♪ I NEED A HERO
THE GUY TRIED TO KILL ME.
- OH!
- [All Cheering]
EXCUSE ME.
THANK YOU.
[Bell Dings]
I DON'T BELIEVE
THIS TOWN.
HELLO.
TELL ME.
OKAY. HE HAS TEAM PRACTICE
EVERY DAY UNTIL 4:00.
ON MONDAYS, WEDNESDAYS
AND THURSDAYS HE WORKS
AT THE BEAMIS MILL TILL 6:00.
WHOOPS. YOU ALREADY
KNEW THAT, RIGHT?
MM-HMM.
OKAY, UM, HE HASN'T DATED
SINCE HE'S BEEN IN TOWN.
AND LATE FRIDAY NIGHTS,
YEAH?
BY THE LIGHT
OF THE FULL MOON, HE, UH,
BREAKS INTO CHURCHYARDS
AND BITES THE HEADS OFF
LIVE CHICKENS.
COME ON, ARIEL.
WHAT IS IT? CHUCK?
LOOK, I NEVER DID THINK HE HAD
ALL HIS DOGS BARKING, ANYWAY.
BESIDES,
WHAT IS WRONG ABOUT GETTING
A LITTLE PSYCHED OVER REN?
HE'S CUTE.
HE'S FROM OUT OF TOWN.
DON'T TELL ME THAT
DOESN'T CURL YOUR TOES.
I KNOW YOU TOO WELL.
YOU WANT OUT OF HERE SO BAD,
YOU PROBABLY MEMORIZE
BUS SCHEDULES.
AND YOU DON'T?
[Pencil Tapping]
HEY, ASSHOLE.
INTERESTED IN SOME
REALLY GOOD SHIT?
OH, MY GOD.
RICH, YOU SLY LITTLE SHIT.
YOU JUST MADE A WHOLE SENTENCE!
DON'T GET SMART-ASS!
YOU KNOW, I'VE BEEN WATCHING
YOU THESE PAST COUPLE WEEKS.
I KNOW YOU'RE NOT STUPID.
AND, UH, I GOT A FRIEND HERE
WHO CAN HELP YOU OUT
FROM TIME TO TIME.
NO. THANKS A LOT.
THANK YOU, BUT I GOT
MY OWN SOURCES.
YOU KNOW, I'VE BEEN GETTING
INTO HOG TRANQUILIZERS.
WHAT DO YOU SAY WE CALL
THIS A SAMPLE, AND YOU KNOW
WHERE YOU CAN GET MORE.
RICH, RICH, HOLD UP, MAN.
LOOK. I DON'T WANT YOUR SHIT.
THEN WHY DON'T I JUST TAKE IT?
YOU'RE TAKING SOME REAL CHANCES
BEING NEW IN THIS SCHOOL.
I GOTTA SHOW YOU SOMETHING.
WAIT! THIS IS TEA!
COME BACK HERE!
[Rich]
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
[Toilet Flushes]
DO YOU THINK I'D DO THAT
WITH A REAL JOINT?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT AN OUNCE
IS GOING FOR THESE DAYS?
I'M GONNA GET YOU.
YOU WAIT.
THE REVEREND
WAS RIGHT ABOUT YOU.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Dad]
SEEMS THAT A BUNCH OF KIDS
WAS RAISIN' SOME HELL...
OUT AT BURLINGTON CRANSTON'S
PROPERTY A FEW DAYS BACK.
TORE UP THE FIELDS
AND TURNED OVER A TRACTOR
AND EVERYTHING.
TODAY, SOMEONE SUGGESTED TO ME
THERE'S BEEN SOME TROUBLE
UP AT THE HIGH SCHOOL.
I THINK IT WAS DRUGS.
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THAT.
WHAT'D YOU SAY?
I CAN'T HEAR YOU.
- HE SAID, "NO."
- AMY.
I SAID, "NO, SIR."
WELL, YOU KNOW, REN,
WHENEVER WE USED TO CALL UP
TO YOUR FOLKS THERE IN CHICAGO,
I DON'T THINK THERE WAS
ANY TROUBLE BACK THERE,
WAS THERE?
AND I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO MAKE OF IT.
BUT IT SEEMS A LOT OF PEOPLE
ARE POINTING A FINGER
IN YOUR DIRECTION LATELY.
AND WHAT ARE THEY SAYING?
WELL, I HAVE BEEN
TELLING YOU...
ABOUT THE TROUBLE
AND THE DRUGS AND--
YOU JUST SEEM TO BE
HAVING A LOT OF TROUBLE
SINCE YOU MOVED HERE.
AND I FIGURED--
YOU FIGURED WHERE THERE'S
SMOKE, THERE'S FIRE, RIGHT?
USUALLY WORKS LIKE THAT.
NOW LOOK, REN.
YOU KNOW THAT I WOULD
NEVER TRY TO TAKE
THE PLACE OF YOUR FATHER.
YEAH, WELL, THERE'S
NO CHANCE OF THAT.
- REN!
- [Door Slams]
[Car Engine Starts,
Tires Screech]
UH-OH, HE'S TAKING THE CAR.
[Tires Skid]
♪ [Rock]
♪ I FEEL YOUR HEART
♪ IT'S BEATING TIME
WITH MINE ♪
♪ YEAH, BUT LOVE, LOVE
♪ LOVE IS ON THE LINE
♪ HE HOLDS YOU DOWN
♪ BUT I KNOW
YOU WANT TO RUN ♪
♪ WELL, YOU'RE HOT, HOT
♪ LOADED LIKE A GUN
♪ OH, YOU FEEL
♪ OH, SO TRAPPED
AND CONFUSED ♪
♪ START WITH NOTHING
YOU'VE GOT ♪
♪ NOTHING TO LOSE
♪ YOU CAN NEVER
NEVER, NEVER, NEVER, NEVER
NEVER, NEVER, NEVER ♪
♪ HIDE YOUR HEART
♪ DON'T EVER, EVER, EVER
♪ EVER TRY
♪ IT'S TIME TO FIGHT
♪ WELL, IT'S TIME
FOR TEARIN' FREE ♪
♪ WELL, COME, COME
♪ RUNNING STRAIGHT TO ME
♪ OH, YOU KNOW
♪ HE DON'T LOVE YOU
LIKE I DO ♪
♪ DON'T MAKE BELIEVE
THAT YOU DON'T FEEL IT ♪
♪ TOO
♪ YOU CAN NEVER, NEVER
NEVER, NEVER, NEVER
NEVER, NEVER ♪
♪ HIDE YOUR HEART
♪ DON'T EVER, EVER, EVER
♪ EVER TRY, WHOA, NO
♪ IF YOU DON'T GIVE
♪ YOUR HEART WINGS
♪ YOU'LL NEVER, NEVER
♪ NEVER, NEVER FLY
♪ WHOA-OA
♪ YOU'LL NEVER FLY
♪ IF YOU WANT YOU CAN FLY
[Screams]
BIG TIME!
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
WATCHING.
THOUGHT I WAS ALONE.
HMM, NOT IN THIS TOWN.
THERE'S EYES EVERYWHERE.
HOW COME
YOU DON'T LIKE ME?
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK...
I DON'T LIKE YOU?
LOOK. YOU NEVER TALK
TO ME AT SCHOOL.
YOU NEVER LOOK AT ME.
YEAH, WELL, MAYBE BECAUSE
IF I DID, YOUR BOYFRIEND WOULD
REMOVE MY LUNGS WITH A SPOON.
CHUCK CRANSTON
DOESN'T OWN ME.
SURE, HE LIKES TO ACT
LIKE HE DOES,
BUT HE DOESN'T.
DO YOU WANNA KISS ME?
SOMEDAY.
HEY, WHAT IS THIS
"SOMEDAY" SHIT?
I GET THE FEELING
YOU'VE BEEN KISSED A LOT.
I'M AFRAID I'D SUFFER
BY COMPARISON.
YOU DON'T THINK
MUCH OF ME, DO YOU?
YOU THINK
I'M SMALL TOWN?
I THINK BOMONT'S
A SMALL TOWN.
I'M GOIN' AWAY.
I'VE ALREADY APPLIED
TO COLLEGES.
YOU KNOW, I APPLIED TO COLLEGES
MY FATHER DOESN'T EVEN KNOW
I APPLIED TO.
HE'S GONNA COME AFTER ME,
BUT I'M GONNA BE GONE.
[Sighs]
WANNA SEE SOMETHING?
SURE.
WE CALL IT "THE YEARBOOK."
IT STARTED, OH, FOUR
OR FIVE YEARS AGO, I GUESS.
IT'S STUFF WE'RE NOT
SUPPOSED TO READ.
THIS IS ALL OUT OF BOOKS?
WELL, MOST OF IT.
SOME SONGS, MAGAZINES.
SOME POEMS
THAT GET MADE UP.
"I'LL SING TO YOU
OF SILVER SWANS,
OF KINGDOMS AND CARILLONS."
"I'LL SING OF BODIES
INTERTWINED, UNDERNEATH
AN INNOCENT SKY."
YOU WROTE THAT?
IT'S NOT EVEN
ONE OF MY BEST.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU HEAR THAT?
[Train Approaching]
WHAT?
THE TRAIN.
YOU HEAR IT?
[Train Whistle Blowing
In Distance]
SOMETIMES AFTER
FOOTBALL GAMES,
WE COME OUT HERE,
JUST A FEW OF US,
AND WE STAND HERE.
THEN, WHEN THE TRAIN COMES,
WE MAKE OUT LIKE CRAZY.
OH, YEAH?
BUT MOST OF THE TIME
WE JUST STAND AND SCREAM.
[Railroad Crossing
Bells Ringing]
GREAT.
YEAH, SAW IT IN A MOVIE ONCE.
REAL LOUD. FROM HERE.
OH!
[Chuckles]
[Train Whistle Blows]
HEY, COME ON.
DON'T SCREW AROUND, HUH?
[Train Whistle Blows]
[Screams]
COME ON.
I'LL TAKE YOU HOME.
- IT'S LATE.
- YEAH.
IT'S KIND OF HARD TO IMPOSE
A CURFEW ON THE YOUNG PEOPLE
IN MY CONGREGATION...
THAT I CAN'T EVEN ENFORCE
IN MY OWN HOME.
HAVE YOU BEEN DRINKING?
NO.
YOU SMOKING SOMETHING?
NO! I WASN'T STEALING.
I WASN'T GAMBLING.
I WASN'T DANCING.
I WASN'T READING BOOKS
I'M NOT SUPPOSED TO.
I AM LATE!
WELL, WHO WERE YOU WITH?
REN MacCORMACK.
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO SEE HIM ANYMORE.
WHY?
I'VE HEARD
HE'S A TROUBLEMAKER.
JUST 'CAUSE HE HASN'T LIVED
IN THIS TOWN FOR 20 YEARS
DOESN'T MAKE HIM A TROUBLEMAKER.
ARIEL, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I'M GONNA DO WITH YOU.
THERE AIN'T NOTHIN'
TO DO WITH ME, DADDY.
YOU LIKE IT OR NOT.
THIS IS IT.
IT DOESN'T GET MUCH BETTER.
[Willard] HEY,
WHAT THE HELL HAPPENED? WHY'D
YOU GET KICKED OFF THE TEAM?
BECAUSE SOMEBODY'S
GOT IT IN FOR ME.
SOMEHOW COACH FINDS OUT
I BROUGHT ARIEL HOME
LATE LAST NIGHT,
SO I'M A TROUBLEMAKER,
RIGHT?
YEAH, BUT THAT'S NOT WHY
I'M OFF THE TEAM, SEE.
OH, NO. I'M OFF THE TEAM
'CAUSE THEY JUST DON'T
HAVE THE FUNDS...
FOR ONE MORE
GYMNAST THIS YEAR,
BUT THANK YOU ANYWAY.
I'M BUSTIN' MY BALLS
TRYIN' TO FIT IN HERE,
AND EVERY DOOR
IS GETTING SLAMMED IN MY FACE.
HEY, MacCORMACK.
SORRY TO HEAR
YOU GOT CAUGHT.
[Boy]
DON'T FOOL AROUND
WITH THE PREACHER'S DAUGHTER!
HOW DOES ANYBODY
LIVE IN THIS TOWN?
YOU KNOW WHAT IT IS, PARTNER.
YOU GOT AN ATTITUDE PROBLEM.
I GOT
AN ATTITUDE PROBLEM?
YES!
AND I'M NOT THE ONLY ONE
WHO'S NOTICED IT, REN.
WE'RE NOT LIVING
IN THE GODDAMN MIDDLE AGES HERE.
WE GOT TV.
WE GOT FAMILY FEUD.
WE'RE NOT STUCK IN
LEAVE IT TO BEAVER LAND HERE.
YEAH, WELL, I HAVEN'T NOTICED
A WET T-SHIRT CONTEST
IN TOWN YET.
YEAH, WELL,
I HAVEN'T EITHER,
BUT I'M WAITING.
PATIENTLY.
I TELL YA WHAT
I'D LIKE TO DO, MAN.
I'D LIKE TO GLUE
A PLAYBOY CENTERFOLD...
INSIDE EVERY ONE
OF REVEREND MOORE'S HYMNALS.
YEAH. YOU KNOW WHAT ELSE
WE COULD DO.
WE COULD START ONE OF
YOUR NIGHTCLUBS, RIGHT THERE
IN THE CHURCH, HUH?
HEY, THAT'S IT.
[Laughing]
THAT'S IT, MAN.
WHAT? WHAT'S IT?
A DANCE.
WHAT?
A DANCE!
WE COULD HAVE A DANCE!
YOU KNOW, A DANCE?
HEY, COME ON, MAN.
YOU'RE GONNA GET ME
ANGRY, MAN!
I'M GONNA TURN THIS TOWN
UPSIDE DOWN!
COME ON! STOP IT!
[Children Chattering]
YOU KNOW, I WAS DOWN
IN DENVER LAST YEAR...
FOR ABOUT A WEEK
AT A BIBLE CONVENTION THERE.
AND THE WHOLE TIME I WAS THERE,
PEOPLE WOULD COME UP TO ME...
AND ASK ME, "REVEREND,
HOW CAN YOU LIVE
IN SUCH A SMALL TOWN,
SO FAR AWAY FROM THE HUSTLE
AND BUSTLE OF THE 20th CENTURY?"
I'D SAY TO THEM
YOU'D NEVER ASK ME THAT...
IF YOU COULD JUST ONCE--
JUST FOR ONE MINUTE--
EXPERIENCE THE FEELING
OF FAMILY...
THAT COMES FROM KNOWING
THAT ALL OF OUR LIVES
ARE TIED UP WITH EACH OTHER'S.
THAT WE FEEL
ALL THE SAME JOYS,
THE SAME SORROWS.
AND THAT WE CARE.
EACH AND EVERY ONE OF US
CARES FOR THE OTHER.
I TOLD THEM I JUST FEEL
CLOSER TO MY LORD OUT THERE.
AND I FEEL CLOSER...
AND SAFER
WITH MY PEOPLE.
AND I THINK
THEY FEEL CLOSER TO ME.
THE LORD SMILES ON US
OUT THERE.
AND THAT'S
WHERE I'M STAYING.
WHY DON'T YOU
HAVE SOME CAKE?
[Murmuring]
[Reverend]
ROGER, THE TOWN COUNCIL
HAS NO INTENTION OF BOWING...
TO THE WISHES
OF A SMALL GROUP OF STUDENTS.
[Roger]
REVEREND, ELEANOR AND I
ARE ABSOLUTELY CERTAIN...
THAT WE KNOW FOR A FACT THAT
THIS BOY IS ORGANIZING A DANCE.
[Reverend]
WE'RE NOT GONNA HAVE ANY DANCE.
LET SOME YOUNG PUNK...
PUSH US AROUND NOW, IT WON'T BE
LONG BEFORE EVERY STANDARD
IN THE COMMUNITY IS VIOLATED.
[Reverend] EXCUSE ME.
COME ON!
BOY, ARE THEY IN A TIZZY!
GET IN THE CAR!
THEY GOT
THE WHOLE COUNCIL GOING.
THERE'S A TOWN MEETIN'
I AIN'T GONNA MISS.
REN, WHERE YOU TAKIN' US?
WE'RE GOIN' OVER THE STATE LINE.
I WANT YOU TO SEE
WHAT YOU'VE BEEN MISSING.
REN, I KNOW YOU'RE NOT GONNA
LET WILLARD FIGHT, RIGHT?
I DON'T FIGHT.
OH, RIGHT.
AND I DON'T BREATHE.
♪ [Rock]
♪ WHEN I WAS A YOUNG BOY
♪ SAID PUT AWAY
THOSE YOUNG BOY WAYS ♪
ARE YOU GONNA DANCE, MAN?
I DRINK BETTER THAN I DANCE.
AW, COME ON.
I'LL WATCH YOU GUYS.
SEE IF YOU CAN SHOW ME
SOMETHING NEW.
WE DIDN'T COME ALL THIS WAY
JUST TO SIT IT OUT, MAN.
I'LL BE OUT THERE.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
I'M JUST GONNA GRAB A BEER.
COME ON, MAN.
DON'T BE AN ASSHOLE.
THEY'RE WAITING TO
DANCE WITH US.
♪ JUST ME AND YOU
COME ON AND MAKE IT ♪
I CAN'T DANCE.
♪ HURT SO GOOD
YOU WHAT?
I-I CAN'T DANCE.
AT ALL.
♪ SOMETIMES LOVE
DON'T FEEL LIKE IT SHOULD ♪
OH.
♪ YOU MAKE IT HURT SO GOOD
ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
BUY HIM A BEER.
YOU HAVE TO TAKE MY JACKET.
♪ DON'T HAVE TO BE
SO EXCITIN' ♪
♪ JUST TRYIN' TO GIVE MYSELF
A LITTLE BIT OF FUN, YEAH ♪
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
MY FEET HAVE BEEN HURTING
ALL SINCE THIS MORNING.
THEY WEREN'T HURTING
IN THE CAR.
I WANNA SIT THIS OUT.
WILLARD, I WANNA DANCE.
I WANNA--
I WANNA GET A BEER.
♪ HEY, BABY, IT'S YOU
♪ COME ON, GIRL
NOW IT'S YOU ♪
♪ SINK YOUR TEETH
RIGHT THROUGH MY BONES, BABY ♪
♪ LET'S SEE WHAT WE CAN DO
COME ON AND MAKE IT HURT ♪
♪ HURT SO GOOD
♪ COME ON, BABY
MAKE IT HURT SO GOOD ♪
♪ SOMETIMES LOVE
DON'T FEEL LIKE IT SHOULD ♪
♪ YOU MAKE IT HURT SO GOOD
♪ [Slower Beat]
♪ SO LONG
♪ I'VE BEEN LOOKING TOO HARD
I'VE BEEN WAITING TOO LONG ♪
♪ SOMETIMES I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I WILL FIND ♪
WAITRESS, GIMME ANOTHER BEER.
♪ I ONLY KNOW
IT'S A MATTER OF TIME ♪
♪ WHEN YOU LOVE SOMEONE
♪ FEELS SO RIGHT
SO WARM AND TRUE ♪
♪ I NEED TO KNOW
IF YOU FEEL IT TOO ♪
♪ I GOTTA CUT LOOSE
FOOTLOOSE ♪
♪ KICK OFF YOUR SUNDAY SHOES
♪ LOSE YOUR BLUES
♪ EVERYBODY CUT FOOTLOOSE
♪ YOU'RE PLAYIN' SO COOL
♪ OBEYIN' EVERY RULE
♪ DIG WAY DOWN
IN YOUR HEART ♪
♪ YOU'RE BURNIN'
YEARNIN' FOR SOMEONE ♪
HEY!
♪ SOMEBODY TO TELL YOU
♪ THAT LIFE AIN'T PASSIN'
YOU BY ♪
I CAN'T HELP MYSELF, WILLARD!
♪ I'M TRYIN' TO TELL YOU
♪ IT WILL IF YOU
DON'T EVEN TRY ♪
♪ YOU CAN FLY
IF YOU'D ONLY CUT LOOSE ♪
♪ FOOTLOOSE
KICK OFF YOUR SUNDAY SHOES ♪
♪ OOH-WEE, MARIE
♪ SHAKE IT
SHAKE IT FOR ME ♪
♪ WHOA, MILO
♪ COME ON
COME ON, LET'S GO ♪
♪ LOSE YOUR BLUES
♪ EVERYBODY CUT FOOTLOOSE
♪ [Rhythmic Clapping]
♪ WE GOT TO TURN IT AROUND
♪ YOU PUT YOUR FEET
ON THE GROUND ♪
♪ NOW TAKE A HOLD
OF YOUR SOUL ♪
♪ I'M TURNIN' IT LOOSE
FOOTLOOSE ♪
♪ KICK OFF
YOUR SUNDAY SHOES ♪
♪ PLEASE, LOUISE
♪ PULL ME OFF OF MY KNEES
♪ JACK, GET BACK
HEY! I CAME WITH THAT GIRL.
DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
YOU'RE LEAVIN' WITH HER.
♪ LOSE YOUR BLUES
EVERYBODY CUT FOOTLOOSE ♪
HEY, I GUESS
YOU DIDN'T HEAR ME
THE FIRST TIME.
WILLARD, NO FIGHTS.
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW THIS GUY.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
FLAKE OFF, HUH?
HEY!
WILLARD, NO FIGHTS.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU SEEN YOUR DICK, PARTNER?
HEY!
[Screams]
[Ariel]
YOU KNOW, RUSTY, HE WAS FIGHTING
TO SAVE YOUR HONOR.
IT'S TOO LATE.
I DON'T FIGHT.
HEY, REN, IS YOUR DANCE
GONNA BE LIKE THIS ONE?
EVERYTHING BUT THE FIGHT.
WELL, FORGET IT.
OUCH! COME ON!
[Screams]
♪ UP ON THE ROOF
♪ OH, YEAH
♪ ONE HUNDRED PROOF
♪ OH, AIN'T THAT FINE
♪ OH, YEAH
♪ YOU CHERRY SLIME
[All Laughing]
OH, YEA. OH, YEA.
I HATE THIS BRIDGE.
GIVES ME THE CREEPS.
[Ren]
HOW COME?
YOU'VE HEARD THIS ONE.
THE INFAMOUS CROSBY BRIDGE
ACCIDENT, RIGHT?
YOU'VE HEARD IT.
NO.
HA, YOU'RE MISSIN' OUT.
ABOUT FIVE YEARS AGO,
THESE KIDS
WERE PLAYING HIGHWAY TAG,
AND THEY WERE DRUNK.
SO, ONE CAR HITS THE OTHER ONE,
AND THEY BOTH GO OVER THE EDGE
OF THE BRIDGE. DEAD.
THAT'S WHEN THEY STARTED
PASSING THE LAWS AGAINST BOOZE,
AGAINST DANCING AND DRINKING
AND-- AND ALL.
MY FATHER
HAD A FIELD DAY.
YOUR FATHER? WHY?
MY OLDER BROTHER
WAS THE ONE WHO GOT KILLED.
GOD, YOU SHOULD HAVE SEEN BOBBY.
HE WAS LIKE WARREN BEATTY,
ONLY TALLER. WASN'T HE?
[Ariel]
MY FATHER WENT OFF
THE DEEP END.
HE DECIDED WE ALL NEEDED
SAVIN', NO MATTER WHAT.
HE'S GONNA PERSONALLY
SAVE THIS LITTLE PISSANT TOWN,
AND HE'S GONNA DELIVER IT
UP TO HEAVEN WITH HIS DAUGHTER
SITTING LIKE A CHERRY ON TOP.
I CALLED OVER
TO RUSTY'S LAST NIGHT.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU FEEL IT
NECESSARY TO LIE TO ME.
I DON'T KNOW WHY YOU FIND IT
NECESSARY TO CHECK UP ON ME.
I'M CONCERNED ABOUT
YOUR WELL BEING, THAT'S ALL.
WELL, HOW COME
WHEN I'M HERE AT HOME,
YOU'RE NEVER AS INTERESTED...
AS TO WHAT I'M DOING OR SAYING
AS YOU ARE WHEN I WALK OUT
THAT DOOR?
WHAM! SUDDENLY,
YOU WANNA KNOW EVERYTHING.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S PROVOKED THIS OUTBURST,
BUT I DON'T LIKE IT,
ANY MORE THAN I LIKE
NOT KNOWING WHERE YOU WERE
FOR SIX HOURS LAST NIGHT.
SHAW, DON'T YOU THINK
WE COULD WAIT ON THIS?
NO, I DON'T THINK THIS CAN WAIT.
AND I'M SICK AND TIRED
OF YOU COMING IN ON HER SIDE.
SHE'S GONNA HAVE TO START
ANSWERING FOR HERSELF.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT GOOD
THAT WOULD DO.
YOU KNOW DON'T LISTEN TO ME
ANY MORE THAN YOU LISTEN TO HER.
[Door Closes]
I'VE NEVER HIT
ANYONE IN MY LIFE.
NO.
WE'RE LOSING HER, VI.
DON'T YOU SEE THAT?
NO.
I SEE YOU CHASING AFTER HER,
AND I SEE HER RUNNING FROM YOU.
SHE'S BECOME SO WILLFUL
AND OBSTINATE.
SHE'S LIKE HER FATHER.
THE TWO OF YOU
WERE SO WONDERFUL ONCE.
YOU HAD SO MUCH
TO TALK ABOUT.
I WAS ALMOST JEALOUS.
IT'S NOT AS IF
WE DON'T TALK.
IT'S JUST THAT...
SOMETIMES PEOPLE
RUN OUT OF THINGS TO SAY.
SHAW.
IT'S 20 YEARS NOW
I'VE BEEN A MINISTER'S WIFE.
AND I'VE BEEN QUIET,
SUPPORTIVE, UNOBTRUSIVE
AND, UH,
AFTER 20 YEARS, I STILL THINK
YOU'RE A WONDERFUL PREACHER.
YOU CAN LIFT A CONGREGATION
UP SO HIGH, THEY HAVE TO
LOOK DOWN TO SEE HEAVEN.
BUT IT'S THE ONE TO ONE
WHERE YOU NEED A LITTLE WORK.
WE COULD REALLY USE
YOUR SUPPORT ON THIS THING.
I REALLY DON'T THINK
MY MOTHER WOULD APPROVE.
OH, YEAH,
BUT WE'RE NOT TALKING
ABOUT A FREE-FOR-ALL.
IT WON'T BE
A DRUNKEN BRAWL.
IT'S JUST A DANCE.
WELL, JUST GIVE IT
SOME THOUGHT, OKAY?
SLEEP ON IT, OKAY?
JUST THINK ABOUT IT.
OKAY, THANKS.
SEE YOU LATER.
SENIOR PROM.
SOUNDS GREAT TO ME.
HEY, HOW YOU DOIN', BOY?
YOU NEED ANY HELP,
YOU JUST LET ME KNOW.
OKAY, YOU GOT IT.
DON'T FORGET.
NOW CHUCK HAS HEARD SOMETHING
THAT'S UPSET HIM REAL GOOD.
AND I WANT YOU
TO TELL ME IT AIN'T SO,
MISTER CHICAGO BIG SHOT.
SEE, HE'S BEEN HEARING
YOU'RE GONNA TRY TO THROW
A DANCE AT SCHOOL.
A SENIOR DANCE.
AND HE FIGURED...
ONLY A SON OF A BITCH
FAGGOT WOULD TRY THAT.
IS THAT
WHAT YOU'RE TRYIN'?
HE SURE THE HELL IS.
EXCUSE ME, GIRLS.
COME ON OUT, REN.
YOU GUY STAY RIGHT THERE. WHOOP!
- IS HE REALLY GONNA
GET US A DANCE?
- YEP. AIN'T YA?
- [Edna]
IT'S ABOUT TIME, MacCORMACK.
- I'LL BE THERE.
THANKS.
LOOK. DON'T YOU HAVE
ANY BETTER MANNERS THAN THAT?
YOUR MAMA TEACH YOU BETTER?
TREAT ANIMALS
LIKE THAT, HUH?
HOW'S IT FEEL?
DON'T FEEL TOO GOOD
NOW, DOES IT, HUH?
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
FIGHT CITY HALL.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
I GOTTA FIGHT CITY HALL?
'CAUSE, MR. MacCORMACK,
THERE'S A TOWN COUNCIL.
IT'S MADE UP
OF ABOUT SEVEN PEOPLE.
SHAW MOORE'S ONE OF THEM.
BURLINGTON CRANSTON IS ANOTHER.
PERSONALLY, I DON'T LIKE
THAT LOUSY SON OF A BITCH.
THEY MEET
EVERY THIRD THURSDAY
OF THE MONTH.
IF THERE'S SOMETHING YOU WANT
IN THIS TOWN, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO TALK TO THEM.
YOU'RE GONNA GET
REALLY CREAMED.
GEEZ. I'M NOT SO GOOD
WITH WORDS.
KEEP THINKING LIKE THAT, REN,
AND YOU ARE GONNA GET CREAMED.
SO, WOODY OVER HERE
DOESN'T KNOW A DANCE
FROM A DIPSTICK.
AND YOU DO?
YOU DO, HUH?
WHICH WAY IS YOUR LEFT?
HUH? WHICH WAY
IS YOUR LEFT?
HE DON'T KNOW
HIS LEFT FOOT
FROM HIS RIGHT FOOT.
I TELL YOU SOMETHING, MAN.
IF I GOTTA GET UP
IN FRONT OF THAT COUNCIL,
THEN YOU ARE GONNA
LEARN HOW TO DANCE.
♪ MY BABY
HE DON'T TALK SWEET ♪
♪ HE AIN'T GOT MUCH TO SAY
♪ BUT HE LOVES ME, LOVES ME
LOVES ME ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT HE LOVES ME
ANYWAY ♪
♪ AND MAYBE
HE DON'T DRESS FINE ♪
♪ BUT I DON'T REALLY MIND
♪ 'CAUSE EVERY TIME HE PULLS ME
NEAR, I JUST WANNA CHEER ♪
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY
♪ LET'S GIVE THE BOY A HAND
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR MY BABY
♪ YOU KNOW
YOU GOTTA UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ OH, MAYBE HE'S NO ROMEO
♪ BUT HE'S MY LOVIN'
ONE-MAN SHOW, OH ♪
♪ WHOA, WHOA, WHOA
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY
♪ MY BABY MAY NOT BE RICH
♪ HE'S WATCHIN' EVERY DIME
♪ BUT HE LOVES ME, LOVES ME
LOVES ME ♪
♪ WE ALWAYS HAVE
A REAL GOOD TIME ♪
♪ AND MAYBE HE SINGS OFF-KEY
♪ BUT THAT'S ALL RIGHT BY ME
YEAH ♪
♪ 'CAUSE WHAT HE DOES
HE DOES SO WELL ♪
♪ MAKES ME WANNA YELL
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY
♪ AH, LET'S GIVE THE BOY
A HAND ♪
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR MY BABY
♪ YOU KNOW
YOU GOTTA UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ OH, MAYBE HE'S NO ROMEO
♪ BUT HE'S MY LOVIN'
ONE-MAN SHOW ♪
♪ OH, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY
♪ [Vocalizing]
♪ 'CAUSE EVERY TIME HE PULLS ME
NEAR, I JUST WANNA CHEER ♪
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY
♪ AH, LET'S GIVE THE BOY
A HAND ♪
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR MY BABY
♪ YOU KNOW
YOU GOTTA UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ OH, MAYBE HE'S NO ROMEO
♪ BUT HE'S MY LOVIN'
ONE-MAN SHOW ♪
♪ OH, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY
♪ LET'S HEAR IT
FOR THE BOY ♪
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR MY MAN
♪ LET'S HEAR IT
FOR MY MAN ♪
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR MY BABY
♪ LET'S HEAR IT
FOR THE BOY ♪
♪ [Vocalizing]
♪ LET'S HEAR IT
FOR MY MAN ♪
♪ [Vocalizing Continues]
♪ LET'S HEAR IT
[Cheering]
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR MY MAN
WHAT IS THIS, ROGER?
I DON'T KNOW THIS BOOK.
I WOULD HOPE YOU WOULDN'T.
OH, REVEREND MOORE,
MRS. EVANS IS CALLING ABOUT
THAT DANCE OVER AT THE SCHOOL.
I'LL CALL HER BACK
RIGHT AFTER JUNIOR BIBLE.
NOW WHAT WERE YOU SAYING?
THIS WAS FOUND
IN ONE OF THE ATHLETIC LOCKERS
OVER AT THE SCHOOL.
A BOOK LIKE THIS SHOULD BE
BURNED. WE SHOULD REMOVE THIS
CORRUPTION FROM THE SHELVES.
THERE'S NO SENSE BLOWING IT UP
INTO SOMETHING THAT IT ISN'T.
HELLO. CAREFUL.
HELLO!
COME ON, MAX.
[Grunts]
I'LL SET UP, VI.
WELL, I THINK IT'S QUITE OBVIOUS
WHAT IT IS.
WELL, IT'S NOT QUITE SO OBVIOUS
HOW I SHOULD HANDLE IT.
REVEREND, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE
MY SAYING SO,
WHEN WE GOT RID OF THAT YOUNG
ENGLISH TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL,
WE DIDN'T GET ANY SUPPORT
FROM YOU.
THAT'S BECAUSE I DIDN'T THINK
WE HAD ANY GROUNDS
FOR HIS DISMISSAL.
REVEREND, AROUND HERE, IT CAUSED
A LOT OF FOLKS SOME WORRY.
WELL, A LOT OF FOLKS WORRY
A LITTLE TOO MUCH.
DOESN'T TAKE MUCH TIME
FOR CORRUPTION TO TAKE ROOT,
REVEREND.
HOW LONG IS THAT, ROGER?
ABOUT AS LONG AS IT TAKES
COMPASSION TO DIE?
SAY, DO I GET A COOKIE?
[Children Together]
NO!
HOW ABOUT SOME MILK?
DID YOU DRINK ALL THE MILK?
YEAH!
[Cheerleaders
Practicing Cheers]
I WANTED TO TALK TO YOU.
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO TELL ME NOTHIN'!
I KNOW WHY
YOU DON'T CALL ME UP.
I WANTED TO TELL YOU MYSELF.
OH, WELL, I KNOW WHY
YOU DON'T WANNA SEE ME ANYMORE.
HEY, I'M NOT STUPID!
I'M NOT BLIND.
IT'S MacCORMACK, AIN'T IT?
YOU'RE JUST DYIN'
TO SCREW MacCORMACK, AREN'T YOU?
- AREN'T YOU?
- YOU'RE SO STUPID!
STUPID? YOU THINK
I DON'T SEE YOU LOOKING AT HIM
LIKE SOME BITCH IN HEAT?
YOU'D WRAP THOSE SKINNY LEGS
AROUND ANYBODY, WON'T YOU?
SHUT UP!
[Grunts]
IS THAT WHAT I GET? HUH?
I TREATED YOU DECENT!
SHIT!
HEY, HEY! PUT THAT DOWN!
DON'T EVEN THINK ABOUT THAT!
- JESUS!
- YOU STUPID!
[Indistinct Yelling]
STOP IT!
NO! OW! OW!
STOP IT, CHUCK!
[Grunting]
NO!
YOU!
[Grunts]
HUH?
[Moaning]
ABOUT THROUGH WITH YOU ANYWAY.
[Engine Starts]
I'M SORRY YOU HAVE
TO SEE ME LIKE THIS.
IT'S OKAY.
I'LL BE OKAY.
I'LL JUST SNEAK IN AT HOME.
I'LL BE FINE.
DO I LOOK OKAY?
YEAH, I THINK
YOU'LL PULL THROUGH.
THANKS FOR COMING FOR ME.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I MEAN, THERE'S NOTHING
TO UNDERSTAND.
IT'S FOR TAKIN' ON MY FATHER.
OH, NO, NO.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT. I GOT NO BEEF WITH HIM.
WAIT. NO, WAIT.
THIS IS MY FIGHT, YOU KNOW?
IT'S WITH THE TOWN.
IT'S NOT WITH ONE GUY.
YOU DON'T GET TO TURN MY FIGHT
INTO SOME KIND OF A "SCREW YOU"
TO YOUR OLD MAN.
HEY, LOOK. UH--
MAYBE, UH--
MAYBE-- MAYBE YOU SHOULDN'T TRY
SO HARD TO FORGET YOUR BROTHER.
OR TRY TO MAKE YOUR FATHER
FORGET HIM, YOU KNOW?
[Sighs]
IT'S NOT THAT EASY.
I KNOW, I KNOW.
DO I STILL GET THE BOX?
HMM?
[Chuckles]
GIVE ME THE BOX.
COME ON.
♪ [Music Box]
THAT'S NICE.
THINK YOU MIGHT EVER KISS ME?
♪ [Continues]
HARVEY AND BERNIE WERE HERE
FOR A LONG TIME.
MMM. THEY STILL TALKING
ABOUT THAT DANCE?
YEAH.
WHAT DID YOU
DECIDE TO DO?
IT'S NOT GONNA HAPPEN.
THAT'S ONE MORE THING
THAT ARIEL'S NOT GONNA
FORGIVE ME FOR, BUT--
CAN YOU STEP OUT OF THE WAY
LONG ENOUGH TO REALIZE THAT
SHE'S DOING ALL OF THIS FOR YOU?
ME? NO.
[Chuckles]
I DON'T SEE THAT.
I JUST KNOW THAT WHEN KIDS
DANCE TOGETHER, THEY BECOME
SEXUALLY IRRESPONSIBLE.
I CAN'T TAKE THE CHANCE OF--
[Laughing]
WELL, WHAT'S SO FUNNY?
[Mutters]
YOU TALK LIKE THAT'S THE ONLY
THING THAT GETS 'EM EXCITED.
DON'T YOU REMEMBER WHEN
WE USED TO LOOK AT EACH OTHER
AND GET EXCITED?
WELL, IT'S JUST
THE SAME WITH THEM.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
PUT THEIR EYES OUT.
NO.
NONE OF THIS IS GONNA UNDO
ONE STUPID ACCIDENT.
I'M RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE SPIRITUAL LIFE
OF THIS COMMUNITY.
SHAW, YOU CAN'T BE A FATHER
TO EVERYBODY.
YOU CAN'T DO THAT.
I THOUGHT THAT AT LEAST
YOU BELIEVED IN ME.
I NEVER STOPPED.
IT'S A TOWN COUNCIL MEETING.
SEE YOU TOMORROW NIGHT.
ONLY FAIRIES DANCE.
HEY, I'LL LAY YOU FLAT, ARIEL.
SUPPORT REN MacCORMACK
AT THE COUNCIL MEETING
TOMORROW NIGHT.
YOU CAN MAKE A DIFFERENCE!
I'M CALLING TO REMIND YOU
TO COME TO THE TOWN COUNCIL
MEETING TOMORROW NIGHT.
HI.
STILL HURT?
MM, NAH.
GOOD.
NERVOUS?
NO, UH-UH.
LOOK, I, UH-- YEAH.
YEAH, I'M NERVOUS.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I'M GONNA
SAY TO THE COUNCIL.
THERE'S ONLY THE SEVEN
OF THEM, THOUGH, RIGHT?
WHO ELSE IS GONNA BE THERE?
EVERYBODY.
[Sighs]
TAKE A DEEP BREATH.
YOU READY?
WHAT IS IT?
HOLY BIBLE?
[Chuckling]
WHAT--
OH, THIS IS GREAT.
THIS IS GREAT!
[Mumbles]
HOW DID YOU KNOW
WHERE TO FIND ALL THIS?
ARE YOU KIDDING?
[Class Bell Ringing]
COME HERE.
I WANNA TELL YOU SOMETHING.
THANKS.
SHH!
[Man Laughing]
SHH! SHH!
COME ON!
[Man Belches]
[Tires Screech]
[Amy, Sarah Screaming, Crying]
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
- OH, MY GOD!
- AMY!
- OH, WHAT IS IT?
- "BURN IN HELL"?
THIS SAYS "BURN IN HELL."
- LET ME SEE.
- [Chattering]
- OH, JESUS.
OH, REN,
WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON?
OBVIOUSLY SOMEBODY'S
TRYING TO MAKE A POINT.
DO YOU SEE NOW?
YOU DON'T GO
WAVIN' YOUR FLAGS AROUND HERE
WITHOUT PEOPLE TAKIN' SHOTS!
NOW THIS IS NOT
THE FIRST TIME.
ARE YOU OKAY?
OH. YOU TOO.
MY BUSINESS WAS OFF.
BUT PEOPLE ARE TAKING
BUSINESS AWAY FROM ME.
YOUR AUNT'S BEEN GETTING
SOME UGLY PHONE CALLS, AND
TODAY YOUR MOTHER LOST HER JOB.
WES!
MOM, IS THAT TRUE? WHAT--
MR. COLLINS THOUGHT
MAYBE I OUGHT TO STAY HOME
AND BE A PROPER MOTHER.
- AND WHAT DID YOU SAY?
- I TOLD HIM TO SHOVE IT.
DAMN IT, ETHEL,
THIS IS SERIOUS!
WES, THERE'S OTHER JOBS!
WHERE?
[Lulu]
SHOULDN'T YOU CALL THE POLICE?
I DON'T KNOW HOW MUCH GOOD
IT'LL DO. I'LL GET JIM EARLHAUS
OVER HERE.
WILL YOU STOP?
NOW WILL YOU STOP?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
THIS TOWN.
IT'S LIKE SOMETHING'S
CHOKIN' EVERYBODY,
ONLY THEY DON'T KNOW
THEY'RE CHOKIN'.
LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING.
WHY THIS DANCE IN THIS TOWN?
IT'S NOT JUST ABOUT A DANCE--
NOT ANYMORE.
I KNOW.
THAT'S WHAT I MEAN.
I WATCH YOU. I SEE.
- YOU'RE NOT GONNA
UNDERSTAND THIS.
- TRY ME.
[Mutters]
WHEN DAD FIRST THREATENED
TO LEAVE, I THOUGHT
IT WAS 'CAUSE OF ME.
I THOUGHT IT WAS SOMETHIN'
THAT I WASN'T DOIN' RIGHT,
YOU KNOW?
AND I FIGURED THERE WAS
SOMETHIN' THAT I COULD DO...
TO MAKE IT LIKE IT WAS
AND THAT HE'D WANNA STAY,
YOU KNOW?
BUT WHEN HE LEFT
JUST LIKE THAT...
AND I REALIZED THAT
EVERYTHING THAT I'D DONE,
HOPIN' THAT HE'D STAY--
EVERYTHING I'D DONE--
IT DIDN'T-- IT DIDN'T
MEAN SHIT, YOU KNOW?
DIDN'T-- DIDN'T MATTER.
AND I FELT LIKE,
WHAT DIFFERENCE DOES IT MAKE?
BUT NOW-- NOW...
I'M THINKIN'...
I COULD REALLY DO SOMETHIN',
YOU KNOW?
LIKE I COULD REALLY DO
SOMETHIN' FOR ME THIS TIME.
YOU KNOW?
OTHERWISE,
I'M JUST GONNA DISAPPEAR.
[Chattering]
[Man]
ALL RIGHT, VIRGINIA.
I GUESS THAT ENDS
THE DISCUSSION ON THIS ISSUE.
AND SO THE PRICE
OF A DOG LICENSE WILL GO
FROM $3.50 TO $4.50.
A LICENSED PET IS A HAPPY ONE.
AND THAT TAKES CARE
OF OLD BUSINESS. BURLINGTON?
[Clears Throat]
THANK YOU, UH, VIRGINIA.
THAT WAS REAL GOOD.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW WE CAN CONSIDER, UH,
ANY NEW BUSINESS.
[Chattering]
[Clears Throat]
WAIT. EXCUSE ME.
BEFORE WE BEGIN, I JUST WANT
TO REMIND ALL YOU KIDS.
WE'RE CONDUCTIN'
AN OFFICIAL MEETIN'.
WE'RE NOT GONNA TOLERATE
ANY DISTURBANCES.
OKAY. THE FLOOR IS NOW OPEN
FOR ANY NEW BUSINESS.
MY NAME IS REN MacCORMACK,
AND I WOULD LIKE TO MOVE...
ON BEHALF OF MOST OF THE SENIOR
CLASS OF BOMONT HIGH SCHOOL...
THAT THE LAW
AGAINST PUBLIC DANCING...
WITHIN THE TOWN LIMITS
OF BOMONT BE ABOLISHED.
[Cheering]
UH, MR. CHAIRMAN,
COULD I ADDRESS MYSELF TO THIS?
- YOU BET.
- EVEN IF THIS WAS NOT A LAW,
WHICH IT IS,
I'M AFRAID I WOULD HAVE
A LOT OF DIFFICULTY...
ENDORSING AN ENTERPRISE...
WHICH IS AS FRAUGHT
WITH GENUINE PERIL...
AS I BELIEVE THIS ONE TO BE.
BESIDES THE LIQUOR
AND THE DRUGS...
WHICH ALWAYS SEEM TO
ACCOMPANY SUCH AN EVENT,
THE THING THAT DISTRESSES ME
EVEN MORE, REN,
IS THE SPIRITUAL CORRUPTION...
THAT CAN BE INVOLVED.
THESE DANCES
AND THIS KIND OF MUSIC
CAN BE DESTRUCTIVE.
AND, UH, REN, I'M AFRAID
YOU'RE GONNA FIND...
THAT MOST OF THE PEOPLE
IN OUR COMMUNITY ARE GONNA AGREE
WITH ME ON THIS.
I DO.
[Chattering]
THAT'S ALL I HAVE TO SAY.
I BELIEVE A VOTE IS IN ORDER
ON THE MOTION.
- ALL THOSE OPPOSED--
- [Ren]
WELL, EXCUSE ME.
I WOULD JUST LIKE TO SAY
SOMETHING IF I COULD.
[Loud Chattering]
IT IS OUTRAGEOUS!
IF YOU THINK THAT YOU--
ELEANOR, SIT DOWN.
I THINK MR. MacCORMACK
HAS A RIGHT TO BE HEARD.
[Cheering, Whistling]
WELL, I JUST--
I-I JUST WANTED TO SAY
A FEW WORDS ABOUT THIS MOTION...
SO THAT Y-YOU WOULDN'T THINK...
THAT WE WERE ENCOURAGING
DESTRUCTION...
WITH THIS IDEA.
"FROM THE OLDEST OF TIMES,
"PEOPLE DANCED
FOR A NUMBER OF REASONS.
"THEY DANCED IN PRAYER...
"OR SO THAT THEIR CROPS
WOULD BE PLENTIFUL...
"OR SO THEIR HUNT WOULD BE GOOD.
"AND THEY DANCED
TO STAY PHYSICALLY FIT...
"AND SHOW
THEIR COMMUNITY SPIRIT.
AND THEY DANCED...
TO CELEBRATE."
AND THAT-- THAT IS THE DANCING
THAT WE'RE TALKIN' ABOUT.
[Woman] YEAH.
AREN'T WE TOLD...
IN... PSALM 149:
"PRAISE YE THE LORD.
"SING UNTO THE LORD...
A NEW SONG.
LET THEM PRAISE HIS NAME
IN THE DANCE."
AMEN.
AND IT WAS KING DAVID--
KIND DAVID WHO WE READ ABOUT
IN SAMUEL.
AND-- AND WHAT DID DAVID DO?
WHAT DID DAVID DO?
[Laughter]
"DAVID DANCED BEFORE THE LORD...
"WITH ALL HIS MIGHT,
LEAPING-- LEAPING AND DANCING
BEFORE THE LORD."
LEAPING AND DANCING.
ECCLESIASTES ASSURES US...
THAT THERE IS A TIME
FOR EVERY PURPOSE UNDER HEAVEN--
A TIME TO LAUGH...
AND A TIME TO WEEP,
A TIME TO MOURN...
AND THERE IS
A TIME TO DANCE.
AND THERE WAS A TIME
FOR THIS LAW, BUT NOT ANYMORE.
SEE, THIS IS
OUR TIME TO DANCE.
IT IS OUR WAY OF--
OF... CELEBRATING LIFE.
THAT'S THE WAY IT WAS
IN THE BEGINNING.
IT'S THE WAY
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN.
IT SHOULD BE NOW.
[Andy]
YOU KNOW YOU WERE RAILROADED,
DON'T YA? HUH?
BOY, WHEN ARE YOU GONNA WAKE UP
AND SMELL THE COFFEE?
SHAW MOORE WALKED INTO
THAT MEETIN' WITH THEM VOTES
ALREADY IN HIS POCKET.
YOU DIDN'T HAVE A PRAYER.
BAD PUN, ANDY.
WELL, WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO NOW?
IT'S OVER.
WHAT IF IT AIN'T?
WHAT IF YOU HAD YOUR DANCE
IN BAYSON?
NO. UH-UH. THE WHOLE POINT WAS
TO DO SOMETHIN' HERE IN BOMONT.
BAYSON'S,
WHAT, 30 MILES AWAY?
NOT WHERE IT RUNS UP
TO THESE TRACKS, IT AIN'T.
HUH?
WELL, I FIGURE IF THE BOMONT
FIRE TRUCKS CAN'T CROSS
THESE TRACKS,
NEITHER CAN THE LONG ARM
OF THE LAW.
YEAH, WHAT ABOUT THE LONG ARM
OF REVEREND MOORE?
REMEMBER HE SAID IF YOU COULD
FIND A WAY TO CONVINCE HIM,
IT WOULDN'T BE A SPIRITUAL
CORRUPTION, HE'D THINK ABOUT IT.
SO?
MAKE HIM THINK ABOUT IT.
[Reverend]
"AND I BEHELD AND HEARD
AN ANGEL...
"FLYING THROUGH THE MIDST
OF HEAVEN, SAYING...
"WITH A LOUD VOICE,
'WOE, WOE,
"WOE TO THE INHABITERS
OF THE EARTH.'
"AND I SAW A STAR FALL
FROM HEAVEN UNTO THE EARTH...
"AND THE ANGEL WAS GIVEN
THE KEY...
"TO THE BOTTOMLESS PIT.
"AND HE...
OPENED THE BOTTOMLESS PIT,
"AND THERE AROSE A SMOKE
OUT OF THE PIT,
"AS THE SMOKE
OF A GREAT FURNACE.
"AND THE SUN AND THE AIR
WERE DARKENED...
BY REASON OF THE SMOKE
OF THE PIT."
- YES?
- I USED TO GET SUCH A KICK...
OUT OF WATCHING YOU WORK UP
YOUR SERMONS.
- AND NOW?
- IT'S DIFFERENT.
I SEE THE STAGE.
I SEE COSTUMES.
IT'S SHOW BUSINESS,
ISN'T IT?
WELL,
IT'S THE ONLY WAY I KNOW TO...
REACH PEOPLE'S EMOTIONS.
I HAVEN'T HEARD FROM YOU
FOR A WHILE.
WHEN WAS IT, THURSDAY?
I WAS ANGRY
AND YOU WERE ANGRY.
I WAS NOT.
YES, YOU WERE.
IF YOU WEREN'T, YOU WOULD HAVE
ASKED ME WHAT WAS WRONG.
YOU KNEW.
ARIEL, I CANNOT
LET THIS DANCE HAPPEN.
REN MacCORMACK MADE
A LOT OF PEOPLE STOP AND THINK.
I OBJECT TO THAT KIND OF MUSIC,
AND I THINK YOU KNOW WHY.
-BECAUSE PEOPLE FORNICATE TO IT.
-I NEVER SAID THAT.
-THAT'S WHAT YOU TOLD THE BOARD.
-THAT WAS NOT MEANT
FOR YOUR EARS!
WHEN DO MY EARS GET OLD ENOUGH?
WHEN YOU STOP PROTECTIN' ME!
- I'M NO SAINT, YOU KNOW.
- IT IS MY DUTY TO LOOK AFTER
THE SPIRITUAL GROWTH OF THIS--
I'M NOT EVEN A VIRGIN.
DON'T YOU TALK LIKE THAT
IN HERE!
WHY NOT?
ISN'T THIS WHERE I'M SUPPOSED
TO CONFESS MY SINS
TO MY PREACHER?
IN CHURCH!
I ASK TO BE FORGIVEN!
- AM I? OH, FORGIVE ME
AND DELIVER ME!
- YOU GET OUT OF HERE!
- [Indistinct]
- THANK HEAVENS YOU'RE HERE.
PEOPLE ARE CALLING.
THEY'RE THERE
OVER AT THE LIBRARY.
[Clapping, Chattering]
ROGER, ELEANOR,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WE DECIDED THESE BOOKS
ARE INFLUENCES ON OUR CHILDREN
WE JUST DON'T NEED.
WHOSE AUTHORITY DO YOU HAVE?
YOU AGREED
THIS WAS GARBAGE.
WAIT. EVERYBODY, LISTEN TO ME!
[Panting]
WHEN DID YOU ALL DECIDE
TO SIT IN JUDGEMENT?
WHO ELECTED ALL OF YOU...
TO BE THE SAVIORS OF EVERYBODY'S
SOULS IN BOMONT?
WE HAVE A PERFECT RIGHT
TO DETERMINE WHAT OUR CHILDREN--
ROGER!
WHEN YOU'VE BURNED ALL OF THESE,
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO THEN?
CHRIS, TAKE THESE OUT OF HERE.
SATAN IS NOT IN THESE BOOKS.
HE'S IN HERE!
HE'S IN YOUR HEARTS.
GO ON HOME, ALL OF YOU.
GO AND SIT IN JUDGEMENT
ON YOURSELVES.
ROGER... GO HOME.
ELEANOR, COME ON.
GO HOME NOW.
COME ON. BOTH OF YOU.
SOMETIMES THINGS
DON'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
IF YOU COULD EXPLAIN TO ME
ABOUT MY FATHER, MAYBE I COULD
EXPLAIN TO YOU ABOUT YOUR SON.
BUT IT DOESN'T MAKE
ANY SENSE.
LOOK. UH, I GOTTA GO.
LISTEN. I KNOW YOU'RE GONNA
DO WHAT YOU GOTTA DO, BUT...
THANKS FOR LISTENIN'.
REN,
THANK YOU FOR, UH--
WELL... THANK YOU.
THAT WAS YOUR FRIEND REN.
HE CAME HERE TO ASK ME
IF HE COULD TAKE YOU
TO A SENIOR PROM.
[Sighs]
WELL, I'M RUNNING OUT
OF ANSWERS, ARIEL.
I KNOW HOW HARD IT IS
FOR YOU.
I KNOW I'M NOT
MAKING IT EASIER.
I JUST DON'T KNOW THAT I BELIEVE
IN EVERYTHING YOU BELIEVE IN.
BUT I BELIEVE IN YOU.
I'M... STANDING UP HERE...
BEFORE YOU TODAY...
WITH A VERY TROUBLED HEART.
YOU SEE, MY FRIENDS,
I'VE ALWAYS INSISTED ON...
TAKING RESPONSIBILITY
FOR YOUR LIVES.
BUT... I'M REALLY...
UH, LIKE A FIRST-TIME PARENT...
WHO MAKES MISTAKES...
AND... TRIES TO LEARN
FROM THEM.
AND, LIKE THAT PARENT,
I FIND MYSELF
AT THAT MOMENT...
WHEN I HAVE TO DECIDE,
DO I HOLD ON...
OR DO I TRUST YOU
TO YOURSELVES,
TO LET GO...
AND HOPE
THAT YOU UNDERSTOOD...
AT LEAST SOME OF MY LESSONS?
IF WE DON'T START
TRUSTING OUR CHILDREN,
HOW WILL THEY EVER BECOME...
TRUSTWORTHY?
I'M TOLD THAT THE SENIOR CLASS
AT THE HIGH SCHOOL
HAS GOT USE...
OF A WAREHOUSE IN BAYSON...
FOR THE PURPOSE OF
PUTTING ON A SENIOR DANCE.
PLEASE...
JOIN ME TO PRAY...
TO THE LORD...
TO GUIDE THEM
IN THEIR ENDEAVORS.
♪ LOOKIN' INTO YOUR EYES
I KNOW I'M RIGHT ♪
♪ IF THERE'S ANYTHING WORTH
MY LOVE, IT'S WORTH A FIGHT ♪
♪ WE ONLY GET ONE CHANCE
♪ BUT NOTHIN' TIES OUR HANDS
♪ YOU'RE WHAT I WANT
LISTEN TO ME ♪
♪ NOTHIN' I WANT'S
OUT OF MY REACH ♪
♪ I'M FREE
♪ HEAVEN HELPS THE MAN
WHO FIGHTS HIS FEAR ♪
♪ LOVE'S THE ONLY THING
♪ THAT KEEPS ME HERE
♪ I'M FREE
♪ YOU'RE THE REASON
♪ THAT I'M HANGIN' ON
♪ MY HEART'S STAYIN'
WHERE MY HEART BELONGS ♪
♪ I'M FREE
♪ RUNNIN' AWAY
WILL NEVER MAKE YOU FREE ♪
♪ AND NOTHIN' WE SIGN
IS ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE ♪
♪ I WANNA HOLD YOU NOW
♪ BUT I WON'T HOLD YOU DOWN
♪ I'M SHAKIN' THE PAST
MAKIN' MY BREAKS ♪
♪ TAKIN' CONTROL
IF THAT'S WHAT IT TAKES ♪
♪ I'M FREE
♪ HEAVEN HELPS THE MAN
♪ WHO FIGHTS HIS FEAR
♪ LOVE'S THE ONLY THING
♪ THAT KEEPS ME HERE
♪ I'M FREE
♪ YOU'RE THE REASON
♪ THAT I'M HANGIN' ON
♪ MY HEART'S STAYIN'
- LIGHTS!
- ♪ WHERE MY HEART BELONGS
[Cheering]
♪ YOU'RE THE REASON
♪ THAT I'M HANGIN' ON
♪ MY HEART'S STAYIN'
♪ WHERE MY HEART BELONGS
♪ I'M FREE
♪ HEAVEN HELPS THE MAN
♪ WHO FIGHTS HIS FEAR
YOU LOOK VERY NICE.
OH, NO.
YES, YOU DO.
NO.
[Chuckling]
YES, YOU LOOK
VERY NICE.
NO.
YES, YOU DO.
YOU LOOK WONDERFUL.
NO-- YOU THINK?
- YEAH. MM-HMM.
- [Sighs]
NO.
[Sighs]
YOU CAN'T VERY WELL
GO TO A PROM WITHOUT A CORSAGE.
[Both Laughing]
THIS IS GORGEOUS!
MOM!
[Sniffs]
WHERE DO YOU THINK
I SHOULD--
HERE'S A WRIST THING HERE.
OH, MOM,
YOU REALLY DIDN'T HAVE TO.
I DIDN'T.
NOW DON'T GO ON TO HIM ABOUT IT
'CAUSE HE'LL ONLY DENY IT.
HEY, I WAS GONNA
COME UP AND GET-- I WAS...
GONNA COME UP AND GET YOU.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU'RE BEAUTIFUL.
WHAT?
I-- I MEAN IT.
YOU ARE BEAUTIFUL.
COME ON.
[Chuckles]
THANK YOU.
[Clears Throat]
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA!
♪ I THOUGHT THAT DREAMS BELONGED
TO OTHER MEN ♪
♪ 'CAUSE EACH TIME I GOT CLOSE
♪ THEY'D FALL APART AGAIN
♪ I FEARED MY HEART
WOULD BEAT IN SECRECY ♪
♪ I FACED THE NIGHTS ALONE
♪ OH, HOW COULD I HAVE KNOWN
♪ THAT ALL MY LIFE
I ONLY NEEDED YOU ♪
♪ OH, ALMOST PARADISE
♪ WE'RE KNOCKIN'
ON HEAVEN'S DOOR ♪
♪ ALMOST PARADISE
♪ HOW COULD WE ASK FOR MORE
♪ I SWEAR
THAT I CAN SEE FOREVER ♪
♪ IN YOUR EYES
♪ PARADISE
♪ IT SEEMS LIKE PERFECT LOVE'S
SO HARD TO FIND ♪
♪ [Continues, Indistinct]
WELL, LET'S
TAKE A CLOSER LOOK.
NO, SHE'LL THINK
I'M CHECKING UP AGAIN.
NO. SHE WON'T EVEN KNOW
WE'RE HERE. COME ON.
YOU'RE THE LAST FOLKS I EXPECTED
TO SEE AROUND HERE TONIGHT.
EVENING, ANDY.
HI, ANDY.
HI. REVEREND,
YOU DONE A GOOD THING HERE.
WELL, I'M STILL NOT SURE
IT WAS THE RIGHT THING.
COMES CLOSE.
SHAW.
SHAW?
SHAW, WHAT IS IT?
IT'S JUST
THE TWO OF US AGAIN, HUH?
SHAW.
WHAT?
WE'RE ALMOST DANCING.
♪ ALMOST PARADISE
[Chuckles]
HI, RUSTY.
HI!
HELLO, WILLARD.
YOU PROMISED
YOU WOULDN'T FIGHT.
DON'T YOU LOOK SWEET.
[Laughs]
WHAT DO YOU WANT, CHUCK?
OH, I GOT A LITTLE BUSINESS
WITH YOUR FRIEND MacCORMACK.
HEY, CHUCK, COOL IT, ALL RIGHT?
NO FIGHTS TONIGHT, OKAY?
HEY, NO FIGHTS, FELLAS.
[Laughter]
[Chuck]
SURE, WILLARD.
ALL RIGHT.
- CUTE. NO FIGHTS, WILLARD.
- AH! DAMN, MAN!
I TOLD YOU, ALL RIGHT.
I PROMISED RUSTY NO FIGHTS
TONIGHT, OKAY?
- [Screaming, Indistinct]
- [Chuck Grunting]
[Rusty] OH, WILLARD!
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO,
RUSTY?
KILL THE SON OF A BITCH!
HELP, SOMEBODY!
[Grunting Continues]
- CHUCK!
- HEY, IT'S MR. DANCE FEVER!
YEAH, YOU'RE A GODDAMN HERO
WHEN IT'S FIVE TO ONE!
[Grunting, Shouting]
BEAT THE SHIT OUT OF HIM!
[Indistinct Shouting]
- [Yells]
- [Grunts]
BASTARD!
WE'RE GONNA DANCE NOW,
MacCORMACK, HUH?
[Grunting Continues]
[Rusty]
YEAH! WHOA!
[Ariel] ALL RIGHT!
HEY, HANDSOME.
GREAT DANCE, MAN.
[Laughing]
OUR HEROES!
REN!
I THOUGHT YOU GUYS WERE GONNA
ACTUALLY FIGHT OR SOMETHING.
[Laughs]
YOU WERE GREAT!
HEY, HEY, WHAT'S THIS I SEE?
I THOUGHT THIS WAS A PARTY!
LET'S DANCE!
[Cheering]
♪
JUST WATCH, ALL RIGHT?
♪ BEEN WORKIN' SO HARD
♪ I'M PUNCHIN' MY CARD
♪ EIGHT HOURS, FOR WHAT
♪ OH, TELL ME WHAT I GOT
[Cheering]
♪ I GET THIS FEELING
♪ THAT TIME'S
BEEN HOLDIN' ME DOWN ♪
♪ I'LL HIT THE CEILING
♪ OR ELSE I'LL TEAR UP
THIS TOWN ♪
♪ TONIGHT I GOTTA CUT LOOSE
FOOTLOOSE ♪
♪ KICK OFF YOUR SUNDAY SHOES
♪ PLEASE, LOUISE
♪ PULL ME OFF OF MY KNEES
♪ JACK, GET BACK
♪ COME ON, BEFORE WE CRACK
♪ LOSE YOUR BLUES
♪ EVERYBODY CUT FOOTLOOSE
♪ YOU'RE PLAYIN' SO COOL
♪ OBEYIN' EVERY RULE
♪ DIG WAY DOWN IN YOUR HEART
♪ YOU'RE BURNIN'
YEARNIN' FOR SOME ♪
♪ SOMEBODY TO TELL YOU
- WHOA!
- ♪ THAT LIFE AIN'T
PASSIN' YOU BY ♪
♪ I'M TRYIN' TO TELL YOU
♪ IT WILL
IF YOU DON'T EVEN TRY ♪
♪ YOU CAN FLY IF YOU'D ONLY
CUT LOOSE, FOOTLOOSE ♪
♪ KICK OFF YOUR SUNDAY SHOES
♪ OOH-WEE, MARIE
♪ SHAKE IT, SHAKE IT FOR ME
♪ OH, MILO
COME ON, COME ON, LET'S GO ♪
♪ LOSE YOUR BLUES
♪ EVERYBODY CUT FOOTLOOSE
♪ CUT FOOTLOOSE
♪ OH, OH, OH, OH
♪ YOU GOT TO TURN IT AROUND
- ♪ AND PUT YOUR FEET
ON THE GROUND ♪
- GO! GO! GO!
♪ NOW JUST TAKE A HOLD
OF YOUR SOUL ♪
♪ AH
♪ I'M TURNIN' IT LOOSE
FOOTLOOSE ♪
♪ KICK OFF YOUR SUNDAY SHOES
♪ PLEASE, LOUISE
♪ PULL ME OFF OF MY KNEES
♪ JACK, GET BACK
♪ COME ON, BEFORE WE CRACK
♪ LOSE YOUR BLUES
[Screams]
♪ EVERYBODY CUT FOOTLOOSE
FOOTLOOSE ♪
[Screaming Continues]
♪ KICK OFF YOUR SUNDAY SHOES
♪ OOH-WEE, MARIE
♪ SHAKE IT, SHAKE IT FOR ME
♪ OH, MILO
♪ COME ON, COME ON, LET'S GO
- ♪ LOSE YOUR BLUES
- [Screaming Continues]
♪ EVERYBODY CUT FOOTLOOSE
♪ JACK, GET BACK
♪ COME ON, BEFORE WE CRACK
♪ EVERYBODY CUT, EVERYBODY CUT
♪ EVERYBODY
EVERYBODY CUT FOOTLOOSE ♪
♪ LOOKIN' INTO YOUR EYES
I KNOW I'M RIGHT ♪
♪ IF THERE'S ANYTHING WORTH
MY LOVE, IT'S WORTH A FIGHT ♪
♪ WE ONLY GET ONE CHANCE
♪ AND NOTHIN' TIES OUR HANDS
♪ YOU'RE WHAT I WANT
LISTEN TO ME ♪
♪ NOTHIN' I WANT'S
OUT OF MY REACH ♪
♪ I'M FREE
♪ HEAVEN HELPS THE MAN
WHO FIGHTS HIS FEAR ♪
♪ LOVE'S THE ONLY THING
♪ THAT KEEPS ME HERE
♪ I'M FREE
♪ YOU'RE THE REASON
♪ THAT I'M HANGIN' ON
♪ MY HEART'S STAYIN'
♪ WHERE MY HEART BELONGS
♪ I'M FREE
♪ MY BABY
HE DON'T TALK SWEET ♪
♪ HE AIN'T GOT MUCH TO SAY
♪ BUT HE LOVES ME, LOVES ME
LOVES ME ♪
♪ I KNOW THAT HE LOVES ME
ANYWAY ♪
♪ AND MAYBE
HE DON'T DRESS FINE ♪
♪ BUT I DON'T REALLY MIND
♪ 'CAUSE EVERY TIME HE PULLS ME
NEAR, I JUST WANNA CHEER ♪
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY
♪ LET'S GIVE THE BOY A HAND
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR MY BABY
♪ YOU KNOW
YOU GOTTA UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ OH, MAYBE HE'S NO ROMEO
♪ BUT HE'S MY LOVIN'
ONE-MAN SHOW ♪
♪ OH, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY
♪ OOH
♪ OOH, OOH, YEAH
♪ 'CAUSE EVERY TIME HE PULLS ME
NEAR, I JUST WANNA CHEER ♪
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY
♪ AH, LET'S GIVE THE BOY
A HAND ♪
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR MY BABY
♪ YOU KNOW
YOU GOTTA UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ OH, MAYBE HE'S NO ROMEO
♪ BUT HE'S MY LOVIN'
ONE-MAN SHOW ♪
♪ OH, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY ♪
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR MY MAN
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR MY MAN ♪
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR MY BABY
♪ LET'S HEAR IT FOR THE BOY ♪