[TRUMPET MUSIC PLAYING]
♪ I'LL BE GLAD
WHEN YOU'RE DEAD ♪
♪ YOU RASCAL, YOU
♪ I'LL BE GLAD
WHEN YOU'RE DEAD ♪
♪ YOU RASCAL, YOU
♪ YOU KNOW
YOU DONE ME WRONG ♪
♪ YOU STOLE MY WIFE AND GONE
♪ I'LL BE GLAD
WHEN YOU'RE DEAD ♪
♪ YOU RASCAL, YOU
♪ I'M GONNA KILL YOU
JUST FOR FUN ♪
♪ YOU RASCAL, YOU
♪ I'M GONNA KILL YOU
JUST FOR FUN ♪
♪ YOU RASCAL, YOU
♪ I'M GONNA KILL YOU
JUST FOR FUN ♪
♪ THE BUGS CAN HAVE YOU
WHEN I'M DONE ♪
♪ I'LL BE GLAD
WHEN YOU'RE DEAD ♪
♪ YOU RASCAL, YOU
♪ I'LL BE GLAD
WHEN YOU'RE DEAD ♪
♪ YOU RASCAL, YOU
[SIGHS]
MORON.
PUTZ, WHERE ARE
THEY BITING?
POP SAYS HE SPOTTED
CATFISH HUNTER
DOWN
AT INDIAN SLOUGH.
CATFISH HUNTER?
MAYBE THIS IS
THE YEAR WE CATCH HIM.
WHERE DO YOU GET
THAT "WE" CRAP?
YOU GOT A MOUSE
IN YOUR POCKET?
THAT FISH
BELONGS TO ME.
I'LL LET YOU VISIT HIM
WHEN HE'S MOUNTED ON MY WALL.
HONEY? YOU FORGOT
YOUR THERMOS.
HI, ARIEL.
HI!
♪ YOU MESSED WITH MY WIFE,
YOU RASCAL, YOU ♪
♪ YOU MESSED
WITH MY WIFE ♪
♪ AND NOW I'M
GONNA TAKE YOUR LIFE ♪
♪ I'LL BE GLAD
WHEN YOU'RE DEAD ♪
♪ YOU RASCAL, YOU
THAT'S MY FISH!
YOU SON OF A...
♪ I'M GONNA KILL YOU
JUST FOR FUN ♪
♪ YOU RASCAL, YOU
♪ I'M GONNA KILL YOU
JUST FOR FUN ♪
♪ THE BUGS CAN HAVE YOU
WHEN I'M DONE ♪
♪ I'LL BE GLAD
WHEN YOU'RE DEAD ♪
♪ YOU RASCAL, YOU
TALK ABOUT HIM,
JOEY!
♪ I'LL BE GLAD
WHEN YOU'RE DEAD ♪
♪ YOU RASCAL, YOU
OH, THAT'S IT.
COME ON.
JUST ONE GOOD BITE.
YES! AND I GOT YOU!
OH, YEAH!
OH, YES!
OH, NO.
OH, DAMN.
Radio: HERE COMES ANOTHER MAN
AROUND THIRD.
HE WILL BE HELD UP.
CASTALDO WITH A DOUBLE...
HEY!
HEY, DICKHEAD!
TURN THAT
RADIO DOWN!
YOU'RE SCARING
ALL THE FISH AWAY.
Radio: HE PLAYED
IN THE TWIN CITIES
FOR THE MINNEAPOLIS MILLERS
BEFORE GOING TO BOSTON.
WE'LL HAVE ANOTHER LOOK.
TURN THE DAMN RADIO
DOWN, WILL YOU?
Radio:
WENT OUT AND GOT IT--
WHO PUT A BUG
UP YOUR ASS?
I SAW HIM.
CATFISH HUNTER?
RIGHT AFTER
I DROPPED ANCHOR,
HE STUCK HIS HEAD UP
OVER BY THAT LOG.
HE JUST LOOKED
AT ME, SMILED,
AND SWAM DOWN
INTO THE MUD.
HE SMILED?
YEAH.
WHEW!
HOLEY MOLEY. HOW BIG
IS HE THIS YEAR?
HE'S THE SIZE OF
A GODDAMN BUICK,
AND I WOULD HAVE HAD HIM
CAUGHT IF YOU HADN'T SHOWN UP.
YOU COULDN'T CATCH CRABS
FROM A $10 HOOKER.
HOW IS YOUR SISTER
BY THE WAY?
HA HA HA!
OH, HO! HEE! HA!
I SAW SVEN
DOWN AT THE DAM.
HE SAYS THERE'S A RUMOR GOING
AROUND THAT RICK RAGETTI'S COUSIN
IS COMING DOWN FROM ST. PAUL
TO BUY CHUCK'S BAIT.
OH, AN ITALIAN
RUNNING CHUCK'S, HUH?
YEAH. WE'LL HAVE THE FIRST
MOB-RUN BAIT SHOP IN WABASHA.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING?
I WAS HERE FIRST.
I GOT JUST AS MUCH RIGHT
TO BE HERE AS YOU DO.
YOU GOT BAD LUCK.
I DON'T WANT YOU
INFECTING MY SPOT.
Radio: HITTING .368...
FIND YOUR OWN
DAMN FISHING HOLE!
HOLEY MOLEY, YOU GOT
A FART IN YOUR BRAIN?
AND TURN THAT DOWN!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
NOT FAR.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH THAT GUY?
HE'S GETTING GOOFIER
EVERY YEAR.
YOU DON'T HAVE THE BALLS
TO TAKE ME ON ANYMORE!
ARIEL'S HAD YOU NEUTERED!
COME ON! LET'S SEE WHAT
YOU'RE MADE OF, YOU--
AAH!
LET THAT BE
A LESSON TO YOU!
YOU PUTZ!
ALL RIGHT, YOU
CHICKEN-LIVERED SCHMEAR!
AAH!
GET OUT OF HERE!
Woman:
ISN'T IT BEAUTIFUL?
HMM? OH.
THE LAVA LAMP?
HA HA!
THE ANGEL.
ARIEL SAYS HE WATCHES
OVER THE HOUSE.
YEAH, WELL, DON'T
GET TOO USED TO HIM.
OUR HOUSE
WILL BE READY SOON,
AND THEN WE'RE
OUT OF HERE.
HOW LONG
HAVE YOU BEEN UP?
FOR A WHILE.
YEAH?
MM-HMM.
WHAT HAVE YOU
BEEN DOING?
WATCHING YOU.
WHAT?
HA HA!
I'M UP!
YES! YOU ARE.
MORNING, HONEY.
WHY DON'T YOU
GO DOWNSTAIRS?
I'LL BE RIGHT OUT
TO MAKE YOU BREAKFAST.
SHE HATES ME.
SHE DOESN'T HATE YOU.
SHE JUST DOESN'T
LIKE YOU VERY MUCH.
MM-HMM.
I THOUGHT
I'D CHECK OUT
SOME RECEPTION HALLS
FOR THE WEDDING TODAY.
OH. UH...
I FORGOT TO TELL YOU,
I TALKED TO POP,
AND HE'S ALREADY
BOOKED A PLACE.
HE DID?
YEAH.
THAT'S GREAT! DID HE GET
THE RADISSON IN LA CROSSE?
OH, NO.
THE PEPIN
DANCE HALL?
THAT WOULD HAVE
BEEN GREAT, BUT NO.
THE MAJESTIC
BALLROOM.
NOT EVEN CLOSE.
WHAT'S LEFT?
SLIPPERY'S TAVERN.
HA HA HA!
YOU'RE SERIOUS.
I KNOW IT'S NOT
WHAT WE WANTED.
NO, NO. IT'S ALWAYS BEEN MY DREAM
TO HAVE MY WEDDING RECEPTION
IN A BAR WHERE YOU CAN PICK
PEANUT SHELLS OFF THE FLOOR.
FIRST OF ALL,
IT'S A TAVERN.
IT'S A BAR.
OK. I'LL CALL HIM.
HE'LL CANCEL.
WE'LL FIND
OUR OWN PLACE.
NO, FORGET IT.
ARE YOU SURE?
YEAH. IT WAS MY IDEA TO LET
THEM HELP PLAN THE WEDDING.
I GOTTA TELL YOU,
IT WAS A GREAT IDEA.
IT'S NICE TO SEE THEM
GETTING ALONG FOR A CHANGE.
IT'S AMAZING HOW WELL
THEY'RE GETTING ALONG.
[ENGINES REVVING]
AH. HA!
HA?
YOU DIDN'T WIN.
I QUIT.
I GOT BETTER THINGS TO DO THAN
DICK AROUND WITH YOU ALL DAY.
REALLY? WHAT?
WE GOT A WEDDING TO PLAN,
BONEHEAD. REMEMBER?
HOW COULD I FORGET?
SEE YOU LATER, JOHN.
SEE YOU LATER, MAX.
HEY, POP.
SHUSH! HE'S HERE.
WHAT? CATFISH HUNTER?
BY THE SAND BAR.
YOU KNOW
THAT DAMN FISH
IS OLDER THAN I AM?
THANKS.
MMM. WHAT THE...
WHAT THE HELL
IS THIS?
WHAT?
THAT'S LIGHT BEER.
GEE. I WEIGH
90 GODDAMN POUNDS,
AND YOU BRING ME
THIS SLOPPIN' FOAM?
ARIEL'S GOT ME
ON A DIET
BECAUSE THE DOC SAID MY
CHOLESTEROL'S A LITTLE TOO HIGH.
LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHING NOW, JOHNNY.
LAST THURSDAY,
I TURNED 95 YEARS OLD.
YEAH.
AND I NEVER EXERCISED
A DAY OF MY LIFE.
EVERY MORNING,
I WAKE UP,
AND I SMOKE
A CIGARETTE,
AND THEN I EAT
5 STRIPS OF BACON.
AND FOR LUNCH, I EAT
A BACON SANDWICH,
AND FOR
A MIDDAY SNACK...
BACON?
BACON! A WHOLE
DAMN PLATE,
AND I USUALLY
DRINK MY DINNER.
NOW, ACCORDING TO ALL OF
THEM FLAB-BELLY EXPERTS,
I SHOULD HAVE TOOK
A DIRT NAP,
LIKE, 30 YEARS AGO,
BUT EACH YEAR
COMES AND GOES,
AND I'M
STILL HERE...
HA! AND THEY
KEEP DYING.
YOU KNOW?
SOMETIMES I WONDER
IF GOD FORGOT
ABOUT ME.
IT JUST GOES
TO SHOW YOU, HUH?
WHAT?
HUH?
IT GOES
TO SHOW YOU WHAT?
WHAT THE HELL ARE
YOU TALKING ABOUT?
YOU SAID YOU DRINK BEER,
YOU EAT BACON,
AND YOU SMOKE
CIGARETTES,
AND YOU OUTLIVE
MOST OF THE EXPERTS.
YEAH?
I THOUGHT MAYBE
THERE'S A MORAL.
NO, THERE AIN'T
NO MORAL.
I JUST
LIKE THAT STORY.
THAT'S ALL.
I LIKE THAT STORY.
GOOD AFTERNOON.
OH, IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU, TOO.
AREN'T YOU
BEAUTIFUL TODAY?
ARE YOU THIRSTY?
HUH?
OH, THERE WE GO.
DRINK UP.
YEAH. DRINK UP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OOH, THERE WE GO.
THERE WE GO.
DRINK UP.
HI, ARIEL.
OH, HI!
ISN'T IT A GLORIOUS
AFTERNOON?
IT'S NOT BAD.
YOU OK?
FEELING ALL RIGHT?
SPLENDID. WHY?
I COULDN'T HELP NOTICING THAT YOU
WERE TALKING TO THE FLOWERS.
WELL,
PLANTS AND FLOWERS
ARE LIVING
ORGANISMS, AND...
AND THEY RESPOND
TO VOICE AND TOUCH,
JUST LIKE ANY OTHER
CREATURE WOULD.
YOU SHOULD TRY IT
YOURSELF SOMETIME.
I GOT A CACTUS
IN MY BATHROOM,
BUT WE GOT NOTHING
TO SAY TO EACH OTHER.
OH.
HA HA!
I BETTER GET GOING.
MAX.
YES.
LISTEN, I'M, UH...
LOOK, I'M COOKING
CANTONESE TONIGHT.
WHY DON'T YOU
JOIN US?
I ALREADY MADE
OTHER PLANS.
ARE YOU SURE?
THANKS ANYWAY.
APPRECIATE IT.
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN
BONNIE AND CLYDE
TURN OUT TO BE BONNIE
AND BONNIE?
LESBIAN BANDITS,
NEXT ON GERALDO.
OH! LESBIANS. YUMMY.
Ariel: WAIT.
WOULD YOU...
John:
YEAH, BUT I LIKE THOSE.
CAN I DO THIS?
NO, NO, NO, NO.
YOU GOT TO WAIT.
HA HA HA!
WHY DON'T
WE JUST
PUT EVERYTHING
IN HERE?
THROW IT ALL IN THERE.
CHOP IT UP.
HA HA HA!
NEED TO BORROW
A PHILLIPS SCREWDRIVER.
OH, HI, JACOB.
YOU BEEN HERE LONG?
MMM, NO.
PHILLIPS.
POP, DON'T YOU
THINK IT'S TIME
YOU START
DATING AGAIN?
WHO WITH?
I HAPPEN TO KNOW FLORENCE
GILBERT AT THE ROTARY CLUB
THINKS YOU'RE
QUITE A CATCH.
SHE LOOKS LIKE
ERNEST BORGNINE.
IS THAT SUCH
A BAD THING?
YEAH.
WHAT ABOUT JANE CLARK?
JANE OF THE JUNGLE! GOT
MORE BODY HAIR THAN I DO.
SHE'S A FUR- BEARING
MAMMAL, FOR GOD'S SAKES!
DORIS ZABRINSKI,
HUH?
I KNOW
SHE'S HEAVY,
BUT SHE LOVES
TO FISH.
DORIS ZABRINSKI
IS DEAD.
SHE IS?
SHE CHOKED TO DEATH
ON A STACK OF PANCAKES
2 WEEKS AGO AT THE LIONS
CLUB CHARITY BREAKFAST.
WOW.
I THINK IT'S HOW SHE
WOULD HAVE WANTED TO GO.
POP.
YEAH.
LISTEN TO ME.
YOU CAN'T SIT AROUND
WAITING FOR ANOTHER ARIEL
TO WALK INTO
YOUR LIFE.
THANKS
FOR THE PHILLIPS.
JACOB.
WHAT?
REMEMBER,
WHEN YOU WERE A KID,
YOUR MOTHER BAKED THAT
RHUBARB PIE FOR MY BIRTHDAY?
SHE SWELLED UP
LIKE A BALLOON,
BROKE OUT IN HIVES.
SHE DIDN'T KNOW SHE WAS
ALLERGIC TO RHUBARB.
OH, SHE KNEW.
SHE BAKED IT ANYWAY
'CAUSE SHE KNEW
IT WAS MY FAVORITE.
WHAT MADE YOU
THINK OF THAT, POP?
I DON'T KNOW.
I THINK ABOUT THINGS
LIKE THAT ALL THE TIME.
HEY, POP.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WOULD YOU GET OUT OF HERE AND
LET ME WATCH MY PROGRAM?
AND CLOSE THE DOOR
WHEN YOU GO
BECAUSE I DON'T WANT
THOSE MOSQUITOES COMING IN.
THEY'RE CRAZY ABOUT
MY MACARONI
AND CHEESE DISH.
Max: HELLO?
ANYBODY HERE?
OHH!
[YELLING IN ITALIAN]
MY NAME IS
MAX GOLD--GOLDMAN.
OUT! OUT!
TAKE IT EASY.
LOOK, RELAX.
WOULD YOU RELAX?
[YELLING IN ITALIAN]
MAMA!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M-A GONNA WHACK HIM!
PUT IT DOWN!
HE TRIED TO STEAL
THE VINO ROSSO!
YOU THINK EVERYONE IS TRYING
STEAL THE VINO ROSSO!
THEY ARE!
THIS IS
A SMALL TOWN.
YOU CAN TRUST
PEOPLE HERE.
LIKE ANTONIO?
NEXT TIME
HE TOUCH-A VINO,
I WHACK HIS HEAD
LIKE A MELONE!
HOLEY MOLEY.
I'M SO SORRY.
SCUSI,
BUT MY MOTHER
IS A LITTLE BIT TOO
PROTECTIVE OF THE WINE.
YEAH. SO I NOTICED!
HA HA HA!
SHE CRUSHED THE GRAPES
HERSELF BACK IN PALERMO.
IT'S
A RARE VINTAGE...
WITH UNIQUE BOUQUET.
IS THAT A NICE WAY
OF SAYING
THAT THE WINE SMELLS
LIKE YOUR MAMA'S FEET?
NO, NO, NO.
I...I WAS, UH...
MY NAME'S GOLDMAN.
MAX GOLDMAN.
I LIVE
IN THE AREA HERE.
MARIA SOPHIA
COLLETA RAGETTI.
AH.
THAT'S QUITE A NAME.
MM-HMM.
RAGETTI!
RAGETTI.
YOU'RE SPAGHETTI
RAGETTI'S COUSIN!
YEAH.
WHY SO SURPRISED?
HOLEY MOLEY.
WELL, I THOUGHT...
I THOUGHT...
I WAS EXPECTING SOMEONE
THAT LOOKED LIKE RICK.
HOW'S THAT?
YOU KNOW, FAT,
HAIRY, HOMELY...
BUT YOU'RE NOT SO FAT.
YOU'RE A SMOOTH
TALKER, MR. GOLDMAN.
HA! THERE'S MORE
WHERE THAT CAME FROM,
MISS RAGETTI.
SO WHEN IS
THE BAIT SHOP
GOING TO BE BACK
IN BUSINESS?
UH...BAIT SHOP?
WHAT IS A BAIT SHOP?
THAT'S WHAT WE CALL IT
IN MINNESOTA.
WHAT DO YOU CALL IT
WHERE YOU COME FROM?
OH, WE CALL IT,
I THINK,
RISTORANTE.
MM-HMM.
RISTORANTE?
YOU MEAN YOU'RE GOING TO
TURN THIS INTO A RESTAURANT?
SI.
NO. YOU CAN'T
BE SERIOUS.
WHY NOT?
WELL,
THERE'S GOING TO BE
A LOT OF NOISE, PEOPLE
COMING, DRIVING WITH CARS.
YOU'LL SCARE
ALL THE FISH AWAY.
THIS IS THE LAND
OF 10,000 LAKES.
GO FIND ANOTHER ONE.
YOU'RE WASTING
YOUR TIME, MISS RAGETTI.
I'M TELLING YOU,
PEOPLE AREN'T GOING TO COME
DOWN HERE FOR I-TALIAN
WHEN WE GOT A CHUCK E.
CHEESE RIGHT IN TOWN.
LISTEN, I DON'T KNOW
THIS CHEESE PERSON,
BUT RAGETTI'S
WILL BE
A ROMANTIC, LAKE-FRONT
RISTORANTE.
IT WILL BE SPECIAL,
CLASSY--
SOMEWHERE YOU
WOULD NEVER GO.
OH, YOU CAN SAY
THAT AGAIN.
VIA.
THERE'S MUCH TO DO
BEFORE THE OPENING
OF MY RISTORANTE.
BAIT SHOP.
RISTORANTE.
BAIT-A SHOP-EE!
RISTORANTE!
RISTORANTE,
HO DETTO!
HAI CAPITO?
RISTORANTE!
YOU SHOULD HAVE
LET ME WHACK HIM.
YEAH.
I'M DONE.
POP, I WISH YOU'D TRY
THE LOW-FAT BACON.
WELL, YOU CAN
WISH IN ONE HAND
AND CRAP
IN THE OTHER
AND SEE WHICH
GETS FILLED FIRST.
THIS WAGON'S GOT
TO GET FILLED FIRST.
I'LL BE BACK.
WELL, PICK ME UP
A PACK OF CAMELS!
ALL RIGHT.
YOU GOT IT.
AH...OOH.
HEY!
HEY, YOU NEED A HAND
WITH THAT? HUH?
MY NAME'S GUSTAFSON.
IL MIO NOME
E FRANCESCA RAGETTI.
HOO HOO HOO!
ITALIAN GIRL!
WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE GO BACK TO MY PLACE?
I'LL SHOW YOU
MY CANNELLONI.
HUH?
OOH.
HI, CHRIS.
HI. HOW YOU DOING?
FINE.
AH!
OOH!
OX!
NAG!
HEY, MORON.
PUTZ, WHERE YOU BEEN? I'VE
BEEN LOOKING ALL OVER FOR YOU.
WHY?
WHAT'S SO IMPORTANT?
THAT!
UGH!
JEEZ, LOUISE,
WHO IS THAT?
THAT'S SPAGHETTI
RAGETTI'S COUSIN.
YOU MEAN SHE'S GOING TO
BE RUNNING THE BAIT SHOP?
RISTORANTE.
HUH?
AND YOU CAN
FORGET ABOUT
LEAVING YOUR BOAT
DOWN THERE.
IT'S ALL
PRIVATE PROPERTY.
CHUCK WOULD BE SPINNING
IN HIS GRAVE IF HE KNEW.
YOU CAN
SAY THAT AGAIN.
I GUESS THERE'S
NOTHING MUCH WE CAN DO.
YOU'RE GOING TO STAND THERE
AND LET THIS HAPPEN?
WELL, WHAT AM I--
I'VE BEEN FISHING THAT SPOT
EVER SINCE I'M 5 YEARS OLD.
IT'S ALL I GOT LEFT.
I KNOW, BUT WHAT AM I
GOING TO DO ABOUT IT?
WE GOT TO COME UP
WITH A PLAN.
WE GOT TO FIND A WAY TO PUT
THE KIBOSH ON ALL THIS MESS.
WELL--
[YELLING IN ITALIAN]
IT'S OK!
I'M A DOCTOR!
OH, SOUNDS LIKE
DAD'S USING
HIS "FREE EXAM"
TRICK AGAIN.
YOU GOT TO STICK
WITH WHAT WORKS.
LISTEN, ASK JACOB IF HE
CAN PULL SOME STRINGS
WITH
THE CITY COUNCIL.
FIND OUT WHAT DAY
THIS RISTORANTE
IS SUPPOSED TO HAVE
ITS HEALTH INSPECTION.
I THINK
I GOT AN IDEA.
[YELLING IN ITALIAN]
THAT'S...
THAT'S GOOD THINKING.
DAD!
MAX IS RIGHT. OUR FISHING
SPOT'S GOING TO BE RUINED.
THEY MAY AS WELL DRAIN
THE WHOLE DAMN LAKE.
STOP MOVING.
YOU KNOW THE SIGN
SHE PUT UP, HONEY?
"PARKING FOR RESTAURANT
CUSTOMERS ONLY."
JUST A LITTLE WHILE
LONGER.
MAYBE THEY'LL HAVE A BIG
GREASE FIRE IN THE KITCHEN.
JOHN!
A GUY CAN DREAM,
CAN'T HE?
YOU GOT TO LET
THIS THING GO, HONEY.
GOT TO LET IT GO.
CHUCK IS GONE, THE BAIT SHOP
IS GONE, THINGS MOVE ON,
AND I SUGGEST
YOU DO THE SAME.
AND STOP FIDGETING!
I DON'T KNOW
WHY THE HELL
I EVER LET YOU TALK
ME INTO DOING THIS.
GOD IF MAX COULD
SEE ME NOW,
I'D NEVER
LIVE IT DOWN.
WOULD YOU RELAX?
WE'RE THE ONLY ONES HERE.
THERE'S NOBODY HERE
EXCEPT YOU AND ME.
HMM.
HA HA HA!
WHAT A PUTZ!
WILL YOU LOOK
AT THAT POOR MAN?
HA HA HA!
Grandpa: AND THEN
THE MAMA BEAR SAID,
"SOMEBODY'S BEEN SLEEPING
IN MY BED, TOO!"
AND FINALLY,
THE BABY BEAR
LOOKED AND HE SAID,
"SOMEBODY'S BEEN
SLEEPING IN MY BED,
AND THE BASTARD'S
STILL THERE!"
HEE HEE HEE!
BUT GOLDILOCKS HAD A
REMINGTON SEMIAUTOMATIC
WITH A SCOPE
AND A HAIR TRIGGER.
THAT'S NOT
THE WAY IT GOES!
AND THAT
WAS THE END...
HA HA HA!
OF THE 3 BEARS.
SING ME A LULLABY.
OH, IT'S TOO LATE.
PLEASE?
ALL RIGHT.
♪ STARS SHINING BRIGHT
ABOVE YOU ♪
♪ LIGHT BREEZES
SEEM TO WHISPER ♪
♪ "I LOVE YOU"
♪ BIRDS SINGING
IN THE SYCAMORE TREE ♪
♪ DREAM A LITTLE DREAM
OF ME ♪
♪ SAY NIGHTY-NIGHT
♪ KISS ME
♪ JUST HUG ME TIGHT
♪ AND TELL ME
YOU MISS ME ♪
♪ WHILE STARS
ARE SHINING ♪
♪ BRIGHT AS CAN BE
♪ DREAM
A LITTLE DREAM OF ME ♪
GOOD NIGHT,
SWEET PEA.
GOOD NIGHT.
HAPPY DREAMS.
OK, THAT LEAVES...
UNCLE WILLY SITTING
NEXT TO THE PLANT LADY.
I'M NOT STICKING THE PLANT
LADY NEXT TO YOUR UNCLE WILLY.
WHY NOT?
BECAUSE
HE'S A GROPER.
HE'D BE ALL OVER HER.
HE'S NOT A GROPER.
HE'S A TOUCHY-FEELY
PERSON.
HE'S NOT GONNA BE
TOUCHY-FEELYING THE PLANT LADY.
IT'S NOT LIKE
SHE'S A CLOSE FRIEND.
WE DON'T EVEN
KNOW HER NAME.
"THE PLANT LADY."
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
IT DOESN'T MEAN
SHE'S NOT IMPORTANT TO ME.
FINE.
GOOD.
ALLIE, HONEY, DON'T PUT THE
QUARTER IN YOUR MOUTH.
YOU'RE NOT
MY DADDY.
John: HEY, WHAT DO
YOU GOT THERE, POP?
Both:
A BACON SANDWICH.
KIDS,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
TRYING TO FINISH THE
SEATING ARRANGEMENT
FOR THE WEDDING
RECEPTION.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO THAT.
MAX AND I HAVE ALREADY
COME UP WITH A PLAN.
OH, NO, DAD. YOU GUYS HAVE
DONE WAY TOO MUCH ALREADY.
HELLO, CHILDREN.
HEY, MORON.
PUTZ.
YOU, UH...
FIND THE RAT?
NO, BUT ALLIE SAID
WE COULD BORROW SPARKY.
WHAT IF HE
GETS AWAY?
I MADE A LEASH.
GOOD THINKING.
WHAT DO YOU GUYS
WANT WITH SPARKY?
WAIT. I DON'T
WANT TO KNOW.
IT'S MEN TALK.
SEE YOU LATER, HUH?
ALLIE,
WHERE'S THE QUARTER?
HEE HEE!
HONEY.
ALLIE, DID YOU
SWALLOW A QUARTER?
I'LL CALL THE DOCTOR.
RELAX. KIDS SWALLOW
QUARTERS ALL THE TIME.
REALLY?
SURE.
IF SHE CRAPS OUT
2 DIMES AND A NICKEL,
THEN YOU CAN START
WORRYING, HUH?
COME HERE.
SAY "AHH."
PERSONALLY CLEANED
EVERY LITTLE CORNER.
JUST LOOK.
LIKE A MIRROR.
MISS RAGETTI,
EVERYTHING APPEARS TO BE
UP TO OUR STANDARDS.
I'M VERY GLAD.
OF COURSE, APPEARANCES
CAN BE...DECEIVING.
OH, SI. SI.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
NOW?
UNLEASH THE BEAST.
YOU WILL BE WEARING
YOUR HAIR NET
WHEN YOU'RE COOKING
FOR THE PUBLIC.
[WHISPERING]
Say yes.
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
SHE SAID, "YES, SIR.
OF COURSE."
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
EVERYTHING SEEMS
TO BE IN ORDER.
ACT RABID.
BE RABID. GOOD LUCK
TO YOU, YOU SCHMUCK.
AAH!
WHAT?
IT'S A RAT!
A RAT? HERE?
VERMIN INFESTATION!
I'M WRITING YOU UP.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT!
IT'S A...
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
IT'S NOT A RAT.
IT'S A...
IT'S A GUINEA PIG.
A GUINEA PIG?
LOOK.
WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
THAT A GUINEA PIG
WOULD RUN THROUGH HERE
ON AN INSPECTION DAY?
HMM?
WELL, LATELY, I MUST SAY
THAT THE CHANCES
ARE PRETTY GOOD.
UH-OH.
OX.
NAG!
I DON'T THINK
WE'VE MET.
I'M MARIA RAGETTI.
HOW DO YOU--
JOHN GUSTAFSON.
AH. YOU LIKE ITALIAN,
MR. GUSTAFSON?
W-WELL, YEAH.
I GUESS SO. WHY?
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
BUON APPETITO.
OH!
E ARRIVEDERCI, BOYS.
SHOULD WE ASK HER
FOR SOME GARLIC BREAD?
♪ HIT THE ROAD, JACK
♪ AND DON'T YOU COME BACK
NO MORE ♪
♪ NO MORE, NO MORE, NO MORE
♪ HIT THE ROAD, JACK
♪ AND DON'T YOU COME BACK
NO MORE ♪
♪ WHAT YOU SAY?
♪ HIT THE ROAD, JACK
♪ AND DON'T YOU COME BACK
NO MORE ♪
♪ NO MORE, NO MORE, NO MORE
♪ HIT THE ROAD, JACK
♪ AND DON'T YOU COME BACK
NO MORE ♪
♪ OLD WOMAN, OLD WOMAN,
DON'T YOU TREAT ME SO MEAN ♪
♪ YOU'RE THE MEANEST OLD WOMAN
I HAVE EVER SEEN ♪
[YELLING IN ITALIAN]
♪ I'LL HAVE TO PACK
MY THINGS AND GO ♪
♪ THAT'S RIGHT
♪ HIT THE ROAD, JACK
♪ AND DON'T YOU COME BACK
NO MORE ♪
♪ NO MORE, NO MORE, NO MORE
♪ HIT THE ROAD, JACK
♪ AND DON'T YOU COME BACK
NO MORE ♪
♪ WHAT YOU SAY?
♪ HIT THE ROAD, JACK
♪ AND DON'T YOU COME BACK
NO MORE ♪
♪ NO MORE, NO MORE, NO MORE
♪ HIT THE ROAD, JACK
♪ AND DON'T YOU COME BACK
NO MORE ♪
♪ GET LOST!
♪ WHO, ME?
♪ THAT'S RIGHT!
♪ HIT THE ROAD, JACK
♪ AND DON'T YOU COME BACK
NO MORE ♪
♪ NO MORE, NO MORE, NO MORE
♪ HIT THE ROAD, JACK
♪ AND DON'T YOU COME BACK
NO MORE ♪
HOW COULD
I BE SO WRONG?
YOU HAVE A GIFT.
NOT ONE CUSTOMER
ALL DAY.
I MEAN, BESIDES HIM.
HEY,
MORE VINO,
SEÑORITA.
YOU GO.
IT'S YOUR TURN.
UH-UH.
I PUT HIS BIB ON.
BAH.
WELL...
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
BEAUTIFUL?
YOU'RE MEANER
THAN A DOG
SHITTING TACKS.
WE PUT EVERYTHING
INTO THIS PLACE.
WE COULD HAVE
RETIRED IN HAWAII.
I HAVE BEEN
TO HAWAII.
WHICH ISLAND?
COME-ON-
I-WANNA-LAY-YOU.
[LAUGHS]
I FIND YOU DISGUSTING.
WELL, JUST AS LONG
AS YOU FIND ME.
HA HA HA!
YOU WANT TO JOIN ME,
MISS RAGETTI?
OH...
HUH?
WHAT THE HECK?
THAT A GIRL.
YEAH.
DING DONG,
THE WITCH IS DEAD.
HERE'S TO US.
AND TO THOSE
LIKE US.
THERE'S DAMN FEW
OF US LEFT.
THAT'S A DAMN
GOOD THING.
TO CHUCK.
MAY HIS BAIT SHOP
NEVER DIE.
Radio: ♪ IF OUR LIPS
SHOULD MEET, INNAMORATA ♪
♪ IF YOU KISS ME SWEET,
INNAMORATA... ♪
MAMA.
GET DRESSED.
WE GO TO TOWN.
MAMA?
♪ WHEN THE MOON HITS YOUR EYE
LIKE A BIG PIZZA PIE ♪
♪ THAT'S AMORE
♪ WHEN THE WORLD SEEMS TO SHINE
LIKE YOU'VE HAD TOO MUCH WINE ♪
♪ THAT'S AMORE
♪ BELLS WILL RING,
TING-A-LING-A-LING ♪
♪ TING-A-LING-A-LING,
AND YOU'LL SING ♪
♪ VITA BELLA...
[JUKEBOX PLAYING VENUS]
♪ A GODDESS
ON A MOUNTAINTOP ♪
♪ WAS BURNING
LIKE A SILVER FLAME ♪
♪ THE SUMMIT OF
BEAUTY AND LOVE ♪
♪ AND VENUS WAS HER NAME
HOLEY MOLEY.
♪ SHE'S GOT IT
IS THIS
SEAT TAKEN?
♪ MY BABY, SHE'S GOT IT
HMM?
OH...
NO.
BEWARE.
THE DEVIL IS A BEAUTIFUL
LADY IN A RED DRESS.
CAN I GET YOU
SOMETHING, MA'AM?
YES, PLEASE.
IT'S SO HOT IN HERE.
MAYBE SOME ICE WATER
COULD COOL ME DOWN.
YES, MA'AM.
WHEW.
MAX...
I'VE BEEN THINKING
IT'S SUCH A SHAME
THAT WE GOT OFF
ON THE WRONG FOOT.
IT'S A SHAME.
I'LL BET IF WE GAVE IT
ANOTHER CHANCE, WE COULD--
BECOME GOOD FRIENDS.
FRIENDS.
OR MAYBE EVEN MORE
THAN FRIENDS.
EH?
HMM?
GO EASY. GO EASY,
BABY, AND WOOSH.
OOH, THIS FEELS
SO MUCH BETTER.
SO NICE. AHH.
SO COOL.
SO NICE.
AHH.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
UH, FRIENDLY.
FRIENDLY.
I WISH I COULD
FEEL LIKE YOU DO,
BUT THESE SILLY
FEUD OF OURS
HAS GOT ME SO UPSET.
WHAT SILLY FEUD OF OURS?
IT'S A TINY,
LITTLE RISTORANTE.
YOU WILL NEVER EVEN
KNOW IT'S THERE.
RISTORANTE?
NEVER!
YOU ARE
A STUBBORN MAN.
RAGETTI'S WILL BE
A VERY GREAT SUCCESS.
YOU SHALL SEE.
NOT IN MY LIFETIME.
BAH!
YOU EVIL TEMPTRESS!
MARIA?
MARIA RAGETTI.
HOW DO YOU
KNOW WHO I AM?
WELL--YOU DO
SORT OF STAND OUT
IN A TOWN LIKE THIS.
I DON'T USUALLY
DRESS LIKE THIS.
UH--YOU LOOK VERY NICE.
I LOOK LIKE
A--A SLUT.
BUT A NICE SLUT.
I WANT TO INTRODUCE MYSELF.
MY NAME IS ARIEL GUSTAFSON,
AND I WANT TO TELL YOU
HOW VERY SORRY I AM
FOR WHAT MAX AND JOHN
ARE PUTTING YOU THROUGH.
YOU KNOW HOW SOME PEOPLE
HAVE TROUBLE SAYING GOOD-BYE?
BELIEVE ME, IT HAS
NOTHING TO DO WITH YOU.
IO NON CAPISCO.
WHY DO YOU SAY SUCH NICE THINGS?
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW ME.
BECAUSE I KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO BE THE NEW KID IN TOWN.
AHH.
HERE COMES
ANOTHER ONE.
HELLO, BOYS.
HEY, HONEY,
HOW WAS CLASS?
ARIEL.
YOU TWO MUST BE VERY
HAPPY WITH YOURSELVES.
I JUST
RAN INTO MARIA,
AND SHE'S IN TEARS.
SHE THINKS THAT
EVERYBODY HATES HER.
SHE'S RIGHT.
I WANT YOU TO GO TO
RAGETTI'S AND APOLOGIZE.
APOLOGIZE?
FOR WHAT?
WE WERE TRYING
TO EXPLAIN TO HER.
SHE SHOULD
HAVE LISTENED.
I'LL MEET YOU
AT HOME, HONEY.
UMM.
I ALWAYS KNEW YOU WERE
ON A SHORT LEASH,
BUT I DIDN'T KNOW YOU
WERE ON A CHOKE COLLAR.
NOBODY'S IN CHARGE
OF MY HOUSE EXCEPT ME.
THAT'S THE WAY
TO TALK, GUSTAFSON.
I'M GOING HOME NOW TO GET
THIS STRAIGHTENED OUT.
YOU'RE THE MAN OF THE HOUSE,
THE KING OF THE CASTLE.
MAX, TOP HER OFF?
SURE.
LONG LIVE THE KING!
[KNOCK KNOCK]
WHAT?
SHE THREW ME OUT.
OH, NO.
JUST FOR TONIGHT.
FORGET IT.
YOU WON'T EVEN
KNOW I'M HERE.
THAT'S 'CAUSE
YOU WON'T BE HERE.
WHAT?
I'M COLD.
HERE'S SOME MATCHES.
SET YOURSELF
ON FIRE.
[SPEAKING SPANISH
ON TELEVISION]
OH.
[MAX BRUSHING TEETH]
YOU GOT 3 TVs ON,
YOU'RE NOT LOOKING
AT ANY OF THEM.
[GARGLING]
[GARGLING CONTINUES]
WHAT A PIG.
HEY, THAT'S
MY TUNA ON RYE.
I'VE BEEN LOOKING
ALL OVER FOR THAT.
WHERE DID YOU FIND IT?
WOULD YOU LIKE A HALF?
HUH?
[CHEERING ON TELEVISION]
THIS MILK
HAS CHUNKS IN IT.
WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
WHAT AM I DOING?
WHAT?
RIGHT NEXT DOOR I'VE GOT A
BEAUTIFUL WIFE, MY OWN BED,
AND A REFRIGERATOR
FULL OF FOOD
THAT HASN'T PASSED
ITS EXPIRATION DATE.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
I'M SAYING I'M GOING
DOWN TO RAGETTI'S
AND APOLOGIZE TO MARIA.
YOU TRAITOR.
YOU BENEDICT ARNOLD!
YEAH, YEAH.
FINALLY.
DIDN'T THINK
HE'D LAST THIS LONG.
SMELLS ALL RIGHT.
AND WHY
ALL OF A SUDDEN
THIS CHANGE
OF HEART?
I HAD A GUILTY CONSCIENCE.
WELL, OK.
ARIEL KICKED
ME OUT OF THE HOUSE.
I KNEW I LIKED
YOUR WIFE.
AND WHAT ABOUT MAX?
MAX? OH, MY GOD,
FORGET IT.
MAX'S MUCH TOO HARDHEADED
TO EVER SAY HE'S SORRY.
HE'S PROUD.
I DON'T KNOW.
OF WHAT?
HE HAS A STRONG
CHARACTER.
I ADMIRE THAT.
YOU ADMIRE MAX?
YOU REALLY ARE
FROM OUT OF TOWN.
BE CAREFUL.
THE GRAPPA
IS VERY STRONG.
YOU ARE SPEAKING
TO A GUSTAFSON.
I CAN HOLD MY LIQUOR.
AND THIS STUFF, TOO.
HOW LONG HAVE
YOU BEEN MARRIED?
6 MONTHS NEXT WEEK.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
I'M DIVORCED.
I'M SORRY.
ANTONIO WAS, UH,
UN UOMO TERRIBILE.
JEEZ, THAT SOUNDS BAD.
IT AIN'T GOOD.
OH, JEEZ.
ENOUGH OF THAT.
I DON'T WANT
TO BORE YOU.
[MUMBLES]
MR. GUSTAFSON?
ECCO QUA.
BUONA NOTTE.
SOGNI D'ORO.
GOOD NIGHT, ARIEL.
HEY.
Max:
BUON GIORNO, SIGNORA.
Cassette recorder:
BUONA SERA.
BUONA SERA,
SIGNORE.
ARRIVEDERCI.
YO HO, THERE, MA.
ARRIVEDERCIO.
ARRIVEDERCI,
SIGNORINA.
BUONA SERA,
SIGNORA.
PA.
ARRIVEDER--
HEY, JACOB.
HOW ARE YOU?
THANKS FOR THE PHILLIPS.
LISTEN...
POP, MELANIE AND I WANTED
TO THANK YOU AND JOHN--
I GOT IT.
WE JUST WANTED
YOU AND JOHN TO KNOW
HOW MUCH WE APPRECIATE
ALL THE HELP YOU'VE GIVEN US
PLANNING THE WEDDING.
THERE'S NO NEED
TO THANK ME, JACOB.
YES, BUT WE ACTUALLY--
NOTHING WOULD
MAKE US HAPPIER
THAN TO SEE YOU TWO
TIE THE KNOT.
THANKS, BUT--
IT MEANS A GREAT DEAL TO
ME TO BE A PART OF IT.
I'M PROUD
OF YOU, SON.
STUDYING UP ON YOUR
ITALIAN, ARE YOU?
YOU THINKING
OF WOOING MARIA?
NO, I'M JUST GOING TO CURSE
AT HER IN HER OWN LANGUAGE.
I THINK SHE'S
A LESBIAN, ANYWAY.
HOW WOULD YOU KNOW?
YOU'VE NEVER SEEN A LESBIAN.
DID, TOO.
SAW THEM
ON GERALDO.
SAY WHATEVER YOU WILL,
I THINK YOU'RE HOT FOR HER.
NOT IN
A MILLION YEARS.
SHE'S JUST A PIGHEADED
I-TALIAN WITCH
WITH PISS AND VINEGAR
RUNNING THROUGH HER VEINS.
HE'S IN LOVE.
♪ O SOLE MIO
♪ MANO NERO
ARIEL.
BUON GIORNO.
OH, BUON GIORNO.
LEI PARLA ITALIANO
MOLTO BENE, SIGNOR.
GRACIAS, FRAULEIN.
WHERE ARE
YOU OFF TO?
SVEN SAID HE SPOTTED CATFISH
HUNTER DOWN AT INDIAN SLOUGH.
THOUGHT I'D TAKE A LOOK.
OH, YEAH.
WHERE'S TWEEDLEDUM?
TWEEDLEDUM?
OH, JOHN.
TWEEDLEDUM.
I SUPP--I DON'T KNOW.
YOU DON'T KNOW?
HE DIDN'T SPEND
THE NIGHT HERE?
NO. LAST NIGHT HE SAID
HE WAS GOING TO RAGETTI'S
TO APOLOGIZE TO MARIA.
YOU MEAN TO TELL ME
HE DIDN'T COME HOME?
[JOHN MUMBLES]
AAH!
HE'S ALIVE.
TAKE THIS.
YOU'LL FEEL BETTER.
WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU PASSED OUT.
I DIDN'T THINK
YOU SHOULD DRIVE HOME.
OH, GOD.
I FEEL LIKE A POLKA BAND
IS PLAYING IN MY HEAD.
YOU'LL FEEL BETTER
AFTER A HOT SHOWER.
COME ON. MAMA.
AVANTI. DOCCIA.
BUT I DON'T NEED
A HOT SHOWER.
WHAT IF HE HAD AN ACCIDENT?
THE ONLY ACCIDENT HE'S GOING
TO HAVE IS WHEN I SEE HIM.
I'M SURE THERE'S A LOGICAL
EXPLANATION FOR ALL THIS.
YOU KNOW, IT MUST BE NICE
LIVING IN NEVER-NEVER LAND.
MAYBE I'LL COME AND
VISIT YOU SOMETIME
WHEN I NEED A BREAK
FROM REALITY.
STEP ON IT.
HE'S GOING
TO EXPLAIN EVERYTHING.
I'M GOING TO LISTEN CAREFULLY,
AND THEN I'M GOING TO KILL HIM.
I'M SURE THERE'S A LOGICAL
EXPLANATION FOR ALL THIS, ARIEL.
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
ALL RIGHT.
WHERE IS HE?
WHAT IS IT?
WE KNOW HE'S HERE.
DON'T DENY IT.
WAIT. YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
I WANT TO TALK
TO HIM RIGHT NOW.
LET ME EXPLAIN.
GUSTAFSON!
GET OUT HERE!
WHAT IN THE--
WHAT?
Max:
WHAT'S GOING ON?
NOTHING'S
GOING ON.
Both:
WHERE'S JOHN?
WAIT A MINUTE!
JOHN--
WHAT?
HOW COULD YOU?
THIS ISN'T
WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE.
GUSTAFSON,
YOU'RE DOING IT AGAIN!
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
FIRST IT WAS MAY,
THEN IT WAS ARIEL,
AND NOW IT'S MARIA!
WATCH THAT DAMN THING.
YOU SAID
YOU HATED MARIA!
THAT'S NOT THE POINT!
YOU SAID I SHOULD
APOLOGIZE TO HER.
APOLOGIZE, YES--
NOT SLEEP WITH HER.
THERE IS
A DIFFERENCE.
DO YOU THINK I HAD
SEX WITH YOUR HUSBAND?
YOU SURE WEREN'T
HAVING SEX WITH ME.
WHY SHOULD I
HAVE SEX WITH YOU?
YOU JUST SAID
YOU HATED ME.
HE SAID
I HATED YOU.
I NEVER SAID
ACTUALLY, I'VE GROWN
QUITE FOND OF YOU.
SO, NOW I'M SUPPOSED
TO HAVE SEX WITH YOU
INSTEAD OF HIM.
YOU ADMIT THAT YOU
SLEPT WITH MY HUSBAND.
NOBODY SLEPT
WITH ANYBODY!
AH, FINALMENTE!
SPEAK FOR YOURSELF!
MMM...
♪ LA DI DA DA DI
♪ YA DA DI
MAMA!
JEEZ. I HAD TOO MUCH
TO DRINK LAST NIGHT.
SURE. BLAME IT
ON THE BOOZE.
AND YOU THINK THAT'S
AN ACCEPTABLE EXCUSE?
WILL YOU
LET ME FINISH?
NO!
FERMI TUTTI!
I KNOW MY MARIA.
SHE DON'T WANT NOTHING
TO DO WITH THAT MAN.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
BECAUSE...
SHE WANTS THAT MAN.
ME?
WHAT DO YOU WANT
WITH ME?
PREFERISCO BACIARE
IL CULO DI UN ALCE.
WHAT IS THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
I'D RATHER KISS
A DEAD MOOSE'S BUTT.
SO, I'LL CALL YOU?
Lena:
3 TIERS LIKE THIS, JA?
THE LEMON CAKE
WITH THE WHITE FROSTING
AND THE YELLOW FLOWERS.
YOU LIKE?
IT'S PERFECT, LENA.
EXACTLY WHAT WE WANTED.
AND NOW FOR
THE BIG SURPRISE...
NO. WHAT SURPRISE?
WE DON'T WANT
ANY SURPRISES.
JOHN THOUGHT OF THIS ONE
ALL BY HIMSELF.
THE GROOM GOES HERE,
AND THE BRIDE,
SHE GOES ON TOP
LIKE THIS,
AND THEN
THIS GOES HERE...
AND THEN, ON TOP OF THE CAKE,
IN THE FROSTING,
WE SPELL OUT,
"MELANIE HAS LANDED HERSELF
ANOTHER HUSBAND."
OH...
THIS IS NOT GOOD.
Max: ♪ MARIA
♪ I JUST MET A GIRL
NAMED MARIA ♪
♪ AND SUDDENLY I SEE
♪ SHE'S NOT THE BITCH
I THOUGHT SHE'D BE ♪
♪ MARIA
♪ OH, MARIA, MARIA,
MARIA ♪
♪ AH, MARIA,
AH, MARIA ♪
♪ MA--
SHH!
OX.
NAG.
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU
WERE A FISHERMAN.
THERE ARE A LOT OF THINGS
YOU DON'T KNOW ABOUT ME.
ANY LUCK?
OOH.
HOLEY MOLEY!
HA HA HA!
I SHOWED YOU MINE.
NOW YOU SHOW ME YOURS.
OH, I DON'T--
OH, YOU MEAN
THE FISH.
OH, COM'E PICCOLO!
IT AIN'T THE SIZE
THAT MATTERS.
ARE WE STILL TALKING
ABOUT YOUR FISH?
VERY FUNNY.
I, UH...
YOU KNOW, MARIA,
I'VE LIVED HERE
ALL MY LIFE.
NOBODY KNOWS
ABOUT THIS PLACE
ANY MORE THAN I DO.
I KNOW EVERYTHING.
I COULD TAKE YOU AROUND
SOMETIME IF YOU...
IF YOU WOULD LIKE IT.
ARE YOU ASKING ME
ON A DATE?
HELL, NO.
BUT IF I WERE--
AND I'M NOT, MIND YOU--
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY?
WELL, IF I WERE
TO ACCEPT--
AND I'M NOT SAYING
I WOULD--
BECAUSE
I HAVEN'T ASKED YOU.
MM-HMM. I WOULD
SAY, UM...
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY?
MMM...
MAYBE.
MAYBE? WHAT KIND
OF AN ANSWER IS MAYBE?
MAYBE IS MAYBE.
THEN MAYBE I'LL STOP BY
AT 7:00 TONIGHT.
MAYBE I'LL COOK SOMETHING
NICE FOR YOU IN THE KITCHEN.
I'LL SEE YOU THEN.
MAYBE.
CIAO.
WHATEVER THAT MEANS.
Maria: WHAT DO YOU THINK,
MAMA?
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
DON'T YOU THINK
IT MAKES ME LOOK FAT?
HE SHOULD BE
SO PICKY.
HE'S GOT THE FACE
OF A MACKEREL.
ANTONIO HAD THE FACE
OF AN ANGEL,
AND LOOK WHERE HE GOT ME.
HOW MANY TIMES DO YOU HAVE
TO GET YOUR HEART BROKEN?
MAX IS DIFFERENT, MAMA.
HE MAKES ME LAUGH.
I DON'T LIKE THIS,
NOT ONE BIT.
BUT IT'S JUST A DATE.
I'M NOT MARRYING HIM.
NOT YET.
[MIMICKING]
"NOT YET."
MAMA, HEY...
ARE YOU SURE YOU LIKE
THE WHITE BETTER?
SI!
"SI"!
DEFINITELY THE BLUE.
OH, BOY.
YEAH.
I'M A LITTLE NERVOUS.
OH, COME ON.
YOU JUST BE YOURSELF.
YOU'LL BE FINE.
YEAH.
WHY DON'T YOU PICK UP
A BOTTLE OF WINE
ON THE WAY?
SHE'LL APPRECIATE
THE GESTURE.
CHECK.
DON'T FORGET, NOW...
COMPLIMENT HER
ON HOW GREAT SHE LOOKS.
OK. ALREADY
GOT THAT COVERED.
LET ME HEAR IT.
MARIA...
YEAH?
THERE MAY BE LOTS
OF FISH IN THE SEA,
BUT YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
I WOULD LIKE TO MOUNT
OVER MY FIREPLACE.
THAT'S NOT...BAD.
YOU NOTICED
THE SEXUAL INNUENDO?
I DID.
SUBLIMINAL MESSAGES--
IT'S HOW YOU GET PEOPLE
TO DO WHAT YOU WANT
WITHOUT THEM KNOWING IT.
WHERE'D YOU LEARN THAT?
GERALDO.
OH, BOY.
HEY! VERY NICE.
YEAH. I WENT TO
NATE'S AUTO BODY SHOP,
HAD ALL THE SEATS
REFINISHED.
IT'S AUTHENTIC
IMITATION LEATHER.
[ENGINE STARTS]
GO GET 'EM, TIGER.
YOU GOT NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
HE'S DOOMED.
[CLATTERING]
THERE ARE MANY FISH
IN THE SEA, MARIA,
BUT YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
I WANT TO MOUNT
OVER MY FIREPLACE.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE...
BUT YOU'RE...
CIAO.
HOLEY MOLEY.
GOOD EVENING, MARIA.
GOOD EVENING.
UH...YOU LOOK NICE.
THANK YOU.
I, UH...
I JUST WANT TO SAY...
WHAT I'M
TRYING TO SAY IS...
THERE ARE MANY WOMEN
FLOATING IN THE RIVER,
BUT YOU'RE
THE ONLY ONE
I WANT TO STUFF
AND STICK
OVER ON MY WALL
OVER THE FIREPLACE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO COME IN?
PLEASE.
I--
I DIDN'T SAY IT RIGHT.
Maria:
I'VE NEVER SEEN
WINE THAT COMES
FROM A BOX BEFORE.
IT'S PRETTY FANCY, HUH?
LOOK. IT'S EVEN GOT
ITS OWN TAP.
OOH.
LOOK AT THIS.
HERE. YOU GOT IT?
SI, SI, SI, SI, SI.
REAL WINE.
THAT'S GREAT. YES.
SO, HOW DO YOU LIKE
THE OLD PLACE?
UH...IT'S CHANGED.
IS THAT GOOD OR BAD?
IT'S THE WORST.
I HATE CHANGE.
WHY?
THINGS NEVER CHANGE
FOR THE BETTER.
WELL, CHANGE BROUGHT ME
HERE TO WABASHA.
ARE YOU SAYING
YOU WISH I HADN'T COME?
HMM...
IS THAT A TRICK QUESTION?
[THUNDER]
[RAIN FALLING]
YOU SEE? NOW THE WEATHER
HAS CHANGED.
SO MUCH FOR DINING
AL FRESCO.
WHOO!
HOLEY MOLEY.
[MARIA LAUGHING]
Max: BOY!
I'M ALL WET.
WOW.
IT'S REALLY
COMING DOWN NOW.
YEAH.
YOU KNOW, THE NIGHT
CRAWLERS WILL BE OUT SOON.
WHAT'S
A NIGHT CRAWLER?
WHAT ARE YOU,
A COMMUNIST?
NO.
NIGHT CRAWLER'S
THE KING OF ALL WORMS.
THEY COME OUT AT NIGHT
AFTER THE RAIN
TO LAY ACROSS THE GRASS,
BREATHE THE NIGHT AIR.
THIS RESTAURANT
IS SITTING ON TOP OF
ONE OF THE BIGGEST
AND BEST WORM BEDS
IN ALL OF WABASHA COUNTY.
AH.
YOU CAN IMAGINE
MY EXCITEMENT.
HA HA HA!               HA HA!
HONEY, WOULD YOU
STOP WORRYING?
MAX IS GOING TO BE
JUST FINE.
I HOPE SO.
I MAY HAVE GIVEN HIM
SOME BAD ADVICE EARLIER.
OH, YEAH?
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
I TOLD HIM, UH...
I TOLD HIM TO...
JUST BE HIMSELF.
YOU SAID WHAT?
Max: DON'T SHINE
THE LIGHT RIGHT ON 'EM.
THEY FEEL THE HEAT, THEY
ZIP BACK INTO THEIR HOLES.
SO I SHOULD, UH...
LIKE THIS?
YEAH. UP. DOWN.
YOU KNOW, MARIA,
THAT WORMS HAVE
BOTH MALE AND FEMALE
SEXUAL ORGANS?
NO! I DIDN'T
KNOW THAT.
WELL, IT'S TRUE.
YOU KNOW A LOT
ABOUT WORMS, MAX.
NO, I DON'T KNOW
THAT MUCH.
OH, YOU DO. YOU DO.
EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE
I PICK UP A TIP.
YES, THAT'S IT.
THAT'S GOOD. LIKE--
THERE'S ONE.
AH. SHH.
QUIETLY, NOW.
WHAT SHOULD I DO?
TIPTOE OVER--
WILL YOU
COME WITH ME?
YES. THEN SUDDENLY
REACH DOWN AND GRAB HIM.
OK. OK.
YOU GET NEAR,
GRAB HIM.
WHOO!
OH!
HA HA HA!
MARIA.
YOU ALL RIGHT, MARIA?
YES.
YOU SCARED EVERY WORM AWAY
FOR A RADIUS OF 5 MILES.
I'M SORRY.
HA HA HA!
WHAT?
YOU HAVE
A VERY BEAUTIFUL SMILE.
MMM.
MARIA?
YES, MAX.
WOULD IT BE ALL RIGHT
IF I KISSED YOU?
YES.
I HAVEN'T BEEN WITH
A MAN FOR A LONG TIME.
ME NEITHER.
BE GENTLE.
MAMA MIA.
HOLEY MOLEY.
♪ WELL, YOU CAN TELL
BY THE WAY I USE MY WALK ♪
♪ I'M A WOMAN'S MAN,
NO TIME TO TALK ♪
♪ MUSIC LOUD
AND WOMEN WARM ♪
♪ I'VE BEEN KICKED AROUND
SINCE I WAS BORN ♪
♪ AND NOW IT'S ALL RIGHT,
IT'S OK ♪
♪ AND YOU MAY LOOK
THE OTHER WAY ♪
♪ WE CAN TRY
TO UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ THE NEW YORK TIMES'
EFFECT ON MAN ♪
♪ WHETHER YOU'RE A BROTHER
OR WHETHER YOU'RE A MOTHER ♪
♪ YOU'RE STAYIN' ALIVE,
STAYIN' ALIVE ♪
♪ FEEL THE CITY BREAKIN'
AND EVERYBODY SHAKIN' ♪
♪ AND WE'RE STAYIN' ALIVE,
STAYIN' ALIVE ♪
♪ AH, HA, HA, HA
♪ STAYIN' ALIVE
♪ SOMEBODY HELP ME...
GOOD MORNING,
MR. GUSTAFSON.
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
MM-HMM.
YOU AND THAT
BEAUTIFUL LADY?
I AM THE THIEF
OF HEARTS,
I AM THE GANGSTER
OF LOVE.
GANGSTER, HUH?
WAS IT MORE OF A HOLDUP
THAN A STICKUP?
NEVER MIND THAT.
EVEN YOUR
INFANTILE PENIS JOKES
SEEM CHARMING AND WITTY
THIS MORNING, SIR.
OK, LOTHARIO,
WE GOT TO GET TO THE
OCTOBERFEST TO MEET THE KIDS.
[SPEAKING GIBBERISH]
I THINK
I LIKED YOU BETTER
BEFORE YOU WERE
GETTING ANY.
[POLKA MUSIC PLAYING]
Man: WHOO!
HI, DEAR.
HI, DAD.
HIYA, JACOB.
HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON?
WE GOT A SURPRISE
FOR YOU.
OH, NO MORE SURPRISES.
ATTENTION!
NO. YOU'LL
LIKE THIS.
IN JUST 8 DAYS,
THESE 2 HAPPY KIDS
WILL BE HUSBAND AND WIFE!
YEAH!
UND...
MY DEAR FRIENDS
MAX UND JOHN
HAVE ASKED ME,
HANDSOME HANS,
TO BE THEIR MUSIC MAN.
[CHEERING]
LET'S CELEBRATE
THE YOUNG LOVERS' NUPTIALS
WITH THE CHICKEN POLKA!
[PLAYING CHICKEN POLKA]
CHICKEN,
MAYOR GOLDMAN?
COME ON. YOU'RE
GONNA LOVE THIS.
YOU KNOW
THE CHICKEN.
YEAH.
I'M IN
THE TWILIGHT ZONE.
ANOTHER ONE OF YOUR
FATHER'S GREAT IDEAS.
YOUR FATHER WAS THE ONE WHO
BOOKED OUR RECEPTION HALL.
I THINK HANDSOME HANS WOULD FIT
IN PERFECTLY AT SLIPPERY'S BAR.
IT'S A TAVERN.
THIS IS A MISTAKE.
YOU'RE RIGHT. WE'LL GET A DJ.
THIS IS CRAZY.
THAT'S NOT
WHAT I MEANT.
MELANIE, I KNOW
I WANT TO GET MARRIED,
BUT IF YOU'RE NOT SURE,
YOU GOT TO TELL ME.
I'M JUST...
I'M NOT SURE.
JACOB.
TELL ME THIS NOW?
WE'RE A WEEK AWAY
FROM THE WEDDING.
JACOB, I LOVE YOU.
YOU JUST DON'T WANT
TO MARRY ME.
NO. THAT'S NOT IT.
I JUST THINK WE SHOULD
TAKE OUR TIME.
I'VE BEEN
TAKING MY TIME.
HOW DOES WAITING SINCE
SECOND GRADE GRAB YOU?
Both:
WOULD YOU STOP IT?
[SILENCE]
IT'S LIKE YOU ARE
ALREADY MARRIED, JA?
HA HA HA HA!
POLKA!
HONEY!
JACOB, I KNOW WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
REALLY? IF YOU'RE
SUCH AN EXPERT,
HOW COME YOU'RE THE ONE
THAT'S BEEN DIVORCED?
MEL...
HONEY?
THE WEDDING'S OFF.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WE'VE ALREADY PAID
FOR EVERYTHING.
HONEY? WH-WH...
WHAT HAPPENED?
I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT HAPPENED.
YOUR DAUGHTER
GOT COLD FEET.
COLD FEET, MY ASS.
YOUR SON INSULTED HER.
WELL, HE DIDN'T SAY
NOTHING THAT WASN'T TRUE.
MAYBE SHE CAN'T
HANDLE THE TRUTH.
WHAT IS THE TRUTH,
MAX?
THE TRUTH IS THAT HER FIRST
MARRIAGE WAS A FLOP.
THAT WAS MIKE'S FAULT,
AND YOU KNOW THAT.
WELL, IF SHE COULDN'T
KEEP MIKE HAPPY,
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK SHE
CAN KEEP JACOB HAPPY?
THAT'S A LOUSY THING.
MY DAUGHTER WOULDN'T
MARRY YOUR SON
IF HE WAS THE LAST MAN
IN WABASHA.
THAT'S FINE WITH ME.
I WAS AGAINST THE WHOLE
THING FROM THE START.
THAT GOES DOUBLE
FOR ME!
THEN IT'S OFF!
YES,
EVERYTHING IS OFF!
THE WEDDING IS OFF,
AND THE FRIENDSHIP IS OFF,
AND THE GLOVES ARE OFF.
LET THE GAMES BEGIN.
COME ON, BABY!
COME TO PAPA!
YES! YES!
ATTABOY!
THAT'S IT!
AAH!
WH...
HEY, GUSTAFSON!
[MOTOR STARTS]
WHAT THE HELL?
COME BACK.
COME BACK! COME BACK!
COME BACK!
OH, DAMN YOU, GOLDMAN!
WHAT A PUTZ!
Clerk:
HI. HOW ARE YOU?
OK.
HOW ARE YOU?
HERE'S YOUR CARD.
THAT'S IT FOR YOU?
YEP.
THAT'LL DO IT.
YOU HAVE A NICE DAY,
MR. GUSTAFSON.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
WHAT...
[CLAPPING AND LAUGHING]
MAX!
WHERE THE...
YOU BASTARD.
♪ DO DOO DOO
[SWING MUSIC PLAYING]
♪ DOO DOO DOO
Record: ♪ 'SWONDERFUL
♪ 'SMARVELOUS...
YOU DANCE VERY WELL.
THANK YOU.
MARIA.
I GOT THIS FOR YOU.
HOPE YOU DON'T MIND.
OH, MAX! MAX!
IT'S A CUBIC ZIRCONIA.
GOT IT FROM
THE HOME SHOPPING NETWORK.
IT'S SO BEAUTIFUL.
HERE.
LET ME HELP YOU.
SEE HOW IT LOOKS.
YOU JUST PUT THAT
LIKE THAT.
YOU DON'T LIKE IT,
HUH?
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
IT'S JUST, UM...
JUST WHAT?
I DON'T KNOW. THINGS
ARE MOVING SO FAST.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH FAST?
I LIKE FAST.
I DIDN'T PLAN ON MEETING
SOMEBODY LIKE YOU
WHEN I CAME TO WABASHA.
OH, BUT YOU'RE
HAPPY, HUH?
YES, BUT THAT
IS WHAT WORRIES ME.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, MAX.
♪ 'SWONDERFUL,
'SMARVELOUS ♪
♪ GLORIOUS,
IT'S GLAMOROUS ♪
♪ THAT YOU SHOULD CARE
FOR ME ♪
OK, SLICK.
SHARPEN THOSE CLAWS.
[MEOW]
♪ BA BA BA BUM
♪ BA BA BA BEE
[HORN HONKS]
♪ BO BO BO BO
BO BO ♪
♪ BA BA BA BO--
AAH!
GET OUT OF THERE!
HOLEY MOLEY.
YOU JUST KISSED YOUR
NINTH LIFE GOOD-BYE, SLICK!
Woman:
THIS ONE IS VERY SWEET.
THAT ONE WITH THE BIG TONGUE AND
THE BIG BROWN EYES IS GREAT.
HMM.
WHAT ABOUT THIS ONE?
THIS ONE?
YES. ONE-EYE.
NO NUTS?
YOU MEAN LUCKY.
YOU DON'T WANT HIM.
I'LL TAKE HIM.
HERE, LUCKY.
[BARK]
[GROWLING]
HA HA HA HA!
HE'S CUTE.
[MEOW]
AHH...
GOOD MORNING, SLICK.
WHAT A NICE KITTY CAT.
YES, YOU ARE.
AND I SEE YOU'VE CRAPPED
ON MY NEWSPAPER AGAIN, HMM?
WOULD YOU LIKE TO MAKE
A NEW FRIEND THIS MORNING, HMM?
LUCKY! KILL SLICK!
LUCKY!
KILL SLICK!
[BARKS]
[MEOW]
[BARKING]
AH HA HA HA!
[REEOOWW]
OW! WHO THE...
JOHN!
COME HERE, BABY.
NOOO!
UHH!
WHOA!
EVERYTHING'S
UNDER CONTROL.
SLICK!
HOW DO YOU
LIKE THAT, YOU PUTZ?
WHY, YOU DIRTY...
I'LL KILL YOU.
YOU RUINED MY
REFINISHED SEATS.
YOU BROADCAST MY NAKED
ASS TO HALF OF WABASHA.
BIG DEAL. TAKE THAT,
YOU VANDAL!
YOU DAMN NEAR
KILLED MY CAT.
THAT MANGY ANIMAL'S
BEEN CRAPPING
ON MY PAPER FOR YEARS!
THAT BUTT-UGLY...
GIVE ME THAT POLE.
GET THAT POLE OFF.
AH!
[DUELING FISHING POLES]
THAT'S IT.
IF MY DOG
WAS AS UGLY AS YOU,
I'D SHAVE HIS ASS AND TEACH
HIM TO WALK BACKWARDS.
[DOOR SLAMS]
ARIEL!
THE TRUTH DOESN'T
WORK WITH ME.
MAX, TIME OUT.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
HOME, AND YOU CAN CALL ME
WHEN THIS STUPID WAR
IS OVER.
SHE LEFT ME.
YOU'RE SURPRISED?
TV: HERE WE ARE.
IT'S SO GOOD.
NOW YOU WANT TO PUT IN
JUST A PINCH OF SALT.
JUST A PINCH.
OOP! DAMN IT!
NOT TOO MUCH.
NOW YOU TELL ME.
YOU DON'T WANT TO
OVERPOWER THE SAUCE.
OH, SHUT UP.
THERE WE ARE.
LOTS OF GARNISH HERE.
TIME TO LOOK
AT THE BIRDS.
THE BIRD.
AAH! FIRE!
FIRE! JACOB,
I GOT A FIRE HERE.
TV:
ABSOLUTELY PERFECT.
ANYBODY CAN MAKE THESE.
IT'S SIMPLE.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
I'M TRYING TO COOK A
GOURMET DINNER FOR MARIA.
UH-HUH.
LOOK AT IT.
OH!
SHE'LL BE IMPRESSED.
TELL HER IT'S CAJUN.
YES.
WHAT DO YOU CALL THIS?
HAVEN'T DECIDED YET,
BUT I'M LEANING
TOWARD MYSTERY STEW.
I DON'T MEAN TO BE
A PESSIMIST, POP,
BUT MAYBE YOU NEED
A BACKUP PLAN.
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE
YOU KNOW HOW TO MAKE?
JELLY SANDWICHES?
GET CRACKING.
I USED TO LOVE
JELLY SANDWICHES
WITH PEANUT BUTTER.
YOU DID, TOO,
WHEN YOU WERE A KID.
[SIGHS]
HEY, COME ON.
GO OVER THERE
AND TELL HER YOU'RE SORRY.
GO AHEAD.
OH, I TRIED TO, BUT
SHE WON'T EVEN TALK TO ME.
NOT THAT I BLAME HER.
[SIGHS]
Mama: YOU SPEND TOO MUCH
TIME WITH THIS MAX GOLDMAN.
I LIKE HIM, MAMA,
A LOT.
HE'LL BREAK YOUR HEART,
LIKE THE OTHERS.
NAH, THIS TIME
IS DIFFERENT.
YOU SAY FERNANDO
IS DIFFERENT,
AND LOOK
WHAT HAPPENED.
I WAS A GIRL, MAMA.
THEN THERE WAS
EDUARDO THE DRUNK.
THAT WAS
A LONG TIME AGO.
MARCELLO THE WOMANIZER
WAS NOT THAT LONG AGO.
I'M NOT LISTENING
TO THIS.
AND NEXT CAME
CARLO THE CON MAN.
ARE YOU FINISHED?
I WISH I WERE,
BUT THEN I WOULD BE
FORGETTING ANTONIO!
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
ALL 5 I WARN YOU AGAINST,
AND ALL 5 YOU MARRIED!
MAMA!
YOU ARE A GOOD GIRL,
BUT YOU ARE
CURSED IN LOVE.
THAT ISN'T TRUE.
FOR ONCE, MARIA,
LISTEN TO YOUR MAMA.
DO YOU CARE FOR HIM?
YES.
THEN LEAVE HIM BE.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
♪ WHAT A DAY
THIS HAS BEEN ♪
♪ WHAT A RARE MOOD
I'M IN ♪
♪ WHY, IT'S ALMOST LIKE
BEING IN LOVE ♪
♪ THERE'S A SMILE
ON MY FACE ♪
♪ FOR THE WHOLE
HUMAN RACE ♪
♪ WHY, IT'S ALMOST LIKE
BEING IN LOVE ♪
♪ AH, THE MUSIC OF LIFE
SEEMS TO BE ♪
♪ LIKE A BELL
THAT IS RINGING FOR ME... ♪
[RING]
♪ ...WAY THAT I FEEL
♪ WHEN THAT BELL
STARTS TO PEAL ♪
♪ I WOULD SWEAR
I WAS FALLING ♪
[RING]
♪ I COULD SWEAR
I WAS FALLING ♪
♪ WHY, IT'S ALMOST LIKE
BEING IN LOVE ♪
[RING]
HEY, POP.
WELL, I'VE REALLY
DONE IT THIS TIME.
I'VE REALLY
SCREWED IT UP.
JAKE AND MELANIE
CALLED OFF THE MARRIAGE.
JAKE'S MOVED IN
WITH MAX.
MAX AND I
ARE AT IT AGAIN.
AND ON TOP OF THAT ARIEL'S MOVED
BACK INTO HER HOUSE WITH MELANIE.
NOW, WHAT AM I GOING
TO DO ABOUT ALL THAT?
HUH?
POP?
LOOKS LIKE GOD
REMEMBERED YOU, POP.
I'M SORRY.
Jack:
HEY, MORON.
HELLO, PUTZ.
MIND IF I
JOIN YOU?
NO. HELP YOURSELF.
I KNEW YOUR OLD MAN
LONGER THAN
I KNEW MY OWN.
HE WAS ALWAYS
VERY FOND OF YOU, MAX.
HE WAS A GOOD MAN.
THE BEST.
YOU KNOW, I DIDN'T
MEAN WHAT I SAID
ABOUT MELANIE
THE OTHER DAY.
YOU KNOW HOW I REALLY
FEEL ABOUT JACOB.
HE'S A GOOD BOY.
YEAH.
I JUST DON'T WANT HIM
TO BE LONELY.
HE DESERVES BETTER.
HE DESERVES MELANIE.
SO, WHAT DO YOU
WANT TO DO NOW?
WANT TO GET DRUNK?
YEAH.
Allie: COME ON, GRANDPA JOHN.
HURRY UP!
YEAH, I'M COMING,
ALLIE.
BUT YOU ALREADY GOT
ENOUGH CANDY IN THIS BAG
TO GIVE THE WHOLE
NEIGHBORHOOD CAVITIES.
TV: WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO TO
ENSURE THAT 6 MONTHS FROM NOW
YOU FEEL HAPPIER AND
MORE LOVED THAN YOU DO TODAY?
'CAUSE YOU KNOW WHAT? THE TRUTH
IS, IF YOU DON'T DO SOMETHING,
NOTHING IN YOUR LIFE
WILL CHANGE.
SPREAD THE SEEDS,
KEEP IT WATERED,
AND WATCH IT GROW.
♪ CH-CH-CH-CHIA
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN
ANYTHING MORE AMAZING?
STOP THE INSANITY!
FROM THE MOST BEAUTIFUL
PLACE IN THE WORLD
COMES THE MOST EXOTIC TANNING
PRODUCT IN THE WORLD--
HAWAIIAN TROPIC.
NATURAL OILS,
TROPICAL FRUITS,
FLORA, NUTS,
AND PROTECTIVE SUNSCREENS.
A COMPLETE SUN CARE LINE
CREATED BY ONE MAN,
RON WEISS,
FOR ONE REASON.
UHH!
AH!
WHAT ARE YOU
FEEDING THIS DOG?
HORMEL CHILI.
EWW!
HE LIKES IT.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
TRICK OR TREAT!
OH, TRICK OR TREAT.
I FORGOT,
JUST PLAIN FORGOT.
HIYA, HIYA, KIDS.
HERE'S A COASTER,
AND THERE'S A STAPLER
FOR YOU.
OPEN YOUR BAG.
THAT'S IT. GOOD SHOT.
HAPPY HALLOWEEN.
HI, UNCLE MAX!
WHO'S THAT? ALLIE?
HELLO, ALLIE.
IS ALLIE HERE?
OH, LOOK AT YOU.
LET'S HEAR
A POLAR BEAR GROWL.
GRRR!
Max: HAPPY HALLOWEEN,
THERE, PUTZO.
HOW DID YOU KNOW
IT WAS ME?
YOU WEAR THE SAME COSTUME
EVERY...CHRISTMAS.
HA HA HA HA!
HALLOWEEN.
Jake: HEY, ALLIE.
HEY, YOU.
HOW'S YOUR MOM DOING?
OK. WANT
TO COME OVER?
YEAH, HOW ABOUT THAT? YOU WANT TO
GO OVER AND JUST SAY HI, JAKE?
SHE'D PROBABLY
THROW ME OUT
THE MOMENT
SHE SAW MY FACE.
UH, MAX, I THINK
I GOT AN IDEA.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
OH!
TRICK OR TREAT!
HEY, YOU! OHH!
MMM! HOW DID
WE DO TONIGHT?
UNCLE MAX GAVE ME
A CAN OPENER
AND A BUNCH OF
LAUNDRY DETERGENT.
HE DID?
YES, HE DID.
HA!
ALLIE?
I'M GOING TO BED,
MOM.
DON'T YOU WANT TO WATCH
THE SCARY MOVIE?
I SAID
I'M GOING TO BED!
WHAT HAS GOTTEN
INTO HER?
YOU LOOK GREAT, MEL.
YOU LOOK RIDICULOUS.
[DOOR CLOSES]
I NEEDED TO SEE
YOU AGAIN, MEL...
TO TELL YOU
HOW SORRY I WAS
FOR THE WAY I ACTED
THE OTHER DAY.
I JUST THOUGHT
I COULDN'T BE HAPPY
UNLESS WE WERE MARRIED,
AND I REALIZE NOW...
I JUST WANT YOU
IN MY LIFE.
THAT'S ALL I WANT.
IF WE EVER DO
GET MARRIED, I...
I PROMISE YOU...
WE'LL USE A PROFESSIONAL
WEDDING COORDINATOR.
HA HA HA!
YOU LOOK TERRIFIC.
OH, JACOB.
MMM, JACOB?
HMM?
THEY'RE WATCHING US.
NO, THEY'RE NOT.
MM-HMM.
YES, THEY ARE.
HA HA! LET'S CELEBRATE.
BEERS ARE ON ME.
I'D LOVE TO, MAX,
BUT I'VE GOT SOMEONE
VERY SPECIAL
WAITING FOR ME
OVER THERE.
OF COURSE,
IF YOU HAD HALF A BRAIN,
YOU COULD HAVE
THE SAME THING.
SHE DUMPED ME.
MAX, WOULD YOU PARK THAT STUPID
PRIDE OF YOURS JUST ONCE?
YOU MIGHT SURPRISE YOURSELF.
I GOT TO SPEAK
TO MARIA.
OH, PUT DOWN
THAT BAT.
SHE DON'T WANT
TO SEE YOU.
WELL, I AIN'T LEAVIN'
HERE UNTIL I SEE MARIA!
OOH, AT LAST,
I GET TO WHACK HIM!
MAMA.
MAMA, PLEASE.
PLEASE, MAMA.
MARIA, WE NEED TO TALK.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO TALK ABOUT.
WELL, AT LEAST GIVE ME
AN EXPLANATION.
I THINK I DESERVE
THAT MUCH.
YES, YOU'RE RIGHT.
I HAVE TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING.
YES?
I HAVE BEEN
MARRIED BEFORE.
TO ANTONIO. I KNOW.
BUT ALSO TO FERNANDO
AND CARLO...
AND EDUARDO...
AND MARCELLO.
HOLEY MOLEY.
YOU'VE BEEN MARRIED
5 TIMES.
SO NOW YOU UNDERSTAND?
MOTHER IS RIGHT.
I'M CURSED IN LOVE.
WAIT! WAIT!
WILL YOU WAIT, PLEASE?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED
WITH THOSE OTHER GUYS,
BUT LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHING ABOUT ME.
I KNOW
I'M NO GREAT PRIZE,
BUT I'M LOYAL,
I'M HONEST,
AND I KNOW
HOW TO TREAT A LADY.
AND ANYBODY
SAYS ANY DIFFERENT
DOESN'T KNOW HER ASS
FROM HER ELBOW.
LOOK, I GOT A WEEK'S
WORTH OF LEFTOVERS
AT THE HOUSE,
SO IF YOU CARE
TO JOIN ME
FOR SOME MYSTERY STEW AND
SOME JELLY SANDWICHES,
I WOULD BE
INDEED HONORED.
THAT SOUNDS WONDERFUL.
YOU MUST REALLY LIKE
JELLY SANDWICHES.
YES.
♪ DING DONG DING DONG DING
♪ DING DING
DING-A-LING DING ♪
♪ YEP, YEP,
♪ I HEAR WEDDING BELLS
♪ RING WOO HOO HOO HOO
♪ RING-A-LONG
DING DONG ♪
♪ RING HEE HOO HOO
♪ RING-A-LONG
DING DONG ♪
♪ RING HEE HOO HOO
♪ RING-A-LONG
DING DONG... ♪
TRES MAGNIFIQUE, MAX.
THANK YOU,
MR. GUSTAFSON.
HONEY, WE'RE RUNNING
A LITTLE BEHIND.
WE'LL MEET YOU
AT THE CHURCH, OK?
DON'T BE LATE.
♪ I HEAR BELLS
WHEN WE'RE TOGETHER ♪
♪ I HEAR BELLS,
WEDDING BELLS ♪
♪ YEP, YEP,
DING-A-LING DING ♪
♪ I HEAR WEDDING BELLS...
SAY, JOHN,
ISN'T THAT SVEN OVER THERE?
SVEN?
HEY, SVEN.
WHAT'S THE MATTER? YOU LOOK
LIKE YOU'VE SEEN A GHOST.
BIGGEST FISH
I EVER SEEN.
CATFISH HUNTER.
YEAH.
OH, YEAH. YEAH.
OH, I FOUGHT THE BEAST
FOR AN HOUR,
AND I HAD HIM
RIGHT UP INTO THE BOAT,
AND THEN...
HE SMILED.
HE SMILED?
SEE?
AND THEN HE BIT
THE POLE IN HALF.
HOLEY MOLEY!
IF I HADN'T MOVED MY HAND
AT THE LAST MOMENT...
JUDAS PRIEST.
OH, THAT--THAT WAS
THE BIGGEST...DAMN FISH
I EVER SEEN.
WHEW.
DON'T EVEN THINK OF IT.
MY BOAT IS BEACHED
NOT MORE THAN A HUNDRED
YARDS FROM HERE.
NO.
WE'LL JUST
GIVE IT 10 MINUTES.
AFTER THAT WE PULL ANCHOR AND
GO STRAIGHT TO THE CHURCH.
NO.
BUT WHAT IF TODAY'S THE
DAY AND WE MISS HIM?
SOMEBODY ELSE
COULD CATCH OUR FISH!
SOME STRANGER WITH OUR
FISH MOUNTED ON HIS WALL!
IT'S TOO HORRIBLE
TO THINK ABOUT.
[RING]
CONGRATULATIONS, JACOB.
MAX, LET'S GET
THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, LET'S
GET THE HELL OUTTA HERE?
WE'VE STILL
GOT MORE TIME.
THAT DAMN FISH WILL BE
HALFWAY TO RED WING BY NOW.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
5 MORE MINUTES.
WE'LL BE LATE!
WEDDINGS NEVER
START ON TIME.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU?
WHAT ARE
YOU WORRIED ABOUT?
I'M GOING.
ALL RIGHT. YOU'LL
HAVE TO SWIM BACK.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
DON'T TOUCH MY MOTOR.
WILL YOU SIT DOWN, JOHN,
FOR CRYING OUT LOUD?
5 MORE MINUTES.
JUST SIT THERE FOR A
MINUTE AND SHUT UP.
MORON.
PUTZ.
HOLY JESUS. MAX!
LOOK, LOOK,
LOOK, LOOK.
EASY, EASY.
DON'T WORRY.
AHH...
LOOK AT HIM GO.
NOW HE'S GOING
TO STOP.
[GASPS]
AND NOW
I'M GOING TO...
UHH!
THAT'S CATFISH HUNTER.
IT'S GOT TO BE.
AAH! OHH!
I THINK
YOU PISSED HIM OFF.
HANG ON, MAX. I THINK
WE'RE GOING FOR A RIDE.
THERE.
UHH! HANG ON.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
IT'S A FISH.
MAYBE
IT'S NOT A FISH.
MAYBE IT'S SOMETHING
FROM OUTER SPACE.
KEEP THE TIP UP.
THE TIP IS UP.
TIGHTEN THE DRAG.
HE BETTER BE DEAD.
THAT'S THE ONLY EXCUSE
I'M TAKING RIGHT NOW.
WORK HIM! WORK HIM!
I'M WORKING HIM,
YOU DUMMY.
PUMP HIM! PUMP HIM!
TIP UP! TIP UP!
THE TIP IS UP,
YOU IDIOT!
YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S NOT AN IMPORTANT DAY.
NO. NO REASON TO BE HERE.
HANG ON.
DROP THE ANCHOR, MAX.
YOU CUT THE ANCHOR,
YOU PUTZ.
WELL, THEN,
GRAB THE NET.
YOU CUT THE NET, TOO,
YOU DICKHEAD.
HERE, LOOK AT IT.
ALL RIGHT.
FORGET THE NET.
JUST GIVE ME A HAND,
WILL YOU?
THE ONLY THING YOU EVER CAUGHT
IN YOUR LIFE WAS A VIRUS.
PUT YOUR GLOVES ON,
WILL YOU?
I'LL SHOW YOU
HOW TO DO IT.
HERE'S
THE WAY YOU DO IT.
NOW WATCH THE FISHERMAN
WORK IT.
GRAB HIM!
CRIME IN ITALY.
HOLEY MOLEY!
MY GOD,
LOOK AT THIS THING.
HOLEY MOLEY!
OK, GET HIS TAIL.
I GOT HIS TAIL!
NOW!
AAH!
OK.
AHH!
[ORGAN PLAYING]
IS THAT
THE MOST BEAUTIFUL THING
YOU'VE SEEN IN YOUR LIFE?
IF I DIE TODAY,
I DIE A HAPPY MAN.
IF YOU DIE TODAY,
I'M TAKING YOUR MOTOR.
HA HA HA HA!
AHH! HA HA HA!
MAX?
HUH?
LET'S LET HIM GO.
ARE YOU
OUT OF YOUR MIND?
DAD TRIED TO CATCH
THAT FISH FOR 20 YEARS.
CATFISH HUNTER DESERVES
TO BE IN THE LAKE WITH POP.
GUSTAFSON, YOU ARE
ONE SICK BASTARD.
GOOD.
GOOD-BYE, CATFISH.
HUH?
WHAT?
HEY! THE WEDDING!
WHAT TIME IS IT?
WE'VE GOT
ANOTHER WEDDING
COMING
IN AT 3:00.
WE'LL MAKE IT BY THEN.
3:00?
♪ GET ME TO THE CHURCH
ON TIME ♪
DON'T SING THAT.
[HORNS HONKING]
MOVE IT!
[HONKING]
AAH! WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
OK, JUST
A LITTLE BIT LONGER.
NO, JACOB.
THAT'S IT FOR ME.
I'M DONE. THAT'S IT.
THE WEDDING HASN'T
STARTED YET.
♪ BUM BUM BA BUM
DO YOU SEE
MY HANDS, JACOB?
JUST KEEP PLAYING.
[HONKING]
WEDDING.
HO--
JEE--
JESUS!
AHEM.
WE'RE HERE!
WAIT! WAIT!
WAIT! HOLD IT!
WE'RE HERE!
WAIT! WE'RE HERE!
WE'RE HERE! WAIT!
WHAT'S WITH THE BOOTS?
I'LL EXPLAIN LATER.
YOU'LL EXPLAIN NOW.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
I'VE BEEN HOLDING
THIS THING UP FOR HOURS.
I WAS, UH...
See what we missed?
Thank God we eloped.
[WEDDING MARCH PLAYS]
YOU GOT THE RING?
UH, YEAH.
MY SON-IN-LAW HAS GOT
THE FACE OF A MACKEREL.
OX.
NAG.
WE ARE GATHERED HERE TODAY
TO JOIN MAXWELL GOLDMAN
AND MARIA SOPHIA
COLLETA RAGETTI
IN HOLY MATRIMONY.
[CHEERING]
THANK YOU.
BE SURE TO WATCH LUCKY
FOR US.
I'M GOING TO MISS
THAT UGLY MUG OF HIS.
DON'T WORRY, MAX.
YOU'RE GOING TO SEE HIM
BEFORE YOU KNOW IT.
I'M GONNA MISS
YOUR UGLY MUG, TOO.
GOD BLESS YOU, SIR.
LET GO OF MY HAND.
I'M VERY BUSY.
YOO-HOO!
CIAO!
♪ MARIA...
OH, MAX,
WHAT'S THAT SMELL?
WHAT SMELL?
OH, WHAT'S THAT SMELL?
HMM?
AAH! AAH! AAH!
WHAT A MORON.
[LAUGHING]
WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE GO BACK TO MY PLACE,
AND I'LL SHOW YOU MY SPICY,
PEPPY PEPPERONI?
WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE GO BACK TO MY HOUSE,
AND I'LL SHOW YOU
MY MAN-SIZED MANICOTTI?
BEAUTIFUL.
I AM THE GANGSTER
OF LOVE.
I AM THE LOTHARIO
OF FARTS.
I DON'T KNOW
WHERE I AM.
GET IN THE CAR, MAX.
I CAN'T.
I FARTED
AND I'M AFRAID TO MOVE.
DEAR--WHA--
WHAT THE HELL
IS HER NAME?
ARIEL?
WHAT'S HER NAME AGAIN?
MARIA.
SHE LEFT ME.
YOU'RE SURPRISED?
YOU DON'T EVEN
KNOW HER NAME.
HEY, DICKHEAD,
I'M STUCK.
I'VE BEEN TO HAWAII.
WHICH ISLAND?
I-KINDA-LIKE-A-POKE-YA.
YOU-LIKE-A-LICKY-DICKY.
I'M-A-KINDA-KINKY.
WANT-A-PEEK-A-PEE-PEE?
SOME STRANGER COULD
CATCH OUR FISH.
SOME SCHMUCK WITH HIS
FISH AND MY FISH
AND YOUR FISH UP
ON THE [BLEEP] WALL,
AND I AM...
[CRACKING UP]
GET ANOTHER ACTOR.
PLEASE.
SHE'S NOTHING BUT A
PIGHEADED ITALIAN WITH--
[RASPBERRY]
ONE MORE FROM THE TOP,
AND A LITTLE BIT MORE
OUT OF BREATH, YEAH?
IF I WAS MORE OUT OF
BREATH, I'D BE DEAD.
YOU'RE STILL A PUTZ.
THAT'S MY LINE!
YOU WILL NEVER
EVEN KNOW IT'S THERE.
OK. MMM!
I LOVE YOU! MMM!
OHH!
HE'S A CRIMINAL.
[CREW LAUGHING]
[LAUGHING]
[EVERYONE LAUGHING]
SHOULD THE VEIL BE UP?
HO--
OX!
JESUS CHRIST.
WHY THE [BLEEP] DON'T YOU LOOK
WHERE YOU'RE GOING THERE?
WHY DON'T YOU COME
TO MY PLACE?
I'LL SHOW YOU
MY BEEFY BOLOGNA.
HUH? NO?
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
MY BONY MACARONI?
OR MY FATTY ALFREDO?
OR MY HARD SALAMI?
I GOT 'EM ALL.
[CREW LAUGHING]