Sean: There's a magic that
happens when you dance.
Everything lines up.
The world is in sync.
And for one perfect moment,
you feel totally alive.
But to make
a living as a dancer
you go through stuff that
doesn't feel so magical.
The rejection.
Crappy pay.
Endless auditions.
That's when it feels
like your world
shrinks down to
the same cold room.
The same fluorescent
lights and the same
indifferent people
day after day.
That's where my
Hollywood story begins.
All right, thanks
for coming in today.
Uh, you guys know
everybody here.
Woman: Can you
take off, um...
Man: Take your shirts off.
Yeah, just take
your shirts off.
Oh, yeah, no shirts.
(Sighing)
Good. That's good.
That's good.
(Music playing)
That's great.
Can you come forward?
Man: And go backwards.
Can you just step
to your left, please?
Just find the light
to your left.
But as you're going left,
you need to go right?
(Grunting)
I want you
to feel the feeling
of feeling the product.
Good. And use the product.
(Grunting)
I just want the feeling
that your hose
is your family.
And I want you to, um,
make love to it.
Oh.
But not in a weird way.
That's good.
Oh, yeah. Okay.
Good. More, more!
Less, less!
Yeah, I wasn't
expecting a beard.
I like the beard.
No, we need the beard to go.
Beard's gotta go.
Woman: Beard's not going.
Man: The beard should go now.
Are you willing to
shave your beard?
Yeah, I'll shave it off.
Absolutely.
You'll shave? He'll shave.
Yeah.
Come on, please?
All: Thank you.
(Exhaling)
This is not working.
(Indistinct conversations)
What are you doin'?
What's wrong with you?
Oh.
Mmm.
Oh. That's nice.
Woman: Hey!
You gonna let her
walk past you like that?
Yeah, exactly
what was that?
Dawg, you gotta move on.
Huh?
Emily's on tour.
All right? It's over.
Hot girl looks at
you like that, man,
you gotta handle it.
Mmm-hmm.
You know better than that.
I know how I'd handle it.
Sorry, everyone,
looks like we found
what we're looking for
and we're out of
time for today,
so thanks again.
Are you serious? Come on.
We've been out
here for three hours.
That's how it goes.
Thank you so much, Elizabeth.
Appreciate it.
Always a pleasure, Jasper.
Yes, it is.
(Chuckling) Nice hats.
Ole.
Ole?
Eddy: Shit.
Jason: Bad. That was bad.
Sean: I don't get it.
I actually had a good
feeling about this one.
Yeah. That one,
and the one before,
and all the other
ones that we didn't get.
Yeah, I thought LA
was supposed to be
the place where
dreams actually happen.
No, what actually
happens is that
we keep putting on this
stupid shit for nothing.
Where did you find
these anyway?
Actually, I don't wanna know.
In the dumpster
behind El compadre.
(All groaning)
It's called vintage, boo.
Y'all act like we
can afford new ones.
Jason: No, that's
called nasty.
That's gross.
Honestly, I can't
take this anymore.
I really can't. You know?
All right.
Let's just chalk this up
as another crappy audition.
Every audition is
a crappy audition.
I thought we were
on our way.
We move out here.
We do the big nike ad.
Everything's looking good.
And then nothing.
I hate to say it,
but what are we
still doing here?
Jason: I feel you, bro.
Okay, it's been rough.
We gotta blow
off some steam.
I know what we need.
(Indistinct conversations)
(Music playing in club)
Yo, the mob is in the house,
y'all!
What's up, Sean?
Brother, how you
doin', man?
Oh, my man!
That's my man.
How you feelin', man?
All right?
How many of y'all tonight?
The whole mob.
Y'all always roam
in packs, though.
I don't know
why you gotta do
that to a brother.
Told you,
this is what we needed.
Jason: Let's have
a good night, y'all.
Oh. What the...
Hey! It's the mariachi
band from earlier.
You ladies play
us something saucy?
That's cute.
That necklace is cute, too.
You get that at Claire's?
Man, you spend all
day comin' up with that?
You musta had a lotta
free time after
not getting that gig.
Whatever,
man, just get outta here.
We're just tryin'
to have a good time.
Man, we ain't goin' nowhere.
We came here to do
a little dancin'.
Unless that's
a problem for you.
It is. So go.
Maybe we should settle it.
(Chuckling) You wanna
battle on the floor?
Please, let's not do
it, all right? Are we
really doing this?
Jason: Right.
Listen, please.
This guy's a douche, man.
And I'm not tryin' to
get all sweaty in this.
Battling him is not the move.
Look, what's the problem?
Did the three amigos
forget their sombreros?
Mexican reference?
Good job, man.
This guy's a dick.
Come on. Let's just go.
No, no.
You picked the wrong
night to get in
my face, little man.
Are you having
a tough day?
It must suck to be
hot for five minutes,
then realize that your
flash mob ain't nothin'
but a joke.
Man: Whatever, man,
you're a joke!
Okay, yeah, we got that.
That's awesome.
Thank you, man.
Look, we've been
there and done that.
Let this go. Let's just go.
No, we came here
to dance, right?
Why don't we line it
up for these clowns.
Come on, let's go.
Come on.
(Indistinct shouting)
(Music playing)
(All shouting)
(Crowd cheering)
Whoo!
Oh!
(Music changing)
(Crowd cheering)
(Indistinct shouting)
Yo!
Aah!
(All cheering)
All: (Chanting) Grim knights!
Grim knights! Grim knights!
That's the last time
I make a fool out of
myself for you. That's it.
Jason: Way to look
out for the crew, bro.
Thanks, man.
I'm outta here.
Hey, man, easy come,
easy go, bro.
If everybody could make it,
it wouldn't be Hollywood.
(Cheering continuing)
(Indistinct chatter)
What time was lunch?
Like 2:30.
There you are, man.
What is this?
Look, we been
talkin' about it, man,
and it's time
to go home, Sean.
I mean, we've gone hard.
And it's nothing
to be ashamed of.
Then what?
You're just gonna bail?
All of you?
Yo, man, wake up, man!
When are you gonna
stop acting like
everything is just okay?
This crew's not
ready for LA, man.
I don't know how
you don't see that.
Because we made 50
grand off the nike spot.
Yeah. Six months ago.
And split 12 ways.
Dawg, I spend more
money on gas going
to auditions
than most people
do on rent.
I'm over it.
I'm done, man.
So what are you gonna do?
Hmm?
You gonna go back to Miami?
We're just all
tapped out, man.
Dude, we're 40 days
late on our rent.
43.
I've run out of stuff
to sell on ebay, man.
I have nothing.
Man, let's just call it
what it is, all right?
We're ready to go back.
So quit then.
Go crawling back
to Miami. Go ahead.
Eddy: Ain't gotta
be like this.
Yeah, it does.
Sorry, I'm not leavin'.
Really?
Yeah. I'm stayin' here.
All right, peace, man.
Eddy: Hold up.
(People cheering on laptop)
Man: Caesars Palace and
international pop
sensation alexxa brava
present the vortex.
I'm alexxa brava.
And welcome to the vortex.
This is more than
just a dance competition.
This is the ultimate showdown.
With the ultimate prize.
Many crews will enter,
but only one can
emerge victorious,
winning a three-year booking
in fabulous Las Vegas.
We are now accepting
video submissions
from the world's
best dance crews.
We're looking for originality,
creativity and pure spectacle.
Does your crew
deserve a Vegas show?
If so, send us your video
and show us that your
crew has what it takes.
(Music playing)
You still got it.
Lookin' good.
Yo, man, you shoulda
called me sooner.
I had no idea
you needed a job.
Yeah. Thank you.
Things have been
a little rough.
Well, this is perfect!
Come on, I'll introduce you.
Glad you came.
How's Camille?
You guys likin' LA?
Yeah, she's great. LA's fun.
What's not to like about LA?
Rumba's the dance of love,
miss Nakamura.
It's a courtship ritual.
That's Chad.
Chad: Copy me.
Quick, slow, quick, slow.
Baba!
You must be Sean.
Mooski, you didn't tell me
your friend was so cute.
Thanks for letting
me stay here.
You're welcome.
Oh. Finally, you are here.
The women's toilet
is leaking like
a broken faucet.
And faucet is broken, too.
Please fix.
Here. You are sleeping here
in the closets of storage.
Please, drop bag
and get to work.
Opa, he just got in.
Let him settle in first.
Come on, I'll buy
you a smoothie
before you get
your hands dirty.
Go! Have smoothie.
This can wait.
Okay.
Have you heard
of the vortex?
Uh. That's something
on vh1, right?
What? Camille loves vh1.
Hey, nothin'.
No, but you should
totally enter that.
Call the mob.
No, come on, man.
The mob is like
the king of the streets.
I mean, sure,
you and eddy had a little
fallout or whatever.
But you can't enter alone.
I mean, don't get me wrong.
Back in the day,
I woulda tore that thing up.
Y'know what I'm sayin'?
I mean, that's not
a bad idea. You and I
on a crew together.
Come on.
I would love to,
but I have a job now, man.
I'm an engineer.
Come on, man.
You're the moose.
There's only one moose.
My life's totally
different now.
I've got a lot
of responsibility.
Dance competitions
are fun and all,
but they're not really
gonna pay the bills.
No, but that's
the beauty of it, man.
This competition
does pay the bills.
For a while, too.
I get it, man. I just...
I can't, man, I'm sorry.
But you should do it.
Yeah.
All right? See you around.
Later, man.
Hello!
Camille: Hi!
Welcome back.
Good day?
Yeah.
So how's Sean doing?
He's okay.
He's got this
really crazy idea.
What?
It's honestly really crazy.
Remember that ad you saw
about the vortex on vh1?
Yeah. What about it?
Yeah, well, he's
thinking about entering it.
And he can kinda
pull it off.
But the only thing is
he doesn't have
anyone to do it with.
And, so, well...
He kinda asked me to do it.
He asked you?
I know. Crazy, right?
And?
No, no, no, I can't.
It's completely impractical.
So you have no interest
in dancing at all?
Nope. Pretty sure that
part of my life is over.
Yup. I don't really
even think about it
anymore, really.
Yeah. It was
the right call.
What would you
tell Mr. mcgowan?
And how would you pull
a crew together that fast?
Exactly.
It's not like you've
been keeping up with
training or anything.
Hey, hey, hey.
I'm in shape.
But at that level?
I doubt you'd be able
to pick up where you
left off.
Oh, come on!
The moose does not
lose these skills.
Shout it! (Laughing)
Wait a second.
You just set me up.
Maybe.
So you really
want me to do this?
You wanna do this.
And if you want something,
I want it for you.
Really? 'Cause I
thought you would've
thought it was crazy.
Please! Since when
did I become that girl?
So you think I
could swing it?
With my job and everything?
You're the dancing moose.
The dancing moose
figures it out.
(Music playing)
Mr. Alexander.
Mr. mcgowan.
What are you doing?
Um...
Oh. It's actually
a focusing exercise, sir.
It gets the blood
flowing faster to
your brain,
thus causing an increase
in productivity, sir.
Um. You should
try it sometime.
It's good for your health.
Actually, I was hoping
that we could talk, sir.
Look, my grandma's not
really doing too well,
and I'm (Sighing) The only
grandson that she kinda
has out here,
and I promised my family
that I'd take care of her.
You have a grandma that
used to bake you cookies
and knit you sweaters.
My grandmother
was a prison warden.
Oh, wow.
I didn't know that.
She must have been
a very strong, tough woman
who probably did
have a soft side, too.
She was a prison warden.
I got that.
So you do understand
that from time to time,
if I need to leave
work to, you know,
take her to the doctor.
I can admire a man who
puts his family first.
As long as he gets
here two hours
early every morning
to cover the time
he's missing.
Two hours?
Two hours.
Yes! Work those hips,
miss turnbuckle,
work those hips.
Twerk it, miss turnbuckle.
Vegas, baby, Vegas.
We got three weeks to
get ready for Vegas.
You comin' down
from there, or what?
What? Oh, hell, yeah!
You better not be
playin' me, man.
What about your job?
Figured it out.
Come on.
What about my job?
Your grandparents?
Oh, they'll be all right.
Chad knows how
to change a light bulb.
Right, Chad?
Yeah.
Moose: I know just
the place to start.
Figure eights.
Work those figure eights.
(Indistinct conversation)
(Bell ringing)
And we're at
a fashion shoot?
Okay.
Oh, I get it.
Costumes. Good thinkin'.
Oh, my God,
that looks terrible!
I told you she
would screw this up.
I'm not finished yet.
I just need some more pins.
Pins won't work!
What is wrong with you?
You are making
her look fat.
What did I tell you?
You're making me look fat?
You don't look fat.
You need to solve
this right now.
She looks like a whale.
Okay, I am gonna
get some more pins.
I'm calling the designer.
Oh, my God, is this
making me look fat?
(Scoffs)
Moose! (Laughing)
What are you doing here?
We're gonna dance on
live television in Vegas...
Blah blah blah!
Come on, we'll fill
you in in the car.
No. Are you talking
about that vortex thing?
I have work. Can't.
Yo! Think this is
a good look for the crew.
(Laughing)
Who's the pretty boy?
This is Sean.
He's an amazing
choreographer.
You've never
heard of the mob?
No.
How have you not
heard of the mob?
I don't get out much.
And, ah, who are you?
Hey, guys, relax, okay?
Andie, this is Sean.
The mob is totally legit.
And, Sean, Andie
knows what she's doing.
All right?
Cool. So she will help
with the costumes then,
right?
(Chuckling) This costume
girl could dance
circles around your ass.
(Laughing) Okay, good to know.
Anytime, anyplace.
Okay, guys,
let's just chill,
all right?
Come on.
Can we talk about this?
Does it always have to end up
in a big, giant dance battle?
(Music playing)
(Laughing)
What is going on here?
Get me off this thing!
All right, hang on, hang on.
Somebody get her a ladder.
Hang on.
We'll get you down.
Oh, my God, the couture!
What is this?
Clean up this
mess or you're fired.
Fired!
Eh.
Sean: Turns out,
moose was well-connected.
First we found vladd,
the human robot.
And we all know he
can do some crazy stuff.
Speaking of crazy,
we hunted down these two
busted-up sign spinners
who turned out to be...
Moose!
What are you doing here?
Sean: The Santiago twins.
Two of the most
amazing dancers
I've ever seen.
Next, Andie took
us to meet Violet.
This is Violet.
Trust me, we need her.
Sean: She makes a mean
banana split, but, hey...
Sean: That's just her day job.
This girl can move.
Then calls went out
to the east coast.
(Cellphone ringing)
Hello?
Sean: Jenny kido.
Does your aunt
still have that van?
Sean: Ditched her
telemarketing job,
grabbed her aunt's van,
(speaking Japanese)
And hit the road.
(Cellphone ringing)
Before heading west,
she picked up monster.
Monster!
Kido!
Road trip! Are you in?
Sean: A sick b-boy
from the Bronx.
They swung through Baltimore
and grabbed our buddy, hair,
who refused to come
without his barber.
But, that guy could
dance his ass off.
How are you?
Sean: Three days later,
we all showed up
at the cha cha palace.
Mr. moose!
Santiagos! Twin killers.
Hey!
Hi, vladd.
Hi! How are you?
Sean: Our crew
was finally complete.
Hi!
Sean: Or so we thought.
Let's call it a day,
miss vanderblast.
You go take a load
off those bunions.
Thank you.
That's Chad, everybody.
He teaches here.
What's up, what's up?
Smooth.
Are we still sayin' that?
Yo. So we're gonna
be training here.
Ana and Boris already
gave us the "all clear."
We'll try and stay
outta your way. Cool?
Cool.
Okay, junior cotillion.
Today, foxtrot promenade.
Five minutes and
we get started.
All right, all right.
Thank you all for coming out.
Yeah. Everybody
knows why they're here.
This isn't just another
dance competition.
We win this thing and
we get our own show.
For three years.
(All cheering)
That means
quitting our day jobs
and dancing full-time.
The first round
of the vortex is
a video submission.
That's right. We got
some really cool ideas.
I work at a lab.
And my boss is at a
conference next week
and if we work fast,
we can shoot our video
there while he's gone.
Only the best of
the best get in.
So we need to
give them a show.
So let's get to
work and put our heads
in the same place. Yeah?
All right, let's do it.
Yeah, if we rehearse
every single day,
I don't think
that'll be a problem.
No, it wouldn't be.
But we need to think
and breathe as a unit.
Thinkin' and breathin'?
No, we need to dance.
We're gonna dance.
Well, obviously,
we're gonna dance,
'cause that's why we're here.
So just to be clear,
if we're gonna be a crew,
who's gonna be in charge?
I am.
What? I'm not doin' that.
What? Go over there!
Where?
(Giggling)
Yeah, come on, we're doin' it.
Chad: Okay, cotillion,
ignore those guys.
Eyes right here.
Keep your eyes
on the Chad.
Come on.
Everybody up. Let's go.
Okay, take your partners.
Just follow what
I'm doin'. Go.
(Violet laughing)
Violet: So cool.
Guys! Seriously?
(Grunting)
Okay, let's move on.
Hit this hard. Come back.
There you go.
(Clearing throat)
I wanna be in your crew.
(Scoffs)
Dude, no offense, man,
but the cha-cha-cha
doesn't really
mesh with what
we're doin' here.
Yeah. So I cha-cha
with cougars?
Pays the bills.
Chicks dig it.
But I have been known
to get pretty crunk.
This competition's gonna
be hard enough as it is.
We don't need any
help from Rico suave
over here.
Ooh. Ouch.
Rico suave, huh?
You don't think
I got it, do ya?
Do you wanna
see what I got?
Nope. No, I don't wanna
see what you've got.
Hit the music.
(Music playing)
Watch.
(Laughing)
(All cheering)
Marcos: That was great!
Bravo!
I can't believe it.
Whatever.
(Laughing)
Martin: Fancy pants.
(Music playing)
(All cheering)
(Grunting)
(Snoring)
Mooski, take
another meatball.
You need to be strong
tomorrow for your video.
I also made veggie loaf
in case anyone wants some.
(Dismissively)
Vegan, vaygan...
Vegan, baba, vegan.
Foo to your vegan!
You need meat. Not grass.
Good for the blood.
Look at how she
eats her balls.
You like the balls?
Yes, thank you.
They're great.
I give you recipe.
You make for him.
See how many he eats?
No, they're actually good.
Texture's a little
different than regular
meatballs, though.
Kinda chewier.
That means he
was a tough goat.
Goat?
Goat. You know.
(Imitates goat bleating)
Moose: Yeah, goat balls.
Yeah, they're a total
delicacy back
in the old country.
Mmm.
And once again, veggie loaf?
Anyone?
I like the meat.
Are you sure you're
okay with the dishes?
Yeah, we got this.
Yeah, go.
We're almost done.
And next time,
I'm cooking dinner.
I do not hate
that idea at all.
(Camille laughing)
Camille: Okay. Sounds good.
Bye.
Adios, muchachos.
Bye!
Those goat balls?
Oh, my God, you shoulda seen
the look on your face.
Hey. I took it like a man.
(Laughing) Like a man.
Right.
I didn't know if you
were gonna cry or puke.
You don't seem
like the crying type.
So I seem like
the puking type?
Well...
God, have you always been
such a perfectionist?
I'm not a perfectionist.
(Laughing)
Must have driven
your ex nuts, huh?
She was a dancer,
too, right?
I'm sorry. Moose told me.
I didn't know if it
was a secret or anything.
No, it's not.
It was a while ago.
She was in my crew and...
She left.
I know all about that.
(Laughing)
Can be really hard.
Dancing together.
Being together.
Gets intense.
Yeah.
(Ana laughing)
(Whispering)
Look, look, look.
Come here.
(Laughing)
It's amazing how long
they've been together.
They still dance.
Sean: Wow. Moose, this
is perfect for the video.
Moose: Wait till you see
what I rigged up in here.
Dude, this place is crazy.
I can't believe you work here.
How long till
your boss gets back
from his conference?
Precisely four
hours and nine minutes
as long as he doesn't
travel faster than 67
Miles per hour.
Sean: But we gotta
work fast. Ready?
Who's on music? Let's roll.
Hmm.
(Electricity crackling)
(Both screaming)
(Laughing)
(Grunting)
(All cheering)
Yo. It's so sick!
Sean: All right,
it's official.
We're lmntrix.
All: Lmntrix.
All (Chanting)
Lmntrix! Lmntrix! Lmntrix!
(All cheering)
Still nothin'
from the vortex?
Nope. Two weeks
and not a thing.
Dude, our video
was great.
I don't get it.
(Sighing)
Yeah. I thought
we killed it.
I wish things
would just work out
just for once.
How'd your
grandparents do it?
Must have been
easier back in the day.
Was it easier back then?
I had to shovel...
(Speaking other language)
Sheep poop.
Yeah. That's how I
paid for our shoes
so we could dance.
Sounds terrible.
Are you kidding?
It was greatest
time of my life.
We dance all night
and forget about everything.
Oh, yeah. The light in
the bathroom, it needs fix.
And one more thing...
Ana!
Ana: What?
Where is the package?
The lemon tricks.
Ana: The what?
Boris: The lemon
tricks thing.
Ana: Oh.
Here.
It's from the vortex.
Alexxa: Welcome, team lmntrix.
Your journey to
the vortex begins now.
Vegas, baby!
Oh, yeah!
Vegas!
(All cheering)
Sean: Caesars!
You guys, it's caesars!
Stop, stop, stop!
Welcome to Caesars Palace.
You guys here for the vortex?
All right, step right
this way to meet alexxa.
So, Jasper, how did you feel
when you found out that
the grim knights
will be competing here?
At Caesars Palace?
Oh, my God. So, so blessed.
When you grow
up like I did,
life puts a cage
around your heart.
All you hear is the can'ts,
the shouldn'ts, the don'ts.
Being in this magical
place and having this
beautiful opportunity?
To me, that is the dream.
Women: Aw.
Believe, yo.
She's so beautiful.
Yo.
That is so inspiring.
Thank you very much.
We got it. Cut.
Hey. Wait, wait, wait.
Can we do it again?
I want us to do
something with a little
bit more passion.
Maybe talk about how
I was bullied as a kid.
Powder!
Man: Lmntrix? All right,
you'll do. Get up here.
So cute! Come here, guys.
Go, go, go!
Oh, hey.
It's the lab rats! Yeah!
I see you got
yourself a new crew.
Y'all come to see
some real dancin'?
Man, let's get outta here.
Ooh.
So it begins.
The drama!
The passion! The vortex.
How intimidating is it
to be going up against
all these tough crews?
No, we're excited.
We're a new crew.
But don't let that fool you.
We're ready.
We been training
really hard to get here.
Now I hear the grim knights
are the crew to beat.
(Clicking tongue)
How do you feel about that?
It's news to me.
We literally
just arrived, so...
Okay. Thank you, guys.
Wait a minute, please!
It is going to be fierce.
I'm alexxa brava,
and I am signing off.
(Indistinct chatter)
Look at this place.
Chad: Smells great.
After that,
you know what I mean?
Jason: Is that Sean?
Look who it is.
What are you guys
doin' here?
What are we...
What are you doing here?
Huh?
Man, it was really
nice of you to call
your crew before you
entered this thing.
I know everybody's
really happy with you.
Celestina: Mmm-hmm.
Crew?
Mmm.
Oh, you mean my crew.
The crew that didn't
leave me in LA.
Look, man, let's just
get one thing straight,
all right?
We were done with LA,
but we were never
done with the mob.
Yeah. So this is
your new crew?
Yeah, well,
they ain't my book club.
Yeah, man.
Glad you made some
new friends, bro.
They any good?
They look pretty good.
Yeah, they're the best
of the best.
The best of the best?
Oh. That's a statement
right there. Yeah.
As long as you believe that.
I believe it.
Guys, we didn't
get that last part.
Could you guys just repeat it?
What?
And could you be
a little bit more hurt?
A little more vulnerable.
Sean: Who are you?
Could you maybe step back?
I'm with the vortex.
What's this about?
Wow!
That was Sean's best friend.
Come on, let's go
check out the room.
Welcome to your suite.
Care of the vortex.
(All cheering)
Feel it.
I love you, too,
my little munchkin puppy.
Yeah, you're such
a little Fluffy muffin.
You're so cute.
We'd have the best
time ever. I wish
you were here. I swear.
(Laughing)
I love you, baby.
Camille says, "hi."
(Makes whipping sound)
Send it to her.
There's a huge
bed upstairs.
(Sniffing)
Wanna check it out?
(Groaning)
Gross.
Please go away.
(Sniffing)
(Coughing)
What is that smell?
It's my scent.
Real smooth, buddy.
Real smooth.
(Laughing)
(Audience cheering)
Jason: Hey, the mob.
Anytime, baby. Mob up.
(Cheering continuing)
Good evening.
Welcome to the vortex.
(All cheering)
Tonight, you'll meet
the dancers of tomorrow.
Finest in the world.
Each vying to be
the lords of Vegas.
With a world-class
show of their own
at sensational Caesars Palace!
(Cheering)
Wish them luck.
They're gonna need it.
(Music playing)
(Grunting)
(Cheering)
Was that hot enough for you?
So talented.
So full of hope and dreams.
They wish they could all stay.
But we only
have room for four.
The crews that will
fight it out in the
battle ring are...
Divine intention.
(Cheering)
Shh.
The mob.
(Cheering)
The grim knights.
And lmntrix!
My God!
Andie: Who ate all
the muffins?
Kido: Andie, you did.
Andie: Is there more coffee?
Kido: Coffee.
All right, guys,
we gotta start
rehearsal soon.
(Sighing)
I don't think I can face
those camera crews anymore.
(Knocking on door)
Maid: Good morning!
Housekeeping?
This way. This is
the place I told you.
Sean.
(Speaking Spanish)
Good luck! Bye-bye!
Man! This is what I call
a great rehearsal space.
All right.
All right, yo,
yo, listen up.
That circus up there,
the cameras,
the people, the drama...
That's nothin'
but a distraction.
Could keep us from
winnin' this thing.
So let's stay focused,
and let's get to business.
All: Yeah!
(Music playing)
Chad: Whoo!
Go!
All: And one, and two...
Go like this. Follow me.
Five, six, seven, eight.
Okay.
Okay. Ready?
Let's go, come on.
Five, six, seven, eight.
One and two and three
and four and five and six
and seven and eight.
Make sure these are clean.
One and two and three
and four and five and six
and seven and eight.
Again, right away, let's go.
One and two and three and...
Stop! Stop! Stop!
He needs to catch on.
He's not doin' it right.
Let's do it again.
Five, six, seven, eight.
One and two and three
and four and five and
six, seven, eight.
No!
Come on,
that was good, man.
Not good enough.
You wanna win?
I know you want
this as bad as I do.
We're tired, man.
Please, help me help
you guys, all right?
Andie: All right, I think
we've all had it for today.
Why don't you guys just
head out. We'll meet you
upstairs.
See you upstairs.
Yeah.
(Grunting)
Look, I wanna try
this thing with you
that I've been
imagining in my head.
(Chuckling)
Better be the dancing
you're talking about.
Easy.
(Panting)
All right.
You're gonna put
that leg right here,
that leg in my hand,
and hold on to
my neck, okay?
And then what?
Just trust me. Okay?
(Laughing)
You're so sweaty.
Come on, be serious. Okay?
So, I'm gonna jump
into your other hand?
Yeah.
Okay.
Three, two... go ahead.
There we go.
Oh, my God.
Oh.
We got it.
All right.
I'm gonna toss you up.
Now what? No!
And you're gonna
go into a layout.
No, put me down. Stop it.
Stop it. Put me down.
You gotta trust me.
You gotta let go.
Okay, I know that
you want some big,
cool move,
but you can't force it.
Sounds like an excuse.
You saying I take
the easy way out,
or something?
You don't know
anything about me.
Do you know why I
was primping those
models when we met?
You know why
I was doing that?
No.
I was a part of this
amazing dance group.
We pushed ourselves so hard
that I blew out my knee.
Thought I'd never
dance again.
Yeah, really messed me up.
So, now, every time
I come down hard,
I'm just waiting to
hear that pop again.
Okay. Look, I get it.
But if you push past it
and get outta your head...
(Scoffs)
Oh, my gosh.
I can get over
an old knee injury, okay?
I'm not scared
to dance again.
What I don't want
to risk is this.
I love that I'm
a part of something again.
It's the closest
thing I know to family.
Sure, winning,
it's cool, it's great.
Hanging out with you guys,
though, being here.
Doing what I love.
It's all I care about.
Yeah, well,
it's not enough for me.
Honey, I was
looking for you.
What's wrong?
Sean. He's so frustrating.
He drives me crazy.
Do you know that he was
wearing ladies' underwear
on his head
when I first met him?
That's pretty funny.
You like him.
No, I don't.
He drives me nuts.
Yeah, that means
you like him.
Stop it.
Oh.
What I would like
is a night off. Okay?
Come on, we're in Vegas,
let's do something.
No, Sean will be
mad if we go out.
Whatever.
Let's get the crew.
Hmm?
Yeah? We go out?
Yeah.
Yeah, let's do it.
Okay. Let's go.
(Indistinct chatter)
We just gotta
get there, okay?
Vladd, what's up?
I think they're in love.
Kinda like us.
Oh.
Poor robot bastard.
Hey.
We're going out.
I know hanging out with us
isn't enough for you,
but the rest of us wanna
have some fun
while we're here.
(Scoffs)
Wait up.
(Music playing)
All: Whoa!
Ow!
Ha!
You wanna get out of here?
Take a walk?
Yeah.
Sean: Hey. You were right.
This was a great idea.
Come on.
Oh, yeah. (Laughing)
Welcome to the Clark inn.
Well, thank you.
(Both laughing)
What is this place?
Vintage...
Vintage park?
Vintage Vegas park.
Yeah.
So, you nervous about
going up against
the mob tomorrow?
Moose told me you
and eddy go way back.
We grew up together.
We were like brothers.
What about you?
What happened
between you and your ex?
Oh. Well, moose
must have told
you about chase.
Mmm-hmm.
Uh-huh.
I don't know.
Long distance
thing was kinda hard.
We were on tour,
so we were always
on different schedules,
different cities.
You know, it just
never seemed to work.
But that was
a really long time ago.
Dancing was the only
important thing to him.
He's an idiot.
(Music playing)
Oh, my God.
You kidding me?
(Laughing)
Thank you.
Old school Bobby brown.
Yeah.
(Both laughing)
(Indistinct chatter)
How come pot stickers taste
so much better in Vegas?
Because they're eggrolls.
Right? Go with this guy.
Give me one.
Try it.
Violet: You like it?
I liked it.
Monster: Ew!
Monster: Don't want your
stinky, goopy mess.
Gauge: Come on, bro.
Let it go, man.
No. No.
Monster: This guy's the worst.
Ugh!
Tries so hard, man.
Just so hard.
Yo. Mooski,
this is your song.
Yeah.
Come on,
moose, you gotta dance.
Nah.
Come on, moose.
Come on.
Do it! Do it!
Give us a little sump'n.
Go, go, go.
Let's go, man.
(All cheering)
What?
All: Whoa!
(Laughing)
Oh, no.
Andie: Moose, I heard.
You okay?
What happened to Camille?
I don't know,
I can't find her.
I've called her
a million times.
I'm sure she's somewhere, man.
People don't just
disappear in Vegas.
Actually, it happens
all the time.
I watched on TV. 20/20.
Scary.
Kido.
Oh. My bad.
Sorry, mooski. Sorry.
She's probably
halfway to LA by now.
Come on, man.
There's no way she
went all the way back.
I had no idea that
girl was gonna kiss me.
Those moves?
I guess you were
just too irresistible.
Look, guys, I'm sorry.
All right.
I shouldn't be here.
It was all innocent fun.
I guess she didn't
know that, but...
I just...
I need to go home.
I mean, I love you guys.
This has all been great
and fun and all, but...
I mean, I love Camille.
Wait. Can't this wait?
We need you here.
We battle the mob tomorrow.
You can't just
abandon us now.
Yes, you can.
Are you kidding me?
No, I'm not kidding.
Get outta here.
Go do what you gotta do.
Sorry to let you guys down.
It's all good, bro.
(Sighing)
Alexxa: (Through speaker)
And the winner is...
The grim knights.
(Cheering)
Yo. Divine intention
just got destroyed
by the grim knights.
Monster: How we gonna
do this without moose?
Hey, guys, come on.
Just stay focused, okay?
We'll be just
fine without moose.
Alexxa: Stay tuned.
Up after the break,
the mob and lmntrix
battle for their lives.
Keep on watching.
And do not forget to text.
Every vote counts.
Are you ready for more?
I know I am.
You ready to do this?
Yeah.
Alexxa: Do we have any fans
of the mob out there?
(Audience cheering)
What about lmntrix?
This is crazy, man.
I never thought
that me and you
would end up
against each other.
Are you seriously
ignoring me right now?
Because I swear to God, man...
Jason: Don't even
worry about it.
It's not even worth it.
Alexxa: Are we ready?
Lmntrix versus the mob.
(Cheering)
Man: In this corner,
hailing from Miami...
The mob!
And in this corner, hailing
from Los Angeles,
California...
Lmntrix!
Round 1. Dance.
(Bell dinging)
Round 2.
Dance.
(Cheering)
(Bell dinging)
Round 3.
Dance.
Come on. Do it.
No.
No. Stop it.
(Cheering)
Your votes have been tallied,
and the results are in.
May I present to you
the winners of this battle
and the surprise sleeper
crew of this competition.
Lmntrix.
(Cheering)
Enjoy that win, man.
Alexxa: In this fight to win
a three-year contract
here at Caesars Palace,
only one battle remains.
A clash between lmntrix,
who barely made
the qualifying rounds,
but somehow eked
their way into the finals,
and the team to beat,
the grim knights.
(All cheering)
See you tomorrow.
There will be blood
on the dance floor.
Hey. Hey. Hey!
What happened out there?
Are you serious?
You tried to pull me
into a dangerous trick
that I wasn't ready for.
We were not ready for it.
But we won. We made
it to the final round.
That's all that matters?
Ah. I should've
known better.
Alexxa brava.
You guys.
Cheers.
Man: (On TV) Next up on vh1,
celebrating the vortex
with an alexxa
brava video marathon.
Sweat sugar dance voodoo!
¶ You want my sweat
sugar dancing voodoo
¶ you want the magic that I do
¶ sweat sugar dancing voodoo
¶ you want my sweat
sugar dancing voodoo ¶
Martin: That's the guy.
Marcos: That's
the grim knights guy.
Hair: What guy?
Martin: That ass clown Jasper.
I knew I'd seen
that damn face before.
I knew it.
Oh, my God, is he
wearing a sparkle thong?
Monster: He looks
like a dead baby.
Violet: Wait till Sean
hears about this.
Oh. Where's Sean and Andie?
I don't know,
but she was super pissed
after the battle.
Hair: I don't know.
Her knee's been
bothering her.
Wait, ice. We need ice.
We gotta keep
these babies chilled.
Where's the bucket?
I think monster use
it to soak his foot.
Ew!
Come on, man.
That's nasty.
Blisters.
You're nasty, bro.
Dancers, blisters.
I do a lotta footwork.
Hey, Andie.
Hey. There she is.
There she is.
Damn, gangster.
I think I go
get ice, too.
All right. Okay, fill it up.
I'll fill that back up.
What was up with Andie?
Something happened to her.
I don't know.
She's really upset.
Alexxa: You're being
so paranoid.
Jasper: You said it
was gonna be the mob.
Relax. It was a last-minute
creative decision.
Lmntrix really
brought it last night,
so we changed up
the plan a little.
(Chuckling)
Hmm.
You guys duking it out
is gonna make for a much
more compelling storyline.
Jasper: Yo, just don't
make a fool outta me.
Don't worry, baby,
it's in the bag.
This is gonna be
some killer TV.
What?
Alexxa: You don't trust me?
Shh.
Jasper: You know I do.
Oh. You do?
Yeah.
Then shut that
pouty little mouth of yours.
Holy balls.
We just saw Jasper
and alexxa mackin' on each
other in the hallway.
What? You sure?
Who else dress like a zebra?
We heard them talking,
and this whole  vortex
thing is scripted.
It's been planned.
She said it was
gonna be killer TV
when we all went down.
So they had it
rigged from the beginning?
We never had a chance?
The grim knights
were always gonna win.
No, but America vote for us.
Maybe they just thought
they were voting for us.
I don't believe this.
Connect the dots, sister.
Jasper was her
backup dancer.
Now he's her private dancer.
Jasper was her
backup dancer?
Yeah. We just saw him on TV
shaking his nasty ass
in alexxa brava's video.
We gotta tell someone.
Who we gonna tell?
The producers?
They're in on it, too.
Of course it's rigged.
It's reality TV.
Nothing's real.
I can't go back to
the sucky phone job.
What about us?
We spin those
stupid sign for living.
Man, this sucks.
For a second,
I thought we had a shot.
Hard to go back to
our old lives now, huh?
Okay, hang on.
We're still going
out there, okay?
We've worked so hard.
This is gonna
be an opportunity
for us to just go
out there and...
What's the point? Huh?
We're not gonna
win this thing.
And I'm not going out there
and humiliating myself
in front of the whole world.
The point is that
we're an awesome crew
and amazing dancers.
So, we're gonna go out
there and still show
them what we've got.
This isn't about
winning some contest
or some silly little prize.
This was about
booking a job.
Everyone in this
room is sick of
scraping around
to pay their rent.
I live in a freakin'
little storage closet.
This was about
all our hard work
finally paying off,
so we can have
some actual stability.
(Sighing)
It was far more
than that for me.
Moose: Camille?
You home?
(Sirens blaring in distance)
I knew I'd find you up here.
Look, I know that
you're probably, like,
super uber galactically
pissed at me right now,
but I'm really sorry.
And I don't know
how I let that happen.
Seeing you and that girl,
I wasn't just
jealous of her,
but also of you.
You were just
having the best time,
and I didn't belong.
I couldn't get out
of there fast enough.
It felt gross.
I just wanted to come home.
But home doesn't feel
like home without you.
Does this feel
like home to you?
(Chuckling)
Are you kidding me?
I love my life with you,
and I wouldn't trade it for
anything else in the world.
But being in the spotlight,
that's a big part
of who you are,
and I feel like
I'm holding you back.
I found the person
I wanna dance with,
all right?
Yeah, we have jobs
and, yeah, we have
a nice apartment,
but, I mean,
we're more than that.
Can't we have it both ways?
Yeah.
That's what you want?
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
(Indistinct conversations)
Ana: Sean!
Sean. Come.
Eat and drink
with us. Yes?
This is so good.
I'm going to eat
the whole thing, I don't care.
No worries.
So good.
She love it here, Sean.
We're moving here.
Mmm.
Oh. You have
to try this. So good.
So, you guys didn't
take off with moose.
Mooski, he knows
what's important.
He doesn't need us.
And we would
never miss finale.
What time tomorrow
you dance, huh?
We're not.
Whole contest is rigged.
This whole thing was
just a waste of time.
The mob hates me.
Andie hates me.
Viva Las Vegas, everybody.
So you give up?
Yeah.
Better to quit now.
That's okay. We go back,
you clean toilets.
I think the one in
the back is clogged, no?
Take it easy on him.
Can't you see his
heart is broken?
You remember how we feel,
European championship?
Boris: (Scoffs) That one.
Sean...
European championship
dance final.
I step on her foot.
I break her foot.
Boom. We lose.
I feel terrible,
but she forgive me.
I'm not perfect.
Ana: Who is perfect?
Where is perfect?
(Boris speaking
other language)
Sheep poop, remember?
Sean,
sometime you just have
to shovel through it.
That's all.
Ana: Yes, you have problems.
You think winning is
all there is to life?
Is this the only
reason you work so hard
and give up so
much to be here?
(Speaking other language)
You know what
you need to do.
You do it.
Wait, wait, wait.
I'm sorry.
I thought I could
fix everything.
I thought I could figure
everything out, but...
Okay, stop, stop,
stop, dude.
You look absolutely
ridiculous when you cry.
Sorry. I just really
need a friend right now.
Look, man,
you're my best friend.
You're family.
Families fight. It's cool.
You've been there
for me when I was
at my worst and,
from the looks of it,
you could probably
use someone in your corner.
But first you gotta
come and apologize to
the rest of the family
'cause they still
hate your guts.
Come on. Get in here.
Don't you dare
tell 'em I cried.
You look crazy when you cry.
I know. I didn't cry,
all right?
Hey.
Hold up.
Yo, please. I've got
a plan, okay?
We can't go down
like this, guys.
Look...
Where's Andie?
She took off already.
You said we were
all going home,
and she didn't wanna
ride in the van with
everybody.
Yeah.
Listen, drop your
bags, please,
and meet me in the basement
in 10 minutes, okay?
(All mumbling)
Andie: (Recording)
Hey. It's Andie. Leave a
message after the beep.
(Phone beeping)
Hey. It's me.
Me and the crew have a plan
and we really need you.
So, if you get
this message in time,
we'll be in the basement.
(Hushed talking)
Thanks for coming, guys.
This all started
out so simple.
I love dancing.
But everyone here knows
that it's not that easy
when you're trying to
make a living out of it.
Every day is a battle,
and we work so hard just
to be unappreciated
by some pop artist
or win some
little competition
that everyone's
gonna forget about
in a couple months.
The thing is,
I wanted to win so bad that
I didn't realize
what I was losing.
Our lifestyle
isn't that easy.
But it's the one
we chose.
So I say we choose to
make the best of it.
Tonight.
Not for the show,
for the people watching,
but for us.
This is what matters.
And I see that now.
Nice.
I thought you were gone.
Well, I'm back.
Lmntrix is dancing,
so am I.
I'm not letting
my crew down.
Thanks for coming in.
I'm not doing this for you.
So, you guys
wanna do this?
Somebody got the music?
What, you thought
I'd let you guys down?
Moose!
And we're back!
We started this thing, right?
Let's finish it.
Yo. Hold up.
You're not going
anywhere without us.
Yo.
Thanks for coming, man.
Gauge: Really?
Everybody, this is my family.
New family,
meet the old family.
Y'all get along, okay?
Yo.
Okay. Let's try.
What's up, man?
Nice to meet you.
All right, so, guys,
what's the plan?
They rigged this thing?
We'll give 'em a taste
of their own medicine.
We bring the fuckin'
house down.
(Cheering)
(Audience cheering)
Good evening,
children of the vortex.
(Cheering)
We are at
Caesars Palace tonight,
and we are ready
to settle the score.
One team will leave here
the champions of the vortex,
with a three-year
Vegas contract.
And one team will just
leave.
(All laughing)
Remember to text your votes.
And be merciless.
And now,
the moment we've
all been waiting for.
The grim knights
versus lmntrix.
(All cheering)
(Music playing)
Whoo!
Come on.
(All grunting)
Come on. Come on.
Let's go.
You want some of me?
You want some? Let's go!
(All cheering)
Y'all know what it is!
Let's go! Grim knights!
Weren't the grim
knights amazing?
(Cheering)
So hot.
They're gonna be
very hard to beat.
Next up, lmntrix.
(All cheering)
Sean: Thank you. Thank you.
I just wanna say how
much we've enjoyed
being a part of this contest.
And, uh, it's been
a life-changing ride.
And to be going up
against the grim knights.
What an honor.
And what
a compelling storyline.
It's gonna make
for some killer TV.
You know, I came here to
win, but I'm okay if that
doesn't happen.
Tomorrow, we might be
back to our day jobs.
But tonight, we're
living the dream together!
Because I'm up
here on this stage
with the best dancers...
No.
The best of friends.
And a phenomenal woman
who's taught me
what really matters.
So what do you say
we all just forget
about this winning or losing,
and just enjoy the show?
(All applauding)
(Music playing)
(All cheering)
Yeah!
Is that fire?
No, no, no.
What the hell's goin' on?
Yo, I don't know.
This is some horseshit.
The mob can't dance.
This is cheating.
I know.
Ah-ha!
Yo, this is crazy.
I know!
(All cheering)
Hey.
Let's do it.
Let's do the move.
Yeah?
You better catch me.
Trust me.
(All cheering)
Oh!
(Audience cheering)
What?
But I haven't even
tallied the votes yet.
Did you see the stuff
on the chandeliers?
I understand.
Yes.
This crew will make
a fabulous show at
the hotel.
Mmm-hmm.
They got the show?
Yes, they got the show.
Go pack my bags.
I need a week in Cancun.
Dancer: What just happened?
Lmntrix just won?
Sean: Like I said, the life
of a dancer is not easy.
But sometimes
everything lines up.
The world is in sync,
and for one perfect moment
you feel totally alive.
(Both laughing)
(Laughing)
B mark!
Man: One, and two, and...
(Splashing)
One, and two, and three,
and four, and five.
(Glass breaking)
You have a tag here.
Oops.
(Grunting)
(All laughing)
There it is!
A mark!
Pot sticker?
(Laughing)
Just shut that
pouty little mouth.
Yeah.
Pot sticker?
Spring roll!
Man: Egg roll!
One more time.
Here we go.
Egg roll, right?
I'm going to shove
my mane in your mouth.
Bite it! Bite it!
Bite it!
Man: One more time.
Ready, and...
Put me down.
You gotta trust me.
I'm sorry,
that was a bit weird
at the end for me.
(Laughing)
You gotta...
Bye, guys.
(All laughing)
(Laughing)
How long do you
want me to hold this?