NARRATOR:
The Earth is at peace.
There is no hunger.
There is no violence.
The environment is healed.
Honesty, courtesy and kindnes
are practiced by all.
Our world has never been more
perfect.
Only it is
no longer our world.
We've been invaded
by an alien race.
They occupy the bodies
of almost all human
beings on the planet.
The few humans
who have survived
are on the run.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PANTING)
Please.
Come with us.
We only want to help you.
Please be careful.
Please don't hurt yourself.
We don't want to hurt you.
Like hell!
No!
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Barely a bone not broken
or organ ruptured.
I cannot tell you
why she is not dead.
This one wants to live.
Welcome.
I am Healer Fords.
What shall I call you?
You have lived many lives
on many worlds.
A wanderer such as yourself,
there must have
been a name.
Call
me
Wanderer.
When will she
be able to work?
Not now.
Of course, Healer.
(GASPS)
MELANIE:  No.
No.
I didn't die.
That's right.
I'm still here.
Don't think this is yours.
This body is mine.
No, mine.
SEEKER:  I don't know
how much you know
about this new world.
Almost every human
has been
successfully occupied.
As with
the other planets
you've inhabited,
we do not
change this world.
But experience it.
And perfect it.
What did you think?
Did you think
I'd just give up?
However,
there are still pockets
of human resistance
that threaten our peace.
Your host was part
of that resistance.
You want me to
locate her memories.
Yes. From those memories,
we can locate other rebels.
MELANIE:  Good luck with that.
But I must warn you.
Most humans fade away,
but a rare few
fight their occupation.
Her name is
Melanie Stryder.
She was born in Louisiana.
Her family escaped
the initial waves
of colonization.
But it was only
a matter of time.
Her father was
discovered alone.
(GUN FIRED)
He took his life
rather than be taken
by our Seekers
and risk the lives
of his children.
Melanie has been on the run
ever since with...
MELANIE:  No! Don't say it!
Don't you say it!
Please.
I beg you.
Is she resisting?
Jamie.
His name is
Jamie Stryder.
MELANIE:  I hate you.
If only I could hurt you.
I understand why
you are resistant.
You believe that
the loss of your will
is too great
a sacrifice.
But we have to think
of the common good.
MELANIE:  Call it
whatever you want.
This is murder.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
One sound and you die.
Do it. I'd rather die.
That's impossible.
You're human.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
JARED:  Come back!
Stop!
Wait!
Look! Look!
Look at me!
(PANTING)
I'm human.
Just like you.
Get off me.
I'm sorry.
My name is Jared Howe.
I didn't mean to scare you.
I haven't spoken to another
human being in two years.
I'm guessing you
haven't been kissed
in a while either.
(CHUCKLES)
Melanie Stryder.
I've got someone
waiting for me.
You're not alone?
It's my kid brother.
He's hungry.
I ran two hours to
get to this house.
I can give you a ride.
Hey, it's faster
than running.
(CHUCKLES) It's even faster
than your running.
(ENGINE STARTING)
MELANIE:  Are you gonna
pretend like you didn't
feel something just now?
I know you felt that.
Stop that!
Stop!
(PENCIL CLATTERS)
MELANIE:
What you're doing is wrong.
And you know it.
After meeting Jared Howe,
Melanie and her brother
stayed with him.
They settled in
an abandoned place
yet to be explored
by our souls.
Left, right. (GROANS)
They could almost
forget the invasion
happening around them.
You haven't kissed me
since that first night.
Melanie,
you don't have to.
We could be
the last ones.
And even if we are,
the last man and woman
left on Earth,
you still
don't have to.
I want to.
When you touch me,
it's...
I don't want you to stop.
You should sleep.
Then sleep with me.
All I'm saying is
we have time.
You don't know that.
You don't know
if we've got
months or days.
We could be
taken at any moment.
We only have this, now.
SEEKER: Wanderer? Wanderer?
Wanderer!
Yes, Seeker.
You have not spoken
for several minutes.
They were lovers?
These humans are not
like the other bodies
you have inhabited.
They have unusually
strong physical drives.
You have to be vigilant.
Yes.
They saw Seekers nearby.
They were not found,
but knew they had to move .
They were headed...
I can't see where.
A safe place with others.
Hope...
Before the long journey,
they spent
the night in an old hotel
they thought was safe.
Jared was out
searching for supplies
for the trip.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Stay here. Don't move.
I want to go with you.
I'll lead them away
and come right back.
I promise. Come on.
(PANTING)
No!
(GLASS SHATTERING)
MELANIE:  Now you know.
I will do anything.
Go on.
There's nothing more now.
There has to be more.
I will keep trying.
(SIGHS)
Please do, Wanderer.
(DOOR CLOSES)
MELANIE:
No! No, no! Wait! Stop!
You were not
meant to see that.
You can't know that!
That could kill them!
Get rid of it.
Get rid of it!
Now! Please!
You were not
meant to see tha.
Quiet.
MELANIE:  Wanderer, please.
(TEARING PAPER)
MELANIE:
After everything you've se,
how can you still help them?
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
MELANIE:  Surprise, surprise.
Look who's here.
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
What a pleasant
surprise, Seeker.
Did you follow me?
Only in case
you needed me.
MELANIE:  Yeah. Right.
She is so full of it.
What are you
doing here?
I thought a change
of scenery might help.
Change.
Wasn't your last planet
completely covered by water?
It's been a week
since you've had
new information.
Do you know
where they are?
MELANIE:  If you can't
say no, say nothing.
Walk away.
Do you pity them?
The humans?
Don't you?
In your other lives,
have you ever felt
anything like this?
They were brutal.
Killing each other.
Killing their planet.
They're lucky they survived
as long as they did.
I do have some good news.
Your identification
of Jared Howe has helped.
There was a sighting.
I am confident
we will find him.
No!
MELANIE:  No!
Ah!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Seeker, I am so sorry.
I don't know
what I was doing.
Perhaps because
you weren't doing it.
SEEKER REED: We have
put you through enough.
Your host appears
too resistant.
You are going to
be re-implanted into
a more compliant host.
MELANIE:  Is he saying
what I think he's saying?
What will happen
to this body?
It is time for someone else
to search her memories.
MELANIE:  Her?
You?
Yes.
My body can be
held for me.
I will return to it
when we have
the information we need.
Then what will happen
to Melanie Stryder?
She will have the death
she originally desired.
Unlike the way humans kill,
it will be done humanely.
MELANIE:
Stop her! Do something!
My Healer
has agreed to this?
No.
He transferred
to Fort Worth.
Don't feel bad.
You are not the only one.
There are others
who have not had
the strength of will.
When?
We make
the transfer tomorrow.
We will stay outside
your door tonight
so no harm
will come to you.
Or to others.
MELANIE:  Please.
I don't care if I die.
I can't have her inside me.
Melanie,
I have to do my duty.
You have to do what's righ.
She'll kill my family.
Jamie, Jared,
she'll kill them.
Wanderer, please.
Your Healer.
Do you think he would help?
I think so.
But I don't know
how to reach him.
We need to find him.
We have to get out of here.
We?
Put the chair
against the door.
No. The other way.
How does this help?
There's no way out.
Yes, there is. That way.
Do it, Wanderer. Move.
Open it.
Come on.
You can do this.
It's not so high.
This is nothing.
It's gonna be okay.
Climb up.
Now jump.
I can't.
It's a good thing I can.
(SCREAMS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Swim!
SEEKER REED: Wanderer?
Are you all right?
You could have killed us.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Run!
Step aside.
Wanderer?
(GRUNTS)
I'm sorry.
We need to steal a car.
Don't worry.
I've done it before.
Let me handle this.
You?
What are you doing? Wait!
Shh! Quiet!
Do you need help?
May I borrow
your vehicle?
Please. It is important.
Certainly.
Can I be of assistance?
No. Thank you.
This is
an extremely
reliable model.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
The tank is full.
MELANIE:  Huh!
It was no trick.
We do not lie.
We trust each other.
You guys take
the fun out of everythin.
Where are we going?
I will take you
to my Healer
in Fort Worth.
Even if your Healer agres
to keep me inside you,
I'll still be a prisoner.
You will still be alive.
That Seeker is
a lot of things,
but she's not a fool.
Sooner or later,
she'll work out
where you're going.
We need a map.
I'll show you the way.
(JIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHS)
(SCREAMS)
What's wrong?
Are the memories
too painful?
How do you think I feel?
I know how you feel.
That's the problem.
When you take the body,
the feelings come with i.
It's a package deal.
You tell me.
You're the one with
the steering wheel.
You sent us
in the wrong direction.
You have been putting
thoughts in my head
to distract me.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
The Seeker was right.
You are an unreasonable
species.
I try to help you
and this is how
you thank me.
We are going
to Fort Worth.
No!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(COUGHS)
Will it still work?
Not anymore.
Now what do we do?
We walk.
Which way?
You can go my way,
or you can go
your own way
and kill us both.
I made a promise.
I promised my brother
I'd come back.
How could I have
been so foolish?
How do I know
I can trust you?
I'm giving you
exactly what you wanted.
Taking you to my family
could get them killed.
We head east.
Come on.
Don't leave tracks.
Walk on the rocks.
Did you really think
you could beat me?
(PANTING)
Save the water.
We're gonna need it.
I need it now.
We've been
walking for ages.
How do you think
you're going to find them?
My uncle had a cabin
out here in the desert.
We were heading
out here to join him.
If he survived.
It's farther than I thought.
I don't know how much
farther I can go.
We've walked too far
to walk back.
(CAR ENGINE HUMMING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
JEB: Melanie.
(GASPS)
Come on, girl.
Stay with me.
Uncle Jeb.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You found us.
Us?
Jamie? Jared?
Are they here?
Are they safe?
MAN: I told you I saw one.
Why did you
give it water?
On account of
it was dying.
MELANIE:  Uncle Jeb!
I'm in here!
Hold it, Kyle.
Why?
She's one of them.
Well, yeah,
she surely is,
but she's also my niece.
Was.
I'm just saying
it's complicated, Ian.
I can make it simple.
Yeah, me, too.
MELANIE:  Aunt Maggie!
Aunt Maggie!
You don't fool us,
parasite!
MELANIE:  Oh, God.
They don't see me.
They only see you.
Now, Maggie.
Don't you "Maggie" me,
little brother.
It could bring
a whole army
down on our heads.
I don't see anyone.
I'm in here.
This is unkind, Jebediah.
Let's go.
Life is unkind, Magnolia.
JEB: Watch your head.
MELANIE:
Where are we, Wanderer?
I reckon
it's safe enough now.
So many humans alive.
We haven't lost.
Jared!
Jared's alive! Jared's...
(GRUNTS)
Enough, Jared.
MAGGIE: Jebediah,
I know it's hard.
But we gotta do
what's best for everyone.
She's gotta
go to Doc's place.
Just like the rest.
Ain't that right, Doc?
No!
Jamie!
I don't see any tracks.
She didn't fly away.
This Wanderer is
living up to her name.
We find her,
we find the resistance.
Melanie?
Wanderer?
They don't know a human can
stay alive in a body.
You can't tell them
I'm in here.
They won't believe you.
They'll think you're
lying to save yourself.
Oh, God.
They're gonna kill us.
I'm sorry.
Move aside, Jared.
Get out of the way.
IAN: We can't keep her
prisoner forever.
It's gonna escape
and lead them to us.
I don't want to
hurt you, Jared.
But I will.
No!
I am what you want!
Stay back!
(GRUNTS)
Ian! Get it!
Leave him alone!
MELANIE:  Keep breathing!
Come on, Wanderer!
Fight him! Fight!
Finish it!
(CHOKING)
JEB: Good evening, everyone.
I hate to remind you,
but this is my place,
and you are my guests.
For the moment,
she is, too.
I don't take
kindly to my guests
strangling each other.
Jeb, it's got to die.
We took a vote.
This ain't a democracy.
It's a dictatorship.
It's a benign dictatorship,
but it's a dictatorship
just the same.
You mind telling us
what you plan on
doing with it?
This ain't never
happened before.
One of our own
coming back.
For right now,
this tunnel is off limits.
If I find any
of you back here,
I'm asking questions second.
I'll take
the next watch, Jared.
Keep it away
from the kid.
SEEKER REED: I do not think
we are looking for Wanderer.
I think we are
looking for a body.
SEEKER PAVO: Even if she were
not hurt in the wreck,
how long could she
survive in this place?
From my experience,
this host has
difficulty dying.
There's too much
land for us to cover.
I am requesting
more Seekers,
ground and air patrols.
Are they really
such a threat?
We outnumber them
a million to one.
He's still pissed
you hit him.
I told him you were sorry.
I'm not.
I know.
No one's ever sorry
for hitting my brother.
It looks like they're
calling off the search.
Not that one.
MELANIE:  Jamie!
Little brother.
Do you know who I am?
You are Jamie.
But you're not Melanie.
I want to know
what happened to
my sister that night.
She said that she
was gonna come back.
he deserves to know
what happened to me.
I'm not a kid.
Please.
To protect you and Jared,
she tried to take her life.
Our healers mended her
and put me in her
hoping I could
find out if there were
other human survivors.
JAMIE: Do you have a name?
They call me Wanderer.
Where do you come from?
Another planet.
What the hell?
Damn it, Jeb, I told you.
You never said nothing about
keeping the kid away from her.
Jamie, that is not Melanie!
She's never coming back.
It's still her body
that we've hurt.
Get out of here now, Jamie,
or so help me, I'll...
Jared.
I'll look after Jamie.
IAN: We'll watch it.
JARED: I don't trust it.
Could be another Seeker.
She...
It
is the furthest
thing from a Seeker
I've ever seen.
I mean, she jumped
between you and Kyle.
They don't do that.
It was trying to find a way
to stay alive and escape.
What, by giving
Kyle the go-ahead
to kill her? It?
That's a good plan.
What the hell has
gotten into everybody?
It is the enemy.
Don't forget it.
You don't feel bad at all.
I mean, I half killed her.
It doesn't matter.
It's not human.
So we stop acting human?
This is a big planet.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
There has been a sighting f
humans in your area.
We are commencing
a full-scale search
immediately.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
JEB: Something, ain't it?
Found this place
by accident.
Really, it found me.
I fell through the roof.
Almost died
trying to find a way
out of these caves.
There's only one.
No one's found it on
their own since I did.
Kept the place to myself.
Good thing, too.
Without this,
we're all dead. Right?
Wanderer?
Sound travels in these caves.
Your name is a mouthful.
You mind if I shorten it?
Life's short.
Especially right now.
Mind if I call you...
Wanda?
We get our power
from the sun, Earth.
Any place we can.
It's actually
an extinct volcano
not quite extinct.
Watch yourself.
Fall in,
you're not coming back.
Afternoon, everyone.
It's all yours.
JEB: Don't you all
look pretty?
You all got
your shades?
BRANDT: Yeah, yeah.
JARED: Make sure
you wear them.
BRANDT: You already
look like an alien.
Makes you feel like
a human being again,
don't it?
Bad joke?
You have the resources
you wanted, Seeker.
I know you must
have seen a lot,
but you ain't seen
nothing like this.
WANDERER: Nothing.
Same way the magicians do it.
Mirrors.
MELANIE:  And they all said
Jeb was crazy.
How many crazy people
could pull this off?
It's almost
ready to harvest.
Can't come too soon.
We sure need the grain.
Everyone here thinks
you're going to betray
us to the Seekers.
Makes sense.
Why else
would you be here?
What I can't wrap
my head around is
what kind of a plan was that?
Walking into the desert
with no backup
and no way
to get yourself back?
So if,
like you say, you weren't
coming here for the Seekers,
why were you doing it?
Then I started thinking,
when they put one of you
in our heads,
do we still exist?
Trapped in there?
If our memories are
still alive, are we?
You gotta believe
some people wouldn't
go down without a fight.
Hell, I know
I wouldn't go quiet.
And I've never seen
fight like in Mel.
What she'd fight for,
more than anything,
is the people that she loves.
I wonder
if a love like that might
play on someone's mind.
Heart.
It might get
somebody to do something
they wouldn't ordinarily do.
Maybe you're here
'cause you do
actually care about
Jared and the kid.
You.
Wanda.
(WHISPERING)
He sees everything.
He's not crazy.
He's a genius.
MELANIE:  I think he's both.
Yeah, I wonder
a lot about
a lot of things.
And I'm not
the only one.
Care to join us, Jamie?
Uncle Jeb.
How did you know
I was here?
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
Mirrors.
Mirrors! Mirrors!
Help him!
I saw something!
Now, come on!
Help!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I saw evidence of humans.
I see evidence of us.
There's nothing here.
Thank you.
They're gone.
They're gone for now.
Jared and the others
are still out there.
Jamie, why don't you
take over guard duty
for a spell?
What do I do?
You just keep an eye on her.
You'll figure it out.
This way.
You can't give
a boy a loaded gun.
That's why I didn't.
MELANIE:
Where is he taking us?
Aren't you
taking me to my cell?
I miss the outdoors.
And I was thinking
that maybe you're
starting to miss it, too.
(WHISPERS) Be real quiet.
Okay. Sit here.
You can open
your eyes now.
What stars are these?
I've never seen
this constellation.
They're not stars.
They're glowworms.
You have to be quiet
or they get scared
and stop shining.
When I miss the sky,
I come here.
It's beautiful.
Wanda?
I heard what
Uncle Jeb was saying.
He thinks that Melanie
might still be alive.
Inside there with you,
I mean.
MELANIE:  Jamie!
Can that happen?
Does it, Wanda?
Why won't you answer me?
Is Melanie still alive?
Wanda, please.
MELANIE:  Forget what I said.
Tell him.
She promised she
would come back.
Yes.
Has Melanie ever
broken a promise to you?
(CHUCKLES)
(SOBS) I love you, Mel.
She loves you, too.
She's so happy you're safe.
Is everybody like that?
Does everybody stay?
No.
Not like Melanie.
She's special.
She's very strong.
She wanted to
keep her promise.
She couldn't have
kept her promise
if you didn't
help her keep it.
Thank you, Wanda.
WANDERER: It's our secret.
Okay?
Good evening, sir.
Can I help you?
(GRUNTS)
I think you can.
Come on, hurry.
You guys all right?
Yeah.
No racing.
Yeah, sure.
It's ready.
I figured it's time
you started earning your keep.
I'll see you both
in the east field.
Morning, Jamie.
Wanda.
JAMIE: Come on.
Wanda?
Yeah.
Wanda.
MELANIE:  Why is he
looking at you?
Why are you looking at him?
Don't forget.
He tried to kill you.
Did you hear me?
Don't you dare smile at him.
(MELANIE EXCLAIMS
IN ANNOYANCE)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(GROANS)
JEB: You better
take care of that.
There. That one drives
faster than the limit.
(BRAKES SCREECH)
SEEKER:  Please
stop your vehicle
and safely exit.
Fire!
AARON: It ain't doing
any good.
I don't care! Keep firing!
(GUN FIRING)
(ENGINE REVS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GUN FIRING)
Don't get caught.
Take him out!
SEEKER:  Please
stop your vehicle
and safely exit.
Switch off your engine
There are others.
JEB: I always liked
science fiction stories.
Never dreamed
I'd be living in one.
How many planets have life?
MELANIE:  Just remember, Wanda,
you're not one of them.
Twelve that we know of.
Four I've never been to.
We've just
opened up a new world.
You've conquered
12 planets?
That's not how we see it.
We have always
lived by bonding
with another species.
It is how we survive.
We try to live in harmony.
(GUN FIRING)
Speed up! Lose it!
No! Let him catch us.
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Let's go!
We've got enough!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
We almost had them.
SEEKER PAVO: Seeker.
This is not who we are.
You have killed a soul.
We have to make sacrifices.
This is a war.
This war is over.
The last of the resistance
will die out on its own.
They will become extinct.
But I think there is a war
raging in you, Seeker.
We're going home.
So are you.
You don't know
what's going on.
We are losing control.
DOC:  Wanda.
If you don't
mind me asking,
how old are you?
Over a thousand
of your years.
I have not completed
one full revolution
of your sun,
yet I have found that
Earth is more beautiful
and harder than
any place I have ever been.
I've gotta say,
this is the most
interesting conversation
I've had in forever.
JARED: What is this?
This has gone on
long enough!
Out of the way!
She's not a threat.
JARED: No?
Aaron and Brandt are dead
thanks to the Seeker
looking for it.
Almost got us, too.
I'm gonna end this
once and for all!
JAMIE: Jared!
You can't!
Why not?
Because if you kill Wanda...
MELANIE:  Oh, no, Jamie!
...you'll kill Melanie.
She's still alive in there.
I believe it.
You're all
letting it fool you!
Come on, Jamie.
I'm so sorry.
I'll go back to my cell.
No.
This'll blow over.
You can stay
in my place.
She'll be safe there.
Mmm.
You tried to kill me
and now you're protecting me?
Strange world, isn't it?
The strangest.
JARED:
What's wrong with you, Doc?
DOC: You want to try? You try.
IAN: Wanda?
I just want you to know
that I trust you.
And I believe you're
telling us the truth.
But I... I gotta ask.
What's it like
for you and her,
living in there together?
It's crowded.
Let me know
if you need anything.
I'll just be
right out here.
(EXHALES)
MELANIE:  I think
he likes you too much.
What is too much?
If I've got
anything to do with it,
you'll never find out.
(GASPS)
I know it's with you.
MELANIE:  Oh, God.
JARED: I'm not gonna kill it.
I just want to talk to it.
It's okay.
I will talk to him.
Her name is Wanda,
not "it."
I'm so sorry about
what happened out there,
to your friends.
I never meant to hurt anyone.
Wanda,
Jamie and Jeb believe,
Ian, too,
that Mel is still
alive and kicking in there.
MELANIE:  I am!
I am!
In fact,
Jeb has this crazy notion that
you're here for Jamie and me.
You brought
Melanie back to us.
I can't believe it.
I don't want to believe it
because her being in there,
trapped,
that makes it
so much worse somehow.
But I gotta know.
Is Melanie in there?
Just tell him I'm here.
Tell him I love him.
(WHISPERS) I'm afraid.
You see,
the thing is, Wanda,
I haven't stopped
dreaming about Melanie.
I dream about you, too.
I miss
everything about her.
And I would do
anything to get her back.
You know what makes
this so much harder?
It's still her body.
If it wasn't
for those eyes...
I got to thinking.
If I can't kiss her,
I can kiss you.
What? No!
What is he doing?
No! Stop it!
Stop! Now!
Don't do this!
No! No!
I knew it.
Mel.
You're really in there.
You hit me
for kissing it.
Mel, I love you.
I know you can't
say it back,
but I love you.
MELANIE:  So now
he believes it, too.
It doesn't help anyone.
Knowing I'm a prisoner in hee
just hurts them more.
KYLE: Wanda!
Hide.
Hide! Hide!
Wanda.
Wanda!
(GASPS)
Wanda, get out of here!
Run!
(GRUNTING)
Grab my hand!
What are you doing? Let go!
Good! If he dies,
he can't kill us!
No!
Help!
You're lucky
your head's harder than
any rock in this place.
You'll live.
Don't be too sure
about that, Doc.
What happened?
Tell him.
It was an accident.
Like hell!
I thought you didn't lie.
Kyle slipped.
Sure he did.
If that's what
it says happened...
Oh, come on.
We all know what happened.
He tried to kill her.
And for some unknown reason,
she saved his sorry ass.
If it's true,
Kyle, you're out.
Did he try to kill you?
It's not saying he did.
You're the one
who has to live
under the same roof.
Kyle, I'm warning you.
Don't you even
look at her wrong.
I haven't shot anyone
in a long time.
Kind of miss the thrill of it.
We gotta get back to work.
Come on, let's go.
JARED: Hey, Jeb.
We're going back out.
JEB: Too many
Seekers out there.
JARED: No.
We lost a lot
on that last run.
There are a couple
of things that I need.
Take Kyle with you.
Come on, Kyle.
And, you,
keep away from her.
You want to take a walk?
Didn't Jared tell you
to stay away from me?
Yeah.
MELANIE:
This is not a good idea.
You can
open your eyes now.
I'm outside!
(CHUCKLES)
That really is the sky.
I like you, Wanda.
I like you, too, Ian.
MELANIE:  You did not say that.
No.
Not like that.
Get his hands off me!
This can't work.
What are you doing?
Let me guess.
You're of two minds
about it.
Is this about Jared?
Yes, it's about Jared.
Melanie is in love with him.
And you?
Tell him. Tell him!
This body loves him.
Since it is now my body,
so do I.
But I also have
feelings of my own.
No, you don't.
Wanda, no.
Stop!
You are not going there.
What about Jared?
This is very complicated.
Is there any way Melanie
can give us some privacy?
Look the other way
a moment?
Step into the other room?
You wish.
I don't think that's
possible right now.
You know,
it's not really me you like.
It's this body.
You couldn't care for me.
If you could hold me,
me,
in your hand,
you'd be disgusted.
You would crush me.
You don't know that.
Wanda! No!
This is so wrong.
You're not even
from the same planet!
I'll do something.
I'll hurt him!
Strange to be in a body
that won't let me use it.
I think you'd
better take me back.
Hallelujah!
As you say,
I'm still of two minds.
Okay.
You're angry when
I kiss a man you do love
and angry when
I kiss a man you don't.
It's very confusing.
(TREMBLING)
I am not weak.
I am in control.
WOMAN:  You will never win.
WANDERER: Jamie.
Where is everyone?
I don't know.
MELANIE:  Why is he lying?
He never lies.
Your leg
should be better by now.
You need to see Doc.
I just came from there.
He told me
to go and lay down.
I'm going to wash up.
I'll meet you in your room.
This doesn't make sense.
What is Doc thinking?
What's more important thn
getting Jamie better?
Hold on.
Wait.
Wanda, go back. Go back!
Wanda, don't go in there!
Turn around. Go back!
Oh, God!
JEB: Enough!
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
No!
(SOBBING)
Monsters!
JEB: Wait! Wanda!
Wanda!
MELANIE:  Wanda! Wanda! Stop!
Get out of my head! Get out!
I'm sorry.
You know, there are
easier ways to die than
starving yourself to death.
Yes.
I could always visit Doc.
What did you expect, Wanda?
You expect us to just give up?
This is our world.
We haven't just lost a war.
We're dying out.
We're trying to
get our people back.
What you're trying
to do is impossible.
It doesn't work like that.
All you are going to do
is keep murdering
more of both of us.
For what it's worth,
I'm sorry.
I can't stay here.
Not with you
slaughtering my family
in the next room.
If you say
our way won't work,
I'll tell the boys
no more hostages.
It's probably for the best.
I don't think Doc
could take much more.
How can I trust you?
I trusted you.
There's something else.
Melanie? Are you there?
Melanie, where are you?
Jamie is hurt.
I need you. Talk to me.
Melanie, please come back.
I can't do this without you.
Wanda.
I want you to know about
Doc and everything.
Don't worry about that now.
We have to get you better.
You sound like Melanie.
Did Melanie
say that just then?
Yes.
IAN: Wanda.
I need you to kiss me.
What about Melanie?
Don't worry about Melanie.
No. Kiss me like
you want to get slapped.
What?
Was she stopping you?
No. That's the problem.
We're alone. She's gone.
Ever since I told
her to get out of
my head, she's...
I'm afraid I've lost her.
She got so angry
before when you kissed me.
I thought she'd come back.
Then I guess you'll have to
make her really angry.
(CLUCKING)
Kiss her.
I lost Melanie.
I don't know
if she's still there.
You need to bring her back.
She hates me kissing you.
Okay.
JARED: Melanie, come back.
I will not lose you.
MELANIE:  Jared.
Melanie?
Oh. Stop!(GRUNTS)
Melanie, you bit me!
Wanda, what the hell?
Melanie,
I'm so glad you're back.
Did I leave?
For three days.
You don't know
what I've been through
to find you.
Yeah, you look like
you were suffering.
We have to help Jamie.
He's hurt.
Come on.
JARED: Stop.
Stop.
Where are you going?
It's infected.
It's got into
Jamie's bloodstream.
He needs medicine.
There's no medicine out there.
You souls have
destroyed it all.
He doesn't need
your medicine.
It's too late for that.
He needs ours.
You have to take
me out of the cave.
You'll have to trust me.
Cut me.
I need a wound
like Jamie's.
I can't do that.
I'll be healed in minutes.
MELANIE:  Take it from him.
Do it yourself.
They'll be
suspicious of this scar.
I can cover it with a cut.
It's gonna be okay.
Excuse me.
Goodness.
We have an emergency.
You can do this, Wanda.
I'm Healer Skye.
What happened?
Tell her you tripped.
Tell her you tripped!
I tripped.
With a knife in your hand.
With a knife in my hand,
cut myself.
You poor thing.
Let's fix you up.
Heal.
Seal.
If it is no trouble,
could I please
have some water?
Of course.
Hurry! Take it!
What do you think?
Perfect.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
What are you doing?
We have to go.
JARED: Is he alive?
Barely.
DOC: What is all that?
Medicine.
Wait! No. No.
We don't know
what that'll do.
She knows what she's doing.
We all know
what will happen
if we do nothing.
He'll die.
JARED: Doc.
It's okay.
WANDERER: Please.
Do it.
Doc, do it.
That's it.
MELANIE:  Come on, Jamie.
Open your eyes.
Please.
Jamie.
Hey, buddy.
You're getting good, Doc.
(ALL LAUGHING)
I've walked out of
plenty of stores
without paying.
First time anyone's
been happy about it.
I liked it better
when we were stealing.
You spoil everything,
Wanda.
WANDERER: No, Wes!
Hello, Wanderer.
Seeker.
Why did you waste
the medicine on me?
Aren't you
going to kill me?
Can I speak
to her alone?
MELANIE:  Does that include me?
I guess it does.
We'll be outside,
Wanda.
You just say the word.
SEEKER: Huh!
Wanda?
Surely,
you go by "Melanie" now.
Did you ask to kill me
yourself, Melanie?
What are you
waiting for?
I'm not here
to kill you.
Oh.
You're my interrogator.
I do want to
know something.
Why?
Why couldn't you
just let me go?
Because I was right.
I know the threat
a weak soul like
you represents.
Unlike you,
I am doing my duty.
I am fighting for us.
We cannot live with them
like the other worlds.
You, more than anyone,
know that.
Did you come alone?
Other Seekers will
come looking for me,
just like I came
looking for you.
No one else is
coming to find you.
You die,
and the danger
dies with you.
The people here
will be safe.
So you are
going to kill me.
Wanda, what is this?
What are you thinking?
Don't put up
walls against me.
Talk to me.
Wanda?
I never got the chance
to say how truly...
There's a way
to make up for it.
what you have been
ending so many lives
trying to do.
I can take a soul
from a body.
MELANIE:  You can do what?
What are you saying, Wanda?
I will only
give you this knowledge
on the condition
you do as I ask
and promise that no harm
will come to any soul.
I can promise you that.
There's one other thing
you must promise.
And you must promise
to keep it a secret.
You have to let me die.
No! No! No!
I can't do that, Wanda.
I... I can't.
It's the only way
I can give you
what you want.
Wanda.
No.
She's out.
JEB: So you don't want us
to kill the Seeker.
She killed Wes.
Who knows how many others?
She wouldn't blink
about butchering us.
There's been
too much killing.
Not death. Exile.
You want us to forgive her.
And let them go,
just like that?
Yes.
We souls can leave
the same way we arrived.
I will send her away.
By the time
she reaches
another planet,
your grandchildren
will have died of old age.
You have always tried
to extract it by force.
The secret is,
you do not remove it,
it removes itself.
You coax it out.
You have always
seen it as the enemy.
It can feel the hate.
It can only be
captured by kindness.
Love.
Ian, help me.
Thank you.
What is your name?
I'm Lacey. (LAUGHS)
My name is Lacey.
I've been
screaming inside for years.
Nobody could hear me.
You're the reason
why she wouldn't
leave me alone.
Yes, she wasn't
just after humans.
She was hoping to find
a way to fight the hosts.
Like me.
And you, Melanie.
Who fight back.
Have a safe trip.
MELANIE:  And a long one.
WANDERER:
Always send the souls to
the most distant planets.
Wanda?
Do you miss it out there?
The other worlds?
I miss many things.
Don't you miss Melanie?
Don't you want
your sister back?
She's here now.
MELANIE:  You know he's right.
Not the way
she needs to be.
I think it's time
to move on.
Leave us?
Yes.
But you can always
come back, right?
I asked you here
so no one would shout.
I wish I could
shout loud enough
for them to hear.
As soon as I knew
what to do with the Seeker,
I knew there was
a way for all of you
to get your loved ones back.
Without hurting the souls.
But, of course,
I knew I had to give
Melanie back to herself.
And leave.
That can't happen, Wanda.
We need you.
MELANIE:  Tell them the truth.
You're not leaving this worl.
Tell them what
you're really gonna do.
Now that you
have this knowledge
of how to extract
a soul from a body,
you can survive without me.
And what does Mel say?
She's always
wanted her life back.
Don't speak for me.
You're lying.
I have to go.
You don't have to
decide right now.
Think about it.
Promise me
you'll think about it.
You are not leaving me.
I can't stay.
But I love you.
I love you.
Don't say it like
you're saying goodbye.
I love you in
every way that I can.
And I'll miss
you the most.
I miss the future
I might have had with you.
You're willing
to sacrifice that?
Sometimes we have
to make sacrifices.
No, I can't let you go.
I won't.
Let me talk to Melanie.
She's not there right now.
She stepped
into the other room,
so I can kiss you.
I really can't
talk you out of it?
No. It's time.
I want to die.
If you had lived
a millennium
always in the body of another,
you might feel
the same way yourself.
MELANIE:  Wanda, my sister.
Yes, sister?
Please don't do this.
Don't you want to be
with Jared? And Jamie?
It doesn't have
to be this way.
You don't have to die.
You really could
go to another world,
the way you've been
telling everyone.
Thank you,
but by the time I got
to the closest planet,
you, Jamie, Jared, Ian,
everyone on this
world I care about
would be long dead.
I don't want to
go on without you.
I love you, Mel.
I love you.
You are the purest soul,
human or not,
that I've ever met.
The universe will
be a darker place
without you.
Be happy, Mel.
Be happy
that after living
so many lives,
I finally found
something to die for.
Goodbye.
IAN: Wanda?
Wanda.
Wanda?
Wanda, can you hear me?
WANDERER: Where am I?
Who am I?
You're you.
Hello, Wanda.
WANDERER: Melanie?
You might want
to see yourself.
IAN: You still do that
with your hair.
Doc, you broke your word.
They broke it for me.
They made me keep you alive.
But I told you
I didn't want to
take another life
in any world.
JEB: We've been taking
souls out of humans
for a month now.
But when we took
the soul out of that body,
she never woke up.
The body was dying.
The only way
to save her was to
put you inside.
You haven't killed a body.
You've given it life.
I miss you in my head.
What are you thinking,
Wanda?
I'm thinking how happy I am.
(RAIN DRIPPING)
It's a strange world.
The strangest.
NARRATOR:  Our world isn't like
the other worlds they came t.
The way they see it,
human beings
are just so alien.
But if one of them
can find a way
to live with one of us,
I wonder.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Seekers.
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
No one gets taken.
Everybody out.
Seeker, I can...
Now.
Hmm.
Little bright out
tonight, is it?
You're human.
Human.
Mmm-hmm.
Not all human.
Are you their prisoner?
(GUN CLICKING)
Yes.
No.
I'm not their prisoner.
I'm their friend.
They're human.
Human as you.
(CHUCKLES)
We thought we were
the last survivors.
So did we.
Till we found
three other groups.
Now four.
Thought I was the only one
who switched sides.
I guess you never know where
you're gonna find your home.