Idiots.
Take the captain beyond the reef
till we get permission
to bring him ashore.
For a moment I thought
you were abandoning me.
Fernand Mondego does not
abandon his friends in the face
ofstupid, suicidal danger.
However, as Monsieur Morell's
official representative
on this voyage, Edmond,
I must officially tell you
you have overstepped
your bounds as second mate.
Officially. There.
I've covered myself.
Ifwe don't get him to
a doctor, he will die.
Doyou understand?
Ofcourse I understand.
Just don't expect me
to do this sober.
-[Horse Whinnies]
- Right.
[Fernand]
English dragoons.
Hello!
Dantes, don't.
[ Whinnying ]
- A little careless,
don'tyou think?
- We have to talk to someone.
Well, I know, but--
We're French sailors!
- Weseekmedicalattention!
- Come on. Come on.
- We come in peace.
- Come on.
We mean no harm!
Edmond!
Come on!Climb!
Look out!
Fernand!
Good. You finally
hit something.
Lieutenant Graypool.
Ifyour thirst for gore demands
the death ofthese poor fools,
thenbyallmeans
shoot them.
But do so with the knowledge
they are no agents ofmine.
Now explain yourselves
or be shot.
Sir, I am Edmond Dantes,
second mate ofthe merchant ship
Pharaon, on ourway home to Marseilles.
This is the shipowner's representative,
Monsieur Fernand Mondego,
son ofthe Count Mondego.
Our captainhas
contractedbrain fever,
so weputinhere forhelp.
Ifhis coma is genuine,
he won't feel my knife point,
will he?
Only a scratch.
[Flesh Cutting]
Edmond!
- Lieutenant Graypool!
- We came toyou in good faith!
- That's for mywounded men.
- And wounded pride, no doubt.
It has been an eventful evening.
IfI hadn't have shot those
dragoons, you might by lying in
pieces on the beach right now.
- I almost got us killed.
- Yes, youdid.
Yet... we survive.
Donne-moi encore
une bouteille du vin
- Whoo-hoo!
- [ Laughs ]
Donne-moiencore
unebouteille du vin
King's toyou, Mondego.
Beingyour friend
isalwaysanadventure. [Laughs]
- Yes, it is, isn't it?
- [ Laughs ]
It's a pity adventurers can't always
be friends though, huh?
What?
Well, it won't always
be like this, will it?
- What areyou talking about?
- Nothing. Drink up.
We're drinking
Napoleon Bonaparte's wine.
[Napoleon]I thinkyou'll find
the 1806 the finer vintage.
As long as you're still awake,
Monsieur Dantes, I wonder...
ifI might have
a word with you.
I'm curious. What's thesignificance
ofthe chesspiece?
It'sjust something
we've done since childhood.
Whenever one ofus has had a victory,
king ofthe moment.
- King ofthe moment?
- Yes.
[ Chuckles ] In life, we're all
either kings or pawns.
I'm moved byyour effort to save
your captain's life, Dantes.
He is my captain...
and my friend, Your Majesty.
Loyal friends
are rare indeed.
In fact, it is upon such
a matter I wish to speak.
I have written a rather
sentimental letter to an
old comrade in Marseilles.
It's a side ofme I prefer
the British not see.
Since they have a habit
ofopening my mail,
I wonder ifyou would
deliver it for me.
Oh, I-I don't--
It'sjust a letter
from one old soldier to another.
It's totally innocent,
I assureyou.
But more important,
it is the price I demand
for the use ofmy physician.
Then I agree.
Good.
You are to deliver the letter
to Monsieur Clarion.
- Canyourememberthatname?
- Monsieur Clarion.
How will I find him?
Oh, he will find you.
Now, I do not wish
this letter's existence
to be known to anyone else.
Not even your boon companion back there.
Doyou understand?
I'm aman ofmy word,
Your Majesty.
Yes, I, uh--
I believeyou are.
What did he want?
Oh, um, news from France.
That's all.
Timeyou were on yourway.
Your captain has been dead
for halfan hour.
Areyou sure?
When you have walked
as many battlefields as I,
young Dantes,
you can feel death.
Kings and pawns, Marchand.
Emperors... and fools.
[ Chattering ]
[Man]
Comeabout!
Drive faster.
[Bell Chiming]
Danglars, what's happened?
Captain Reynaud is dead, sir,
and Edmond Dantes
disobeyed my orders.
Come to my office
and report, Danglars.
- And you, Edmond.
- Will you be needing me,
Monsieur Morell?
Go.
Mercedes.
- Where is he? Where is Edmond?
- How lovely to seeyou too.
Youjust missed him,
I'm afraid.
Could be a while.
I think he's in trouble.
He said he'd meet us
by the rock. Come on.
I told Dantes
not to go ashore.
Is this true?
I accept
all responsibility.
As well you should.
It was all his idea, monsieur.
It should have
been your idea.
Puttin' into Elba didn't save
the captain's life, monsieur.
- I wasprotectin'themerchandise.
- You were protecting yourself...
byhidingbehindyourrank
andstayingaboard.
Edmond Dantes, I am making you
the new captain ofthe Pharaon.
You presume to demote me?
There is no demotion.
You will remain first mate
under Captain Dantes.
Unless, ofcourse, you choose
to seek another berth.
NowIimagine there's
a certainyoung lady...
who will want
tohearthisnews.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Thankyou.
Monsieur Morell?
- I understand you had a shipjust
returned from Elba, monsieur.
- Yes.
Did anyone aboard
get ashore there by any chance?
They did, but they're
not here at the moment.
Thankyou, monsieur.
- May I saywho has called upon them?
- Clarion.
The name is Clarion.
- Makelove tome.
- Willyouevergive up?
- He doesn't have to know.
- I'd know.
So would I.
- It'd be our little secret.
- I don't believe in secrets.
You think Edmond doesn't have secrets?
He does. Ask him.
- I know whatyou want, Fernand.
- You do?
Rememberwhen we were kids and
Edmond got that whistle for his
birthday, and you got a pony?
You were so mad Edmond
was happierwith his whistle
than you were with your pony.
I'm not going to be
your next whistle.
How long doyou think
it's going to be before
he can afford a wife?
Twoyears.
Twoyears. That's all.
Thenhegetshis captain's
papers, andwe canmarry.
Twoyears. Icouldn't wait
twoyears foranything,
particularly
a bride likeyou.
Hey!
-[Mercedes] Thereheis.
- Hey!
- [ Laughs ] Whoo!
- Mercedes!
[Mercedes]
Imissedyouso.
The missing is over now.
- Areyou in trouble?
- No. I'm captain. Come on.
Monsieur Morell
gave me the Pharaon.
Edmond!
King's to me.
[ Chuckles ] Yours is a life
truly blessed, Edmond.
[ Clicks Tongue ]
Come on.
- You're still the best man.
- I know.
Come on!
Stop that.
You'll go bald.
Doyou keep secrets from me?
Secrets? No.
Why?
Ask me anything
and I'll tell you.
We don't have to wait
twoyears anymore.
- As soon as I can afford
the ring, we'll wed--
- I don't need a ring. I don't.
This will be my ring.
And no matterwhat happens,
you will never see it
offmy finger.
Ever.
[Danglars]
Hello, my fineyounggentleman.
Care tojoin me?
So tell me, Mondego,
how did you ever
become friends...
with that righteous little ponce,
Edmond Dantes?
He claims to be my friend,
yet he has the audacity
to keep secrets from me.
What secrets?
[Tapping]
To the new captain
ofthe Pharaon.
AllIam Iowe
toyou, Father.
May this happy moment
be but the dawn...
ofa long and wonderful life
foryou both.
[DoorOpens]
- Which ofyou is Edmond Dantes?
- I am.
EdmondDantes,
youare underarrestbyorder
ofthemagistrate ofMarseilles.
- Arrest?
- On what charges?
Thatinformationis
privileged. Takehim.
I demand an explanation.
I demand an explanation!
I'll be back tonight.
Don't worry, Father. This is a mistake.
Mon Dieu.
Well, Imustsay, Dantes,
youdon'thave thelook ofa traitor.
Traitor?
Now, attend me well, Dantes,
foryour life may depend on it.
Didyouhaveanypersonal
contact with Napoleon
whenyou were on Elba?
Elba, yes, I did.
Well, we did.
I was with the
Count Mondego's son, Fernand,
almost the entire time.
- Doyou know Fernand?
- He's a recent acquaintance, yes.
Oh, thereyou are.
He'll vouch for me.
No doubt, butyou said,
''almost the entire time.''
Except forwhen Napoleon asked
me to deliver a personal letter
to a friend in Marseilles.
Well, Dantes, itis for
accepting that treasonous
correspondence...
thatyou have been denounced
byyour own first mate,
a Monsieur Danglars.
- What?
- Did you deliver the letter?
No, sir, someone was
supposed to find me.
It's-- It's still
in myjacket. Here.
- Haveyou read this?
- No, sir, I can't read.
Well, Dantes,
this is a letter to one
of Napoleon's agents.
It gives the times and
the locations ofthe British
beach patrols on Elba.
Sir, I swear on my mother's
grave, I had no idea.
He swore its contents
were innocent.
No, it's you
that's innocent.
Foolish and innocent.
I believe these are
the worst charges that could
be leveled againstyou.
Fortunately, as I've
interceptedthis document,
there'snoharm done.
God knows how
you're going to survive in
this world, Edmond Dantes.
Butyouareno traitor.
You may go.
Thankyou, sir.
Wait, uh, did Napoleon
tell you who's supposed
to pick up the letter?
Monsieur Clarion.
What name did you say?
Haveyou mentioned
this name to anyone else?
Monsieur Mondego
oranyone?
No, sir, in fact,
Monsieur Mondego knows
nothing ofthis letter.
This is very
dangerous information.
One can never be too careful
in times like this.
- Don'tyou think?
- Yes, sir.
Mm-hmm.
I've given you rather
a stressful time.
I wonder if, byway ofan
apology, I could offeryou
my carriage home.
-[DoorCloses]
- It'sjust throughhere.
[Hoofbeats, Carriage
Approaching]
Thankyou.
MonsieurVillefort?
MonsieurVillefort!
Whoa. Whoa!
Where areyou taking me?
[Edmond]
This isamistake.
- I'm allowed to go home.
- From now on, your home is
the prison Chateau d'If.
- No! No! No!
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Groans ]
- Hey!
[Man]
Shoothim now!
Mountup!
Getafterhim!
Fernand! Fernand!
- Monsieur?
- It's all right.
He's right here. Fernand!
I've been arrested for treason.
I barely managed to escape.
When we were on Elba,
Napoleongavemealetter.
I didn't tell you because
he made me promise not to.
Hesaidit wasjust
somenote toan oldfriend.
But the bastard lied to me!
He lied.
It was to one ofhis agents.
Somehow the authorities found out.
I don't know what to do.
There's gendarmes on
horseback right behind me.
All right.
Wejust have to think.
I hope I haven't
compromised you.
I was hoping your father
could help me.
He's in Paris.
He's very ill.
- How far back are the gendarmes?
- Minutes.
- Doyou need money?
- Yes, thankyou.
- Doyou have a pistol?
- Ofcourse not.
Good.
Stop it, Fernand.
I don't have time for this.
I saw Napoleon
giveyou that letter.
It was you?
Well, it wasn'tjust me.
It was Danglars's idea.
Why didn'tyou
come to me first?
Why did you keep it a secret from me?
I thoughtyou were my friend.
I told you I gave Napoleon myword.
He lied to me!
I know, Edmond.
I read the letter.
You-- You read--
Why areyou doing this?
Oh, it's complicated.
Complicated.
Don'tberidiculous.
- Get out ofmyway.
- I can't letyou go, Edmond.
Get away from the window.
Don't make me
take offyour hand!
[ Groans ]
[Groaning]
[ Shouts ]
[ Groans ]
Why? In God's name, why?
-[HoofbeatsApproaching]
- Becauseyou're the son ofa clerk!
And I'm not supposed
to want to beyou.
[DoorOpens]
- In here!
-[Man]Get!
- Wait.
-[Sword Clatters On Floor]
-[Man]Holdit. Holdit.
To remember better days.
Come on!
I told you it wasn't always
going to be this way, Edmond.
Father! Where ishe?
The study.
What's he done now?
Now, youlisten tome, Father.
Iam the chiefmagistrate,
an officialofthenewregime.
I cannot afford to have
my own father mixed up
in treasonous affairs!
You know--
[ Chuckles ]
In the end, treason
isamatterofdates.
I shall be the patriot,
and you the traitor,
when the emperor returns.
Stopit. Stopit,
youoldruin.
Those daysare over.
Napoleon Bonaparteisnolonger
the emperorofanything.
Ifyou continue
to dabble in this lunacy,
you run an excellent chance...
ofbeing arrested and ruining
our entire family all because
ofyour idiotic sympathies.
At least I have sympathies.
For God's sake, Father,
all Valentina is saying...
is that as a family
our fates are intertwined.
- Surelyyou can see that.
- See? Ah!
I'm an old ruin.
I don't see as well as I did.
You will excuse me.
[Men Groaning]
- Move it.
-  [ Whistling ]
Move.
[ManScreaming]
Welcome, Monsieur Dantes.
I am Armand Dorleac,
the warden ofChateau d'If.
Monsieur, I knowyou must
hear this a great deal,
- but I assureyou I am innocent.
- [ Scoffs ]
Everyone must say that,
I know, but I truly am.
- Innocent.
- Yes.
Iknow. Ireally doknow.
- You mock me?
- No, my dearDantes.
I know perfectlywell
thatyou are innocent.
Why else would you be here?
-[LiquidPouring]
- Ifyou were trulyguilty,
thereareahundredprisons in France
where they wouldlockyouaway,
but Chateaud'Ifis where they
put the ones they're ashamedof.
Let's have a look at
your quarters now, shall we?
''Godwillgivemejustice. ''
People are always trying
to motivate themselves.
Or they keep calendars,
but soon they lose interest
or they die.
- There's a window.
-AllI'm left with isarather
unsightly wall, I'm afraid.
So Iconceivedofanother waytohelp
ourprisonerskeep track oftime.
Everyyear, on theanniversary
oftheirimprisonment,
we hurt them.
Usuallyjust
a simple beating really.
Although, on their first day here,
in your case, today,
I like to do
something rather special.
[ Gasping ]
And ifyou're
thinkingjust now,
''Why me, O God?''
- the answer is,
God has nothing to do with it.
- All right?
In fact, God is never
in France this time ofyear.
God has everything to do with it.
He's everywhere. He sees everything.
All right.
Let's make a bargain,
shall we?
You ask God for help,
and I'll stop the moment he shows up.
[ Screams ]
-[Whip Continues]
-[Screaming Continues]
MonsieurVillefort,
haveyou not heard?
- Napoleon has escaped from Elba!
- What?
Landed 1 00 miles from here.
He marches on Paris!
Pack all my files.
And tell that idiot clerk
to find the ledger!
We are here to plead the case
of Edmond Dantes, Magistrate.
Not now! Dantes?
We have not met, monsieur.
I am Fernand Mondego,
the son ofCount Mondego.
I am here to swear
to Edmond Dantes's innocence.
This ishis employer,
Monsieur Morell, his father,
andhis fiancee, Mercedes.
Edmond Dantes is charged
with high treason.
- Yetyoustandbyhim?
- Ofcourse I do.
What ifI was to tell you
that Dantes is also
charged with murder?
- Murder?
- Edmond would never do such a thing.
Dantes carriedaletterfrom
Napoleon to one ofhis agents.
When we triedtoarresthim,
hekilledone ofmymen.
No, ifyou knew him,
monsieur, you would know
that was not possible.
Have mercy, please.
You have proof
ofthis treason?
That is government business.
Please. Please,
just tell us where he is.
I cannot, mademoiselle.
He was handed over to the king's men.
Ican understandyourpain
at thisbetrayal.
But my advice to all ofyou
would be to forget Edmond Dantes,
particularlyyou,
mademoiselle.
Takesolacein the comfort
ofyourgoodfriendhere...
and perhaps some good mayyet come
ofthis unhappy affair.
Now, you will excuse me.
I have to attend some other matters.
My son is no traitor!
[Fernand]
I will trytoreason withhim.
- Let's leave this to Fernand.
He can plead the case.
- It's impossible. Never.
I will not give up
on Edmond yet.
I will never
forgetyour kindness.
And I shall never
cease to give it.
Not that I don't appreciate
the embroidery ofthe crimes,
but still, murder?
It's quite simple really.
When you reported Dantes's
receiving the letter to me,
I didn't quite understand
whyyou were betraying him,
but now having seen
his exquisite fiancee,
I understand completely.
What prompts you to be
so accommodating?
Sit down, Mondego.
[ Grunts ]
Come back!
What's my crime?
I'm innocent!
[Clattering]
[ Mouthing Words ]
[Bird Twitters]
[Twittering Continues]
[FootstepsApproaching]
Happy anniversary, Dantes.
[ Gasps, Groans ]
Until nextyear.
[ Gasps ]
[ Panting ]
[Dorleac]Hasitreallybeen
fouryears, Delius?
-[Whip Cracking]
- Or Danton? Whatishisnameagain?
[DoorClosing]
[Tapping]
[Tapping Continues]
[ Gasping ]
Forgive my intrusion.
But I was under
the impression that I--
I was digging
toward the outerwall.
Parlez-vousanglais?
Italiano?
I am Abbe Faria. I have been a prisoner
in Chateau d'Iffor 1 1 years.
Five which
havebeenspent...
digging this tunnel.
[ Laughs ]
There are 72,51 9 stones...
in mywalls.
I've counted them many times.
But haveyou
named them yet?
- [ Sobbing ]
-Shh, shh.
Shh, shh.
Once I was as you are now.
But I promise, it will pass.
I promise, I promise.
Now, may I stand
on your shoulders?
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunting ]
[Panting]
Takeme down.
Please, take me down now.
Take me down.
[ Grunts, Pants ]
I have not seen the sky
these 1 1 years. Thankyou.
Thankyou, God.
There is no talk ofGod
in here, priest.
What about
the... inscription?
It's faded,just as God
has faded from my heart.
-Andwhathas replacedit?
- Revenge.
[ Chuckles ]
Hold these.
Follow me.
Perhaps your thoughts
ofrevenge...
are serving God's purpose
ofkeeping you alive...
thesesevenyears.
- To whatend?
- [ Chuckles ] Escape.
There we go.
[ Chuckles ]
You spoke ofescape.
Yeah.
There are only two possibilities
ofreaching the outerwall...
and finally the sea.
I simply--
I simply chose the wrong one.
Now, ofcourse,
with two ofus,
we could dig in
the opposite direction.
With both ofus together, then,
ofcourse, we could possibly
do it in, oh, eightyears.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, doessomethingelse
demandyour time?
Somepressing appointment,
perhaps?
In return... foryour help,
I offer something priceless.
My freedom?
No, freedom
can be taken away,
as you well know.
Iofferknowledge,
everythingIhave learned.
I willteachyou, oh,
economics, mathematics,
-philosophy, science.
- To read and write?
Ofcourse.
When do we start?
I got it. I got it.
[FootstepsApproaching]
[Man]
Lights out. Lights.
Let'shave 'em. Come on.
[Abbe's Voice]
Theslotopens twicea day.
Once foryourtoiletbucket,
which is where wehide the dirt.
[Man]
Come on.
Andoncein the evening
foryourplate.
[Man]
Lights out. Out.
Come on, priest.
Thankyou.
Between those times we can workall day
withoutfearofdiscovery.
''Soneglectbecomes...
ourally. ''
Excellent.
Soyou were in
Napoleon'sarmy.
We had such dreams then.
However, one night...
my regiment ran down...
a band ofguerrillas,
who ran into a church
for sanctuary.
I was ordered to burn...
down the church...
with them inside it.
Did you?
To my everlasting shame, I did.
I did.
How did you come to be here?
The following day
I deserted...
to devote my life
to repentance...
and to God.
I worked as
private secretary to...
the enormouslywealthy
Count Enrique Spada.
Spada was
a righteous man.
Sadly, a couple
ofyears later, he died...
amidst rumors that he had
hidden his limitless fortune.
[ Grunts ]
- Two weeks later, I was arrested.
- Why?
Napoleon wanted
Spada's treasure.
He did not believe that
I had no idea where it was.
So he had me thrown in here
to refresh my memory.
Andsohere I've remained
with onlyGod...
for company
until he sent meyou.
God is no more real
than your treasure, priest.
Perhaps.
[RatHisses]
- Ooh! Hurry. Get it.
- [ Shouts ]
[ Both Laughing ]
Compute this.
2,500 cubic centimeters
ofrock and dust a day...
for 365 days.
Equals three-and-a-half
meters a year,
1 2 feet, a foot a month.
[ Grunts ]
Three inches a week.
In Italian.
[Whip Cracking]
[ Speaking Italian ]
[Abbe]
Donot waste thelight.
You were a soldier, priest.
Soyou know weaponry.
[ Grunts ]
Teach me.
Or dig alone.
You force me to walk
a fine line, Dantes.
This is ridiculous.
The stronger swordsman
does not necessarilywin.
It is speed!
Speed ofhand.
Speed ofmind.
Now, sweepyour hand
through the drops...
withoutgetting wet.
Like this.
[ Grunting ]
How long must I keep this up?
I am going down the tunnel.
Parry. Up.
[ Grunts ]
Like that.
Time to study.
Define economics.
Economics is the science
that deals with the production,
distribution and
consumption ofcommodities.
Translation.
Dig first, money later.
-[FootstepsApproaching]
-[Men Chattering]
[Chattering Continues]
Thankyou.
Happy Christmas, Edmond.
Give or take a month or so.
Good. Whom areyou fighting?
Danglars? Mondego?
Who doyou think?
[ Grunts ]
Good! Too good.
Wehave Newton's thirdlaw.
There is a reaction
to every action...
in physics... and in man.
Thus my quest forvengeance
is a reaction to the actions
of Danglars and Mondego.
[ Exhales ]
Up, up.
I want that seat.
You once told me that Villefort
had you rearrestedjust after...
hehadclearedyou
ofall the charges.
You may go.
Yes, that's true.
Then why wouldhego
through thatcharade...
unless he had reason to change his mind
about letting you go?
- Think, Edmond.
- I'm trying.
- What happened?
- He asked me--
Did Napoleon tell you
who was supposed to
pick up this letter?
- I told him--
- A Monsieur Clarion.
-Andnothingmore?
- Nothing. He burnt the letter
and said I could go.
Ah.
He burned... the letter.
Yes.
Strange thata chiefmagistrate
wouldburn evidence...
ofa treasonous conspiracy...
and then imprison
the only man...
who was aware of
Monsieur Clarion's connection...
to that conspiracy.
- He was protecting someone.
-Ah.
-A dearfriendperhaps?
- No. No.
A politician like Villefort
would have rid himself
ofsuch friends.
Clarion couldbearelative.
A close relative, possibly--
No!
Villefort's fatherwas
a colonel in Napoleon's army.
Villefort wasn't
protecting Clarion.
He was protecting himself.
Danglars, who falsely said he saw
Napoleon give me that letter.
Mondego, who told
Villefort I had it.
And Villefort himself,
who sent me here.
Bravo, Edmond, bravo.
[ Shouts ]
[Metal Tapping]
Oh, my God. Oh, oh.
Oh.
Edmond, light. Light.
Quick. Light.
Oh, please, God.
What is that? Look.
Look. Look!
Roots. Plant roots.
Ifthese are plant roots,
then we are only months away.
Yes. Well done, priest.
I'll get my chisel. [ Kissing Sound ]
Good. Good.
- [ Grunting ]
-[Tapping]
Priest!
[ Groans ]
In God's name, go on.
- [ Grunting ]
- Go on. Go on!
[ Groans ]
[ Groaning ]
[Grunting]
[ Groaning, Panting ]
Lungs...
are punctured.
- Don't talk. Don't talk.
- Listen.
There's not much time.
Under th-those books,
there's loose rocks.
Bring me whatyou find.
Quickly, quickly.
[ Groans ]
Open it.
When I told them
Ididnotknow...
where the treasure
ofSpada was, I lied.
You lied?
I'm a priest,
not a saint.
There,
on that island
offthe Italian coast.
- Monte Cristo?
- Yes, yes.
Use-- Useyour head.
- Follow the clues.
- The tunnel's blocked. I can't escape.
No, keep digging.
When you escape, use it for good,
only for good.
No, I will surely
use it for my revenge.
Here now
is your final lesson.
Do not commit--
Oh. Do not commit
the crime...
forwhich you now
serve the sentence.
God said,
''Vengeance is mine.''
I don't believe in God.
That doesn't matter.
He believes in you.
Priest?
[Footsteps]
[Pascal]
Plates out.
Let's have it.
Oh.
Oh, God.
[ Panting ]
- [ Keys Clinking ]
- He's always awake.
[Lock Sliding Open]
[ Door Creaking ]
First time in 1 2 years
he hasn't said ''thankyou.''
-[Claude]Dead.
-[Pascal]How?
Felloffhisbed,
didn'the?
- He's a bit dirty, isn't he?
- They all are.
Well,
let's sew him up...
and then see Dorleac.
One, two, three.
Right, let's get Dorleac.
[ Door Creaking ]
-[Lock Sliding Closed]
-[Claude] Why'dyoulockit?
He'snotgoinganywhere.
[Maurice]
Idon'tknow. Habit, Isuppose.
Good-bye, priest.
You're free now,
as I will never be.
[WindHowling]
So the old pope has finally gone
to St. Peter's.
Well, bring him along.
- Let's bury him, then.
- Youready?
One. That'sit.
[Grunts]
- Keep going.
- Come on, come on.
I haven't got all day.
Actually, I do.
[Laughing]
I'vegot--
I'vegotall the time
in the world!
[Laughing]
Come on.
[KeyRattles In Lock]
Monsieur Dorleac!
[Dorleac]Heavenly Father,
webequeath toyou...
theseremains
ofyourhumbleservant.
Whatever his name was.
God, I'm so bored.
Monsieur Dorleac!
Did he, in fact,
have a map?
[Maurice]
No, gov.
[Dorleac]
Where's the, uh--
Stop!
Monsieur Dorleac!
What doyou mean, after three?
We throw him at three or before three?
- After three.
- One... two...
- Monsieur Dorleac!
- and th--
- Don't, Mr. Dorleac!
- One...
- two...
- Don't throw the body over the cliff!.
- Aah!
- three!
[ Gasps ]
[ Wheezing, Grunting ]
[ Muffled Grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Panting ]
We could have handled that
a bit better.
Thankyou, priest.
Thankyou.
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Whooping, Laughing ]
[ Hysterical Laughing ]
So, miamice,
I would askwhoyou are,
but in view ofyour
shredded clothes...
and the fact that
the Chateau d'Ifis two miles away,
what's the point?
As for me, I am Luigi Vampa,
a smuggler and a thief.
My men and I have come
to this island to bury alive
one ofour number...
who attempted to keep
some stolen gold for himself...
instead of, uh, sharing it
with his comrades.
Interestingly enough, there are some
ofhis more loyal friends...
who are insisting
that I grant him mercy,
which, ofcourse,
I cannot do,
for I would quickly lose control
ofthe whole crew.
- That's whyyou are
such a fortunate find.
- Why is that?
You provide me with a way
to show a little mercy toJacopo,
that maggotyou see
tied up over there,
while, at thesame time,
notappearing weak.
Andasaspecialtreat,
thelads willget tosee
alittle sportas well.
How do I accomplish
all this?
We watch you andJacopo
fight to the death.
IfJacopo wins,
we welcome him back to the crew.
Ifyou win, I have givenJacopo
the chance to live,
even ifhe did not
take advantage ofit,
and you can take his place
on the boat.
What ifI win,
and I don't want to be a smuggler?
Then we slityour throat,
and we're a bit shorthanded.
I find that smuggling
is the life for me...
and would be delighted
to kill your friend, the maggot.
Oh, uh, by the way,
Jacopo is the best knife
fighter I've ever seen.
Perhaps you should
get out more.
ReleaseJacopo
andgivehim backhisknife.
Then we let
the games begin.
-[Laughing]
- Get up, maggot.
- Come on, come on!
- [ Yelling ]
[ExcitedShouting]
[ Disgusted Muttering ]
As you hope to live,
do not move an eyelash.
SenorVampa,
allowJacopo to live.
He's already suffered enough
with the prospect ofbeing buried alive.
The men that wanted
to see some sport have seen it.
Those who wanted mercy
forJacopo will get it.
And by keeping me
andJacopo,
you will haveyet another skilled sailor
and fighter foryour crew.
It's a deal.
- What is his name?
-[Man] You'vegot the devil,Jacopo!
His name?
We shall call him Zatarra.
- Sounds fearsome.
- It means driftwood.
[Men Laughing]
I swear
on my dead relatives,
even on the ones
that are not feeling too good,
I am your man forever.
I know.
[ Chuckling ]
Eyes in the back ofyour head.
[BellRinging]
Haveyou never seen
Marseilles before?
It was my home.
Butyou do notjoin
the others ashore.
-[Man]Overhere!
- Listen to me, Zatarra.
Whatever happened toyou,
you cannot make it right
by staying here on this boat.
Go. It's up toyou.
''We are kings or pawns,''
a man once said.
Si.
Who told you this?
Napoleon Bonaparte.
Bonaparte?
[ Laughing Continues ]
Oh, Zatarra,
the stories you tell.
[ Laughing ]
Someday I may come
to find you.
A man is always in need
ofa good friend.
Truly.
[SeagullSquawking]
[Morell's Voice]
Danglars, what'shappened?
Captain Reynaudis dead, sir,
andEdmondDantes disobeyedmyorders.
Zatarra,
areyou all right?
Everything's changed.
I wantyou to buy a boat,
just something the two ofus can handle.
Wait for me to return.
I make my next visit alone.
Is-- Is this the home
of Monsieur Morell?
My grandfather
isn't well, monsieur.
Even ifhe were,
he would not receive visitors
at 1 1 :00 in the evening.
Perhaps he might make
an exception...
for a man who is seeking
E-Edmond Dantes.
[Dog Barking]
I apologize
for the hour.
Old people never sleep.
Sit down, sit down.
-Julianne, some sherry.
- [ Sighs ]
So, MonsieurZatarra,
you werea friend
ofEdmond?
- Monsieur Morell?
- Yes?
You knew... Edmond also?
Like a son.
I was hoping you could tell me where
to find his family.
Unfortunately,
his father hanged himself...
after learning
of Edmond's treason.
[ Whispers ] I see.
I see.
And...
this...
treason you speak of--
- Who accused him?
- Who knows?
MonsieurVillefort,
the man who had Edmond arrested,
leftforParissoonafter
to take up thepost...
ofchiefprosecutor.
Ofcourse, the shock ofhis father's
violent murder...
mayalsohave spurred
his departure.
They werestrange times.
You seem to have fallen
on difficult times yourself, sir.
After Edmond's death,
I reluctantly took on a partner.
-[Puts Bottle Down]
- One ofmy captains.
Andthen one day,
Danglars forcedme out.
[MorellSighs]
My fate is nothing
compared to Edmond's.
Perhaps your luck
is about to change.
[ Scoffs ]
I shall search out
Edmond's fiancee.
You mean
the Countess Mondego?
- Countess?
- Yes.
A month after poor Edmond
was arrested,
Mercedes wed
his best friend.
- Fernand.
- Yes, that's right.
Andwith the death
ofhis fatherandbrotherin the war,
Fernandbecame CountMondego.
They live in Paris now.
Count and Countess Mondego.
Areyou all right?
Yes. I must go.
- I'm sorry I was not more helpful.
- Oh, no.
You told me
what I needed to know.
Edmond Dantes is dead.
[Footsteps Retreating]
Zatarra.
Zatarra, you will be so proud ofme.
I found a nice little skiff.
We couldn't afford a sloop.
Got a really good deal.
Za-Zatarra?
Zatarra.
[ Hysterical Laughing ]
[ Kissing ]
[ Grunting, Laughing ]
[ Chortling ]
Whoo-hoo!
[ Whistling ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
Zatarra, the boat
cannot hold no more,
and there are at least
eight more boatloads down there!
Doyou not understand?
You are wealthier than any man
I have ever heard of.
Whateveryour problems were,
they are over.
Whatdoyou want tobuy?
Revenge.
Okay, revenge. Who?
Danglars, Villefort,
Fernand and Mercedes.
Right.
We kill these people,
then we spend the treasure.
No, we will study them,
learn theirweaknesses.
Why notjust kill them?
I'll do it.
I'll run up to Paris--
bam, bam, bam, bam!
I'm back before week's end.
We spend the treasure.
How is this a bad plan?
Death is too good for them.
They must suffer
as I suffered.
They must see theirworld,
all they hold dear,
ripped from them
as it was ripped from me.
You will need a better name than Zatarra
ifyou are to accomplish that.
Then I shall
become a count.
I bid you
good afternoon, sir.
I'm here to purchase
your lovely home.
[ Laughing ]
The very cheek!
I shall haveyou horsewhipped!
Now, get offmy property,
you vagabond,
before I set the dogs on you,
you hear?
Thankyou.
[Crowd Gasping, Exclaiming]
[ Gasping ]
[CrowdExclaiming]
Ladies and gentlemen,
it is with great honor
that I present toyou His Grace,
the Count of Monte Cristo.
[Fireworks Continue]
It's so beautiful.
Greetings.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
[ Excited Chattering ]
My dearcount, allowme tointroduce
toyoumyhusband,
MonsieurVillefort,
Chief Prosecutor.
Very kind ofyou
to think ofus.
Oh, I am the one honored
with your presence.
Now, please,
enjoyyourselves tonight.
What do we know about him?
Not enough.
Where are they?
Areyou sureyou invited them?
Yes, Your Grace.
But I just learned that Count Mondego
has retired for the evening.
He has a morning appointment
he cannot miss.
[ Groaning ]
[Doors Slam]
[Clock Bell Dinging]
You're up early, my dear.
Is the Viscount Tourville dead?
Unless his heart is situated somewhere
other than the left side ofhis chest,
I suspect he is.
God grant him peace.
He did no more than defend
his family's honor.
Much good it did him.
His wife and I
were happy in our passion.
You were happy in your ignorance.
Now comes the viscount's
valiant defense ofhis honor,
and you are pained.
- She is ruined, and he is dead.
- Don't flatteryourself.
I was neither happy
nor ignorant,
having known about the last three women
before Madame Tourville.
I'm sorryyou
are humiliated.
The combination of Paris
and me is hardly a recipe for fidelity.
Andsincemyattemptsatdiscretion
have evidently failed,
there seems little point
in keeping up pretenses.
It's actually quite...
liberating.
Wouldn'tyou say?
[Edmond]
His finances?
[Jacopo]He's losingmoney
at the othercasinos.
They'renoteven
cheatinghim.
Haveyoulooked
intohisshipping?
Hegotabankloan forhis ownboat
severalyears ago.
- Doesn'tuse Danglars.
- Makesure we own
thatbankbytomorrow.
Tell the othershipping
companies tostayaway from Mondego.
I want togivehim no choice
but to crawlback to Danglars.
Now, tell the dealers--
takeitall.
Do try to understand.
I have a very large
consignment ofcotton ready to be sent,
and I shall make my payment on the ship
as soon as it is delivered.
So obviously I need the vessel
in order to deliver it.
Unfortunately,
the bank can offer no further
extensions, Count Mondego.
Isuggestyoufind
alternatemeans ofshipping.
[Horse Whinnying]
Well, well. To what do I owe the honor,
Count Mondego?
Can't imagine whyyou've been
avoiding me after all theseyears.
I'm prepared
to overlookyour faults...
and perhaps resume
our dealings.
Business not going
so well these days?
[WheezingLaugh]
Zatarra?
Jacopo.
Did you fall offthe bed?
After 1 3 years ofsleeping
on a stone slab, I can't.
Mi Maria.
Does that hurt?
Did you come here
for a reason?
Mondego has a son.
- Albert wishes to talkwith us.
- Not now!
Tell him I'm trying
to protect his inheritance.
Areyou afraid he's
going to squander his as you haveyours?
I don't recall hearing your
complaints when I elevated you
from a fishmonger's daughter.
Please, I must finish this,
then I shall be going out.
May I remind you, my love,
that in Paris there are
mistresses aplenty,
butyou have
only one son.
Come in, Albert.
- ForGod'ssake, bebrief.
- I will, Father.
Several ofmy friends
are going to Rome for two weeks
during Carnival.
- I would like to accompany them.
- Rome?
- And no chaperons? You're only 1 5.
- Almost 1 6.
Make it my birthday present,
Father, please.
- I won'tgetinto trouble.
- No.
Ofcoursehe cango.
Icoulddo withsomepeace
andquietaroundhere.
- Rome!
- [ Cheering ]
[ Shouting ]
[Upbeat]
[ Gasping, Yelling ]
[Man]
Albert!Albert!
- Over here! Over here!
- Over here!
Milady?
Can't hide forever.
[ Grunts ]
Who areyou, and why
areyou doing this?
- We are bad men, and for the money.
- My money is in mywaistcoat.
Not anymore.
Besides, it's notyour money
we're interested in.
You are the only son
ofCount Mondego, areyou not?
Ransom?
Send your note and be damned.
I wish it were that easy,
but a note won't reach
your father for two weeks,
andthen there's the endless
debatesabout whether
wekilledyoualready.
No, a notejust doesn't have the impact.
Perhaps ifwe send him your ring.
Yes. My ring bears
the Mondego crest.
- While still attached toyour finger?
-[Men Laughing]
Listen to me, vermin.
I am Albert, son of Fernand,
Count Mondego,
andyouhavehadyourlastlaugh
atmy expense.
- Doyourworst.
- Ifyou insist. Peppone, the knife.
Cut this boy's ropes,
or I will be forced to start cutting
your miserable corpses.
Now!
Follow me, young man.
You see the surface? Wait for me there.
- I don't know how to thankyou.
- Go. We'll talk later.
Well done, gentlemen.
Many thanks, Your Grace.
Albert.
Areyou all right?
Sir, I oweyou my life.
You've had quite an ordeal.
You're an extraordinaryyoung man.
I insist, you must come to my estate
for breakfast tomorrow.
Agreed?
Agreed.
May I ask
whoyou are, sir?
For the present, your friend.
Tomorrow, your host.
For the short time
formality stands between us,
the Count of Monte Cristo.
He's out in the waiting room.
Heshowedcourage
in the tunnels.
He's a means to an end.
Yes, Your Grace.
Young man.
Albert, comein. Come, come.
Come on.
- You've had quite a night.
- Yes.
[Albert]
Whatanadventure.
Everything's an adventure
when you'reyoung.
- One thing puzzles me, sir.
- Hmm.
How did you come to know
ofmy kidnapping?
I have many connections,
some ofwhich
are less than reputable.
I paywell to be informed
ofanything ofnote
in any city in which I stay.
And the kidnapping
ofa count's son is ofnote.
But why riskyour life
rescuing me?
The son
ofa fellow noble.
It was the least
I could do.
Judging byyour character,
I'm sureyou would have done the same.
Your fatherwill
be proud ofyou.
You must come to Paris
and meet my parents so they
may thankyou in person.
Unfortunately, I cannot.
Business, you see.
Please, it is
a matter ofhonor.
-Jacopo?
- Yes, Your Grace?
The Spada matter--
where do we stand?
- Even now, the gold--
- The shipment?
Oh, I-I'm sorry, Your Grace.
The shipment is in transit,
uh, boundforMarseilles.
- And it arrives?
- Not for another three weeks,
Your Grace.
Three weeks? That'smore
than enough time to visitin Paris.
- Verywell.
- Excellent.
- And you'll be therejust in time.
- In time for?
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
- Happy birthday.
- Thanks.
[Pounding]
[Man]
The CountofMonte Cristo.
Count!
- Albert.
- Your Grace. Father!
MayIpresent
the CountofMonte Cristo.
- 'Tis a pleasure.
- The pleasure is mine,
Count Mondego.
I've been looking forward
to this moment for some time.
You do me much honor,
when it is I who are indebted toyou...
for the rescue ofmy son.
May I present
the Countess Mondego.
Mercedes.
Countess.
You would have to be a mother
to truly appreciate the service...
you've done
for my son and me.
Monsieur, I shall never forgetyou.
Please, madame,
it was nothing.
I am sure that within a month,
you will not even remember my name.
Hmm?
May I steal yourwife?
- I'm sorry?
- For the waltz.
Ofcourse.
Isn't he wonderful, Father?
[ Waltz ]
- What's the matter?
- Uh, nothing.
Youjust remind me
ofsomeone from long ago,
someone who was
very dear to me.
I'm flattered.
What happened to him?
He died.
But I'm not that man.
-[Pounding]
-[Man]MonsieurandMadame Villefort.
What are they doing here?
Prosecutor Villefort.
- What areyou doing here?
- Oh, Madame Villefort, monsieur.
I'm so glad you could come to see me
while I'm still in town.
- We were delightfully
surprised to getyour note.
- Thankyou.
Would you be so kind
as to excuseyour husband
and I for a moment?
I'm told you are an expert
in the interpretation
ofthe law.
I have a certain matter
that perhaps you could
help me with.
Excuse me.
Fernand. Fernand!
The toast!
Not right now.
I have state business to attend to.
Our guests expect it.
Albert expects it.
You give it, my dear.
I'm sure it'll be splendid.
You are his father!
It is the leastyou can do.
You know how he admires you.
Then he will forgive
my absence.
But--
I thought we agreed
not to meet socially.
How could I pass up
the Count of Monte Cristo?
Quite.
- What doyou know ofhim?
- He's foreign,
rich.
I hear he aided
your son.
- Why does he seekyour counsel?
- Why should I tell you?
When my son
returned from Rome,
he mentioned he'd
heard Monte Cristo saying
he was expecting a shipment.
Healsoheard the words ''gold''...
and ''Spada.''
- Hmm.
- You don't believe--
Monte Cristohas found
the treasure ofSpada.
Not an hour ago,
he asked me to help him avoid
troublesome inspections...
on a shipment coming
from Marseilles.
- Hmm.
- I could have him arrested.
Don'tdo that.
Let'sjustrelievehim ofit.
- How doyou propose--
- I have an acquaintance
who deals in these matters.
Tell Monte Cristo
you'llgethisshipment through Customs,
but that it will
have to stay in port overnight.
I shall have it removed
and taken to my old family
estate in Bouchon,
where we shall meet
the following day.
I require 70 percent.
And yetyou'll only get 50.
Done.
[Man Laughing]
Yes, itis, isn'tit?
[Man]
Yes, well, Iknow. Yes.
[ Clinks Glass ]
[Conversation Quiets]
Ladiesandgentlemen,
unfortunately, my husband has been
detained by business.
Andsoitis
leftup tome to--
To introduceyou...
to the Count of Monte Cristo
yet again.
Yousee, Ihadtheaudacity
tobeg the count...
to allow me to give
the birthday toast to Albert.
I wassoinsistent, andsuch
is thegraciousness ofourhost,
thathereluctantlygave up
his fatherlyright...
in order to accommodate a guest,
even one as boorish
as myself.
- Ahh.
- [ Murmuring ]
Young Albert
has made far too much...
oftheassistance
Igavehim in Rome.
When I arrived
in the catacombs,
I watched as the criminals,
who tied Albert to a wall,
threatened to cut off
his finger and send it to his father...
as evidence
ofhisabduction.
[Woman]
Goodness!
The boy's reply to all this was...
''Doyourworst.''
[ All Gasping ]
Life is a storm,
myyoung friend.
You will bask
in the sunlight one moment,
be shattered on the rocks
the next.
What makes you a man...
is whatyoudo
when thatstorm comes.
Youmustlookinto thatstorm
andshout, asyoudidin Rome,
''Doyourworst...
for I will do mine.''
Then the fates willknowyou
as weknowyou,
asAlbertMondego,
theman.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[HorseSnorts]
Giddap!
Edmond, Villefort told me
thatyou were executed.
- Did he?
- Oh, God.
- Countess, you are mistaken.
Back to the Mondegos'.
- No!
- Madame, I'm only thinking
ofyour reputation.
- I beg you, Edmond.
- I don't care howyou returned.
- I am not this Edmond.
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it!
[ Sobbing ]
So, what areyou?
A spirit?
Some ghost sent to torment me?
This Edmond,
you loved him?
Yes.
For how long?
For all ofmy life.
And how long after he died
beforeyou married the count?
That isn't fair.
We've reached your home,
Countess.
You're right.
You cannot be my Edmond.
Well, thereyou are.
You said ityourself.
Edmond Dantes is dead.
Good night.
Countess.
Ifyou ever again presume
to interfere in my affairs,
I will, I promise, finish thejob
I started the daywe met.
Doyou understand?
- I understand you are mad.
- Mad?
My enemies are falling
into my traps perfectly.
Mad, Your Grace,
for ignoring this:
You have a fortune,
a beautiful woman who loves you.
Take the money,
take the woman and liveyour life.
Stop this plan.
Take whatyou have won.
- I can't.
- Why not?
I am still your man, Zatarra.
I swore an oath.
I will protectyou.
Even ifit means I must
protectyou from yourself.
I'll driveyou home now.
I'll walk.
[Chattering]
Put two chests
on the Pharaon for our cut.
Mondego will never notice.
Come on.
Get aboard.
- Philippe Danglars?
- Yeah?
You are charged with the theft ofgoods
from a certain merchant ship.
This is absurd.
We can resolve
this matter easily.
These men will perform
a search ofyourvessel.
Count Mondego set me up.
But I'll not hang for him.
[ Grunts ]
Who areyou?
I'm the Count of Monte Cristo.
But my friends call me Edmond Dantes.
[ Whispering ]
Dantes?
[ Choking, Gasping ]
Cut him down before
he can't talk.
[ Gasping ]
[HissingSound]
[Footsteps]
[ Grinding Sound,
Hissing Increases ]
Boy, don't do that.
That's-- That's too much.
My dearVillefort.
I hopeyou don't mind
ifI join you for a short while.
Your Grace,
I was not expecting you.
I want to thankyouinperson
forhelpingme with myshipment.
That, yes. I-I made all
the arrangements earlier.
I can promiseyou there'll be
no more problems from our end.
Excellent. I think this
couldbe thestartofalong
andfruitfulrelationship.
Speaking ofwhich,
may I pose a question?
Yes, ofcourse.
Anything in the world.
I wasjust curious.
Why did you tell
Countess Mondego 1 6 years ago...
that Edmond Dantes
had been executed?
Hmm?
Uh, I don't understand.
Wh-What on earth areyou talking about?
It's a perfectly
simple question.
How doyou know these things?
- [ Grinding Sound ]
- That's, uh--
That's quite enough.
Whew! You don't understand.
Dantes was accepting
a letter from Napoleon.
- That was clearly treason.
- But we both know
he never delivered it.
Packing a man offto prison
with such knowledge
is bad enough. But to tell--
Your Grace, I have no idea
what is provoking
this perverse discussion.
Now I ask myself,
''What did my old friend
Villefort stand to gain...
by telling Mercedes
that Edmond Dantes is dead?''
The answer is...
absolutely nothing.
Just as you say, nothing.
So why--
But ifmy old friend,
now chiefprosecutor of France,
doesn't gain from this lie,
well, who does?
My dear Count, it's far too hot in here
and you're fully dressed.
- It's time we both left.
- I think the clearestbeneficiary...
is Fernand, Count Mondego.
I don't understand what
this inquisition has to do
with our business relationship.
I'm about to tell you.
Sit down, Mondego.
I'm an ambitious man.
And I have furthered these ambitions...
by scooping up Bonapartists.
But now with Napoleon
on the loose, I have,
shall I say,
a thorn in my side.
Once merely an irritation,
now potentially lethal.
- Be lethal in turn.
- Well, the problem is such...
that I, myself,
cannot attend to it.
So I have a proposition
foryou.
How is your father?
Alive, unfortunately.
We share the same misfortune.
You remember?
[Pounding On Door]
Why is this door locked?
I demand thatyou release me
from this room at once.
You've proved yourself
no friend ofmine.
Your fatherwas a loyal supporter
of Napoleon, wasn't he?
Possibly involved in plotting
Napoleon's escape from Elba.
The emperor arrives soon!
[Edmond's Voice]
Aninconvenientparentfor
anambitious civilservant.
But then he died, suddenly
and opportunely murdered,
again some 1 6 years ago.
The Emperor Napoleon.
[ Groans ]
Themurdererneverapprehended.
Howharddidyoulook forhim?
You have no proof,
no witnesses.
Youjust have theories.
J-Just conjectures.
On the contrary.
I have Count Mondego.
Young Mondego. Why?
Becauseyour son
lacked the courage.
[Villefort's Voice]Mondegois the one
whopulledthe trigger!
He'dneverconfess
inamillionyears!
You're right,
he wouldn't.
- Butyoujust have.
-[Steam Hisses]
Monsieur Villefort,
youare underarrest
forconspiracytomurder.
You remember?
Dantes?
A courtesy for a gentleman.
[DoorCloses]
[ Chuckling ]
- [ Clicks ]
- [ Panting ]
You didn't think
I'd make it that easy, did you?
[Man]
Hyah!
Edmond?
I thought we had
finished our conversation
in the carriage.
So did I.
Until I realized...
you said the name ''Dantes.''
A name that
I had never mentioned.
What doyou want ofme?
I want to be free ofyou,
the wayyou obviously
are free ofme.
Just a few answers from you,
and I shall be gone forever.
Askyour questions.
Where haveyou been?
Thirteen years in
the Chateau d'If...
and everywhere else
you can imagine.
The Chateau d'If
for 1 3 years.
Did you suffer?
[ Scoffs ] Areyou finished now?
I have a good deal on my mind.
- What happened afterward?
- Much.
- Why did you not come to me?
- Why did you not wait?
You married the very man
who betrayed--
I told you that night
on the rocks, remember?
That it would never leave my finger.
And it never has.
- Why?
- You know why.
Ifyou ever loved me,
don't--
don't rob me ofmy hate.
It's all I have.
Let it go, Edmond.
Let it go.
I don't know what dark plan
lies within you.
Nor do I know bywhat design
we were asked...
to live without
each other these 1 6 years.
- But God has offered us
a new beginning--
- God?
Don't slap His hand away.
Can I never escape Him?
No. He is in everything.
Even in a kiss.
[Birds Twittering]
[Knocking On Door]
My lady?
Where's the count?
Um, the count wouldlike
foryou tojoinhim thisafternoon.
-Join him?
- Uh, yes,
in, uh, leaving the country
with your son.
Mmm, uh, I'll have someone
bring you toyour house...
andyoujust
wait there forme.
- And wejust--
- Thankyou!
- Yes, yes, but--
- I need to go home and pack.
Yes, yes. My lady--
- Where's the count?
- Upstairs, my lady.
What's wrong?
I'm bankrupt.
All my debts have been called in.
- Also, I'm to be arrested.
- Forwhat?
Piracy, corruption
and murder.
- Didyoudoall these things?
- Yes.
There issimplynot time to talk.
Thegendarmesare on the way,
apparently, so hurry up
and pack something.
I'm not going
with you, Fernand.
[ Panting ]
You are mywife.
I have made
arrangements for us.
We shall be verywell
taken care of.
Now go and find my son.
- He's notyour son.
- I beg your pardon?
Albert Mondego is the son
of Edmond Dantes.
Why doyou think I rushed off
so quickly to marryyou
after Edmond was taken away?
Premature.
Well, aren'tyou
a piece ofwork.
So he's the bastard son
ofa dead traitor.
He always was disappointing.
Good-bye, Mercedes.
You did please me some ofthe time.
You never pleased me.
[ Whinnies ]
[ Whispering ]
What is this?
[Clattering]
Monte Cristo.
King's toyou, Fernand.
[ Panting ]
Edmond?
But how--
How did I escape?
With difficulty.
How did I plan this moment?
With pleasure.
-[ThunderRumbling]
- Soyou've taken Mercedes?
And everything else...
exceptyour life.
Why areyou doing this?
It's complicated.
Let'sjust say it's vengeance
for the lifeyou stole from me.
Well, I see someone
has taughtyou the sword.
How did you ever
call yourselfmy friend?
- We were friends, Edmond.
- [ Yells ]
You sent me to hell!
Why?
Takeyourvengeance.
[ Panting ]
But know the blood
you spill is noble.
Blood that will never
run through yourveins.
You're no more a count
than I am a commoner!
[ Grunting ]
You don't have it in you.
- Touch him, and I'll kill you.
- Boy, let me explain.
It's been explained.
I spoke to Madame Villefort
on the street.
She told me how I was a silly,
trusting dupe that my friend,
the Count of Monte Cristo,
used to get into our lives.
- Albert, listen to me.
- I will not!
Forgive me for being
such a fool, Father.
You were betrayed.
Ofcourseyou're forgiven.
You were my friend.
I looked up toyou.
There's a history here
you know nothing about.
He loved your mother,
and yet she chose me.
- Now he intends to steal her away.
- Lie. Get out ofmyway!
Boy, ifIhave to,
I willkillyou.
I will not stop now.
- Norwill I.
- So be it.
[Mercedes Shouting]
No!
[ Clicks ]
Albert,
I found the noteyou left
explaining whereyou'd gone.
But now I must
explain something toyou.
Whereyou really come from.
Albert, youare
theson ofEdmondDantes.
The man you know as
the Count of Monte Cristo.
Well, I'm afraid
it is true.
Youare the walkingproof
thatyourmother
was asmuch ofa whore...
in heryoungeryears
as she is today.
[Albert]
You--
You let me fight him?
It didn't do
any good though, did it?
Fernand, I beg you.
No more!
I want no more ofthis.
Justgo.
Callitmercy.
Mercy, Fernand.
You've only got one shot,
and it will take
more than that to stop me.
Well, then I'd best
put it where it will do
the most damage.
[Albert]
No!
Mother!Mother!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Lookwhat I've done.Jacopo!
Hyah!
Once again, Zatarra,
God sees you out of
the corner of His eye.
She'll live.
[ Whinnies ]
-[Fernand]Edmond!
- [ Whimpers ]
Edmond!
Please don't go
out there. Don't.
Edmond, don't go.
You try.
Don't ever quit.
Zatarra,
you must end this.
Even the priest
will understand that.
- Edmond!
-[Mercedes Whispering]
Please don'tleave.
Watch overyour mother.
Now, I couldn't live in a world
whereyou have everything
and I have nothing.
[ Groans ]
What happened
toyour mercy?
I'm a count,
not a saint.
[ Panting ]
You were right, priest.
You were right.
This I promiseyou...
and God:
All that was used
forvengeance...
will now be used for good.
So rest in peace, my friend.
So, Zatarra,
painful, huh?
No.
I bought this place,
thinking one day
I would tear it down.
But now the only things
I care about...
are walking off
this island with me.
Let's go home.