KENNY LOGGINS SINGING:
Revvin' up your engines.
Listen to her how I and roar.
Metal under tension...
beggin' you to touch and go.
Highway to the danger zone.
Ride into the danger zone.
Headin' into twilight...
spreadin' out her wings tonight.
She's got you
jumpin' off the deck...
shovin' into overdrive.
Highway to the danger zone.
I'II take you
right into the danger zone.
Highway to the danger zone.
Gonna take you
right into the danger zone.
Good morning, Scott.
Morning, Willis.
How are you?
Ghost Rider, this is strike.
We have unknown aircraft.
Inbound, Mustang.
You're vector zero-nine-zero
for bogey.
Who's up there?
Cougar and Merlin
and Maverick and Goose.
Great.
Maverick and Goose.
Talk to me, Goose.
Roger. I got him.
Contact, 20 left at 30 miles.
Nine hundred knots closure.
Cougar, you hear that?
Roger.
Merlin, you got him?
Roger. I've got radar contact.
I'II get a visual.
Cougar, you hook them.
Roger. And I'II clean them
and fry them. Ha ha.
Mustang.
Mustang, this is Ghost Rider.
Two-zero-three.
I've got him inbound.
Bogey heading two-seven-zero
at 10 miles.
Nine hundred knots closure.
Ghost Rider,
take angels 10-Ieft-three-zero.
Are we supposed to have
visitors today?
Negative, sir.
Merlin, see if he's alone.
Roger.
Goose, you see a trailer?
Negative, Merlin.
Looks like he's a single.
I'm going head-to-head with him.
Take it easy, Maverick.
I don't like this shit.
I'm breaking high right
to see if he's really alone.
We've got
1,000 knots closure, Mav.
He's coming right at us.
OK, buddy, what's on your mind?
Holy shit, there's two of them !
Whoo! MIG-28s!
No one's been this close before.
What are they doing here?
What's the position?
Two hundred fifty miles out.
Two hundred fifty miles?
Clear them out.
Cougar, you've got MIG-1.
I'm going after MIG-2.
I lost him in the sun.
Shit, what's he doing?
You got him, Merlin?
He's coming around,
right on our tail.
God damn it!
This bogey's all over me.
-What's their range now?
-Two hundred miles, sir.
If they break 150 miles,
launch the alert-five aircraft.
OFFICER: Yes, sir.
Air speed 300. Get him, Mav!
I'm going for missile lock.
Let's scare this guy
out of here.
Come on, lockup, baby.
Lockup, baby.
Lockup.
I got him locked.
Bingo!
We got him, Mav.
He's bugging out and going home.
Mustang, this is Maverick.
MIG-2 is headed home.
What's their position?
One hundred eighty miles,
bearing zero-one-zero, sir.
[Beep]
Cougar,
He's got missile lock on us!
Get away from this guy!
What is this shit?
He's engaging me.
Damn it, Mustang,
this is Ghost Rider.
This bogey's all over me.
He's got missile lock on me.
Permission to fire?
Don't fire until fired upon.
Goose, there they are below us.
The MIG's in perfect
firing position.
He's right on Cougar's tail.
No way, Goose.
He'd have fired already.
He's trying to piss us off.
Maverick, get down here
and get this asshole off me.
Easy, Cougar.
Bring him back. Hard right.
Help me engage.
I'm on my way.
Can't shoot this son of a bitch.
Let's try having some fun.
Is this your idea of fun, Mav?
Greetings.
Watch the birdie.
Jeez, I crack myself up.
This is a great shot, Mav.
I should be a photographer.
Cougar...
your tail is clear.
MIG-1 has bugged out.
[Breathing erratically]
Cougar, this is Maverick.
We've had enough fun
for one day, don't you think?
I'm getting a little low
on fuel, so we're heading home.
We'll see you on deck.
We're running Low on gas.
We've gotta get out of here.
[Beeping]
Cougar.
We're on vapor, Cougar.
Let's do it.
Cougar! Come on, Cougar!
MERLIN: Take it back
to the ship, man.
Come on, Cougar.
Get him on deck
as soon as possible.
He's gotta be Low on fuel.
Cougar, we've got to land
this thing.
We are way Low on gas,
you understand me?
You all right, man?
CONTROL: Maverick, you're at
3/4 of a mile. Call the ball.
Roger. Maverick has the ball.
MERLIN: Cougar, let's Land!
Goose, Cougar's in trouble.
Come on, Mav,
we're gettin' Low on gas.
Let's Land this sucker.
MERLIN: Cougar!
God damn it, Maverick.
We got no fuel for this.
We're going after Cougar.
You tell him to land that plane.
That's an order.
CONTROL: Ghost Rider,
you are instructed to land.
Land immediately.
Any of you boys seen
an aircraft carrier around here?
Mav, we've got a little problem
up here.
That MIG really screwed him up.
I don't think
he can make it back.
You're OK, Cougar.
Just stay on my wing.
I'II take you all the way in.
Just stay with me.
Easy, Cougar.
Just a walk in the park, buddy.
You're a Little Low.
You're a Little Low, Coug.
Come on, buddy. Pull up.
MAVERICK: Pull up, Cougar.
That's it.
Almost there.
CONTROL: You're well below
glide path.
Three quarters of a mile.
Call the ball.
Roger ball.
MERLIN: We're too Low, Cougar.
We're too Low, Cougar.
Pull up!
Some more power!
Come on, pull again!
AIR BOSS JOHNSON: Come in.
Sir.
Cougar,
you should be in sick bay.
What's on your mind?
My wife and kid, sir.
Almost orphaned him today,
without ever seeing him.
I don't know what happened
up there...
but I was so scared.
Come on, we've seen this before.
No, sir.
I'm holding on too tight.
I've lost the edge.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm sorry.
Cougar.
Thanks, Maverick.
JOHNSON:
Maverick, Goose, come in here.
MAVERICK:
What the hell's going on?
I don't know.
Oh, shit.
Maverick, you just did
an incredibly brave thing.
What you should have done
was Land your plane!
You don't own that plane...
the taxpayers do!
Son, your ego is writing checks
your body can't cash.
You've been busted...
you lost your qualifications
as section leader three times...
put in hack twice by me...
with a history
of high-speed passes...
over five air control towers...
and one admiral's daughter!
Penny Benjamin?
And you, asshole...
you're Lucky to be here.
Thank you, sir.
And Let's not bullshit,
Maverick.
Your family name
isn't the best in the Navy.
You need to be doing it better
and cleaner than the rest.
Now, what is it with you?
Just want to serve my country,
be the best pilot in the Navy.
Don't screw around with me,
Maverick.
You're a hell of
an instinctive pilot.
Maybe too good.
I'd like to bust you,
but I can't.
I got another problem here.
I got to send somebody
from this squadron to Miramar.
I've got to do something here.
I still can't believe it.
I got to give you
your dream shot.
I'm gonna send you up
against the best.
You two characters
are going to Top Gun.
For five weeks...
you will fly against the best
fighter pilots in the world.
You were number two.
Cougar was number one.
Cougar lost it,
turned in his wings.
You guys are number one.
But you remember one thing--
you screw up just this much...
you'll be flying a cargo plane
full of rubber dog shit...
out of Hong Kong.
Yes, sir!
That is all.
You can tell me about the MIG
some other time.
Gentlemen!
Good Luck, gentlemen.
-Thank you, sir.
-Thank you.
SONG: Out along the edge...
is always where I burn to be.
The further on the edge,
the hotter the intensity.
Highway to the danger zone.
Gonna take you
right into the danger zone.
Highway to the danger zone.
Right into the danger zone...
During Korea,
the Navy kill ratio was 12 to 1.
We shot down 12 of their jets
for every one of ours.
During Vietnam,
that ratio fell to 3 to 1.
Our pilots had become dependent
upon missiles.
They had lost some
of their dogfighting skills.
Now, Top Gun was created
to teach ACM--
Air Combat Maneuvering.
Dogfighting.
This gives me a hard-on.
By Vietnam's end,
that ratio was back to 12 to 1.
Don't tease me.
Blinds, please.
I'd like to take this
opportunity to introduce you...
to our commanding officer
at Top Gun.
The first man awarded
the Top Gun trophy.
You will not find
a finer fighter pilot...
anywhere in the world.
Commander Mike Metcalf.
Call sign, Viper.
Gentlemen...
You are the top one percent
of all naval aviators.
The elite.
The best of the best.
We'll make you better.
You'll fly at Least
two combat missions a day...
attend classes in between...
and evaluations
of your performance.
In each combat sequence...
you're gonna meet
a different challenge.
Every encounter is going
to be much more difficult.
We're gonna teach you
to fly the F-14...
right to the edge
of the envelope...
faster than
you've ever flown before...
and more dangerous.
Now, we don't make policy here,
gentlemen.
Elected officials,
civilians do that.
We are the instruments
of that policy.
And although we're not at war...
we must always act
as though we are at war.
GOOSE: What are you doing?
MAVERICK: Just wondering...
who's the best.
In case some of you wonder
who the best is...
they're up here on this plaque.
The best driver and his R.I.O.
from each class is on it.
And they have the option...
to return here
to be Top Gun instructors.
You think your name's
gonna be on that plaque?
Yes, sir.
That's arrogant, considering
the company you're in.
Yes, sir.
I like that in a pilot.
Just remember,
when it's over out there...
we're all on the same team.
Gentlemen,
this school is about combat.
There are no points
for second place.
Dismissed.
Nice going.
The plaque for the alternates...
is down in the Ladies' room.
[Overzealous Laughter]
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, you kill me. You really do.
No, no, no.
There's two o's in Goose, boys.
[Disco music playing]
Hi.
This is what I call
a target-rich environment.
You Live your Life
between your Legs, Mav.
Goose, even you could get laid
in this place.
I'd be happy to find a girl
who'll talk dirty to me.
Mav, you want to know
who the best is?
That's him. Iceman.
That's the way he flies.
Ice cold. No mistakes.
Just wears you down.
You get bored, frustrated,
do something stupid...
and he's got you.
Hey, Slider, I thought you
wanted to be a pilot, man.
What happened?
Goose, you're such a dickhead.
Whose butt did you kiss
for this?
Well, the List is Long,
but distinguished.
Yeah, well, so is my Johnson.
So you're flying
with Iceman, huh?
Mr. Iceman to you.
Hey, Mother Goose,
how's it going?
Tom, this is Pete Mitchell.
Tom Kazansky.
Congratulations on Top Gun.
Thank you.
Sorry to hear about Cougar.
We were close in flight school.
He was a good man.
He still is a good man.
That's what I meant.
I thought so.
Say, you need any help?
With what?
You figured it out yet?
What's that?
Who's the best pilot.
No. I can figure that out
on my own.
I heard that about you.
You like to work alone.
Mav, you must have soloed
under a Lucky star.
First the MIG...
and then you guys slide
into Cougar's spot.
We didn't slide
It was ours, OK?
Some pilots wait their career
to see a MIG up close.
I guess you guys
are Lucky and famous, huh?
ICEMAN:
No. You mean notorious.
I'II see you Later.
You can count on it.
They were abused children.
We're gonna have a good time.
Always.
GOOSE: OK, I guess
it's my turn, isn't it?
AII right. The bet is $20.
$20.
You have to have
carnal knowledge...
of a Lady this time...
on the premises.
On the premises.
GOOSE:
Come on, Mav. A bet's a bet.
I don't know.
It just doesn't seem fair...
for you, I mean.
But, uh...
she's lost that Loving feeling.
-She's Lost--no, she hasn't.
-Yes, she has.
She has not lost that lov--
-Goose, she's lost it.
-Mav, come on.
I hate it when she does that.
Shit.
Excuse me, miss.
Hey, hey. Don't worry.
I'II take care of this.
[Singing]
You never close your eyes...
anymore when I kiss your Lips.
There's no tenderness...
Like before in your fingertips.
You're trying hard
not to show it...
CROWD SINGING: Baby...
but, baby, believe me,
I know it.
You've Lost that loving' feeling.
Whoa, that Loving' feeling.
You've Lost that Loving' feeling.
Now it's gone, gone, gone.
Whoa-oh-oh.
Ba dum, ba dum,
ba dum, bum, bum.
Sit down.
Thank you.
Baby, baby...
I'II get down on my knees
for you.
I Love that song.
I've never seen that approach.
How long have you two
had this act?
Oh, I don't know. Since...
Puberty?
Right. Puberty.
I'm Charlotte Blackwood.
I'm Maverick.
Maverick?
Did your mother not like you
or something?
No. It's my call sign.
You're a pilot.
That's right. A naval aviator.
Oh.
Actually, we've only done this,
uh, twice.
Oh, how did you do?
Crashed and burned
on the first one.
It wasn't pretty.
And the second?
I don't know.
I'II tell you tomorrow...
but it's Looking good so far.
Well, uh...Maverick...
my friend's just arrived...
so it's been
great talking to you.
Perry. Hi.
Hi. Here you go.
I'II be with you
in just a second, OK?
Listen, can I ask you
a personal question?
That depends.
Are you a good pilot?
I can hold my own.
Great.
Then I won't have to worry about
you making a Living as a singer.
Hi.
-Here's your drink.
-Thanks.
I'm gonna need a beer
to put these flames out. Yo!
That's great, Mav. Real slick.
It was a Long cruise,
was it, sailor?
It was too long.
What'd you want to do...
just drop down on the tile
and go for it?
No. Actually,
I had this counter in mind.
Great. That would be very,
very comfortable. Yeah.
It could be.
Actually,
I came in here to save you...
from making a big mistake
with that older guy.
Really?
So I could make a bigger one
with a young guy like yourself?
Maybe.
I've got to be at work
early in the morning.
Then what are you doing here?
Your friend was magnificent.
Naw.
JESTER: You'll also be trained
and evaluated...
by a few civilian specialists.
The civilians are here...
because they are our best source
of information on enemy planes.
One of the most qualified
is our T.A.G.R.E.P.--
call sign, Charlie.
She has a Ph.D.
in astrophysics...
and she's also
a civilian contractor...
so you don't salute her,
but you better Listen to her...
because the Pentagon Listens
to her about your proficiency.
It's all yours, Charlie.
Thank you.
Hello. We will be dealing
with F-5s and A-4s...
as our MIG simulators.
Now, then,
as most of you know...
the F-5 doesn't have
the thrust to weight ratio...
that the MIG-28 has...
and it doesn't bleed energy
below 300 knots Like a MIG-28.
However, the MIG-28
does have a problem...
with its inverted flight tanks.
It won't do
a negative ''G'' pushover.
The Latest intelligence
tells us...
that the most it will do
is one negative--
Excuse me, Lieutenant.
Is there something wrong?
Yes, ma'am. The data on
the MIG is inaccurate.
How's that, Lieutenant?
I just happened
to see a MIG-28.
We! We.
Sorry, Goose.
We happened to see a MIG-28
do a four ''G'' negative dive.
Where did you see this?
That's classified.
It's what?
MAVERICK: It's classified.
I could I tell you,
but then I'd have to kill you.
Lieutenant,
I have top-secret clearance.
The Pentagon sees to it
that I know more than you.
It doesn't seem so in this case,
now, does it?
So, Lieutenant...
where exactly were you?
Well, we--
Thank you.
Started up on him when
he pulled through the clouds...
and then I moved above him.
If you were directly
above him...
how could you see him?
Because I was inverted.
Bullshit.
GOOSE: No, he was, man.
It was a really great move.
He was inverted.
You were in a four ''G''...
inverted dive with a MIG-28?
Yes, ma'am.
At what range?
Um, about two meters.
It was actually
about one and a half.
I've got a great Polaroid of it,
and he's right there.
MAVERICK:
It was a nice picture.
Uh, Lieutenant.
What were you doing there?
Communicating.
Keeping up foreign relations.
That was it.
Giving him the bird.
You know, the finger.
Yes, I know the finger, Goose.
I'm Sorry.
I hate when it does that.
Excuse me.
So you're the one?
Yes, ma'am.
AII right, gentlemen,
we have a hop to take.
The hard-deck on this hop
is 10,000 feet.
There'll be no engagement
below that.
Move it!
Lieutenant.
GOOSE: OK, well,
don't be late again.
You look great, honey.
MAVERICK: Thanks, dear.
See you in preflight.
Lieutenant,
why didn't you tell me...
that you were a famous
MIG insulter?
Would it have made
any difference?
Not in the ladies' room, no.
What would have?
I'm an instructor
at this school.
I see 20 new hotshots
every 8 weeks.
Now, I'm sure
you can figure that out.
Look, Lieutenant...
I'd just really like to hear
about the MIG sometime.
You've got security clearance.
You can read about it.
Maverick.
I'm curious.
Who was covering Cougar...
while you were showboating
with this MIG?
Cougar was doing just fine.
Uh-huh.
JESTER: Gentlemen,
this is your first hop.
The jets you are flying against
are smaller, faster...
and more maneuverable...
just like the enemy MIGs.
The clock is ticking,
and we're now keeping score.
I lost him, Goose!
Show me what you got, kid.
I lost him !
I'm looking!
Got him ! He's on our tail!
Coming hard!
Yeah, I got him. Here we go.
Talk to me, Goose.
He's still back there,
closing in on us.
He's closing fast.
You can run, kid,
but you can't hide.
Jester, let's see if I can
give you a run for your money.
Watch the mountains!
He's still back there.
Come on, Mav,
do some of that pilot shit.
Yeah, I got him.
Bring it right.
I've had about enough
of this shit.
I'II hit the brakes.
He'll fly past.
OK, you're mine.
Whoo!
Jesus Christ!
Let's see what
you got now, Jester!
OK, man, let's turn and burn!
He's going vertical. So am I.
We're going ballistic!
Go get him !
He's going
for the hard-deck.
Let's nail him first, Mav!
MAVERICK:
No way, Jester. You're mine.
I got you now!
Whoo!
Jester's dead, whoo-hoo!
Jester's dead, yee-haw!
Get your butts
above the hard-deck...
and return
to base immediately.
Yes, sir.
Tower, this is Ghost Rider
requesting a flyby.
Negative, Ghost Rider.
The pattern is full.
No, Mav,
this is not a good idea.
Sorry, Goose,
but it's time to buzz the tower.
[Sonic boom]
Goddamn son of a bitch!
GOOSE: Yee-haw!
Ha ha! Great balls of fire!
Yee-haw! Jester's dead!
You won? That's bullshit.
Didn't everybody?
Hell, no, man.
We got our butts kicked.
30 seconds.
We went like this.
He went like that.
I said to Hollywood,
''Where'd he go?''
Hollywood said,
''Where'd who go?''
He's laughing at us
right on the radio.
It's me laughing, dickhead.
We won!
AII right!
They won, too, man.
ICEMAN:
That's not what I heard.
GOOSE: We did. We got Jester.
SLINGER: Below the hard-deck
does not count.
Hard-deck, my ass.
We nailed that son of a bitch.
ICEMAN:
You guys really are cowboys.
MAVERICK:
What's your problem, Kazansky?
You're everyone's problem.
That's because every time you go
up in the air, you're unsafe.
I don't like you
because you're dangerous.
That's right...
Ice...man.
I am dangerous.
Maverick, you and Goose get your
butts out of that flight gear...
and up to Viper's office now.
Remember, boys.
No points for second place.
You're a lot brighter
than you look.
You shut up, OK?
Don't worry, Goose.
Two of your
snot-nosed jockeys...
did a flyby on my tower
at over 400 knots!
I want somebody's butt!
I want it now!
I've had it!
God damn it! That's twice!
I want some butts!
Well, that'll just about cover
the flybys.
Follow me.
Gentlemen...
you had a hell of a first day.
The hard-deck for this hop
was 10,000 feet.
You knew it, you broke it.
You followed
Commander Heatherly below...
after he lost sight of you
and called ''no joy.''
Why?
Sir!
I had Commander Heatherly
in my sights.
He saw me move in for the kill.
He then proceeded
below the hard-deck.
We weren't below 10,000
for more than a few seconds.
I had the shot....
there was no danger,
so I took it.
You took it...
and broke a major rule
of engagement!
Then you broke another one
with that circus stunt flyby.
Lieutenant Mitchell...
Top Gun rules exist for your
safety and that of your team.
They are not flexible,
nor am I.
Either obey them,
or you are history.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir!
Dismissed.
I really enjoyed that, Mav.
Thanks a lot.
Holy shit!
Ahh.
Maybe I could learn
how to be a truck driver.
You have the number
of that driving school on TV?
Truck Master, I think it is.
I might need that.
His fitness report says it all.
He's a wild card.
Flies by the seat of his pants.
Completely unpredictable.
He got you, didn't he?
Yeah.
Maverick.
I flew with his old man.
Tell me one thing.
If you had to go into battle,
would you want him with you?
JESTER: I don't know.
I just don't know.
Still awake?
Yeah.
What's up?
Can't sleep.
When I first realized
we were going to Top Gun...
all I could think about
was getting that trophy.
I gotta be
straight with you, Mav.
Right now,
I just hope we graduate.
I've got a family
to think about.
I can't afford to blow this.
I guess that flyby
wasn't such a big hit, huh?
Look, man,
I know it's tough for you.
They wouldn't let you
in the academy...
'cause you're
Duke Mitchell's kid.
You have to live
with that reputation.
But it's like every time
we go up there...
it's like you're flying
against a ghost.
Makes me nervous.
You're the only family I've got.
I'm not going to let you down,
I promise.
Get out of here.
A rolling reversal would work
well in that situation.
If I reversed on a hard cross...
I could immediately
go to guns on them.
At that speed, it's too fast.
It's a little bit
too aggressive.
Too aggressive?
Yeah, I guess
when I see something...
I go right after it.
You didn't tell me
who you were the other night.
You didn't give me a chance,
did you?
You deserved it.
I know.
But, uh, you were tempted...
to ask me out for dinner.
-No.
-No?
No. I don't date students.
I can see
it's dangerous for you...
but if the government
trusts me...
maybe you could.
It takes a lot more
than just fancy flying.
Crash and burn, huh, Mav?
Slider...
you stink.
Let's go!
OK, Ice, yeah!
KENNY LOGGINS SINGING:
I'd say it was the right time...
to walk away.
When dreaming
takes you nowhere...
it's time to play.
Bodies working overtime.
Money don't matter.
The clock keeps ticking.
Someone's on your mind.
Funny,
but it's always the same.
Playin',
playin' with the boys.
Stayin',
playin' with them boys.
After chasing sunsets...
one of life's simple joys...
is the boys.
I don't want to be the moth...
around your fire.
I don't want to be obsessed
by my desire.
You play too rough.
Playin',
playin' with the boys.
I'II be stayin'...
WOLFMAN: We won! We won!
GOOSE: Come on, Mav.
Just one more game.
That evens it.
We can take them.
I've got some things
I gotta take care of.
Just one more game.
Please? For me?
-Sorry.
-You're sorry? Come on.
WOLFMAN:
Mother Goose, you pussy!
Damn it.
CHARLIE: Lieutenant.
MAVERICK: Uh...
CHARLIE: What, no singing?
Look, I'm...I'm, um...
No apologies.
If you don't mind...
I'm gonna just take
a quick shower...
while you're
finishing up here.
Yeah. I do mind.
I'm hungry.
And then...
I thought about it.
I thought...
''You know, Charlie,
he's a smart guy.
''Why don't you just tell him
why you've got him here?''
Well?
It's the MIG.
The MIG.
You're the only pilot
who's been up against a MIG-28.
I'm trying for
this big promotion at work...
and if I get it,
I won't be here much longer.
Seems to me
you've got it all figured out.
Yeah.
Except you did forget the wine.
Oh.
Sorry.
You always get what you want?
No, not always.
Yeah, maybe.
Then relax about the MIG.
OTIS REDDING ON STEREO:
Sittin' in the mornin' sun...
MAVERICK: This music.
I'II be sittin'
when the evenin'...
CHARLIE: An old friend?
My folks loved it.
I haven't heard this in years.
My mother used to call down
from her room...
and have me play this
over and over again.
I got so sick of it.
But not her.
She'd just sit up there alone...
just listening for hours.
Just listening.
She died shortly after him.
What happened to your father?
I guess I kind of figured
with your security clearance...
you'd know more about him
than I do.
Well, I didn't get that far.
Oh.
Well, it's a big mystery.
He disappeared in an F-4
November 5, 1965.
The stink of it was...
he screwed up.
No way.
My old man was
a great fighter pilot.
But who the hell knows?
It's all classified.
Somebody must know.
Yeah, somebody knows everything.
Is that why you're always
second-best up there?
You are direct, aren't you?
I'm sorry I was late.
I'm sorry for being direct.
No apologies.
This is going to be complicated.
Where are you going?
I'm going to take a shower.
Thank you.
I enjoyed being here.
[Motorcycle starts]
It looks like you need
another shower.
Right.
I'm going to be honest with you.
Your MIG sighting is
really important to my work...
but, um...
I don't normally invite students
to my house.
You're, uh...
But please understand,
I still have a job to do.
-Morning.
-Sir.
I'm glad we got that straight.
I told her
how tough it is here--
my ass dragging
like an old tired dog.
I told her that you didn't
even have a woman here.
You know what she said?
''He probably doesn't have one.
He's got eight.''
BOY: Daddy!
CAROLE: So, you're in love
with one of your instructors.
MAVERICK: Is that right?
-I didn't tell her that.
-Yes, you did.
I can't believe you said that!
That was a secret.
VIPER: The bogey has
good position right here.
AII right, freeze frame.
Moment of choice.
The F-14 is defensive.
He has a chance to bug out
right here.
Better to retire
and save your aircraft...
than push a bad position.
Charlie, jump in here anytime.
You stay in that diamond
another three seconds...
the bogey's gonna blow you
out of the sky.
You take a hard right,
select zone five...
you can extend an escape.
You made a bad choice.
Charlie.
Aircraft one
performs a split ''S''?
That's the last thing
you should do.
The MIG's right on your tail.
Freeze there, please.
The MIG has you
in his gun sight.
What were you thinking
at this point?
MAVERICK:
You don't have time to think.
If you think, you're dead.
That's a big gamble with
a $30 million plane, Lieutenant.
Unfortunately,
the gamble worked.
The MIG never got a clean shot.
Maverick makes an aggressive
vertical move here.
Comes over the top...
and he defeats the bandit
with a missile shot.
The encounter was a victory...
but I think that we've shown it
as an example of what not to do.
Next.
Gutsiest move I ever saw, man.
Now, this is a perfect example
of a textbook maneuver.
Lieutenant.
Maverick.
Lieutenant!
My review
of your flight performance...
was right on,
in my professional opinion--
I can't hear you.
MAVERICK: Jesus Christ!
And you think I'm reckless!
When I fly,
I'II have you know...
that my crew
and my plane come first!
CHARLIE: I'm going to finish
my sentence, Lieutenant!
My review of your flight
performance was right on!
Is that right?
That is right.
But I held something back.
I see real genius
in your flying...
but I can't say that in there.
I was afraid that everyone
would see right through me.
And I just don't want anyone
to know I've fallen for you.
BERLIN PERFORMING:
Watchin' every motion...
in this foolish lovers' game.
Haunted by the notion...
somewhere there's a love
in flames.
Turning and returning...
to some secret place inside.
Watching in slow motion...
as you turn my way...
and say...
''Take my breath away...''
''my love.''
''Take my breath away,
my love.''
-Hey, Maverick.
-Yeah.
-You hear about Ice?
-What's that?
He won another one.
-Really?
-Yeah.
MAVERICK: I feel the need.
BOTH: The need for speed.
JESTER:
Gentlemen, this is hop 19.
Multiple aircraft,
multiple bogeys.
Your training is half over.
The competition for the Top Gun
trophy remains tight.
First place--Iceman.
Second place--Maverick.
Just two points behind.
There they are.
Three miles, left, 10 o'clock.
I don't think they see us yet.
OK, I see them.
Two A-4s, left, 10 o'clock.
Continue left turn.
Good morning, gentlemen.
The temperature's 110 degrees.
Holy shit! It's Viper!
Viper's up here. Great!
Oh, shit.
Great. He's probably saying...
''Holy shit,
it's Maverick and Goose.''
Yeah, sure he's saying that.
I've got my eye
on the northern bogey.
Roger. I got the southern guy.
Hollywood, you lead.
I'II cover you.
Break now, Jester.
Hollywood, we're losing Viper.
Let's stay on Jester.
Roger. I'm on him.
Goose, find Viper.
He's out there somewhere.
Stay with Hollywood, Mav.
We're covering his wing.
Goose! There's Viper.
Three o'clock low.
Stay with Hollywood.
We're his cover.
Don't you leave me, Maverick.
Hollywood, you're looking good.
I'm going after Viper.
Goddamn you, Maverick!
Mav, don't leave him.
Goose, Hollywood's OK.
I want Viper.
Stand by. Viper's coming down.
Holy shit, we're head-to-head.
I can't believe
we're doing this.
Whoo! Rock and roll!
Here's our chance!
It's a big one, Goose!
Come on, goddamn it!
Come on, Mav, keep coming!
OK, Sidewinder missile selected.
Come on, baby. Come on.
Come around, come around.
That's it, that's it.
Jesus, this guy's good!
Goose! Where's he going?
Come on! Come on!
Keep coming, keep coming!
Come on, baby.
Damn, this kid's good.
He's too close
for missiles, Goose.
I'm switching to guns.
Come on! Come on!
Stick with it.
Hold it! Goose, check our tail!
Shit! There's Jester!
Bingo, Maverick's dead.
You're out of there, kid.
Shit!
Defense Department
regrets to inform you...
that your sons are dead
because they were stupid.
Great balls of fire!
OK, knock it off, gentlemen.
Let's go home.
Viper has the lead.
30 seconds, Wolfman,
I'm coming in.
Shut up!
Butt nose.
JESTER: That was some of
the best flying I've ever seen.
Right up to the part
where you got killed.
You never,
never leave your wingman.
Maverick...
it's not your flying.
It's your attitude.
The enemy's dangerous...
but right now,
you're worse than the enemy.
You're dangerous and foolish.
You may not like your wingmen,
they may not like you...
but whose side are you on?
GOOSE: At least Viper
got Iceman before he got us.
We still got a shot at it.
MAVERICK: That was stupid.
I know better than that.
That will never happen again.
I know.
[Singing] You shake my nerves,
and you rattle my brain.
Thinkin' 'bout your love
drives a man insane.
You break my wiII.
Oh, what a thrill.
Goodness, gracious,
great balls of fire.
CAROLE: Would you go fetch him?
Doesn't he ever embarrass you?
MAVERICK: Hell, no.
Well, there was the time--
-Admiral's daughter.
-What?!
He told me all about the time...
you went ballistic
with Penny Benjamin.
MAVERICK:
Did he? Well, that's great.
CAROLE: He tells me
about all of them, Maverick.
How my Iittle angel, Goose,
goes home early for church...
and you, you always go home
with the hot women.
MAVERICK:
AII right, thank you, Carole.
I'm gonna go embarrass myself
with Goose for a while.
Whoo! Whoo hoo!
Ow!
BOTH: You shake my nerves,
and you rattle my brain.
Thinkin' 'bout your love
drives a man insane.
You broke my will.
Oh, what a thrill.
Goodness, gracious,
great balls of fire.
CAROLE: I'd love to be able to
warn you off about Maverick...
but I just love him to death.
I've known Pete
for a lot of years now...
and I'm telling you
one thing's for certain...
there are hearts breaking open
all over the world tonight.
Why?
Because unless you are a fool,
that boy is off the market.
in love with you.
Hey, Goose, you big stud!
That's me, honey.
Take me to bed
or lose me forever!
Show me the way home.
Come on.
Sing with the family.
A-ha!
[Singing] You shake my nerves,
and you rattle my brain.
Thinkin' 'bout your love
drives a man insane.
You broke my will.
Oh, what a thrill.
Goodness, gracious,
great balls of fire.
Yee-haw!
Ow!
Maverick...
you big stud.
Take me to bed
or lose me forever.
JESTER: OK, gentlemen,
this is hop 31.
Two weeks to graduation.
Top Gun trophy's
still up for grabs...
so every point counts.
KENNY LOGGINS SINGING:
Revvin' up your engine.
Listen to her howl and roar.
Metal under tension...
beggin' you to touch and go.
Highway to the danger zone.
Ride into the danger zone.
It's bottom of the ninth.
The score is tied.
It's time for the big one.
You up for this one, Maverick?
Just a walk in the park,
Kazansky.
Contact.
Multiple bogeys. 1-6-5.
Two miles. Looks like
they're going away from us.
Ho, I see them.
Tallyho.
Right, two o'clock. I'm in.
I'm in.
That son of a bitch
cut me off.
Come on, come on. Jesus Christ.
Ice, take the shot.
Ice, get the hell out of there.
I can't get the angle.
I'm too close for missiles.
I'm switching to guns.
Ice, fire or clear.
Look at this.
Jesus Christ, I could take
the shot right here!
I need another 20 seconds,
then I've got him.
I'm moving in.
I've got the shot.
Mav, let's get in there.
Come on, Mav.
Maverick's getting impatient.
Come on, take the shot.
Ten more seconds,
then I've got him.
Ice, get out of there.
Let's do it, Mav.
Ice, come off high right.
I'm in.
Five more seconds.
Come off high right, Ice.
I'm in.
I'm off him. Shit!
We're in his jetwash.
Holy shit!
GOOSE: This is not good.
We got a flame out back.
Engine one is out.
Engine two is out.
Goose, I'm losing control,
I'm losing control!
I can't control it.
It won't recover. Shit!
It's coupling up.
We're out of control.
This is not good.
ICEMAN: Mayday! Mayday!
Mav's in trouble.
He's in a flat spin,
heading out to sea.
Altitude 8,000! 7,000!
Six. We're at six, Mav.
Aah!
I'm pinned forward, Goose.
I can't reach
the ejection handle.
Goose, you have to punch us out.
I can't reach
the ejection handle.
Eject!
I'm trying.
Eject! Eject! Eject!
Watch the canopy.
Goose! Goose!
Oh, no.
Oh.
Oh, God.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Oh.
DIVER: Sir, let go of him.
You got to let him go, sir.
VIPER: How you doing?
MAVERICK: I'm all right.
VIPER: Goose is dead.
I know.
VIPER: You fly jets long enough
something like this happens.
He was my R.I.O.
My responsibility.
My squadron in Vietnam,
we lost 8 of 18 aircraft.
Ten men.
First one dies, you die, too.
But there will be others.
You can count on it.
You got to let him go.
MAVERICK:
I think maybe it was my fault.
I don't know.
I don't know
what the hell went wrong.
I'd like to help.
I know it's difficult.
God, I want him back.
I'II be here if you need me, OK?
God, he loved flying with you,
Maverick.
He'd have flown anyway...
without you.
He'd have hated it,
but he would have done it.
INQUIRY COMMANDER: We find that
the F-14 flat spin...
was induced
by the disruption of airflow...
into the starboard engine.
This disruption
stalled the engine...
which produced
enough yaw rate...
to induce a spin
which was unrecoverable.
There was no way...
Lieutenant Mitchell
could either see or avoid...
the jetwash
which produced the engine stall.
Therefore, the board finds
Lieutenant Pete Mitchell...
was not at fault
in the accident of 29 July.
Lieutenant Mitchell's record
is cleared of this incident.
Lieutenant Mitchell is restored
to flight status without delay.
These proceedings are closed.
Get him up flying soon.
JESTER: Come on, kid.
Get in there. Engage.
SUNDOWN: You got a bogey
at two o'cIock low.
You got the angle.
Piece of cake.
JESTER: Take the shot, kid.
SUNDOWN:
You can engage any time.
Hey, where the hell
are you going?
Uh, it's not good.
It doesn't look good.
It doesn't get to look
any better than that.
SUNDOWN: Hey, man,
we couId have had him.
Hey, we could have had him, man!
I will fire when I am
goddamn good and ready!
You got that?
JESTER: He can't get back
in the saddle. Won't engage.
VIPER:
It's only been a few days.
JESTER: You know,
he just might not make it back.
Keep sending him up.
Mitchell...
I'm sorry about Goose.
Everybody liked him.
I'm sorry.
Hi, it's Wolfman.
Yeah, Maverick just quit.
Excuse me.
May I?
Please.
CHARLIE:
I'II have what he's having.
Hemlock, is it?
MAVERICK: Ice water.
CHARLIE: You weren't going
to say good-bye?
I heard you got that job
in Washington.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
But I wasn't gonna leave
without saying good-bye.
It's good to see you.
CHARLIE: Thanks.
Where you going?
You don't even have a ticket,
do you?
I've seen all the evidence.
It's not your responsibility.
It's not your fault.
You're one of the best pilots
in the Navy.
What you do up there,
it's dangerous.
But you've got to go on.
You don't understand.
When I first met you...
you were larger than life.
Look at you.
You're not going to be happy
unless you're going mach two...
with your hair on fire.
You know that.
Naw, it's over. It's just over.
CHARLIE:
To be the best of the best...
means you make mistakes,
and then you go on.
It's just like the rest of us.
MAVERICK:
You don't think I know that?
I'm here to help.
Look, thank you.
But if I wanted help, really,
I would have asked for it.
So I'm too late.
You've already left.
You didn't learn
a damn thing, did you?
Except to quit.
You've got that maneuver down
real well.
So long, Pete Mitchell.
[Rings doorbell]
MRS. METCALF:
Well, hi, Maverick. Come on in.
-How you doing?
-Good.
-You sure you're feeling OK?
-Fine. Great.
-Can I get you a drink?
-No, thank you.
Make yourself comfortable.
Mike will be right down.
OK. Thank you.
I flew with your old man.
VF-51, the Oriskany.
You're a lot like he was,
only better...
and worse.
He was a natural heroic
son of a bitch, that one.
So, he did do it right.
Yeah, he did it right.
VIPER: Is that why you fly
the way you do...
trying to prove something?
Yeah, your old man did it right.
What I'm about to tell you
is classified.
It could end my career.
We were in the worst dogfight
I ever dreamed of.
There were bogeys like fireflies
all over the sky.
His F-4 was hit,
and he was wounded...
but he could have made it back.
He stayed in it.
Saved three planes
before he bought it.
MAVERICK: How come I never
heard that before?
That's not something the State
Department tells dependents...
when the battle occurred
over the wrong line on some map.
MAVERICK: So you were there?
VIPER: I was there.
What's on your mind?
My options, sir.
Simple.
First, you've acquired enough
points to show up tomorrow...
and graduate
with your Top Gun class...
or you could quit.
There'd be no disgrace.
That spin was hell.
It would've shook me up.
So you think I should quit?
I didn't say that.
The simple fact is you
feel responsible for Goose...
and you have
a confidence problem.
I'm not going to sit here
and bIow sunshine up your ass.
A good pilot is compelled
to evaluate what's happened...
so he can apply
what he's learned.
Up there, we got to push it.
That's our job.
It's your option, Lieutenant...
all yours.
Sorry to bother you
on a Sunday, sir...
but thank you very much
for your time.
VIPER: No problem. Good luck.
[Applause]
Gentlemen...
Where's Maverick?
I don't know where he is.
You know what
he's planning to do?
Got to be hard on the guy,
though, you know.
Good luck.
Hi, Mav.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
-Congratulations.
-Thanks, Mav.
Sir.
Gentlemen,
I hate to break up the party...
before it really
gets out of hand...
but there's work to be done.
Some of you have to depart
immediately.
We have a crisis situation.
-Ice, Slider!
-Yo.
-Hollywood, Wolfman!
-Yes, sir.
Maverick!
Sir.
Maverick, you'll get your R.I.O.
when you get to your ship.
And if you don't...
give me a call.
I'II fly with you.
Sir.
AIR BOSS JOHNSON:
Gentlemen, this is bull's eye.
The communications ship,
S.S. Layton...
has become disabled and wandered
into foreign territory.
A rescue operation
is to begin within the hour.
Your mission is to give
air support to that rescue.
There are MIGs in the area,
and tensions are high.
If you witness a hostile act,
you will return fire.
Those MIGs carry
the Exocet antiship missile.
They can fire them
from 100 miles away.
Gentlemen,
this is the real thing.
This is what
you've been trained for.
You are America's best.
Make us proud.
-Ice.
-Yes, sir.
-Hollywood.
Sector 2.
Maverick, you back them up
with Merlin on ready five.
Yes, sir.
Rise!
Excuse me, sir.
This is not personal...
but with regard to Maverick,
is he the best--
JOHNSON: I know what you're
thinking. Just get on it.
ICEMAN: Mustang, can you
give me a mode four check?
Voodoo-one, you got a pair
of bogeys, 12 o'cIock, 15 miles.
Voodoo-one, zero-nine-zero.
Radar contact 15 miles.
They're doing 500 knots.
Roger. That's your bogey.
SLIDER:
Got 'em dead ahead. 15 miles.
Air speed is 600 knots.
SLIDER:
Bogeys just hit 650.
Let's take a wider split.
They're at 15,000 feet.
Dead ahead, 10 miles.
Air speed is still increasing.
800 knots.
Dead ahead now. Eight miles.
'Wood, you got 'em?
Not yet. I can't see 'em.
They must be close.
I'm getting a hard-on.
'Wood, I'm taking the lead.
Let's identify 'em.
HOLLYWOOD:
Roger. You got the lead.
I'm on your left side,
a little low.
Maverick's up and ready
in alert five.
Good, good.
SLIDER: Hollywood,
my bogey's still locked up.
He's drifting to the left.
Still maneuvering on course
zero-nine-zero.
ICEMAN: OK, 'Wood,
let's bring it to the right...
and we'll get
a better angle on him.
SLIDER:
Ice, we got a problem here.
We've got four aircraft
on radar.
Not one pair, two pair.
Repeat, four bogeys!
'Wood, we got four bogeys.
Make that five!
There's five, sir.
That's five?
Yes, sir.
Oh, shit!
He's got a radar lock on us.
Get out of there, Hollywood,
God damn it!
Break left!
I'm hit! We're coming apart!
I can't control it!
We're going down!
'Wood's been hit!
Shit!
Voodoo-one, Wood's been hit!
We've lost Hollywood.
We've lost our wingman.
Launch Maverick on alert five.
Get a bearing
on Hollywood and Wolfman...
and launch the rescue helicopter
immediately.
Maverick's airborne.
MERLIN:
Iceman, what's your position?
ICEMAN:
Zero-nine-zero at 180 miles.
On the left!
Three MIGs, dead ahead,
coming down the left side!
ICEMAN:
I'm going after them.
I'm breaking around
to the left.
SLIDER: Four on our tail.
That makes six of them.
Lead MIG is coming
into gun range.
He's firing. Break right!
Mustang,
we are totally defensive!
Launch the alert fighters!
Where are they?
One hundred sixty miles
and closing in fast, sir.
Ready Willard and Simkin
off 'Cats Three and Four.
Maverick's supersonic.
I'II be there in 30 seconds.
ICEMAN: Haul your ass!
I'm engaged with five!
I'm in deep shit!
What about Willard and Simkin?
Both catapults are broken.
We can't launch
any aircraft yet, sir.
-How long?
-It'll take 10 minutes.
Bullshit, 10 minutes.
This thing will be over
in 2 minutes.
MIG, 12 o'clock high!
Watch your back!
Break right!
ICEMAN:
Shit, that was close.
Maverick, how about some help?
Come on, kid. Hang in there.
Jesus Christ!
Maverick, how about some help?
Engage, damn it!
He's on our tail!
Watch out!
Shit, we just flew
right through his jetwash!
Get control, get control!
MERLIN:
Good recovery, Mav.
OK, let's get in there.
Come on, we got to help Ice.
Let's get back in the game,
Maverick!
MAVERICK: It's no good.
MERLIN:
Get in there, Maverick!
God damn it!
Maverick's disengaging.
I knew it! Shit!
God damn it, Maverick!
MERLIN:
Maverick, you can't leave him !
Maverick, what are you doing?
MAVERICK: Talk to me, Goose.
MERLIN: Ice is in trouble!
MERLIN: He won't last alone!
Get in the fight,
for God's sake!
Maverick!
Maverick's re-engaging, sir.
I can't shake them !
Ice, I've got your MIG
dead ahead.
I've got him dead ahead.
Good tone. I've got good tone.
I got tone! Firing!
Where? Where are they?
One hundred fifty five miles.
Two MIGs dead ahead.
Closure 800 miles an hour!
I see 'em.
I'm gonna take 'em
down the left side.
MERLIN: Oh, my God!
Ice is right below us.
He's got a MIG on his tail.
He's firing! Break left!
He overshot!
I'm coming in, Ice.
Two MIGs dead ahead.
I got him, Mav,
one MIG passing between us.
MIG on your left, three o'clock!
He's going to fire!
Maverick, check the guys
to the north!
Banking left, banking left!
There he is!
Get him, Ice. Get him !
OK, you guys, I'm coming in.
Maverick, got a MIG on our tail!
We gotta get out!
I can't leave Ice.
He's still coming around!
He's gonna get behind us!
I'm not leaving my wingman.
I'm on his tail.
I'm going for it. I'm going
for the shot right now.
Roger, engage!
I've got radar lock.
I'm taking a shot!
Fire!
-Bingo!
-Wash that sucker!
Ice, MIG to your right!
He's firing!
I'm hit, I'm hit!
We're hit in the right engine!
I'm shutting it down!
Coming in, Ice.
That bogey's still behind you.
I'm maneuvering for a shot.
ICEMAN: Stay with him, Mav!
Take the shot! Nail him !
Ice, I can't get a tone.
Shoot, Maverick!
I can't get him off my tail!
Maverick, we're hit again!
It's OK.
Both engines are functioning.
Ice, on the count of three,
break hard right.
Three...
two...
one!
Break right!
Firing!
Damn it, I missed!
ICEMAN: Don't let him go.
Keep on him, Mav!
I got him.
Here comes a shot.
Concrete!
Maverick, move!
There's a MIG on your tail!
We've only got one missile left.
Approaching 110 miles, sir.
God damn it!
MERLIN: I got him !
He's on us! He's on our tail!
Shit!
You haven't lost him !
He's still with us!
What are you doing?
You're slowing down!
I'm bringing him in closer.
You're gonna do what?
This is it, Maverick!
I'm gonna hit the brakes.
He'll fly right by.
He'll get a lock!
Now!
I got a good lock.
Firing.
Whoo! Scratch four!
Mustang, this is Voodoo-three.
Remaining MIGs are bugging out.
[Cheering]
Mustang, this is Maverick,
requesting flyby.
Negative, Ghost Rider,
the pattern is full.
Excuse me.
Something I should know about?
Thank you.
God damn that guy!
Yeah!
You!
You are still dangerous.
But you can be my wingman
anytime.
Bullshit.
You can be mine.
Maverick. How does it feel
to be on the front page...
of every newspaper
in the English-speaking world?
Even though the other side
denies the incident...
congratulations.
Thank you, sir.
They gave you
your choice of duty--
anything, anywhere.
You believe that?
Where do you think
you want to go?
I thought of being
an instructor, sir.
Top Gun?
Yes, sir.
God help us.
THE RIGHTEOUS BROTHERS SINGING:
You never close your eyes...
anymore when I kiss your lips.
And there's no tenderness...
like before in your fingertips.
You're trying hard
not to show it...
baby...
But, baby...
baby, I know it.
You've lost that lovin' feelin'.
Whoa, that lovin' feelin'.
You've lost
that lovin' feelin'...
Hello, Pete Mitchell.
I heard the best of the best
were gonna be back here, so...
This could be complicated.
You know, on the first one,
I crashed and burned.
And the second?
I don't know...
but, uh...
it's looking good so far.
THE RIGHTEOUS BROTHERS:
So don't...
don't...
don't let it slip away.
Baby.
Baby...
I'm beggin' you, please.
Please.
I need your love.
Need your love.
Yeah, bring it on back.
Bring it on back.
Bring back...
that lovin' feelin'.
Whoa, that lovin' feelin'.
Bring back...
that lovin' feelin'.
Whoa, that lovin' feelin'...
[New song begins]
CHEAP TRICK PERFORMING: Ooh.
It's just a ball of dust...
underneath my feet.
It rolls around the sun.
It doesn't mean that much to me.
I take a chance
on the edge of life...
just like all the rest.
I look inside and dig it out...
'cause there's no points
for second best.
There's a...
ragin' fire in my heart
tonight...
growin'...
higher 'n' higher...
in my soul, oh.
There's a...
ragin' fire in the sky
tonight.
I want to ride
on the silver dove...
far into the night...
till I make you take me...
on your mighty wings.
Make you take me...
on your mighty wings
across the sky.
Take me on your mighty wings.
Take me on your mighty wings...
tonight.
Mmm, with just a littIe luck...
a little cold blue steel...
I cut the night
like a razor blade...
till I feel
the way I want to feel.
There's a...
ragin' fire
in my heart tonight...
growin'...
higher 'n' higher...
in my soul, oh.
There's a ragin' fire
in the sky tonight.
I want to ride
on the silver dove...
far into the night...
till I make you take me...
on your mighty wings.
Make you take me...
on your mighty wings
across the sky.
Take me on your mighty wings.
Take me on your mighty wings...
tonight.
Oh...
I'm going to make you take me...
on your mighty wings.
Make you take me...
on your mighty wings
across the sky.
Take me on your mighty wings.
Take me on your mighty wings...
tonight.
On your mighty wings.
Make you take me...
on your mighty wings
across the sky.
Take me on your mighty wings.
Take me on your mighty wings...
tonight.