[Bell Clanging]
[Train Horn Blows]
[Man Narrating] If you ask me,
there's a moment in everybody's life
when you're helpless-
just helpless with hope and trust.
And here you go.
[Narrator] And then something happens-
something too big to understand-
and then everything changes forever.
If you ask me, you start out
with goodness so pure and clear,
you don't even know it's there,
because that's the way it is
when you don't know anything.
And then-
- [Loud Thud]
- The news begins to arrive.
[All Screaming]
WAITING FOR FOREVER
♪♪ [Folk Rock]
[Man]♪ Someday you will find me ♪
- [Children Giggling]
- ♪ I haven't gone too far ♪
♪ I miss the way we were back then ♪
- ♪ How we laughed ♪
- [Children Laughing]
♪ I can feel you in my heart ♪
♪ There's a world in your eyes ♪
♪ I can see it getting brighter ♪
♪ All the hours
that we turned into days ♪
♪ We were young ♪
♪ Seemed like life would go on,
last forever ♪
♪ All I had was you by my side ♪
Emma.
[Man] Miss Twist?
You have to board now.
Thank you.
[Train Passing]
- [Children Giggling]
- ♪ Someday you'll answer ♪
♪ Remember how we were ♪
[Train Passes]
♪ When all our hopes and dreams ♪
[Children Laughing, Chattering]
♪ Just glided through the air ♪
♪ I can feel it in my heart ♪
- [Children Laughing]
- [Dog Barking]
♪ I can feel you in my heart♪
[No Audible Dialogue]
♪ That's the way that it was ♪
♪ In the past you remember ♪
♪ When we ran
through the winds and the rain ♪
♪ We were young ♪
♪ Seemed like life would go on,
last forever ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah ♪
♪ And now everything has changed ♪♪
[Woman]
Why you still chewin' on that cigar?
Here. Put it down.
I-I got to hold on to something-
something in this life.
Oh, my goodness.
I just wanted to say thank you
very much for picking me up.
Well, you welcome, young man.
Honey, he only stopped
and picked you up to annoy me.
- No, to neutralize you.
- What?
My birthday cigar-
now that's meant to annoy you.
- Wait. Today's your birthday?
- Actually, it was yesterday.
- Sixty-two years old.
- Well, happy birthday.
Well, thank you, young man.
Sit back.
Dorothy and me- we like to drive
straight through the night.
Ain't that right, Dorothy?
Yes, baby. That's right.
Give me this nasty thing.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Could you take me to the Carlton,
please?
- You got it.
- Thank you.
- [Man] You married?
- Not officially.
But l'll tell you the truth,
I might as well be.
- You got a girlfriend then?
- I certainly do.
That's why I'm going back
to Pennsylvania.
I'm going back to the place
where we both were born.
Her parents still live there.
- Her name is Emma.
- Emma.
Emma!
So how long have you and Emma
been together?
Oh. Well, what exactly
do you mean by "together"?
Well, together- a couple. Couple.
Well, I- I guess
I'd have to say forever, sir.
I mean, I-
We went to school until I was 10.
That's probably more what you mean.
And then I, um, moved away.
So you and Emma live together now
in Pennsylvania?
No, no. She's mostly in California,
but her dad is sick, I hear,
so she's-
- You-You hear?
- Pardon?
- You hear her dad is sick.
- No. My friend told me.
- My best friend Joey-
- Wait, wait. No, no, no, no, no.
Just- Just a moment now.
Maybe it's none of your business,
Albert.
- Dorothy!
- No. You leave that boy alone.
Dry up now.
Goodness.
Stop that. If you don't stop-
Stop that!
[Laughing]
Doggone you!
- You hound dog.
- [Laughing]
Silly man.
Here you go.
Hey. You know, I know this
may sound like a line, but...
aren't you that girl on the TV show?
You look just like this chick that's
on this TV show that my wife watches.
Actually, I am.
I am that person.
But it's a terrible TV show.
So I'm really sorry.
Um, here's your fare, and here's
a little extra for sitting through it.
Okay?
Thanks.
- Albert.
- What?
Albert, you should hear
this love story. Tell Albert.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
- You really want to hear that again?
- Tell him, baby.
Tell me what?
You're not gonna believe this, Albert.
Tell him.
So, we're in the fifth grade.
Me and Emma were always together.
Her house and mine- they seemed
pretty far apart back then,
but there was really just
a beautiful park between them.
When we weren't in school,
we spent hour after hour in that park.
- [Dogs Barking]
- [Giggling]
But it's funny- talking?
I don't remember talking.
I don't remember leading or following.
It was like we were
inside of something bigger...
that moved us around and took care of us
so we didn't have to
think about anything...
except flying on a swing
or running free.
[Train Horn Blows]
- And here you go.
- Thank you very much.
Anyway, one day
we're sitting in this classroom,
and as usual,
I was showing off for Emma.
But then the teacher tells us
to be quiet and listen to the news.
[Man On TV] It's a horrific event.
This is a train collision.
They are saying on the scene that at
least 10 of those injured are critical.
That number is expected to rise
as the e vening goes on.
[Narrator] Emma took me back to the
main road to wait for my mom and dad,
and we just sat there on this rock,
looking toward the bend.
You could hear the cars
before you could see them.
And every time you could hear the cars,
I'd think,
"Oh, boy. Oh, yeah. Here it comes.
Good again. Good again."
And after a while,
we went back to my house.
And no one would come right out and say
what my brother Jimbo thought-
that Mom and Dad
were in that train accident.
[Crash]
Emma- Emma took me outside, and-
and we just sat there for a long time.
[No Audible Dialogue]
Then she whispered something.
Well, the next morning I got up, and...
there was no car there.
And then I knew.
I knew Mom was never gonna
tuck me in again,
that my brother and I were gonna
have to move to Massachusetts...
to live with my aunt and uncle.
And I-
I had to say good-bye to Emma.
[Dorothy Sobbing]
Dorothy, pull over.
Let me drive, sweetheart.
Honey, would it be wrong for me to ask
what it was that she whispered to you?
Not at all.
What she whispered was...
- "They will always be there.
- Oh.
You will always be loved."
Can you believe that,
from a 10-year-old?
And get this.
- [Sobbing]
- She was right.
Oh, my goodness.
- Dorothy.
- What?
I mean it, sweetheart. Pull on over.
You're weaving all over the road.
- Okay. Okay.
- Pull over. Let me drive, sugarplum.
- All right?
- Mm-hmm.
[Dorothy Sobbing]
[Albert] Come on, Dorothy.
[Rings]
[Man] Miranda. Miranda!
I'm getting it. I'm inside now.
- Hello?
- Hey, Mom.
Emma.
We have been on pins and needles, honey.
Where are you?
- [Man] Why didn't she call?
- I missed the connection.
Oh. Her plane has been delayed.
She'll be here tomorrow.
- Is Aaron with you?
- No.
Oh. I'm so disappointed.
- I'm okay, Mom.
- Mm-hmm.
- Aaron's not with her.
- Good. He's a jerk.
Shh, shh.
We watched the show last week.
We loved it.
You were so good. You both were.
Yeah, well, honey, why they canceled it-
we-we just can't figure that out.
Yeah. All right.
How are you? You sound a little-
No, no. I'm- I'm great. I'm fantastic.
Oh.
[Inhales] Oh, I'm so excited.
- Me too.
- Yeah, I guess I'll see you tomorrow.
- Bye. Love you.
- Okay. Me too. Bye.
[Man On Radio] And looking at your
Los Angeles traffic this afternoon,
[Cell Phone Beeping]
Sig Alert on the 405 southbound-
[Miranda] Hello?
Yeah. Hi. Is, uh- Is Emma there?
No. I'm sorry. She's not.
But she should be here soon though.
May I- May I ask who's calling?
[Horn Honks]
- Hey. What's up, Aaron?
- How could you do this?
What?
- Aaron.
- Yeah, Emma told me.
Well, it's not like you
never mess around on Emma!
I went out with her once.
Hey! [Thuds]
[Miranda] May I ask who's calling?
Hello?
Wait, baby.
Okay. Here's our address
and our phone number.
- Put it somewhere safe.
- Okay.
You won't lose it? You won't forget?
Forget? Even if it takes 50 years,
I'm inviting you to the wedding.
Oh! Oh!
[Groans]
- You take care of yourself. You hear me?
- You too.
Bye-bye.
Jimbo.
[People Chattering]
[Man]
Make that in fives and 10s, please.
- Thanks for calling me.
- Thank you so much.
Jimbo! Jimbo!
It's so good to see you, big brother.
Good seeing you.
[Man] What's up with that?
Look at this tie.
This is a beautiful tie.
- Look at you, huh?
- You look terrific.
Go. Get your bag.
What was that?
Wow.
High. The ceilings are so high.
- It's like a temple.
- Mm-hmm.
Leather.
Sorry.
Listen. You gotta call, pal. All right?
That's all there is to it.
Call? I didn't even know
until, like, four days ago.
So four days ago you call, okay?
You can't just come blowing into town
and start playing with my tie
in front of everybody.
Come on. You haven't seen
your little bro in a long time.
- Give the poor guy a smooch.
- A smooch.
Willie.
He really is very happy to see me.
- [Slaps Desk]
- Hey. Uh-uh. Don't.
No. Don't do that, all right?
Look at me.
Okay?
Cut that out right now, or we're gonna
have a very bad time here, my friend.
Do you hear me?
[Sighs]
So let me guess.
- Emma's back.
- Her dad's sick, so she came home.
You're still following her
all around like a puppy dog?
And you still haven't said
one word to her.
- [Phone Rings]
- Very good, Will.
[Woman On Intercom]
Jim Donner. Line three.
Jim Donner, mortgages. Could you please
hold on for one second? Thank you.
Kind of busy around here, Will.
Okay.
Um, I'm gonna go to Joey's.
Go to Joe's.
It was good to see you.
Yeah. Can I have the account number,
please?
...668?
- Thanks.
- [Door Closes]
[Door Chimes]
Bap-bap.
Dolores, baby. Get out here.
Up, up.
- What?
- It's Willie.
- Willie?
- Willie's here.
- [Laughing]
Willie!
- Hey.
- It's so good to see you!
You too.
- Oh!
- All right. Come here. Come here.
- Come here.
- Gosh!
[Laughing]
Welcome home, buddy.
You've gotta introduce me to this one.
Say hi.
- Hey, Gabe.
- Say hi to Willie.
[Imitating Clattering Toy]
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
[Door Opens]
Hi, Mom.
[Chuckling]
Oh. Oh, my baby.
My baby. My baby.
Oh, you're really here.
Look at you. Oh, my golly.
- You look so wondeful.
- Yeah?
Oh, your eyes. No. Really.
They are so clear and bright.
- Are they?
- Yeah. They are, honey. They really are.
You look so- mmm- happy.
I do? You- You do too.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. You do too.
Oh.
I missed you.
Missed you so much.
So much.
Daddy's fine. You'll see. Come on.
Oh, I'm so sorry
that Aaron couldn't come.
Oh-
- Are you hungry?
- Uh, no, I just want to see Daddy.
Oh. Well,
he wants to see you too, sweetheart.
- So much. So much.
- How is he?
Oh, you know,
the doctors say all kinds of things.
One says kidneys.
Another says the... liver.
[Father] They say anything about ears-
that my ears are going?
[Sighs]
I'm dying. Let's get this show
on the road. Mmm.
Huh.
Hey.
- [Chuckles]
- Hi, Daddy.
Oh!
You're looking good. [Chuckles]
You didn't have to come home.
- I really wanted to come home.
- Hmm.
You know, I don't know why. I just can't
imagine any lack of entertainment...
out there in the entertainment
capital of the world.
Unless you find dying entertaining.
Oh, Dad. You're not dying. Stop that.
- Yeah, well, I know I'm not.
- [Sighs]
Well, then why do you say such things,
hmm?
Oh, you know, for laughs. Just-
I thought that was your game
these days- comedy.
[Sighs]
[Chuckles]
[Exhales]
I should probably go put my stuff away.
Yeah. You don't want to have
too much fun all at once.
Okay.
[Sighs]
- Our baby.
- Would you stop with the-
[Sighs]
I'm gonna be frank with you.
This is such an easy to operate oven
that I let my son operate it.
- Joe, this is fantastic!
- This is a three-year-old-
I'm so proud of you.
I mean, it's been long enough.
Hold on to this for a second.
My wife needs me right now.
I keep my family in the store.
I'll be right back.
- I'll be right with you.
- I'm really proud of you.
What is it?
He said he's gonna knock on Emma's door
and tell her everything.
[Chuckles] That-a-boy.
- When?
- Soon.
- How soon?
Soon. Okay. But how soon, Will?
Today or tomorrow.
- Listen, Will.
- [Gabe Roars Playfully]
- Let's listen to Daddy.
- I want you to look at me in the eyes,
and I want you to give me
your word of honor...
that today, or tomorrow,
you're gonna go to Emma's house
and you're gonna knock on her door...
and you are finally gonna get
this asinine bull honky over with.
Okay?
Gabe-
[Grunts]
I'm gonna tell Emma everything.
Okay? I'm gonna tell her
that I love her. Yeah?
That I've always loved her.
That in my dreams...
I breathe her in-
I inhale her,
and I feel her right here.
Here. Here. In the blood in my heart.
Here. Blood.
[Will] Heart. Heart.
Okay. Hold on. Just wait a second, Will.
What?
In the blood in your heart?
That's insane.
In his blood. It's very nice.
You know, what's wrong with you?
Let him go on.
I'm sorry, sir, but I am just not
used to being ignored. Now-
I'm really sorry. Uh, actually,
let me ask you a question.
I see you've got your lovely husband
here, and he's being very patient.
What would you say if he
came to you one day, and...
he told you that in his dreams
he sucks you into his lungs,
and at that point
you go into his bloodstream?
And you're actually- physically
you are inside of his blood,
inside of his heart-
the chambers and valves and such.
How would that make you feel?
Oh!
Well, now.
- Isn't that tub nice?
- Mmm.
It's supposed to be just for
your father, but I love it.
- Do you love it?
- I do.
Oh, thank you.
[Emma] Hmm.
- It's so weird.
- What, honey? What's weird?
I don't know.
I was little. Suddenly I'm not little.
[Chuckles]
I mean, that tree house-
it seems like a dream.
I remember Daddy making it.
I was the nail girl.
Now look at it.
Look at me. [Chuckles] Look at us.
Poof. It's just so weird.
[Sighs]
Was I a nice little girl?
Oh, for heaven sakes,
why would you even ask me that?
You were the most wonderful,
clever, bright,
happy, happy,
happy little girl that ever was.
And you haven't changed a bit.
[Miranda Groans]
Are those bugs getting to you?
Because they're certainly getting to me.
- Let's go inside.
- Okay.
[Gasping]
[Train Passing]
At least I know where to find you.
Susan's making dinner.
Kids want to see you. Get in.
[Gasping]
What's wrong with you?
I don't know.
You don't know?
- Nothing. It's okay. I'm fine.
- Mm-hmm.
I just gotta make sure
that you're real children.
It's very important with juggling.
Not- Not little goblins
or anything like that.
The child here is not real.
It's an alien.
- [Giggling]
- [Laughing]
All right. Okay.
Really. I'm gonna- Whoa. Whoa.
- Higher!
- Okay.
- Yay!
- [Giggling]
- [Sizzling]
- Food!
- Ooh! Ooh!
- Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
- Oh! Oh!
- [Splash]
[Both Laughing]
[Girl] He gets paid 40 bucks.
Isn't that right, Uncle Will?
We're gonna have to get Q-tips,
because I said "ducks."
- I get paid in little fuzzy baby ducks.
- Ducks?
- [Quacking]
- Wait, wait. Wait, wait, wait.
Is that really true, Willie?
- Do you really make $40 a day?
- Uh, on a good day.
Wow. See?
- [Boy Chuckling]
- Yeah?
How much you paying in tax
on that $40 that you're making?
Come on. You've gotta be kidding.
Really, Jim?
What? I'm just curious. Does he pay tax
on the money that he makes?
What's wrong with that? Should I?
You don't need to pay any income tax.
Okay?
Want some dessert?
Maybe you'd like a cup of coffee
or tea or something like that?
- Yeah.
- That's the solution...
to the problem, Will.
You just don't worry about it.
Problem? What problem? I mean,
where's the problem?
He- He doesn't have a problem.
He doesn't have a problem.
He doesn't have a home.
Hey, guys. Eat your salad.
Please. Thank you.
He doesn't have a job. I have a home.
No. A room in some
fleabag motel is not a home.
Doesn't have any clothes.
Doesn't have a car.
- I had a car.
- You had a car?
Yeah, but I hated it, 'cause I always
had to put it somewhere.
Yeah. Life is tough,
having to put that car somewhere.
Aren't pajamas clothes?
[Chuckles]
Can I tell you something right now?
There's nothing like 'em.
Just-Just feel 'em. Feel 'em. Yeah.
- They're soft.
- [Girl] It's so soft.
They're cheap. And your legs-
Your legs-
They're just as free as a bird.
Just comes out of nowhere.
- Oh, yeah!
- Oh, Uncle Will!
Kids. Go inside. Go.
[Girl] Aw.
Go play. Come on.
Give us a couple minutes.
Come to me.
- No?
- [Giggling]
You remember that TV show?
What TV show?
You remember. It was that,
um- that news show,
where you said that guy was Will.
Anyway, Willie, so listen.
There was this news program, okay?
And there was this guy who had this cat.
Now, all day long,
he had to check the refrigerator...
to make sure that he didn't
put the cat inside of there.
- The refrigerator?
- That's right, Will. The refrigerator.
- And the cat?
- That's right, Will. The cat.
He was nuts.
[Susan] Hey. You know what?
He wasn't nuts. He had a disorder.
Yes, Will. A disorder called F'ing nuts.
Now, as soon as this lunatic closed
the door, he had to open it again...
to make sure that the cat wasn't inside.
All day long, right? He was doing this.
He was opening, closing, opening, closing.
And he talked about it-
Talked about it very clearly.
Like it was a very reasonable
thing for him to do.
Because who knows?
Maybe the cat could have
gotten in there, right?
Before he saw it.
Before he closed the door.
And so Susan leans over to me,
and she says,
"That guy"-
She says, "That's your brother."
Hmm? She says, "That's Will with Emma.
He can't help it."
And you know what, Willie?
She's right.
Okay? You talk like following
this woman around everywhere...
is something that makes sense,
but it doesn't.
Okay? It doesn't make sense. It's called
stalking, and it's against the law.
And I want you to stop telling my kids
that life is nothing
but a bowl of cherries...
and that everything is just peachy,
okay?
What life is, what isn't-
that's my area. All right?
I'll handle that topic with my kids,
if that's all right with you.
Our mother said "peachy."
I remember it. She used to say,
"If this isn't peachy,
I don't know what is."
Jimbo says "peachy."
Willie, how did this whole thing start?
I don't know.
For a while, uh,
after the train,
I'd come back here in the summer,
and I'd see her.
And then I- I stopped coming back.
Um- But we'd write.
Then that stopped.
So, when she went off
to college in Oregon,
I just-
I just went to Oregon.
And when you follow Emma, how-
how often do you actually see her?
It doesn't matter.
It's just being around
where she might be.
That's plenty.
I, uh-
Here.
I think it would be best for everybody
if I just went back to Joey's.
[Father] I don't know whether I'm dying
or I'm not dying.
I just- I don't understand why you
find the topic of death objectionable.
- I don't find it objectionable.
- Yes, you do.
I can see it in your face you do.
He's joking. Can't you tell he's joking?
[Sighs] You know, before you leave,
do you think you could
take your mother aside
and explain the concept of punch lines?
See, jokes have punch lines. Me
talking about being dead- no punch line.
- Me dead- big punch line.
- [Laughs] You're too much.
Isn't he too much?
[Sighs]
So, honey, tell us about everything.
Tell us. Just tell us.
Mmm, everything, like what?
Oh, uh, you know, California,
the show, Aaron.
How's- How's everything with Aaron?
Eh-
Oh, no. You're not having problems?
Not really. I don't know.
Sometimes things just get complicated.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. Well, sweetheart,
you know what you have to do?
You have to just-
[Whistles] un-complicate them.
[Sighs] I am hating this. [Chuckles]
- Hating what?
- [Sighs] Hating this.
This moment. This moment in my life.
You have no idea how I detest this.
[Cutlery Clinks]
Richard, that is not acceptable.
You haven't seen
your daughter in, uh, what,
over two years.
And she's traveled
3,000 miles to see you,
and you make a comment like that.
No. That's- I don't know why. Why?
Because I was joking, Miranda.
That was a joke. Just a little joke.
What the-
You were hating it too.
I know you were. I could see it.
[Sighs]
So how is Aaron?
- [Chuckles]
- [Giggles]
[Air Blowing]
- That's cool. You have enough covers?
- Yeah.
- You want another pillow?
- I'm good.
All right.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
I had that same thing once, Willie,
when I couldn't breathe.
- You did?
- Yeah.
I was maybe six.
I got lost in this great big store-
a department store or something.
Everything was really high up.
I didn't know where I was.
I didn't know where to go.
Couldn't find my mom or my dad.
All these strange faces
just looking down at me.
And my throat just closed up.
Yeah.
That's what it was.
My throat just closed up.
Yeah. It's normal.
It's just terror.
Good night.
Night.
♪♪ [Folk Rock]
- [Man] ♪ Though the days are long ♪
- What do you think?
- You look great.
- Yeah?
- Thank you.
- ♪ Twilight sings a song ♪
♪ Of a happiness that used to be ♪
- Say bye-bye.
- Good luck, Will.
Bye.
♪ Soon my eyes will close ♪
♪ Soon I'll find repose ♪
♪ And in dreams
you're always near to me ♪
♪ I'll see you in my dreams ♪
[Giggling]
♪ Hold you in my dreams ♪
♪ Someone took you out of my arms ♪
♪ Still I feel ♪
♪ The thrill of your charms ♪
♪ And I'll see you in my dreams ♪♪
Aaron?
- [Chuckles]
- Oh, my gosh.
I can't believe this.
- Oh, what a surprise.
- [Chuckles]
- Come in. Come in. I'm sorry.
- Uh, you, uh- you, uh- you must be-
- Emma's mother. Miranda.
- Right.
I-I can't believe this. I'm so goofy,
I couldn't even introduce myself.
- Oh, well, I didn't.
- I must seem like a-
- Like a- I don't know what.
- No, no, no. Not at all.
- A goofy teenager or something.
- No. No, no.
Does she know-
Does she know you're here? Because, uh-
Em!
Does she? Because she
didn't say anything. Does she know?
- No. No, no. Actually, she doesn't.
- She doesn't know you're here.
- Well, that's even better.
- Yeah?
Honey, look.
[Chuckles] Can you believe?
Look who's arrived.
[Chuckles]
I forgive you.
Oh, is this when I'm supposed to say
I forgive you too?
Forgive me for what, Emma?
[Miranda] Oh!
No! Richard!
- [Richard] What just happened?
- Richard!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Mom.
I'll clean it up later.
[Richard] Miranda.
- What the heck's going on?
- I'm sorry.
What?
Uh, uh-
- [Knocking]
- Oh. Excuse me.
- Yeah.
- Oh, I wonder who that could be.
Yeah. What?
- [Richard] Who's there?
- Are you selling something?
- Miranda.
- No.
I'm sorry. We're having
a very busy moment here.
- C-Come back another time.
- Uh-
[Miranda Sighs Deeply]
Why don't-
Why don't you come into the kitchen.
- I'm sorry.
- Come into the kitchen.
[Out Of Breath]
[Miranda] Uh-
Well, why- Why don't-
Why don't you sit, Aaron.
Right.
Can I, uh- Can I get you something?
No. Thank you.
- You sure?
- Yes, yes.
Ah.
I'm just gonna clean up a little bit,
if you'll excuse me.
I'll be right-
[Out Of Breath]
[Sighs]
He told her he forgave her.
- For what?
- I don't know.
- Oh, for crying-
- Richard. Richard.
Forgive her for what?
- Mr. Twist.
- Forgive her for what?
I really think it's best
if it comes from Emma, sir.
[Groans]
Forgive her for what?
She cheated on me...
with a friend of mine.
Well, let's not share this
with her mother, okay?
- Okay.
- [Chuckles]
- You okay?
- Uh, yeah.
[Chuckles]
[Hinges Creak]
[Miranda] Sweetheart,
I brought you some nice soup.
And Aaron called.
He-He wants me to tell you
that he's staying at the Colonial.
Okay? So that's where he is.
All right. Well, now you just rest.
I'll, uh- I'll leave
your soup by the door.
Sweetheart.
- I'm going out.
- Oh, that's wonderful.
- Did you have your soup?
- Yeah. Thank you.
Oh, good for you.
And so good to see you up.
Take- Take the Volvo if you want.
[Emma] No, I'm walking.
I just want to walk.
Oh. Okay. Well, have fun.
Um, yeah. Enjoy yourself.
"Enjoy yourself"? "Enjoy yourself"?
- [Laughing]
- Yes. Yes. "Enjoy yourself."
I mean, she could use some enjoyment.
Why is that not a good thing to say?
Enjoyment? What do you think? She's
gonna take a walk to the lollipop store?
Lollipop store? What lollipop store?
I don't even know what you're
talking about, lollipop store.
Well, that's refreshing.
Usually you have no idea that you
don't know what I'm talking about.
[Chuckles]
It could be me, Richard.
It could be me.
But couldn't it also be you?
I mean, the way you speak to me-
Honey, sweetheart, please.
You tell me what you mean
by the lollipop store.
And then I will try to respond.
I want to respond. I do.
I really want to talk
about our daughter.
I want to talk about Emma,
our little girl,
because I-
I think that it's killing- killing me.
I think that it's killing me
to see her like this.
Do you have any idea how unattractive
the expression on your face is right now?
I hate you.
Good.
You are so horrible to me.
Oh, that-a-girl. Now you're talkin'.
Huh? Now you're talkin'.
I wish you were dead. I do.
Oh. Miranda. Remember this.
- I want you to die.
- Oh!
I want you to die, 'cause I hate you!
- Okay!
- I do! I hate you!
Listen to this.
Hang on to this. Hang on.
- I hate you! I hate you!
- [Door Closes]
- Remember this!
- I hate you!
No! I hate you! I hate you.
Keep it up. Keep it up. You're strong.
- I hate you!
- That's strong. Hold on. Hold on.
- [Sobbing]
- Hold on. Hold on.
Don't lose it. Okay.
- All right. Shh.
- [Sobbing]
Okay. No, no, no.
Come on, come on, come on.
Oh, no, no, no.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Oh, no.
It's okay. It's okay.
You need to be strong when I'm gone.
[Sobbing]
You're my girl.
You're my girl. You're my strong girl.
Do you have any idea...
how beautiful the expression
on your face is right now?
[Chuckles]
It's okay.
[Erratic Breathing]
Emma?
- Yeah?
- It's-
It's Will.
Willie?
Oh, my goodness. Hi.
Wow! Hey.
- Hi.
- Hey.
[Both Chuckling]
Will Donner.
Um- How-
I- I was- I was just walking,
and I just saw you.
This is really something. How are you?
- I know. I- I'm good. I'm really good.
- How are- How are you?
I'm fine. Doing fine.
I-
- Weird. I don't know.
- I know. I know.
Gosh. Look at you. Whiskers.
Look at you. Breasts.
[Laughing]
Yeah.
So, what? Do you-
you live here now? Did you move here?
- I'm here. I'm always here.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Well, what?
Did you just move back, or-
No.
- You're just visiting?
- Yeah.
Yeah. I'm just visiting.
What's it been? Like years and years.
It's been forever.
It was the end of summer.
I was visiting Joey, remember?
It was all muggy and hot out,
and then we went swimming,
but you hsd to go to your dance lesson.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Joey-
I haven't thought about him in so long.
Hey. Emma.
- Yeah?
- Uh-
Do you want to go sit somewhere?
Oh, Willie, I can't.
I'm meeting somebody.
I'm really happy to see you though.
You look really great.
Thanks.
You look beautiful.
Thank you.
But I- I would also say you look like
you've been through the wringer.
Do you want to walk
with me for a little?
- Sure.
- Okay.
[Door Closes]
- Hey, Jimbo. Is my brother around?
- Uh, he's not actually.
Uh, you know, today's the big day.
Didn't you know that?
- Know what?
- He finally went to Emma's.
No, no. See? See, this is the thing.
- What thing?
- He's sick. All right?
And somebody's gotta do something. Okay?
Somebody's gotta step in.
- What are you talking about, he's sick?
- Just look at him.
Who is he talking to half of the time?
Jimmy, you know exactly
who he's talking to.
Oh, I do?
Your mom and your dad.
You know what he thinks
about his mommy and daddy?
He thinks they went to a Broadway show
on a Thursday afternoon.
Matinee on a Thursday?
No, that doesn't happen.
You ever see my mother
without a cigarette in her hand?
My Fair Lady? No way.
Dad was taking her
to radiation treatments.
Breast cancer,
lung cancer, liver cancer.
And how do I know this? How do I know?
I know because he told me...
when I was 11.
He wants to believe in this...
fairy tale.
You know? Our beautiful mother,
our- our handsome father-
frickin' Prince Charming, Cinderella.
Matinee my ass. Everything was as bad
as it could get, and then it got worse.
Willie, this is where I'm going.
[Sighs]
Well, looks to me like you're not
so crazy about going in.
I have to, Willie.
Emma.
There's something I've wanted to
say to you for a long time.
A long, long time.
Uh, Pistilli's is right
around the corner.
We used to go there all the time.
Maybe we could sit down in Pistilli's,
and l'll buy you a soda, and, uh-
and l'll tell you what I have to say.
Won't take long. I promise.
I really can't, Willie.
Okay.
But if you won't come with me, then
I'm gonna wrap myself around your leg,
and you're gonna have to
drag me everywhere you go...
for the rest of your life.
Come on.
Do I really look terrible, Willie?
Uh, horrible.
Truly? Come on.
No, no. What you look is tired.
Oh, Willie.
So where do you live now?
Uh, I guess I would have to say...
I'm in the process of choosing
somewhere to live at the moment.
- Oh, that can be exciting.
- Oh, yeah. It is very exciting.
[Laughing] What do you do?
Uh, "do"?
Yeah. You know,
for a living- to make money.
Guess.
- What?
- I'll show you.
These will work.
- [Man] Wow. What's he doing?
- I'm sorry.
- I can't believe he took my-
- This.
This is what I do for a living.
Wow.
[Man] Look at that.
[Man #2] Wow. Whoa, buddy.
I, uh, show off for you.
- For me?
- Yeah.
Come on.
- [Woman] Thanks.
- [Man] Good job.
Hi. Welcome to the Dirty Truth.
Just sit anywhere you like.
[People Chattering]
♪♪ [Background: Rock]
[Cell Phone Ringing]
I really have to go, Willie.
Wait.
Look.
Those are our stools.
They kept the same stools.
These are the stools we always sat on.
Hey, buddy. Uh, could I ask you
to please do me a huge favor?
Would it be okay if you and your gal
just moved over two stools?
Why?
You're not gonna believe this,
but, years ago, this place
was a soda shop...
and, uh, those were our stools.
Now, would it be okay
if you just moved over?
- No, it wouldn't be okay.
- Really?
Yeah, really.
I can't believe that.
It's fine. We should go.
I'm really just curious.
Why wouldn't you do that?
Okay, look, if you wanna fight,
I gotta tell you something.
You picked the ideal guy,
because you will cream me.
I don't know what it is.
I got no fighting skills whatsoever.
None. It's pathetic.
The idea of being hit in the nose-
It's just- It's that sound.
It's that crunch.
This is a peaceful place
for me. It's a no-fly zone.
Hit me in the shoulder. No, no. Don't.
- That's my second-favorite place.
- [Laughing]
- You couldn't do better than
this clown? - He's not a clown.
I actually- I kind of am.
But how did you know that?
It's all right, babe. Let's just go.
Thank you.
Our stools.
Um, do you remember
how they used to spin?
This one is kind of gunked up.
- Try yours.
- No.
Come on. Just one.
Just one little spin.
- [Stool Squeaking]
- Oh.
Emma Twist is twistin'.
[Laughing]
Do you see? She's back.
Oh. Could you bring me a bottle...
of the cheapest champagne
you can get your hands on?
Comin' right up, sir.
Look at Mr. Big Shot ordering booze.
- What are you doing?
- We're celebrating.
No. I mean when you're
talking like that-
talking to no one.
You know who I'm talking to.
- No, I don't.
- You know.
No, Willie, I really don't.
Say hello. They've been missing you.
Remember what you said?
"Do you know that you will
always be loved?"
Willie.
Oh, Willie.
[Sighs Deeply]
Okay?
[Sniffles] Almost.
Yep. I'm okay. [Laughs]
[Sighs] You're not a clown.
Thank you.
- Here you go, sir.
- Ah.
Perfect.
Yeah. Um, thanks.
Come.
Come, come, come, come, come, come.
Oh, I used to love that.
[Laughs] What?
[Emma] This was so not meant for heels.
[Cell Phone Ringing]
[Ringing]
[Murmurs]
What is happening to me, Will?
What do you mean?
I don't know.
I feel like I'm going crazy.
I know I said that everything was fine,
but everything's not fine.
Why does everything have to be so hard?
You know? Why can't it just be easy?
I just have to keep on pretending
and pretending and pretending...
just to keep myself from
bawling my eyes out forever.
Maybe you have a lot to cry about.
Do you want any of this?
[Sniffles]
I don't either.
What are you doing?
[Laughing]
Come on.
[Grunts]
Feez!
- Okay.
- [Yelps, Laughs]
[Laughing]
[Squeals]
Wait. Stop, stop, stop,
stop, stop, stop.
Touch my knee right here
where my finger is.
I feel nothing. Nothing.
Completely numb.
Do you know why?
Why?
'Cause you and I were sitting
on this merry-go-round,
and you got off 'cause you were scared
'cause it was going so fast.
But I stayed on,
and then I went flying off...
and landed right on this knee.
And ever since then,
this spot right here has had
no feeling whatsoever.
- Remember?
- Yeah.
I do remember that.
Close your eyes.
- Do you feel this?
- Yeah.
- This?
- No.
- [Laughs]
- That's the spot.
Nothing.
Oh!
You know that person that I'm supposed
to meet at the motel?
Mm-hmm.
Well, he came by my house today,
and I just started
throwing things at him.
Is he a friend of yours?
He wants to marry me.
[Sighs]
Uh, well,
it sounds to me like, uh, if-
What with all
the throwing things and whatnot,
you're leaning toward not wanting
to marry him back.
I mmet someone else.
Okay. Um- Someone else?
I cheated on my boyfriend
with this other person.
[Sighs]
It's the way I did it. You know?
It was so sloppy. I was so selfish.
If you- If you don't like what you did,
then tell the person you hurt
that you're sorry.
What else can you do?
It's gone too.
- What?
- The vine forest.
- This is where it was.
- No.
Yeah. At the end of the path
that led to the park.
Right here.
Do you remember?
We were happy.
♪ Though the days are long ♪
♪ Twilight sings a song ♪
[Together]
♪ Of a happiness that used to be ♪♪
[Both Laugh]
Come here.
[Sighs]
- Pajamas.
- Yeah?
Yeah. You saw me in California.
So wait a minute then.
You put 60 cents in my hat-
two quarters and a dime.
I still have them.
But... you didn't say anything.
- No.
- Why?
- 'Cause I was waiting.
- For what?
Now.
So- So wait a minute.
You- You've been following me?
No. I go where you are.
You've been following me.
So you knew that I was here,
that I came home.
And you followed me from Los Angeles?
I lived in San Francisco.
Did you go to San Francisco?
And before that, Oregon.
Okay? Please listen to me now.
Because what I wanted
to tell you before- this is it.
I am imagining a day...
where I get up...
and I know that I will not see you...
because you're far away.
Okay? I will not see you.
No chance. Will not.
And now- now I'm imagining a day,
when I get up,
and I know that I might see you.
Okay? Might. Could. Maybe.
Of those two days,
that's the day I want,
that's the day I choose.
And how can one step away from you...
ever be anything for me
but a step in the wrong direction?
How?
Is this a joke?
'Cause if this is a joke, Will,
I gotta tell you something.
Jokes have punch lines.
Okay? So where's the punch line here?
What?
You're not joking.
No.
You gotta stop this.
Don't you see that you gotta stop?
If you say that I do.
I'm saying that you do. Okay?
This is not the way the world works.
We're not kids anymore.
You don't even know me.
- You need to promise me.
- Okay.
Promise me that you
will not go where I go.
Okay.
'Cause this is so wrong, Will.
It is so wrong.
Wh-What's wrong?
Everything. Okay? Everything.
Life is not simple. It is not easy.
Horrible things happen.
And people do terrible things, Will.
They do.
I-
I don't believe she really means this.
What are you doing? Don't do that!
- But, Emma, it was you.
- What was me?
- Them.
- What?
No.
I need you to promise me, okay?
I need you to say it-
that you will not follow me anymore.
Why-Why would I go where
you don't want me to go?
Promise me, Will! Okay? Just promise me.
Okay. Yes.
Yes.
- Yes. Ye-
- [Footsteps Departing]
Well, it's not like you never
mess around on Emma!
Denis?
Oh, no. No. I'm sorry.
I-
[Knovking]
[Exhales]
I'm sorry.
Oh, Emma. Emma.
I've just been so crazy, Aaron.
I've been calling all night,
and your mother said you left hours ago.
And, uh, I've had all
these horrible thoughts.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I met this guy.
I should've just come here.
A guy?
This guy I knew. He's been following me.
Been following you?
[Sighs]
Look, it-
It doesn't matter, okay?
I took care of it.
I think I should just go home.
No, no, no. No, no, no, no.
- Ow. Ow.
- No, no, no, no.
I'm sorry. Please. Please.
[Exhales]
I am exhausted.
Well, what exactly were you
doing with this guy...
that was so exhausting?
- Oh, Aaron.
- No. I won't-
What do you mean following you?
- Look, it doesn't matter.
- Yes, it matters.
It matters to me.
In Los Angeles-
Was he following you in Los Angeles?
Yeah.
You know this for a fact?
[Sighs] Yes.
Wh-What's his name?
Will Donner.
No, I don't like
the sound of this one bit.
I mean, this is- This is dangerous.
Aaron, listen to me.
This afternoon,
I threw a ceramic cat at you.
Isn't that what we should
be talking about?
Yeah. Yeah, you're right. All right.
Okay, so, uh, tomorrow, we'll just, uh-
We'll just start over.
- Okay.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Beeping]
[Female Operator]
City and state, please.
Los Angeles Police Department.
[Policeman Chattering]
[Man]
♪ Well, good-bye to all that I knew ♪
♪ I'm leavin' and you should leave too ♪
- ♪ I said all I needed to say ♪
- [Horn Honking]
♪ Now we can both be on our way ♪♪
[Siren Blares]
What are you doin'?
Get out of the road. Come on.
[Police Radio Chatter]
You know there's no hitchhiking
along this highway?
No.
- Where you headed?
- I have no idea.
May I see your identification, please?
[Laughs] Mr. Donner, this driver's
license expired over four years ago.
Well, then it's a good thing
I'm not driving.
You still at this address?
No, sir, I'm not.
Can you tell me where your home
is at now, Mr. Donner?
Not even close.
Sit tight. I'll be back in a moment.
[Will] Why would I remain silent
if you want to ask me questions?
[Detective]
A man was killed in California.
He was involved in a relationship
with a Miss Emma Twist.
Do you know Emma Twist?
You must know that I do.
- Do you follow Emma Twist?
- I did.
- And you don't follow her anymore?
- No.
- Why'd you stop following her?
- Because she told me to.
Do you know where you were
on the first of October, Mr. Donner?
No.
Do you- Do you know where you were?
We're not suspects in a murder case,
Mr. Donner. You are.
Where were you on the first of October?
No. No.
Emma, no.
No. I have to go. I have to go back.
Mr. Donner,
that's not gonna be possible.
A warrant for your arrest
has been issued in California.
- I really have to go now.
- Mr. Donner, you have to sit down.
- Just sit down!
- I have to leave. No, no. No!
- [Shouting]
- Get him down!
- Emma! Emma!
- Keep him down!
- [Detectives Shouting]
- Emma! No!
No!
- [Screaming]
- [Phone Rings]
[Ringing]
[Clears Throat]
[Beeps] Hello.
Uh, yes. One minute.
Hello.
[Lock Turns]
[Officer] Wake up. Let's go.
[Inmates Chattering, Muttering]
Mm-hmm.
[Officer] He's free to go.
Thanks for coming so far to get me.
I'll- I'll pay you back.
[Exhales] Come on.
Come on.
[Crying]
- They treat you all right?
- [Sniffles]
Look, they don't have
any evidence, all right?
That's why they let you go.
I know you didn't do this.
I know. I know that. I know.
You have to jump through
their hoops though. Okay?
You have to get a lawyer.
And... you're gonna have to get
your act together. Okay?
I've been trying. I promise.
I just- [Sniffles] I can't-
I can't stop crying.
Will, you just- You just
gotta pull it together.
[Erratic Breathing]
- Jimbo.
- Hmm?
Everything's not peachy.
There- There aren't any
matinees on Thursdays.
[Will Crying]
I'm sorry.
[Crying]
The flight leaves soon.
[Woman On P.A.]
Flight 4789 from Chicago O'Hare...
is now arriving at Gate B1.
Come on.
[People Chattering]
Oh, my gosh. Where did you get that?
It's from the train wreck.
It's for the bail.
Put that away, Will.
You just carry that around with you?
Hey.
You have a brother who's a banker.
[Sniffles]
What's wrong with you, kid?
Hmm? You ever hear of interest?
No. No.
Is- Is Emma still home?
She's getting married.
Her dad's in rough shape,
though, so it's all...
kind of up in the air.
I got all this from Joey.
You okay?
I- I'm gonna go get some gum.
- Do you want anything?
- I'm okay.
Gummi Bears?
Yeah. Get me some Gummi Bears.
[Chuckling]
[Woman On P.A.] Ladies and gentlemen,
Flight 935 to Pittsburgh...
will begin general boarding
in 15 minutes.
All passengers requiring
assistance for preboarding...
are invited to start boarding now,
followed by our Gold Club
and first-class passengers.
Willie?
- [Emma] I'll take it.
- Thanks. Thanks, honey.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
[Sighs]
We need some air.
- What do you say?
- Yeah.
Come on.
♪♪ [Background: Blues Rock]
- The wine list, sir.
- Oh.
[Stool Squeaking]
- We'll do, uh, number 3.
- You got it.
What?
I mean, the idea of this guy-
this little boy I knew-
doing such a thing is just-
I can't fit it in my head.
I just can't.
I can't believe someone was killed.
I just- I just can't.
You know, the thing is that sometimes-
[Clicks Tongue] stuff happens.
And you just- You just move on.
- you move on.
- [Bartender] Here you go.
[Clears Throat]
We have to wait, Aaron.
I mean, we have to.
My dad, he's either gonna
get better or he won't, you know?
It's just no good this way
for him or for us-
all worrying and rushing.
I think you should- you should go back.
I'm gonna stay here for...
however long it takes.
I'm so sorry, Aaron, but...
it's just how it's gonna be.
No, it's okay.
- Here.
- Uh-uh.
No.
It's good. You love tapioca.
Yeah.
Here, honey.
Who do you know in Savannah?
Willie.
Yeah.
I'll be right back, okay?
[Beeping]
[Radio] The side has something going
now. Crowd's loving it. [Phone Rings]
Now the big guy, hitting.342
with 92 R.B.I.s.
Hello?
Uh-huh.
Willie.
Willie Pajamas?
Uh-huh. Hold on.
- Albert.
- Yeah?
- It's about Willie Pajamas.
- What?
Okay.
Uh-huh.
Daddy?
Daddy.
Dad?
Mommy?
Mom!
What?
Richard.
[Stammers]
[Both Sobbing]
[Aaron] What do you mean following you?
- [Emma] It doesn't matter.
- Yes, it matters.
It matters to me. Wh-What's his name?
Will Donner.
[Police Radio Chatter]
[Woman On Radio]
Arrest in progress at 348 South Palm.
[Indistinct] ...suspect now in custody.
[Sighs Deeply]
Excuse me.
Weren't you Larry Lightning Bolt in Miss
Hyderman's first-grade science play?
What do you know- Rhonda Rain Shower.
- Right?
- That's me.
- Geez.
- Yeah.
[Sighs] Well, thanks for
meeting me here.
- Yeah, sure.
- It's been so long.
Look. Um-
Joey, I'm afraid
I've just been making messes.
From what I have heard,
you've had sort of a, uh- a rough year.
We- Who did-
Who did you hear that from?
From Willie.
Willie.
Yeah. Look,
that's the reason I called you.
I've just been feeling so badly
about all the terrible things...
that have happened to him because of me.
I know that he stayed with you when he
was here,
so I figured you'd be in touch.
I don't even know
why he ever even liked me.
Liked you? This kid was ready
to climb inside your aorta.
- For crying out loud.
- What?
Uh, never mind. It-
It works when Will says it. [Chuckles]
[Chuckles]
Look. Um, if you talk to him,
will you tell him how sorry I am?
Okay.
[Thunder Rumbles]
Hey, Jim.
Oh.
Uh, Willie sent this.
He's in San Francisco.
He's performing
at the Fisherman's Wharf.
He sent it with another letter to me.
He didn't know where to send it
after your dad died, so-
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
How's your mom doing?
- She's fine.
- Is she?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Good. Well-
Thank you.
[Will's Voice] Dear Emma-
Those two words, "Dear Emma,"
take me away to another time,
when we used to write to each other
after Mom and Dad died.
I used to tell you about
my new friends and my new life.
And you used to tell me about
the grand time my mom
and dad were having in heaven.
Truth is nothing.
What you believe to be true
is everything.
And the main thing
that I used to believe
was that I would be with you forever.
Forever.
The reason it has taken me
so long to write to you...
is that I see
that I have been a fool.
- I've spent my life fooling myself.
- [Bell Clanging]
Every letter I've ever written to you
has been a love letter.
[Chuckles]
How could they have been anything else?
I can see now that all of them,
except this one,
were bad love letters.
Bad love letters beg for love back.
Good love letters ask for nothing.
This, I'm pleased to announce,
is my first good love letter to you,
because there is nothing more
for you to do.
You've already done everything.
I have enough of you
in my head to last forever.
So please don't ever worry about me.
I'm peachy. I really am.
I have everything.
If I had one wish,
it would be that your life...
brings you a taste of the happiness
you have brought to me,
that you can feel
what it's like to love.
Your friend forever,
Will.
[Chattering]
- Vacation?
- No, I'm looking for a friend.
He juggles.
Juggler. Do you- Wears pajamas.
- White boy pajamas?
- [Man #2 Murmurs]
That's him.
That is- That's him. That's Will.
- Him down there. Gateway Marketplace.
- Yeah.
He don't be there till dark.
Thank you so much.
- You're welcome. Welcome.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
[Woman] Balloons!
Get your balloons here!
[Man] Candy apples!
- [Woman #2] Cotton candy!
- [Woman #3] Hot oysters!
Get your cotton candy right here!
♪♪ [Folk Ballad]
[Man] ♪ Back when we were young ♪
♪ We ran into the sun ♪
♪ It's like we fell apart ♪
♪ Yes, you stole my heart ♪
♪ I searched these wasted years ♪
♪ To wipe away the tears ♪
♪ As my heart began to crack ♪
♪ Can't go back ♪
♪ And I can hardly speak ♪
♪ When you're in front of me ♪
♪ I can't breathe ♪
♪ Two paths that would not cross ♪
[Crowd Gasps]
♪ You left me feeling lost ♪
♪ But I love you just the same ♪
♪ Let the magic reign ♪
♪ With a blanket made of stars ♪
♪ To wrap the both of us ♪
♪ As we fell into the light ♪
♪ Our worlds collide ♪
[Applause]
♪ 'Cause that's the way ♪
♪ That our worlds collide ♪
♪ And here I am ♪
♪ And here I stand ♪
♪ Our worlds collide ♪
[Whispers] Are you following me?
[Giggles]
[Man, Woman]
♪ And I would wait for you ♪
♪ And I'd wait forever too ♪
♪ You're in ♪
♪ You're in my heart ♪
♪ In my heart ♪
♪ It's true ♪♪
[Subrip & Sync: easytobeaman]
♪♪ [Folk Rock]
[Man] ♪ Someday you'll find me ♪
♪ I haven't gone too far ♪
♪ I miss the way we were back then ♪
♪ How we laughed ♪
♪ I can feel you in my heart ♪
♪ There's a world in your eyes ♪
♪ I can see it getting brighter ♪
♪ All the hours
that we turned into days ♪
♪ We were young ♪
♪ Seemed like life
would go on, last forever ♪
♪ All I had was you by my side ♪
♪ Someday you 'll answer ♪
♪ Remember how we were ♪
♪ When all our hopes and dreams ♪
♪ Just glided through the air ♪
♪ I can feel it in my heart ♪
♪ I can feel you in my heart ♪
♪ That's the way that it was ♪
♪ In the past you remember ♪
♪ When we ran through the winds
and the rain ♪
♪ We were young ♪
♪ Seemed like life
would go on, last forever ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah ♪
♪ And now everything has changed ♪♪
♪♪ [Folk Rock]
[Man] ♪ Though the days are long ♪
♪ Twilight sings a song ♪
♪ Of a happiness that used to be ♪
♪ Soon my eyes will close ♪
♪ Soon I'll find repose ♪
♪ And in dreams
you're always near to me ♪
♪ And I'll see you in my dreams ♪♪
[Subrip & Sync: easytobeaman]