(CARLISLE) I've caught Ripley in a lie
and he knows it.
We've got a son
knowing we're on to his dad.
- Ripley's wife?
- What about her?
Have you worked out what she's hiding?
(DANNY) This copper is trying to say
I had a fight with the bloke who died.
- I don't know if I did or not.
- Which copper's saying this?
So Mike Hooley's body was moved
from your flats to your arcade
by someone who had keys to both.
Did you have anything to do
with beating Steve up?
No, I didn't. But I wish I bloody well had.
He got out of it on cider
and lay down on the railway line.
I'd know if he was the type
to try and kill himself.
Why are you behaving like this?
You're my daughter, for God's sake.
Not now, I'm not.
I killed Mike Hooley. I sold him drugs,
I beat him up. I killed him.
(WALK TALL BY VAL DOONICAN)
# Walk tall
# Walk tall, walk straight
# And look the world right in the eye
# That's what my mama told me
# When I was about knee high
# She said son, be a proud man
# And hold your head up high
# Walk tall, walk straight
# And look the world right in the eye
# All through the years that I grew up
# Ma taught these things to me
# But I was young and foolish then
# And much too blind to see
# I ignored the things she said
as if I'd never heard
# Now I see and understand
# The wisdom of her words
# Walk tall, walk straight
# And look the world right in the eye
# That's what my mama told me
# When I was about knee high
# She said son, be a proud man
# And hold your head up high
# Walk tall, walk straight
# And look the world right in the eye
# I started going places
# Where the youngsters shouldn't go
# I got to know the kind of girls
# It's better not to know
# I fell in with a bad crowd
# And laughed and drank with them
# Through the laughter Mama's words
# Would echo now and then
# Walk tall, walk straight
# And look the world right in the eye
# That's what my mama told me
# When I was about knee high
# She said, Son, be a proud man
# And hold your head up high
# Walk tall, walk straight
# And look the world right in the eye #
You lying, two-faced bastard.
You are full of shit.
You're poison. Poison.
- Here you are, sir.
- Get out!
So what was the idea, eh?
Screw me so you could screw my son?
I haven't screwed your son.
His confession doesn't even tally
with the victim's injuries.
Hardly worth screwing me at all,
then, eh?
When I came to see you,
it was part of the investigation.
But that stopped
from the moment we first talked.
We lay in each other's arms
in that hotel room
and you asked me about my family,
about my son.
Because I was curious about your life,
like any lover would be.
No, you are not my lover.
You are just some seedy copper
who fancied me.
You were dead on when you said that
people always went for the same type
because Ripley is a lying bastard, too.
I didn't want it to end. What else
could I do? I had to lie about who I was.
So, you were lying before you fell for me
and you were lying after?
Was there ever a time you weren't lying?
Wait!
Oh, I see.
You'd even use my wife to get at me,
wouldn't you?
You're out of order, D.I. Carlisle.
I was just assuring Mrs Holden
that Danny isn't in trouble.
Well, perhaps not as much trouble
as he wanted to be.
Why don't you pick on somebody
your own size?
Danny came to me.
If I'd wanted to arrest him,
I could have done it last week
when I picked him up for supplying
speed. The boy is clearly very confused.
- Well, he's not the only one, is he?
- Danny's doing drugs?
Come on, love. Let's get our son home.
You just leave my family alone.
I'm sorry,
but am I being the thick one here?
How's confessing to a murder
you didn't do helping, exactly?
- I think they're coming after you.
- Who's coming after me? The posse?
- Indian tracker and a bounty hunter?
- They think you killed Mike Hooley.
That Carlisle bloke,
did he actually say that?
Not exactly.
A minor dope charge for a minor dope.
He did it because he was trying
to protect his dad.
What's so bad about that?
He's going around confessing to crimes
he didn't do and I didn't do.
He's a bloody liability.
- That's your son you're talking about.
- He could have been charged.
- Carlisle wouldn't have charged him.
- Carlisle wouldn't, would he?
You know all about him, do you?
- Who are you bullying now?
- I don't bully anybody.
- Tell that to Steve.
- Did he tell you I beat him up?
He doesn't have to.
- No.
He doesn't have to, does he? Look at you.
Yeah. Look at me. Look at me.
- Ripley, for God's sake!
- Look at me. What do you see here?
What's my name? Mr Pony and Stabling?
Mr Ballet Lessons?
Bathroom suite in girlie pink.
Mr Rowing Machine
that you hang your clothes off?
Home cinema
with multi-channel playback.
Mr Renault,
like that Froggie footballer drives?
Is that my name?
I didn't realise you were totting it all up.
- I'll get Steve to pay you when I leave.
- Why you...
Thank your lucky stars
that I'm a modern parent.
(SHYANNE SOBBING)
You don't just walk in off the street
and confess unless you feel guilty.
Danny Holden's confession
must still mean something.
I don't think it means anything.
So you think the Holden family
are innocent?
Nobody is innocent.
(BLYTHE) What does she want?
Go and see if you can win
that diver's watch on the grabber.
(CARLISLE) It's good to see you.
- Is it?
- Yeah.
Two times in my life
I've been happy, really happy.
Once in Glasgow.
1989, at some festival in the park.
A summer's evening.
This singer came on...
sounded exactly like Aretha Franklin
with a Scottish accent.
If Proust had drunk McEwans, he'd have
written about moments like that.
And the other time?
The other night when we made love.
Even though you knew
you were lying to me?
Yeah, even then.
What about you?
I don't know. It was...
like when someone turns on the lights
and you realise
you've been sat in the dark for hours.
- That is exactly how I feel.
- Good.
Then it might give you some idea
of what you're putting me through.
It hurts.
You think I want to just smile
and put this down to experience?
You knew everything.
I only had half the story
so how will I ever know
if you were for real?
- Just give me a chance to make it right.
- I'm already making it right.
With my family.
You made me realise that's where
I should be looking for happiness.
Not from some sneaky affair
in a hotel bedroom
with a man who tells ten lies
before breakfast.
So in a way, in the end,
you did do me a favour.
I need you.
I need you and you need me.
We'll get over it.
I got you a doughnut.
Pink icing.
Hundreds and thousands.
I want to check the CCTV footage.
- I've written it all up.
- No. You're not listening.
I want to check the CCTV footage.
I want to interview Mike Hooley's
fiancee, I want to re-interview his mates.
I want to read
all the forensics reports again.
I want a search warrant
for Ripley Holden's house.
I want to find the taxi driver
that took Ripley Holden home
on the night of the arcade opening.
Right. What's the...
We're going to assess motive,
means and opportunity.
And to use the American vernacular,
we are going to nail
Ripley Holden's sorry ass.
(LISTENING TO REGGAE MUSIC)
There's nothing so bad
that ska can't make better.
Absolutely.
How are you feeling?
- On the mend, I think.
- So what happened?
The bastard jumped me from behind.
You know I'd never do a thing like that,
don't you?
- I think I do, yeah.
- That's right.
Because I like a man to see my face
when I'm hitting him.
It was the shock more than anything.
It wasn't just a punch.
He hit me with something.
Then he had me off balance.
I think I got one clean right hook
to his mouth.
Steve, do yourself a favour.
Don't make out
like it was Ali and Frazier,
talk like a fighter when you're not.
You end up looking like a limp dick
in a condom.
So, did he kick you or what?
Why do you need to hear this?
I need the details so I can go out
and find the loser that did it.
Until I do, Shyanne's blaming me.
For a moment there
I thought you were concerned about me.
I am concerned about you.
Look.
What's this?
- Compensation.
- What for? My injuries?
There's enough there for you to go
and start up somewhere else.
Why would I do that?
It's what you do when you're giving up
the woman you love.
I wasn't aware that I was.
One day, Shyanne'll look at you
and she'll see a dried up orange at
the bottom of a fruit bowl, so why wait?
This way you come out ahead,
financial-wise.
So you're trying to buy me off?
Clearly you didn't get the message
last time we spoke.
So I thought this would
make you more cooperative.
May I remind you that although
the corpse incident was unfortunate,
we are a family entertainment centre
with years of respectable trade.
We have always been ahead of our time.
We were one of the first arcades
on the Fylde coast to have carpet down.
Go on. Keep going. You can do this.
Our new casino hotel will have
wheelchair access to all machines
to allow the disabled
of all shapes and sizes
to enjoy the full range of our facilities.
This is crap, isn't it?
No, I just think
you've just got to relax more.
Just be yourself.
It was being myself that lost the
planning permission in the first place.
The Enterprise Committee
wouldn't be coming down to see you
if they weren't taking your appeal
seriously, would they?
You've got to remember who you are
and what you've achieved.
That's right. I'm Ripley Holden.
I'm a showman. I can persuade anyone
if I put my mind to it.
I could charm the bollocks off a donkey.
And then sell them back to him.
I should start breaking windows
more often.
To a fresh start.
A fresh start.
Jim got that Lover's Guide video
from a car boot sale.
I could borrow it if you like.
Yeah. Right, I'll look forward to that.
You're going to be late. It's 11:30.
Put the champagne on ice.
I'll be back tonight with a song
in my heart and a 40-foot hard-on.
Well, I'll look forward to the song.
When you came in to talk to us last time,
you seemed to suggest that Mike Hooley
was a bit of a lad.
How do you mean? The prossie and that?
Not just that.
Well, he's dead now, isn't he?
So... story over.
- He liked a night out, didn't he?
- Who doesn't?
Would he ever get into any sort
of trouble on his nights out?
He could look after himself
but he didn't go looking.
Did he like the arcades or was that
just something that he did here?
No. He was keen on the slots.
Always banging on about a system.
- A system?
- Yeah, where he could win.
Man against machine.
He was big on all that.
So it'd be fair to say that
he wasn't over-fond of arcade owners?
I don't know about that.
He just wanted to win a few bob.
Is that what you and him
were fighting about?
Him causing trouble in the arcades?
We were pissed. You know how it is.
Was it about him causing trouble
with this man?
- It was about his fiancee, Emma.
- What about her?
He used to beat her up.
We all knew he did it
but he'd just come up
with some crap excuse or other.
So I just wanted to have a word.
Sort him out before the wedding.
That's what the ruck was about.
Here, you got that business plan
we talked about?
I have. It's a tissue of lies
and bogus statistics.
That's just the kind I like.
Just as long as they don't
look at it too closely.
Isn't that what you said to that hooker
I laid on for you the other night?
Have you seen your mother anywhere,
love? I need to speak to her.
My mother?
That's not you, is it, Ruth?
You scrub up nicely, don't you?
I'd give you one myself
if I hadn't changed my ways.
Barry, if any kids stray to the over-18
section, shoot to kill, all right?
Not now, Barry.
Look, just keep nodding
and look like you're enjoying your work.
Here, have this one on me, my friend.
Hey, up.
I need to talk to you about this plan
to remortgage the arcade.
- It's not looking great.
- It doesn't matter.
We're going to win this appeal,
get the planning permission
to put the casino hotel back on track.
Confidence is commendable
but you got to realise that if we fail...
There is no such word today.
This is where we turn this thing around.
Look.
Gentlemen.
Welcome to our family
entertainment centre.
This way.
And this is Ripley Holden's Casino Hotel.
(I'M GONNA MAKE YOU LOVE ME BY
THE TEMPTATIONS AND THE SUPREMES)
# I'm gonna do all the things for you
# A girl wants a man to do
# Oh, baby
# Baby
# I'll sacrifice for you
# I'll even do wrong for you
# Oh, baby
# Every minute, every hour
# I'm gonna shower you
with love and affection
# Look out it's coming in your direction
# And I'm, I'm gonna make you love me
# Oh, yes, I will
# Yes, I will
# I'm gonna make you love me
# Oh, yes, I will
# Yes, I will
# Look here
# My love is strong, you see
# I know you'll never get tired of me
# Oh, baby
# Baby
# And I'm gonna use every trick
in the book
# I'll try my best to get you hooked
# Hey, baby
# I'm yours
# And every night, every day
# I'm gonna say
# I'm gonna get ya, I'm gonna get ya
# Look out boy 'cause I'm gonna get ya
# I'm gonna make you love me
# Oh, yes, I will
# Yes, I will
# And I'm gonna make you love me
# Oh, yes, I will
# You know I will
# Every breath I take
# And each and every step I make
# Brings me closer, baby
Closer to you
# And with each beat of my heart
# For every day we're apart
# I'll hunger for every wasted hour
# Every night
# And every day
# I'm gonna get ya, I'm gonna get ya
# Look out 'cause I'm gonna get ya
# And I'm gonna make you love me
# Yes, I will
# I'm gonna make you love me
# Oh, yes, I will
# Yes, I will
# I'm gonna make you love me
# Oh, yes, I will
# Yes, I will
# And I'm gonna make you love me
# Oh, yes, I will
# Yes, I will... #
I think that went quite well, don't you?
They said no.
It's like women, isn't it?
They have to say no a couple of times
for appearances sake.
Talking of women...
here comes Mary, Queen of Scots.
- How's business?
- Couldn't be better.
All I need now is for you to fall off
the end of the pier.
Believe me, I don't want to stay here
any longer than I have to.
I thought you were staying
in that swanky hotel on the front.
What've you got to complain about?
It doesn't make Blackpool
any more palatable.
Yeah, well, someone like you
would never understand Blackpool.
Oh, where a schoolboy can sell you drugs
and you end up dead
if you overstep the mark?
Come on, that could happen anywhere.
Everybody knows
this country's gone soft on criminals.
We've tracked down the taxi driver
that picked you up
from Terry Corlette's at 3:30 a.m.
On the night Mike Hooley died.
- Says he didn't take you straight home.
- So?
He says he dropped you outside here
at 3:45.
I fancied standing outside my arcade
and admiring it.
Something you wouldn't understand.
Not being a businessman.
Is that when you saw Mike Hooley again?
I'm not going to fall for that one.
(SLOT MACHINE BEEPING)
Oh, and Carlisle?
Give Jim Allbright my love next time
you're having one of your little chats.
(SIREN WAILING)
Are you out here all the time?
More or less.
Overnight?
No, I go home around midnight.
Back on 5, 5:30 in the morning.
But nobody's to know that, right?
How do you mean?
I mean, as far as most people
are concerned, you're here 24 hours.
- Mike Hooley's fiancee can't hang around.
- Nice talking to you.
Was it?
We realise this is difficult,
but why were you going to marry Mike?
Why do you think?
Why does anybody marry someone?
A question I ask myself on a daily basis.
Did you love him?
Yeah. I loved him.
What did you love about him?
You know, he enjoyed life.
Liked a drink? Bit of a gamble?
Yeah.
Bookies, fruit machines, you name it.
And he didn't mind a fight, I hear.
He was just a normal lad.
Well, no, I'm not...
saying he was a troublemaker,
but if he kept getting threatened,
maybe, through the course
of an evening,
would he walk away or would he,
perhaps, stand his ground?
Well... he did have a bit of a temper.
Even with you?
- What do you mean?
- Did you and him ever have any fights?
All couples have fights.
- Did they ever get violent?
- No.
Who's been telling you that?
Have you finished your coffee?
Yeah. Why?
What was he doing at a place like this?
He was visiting a prostitute.
- No.
- Yes, I'm afraid.
Why did you have to bring me here?
Why are you doing this?
So, Emma, did Mike used to hit you?
Yeah, of course I do.
Of course I do.
No, I can't right now.
Yeah. Okay. See you.
See you.
You look like the cat who got the cream.
Maybe I did.
Is it a secret?
Yeah, it's a secret.
Okay.
Don't you want to know what it is?
- Aren't you just a little bit curious?
- Well, of course I am.
But I'm not going to
chase you around asking.
I'm going to drive you mad
by pretending I don't care.
Okay, I can play that game.
It's made you happy.
That's the main thing.
- Yeah, it made me happy.
- Good.
Do you want to know what it is yet?
Why don't you tell me.
And you'll be pleased for me
because it makes me happy?
Yes.
- And you promise not to tell Dad.
- Okay. I promise.
Steve asked me to marry him.
Oh. Right.
- What did you say?
- Yes, of course.
Well...
You said you'd be pleased for me.
You can't even do that, can you?
You can't even pretend.
Shyanne. Come on, love, don't be silly.
I was just surprised, that's all.
- I thought you were on my side.
- I am on your side.
- Marriage is a big step, isn't it?
- Who's getting married?
- I am.
- Who to?
- I got married when I was your age.
- So?
I thought that was one of the things
that irritated you about me.
- Married young, stayed at home.
- You're not that unhappy.
You have no idea.
You're just saying this
to spoil everything.
- You're saying it because you're jealous.
- No, I am not jealous.
I just don't want you to get carried away
and regret it.
Just because your love life's
so far behind you,
you can't remember what
it even feels like to get carried away.
I know exactly what it feels like
to get carried away.
- That's what I'm trying to tell you.
- Yes, sure you are.
Why do you think I ended up
having an affair? You tell me that.
What?
You had an affair?
It's over now.
It was stupid.
It was more in my head
than anything else.
You can't have had an affair.
You're my mum.
I was just trying to prove a point
to you. It's nothing to get upset about.
But, Dad.
What about Dad?
Does he know?
No, of course he doesn't know.
What good would telling him do?
It's over and done with now.
Just forget I said anything about it.
Forget that my mum had an affair?
It was nothing.
But, enough for you
not to want Dad to know.
Shyanne, you told me a secret
and I promised to keep it.
I didn't promise you anything.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Have I got a bat in the cave or what?
I was just wondering
how well you and Mum knew each other
when you got married.
You know what I miss
since I became middle class?
- Having the telly on when we're eating.
- Me, too.
I deal with all the flossing
and side plates and shit.
Did you know her that well?
I knew her well enough
to want to marry her.
If I'd known her any better,
clearly I wouldn't.
And do you think that you got
to know her better over the years?
- Of course. What sort of question's that?
- Of course he did.
What are you? The Liverpool Echo?
Just ease off, Shyanne,
and eat your food, will you?
I'm just interested in what's kept
your marriage going for so long.
- That's all.
- Let's just drop it now.
Do you want to say something?
Ask Mum.
- Any idea what she's going about?
- She's not worth it.
I got engaged today.
You did what?
Steve and I got engaged to be married.
- You are joking.
- No.
And you knew about this?
She told me this afternoon, yeah.
What do you think of the ring?
It's very shiny.
I wanted him to take it back.
I said he couldn't afford it.
But, well, he said he'd come into
some money, unexpectedly.
Did he?
Mike Hooley's fiancee's told us
that he used to hit her.
If he hit her, he wouldn't think twice
about hitting that prostitute Hailey.
- How does that get us closer to Ripley?
- It doesn't.
It might have been the prostitute.
It might have been Hooley's best man.
Last week it might have been
Danny Holden.
I'm trying to keep
an open mind here, sir.
On the one hand,
there's keeping an open mind,
on the other, there's being a feather
for every wind that blows.
I'll set up another interview
with that prostitute.
You do that, Blythe. You do that.
What do you want, Danny?
Nothing.
Do you think Shyanne's getting married
to Steve because he got beat up?
Maybe.
A bruise and a broken nose
will get you a long way with women.
- So you think she is?
- Maybe.
Yeah, but Steve's a wanker.
Yeah, but at least he's not a drug dealer.
Carlisle got that wrong.
I was just getting it for a friend.
That's why you had to lie about
not seeing Mike Hooley in the club?
You'd sold him some gear, hadn't you?
That's why I'm lying through my teeth
now, trying to get us out of this mess.
- So it's all my fault.
- Oh!
Finally he gets there.
Come on.
I want to show you something.
Take a look around you.
Is this what you want for yourself?
Is this your ambition?
Listen, Dad,
I've got something to tell you.
I was 16 years old.
I'd run away from home.
No roof over my head. Hungry.
I'd heard that perverts hung out
at one of the arcades.
Pay for rent boys and that.
I'm not proud to tell you, Danny.
But I went down there.
I was playing on one of the machines...
and sure enough,
this old bender came over.
I was about to go with him.
You know what happened?
- No.
- I got three bars on a win line.
Ten quid jackpot payout.
The old Bar X machine.
That's when I knew, I'd found my calling.
I saw what I could do.
- Will you just listen...
- No more listening.
It's always excuses with you.
You're bloody useless.
You're that far away from being a loser.
Take a look around you.
This is where you're going to end up
if you don't shake yourself.
I want you to stay here
and think about that.
All I heard from Natalie for 20 years was,
"Let the kids think for themselves".
That's all good in theory, but what if
they're thinking something stupid?
- Where are you going with the machines?
- They need emergency maintenance.
Now he doesn't want to
play football anymore.
No. He'd rather sell speed to idiot Mancs.
She's chucking away a good education
by getting married to the living dead.
That'll never last.
When they're born, you think you'll
never love anything this much again.
And you're dead right. You don't.
I think you're looking on the black side.
Thanks for sharing that insight with us,
Trisha.
Take the rest outside and make sure
that door looks like it's been burgled.
I'm only saying...
You're only saying shit. That's your
trouble. You're always only saying.
You've got a trap like a groupie's chuff.
What are you talking about?
Carlisle dropped by.
Said he'd spoken to a taxi driver.
So?
I'm thinking he's bound to get there
in the end. Then I thought,
"How did he find out
I'd taken a taxi in the first place?"
There are records and stuff.
- Maybe the driver came forward.
- No chance.
Bloke drove like an asylum seeker.
Albanian speed limits.
I don't think he wants to get too cosy
with the police.
You think I told Carlisle about the taxi?
Hang on, Jim.
You're not saying that, are you?
No. I'm saying you told him about the
taxi, about the flats, about the hookers.
You told him about my lad.
It's a miracle you're not on your phone
now, telling him about these machines.
I don't believe this.
Why would I grass you up?
Because wherever you are,
whoever you're with,
you wanna make yourself look important.
- And I wasn't falling for it anymore.
- Not like you, then.
No. Because I am important.
Hang on, lads.
This is getting out of hand.
The times I've stood up for you when
your gaming licence was up for renewal.
Don't get sentimental on me, Jim,
you'll have me filling up.
Let's just put it down
to you being a prick.
(DOOR SLAMS)
- Are you all right?
- Not really.
- What is it?
- Nothing.
I've been in town with Dad.
Then I walked home thinking about stuff
and that, you know...
You know, when sometimes
there's like a gap in your head
where the right word should be.
Or you think of an idea in a dream
and you know it's a dream
and you think, "If I remember that,
everything will be all right."
But then you wake up
and the word's gone.
Do you know what I mean?
Danny, love, I just want to be left alone
for a bit. Is that all right?
Sure. Yeah.
Ta.
You think, "If I can't rely on my family,
at least I've got my mates."
Then you find
you can't even depend on them.
I don't think that's true about Jim.
All I was going through,
and that creosoted bastard
was listening to me suffer and he knew.
He knew all along.
You're being too hard on him.
You know this forgiving thing
you do, Terry.
Forgiving your wife, forgiving me,
forgiving Allbright?
I'm sure it's all very admirable
but it doesn't half get on my tit.
We all do bad things, don't we?
- What's that supposed to mean?
- What about that slap?
What slap?
- See. You've forgotten about it already.
- Me and you? The other day?
Come on, that was nothing.
Exactly. I've been thinking about that.
You don't slap another bloke.
Not if you respect him, you don't.
You punch him.
You slapped me like I was a little kid
or a girl or something.
So what, you'd have preferred it
if I'd given you a good kicking?
At least I'd have felt valued.
Maybe I will give you a good kicking,
make you feel better about yourself.
Maybe you will.
Come here, come on.
Shyanne will come to her senses.
It's like you said, you know,
she's digging her heels in
because she thinks I've got something
to do with beating him up.
So?
So, I'll find out who did it
and then it'll be all right.
He must love her a lot.
He's bought her a ring
and that means nothing.
Did you see the diamonds in it?
It must have cost him a bit.
He can't afford that.
- He's trying to buy her. That never works.
- That's good coming from you.
How come this is about me
all of a sudden?
- All right. No need to get so defensive.
- I'm trying to comfort you here.
You say that
like you're doing me a favour.
Believe it or not, it's what most normal
husbands do as a matter of course.
You know, I'm not surprised
she's marrying that prick.
I think she looks at us
and thinks she can't do any worse.
(OOH LA LA BY THE FACES)
# Poor old Grandad
# I laughed at all his words
# I thought he was a bitter man
# He spoke of women's ways
# They trap you and they use you
# Before you even know
# For love is blind
and you're far too kind
# Don't ever let it show
# I wish that I knew what I know now
# When I was younger
# When I was stronger
# The Can Can's such a pretty show
# They'll steal your heart away
# But backstage back on earth again
# The dressing rooms are grey
# They come on strong
# And it ain't too long
# For they make you feel a man
# For love is blind
# And you soon will find
# You're just a boy again
(MEN WHISTLING)
# When you want her lips,
you get her cheek
# Makes you wonder where you are
# If you want some more
and she's fast asleep
# Leaves you twinkling with the stars
# Poor young grandson
# There's nothing I can say
# You'll have to learn just like me
# And that's the hardest way
# Ooh la la
# Ooh la la la la, yeah
# I wish that I knew what I know now
# When I was younger
# When I was stronger #
We could bring forensics here to check
this room with a fine-tooth comb.
My bet is they could find evidence
that Mike Hooley was in here.
That doesn't prove anything.
He could have wandered in
when I went to drum up some business.
- At 4:00 in the morning?
- My peak time.
So he died,
was moved to the bedsit opposite
and the following night
he was moved to the arcade
and you expect us to believe
that you didn't see or hear anything?
- We know he liked to beat up women.
- He wouldn't be the first.
If you're lying,
you're perverting the course of justice.
And if there's any doubt that
he was still alive when you moved him,
- it could be manslaughter.
- I didn't kill him.
No, I don't think you did. But I think
you moved the body, didn't you?
I panicked. All right?
He collapsed and I panicked.
And was this before or after
you supplied him with drugs?
(WHISTLES)
I sniffed a couple of poppers
and I turned to get ready.
I heard him fall and he was dead.
I didn't know what to do
so I dragged him to an empty bedsit
over the hall.
You dragged him there by yourself?
I used to be a dominatrix
in Burton-on-Trent. You never lose it.
- So why move him again to the arcade?
- It was the only place I had keys to.
I thought maybe it'd look
more like an accident in there.
You had keys to Ripley Holden's arcade?
He keeps a spare set here
for emergencies.
The alarm code's on the fob.
- He trusts you with a spare set of keys?
- He trusts me with a lot of things.
Why is any man dropped off in town
at 3:45 in the morning?
He's searching for a shag.
Ripley drops in on Hailey
but who's turned up at the same time?
Mike Hooley. That bastard
who's been annoying him all night.
It's a bit of a coincidence, isn't it?
Well, how about he put the word out
that he wanted to nail Mike Hooley
for scamming his arcade
and Hailey rang him when he turned up?
So why didn't he move the body
to the arcade on the same night?
Because it was too late.
Because Hallworth begins his one-man
protest at 5:00 in the morning.
No. Hailey was scared out of her wits.
Why? Because she killed Mike Hooley.
He's gone there, started on her, she's hit
him with a weapon in self-defence.
She's scared all right.
She's scared of Ripley Holden.
I'm sorry about being so mean to you.
About, you know...
- I'm sorry I told you.
- No. I'm glad you did.
Right.
- You're not going to leave Dad, are you?
- No, love.
And it is over?
Yes.
It's me and Danny who make you
unhappy and we'll be leaving home soon.
No, it isn't.
It's not your fault. Really it's not.
You know all the times
you tried to talk to me...
and ask me about my feelings
and all that.
I ignored you and was sarcastic and stuff.
It was like I knew I was doing it,
but I couldn't stop.
And then it was just something I did.
It didn't mean I hated you.
I know, love.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
It's that copper.
Is your husband in?
No. He's at the arcade.
He's had another break-in.
Oh. I'm sorry to hear that.
Yeah, well, there's a big market
for second-hand gaming machines.
People steal to order.
Still, it's unlucky.
What with the other break-in.
Hm. He's going through
an unlucky phase.
We all are.
Amen to that.
So, shall I get him to give you a call?
Yeah, if you could tell him
I'd like to talk to him.
Yeah. Sure. Okay. I could do that.
Is there anything else?
Because I was going out.
- That's it.
- Okay.
Take care.
It's not just the money, Ruth,
it's the psychological damage.
I know. Fear goes right past my brain
and into my bowels.
Barry, we're going to need
a 360 degree ceiling unit installed
and let's apply to the police
for instant bells.
Nobody touch anything here until
the insurance assessors have got here.
Now come on, chop, chop.
Got to keep moving forward.
The thing is my investment, my ?2,000.
Me and Barry were noticing that, maybe,
if you're doing insurance fiddles,
it might be a good time
to get our money out.
Now? It's the best time to buy.
It's called a bear market.
We feel a bit out of our depth,
to be honest.
I was thinking, maybe a fixed-rate bond
might give me a better return.
Did he just say that or
are you throwing your voice?
It's just, well, it's all I've got.
And if the casino hotel doesn't get built,
I've lost my savings.
And I was hoping to treat myself
to an endoscopy this winter.
So it's come to this, eh?
My oldest, trusted business partners
want out.
Well, not out, exactly. Just less in.
- Read the Bible, have you, Ruth?
- Yes.
Parable of the Talents
mean anything to you?
The slave that hid the talent
in the ground?
What return did he get
on his investment, eh?
He was cast out into the outer darkness
where there will be a weeping
and a gnashing of teeth.
Oh. Come on.
This is your new idea?
Remortgage my house? Shangri-La?
No way. No bloody way!
I'm not risking that.
What's wrong with remortgaging
the arcade?
The bank won't let you.
You've already borrowed too much
against projected future earnings.
Well, go out and find some new investors
to tide us over.
With respect, Ripley, if Ruth and Deaf
Barry are starting to have doubts...
And it won't be long before your big
investors want their money out, too.
- I'll get planning permission in 6 weeks.
- Nobody believes that except you.
Well, I've been here before.
The only one that believes in me.
Do you think that scares me?
No, it gives me a hard-on.
At least let me look into
what you could raise on the house.
- It's everything I've ever worked for.
- I'm not asking you to sell it.
You find another way, pencil dick,
or you can just walk out of here, sacked.
Come on, Ripley.
No need to take that sort of tone.
Go on. Go out there and look again.
Or you can find some other sucker
to buy your shags for you.
Danny?
No.
Oh, no.
(CHILDREN SQUEALING)
Danny!
Danny.
What are you doing? Come here.
What are you doing? You don't do this.
This isn't down for you, Son.
Come on.
Why this?
- Because it's what you did.
- Jesus!
Because I did it. Who told you I did it?
Shyanne.
Did she?
If you're as unhappy as I was,
I wouldn't wish that on anybody.
And not you. Not my son.
It just seemed like the right thing to do.
Is it school? A girl? What?
No.
It's not a girl.
What's funny about that?
It's like you said... I'm useless.
I didn't mean that.
I just said that to shake you up a bit.
But topping yourself...
Wasn't there anyone you could talk to?
Come on. A mate? Anybody?
I rang the Samaritans.
They clearly did a first-class job,
didn't they?
Mum answered. I recognised her voice.
(RIPLEY SIGHS)
(LAUGHS SOFTLY)
Of all the luck, eh?
Come on. Let's get you home.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
I beat up Steve.
Don't you think I guessed that already?
I knew it had to be you.
I was only trying to help.
Then you got the blame.
It doesn't matter.
There's nothing you do that's so bad
that we can't sort it out. Nothing.
I moved the body, Dad.
You what?
I moved Mike Hooley
from your flats to the arcade.
- You did?
- Hailey rang me on my mobile.
How do you know Hailey?
She was panicking
because he'd collapsed at her flat.
He looked dead and she knew you'd get
in the shit if he was found there.
So you thought you'd move him
to the arcade?
For safe keeping. I was going to move
him early next morning.
And that copper knows, Dad.
He looks at me and he knows.
And he's going to get the forensics
and say I murdered him when I didn't.
No, he's not.
I just couldn't see a way out. I'm useless.
You know, when I lay down
on those railway tracks?
I look back now and I think,
"What was that all about?"
I would have missed so much.
You know, it's like walking out
before the end of a film.
What if you don't like the film?
At least hang around to see
how it turns out.
Odds are it's gonna get better.
Unless Hugh Grant's in it, in which case
you might be better off topping yourself.
Don't you know how much...
What I'm saying is...
it'd tear me apart
if you came to any harm.
- It'd kill me, too. Do you understand me?
- Yeah.
Any problem,
any time things are getting too much
for you, you come to me. Understood?
This body business, that Carlisle,
I'll find a way out for you.
- Don't you worry about it any longer.
- How?
I'll sort it, Danny. I promise you.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
I've just dragged my lad
off the railway tracks.
He was trying to top himself because
of what you're putting him through.
- Danny?
- Yes, Danny. My lad.
Scared out of his wits 'cause he thinks
you're going to arrest him.
- I'm sorry he's taking it so badly.
- What will it take, Carlisle?
What will it take for you to stop
hounding the lad?
I'm doing my job.
You know bloody well Danny didn't do it.
Maybe he didn't.
But in the absence of any better suspect
I'm duty bound to carry on
building a case against him.
If you've got to pick on someone,
pick on me.
Is that you telling me
I have reason to suspect you?
- Lf you like. Yeah. Why not?
- So what are you admitting to?
What?
I can't just suspect you
because you've told me to.
What exactly are you admitting to?
I moved Mike Hooley's body
to the arcade.
There. You happy now?
- You moved the body?
- Correct.
Why?
I didn't want the planning people
thinking that my future casino hotel
was being used as a part-time brothel.
Let's get you down to the station,
get your statement and get you charged.
What, you're making this official?
I thought this was off the record,
you know, man to man.
You've just come here
and confessed to a very serious crime.
Now, why would I want to keep that
off the record?
www.tvsubtitles.net