(bell ringing)
Too late. I saw them.
Saw what?
Your free lunch tickets.
Sucks being poor.
Before the recession,
my mom was a real estate agent.
Solid middle class.
Now she's the only black waitress
working at the Lima Country Club,
taking orders from a bunch of
rich old white guys who barely tip.
And it kills me,
she's working extra shifts
to pay for my dance lessons.
Wait... you dance?
Let's just keep that between us.
Oh... young love.
BLAINE: Do you remember when
you first started dating Santana
and I started dating Kurt,
back before everyone was
so busy and so... far away.
Things were so much simpler.
We had so much more hope and innocence.
Every day was just like Valentine's Day.
We're still young.
Shouldn't we still be
experiencing those things?
(bell ringing)
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
Hey.
Somebody slept late.
It's lunchtime.
Do you want a Croque Madame?
We didn't go to bed till late.
Thank God for earplugs.
I love you both but I don't
want to hear any of that.
We didn't do anything.
He didn't even talk to me,
we just, like, laid there.
I'm gonna take this down to the park
and watch drug deals go down.
It's good to see you again, Finn.
You, too, little brother.
Um, so, are you hungry?
Can I make you some eggs?
Yeah. Thanks.
Wow, this place is awesome.
It's not the ideal neighborhood, but
at least we can sort of see Manhattan.
I can't do this, Finn.
I don't understand.
I don't know what's going on.
Why are you here and why aren't
you in your uniform?
Because I'm not in the Army.
Well, I was, for 16 days...
(Drill Sergeant yelling)
FINN: It wasn't that bad.
I really felt like I was someplace.
I could make a difference,
and I'm pretty used to getting yelled at,
so I was doing okay.
Then, one day, I was cleaning Rachel...
they make you give your rifle a name...
(gunshot)
Right through my thigh.
Thank God it didn't hit any bone.
I got a semi-honorable
discharge.
So I've been backpacking through Georgia
for the past couple months.
I'm sorry I didn't call you, but...
but I was just so embarrassed.
I mean, I left with
so much certainty and confidence.
I was gonna redeem my dad
and make you proud.
I couldn't face you
seeing me as a Lima loser.
Enough of this...
enough lumping around.
All right, so what?
The Army didn't work out.
Plans change.
You're here now, with me, in...
in the greatest city in the whole world
and what a better place for you and I
to find you a new dream.
Like what? Before the Army,
you applied to Pace to be an actor.
You know, that was obviously
not the right school but...
I don't know, maybe NYADA is.
I mean, why don't you come with me
to all of my classes this week,
and if you love it,
then you can move in here
and we'll spend the whole
year just finding a way
for you to get in.
You serious?
I love it here, but something
has always been missing.
I let you go once and I'm not
gonna let it happen again.
I mean, I'm not jealous,
I just think that it's insane
that all Porcelain had to do
to get an internship
with Vogue.com
is take photos of every ridiculous outfit
he's ever paired with a Cossack hat,
and a see-through raincoat
and then show up at an interview
where he is lauded as a visionary
because his jodhpurs happened
to match his riding crop.
Well, you know, you could
follow your dream, too.
Your mom gave you that money and said
you could go to New York,
too, iyou wanted.
I like being in college.
My schedule is crazy but I love being
a cheerleader and I like the idea that
I'm never more than
a few hours away from you.
Can't you do laundry at school?
Mm-mm. My first week there,
I heard a rumor
that all the water in Louisville
is just purified runoff from
the Kentucky Derby stables.
Nasty. But...
mo importantly, I promised myself that
I would only do laundry at home, that way,
no matter how busy I got,
I would be forced
to come home every few weeks,
and then I'd get to see you.
Are you okay?
Yeah, sorry.
I was up late last night,
reading Desecration:
Antichrist Takes the Throne.
It's the ninth book in
the Left Behind series
of the apocalyptic Christian
novels about the end times
and the rise of the Antichrist,
who name is Nicolae Carpathia,
or Barack Obama, depending on who you ask.
Brit, those Left Behind books
are really intense.
What teacher is making you read those?
And don't tell me that
Mr. Schue is doing
Christian music week.
It's not a class,
it's an after-school club
that Sam and Joe and Kitty
and Dottie Kazatori are in.
And you should come tomorrow.
Who's Dottie Kazatori?
She's Tina's assistant.
Everyone graduated and things got weird.
(school bell ringing, phone buzzing)
Hey, stranger.
(phone ringing) Hey. Uh...
Crap! Can you hold on
one second?
Isabelle Wright's office.
How can I help you?
Um, it's me, Kurt.
(phone ringing) Oh, my God, I'm so sorry.
Uh, look, ve taken over Isabelle's phones
for the week, and they
just won't stop ringing.
It's... it's okay.
If you want to call me back
later, we can talk then. I can't.
Isabelle says we have to get the column
on the Web site by midnight tonight.
(phone ringing, Kurt groans)
Look, I know this is frustrating.
It's frustrating for me, too,
and I don't want to miss our phone dates
but, you know, this-this
could be a career for me.
I get that; I-I do.
I really get it.
It's just...
I... really miss you.
A lot, okay?
I miss talking to you
and I miss hugging you
and I miss messing around with you...
Me, too.
But you're coming in two weeks, right?
I know, but... what am I
supposed to do until then,
just hold my breath?
(phone ringing)
Shoot. Joan Didion's calling.
She always has the best gossip.
Um, all right, I will call you or text you
on a break, okay? Okay.
Okay. I love you.
(bell ringing)
FINN:
Look at her, she's amazing.
Even when she's not all dolled up.
I've never seen her so alive.
She's found the place where she belongs,
where she thrives.
I just wish I could find a place for me
because I definitely don't belong here.
I'd never get into NYADA,
and what the hell
am I gonna do in New York,
run a hot dog cart outside
of Madison Square Garden?
No way.
I used to be the man of her dreams,
but now we're not even in the same world.
(Duncan Sheik's "Barely Breathing" begins)
♪ I know what you're doing ♪
♪ I see it all too clear ♪
♪ I only taste the saline ♪
♪ When I kiss away your tears ♪
FINN:
♪ You really had me going ♪
♪ Wishing on a star ♪
♪ But the black holes that surround you ♪
♪ Are heavier by far ♪
♪ I believed in your confusion ♪
♪ You were so completely torn ♪
♪ It must have been that yesterday ♪
♪ Was the day that I was born ♪
♪ There's not much to examine ♪
♪ There's nothing left to hide ♪
♪ You really can't be serious ♪
♪ If you have to ask me why ♪
BOTH: ♪ I say goodbye ♪
♪ 'Cause I am barely breathing ♪
♪ And I can't find the air ♪
♪ I don't know who I'm kidding ♪
♪ Imagining you care ♪
♪ And I could stand here waiting ♪
♪ A fool foanother day ♪
♪ I don't suppose it's worth the price ♪
♪ It's worth the price,
the price that I would pay ♪
(no voice)
♪ I rise above ♪
♪ Or sink below ♪
♪ Every time ♪
♪ You come and go ♪
♪ Please don't ♪
♪ Come and go
♪ Oh! ♪
♪ 'Cause I am barely breathing ♪
♪ And I can't find the air ♪
♪ I don't know who I'm kidding ♪
♪ Imagining you care ♪
♪ And I could stand here waiting ♪
♪ A fool for another day ♪
♪ I don't suppose it's worth the price ♪
♪ It's worth the price,
the price that I would pay ♪
♪ But I'm thinking it over anyway ♪
♪ I'm thinking it over anyway ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Ooh, oh ♪
♪ I know what you're doing ♪
♪ I see it all too clear. ♪
(Rachel squeals happily)
Dude, I'm not wearing a suit
for a night out on the town.
I didn't even bring a suit.
Then you can't wear Dad jeans
and a rugby shirt to Callbacks.
What's Callbacks?
This amazing bar
that all the NYADA students go to,
and Friday nights are the best
because everybody gets up and sings,
and it's where we're going tonight,
and it's gonna be great.
So I have to dress up to
go to a karaoke bar?
Come on, Finn, we'll let you
sing "Don't Stop Believin',"
or something equally uplifting.
I don't... I don't know.
I'm so out of practice, I
haven't even sang in the shower
since Nationals.
(knocking on door)
Surprise!
Blaine!
Hi.
KURT: This is amazing!
But I wasn't expecting you
for another two weeks.
I know, I just couldn't wait any longer.
I miss you too much.
Oh, I miss you, too.
So good to see you.
Wait!
I can't believe you're here.
I missed you so much. Hi.
Hi. Oh, Finn!
What are you doing here?
I'm... not really sure
at the moment, but...
It's fantastic...
we're all together here.
Just like the good old days.
(playing a mellow tune)
You okay?
You seem a little...
I'm-I'm great.
It was just a...
it was a rough flight.
I had a middle seat because
I booked the ticket
so last-minute.
Well, I, for one, am glad you did.
It's our first night out in New York.
We'll never forget this.
Uh, Coke and, uh...
Oh, amaretto sour,
please... virgin.
It's good. Hey, Finn, Rachel.
Brody, hi.
Hey, Brody, good to see you again, man.
Yeah, you too, you too.
So, how's the, uh,
visit been going so far?
Amazing. I took him to school
to get the full NYADA experience together.
Cool. Well, in that case,
I hope you're singing tonight.
You haven't really been to NYADA
until you've sung at Callbacks.
This is what I've been trying to tell him,
and I really, really want him to sing.
"Give Your Heart a Break" with me, but...
But I'm not a student, so...
Well, you're with Rachel,
which makes you honorary.
And I'm buddies
with Pascal, the piano player.
And the song works better as a duet, so...
Well, why don't you guys sing it together?
It's a NYADA tradition, right?
And you guys
are both NYADA students.
Finn.
Yeah.
All right, let's do it.
I love you.
Wish me luck.
I'm so nervous.
It's my Off-Off Broadway debut.
BRODY: It's all good.
I got your back.
(Demi Lovato's "Give Your
Heart a Break" begins)
♪ The day I first met you ♪
♪ You told me you'd never fall in love ♪
♪ But now that I get you ♪
♪ I know fear is what it really was ♪
♪ Now here we are ♪
♪ So close yet so far ♪
♪ Haven't I passed the test? ♪
♪ When will you realize ♪
♪ That, baby,
I'm not like the rest? ♪
♪ Don't wanna break your heart,
wanna give your heart a break ♪
♪ I know you're scared it's wrong ♪
♪ Like you might make a mistake ♪
♪ There's just one life to live ♪
♪ And there's no time to wait, to waste ♪
♪ So let me give your heart a break ♪
♪ Give your heart a break ♪
♪ Let me give your heart a break ♪
♪ Your heart a break ♪ ♪ Oh, yeah, yeah ♪
BRODY: ♪ On Sunday ♪
♪ You went home alone ♪
♪ There were tears in your eyes ♪
♪ I called your cell phone ♪
♪ My love, but you did not reply ♪
♪ The world is ours ♪
♪ If we want it, we can take it ♪
♪ If you just take my hand ♪
♪ There's no turning back now ♪
♪ No turning back ♪
♪ Baby, try to understand ♪
♪ Don't wanna break your heart ♪
♪ Wanna give your heart a break ♪
♪ I know you're scared it's wrong ♪
♪ Like you might make a mistake ♪
♪ Don't wanna break your heart ♪
♪ Maybe I can ease the ache, the ache ♪
♪ So let me give your heart a break ♪
♪ Give your heart a break ♪
♪ Your heart a break ♪
♪ There's just so much you can take ♪
♪ Give your heart a break,
let me give your heart a break ♪
♪ Your heart a break ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, yeah. ♪
(cheering and applause)
Oh, my God, you guys.
It's so amazing up there.
You have to do your
Sweeney Todd mega-medley.
And risk a Page Six spread?
I don't think so.
KURT: "Vogue.com intern sings
without warming up."
Not happening. I want
to sing something.
Yeah, just, uh, ask Pascal.
Pascal.
How was I? Was I good?
Yeah. Yeah!
Um, hi, everyone.
I, um... I want to sing a song
that's very special to me.
This is a song that I sang
the first time I ever met
the love of my life.
Um, so, Kurt, this is for you.
♪ Before you met me I was all right ♪
♪ But things were kind of heavy ♪
♪ You brought me to life ♪
♪ Now every February ♪
♪ You'll be my Valentine ♪
♪ Valentine ♪
♪ Let's go all the way tonight ♪
♪ No regrets ♪
♪ Just love ♪
♪ We can dance until we die ♪
♪ You and I ♪
♪ Will be young forever ♪
♪ You make me ♪
♪ Feel like I'm living a teenage dream ♪
♪ The way you turn me on ♪
♪ I can't sleep ♪
♪ Let's run away
and don't ever look back ♪
♪ Don't ever look back ♪
♪ My heart stops when you look at me ♪
♪ Just one touch ♪
♪ Now, baby, I believe ♪
♪ This is real ♪
♪ So take a chance ♪
♪ And don't ever look back ♪
♪ Don't ever look ♪
♪ I'm-a get your heart racing ♪
♪ In my skintight jeans ♪
♪ Be your teenage dream tonight ♪
♪ Let you put your hands on me ♪
♪ In my skintight jeans ♪
♪ Be your teenage dream tonight ♪
♪ You make me ♪
♪ Feel like a teenage dream ♪
♪ The way you turn me on ♪
♪ I can't sleep, let's run away ♪
♪ And don't ever look back,
don't ever look back ♪
♪ My heart stops when you look at me ♪
♪ Just one touch ♪
♪ Now, baby, I believe ♪
♪ This is real ♪
♪ So take a chance ♪
♪ And don't ever look back, no ♪
♪ And I'm-a get
your heart racing ♪
♪ In my skintight jeans ♪
♪ Be your teenage dream tonight ♪
♪ I'll let you put your hands on me ♪
♪ In my skintight jeans ♪
♪ Be your teenage dream ♪
♪ Tonight. ♪
(cheering and applause)
So, you and your friend
sounded great together.
Oh, I wish you would have
gotten up there and sang with me.
Yeah, I just...
I don't fit in here.
This place is just too big.
It moves too fast.
People are too talented.
No. I felt that way
when I first moved here.
Even in Ohio, I knew
you were meant for this.
I'm just not.
So, that was... moving.
I guess I'm kind of
wondering why that was.
Well, you know, I, uh...
I really missed you.
I miss you, too.
And I'm really glad that you're here.
But you've been so emotional
and weirdly sad.
Please stop pretending
that there's nothing wrong.
I was with someone.
So, are you sure you and that
Brody guy are just friends?
Look, I told you, everything's...
Just, ple-please...
don't lie to me.
I couldn't get in touch with you, okay?
I-I... you weren't
answering my calls
or my text messages.
I didn't know where you were
or even if you were okay.
So you were with him.
I kissed him, but that's it.
Okay, and only just because you told me
that you wanted me to be free.
I can't believe
I even said that.
I'm so stupid.
It was Sebastian, wasn't it?
No, it... it wasn't Sebastian,
but it doesn't...
It didn't mean anything.
It was just a hook-up, okay?
Who was it?
It doesn't matter who it was with, Kurt.
What matters is that I was by myself.
I needed you.
I needed you around,
and you weren't there.
And I was lonely, and I'm...
I'm really sorry.
You don't think that I've been lonely?
You don't think that I've had temptations?
But I didn't act on it
because I knew what it meant.
It meant something
horrible and awful and...
I'm so sorry, Kurt.
I really am.
♪ You and me ♪
♪ We used to be together ♪
♪ Every day together ♪
♪ Always ♪
♪ I really feel ♪
♪ That I'm losing my best friend ♪
♪ I can't believe this could be the end ♪
RACHEL and KURT:
♪ It looks as though ♪
♪ You're letting go ♪
♪ And if it's real ♪
♪ Well, I don't want to know ♪
♪ Don't speak,
I know just what you're saying ♪
♪ So please stop explaining ♪
♪ Don't tell me 'cause it hurts ♪
♪ Don't speak,
I know what you're thinking ♪
♪ I don't need your reasons ♪
♪ Don't tell me 'cause it hurts ♪
♪ Our memories ♪
♪ Well, they can be inviting ♪
♪ But some are altogether mighty ♪
♪ Frightening ♪
♪ As we die ♪
♪ Both you and I ♪
♪ With my head in my hands ♪
♪ I sit and cry ♪
♪ Don't speak,
I know just what you're saying ♪
♪ So please stop explaining ♪
♪ Don't tell me 'cause it hurts ♪
♪ No, no ♪
♪ Don't speak,
I know what you're thinking ♪
♪ And I don't need your reasons ♪
♪ Don't tell me 'cause it hurts ♪
♪ Hush, darling ♪ ♪ La la la la ♪
♪ Don't tell me ♪
♪ 'Cause it hurts. ♪
KURT: You can't just run away.
Dude, you totally spooked me.
I thought I was the only one awake.
Been waiting for somebody to come out.
I was hoping it'd be Blaine.
You guys okay?
I kind of feel like I'm going to die.
Guess I don't have to ask you
what you're doing, apparently.
I'll talk to her later about it.
I... I just got
to get away for a bit.
Six months ago, did you ever think
that things would be like this?
Sometimes, I miss high school, you know?
Come on, give me a hug before I go.
Do you want me to say anything to Rachel?
No.
(school bell ringing)
Hi, Boobless. It is my duty
as a soldier of the Lord
to invite you to McKinley's
newest and most important club,
the Left Behind Club. Kitty thinks
the end of times is coming.
It's a fact that the Book of
Revelations predicted Twitter.
It's one of the seven
signs of the apocalypse,
along with porn,
unexplainable weather anomalies,
Martian rovers, Barney Frank,
the Middle East, and MSNBC.
The Left Behind Club accepts everyone,
even losers and lezzies, so
your whole Glee Club's invited.
Well, you're welcome to join us
as long as you're not a Muslim.
It's like Kirk Cameron said,
it's never too late...
until it's too late.
Okay, everybody, listen up.
Y'all are sinners, and you
better get right with God
toot sweet, because Jesus
just logged onto Orbitz
and booked himself
a plane ticket back to Earth.
See, he's got an awesome dad named God
who's throwing him a bitchin'
party called Armageddon,
where he's gonna get to
kick off his sandals
dance a little bit,
judge the crap out of everybody.
SANTANA: Hi. I have a question.
What the hell are you talking about?
Um, the Rapture.
When the end times come,
the true believers in Christ
will be lifted up,
body and soul, into heaven,
leaving everyone else to duke it out.
What about those of us
who are still on the fence
about all of this?
I don't know what there is to be
on the fence about, Dottie.
Sorry I made you come to this.
That's okay.
You're half-Jewish, right?
Mm-hmm. Does that mean you'll
float up to heaven at half speed?
I just heard there's an
elderly Japanese woman
who fell down in the bathroom.
She doesn't speak English,
and she needs your help.
I'll be right back.
Santana, come on, we should help her.
SANTANA: No, wait, Brit...
I'm pretty sure I know
what's going on here.
Okay, everybody, let's go.
Move it, move it, move it!
What's everybody doing?
JAKE: Fake Rapture.
It was Kitty's idea.
I can't find any Japanese ladies.
Hello? Where did everyone go?
Oh, my God.
We've been left behind.
We've been left behind!
That's what it feels like to be
left behind, Dottie Kazatori.
JAKE: Kitty! This has
gone way too far, okay?
(Dottie whimpering, mumbling)
Dottie seems... pretty damaged.
(Dottie keening)
MARLEY:
I think I'm gonna go, now.
No! Wait. Please don't go.
I just really don't like that Kitty girl.
And... I can't believe you do.
Brittany, can-can we
please go home?
I don't think this club is good for you.
I'm not leaving.
Being left behind sucks.
It's just a stupid prank.
You don't get it.
You me behind, and it hurt.
(hyperventilating)
That's exactly what it felt like.
(school bell ringing)
Oh, my God.
(laughing)
Hey, buddy. Hi.
You look great.
Oh, it's good to see you.
Wait, I don't...
Hold on, I don't get it.
What happened...
what happened to the Army?
It... didn't work out.
Okay.
Well, um...
when'd you get in?
Have you spoken with Rachel?
She...
She's been worried sick about you.
It's so good to
see you, Mr. Shue.
Can I talk to you about something?
Yeah, of course.
(stifled sob)
(school bell ringing)
Hey.
Um, by the time I got up,
you were already gone.
I didn't get a chance
to say good-bye.
Why'd you do that to him?
I don't know.
I just...
There's no excuse.
He won't talk to me.
I don't even know if we're broken up.
Finn! Dude, what's up?
I'm just passing through,
visiting my mom and Burt,
and Mr. Shue said I could
come by if I wanted.
Finn Hudson in the house, yo!
Do you know who that is?
Oh! SAM: Listen up!
For all of you guys
who don't know, this is
Finn Hudson right here.
I thought you joined the Army!
I-I did, but...
WILL: But things don't always work
out the way you planned them to.
And I said to Finn
the same thing I say everyone
who comes through this club:
We're a family, and you're
always welcome here.
Even if you just need to take a
break and think things through.
In any case, we have a lot to do today.
First order of business:
Deciding what the fall
musical's going to be.
(cheers) All right!
So I'm passing out a list
of possibilities. Peter Pan?
Fiorello? What the heck?
Unique wants to do Hedwig.
Uh, Tina wants to do Pacific Overtures,
Miss Saigon, and Flower Drum Song.
The challenge is picking something
that plays to our collective strengths,
and that won't set off a firestorm
in the community like Rocky Horror did.
You should do Grease.
Grease?
I know it 'cause the song
I auditioned for Glee Club
was from Grease, remember?
Yeah. Guys like it.
Girls like it.
People like my mom like it.
It's about high school,
and growing up, and...
being true to yourself.
Plus, the songs rock.
The wisdom of Solomon...
All right.
Grease is the word.
Yes! (cheering)
Finn's back!
What's that? Open it.
Okay.
I'm officially on the blue ribbon panel
to improve arts education.
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, my goodness, Mr. Schuester
goes to Washington.
Oh, congratulations! Thank you.
Thank you. (giggling)
And what would you say
about Miss Pillsbury
also going to Washington?
, my gosh, I'd love to.
For like a long weekend, or something.
That would be wonderful.
No, like...
like for a few months.
I want you to be there with me.
(laughs nervously)
What about my job?
That's what a tenure's for.
Your job will be waiting
when you get back.
This is not that I'm
afraid of losing my job.
This is that I like my job.
Look, this isn't a permanent thing, Emma.
It's like an extended vacation.
A sabbatical.
Teachers take them all the time.
I don't want a sabbatical.
But I-I thought you
were supportive of this.
I am, because I know how
much this means to you,
but this is for you.
I didn't know you just expected me
to drop my entire life.
Emma, I love you.
You're my fiancée.
All I'm saying is,
I don't want to be alone
and not be with you.
And I don't want to sit alone
in some hotel room somewhere
doing nothing, while you're off
fulfilling your dreams.
You know, I don't think
what I'm asking is so crazy.
I thought you'd be excited.
So you thought I'd just pop the champagne,
follow you around like an
obedient little puppy dog?
Is that really all you think of me, Will?
No, of course not, Emma.
Oh, come on, we still
need to talk about this.
We just did.
You just don't like what I have to say.
(distant phone ringing)
Well, someone's either
seriously crushing on you,
or seriously trying to
make up for something.
The latter.
Ouch. He cute?
The cutest.
Oh, that sucks. I'm sorry.
Hey, you need to
go binge-shopping?
Isabelle's summoning us
to the conference room.
I can cover for you.
I'm okay.
I'll be okay.
(school bell ringing)
You wanted to see me?
Sophomore year I used
to sit in this back row,
and secretly watch you.
I counted the number of times
you'd smile at me,
and I'd die on days that you didn't.
I miss this place so much.
It's where we fell in love.
Where I could say things with music,
when words just weren't enough.
And I need to tell you something
that I don't know how to say.
(Taylor Swift's "Mine" beings)
♪ You were in college ♪
♪ Working part-time
waiting tables ♪
♪ Left a small town, never looked back ♪
♪ I was a flight risk ♪
♪ With a fear of falling ♪
♪ Wondering why we bother with love ♪
♪ If it never lasts ♪
♪ I say can you believe it? ♪
♪ As we're lying on the couch ♪
♪ The moment I could see it ♪
♪ Yes, yes, I can see it now ♪
♪ Do you remember ♪
♪ We were sitting there by the water ♪
♪ You put your arm around me ♪
♪ For the first time ♪
♪ You made a rebel of a careless man's ♪
♪ Careful daughter ♪
♪ You are the best thing ♪
♪ That's ever been mine ♪
♪ And I remember that fight,
2:30 a.m. ♪
♪ When everything was slipping ♪
♪ Right out of our hands ♪
♪ I ran out crying ♪
♪ And you followed me
out into the street ♪
♪ Then you took me by surprise ♪
♪ You said I'll never leave you alone ♪
♪ You said ♪
♪ I remember how it felt ♪
♪ Sitting by the water ♪
♪ She is the best thing ♪
♪ That's ever been mine... ♪
♪ Ooh, whoa... ♪
♪ You made a rebel of ♪
♪ A careless man's careful daughter ♪
♪ You are the best thing ♪
♪ That's ever been mine ♪
♪ Do you believe it? ♪
♪ We're gonna make it now ♪
♪ And I can see it ♪
♪ I can see it now. ♪
Wow.
Sad songs make me really sad,
and I don't want to be sad.
I haven't been a good girlfriend to you.
I can't come home on the weekends and
pretend that things are the way they were,
because they aren't.
And I don't want to be like
all of those other
long-distance relationships,
that, you know, hang in there
for a few months, and then...
break up when someone eventually
cheats or things get weird.
I would never cheat on you.
I know.
I know, and I would
never cheat on you, either,
but... if we're being
completely honest,
I had, well, I guess
the best way to describe it would be...
an energy exchange?
SANTANA: I was cramming for this
really boring sociology class,
and I looked up, and this girl
was staring at me.
She smiled a little too long,
which means she was either crazy,
or a lesbian.
And judging by the stack of
Virginia Woolf she was reading,
she was into me.
So I smiled back.
I had an attraction.
And you,
you may have had one
or you might have one,
and that happens.
Let's just do the mature thing here, okay?
This is not an official breakup,
but let's just be honest that
long-distance relationships are
almost impossible to maintain.
Because both people are rarely
getting what they need,
especially at our age.
(sniffles) This sounds a
lot like a breakup to me.
You know this isn't working.
You know I will always love you the most.
I love you, too.
(school bell ringing)
I'm sorry about the Left Behind club.
That's Kitty's thing, not mine.
I just don't get it.
I don't get why someone like
you is with someone like Kitty.
What do you mean, someone like me?
You act like you don't care
what anyone thinks, but you
obviously are just as desperate
to fit in as everyone
else if you'll date her.
You don't know how it feels
to really be on the outside.
The blacks kids think I'm too white;
The white kids think I'm too black.
Kitty's funny and hot,
and yeah, a little crazy,
but you know what, she likes me
and when I'm next to her,
no one makes fun of me
for once.
What's happening here?
You coveting my man,
itty-bitty?
Kitty, come on, ease up.
I heard they're opening up
a new Ronald McDonald House
in Lima just for you
and your finger-licking,
lard-loving,
Gilbert-Grape-looking mama. Hey!
That's enough.
I'm sorry, or what?
Or I'm breaking up with you.
You do not want to break up with me, okay?
I am like a bad Carrie Underwood
song once I get going.
Yeah, well, I'll take my chances.
We're done.
You did this.
Well, you're both gonna regret this turn
of events because I will
tell you one more thing.
Obama's gonna lose.
(screams)
Thank you.
You didn't have to do that.
Actually, I think I did.
Hey, do you want to go through
sheet music for Grease?
I was thinking of auditioning
for Sandy, and I think
you'd be really great...
Actually,
I have to go.
But I'll see you later
in Glee Club, okay?
Okay.
(school bell ringing)
(footsteps approaching)
This is where you proposed to me.
When you did, you reminded me it
was where we had our first date.
It's also where we first met.
Do you remember that?
Yeah, glee rehearsal.
You, uh, you really freaked me out.
This place is kind of like our Jerusalem.
All roads seem
to just lead us back here.
I went to your house
and to the tire shop.
I should have known you
would've just been here though.
I know it sounds kind of weird,
but I just felt like singing up here.
Seems to have helped me
figure out stuff before, so...
Yeah, I would have just,
you know, come here first,
if you would have picked up your phone
or answered my text messages.
Instead I had to get on a
plane and drive around town,
looking for you, like an idiot.
I'm sorry.
I just needed time to think.
You had four months.
I hated you for what you did
to me at that train station.
I was trying to help you.
I hated you.
But then when I got to
New York, I thought how much
you love me
and how hard that must have been for you.
And I thought,
this...
this is what a man looks like.
This is how a man loves.
But you...
not telling me where you were
for four months
and sneaking out before sunrise,
in the middle of the night,
without saying good-bye,
that is not being a man, Finn.
I'm trying to give you your freedom!
I don't need you to give me my freedom!
I am a grown woman.
I don't need you to hide from me,
to keep me from doing
what is right for me.
Like that Brody guy?
I didn't do Brody, okay?
And don't you think that I would
have rather have been with you?
Well, didn't you say he was on Broadway?
Right? And he's got,
like, three-percent body fat.
Who am I?
I barely even graduated high school,
and my life has absolutely
no direction.
Don't you get it?
No matter how rich
or famous or successful I become,
when it comes to you,
I'm...
I'm always gonna be
that moon-eyed girl
who freaked you out at
our first glee rehearsal.
You were the first boy
who made me feel loved
and sexy
and visible.
You are my first love.
And...
I want, more than anything,
for you to be my last.
But I can't do this anymore.
At least, not now.
We're done.
Wow.
What am I gonna do with my life?
I don't have my girl, I don't have a job,
I don't have a place in this world.
You have you.
And that's better than
anyone else on the planet,
as far as I'm concerned.
(kissing)
(sighs)
(Coldplay's "The Scientist" begins)
♪ Come up to meet you ♪
♪ Tell you I'm sorry ♪
♪ You don't know how lovely you are ♪
♪ I had to find you ♪
♪ Running in circles ♪
♪ Coming up tails ♪
♪ Heads on a science apart ♪
♪ Nobody said it was easy ♪
FINN and BLAINE: ♪ It's such
a shame for us to part ♪
♪ Nobody said ♪
♪ It was easy ♪
♪ No one ever said it would be this hard ♪
♪ Oh, take me back to the start ♪
♪ I was just guessing ♪
♪ At numbers and figures ♪
♪ Pulling the puzzles apart ♪
♪ Questions of science ♪
♪ Science and progress ♪
♪ Do not speak as loud as my heart ♪
WILL and EMMA:
♪ But tell me you love me ♪
♪ Come back and haunt me ♪
♪ O Oh, and I rush to the start ♪
RACHEL and FINN:
♪ Running in circles ♪
♪ Chasing our tails ♪
♪ Coming back as we are ♪
ALL:
♪ Nobody said it was easy ♪
♪ Oh, it's such a shame for us to part ♪
♪ No one ever said ♪
♪ It would be so hard ♪
♪ I'm going back to the start ♪
ALL:
♪ Nobody said it was easy ♪
♪ Oh, oh... ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Yeah ♪ ♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Nobody said it was easy ♪
♪ Nobody said ♪ ♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ It was easy ♪
♪ Oh, oh... oh, oh... ♪
♪ Nobody said ♪
♪ It was easy ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ No, no... no... no... ♪
ALL:
♪ Nobody said it was easy. ♪
(song ends)
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com