So here's what you missed on Glee:
The New Directions! are headed to Nationals
in beautiful Los Angeles,
and Sue gave Mr. Shue an ultimatum that,
if they don't win, the club is finished.
Michael William Schuster!
But he says he knows a
championship team when he sees one.
You guys are ready.
Although last time I counted,
they don't even have enough members.
They'd better scare up
three band members stat.
Finn lead the Glee Club
to victory last year,
but now they don't have a leader
and they also don't have Rachel.
Or Kurt. Or Santana.
Or Britney. Or Mercedes.
Or Rory, the Irish kid. Where'd he go?
And they're also up against
a performing arts school
where they don't even take classes
and they're all, like,
acrobats and contortionists.
And that's what you missed on Glee.
(school bell ringing)
(humming)
Hey, you wanted to see me?
Yeah. Have a seat.
(clears throat)
Um, I just want to let
you know that even though
I've kind of, like, checked out of school
since I'm not going to college,
I'm totally committed
to Glee Club, you know.
I've had Artie and Blaine
drilling me, like, nonstop
on the rights and lefts
of the choreography,
and I've recruited three hot
Cheerios! to get us to 12...
You don't have to prove
yourself to me, Sam.
Finn transformed this
club when he joined up.
He wasn't just a male lead,
he was the captain of the football team.
He was the coolest kid in school.
I mean, a real dude, you know?
He was our secret weapon
at those competitions.
Other schools might have
had their version of a Rachel
or a Kurt, but no one had a Finn.
Yeah, he... he made it seem pretty cool.
When he recruited you,
he wasn't just looking
for another voice in here.
He was looking for someone
to take his place after he graduated.
Someone to help lead all
of these wonderful misfits.
I'm not Finn, Mr. Shue.
Finn was, like, a real leader, you know?
And so are you.
And I'm gonna need you to be
that guy when we get to L.A.
The kids want you to be that guy.
They're all waiting for you to see yourself
the way they see you.
The new kids love you,
and so do the older ones.
I'm sure that everything is
gonna be fine once we get there.
But if the time comes,
and you need to step up,
I'm gonna be counting
on you to get it done.
They're here.
Hey, guys.
Good morning.
How's it going, man?
We just wanted to come in and say
that, uh, Finn really cared about you guys.
More than you know.
Finn always said that winning nationals
was the greatest
accomplishment of his life.
But I honestly believe
that coaching you guys
to winning would have
meant even more to him.
BURT: Now, now we're not saying
go out there and win it for Finn.
That wasn't his style.
Um, what Finn would have said was
this is the time of your lives right now.
You're never gonna forget it,
and in a moment, it's all gonna be over.
So no sad faces.
No regrets.
Just go out there and have a blast,
and, you know, it'll be okay
if you won the damn thing.
(laughter)
And the best part about
it is that Burt and Carole
have agreed to come with us as chaperones.
(cheering)
But I think before we go,
we need a little mood music
to send us off.
Brad?
(Randy Newman's "I Love L.A." playing)
♪ Hate New York City ♪
♪ It's cold and it's damp ♪
♪ And all the people dress like monkeys ♪
♪ Let's leave Chicago to the Eskimos ♪
♪ That town's a little bit too rugged ♪
♪ For you and me, bad girl ♪
(whooping, applause)
(laughs)
WILL: Yes, yes!
♪ Rolling down Imperial Highway ♪
♪ With a big nasty redhead at my side ♪
♪ Santa Ana winds blowing
hard from the north ♪
♪ And we were born to ride ♪
♪ From the South Bay to the Valley ♪
♪ From the West Side to the East Side ♪
♪ Everybody's very happy ♪
♪ 'Cause the sun is shining all the time ♪
♪ Looks like another perfect day ♪
♪ I love L.A. ♪
♪ I love it, I love L.A. ♪
♪ We love it! Yeah, I love L.A. ♪
♪ I love it ♪
♪ I love L.A. ♪
♪ Whoo-ooh! ♪
♪ I love it, I love L.A. ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We love it ♪
(humming melody)
♪ I love L.A. ♪
♪ I love it, I love L.A. ♪
♪ Oh-oh, I love L.A. ♪
♪ We love it! ♪
Sorry, sir, can't release the rooms.
Don't look now, but I think
someone famous just came in!
Even better! It's Mercedes Jones!
I was hoping you'd make it!
Are you crazy? I wouldn't
miss this for the world.
Ooh, I heard that you got a record contract
because either Usher, Kelly Clarkson
or Michael Jackson's daddy
bought your album in
a 7-Eleven parking lot.
MERCEDES: I was selling my CD
Hell 2 the No in a parking lot.
Now, I ain't gonna lie, business was wack.
But then this Mexican lady bought one.
I think she felt sorry for me.
Turns out, that Mexican angel
on earth was the housekeeper
to Kanye West.
She gave it to Kanye,
who gave it to Kim, and she
gave it to Ryan Seacrest,
who gave it to Sony
Records... the Sony Records.
Next thing I know, I'm sipping Perrier
with a bunch of rich dudes.
All right, I like this plan,
and I love that you guys like my songs.
So, yes, I'll write for
the artists on your label.
But there is a catch, so listen up.
In exchange for six songs,
I want my own album deal.
And I'm talking all the perks,
all the P&A that you can muster
and two music videos that you pay for.
And if it sells,
I don't have to do a lame
follow-up Christmas album.
Hold up.
Is that dog alive?
Oh, it's a faux-huahua.
A fake Chihuahua.
(laughs)
Mr. Shue, Mercedes is here!
- Oh, hey, Mercedes.
- Hi!
I'd like to speak to a manager, please.
What seems to be the problem here?
WOMAN: Well, one hour ago,
I got a call from Detective Sue Sylvester
with the LAPD saying that
a 50-year-old Ohio man
with a perm had abducted 12
emotionally disturbed teenagers,
and if he tried to make a reservation,
I was to contact the FBI.
Oh, my God, that's them.
Who?
Do you seriously have no idea who that is?
Do none of you read the show choir blogs?
No, Blaine, we don't.
None of us read the show
choir blogs. Just you.
That's Throat Explosion.
And that's their leader, Jean-Baptiste.
Jean-Baptiste was born in
Quebec to acrobatic parents.
He trained with Cirque du Soleil
before emigrating to Ft. Wayne
where he used his
French-Canadian circus stylings
to turn the entire show
choir world upside down.
Bonjour !
You must be the New Directions.
And you... must be Blaine.
How did you know my name?
Show choir blogs.
I'm, you know, I'm Sam Evans,
and I'm the leader of the New Directions.
And, you know, I know you guys
are all really good and stuff,
but that's just gonna get
us out of our comfort zones
and send us over the top.
Well, it was really great to meet you, Sam.
Best of luck, New Directions.
We really can't wait to see your set.
And crush you like a bug.
Bye!
Excuse me.
What is with the turtlenecks?
That was tense.
Oh, I wouldn't miss this
show choir high school drama.
Come on, tell me all about it. Let's go.
Like a bug. That was good.
He was right here in my face.
Why didn't I think of that?
He smells like a winner.
MAN (on TV): Another golden day
of sunshine here in Los Angeles.
Hey, Marley, it's Ryder.
Can I come in for a minute?
- Hi.
Can I talk to you?
- You can come in.
- Okay.
Look, you and me are
probably never gonna happen.
And... like, I'm slowly accepting that.
But that doesn't mean
I don't care about you.
Or that I don't occasionally look
at your Facebook page to check your status.
Single, and it's going to stay that way.
Talking about where you
put what your job is.
It used to say, "Singer/Songwriter,"
now it just says "Undecided."
I entered my songs into this contest.
And you lost?
Worse. I didn't hear back at all.
And I took that as...
I don't know... a wake-up call.
Oh, come on. That's only one contest.
Actually, I've entered a
bunch of contests, Ryder.
Anyway, what's so wrong
with joining Accounting Club
when we get back?
(chuckles) Uh...
I'll tell you one thing.
I think, uh, Accounting Club
interferes with Glee Club.
Marley, are you planning
on quitting Glee Club?
I didn't want to let anyone down.
And since this is going to be my swan song,
I just want it to be fun.
So, please, don't tell anyone.
Are you sure we should be doing this?
I mean, if we get caught...
Oh, just go!
Trust me, when I was in the Warblers,
sneaking onto stage the night
before a show was tradition.
We had other traditions, but
I can't really speak of them.
We're not doing anything wrong.
We're just, you know, getting a feel
for the layout of the stage... our stage.
So should we sing a song or hold hands
or say a prayer or something?
Because if I'm being honest,
this ghost light's kind of freaking me out.
All right, everybody,
circle up. I have a surprise.
Finn Hudson made us a promise
at the beginning of the year:
that we were all going
back to nationals together.
Even when we lost sectionals,
which was totally not Marley's fault,
Finn told us that it wasn't over.
He said that we'd be right here, together.
Now, maybe you're
thinking, "Finn isn't here."
Well, he is.
I made sure of it.
JEAN-BAPTISTE: Well, well!
Les Directions Nouveau !
Uh, apparently, we had the same plan
for an illegal midnight rehearsal.
"We?" You're alone.
Am I?
Existentially, yes, Blaine.
Perhaps.
We are all alone.
But tonight, tonight,
this stage belongs to us
from midnight until dawn.
You see, I called in a
few show choir favors.
So, we'll just give you three minutes
to gather your feelings and leave.
Who is that?
Your spirit guide?
Dolph, enough.
Have some respect.
Look, everyone knows
you're that show choir.
And everyone knows it's been
a very rough year for you.
And now everyone is just waiting
and watching... you.
Tonight, you have our
condolences, New Directions.
But let's just be very, very clear.
Tomorrow, you will not have
our mercy, pity or restraint.
We are Throat Explosion.
Expect us!
Seven, eight!
(feet stomping rhythmically)
- How'd you learn to do that?
- Have you met my son Kurt?
I cannot believe this
is our last competition.
I am not ready for this to end.
Do not start crying again.
I'm not gonna cry.
It's just that some of
my best memories from Glee
- are these competitions.
- BURT: Yeah, well, you know what?
That's why guys love
playing sports so much.
It's not so much about
the winning and the losing.
It's about going to war with your buddies.
You know? The camaraderie.
That's right. That's why you see a bunch
of 50-year-old men humping
around a softball field
or playing flag football.
They're trying to recreate that feeling
they're never gonna get back.
Oh, my God, yes!
That's it. Ugh.
It's so depressing.
I can't believe this
is our last competition.
My life's gonna be so empty from now on.
At least you get to have one.
Oh, my God. I can't believe I said that.
I am so sorry.
No. It's okay.
I'm sorry.
That was totally insensitive of me.
- Tina always does this.
- No, no, no.
It's fine, honey, really.
You didn't do anything wrong.
BURT: You know what,
guys? Why don't you go?
And, uh, you go practice or something,
and I'll have Carole finish up the sewing,
and I'll drop the dress by your room, okay?
Relax.
No eating anything from
the minibar; it's expensive.
If you want something,
go down to the 7-Eleven.
(door closes)
You okay?
I don't think I can do this.
I really wanted to.
But being around all his friends just...
I thought it would make me feel
close to him.
And I know this is awful to say, but...
every time that they laugh
or smile or skip away,
I just feel like my insides
are being ripped out.
Well, we don't have to stay.
Schuester can handle things on his own.
Tina's right though, you know?
When those kids leave McKinley,
it'll be like the last of him leaving, too.
Yeah.
It'll really be over.
I spend the days pretending
that it's not real.
But being around all of them...
I can't pretend.
Is that a bad thing?
Whatever you need.
We can get a room at the Montage.
Drive down to Laguna Beach.
I know how much you loved that show
- when it was on.
- (chuckles) I did.
Or we can fly home.
Whatever you want.
Okay.
Dude, come on. Get dressed.
We got to be down there in 15 minutes.
So, you're talking to me now?
I just don't feel like losing
nationals because of you.
You barely even waited
until the body was cold
before you moved in on Marley.
Not cool.
I screwed up; I get that.
But you didn't even give me
a chance to apologize to her.
Or try and work things out.
I thought we were friends.
We were.
I mean... we are.
At least, we should be.
All right, don't cry.
I'm going, I'm going.
Listen, man, I'm not
supposed to say anything,
but, uh, Marley's quitting
Glee Club when we get back.
Why?
She sent her songs out
to some stupid contests
and never heard back, so now she thinks
it's the universe trying to
tell her to give it all up.
(sighs) That's crazy.
She sent me a few of her songs
though, and they're awesome.
I was thinking if we could find someone
out here in L.A., you know,
someone... someone real
who could tell her they're good.
Sure, I got CeeLo on speed dial.
No, I know I don't know anybody famous,
but we do know someone almost famous.
- What's wrong?
- Finn's plaque... it's missing.
Don't panic. I'm sure it's here somewhere.
It's not in here. I put it right here.
It's gone.
It's probably just...
(Jean-Baptiste chattering)
It's obviously a really big deal to them.
Give it back!
Give what back? Your talent?
Because you obviously left that in Ohio.
All right, just give us the plaque back.
Gentlemen, let's get serious.
You've got zero chance of winning.
You lost your sectionals.
So you're only here on a technicality.
And everyone knows all your
decent singers graduated.
And a little piece of wood with a picture
of a guy on it isn't gonna change...
You're a tool, man! Come on!
Okay, break a leg.
Sam, just... just let it go.
They're just trying to psych
us out; they're being idiots.
We got to get our game faces
on and win this thing, okay?
Okay, guys, look. The
plaque doesn't matter.
You know why?
Because I believe with all
my heart that Finn is here.
He's right here with us, right now.
And he's holding all our
hands, and he's telling us,
"The show must go all over the place."
And when we're up there onstage,
he's gonna be sitting right
next to Mr. Shue cheering us on.
And when we win our
second nationals trophy,
he's gonna be cheering us on even louder.
All right?
So let's do this! Let's go!
Yeah! (all cheering)
Let's go!
(whooping, cheering)
Let's do this.
ANNOUNCER: A reminder
from the City of Angels!
The 405 Freeway is closed
for repairs this month.
Also the subways isn't working
and bus service has been
canceled due to snipers.
Also if you try to walk,
people will look at you weird.
Hi, guys.
Also watch out for terrorists.
And now let's meet our judges!
Please welcome living legend
and Academy Award winner,
Miss Marlee Matlin!
(crowd cheering)
Give a warm hand
for entertainment icon
and Emmy Award winner,
Jackée!
(crowd cheering)
But you all can just call me Jackée.
(cheering continues)
A round of applause for the
inventor of the fitness craze
that's sweeping the nation, Prancercise,
Joanna Rohrback!
(crowd cheering)
And now from Oklahoma City,
The Amazonians!
(The Go-Go's "Vacation" playing)
♪ Can't seem to get my mind off of you ♪
♪ Back here at home,
there's nothing to do ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
* I see I was wrong *
* See I was wrong *
* And I'm not so strong *
♪ I should've known all along ♪
♪ That time would tell ♪
♪ Two weeks without you ♪
♪ And I still haven't gotten ♪
♪ Over you yet ♪
♪ Vacation, all I ever wanted ♪
♪ Vacation, had to get away ♪
♪ Vacation meant to be spent alone ♪
* Meant to be spent alone *
♪ Vacation, all I ever wanted ♪
♪ Vacation, had to get away ♪
♪ Vacation meant to be spent alone ♪
♪ Vacation, all I ever wanted... ♪
Yeah.
Wow, thanks.
♪ Vacation meant to be spent alone ♪
♪ Vacation meant to be spent alone. ♪
(applause) Huh.
Okay, a Belinda Carlisle
triple medley is impressive,
but it's not that great.
We're still safe.
ANNOUNCER: And now,
from Fort Wayne, Indiana,
please welcome Throat Explosion!
(Styx's "Mr. Roboto" playing)
* Domo arigato, Mr. Roboto *
♪ Domo arigato, Mr. Roboto ♪
♪ Mata o hima de ♪
♪ Himitsu wo shiri tai... ♪
(crowd cheering)
♪ You're wondering who I am ♪
* Secret, secret, I've got a secret *
♪ Machine or mannequin? ♪
♪ With parts made in Japan ♪
* Secret, secret, I've got a secret *
♪ I am the modern man ♪
* Oh-oh, oh-oh, oh *
♪ Domo arigato, Mr. Roboto ♪
* Domo! * * Domo! *
* Roboto! *
♪ Domo arigato, Mr. Roboto ♪
* Domo! * * Domo! *
* Roboto! *
♪ The time has come at last ♪
* Secret, secret, I've got a secret *
♪ To throw away this mask ♪
♪ Now everyone can see ♪
* Secret, secret, I've got a secret *
* My true identity *
* Domo *
(One Republic's "Counting Stars" playing)
♪ Lately, I've been,
I've been losing sleep ♪
♪ Dreaming about the
things that we could be ♪
♪ Baby, I've been, I've been praying hard ♪
♪ Said no more counting dollars ♪
♪ We'll be, we'll be counting stars ♪
♪ Like a swinging vine, swing
my heart across the line ♪
♪ And in my face is flashing signs ♪
♪ Seek it out and ye shall find ♪
♪ Old, but I'm not that old ♪
♪ Young, but I'm not that bold ♪
♪ I don't think the world is sold ♪
♪ I'm just doing what we're told ♪
♪ I feel something so right ♪
♪ Doing the wrong thing ♪
♪ And I feel something so wrong ♪
♪ Doing the right thing ♪
♪ I could lie, couldn't I, could lie ♪
♪ Everything that kills
me makes me feel alive ♪
♪ Lately, I've been,
I've been losing sleep ♪
♪ Dreaming about the
things that we could be ♪
♪ Baby, I've been, I've been praying hard ♪
♪ Said no more counting dollars ♪
♪ We'll be, we'll be counting stars ♪
♪ Take that money, watch it burn ♪
♪ Sink in the river,
the lessons are learned ♪
♪ Take that money, watch it burn ♪
♪ Sink in the river,
the lessons are learned ♪
♪ Take that money, watch it burn ♪
♪ Sink in the river,
the lessons are learned ♪
♪ Take that money, watch it burn ♪
♪ We'll be, we'll be counting stars. ♪
(crowd cheering)
(bell dings)
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
please take your seats.
Three minutes until showtime.
(sighs)
They aren't here.
Well, if they were coming,
they'd be here by now, so...
I can't believe I said all
that stuff in front of her.
Oh, it's cool, Tina. You can't help it.
They're with us in spirit.
Just like Finn.
Let's bring it in.
(clears throat)
Okay.
We're not like the other teams here.
We don't have the big budget or the...
the giant pool of students to choose from.
We're also different
from these teams because
we didn't come here to win.
We came here to sing and
dance our hearts out...
Oh, that's horse poop, Schuester.
We were halfway down to Laguna
before Burt convinced me to turn around.
I never said a word.
Oh, you didn't have to.
None of you did.
I could hear Finn's voice in my head.
"This is nationals, Mom.
I coached those kids.
You leave them and you're leaving me."
You guys are his legacy.
Which means
I don't want to hear any garbage about
doing your best or giving
it the old college try.
Go out there and wipe the
floor with the other teams!
Wipe it!
- CAROLE: Yes!
- Yeah.
You guys are the reigning
national champions.
Okay? Get out there and
show them how it's done.
Perfectly said.
Hands in, everyone.
SAM: All right.
ALL: Amazing!
ANNOUNCER: And now, raise the roof
for last year's national champions,
from Lima, Ohio, The New Directions!
(crowd cheering)
(Boston's "More Than a Feeling" playing)
♪ I looked out this morning
and the sun was gone ♪
♪ Turned on some music to start my day ♪
♪ I lost myself in a familiar song ♪
♪ I closed my eyes ♪
♪ And I slipped away... ♪
♪ It's more than a feeling ♪
* More than a feeling *
♪ When I hear that old
song they used to play ♪
* More than a feeling *
♪ And I begin dreaming ♪
♪ Till I see Marianne ♪
♪ Walk away ♪
♪ I see my Marianne ♪
♪ Walking away ♪
♪ Hey... ♪
♪ When I'm tired and thinking cold ♪
♪ I hide in my music, forget the day ♪
♪ And dream of a girl I used to know ♪
♪ I close my eyes ♪
♪ And she slipped away... ♪
* She slipped away *
♪ She slipped away... ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah... ♪
♪ It's more than a feeling ♪
* More than a feeling *
♪ When I hear that old
song they used to play ♪
* More than a feeling *
♪ And I begin dreaming ♪
♪ Till I see Marianne walk away... ♪
♪ More than a feeling. ♪
(crowd cheering)
(Neil Diamond's "America" playing)
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Far... ♪
(mouthing): Oh, my God.
♪ We've been traveling far ♪
♪ Without a home ♪
♪ But not without a star ♪
♪ Free ♪
♪ Only want to be free ♪
♪ We huddle close ♪
♪ Hang on to a dream ♪
♪ On the boats and on the planes ♪
♪ They're coming to America ♪
♪ Never looking back again ♪
♪ Home ♪
♪ To a new and shiny place ♪
♪ Make our bed and we'll say our grace ♪
♪ Freedom's light burning warm ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Everywhere around the world ♪
♪ Everywhere ♪
♪ They're coming to America ♪
♪ Coming to America ♪
♪ Every time that flag's unfurled ♪
♪ They're coming to America ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Got a dream to take them there ♪
♪ They're coming to America ♪
♪ Got a dream they've come to share ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ They're coming to America ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ We're coming ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ We're coming ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ They're coming to America ♪
♪ Coming to America ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ They're coming to America ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ They're coming to America ♪
♪ Today! ♪
(crowd cheering)
(U2's "I Still Haven't Found
What I'm Looking For" playing)
(humming melodically)
This was Finn's favorite song.
(sobs softly)
They're singing all of his favorite songs.
(humming continues)
♪ I have climbed ♪
♪ Highest mountains ♪
♪ I have run ♪
♪ Through the fields ♪
♪ Only to be with you ♪
♪ I have run ♪
♪ I have crawled ♪
♪ I have scaled these city walls ♪
♪ These city walls ♪
♪ Only to be with you ♪
♪ But I still ♪
♪ Haven't found what I'm looking for ♪
♪ What I'm looking for ♪
♪ But I still ♪
♪ Haven't found what I'm looking for ♪
♪ What I'm looking for ♪
♪ I believe ♪
♪ In a kingdom come ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Then all the colors will ♪
♪ Bleed into one ♪
♪ Bleed ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah ♪
♪ Well, yes, I'm still running ♪
♪ Yes, I'm still running ♪
♪ You broke the bonds ♪
♪ And you loosed the chains ♪
♪ Carried the cross of my shame ♪
♪ Oh, my shame ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ You know I believe it ♪
♪ I believe it, I believe it ♪
♪ But I still haven't found ♪
♪ Still haven't found ♪
♪ What I'm looking for ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ But I still ♪
♪ Haven't found ♪
♪ No, no ♪
♪ What I'm looking for ♪
♪ Oh, no, no, no ♪
♪ But I still ♪
♪ Haven't found what I'm looking for ♪
♪ What I'm looking for ♪
♪ But I still ♪
♪ But I still haven't found ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ What I'm looking for,
what I'm looking for ♪
♪ Looking for ♪
♪ But I still haven't found ♪
♪ What I'm looking for! ♪
(crowd cheering)
That was incredible!
(excited chatter)
Uh, wait. Uh, where's Sam?
Hey. You okay?
I did my best, Mr. Shue.
Hey, you did great.
(sighs softly)
I did my best.
(car horns honking,
siren wailing in distance)
Three minutes.
Sorry?
The next time one of
your songs gets rejected,
you can throw yourself a pity
party for exactly three minutes.
And then you need to haul your ass up
and start writing another one.
'Cause your songs are really good.
And I don't care
that a bunch of yahoos rejected them.
They're stupid and they're wrong,
and they're gonna be sorry someday.
I know about rejection.
I lost almost every single solo
to Rachel Berry in high school.
I got dumped by my first record label.
I even got dumped by Sam Evans.
No, wait.
I dumped him. Twice.
(laughs)
You are loaded to the gills with talent.
Aw.
And someday soon, I'm gonna be
hitting you up for songs.
Thank you.
How'd you get them?
Couple of birdies.
You know, those guys,
they really care about you.
That don't mean you should date them.
- Mm-hmm.
- (chuckles)
Don't ever give up on
your dreams, Marley Rose.
You're too good.
Oh. (laughs)
♪ ♪
JACK JASON: And in fourth place...
from Lake Tahoe, Vicious Harmony!
(applause)
JACKEE: And third place goes to...
our bronze beauties, The Amazonians!
(crowd cheering)
Are you all right, Mr. Shue?
You never looked this nervous before.
Yeah, just, uh...
there's a lot riding on it this time.
And now the pivotal moment is here.
For there can only be one
champion show choir per nation.
JACKEE: Second place goes to...
(gasps)... New Directions!
Which means the winner of the
National Show Choir Championship
is Throat Explosion!
(crowd cheering)
♪ ♪
So Jean-Baptiste mailed it here?
Yeah, he said that when he found out
one of the people on his
team stole it, he was furious.
Then he apologized and
said that he made sure
that the thief was kicked off the team.
Huh. A bully with a moral code.
All right, guys, time to put
our new trophy in the case.
I've always found that
second place trophies
are just a lasting reminder
that you didn't win.
WILL: Hey, there were
16 teams in that competition.
We beat 14 of the best
show choirs in the country.
I'm sorry we let him down.
Let who down? Finn?
We just really wanted
to win this one for him, and for you.
We had a plan that we were
gonna call you up on stage
and give you the trophy to keep.
It's not right.
This is not how the
story was supposed to end.
You're right.
Oh, it would have burned Finn
to have lost to those guys.
All we would have heard for months was
how the judges had robbed you
or how you were so much better than them.
BURT: But then he would have stood up
and he would have told you that even though
most of you had never been in
a show choir before this year,
you still stood tall
against the best of the best.
And you know what? Even though Finn
didn't have the best
voice or the best rhythm
or the best throwing arm,
he always brought out the best in himself
and in others, and the
great thing about him is
he always managed to find
a way to feel like he'd won.
I was really proud of you guys up there.
Hearing those songs was so healing for me.
And... I don't know... I
saw how much he meant to you.
So, win or lose, he lives in you guys.
WILL: Okay, guys.
Let's put this trophy where it belongs.
ARTIE: A second place showing
is superior to when Finn decided
to make out with Rachel onstage
and we ended up in 12th.
Principal Sue wants to see you, Schuester.
Dead man walking.
SUE: Well, Roz, I got to admit,
I didn't think you had it in you.
Between the toxic fumes from
your excessive beauty products
and all those MoonPies I see you
shame-eating in the bathroom stalls
when you don't think anyone's looking,
I didn't think there was room
for the kind of fire and creativity it took
to uphold the Cheerios! honor
and bring home another
national championship.
I'm sure it gives you
great disappointment to know
you weren't the only reason the
Cheerios! won all of those years.
Come back when you've won 16 more
and had a child with a celebrity crooner.
Then you can talk trash, Roz.
Until then, as principal...
Are they almost done?
She'll get to you when
she gets to you, loser.
I... second place is not losing.
It's like winning a silver
medal in the Olympics.
Sure, if there was
an Olympic event in being totally gay.
ROZ: Whoa.
Just like my date with John Salley.
(chuckling)
Well, bye, all.
If you need me over the summer,
you can reach me at my beach
cottage in Saint-Tropez.
But there ain't no phones.
(chuckles)
(humming)
Come on in, William.
(sighs softly)
I bet you're hoping for
a last-minute reprieve
and that I'll say something
about how your plucky band
of pinhead minstrels overcame
so much to get where they did
and how second place is
actually an achievement.
I... I can't say I wasn't secretly
hoping you would consider it.
I have considered it.
More than you know.
But I just can't.
In the words of ex-Principal Figgins,
my hands are tied.
I'm the principal now, William,
and my job is concerned with
the health of the entire school,
not just the fiefdoms that I like.
And I do like you, William.
That's why I'm so mean to you.
That being said,
the Cheerios! stay because they won.
So does the debate team, the football team,
the girls soccer team
and mock U.N.
However, diving,
academic decathlon, actual decathlon
and, yes, the glee club need to go.
Should I fight?
Sh... should I make a
speech about the arts or...
or how much this club
means to me personally?
No, no.
Save that for your wife.
It'd probably turn her on.
That won't make any difference here.
So this is really it.
What's gonna happen to the choir room?
Well, it's prime real estate.
I'll probably turn it into two classrooms.
And since we won't be
needing the band anymore
to play everything from obscure Broadway
to Queen at a moment's notice,
probably sell off their equipment
and buy some computers.
Butt chin up, Schuester.
Look where you were
four years ago when you started this thing.
You've got a national championship trophy
from last year in that case
and a bunch of other loser
trophies standing with it.
You and your team have
done phenomenally well,
and you did it with the
world's greatest nemesis
playing her best game against you.
You didn't lose, William.
The game is just over.
- Oh, my God.
- SANTANA: Now what?
Your band booked a huge gig playing a show
at the Union Square subway station?
Why do you want to know? So
you can steal his dream, too?
- Exactly.
- It's Glee Club.
They've been disbanded.
They didn't win at
nationals; they're turning
the choir room into a
computer lab or something.
And Sue isn't backing down this time.
It's over.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -