Here's what you missed on Glee.
BRAZIL
Will's wife put the "Terri"
in "terrible relationship,"
- so now she's his ex-wife.
- What is wrong with you?
Kurt met this kid Blaine
who he really likes
and he seems really nice,
but he sings in the Glee Club
at another school.
They're called The Warblers.
The Warblers are like rock stars.
Kurt isn't liking his
own school at all, because
Karofsky's been coming after him,
and nobody knows why.
You can't punch the gay out of me
any more than I can punch
the ignoramus out of you.
Well, Kurt knows why,
but he hasn't told anyone.
And that's what you missed on...
Glee!
Morning, Sue.
Oh, I'm gonna stop you right there.
That's Principal Sue.
What?
Oh, you heard me right.
My years-long quest for power
has finally bore fruit.
Wait, what happened to Figgins?
Well, you need to start
listening to the news, William.
A particularly virulent
strain of monkey flu
has arrived in Ohio from Borneo,
where it had been festering
in a small clutch of loud,
bisexual primates,
not unlike your very Glee Club.
How...
How did Figgins get it?
And that's what it
means to be an American.
- I think I have a fever.
- Can it.
Now.
'Sup?
So Figgins is sick.
How does that make you principal?
Well, through the blackmail
of prominent local politicians,
I strong-armed some extraordinarily broad
clauses into my contract.
My first order of business?
Destroy the Glee Club.
I... I thought we were friends.
That got boring.
Just one of the perks of
being a high school teacher:
Constant exposure to illness.
All right, guys, um...
Time to start thinking
about song selections.
I mean, I feel like I might have a fever,
but it's important
that I power through it.
Okay.
I definitely have a fever.
Lookin' good, Puckerman.
Someone's been eating their wheaties.
These guns are fully loaded.
Mr. Shue?
I, for one,
think we should use our
set list for sectionals
to start exploring the oeuvre
of one Bernadette Peters.
Someday, I'm gonna go to
Paris and visit the oeuvre.
I just want to dance.
Mr. Schuester,
you look a little green.
Um...
I think I'm gonna go see the nurse.
But first I feel like I
should get you guys a sitter.
At this point, it would be a good idea
to add any of your aromatics, like...
We're going to cover the pan
until the clams open up...
I can take care of myself.
Is that why Mrs. Weiss
called me from next door?
Because, according to her,
she's here morning and night.
Lift your head up.
You're making me feel worse.
Oh, honey.
I'm probably revealing too much,
but I do still love you.
And you have to admit,
no matter how toxic
our marriage was,
I was really good
at taking care of you when you were sick.
That's because you like
me best when I'm weak.
Maybe.
I mean,
that's what my therapist says.
You're seeing a therapist?
And I'm medicating, too.
Now roll over,
and pull your pants down,
- because we're gonna take baby's temperature.
- No.
But baby knows it's the only way
that we can get an accurate reading.
Stop, Terri.
I don't want to play sick baby with you.
Now, get out of here.
What are you doing?
Singin' in the Rain.
We were together sixteen years.
You think I don't remember
what movie makes you feel
better when you're sick?
Then they're not good,
so don't eat those.
Just go ahead and discard those.
And that is how you steam clams.
I'm shaking.
And it's either from
low blood sugar or rage.
I knew it was only a matter of time
before Rachel tried to
take over the Glee Club.
Class, in Mr. Schuester's absence,
I'd like to go around and ask everyone
what solos they'd like to
hear me perform at sectionals.
All right, you know what?
Let me at her!
We'll forget all about
it tonight at bowling.
I can't.
Blaine asked me to hang out.
I've been looking forward to it all week.
Wait.
Are you two going out?
Because I think you need to come clean.
What? No.
I don't want another
Jessie/Rachel traitor scenario to overcome.
Please, Mercedes. Mum's the word.
We'd be happy for you.
I mean,
we know how lonely you've been.
All right, we just hang out.
Nothing about Glee Club
even ever comes up.
It's just nice to have someone to talk to.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- I mean, someone like me.
But I promise to make it up to you.
We'll hang out Friday night.
Excuse you.
Whoa, whoa.
A couple more.
Thanks.
So what are we going to do about
Glee Club while Mr. Shue is sick?
I have an idea.
Have you met the new Spanish teacher?
It's not easy being a substitute teacher.
Kids feel like they get the day off.
They'll goof off, egg your car, cut class,
break into your car, throw spitballs,
put an alligator in your car...
And I don't even have a nice car.
So I try to relate to the kids,
listen to what they have to say,
make it fun for them.
Lindsay Lohan es bien loca, ¿no?
Because I'm the cure for the common class.
Excuse me, Miss Holliday?
A word?
I understand that you are subbing
for Mr. Schuester's Spanish class,
and I was wondering if you
might not want to take over
his Glee Club duties, as well.
What makes you think I know
the first thing about Glee Club?
You subbed for my English class last week.
And you were extraordinary.
♪ Conjunction junction,
what's your function? ♪
♪ Hooking up words and
phrases and clauses. ♪
♪ Conjunction junction,
what's your function? ♪
♪ Hooking up cars and
making 'em function, ♪
♪ Conjunction junction... ♪
Are you on anything?
'Cause this is trippy.
You smell homeless, Brett.
Homeless.
Miss Holliday, we are floundering.
Won't you please take over Glee Club?
I thought you'd never ask.
Yay!
Muchas gracias.
Dude, what are you doing?
Kurt got us a substitute,
so I'm buttering the floor.
But sectionals is, like,
two weeks from now.
Hey, Gigantor.
We're all gonna swap names, yo.
Um, did I hear something
about a substitute?
Yes! It works!
Well, at least I didn't
fall and break my talent.
I'm fine.
Oh, what the hell?
Hola, clase.
Nothing says "bienvenidos"
quite like a buttered floor.
Let's start with some introductions.
My name is Holly Holliday.
What's yours?
Go.
I'm Finn Hudson.
I'm quarterback of the football team.
I'm Rachel Berry,
his loud, loud girlfriend.
I'm Mike Chang.
Those aren't your names.
- You know why I know that?
- You're psychic?
I know this because I recently watched
a video of you guys
performing at regionals,
where you came in last.
Maybe it's because the songs
were about thirty years old, but...
Those songs are classics.
Those songs are amazing.
But they sounded like somebody
else's favorite songs. Not yours.
- Just sayin'.
- She speaks the truth.
I'm not your average,
run-of-the-mill substitute teacher.
I want you guys to do things
that you want to do.
I want you to have fun in our fabulous
but fleeting time together.
What do you say we have
class outside today?
It's raining outside.
Well, then let's take a
field trip to Taco Bell.
Oh, yeah!
Should we toke up some
medical-grade marijuana?
I wish.
Yes!
- It's really hard not to like this woman.
- Okay...
No.
We can't just goof off all day.
We have to write a set
list for sectionals.
You're right.
What songs would you like to do?
Oh. Don't get asked that
question much, do we?
Ms. Holliday is right.
Mr. Schuester's set
list sometimes seems like
he hasn't listened to
the radio since the '80s.
He never listens to what I have to say.
Mr. Shue, can we do that new
Cee-Lo song, "Forget You"?
Uh, no.
Come on, guys,
there's got to be a Journey
song we haven't done yet.
Cee-Lo!
That's what I'm talking about.
Okay, excuse me?
What would you know about Cee-Lo?
'Cause you're like, 40.
Top 40, sweet cheeks.
Hit it!
♪ I see you driving 'round town ♪
♪ with the guy I love,
and I'm like "Forget you!" ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh... ♪
♪ I guess the change in my pocket
wasn't enough. ♪
♪ I'm like, "Forget you!" ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh... ♪
♪ And yeah, I'm sorry
I can't afford a Ferrari, ♪
♪ but that don't mean
I can't get you there. ♪
♪ I guess she's an Xbox
and I'm more an Atari. ♪
♪ Mmm, but the way you
play your game ain't fair. ♪
♪ I pity the fool
that falls in love with you. ♪
♪ Ooh, she's a gold digger. ♪
♪ Well... ♪
♪ Just thought you should know. ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh... ♪
♪ I got some news for you. ♪
♪ Yeah, go run and tell
your little girlfriend. ♪
♪ I see you driving 'round
town with the guy I love ♪
♪ and I'm like, "Forget you!" ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh... ♪
♪ I guess the change in
my pocket wasn't enough. ♪
♪ I'm like, "Forget you
and forget him, too!" ♪
♪ Said if I was richer
I'd still be with ya. ♪
♪ Huh, now ain't that some... ♪
♪ Ain't that some... ♪
♪ Although this pain's in my chest, ♪
♪ I still wish you the
best with a "Forget you!" ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh... ♪
♪ Now, baby, baby, baby... ♪
♪ Why'd you wanna
wanna hurt me so bad? ♪
♪ So bad, so bad, so bad... ♪
♪ I tried to tell my mama, ♪
♪ but she told me,
"This is one for your dad." ♪
♪ Your dad... ♪
♪ Yes, she did... ♪
♪ Why... ♪
♪ Uhh... ♪
♪ Why, baby, baby... ♪
♪ I love you. ♪
♪ I still love you, hey! ♪
♪ I see you driving 'round
town with the guy I love ♪
♪ and I'm like, "Forget you!" ♪
♪ Forget you... ♪
♪ I guess the change in my pocket wasn't enough. ♪
♪ I'm like, "Forget you,
and forget him, too!" ♪
♪ Oh, baby. ♪
♪ I said, if I was richer ♪
♪ I'd still be with ya. ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah... ♪
♪ Oh, now ain't that some... ♪
♪ Although there's pain in my chest, ♪
♪ I still wish you the best ♪
♪ Wish you the best... ♪
♪ with a "Forget you!" ♪
♪ Ooh-hoo, hoo, hoo. ♪
Let's go get some tacos!
Yeah! Yes!
This is not up for discussion, fellas.
You do not spray athlete's foot medicine
in your teammates' eyes.
Come on!
Can I help you, Sue?
Principal Sue,
and I'm here to inform you
that effective 4:00 P.M. today...
The football team is
officially... disbanded.
Well, if you're cutting the football team,
who are your Cheerios! going to cheer for?
I will get back to you
on all of this later.
No.
Humiliation.
Bested by the Beiste,
less than 24 hours after my
plan to replace all chairs
in the school with sharp
poles was thwarted...
A resounding defeat in
my war against sitting.
Reality is, I'm a champion,
and once I get power, I do not let it go.
I need a cause.
That's it.
Becky, get your fanny in here,
and bring your pad.
Yes, Coach?
Becky, take a memo.
- I'm banning po-tater tots.
- Outstanding.
Mr. Shue, I'm so glad you're better.
We can't win sectionals without you.
Mike, I know. Now, I'm gonna
run through a number here,
and after a bit,
I want you to join in, got it?
- Got it.
- All right.
♪ Though the world is full
of a number of things, ♪
♪ I'm sure we should all
be as happy as... ♪
♪ But are we?
No. ♪
♪ Definitely no. ♪
♪ Positively no. ♪
♪ Decidedly no.
Uh-uh! ♪
♪ Short people have long faces, ♪
♪ and long people have short faces. ♪
♪ Big people have little humor, ♪
♪ and little people have no humor at all! ♪
♪ And in the words of
that immortal God, ♪
♪ Samuel J. Snodgrass, ♪
♪ as he was about to be
lead to the guillotine... ♪
♪ Make 'em laugh, make 'em laugh. ♪
♪ Don't you know everyone wants to laugh? ♪
♪ My dad said, "Be an actor, my son." ♪
♪ "But be a comical one." ♪
♪ "They'll be standing in lines
for those old honky-tonk monkeyshines." ♪
♪ Now you could study Shakespeare
and be quite elite, ♪
♪ and you can charm the critics
and have nothin' to eat. ♪
♪ Just slip on a banana peel,
the world's at your feet. ♪
♪ Make 'em laugh,
make 'em laugh, make 'em laugh. ♪
♪ Make 'em...
Make 'em laugh. ♪
♪ Don't you know everyone wants to laugh? ♪
♪ My grandpa said,
"Go out and tell 'em a joke." ♪
♪ "But give it plenty of hoke." ♪
♪ Make 'em roar, make 'em scream. ♪
♪ Take a fall, butt a wall, split a seam. ♪
♪ You start off by pretending
you're a dancer with grace. ♪
♪ You wiggle till they're
giggling all over the place. ♪
♪ And then you get a great
big custard pie in the face. ♪
♪ Make 'em laugh, make 'em laugh,
make 'em laugh. ♪
♪ Make 'em laugh, make 'em laugh. ♪
♪ Don't you know everyone wants to laugh? ♪
♪ Ah ha ha ha ha ha, ha ha ha ha ha ha! ♪
♪ Ah ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha! ♪
♪ Ah ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha... ♪
♪ Make 'em laugh! ♪
♪ Make em laugh! ♪
♪ Make 'em laugh, make 'em laugh! ♪
♪ Make 'em laugh!♪
I don't understand who gave her
the authority to take over Glee Club.
- What?
- I was doing a fine job of
running Glee in your absence,
and then Kurt, jealous,
asked her to take over.
I'm not too worried about it, Rachel.
I really appreciate your concern, but...
I'm not worried about someone
coming in and usurping me.
You kids love me.
Sue doesn't.
You know what's so nice,
is having someone fun at this school.
Mm. We're back. Okay.
Oh, Hoarders is great, but...
Animal Hoarders is better.
Hoarders and red wine.
♪ I'm buzzed! ♪
You have to get well, Mr. Schuester,
because every day
you're here, she's there,
and it becomes more and more likely
that she's going to start
running the Glee Club,
and you're going to become the substitute.
Oh, we have to get there early on Friday.
It's league night for little people,
and they'll buy up all the small
shoes if they get there first.
Oh, I totally forgot.
Greg Evigan is starring in
rent at the community playhouse,
and Blaine got us tickets.
"Us" as in all of us?
I think he could only score two.
Wait. Where do you think
you're going with those?
Principal Sue banned the tots.
She can't do that!
They look like deep-fried deer poop.
Take it up with principal Sue.
We'll get you some-some...
Ugh! Okay.
Why did you take away our tots?
You don't have an appointment.
Jackee,
I am like my idol,
Richard Millhouse Nixon.
Regarded in his time as
petty, corrupt and venal,
he actually always had the best
interests of his people in mind.
And also like Richard Nixon,
I'm obliged to inform you
that this conversation is being recorded.
I want my tots.
Nutrition is abysmal at this school.
You know what this is?
Toilet brush. It's broccoli.
When I showed this to Brittany
earlier, she began to whimper,
thinking I had cut down a small tree
where a family of gummy bears lived.
I am declaring a war on junk food.
I'm getting my tots back.
Becky, that can't happen again.
Keep 'em out.
Roger that. Thank you, coach.
- Hey, Rachel.
- Hello, miss Holliday.
I'd like you to know
that I have a very severe
bruise on my right buttocks
from your game of gangsta
rap musical chairs.
I'll be going on record with
the school nurse later today.
Rachel, you suck.
Oh, my God, you're like a total drag.
Has anyone ever told you that? I have.
Oh, Puckerman, here are the answers
to the pop quiz I'll be
giving in Spanish class later.
It is so boring in there.
Thanks, miss h.
Righteous.
You know what? Maybe I
should be more like you.
All fun, and just forget
about the consequences.
Well, frankly, yes, you should.
I mean, at least sometimes.
When was the last time
that you did something
just because you thought
it would be a blast?
Take Glee Club.
I mean, you have all these great ideas.
When is the last time you
actually did one of them?
Mr. Shue can be a little
tight-fisted with song selection, but
I would like to do something
a little bit more upbeat
and glamorous with a good dance beat.
Sounds reasonable to me. Have you asked?
Mr. Shuster, I want to
do more of an upbeat,
glamorous song with a
really good dance beat.
No, but I have good news.
I found a journey song
we haven't done yet.
Rachel, I used to be just like you,
trying to get everything so
right, hanging on so tight.
What happened?
I got punched in the face. Anyway,
why don't you let me know the name
of this upbeat, glamorous
song with the nice dance beat,
because, hot stuff, you
are doing it in Glee Club.
I kind of need a partner
to do the song I wanted.
I thought you'd never ask.
That's kind of my catch phrase.
So...
What meds are you on?
Um, antidepressants and
anti-anxiety when I need them.
Are you happy?
You know, I think I feel like
for the first time maybe I could be happy.
How about you?
Happy? Yeah.
If I'm gonna be honest,
no.
I still feel like I'm
searching for something.
Here. Some more.
There...
Thanks, Terri.
Baby likes his soup.
Oh.
You know, I remember something
else that baby loves a lot.
Okay.
Rubbing menthol.
I love that stuff. I know you do.
Take your shirt off, lie
on your stomach. Come on.
What? I'm not going to kill you.
It'll make you feel better. All right.
Here.
Don't.
I don't want to get you sick.
I don't care.
Look at this crap.
Foam fish sticks?
Principal Sylvester's only
serving predigested food now
to give us more energy.
I mean, do I look like a damn baby bird?
Don't fret your culinary disappointments.
I come bearing gifts.
You brought tots?
Better. I've set you up on a date.
I get it.
My new budding friendship with Blaine
is making you feel left out,
jealous. Who's the guy?
Anthony Rashad.
Why him?
No reason.
Oh, so it has nothing to do
with the fact that he's one of
the five black guys at this school?
Uh, no, he is a wide
receiver on the football team,
he is very good-looking,
and he is a member of
the black student union.
Any non-black activities?
I don't know...
My Google search was a little...
I can't take this anymore.
Mercedes, trust me, love is just
around the corner. What's up, homo?
That's not what I'm talking about.
Tots!
Oh, my God!
Tots! Tots! Tots!
Tots! Tots!
Tots! Tots! Tots! Tots! Tots! Tots!
So the tot wars have begun, Becky.
♪ You can like the life you're living. ♪
♪ You can live the life you like. ♪
♪ You can even marry Harry, ♪
♪ but mess around with Ike. ♪
♪ And that's good! ♪
♪ lsn't it grand? ♪
♪ lsn't it great? ♪
♪ lsn't it swell? ♪
♪ lsn't it fun? ♪
♪ lsn't it? ♪
♪ But nothing stays. ♪
♪ ln fifty years or so, ♪
♪ it's gonna change, you know. ♪
♪ But, oh, it's heaven nowadays. ♪
♪ And all... that... jazz... ♪
Hey, buddy,
You look terrible...
You should be home in bed.
There's no reason for you to be here.
Well, the kids need me.
No, literally, there's no
reason for you to be here.
The kids prefer the
substitute, and so do I.
I got to be honest with you, Will.
A lot of it's the hair thing.
In fact, right now I'm
tempted to sell your scalp
on the black market as a tiny,
full-length shearling coat
for only the most fashionable
of premature babies.
Oh... I long for the day when Figgins
gets better and comes back.
Well, that's not gonna happen.
The school board has been just flooded
with e-mails from parents
thrilled with my tough stance
on healthy teen lunches.
Figgins has been fired,
and I've been formally
offered the position.
So, why don't you go home,
rest, watch some tv, die.
It doesn't matter...
'Cause you know what?
As my first official act
as full-time principal,
you are fired.
Drunk people who get married
to someone just saying that
they met an hour ago by
an Elvis impersonator...
I mean, that's the
bigger insult to marriage
than two gay guys getting
hitched. Totally. It's, like,
if marriage is so sacred, they
should just outlaw divorce.
Right? Right. Right.
What do you think, Mercedes?
Oh, about, uh, "don't ask, don't tell".
No, we're on prop 8 now.
Totally for it.
Against it.
Right.
I'm sorry, I kind of just blanked out.
Oh, don't apologize...
We should talk about stuff
that you're interested in, too.
I know...
Let's play a game.
Okay, on the count of three,
name your favorite 2010 vogue cover.
Okay, ready?
One, two, three...
Marion Cotillard. Yes!
Marion Cotillard. Oh, my God, stop it!
Yes, I know. She's amazing!
Amazing! Amazing!
Amazing.
Gay!
Gay! Gay. Gay, gay, gay.
Gay, gay, gay, gay, gay, gay, gay.
Oh, my gosh, I open my mouth
and a little purse falls out!
That's so gay.
How did that get in there?
Mercedes?
I was just talking
about the Buckeyes...
I'm a college football fan.
I like sports, too, you know.
Oh, way to break the stereotype.
Excuse me. I know it's not on your menu,
but I was wondering if you guys had...
You want some tots?
You kids must go to McKinley.
So, what were we talking about?
Has anyone read Patti Lupone's new book?
I'm kidding. Of course
I have. You scared me
so much there.
I know, I was...
Nice job, band dudes.
It feels like the sun is shining in here.
And the body's still warm.
Hi. I'm Will Schuester,
and this is my choir room.
I'm sorry we had to meet like this.
The kids really love you.
You must be a great teacher.
You don't believe that...
If you did,
you wouldn't have taken my job so easily.
Guys, you want to take five?
Okay, you want to have this
conversation, let's have it.
You're a substitute...
Of course you can...
Paint murals and let the
kids sing whatever they want.
You're never around when they have to deal
with the hangover of all that fun.
16% of all high school
students dropped out last year.
We can't just expect them
to sit up and pay attention.
These kids feel special.
They have a voice, and
if we don't listen to it,
they just tune us out.
I give my kids a voice.
I just don't let it run free.
I'm the teacher...
It's my job to know
more than they do. Right,
but you don't know more
about what they care about
the most... Themselves.
These kids get bored,
they change their Facebook status.
They're entitled to have
all of these emotions,
and not only that, they're entitled
for the world to care about them.
That's what this generation is about.
A great teacher is
supposed to show them that
there are other points
of view besides their own.
Okay, fine. What do you do when
a kid does something
really great in your class?
Praise them. I tweet them
about it right there and then,
and for those 30 seconds, I know
that that kid has a connection
with me.
Look, it's... a terrible economy,
and good teaching jobs
are hard enough to get,
let alone one in the arts.
I just...
I'm sorry, but I... I can't
turn this opportunity down.
You want to tell Ms.
Holliday why we're here?
Remember when I asked
to be excused from class?
May I be excused? I'm
gonna go shove some tots
up the tailpipe of coach Sylvester's car.
Sure!
I told her not to touch my tots.
You did $17,000 worth of damage.
I drive a very rare and
desirable automobile, ladies.
Prized by collectors
for its peerless grace
among vintage European sports cars,
one out of seven in existence.
The 1979 Lecar.
You know how many hours it took
to find a mechanic who
even knew what a Lecar was?
She's your student.
I would love to hear what
you suggest as punishment.
I was gonna suggest clapping erasers,
but you guys are mostly
dry-erase here, so...
You know what you might
not find so funny, Mercedes,
is that tampering with
an automobile's exhaust
is a felony.
And you can rest assured that I
and my attorney, Gloria Allred,
will be pressing charges.
So...
Am I going to jail, or...
Undetermined. Great.
Get the hell out of my office.
You have absolutely no idea
what you're doing, do you?
No. Not really.
By the way, berets are out.
Sorry for just coming over like this.
I wanted to do this in person.
Plus, I heard you have expensive beer.
I'm glad you did. And I do.
Look, I was out of line before...
you have every right to
teach however you want.
And the fact is, the
kids clearly love you.
I'm a terrible teacher.
Don't argue with me...
I know I am.
Today...
Mercedes got in trouble
for shoving tots up Sue
Sylvester's tailpipe,
and we were sitting in Sue's office,
and Mercedes was looking at me like...
And I just was totally lost.
What did... What did Sue do to her?
Whatever. I don't know.
She, like, suspended her or whatever.
Oh! See?
God, I do that every time!
As soon as things get serious, I retreat.
God, I... I didn't used
to be like this, you know?
I...I... I was...
More like you.
Spaulding High School, ten years ago.
Good morning, class.
I was subbing for a math teacher.
The syllabus says that
you're on algorithms,
so let's start with some easy ones.
Let's start with you kissing my ass!
Her name was cameo.
She was like an attractive biggie smalls.
Okay, Miss... Cameo.
Miss Cameo, do you find that algorithms
are hard for you to understand?
Do you find my fist hard to understand?
I have some really great tricks
that make them very easy to learn.
Tricks? What are you, some
type of magician substitute?
I'm a Christian,
and that devil magic stuff
offends me!
Cameo!
I woke up in an empty classroom.
They'd stolen my air Jordans.
From that moment, I realized
I got to keep things moving,
I got to keep it mellow and fun.
Yeah, to keep from
getting your butt kicked.
And I do, in all ways.
I never sign more than
a month-to-month lease.
I only eat off paper plates.
I live on one-night stands.
Last year a guy
asked me to marry him; I moved.
Sounds... lonely.
Yeah.
Well... It works for me.
But it doesn't work for those kids.
I'm resigning.
Wow, Will.
I mean, wow. What are you doing here?
You should've called.
I brought you some more soup.
But I guess baby's feeling
a lot better if he's healthy enough
to have a beer with a friend!
No, no. I...
Hi. I'm-I'm holly Holliday.
Are you a porn star or a drag queen?
I'm Terri Schuester, Will's wife.
Wow.
Your wife's kind of a bitch.
She's my ex-wife.
And I have no idea what she's doing here.
Do I have to remind you what went on here?
Can we talk about this another time?
Why, 'cause this is embarrassing
in front of your new girlfriend?
Where has she been the past two days, huh?
Okay, I'm just gonna go home.
No.
I'm sorry, Terri.
Last night was a mistake.
I knew it as soon as it happened.
I was lonely and...
You were there.
I-I am sorry.
No, I'm... Honey, I'm sorry.
I just...
I'm really out of control right now,
and... I'm gonna come back.
Okay?
Terri. Yeah?
Don't.
Don't come back.
This is your last chance, Will.
It's never gonna happen again.
If I leave now, I'm never gonna come back.
You're gonna regret this, Will.
I swear to God, you're gonna regret this.
Are you okay?
Tell me again about this
life with no consequences.
It's kind of awesome.
Psst!
Look what I snuck in.
My heart was racing.
Are you out of your mind?!
After what you did to Sue's Lecar?
You're gonna end up in prison!
So? You know what they have in prison.
Tots.
I'm not breaking it off with Blaine.
I really like him.
You are substituting
food for love, Mercedes.
And more importantly,
you're substituting me for a boyfriend.
Look at me. Two weeks ago,
I thought there was no way I'd
ever find someone like Blaine.
And there he was.
You will find somebody.
But until then,
you just got to take care of yourself.
And treat yourself with a little respect.
You're right.
I got to go.
Where?
I'm gonna go talk to that Anthony kid.
First time I saw him, I
thought he was kind of cute.
Maybe we have a shot.
Question for you.
You tell anyone else what happened?
How you-you kissed me?
You kissed me, Karofsky, and I understand
how hard this is for you to deal with,
so no, I haven't told anyone.
Good. You keep it that way.
'Cause if you do,
I'm gonna kill you.
Is is where I grovel to
try to get my job back.
No groveling necessary, William.
I'm returning you to your position.
You know, one of the marks
of a successful leader
is appointing trusted lieutenants,
and Ms. Holliday was
clearly not up to the job.
You irritate me, William.
You make the under-flaps
of my breasts burn,
like when I used to rub
them with poison sumac.
But your kids sure love you,
as evinced by the amount
of treacly blubbering
I had to sit through.
Mr. Shue's the only teacher
at this school who asks you
how you're doing and actually
wants to hear an answer.
Mr. Shue's the only teacher at this school
that ever really touched me.
Besides Mr. Ryerson.
He taught me how to tie my shoelaces.
I used to think that I was the best thing
that happened to this school, but...
I was wrong.
Mr. Schuester is.
Mr. Shue taught me the
second half of the alphabet.
I stopped after "m" and "n."
I felt they were too
similar and got frustrated.
You know, William, one thing I learned
in my time as president...
Principal.
You can't force public opinion.
I pardoned you.
Sometimes you got to give
the inmates what they want.
You throw 'em a comb, and hope they stop
beating each other long enough
to whittle it into a shiv.
Well, I am relieved.
I sort of thought I'd been replaced.
Aw, shut your gash, Nancy.
And as a condition
of my not pressing charges, your Glee Club
will return my Lecar to mint condition.
I suggest selling yourself
on craigslist under the heading
of "men seeking men with butt-chins."
All right, all right,
thank you very much, guys.
Please, please, sit down. Just...
Thank you...
For that and...
And for all the kind words
you said about me to Sue.
The feelings are mutual.
Now, we got to get crackin', though.
We lost a few days there,
and it's all gonna be
about focus and hard work for the next
couple of days. I guess
Ms. Holliday really is gone.
I know you guys liked her,
and she was a lot of fun,
but she and I both agreed
that this is what was best.
Don't get us wrong, Mr. Shue,
we always wanted you as our teacher.
She was just kind of a nice break.
She did loosen us up.
And she actually had
some good ideas for a sub.
Yeah. I get it.
And maybe we can, uh,
incorporate those...
after sectionals.
Now, when I'm sick,
there is only one thing
that makes me feel better.
Gin and juice.
No. Singin' in the rain.
I must've watched it, like,
ten times over the past three days.
It's actually what
inspired me to try this out
as a contender for our
first song at sectionals.
When is the song from?
Well, the movie opened in 1952.
But... But... But it's...
But it's really timeless.
Mary Todd Lincoln in the house!
My husband was probably
gay, and I'm bipolar,
which makes me yell things like...
"That teapot's spreading lies about me!"
Or... "That can't be my baby,
because I don't love it!"
Ms. Holliday, can I talk to you for a sec?
Sure.
Guys, practice your bipolar rants, okay?
See? History can be fun!
How are you holding up?
Okay.
I'm back to my itinerant ways, I guess.
I do miss Glee Club, though.
Well, as much as the kids like me,
they sure do miss you.
Which is why next time I'm sick,
I'm requesting you as the Glee sub.
Really?
Mr. Schuester, that's so nice of you.
It would be nice to feel like
a part of something, you know?
I know.
I actually need your help
with something else, though.
See, I've been dying to
do singin' in the rain
with the kids, show them how great it is,
but they're convinced
it's too old-fashioned. Mm.
Would you mind helping me make
it a little more... modern?
I thought you'd never ask.
♪ Uh-huh, uh-huh. ♪
♪ Yeah! Holly! ♪
♪ Good girl gone bad. ♪
♪ Uh-huh, uh-huh. ♪
♪ Take three. ♪
♪ Action! Go! ♪
♪ Uh-huh, uh-huh. ♪
♪ You have my heart, ♪
♪ and we'll never be
worlds apart. ♪
♪ Maybe in magazines, ♪
♪ But you'll still be my star, ♪
♪ baby, 'cause in the dark ♪
♪ you can't see shiny cars. ♪
♪ And that's when you'll need me there. ♪
♪ With you, I'll always share. ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm... ♪
♪ I'm singin' in the rain. ♪
♪ We'll shine together. ♪
♪ Just singin' in the rain. ♪
♪ What a glorious feelin'. ♪
♪ Be here forever. ♪
♪ I'm happy again. ♪
♪ Be your friend. ♪
♪ Stick it out till the end. ♪
♪ I'm laughing at clouds. ♪
♪ More than ever. ♪
♪ So dark up above. ♪
♪ Still have each other. ♪
♪ I'm singin'... ♪
♪ Singin' in the rain. ♪
♪ You can stand under my umbrella. ♪
♪ Ella, Ella, ay... ♪
♪ Ay, ay, under my umbrella. ♪
♪ Ella, Ella... ♪
♪ Ay, ay, ay, ay, ay... ♪
♪ These fancy things ♪
♪ will never come in between. ♪
♪ You're part of my entity. ♪
♪ Here for infinity. ♪
♪ When the world has took its part, ♪
♪ when the world has dealt its cards, ♪
♪ lf the hand is hard, ♪
♪ together we'll mend your heart. ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm singin' in the rain. ♪
♪ We'll shine together. ♪
♪ Just singin' in the rain. ♪