So here's what
you missed on Glee:
Nationals is in New York City,
and everyone's really excited.
Jessie St. James
is back in town,
and he's starting a show choir
consulting business.
Two things that I'm great at...
Show choir and destroying the competition.
The New Directions!
Should hire him.
A.) They really want to win
and B.) He's super-handsome.
Terri's back, too,
and Sue wants the Honey Badger
to take out the Glee Club Terri's back,
too, and Sue wants the Honey Badger
to take out the Glee Club
before they can get
to New York.
And that's what
you missed on Glee.
Sync by Thanh Hoang
www.Itfriend.ORG
www.Addic7ed.com
New Directions!,
I would like to introduce you
to our new show choir consultant...
Jessie St. James.
I don't trust this guy.
How do we know he's not
just going to trick us
into doing something stupid,
so his Alma mater wins?
I don't think I need to do much tricking
to get you to do something stupid, Finn.
Guys, Jessie is just a consultant.
I still make all the calls.
Now, I have all the confidence
in the world in you guys.
I just think we could use
all the help we can get.
Because...
This is it.
We've been working so hard for two years
for this moment, and that
moment is finally here.
Now, I was talking with
Jessie, and he agreed
that we should continue
with our successful trend
of doing original songs
for the competition.
I was thinking of doing one group number
and one duet.
Rachel and I should sing a duet.
We killed it last year
at Regionals with "Faithfully."
Yeah, killed us...
we lost.
May I?
Uh, yeah.
I agree that Rachel should sing lead,
but Finn, I think it's best
if you sit this one out.
Fact is, most of the other guys
in here are better singers,
and Mike Chang, who can't
even sing, can at least dance.
You kind of sing and dance
like a zombie who has to poop.
You-you see? You see
what I'm talking about?
The guy's a jerk!
Jessie, maybe you could, uh,
be a little bit gentler
with your advice.
Gentle?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
I didn't realize that we were training
for the "good try" ribbon at Nationals.
I thought we were in it
to win the whole damn thing.
And there's only one way we can do that.
Poison darts?
The Vocal Adrenaline strategy is simple...
Identify your best performer
and build the entire performance
around them.
So what does everyone else do?
And who's our star performer?
We're going to have auditions to find out.
I'm going to post
a sign-up sheet
later this afternoon.
Mr. Shue,
don't you think this
is kind of not our style?
Normally, I'd agree with you,
Finn, but this is the big time.
I think we should listen to Jessie.
I just don't know what
you're so angry about.
Honey Badger, I am lactating with rage!
The Glee Club travels
to New York for Nationals in one week.
They have purchased airline tickets...
Tickets that I would like to screw up.
I asked you to recruit
an expert computer hacker,
and you bring me this.
Do I get a super villain nickname?
Your nickname is Panda Express.
But I'm not Chinese.
Neither is the food at Panda Express.
Look, I'm on top of this.
All the official travel for the school
goes through
the Lima Heights Travel Agency.
All we have to do is e-mail them
through Principal Figgins'
e-mail account.
So what's the hold up?
We don't know his password.
Principal Figgins is an idiot...
Something America is chock full of.
What is the most common password
in America?
One, two, three, four?
We're in.
Outstanding.
The travel agency sent arday
confirming an itinerary
with a layover in Chicago
before heading on to New York.
Compose an e-mail
requesting a flight
that's routed through Tripoli.
Tripoli?
Wait, isn't that in Libya?
The second that plane touches the tarmac,
they'll be swarmed by armed militants.
Wait, are-are we trying
to have the Glee Club killed?
Or kidnapped and killed.
Panda... make it so.
Someone really woke up on the
wrong side of the bed today.
You have no idea.
Mr. Schuester?
Oh, hey, Becky.
Mr. Schuester,
I'm Donna Jackson.
I'm Becky's mom.
I really need to talk to you.
I want to be in Glee Club.
Well, that's great, Becky.
Can you sing?
Not really, but neither can most
of the kids in Glee Club.
But I-I thought
you were having
such a good time on the Cheerios!
Sue kicked her off.
Becky, you're off the Cheerios!
I don't want to see you anymore.
Is that understood?
Did I do something wrong, Coach?
You heard what I said.
I want your pom-poms on my desk
by the end of the day.
I... I-I don't know what to say.
Becky's been totally depressed.
She hasn't been eating...
Can I please be
in Glee Club, Mr. Shue?
I just want to belong.
Becky...
We're a week away from Nationals.
I mean... I mean, the...
the season is almost over.
I'd love for you to join next year.
But for now, I...
I'm afraid there just
isn't a place for you.
We understand.
Thank you for your time.
Yeah.
I hate this school.
You are a terrible person.
Becky was loyal to you, Sue.
Cheerios! Gave her
a sense of purpose,
and then you just rip it away
from her for no reason.
I'm going to be honest with you, Will.
I do have a reason.
She reminds me of my sister.
What does that have to do with anything?
You love your sister.
I do, William, and she died yesterday.
What?
You know, when we were younger,
people always told me
Jean wouldn't live very long.
Used to be that people
with Down's didn't live past 30.
But then she turned 35, and then 40,
and when she turned 50, I thought, somehow,
we might grow old together.
Last week, she got pneumonia.
Doctor said it wasn't bad,
and they put her on antibiotics.
I was there with her.
I wanted to stay the night,
and she told me to go home.
At 2:00 A.M., I got the call
that she had passed away in her sleep.
Sue, I am so sorry.
Could you leave me alone, please?
To think, two short years ago,
I was marching down this hall
to sign up
for Glee Club auditions.
And now, look at me...
look at us.
Nationals.
So much has changed.
I didn't have my bangs,
I'd never had a boyfriend,
and I still had
a tiny layer of baby fat.
But there's one thing that
hasn't changed... my dreams.
I'm still going to be a star,
which means I would kill
to get this solo.
Hey, you haven't signed up
to be the lead vocalist
at Nationals.
Santana, Mercedes and Kurt have.
Hey.
You're the male lead of this group, Finn.
Everybody looks to you for guidance.
I don't need Nationals
to feel better about myself.
We-we-we've...
we've been working
towards this moment for two years now.
And I've been busting my ass to be
a better singer and dancer for two years.
And that Jessie ki
comes in, and he wipes out
all that hard work in ten seconds.
My confidence is shot.
No, you're...
you're really good, Finn.
Okay?
You have to believe me.
I'm... I'm Lima good.
Not New York City good.
R-Rachel, I'm sorry.
I'm not auditioning.
Wow, Will.
That's a lot of vests.
Um, okay...
let's get started.
So I've got one box for going with you,
one box for storage and
one box for giving away.
I'm not going away forever, Emma.
Rehearsals for April's show
start two days after Nationals,
and then opening night
is three weeks later.
I'm guessing we close that night
and then I'm back on a bus,
back to my vests the next day.
Will you stop?
Stop with all that.
You're too afraid to admit
that you're leaving, but you are.
That's why you've asked me
to help pack up your apartment,
and that's why we're going
through your vests.
Do the kids know?
No way.
Can't let anything distract them
from the task at hand.
Besides, by the time they get back
from summer break, I'll be home.
You are so organized.
Thank you.
Whoa.
That one's a keeper.
I wore this the first week of Glee Club.
Mmm. Right.
What about, um...
what about this one?
Will, did you wear this
the first time you tried
the new coffee machine
in the teacher's lounge?
That's the one I was wearing
the first time I met you.
Well, you know what?
You have to let it all go.
You're following your dreams.
Coach Sylvester?
We brought you some flowers and stuff.
We're sorry for your loss.
Put them over there with the rest.
There were more arrangements,
but I had to throw some of them out.
I'm allergic to pansies.
And I don't mean that as a
swipe at either of you.
So... why'd you bother
doing this...
Buying me flowers, comforting me...
After I've actively
made your life a living hell
and enjoyed doing it?
We both know what it's like
to lose someone really close to you.
I sort of do.
My dad died when I was a baby.
Yeah. His dad's dead,
and my mom's dead.
So how do you think you can help me?
Are you here to tell me how to
deal with this? Not at all.
'Cause if I was being honest with you,
Eddie Munster and Herman Munster,
I don't know how to deal with this.
I can't go back into that nursing home
and start sorting through Jean's things.
And I won't plan a funeral.
Have you told your mother yet?
As far as I'm concerned,
she said her good-byes to us
years ago.
If you boys would really like to help me,
you might start by explaining
why it was her time and not mine.
She's the sweetest person I ever met.
And as both of you can attest,
I'm probably the meanest,
so how come I'm the one
still standing here talking to you?
We need to help her.
She's overwhelmed, and...
She needs us to help her.
Seriously?
I'd like to put
the "fun" back in "funeral"
just as much as the next girl,
but why would the Glee Club
help Coach Sylvester plan a service?
We're not doing it for Sue;
We're doing it for her sister.
Jean is just like us, guys.
I mean, she's been an outsider
and an underdog
all of her life.
We, of all people, should celebrate that.
Can I say something?
When someone dies, yes, it's a tragedy,
but it's also a part of life.
And you can't let death
put your life on hold.
Now, I don't mean to be blunt,
but I don't think you should be
planning a funeral
the same week you should be focusing
on the set list for Nationals.
Seriously?
You... you're serious?
Actually, yes, I am.
Do you know what Vocal
Adrenaline is doing right now?
They're in their third week
of 24-hour-a-day rehearsals.
They're on an I.V. drip.
That's how hard they're working.
Do you know what happens
in Vocal Adrenaline
if someone dies during a number?
They use them as a prop,
like Weekend at Bernie's.
No.
Thanks for your input, Jessie, but we're
helping Sue
with the service for her sister.
Rachel, you said I needed
to be more of a leader
of this club...
well, here goes.
I'm making the call.
We're doing this.
Sue, hold on a second.
Finn and Kurt told me that you agreed
to let the Glee Club help out
with your sister's funeral, and I...
I just wanted to say that we're honored,
and it takes a big person
to reach out like that
and ask for help.
I didn't ask for help;
They volunteered.
And I only agreed on the condition that.
Frankenteen and Lady Trousers help me
clean out Jean's room at the nursing home.
They look like they could use the exercise,
and I like the idea of using
your glee club as unpaid labor.
Sue, I know you're going
through a hard time right now.
And despite our differences,
I just, I just want you to know
that you can lean on me if you need to.
Oh, William, I wouldn't dare lean on you.
So much grease in your hair,
I'd probably slide right off.
I'm still not convinced
that this is the best idea.
I don't want any of the kids
to feel like they're losers.
But that's a crucial part of the process.
You see, I took a class at UCLA
in judging for reality TV shows,
so I'm totally ready to give feedback
that's both blistering and unhelpful.
It was a really good class.
I learned a lot.
We're ready for the first contestant.
My name is Santana Lopez,
and I will be singing
Amy Winehouse's "Back to Black."
* He left no time to regret *
* Kept his lips wet *
* With his same old safe bet *
* Me and my head high *
* And my tears dry *
* Get on without my guy *
* And I tread a troubled track *
* My odds are stacked *
* I go back to black *
* We only said good-bye
with words *
* I died a hundred times *
* You go back to her *
* And I go back to... *
* Black *
* I go back to *
* I go back to... *
* We only said good-bye
with words *
* I died a hundred times *
* You go back to her *
* And I go back to black. *.
Fantastic, Santana.
Thanks so much for coming in.
Wait, th-that's all
you have to say?
You spent the entire performance
scribbling notes.
Well, if you really must know,
I was simply writing down
that I don't think that
your performance went very deep
into the emotional truth of the song.
Oh, is that so?
Well, I happen to have
some feedback for you.
Thanks, Santana,
th-that's all we'll need.
I'm about to go all Lima Heights.
Th-Thank you.
Hello, I'm Kurt Hummel, and I'll be singing.
"Some People" from Gypsy.
Ah, great selection, Kurt.
Hit it.
* Some people can get a thrill *
* Knitting sweaters and sitting still *
* That's okay for some people *
* Who don't know they're alive *
* Some people can thrive and bloom *
* Living life in the living room *
* That's perfect for some people *
* Of 105 *
* But I at least gotta try *
* When I think of all the sights
that I gotta see *
* And all the places I gotta play *
* All the things that I gotta be at *
* Come on, Papa,
what do you say? *
* Some people can be content *
* Playing bingo and paying rent *
* That's peachy for some people *
* For some humdrum people to be *
* But some people ain't me *
* I had a dream *
* A wonderful dream, Papa *
* Good-bye to blueberry pie *
* Good riddance to
all the socials I had to go to *
* All the lodges I had to play *
* All the Shriners I said hello to *
* Hey, L.A.,
I'm coming your way *
* Some people sit on their butts *
* Got the dream, yeah, but not the guts *
* That's living for some people *
* For some humdrum people, I suppose *
* Well, they can stay and rot *
* But not Rose. *.
All right.
Good job, buddy.
Kurt...
You do know that song was meant
to be sung by a woman, right?
Yes, I'm aware.
And the Glee Club
sort of dealt with that whole
boys singing songs
that are meant for girls.
Oh.
It's kind of old news.
Then you must know that that song was done
to great fanfare by
such Broadway legends as.
Merman, LuPone, Bernadette.
Those are some awfully big heels to fill,
and I'm just not quite sure
that you nailed it.
Usually, at this point,
the reality show would
go to commercial, then we would
take a five minute break
to regroup and get touch-ups
done on our makeup.
So I'm gonna hit the little boys' room.
You're doing a great job, though.
I really think that
you should comment more.
Don't be shy.
Jessie St. James
totally Jessie St. Sucks.
He said I shouldn't be singing girl songs.
I make my living singing girl songs.
I think the winner of four
show choir championships
might be able to give us all
some valuable insight.
We know you're in love with him, Rachel,
but do you have to be so obvious?
Don't use the fact that
Jessie and I once had feelings
for each other as an excuse
for my inevitable win.
Correction:
You had feelings for him,
he made breakfast on your head.
Look, Jessie and I both
appreciate the integrity
of show choir too much
to soil the competition.
He's just gonna vote for whoever is best.
That would be me. You guys
can fight over who's gonna
come in second all you want,
because I kicked that song
square in the balls.
I'm so gonna win this thing.
No bother warming up, Rachel.
I'm about to go out there
and wrap this thing up
like a Christmas present.
* Oh, she may get weary *
* Them young girls...
they do get wearied *
* Wearing that same old shaggy dress *
* Yeah *
* But when she gets weary *
* Try a little tenderness *
* Oh, maybe, Mmm *
* You won't regret it, no *
* Young girls...
they don't forget it *
* Love is their whole happiness *
* Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah *
* But it's all so easy *
* All you got to do is try *
* Try a little tenderness *
* Yeah, all youot to do isman *
* Hold her where you want her *
* Squeeze her, don'tease her *
* Never leave her *
* Get to her, got to try *
* Try a little nderness *
* Oh, yeah *
* Squeeze her, don'tease her *
* Never leave her *
* Try, try, try, yeah *
* Tenderness *
* Oh, yeah *
* You got to, you got to, yeah, yeah *
* Rub her gentle, man *
* Don't bruise her, no, no *
* You g to loveer, tease r, squee her, ye *
* Try a ltle tenderness. *.
Sync by Thanh Hoang
www.Itfriend.ORG
www.Addic7ed.com
WILL oo!
Wow, Mercedes!
Just... wow.
You know, seeing you up there
brought me back to the first time
you auditioned for Glee Club.
You were great back then,
but you were just amazing now.
Thank you for singing that.
And thank you for reminding me
where we started,
and where we're going to now:
Nationals.
Thank you, Mr. Shue.
I couldn't have done it without you.
You're not a star, you're just
a girl who can really sing.
Ex-Excuse me?
I don't think you want this
badly enough, Mercedes.
How many times did you practice that song?
Practice?
No, I feel my material,
and I sing with emotion.
I'm in the moment,
Mr. St. James.
I don't need to practice.
Actually, you do.
And how long did you
work on that choreography?
Oh, wait, there was none.
You're lazy, Mercedes.
Not too lazy to come up there
and let you taste my fist!
Whoever gets this solo
is gonna have to work on it day and night.
Do you think you're ready for that?
I do.
I don't.
I hate him.
Hi. My name is Rachel Berry,
and I'll be singing the most
difficult song I've ever sung.
Great. What song?
Uh, Barbra's closing number
to my favorite movie...
Funny Girl.
Rachel, in your head,
are you singing to anyone in particular?
Not really.
Oh.
* Oh, my man, I love him so *
* He'll never know *
* All my life is just despair *
* But I don't care *
* When he takes me in his arms *
* The world is bright *
* All right *
* What's the difference if I say *
* I'll go away *
* When I know I'll come back *
* On my knee someday? *
* For whatever my man is *
* I am his *
* Forevermore *
* Oh, my man, I love him so *
* He'll never know *
* All my life is just despair *
* But I don't care *
* When he takes me in his arms *
* The world is bright *
* All right *
* What's the difference if I say *
* I'll go away *
* When I know I'll come back *
* On my knee someday? *
* For whatever my man is *
* I am his *
* Forevermore. *.
She may be difficult,
but boy, can she sing.
Bravo!
I have to be honest.
That was brilliant.
I have nothing but the tip of my hat.
Garbage. This whole
thing is rigged.
Hold on, Santana.
Like I said before, I make
the final call here.
Well, then, make it.
Out of respect to you all,
I'm going to take a couple days
and consider all the results.
Now, I will let you all know by Friday.
Great job, everyone.
We sorted Jean's stuff into piles.
Over there are some old
magazines and newspapers
that you can just toss out.
And this is stuff
you're definitely going to want to keep.
Uh, photos and stuffed animals.
And this third pile is stuff
that we don't really know what to do with.
Um...
Pom-pom.
Toss it.
It's not worth anything.
Are you sure?
Willy Wonka
and the Chocolate Factory.
Oh, I love that movie.
Then, you can take it.
It's probably worn out.
She watched it at least three times a week.
Just toss it all out.
What?
You heard me. It's all junk.
I'll take the stuffed animal.
Jean's had this since she was six.
Everything else, just toss
it out; I don't need it.
But there are a lot of memories here.
You know, I'm not short
on memories of my sister, so...
I know what it's like
to lose someone.
When someone dies, it hurts.
Very astute, Porcelain.
That's a little nugget of wisdom
I'd really like to jot down.
Coach Sylvester, we're just trying to help.
You know what, Cottage Cheese?
You're not helping.
You're actually making things worse.
So do me a favor and take
all this stuff to the Dumpster
on your way to the rehearsal
for whatever treacly ballad
you're planning on using
to ruin my sister's funeral.
Why did you agree to this, then?
If you hate us so much, then why
are you letting the Glee Club
plan the service?
I was afraid no one would come.
Jean didn't know a lot of people.
I figured, with the Glee Club there,
at least she'd have a full house.
Hey, Sue.
You look nice.
Thank you for coming.
Jean always stood up for you
when I told her stories about
how evil your hair was.
Did anyone come?
It's a full house, actually.
Workers from the home,
other residents, their families.
Your sister touched a lot of people.
What do you think, Coach Sylvester?
You told us that Willy Wonka
was Jean's favorite movie.
The way you described Jean
made her sound so special,
so we wanted her funeral
to be special, also.
Something to capture and express
the Joy of her life,
rather than the sadness of her death.
It's lovely.
Let's sit.
Welcome to the most unusual funeral
that I have ever attended.
Which makes sense, because Jean
was the most unusual person
that I ever had the pleasure
to spend every Sunday
for the last 30 years with.
I think that Jean's sister Sue
would like to say a few words.
I miss my sister.
Every night, at 10:00 or so,
she used to call me on the phone,
and when I asked her why...
She'd tell me that her body told her...
She wanted to hear my voice.
Hey...
I'll read it.
"I miss my sister.
"The smell of her shampoo.
"The way she could always convince me
to read her
another book."
"When you love someone like I loved her,
"they're a part of you.
"It's like you're attached
by this invisible tether,
"and no matter how far away you are,
"you can always feel them.
"And now, every time
I reach for that tether,
"I know there's no one on the other end,
"and I feel like I'm falling
into nothingness.
"Then I remember Jean.
"I remember a life led with no enemies,
"no resentments, no regrets...
and I'm inspired...
"to get up out of bed and go on.
"I miss my sister so much.
"It feels like a piece of me
has been ripped off.
"Just one more time, I want to hold her.
"Ten more seconds...
is that too much to ask?
"For ten more seconds to hold her?
"But I can't
"and I won't,
"and the only thing keeping me
"from being swallowed whole by sadness
"is that Jean would kill me if I did.
"So, for now, I'm just going to miss her.
"I love you, Jeanie.
Rest in peace."
This was Jean's favorite song.
Hold your breath.
Make a wish.
Count to three.
* Come with me *
* And you'll be *
* In a world *
* Of pure imagination *
* Take a look *
* And you'll see *
* Into your imagination *
* We'll begin *
* With a spin *
* Traveling in the world of my creation *
* What we'll see *
* Will defy *
* Explanation *
* If you want to view paradise *
* Simply look around and view it *
* Anything you want to, do it *
* Want to change the world *
* There's nothing to it *
* There is no *
* Life I know *
* To compare with pure imagination *
* Living there, you'll be free *
* If you truly... *
* Wish to be. *.
Thank you.
Sorry.
Long line in the restroom.
Everyone was fixing their mascara.
Mm.
You did such a great job with the funeral.
I'm so proud of you.
Why are you crying?
Because I'm breaking up with you.
Because of Rachel?
'Cause you still love her?
I shouldn't have done this with you.
I thought that I could fix
everything from last year, but I...
I can't.
I just can't, and
that feeling that Sue was
talking about in there of being
tethered to someone...
I... I just...
I don't feel that way about you.
But you do with her?
No.
We're not breaking up.
I can handle your confusion with Rachel
until you get over it.
We're gonna stay together,
and next year,
we'll be prom king and queen...
Just stop it.
Okay? I don't want that life.
Don't you feel anything anymore?
This is real.
This is happening.
Are you happy now?
Is this me feeling enough for you?
Quinn, I'm sorry.
I still love you.
Just don't touch me!
Action.
Well, it was a tough competition,
but here's the dope.
Santana... too mean.
Kurt... too controversial.
Mercedes... I said it twice,
and I'll say it again.
Lazy B-O-N-E-S.
Rachel is the clear winner.
I'm really not comfortable
having this conversation taped.
Well, I can't practice reality
show judging without a camera.
It's like practicing skiing without skis.
I've totally done that.
Okay, Brittany, can you
just turn that thing off?
Just the off switch... right...
right over there. Just...
Yeah, I know how
to turn it off. Thanks.
Okay. It's cool.
Jessie, maybe you can come on.
Fondue for Two and judge my Cat.
Rock and roll.
I have to be honest, Jessie.
The more we talk about this,
the more uncomfortable
I feel about all of it.
It just feels like I'm telling
one of my children
that they're my favorite.
Well, that's what my parents
told me in front of my siblings.
Sure, some might say that it led
to my brother's whippet addiction
and my sister's bulimia, but
my parents owed them the truth.
You really think picking Rachel
means we beat Vocal Adrenaline?
It's in the bag.
Coach, can I come in?
Hello, Becky.
I'm turning in my pom-poms
and the megaphone
that you got me.
I'll miss our time together...
I'm gonna stop you right there, Becky.
Have you ever heard of menopause?
Well, I fired you in a hormonal fury
I like to call womb rage, and I apologize.
Now I'd like you to
pick up those pom-poms
and that megaphone.
You know why?
Next year, you're Captain of the Cheerios!
Oh, my gosh, thanks, Coach!
Got to call my mom!
Uh, hold it right there.
I'm not finished.
I want you to give me a hug.
Come here.
That seat taken?
No.
William, I have to say something.
In the history of our relationship,
I've said many things to you,
but there's one thing I've never said.
Good luck.
You know, I spent all this time hating you,
and hating that Glee Club.
I do this thing where I sort of alternate
which one of those kids I hate the most.
Right now, it's the dancing Asian.
But after what you did for my sister,
I just can't do it anymore.
You have something Jean
had that I do not have.
A pure heart.
You're a very good friend, William,
and I have not been that to you.
Yeah, you really haven't.
So, it's time for a change.
Starting today, I will no longer
be going after the Glee Club.
Frankly, I have bigger fish to fry.
I'm running for the United
States House of Representatives.
I'm... I'm sorry.
What-What did you say?
In the last year of her life,
Jean faced ballooning health care costs
and cuts to her disability payments.
Well, the Sue Sylvester
American Liberty Party thinks
that's a load of phooey.
There is one slight problem.
In a fit of pique, I rerouted
the Glee Club's plane to Libya.
Wait... what?!
It took some effort.
It was a long fit of pique.
I had some help... Panda Express
really came through for me.
So we're not going to New York?
I can explain that.
Will, I'm gonna leave you two alone,
as this just became super awkward.
These are first-class tickets
on American Airlines.
How did you afford them?
Well, do you know that if you complain
to the airline about contracting monkey pox
in the bathroom on the plane,
you can get the president of the airline
on the phone within an hour?
But you didn't?
No, of course not.
Have you been on their planes?
They're immaculate.
No, it turns out that one
of the vice presidents
of American Airlines is a big supporter
of the arts or something,
so when I told him
your Glee Club's sob story,
he gladly came up with the tickets
for you guys to make it happen.
This is amazing, Terri.
Wait.
What's the catch?
I'm moving to Miami.
Sheets N' Things is opening
a new branch down there,
and they have asked me to manage it.
Like, full on manager?
The assistant title is officially dropped.
Look, Will, I know that I made your life...
Challenging sometimes, but...
...it was only because
I loved you so much.
I loved you, too.
We just weren't right.
No regrets, though.
No. Not one.
Just try to relax a little bit while
you're down there, okay?
Oh. Yeah.
I mean, you deserve
to enjoy yourself.
Okay.
I'll see you around, Will.
Hey.
Is everything okay with Terri?
Yeah. Finally.
It is.
Is... Are you wearing
one of my old vests?
Yeah, I didn't have the
heart to throw it away.
Emma, this isn't forever.
I hope it is.
Really, Will, you deserve this.
You've given so much for so long,
and now it's your turn.
But, um, don't be a stranger, okay?
Thank you.
Jessie?
That's sweet.
You remember the masculine
click of my designer boots.
Okay, why did you ask me
to meet you here right
before the list goes up?
Is this good news, or is it bad news?
Rachel, I did wrong by you last year,
and I came back to make that wrong right.
And I came here to tell you
that you're going
to be the featured soloist
at Nationals in New York.
Wait, wait. How do you know?
Did Mr. Schuester tell you?
Let it suffice to say
that I was very involved in the decision.
Oh.
No. I-I... I feel bad.
Everyone else worked so hard.
Now they're just going to hate me.
They sort of already do, and
you know as well as I
that sometimes that's the price of fame.
I used to think that fame was
the only thing that mattered.
And now I realize that there's something
that matters to me more.
What?
You.
Come on.
I think the list is posted.
This doesn't make any sense.
Guys, it was a tough decision,
but it's for the good of the club.
Although this is deeply personal,
try not to take it personally.
Um, you guys might want
to read what the list says.
What? Why?
Oh, Mr. Shue,
thank God you're here
to put these trolls out of their
misery. Can you just announce
my win so that I can get on
with teasing the losers?
I heard your performance, Santana.
This is mine, and you know it.
See, Jessie? This is
the kind of infighting
and "me first" attitudes
that I wanted to avoid.
What you call infighting,
I call motivation.
And this is just the beginning.
Once we get to Nationals,
I'll have them willing to kill
each other for that solo.
No.
I've changed my mind.
We're going back to what got us here...
Original songs sung by the entire club.
We're a team,
and we're best when we work as one.
You're going to lose.
Whatever we do,
we're going to do it together.
Actually, Santana, you sounded pretty good.
Thanks. You guys were all
pretty dope, too.
Even Rachel.
I wish I could sound like you do, Santana.
I mean, how do you get that raspiness?
So nice. I smoke cigars.
All right, guys, time to get to work.
Now, I want two hit songs
by the time the wheels
touch down at JFK. Come on.
Hey. Thanks.
For what?
I know you're hurting right now,
but it's really cool
you didn't quit Glee Club.
If I quit Glee Club, my big plans
for New York would have been ruined.
What plans?
You'll see.
Sync by Thanh Hoang
www.Itfriend.ORG
www.Addic7ed.com