Oh, look.
Rachel Berry was
great on Broadway
and maybe she can work on TV,
but the show and her performance
is the kind of thing
that ends careers,
not starts them.
I said I only wanted
to hear the good ones.
Well, that was a good one.
It says maybe
you can work in TV.
Rachel, it's Lee.
Oh! Lee.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Uh, I've met you before.
Nancy.
Yeah.
Yes. You know, um...
I'm a publicist, Oh...
and, uh, give me a buzz, okay?
- Okay. Well, thank you for this.
- Rachel.
Congratulations on that baby.
Oh, yeah.
Rachel, I have some bad news.
I have been fired.
Apparently, I was right
that people want to see
live TV shows...
just not this one.
I think we are the first show
in history to get a zero share.
Well, do you think that
if we can get more people
to watch the second episode...
If we were to do
another episode,
there would be protestors
from UNICEF,
the ADL, the NAACP,
PETA... I mean,
my BlackBerry
is buzzing with angry e-mails
from NAMBLA.
I think that you
actually found a way
to offend every
special interest group
in this country.
And I don't want to point
fingers, but I have to.
At you, because
you're the face of it.
Okay?
I don't know
what I'm going to do.
I've got two families to feed.
Actually, I do know
what I'm going to do.
I'm just going to end up
running another network.
Mr. Paulblatt, I'm...
I'm so sorry.
I just... I can't imagine
how you feel.
Oh, well, you should, be...
because you're also fired.
That's So Rachel
has been canceled.
I mean...
I'm not the only one
going down with this ship.
No. I mean,
unlike me,
I would highly doubt
that you ever work
in television again.
That's so rude.
I shouldn't have said that.
Not "highly doubt."
I'd be surprised.
Not "surprised."
Floored.
Wh... I'm...
What-what-what am I
supposed to do?
Do what everyone
who just failed miserably does:
Blame everyone else.
And then go home.
I don't even know
where that is anymore.
♪ Like anyone would be ♪
♪ I am flattered by your ♪
♪ Fascination with me ♪
♪ Like any hot-blooded woman ♪
♪ I have simply ♪
♪ Wanted an object to crave ♪
♪ But you ♪
♪ You're not allowed ♪
♪ You're uninvited ♪
♪ An unfortunate slight ♪
♪ Like any uncharted ♪
♪ Territory ♪
♪ I must seem
greatly intriguing ♪
♪ And you ♪
♪ You speak of my love like ♪
♪ You have experienced ♪
♪ Love like mine before ♪
♪ But this ♪
♪ Is not allowed ♪
♪ You're uninvited ♪
♪ An unfortunate ♪
♪ Slight ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh oh ♪
♪ I don't think you unworthy ♪
♪ I need a moment ♪
♪ To deliberate. ♪
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
Baby...
Oh...
Oh, thank God.
What's going on?
Where's Dad?
Sweetie...
Dad and I are getting divorced.
What?
N... no.
No, this isn't happening.
Oh, my God, I feel like I died
and now I'm in hell.
It's been bad for a long time.
We agreed to wait to tell you
until you came out of seclusion.
You had enough on your plate.
I'll tell you more over dinner.
I, um...
I don't know how long
I'm going to be staying.
Is that all right?
You can stay with me
as long as you want.
But we put the house
on the market
a couple weeks ago.
They say you have
to lose everything...
before you can really
find yourself.
One soy latte, please.
Oh, my God,
it's William McKinley's
own Rachel Berry!
Oh, no, my God,
no, please. No. Shh.
You can't hide from me.
I work her now, since Sue
cut my janitor's wages.
Oh, this soy latte's on me.
May I please have my card back?
No matter how bad
things have been for me,
but your humiliation
makes me see
that things can
always get worse.
That's terrible.
Gratitude.
Great. Well.
Might as well just take
all this off now.
What was that?
You know, it's just
the story of my life.
All I've ever wanted
is to come home
and have everyone know my name,
and now they do,
but only because
I was involved in the worst
television show in history.
No one has heard
from you in months.
Well, that's because
I went into hiding.
Yeah.
But you know, I'm good now.
I'm good, and...
I'm getting my life
back together and...
and everything is good.
Well, I'm gonna help you
figure this out.
Thanks.
I just...
I don't understand.
Why are you back?
Are you visiting
family? Where's Kurt?
Uh...
wow, you really
have been in hiding.
Uh...
Rach, Kurt and I broke up.
What?
Yeah, it...
got pretty rough
after everyone left
and it was just...
him and me, alone in the loft.
I guess we're "too young."
Everybody says this is
exactly what happens
to high school relationships
after the first year
of college, but I...
I thought we were different.
I'm really sorry.
I got super depressed
after we broke up,
and, uh...
my schoolwork sort of
started to slip
and I got cut from NYADA.
What?
Uh... when are you gonna go back
to New York?
I think I'm going to take
a little break.
I wanted to be home, too.
Yeah.
I moved in back with my parents.
And I-I got a job.
At Dalton.
I am the new coach
for the Warblers.
But you don't...
you don't need
a college degree for that?
Well, I'm not a real teacher,
but the faculty advisor
got Ebola or something,
so the timing was perfect.
You know what?
I think we need to make
a promise to each other.
And I think that,
from here on out,
it's you and me, together,
and we are going to turn
these lemons into lemonade.
Okay?
All right.
♪ Lift up your head ♪
♪ Wash off your mascara ♪
♪ Here, take my Kleenex ♪
♪ Wipe that lipstick away ♪
♪ Show me your face ♪
♪ Clean as the morning ♪
♪ I know things were bad ♪
♪ But now they're okay ♪
♪ Suddenly Seymour ♪
♪ Is standing beside you ♪
♪ You don't need no makeup ♪
♪ Don't have to pretend ♪
♪ Suddenly Seymour ♪
♪ Is here to provide you ♪
♪ Sweet understanding ♪
♪ Seymour's your friend ♪
♪ Nobody ever ♪
♪ Treated me kindly ♪
♪ Daddy left early ♪
♪ And Mama was poor ♪
♪ I'd meet a man ♪
♪ And I'd follow him blindly ♪
♪ He's snap his fingers ♪
♪ And me, I'd say sure ♪
♪ Suddenly Seymour ♪
♪ He purified me ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Yes, suddenly Seymour ♪
♪ Suddenly Seymour ♪
♪ He showed me I can ♪
♪ Showed me I can ♪
♪ Learn how to be more ♪
♪ The girl that's inside me ♪
♪ With sweet understanding ♪
♪ Sweet understanding ♪
♪ Understanding ♪
♪ Seymour's your ♪
♪ Man... ♪
America...
Ohio's winningest
cheerleading coach is now.
Ohio's winningest principal.
Test scores are up,
body mass indexes are down.
How'd I do it?
The Sue Sylvester
Three-Point Plan.
a complete
dietary overhaul.
Protein shakes
and raw kale.
What am I supposed to do
with saltpeter?
Well, if you sprinkle it
on your kale,
keep your sex drive down.
Bon appétit.
Sue Sylvester is triumphant.
mandatory random weigh-ins
and body shaming.
Uh-uh.
Step up.
Into the pigpen.
occasionally releasing hounds.
My crowning achievement?
Getting rid of that glee club.
Making sure that every last one
of those sitter-diddled
transvestites
were forcibly transferred
to other schools
and converting this place
into the beehive of learning
it is today.
Heck, I even got William
that job at Carmel High
to assure myself nothing
but blissful night's sleeps.
Look at this place.
I am helping to create
the next great innovators
in this country.
You know why America's
falling behind?
Because every kid thinks
they should be a rap mogul
or a movie star.
Yes, young man whose name
I will never care to know,
if there's one thing
I am most proud of,
it's the fact that
I have proven,
once and for all,
young minds do not need
the humanities
or the arts.
I'll admit it.
It's been a rough few months,
but all things considered,
I'm feeling okay.
Year three of NYADA
is about to start,
and that means
work study program.
In year three,
all students are required
to go out into the world
and hone their craft
as pseudo-professionals.
We're encouraged to be creative,
get out of New York,
shake things up.
I'm lucky because I've already
secured my internship
at the
Lexington Retirement Home,
where I will spend a year
directing a stage production
of The Real Housewives
that I wrote myself.
And speaking
of shaking things up,
since I broke up with Blaine,
I haven't been seeing anyone
out of respect to him,
but I finally decided
to take the plunge.
I got on Tindr, and I signed up
for an afternoon of speed dating.
Hi, I'm Rich.
- I'm Barry.
- My name's John.
Kurt.
I do pirate reenactments
and I'm also a psychic.
I am an accountant by day,
and by night,
I am also an accountant.
To pay the rent, I work
at a Mediterranean-themed
vegan restaurant for pets.
I'm getting something.
I sense that
you just broke up with someone.
That-that's amazing.
Uh, I-I did.
I-I was actually engaged.
Uh, he asked me.
I-I feel like that's important
for people to know,
but I'm the one
who called it off.
Yeah, he-he's a great guy,
and if I learned...
Wait, you haven't dated
since you broke up, have you?
Wow, you are psychic.
I don't need
to be a psychic to tell
that you're not over this dude.
We're going up against
Mr. Shue at sectionals,
so I could really use
whatever notes you have
on how the Warblers are doing.
You really don't want my notes.
I won the gold star
at the loser Olympics.
You can flame out as
spectacularly as you want on TV,
but you're still Rachel Berry,
and Rachel Berry is
a show choir genius.
♪ Bow ♪
♪ Bah, dah ♪
♪ It's late in the evening ♪
♪ Glass on the side ♪
♪ Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh ♪
♪ I've been sat with you ♪
♪ For most of the night ♪
♪ Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh ♪
♪ Ignoring everybody here ♪
♪ We wish they would disappear ♪
♪ Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh ♪
♪ So maybe we could
get down now ♪
♪ Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh ♪
♪ I don't want to know ♪
♪ If you're getting ahead
of the program ♪
♪ I want you to be mine, lady ♪
♪ Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh ♪
♪ To hold your body close ♪
♪ Take another step
into the no-man's-land ♪
♪ For the longest time, lady ♪
♪ Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh ♪
♪ I need you, darling ♪
♪ Come on, set the tone ♪
♪ If you feel you're falling ♪
♪ Won't you let me know ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh ♪
♪ If you love me ♪
♪ Come on, get involved ♪
♪ Feel it rushing through you ♪
♪ From your head to toe ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh ♪
♪ Sing ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Can you feel it? ♪
♪ All they guys in here
don't even want to dance ♪
♪ Can you feel it? ♪
♪ All that I can hear ♪
♪ Is music from the back ♪
♪ Can you feel it? ♪
♪ I found you hiding here ♪
♪ So won't you take
my hand, darling? ♪
♪ Before the beat kicks
in again ♪
♪ Can you feel it? ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Oh-oh ♪
♪ Can you feel it? ♪
♪ No, no, no, no ♪
♪ Oh, no ♪
♪ If you love me,
come on, get involved ♪
♪ Feel it rushing through you ♪
♪ From your head to toe ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Sing! ♪
Oh, my God.
So, um, any thoughts?
Oh, my gosh, well, I have three.
First of all,
that was incredible.
Second of all,
you're way past the maximum age
to be dancing and singing
with these guys.
And third, thank you.
That was the first time
I've laughed
and smiled
in a really long time.
Of course.
Come on, let's go!
My grandma's got one leg,
and she can run
faster than that! Go!
I need water.
Could you stop being
such a whiny Hummel
and get back in there?
Um, excuse me, I haven't
been out of this school
for that long,
but when I was here,
we worked really hard
to make sure bullies like you
don't use words like that.
Rachel, no, it's cool.
Spencer is totally gay.
Kind of a
post-modern gay teen.
You see, positive
representations of gays
in the mass media has given me
the confidence
I need to be myself,
which, turns out is kind of
an arrogant jerk.
Oh, and your show sucked.
Isn't he a sweetheart?
You're gonna let him
disrespect you like that?
Look, like I said, Rachel, okay,
I'm the assistant coach, okay?
I can't yell at them
like Coach Beiste.
Come on! If salmon had legs,
we'd have it for dinner,
not breakfast!
Okay, these guys
are really good.
Yeah, they are.
Yeah, Sue, uh,
spent the off-season
recruiting players
from all over the state.
She actually bought a, uh,
apartment complex
and moved all the families into.
I think it's legal.
But what about the arts?
What about music and painting?
It's not right. What about
the kids that don't play sports?
Look, Rachel,
I agree with you, okay?
If you have a problem,
just take it up with Sue.
Can I help you?
I'm here to speak
with Sue Sylvester.
It's okay, Janet.
Let her in.
Janet is part
of the free labor arrangement
I have with the
Ohio Department of Corrections.
She's a convicted counterfeiter.
But don't worry,
she's chained to the desk.
Congratulations, BTW.
The, uh,
humiliating public nature
of your epic flame out
exceeded my expectations
in a major way.
Look, I'm not here
to talk about me.
I'm here to talk
about the glee club.
Well, there is no glee club.
In fact, I exterminated
all the arts programs
at this school.
You can't deprive these kids
an education
in music and theater.
Oh, I can and I did.
And it about you, Rachel.
You were the very best
the arts had to offer.
Which means the arts, clearly,
don't have much to offer,
now do they?
There is no glee club
at this school.
There will never be a glee club
at this school
as long as I'm in charge.
Now get the hell
out of my office
before I sic
a convicted felon on you.
I've been watching her
out of the corner of my eye
for the last few minutes.
I'm pretty sure
she's fashioning a shiv.
You want to order?
Uh, no, I'll wait.
Uh, hot date.
Hi. Sorry.
I know I'm a little late,
but it's really coming down,
and I also had to stop by
the Mercer Kitchen
just to check on something.
You're never gonna guess.
So, it turns out that
they are totally available
on Labor Day for our wedding.
Why am I always
the first one to arrive?
Um, did you not hear
what I just said?
They're available
for the wedding on Labor Day.
Okay, l-let's-let's just order.
I'm starving.
I don't want to fight
about this,
but I really feel like the whole
wedding planning thing,
it's just all falling on me.
What's the matter?
Tell me. Are...
Are you having second thoughts?
Have you noticed
how exhausting it's been
ever since you moved back in?
The other day,
we got into a three-hour fight
because I used a towel
to wipe off my mouth
while there was still toothpaste
on my face.
Well, how is someone else
supposed
to use it
when you leave it like that?
Living together is supposed
to be a trial run,
and I got to tell you,
I think we are failing it.
Thank you for finally
saying something truthful.
Where's that guy been?
Huh? Where have you been?
You've been completely aloof
and totally remote and distant.
It's like I don't even
know you anymore.
I feel like you're just
silently judging me.
What do you even want anymore?
Do you even want this wedding?
Do you even want to marry me?
Maybe I don't!
What changed?
Was it something that I did?
Because...
Because you know...
I love you, I love you so much.
And I-I really think
we can make this work.
I love you, too.
But we-we're kids.
Look.
We had a great run,
but let's just call it quits
before we completely
hate each other.
I will never forgive
you for this.
Kurt Hummel?
Hey.
I'm Ricardo.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
My spin class ran late.
I...
Are you okay?
I-I-I'm sorry.
I have to go.
Bop, bop, bop, bop.
Bop-bop, bop, tsa-tsa-tsa.
Thoughts?
Come on, Danny, pay attention.
You're the only person I trust
to show this stuff to.
You see, Vocal Adrenaline is not
like the New Directions!
They're all about precision
and big dance ensembles.
Perfection.
Can't rely on my old tricks
if I want
to get us a win at sectionals,
which means...
no waiting till the last minute,
no Mercedes to park and bark,
and  no Journey.
What I need to know
is if I'm crazy
for considering having
the entire team do
a synchronized backflip.
Ha!
Oh, why do I worry
about anything
when I get to come home every
night and see that face?
Come on, you want to learn
some of Daddy's dance moves?
Here we go, you ready?
You ready?
A five, six, seven, eight.
♪ Bop, Ba-dop ♪
♪ Ba-dop, bop, bop-Ba ♪
♪ Ba-dop, Ba... ♪
♪ Bop, bop ♪
♪ Ba-dop, bop, bop-Ba ♪
♪ Ba-dop, Ba... ♪
♪ Have you seen her? ♪
♪ So fine and pretty ♪
♪ Fooled me
with her style and ease ♪
♪ And I feel her ♪
♪ From across the room ♪
♪ Yeah, it's love
in the third degree ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ Baby, baby ♪
♪ Won't you turn
your head my way? ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ Baby, baby ♪
♪ Well, don't skip romance ♪
♪ 'Cause you're old enough ♪
♪ To dance...
the night away ♪
♪ Ooh, baby ♪
♪ Dance, dance,
dance the night away ♪
♪ Ah, come on, baby, baby ♪
♪ Dance... the night away. ♪
All right!
Great job, guys.
It's, uh, it's getting better.
Remember,
my office door is always open
if any of you have
any problems, so, um...
Am I dreaming?
Is that star of stage
and screen Rachel Berry?
I think the correct term is
"unhireable."
Come on,
your show wasn't that bad.
I actually liked, um...
a-a bunch of it.
You're a terrible liar.
No, I've just always
seen the best in you.
When I was in high school and
everyone thought I was a loser,
I knew that one day I
would have the chance
to show them the truth.
And, well, I got my shot, and
all I did was prove them right.
That was just
one misstep, Rachel.
Yeah, well, that's really
all you get these days.
No, I don't believe that.
I mean, there's always
something else,
especially for someone
as talented as you are.
I mean, look at me.
Here.
Yeah, I lost the New Directions!
But now I'm coaching the most
famous glee club in the world.
Yeah, which I have some pretty
strong feelings about.
I wanted to keep coaching,
and McKinley doesn't have
a glee club anymore.
Well, that never
stopped you before.
I don't have any fight
left in me, Rachel.
I have a baby, and, uh...
And Carmel pays five times
what McKinley did.
This is a good thing.
Besides, it's not like any
of you guys are there anymore.
Well...
No, don't, please.
Don't give me some speech
about being a part of something
special makes you special,
and that I should just
believe in myself,
because we're way past that.
How about this?
Have you ever seen a guy
shoot a bow and arrow?
When would
I have seen that?
Wait, well, here-here it is.
The power is created by
the bending of the bow, okay?
So-so the more...
the more the bow bends,
the more potential energy
is created.
Life's challenges are just
the bending of the bow.
Well, think about it.
Okay.
The bigger the challenge,
the more the bow bends,
the more potential you create
to do something amazing. Right.
All you have to do is just...
find a purpose.
- Find the arrow that you're gonna
put in that bow. - : Okay.
- You still got it.
- I still got it!
Oh, my God.
No.
No. The only difference
with my situation is that
the bow didn't just bend,
it broke.
- What's going on?
- We're here for an intervention.
Rachel, we want to help you.
We are gonna watch.
That's So Rachel.
On, no. No, we're not.
No, we're not, you guys.
No, no, I think it's time.
I think you're ready to face your fears.
No, I-I don't think so, Blaine.
Until you sit and watch
That's So Rachel
and realize
it really wasn't that bad,
you're never gonna get over it.
- Is this really happening right now?
- Mm-hmm.
Ah, here we go.
I am so
tired Oh, my God, you guys.
From that train ride from Ohio.
Oh, thank heavens
I inherited this loft
from my two dead
gay grandmothers.
Looks just like your apartment.
It's nice.
Rachel, look!
It's my grandmothers... s'
purple piano!
I learned how to play on this!
Uh, excuse me?
That's my piano.
It came with the apartment.
Wait. Someone else
lives here?
That's right.
- I'm Nittany Cuthbert,
- Oh, my God.
- And this is Infiniti Domingo.
- It's uncanny.
I feel like I can't breathe.
What y'all doing
in the apartment
we bought two years ago?
And I'm Blartie,
and I live here, too.
I knew it was
too good to be true.
♪ ♪
It's so horrible!
No, it's not that bad.
Blaine.
It's horrible.
Here, Rachel.
I thought these guys
could help you
with your audition for Cats.
Oh, the cats! The cats were
the worst part, you guys.
They have cancer.
Ugh! And then they
started spraying everywhere.
Cert!
Where have you been?
Let's just say I fed
my worm to a warbler.
He is so funny.
Come here, kitty. Ah.
- Oh, my God.
- Nailed him.
It looks like Cert forgot
to take his narcolepsy medicine.
- He'll be fine.
- Yeah.
I thought you were
gonna be singing.
- Where's the singing?
- Well, they cut it.
Gosh, Rachel,
New York is the worst.
- Even the muggers have muggers.
- Well, what happened?
I was... I was...
robbed at gunpoint,
and... paralyzed in fear.
And I'm paralyzed.
Anyway, Rachel...
Line!
Okay, uh, Mr. Shue,
can we just please pause it?
- I-I can't watch anymore. I get it.
Like... - All right.
Please.
I think it's charming.
- It's a monstrosity.
- Oh, you're right.
I mean, this isn't the beginning
that you had hoped for,
but it is... still
a beginning.
And since when are you a girl
who does it the easy way?
It's just a TV show;
it's not who you are.
I mean, you're not gonna
be defined by this failure.
The future will judge you
based on what you do
to come back from it.
♪ ♪
Look, I know
you've been through this
with Sue Sylvester,
but she's wrong.
Depriving a student an education
in the arts is so...
I agree.
I think the arts are
extremely important.
But unfortunately,
the principals are in charge
- of the schools.
- Right, but aren't you in charge
of the principals?
Even if I wanted to go
over Sue Sylvester's head,
and reinstate the Glee Club,
it would be impossible
at this point.
The budget's already
been set for the year,
and there is... no
money for any new programs.
What if I gave the money?
I-I have some left over
from That's So Rachel.
It's not much,
but I'd be willing to donate it
if it meant bringing back
the Glee Club.
Hmm.
You know...
I have to admit, I...
wouldn't mind seeing Sue
Sylvester taken down a peg.
I mean, the grades are up, but
I'm not sure about the caning.
I have a sneaking suspicion
she's angling for my job.
That would not surprise me.
All right.
You've got a deal.
- On one condition.
- Okay.
- You run it.
- Excuse me?
I don't know, Rachel,
you seem like
the perfect candidate to me.
Hey, Rachel.
Oh.
I showed up.
Six months ago you said
that we would all meet
at that spot outside the loft,
'cause no matter what,
our friendships
were the most important thing.
♪ ♪
Well, I was the only one
who showed up.
And you were clearly
in the midst
of a nervous
breakdown. And...
well, Blaine...
well, I-I blew it.
I blew the best thing
that ever happened to me.
Are you sure
you're not just saying that
because you're lonely?
I mean, New York must feel
pretty empty
without all of us there.
No.
Blaine's the love of my life.
I started seeing this therapist
who said that I have
this thing with love.
You know, men fight as a way
to stay connected, but
Blaine wasn't like that.
He wasn't afraid of intimacy.
Ha-has he said anything?
He-he seems to be
in a good place about it.
Well, that's great.
Well, m-maybe I can fix it.
D-Do you think you can arrange
a meeting between he and I
in-in a neutral place
somewhere here in Lima?
Uh, I'm confused.
How do you plan
to fix things long distance?
Well... maybe
it doesn't have
to be long distance.
Look, I... I want to
be here with you guys.
Uh, you've got to help me.
Maybe we can have our
redemption here together.
I think I have the perfect idea.
Thank you so much, gentlemen.
Yeah, we know that in the past
the Glee Club and the AV Club
have had friendly relations.
And we plan to keep that intact.
And we promise
to learn your names, yes.
And that goes for the band, too.
What is this?
We're bringing
back the Glee Club.
I went over your head and
got express written consent
from the superintendent
and there is
nothing you can do to stop us.
Let me get this straight.
The superintendent gave you
permission to demolish
a state-of-the-art computer lab
to make room for a glee club.
He may have been aware
that this was a computer lab.
And who will be running
this glee club?
You, Rachel?
And me.
It's part of my third-year
work study program at NYADA.
Okay, well, I have to, uh, admit
I'm surprised at the speed
with which two
of the Glee Club's
more promising graduates
have tucked their tails
between their legs
and snuck back to high school.
And while I'm always tickled
at the sheer novelty of having
a middlesex like porcelain,
'cause it's just so
whimsical to talk
to somebody who looks and sounds
so much like
a gay cartoon walrus,
you,
Rachel Berry,
well, you crossed a line.
I don't appreciate
being told off.
When we met up in New York,
you insulted me
in front of my beau.
Simply because I
flew a thousand miles
to be at your opening night
so I could walk out
in the middle
and have sex all over
your apartment.
And then you do this.
You two have just entered.
Sue Sylvester's Thunderdome.
And I will show you no mercy.
Give no quarter, and my battle
with Will Schuester
will look like
two adorable little baby pandas
play wrestling
in comparison to what I'm going
to unleash on both of you.
You will beg for death.
When will it come?
You think you bottomed out
with that abomination
of a TV show you ran?
No, Rachel Berry,
your national nightmare
has just... begun.
You smell like a nursing home.
Just be cool.
Keep your words
as straight as an arrow.
Hi!
I hope you weren't waiting long.
Uh, no, no. H-Hi!
Hi. Hello.
Hi. Hi.
Um, I-I appreciate
you coming to see me.
I-I would understand if you
had told me to screw off.
No! No, no.
I-I've wanted to see you, uh...
Well, I-I'm here
to get you back.
I-I don't mean
to blurt it out like that,
but for-for the sake of clarity,
you should know that first
I'm going to get your
forgiveness and-and then
I'm gonna get your heart back.
Um...
I'm seeing someone.
Don't cry. Be cool.
Smile, Oh, God.
I'm gonna be sick.
And I, I wanted
to tell you in person
especially because you know him.
Please don't say
Sebastian Smythe.
Hey, Kurt!
Karofsky.
I knew this would be a
little weird for you.
It's a living nightmare!
What? No, it's-it's
not weird at all.
No, uh-uh, so, how'd
you two meet up again?
Well, um, it was actually just
a few months ago right here
as a matter of fact.
I was a little bored.
So, I decided to come
to Country Bear Nights
here at Scandals,
and there was Dave
doing the Electric Slide.
♪ ♪
Fun!
Yeah.
We got to talking mo-mostly,
mostly about you.
I was just so angry
with what had happened.
And it was just me venting
about the breakup.
But I reminded him,
you know, how much you helped me
during that dark time
in my life.
And, uh, just, you know,
you forgave me
for all the crap
I put you through.
Anyway, we got to talking,
hanging out, and...
here we are.
Here we are.
Yogi and Boo Boo.
That's his nickname for us
'cause I'm his big bear
and he's my little cub.
Aah! I'm gonna be sick!
I'm gonna throw up!
And when did Blaine
start liking bears?!
I know this isn't
what you wanted.
And I know this isn't gonna
be easy, but I just wanted
all of us to be able
to be adults about this.
And I'm hoping
we can be friends.
You know, we can
all hang out and stuff.
Sounds like fun.
Um, if-if-if can you excuse me.
I have to use the restroom.
Perfect.
Definitely want this.
Put it right there.
I always thought one day Finn
would take this place over.
Yeah, well, it's just
for a couple months
till I get my feet
on the ground.
You know what that means yet?
Broadway.
It was always my dream.
Still is. I had it once
and I lost it,
but I'm gonna get it back.
So... don't bet against me.
I never have and I never will.
I, um...
I wanted to bring you something.
I think it belongs right here.
And just
a little friendly reminder,
you're gonna be facing
off against Blaine
and me at sectionals, so, um,
I think it's time
you start recruiting.
Yeah.
I think
you're gonna like it here.
♪ The snow glows white
on the mountain tonight ♪
♪ Not a footprint to be seen ♪
♪ A kingdom of isolation ♪
♪ And it looks
like I'm the queen ♪
♪ And the wind is howling ♪
♪ Like this swirling storm
inside ♪
♪ Couldn't keep it in ♪
♪ Heaven knows I tried ♪
♪ Don't let them in,
don't let them see ♪
♪ Be the good girl
you always have to be ♪
♪ Conceal, don't feel ♪
♪ Don't let them know ♪
♪ Well, now they know ♪
♪ Let it go, let it go ♪
♪ Can't hold it back anymore ♪
♪ Turn away and slam the door ♪
♪ I don't care ♪
♪ What they're going to say ♪
♪ Let the storm rage on ♪
♪ The cold never bothered me
anyway ♪
♪ It's funny how some distance ♪
♪ Makes everything seem small ♪
♪ And the fears
that once controlled me ♪
♪ Can't get to me at all ♪
♪ It's time to see
what I can do ♪
♪ To test the limits ♪
♪ And break through ♪
♪ No right, no wrong ♪
♪ No rules for me ♪
♪ I'm free ♪
♪ Let it go, let it go ♪
♪ I'm one
with the wind and sky ♪
♪ Let it go, let it go ♪
♪ You'll never see me cry ♪
♪ Here I stand ♪
♪ In the light of day ♪
♪ Let the storm rage on... ♪
The cold never bothered me
anyway.
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com