♪ Glee 2x22 ♪
New York
Original Air Date on May 24, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
KURT (laughs):
A year and a half ago,
the New Directions were nothing
but a group of six misfits,
stumbling their way
through a horrific rendition
of "Sit Down,
You're Rocking the Boat."
Now here we are,
at the top
of the show choir heap:
Nationals!
I want to hit up Central
Park, get my frolic on.
I want to throw stuff
off the Brooklyn Bridge.
You guys, hold
on. I mean,
we still have
two songs to write.
Okay, Mr. Bossy Pants.
But I think we might have some
time for a tune before we leave.
(a cappella):
♪ Start spreading the news ♪
♪ I'm leaving today ♪
♪ I want
to be a part of it ♪
♪ New York, New York... ♪
Guys, I have news.
To celebrate our impending win
at Nationals,
I got us all 13 tickets
to Broadway's longest-running
show ever,
Cats!
(Brittany whoops)
Yeah, you did.
You might want to check the
dates on those tickets, Rachel,
because Cats closed
about 11 years ago.
He did seem crazy.
Charged my credit card
by swiping it through
his butt-crack.
Okay, welcome
to Intercontinental
New York Times Square.
- Your rooms are on the seventh floor.
- Great.
You planning on fitting all
those kids in two rooms?
Yeah, well,
it's all we can afford.
I was just thinking about splitting
them up, boys and girls.
You guys in for the show
choir competition?
Yeah. Why?
Most of the other teams
split by sexual orientation.
Oh. Did you know that
New York City was built
right on top of
Old York City?
I'm pretty sure
that's not true.
Oh, I'm
just pretty.
Hi.
I'm surprised at how well
Quinn is taking the breakup.
I guess I was wrong about her
being a vindictive harpy.
I guess she just accepted
the inevitable.
Or maybe she's
just distracted
by the awesomeness of
New York. I know I am.
Hey, do you know why it smells
like it's wet here all the time?
No. So, what's going on
with you and Jessie?
I don't know. He
keeps texting me.
But I told him I don't want
to talk till I get back.
No boys, no distractions
until we win that trophy.
Hey, Finn, where the
hell is Puckerman?
Um...
I'll have a Manhattan.
Do you even know
what's in a Manhattan?
Yeah, me,
for the first time.
Which is why I want
to celebrate with a cocktail.
(laughs)
Guys, group meeting,
in the room now.
Do you know that I can get
ahi tartare and a steak
sandwich at 3:00
in the morning
from their all-night
dining menu?
I feel like Eloise.
I have pills for that.
All right, guys,
this is your time.
Now, you are all on lockdown
till you finish writing
our songs for Nationals.
I want at least two solid verses
by the time I get back.
Aren't you going to help us?
Uh, um... I will be back
and read your amazing creations
and give notes, but right now,
I have to head to the theater
to, uh, fill out some paperwork.
(sighs)
Broadway.
(guitar plays upbeat tune)
♪ In the middle of the night
I'm in bed alone ♪
♪ Don't care if you're glass,
paper or Styrofoam ♪
♪ When I need some water, baby ♪
ARTIE & BRITTANY:
♪ Coffee or gin ♪
♪ You're the only thing ♪
♪ I want to put them in ♪
♪ My cup, my cup,
sayin' what's up? ♪
♪ To my cup, my cup ♪
♪ More of a friend
than a silly pup, my cup ♪
♪ You know what it is ♪
♪ Saying what's up? ♪
♪ To my cup ♪
(Artie sighs)
♪ I'm saying what's up?
to my cup ♪
(sighs)
♪ I'm saying what's up? ♪
♪ To my cup. ♪
(sighs)
(whoops)
Awesome.
Hold on.
Are you singing about a cup?
Yeah, totally.
We got to get out of here.
Wait. No, no, no. Mr. Shue gave
us explicit instructions...
To write a song,
and our problem is,
is that our only inspiration are
mattresses and bathroom cups.
Quinn's right. We're in the
artists capital of the world.
Poets, musicians,
actors, playwrights.
Every dreamer that's ever lived
has passed through this city.
And if we want our dreams
to come true, we need to be
out there with them,
not stuck in here.
Guys, I don't think
this is a good idea.
I mean, we still got
those songs to write.
If we don't write them,
we're going to lose.
No. They're right.
Can't you hear the city
calling to you?
We don't need to write songs
for Nationals.
New York's going
to write them for us.
("New York New York," "I Love
New York" mash up begins)
♪ I don't like cities,
but I like New York ♪
♪ The famous places
to visit are so many ♪
♪ Other places
make me feel like a dork ♪
♪ I told my grandpa
I wouldn't miss on any ♪
♪ Los Angeles is for
people who sleep ♪
♪ Got to see the whole town ♪
♪ Right from Yonkers
on down to the Bay ♪
♪ Paris and London,
oh, baby, you can keep ♪
♪ Baby, you can keep ♪
ALL: ♪ Other cities always
make me mad ♪
♪ Other places always
make me sad ♪
♪ No other city
ever made me glad ♪
♪ Except New York, New York ♪
♪ It's a wonderful town ♪
♪ I love New York ♪
♪ New York ♪
♪ If you don't like
my attitude ♪
♪ Then you can get lost ♪
♪ Manhattan women are dressed
in silk and satin ♪
♪ Just go to Texas,
isn't that where they golf? ♪
♪ There's just one thing
that's important in Manhattan ♪
ARTIE: ♪ New York is not
for little wussies ♪
♪ Who scream ♪
(girls screaming)
♪ Pick up a date,
maybe 7:00 or 8:00 ♪
♪ Paris and London,
oh, baby, you can keep ♪
♪ Baby, you can keep ♪
♪ Other cities always
make me mad ♪
♪ Make me mad ♪
♪ Other places always
make me sad ♪
♪ Make me sad ♪
♪ No other city ever
made me glad ♪
♪ Except New York, New York ♪
♪ It's a wonderful town ♪
♪ I love New York ♪
♪ New York ♪
♪ We sailed the seas
and we've been the world over ♪
♪ Made the Mandalay ♪
♪ We've seen the sphinx and
we've seen the Cliffs of Dover ♪
♪ And we can safely say ♪
♪ New York ♪
♪ Other cities
always make me mad ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh, oh ♪
♪ Other places always
make me sad ♪
♪ New York ♪
♪ No other city
ever made me glad ♪
♪ Except New York, New York ♪
♪ It's a wonderful town ♪
♪ I love New York ♪
♪ New York, yeah ♪
♪ New York, New York ♪
♪ I love New York ♪
♪ New York, yeah ♪
♪ New York, New York. ♪
(whooping and cheering,
indistinct chatter)
Hey, can I try something out
on you guys?
I think that one
of our songs
should be a duet
with me and Rachel.
I just want to win.
We all know that
you two doing a duet is
our best shot at that.
Awesome.
Okay, can we just talk about
the Jewish elephant in the room?
Ask her out, dude.
Who? Rachel? But she's totally
into Jessie right now.
You're in New York,
the city of love.
I thought that was Paris.
Anything's possible here.
You need to ask her out tonight.
Take her
on one of those big,
awful dates
you see in those
unwatchable romantic comedies
that you grow a vagina
if you watch all
the way through.
This is your shot, dude.
If I was in love with a girl,
and I wasn't homeless,
I'd totally go for it.
(laughter, screaming,
and indistinct shouting)
(gentle melody plays)
♪ If you're not home,
I'll sit here on your doorstep ♪
♪ Button up my coat and wait ♪
♪ We'll go upstairs ♪
♪ Close the curtains
and we're all set ♪
♪ To pick up
where we left again ♪
♪ There's question marks
hanging over us ♪
♪ But we won't give the time
of day, oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ 'Cause all we got
is these few stolen seconds ♪
♪ And we can't let them go
to waste ♪
♪ The stars collide ♪
♪ We come back to life,
we come back to life ♪
♪ The sparks, they fly ♪
♪ One look in your eyes ♪
♪ My heart's open wide ♪
♪ I know
time's running out now ♪
♪ But we'll hold back
the sun somehow ♪
♪ See the sky ♪
♪ We've still got tonight ♪
♪ We've still got
tonight. ♪
(sound of person clapping)
April?
She's still at dinner
with the rest of the crew.
Oh. Sorry I was just trying out
a new idea for the show.
I've been working here 25 years.
Seen a lot of talent
come and go.
And let me tell you
something, kid.
You got it.
Hi.
What's so important?
Uh, these are for you.
I thought since, uh,
we're both captains and all,
we should write a duet
for Nationals.
The tie and... flowers,
Central Park?
Oh, it's a... a work date.
Uh, totally professional.
Oh, my God, I can't
believe we're at Sardi's.
Sardi's! The birthplace
of the Tony Award.
What's a salad "nicose"?
One day they're gonna
put a cartoon likeness
of me on these walls.
I like the way
you dream so big.
I don't know how to do that.
You look so pretty tonight.
Rachel, I... I have
something to say to you.
Oh, my God!
(whispers):
That's Patti LuPone!
Oh, no, oh, my God,
I can't do this.
No. No, I have to-- I mean,
if not for me, then for Kurt.
I mean, he'd kill me
if I didn't. Okay.
Excuse me, uh,
Miss LuPone?
I have to say
that you're my idol.
Well, thank you.
That's very sweet of you.
Are you an actress?
Yes. I'm-I'm in high school.
We're in town for the National
Show Choir Championship.
I was in choir
in high school.
It was my favorite class.
What's your name?
Rachel Berry.
Well, Rachel Berry,
promise me one thing--
you'll never give up.
Yes, Ms. LuPone, I promise.
(chuckles)
Good luck.
Thank you.
(whispers):
He's cute.
(exhales)
(laughs quietly)
Being in New York is like...
falling in love over and
over again every minute.
Tonight felt like one
of those awesome nights
you see in all those
amazing romantic comedies.
All we need now is just
a group of street singers
to serenade us,
and it would be perfect.
(accordion playing
mid-tempo intro)
♪ Oh, this is the night ♪
♪ It's a beautiful night ♪
♪ And we call it ♪
♪ Bella notte ♪
♪ Look at the skies ♪
♪ They have stars in their eyes ♪
Wait.
♪ On this lovely ♪
This is the moment
♪ Bella notte... ♪
in those romantic comedies
where... I kiss you.
(song continues)
I thought this was just a work date.
Really?
♪ ♪
♪ You'll find enchantment ♪
(whispers): No.
♪ Here ♪
♪ The night will weave
its magic spell ♪
♪ When the one you love
is near ♪
I can't.
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ This is the night ♪
♪ And the heavens ♪
Take a chance on me.
♪ Are right ♪
♪ On this lovely ♪
♪ Bella ♪
I'm sorry, Finn.
♪ Notte ♪
I can't.
♪ ♪
♪ This is the night ♪
♪ And the heavens ♪
♪ Are right ♪
♪ On this lovely ♪
♪ Bella ♪
♪ Notte... ♪
♪ ♪
- Rachel, wake up, wake up.
- Why?
We're going
to breakfast at Tiffany's.
RACHEL: We're gonna get into
so much trouble for this.
How awesome are these bagels?! Mm.
It's the water.
Ah, you're the only one
besides me
who understands
how amazing this place is.
Which is why I have
a secret to tell you.
When we graduate I'm coming back
here and I'm going to college here.
This is where I belong.
I am so coming, too.
Really?
And I talked to Blaine;
he's on board as well.
Good.
What am I gonna do about Finn?
I mean, I... I think
he wants to get back together,
and I... I really do, too, but
I can't have anything keep me
from my Manhattan destiny.
Bring him along.
He'll be great if we need
to move anything heavy.
No.
Finn won't come--
he's too much of a country boy.
Ah, the age-old dilemma:
love or career?
You're gonna have
to make a choice.
I don't... I don't know how.
I do.
Follow me.
W-W-Wait!
Wait.
♪ ♪
I love this show, but it's not
helping me make up my mind.
We have to go in.
Strike that.
We have to break in.
No, we-we can't be in here.
They say that if you
get arrested in a theater,
you're blackballed for life!
It's 9:00 a.m....
Hey!
You're not supposed
to be in here.
We're extras.
th-they told us to come early.
We're, um, being...
being fitted for
our munchkin costumes.
You're from Indiana, right?
Ohio, actually.
And you got some
big Broadway dream
about singing a song
on a real Broadway stage.
Look, we're-we're
really sorry...
You got 15 minutes.
(laughs)
♪ ♪
(squeals)
If you have to
make a choice,
you have to visualize
both of the options.
How?
Sing.
Picture yourself standing
in front of a full audience,
belting out the final song
of one of the greatest
musicals of all time.
There's no orchestra.
Make one.
In your mind.
(orchestra plays softly)
♪ I'm limited ♪
♪ Just look at me ♪
♪ And just look at you ♪
♪ You can do all
I couldn't do ♪
♪ Glinda ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Now it's up ♪
♪ To you... ♪
♪ ♪
♪ I've heard it said ♪
♪ That people come
into our lives ♪
♪ For a reason ♪
♪ Bringing something
we must learn ♪
♪ Well, I don't ♪
♪ Know if I believe ♪
♪ That's true ♪
♪ But I know I'm
who I am today ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ Like a ship blown
from its mooring ♪
♪ By a wind
off the sea ♪
♪ Like a seed dropped
by a skybird ♪
♪ In a distant wood ♪
♪ Who can say ♪
♪ If I've been changed ♪
♪ For the better? ♪
♪ But because I knew you ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
BOTH:
♪ I have been changed ♪
♪ For good ♪
♪ And just to clear the air ♪
♪ I ask forgiveness ♪
♪ For the things I've
done you blame me for ♪
♪ But then I guess we know ♪
♪ There's blame to share ♪
BOTH: ♪ And none of it
seems to matter ♪
♪ Anymore... ♪
♪ Like a comet ♪
♪ Pulled from orbit ♪
♪ Like a ship blown ♪
♪ As it passes the sun ♪
♪ From its moorings
by a wind off the sea ♪
♪ Like a stream
that meets a boulder ♪
♪ Like a seed dropped ♪
♪ Halfway through the wood ♪
♪ By a bird in the wood ♪
BOTH:
♪ Who can say... ♪
♪ If I've been changed ♪
♪ For the better ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ I have been changed... ♪
♪ ♪
♪ For good... ♪
(both holding last note)
(song ends)
Thank you, Kurt.
I see it now.
I don't have to choose
between... (sighs)
my career and... love,
because this...
I mean... this stage,
Broadway, New York...
...that's my true love.
(groans)
Quinn! Quit hogging
the bathroom.
I needs to re-pencil
my eyebrows on.
Doesn't she get...
It's all yours.
Everybody's already
in the other room working.
Oh, yeah?
Is Mr. Shue in there?
'Cause I think
I'm gonna tell him
that Rachel and Kurt
keep sneaking off.
You can't do that--
he'll have to suspend them.
And then there goes
our chances at Nationals. Darn!
You know what?
We get it.
You're pissed about Finn
dumping your sweet ass.
Get over it.
I don't want to get
over it! Okay?
The only person that you're
sabotaging here is yourself.
I don't care about some
stupid show choir competition!
Well, you should!
Because this is
the one chance that we have to
actually feel good about ourselves.
Aren't we supposed to be
the popular girls?
So why can't we have
our dreams come true?
She has love, Tina has it,
even Zizes hooks up.
(exhales)
I just want somebody
to love me. (sniffles)
I think I know how
to make you feel better.
I'm flattered, Santana, but
I'm really not that into that.
(sniffles)
No.
No, I'm not talking about that.
I'm talking about a haircut.
Yes, totally.
WILL:
I'm sorry about the pillows.
I mean, this really was
a... a wake-up call for me
as an educator and
a chaperone, so...
Look, I get it.
Kids are kids.
Good luck at Nationals.
Thank you.
GOOLSBY:
I'll second that.
And why would you be wishing
my glee club luck at Nationals?
Oh, I wasn't talking
about the glee club.
I was wishing you luck
in your Broadway debut.
How did you find out?
It's all over
the Broadway blogosphere.
And by Broadway blogosphere,
I mean the one blog that
actually cares about Broadway.
Can I give you
a piece of advice?
Don't tell your kids.
It'll just shake
their confidence at Nationals
and they won't perform as well.
I hate my kids.
I would literally
whip them if I could.
Every time I see them
achieving...
just reminds me of everything
I missed out on.
I love my kids.
What? No, you don't.
They're hideous.
My kids are at least attractive.
Yours look like they haven't
been baked properly.
(laughs softly)
I've watched them grow
into mature young men and women.
And that's been the joy
of my life.
You're tearing up.
People are starting to stare.
I bet they think
I just broke up with you.
See you on the ice,
Schuester.
(groans)
All right, guys,
who's up for some real
New York City... pizza?
We heard.
Heard what?
About you leaving
to be on Broadway.
(sighs)
Look, I haven't made up my mind
about anything.
We get it.
And we're happy for you.
You've inspired us in
so many ways, so...
this is just another.
I don't understand.
Who-who told you guys?
Goolsby.
You okay, Mr. Shue?
I'm not going.
I'm staying with you guys.
I had my moment on the stage
and it was glorious.
But you and I...
have some unfinished business
to take care of.
Now get out your notebooks.
Time to get to work.
Come on,
this is Nationals, people.
(Will laughs, others "oohing")
Yes, Puck.
I want in, I want in.
Oh, gee!
(laughing)
RACHEL:
We made it.
We're one of the top 50
show choirs in the nation.
Tomorrow only ten will move on
to Showcase,
where they'll vie
for the National Championship.
We have so got this.
Okay, usually
I'm pretty cautious
about getting your hopes up,
but honestly, guys?
I think we got a really good
shot at winning this thing.
All right, everybody put
your hand in the middle.
One, two, three.
ALL:
New Directions!
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ ♪
Peace up.
A town down.
Yeah. What?
♪ Okay ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Let's go ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ I'm in the club
with my homies ♪
♪ Trying to get a lil' V-I,
keep it down on the low-key ♪
They're really good.
♪ 'Cause you know how it is ♪
♪ I saw shorty,
she was checkin' up on me ♪
♪ From the game
she was spittin' in my ear ♪
♪ You would think
that she knew me ♪
♪ I decided to chill ♪
♪ Conversation got heavy ♪
♪ She had me feeling
like she's ready to blow ♪
♪ Watch out down below ♪
♪ Watch out, oh ♪
♪ Down below, watch out ♪
♪ She was saying "Come get me" ♪
♪ So I got up
and followed her to the floor ♪
♪ She said "Baby, let's go" ♪
♪ Baby, let's go ♪
♪ When I told her, I said... ♪
Hey. I gotta talk to you.
Hold on a sec.
I do this thing
where I get my kids to sign
a T-shirt to send to all
the teams we beat at Nationals.
Yeah, well,
don't bother getting us one.
I have a sneaking suspicion that
we're about to kick your ass.
You're about to go up against
the top show choirs
in the country
and your team spent all week
mooning about how fun
and exciting New York is.
You're a bag of meat.
Take a large.
You're about a large, right?
Extra large.
What are you doing?
Buying you a T-shirt, Goolsby.
I'll send it to you...
after we win Nationals.
♪ Got the beat, got the beat,
we got the beat. ♪
(coughing)
Santana?
(toilet flushing)
Oh, shoving your fingers
down your throat
like the rest
of your brainwashed
Vocal Adrenaline
brothers and sisters?
I'm not throwing up
on purpose.
I'm so nervous
I can't keep any food down.
I used to love singing.
It was the only thing
that relaxed me.
Now I hate it.
Do you think I'm an idiot?
No.
I think you're kind of mean,
but I don't think you're stupid.
I know what you're
trying to doing.
You're trying to get me
to feel bad for you
so that I don't try as hard
to crush you on the stage.
What did I ever do to you
to make you hate me so much?
When I came to your school,
I heard that the Glee Club
was where kids went when no one
else would take them.
A safe place.
For some reason, you made me the
only one who wasn't safe there.
Where are you going?
To the Philippine embassy.
I'm going to beg them to revoke
my visa and deport me back home.
That's the only way
I'm going to be able
to escape Vocal Adrenaline.
Wait... wait.
It's because you're good.
That's why I hated you.
That's why I sent you
to that crack house.
I'm sorry.
But you have to go out there
and sing.
You have a gift.
Something that Dustin
Goolsby would kill for.
I can't. I'm going to barf
all over the stage.
If you feel like you're going
to throw up
just look at me,
and I'll help you through it.
Why?
Don't you want to win?
Guys like us
have to stick together.
I'm going to hug you now.
(both laugh)
ANNOUNCER: And now, our returning
champions from Carmel High,
Vocal Adrenaline.
(applause, whooping, whistling)
(loud cheering)
(loud cheering continues)
(cheering, whooping,
whistling continue)
(cheering dies down)
What are you doing?
I'm making something right.
(gentle intro playing)
♪ Mmm... ♪
♪ Mmm, mmm, mmm, mmm ♪
♪ All my life ♪
♪ I've waited for the right ♪
♪ Moment to let you know ♪
♪ I don't wanna let you go ♪
♪ But now I realize ♪
♪ There's just no
perfect time ♪
♪ To confess how I feel ♪
♪ This much I know is real ♪
♪ So I refuse to ♪
♪ Waste one more second ♪
♪ Without you ♪
♪ Knowing ♪
♪ My... ♪
(holding high note):
♪ Heart... ♪
(cheering)
♪ I don't need anything else ♪
♪ But your love ♪
♪ Nothing but you means ♪
♪ A thing to me ♪
♪ I'm incomplete ♪
♪ When you're not there ♪
♪ Holding me, touching me ♪
♪ I swear ♪
♪ All of the rest could just ♪
♪ Disappear ♪
♪ And I wouldn't even care ♪
♪ As long as you're there... ♪
(holding note)
♪ ♪
(loud cheering)
(song ends)
(loud cheering continues)
You wrote an amazing song, Finn.
I didn't know you had it in you.
Who cares about the song?
What I don't understand is,
all you've ever wanted is
for us to
be together,
and I'm basically standing here
begging for you,
and suddenly
you're not interested.
I-I am interested.
More than interested.
This is my dream.
Being here in New York.
I'm not gonna let anyone
or anything keep me from it.
I'm sorry, Finn.
I love you.
But...
(sighs) ...there's nothing
you can say or do
that's gonna
change my mind about it.
ANNOUNCER:
And now, from William McKinley
High in Lima, Ohio,
the New Directions!
(applause)
(applause dies down)
(slow intro playing)
RACHEL & FINN:
♪ Face to face ♪
♪ And heart to heart ♪
♪ We're so close ♪
♪ Yet so far apart ♪
♪ I close my eyes ♪
♪ I look away ♪
♪ That's just because ♪
♪ I'm not okay ♪
♪ But I hold on ♪
♪ I stay strong ♪
♪ Wondering if ♪
♪ We still belong... ♪
♪ Will we ever ♪
♪ Say the words ♪
♪ We're feeling ♪
♪ Reach down
underneath and... ♪
I couldn't stay away.
♪ Will we ever ♪
From the show... or her?
♪ Have a happy ending ♪
♪ Or will we forever ♪
♪ Only be pretending? ♪
♪ Keeping secrets safe ♪
♪ Every move we make ♪
♪ Seems like no one's ♪
♪ Letting go ♪
♪ And it's ♪
♪ Such a shame 'cause if you ♪
♪ Feel the same ♪
♪ How am I ♪
♪ Supposed ♪
♪ To know... ♪
♪ Will we ever ♪
♪ Say the words
we're feeling ♪
♪ Reach down underneath and ♪
♪ Tear down all the walls? ♪
(applause)
♪ Will we ever ♪
♪ Have a happy ending ♪
♪ Or will we forever ♪
♪ Only be pretending? ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh... ♪
♪ Pretending ♪
♪ Pretending... ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh... ♪
(silence)
Was that scripted?
No.
(scattered applause)
(upbeat intro playing)
♪ ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ You and me keep on dancing ♪
♪ In the dark ♪
♪ It's been tearing me apart ♪
♪ Never knowing what we are ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey, you ♪
♪ And me keep on
trying to play it cool ♪
♪ Now it's time to make a move ♪
♪ And that's what
I'm gonna do ♪
♪ Lay it all down ♪
♪ Got something to say ♪
♪ Throw your doubt away ♪
♪ Do or die now ♪
♪ Step onto the plate ♪
♪ Blow the door wide open ♪
♪ Like up, up and away ♪
(cheering, whistling)
♪ Let's light up
the world toni-i-ight ♪
♪ You got to give up the bark ♪
♪ And bi-i-ite ♪
♪ I know that we got
the love all ri-i-ight ♪
♪ Come on and
li-li-light it up ♪
♪ Light it up tonight ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey, you ♪
♪ And me, turn it up
ten thousand watts ♪
♪ Tell me why
we've got to stop ♪
♪ I just want to let it rock,
hey, hey, hey, you ♪
♪ And me keep on
staring at the road ♪
♪ We don't know where to go,
step back, let me take control ♪
♪ Lay it all down ♪
♪ Got something to say ♪
♪ Throw your doubt away ♪
♪ Do or die now ♪
♪ Step onto the plate ♪
♪ Blow the door wide open like ♪
♪ Up, up and away ♪
♪ Let's light up
the world toni-i-ight ♪
♪ You got to give up
the bark and bi-i-ite ♪
♪ I know that we got the love
all ri-i-ight ♪
♪ Come on
and li-li-light it up ♪
♪ Light it up tonight ♪
♪ Let's light up
the world toni-i-ight ♪
♪ You got to give up the bark
and bi-i-ite ♪
♪ I know that we got
the love all ri-i-ight ♪
♪ Come on
and li-li-light it up ♪
♪ Light it up tonight. ♪
(song ends)
(applause, cheering
and whistling)
Don't you think this is gonna
look so hot on Lord Tubbington?
I'm gonna go find it
in an extra large.
(throat clearing)
I think we were good.
Good? We were amazing.
The kiss was... interesting.
Yeah, I'm-I'm calling it
The Kiss of the Century.
JESSIE:
You're wrong, Finn.
That kiss was unprofessional.
It was too personal and intense.
The judges won't like it.
They'll consider it common
and vulgar, and it cost you
Nationals. Hi, Rachel.
You look amazing,
and you sounded great.
Just shouldn't have kissed him.
Why are you
here, Jessie?
For you.
Dude, back off.
You're just jealous.
(scoffs)
Jealous of what we have,
and what we shared
with the entire audience,
because it was shared between
two people who love each other.
It was the Superman of kisses.
It-It came with its own cape,
right, Rachel?
(high-pitched shrieking
and excited chatter)
What's-What's
happening?
They just posted
the top ten for showcase.
Everybody, gather around!
It's a moment
two years in the making.
Okay, what should we do?
Let's go look at it...
together.
Come on, come on.
RACHEL:
Oh, I'm too nervous to look.
I'll go.
What did we place?
Well, Mr. Shue?
Say it. What did we rank?
We didn't.
I'm so sorry, you guys.
We aren't in the top ten.
Oh my God,
you should have seen it.
We all looked at the top
ten list for Showcase,
and we all just
went numb.
And then Jessie kept
going on and on
about how Rachel and Finn's
kiss is what cost us Nationals.
While I understand
passion, I do think
that was unprofessional,
but sorry. Keep going.
Okay, then we get back to
the hotel, and Santana loses it.
I mean, and the plane ride
was completely silent.
Like, no one said a word.
We all just sat there
with our faces buried
in our complimentary copies
of SkyMall.
Wait, I don't get it.
You don't seem that sad at all.
Well, it was still amazing.
I mean, I flew on a plane
for the first time in my life,
I had breakfast at Tiffany's,
I sang on a Broadway stage.
I love you.
I love you, too.
You know, when you stop
and think about it,
Kurt Hummel's had
a pretty good year.
Oh, look who's here.
Hey, what are you guys
doing here?
Uh, nothing.
Just, uh, getting a coffee.
We ran into each other
in the parking lot.
We're on our way
to get some sheet music.
Tomorrow's my audition for
the summer show at Six Flags.
Whereas I'm spending my summer
composing Pip, Pip, Hooray!
The Broadway music
about Pippa Middleton.
I have no idea who that is,
but it sounds totally awesome.
(laughs)
We'll see you in class.
Bye.
Bye, guys.
Okay, so here are the nominees
for my songs tomorrow.
I think I could
probably...
Do you think
they know?
I don't think
anybody knows.
(school bell ringing)
BRITTANY: Hey.
You still pissed?
Do you think this
voodoo doll looks enough
like Rachel Berry
to actually work?
Come on. We can't be mad
at Rachel forever.
Uh, yes, we can.
How could you
possibly be so calm?
I don't know. I hated losing
just as much as everyone,
but this year wasn't
about winning for me.
Clearly, 'cause we
got our asses kicked.
Yeah.
Sorry.
What was it about?
Acceptance.
I know that all the kids
in the glee club-- they fight,
and they steal each other's
boyfriends and girlfriends,
and they threaten to quit,
like, every other week,
but weird stuff like that
happens in families.
Yeah, well, this is a club.
This is not a family.
Okay, well, family is a place
where everyone loves you
no matter what,
and they accept you
for who you are.
I know I'm going to be
a bridesmaid at Mike
and Tina's wedding,
and I'm gonna be
anxiously awaiting,
just like everyone else,
to see if their babies
are Asian, too.
When they find an operation
to make Artie's legs work again,
I'm going to be there
for his first steps.
I love them.
I love everyone in Glee Club.
And I get to spend another year
with everyone I love,
so, I'm good.
What about you and I?
I love you, Santana.
I love you more
than I've ever loved anyone else
in this world.
All I know about you and I
is that, because of that,
I think anything's possible.
(sighs)
You're my best friend.
Yeah, me, too.
(laughs)
When did you
get so smart?
(school bell ringing)
(sighs)
Where have you been?
Hiding out.
Everyone hates me.
No, they don't.
It doesn't explain why
you haven't said a word to me
since we've been back.
'Cause you should be more pissed
at me than anyone else.
I screwed up!
I'm humiliated.
We worked so hard
for everything,
and I was supposed
to be this big shot leader,
holding everyone together,
and... I blew it.
Cost us the
championship.
Look, being an artist
is about expressing
your true feelings,
in the moment,
no matter what the consequences.
What were you feeling
in that moment?
That I loved you.
And that I would have
done or given anything
to kiss you
one more time.
So you did.
You know, you gave it all up
for one kiss.
Yeah.
Was it worth it?
What about you?
Was it worth it for you?
Yeah.
(sighs)
'Cause I know in my heart
we'll have another shot
at Nationals.
You have to know that I...
I'm leaving, Finn.
I'm going to New York,
and I'm never coming back.
Graduation's a year away.
You got any
plans till then?
Okay. Let's go.
Where are we going?
Final Glee Club meeting
of the year.
No other show choir
who finished in 12th place
has ever felt so honored.
(school bell ringing)
(indistinct chatter)
Hi.
Hiya. Come on.
You guys want to see
what 12th place looks like?
== sync, corrected by elderman ==