♪ (peaceful)
♪
Seems like only yesterday
I was saving this place
from being totally destroyed.
Hey, you guys remember that?
You only mentioned it about
15 times on the train here.
Yes, and we never hear a peep
out of you about your exploits.
Heh heh. Point taken.
I'm glad you all wanted to come,
but I don't think it's
going to be that exciting.
I pretty much just
have to smile and wave
as the dignitaries arrive.
Yes, but you get to smile
and wave like a princess.
How exactly is that different
than smiling and waving
like, not a princess?
It isn't.
What's wrong, Twilight?
Why the long face?
I've just been feeling a little
unsure about things lately.
It doesn't seem that my
new role as a princess
equates to all that much.
That's just silly.
You've got a real important
role in Equestria.
Princess Celestia wouldn't have
asked you to come today
if she didn't think so.
I guess you're right.
Of course we are.
Now hurry along.
You don't want to risk
having that important role
diminished because you're tardy
for your regal meet and greet.
♪ (fanfare)
The Duke and Duchess
of Mare-tonia.
♪ (processional)
♪
Spike: That was it?
Princess Celestia had
you come all the way
to the Crystal Empire
just to do that?
I mean, whoa, really
regal and important!
(nervous laugh)
(smack)
Subtitles by YayPonies
http://yayponies.eu
HoH version
(echoing hoof sounds)
(door opens)
Your Highness.
Thank you for understanding our
desire to keep the number
of those privy to these
confidential discussions
to a minimum.
Of course.
(door closes)
Is there anything else I can
do to assist with their visit?
I'm sorry, Twilight, but
their visit is already over.
Oh.
Something wrong?
I guess I just don't really
understand why I'm here.
Couldn't one of the Royal Guard
have unfurled the banner?
Having all four of us in
the Empire to greet them
lets the dignitaries
know that their visit
is considered an important one.
Plus, it gives me
an opportunity
to see my favorite
sister-in-law.
And I'm happy to see you.
All of you.
But...
But, I...
Well, it's just that Princess
Luna raises the moon.
Princess Celestia
raises the sun.
You protect the Crystal Empire.
And all I seem to do is...
smile and wave.
♪
♪ It isn't that I'm ungrateful
♪ For all the things
♪ that I've earned
♪ For all the journeys
I have taken ♪
♪ All the lessons that
I have learned ♪
♪ But I wonder where
I'm going now ♪
♪ What my role is meant to be
♪ I don't know how to travel
♪ To a future that I can't see
♪
♪ I have my wings
♪ I wear this crown
♪ I'm a Princess this is true
♪
♪ But it's still
unclear to me ♪
♪ Just what I am meant to do
♪
♪ I want to have a purpose
♪ Want to do all that I can
♪ I want to make
a contribution ♪
♪ I want to feel part
of the plan ♪
♪
♪ Your destiny's uncertain
♪ And that's sometimes
hard to take ♪
♪ But it will become
much clearer ♪
♪ With every new
choice you make ♪
♪ Patience is never easy
♪ I understand
wanting more ♪
♪ I know how hard
it is to wait ♪
♪ To spread your
wings and soar ♪
♪ But you stand
here for a reason ♪
♪ You are gifted
and you are strong ♪
♪ That crown is upon your head
♪ Because you belong
♪ Know that your time
♪ is coming soon
♪ As the sun rises
♪ So does the moon
♪ As love finds a place
♪ in every heart
♪ You are a princess
♪ You'll play your part
♪ We understand
you wanting more ♪
♪ A chance to shine
♪ A chance to soar
♪ Soon will come the
day it turns around ♪
♪ Know that your time
is coming soon ♪
♪ As the sun rises
♪ So does the moon
♪ As love finds a place
♪ in every heart
♪ You are a princess
♪ You'll play your part
Your time will come.
♪
♪ (scary)
(clatter)
(heavy breathing)
Very sorry.
You came out of nowhere.
Is he friend or is he
foe, the pony wonders.
I can assure you.
I am no "friend".
I am Lord Tirek.
And I will take what should
have been mine long ago.
(whoosh)
(thud)
(evil laugh)
(frightened gasps)
Sister, are you all right?
I've just had the
most terrible dream.
Why do you think I'm here?
You know as well as I that this
was not a dream, but a vision.
Then we haven't much time.
The stronger he becomes, the
more we are all in danger.
♪
Celestia: Tirek and his
brother Scorpan came here
from a distant land, intent on
stealing Equestrian magic.
But Scorpan soon came to
appreciate the ways
of Equestria, even befriending
a young unicorn wizard.
Luna: Scorpan urged his brother
to abandon their plans.
When Tirek refused,
Scorpan alerted us
to Tirek's intentions.
Celestia: Scorpan
returned to his own land,
and Tirek was sent to
Tartarus for his crimes.
But it appears he has
found a way to escape.
We believe it happened
when Cerberus
left his post at
the gates.
But that was a long time ago.
Why is he just now
starting to steal magic?
His time in Tartarus
left him very weak.
He has just now gained enough
strength to use his dark powers.
But with each passing moment,
he grows stronger still.
And I know just the
Princess who could stop him.
Yes! I'll find him and--
No, Twilight,
I'm afraid I must call on
another to stop Tirek.
Discord.
(gasp)
As in Discord, Discord?
Yes.
I don't think it's
that big of a surprise.
He can be very helpful.
He can sense when there's a
magical imbalance.
The next time
Tirek steals magic,
Discord will be able
to track him down.
So what are you supposed
to do in the meantime?
(sigh) Nothing.
Unless of course one of you
needs me to smile and wave.
Where are you going?
To the Castle of
the Two Sisters.
I'm not really
needed anywhere else.
Might as well catch up
on some of my reading.
You want some company?
Applejack: It has been a while
since we've visited the castle.
Might be fun.
Maybe I could use a
little company right now.
Rainbow Dash: (sigh) I
still can't believe
we had to give
back the Elements.
It had to be done or the Tree of
Harmony wouldn't have survived.
But Twilight was right.
Even without the Elements, our
friendship is as strong as ever.
I just hope another
"friend" of ours
never makes us sorry we
had to give them up.
Discord: Oh ho!
You're talking
about me, I presume?
How'd you guess?
My ears were burning.
(hiss)
What are you even
doing here, Discord?
Oh! Just a bit of light
reading before I head off
on my extremely
important mission.
I suppose you all know
that I've been tapped
to capture a
certain escapee.
Big deal.
You're right, Spike,
it is a "big deal".
(pop)
Seems I possess a magic that
gives me quite an important role
in Equestria.
Maybe they should make
me an Alicorn Princess.
(cheering crowd)
(kisses)
In your dreams.
Oh, I never dream
of such things.
Ask Princess Luna.
Don't you have a creepy
magic-stealing villain
to track down?
Yes, yes, yes, of course.
It's just that I couldn't help
but notice that Twilight
hasn't yet opened this
little chest of hers.
It got me thinking.
What if what's locked inside is
something that could help her
prove her royal worth?
I only bring it up because she
said that she'd been feeling
like her role as a princess
doesn't equate to much.
Wait a minute!
How do you know how
she was feeling?
Oh, my.
Is eavesdropping not the way
you're supposed to find out
what your best pals are up to?
Woe is me.
Will I ever learn the intricate
nuances of being a good friend?
Ahem!
Well, in any case, I suppose
now is as good a time as any
for me to make my exit.
And good riddance!
Oopsey doopsey,
I almost left with the little
journal you've all been keeping.
What a fascinating read.
Haven't you girls
just learned so much?
I've bookmarked a few of the
more interesting passages.
You really should take a look.
We're still on for tea later
aren't we, Fluttershy?
I wouldn't miss it.
I'll bring the
cucumber sandwiches.
(slam)
Sometimes I think the "reformed"
Discord is more obnoxious
than the "before he
was reformed" Discord.
Indeed.
But he could be
right, couldn't he?
What if there is something
important in that chest?
There's only one
way to find out.
Anything?
(negative murmurs)
There must be something
in this library
that can help me figure
out how to open it.
The answer is in
one of these books.
I just know it.
♪ (scary)
(thud)
♪
Tirek, I presume.
Discord.
You're free?
As a bird.
I commend you on
your escape.
I'm afraid the
feeling isn't mutual.
I should have known you would
want to have Equestria
all to yourself.
Oh, I'm not doing
this for me.
I'm doing it for my friends.
Just between the two of us,
it's mostly for Fluttershy.
Fluttershy?
You're not saying
you're friends with...
Ponies!
Surprise!
I am surprised that someone with
your intellect does not see
this "friendship" is but a
new form of imprisonment.
Clearly you've had to
abandon your true nature
to stay in their good graces.
♪
I have done nothing of the sort.
Please. I've seen this before.
But he was always weak-minded.
You are Discord.
You are legend.
You cannot fall into the same
trap that claimed my brother.
Help me to grow strong and be
rewarded with something
far greater than
friendship...freedom.
Once I have stripped these
ponies of their magic,
nothing would give
me greater pleasure
than to see their world
turned upside down.
Who better to do so than the
master of chaos himself?
Join me, Discord, and
reclaim your greatness.
Unless, of course,
"pony errand boy"
is the role you've always
wanted to play in this world.
♪
I think I've found something!
I've been reading our journal
and there's something
interesting about the sections
that Discord bookmarked.
Applejack, do you remember
when you had to tell everypony
that the tonic Granny bought
from the Flim-Flam brothers
didn't really work?
How could I forget?
It was one of the hardest
things I ever had to do.
(gulping)
I hate to disappoint everypony,
but there's no way Granny
could have made that dive
because this tonic is a fake.
(gasp)
But in that moment, I
knew had to be honest.
I just knew it.
But what that's got to do
with opening the chest?
I've found that each of you
has had to face a situation
where living up to the
Element of Harmony
you represent wasn't easy.
Fluttershy, it was when you
realized that the way to show
kindness to the Breezies was by
forcing them to leave your home.
The looks on their
poor little faces.
But I knew that as
difficult as it was,
pushing them away was the
kindest thing I could do.
Rarity, even after Suri took
advantage of your generosity
at Fashion Week
in Manehattan,
you didn't let it cause you to
abandon your generous spirit.
I simply couldn't have
lived with myself
if I didn't do something
special for the friends
who have always been
so generous to me.
Rainbow Dash, you had the chance
to fly with the Wonderbolts
at the Equestria Games
but instead you chose to
compete with your friends.
Sure. But being loyal to my
friends was way ...
My turn! My turn!
Pinkie Pie, you realized that
seeing your friend laugh
was more important than proving
you were a better party planner
than Cheese Sandwich.
Best party I've ever had.
It's clear we've all had our
moments to shine, Twilight,
but I'm with Applejack.
What does any of
this have to do
with the opening of the chest?
All of you had tough
choices to make,
but when you made the right
one and embraced your Element,
it helped somepony else
make the right choice too.
Each of you received
something from the pony
whose life you helped change.
I know it sounds crazy, but
maybe there's something special
about those objects that could
lead us to the location
of the keys.
The chest is connected
to the Tree of Harmony.
The Tree is connected
to the Elements,
and the Elements are
connected to all of us.
There must be a connection!
I hate to admit it,
but maybe Discord
was trying to be a
good friend after all.
I don't see anything on them
that would give us a clue
as to where the keys might be.
They're just ordinary,
everyday objects.
Come on, Boneless!
Give us that key!
I don't think that's
going to work.
(whoosh)
(gasp)
♪
(whoosh)
There's still one key missing.
The key that represents
the Element of Magic.
My Element.
Oh, but I'm sure that if
we've gotten our keys,
you have too, Twilight.
Think, Twilight! When have you
completed a difficult magical
task and in doing so encouraged
another pony to do the same?
I haven't.
If I had, I would have written
about it in the Journal.
Don't worry, Twilight, I'm sure
you'll get your key eventually.
(retching)
What's it say?
That I'm needed in
Canterlot at once.
♪
I came as quickly as I could.
Is something wrong?
Is it Tirek?
I am afraid I put too
much trust in Discord
and the effect that friendship
would have upon him.
Discord has betrayed
the ponies of Equestria
and joined forces with Tirek.
(frightened gasps)
(whoosh)
How could he do this?
I thought our friendship
meant something to him.
I thought he had changed.
Tirek has stolen enough magic
that he now has the strength
to steal flight as well.
Without Pegasi to
control the weather,
there will be no
rain in Equestria.
There is word he has gone
after earth ponies as well.
Without their strength,
they will not be able
to tend the land.
Ponies will no longer be
in control of their world.
That power will
belong solely to Tirek.
There is no doubt that Tirek
is after alicorn magic.
With Discord by his side,
we will not be able to
stop him from taking it.
Once it is in his possession,
his power will know no bounds
and all hope will be lost.
But there is one solution.
It is only by making
this sacrifice
that Equestria and the lands
beyond it might be saved.
We must rid ourselves
of our magic
before Tirek has the chance
to steal it from us.
(gasp)