Oh, Opalescence. Can you just picture it?
Moi, stepping up in astounding new gown
at the Grand Galloping Gala in Canterlot!
Why, yes! I did make it myself.
Thank you so much for asking.
Oh, Opal, of course you can help me. Thank you.
What's that? You wanna help me more!
Oh, aren't you the sweetest thing?
Careful now. Don't move.
This shouldn't take long at all.
Howdy, Rarity?
Shh... Can't you see Rarity
is trying to concentrate?
What do you think she's makin'?
Looks like a dress.
Well, that makes sense.
Since this is a dressmaker's shop and all.
Is there something I can help you with?
Oh, so very sorry to trouble you,
Rarity, but I need a quick favor.
Could you please fix the button for me?
It's my dress for the Grand Galloping Gala.
Oh, no, no, no! You can't wear this... old thing.
You need a glamorous new outfit for the Gala.
And I'll make it for you. No problem at all.
It will be my pleasure!
Oh, that's really sweet of you to offer,
Rarity, but I can't let you do that.
It would be so much work. This dress is fine.
Twilight Sparkle.
I insist on making you a new dress.
-But...
-No no, not a word!
I won't take no for an answer.
Well, in that case... Thank you
for your generosity, Rarity.
Knowing your handiwork, I'm sure
it will be absolutely beautiful.
Let me guess, Applejack.
You don't want a new gown either.
Gown? Shoot. I was just gonna
wear my old work duds.
You can't possibly be serious, Applejack!
You absolutely must wear formal attire.
Nah.
What if I just spruce up your...
duds for you a little bit?
Okay, sure. Why not?
Since you're up for it and all.
Just don't make them too... froufrou-y.
Deal!
Look out below!
Sorry. New trick. Didn't quite work.
Idea!
I'll make you an outfit for
the Gala too, Rainbow Dash.
Outfit for the what now?
I'll make one for you and you and all of you.
Oh! And of course Pinkie and Fluttershy too.
Oh, and when I'm done, we can
hold our very own fashion show!
What a great idea!
If you're sure you can handle it.
Oh, it'll be a little bit of work, but it
will be a wonderful boost for my business.
Plus, fun!
Oh, I love fun things!
Then it's settled.
We'll have a fashion show starring us.
So all you have to do is make a
different, stunning, original...
...amazing outfit for one, two, three, four,
five... plus yourself, six ponies?
And lickety split?
Oh, Applejack.
You make it sound as if it's going to be hard.
Thread by thread, stitching it together
Twilight's dress
Cutting out the pattern snip by snip
Making sure the fabric folds nicely
It's the perfect color and so hip
Always gotta keep in mind my pacing
Making sure the cloth's correctly facing
I'm stitching Twilight's dress
Yard by yard, fussing on the details
Jewel neckline
Don't you know a stitch in time saves nine?
Make her something perfect to inspire
Even though she hates formal attire
Gotta mind those intimate details
Even though she's more concerned with sales
It's Applejack's new dress
Dressmaking's easy
For Pinkie Pie something pink
Fluttershy something breezy
Blend color and form...
Do you think it looks cheesy?
Something brash, perhaps quite fetching
Hook and eye
Couldn't you just simply die?
Making sure it fits forelock and crest
Don't forget some magic in the dress
Even though it rides high on the flank
Rainbow won't look like a tank
I'm stitching Rainbow's dress
Piece by piece, snip by snip
Croup, dock, haunch, shoulders, hip
Thread by thread, primmed and pressed
Yard by yard, never stressed
And that's the Art of the Dress!
That's it. Keep them closed.
Don't look.
Okay, you can look now!
These are your new outfits.
What do you think of your old duds now,
Applejack? Pretty swanky, are they not?
And Twilight! I made this dress for you...
...and I designed each outfit theme to perfectly
reflect each pony's unique personality.
Oh, it took me forever to get the colors right
on this one, Rainbow Dash, but I did it.
Oh, and it turned out
BEAUTIFUL, don't you think?
Ooo, and I know you are going to love
yours, Fluttershy. It just sings spring!
And Pinkie Pie, look! Pink! Your favorite!
Aren't they all amazing?
Wow...
-They're...
-Yeah, they're...
They sure are...
-...sumth'n.
-Yes! Something.
I love something! Something is my favorite!
It's... nice.
But what's the matter? Don't you like them?
They're very nice...
And we're plum grateful cause
you worked so hard on them.
Mine's just not as cool as I was imagining.
She asked.
I guess what we're all saying is that
they're just not what we had in mind.
That's okay. Not a problem.
There's plenty more where that came from.
They were only a first pass.
You're my friends and I want
you to be 110% satisfied.
Not to worry, I'll redo them.
Oh, Rarity. You don't have to do that.
They're fine.
I want them to be better that just fine.
I want you to think they're absolutely perfect.
Are you sure?
I mean, we wouldn't wanna impose.
Oh, it's no ???. Really, I insist.
Well, in that case... Thank you again, Rarity.
What have I gotten myself into?
Hello?
You wanted to see me, Rarity?
Fluttershy! Your new-new gown's ready.
I completely revised it and
I know you're going to love it.
What do you think?
I...
...love it.
Oh, you're just saying that.
No, no. I do.
It's... nice.
"Nice"?
Nice.
If you don't like it, you should just tell me.
Oh, but I do like it.
Like it or love it?
Um... both?
Which is it?
Please stop asking me this, I...
Well, just tell me what you really think.
No, that's okay...
Tell me.
No... it's fine...
Tell me!
I... like it...
Tell me, tell me, tellmetellmetellme!
All right! Since you really wanna know...
The arm's sized tight, the middy collar
doesn't go with the shawl lapel...
...the hems are clearly machine-stitched,
the pleats are uneven, the fabric looks like toile...
...you used a backstitch here when it clearly called for a
topstitch or maybe a traditional blanket stitch...
...and the overdesign is reminiscent of
prêt-à-porter and not true French haute couture.
But, uh... you know...
um, whatever you want to do is fine.
Now, the stars on my belt need
to be technically accurate.
Orion has three stars on his belt, not four.
Stitch by stitch, stitching it together
Deadline looms
Don't know the client's always right?
Even if my fabric choice was perfect
Got to get them all done by tonight
Pinkie Pie, the color's too obtrusive
Wait until you see it in the light
I'm sewing them together!
Don't you think my gown would be
more "me" with some lollipops?
-Well, I think...
-Balloons?
-Well...
-DO EET!
Hour by hour, one more change
I'm sewing them together, take great pains
Fluttershy, you're putting me in a bind
Rainbow Dash, what is on your mind?
Oh my gosh, there's simply not much time
Don't forget, Applejack's duds must shine
Dressmaking's easy
Every customer's call
Brings a whole new revision
Have to pick up the pace
Still hold to my vision
That constellation is Canis Major, not Minor.
French haute couture, please.
What if it rains? Galoshes!
More balloons! Oh no, that's too many balloons.
More candy! Oh, less candy.
Oh wait, I know. Streamers!
-Streamers?
-Whose dress is this?
Streamers it is.
What?
Aren't you going to tell me
to change something too?
No, I just want my dress to be cool.
Do you not like the color?
The color's fine, just make it look cooler.
Do you not like the shape?
The shape's fine, just make
the whole thing... you know, cooler.
It needs to be about 20% cooler.
All we ever want is indecision
All we really like is what we know
Gotta balance style with adherence
Making sure we make a good appearance
Even if you simply have to fudge it
Make sure that it stays within our budget
Got to overcome intimidation
Remember, it's all in the presentation!
Piece by piece, snip by snip
Croup, dock, haunch, shoulders, hip
Bolt by bolt, primmed and pressed
Yard by yard, always stressed
And that's the Art of the Dress!
Oh, Opal. These are the ugliest
dresses I've ever made.
Okay. I did exactly what each of you asked for.
Now don't hold back.
Let me know what you really think.
-Oh my!
-It's... perfect!
-It's cool!
Wow. They're the best duds I ever did see.
It's exactly what I asked for!
Thank you, Rarity.
Are you as happy with the as we're?
Well, I'm... happy that all of you are happy.
I'm just relieved to finally be done.
You are never gonna believe this!
You've heard of Hoity-Toity?
The bigwig fashion hotshot in Canterlot?
Uh-huh. He heard about your fashion show.
Well, maybe I happened to mention it to him...
He's coming here all the way from
Canterlot to see your work, Rarity!
Whoa, Nelly!
You could sell a ton o' dresses to this guy.
You business will be boomin'!
Hoity-Toity?
He's coming here?
To see THESE dresses?
Yep! Get ready for all
of your dreams to come true.
There he is!
Okay. Relax, Rarity.
Your friends like their outfits and so will he.
What's wrong with the lights?!
Oh, yes. That means the show's starting. Good.
Since the beginning of time the elite
of Equestria have longed for pony fashions...
...that that truly expressed the
essence of their very souls.
Patiently waiting decades... no, centuries!
...for the perfect pony gown.
Today at long last, Equestria, your wait is over!
Let's hear it for the breathtaking
designs of Ponyville's own...
Rarity!
Why's everypony lookin' at us like that?
Oh dear.
You think we overdid it?
Nah.
Okay, maybe a little.
Those amateurish designs look like a piled-on
mishmash of everything but a kitchen sink!
It's a travesty, it's what it is.
Those outfits are the ugliest things
I've ever seen, oh for shame.
Who is responsible for subjecting
our eyes to these horrors?
Not to mention wasting my valuable time.
Hide me.
Come on out and take a bow, Rarity.
You worked really hard for this.
Yes! Alright, woohoo! Go, Rarity!
Rarity? You okay in there?
You haven't come out for days.
I'm never coming out! I can't
show my face in Ponyville ever again!
I used to be somepony. I used to be respected.
I made dresses. Beautiful, beautiful dresses!
But now everypony is laughing at me.
I'm nothing but a laughingstock!
You're not a laughingstock, Rarity...
-She kind of is.
-Shhh!
Come on out and talk to us.
Leave me alone!
I vant to be alone! I want to wallow in...
...whatever it is that ponies
are supposed to wallow in!
Do ponies wallow in pity?
Oh, listen to me, I don't even know
what I'm supposed to wallow in!
I'M SO PATHETIC!
Now what do we do?
Panic?
That's your answer for everything!
Well, we can't just leave Rarity like this.
She'll become a crazy cat lady!
She only has one cat.
Give her time.
Exile...
I guess technically I'd have to
move away to live in exile.
Where would I go? And what would I pack?
Oh, it's going to take me forever
to do all of that packing.
What are you supposed to pack
when you go to exile?
Are you supposed to pack warm?
Opal?
Opal, how did you get up there?
Hang on, you poor dear! Mama's coming!
Rainbow Dash?!
How dare you strand my poor Opal on the tree.
Well, how else were we gonna get
you out here to show you...
...this!
What is it? It's not... You...
We all finished your dress for you.
Thanks to Fluttershy's
freaky knowledge of sewing.
Do you like it?
Like it?
Like it?!
Uh-uh. She doesn't like it.
No, I don't like it.
I LOVE IT!
You ponies did an amazing job.
It's exactly the way I imagined it.
We just followed your brilliant design.
Like we should have let you do for our outfits.
Those first dressed you designed were perfect.
We're so super sorry.
You worked really hard to make our
dresses exactly the way we wanted them.
We all saw how well that turned out.
Oh, I forgive you.
Well, that's mighty big of you.
But my whole career is still ruined!
Oh, right. That.
Maybe not.
All right, I haven't got all day.
Take two.
Hello...
Oh, this can't be the same designer.
Simply magnificent!
And suddenly I have a fresh craving
for some Dutch apple pie...
Candied apples on a stick?
Apple turnovers? Apple cobbler?
Brilliant!
Oh, spectacular!
Now this is a fashion show.
All of these dresses are absolutely amazing.
Who is responsible?
Step forward, show yourself!
Bravo! Bravo!
Magnifico! Oh boy!
Oh, thank you. Thank you!
Oh, thank you so much!
"Dear Princess Celestia."
"This week my very talented
friend Rarity learned..."
"...that if you try to please everypony,
you often times end up pleasing nopony."
"Especially yourself."
"And I learned this:"
"When somepony offers to do you a favor..."
"...like making you a beautiful dress..."
"...you shouldn't be overly critical
of something generously given to you."
"In other words, you shouldn't
look a gift horse in the mouth."
Rarity, my congratulations.
You are the most impressive fashion maven.
Would you do me the great honor
of allowing me to feature your couture...
...in my best of the best boutique in Canterlot?
Now, I'll need you to make a dozen
of each dress for me by next Tuesday.
Synced by Nathan2000
http://mlp.wikia.com/wiki/User:Nathan2000