Oh. Hi, Pinkie Pie.
This is your singing telegram
I hope it finds you well
You're invited to a party
Cause we think you're really swell
Gummy's turning one year old
So help us celebrate
The cake will be delicious
The festivities first-rate
There will be games and dancing
Bob for apples, cut a rug
And when the party's over
We'll gather round for a group hug
No need to bring a gift
Being there will be enough
Birthdays mean having fun with friends
Not getting lots of stuff
It won't be the same without you
So we hope that you say yes
So please, oh please, R.S.V.P.
And come and be our guest
Next time I think I'll just
pass out written invitations.
Nice one. Now let me show you
how it's really done.
Hey, girls!
Hey, Pinkie Pie.
Howdy!
Just wanted to tell you how happy I am
that you could make it to Gummy's party.
Are you kiddin'? I wouldn't have
missed it for the world.
Me neither.
When Pinkie Pie throws a party, I am there!
TADA!
Ah, it's just a boring old apple.
Don't worry. There're plenty of other surprises in there.
What kind of surprises?
I can't tell you that, silly.
Then it wouldn't be a surprise!
This punch is simply divine.
Is this the same recipe you used
for your "Spring has Sprung" party?
No, something new.
It's Gummy's favorite!
Ooh! This is my jam!
Having fun?
A blast!
You always throw the best parties, Pinkie Pie.
They're always the best parties,
cause my best friends are always there!
Come on, everypony!
Gummy wants to dance!
Go Gummy! It's ya birthday!
Hooie! I am beat.
Haven't danced that much since...
Well... since you last party.
Thanks again for the invite!
See you later, birthday alligator!
Bravo for hosting yet another delightful soirée.
It's been lovely.
You sure you don't wanna stay?
There's still some cake left.
Uh... I think I'm gonna pass.
Great party, though.
We should do this again soon.
We should do this again soon!
Oh. Hi, Pinkie...
It's soon!
Pardon me?
You said we should have
another party soon and... it's soon!
Here is your invitation!
"You're invited to Gummy's after-birthday party."
"This afternoon at 3 o'clock."
All our bestest friends are invited...
...and here's gonna be dancing and games
and cake and ice cream and punch...
This afternoon?
As in "this afternoon" this afternoon?
Yes, indeedy!
Oh, gosh.
I wish I could make it but I've
gotten a bit behind in my studies.
I've really gotta hit the books.
I understand. Your studies come first.
But don't worry! We'll be sure
to save you some cake.
Please do!
Oh! And Twilight, you shouldn't hit the books.
You should really just read them.
I'll keep that in mind.
Oh hi, Pinkie Pie.
What brings you here round these parts?
Who's ready to shake their hoof-thang?
It's an invitation at Gummy's
after-birthday party this afternoon!
There's gonna be dancing and games
and cake and ice cream and punch...
This afternoon?
As in "this afternoon" this afternoon?
That's funny. That's just what Twilight said.
And the answer is "Yes, it's this afternoon".
Oh... Well, I... I, uh...
I don't think I can make it, cause, uh...
I have to, uh...
Uh, you know... I, uh...
Pick apples!
Yep, apples, cause that's what we do.
With, uh... apples. We, uh...
Pick 'em.
Okie dokie lokie!
A party is still a party,
even if there're only three guests.
Anything else I can do for you, most beautiful one?
Mmm... Perhaps you could take a bath.
How do I put this delicately...
You smell like a rotten apple core...
...that's been wrapped in moldy hay
and dipped in dragon perspiration.
Ooh, love the new hat.
Very modern. What's the occasion?
Gummy's after-birthday party is this afternoon.
I'm delivering the invitations.
The party is this afternoon?
As in "this afternoon" this afternoon?
It's so strange. Everypony keep saying that?
Oh, do they?
I know it's short notice, but we had
such a great time at this birthday party...
...I thought we could have even
more fun at this after-birthday party.
And I'm sure that we would,
but I'm going to have to decline.
I have to... wash my hair.
Don't be silly. Your hair doesn't look dirty.
-It doesn't?
-Nope.
See? Dirty.
I have to go.
Huh. No Twilight, no Applejack, no Rarity.
Oh well. A party is still a party,
even with only two guests.
This afternoon?
-As in...
-Yes!
As in "this afternoon" this afternoon.
Oh man, we'd love to, but...
...we're... house-sitting this afternoon.
Huh... Both of you?
It's a... a big house.
Uh, look at the time!
We'd really better get going.
Wait!
Maybe I could bring you some
after-birthday cake and ice cream?
Who you house-sitting for?
Harry.
Harry?
Yeah, I don't think you known him.
That's strange. I know just about
everypony around here.
He's... a bear.
A bear?
Yep! He's a bear, all right.
And he'll be pretty upset if we don't
get over to his house soon, heh.
Wait!
There's a bear around here who lives in a house?
It's... really more of a cave.
But he sticks the place up
so much it feels like a house.
And, uh... he wants us to look after
his house, uh, cave while he's...
At the beach!
He's vacationing at the beach?
Yep! He loves to...
-Collect seashells.
-Play volleyball.
-Collect volleyball.
-Play seashells.
Gotta go!
Something strange is definitely
going on around here, Gummy.
Sure Rainbow Dash and Fluttershy had to
house-sit for that vacationing bear...
...but what are the chances all my other friends
would have plans this afternoon too?
Rarity has to wash her hair...
Applejack has to pick apples...
Twilight is behind on her studies
and has to hit the books...
The more I think about it, the more
those are starting to sound like...
Excuses!
That didn't look like studying.
Or hitting.
Oh! You must be here for...
Shh!
-Is Pinkie Pie around?
-Oh, I don't think so.
Good.I don't want her
to know anything about this.
Yes, of course. I'll be right back.
But... we're friends.
What wouldn't Twilight want me
to know anything about?
She's coming back.
There you go.
Thanks. And remember, not a word to Pinkie Pie.
Hey! What's with the tin can?
Time to get to the bottom of things.
I think our cover's been blown.
I need a new disguise.
She didn't see you at the sweet shop, did she?
I don't think so.
Oh, good. I'd hate for her to ruin everything.
Me too.
-Have you seen her?
-Not since this morning.
Me neither. Can you believe she was planning on
throwing an after-birthday party *today*?
I'm just glad I was able to come up
with an excuse for why I couldn't be there.
Me too. This obviously
going to be so much better.
As long as we keep her from
finding out about it, it will.
See you later!
I thought everypony loved my parties.
Hi, Pinkie Pie!
Uh-oh.
Rainbow Dash! Wait!
WHERE'RE YOU GOING?!
WHAT'S THE REAL REASON YOU DON'T
WANNA COME TO GUMMY'S PARTY?!
WHAT'S IN THOSE BAGS?!
Applejack! We have a problem!
I know you're in there!
Oh, uh... howdy partner!
Mind if I... take a look inside the barn?
No... I mean, yes... I mean,
you can't come in here.
Rainbow Dash just went in there.
Oh, well, she was just
bringin' in some... supplies.
Yep, supplies for the... renovation.
Fixin' up the whole thing, top to bottom.
Uh... lotsa construction going on
in there right now!
You heard her. Construction!
Yup! Construction. That's my story
and I'm stickin' to it, heh.
Okie dokie lokie.
Secrets and lies. It's all secrets
and lies with those ponies.
They're up to something, Gummy.
Something they don't want me to know about.
Well, I'm gonna know about it.
I'm gonna know about it big time!
And I know just who's gonna
tell me all about it.
TELL ME ALL ABOUT IT BIG TIME!
Wow... Nice spread!
It's all yours, Spike.
All you have to do is talk.
That's it? Oh, you got it.
Okay... Uh, beautiful weather we're having, eh?
I love sunny spring day, don't you?
The birds chirping, the flowers blooming...
No, no, no.
Talk about our friends.
Oh. Okay.
Let's see. There's Twilight Sparkle,
she's a unicorn.
Good with magic, real brainiac.
And then we got Rarity. Total knockout!
Twilight seems to think I don't have a chance
with her, but... eh, what does she know?
Let's see, there's... there's Fluttershy,
a pegasus afraid of height.
Huh, what's up with that?
No! You're not understanding me!
I want you to confess!
Confess?
CONFESS!
I'm the one who spilled juice all over Twilight's
copy of Magical Mysteries and Practical Potions!
And?
And I'm the one who used up
all the hot water in Ponyville yesterday...
...when I took a seven-hour bubble bath.
And?!
And sometimes, when no one's around...
...I do this.
Looking good, Spike. Looking real good.
No... No! No! NO!!!
Wh... What do you wanna hear?
Tell me what you want me to say and I'll say it!
Tell me that my friends are
lying to me and avoiding me...
...because they don't like my parties and
THEY DON'T WANNA BE MY FRIENDS ANYMORE!!!
Your friends are all lying to you and avoiding you...
...cause they don't like your parties and
they don't wanna be your friends anymore!
AHA! I KNEW IT!
Oh no.
My friends don't like my parties and
they don't wanna be my friends anymore.
Uh... So...
Thank you all so much for coming!
It means so much to Gummy.
CouLd i HavE sOme MoRe PunCh?
Well, of course you can
have more punch, Mr. Turnip.
tHis iS onE grEat PartY!
You rEally OuTdone yOurselF!
Why, thank you, Rocky.
I aM haVing A deLigHtful TiMe as WelL.
I'm so glad, Sir Lintsalot.
MiNd if i troUble You FoR anOzer sLiCe oF CAKE?
Anything for you, Madame La Flour.
I'm jUst Glad NonE of tHem pOnieS sHowed Up.
Oh. They're not so bad.
nOt so BaD?!
PleAsE. tHey'Re a buNcHa lOseRs!
Oh, come one now.
"Losers" might be a little strong,
don't you think?
AfTer The wAy tHeY tReAteD yOu?
I sAy "LosErS" Isn'T stRoNg eNOugH.
It was pretty rude...
PreTtY rUde? iT wAs dOWnrIgt DesPicabLe!
It was, wasn't it?
iF i WerE yOu, I wOulDn'T
sPeaK tO tHem EveR agAiN.
You know what? I'm not gonna
speak to them ever again.
And I'm not gonna invite them
to another party as long as I live.
The don't DESERVE to be invited to my party!
Not after the way they've been acting.
-deSPicAblE!
-bUncHa lOsErs!
yES, ZaT's RIGht.
wEll dOnE!
-YEs!
-yOu ShOw 'eM!
Who could that be?
Hey there, Pinkie Pie.
Sorry I was in such a rush earlier.
Has some place to be and
couldn't slow down and say hello.
You know how it goes.
I know how it goes, all right.
Yeah... So, why don't you come
with me over to Sweet Apple Acres?
No thanks. I'm spending time with my real friends.
Isn't that right, Madame La Flour?
oUi! zat is CorrEcT, MadAMe.
Uh... Pinkie Pie?
Another slice of cake, Sir Lintsalot?
i'D LOve One.
Alrighty. Whaddya say we get on outta
Creepytown and head over to Applejack's...
She'S Not gOinG anyWHeRe.
I most certainly am not.
I'm having a wonderful time right here.
You should really just come with me.
you hEard tHe lADy!
sHE aIn'T goinG NowHerE, ChuMp!
Who you calling a chump, chump!
That's it. Party's over.
Come on, Pinkie Pie.
No!
Pinkie Pie, let's go!
I said no!
You, ugh... have to... come with... me!
No... I... don't!
Oh, you want to do this the hard way?
We'll do this the hard way!
We're... here...
Surprise!
I really thought she'd be more excited.
Excited?! EXCITED?!
Why would I be excited to attend
my own farewell party?!
Farewell party?
Yes! You don't like me anymore so you
decided to kick me out of the group...
...and throw a great, big party to celebrate.
A "Farewell of Pinkie Pie" party.
Why in the world would you think
we didn't like you anymore, sugar cube?
Why?
Why?!
WHY?!
Because you've been LYING
to me and avoiding me all day!
That's why!
Uh, yeah. Because we wanted
your party to be a surprise.
We've been planning this party
for such a long time...
...we had to make excuses for why
we couldn't attend Gummy's party...
...so that we could everything ready for yours.
If this is a farewell party...
...why does the cake I picked up
from Sugarcube Corner say...
..."Happy birthday, Pinkie Pie"?
Because it's my birthday!
Oh, how could I have forgotten my own birthday?
And you like me so much, you decided to
throw me a surprise party.
That's what we've been trying to tell you, darling.
You girls are the best friends ever!
How could I have ever doubted you?
It's okay, Pinkie Pie.
It could have happened to any of us.
I'm just glad I haven't been
replaced by a bucket of turnips.
Huh?
You don't wanna know.
Alright, girls! Enough of this gabbin'.
Let's party!
"Dear Princess Celestia."
"I am writing to you
from the most delightful party."
"I'm not only having
a great time with my friends..."
"...but also was given the opportunity
to learn a valuable lesson about friendship."
"Always expect the best from your friends
and never assume the worst."
"Rest assured that a good friend always
has your best interests at heart."
"You faithful student, Twilight Sparkle."
You girls wouldn't mind if we celebrated Gummy's
after-birthday party too, would you?
His party was cut short and
he's pretty upset about it.
Why not? Let's have a party for Gummy.
Synced by Nathan2000
http://mlp.wikia.com/wiki/User:Nathan2000