Previously on Smash.
How Marilyn, it's beautiful and tragic.
I think she make a great musical.
I've got a callback from Marilyn.
I got a callback.
Ivy Lynn, this is Karen Cartwright.
Classic... you put in ten years
in the chorus,
and Karen-something
shows up.
I have a pretty clear sense
of what I bring to the party.
She's trying to get me fired.
He is taking advantage of her.
Maybe Ivy's taking advantage of him.
She did get the part.
I could have done that.
I could have slept with him.
But I didn't.
You came into this marriage
with nothing.
Except love.
Jerry has no involvement.
You poisoned my investors, you jackass!
Got $7 million under there?
No, but I do have friends.
It was idealistic to think
that we could do this without a star.
The incomparable Rebecca Duvall.
♪ Fade in on a girl
Her agent, her manager...
Everyone said she could sing.
- You had dinner...
- Okay.
And then you slept with my wife.
No one applauded.
I can't even see you talking to him.
- It was nothing...
- Stop, Julia, stop.
- [Chokes]
- Oh, my God. Rebecca?
I'm not going back into the show.
Will you marry me?
The real question is,
who's going to play Marilyn?
Where's Karen Cartwright?
You're going on as Marilyn, tonight.
Why wasn't it me?
She just had something that you don't.
I'm not gonna tell anybody.
You are fired is what you are, Ellis.
I think I left something in your room.
What are you doing
with my engagement ring, Ivy?
I'm sorry.
We just need one minute.
No, we don't.
Actually, the more
you hurt, the better.
Knock it off, Derek.
Don't ever doubt you're a star.
[Vocalizing]
♪ I know I've kept you waiting ♪
♪ I know I made you mad ♪
♪ but this time
that we've spent creating ♪
♪ was the best time I ever had ♪
♪ now, I love to sit with memories ♪
♪ but they won't come
until we're gone ♪
♪ so give me a kiss, and cut, print ♪
♪ moving on
♪ tell me
a brand-new story ♪
♪ together we'll turn the page ♪
♪ the grass is always greener ♪
♪ on some new technicolor stage ♪
♪ and if a duckling never swims ♪
♪ she'll never become a swan
♪ yes, I'm diving in, so cut, print ♪
♪ moving on
♪ yes, there have been nights
I'll long to relive ♪
♪ but sometimes you gotta roam ♪
♪ you can't fight
when something's gotta give ♪
♪ but you'll always be
♪ my home away from home ♪
♪ now, I like to play a love scene ♪
♪ but don't let it last too long ♪
♪ play me
the eight-bar intro ♪
♪ of some new, lush, romantic song ♪
♪ I'm not afraid to take that leap ♪
♪ with you to depend upon ♪
♪ now tell me your name ♪
♪ cut, print, moving on ♪
♪ we told the same jokes,
we breathed the same air ♪
♪ we couldn't tell night from day ♪
♪ but just like the end
of a love affair ♪
♪ we all know the time comes ♪
♪ to break away
♪ it's time to break away ♪
♪ last year we all were strangers ♪
♪ this year we're like old friends ♪
♪ I know that this location ♪
♪ is not where our story ends ♪
♪ get up
♪ 'cause the rat race never ends ♪
♪ 'cause life is a marathon
♪ life is a marathon
♪ and I plan to run
so much more than a sprint ♪
♪ what's next?
♪ Well, I can't even give you a hint ♪
♪ but, boys, that's a wrap ♪
♪ so cut, print
♪ moving on
♪ and on
♪ ah, on
♪ moving on
♪ ah, ah, on
[elevator bell dings]
After you.
You can get the next one.
Okay, everyone,
now that we're finally here,
first things first, please...
For a job well done...
[Cheers and applause]
In Boston.
That was then.
This is now.
Eileen.
I trust you all
enjoyed yourselves up there.
We had a successful run.
I would say, overall,
the experience was instructive.
But before we apply its lessons,
there's a small question of where.
It is my goal to book us
a Broadway theater
by the end of this week.
In the meantime, if any
of you get any other offers,
go on vacation, or frankly even
think about getting a haircut,
let us know.
While I'd like to publicly state
that it is my intention to
pick up everyone's contract...
[Applause]
Depending on the changes
made by the creative team,
we may not be able to do that.
But we're not there yet.
We thank you.
And we hope to see you
on Broadway soon.
And no raises, so don't ask.
[Laughter]
Karen, can I have a word, please?
Sure. Yes.
"Some of you will cease to exist
after the creative team's changes"?
- I'm not worried.
- You should be.
She's part of the creative team now.
If I were you,
I'd keep an eye on my back,
make sure there's no target on it.
I'm planning a little soiree
for the press this weekend,
a sort of coming-out party
for the show.
I'd love it if you'd sing something,
perhaps the opening number.
Of course.
Yeah, that'd be great.
Anything for you.
Great.
Well, maybe you'd like to choose
a couple backup singers.
It can be whoever you want.
Well, Jessica and Beth, of course.
And one more.
- Joy.
- Joy. Great.
Linda?
Yes.
Would you grab Jessica,
Beth, and Joy for me?
Hey, girls...
I hope you're ready.
It all starts now.
[Chuckles]
[Sighs]
[Orchestra tuning up]
♪
SMASH
S02 Ep 01x02 - On Broadway
Sync and corrected by dr.jackson
for www.addic7ed.com
Moving on...
Michael Swift wants to be
let out of his contract.
He feels that he did us a favor
when we were in a bind
and we have ample time to recast.
I, uh, trust there are no objections?
Nope.
Okay, good.
Let's talk about the reviews.
Uh, remember, I haven't read them.
- You're not serious.
- She never does.
I just read Tom's face.
It tells me everything I need to know.
Oh, did Tom's face tell you
what they singled out, then?
Me, the cast...
Derek.
She's the one who hasn't read them.
I don't need some critic
getting in my head.
I sat in the audience for three weeks.
I know there are things
that need to be done.
I want this to be the best it can be.
And that's what we're going to do.
After my meeting tonight
with Jordan roth,
we're going to book the best theater
Broadway has to offer...
The St. James.
Oh, the St. James
would be so amazing.
Oklahoma! Opened there.
The king and I.
Both:
The producers.
- Big hits.
- Long runs.
- Good juju.
- Yeah, okay, great, um...
What if we don't get
a theater today, hmm?
I've got a lot of projects
waiting to hear
how busy I'm gonna be...
I want to know what to plan for.
Don't worry about it, Derek.
I'll get it.
Meanwhile, keep our leading lady happy.
Everyone's talking about her.
They want to know if she's
as good as they've heard.
Oh, she's better.
Yes, we all know
where you stand on the matter.
Oh, and it's not just me.
Or didn't you read the reviews either?
Oh, God, not listening.
Going outside.
"When Karen Cartwright implores you
"to let her be your star,
you'd have no problem answering
with a resounding 'yes, '
if it weren't..."
I'm aware.
It's not you I'm worried about.
I'm handling it.
Yeah, well, can we not do it
on Tom time, please?
Sometime this century would be nice.
Call me when you have a reason to.
[Door closes]
Bye, Derek.
Thank you, Ana, for letting me move in
and everything.
Well, thank my roommate
for doing that Disney cruise.
Where are you going tonight,
by the way?
Derek is taking me
to see Veronica Moore
and then meet her after.
Oh, you get to meet her?
I'm so jealous.
She's incredible.
You're gonna love the show too.
It's about this, like, sweet,
1950s aretha/etta James type,
but she has
this really overbearing mother.
- Well, don't spoil it.
- Here.
- How do I look?
- Like you care.
Maybe I do.
See ya later, sweet cheeks.
Bye.
So what'd your agent say?
When I told him that
he should expect a phone call
about my contract,
he said that the agency
had already received phone calls
for their other clients.
Maybe they're calling alphabetically.
They just haven't gotten to "l" yet.
Did you get a call, Sam Strickland?
Yeah.
What can I do about it?
Besides be on your best behavior...
Which I know you already are...
You got to find a way
to stay with the show.
Any suggestions?
Well, you're an amazing singer,
an even better actress.
Remind everybody why they fell in love
with you in the first place.
Once you do that,
you can get back on the road
to becoming the star
you were intended to be.
What is a star, anyway?
Do they even still exist?
[Mama makes three playing]
♪ A boy I go to school with
calls me up for a date ♪
♪ he said, "I'll come and get you" ♪
♪ "'bout a quarter
to 8:00" ♪
♪ we go off to a movie
where he steals a little kiss ♪
♪ and then we park around the corner ♪
♪ to explore a little bliss ♪
♪ I think his heart's
a-pounding ♪
♪ but it isn't my man
♪ it's my mama out the window ♪
♪ with a frying pan
♪ saying, "hey there, mister,
that's my little girl" ♪
♪ "keep your cultivating fingers
off my precious little pearl ♪
♪ I never get to keep no company ♪
♪ because one and one is two ♪
♪ but, baby
♪ mama makes three
♪
Now, ladies, listen up.
♪ I moved away and finally meet
the man of my dreams ♪
♪ he put the diamond on my finger ♪
♪ how it sparkles and gleams ♪
♪ we have a simple wedding
with the shoes and the rice ♪
♪ and then we head off
to our honeymoon ♪
♪ to really break the ice
♪ I whispered, "dim the lights" ♪
♪ and go to slip on something red ♪
♪ but when I turn around,
you know who's lying in bed ♪
♪ saying, "hands off, mister,
that's the light of my life ♪
♪ I ain't giving up my daughter
just because she's your wife" ♪
♪ we'll never add a branch
to our family tree ♪
♪ because one and one is two
but, baby ♪
♪ mama makes three, oh ♪
♪ mama makes three, yeah ♪
♪ yeah ♪ mama makes three
♪ mama makes three, yeah
♪ hey, mama, I love you still but
- ♪ oh
- ♪ hey, mama
♪ I've had my fill ♪ ooh
♪ hey, mama,
you're where it began but ♪
- ♪ whoo
- ♪ hey, mama
♪ I love my man, hey, mama,
please leave us alone ♪
♪ hey, mama, just use the phone ♪
♪ hey, mama, you had romance
♪ yeah, yeah
♪ so, mama, give a girl a chance ♪
♪ just give me a chance,
give me a chance ♪
♪ give a girl a chance
- Hey.
- How you doing?
I'm good.
Karen Cartwright.
- Ah.
- Veronica, you were incredible.
Ronnie.
Great to meet you.
Derek's told me all about you.
Y'all give me a second.
Let me get dressed.
And I'll be back.
Come in.
You ready for your last performances?
Not really.
It's sad to leave.
It's time to move on.
We're doing a revival of The Wiz
after I finish with you.
I know.
I can't wait.
Another good-girl role
for Broadway's sweetheart.
As long as you keep
winning them Tonys, darling.
Oh, if you don't mind me saying,
the speech you gave
when you won your first one,
about the things you gave up
when you started out
and how those sacrifices
weren't for nothing,
it was a huge inspiration to me.
I have a question, Ronnie.
What is the best piece of advice
you would give to someone
who's about to get
exactly where you are?
That's easy.
Protect the work.
The moment you lose focus,
the moment the work suffers.
Someone's always waiting
to take you down, honey.
But if the work's good,
they won't be able to.
That's good advice.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Get ready.
This is gonna be you in six months.
[Reporters shouting,
camera shutters clicking]
Look at 'em.
Two years later, they're still smiling.
- Eh.
- So it's a piece of fluff.
Bombshell will take us
to the next level.
You know we have some stuff
to fix first, right?
I mean, it isn't perfect.
Of course.
Everyone has their work to do,
even you.
Oh!
[Cell phone chimes]
Okay. Time to go.
I promised Frank that I would be there
when he got home from his dinner
with the new superintendent.
I am so glad it's working out
between you two.
We're trying.
I know you are.
So how long do you think
till we hear from...
Eileen.
Jerry.
I thought I felt a chill.
That seat's taken.
Oh, by, uh, Jordan roth.
I don't see him.
Maybe he knows,
like everyone else knows,
you don't have the capital yet
to take Bombshell to Broadway.
I could help.
I have a lot of friends.
Yes, mine...
The ones you stole.
If only you would stop,
stop thinking the worst of me.
I know you,
and I know what you're up to.
You saw my show, and you saw
it was better than anything you have.
So you called all the theater owners
to block my way,
hoping that I would come to you
in my time of need.
If you want in, you should just say so.
I want in.
Get out of here
before I throw another drink
in your face.
[Laughs]
Eileen, I'm so sorry I'm late.
Jordan. Nonsense.
You already called.
Does he know?
No.
Should we tell him?
I have offered
Bombshell to the St. James.
Isn't that wonderful?
[Cell phone ringing]
Oh.
It's Nick, my boyfriend.
Excuse me.
Hi.
Guess what.
I hope you're sitting down.
We're going to Broadway.
- Excuse me.
- Mm.
♪ let me be your star
All:
[vocalizing]
[Claps] And then people will clap,
Eileen will speak,
and the other number will start.
Uh, another?
Eileen only asked me to do one.
Oh, it's not you.
It's Ivy and the ensemble.
They're going to sing Smash.
Linda, can we do something
about the angle of this piano?
I feel like I can't see anyone.
Well, sure.
What if we...
I know you won't believe me,
but this isn't about you.
No, it's about you, as usual.
Excuse me.
Seems like old times.
Can I ask you a question?
Go ahead.
What is my future
with this show exactly?
I want to do everything I can
to ensure that
when it opens on Broadway
that I'm a part of it.
And my agent still hasn't gotten
a phone call...
That's why you asked to sing.
Okay, here's my answer.
It's not gonna be easy.
You need to apologize to Karen
for whatever it is that went on
between you two.
I already did, in Boston.
[Chuckles]
Well, maybe you were apologizing
for the wrong thing.
[Clears throat]
After the whole Michael...
Well, you know...
Um...
I spent a lot of time
telling my husband
I was sorry for what I did.
But it meant nothing until I apologized
for why I did it.
If you could stop making this
about what happened
and tell her why it did,
you might just get a second chance.
Ivy, you're up.
Good luck.
I'm rooting for you.
So, Derek,
another big moment for you...
Bombshell and The Wiz
treading the boards the same season.
Mm hmm.
Did you see the show in Boston?
Not only did I see it,
I saw it with Rebecca Duvall.
I don't suppose you have
anything to say
about her abrupt exit from the show?
No comment.
Really?
Ah.
Okay.
Okay, Rebecca Duvall is a superstar.
And like most superstars,
she knows what she's good at...
And what she isn't.
If I didn't know any better, I'd think
you were suggesting
she poisoned herself
to get out of her contract.
I did not say that, Michael,
but it would've made a better story.
You gonna sit down and order something?
No. I'm... I'm waiting
for my friend.
Get you something while you wait, then?
No.
Thanks.
I'm Jimmy, by the way.
Do you talk
to all your customers this much?
Are you a customer?
Mm, I thought
you were just another actress
taking a meeting at my station
who won't order anything
but a glass of water.
I'm not like that.
Karen?
Michael Riedel.
I can't wait to see you in the show.
- Oh.
- I hear amazing things.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Still or sparkling?
Tap.
Hey.
I got your text.
Is everything okay?
Did you know about Ivy
singing at the party?
No.
I keep thinking about what Ronnie said
about protecting the work,
and I'm worried
I won't be able to with Ivy
in my face all the time.
I mean, I thought...
Just say the word...
And I will let her go.
Okay.
Consider it done.
How was your meeting with Casey?
He offered me the general
in thebook of mormontour.
Wow! That's...
I mean, congratulations! Wow!
Eh, it's a great part, but I think
I'm gonna stay in the city, you know?
Forbombsh...
You have ten lines in our show.
In mormon, you'd be front and center.
Without you.
Sometimes you have
to put what's right for you
above what's right for someone else.
Have you ever done that?
You didn't allow yourself
to feel a second of happiness
over the reviews you got.
I mean, what did Variety say again?
I... [Sighs]
"Levitt's score is a marvel,
"full of charm and pizzazz
in its pastiche numbers
and unparalleled emotion
in its introspective moments."
Look, I allowed myself
some happiness in private.
I just didn't want it to seem
like I was gloating around Julia.
I mean, she got...
Slammed in reviews
she doesn't even know about.
[Sighs]
They loved her lyrics.
I'll tell her, in time, just not yet.
Her focus needs to be on her marriage.
We're partners, Sam.
It's my job to protect her.
As her partner, it's your job
to be the one person who doesn't.
I mean, if you can't tell her, who can?
Maybe I'll never have to.
Maybe she'll figure out her problems...
Is that...
Frank?
Huh.
- Oh, my God, is this for real?
- Yeah.
"Rebecca Duvall
has just released a statement
"claiming the reason she left
Broadway-bound musical Bombshell
"was not due to illness
as previously reported,
"but because the director, Derek Wills,
sexually harassed her
in her dressing room."
Is this some sort of joke?
Everyone knows Rebecca Duvall
would sleep
with a follow spot operator
if it meant more light
on her downstage.
This must be
what Derek called me about.
Find you guys later?
There's something
I have to take care of first.
- Good luck.
- Your life depends on it.
Thanks for understanding.
What, some actress
throwing you under the bus
to save face?
You may be a womanizer,
but I know there's no merit
to her story.
Yeah, well, you might want to tell that
to the producers of The Wiz for me.
- I'll call 'em now.
- Thank you.
I'll say hello to Eileen.
And here I was,
throwing a party and thinking
I could talk about the show
and not its director's personal life.
Michael Riedel
said he's coming tonight.
I want you to turn him away
at the door.
I don't think so.
He is the reason
she retaliated the way she did.
He just ran a quote out of context.
I don't blame Michael Riedel
for your mess,
and neither should you.
Now, let's just hope it doesn't blow up
into something bigger.
I'm going to see if Jordan's arrived
for the announcement.
Frank!
It's so good to see you!
Hey, Linda, how are you?
Oh, better, now that I've had a break.
How are you?
- I'm good. Thanks.
- Oh, that's wonderful.
You know how much I've always admired
you and Julia's relationship.
Our relationship?
Yes.
I'm glad you've worked it out.
Yeah, we, uh...
We did. Thanks.
[Chuckles awkwardly]
Hi.
Okay, here we go.
Eileen had the cocktails
named after Marilyn movies.
Isn't that cute?
I got you
a "clash by night."
- Does everyone know?
- Know what?
Linda just told me how happy she is
that we're working on our marriage.
Does everyone know about Michael?
Shows are like families.
Everyone knows everything.
Of course.
How could I ever think
that our private life is private?
I'll take
another "clash by night."
[Whispering] Maybe...
Maybe I shouldn't say anything.
It could've just been a good-bye
between good friends...
[Inhales sharply] Very good friends.
She's your best friend.
You should tell her.
[Sighs]
Wha you can't make it?
Why not?
What do you mean "let's talk tomorrow"?
Well, do I still have
the theater, or don't I?
No, you don't have to go.
Jordan roth isn't coming.
Something must've happened.
Maybe he heard about Rebecca.
Maybe he read Julia's reviews.
Well, the press are here
waiting for an announcement.
If he doesn't show,
they're gonna notice.
I need something to distract them
while I get to the bottom of this.
Why not use her?
Hi.
Good thinking.
Uh, everybody, please,
put your hands together
for Bombshell very own
Marilyn, Karen Cartwright,
plus, a very special guest...
Two-time Tony award winner
Veronica Moore.
[Applause]
[On Broadway playing]
♪ They say the neon lights are bright ♪
♪ on Broadway
♪ they say there's always magic ♪
♪ in the air
♪ but when you're walkin' down
the street ♪
♪ and you ain't got enough to eat ♪
♪ the glitter rubs right off ♪
♪ and you're nowhere
[vocalizing]
♪ They say the women treat you fine ♪
♪ on Broadway
- ♪ on Broadway
- [Mouths silently]
♪ But looking at them
♪ just gives me the blues ♪
♪ 'cause how you gonna make some time ♪
♪ make some time
♪ when all you got
is one thin dime? ♪
♪ one thin dime
♪ and one thin dime
♪ won't even shine your shoes ♪
[Both vocalizing]
♪ They say that I won't last too long ♪
♪ on Broadway
♪ I'll catch a greyhound bus for home ♪
♪ they all say
♪ but they're dead wrong,
I know they are ♪
♪ know they are
♪ 'cause I can play this here guitar ♪
♪ here guitar
♪ and I won't quit till I'm a star ♪
♪ on Broadway
- ♪ on Broadway
♪ oh, hey, yeah
♪ hey, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ yeah
both:
♪ on Broadway
[cheers and applause]
Thanks.
- Thank you.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Bravo.
- Thank you.
I wasn't doing so well,
but I feel better.
How did you do that?
I'm your muse.
It's what we do.
[Dramatic music]
♪
Just, um...
Is that why you called me...
To tell me you're with Karen?
Because you didn't have to.
It's very clear to everyone...
Look, I am not with Karen.
And that is not why I called you.
Well, then why did you call me?
Oh, my God.
You're letting me go.
Because of her?
Ivy.
What happened to the drinks?
Who were you with tonight
before you met me?
What?
No one.
Tom saw you.
She's just...
[Sighs]
Someone from school, you know,
the new superintendent.
It was nothing.
Well, then why didn't you just
tell me you were meeting?
Are you kidding me with this?
It's just a question.
I'm not accusing you of anything.
Not accusing me?
My God, Julia, really?
Coming from you?
[Scoffs]
[Clears throat]
Frank.
No, Julia.
I can't believe this...
Suspecting me of something
when you're the one who did everything.
Frank, calm down.
And you didn't do it just once either.
And that's just the affairs
that I know about.
[Softly] Frank, let's just
talk about this calmly, okay?
You know what?
Mary, the woman from school...
I didn't sleep with her.
I wanted to.
Maybe...
Maybe I should to even the score, huh?
Would that make it okay?
Or should I just sleep
with someone in the cast...
Keep it in the family?
After all, you did, and Tom did.
And... and Derek did
with every actress
who put on a Marilyn wig.
Why the hell can't I?
Can I quote you on that?
Oh, come on.
Karen.
[Laughs]
- Look, I...
- I...
After you.
- Having me fired...
- Ivy, I...
Was absolutely right.
You hate me.
You should.
But even you can't hate me
as much as I hate myself
for what I did.
And the crazy part
is that you don't even know
how bad it got.
That night
of your first preview in Boston,
I was a mess.
I almost...
I almost did something really stupid.
And for what?
Because I was jealous?
Because of a part in some show?
I'm truly sorry...
That I ever got in your way.
Good luck.
You deserve it.
[Tender piano music]
♪
What happened?
And where's Frank?
Gone.
My marriage is over.
I'm so sorry.
[Cries and laughs]
And to think that,
I thought, when I saw your face,
that you were gonna tell me
about the reviews.
[Laughs]
I promised I wouldn't.
I read them opening night.
[Sniffles] I pretended that I didn't
'cause I was so mortified.
Everything that I've done...
Has turned out so wrong.
What if I can't fix it?
I'll help you.
I'm your partner.
[Soft jazz music]
Eileen, hi.
Um, I know Derek was gonna let Ivy go.
But I've been thinking...
Eileen, before we even print a word...
Sorry, excuse me, darling.
Okay, I got a plan.
Um, you need to make a statement
in support of me, please.
I can't do that, Derek.
Yeah, you can.
Just do it.
This place is all full of journalists.
Just pick one.
I'm serious, Eileen.
If you want me to continue
with the show, you...
I don't give a damn what you do, Derek.
There is no show.
What do you mean, there's no show?
Someone tipped off the government
about the money I've been using
to finance the show
and who it came from.
Bombshell is under investigation
and, as such, is frozen,
along with the remaining funds.
Now, if you'll forgive me,
I have to go talk to my lawyers.
I saw what happen.
All this hard work...
It can't really be over, can it?
It's not unheard of, you know.
That's crazy.
A whole year gone by...
It's like waking up from some dream.
Yeah, well, at least you woke up.
It looks like my nightmare
is just beginning.
If I lose The Wiz and Bombshell...
Maybe I can help?
I'm still your muse, aren't I?
Yeah, something like that.
Look, I hope you find something else
for yourself, Karen...
Something that hits you
the way Bombshell hit me.
Oh, if you do...
Give me a call.
I might need a job.
[Grunts]
[Teaspoon clinking]
How you feeling?
Oh, uh...
[Sighs]
As bad as I should.
- [Sighs]
- [Sniffles]
[Groans] You really
don't mind me crashing here?
Not as long as you can make room
on this sofa for me.
I'm gonna tell Sam
he should take the tour.
I'm sorry.
Single again, at this age...
Who'd want me?
Anyone in their right mind.
Then I probably wouldn't want them.
[Sighs]
You know what?
Why don't you just stay here?
- What?
- Why not?
It'll be like old times...
Or a sitcom.
Maybe even get some work done.
Plus, I'd get to see Leo more.
I mean, if you really mean it,
just, you know...
Just until I figure out
what's happening.
Don't make me beg.
Okay, wait.
Uh-uh.
One condition, though.
Don't hide anything from me anymore...
Not the truth, not the newspaper.
Hand it over.
- Are you sure?
- Look...
I can't feel any worse
than I do now, right?
Okay.
You're gonna need
something stronger than tea.
Hi.
You're, uh, here
for the ensemble, right?
That's right.
Oh.
You were inBombshell.
What a mess, huh?
Actually...
It was pretty great.
[Crowded House's
Don't dream it's over playing]
♪
♪ there is freedom within
♪ there is freedom without ♪
♪ try to catch the deluge
in a paper cup ♪
♪
♪ there's a battle ahead
♪ many battles are lost
♪ but you'll never see
the end of the road ♪
♪ while you're traveling with me ♪
♪ hey, now, hey, now ♪
♪ don't dream it's over
♪ when the world comes in
♪ they come, they come ♪
♪ to build a wall between us ♪
♪ we know that they won't win ♪
♪
♪ now I'm towing my car
♪ there's a hole in the roof ♪
♪ my possessions
are causing me suspicion ♪
♪ but there's no proof
♪ hey, now, hey, now ♪
♪ don't dream it's over
♪ when the world comes in
♪ they come, they come ♪
♪ to build a wall between us ♪
♪ we know that they won't win ♪
♪ don't ever let them win
♪
Hey, you done?
Bar's closing.
- Sign says
you're open till 1:00.
It's only quarter to.
Yeah, and you've been
watching your ice melt
for the past 20 minutes.
While I appreciate
you actually ordered something,
people got to get back
to their real lives.
Yeah.
This is my real life.
- Alone at a bar
at 12:45... sorry.
You really don't have
the "talking to customers"
thing down, do you?
You want to teach me?
Keep the change.
I'm good.
Thanks.
Is he always like that?
Yeah, kind of.
Hey, um, don't I know you?
- I doubt it.
- Karen Cartwright?
[Laughs] I saw you in Bombshell.
You were incredible.
I was so sorry to read
about what happened.
Me too.
Thanks.
Hey, um, will you do me a favor?
Can you sign this for me?
- [Chuckles]
- I know, it's really corny.
But, um, I have
this collection of programs
from failed musicals...
Oh, damn, I'm sorry.
I have this thing...
I just start talking before I realize
that I'm talking, and then...
It's okay.
Ky, we got to get going.
[Groans]
Oh, are you two...
Are you guys, like...
Us?
[Laughs]
No. God, no.
I mean, he's not...
But does it look like we are?
[Chuckles]
You have a good night.
♪ I'm high above the city ♪
♪ I'm standing on the ledge ♪
♪
♪ the view from here is pretty ♪
♪ and I step off
forgot my phone.
Sorry.
♪ And now I'm falling ♪
Oh, you didn't see this.
He's not playing the piano.
He's not supposed to.
What is that he's playing?
It's, uh...
[Chuckles]
Just a song he...
We wrote
for, um... for this musical
we're working on.
Cool.
Look, you really got to go.
I'm sorry.
♪ That I'm from
♪ oh, Broadway, here I come ♪
♪
♪ Broadway, here I come ♪
♪ the people all are pointing ♪
♪ I bet they'd never guess ♪
Derek.
Karen, it's late.
What's going on?
You need to hear something.
What are you talking about?
Listen.
♪ But even though I fear it ♪
♪ I'm playing all my cards ♪
Where are you?
What is that?
Something else.
♪ Baby, you are gonna hear it ♪
♪ when I give them my regards ♪
♪ I'm falling, baby
♪ through the sky through the sky ♪
♪ I'm falling, baby, through the sky ♪
♪ it's my calling, baby
♪ don't you cry, don't you cry ♪
♪ I'm falling down through the sky ♪
♪ and I refuse to go numb
♪
♪ oh, Broadway, here I come ♪
♪ Broadway, here I come ♪
♪ Broadway, here I come
♪ Broadway, Broadway, here I come ♪
♪ here I come
♪
♪ and the last thing I hear ♪
♪ as the impact grows near ♪
♪ is it a scream
or a cheer? ♪
♪ well, never mind,
I'll never find out ♪
♪ 'cause, Broadway, I am here ♪
Hello?
Excuse me.
Hey.
You're here.
Uh, I work here.
- Right.
- [Chuckles]
Uh, I'm sorry to ambush you.
I'm Karen, by the way.
Um, I left you a few messages,
but you never called back.
Girls just usually call
to yell at me, so...
Well, that's not
what I was calling to do.
I was hoping we could talk
about your music.
My what?
You guys are writing a musical.
I mean, I'd love to hear more.
There's nothing to hear.
I don't...
I don't write anything.
So the song you played
last week after closing,
that wasn't yours?
Your friend just lied
when he said it was from your musical?
- Are you always like this?
- Like what?
[Laughs] Uptight.
I mean, if you stopped
clenching your jaw like that,
you know, you could actually be cute.
- I don't clench my jaw.
- Relax.
- That's really rude.
- Okay, you're doing it again.
You know, my...
My shift's over at 5:00,
if you want to hang out.
No, I don't...
I don't want to hang out.
I just want...
You know what?
Forget it.
See ya.
Dude, was that Karen Cartwright?
No idea.
She's the girl I told you about,
the one that was here the other night.
She's a big deal.
She could help us.
We do it on our own, all right?
We don't need anyone's help.
Move it.
I'm late.
Derek, it's me. Um, I just
wanted to let you know
I finally got in touch
with that composer.
- Hey! Hey, Karen, wait up!
- Um, it turn...
And... um, I got
to call you back.
Hey.
Look, I'm sorry about whatever
he said to you back there.
That guy's your friend, right?
Why, exactly?
I know.
He's complicated.
But he's a really good guy
when you get to know him
and an amazing composer.
He's just really protective
of our stuff.
Well, I wanted to hear more,
play it for my friend Derek,
see what he thought.
Derek, as in Derek Wills?
[Chuckles] Like... like
the Derek Wills? He's, uh...
Irrelevant to this conversation,
since your friend
clearly isn't interested.
Yes, he is.
He just doesn't know it yet,
and so am I.
Look, can you meet me
in a couple hours,
when I'm done with my shift?
There's something I want to show you.
I realize your clients
haven't gotten paid, Saul.
No one has.
I'm truly sorry.
But mark my words, I'll have
this all ironed out,
tout de suite!
Now, if you'll excuse me...
The fact I was able to stage
a single number
in the middle of that circus
you and Julia created
is nothing short of a miracle.
"Circus"... how choice.
Let's talk about you juggling
every Marilyn in the show.
Boys, there's nothing to be gained
by turning on each other.
But it feels good.
All right, then...
Maybe we should turn on you.
Did it not even seem
a little bit strange to you
that a Brooklyn bartender
and his funny little friends
had millions of dollars
in cash lying around?
I have spent the last three hours
with the federal government
and my accountant,
going through every bill,
receipt, and pay stub
since the beginning of time.
It's all in order.
Did they say
when we could get back to work?
No, but we're still alive.
Karen is singing tonight at
the American theatre wing gala.
Every Broadway bigwig will be there.
So, for now, I'd like
to ask both of you
please not to accept any other project
until all of this is settled.
Yeah, I can't make that
guarantee... I need to work.
You have offers
after last week's revelations?
Yeah.
Rebecca Duvall has moved on,
so have the tabloids.
So, beyond directing
one of Broadway's
biggest stars in The Wiz,
- yes, I have several offers.
- Amazing.
What a business.
Oh, Tom.
Did you pack something warm
for your trip to the moral high ground?
Why don't you both
get out of my office?
I'll let you know what happens tonight.
Julia and I are here for you,
whatever you need.
You are.
This is the third meeting
Julia's missed.
She had a college thing with Leo.
[Phone ringing]
It's Miriam Abramson's office
on line e... on
the American theatre wing.
I'm so jealous.
You're going on tour
with The Book of Mormon,
and I can't even get a callback
for an eHarmony commercial.
You got to bug your agent more.
Are you kidding me?
That's all I've been doing.
But you are Ivy Lynn.
She don't stay down for long.
At least you're not Lisa McMann.
Approaching, approaching.
Oh, my God, oh, my God,
oh, my God, oh, my God...
I cannot face that woman today.
She's been plugging away
longer than I have.
Ivy? And Sam?
- [Squeals] Oh, my God!
- Lisa McMann!
- Hi!
- Oh!
This is too funny!
I was just thinking about you guys
and that awful Shakespeare festival
we did in the adirondacks.
Ugh, don't remind me.
[Laughs]
So what have you been up to?
Stationery!
Yeah!
I got out of the biz,
and my whole life changed.
Now I make my own hours.
People actually want
what I'm offering...
No more rejection,
rejection, rejection.
Oh, um...
Here is my guesthouse.
Yeah.
[Giggles]
Oh, how about you guys?
Hello, darling.
How's my second favorite
agent in the world?
Oh.
Very sweet.
Loving the purple.
- Thank you.
- So...
Got some news for me?
What's happening with The Wiz?
Well, Ronnie's a big fan, as you know,
and she remains that way.
She fought hard for you
with the producers.
Whoa, wait.
Am I hearing a past tense in there?
They're letting you go.
Just because I shagged
a couple of actresses?
That's ludicrous.
Well, it's not just because of that.
The local news has a story.
We got the heads-up
an hour ago.
Five dancers have come forward
and are accusing you
of sexual harassment.
I have the names here somewhere.
Um...
I don't want to talk
to her assistant again.
I want to talk to her.
Looks nothing like you.
[Chuckling]
I knew I should have moved offices.
Jerry...
I'm in a particularly tight spot,
and you owe me.
- I do?
- Yes.
You're giving me your table tonight
for the American theatre wing gala.
I thought you were already going.
I thought I was too.
But Miriam Abramson's
assistant called to say
that I am no longer on the guest list.
Is that so?
I have only a small window
of opportunity for Bombshell,
and I will not have it closed.
I refuse to be treated like a criminal.
So...
You want to be my date, hmm?
[Laughs] Oh, no.
You're not going.
It'll be just me and my creative team.
I hear Julia's a mess.
The Wiz dropped Derek
like a hot potato.
Julia's fine.
And so is Derek.
My team couldn't be more unified.
They'll sail through.
You're welcome.
[Cell phone vibrating]
[Cell phone ringing]
Hello?
Hi, boys.
I need Julia too.
Is she there?
Oh, she's meeting with her realtor.
What's going on, Eileen?
I'm on my way home.
Okay, we've got
a slight change of plans.
Karen's no longer singing tonight.
Instead, it'll be the four of us,
8:00 at the Plaza,
and I want you on
your best behavior, all of you...
No fighting, no surprises, no scandals.
Is that understood?
Bloody paparazzo.
Of course.
And, Tom, tell Julia
it's cocktail attire.
Yep.
No!
[Clears throat loudly]
No, I can't, not tonight.
I'm not up for it, maybe tomorrow.
You have to.
Eileen needs us.
Besides, it's been a week.
You're starting to merge
with the couch.
Some air will be good for you.
I got some air today.
I met Leo in Riverside Park.
And then you came home
and put your pajamas back on?
I may have met him in them.
Julia!
Look, it's...
It's bad enough
that I destroyed my family.
Now Frank is telling people,
and everyone is writing me.
I have to relive the whole thing
every time I check my email!
I know it's hard,
but we can't abandon Bombshell
in her hour of need.
None of your relatives are gonna
be at the thing tonight.
No, just industry people...
That's worse.
They'll eat me alive.
Look, if there was anywhere else
that you wanted me to go
with you tonight...
The Bronx zoo, whole foods...
The shower?
I am asking my friend Tom
to tell my partner Tom
that I need the night off.
Please?
I will tell Eileen you're sick
and represent the team myself.
Thank you.
You're the best.
Yes, I am.
And I promise, I'll get back up soon.
Just a...
Just a little longer?
This is... this is what
you wanted to show me?
He doesn't write anything down, really,
except, occasionally, when he's wasted.
Uh, this one is particularly amazing.
He doesn't know I saved it.
Read the lyrics.
I think they start
on the cocktail menu.
I don't understand... do you
guys have a musical or not?
We do.
We're still working on it,
but most of the songs are written.
Does your friend even know you're here?
- Uh...
- Look...
I just came from a clearasil audition
and then found out the one thing
I was looking forward to
got canceled tonight,
so you can understand
I was hoping to get involved
with something that's real.
This obviously isn't it.
Let me know if it ever
comes together, okay?
Find someone to play this for you.
And if you like it
or you want to hear more,
come to our place tonight...
We're having some people over.
Maybe if you stop by and got
to know Jimmy a little better,
he'd let his guard down,
play you some stuff.
Think about it?
[Buzzer sounds]
[Woman speaking indistinctly
on television]
Um...
You can just...
Leave it at the door, whatever it is!
Thank you!
Julia?
It's Ivy.
Oh!
Hello, Daisy.
Can I have a word?
- I can't talk to you, Derek.
- Oh, yeah, you can.
We need to have a little chat
about your understanding
of the phrase
"sexual harassment."
You know I never touched you.
I didn't say you did.
You only hit on me through
four callbacks of Sweet charity,
and when I finally said
I wouldn't sleep with you,
I mysteriously lost out on the job.
Oh, well, as I recall,
you didn't get the job
'cause, while you were
a pretty good dancer,
you were only an okay actress,
which is why,
after all these years,
you're still teaching pilates.
You're unbelievable.
Is that really
what you came here to say?
Yeah, pretty much.
Since when is it harassment
to ask someone out on a date?
You don't get it.
You're a big-shot director.
You're in a position of power
from the minute
you wake up in the morning,
and you don't treat
that power with respect.
Or did you really think women say yes
because they actually like you?
I'm sorry. I thought
I was gonna be venting to Tom.
Are you sure this is okay?
Of course, I'm thrilled
to be of use to anyone.
I know you guys
are super successful now.
But did you ever feel like giving up?
Um, I could barely get up
to answer the door.
[Chuckles]
Ugh, I just don't know what to do.
Now I'm going in for parts
that I would have passed on
two years ago.
Maybe I should just quit.
I've been where you are.
It's a brutal business.
But just when I'd want
to throw in the towel,
something would happen to remind me
of why I love it in the first place.
And thus, the dysfunctional
cycle continues.
[Chuckles]
Oh, yeah.
- It cures everything.
- It really does.
[Indistinct chatter]
Ooh, I see...
Tom, Tom, Tom, Tom, Tom, Tom!
Listen, I've been meaning to call you.
Oh, honey, I've been so worried.
You are... why?
If they said half the stuff
about a show of mine
they're saying about yours,
I would be on suicide watch.
Ah!
Well, you know our business.
So much is exaggerated
or just plain made up.
Hey, you think I believe half of it?
But I mean, come on, it's absurd.
I mean, even Derek couldn't be
as much of a dog as they're saying.
You know, that's the kind
of thing that...
And Eileen rand running
around with a drug lord?
- Well, honestly...
- Oh, wait.
I really don't know the specifics.
Please do not thank me,
but I have ordered everyone
to stop talking about Julia
having a nervous breakdown.
Well, thank you anyway for that.
Um, but she's doing fine.
The split was amicable.
Well, you mean it's true?
You know what?
You have nothing to worry about.
You are too good... someone's
gonna snatch you right up.
In fact, I have this idea that...
What?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
J-Julia and I haven't
broken up.
I was talking about...
No, we're fine.
Harvey, look at me.
Julia's fine.
We are still together.
So I guess I will see you both tonight
at that theatre wingding thing?
Yes?
The two of you, together?
Yes, you will.
Uh, Julia will not only
be there with me,
but, uh... uh...
We're giving a speech...
A tribute, um, as a team...
Both of us, together.
And I will be right there
cheering you on, as always.
All right, later.
[Laughing]
Bye. Bye.
So it's up to six dancers now?
Well, thank you
for telling me that, Peggy.
Clearly, you're taking
no delight whatsoever
- in my misfortune.
- Derek on two.
Bye, Peggy.
Did you not hear a word
I said to you this morning?
I didn't do anything.
Oh, you did a lot. It's just
catching up with you now.
Yeah, whatever.
What time is this thing again tonight?
You're not coming.
Bombshell needs ambassadors,
not another liability.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, Julia the adulteress
is now Ambassador,
but the serial seducer isn't?
Is this a gender thing?
You know what?
I'm hanging up now, Derek.
You're not going to
'cause I'm gonna hang up first!
[Phone beeps]
[Cell phone beeps]
Another one of these.
Ahh. I have a question
for you, young mate.
Hmm?
If you have something somebody wants,
does that mean you
can't sleep with them?
Dude, I don't know.
My shift's over.
Dan, he's all yours.
Oh, come on.
All women like me.
Hello.
You're not a dancer,
by any chance, are you?
Back off, dude.
She's with me.
I think the lady can speak for herself.
[Eurythmics'
would I lie to you?]
♪
All: Whoo!
♪ would I lie to you?
♪ Oh, yeah
all:
♪ would I lie to ya, honey?
♪ Oh, no, no, no
all: ♪ now, would I say
something that wasn't true? ♪
♪ I'm asking you, sugar,
would I lie to you? ♪
♪ my friends know what's in store ♪
♪ I won't be here anymore
♪ I've packed my bags,
I've cleaned the floor ♪
♪ watch me walkin',
walkin' out the door ♪
All:
♪ believe me
♪ I'll make it, make it
all:
♪ would I lie to you?
♪ Would I lie to you, honey?
♪ Now, honey,
would I lie to you? ♪
All: ♪ now, would I say
something that wasn't true? ♪
♪ I'm asking you, sugar,
would I lie to you? ♪
♪ tell you straight, no intervention ♪
♪ to your face, no deception ♪
♪ you're the biggest fake,
that much is true ♪
♪ had all I can take,
now I'm leavin' you ♪
♪
All:
♪ ah, ah, ah
♪ would I lie to you?
♪ Would I lie
to you, honey? ♪
♪ now, would I say something
that wasn't true? ♪
♪ I'm asking you, sugar,
would I lie to you? ♪
Honey, I'm home.
Listen...
I may have done something.
- I know.
- Ah.
- I heard.
- You heard?
Mary Testa just called.
She said that she heard
from Jackie Hoffman,
who heard from Cheyenne Jackson,
who heard from Harvey fierstein
that we're presenting tonight?
- Yes. Well...
- You could have told me.
That's important!
I only said no because
I didn't want to sit at a table
and be silently judged all night.
I can't say no
to the entire American theatre wing.
How did this happen?
Um...
Okay.
First of all, you can stand.
Good to know.
Tell me!
Well, I got a call out of the blue...
- Uh-huh.
- From the head
of the theatre wing...
I forget her name.
Miriam Abramson.
I've met her.
Right, of course you have.
Well, apparently Miriam needed someone
to speak about the theatre wing
and all the beatific stuff it does,
and when they heard we were coming,
they thought, who better than us?
That is so nice...
The community supporting us
after everything
we've just been through.
Mm.
What do you want to say?
Do you want me to just
take a stab at it?
I've already jotted down
a few thoughts.
- A few?
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
I've got to do my hair.
Here, you take over
you're actually excited about this.
Excited? No.
But I can do this.
You're my partner,
and I'm not gonna let you
stand up there alone.
Oh, and try and keep it brief.
I hate it when presenters run on.
[Sighs] Giving notes already
before I've even started...
Julia's back!
[Keyboard playing]
♪ Caught in the storm
or something like that.
Wow.
He's crazy good.
- Like Jonathan Larson good
- yes.
Maybe they're writing the nextrent.
I know.
It's amazing.
I'm not crazy for stalking
this guy, right?
Honey, I'm ready to stalk him.
Is he straight?
He can't be straight.
I mean, it's musical theater.
It doesn't matter if he is or he isn't.
He's not interested in me...
He called me "uptight."
Okay, I say this with love,
but you did sound
a little uptight just now.
You guys, just give her a break.
She's just out
of a three-year relationship,
and she's a little bit rusty.
She doesn't realize
when a guy is hitting on her.
You guys are missing the point.
All I want to do is hear
the rest of his songs.
I just have to figure out how.
I can think of one way.
I knew you were gonna say that.
♪ She's a really good girl,
but not for long ♪
♪ how can she get him
to share his songs? ♪
Okay, you're definitely not
writing the next Rent.
- Oh, please.
- Oh.
No, she isn't.
But she just gave me a better idea.
Thanks for checking in.
Yeah, well, don't go pulling
a Lisa McMann on me
while I'm on tour, okay?
Well, maybe she's got the right idea.
She gave it her all,
and when it didn't pan out,
she exited stage left,
and now she's
the happiest person we know.
What would you do
if you couldn't do this?
Ah, see, you don't have an easy answer.
I gotta call you back.
Good evening.
[Jazz music]
♪
Hi, there.
Sorry to intrude.
Miriam, lovely to see you.
I was really so touched
that you thought of us for this honor,
especially in light of recent events.
- I'm sorry. What?
- Oh, God.
I was just wondering if you knew
when in the program
that we'd be speaking.
I get a little stage fright sometimes.
But if I know when it's coming, then...
- I don't... I-I'm sorry...
- Okay, pardon me, hi, hi.
Someone asked you to speak tonight?
You did.
You asked Tom...
Levitt?
No, I'm quite certain I didn't
and wouldn't either.
Hi. Hi. Hi.
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
[Whispering] And you're gonna be.
Miriam. Excuse me.
[Whispering] Julia.
Julia?
Can you please stay,
so we can talk about this?
I had a million reasons
to be embarrassed
before I came here tonight,
and you just created a new one.
I got caught in a moment,
and it got away from me.
I was gonna tell you the truth.
But when you heard about this,
you were so happy,
for the first time in weeks.
It got you off the couch.
That doesn't make it okay!
Excuse me.
I have to tell you,
I just saw heaven on Earth
again for the third time.
- Wonderful.
- I'm so glad.
The new Fella's not so good.
- Great.
- Helpful.
Julia...
Look...
I'm really worried about you.
I feel awful about everything
that you're going through
with Frank and Leo, but it is very hard
to watch you be this down for so long.
Well, I'm sorry.
Maybe you'd bounce back faster,
but we're different people,
and I need to do this on my own time.
But it's not just your time.
It's mine too.
As partners, if you're down
for the count, then so am I.
Is that what this is about?
I'm holding you down?
[Scoffs]
No.
You're doing it again.
You're hiding something.
Talk to me.
I'm not made of glass.
Fine.
Word on the street is that
you couldn't hack it
on Bombshell,
that you had a nervous breakdown,
and that I should be looking
for another writing partner
before my career goes down with yours.
You keep promising
you'll come out of it,
but then you find another reason
to crawl back onto the couch.
I am running out of excuses for you.
Mm hmm.
I don't want a new
writing partner, okay?
I just want my old one back.
So this is greenpoint.
Half pierogies and half poseurs...
What's not to love?
So where is this guy?
I'm looking.
[Southern accent] I'm gonna
get me some moonshine...
Or that.
- That's Kyle. Don't you dare.
- Too late.
Oh, there he is, in the red flannel.
Okay, I'll admit
that's worth getting
on the "G" train for.
What are you waiting for?
Go say hi.
- Okay.
- Go.
Don't be uptight!
[Indistinct chatter] Hey.
Nice place.
Thanks.
Nice shoe.
Oh.
[Chuckles]
It's sticky.
Kyle said he invited you.
I said you didn't know
where Brooklyn was.
I hate to rock your world.
I used to live in Brooklyn.
You are rocking my world.
Uh, my first apartment
was in Fort Greene, FYI.
Did it ever occur to you
I might be a little cooler
than you think?
Well, you just said "FYI," so, no.
[Both laugh]
So what does a girl got to do
to get a drink around here?
♪ You don't know how I feel ♪
Ky, we need some more brew!
♪ You still don't know how I feel ♪
That.
You can have mine for now.
Thanks.
Okay, what is going on with you?
Oh, God, haven't you heard?
Well, picture
a whole line of rockettes...
A big pile of girls,
all telling lies about me.
You know what I'm like.
I'm not that bad.
Oh, come on!
Look...
I know it was a big mess
at the end, and...
I was a complete ass, all right?
But I'm not a monster, am I?
Why do you care
what I think all of a sudden?
Shouldn't you be asking Karen?
Isn't she your muse?
Oh, maybe.
Whatever.
You're my friend.
All right, you were my friend.
I was a lot of things, Derek.
But now I don't know what I am anymore.
Or if I even want to stay
in this business.
You're far too good to pack
it in... don't be so stupid.
I couldn't have been that good.
I wasn't Marilyn.
You were my Marilyn.
What do I know?
I made a million stupid mistakes.
Just prove me wrong.
You are a singular talent.
Don't give up.
I don't think you're a monster.
Nope, not gonna happen.
Right.
[Soft jazz music]
♪
Miriam...
How great to see you.
What a night.
Everybody's here.
Eileen, I was told
you wouldn't be joining us
this evening.
Well, you were told wrong.
I wouldn't dream of missing this.
After all, what's more important
to me than our community?
I would think, at this moment,
your legal troubles.
Miriam, you and I have
a long history together.
Surely you know
I'm a woman of integrity.
I have an organization to protect.
In these economic times,
we can't afford even
a whiff of impropriety.
So I trust you'll understand
why I have to ask you
and your team to leave.
I should have known
they were here with you.
I'm so sorry no one in New York
will get to see
what you lost everything for.
Best wishes to you.
Oh, yes.
[Chuckles]
Yeah, yeah, I liked the strokes too,
when I was 15.
Ugh!
You know what you are?
A snob.
Me?
- Yeah.
- I'm a snob?
Uhhuh.
At least I'm not uptight.
No, no, don't change the subject.
You heard me, snob.
Deal with it.
So is that the piano you don't play?
Yeah, I play a little...
Whatever...
When I'm in the mood.
Well, I sing a little
when I'm in the mood.
Oh, I'll bet you do.
So how will I know
if you're in the mood.
Well...
It'll be very obvious.
I might, like, look around and...
Figure out what the vibe is.
[Laughing] Okay.
And then I might just...
Stand up...
And stretch...
Warm up a bit.
I think I get the picture.
And then I...
I might just finish my drink.
Oops, already did...
Kind of.
Oop.
Oh!
- Oh...
- [Laughs]
And, um, probably just...
Sing a song.
♪ You can push me away
♪ I can take it
♪ I can make you a promise
and break it ♪
♪ we know the way it goes by now ♪
♪
♪ running off just to see
if I chase you ♪
♪ I pretend I know how to replace you ♪
♪ still, we get tangled up somehow ♪
♪ hear it thunder
♪ and I wonder
♪ how long can I hang on?
♪ I'm caught in the storm
♪ I'm caught in the rain
♪ I'm caught in the rush
that hides this pain ♪
♪ I'm ready to drown
♪ but it's comin' down
♪ but I feel so alive
♪ just let me go
♪ just walk away
♪ if you love someone
♪ you never let them stay
♪ caught in the storm
You son of a bitch.
[Indistinct chatter]
Hold up a second!
- You stole my songs?
- What? No.
- I should kick your ass.
- Would you calm down?
I just showed her one... I had
no idea she was gonna do that.
I.. I'm so sorry.
I didn't think you'd get so mad.
Stay out of this, princess.
Oh, my God.
I-I just think you're
really talented.
I want to help.
I don't need your help, all right?
I-I write for myself.
You want to go write
your own musical? Great.
Go ahead.
Leave mine alone.
It's not just yours!
Yeah, says the guy who sits there
and watches me write the songs.
Hey... your music
is really good.
I know it's scary
to put yourself out there,
but you have to... otherwise,
you're never gonna know
how good you are.
Yeah.
Well, unlike you,
I don't need other people
to tell me I'm good.
I know I'm good.
- I know I'm good too.
- Oh, yeah?
Then why aren't you out there
onstage, in the city,
taking your curtain call,
instead of out here,
begging two strangers for a song
to help you get there!
You know, I think you should
just take your friends and go.
Don't worry.
We're going.
Well, we came, we saw, we got shunned.
I say we go.
We're going...
But not until we do something
very important.
What's going on?
I want to help.
Good.
I want the world
to see what it would miss
if Bombshel went away.
And how do we do that?
We put on a performance
they'll never forget.
I like it.
Calling Karen?
On it.
Straight to voice mail.
What do we do now?
[Soft piano music]
Hi. Sorry.
I came as fast as I could.
Oh, no, please, Ivy.
We're just so grateful to you
for doing this.
Hey, I'm just excited someone
still wants to hear me sing.
I realize you didn't want me here,
but here I am.
Oh, please.
None of us are supposed to be here.
[Indistinct chatter]
Hello. Hi.
I'm Julia Houston.
Just wanted to make
a little impromptu tribute
to Miriam Abramson for pulling
off this incredible night.
Right?
[Applause]
I am happy to introduce...
Ivy Lynn...
One of Broadway's future stars,
who will be singing one of our songs
from Bombshell, coming to Broadway...
This season.
Yeah.
[Applause]
[Slow, jazzy piano music]
♪
♪ the field was bright with clover ♪
♪ I saw the finish sign
♪ I started as a rover
♪ and then victory was mine
♪ I thought the race was over ♪
♪ but they just keep moving the line ♪
♪
♪ they cheered at my persistence ♪
♪ but prayed for my decline
♪ the path of least resistance ♪
♪ led to Hollywood and vine ♪
♪ I tried to go the distance
♪ but they just keep moving the line ♪
♪
♪ I jumped all of the hurdles
♪ to break out of the pack
♪ I started on the outside
♪ and then hit the inside track ♪
♪ I left the other fillies
♪ back at the starting gate
♪ was ready, on my mark, I got to set ♪
♪ to hurry up and wait
♪ so talent and ambition
♪ won me a chance to shine
♪ I aced the big audition
♪ but it's rainin' on cloud nine ♪
♪ can't beat the competition
♪ 'cause they just keep
♪ moving the line
♪ I handled every corner
♪ each bump along the track
♪ and when I saw the ribbon
♪ well, there was no turning back ♪
♪ I won the photo finish
♪ I posed for all the men
♪ but before I got my trophy
♪ well, the race began again
♪ so I made friends with rejection ♪
♪ I've straightened up my spine ♪
♪ I'll change each imperfection ♪
♪ till it's time to drink the wine ♪
♪ I'd toast to resurrection
♪ but they just keep
♪ moving the line
♪ please give me some direction ♪
♪ 'cause they just
♪ keep
♪ moving
♪ the line
[cheers and applause]
[Sighs happily]
Now I'm ready to go.
How *** made an impresion last night?
More than you know.
Turns out the U.S. attorney's
wife was there.
How about that?
What a happy coincidence.
Yes, and it seems that
we're allowed to resume work
on the show, just so long
as it's not for profit
or public consumption.
But how can you resume work on the show
if you don't have the money
to pay anyone?
[Chuckles]
How much do you need?
I'll have my lawyer draw up a contract.
I don't want to owe you
anything but money.
[Elevator bell dings] Wonderful.
Dude...
Yo!
All right, cut the cold shoulder.
Just spit it out.
You know what I'm upset about.
You cost us our one shot
with a real Broadway actor
with actual connections.
Look, I'm sorry if I...
Overreacted.
That girl just bugs me.
She's so full of herself, you know?
Well, she's gone, so you got
your way, as always.
You know, I've been
cleaning up your messes
since we were kids.
[Sighs]
Without me, you wouldn't have a job
or an apartment or any friends
because you piss everyone off.
And that girl was the one person
who could have gotten us closer
to everything I've ever wanted.
Would it have killed you to do
something for me for once?
I made coffee this morning.
And by the way,
I don't just watch you write.
I'm writing the book for this thing.
Selfish prick.
Wow.
What's the occasion?
These are apology muffins.
Ah.
They do look very guilty.
Tom, I am so sorry for everything.
Last night I got so excited
about the show again,
just hearing Ivy sing our song.
I promise I will work
from here to eternity
to make it up to you...
And to Bombshell,
if we're lucky enough
to get another chance.
Than
and I'm sorry I lied to you.
It was dumb.
So, in the spirit of honesty
and as your friend and partner...
Can I say something?
Yes.
It's time to retire the scarves.
[Both laugh]
[Distant car horn honking]
Yo.
Hey.
Sorry.
At least someone
had a good time last night.
[Giggles]
[Knock at door]
Hey.
How did you find me?
Oh, my God, where did you get that?
I may have left that
on their fridge last night.
Hmm. What?
- What's up, Jimmy?
- Come on.
- Hey.
- You need to get back inside.
[Continues indistinctly]
Um...
This is everything I've written so far.
Oh.
I didn't expect this.
Yeah.
The only reason
I'm trusting you with this
is because I owe it to Kyle.
Thank you.
I think this could be really big.
[Elevator bell dings]
I figured you might need
a little extra caffeine
this morning
and a little extra grease.
You're too kind.
And I wanted to thank you
for what you said last night.
You really helped pull me
out of my funk.
What did I say?
I'm teasing, darling...
Anytime.
This storm's gonna pass for you too.
Right now you're just
in the worst of it.
And...
I'm sorry.
Is this a bad time?
Do you have company or something?
Actually, I do.
We're just having
a little work session.
- Hey.
- Oh, hi.
I'm sorry.
I-I didn't mean to intrude.
I heard you saved the day last night.
I was on the subway
when they called me.
Yeah.
It was fun.
[Chuckles]
So I guess I'll see you guys around.
Bye.
[Sighs] Right, then...
This kid's song better be good enough
to get me out of bed
with a stinking hangover.
- Let's see, shall we?
- Mm-hmm.
♪ High above the city
- What was that about?
- Nothing important.
♪ I'm standing on the ledge ♪
♪ the view from here is pretty ♪
♪ and I step off the edge
Sync and corrected by dr.jackson
for www.addic7ed.com