♪
♪ I was a girl
in a village ♪
♪ doin' all right
♪ then I became
a princess overnight ♪
♪ now I gotta figure out
how to do it right ♪
♪ so much to learn and see
♪ up in the castle
with my new family ♪
♪ in a school that's
just for royalty ♪
♪ a whole enchanted world
is waiting for me ♪
♪ I'm so excited to be
♪ sofia the first
♪ I'm findin' out
what bein' royal's all about ♪
♪ sofia the first
♪ makin' my way
♪ it's an adventure
every day ♪
♪ sofia
♪ it's gonna be my time
♪ to show them all that I'm
♪ sofia the first
The floating palace!
Oh! Sofia, there you are!
You have to come out
to the terrace this instant.
I'll be right there.
I'm almost done
with this story.
Finish it later.
Come on!
What's so important?
You'll see.
( giggles )
Hello, ladies.
Dad, are we there yet?
We sure are.
Welcome to merroway cove!
Rollie, it's beautiful.
It's just as I remember it.
My father brought me
here when I was a boy.
Remember, baileywick?
All too well, your majesty.
Are you okay, baileywick?
Yes, sofia.
I'm just getting used
to being on the water.
What a perfect place to spend
our summer vacation.
Daddy, isn't merroway cove
where the mermaids live?
Mermaids?
I'm afraid those stories
are just old fisherman's tales.
Last time I was here,
I didn't see any mermaids.
And I looked,
right baileywick?
You did indeed.
Maybe they stayed underwater.
I'm reading a book about
mermaids right now,
And it says a lot of times
They only come up to the surface
When they know humans
aren't looking.
Nonsense!
Admiral hornpipe!
I have sailed the 17 seas,
And seen all manner
of creatures,
But not one single mermaid.
The truth of
the matter is,
There is no truth
to the matter.
Mermaids are not real.
But it says so in the book.
Not all stories
are true, sofia.
Right. Now who wants to go up
to the wheelhouse
And help me sail across
this lovely cove?
Both:
I do! I do!
Well, off course you do.
Tally-ho!
Come along, everyone.
( sighs )
Lunch is now being
served on the lido deck.
Mmm. Blueberries
a la clover!
Huh?
Clover!
Hey, princess!
You're suipposed to be
back at the castle.
Surprise!
Stay there.
I'm coming down.
The princess may
be on vacation,
But there's no rest for
the wicked, wormy.
Not when there's
a kingdom to take over.
( caws )
And we won't even need
princess sofia's amulet
To do it.
Because I found another way.
The mermaid comb
of merroway cove.
The mermaids that live
in the bottom of this cove
Have a magical comb
that can harness
The power of the ocean
like this!
Ooh, if I can get my
hands on that comb,
The entire kingdom
will bow at my feet.
Stop lounging around, wormy.
It's time to go fishing
for mermaids.
So how'd you get on board?
Well, I was taking a nap
in one of the boxes
In the castle kitchen,
when I woke up, I was here.
Oops.
But that's cool,
'cause I could
use a vacation.
I could see it now.
Lying on a beach,
sipping on a coconut...
( gasps )
did you see that?
See what?
Let's look from
the swimming platform.
Look for what?
Sofia?
Huh?
( sighs )
What're you looking for?
I thought I saw...
Saw what?
Uh, a mermaid.
Ha! Mermaid.
Oh, you're serious.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
( sighs )
I guess they
are just stories.
Both: Huh?!?
( gasps )
What was that?
A mermaid!
Where'd she go?
( gasps )
Oh!
Be careful, princess!
Stop! You're just getting
yourself more tangled.
Here! Take my hand.
Hold still.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
My name is sofia.
What's yours?
I'm oona.
You're a mermaid.
Yeah, I am.
And I'm clover.
Hello, clover.
What're you?
I'm a blue ribbon
bunny, baby.
Oh! Mermaids can talk
to animals?
Of course.
Can't humans?
Not usually.
This is some boat you have.
It's a floating palace.
I saw it enter the cove.
I've never seen
anything like it.
Does your necklace
always glow like that?
Oh! It only glows
once in a while.
It's enchanted.
Hey! So's my comb!
Really?
At least that's
what my mom says.
But she won't tell me
what it's powers are,
'cause she says
I'm not old enough yet.
Oh, I'd better go.
Why?
We're not supposed to spend
too much time at the surface.
Well, it was nice
meeting you, sofia.
Wait! Don't go.
Ow!
What's wrong?
I can't swim. I must've
hurt my fin in the net.
I'll help you.
Oh, whoa, whoa!
Here, take my hand.
( gasps )
Uh, sofia?
Your legs are going away.
What's happening?
Sofia! How'd you do that?
With each deed performed for
better or worse,
A power is granted,
a blessing or curse.
My amulet gives
me special powers
When I do good things.
I helped you out of the net.
So the amulet gave me the power
to transform into a mermaid.
Do you know what that means?
What?
I can swim in the water
like a mermaid!
Sofia!
Sofia?
This is incredible!
Ah!
I can't believe your amulet
turned you into a mermaid.
Now I can help you back
to the platform.
But I need to get home.
No. Just at the bottom
of the cove.
Great. Clover?
I'll be back soon.
I'm going to see where
the mermaids live.
Okay, have fun.
Wait! You're going where?
Pardon me, 'scuse me, pardon me.
Sorry. Still getting
used to the tail.
Man, this is one
strange vacation.
Hey! That's my lunch!
Finders keepers, bunny!
( laughs )
Oh, you won't be keeping
it for long, seagull.
( laughs )
Right, we'll just
borrow this lifeboat
And find a nice, private
hding place
Where no precocious prinsesses
will get in our way.
Oh, wormy.
This cave will be the perfect
spot to hatch our scheme.
Now, let's find that spell.
We are going to transform
ourselves
Into the most magnificent
sea creatures.
Then we can dive straight
to the bottom of the cove
And find that mermaid comb.
Where is it?
Aha! There!
( clears throat )
Air to water, land to sea,
Actuus gillen maritee!
( laughs )
it worked!
( gurgles )
Oh, relax, wormy.
This way, we'll blend in with
the other sea life.
Wow, you guys sure stick out.
New around here, eh?
Oh, love the clown mask.
Very funny.
( fish laughing )
Ooh, everyone's a critic.
No matter.
( laughs )
Soon the mermaid comb
will be ours
And then the entire kingdom.
Off we go, wormy!
( laughs )
That way, sofia.
Throughh the kelp forest.
It looks just
like seaweed, oona.
That's because
kelp is seaweed.
Wow, it's like a whole
new world under the sea.
Is it much farther?
Down there.
Just past this ledge.
Oh, wow.
Here we are.
Let's go inside.
In the ship?
Uh-huh.
Whoa. It's all broken up.
Is this where
you live, oona?
No, this is my hideaway.
It's where I keep
all my treasures.
Oona? Oona, are you back?
Aw.
Quick! Hide over here!
Why?
That's sven.
He's my friend,
But he gets very suspicious
around strangers.
Maybe she's in her shipwreck.
Oona? Oona?
There you are.
Oh, hi, sven.
Where have you been?
And who is this?
I have not seen you
in the cove before.
No.
( giggles )
She's, uh, visiting
from another colony.
I hurt my fin and she
helped me get back.
( gasps )
oona! You hurt your fin?
You must see the doctor
immediately.
See the doctor about what?
Oona hurt her fin!
Sven, relax.
Let's have a look.
Oh, all you need
is a little moon kelp.
Ooh! I'll get it!
Who's your friend?
Oh, this is sofia.
Sofia, this is cora,
my sister.
Big sister.
Pleased to meet you.
Here's the moon kelp.
I'll take that.
I can do it myself, cora.
It needs to be
put on just right.
There. How does that feel?
Good.
You really should be
more careful, oona.
I am careful.
What're you doing here anyway?
Mom qwanted me
to check on you.
I'm fine, cora.
I'm always fine.
Just checking.
Cora still treats me like
a little mer-baby.
That's what big sisters do.
I have 12.
So if this is your hideaway...
Where do the rest
of the mermaids live?
Oona hasn't shown
you the cove yet?
Oona, where are
your manners?
Let's show our guest around.
Give her a tour.
A tour?
Welcome to your
personal tour
of merroway cove
Provided by the savviest
seashorse in the 17 seas.
That's me.
Our tour begins right here
in oona's lovely shipwreck.
Hideaway.
If you say so.
Sofia, welcome to the cove!
♪ if you're surfing
across the ocean ♪
♪ for a nice place to stay
♪ been swimming around the dock
of every harbor and bay ♪
♪ well, look no further than our
little realm ♪
♪ you may be, under the sea,
but you'll be overwhelmed ♪
♪ you'll be so glad that you
dove ♪
♪ down into merroway cove
♪ our coral reefs are such
a lovely sight to behold ♪
♪ the water is not too warm
and never ever gets cold ♪
♪ our schools of fishies
have college degrees ♪
♪ and every shark I might remark
says "thank you" and "please" ♪
♪ you'll be so glad that you
dove ♪
♪ down into merroway cove
♪ see the kelp is awfully yummy
mwah. ♪
♪ and the fish
are nice and chummy ♪
Yeah!
♪ the crabs are
far from crabby ♪
♪ well, in fact,
they're down right blabby ♪
♪ through the seaweed
we can sneak ♪
♪ for a game of hide and seek
♪ in our underwater nook
♪ every party's off the hook
♪ so, now we've reached the
final stop ♪
♪ on this our little tour
♪ it's got
a thousand windows, yeah, ♪
♪ but not a single door
♪ a castle of coral where
mermaids reside ♪
♪ won't you stay
just for the day ♪
♪ and I'll show you inside
♪ you'll be so glad that you
dove ♪
♪ I'm so glad that I dove
♪ you found a treasure trove
♪ here in merroway cove
♪ throw every care away
♪ troubles all
will wear away ♪
♪ 'cause you're
in merry ol' merroway... ♪
♪ cove
♪ it's nautical and it's nice
♪ it's a virtual paradise
♪ merry old merroway cove
Yeah!
( giggles )
( gasps )
wormy!
It's the mermaid comb!
So, do you wanna
see my castle?
I'd love to.
Is that who I think it is?
It's amazing.
Oh, it's the princess,
all right.
I don't know how she turned
herself into a mermaid,
But I will not
let her stop me
From getting that magical
mermaid comb!
Huh?
Why is it getting so dark?
What is that?
Your floating palace.
Look out!
Oop!
Oona. Mom wants us back
at the castlle.
But cora--
now.
Hurry.
I have to go, sofia.
Maybe I'll see you later?
What's going on, cora.
Why does she want to see us?
You'll find out
when we get there.
No one ever tells
me anything.
The ship has stopped,
your majesty,
But they haven't cast
any nets yet.
Oh, thank goodness.
You're both safe.
Why wouldn't we be?
A human vessel
is in the cove.
Oh, mom. It's not like humans
are dangerous or anything.
Yes, they are.
No, they're not.
Who are you?
I'm sofia.
What's your name?
I'm plank. The senior
advisor to the queen.
Are you from this colony?
Sofia's my new friend.
Hi.
Well, you and oona
are too young
To know what humans
are capable of.
The last time a ship
entered the cove,
Years before you were born,
A few mermaids were playing
near the rocks at the surface.
The humans tried
to capture one of us.
Luckily,
a storm came
And sank the
ship before anyone was caught.
Is that the shipwreck
that oona always plays in?
She prefers
the term hideaway.
Yes, the very one.
But many of our
people were hurt.
This is the reason we avoid
going up to the surface, oona.
If the humans in that ship
discover we're down here,
We could all be in grave danger.
But they don't mean any harm.
Queen emmaline, there is
only one course of action.
We must remove
the ship from our cove.
No!
You can't do that!
It sounds like we have to.
But how?
With the queen's trident.
It has the power
to change the weather.
Your majesty,
you could whip up a storm
That blows the ship
right out of the cove.
Sounds a little drastic, plank,
don't you think?
But a storm is a hard
thing to control, plank.
If it grows too large,
it could sink the ship.
Then so be it.
No!
Easy now, big fella.
What's the matter?
You wake up
On the wrong side
of the sea bed this morning?
There has to be
another way.
Do you have a better idea?
Yes. I could get the humans
to move the ship on their own.
And how could you do that?
Because its' my ship.
Well, my dad's ship.
( all gasp )
You're not
making any sense.
You're a mermaid.
Well, not exactly.
I'm really a human.
What?
( all gasp )
I've never seen a human
who can change into our form.
Perhaps she's some
kind of witch.
A witch?
Sofia is not a witch.
She's my friend.
She helped me when I was hurt.
Cora, you saw.
All I saw is that
you hurt your fin.
Cora.
I saw them.
Sofia was helping
oona swim.
I can get the ship to
leave, your majesty.
Just give me the chance.
Please, mom.
We can trust her.
We can't trust any humans.
Plank. Sofia come forward.
Do you give your word that you
will move your ship immediately?
I do.
Then go, child.
Leave this cove
And never return.
I will, your majesty.
Thank you.
Goodbye, oona.
Bye, sofia.
With all due respect,
your majesty.
Everyone must be given the
chance to do the right thing.
Let me just
say that seahorses
Are very good judges of
character
Will do what she says,
your majesty.
No one asked you, sven.
No one ever does.
That's why I have to speak up.
It doesn't matter what we say,
sven.
It's not like anyone listens.
Sofia. Sorry about my mom.
She's not always like that.
Plank is, but my mom isn't.
That's alright, I understand.
It's just too bad
I have to go.
I mean, we just
became friends.
I know.
I'll miss you.
Me too.
Hello, there!
( screams )
Going so soon?
Don't be scared,
little mermaid.
I only need your comb.
( eleectric shock )
( screams )
The comb must have some kind
of protection charm on it.
Catch that mermaid, wormy!
( gurgles )
( coughs )
( sighs )
Help! Sofia!
Oona?
I'm coming!
Oh!
Pardon me, 'scuse me,
pardon me.
Out of my way, seafood!
Pardon me, 'scuse me...
I'm sorry, excuse me.
( yells)
( gurgles )
Well done, wormy.
( panting )
where did they go?
Oona? Oona?
Oona?
Excellent.
Now, let's take the
mermaid back to the boat
So I can find a spell that will
break the protection charm.
Oh, unless you'd like
to save us all the trouble
And hand over
the mermaid comb now.
Okay.
You mean it?
Never!
( groaning )
Oh, that was unwise.
And surprisingly painful.
But... I will get your comb
one way or another.
Let's go, wormy.
( gurgles )
Oona?
Oh, no.
Why isn't the ship
moving yet?
They haven't even
lifted the anchor!
Patience, plank.
Help! Help!
A sea monster took oona!
It chased her
into the kelp forest.
And then they disappeared.
Oona's gone?
That's not possible.
We all know there are no sea
monsters in these waters.
But I saw it!
The humans must have
taken oona captive
And sent the girl back
to lie to us.
That's not true!
Queen emmaline, use your trident
to conjure a storm so fierce,
It will sink the ship so we
can take oona back ourselves!
No!
( all gasping )
Then have your people
return my daughter at once.
I-- I can't!
Then you give me no choice.
Wait!
I'll find a way to bring oona
back.
I just need a little time.
Please, your majesty.
You have until sundown.
Okay.
We should sink
the ship now.
And endanger
all those people?
Plank, I know
what happened to you
The last time humans
were in the cove.
Follow the girl.
Just keep an eye on her.
And let me know
if you see oona.
I will, your majesty.
Mom, is oona going to be okay?
Of course, cora.
One way or another
we'll get her back.
Let me out,
you ugly sea monster.
Not until I get your comb.
And let's not get personal.
♪ bum, bum-bum, bum
Operation lunch rescue
has begun.
( humming )
Target has been spotted.
( yells, crashes )
You okay, mate?
( yells )
( both groaning )
Mission not accomplished.
Are you satisfied?
Now both of us
have lost our lunch.
My lunch.
It's nobody's lunch now.
Right, I'm off.
Come on, stop it!
Ow.
This is awkward.
Mm-hmm.
Your majesties,
Lunch is served
on the terrace.
Still getting our sea legs,
are we?
I've never felt better,
admiral hornpipe?
Baileywick,
will you find sofia
And let her know
it's time to eat?
Right away, your majesty.
Oh, probably back to her
room to finish her book.
Hmph. I don't know why anyone
would want to stay inside
On such a prefect day.
Sofia, wait!
What is it?
Let me look at you.
Hold still.
Hmm.
Seahorses always know when
someone is telling the truth.
And you were
telling the truth!
Which means oona really was
captured by a sea monster
We have to find her.
I'll help you look.
But she could be anywhere.
Then we'll search
the entire cove.
But we only have until
the end of the day.
Is there anyone in
that ship of yours
who can help us?
Sofia! There you are.
Baileywick, I need to talk
to mom and dad right away.
Look who I found.
Sofia! Why is your
hair wet?
You know you're
not supposed to go
swimming by yourself.
I need your help.
Something terrible
has happened.
What?
Well, it's a long story.
But... I met a mermaid.
You did?
No way!
Where is she?
I want to see her.
Amber! Sofia's
just kidding... Right?
No, dad. I really
met a mermaid.
Impossible!
But I did.
Her name's oona,
And we need
to rescue her.
From what?
A sea monster
kidnapped her,
admiral hornpipe,
And her mother,
the mermaid queen,
Thinks we took her,
so if we don't save
oona by sundown,
The queen is going
to make a storm
That is going to sink
our floating palace.
Ha! That's preposterous.
It does seem a little
farfetched, sofia.
It sounds... Like one
of the stories in
her mermaid book.
Well, perhaps sofia
fell asleep reading
her book
And dreamt about
all this balderdash.
It's not balderdash.
So then, can we meet
one of these mermaids?
Well... No.
You can't.
Not right now.
'cause oona's missing,
And the others are too scared
to come up to the surface.
Well, there you have it.
Either she dreamt it,
Or she's making it up.
Sofia doesn't make
things up.
She's always pretending
to talk to that bunny of hers.
Clover. He'll help me.
I gotta go.
( audibly struggling )
Still awkward!
Clover, I've been looking
everywhere for you.
Oh. What happened?
This seagull took my lunch.
The lunch you took
from the galley.
Where else was I supposed
to get it?
Oh, it doesn't matter.
I really need your help.
Are you two talking?
What does it look like
we're doing?
Oona's in trouble.
Oona the mermaid?
You know her?
Yeah.
A sea monster
kidnaped her.
A sea monster?!
Can you help me
look for her, clover?
Sure, kid.
I'll hop up to the top
of the palace.
Oh, I bet you could see
the whole cove from up there.
Righto. And I'll
search from the air.
You will?
Thanks, mr. Seagull.
Well, thanks
mr. Farley seagull.
I'm going back in the water.
Oh, I hope we can find her.
We will.
( audibly struggling )
Whew. One step down...
Way too many to go.
Huh? Where are they going?
And where's oona?
( merpeople muttering )
Plank. Any news?
The girl went up to a ship,
Then came back in the water
and swam off.
Was oona with her?
No.
And need I remind you
that not only is oona
in jeopardy,
But so is the mermaid comb.
If the humans take it,
they'll have the power
Of the ocean
at their fingertips!
Use your trident.
Conjure a storm
that will sink
their ship.
Then we can swim
inside it
And take oona
back ourselves.
If we sink their ship,
the humans could all perish.
But mom,
we can't just
let them keep oona.
I'll give them one more hour.
If your sister
isn't released by then,
We will bring their ship
to the bottom of the cove.
You can keep me in here
as long as you want.
I'm never giving up my comb.
I promised my mother
I wouldn't let anyone
else have it.
Oh, then it'll be
a terrible shame
When that promise
is broken,
Because
the mermaid comb
of merroway cove
Will be mine!
This spell is going
to undo the magic charm
Protecting your comb
And deliver it
right into the palm
of my hand!
Oh, I mean flipper--
Er, whatever this is.
( clears throat )
Forces of magic,
with power beyond
measure,
Break the enchantment
And bring me the treasure!
But what-- what is that?
( exclaims )
Didn't work.
( comical shrieking )
Oh, wormy, I'll get you
back in the water.
I'll have to find
another spell.
( gasps )
oona!
Okay. Sofia's gonna
owe me big time for this.
( sighs ) pretty good
view from up here.
( gasps )
No rats on my ship!
Hold up!
Stop! Whoa, I say!
Off with it!
You are just as
heavy as you look,
you know that?
Are you kidding me?
I must have shed
five ounces
Climbing up
all those stairs.
I found oona.
You did?!
Yeah, but now
I can't find sofia.
Hey, there she is.
Down there!
We should keep looking.
I'm going to check in
with clover.
Maybe he saw something.
Right. And who is
clover, exactly?
Clover: Sofia!
Huh?
Aah!
Thanks for
the soft landing.
Sofia, the sea monster
has oona on a boat.
Where?
You.
!
Wait. You're going alone?
No. Farley and spin
are going with me.
No one else believes me,
so I have to try myself.
Be careful, sofia.
Yes!
Now, this spell
Will surely get that comb.
( clears throat )
Suspendus denati
venite!
Aaaahhh!
Merlin's mushrooms!
I'll have to consult
my other spell books.
Hmm. Which book?
Ah!
The joy of sorcery.
Yes. Perfect.
Farley!
( gasps )
sofia!
Where's that monster?
Up there.
He's trying to steal
my enchanted comb.
Don't worry.
I'll get you out.
Where's the key?
I don't know.
( sofia gasps )
There it is!
( muttering )
( exclaims and mutters )
( gasps )
Aah!
Go, sofia!
Hurry!
♪ not so fast!
The key! No!
Oh, where'd it go?
What happened?
Did you see a key?
A key, a key, a key.
What's a key?
We've got to find it.
Oh, well, I was aiming
for the princess,
Not the key,
but not to worry--
I still have you.
( devious chuckle )
( moans )
I can't wait any longer.
It's time we take matters
into our own hands.
Everyone, go back to your
homes until we return.
Plank, let's go
get my daughter back.
Yes, your majesty.
I'm coming too.
No.
It's going to be
too dangerous up there.
But she's my little sister,
And I'm supposed
to look out for her.
We will find oona,
I promise.
( sighs )
Looks like
a storm's coming!
It's not coming.
Queen emmaline
is bringing it.
Whoa.
Ohh! Daddy?
It's just a little
squall, amber.
( amber gasps )
Baileywick, can you
make sure sofia's all right?
I'll go check on her.
The queen is going to sink
my family's ship.
Let's tell her we found oona.
She won't believe me.
No one believes me.
I don't know
what else to do.
Uh, your necklace
is glowing.
What's that?
Let's find out.
Ariel?
Princess ariel?!
What are you doing here?
Sofia's amulet
brought me here to help.
Now, what's going on,
sofia?
My friend oona
is in trouble.
I tried to save her,
but...
You couldn't do it
on your own?
No.
We all need a little
help sometimes.
Once, prince eric
needed my help
when his ship sank.
My family's ship
is in danger, too.
Mm-hmm. Well, luckily,
There's one answer
to both your problems.
There is?
Follow me.
♪ you tried to save
your mermaid friend ♪
♪ but found it hard to do
♪ you think your quest
♪ is at an end
♪ but that is far from true
♪ for though our worlds
have different ways ♪
♪ there's one thing
that we share ♪
♪ we both adore
our families so ♪
♪ with love
♪ beyond compare
♪ whether you live on land
♪ or sea
♪ we're all devoted
to our family ♪
♪ alone you cannot win
♪ you need a helping fin
♪ the love we share
♪ can set them free
♪ joining together
♪ is the key
♪ for if our two worlds
work in harmony ♪
♪ you could
end your troubles ♪
♪ if only they would see
♪ the love we share
♪ can set them free
♪ right there is a mermaid
who wants to save her sister ♪
♪ show her that you
feel the same ♪
♪ and you may just
enlist her ♪
Both:
♪ joining together
♪ is the key
♪ we have to learn
to work in harmony ♪
♪ you could
end your trouble ♪
♪ if only she could see
♪ no matter where
♪ in sea or air
Both:
♪ the love we share
♪ will set
♪ them free
Thanks, ariel.
I know what to do now.
Sofia, what mermaid
is gonna trust a human?
A mermaid whose little
sister is in trouble.
You!
Just cool your fins, cora.
Where's my sister?
Sofia is telling
the truth.
I saw the sea monster
with my own eyes.
Both of them.
You did?
He's after oona's comb,
and he knows magic.
You're oona's big sister,
and the only way to save her
Is for us to work together.
You said the monster
wants oona's comb?
That's what she told me.
Then we have to free her
before he gets it.
It has the power
to control the ocean.
It does?
Mom gave the comb to oona
So no one
would abuse its powers.
But she doesn't even
know what it can do.
She should have
given it to me.
I know how to use it.
And then oona wouldn't
be in danger.
So will you help me?
Anything for oona.
( storm rumbles )
Ohh! But what
about the storm?
We have to stop it
before it gets too big
And sinks our palace.
Don't worry.
I can stop queen emmaline.
You and what army, sven?
( whistles sharply )
( all clamoring )
this one, cora.
Actually, this is just
the immediate family.
We'll pick up the cousins
on the way.
Let's hit the waves, gang!
Come on!
Where are you, sofia?
Ohh!
Aha!
What are you doing back here?
Oona's still in danger,
So I thought you and I
could team up.
We'll be unstoppable.
Operation mermaid
rescue has begun.
♪ dunh dunh dunh dunh
dunh dunh dunh dunh! ♪
The storm isn't
big enough yet.
Bring forth a typhoon.
( sighs )
so be it.
( audibly struggling )
What's wrong?
My trident!
We got it!
Let's go, fellas!
( all celebrating )
Give the queen
her trident!
Sven! What's
gotten into you?
Oona was taken
by a sea monster.
I saw her!
You did?
Impossible!
The human must have
bewitched you, sven.
Give the queen
her trident.
Sorry, plank, no can do.
Sven! Get back here!
Your majesties.
Did you find sofia?
She's not in her room,
But I have all the servants
looking for her.
I'll bring her here
as soon as we find her.
Okay, but be quick.
At last,
I have found the spell
That will retrieve
your comb!
Eclypso facto!
Break the charms
And float into
my waiting arms!
Nooooo!
Not so fast,
mr. Sea monster!
Give me the comb,
and I'll let your
mermaid friend go.
Don't give it to him,
sofia.
Don't worry. I have a plan.
What are you going to do
if I don't give it to you?
Make me vanish or something?
Yes! That's exactly
what I'll do!
No!
Sofia!
Oh, you leave me no choice!
Vanitzo wayfaria!
You tricked him?
Uh-huh.
But you won't
trick me again!
Aaahhhh!
Blackout device
deployed!
Clover!
Magic wand secured.
Magic wand unsecured.
Your animal friends
Can't help you this time.
But my mermaid friend
can! Cora!
( gasps ) cora!
Cora!
Waters rise at my command!
( gasps )
aaahhhh!
Aaaaaaahhhhhhhh!
Thanks for
rescuing me, sofia.
It wasn't just me.
Oona!
Cora!
You saved me!
I guess having a big sister
Looking out for me
isn't such a bad
thing after all.
Here.
This belongs to you.
Thanks.
Maybe you can show me
how to use it some time.
Sure... If mom lets me.
Right.
Come on! We have
to find your mom!
Swim, seahorses, swim!
Sven!
Mom!
Oona!
You're all right!
Thanks to sofia.
What?
You were wrong
about her, plank.
We all were.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what to say.
( storm rumbles )
Ohh! I have to
stop that storm.
Your majesties.
Did you find sofia?
Not yet. But--
Your majesties, wait!
Wait for us!
Miranda! Is that
what I think it is?
( gasps )
it's a mermaid.
A mermaid!
Is she making
the storm go away?
I don't know.
Barnacles,
it's a mermaid!
Look!
The storm's breaking up!
Your family's
going to be okay.
Aaahhh!
You know, you
don't have to drop me
every time we land.
I know. But I enjoy it.
( giggling ) oona,
can you wait here?
Sure.
I'll be right back.
Mom! Dad!
Thank goodness
you're all right!
I'm sorry
we doubted you,
sofia.
It's okay, dad.
So, do you want to meet
the mermaids?
Right now?
Yeah!
You bet I do!
Uh, I mean, why not?
I think it's about time
we all became friends.
Oh! Sofia! I knew you were
telling the truth all along!
What are we waiting for?
Let's go see them!
Oh! Hi!
Whoa! She's got a tail
and everything!
She's a mermaid, james.
Try to keep up.
This is my friend oona.
Oona, this is my family.
Hi.
Hi!
Hey!
Pleased to meet you, oona.
Well, hello there!
Do you want to meet my family?
We'd love to!
That's oona's sister, cora.
Oh! Hmm!
Whoa!
Oh, my.
This is my mom,
queen emmaline.
Your majesty. It is an honor
to make your acquaintance.
The honor is mine.
Oooh!
Water to air,
sea to land...
Turn us back
to bird and man.
Whoa!
Well, at least
that spell worked.
Come along, wormy.
I need a vacation.
Ohh.
I love your headband, cora.
What's it made of?
Whoo-hoo!
Oh!
James!
( all laugh )
( sofia giggles )
I'm glad everyone's
getting along.
Me too! It means
we can be friends now.
It means we can all
be friends now.
♪