♪ I came from the city ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Got my name from the city ♪
♪ Where ♪
♪ The most dangerous city ♪
♪ Let's take a trip back ♪
♪ Back into time ♪
♪ 1977 ♪
♪ It was maximum crime ♪
♪ The president neglected us ♪
♪ Him and six masterminds ♪
♪ Six powerful men
Put New York through some drastic times ♪
♪ The rich and selfish ones ♪
♪ Feed off the welfare ones ♪
♪ And which borough suffered the worst?
♪
♪ Where I'm from ♪
♪ The Bronx ♪
♪ We had to rumble
With rivals on the rubble ♪
♪ While buildings around us
Would crumble, unh ♪
♪ I dreamed right ♪
♪ But it seemed like
Nothing find me but trouble ♪
♪ I see the light ♪
♪ It's right there
At the end of the tunnel ♪
♪ Had to find my rope ♪
♪ To pull me up ♪
♪ 'Cause I needed some kind of hope ♪
♪ To fill me up ♪
♪ Till I met one guy ♪
♪ Took me under the wing ♪
♪ I could have died if this man
Ain't intervene ♪
♪ He was an orphan
My savior ♪
♪ Free-spirited ♪
♪ No man braver ♪
♪ He was honored and gifted ♪
♪ His name was Shaolin Fantastic ♪
♪ The lady-killing romantic ♪
♪ Can't forget the day we met
And this story recants it ♪
-♪ But yo, my life began last year ♪
-♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Southmore High School ♪
♪ That summer I saw her
Said to myself ♪
♪ She'll be my wife soon ♪
Mylene, Mylene
- ♪ Grown up in a broken city ♪
- My butterscotch queen
-Mylene, Mylene
-♪ I've seen shame but I don't want pity ♪
-Mylene, Mylene, Mylene
-♪ Maybe I'm too young... ♪
Mylene, Mylene
My butterscotch queen
This summer
Could you be my girl
And I could be your king?
I beg your pardon
But I been loving you
Since first day of kindergarten
I blush when you see me
I cry when you sing
'Cause when you sing, it's like...
♪ 'Cause I will not forget ♪
-♪ The love you gave ♪
-It's like...
- It's like how red velvet feel
That's how you sing
I pray to God
you ain't burning up my eggs, boy.
Ooh!
Aww!
Whoo! Whoo! Whoo!
You ain't got but one responsibility
in this house.
-Not fucking up my breakfast.
-I'm sorry.
Pshh...
"When you sing
-It's like how red velvet feel"
-Come on, man. Get off.
"That's what it's like when you sing
Tender, like crying tears"
Give me that.
Leave him alone, Leon.
Morning, Queen Sheba.
Zeke.
- Keep your head out the clouds please?
. That's my point exactly.
Which reminds me, later on,
me and you gonna have a conversation
about the damn toothpaste.
What conversation you need to have
with my nephew about toothpaste?
Mylene, when you sing
Boy go through toothpaste
like he work at Colgate.
- When you render your splendor
- Tumbleweed on his head.
-Bathroom look like a pubic rain forest.
-I surrender to the tender you engender
His mama would not want
his father figure going easy on him.
Father figure?
- Rasping gasping love song
- Come on, now.
Don't get me started on the toilet tissue.
Boy must have the cleanest drawers
in the Bronx.
-One of us gotta be clean.
-Whoa, Shakespeare.
Enjoy your last day of school,
'cause come summertime,
I'll make a working man out that ass.
Take a shower, Leon.
♪ 'Cause I will not forget
The love you gave ♪
- ♪ But be that as it may ♪
♪ Every night I pray ♪
♪ For brighter stars
More golden days ♪
♪ And to be taken far away ♪
♪ Be that as it may ♪
♪ I know it's wrong for me to stay ♪
♪ I cannot bear these shades of gray ♪
♪ So now I'm on my way ♪
♪ Be that as it may ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ I will not ♪
♪ Forget the love ♪
♪ You gave ♪
So, I think that was the one, right?
-Mylene.
-What?
My God. That was--
-Did it sound professional?
-That was superflicious.
What's "superflicious"?
-"Superflicious"?
-Yeah.
"Superflicious" is super
plus official plus delicious.
That's not a real word.
It is if I say it is.
So, after school we take this
direct to Marrakesh Records, right?
-It don't work like that.
-How you know?
They don't accept submissions.
I looked it up.
Caught red-handed.
You know Daddy don't allow anything
but church music in here.
Don't tell Papi, please.
Only if you hand out the pamphlets.
Coming.
♪ Hand me down my walking cane ♪
♪ Hand me down my hat... ♪
- Good morning, my sweet angel.
- Good morning, Dad.
Come on, son.
You missing spots over here.
We're gonna be late for school, Dad.
No, Boo-Boo, you make yourselves late.
Wait to the last minute
to do your morning chore.
Ooh!
- That's jive.
- No, that's jive.
Come on.
This ain't Little House on the Prairie.
-Dizzee's got a point, Dad.
-No, he don't.
'Cause that there is my little house.
And this here is my little salon.
And that patch of sidewalk,
that's my little prairie.
Less than a hundred years ago,
the Bronx was all prairie.
Winston!
What are you rattling on about?
What's going on?
You gonna make the boys late for school.
How am I supposed to teach them discipline
if you undermine me?
I have to go to the writer's bench.
- All right.
- Don't be late.
♪ Do-do, do, do-do... ♪
They're like,
"Who you gonna give your demo to?"
-I don't know. Different people.
-Maybe I could help.
Smoke this joint with me?
Mylene, I know you enough
to know you got a plan.
-Do you really think it was any good?
-Yeah, Mylene.
It's better than the original.
-Misty Holloway?
-Yeah.
Come on. Be serious, Zeke.
You sounded as good as she does on that,
remix you always talking about.
-Carlo Pakoussa?
-Yeah.
I wish.
Zeke's about to
pop the big question to Mylene.
And tonight we all gonna see Star Wars.
Mylene ain't seeing no Star Wars.
And tell Zeke not to waste his breath
'cause my girl got big plans.
Her life's about to change.
She gonna turn him down flat.
Mylene, can I tell you something?
When you sing, it's like...
how red velvet feel.
That's how you sing.
Like how butterscotch taste.
Warmed up though,
like how they serve it sometimes?
You sounded like that.
You're tender, like...
like crying tears tender.
And at the end,
right there at the finale...
Damn, holy shit.
Your roar is a motherfucker, girl.
Yeah, you talk good.
Ain't talk when it's true.
God. I'm sorry.
We don't do this no more.
But we could.
-No.
-But it's not like we do it all the time.
Or ever, really.
-Ay, bendito, don't be difficult.
-But--
What are you doing tonight, for real?
We can go see Star Wars together. Hey.
I want you to be my girl.
No. I got plans.
-What you talking about?
-Okay. Can you keep a secret?
Yeah.
Okay, so tonight, Regina's getting me
and the girls into Les Inferno.
Les Inferno? Are you crazy?
- Gangsters be there and shit!
- Shut up.
I'm sleeping at Yolanda's
'cause it's easier to sneak out.
DJ Malibu is spinning there tonight.
There's a dance competition. The winner
gets to have dinner with Malibu.
That's what the tape's for.
I'm gonna win the dance-off,
get him the tape
so he can listen to it and say:
"Shit,
she's the next Donna Summer."
And then sign me to his label.
That is so stupid.
Okay, I'll tell her.
- You're stupid.
- Mylene!
Ven aqui! Daddy wants to see you.
I told him you were singing devil music
and he said--
Thy voice shall only be lifted
to the glory of God.
But, Papi, Ezekiel and I were just
preparing for Sunday's service.
-Okay?
-Sorry, I--
Should I ask Ezekiel
which hymn you were singing?
That's not what your sister told me.
This is the last time you do this.
What you gonna do?
Sucker.
Your sister said that you made a tape
singing that dirty Donna Summer's music?
Actually, Dad, it's Misty Holloway.
- So, it was disco?
- Mylene!
Yo, Ra.
- You are in my church!
- Bye, Mylene.
Straighten out or get out of my house.
Get the fuck out.
-Yo, Zeke! Still ain't getting none?
-Mind your own.
I thought you was smart?
It ain't never gonna happen!
You are grounded again.
You will not be sleeping
at Yolanda's tonight.
-Papi!
-Looks ugly this time, man.
Be home by 10, go to your room
and study the word of God.
What?
Mama, por favor, you promised me
I could stay at Yolanda's tonight.
Please, don't provoke him.
Your father's word is final.
-10 p.m.
-You always take his side, man!
Go!
- Yo, what's got you down, girl?
- God!
-Yo, did you ask her?
-Man, I tried.
What? What you mean, you tried?
My dad's tripping, man.
He's not gonna let me go out tonight.
That means I won't be able
to get my tape to DJ Malibu.
She's dead set
on going to Les Inferno tonight.
Les Inferno?
-Yeah.
-Man, that's an epic turn of events, bro!
You gotta get in with a lady.
Those Holy Rollers go to bed early.
We'll wait till your parents are asleep
and then we'll sneak you out.
You'll be back before
anybody knows anything.
♪ Hey, I'm getting some dick tonight
And the feeling's all right ♪
♪ 'Cause my pussy is tight ♪
Yeah!
- ♪ Hey, you ♪
♪ You're losing, you're losing
You're losing, you're losing ♪
♪ Your vitamin C ♪
♪ And you ♪
♪ You're losing, you're losing
You're losing... ♪
See, Shaolin was in the yards,
and saw the dude hot one-ten,
and so he karate-chopped his ass.
Waa-taa!
And that's how the war started.
- How do you know? You talk to Shao?
- Dude, shut up.
No one's ever even seen Shao,
let alone talked to him.
It's not a war they're fighting.
But for all of us.
When we see our names on these trains,
if only even for a fleeting moment,
we can say: "I was here."
Crash, you paint spotlights
and Bat-signals.
Daze, you paint constellations,
breadcrumb trails of sparks
that tell a story.
Shao 007,
man...
his Pumas are always pristine.
His hands are samurai swords.
And his pieces, they're all fireworks.
Big, bright, explosive.
Have you seen Shao's latest?
"Clan of the Dragon Fist."
Wait.
Shaolin Fantastic has a new piece?
-I gotta check it. Where's it at?
-The rubble fields, by Charlotte Street.
- I'm out of here.
- You crazy!
- You're going now?
- Savage Warlords territory, you can't--
A life lived in fear is a life half-lived.
-Say what?
-Ciao for now.
♪ You're losing, you're losing... ♪
Rumi... I like him.
He's weird, though.
♪ Hey, you... ♪
Graffiti vandalism
is a symptom of a far greater sickness.
The colossus on the Hudson
has fallen deathly ill.
Unemployed, crime ridden, graffiti-soaked,
the city's bankruptcy has put its finances
in the hands of un-elected businessmen,
and so the mayoral election is heating up.
Mayor Beame is in bad trouble.
I'm confident we can improve
the quality of life here in our city.
But underdog candidate
Ed Koch is not so sure.
Our mayor's a failure.
Graffiti and crime plague our streets.
Instead of taking responsibility,
he hands responsibility
to corrupt local leaders.
Poverty pimps like Francisco Cruz
in the Bronx.
Cruz lines his pockets
with your tax dollars
while claiming to provide services
to his people.
They're bleeding our resources dry.
Ed Koch for mayor.
Tough, competent, tireless and fair!
What did this Koch call me?
"Poverty pimp,"?
He gets elected,
your whole operation here goes away.
No one will do more for you
than the mayor can.
Koch is a loser.
I'll help Beame get elected,
but if your boss wants votes, he's gotta
help me build something special.
Looks like the goddamned Taj Mahal.
The Charlotte Street Taj Mahal.
You tell the mayor
he has a very simple choice.
Lose the election...
or fund my vision.
So, in order to meet with Malibu,
Mylene gonna have to dance
in a contest at Les Inferno?
All the hustlers up there.
-She gonna fuck around and get turned out.
-Not Mylene.
She ain't like that.
Is she?
Clan of the Dragon Fist!
Over on Charlotte Street.
Clan of the Dragon Fist.
-Your brother's a fucking weirdo.
-You have no idea.
I'm talking about Shao 007.
A new piece on Charlotte Street.
Clan of the Dragon Fist.
But that's Savage Warlords territory!
But it's Shaolin Fantastic.
So, take a deep breath and follow!
Come on.
Shaolin Fantastic, man.
Clan of the Dragon Fist.
Dizz, it's a master blaster.
Yo, tonight, we go to the yards.
You gotta let your hero know you exist.
Not so loud, Boo.
I feel like we're being watched, y'all.
Probably by Shaolin.
I think I seen Shaolin Fantastic
the other day.
No way.
Up on the roof. Flying.
Right there. Roof to roof.
- You see his face?
- No, but I saw the red Pumas.
I heard Shaolin's so slick,
he snuck into Yankee Stadium
and stole Chambliss'
walk-off home run bat.
He fearless, man.
You gotta be
to live in Savage Warlord territory.
-Dizz, man.
-What's up, Boo?
You afraid of Warlords?
I ain't afraid of no stupid Warlords.
Seriously, though,
can we please go now?
Fuck y'all doing on our turf, punks?
We writers, little man, not gangsters.
All we find, all we keep.
Y'all got money?
I said all we find, all we fucking keep!
-Who the fuck y'all looking at?
-Little nigga, let me talk to you.
-Don't touch me.
-Hey, hey!
Boo!
Hey, Boo. Hey, get back, stop!
Savage Warlords are gonna
beat your ass, fuckers!
Get the hell off me!
- Leave my fucking brother alone!
- Get off me.
After I smash his ugly face.
Napoleon!
We told you to fucking look out
and you taking these fools off
for their lunch money?
Yo, bounce.
The fuck's wrong with you?
You begged to be our lookout
at Les Inferno tonight,
-but you can't handle the responsibility!
-Oye, oye, oye.
-Savage Warlords, be on your way.
-Yo, it's Papa Fuerte!
- Everybody else, to school!
- Come on.
Let's go!
Pa fuera de la calle. Fuera de la calle.
- Yo!
- Run! Run!
Anybody wants some static,
still be there by the time I count three.
Uno, dos, tres.
Ha!
Que pendejo.
He reminds me of me.
Come on, Stanley, join the party.
"Clan of the Dragora Fist."
I can never make heads or tails
of this graffiti shit.
I'll tell you what, Stanley.
You bring me art classes, art supplies,
and art teachers for our schools here,
and I promise you,
this right here is gonna be
hanging at the MoMA,
not on the side of some
burnt-out buildings or the five train.
Look at that.
Landlord's paying these gangs
to burn buildings
to collect the insurance money.
I got an epidemic on my hands here,
but I gotta hear it
from the fire chief over at Engine 71
that you closed two more firehouses?
I'm down four fucking firehouses
in the last nine months here, Stan.
-The mayor knows he owes you.
-Fuck the mayor!
Listen up. I know some of y'all are gonna
want to make some money this summer,
so remember, Francisco Cruz is offering
paying summer jobs and internships.
Make sure you visit his center,
tell him Ms. Green sent you. I want you
to live with confidence this summer, okay?
Okay, settle down!
Settle down! We are not done yet.
And I got plenty of detention slips
if y'all want to keep acting a fool.
Now, as promised,
it is time for me to announce the winner
of the poetry writing contest.
Imani, please sit.
The winner for the best poem is...
Ezekiel Figuero.
- Aww.
- Everybody applaud. Come on.
My God.
-Faggot!
-Hey.
Faggot.
All right, that's enough, quiet down.
- Brainiac bitch.
- Okay, Ezekiel.
Come on up and get your prize
and recite your poem.
...I can't. I hurt my back.
Is that right? That's fine.
I'll come to you.
Ooh!
-Thanks, Ms. Green.
-"Thanks, Ms. Green."
Mock him again
and I'm going Lady Macbeth on your ass!
- Fuck you.
- Ooh!
I'd like for you to read your poem,
Ezekiel.
Yeah, I'd rather not.
Why not?
Because, I didn't write it.
I copied it from a book. That's all.
Here's your candy back. I'm sorry.
Why you lying?
Whoo! We outta here.
Ezekiel Figuero...
- we need to talk. Okay, everybody.
- Meet me by the flagpole.
Have a great summer.
I'm going to miss you.
- You're my favorite teacher.
- Have a good one. Take some good pictures.
You know, Ezekiel really did write
that poem. Unfortunately, you know,
he's not manly enough
to stand up and admit it.
-Mylene.
-Zeke.
Come on.
Have a great summer, Ms. Green.
-You have a great summer, baby.
-Okay.
Look out onto that vista there, Stanley.
Tell me what you see.
I see a national disgrace.
I see something beautiful, Stan.
I see houses.
Like that model in my office.
Not projects that were built to segregate
and warehouse the working poor.
I see homes, Stan.
Homes for my rainbow people.
I see ball fields for the kids.
A library, right over there.
Full of kids nourishing
their intellectual curiosity.
Prepping for internships,
colleges and good jobs. And over there,
what the hell, a man-made lake.
With ducks, Stan.
I see a proud community. And I see
my contractors building that lake
and constructing these homes.
I see a new South Bronx,
an attainable future for my people.
-That's a hell of a dream, Cisco.
-No, it's not a dream, Stanley.
Your mayor sucks.
Everybody knows it.
In your own words,
he's desperate for me to deliver
20,000 new voters for the primary, right?
- Twenty-five.
- Well, I'm gonna deliver 50,
you keep the change.
Mira, I did the research, Stan.
And those houses are gonna cost
at least ten million.
And your midget mayor,
he's gonna pick up the tab.
-Ten million don't--
-If the mayor wants my loyalty
and my votes and the blood of my people,
then that ten million comes directly
right the fuck here!
I'll make it happen. Okay? You happy?
I'm always happy, Stan.
Sadness is for suckers.
Come on, we'll get an egg cream.
But, Ms. Green, your poetry contest
was poetry writing, not poetry reciting.
So, you did write it.
-I didn't say that.
-I don't know why it is, Ezekiel,
that you seem to want to be nothing,
when with just a little courage...
you could really be something.
I got courage.
No, you don't.
Leaders lead.
Cowards cower.
Now I understand
that your poem is personal.
I understand that it might make you
feel uncomfortable to share it.
But take a look around.
The Bronx is a war zone.
Our community is dying.
And it's gonna take leaders to save it.
That means you.
That is why I have been trying
to get you to stand up
and share your gift with the class.
But every time, you take the easy way out.
Well, luckily for you, I'm probably
not gonna be in school next year.
How would your mother and father feel
if they were alive?
To hear you talking like that?
You live with your aunt and her boyfriend,
right?
Do you think that they took on the burden
of raising you
just so you could drop out of school?
Be dead,
be in jail by the time you turn 21?
-I don't know.
-You don't know.
Maybe I was wrong about you.
Maybe you really didn't write this poem.
I wrote it.
Then prove it.
Boom, then crash
The shattering of glass
I dived to the floor
Busted my ass
"What the hell was that?"
Was all that I said
Then I seen a pool of blood
Then I see my moms was dead
No emotion in the commotion
I wasn't even sad
Even when I learned
That the bullet was meant for my dad
Vietnam made Pops crazy
He was already half-dead
So, why couldn't that have been him
That they shot in the head?
All the news that fits the print
Mama's death went unreported
Not a whiff, word or hint
"They don't care about us niggas"
Is how my pops explained it
But I didn't know I was a nigga
Until my dad proclaimed it
Six months later
My pops was dead, too
Drug-related shots fired
His skin turned cold blue
On the news that night
The president's wife got a new hairdo
The news guy said
"I like it. How about you?"
No word about my pops
In the Post or on CBS
Why was that, you ask?
Take a fucking guess
And, yeah, why is that?
Is what politicians should be asking
But who's got time for questions
When y'all skiing up on Aspen?
Bronx get gunshots to the head
And all y'all swerving us is Aspirin
My mama was so lovely
She would have made your head spin
Level the playing field
And y'all would see who would really win
And, yeah, I got anger
But I don't let it take me down
Because my mama taught me better
And she holds me up when I fall down
Rest in peace, Moms
Don't worry about your son
Someday I'll make you proud
Because, yeah, I am the one
Ezekiel...
there are opportunities out there
for your advancement.
Francisco Cruz, he...
♪ Step out in the limelight... ♪
What if Malibu will only listen to
your tape if you get down with him?
What you gonna do then?
Listen, he's not like that.
My God, Mylene.
You don't know nothing about the world.
So, you hit her with the poetry
and she still said no? That's cold.
I don't know, man.
I'm trying everything I got, Ra.
Well, listen, man.
Mylene's looking for a man.
Dress slick, right? Act smooth.
Savoir faire, man.
These are men, Mylene.
Look, it's different.
Like, last time I was there,
I met this dude, Little Wolf.
He's Cadillac's main man,
and I mean, he was so fine,
and like, he had gap!
I'm talking about g-money like this!
Took me to a high post hotel and stuff.
Howard Johnson's is high post?
Well, they had
good room service and champagne.
Listen, I'm gonna give you some advice.
You let Malibu take you to the hotel.
Shit.
You sing a sexy song for him
in your lingerie and shit.
Shake your little culo.
Culo?
That's how you get a record deal.
Fucking Howard Johnson, Ra?
You need to calm down, first of all.
Both of y'all need to calm down.
Fuck! You're right, Ra.
We gotta get into Les Inferno.
Stop.
you can't sweat a freak, man.
I'm not planning on getting down
with nobody, all right?
-You have to show up looking fly.
-Yeah.
-With the suave bolla. Okay?
-Suave-- Okay.
I just wanna meet DJ Malibu
and give him my tape,
so I can get out of my father's church
and never look back.
-That's it.
-You have to get her something. A gift.
Okay.
Not expensive
because you ain't got no money.
But, you know, something that says:
"I know you, girl.
I know you deep into your Taino
Puerto Rican punany, mamasita."
Don't talk about her like that.
Look, number one:
you need to be there to dance with her.
you need to be dangerous.
Okay.
Any dude that messes with her
gotta get the hammer.
Bang, bang. It's over.
Where the hell would I cop a gun?
It's a stupid idea.
-Stupid.
-Look, man.
The gun's a personal choice.
That Clan of the Dragon Fist piece
was fly.
But let it be your last,
and focus, Grasshopper.
Tonight your quest will end
and your journey will begin
if you bring me back the Pakoussa.
The Pakoussa? By Misty Holloway?
-Where is it?
-The Jamaican on Charlotte Street.
Protected by the Warlords, so watch out.
Bring me back the Pakoussa, Grasshopper.
Osu.
And Grasshopper!
Have you found yourself a wordsmith yet?
Not yet.
Then you must learn
to trust and choose wisely.
You're well-liked but always alone.
The journey requires a wordsmith.
Bring me the Pakoussa by midnight,
Grasshopper.
Whoo!
The gift.
It's a must-have,
and it's gotta be personal.
So, what's she like?
-Perfume? Clothes?
-That "Far, Far Away" joint.
-Misty Holloway?
-The remix, by Carlo Pakoussa.
She crazy for it. Plus, it's rare.
I heard they only made like 50 copies.
That Jamaican's spot
on Charlotte Street got rare stuff.
Boom! Get that shit.
- Get in the club.
- Yeah.
Get the DJ to play it.
-Okay. Yeah.
-Right?
Okay. Wait, wait, wait.
Then you take her in your arms.
You sweep her up,
and you dance a sexy hustle.
-♪ I party like this ♪
-Hey.
Right, nena. Good.
♪ I never felt quite like this ♪
Damn, look at you, girl.
-Okay. I see you, girl.
-All right? All right?
And you gonna claim your terrain,
Mandingo style. All right?
Okay, you gonna have to show me again
'cause I don't understand all that.
-You don't know how to hustle?
-No. I don't know what you just did.
Okay, look. You don't have to do that.
But you definitely have to get
that fucking record though.
- ♪ Wild in the streets ♪
♪ Wild in the streets ♪
♪ In the heat of the summer
Better call up the plumber ♪
♪ And turn on the street pump
To cool me off ♪
♪ With your newspaper writers
And your big crime fighters ♪
-Come on, Uncle Johnny.
-Why?
Napoleon, tell them to cut it out, yeah?
- What'd you say?
- Yeah.
What's this about you not signing
our new contract, Johnny?
"In exchange for 50 dollars a week,
we, the Savage Warlords, junior branch,
promise not to disturb Kingston Top Stop
Variety Store or its owner."
You double the price now?
Savage Warlords are mad as hell.
We'll take care of that.
You know how long me working here?
- Shut up and sign it.
- That's right.
I can't pay no $50 a week,
you evil midget.
Please, have mercy.
- Don't let the man take my record!
- Yo!
- I'll sign. I'll sign.
- Go! Go! Go!
Get the record!
Yeah!
♪ Wild in the streets ♪
- Hey! Damn!
- Aw, yeah!
Fuck.
- ♪ We got a gang called Shady ♪
- Cut him off! Cut him off!
- ♪ And a midnight lady ♪
♪ And two transvestites... ♪
Go! Let's go!
♪ You best believe us ♪
♪ Your teenage Johnny's ♪
♪ Gonna be a man ♪
♪ Wild in the streets... ♪
I'm gonna kill you!
- Yo, we got him.
- We got you now, boy!
No, no, no. Fuck.
Fuck!
Come on, man.
And yo, Shao...
that's when our journey began.
I'll never forget...
the first day we met.
Yeah.
Hey. Motherfucker!
Motherfucker!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey, yo, we're gonna get you, man!
That's right, you better run!
Keep running!
Hold it there.
-Yo, is that the record?
-Yeah.
Yes!
Yo, wait, wait, wait.
So, how much you pay, man?
...I got it for free.
-For free?
-Yep.
I almost got killed. Could've got killed.
Might still get killed.
Let's get off the street.
I got it for free.
All right. All right. Okay.
Dinner!
So, all y'all kids
going to the movies tonight?
Regina and I gonna go see
that new horror flick.
- Which one?
- Satan's Cheerleaders.
-I heard about that.
-Satan's Cheer--?
You boys going with them?
We're gonna see
that new metagalactic one.
-Um, Wars on Mars.
-Mars Wars.
I hate science fiction.
It's called Star Wars, fools.
Star Wars.
What about you, Mylene?
I--
-I have to be home soon.
-You sure you gotta go?
Yeah, my chariot
turns to a pumpkin at 9:45.
I see.
Okay, Dad. Okay. Okay.
- All right. Okay.
- That was real nice.
You wearing gloves now, son?
I told you, Dad, I'm into pop art now.
I quit writing graffiti.
Well, I just saw "Rumi 411" on the wall.
It's like a copycat thing, Dad.
If you get locked up again,
I'm gonna leave you in there, Dizz.
You gonna end up getting married
to a big old man named Mario.
Just watch your ass out there, son.
-You want a brownie, sugar?
-No time for brownies, love.
-Late for the solstice jam.
-What you gonna wear tonight?
Yo, not so loud.
I was thinking,
you can't be dancing
in this contest at Les Inferno
by yourself.
Maybe we could dance together.
Together?
You know they don't let kids in there.
- ...Planet Xenon!
- But you're a kid.
Yeah, but I'm female. And I'm fly.
I'm gonna project my aura
to Planet Wakoobee.
You be careful on your surfboard.
Please don't go.
I'm begging you. That place is evil.
Yo. No más, okay?
I'm going. That's that.
Love you.
All right, Boo, count six.
Rustoleum Federal Safety Purples.
Now, what do you do if Shaolin Fantastic
appears in the train yards?
- Run.
- Good.
'Cause Shao'll pull your pants down
and spray-paint your nut sack.
Exactly, Boo.
This Misty track is the joint.
Yo, Zeke ain't gonna get into
Les Inferno by himself, you know?
I just hope he doesn't keep asking me
'cause I can't, like, reject him again.
- Mylene.
- Poor Zeke.
-I feel bad for your man.
-Yolanda, Zeke is my friend.
-Not my man, okay?
-That means I could go out with him?
- I didn't say that.
- 'Cause you like him.
-Let's just figure out what I'm wearing.
-Yeah!
Now, if you do have to run
from Shaolin, remember,
what rail do you watch out for?
Duh. The third rail.
Yo, I heard he's called Shao 007
'cause he got a 7-inch weenie.
That's pretty average, Boo.
Up next. Gangs for hire.
A special report. Our fearless...
Very conservative.
It's not like any hustlers, gangsters
or pimps are gonna notice her.
You think so?
Ooh.
No, man. You gonna have to fly solo, man.
-Solo?
-To Les Inferno. You gotta go alone.
But when you storm the gates,
you need to dress to kill, man.
You need to be off the chain,
you need to be ready, okay?
-Okay. I'm ready.
-You ready?
-I'm ready.
Shh!
...most violent gang is also...
Let's go.
I'm ready.
The Savage Warlords
have begun dabbling in murder-for-hire.
A hit that left four dead last week
is being blamed on...
Yeah. Yeah.
I don't know about this, brother.
These are your father's fine vines.
My father don't care
about stuff like this.
This is the one.
I'm ready.
Damn straight.
You got the record.
I got the record.
-You're looking fly.
-I'm looking fly.
Remember,
you gotta be harder than hard up there.
-Be ready to fight anyone for your woman.
-She's mine.
What?
They never gonna let you in
with them rags on your feet.
- Two bodies found...
- Yeah, faster, baby. Yeah.
...casualties of a turf war
as Nicky Barnes of Harlem
and Fat Annie of the South Bronx fight
for control of the heroin trade north...
"And then the Lord laid the sins
of the father upon the child.
For though he is merciful,
even the righteous are born in sin
and must bear the iniquities
of their fathers."
- ♪ Talkin' 'bout bad, bad girls... ♪
Hey, girls.
My God.
See, I told you she coming.
That's right, girl.
I've got mad respect for you...
...and for that dress.
- Do you like it?
- Like it?
- Girl, you look almost as good as me.
- Shut up.
Malibu is gonna sign you for sure.
Girl, he better.
Let's go.
Keep looking real good.
- ♪ Hey, you ♪
♪ You're losing, you're losing
You're losing ♪
♪ You're losing
Your vitamin C ♪
Nice and quiet, Boo.
These lamps,
they belong to Shaolin Fantastic.
Shit. Check this out.
Shh!
He's here, Dizz. Look.
Don't worry. That's from
last week. But if you see the red Pumas--
I know. Run.
Who wants to get in?
Why you keep checking your watch, Wolf?
You got someplace to go?
Just waiting on your birthday cake, boss.
Ordered you a real special one this year.
Store-bought is fine by me.
Not like that Nicky Barnes.
What kind of drug lord poses
on the cover of Time magazine?
Mr. Untouchable..
Since that cover,
people calling Nicky "the king."
All hail the king.
-Nicky--
-"King"?
Shit.
Would Shaolin really come after us?
What'd he want from us?
I mean, I heard he's so rich
he got 100 pairs of Pumas.
I don't know. Yo, Boo.
Why you letting it drip like that?
What'd I teach you?
"Hold it upright."
Hold the can upright.
Move on. Move on. That's done.
But seriously.
You think he got enough money
for that many shoes?
Enjoy the music.
Shit. Nicky Barnes ain't got nothing
this birthday girl ain't got.
I got this here club,
plus the disco downstairs,
plus three after-hours joints,
prostitution, gambling,
numbers, a day-care center.
And I still got time to control
half the cocaine in the Bronx.
All Nicky do is sling dope.
And I'll tell you something else, Wolf.
Mark my words, this time next year,
I'm gonna take motherfucking Nicky Barnes
the fuck out
and expand to Harlem.
Sound good to you?
-Nephew?
-You the boss.
- All hail the queen.
- Here, here.
-That's right, motherfucker.
-I got the music.
You wanna check your watch
or you wanna play?
Shit.
You got my favorite song.
The greatest hits.
It's all there?
A quarter ounce in twenty-fives.
You sound like you expect
something different, boss.
I expect shit to be right.
Move that shit.
♪ Pulling me closer ♪
Well, look who's here.
Like Paul Revere.
Come kiss these dice for me, baby.
Hey, come on now,
you got a grip of my money right there.
And I'm about to get some more.
You know I like 'em young, right?
Yeah, I do. I remember.
Ha!
- Shit.
- Damn.
What'd I say? Hey.
Got you something sweet, Miss Annie.
- You got more manners than my own son.
- Happy birthday, Annie.
Thank you, sugar.
Now give me some sugar, baby.
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
So young and so fine,
like ripe blackberry wine.
That boy's gonna be a boss someday.
He's gonna rock it like a Rockefeller.
What's my name? What's my name?
'Cause I think you forgot.
First time I saw him out back
parking cars for nickels, said to myself:
"I'm gonna groom him real good."
♪ Burn, baby, burn ♪
- Yo!
- ♪ Burn, baby, burn ♪
- ♪ To my surprise ♪
♪ Listen ♪
♪ One hundred stories high ♪
- ♪ People gettin' loose, y'all ♪
- Whoo!
Whoo! Sailor.
Take it easy.
♪ Folks are screamin' ♪
♪ Out of control ♪
♪ It was so entertainin' ♪
♪ When the boogie started to explode
I heard somebody say ♪
♪ Burn, baby, burn ♪
What took your slow ass so long?
You know I can't dance
without my lucky lollipops.
Yo, Shaolin Fan-faggot.
Come here. Come here. Come here.
Come here. Come here.
Sit down. Sit down.
Come here.
My cousin here tells me
that you kissed my mama
on her big juicy lips.
Did you do that?
Did you slip her some birthday tongue?
See, what happened was I was turning
my head while she was kissing me.
Hey!
You see this fucking barboy?
Wanders in one day
off the motherfucking street.
What happened,
nobody wanted your little stank ass?
His mom was tricking,
and his pops is a bum.
Now, he think he run things around here.
But there's only one king around here.
- Shit.
- Disco King Cadillac.
-Get off me!
-I ought to pluck your eyeball out...
Get his ass, pay him for that shit.
...wear it around my neck
if you don't answer.
- Fuck off of me.
- Did you kiss my mama on the lips?
♪ Do it now, ha ♪
- Ladies. How you doing?
- Yo, Pito!
- Hey.
- Yeah.
- ♪ Once I was a boogie singer ♪
-Pito, baby.
-¿Cómo estás nena?
- ♪ Playing in a rock 'n' roll band ♪
Hi. Yeah.
- ♪ I never had no problems... ♪
- Hey, over here.
-Now, what's up? Talk to me, baby.
-Hey, come on. Let us go.
I'm a friend of Little Wolf.
This is my friend Mylene.
Hi.
- ♪ Got to start to feelin' so low ♪
- Over here. We wanna get in.
- ♪ And I decided quickly ♪
♪ To disco down and check out the show ♪
Get your fucking hands--
Get the fuck off me.
Did that hurt your feelings?
You should stay. He should stay.
Man, if you don't get
your fucking hands off me--
- The fuck you gonna do?
- The fuck am I gonna do?
♪ You're angelic in every way
You shine like the moon ♪
♪ Just take my hand and we'll levitate
Not a moment too soon... ♪
- How you doing?
- Whoo!
My God.
My God. Regina, you know these people?
Okay.
-Yo, who's that?
-♪ ...backseat of my Cadillac ♪
I think that's that young broad.
Little Wolf...
-♪ ...of my Cadillac ♪
-He took her to the Howard Johnson's.
♪ Let me take you there, you there... ♪
Look who's checking you out.
♪ Heaven's in the backseat
Of my Cadillac ♪
Yeah.
She ain't never been to a hotel before.
Sweet-ass pussy--
No, I'm talking about
the one next to her.
-Who is he?
-That's Cadillac. He runs this place.
- His moms is Fat Annie.
- And I'll bet you he knows Malibu.
And just wait till you
see him dance, girl..
Bring her to me.
He wins the dance-off,
like, every single week.
Wolves on the prowl.
My God.
Shit.
♪ Heaven's in the backseat
Of my Cadillac ♪
♪ Let me take you there ♪
Next.
Misty Holloway, "Far, Far Away"?
What the fuck? You trying to be a DJ?
I got money.
You don't have a woman with you,
I can't let you in.
-My woman's inside.
-Get off the line.
I have to get inside.
-Just take the money.
-Listen...
you're making yourself look bad,
especially with that record in your hand.
-Please. She's inside.
-Don't have a woman, I can't let you in.
-You cannot get in.
-Take the money.
-Get the fuck off the line, I said!
See, where I'm coming from as an
entrepreneur with fingers in many worlds,
you understand,
is that your mind has to be right
before you ever enter the Coliseum,
you understand?
You have to see yourself as a star.
I do.
And you are.
I see star all over you.
And I know one or two people
in that stratosphere.
Really?
Do you know Malibu?
Know Malibu?
I own Malibu.
I financed his label. You understand?
Wow, so...
you must think you're a real big man?
You ain't the first big man I met...
Cadillac.
I like your style.
I like it a whole lot.
Please, I will do anything.
-I have to get inside.
-You again?
-The fuck do you want?
-Please, I have to get inside!
-Nobody-- No.
-Please, just fucking take it.
-I don't want your fucking money.
-I have to get inside!
-You can't get inside.
-Don't touch--
Fuck you and your record, man.
-Fuck! Fuck outta here.
-Fuck you!
- Fuck you.
- Let me get that.
- Get the fuck out of here.
- I swear...
Mi gente, Malibu's here.
♪ She loves her daddy ♪
♪ Daddy, Daddy Cool... ♪
- I'll watch your car for a dollar.
- Watch his car for free.
-That's DJ Malibu, stupid.
-♪ Daddy, Daddy Cool ♪
-Yo, Malibu, anything you need, I got you.
Chicks, coke,
and a crate of Paul Masson champagne.
Yo!
Where's my record?
Right fucking here.
I got a good mind
to jack you up for what you did.
What I--? You stole the record from me.
- Give me the fu--
- Yo, Shao.
Take that shit around the corner, man.
Yeah. Looking good...
Now. Around the fucking corner.
Come on, little man.
Come around the corner.
I go around, I'm gonna knock you
to Sunday, wait for you on Tuesday.
At Les Inferno,
you can be anything you want.
It's Fat Annie's birthday, y'all!
I'm DJ Malibu...
-Malibu!
-...and I'm here to lay in the groove
that'll make you move!
- ♪ The Bus Stop ♪
♪ Are you ready ♪
♪ For the Bus Stop? ♪
♪ The Bus Stop ♪
♪ Form a line to the front ♪
♪ Form a line to the back ♪
Watch your back, Fred Astaire.
Malibu sees a whole lot of potential
dancing out there.
♪ I wanna stay right here ♪
♪ Everybody here is dancin' ♪
♪ All I wanna do is get your body
Next to mine ♪
Get Cadillac to introduce you.
-What?
-Malibu.
Give him your tape, and ask him
to dance with you in the competition.
Do it.
All I'm saying is, you dance
with Cadillac, you gonna win for sure.
Go, Malibu!
♪ Can you dance-off? ♪
♪ Feel the burn ♪
♪ Sashay, girl ♪
♪ Sashay... ♪
I have this tape...
of me singing. Do you think you could
get it to Malibu for me?
Maybe if we dance together?
Sure.
I'll make sure he gets it.
And I'd love to dance.
But let's talk about what
you gonna do for me.
You like hotels?
♪ Sashay now, sashay now
Sashay now... ♪
I'm not like that.
Let's go.
-Come on.
-She just need a dance.
Oye.
- Regina, baby.
- Let's go.
What the hell?
♪ Bus Stop ♪
All right. If you don't got a lover,
you better grab somebody's mother,
'cause the dance-off's gonna begin
as soon as this "Bus Stop" jammy end.
What the fuck you doing?
Yo, I'm gonna give you one last chance
to give me this fucking record.
Why? I thought you was gonna kick my ass.
Know who you're talking to?
-Why you want the record so bad?
-None of your damn business.
You know I'll fucking kill you
without blinking?
Then kill me. This record's for my girl.
You ain't fucking getting it.
If I fuck up my pants,
I'm gonna kill you twice.
-Give me the fucking--
-Get off.
Yo, give me this fucking record!
Fuck you! Ain't no girl worth it!
Motherfucker, you punch like a girl.
Ain't no biting, motherfucker.
So many sharks in the sea.
Ladies, who's it gonna be?
Put those lips in motion,
and show the fellas your devotion.
Give me the record.
-No.
-Give me the fucking record.
No!
Why you here by your lonesome?
I told you. This record's for my girl.
It's her favorite.
I gotta go in that club,
get the DJ to play this record.
I'm gonna win her heart back.
Exactly what I'm gonna do.
You a fucking nut.
Cadillac win that contest every time
with a different chick each week.
♪ Whoa, I wanna stay right here ♪
- Do it.
- ♪ Everybody here is dancin' ♪
♪ All I wanna do is get your body
Next to mine ♪
♪ So, baby, won't you take it to me? ♪
Your life or your motherfucking record!
You choose.
Kill me.
I'm in love, man.
-Do me a favor. Put me out of my misery.
-I'll do this shit.
So, do it.
'Cause I ain't no hard rock like you, but
when it comes to my girl, I'm all heart.
I'm do or die.
So, kill me all you want to.
Stab your hate into my love.
You might kill me,
but you'll never beat me.
'Cause I got love, and you'll probably
never know what that is.
What you got, man?
What you got?
Ooh!
You're a funny one, young'n.
You got a real good way with words, man.
I'll tell you what.
I'll get you in. You give me the record.
What you want for the record?
I can get you into the club,
get DJ Malibu to play your record,
dance with your girl,
as long as I get that record.
And you don't never tell nobody
how it all went down.
I don't need you. I could get in myself.
Sit out here in this swampy,
fucking heat by yourself
while your girl's inside
getting served by a gangster, then.
Whoo!
I'm sorry about my behavior back there.
Pretty girls, they just--
They just make me nervous.
I didn't know what to say,
but I wanna make it up to you.
That's a sign.
If you really wanna get
your tape to Malibu...
you'll be my partner for this competition.
He's looking for his next star.
There's a lot of good dancers
out there tonight.
Yeah, but I'm only looking for one.
I can't give you the fucking record!
But decide quick
'cause if your girl's really all that...
Cadillac's dicking her down right now.
Sixty seconds till the dance-off, y'all.
-Fifty-nine... 58...
-Wait.
Get off your ass!
It ain't too late.
♪ Are you ready ♪
♪ To do the Bus Stop? ♪
-♪ Do the Bus Stop... ♪
-Hey, that's her.
-Which one?
-The beautiful one.
Getting served up, just like I told you.
- Mylene!
- Didn't I tell you?
-Hey, Mylene!
-Come on. Hey. We gotta go.
-Come on. We gotta go!
-Mylene!
Where you think you going?
I knew you was gonna try--
Yo, yo. Yo, yo.
Let them on through. Let them through.
What you got for me, baby?
Cadillac got somebody real here.
He and his girl wanna go first
in the dance-off to this record.
-Give it to him.
-No requests. You know better than that.
Grown and imported by his father.
- In Bolivia.
- He's a don.
Yeah. We'll see about that.
Whoo!
Don San Juan is his name.
"Don San Juan," that shit ain't his name.
How you fucking know? You from Bolivia?
You mean to tell me...
his name just so happens to be
the motherfucking capital of Puerto Rico?
You insulted my family name.
I don't think you wanna do that.
See? You fucked up.
You don't even know who his family is.
Bitch,
who the fuck you think you talking to?
Who you think you talking to?
Motherfucker, they call me the best.
I pass every test.
I done ripped that S
off of Superman's chest.
Get it straight, homeboys.
I don't take no fucking requests.
You might have ripped the S
off his chest,
but nevertheless, take this request
this ain't no jive.
Play the record, and keep your ass alive.
You coming to me with a threat?
Boy, you don't know me yet.
Nigga, youse a young'n,
but baby, I'm a vet.
And I don't spin nothing
that ain't on my set.
This ain't no threat, bro.
This is something real.
I don't really care how you fucking feel.
-Our product has the Bolivian seal.
-Pbbt!
I'll make it snow all night on you
for one record.
So, baby, what's the deal?
You make it snow all night?
Bolivia's finest.
Let me see this bullshit.
♪ Don't stop, I'll tell you when ♪
"Misty Holloway, Pakoussa Remix"?
How the fuck did you get this?
In my family,
it's impolite to ask questions like that.
So, don't worry about it.
That accent is busted.
Whoo!
Boss, cake's almost here.
I'm gonna get Cadillac.
What kind of son is late
for his mother's birthday?
He's fucking around.
I'll get him, bring him up.
All right, then.
All right, all right, all right.
Time for something smooth...
...for the lovers who wanna groove.
A remix so romantic and so rare,
some said it didn't exist nowhere.
Yo, cuz.
-Your mama's lighting candles now.
-Not right now.
She asked for you
to sing her "Happy Birthday."
-Never fear...
-She didn't ask nicely.
Malibu's got it right here.
You think about that dance.
- Yo, this is my song.
- ♪ ♪
What?
- How'd he know it was-- What?
- ♪ ♪
♪ ♪- My God.
You're here?
♪ ♪- You got in?
You truly are as fine as wine
And so divine
You know I had to make you mine
No matter the time
-Zeke, you're ridiculous.
-So, I scaled that mountaintop
- To get that record dropped
- ♪ ♪
Just to see the clouds part
- As your pretty lips did the same
- ♪ ♪
- Hoping, one day, they'd utter my name
♪ ♪- ♪ Tell me ♪
♪ Tell me ♪
- ♪ Tell me ♪
- ♪ ♪
-♪ Take me out of myself again ♪
-♪ Out of myself... ♪
Feast your eyes
on these two young doves.
-The very definition of pure, sweet love.
-♪ Show me love, show me how to love ♪
-♪ How to love ♪
-♪ I can't do this on my own ♪
-♪ I can't do this without my love ♪
-♪ Take me out of myself... ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
-♪ Help me lose control ♪
-♪ I can't do this on my own ♪
♪ Show me love ♪
♪ Show me happiness ♪
♪ I can't do this on my own ♪
-Malibu.
-♪ I can't do this ♪
-♪ I can't do this on my own ♪
Whoo!
Ha! Who's the lucky lady
gonna be tonight? Yeah.
Come on!
Losers need not apply
'cause Cadillac's just too fly.
♪ Fee, fie ♪
♪ Fo, fum ♪
♪ I'm looking down the barrel
Of the devil's gun ♪
-♪ I said ♪
-Whoo!
♪ Nowhere to run ♪
- ♪ We've gotta make a stand ♪
- ♪ Against the devil's gun ♪
Ho! Mix it up, mix it up.
Yeah, baby. Last chance for partners!
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
What the fuck is this here?
-You're making Annie feel all emotional.
-♪ Happy birthday, dear... ♪
♪ You know his finger's on the trigger ♪
♪ He's waitin' to deliver ♪
♪ Can we ever figure out ♪
♪ A way to make the people shout? ♪
Whoo!
♪ You're lookin' down the barrel
Of the devil's gun ♪
♪ Nowhere ♪
♪ To run ♪
♪ You've gotta make a stand
Against the devil's gun ♪
-♪ He's watching us burn ♪
-Hey!
♪ He's watching us burn ♪
Get off me!
♪ One day we'll learn... ♪
- Look, that what you want?
- Hey!
♪ One day we'll learn ♪
- ♪ Payback ♪
Get the fuck out now!
I got you now, bitch!
Where the fuck is he?
- ♪ You'll get that payback ♪
♪ How about now? ♪
Where the fuck is Cadillac?!
Ooh...
Stop the press.
Who's this young boricua mama,
dancing to impress?
Looks like King Cadillac's
found himself
-the very best.
-♪ We've gotta make a stand ♪
♪ Against the devil's gun
I said ♪
- ♪ Fee, fie ♪
♪ Fo, fum ♪
♪ I'm looking down the barrel
Of the devil's gun ♪
♪ I said ♪
-Yeah!
-♪ Nowhere to run ♪
♪ You've gotta make a stand
Against the devil's gun ♪
Fuck you!
♪ Fee, fie... ♪
- Come on.
- Okay!
Get out of the way!
♪ I said ♪
♪ Nowhere to run ♪
- Hey.
- ♪ We've gotta, gotta, gotta ♪
♪ Gotta get the gun ♪
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What you got, hot shot producer?
I see your 50 and I raise you 300.
- Aw, come on.
- Coño.
Too rich, I'm out.
Don't hate me because I'm beautiful.
Oye, Juan.
Tráeme algo especial ahí.
Un brindis.
To Stan, for supporting my housing vision.
And also, a toast.
- To Jackie.
- Thank you, Cisco.
God bless those who win early.
When the night is long.
- Salud.
Thanks for getting me and the girls out.
Yeah. No doubt.
- That was--
- Horrible. I know.
I just want to go to bed.
But... I should give this to you.
No, that's-- That's for you.
I got that for you.
I don't want it.
But it's-- You love it.
-It's your favorite.
-Zeke, we're not-- We're not dating.
-We're not a couple.
-Let's start. Let's make it official.
-Zeke--
-I wanna be your man, Mylene.
I know you like me.
And I like you so much,
I can't hardly breathe.
I like you so much, I feel like I got
thunder and lightning inside of me.
You make me nervous.
But you also make me calm.
Real calm.
Calm almost like how God must be calm,
you know, Mylene? Calm from loving.
I love you.
Mylene, I love you.
What do you think about that?
Okay, look. I don't mean
to be conceited or nothing.
You know I'm not like that anyway.
But if you see how you're
looking at me now,
that ain't the look of someone
who don't like someone.
So, come on.
What do you say??
No.
No. Because I'm gonna be a singer, Zeke,
-I'm gonna be a disco star.
-I know you will. I know.
And someday soon,
I'm gonna cross that East River,
and I can't let anybody
distract me from that.
-I won't distract you.
-Yes, you will.
And it's sad because you are so gifted.
You're so smart
and you just mess around with it.
Like today in class when you were supposed
to stand up and do that poem.
You say you want me,
but you don't know
what it is that you want. But I do.
And even if I was gonna be with somebody,
which I'm not,
I'm gonna be with a man
that has goals and has a plan.
Not a kid from the neighborhood.
Not a boy. Not you.
-Mylene--
-Not now.
If you give it a chance--
I don't love you, Zeke. I don't love you.
And it's quits.
Mylene.
"Even in the darkness,
there is light, for God is gracious,
and tells us,
'Ye be kind to one another,
tender hearted, forgiving for one another,
as God in Christ forgave you.'"
Dios mío. What are you wearing?
Ramon, tranquilo.
¡Tranquilo nada!
Cover yourself.
-¡Tranquilo nada!
-Ramon!
Have any idea what time it is?
Your mother almost died.
-I'm sorry.
-Casi me da un heart attack.
Look at yourself.
Look at you. Our own daughter.
A teenage whore.
-Ramon!
-Puta, Lydia.
I went out with my friends
to listen to music.
I didn't drink, I didn't smoke--
-You didn't drink? You didn't drink?
-No.
-No, no.
-You didn't smoke? No?
Mentirosa. Again, you are a liar.
I may have had one drink
and a cigarette, pero Mami,
-that's what teenagers do.
-Ramon!
-No, not my teenager. Not you.
-Ramon, por favor.
No "Ramon"! And this?
You want to be like Misty Holloway?
What is this disco garbage?
It's poison.
You are not this. You will never be this.
Do you understand me?
You'll never be this. Never be this!
-You went through my things?
-Yes!
I will not tolerate blasphemy.
You will not associate with garbage.
You will not sing disco,
and from now on,
you will never leave this house. Ever.
I will sing, Papi.
And you cannot stop me.
I can't stop you?
-No!
-I'll show you how I stop you.
- Ramon!
- I'll show how I stop you!
- I will beat the evil out of you.
- Ramon!
I'll beat it out of you!
You are my darling angel.
I will beat you all night
- to separate from you and El Diablo!
- No!
-No, Ramon! Ramon! Stop it.
-No! You cannot.
- No!
- No, no!
Let her go! No! No!
Lydia!
Go to your uncle!
I...
We were in the studio,
finishing up the rhythm track.
I'm producing.
We're this close. We're so close.
And right outside the door,
good old Hector,
he's got like,
five chicks that wanna blow him,
-three dope dealers.
-No.
Now that your luck's gone bad,
you're telling stories.
I wanna do one more overdub
because I'm a perfectionist.
There's a reason I got three Grammys.
- ¿Qué?
- I need to talk to my uncle.
¿Qué te pasa? Pero dime que te pasó.
How much is the music producer in for?
- Mylene, calm down, please.
- He's down 25 large.
La sobrina.
¿Nena?
And she's right. I ain't shit.
I ain't ever gonna be shit.
She has no business being with me.
I just-- I'll probably--
I'll probably end up working in a fucking
supermarket my whole fucking life!
Can you fill us in with anything
about Les Inferno? The shoot-out?
My heart got shot out.
My fucking heart got shot out.
Yo, osu, wordsmith.
Who the fuck is that?
Some wild, wild west shit back there.
This motherfucker
with the fake karate and shit.
Now what did I do?
I got you in.
I got Malibu, who's dead,
to play the record,
which in fact is the last record
that he'll ever play.
While motherfuckers shooting
from both sides,
while your stupid ass is trying
to get the record
off of Malibu's turntables,
all for a bitch
-who thinks she's better than you.
-Don't call her a bitch.
A motherfucking bitch!
-Don't call her a bitch!
-Sit your ass down.
Yo, you got the gift.
But you look like a bitch
crying over a bitch.
I don't understand all the crying
over a female.
You don't know. You don't know.
I don't know? I don't know? About what?
-Not about to say "love," are you?
-What if I did?
Then I say you're fucking right,
I don't understand anything about love.
Who is this dude, man?
- Yeah, who the fuck is this dude?
- Yo,
- who you getting loud with, shortstop?
- Hey.
-You, nigga.
-Aww, little munchkin.
Hey, man. We're all cool.
We're all cool.
Let me see this.
I write, maybe y'all seen me up.
- Whoa.
- No!
- Get the fuck outta here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You're Shaolin Fantastic?
The lady-killing romantic.
Hell, no.
Yo, Zeke. Is this really him?
I don't know. I just met the dude.
Hey, man. Just look at his shoes.
Bro, this little guy--
This is my brother, Boo-Boo.
And that's my other brother, Ra-Ra.
Do you know who I am?
Rumi 411.
You stay up with Crash and Daze.
You also down with the Soul Artists?
I spray all-city.
Yo, where's my record at, man?
-You like Misty Holloway that much?
-Where's my record?!
Here's your fucking record.
Here. Go fetch.
Why do you need the record?
It's for the get down.
What's the get down?
You don't know what the get down is?
You're a natural, and you don't know
who Grandmaster Flash is?
Shit. All right, punks.
Y'all want to go to the flyest...
secret underground party
in the entire Bronx...
you follow me.
You decide.
Let's go.
- Yo.
- Shao. What's up?
They with me, all right? All of them.
Yo!
Aseke.
Hey!
My God.
Ra, this is crazy cool.
B-boy hard rocks in here.
They don't like outsiders.
Like, they really don't play, man.
Y'all gotta pretend like y'all know
what's what.
Why y'all look so scared, man? Come on.
Yo, Shaolin!
Yo!
♪ Let's dance ♪
♪ Break it down
Let's dance ♪
♪ Drop the beat and let's dance ♪
♪ Good evening ♪
♪ Welcome aboard Disco Airlines... ♪
♪ Get down to the beat of the sound ♪
You're late, Grasshopper.
I got the Pakoussa though.
Shit.
Yo!
All right. All right. I'm impressed.
But have you found your wordsmith yet?
I think I found him tonight.
So, can you teach me how to DJ now?
I'm ready right now, Grandmaster.
Just show me the magic.
Tomorrow we begin. But tonight?
We party.
Whoo!
The Grandmaster pinpoints
the get down part.
Sometimes the drums only play
for ten seconds,
and the rest of the record
is violins and singing and shit.
He won't play that bullshit,
so he plays the same record on two decks.
While the get down plays on one,
he cues the same part on two.
Now, I don't know how he knows
exactly when to do it,
but the moment one finishes,
bang, he flips the mixer...
the beat goes on and on.
The beat goes on, the wordsmith can go on.
Man, what the fuck is the wordsmith?
The MC. The master of ceremonies.
♪ B-boys and B-girls
In the place to be ♪
♪ Are you ready to rock this spot
So viciously? ♪
- Come on!
- And the beat goes on and on.
And the beat goes on and on.
Yo, Flash, I think I wanna tell
some people, y'all listen to Cowboy.
Yeah.
♪ Yes, yes, y'all
To the beat, y'all ♪
♪ Freak, freak, y'all
♪ Yes, yes, y'all
And you don't stop ♪
-♪ All the ladies, all the ladies ♪
-I love you!
♪ All the ladies in the house ♪
♪ Let me hear you say "" ♪
♪ Say "" ♪
♪ Homeboys ♪
- ♪ Homeboys, homeboys ♪
♪ In the place to be
Let me hear you say ♪
♪ "Make money, money
Make money, money, money" ♪
♪ Make money, money
Make money, money, money ♪
♪ Say "take money, money
Take money, money, money" ♪
♪ Take money, money ♪
♪ Take money, money, money ♪
♪ Yes, yes, y'all
To the beat, y'all ♪
♪ Freak, freak, y'all ♪
♪ And you don't stop ♪
♪ Say, get live
Socialize ♪
♪ Come on, girls
Let's take a ride ♪
♪ Fellas, let's spin them fast
'Cause my DJ ♪
♪ Grandmaster Flash ♪
- ♪ He's back for more... ♪
Nena, are you okay?
¿Qué pasó?
So, I went to Les Inferno.
Fat Annie's?
And then they shot him. In front of me.
- They shot up the whole place.
- What--
What were you thinking?
It was the only way.
What do you mean?
It's the only way I'm gonna... sing.
- Nena.
I'm gonna help you.
All a man has is his word.
I promise you.
You're gonna sing.
- ♪ And you know that ♪
♪'Cause we got it like that ♪
♪ Any man out there
Who think he can rhyme ♪
♪ Step right up and get in line ♪
Yo, man. Look, man, look.
Look, look, look,
if anyone can rock this shit, it's you.
♪ I'm gonna hand this mic
To the chosen one ♪
Yes, you're a poet and you know it.
Come on.
-It's an open mic, man.
-No.
Fuck you mean, "No?"
Let's go!
Take a deep breath and jump.
-No!
-Come on, man.
- You got to.
- Three!
- Come on.
- We're close to one.
- Two!
-One!
-This is your moment.
Kill this, let's go! You got it!
No, no, no.
You think you a wordsmith?
Kick a fly rhyme.
Get up here.
Come on, Zeke!
Yes, yes, y'all.
To the beat, y'all.
My name is Zeke and I'm a treat, y'all.
Get out of here.
Treat?
Your rhymes stink like my feet!
-Someone get this garbage on the street.
-Yo, disco faggot, you don't belong here.
You fucking suck!
Get that motherfucking disco duck
the fuck outta here.
Before he ruin our party!
And fuck his duck-ass...
...burger-ass crew, too!
- Run 'em out.
- Get out. I'll beat your ass.
You crazy?
-Wait, no, no.
-I ain't tripping. He tripping.
You still playing.
-Don't touch me.
-Get back, man. Yo!
Whoa!
You dare to turn against my brother?
Shaolin Fantastic.
♪ Tell me ♪
-♪ Tell me ♪
-♪ Whoa ♪
- ♪ Tell me... ♪
Master my Shaolin style,
and you, too,
can reach Olympian heights.
There are none who can match him.
- ♪ Whoa ♪
♪ Take me ♪
♪ Yo, I can still recall
That fateful hour ♪
-♪ Leaders lead and cowards cower ♪
-♪ Help me ♪
♪ Shaolin Fantastic, no man braver ♪
♪ He showed me my superpower ♪
♪ All right, y'all
Let me catch Shaolin's pass ♪
♪ Shaolin's fantastic, nothing but class ♪
♪ With you and your wack style
I should wipe my ass ♪
Yeah.
♪ Knick knack paddy whack
Give a dog a bone ♪
♪ Spank him like his daddy
And send the boy home ♪
♪ Shots fired
Now you really should pause ♪
♪ But since your mouth's open
You can taste these good bars ♪
-♪ What say you, sucka? ♪
-Yeah!
♪ And your friends
I got them too ♪
-♪ Looking like a Bozo clown-ass crew ♪
-Yeah?
♪ Thinking you bad
With your waffle cabeza ♪
♪ When it comes to big domes
Yo, you won the race-a ♪
That's right!
♪ This ain't a battle
This is only scrimmage ♪
♪ Please refrain from applause
Till I am finished ♪
♪ Dressed in my disco clothes
And still kill it ♪
♪ The best in the Bronx ♪
♪ Eventually you'll get it ♪
♪ Let me introduce you
To the Get Down crew ♪
♪ Ra-Ra, Dizzee, Shaolin and Boo ♪
♪ Y'all beneath us
We got nothing to prove ♪
♪ Follow instructions
When you step into school ♪
♪ Rock to the beat
And it just don't stop ♪
♪ Fly girls in the house
Make their panties drop ♪
♪ Crews come for me
Everywhere we go ♪
♪ Now that we got the spot jumping ♪
♪ Everybody say "ho" ♪
Ho!
-  ♪ Say "ho" ♪
- Ho!
♪ Say "turn nothing into something" ♪
♪ Turn nothing into something ♪
♪ Say Dizzee rocks the house ♪
♪ Say Ra rocks the house ♪
♪ Say Boo-Boo rocks the house ♪
- ♪ Shaolin rocks the house ♪
- My God. My God.
- ♪ And Flash rocks the house ♪
- My God.
♪ Yes, yes, y'all, and you don't stop ♪
- Shit.
-Whoo!
-Yo, damn!
- Damn.
- Check this out, man.
- Bro, you killed that.
- Yo, we's got comics.
You like that? You have fun, y'all.
Hey, respect the temple.
Respect the--
Hey. Hands off everything, munchkin.
Yo. Everybody, gather around.
Gather around.
This is the Aladdin's Cave.
No one else has seen this before.
Shit. We must be special.
- You ready?
- Yeah!
- Are you ready?
- Yeah.
Bung! Doo-doo!
Bung!
Ba-dow!
Shit!
This is my lifetime collection, man.
Alphabetized and everything.
Yo, Shao, man.
This is where you stay at?
You know,
other than staying at my girl's crib.
That's where I keep my custom AJ Lesters.
- Custom?
- Hoo-hoo!
He said custom?
Yo, so how do you rig up the electric?
You wired it yourself?
-Magic. Says who?
-No such thing.
Boo! Be careful, man!
How the fuck do you brush your teeth?
Yo, the city ain't cut off
the water in the building yet.
- Shit, there is water. He ain't lying.
- Man.
If I knew Flash's secret,
-I could extend the get down right here.
-This-- This--
This is def, man. This shit's def.
Yo, yo. Yo, Shao.
-Yo.
-The sun's coming up.
I can't see the train here.
-Can we get on the roof?
-Let's hit the roof.
To the roof!
All right. Let's do it.
- Yo, yo, yo.
- All-city.
I'm the king of New York.
- Heads up.
- Snap.
Stick with me, little man.
I'll teach you how to fly. Hoo!
-Yo, Zeke.
-Yeah, bro?
Tonight was pretty dope, right?
Yeah, bro. Yeah.
Shaolin Fantastic, he's kind of cool?
Yeah, he is.
Hey, hey. Brah, brah, come on.
You're cool, too.
-Don't you wanna see Dizzee's burner?
-Last one up eats a dick.
Hey, fuck you!
- Motherfucker.
- Hey, Shao.
Will you sign my book?
I'll do one better.
I'm retiring from my writing.
Gonna be a full-time DJ.
So, all my stuff downstairs...
it's all you, Rumi.
For real?
For real.
Thanks.
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo.
Huddle up, fellas, huddle up.
Huddle around. Let's do it.
I'm about to introduce you
to the three kingdoms.
Okay? We got the west.
There's the land of DJ Kool Herc.
-Who's Kool Herc?
-If you don't know who Kool Herc is,
you need to ask somebody.
Well, I am asking somebody.
Let's just say
he has the biggest sound in the Bronx.
Over here are his rivals.
Bambaataa and the Zulus.
And who's right here?
- We are.
- Yeah, well...
Right now, right here...
and will always forever be the land...
the kingdom...
of Grandmaster Flash.
Yeah, but what about our kingdom?
Well...
that's a good question.
Y'all want your own kingdom,
or you wanna...
be peasants in someone else's kingdom?
We want our own kingdom.
Then so it shall be.
Stick with me and we'll run shit.
We'll be musical kings.
Fantastic Four Plus One.
Running shit
from Hunts Point to Riverdale.
Large and in charge.
Yeah.
Train!
Shit.
- Shit!
- My God.
- That's us, Boo.
- Shit!
That's our train!
That's the train!
All-city, yo!
All-city!
Get a better angle, get a better angle!
- Check this out.
- Hey, yo.
Think we could run the Bronx?
What?
You and me, the Jackson Five
Kipling brothers over there...
I don't know who can fuck with us.
Plus, you're a natural wordsmith, man.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
You a natural everything.
Yo, we gonna be bigger than Les Inferno.
We gonna be bigger than...
the Yankee Stadium.
We gonna be bigger
than the whole fucking Bronx.
We gonna be bigger than the world.
There you go. We broke night.
♪ Be that as it may ♪
♪ Every night I pray ♪
♪ For brighter stars, more golden days ♪
♪ And to be taken far away ♪
♪ Be that as it may ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ I will not forget the love you gave ♪
♪ I will not forget the love you ♪
♪ Gave ♪
n and Boo ♪
♪ Y'all beneath us
We got nothing to prove ♪
♪ Follow instructions
When you step into school ♪
♪ Rock to the beat
And it just don't stop ♪
♪ Fly girls in the house
Make their panties drop ♪
♪ Crews come for me
Everywhere we go ♪
♪ Now that we got the spot jumping ♪
♪ Everybody say "ho" ♪
Ho!
-  ♪ Say "ho" ♪
- Ho!
♪ Say "turn nothing into something" ♪
♪ Turn nothing into something ♪
♪ Say Dizzee rocks the house ♪
♪ Say Ra rocks the house ♪
♪ Say Boo-Boo rocks the house ♪
- ♪ Shaolin rocks the house ♪
- My God. My God.
- ♪ And Flash rocks the house ♪
- My God.
♪ Yes, yes, y'all, and you don't stop ♪
- Shit.
-Whoo!
-Yo, damn!
- Damn.
- Check this out, man.
- Bro, you killed that.
- Yo, we's got comics.
You like that? You have fun, y'all.
Hey, respect the temple.
Respect the--
Hey. Hands off everything, munchkin.
Yo. Everybody, gather around.
Gather around.
This is the Aladdin's Cave.
No one else has seen this before.
Shit. We must be special.
- You ready?
- Yeah!
- Are you ready?
- Yeah.
Bung! Doo-doo!
Bung!
Ba-dow!
Shit!
This is my lifetime collection, man.
Alphabetized and everything.
Yo, Shao, man.
This is where you stay at?
You know,
other than staying at my girl's crib.
That's where I keep my custom AJ Lesters.
- Custom?
- Hoo-hoo!
He said custom?
Yo, so how do you rig up the electric?
You wired it yourself?
-Magic. Says who?
-No such thing.
Boo! Be careful, man!
How the fuck do you brush your teeth?
Yo, the city ain't cut off
the water in the building yet.
- Shit, there is water. He ain't lying.
- Man.
If I knew Flash's secret,
-I could extend the get down right here.
-This-- This--
This is def, man. This shit's def.
Yo, yo. Yo, Shao.
-Yo.
-The sun's coming up.
I can't see the train here.
-Can we get on the roof?
-Let's hit the roof.
To the roof!
All right. Let's do it.
- Yo, yo, yo.
- All-city.
I'm the king of New York.
- Heads up.
- Snap.
Stick with me, little man.
I'll teach you how to fly. Hoo!
-Yo, Zeke.
-Yeah, bro?
Tonight was pretty dope, right?
Yeah, bro. Yeah.
Shaolin Fantastic, he's kind of cool?
Yeah, he is.
Hey, hey. Brah, brah, come on.
You're cool, too.
-Don't you wanna see Dizzee's burner?
-Last one up eats a dick.
Hey, fuck you!
- Motherfucker.
- Hey, Shao.
Will you sign my book?
I'll do one better.
I'm retiring from my writing.
Gonna be a full-time DJ.
So, all my stuff downstairs...
it's all you, Rumi.
For real?
For real.
Thanks.
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo.
Huddle up, fellas, huddle up.
Huddle around. Let's do it.
I'm about to introduce you
to the three kingdoms.
Okay? We got the west.
There's the land of DJ Kool Herc.
-Who's Kool Herc?
-If you don't know who Kool Herc is,
you need to ask somebody.
Well, I am asking somebody.
Let's just say
he has the biggest sound in the Bronx.
Over here are his rivals.
Bambaataa and the Zulus.
And who's right here?
- We are.
- Yeah, well...