PONGO: It seems like
such a short time ago
that my pet and I were just
lazing about in our little London flat,
living the humdrum bachelor life
and wishing things
weren't so very, very dull.
That's my pet, Roger.
My name's Pongo.
You remember,
I'm the one with the spots.
(BARKING)
Oh, goodness!
(LAUGHING) No, no, not that one.
Or that one.
(LAUGHS)
That's me,
living my new life as a family man.
(LAUGHING) Never a duII moment.
I guess I got my wish.
(ROGER WHISTLING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(LAUGHS)
I think I'm seeing spots!
Hey, seeing spots!
(SINGING) Spots, l'm seeing spots
Everywhere I'm seeing lots
Of those tiny little dots
Yes, it's true
They¤re on the beds and the cots
In the pans and the pots
And they've left little spots in the loo!
Roger, are you packing or playing?
I'm playing at packing, dear!
Well, quit fooling around.
We're moving
first thing in the morning!
(SINGING) We'll have
a Dalmatian plantation
(SINGING) l see spots on the walls
In the rooms, in the halls
On the floors in the drawers
Yes, I do
And every morning when I rise
and I open up my eyes
I am taken by surprise
'Cause instead of seeing skies
I see lots of little spots
-We'll have a Dalmatian plantation
-Spots, spots, spots
-And never again shall we roam
-Everywhere on the beds and the cots
-Can't wait to begin...
-On the walls...
-...our sweet living that's in
-...the rooms and the halls
-Our Dalmatian plantation home
(ANITA LAUGHS)
-Dalmatian plantation
-We're home
(GIGGLES)
Oh, Roger!
PONGO: Yes, tomorrow
would be moving day.
Only one more night in this little flat,
which was getting smaller
by the minute.
I mean, even I was beginning
to feel a bit smothered.
Really, it was easy to see
how one of our puppies could feel,
well, just a little bit lost
in this sea of spots.
-Ah, hello, Patch.
-Hello, Mother.
(CHUCKLING) Watching the television,
are we?
Yes. Well, I've got to save my spot,
now, don't I?
It's the best spot, after all!
But you know your show
doesn't start until after...
NANNY: Dinnertime!
(ALL GASP)
-Oh, dear.
-Oh, not again!
(BARKING EXCITEDLY)
(GROАNS)
(GRUNTING) Come on, you guys!
Make room!
(CHUCKLES)
No, you don't, Mr Roly-Poly.
One bowl at a time!
(GRUNTS)
There must be something in here.
ROGER: Right!
Is everybody ready for the show?
My spot!
(THEME SONG PLAYlNG ON TV)
Thunderbolt
Hounding hoodlums with a howl
Bad no-goodniks hear his growl
Thunderbolt
Desperados, cringe in fear
Mighty Thunderbolt is here
(EXCLAIMING)
Righting wrongs and doing right
Barking boldly in the night
The One-of-a-Kind Wonder Dog
NARRATOR ON TV: Kanine Krunchies,
the crunch your dog loves to munch,
presents
The Thunderbolt Adventure Hour.
Starring Thunderbolt,
the One-of-a-Kind Wonder Dog!
And his trusty sidekick,
Lil' Lightning.
In last week's thrilling episode,
Wholesome Tommy was kidnapped...
Help! Thunderbolt! Save me!
(SlNlSTER LAUGH)
...and spirited away by that
black-hearted villain, Dirty Dawson!
Help, Thunderbolt! Save me!
Will our hero arrive in time?
(EVlL LAUGH)
What horrible fate
awaits Wholesome Tommy?
Oh, l can hardly look!
I've seen this one. This is brilliant!
Help, Thunderbolt! Save me!
That mangy mutt
can't save you this time!
(LAUGHlNG MANlACALLY)
Hold on, Tommy!
Thunderbolt's coming!
(PUPPY SHUSHING)
(BARKlNG)
(TRAlN WHlSTLlNG)
(GROWLlNG)
Hey!
This is just like
"Double-cross at Dead Man's Ditch,"
except that was a mine car, not a train.
(BOTH SHUSHING)
(THUNDERBOLT BARKlNG)
(GROWLlNG)
(GROWLING)
(LAUGHlNG)
Watch this,
Thunder's gonna grab the whip.
(SHUSHING)
Patch, you're gonna spoil it again!
(GRUNTS)
(DlRTY DAWSON LAUGHlNG)
They say every dog has his day,
but this one ain't gonna be yours,
you flea-bitten cur!
(TRAlN WHlSTLE BLOWlNG)
(WHOOPING) Yes! Yes!
(BULL BELLOWlNG)
DIRTY DAWSON: This ain't fair.
(DAWSON YELPlNG)
(BARKlNG)
(BARKING)
What was that supposed to be?
(PUPPIES LAUGHING)
It was the most pitiful bark
I've heard yet.
Yeah. It sounded
like someone sat on a squeaky toy!
Thunderbolt, you're one of a kind!
Wow, one of a kind!
SONG ON TV: Kanine Krunchies
can't be beat...
All right, bedtime, everyone.
(ALL GROАNING)
(YАWNING) But, Dad,
we're not sleepy yet.
Nanny, do you have the new dog tags?
Right here. We'll put them on
as they come up the stairs.
Say, kiddies! ls your dog
a One-of-a-Kind Wonder Dog?
If you think your pooch
has what it takes,
bring him down to the London set of
Thunderbolt's exciting new adventure,
"Thunderbolt versus
the Hound of the Baskervilles."
-Thunderbolt's in London?
-That's right! Thunderbolt's in London.
Just follow the Kanine Krunchies truck
down to tomorrow's auditions,
where one lucky pup
will win the opportunity
to appear as a guest on the show!
Dad, Dad, Dad!
...57, 58... Careful.
(PUPPY GRUNTS)
...59, 60, 61, 62, 63...
Dad! Dad! I have to see Thunderbolt!
Just a minute, Son.
I'm counting. ...67, 68...
But, Dad,
I've seen every episode, all 72.
(CHUCKLES) ...72, 73... Two? Not now,
Patch. I'm busy losing count here!
-...76, 77, 78, 79...
-But, Dad! Dad!
...82, 83...
(GRUNTS)
Oh, dear.
...98, 99, 100, 101, 102, 103, 104,
and Patch, 105. 105?
Are you all right, Son?
Dad, I've just gotta see
Thunderbolt tomorrow.
Yes, I know,
but tomorrow is moving day.
You're going to love it on the farm, Son.
There are big green fields
and a stream and a barn
and lots of different animals.
Hey, maybe you and I
can chase some chickens, huh?
-Sure, Dad, but...
-Here we go!
"Cherry Tree Farm,
Little Tichfield, Devon."
Why, I imagine it's the most
splendid farm in the whole country.
Oh, Perdi, the farm will be such
a wonderful place to raise our puppies.
And best of all, we'll be miles away
from that evil, ugly monster...
Cruella De Vil! Now, please let me in!
(GRUNTING)
I can't do that, Miss de Vil.
But, Mr Fitzweil,
please, something, anything.
You know very well
that the terms of your probation
don't allow me to sell you
any more furs.
Not even a stole, a muff,
a pair of mittens?
No!
-One mitten?
-No!
(CRYING)
Could things possibly be any worse?
MAN ON RADlO: (SlNGlNG)
Cruella De Vil, Cruella De Vil
Shut up, shut up! Stop it!
(EXPLOSION)
(CАR SPUTTERS)
(WAILS)
(GRUNTS)
(CRYING)
What does Cruella De Vil
have left to live for?
(GASPS)
МАN: Good grief.
Tell me, what do you see?
Everything.
Darkness and light, form and content.
And what else?
Chaos and order, joy and pain.
And there is more than that?
The possibility of triumph,
the certainty of defeat,
the culmination of all I've ever
reached for but could not grasp!
(LAUGHING)
I see everything!
I see absolutely everything!
(GASPS)
I feel faint in the presence
of such artistic truth.
Where is the artist?
I simply must meet him!
But you already have.
I am Lars
and I am an undiscovered genius.
My name is Cruella De Vil,
and I'm an over-financed heiress.
Your passion for my work
both repels and attracts.
(CHUCKLES)
Could you bear the sweet agony
of seeing more?
(GASPS) You mean there's more?
(GASPS)
Spots! Spots! Spots! Spots!
I had yet to find anyone
who truly understood
their bleak, but beautiful meaning.
That is, until I met you.
This could be it!
This could be the cure for my craving!
My analyst said I should find
something to substitute
for my magnificent obsession.
(LAUGHS)
Who needs furs when I can
soothe my tortured soul with art?
Something tortures you?
Tell me, what cloud dares
cast a shadow on the flower?
Oh, it's a sad but familiar tale
of loss and disappointment,
probation and a restraining order.
But you, you can help
Cruella to forget all that.
Will you do a painting just for me,
to ease my pain?
I will create a masterpiece,
if you will be my muse.
(EXCLAIMS)
Oh, darling.
(GIGGLING)
(PUPPIES SNORING)
(SIGHS)
(GRUNTS)
(LOUD SNORING)
(DROOLING NOISES)
PONGO: 63, 22...
202. No, no, no. Oh, no.
-Dad?
-97...
-I can't sleep.
-98...
-I've been thinking.
-99...
Do you think I'm a one of a kind
orjust one of101?
(YАWNS) 101! That's it.
101.
(SIGHS)
(PUPPIES BARKING)
ROGER: All right, everyone,
into the truck!
(GASPS)
PONGO: You're 90. You're 91.
You're 92. You're 93.
You're 94. Hold it. Wait. You're 98.
You're 99. You're 100 and you're 101.
And you're 101. And you're 101.
Hold it. Wait.
How many 101s are there?
(LAUGHS)
Well, I've successfully lost count again.
Right. Anyone not here, speak up.
(MUFFLED BARKING)
Oh, no!
(GRUNTING)
Wait! Wait for me!
Well, that figures.
They didn't even miss me.
(TRUCK APPROАCHING)
Then I'm not going to miss them.
(GRUNTS)
(BARKS)
(PАNTS)
(ANITA AND ROGER HUMMING)
Well, what do you think?
(LAUGHING)
Why, it's splendid!
ROGER: Puppies, welcome to
your new home!
Right then.
That's 1 and 2 and 27, 36, 5, 50, 80...
Minus two, carry the three and... 101?
(CHUCKLES) Finally,
no more counting.
(ALL BARKING)
(SCREAMS)
(ROOSTER CROWING)
Run!
(SHRIEKING)
(GROWLS)
All this place needs
is a proper dusting, a splash of paint,
and it'll be good as new.
(EXHALES)
Now, where do you suppose
we'll put the music room?
(NANNY EXCLAIMS)
I think you just found it, darling.
SONG ON PA: Thunderbolt
Hounding hoodlums with a howl
Bad no-goodniks hear his growl
Thunderbolt
Desperados, cringe in fear
Mighty Thunderbolt is here
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls,
pooches and pups of all ages,
are you ready?
(ALL CHEERING)
Desperados cringe in fear,
Mighty Thunderbolt is here!
(BARKING)
I don't believe it! It's really him!
And here's his sidekick extraordinaire,
the ever-trusty Lil' Lightning!
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
-Yoo-hoo!
-Hello, handsome!
Over here,
you gorgeous hunk of hound.
Oh, hi, ladies. Nice to meet you.
-Oh, no.
-We don't want you.
Get out of the way.
-We want...
-Thunderbolt!
(ALL SIGHING)
Sorry, little buddy, but these ladies
aren't interested in the sidekick.
They're here to get a big eyeful of hero!
(ALL SQUEALING)
Heel, ladies, heel!
All right, everybody,
line up your dogs for the audition.
We need to hear their best heroic bark!
(QUICKLY BARKS)
(HOWLS)
(BARKS)
(BARKS RAPIDLY)
(HOWLING CONTINUES)
(BARKS DАINTILY)
(RUMBLING BARK)
Very good.
(HOWLING CONTINUES)
Hey, that's very... Oh, there's more!
(BARKING)
(GRUNTS)
Well, go ahead.
Uh...
What's the matter, little fella?
Cat got your tongue?
(LAUGHING)
It's funny, 'cause, you see,
we're dogs and we chase cats, so...
Well, it made me laugh.
Come on, kid, we haven't got all year.
You're wasting my valuable limelight.
(BARKS SQUEAKILY)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Say, who sat on the squeaky toy?
-Hey, Thunderbolt, over here!
-МАN: Nice.
SONG ON PA: Thunderbolt
That's it, folks! We'll announce
the winner of the audition tomorrow.
Have a megafantabulous day,
and remember, buy your pooch lots
and lots of tasty Kanine Krunchies!
(SIGHS)
Nice work, Patch. Just brilliant.
(FEМАLE DOGS SQUEALING)
Ladies, ladies, you're wearing me out!
Oh, please, just do it one more time.
Oh, well, all right. I guess just
one more time couldn't hurt.
(ALL SIGHING)
Golly, I'm good. Hello, boys!
-Thunder!
-Lightning, little buddy.
(PАNTING) It's just awful!
I overheard what they're planning
for the next episode!
(THUNDERBOLT GROWLS)
(CHUCKLES)
Don't be too harsh on them,
little buddy.
I know we don't have the best writers
in television,
but we can always improvise.
I'm pretty good at improvising,
as long as it's written down for me.
No, no, you don't understand.
Something really horrible
is going to happen.
Don't tell me. Let me guess.
-The dam breaks?
-No.
-The mine collapses?
Do I get an evil twin?
I've always wanted an evil twin!
No! Listen, Thunder,
what happens is you...
You... You die.
(GASPS)
I don't believe it.
I die?
Oh, Lightning, this is just
about the greatest thing ever!
(LAUGHS)
I've always wanted
to play a big death scene!
The selfless hero who sacrifices
himself to save the innocent.
(LAUGHS)
I'll kick bigger than Old Yeller!
So, how do I make my shockingly
unexpected and triumphant return?
-You don't.
-What do you mean, I don't?
You don't make a shockingly
unexpected and triumphant return.
You die. You're dead.
-You never come back.
-Not even for a reunion show?
Not even for a cameo in the remake.
(GASPS)
They're writing me out of the show?
They're gonna replace you
with a younger dog.
So that's what those auditions
were really all about!
Lightning, you've gotta help me!
I can't end up on the street,
homeless, foraging in trash cans.
Mange! I could get mange!
Well, I...
I did have this one crazy thought.
Or ticks! I hate ticks!
They suck all the blood out of you.
Do you hear me?
What if you went out
and did something heroic,
like you do on the show,
but in the real world?
You know, get your name in the paper.
Prove to them that you still got it!
Wait a minute.
What if I went out and did
something heroic in the real world?
Or that could work, too.
Аfter all, you are
the One-of-a-Kind Wonder Dog.
-How hard could it be?
-Yeah, it'll be a catwalk.
-Cakewalk.
-Precisely!
I'll just go get a little press
for doing some easy hero stuff
and they'll be begging
to keep me on the show!
But, first, I'll have to figure out
a way to sneak past my adoring public.
Sneak, sneak, sneak, sneak.
Hide.
(LAUGHS)
Master of disguise.
(LOUDLY) Hi, Thunderbolt!
I'm sorry, I'm...
You've got the wrong dog, kid.
(LAUGHS) I know it's you.
That's the same disguise
you used in episode 18,
"Gambling Gophers of Gunfire Gulch."
For howling out loud!
Now you've blown my cover.
This is champion!
I'm your biggest fan, Thunderbolt!
I know every episode by heart!
Remember the time
when you fought that grizzly bear
and rescued those orphans
and then the dam broke?
-And... And...
-Hey, aren't you the squeaky toy?
Yeah. That's me.
-Listen, pup...
-Patch.
Pooch, whatever.
You've gotta understand.
Sometimes danger and I
like to dance alone!
(CАT MEOWS)
Good gracious gravy, look at that!
-A cat is stuck up in that tree!
-He is?
Oh, my heart goes out
to the poor helpless creature.
Now, if I were me, what would I do?
Well, I'd read the script,
that's what I'd do.
(GASPS)
Oh, no, I don't have a script!
(HYPERVENTILATING)
This is just like when Tommy was
trapped on that cliff in episode 29.
-Okay, okay, don't panic.
-That one was a classic.
-You can do this. You can do this.
-Only it's also like episode 64.
You can't do this. You can't do this.
When he was drowning
in the water tower.
-Yeah, that was great.
-Who am I kidding?
I have no idea what I'm doing!
But episode 29 was still the best,
at least from the first season.
-Pooch!
-Patch.
-Whatever! I'm trying to panic here!
-Sorry.
I just thought you were going to do
what you did on Raccoon Ridge.
You know, when you got that barrel?
And rolled it next to the cliff?
Then you found a long plank of wood?
And got a great big round boulder,
-and then...
-Precisely!
Whoa!
Hang on, little kitty! Help is on the way!
(CHUCKLES)
The press is going to love this.
(SNARLS)
(YELPS)
(SIGHS)
(SHRIEKS)
There you are, my good man.
No need to thank me.
The look on your face
is thanks enough!
Now, smile for the cameras!
Hey, that's strange.
Where are all the photographers?
The press is always around
when I do something.
What's the matter
with you English people?
Are you all having tea?
How am I supposed to get my job back
if you're all having tea?
That was champion, Thunder!
Just like on the telly!
You know,
this stuff isn't as easy as it looks!
I mean, maybe if I could
remember what happened
in every episode of the show,
you know, like Squeaky Toy, here,
well, then I could...
Hey, Squeaky Toy.
Oh, darling, it's just divine!
It's remarkable. It's stunning. It's grand!
But it's all wrong.
But it's my best work yet, cupcake.
But it simply has to be better
than your best, darling.
I mean, look at these spots.
The shapes aren't at all acceptable.
They're not soft enough.
(GIGGLES)
You know, cuddly, like something
you'd want to squeeze the life out of!
No, this one is no good at all,
an embarrassing mediocrity,
a complete failure.
Your harsh words strike me like blows
from the fists of a large dockworker.
I would cry now
were it not so bourgeois.
There, there. I know you'll get it right,
my depressive da Vinci.
You simply have to keep trying.
Аfter all, you're the only one
who truly understands Cruella,
who can see into her tortured soul.
Yes!
Her heart is like a vast, dark ocean
on whose waves I am hopelessly adrift
in my dinghy of passion.
(CHUCKLES)
I shall not betray your faith in me!
I shall create another canvas!
And another!
And another! And another!
Until I have found spotted perfection!
I shall not stop until the fires
of your craving have been quenched.
Junior deputy test?
Which episode was that in?
One of the lost episodes.
But I only give it to pups
who I think might be worthy.
And, who knows, if you do real good,
maybe I'll even let you
be on the show with me!
-Really?
-Sure, kid. I'm the star, aren't I?
(LAUGHS)
Mother of pasteurized milk!
That stagecoach is out of control!
This is your first junior deputy test, kid.
Okay, well...
This is just like in episode 37,
"Stagecoaches of Serpent Summit."
Very good. Now, episode 37, was that
the one where I leap, run and pounce?
No, no. That was the one
where you run, pounce and leap!
Precisely! Stand back!
(EXCLAIMING)
Get a hold of yourself, man.
You're out of control!
(NEIGHS)
Whoa!
It's okay! I'll get the brake!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(BARKING)
Still no photographers. How odd.
MAN: (SlNGlNG) There may be days
when things don't go right
And your shoes re¤use to dance
To make the winds of fortune
blow right
¤ou might need a second chance
So if you get one try and that don't fly
Stop and count to 10
And if at first you don't succeed
Try again
Here's your next test, kid.
Wow, bank robbers! Episode four.
(WHISTLING)
Beginner's luck is overrated
Once you blink it's come and gone
The only way to cultivate it
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Is to keep on keeping on
Yeah
Still no photographers?
Try and try and then
If at first you don't succeed, yeah
Try again
-Try, try again
-Yes, my friend
Try, try, try again
-Those men are frozen with fear.
-No wonder.
Those crazed badgers
are trying to eat their heads!
It's just like in episode 27,
when you whipped those two grizzlies.
BOTH: Huh?
And don't you never stop, no
-What is it?
-Looks like we've stumbled
on a band of cattle rustlers.
-Aren't those monkeys?
-Even worse, monkey rustlers!
Sounds like episode 34 to me.
Right answer, once again,
Junior Deputy.
I passed the test?
-Think you can handle it?
-You bet!
Let's get those monkey rustlers!
Now if you find you're batting zero
And a legend you are not
(BARKING)
You can still wind up a hero
if you give it one more shot
If you don't give in, you're gonna win
The only question's when
So if at first you don't succeed
-Try again
-Try, try, try again
-Try, try again
-And again
-Try again
-Try, try, try again
Try again
Hey! Get over on the right side
of the road, buddy.
Sheesh, London drivers.
(LAUGHING)
I tell you, Thunder,
this is the best day ever.
Yeah. You know, I never knew
it would be so much fun out here
doing this real hero stuff.
What do you mean?
Don't you do this all the time?
Oh, well, kid...
(CHUCKLES)
Well, you know, it's...
Of course, I do! I do this all the time!
(COUGHS)
-So let's talk about you, kid!
-Me?
Yeah, what's your story?
-Well...
-Hold on. Okay. Go on.
Missing!
What do you mean, he's missing?
-We've looked.
-And looked.
But there's just
no sign of Thunderbolt anywhere!
This is a catastrophe!
A calamity! A cataclysm!
We have to shoot first thing
in the morning
and I find out my star is missing.
How can you shoot a show
without a star?
How do you spell "cataclysm"?
How can you shoot a show
without a star?
How can you shoot a show without a...
A star? This is it!
This is megafantabulous!
We'll rewrite this episode
to star Lil' Lightning!
Oh, I'm a genius!
Get the writers! Fire the director!
This is going to be a whole new
direction for The Thunderbolt...
(SNICKERS)
"А whole new direction!"
What do you think of that,
Thunderbolt, old pal?
Finally, I'll be able
to step out of your shadow,
you overrated, overacting ham!
The Lil' Lightning Adventure Hour.
It has a nice ring, doesn't it?
What do you think?
(LAUGHING)
I have failed you, my muse!
Oh, fickle bird of inspiration,
to what far shore have you flown?
Poor pathetic Lars, do not despair.
I know exactly where to find
the inspiration we crave.
Well, this is art, after all. Art!
Our creativity cannot be thwarted by
trivial matters like restraining orders.
Yes, sacrifices must be made!
Gone? They're all gone?
How unspeakably rude ofAnita
to move away
without even leaving
a forwarding address!
Lars, now what am I to do?
Why, you little... What's this?
I know you. Oh, this is delicious.
"Cherry Tree Farm,
Little Tichfield, Devon."
(BARKS)
(LAUGHS)
Oh, no.
Freckles, dear. Stop helping.
(TEA KETTLE WHISTLING)
Oh, my, the tea!
(BARKING)
Yes, the paper!
No time to read this
if I'm going to finish my new song.
Well, I come from this really big family.
I knew a guy came from a big litter,
10 or 12, I forget.
-There's 101 of us.
-101 Dalmatians?
Hey, I heard about you guys.
Yeah, you were on the Twilight Bark.
Well, that's just it, isn't it?
I'm afraid all I'll ever be is one of101.
(SIGHS)
Аt least that's what my dad thinks.
Hey, Thunderbolt?
How do you become a
One-of-a-Kind Wonder Dog, anyway?
Well, in my case, it all hinged
on getting just the right agent.
But, you know, kid, getting there
isn't so tough, it's staying on top.
That's the real challenge.
You think you're doing great
and all of a sudden,
there's somebody trying
to take your place.
Crowd you out!
-Push you aside!
-Steal your spot!
-Precisely!
You know, you're all right, kid.
(GIGGLES)
I'll tell you what, little buddy.
I'm planning on doing
some more big hero stuff today.
You stick with me, maybe you'll get
your picture in the paper,
show the world that
you're not just another dog.
(BARKS)
Oh, no, no, no. Like this.
(CLEARS THROАT)
(INHALES)
(BARKS LOUDLY)
(ALL SQUАWKING)
Uh-oh.
(SQUАWKING)
(LAUGHS)
What? Patch in London?
Don't you worry.
I'll keep an eye on things here.
This is all my fault.
If only I hadn't lost count.
Stop blaming yourself, dear.
The important thing now is that
we find him before Cruella De Vil does!
It's not fair, Horace, me lad.
It's just not fair.
How come she gets off
with probation and a restraining order...
While we's left rotting away in here?
Off your bums, lads.
Sprung for your bail, somebody has.
It must be Mum come to spring us!
Mum never liked me.
Must be good old Dad!
Dad never liked you, either.
Jasper, Horace.
It's time to finish the job.
Oh, no, not her.
We always get
the worst end of it with her.
Well, if she wants us to work for her
this time, we won't be made fools of.
You look just like Mum.
Shut up, you! I ain't going
through with this, I tell you. I ain't!
Here he comes now!
(GRUNTS)
-Go on, Jasper. Go on.
-Go! Go on, go!
Аfternoon, love! Something I can...
(SCREAMING)
Hello, there.
Something I can do
for a pretty young lady like yourself?
Of course you can, you naughty man.
(CHUCKLES)
You can just give me this truck!
(SCREAMS)
(WHOOPING)
They're all inside, Jasper!
Go ahead and start it up!
(KANINE KRUNCHIES
MUSIC PLAYING)
Whatever in the world?
Hmm?
(SLURPS)
(GROАNS)
LUCKY: Hey, where's he going?
(BOTH GASPING)
-Kanine Krunchies!
PUPPY 1: What's that?
PUPPY 2: Hey, Kanine Krunchies!
(WHOOPING)
It worked, Jasper.
Like a dream, Horace, me lad,
like a dream!
You! I should have known
it was you terrible men!
Now let those puppies go right now
or I'm going to knock
the stupid out of both of you!
Here now, lady, we don't want
to have to hurt you none, so...
(SCREAMS)
(PАNTING)
HORACE: Calm down.
She's... She's mad, I say. Come on!
(SQUEALS)
(EXCLAIMS)
(SCREAMS)
Right. That's it, then.
I've had just about enough of this!
(WHIMPERING) Oh, no!
JASPER: There now.
That ought to hold you right proper.
-Jasper?
-What?
Can we just go back to jail, now?
Your muse has returned!
(GIGGLES)
But I am a failure.
You should despise me.
Stop being such a wet blanket and
come see what I've brought for you!
A gift? For me?
How very Christmas morning
with the twinkle lights of you.
The gift of inspiration!
Well, of course, these are only just
about the most adorable little puppies
I've ever seen in my whole life!
Look at these cute little darlings!
Fuzzy wuzzy little puppy poo.
Poo poo, little puppy poo.
Did you see that? Did you see that?
He gave me a little kissy!
I'm going to kiss him back now.
He's having a wobbly.
And you mean for me
to do a painting of them, don't you?
That's an absolutely lovely idea!
It makes me smile a lot.
(CАCKLES)
"Painting of them," he says.
(ALL LAUGHING)
No, no, no, darling. I don't want you
to make art of the puppies.
I want you to make art
with the puppies.
Use their coats as canvases.
Create a masterpiece
in a new medium.
Together, you and I will stun the art
world with our ruthless originality!
But that means...
(GASPS)
How could you do such a thing
to the cute little puppies?
-Poison them.
-Drown them.
Bash them in the head!
I may be eccentric,
but I am not a sicko!
-What?
-And you'll not hurt one spot
on these innocent
little creatures' heads,
not as long as I have
anything to say about it!
(MUFFLED PROTESTS)
I thought you were a man of vision,
someone who understood my passions,
who understood the complexity
that is Cruella!
Does no one get the point?
Lars, you're such a disappointment.
Well, if I can't have a masterpiece,
at least I'll finally have
a fabulous Dalmatian coat.
That's almost as good,
don't you agree?
(GULPS)
(PUPPIES WHIMPERING)
(PUPPY BARKING)
(BARKS)
(EXCLAIMS)
What's gotten into you, girl?
(BARKING LOUDLY)
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
(BARKING)
(WOМАN SCREAMING)
Kidnapped? How many?
(BARKING)
(WOМАN GRUNTS)
(DOG ON BUS BARKING)
(BARKING)
(HOWLING)
Uh-huh...
Wretched dogs.
(BARKING)
Oh!
(BOTH BARKING)
Steady, lads!
(DOGS BARKING EVERYWHERE)
I just can't understand it.
We've been out here
doing hero stuff all day
and none of these
London photographers seem to care.
Why do you want
photographers around?
Kid. Look, I got something to tell you.
(DOG BARKING)
Something I guess
I should've told you a long time ago.
I don't know how to say this,
but the truth is...
Thunderbolt, listen!
There's an emergency!
Sounds like a kidnapping!
Being held in a warehouse,
a devil woman, 101 Dalmatians.
Hey, what a coincidence!
You come from a family of101, too!
Wait, what's the matter, kid?
That is my family.
Cruella must have them again!
-Cruella?
-The devil woman!
She's the one
who kidnapped us before.
This is awful. What am I going to do?
Wait a second. Thunderbolt!
You'll help us, won't you?
Yes. Well, kid, that's what
I wanted to talk to you about.
You see, I'm not really a...
Of course, I'll help you, Patch.
Yeah, the world-famous Thunderbolt
rescues the world-famous
101 Dalmatians.
(BARKING)
Sounds like a good story to me!
Newsworthy, even.
Come on.
We'll let them know I'm on my way.
The villains will soon cringe in fear!
Mighty Thunderbolt is here!
(BARKS)
(BARK ECHOING)
POODLE GIRL: It's just wonderful!
I heard it through the Twilight Bark!
SWOONING DOG GIRL 2: Tell all!
POODLE GIRL: Well,
Thunderbolt is going to save
those little Dalmatian puppies!
(GASPS)
-The ones that were kidnapped?
-That's right!
SWOONING DOG GIRL 2:
Isn't he just a dream?
More like a nightmare!
What if Blunderbolt gets lucky
and succeeds?
If the press got wind of that,
I'd never be rid of him!
-Look, that must be the warehouse.
-Let's try over there.
-Hey, do you think you can reach that?
-No problem.
Thunderbolt, old pal.
-Lightning?
-Lightning! What are you doing here?
I came as soon as I heard.
Thought you might need a bit of help.
-Thanks for coming, little buddy.
-Wouldn't miss it.
JASPER: What's that supposed to be?
Leave us alone, Jasper.
I think it's kind of pretty.
-So, what's the plan, kid?
-See those guards?
I think you can sneak past them.
Remember the end of episode 39,
"Flight from the Forbidden Fort"?
The one where I ran,
jumped and sprang?
No, no. Sneaked,
evaded and triumphed.
Oh, yeah, of course. I get it.
Hey, you're a pretty smart kid.
That's a good plan, stealthy.
But we don't need any of that!
This is Thunderbolt!
Villains always cringe in fear
whenever Thunderbolt is here!
So true.
What we need is a full frontal assault!
How hard can it be?
That's right! How hard can it be?
Follow me!
I'm right behind you, pal.
Sort of looks like you,
except you don't have that much hair.
(BARKING)
It's Patch.
And he's brought Thunderbolt!
He'll save us!
Here now, where'd you come from?
-Get out of here, you stupid mutt!
-Maybe they didn't hear you.
Don't worry, kid. This'll be take two.
(BARKING)
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
That's more like it.
What have we here? It's you.
(GIGGLES)
I owe you a debt of gratitude,
my photogenic little friend!
If it wasn't for you, I'd have never found
your brothers and sisters.
And now I have you all!
(LAUGHING МАNIACАLLY)
Thunder, are you playing dead?
(GROАNS)
-That hurt. That really hurt.
-I knew you were faking it.
(CHUCKLES)
-He's been faking it, all right!
-Lightning, little buddy!
I am not your little buddy,
and you are no Wonder Dog.
This kid trusted you,
and look where it's got him!
-What does he mean?
-He's been lying to you all day, kid.
He doesn't care
about you or your family.
He was just trying to get his name in
the paper and save his job. Ask him!
No! Well, yeah. But... But...
But, but, but.
Hey, genius, you're no hero.
You're a fraud.
And by the way,
there never was a plan to recast you.
I just had to get you out of the way.
(LAUGHS)
Now I gotta go
take your place on the show.
My show.
(LAUGHING МАNIACАLLY)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Thunder?
I don't understand. You lied to me?
I put on an act. I'm an actor.
It's what I do.
But you said
I could be yourjunior deputy...
I made all that up! I just needed
someone who knew the script.
-But you said that you'd help us.
-Don't you get it, kid?
All that running around
and saving the day stuff, it's...
It's make-believe! It's not real.
You promised!
(CRYING)
Patch, I just...
(SIGHS)
You lied.
I'm sorry, all right?
(CRYING)
I'm not a real Wonder Dog.
I just acted like one once.
(PUPPY WHIMPERS)
-I'm hungry.
-I want to go home. It's scary here.
Where's Mother?
(WHIMPERING)
Patch?
Are you okay? Patch?
Dad was right. I am just one of101.
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry, Lucky. This is all my fault.
Hey, didn't Thunderbolt get out
of a cage like this once?
You know, in episode 13,
"The Flaming Flea Circus."
Episode 18.
Episode 18!
(PUPPIES BARKING)
Did you see what Patch just did?
Wizard, Patch! Absolutely wizard!
Hey, shut your yapping!
I'm trying to get me beauty sleep.
(SNORING)
Okay, you guys,
stick together and be quiet.
Don't look so put out.
My favourite furrier
will be open in the morning
and then we'll be out of your hair.
Perfect! Episode 53,
"The Mineshaft Mix-up."
Everybody, stay here
until I tell you it's safe to come out.
What is it with...
(SCREAMS)
-You let the puppies get away!
JASPER: Hold on!
HORACE: They can't have gone far.
Here, start searching!
When that crazy bird finds out
we lost them again, she'll skin us!
Horace! Jasper!
-What are you looking for?
-Nothing, mum!
We haven't lost the doggies
or anything!
You let them escape?
-Jasper fell asleep!
-You were snoring like a train!
(PАTCH BARKING)
The lift is barking.
The mutts must already be downstairs.
-Funny how we never heard the lift.
-Shut up, you!
-Come on, they'll be back soon!
-Aren't we going down?
Nope. We're going up!
Ready, Rolly?
No, no. No, no, no, no, no, no!
Whoa!
Can I do that again?
Okay, now the rest of you.
I'm just saying,
maybe the puppies are still upstairs
and they just tricked us
into coming down here.
Come on now, Horace.
Dogs ain't that smart.
They haven't got the big,
educated brains we got.
97, away! 98, away!
99, away!
(SCREAMS)
(LAUGHS)
Get him!
(PАNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUMBLING)
(MUFFLED GRUNTS)
VENDOR: Thanks, guv.
BUS DRIVER: Cheers.
Come on. We're gonna hitch a ride!
(SNARLS)
(GASPS)
(GASPS) Here they come!
There they are! Get them!
(PАNTING)
-What happened?
-She pushed me!
Did not!
(PUPPIES SCREAMING)
(PАTCH GRUNTING)
The crazy lady is right behind us!
(GROАNING)
(GIGGLING) He had a birdie
in his mouth!
You idiots! Here, take the wheel!
(ALL GASP)
Speed up, you imbeciles,
or we'll lose them!
Ha-ha!
That's one! Just 98 more to go!
Okay, okay, quiet on the set.
We're rolling!
And action, Wholesome Tommy!
Lightning, you're one of a...
(GULPS)
(HORN HONKING)
(SCREAMING)
Patch, help me!
Well, well,
if it isn't the little half-pint hero again!
(LAUGHING МАNIACАLLY)
Wow! Check out Patch!
(SCREAMING)
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
What do we do now, Patch?
See those windows? We can
reach them from the upper deck!
You go ahead, I'll hold them off.
Somehow.
(BARKING)
Oh, here's a feisty one.
(THUNDERBOLT BARKS LOUDLY)
PАTCH: Thunderbolt!
How you doing, kid?
-But I thought...
-Come on, haven't you seen the show?
I always arrive just in the nick of time.
Look, I may not be a real hero,
but I can act like one!
(BARKS)
(GASPS)
Lightning, don't let them hurt me!
Heart. My heart.
Lightning, this might be the end!
(HOWLING IN PАIN)
(SHUSHING)
PUPPY: She might see us.
Give me that!
I'll put this mongrel out of his misery!
(GROАNS)
(HOWLS)
Lightning, I can feel the warm
kiss of life ere it parts my cheek.
Do not mourn me when I am gone!
It is enough
that you were here at the end.
(DRAМАTIC SIGH)
Goodbye, old friend.
(SOBBING)
Good night, sweet prince!
(SCREAMS)
(ALL SCREAM)
(COUGHS)
(BARKING)
ON RADlO: Dispa¤h to Car 47,
what's your situation? Over.
No, no, fellas. I'm not with them!
I was trying to help
Thunderbolt, honest!
That's what I do. I'm a sidekick.
We're a team!
Come on, fellas! Come on!
Don't you watch TV?
Now, who's the pathetic ham actor?
I am painting spots, but she doesn't
like them so good and then she says,
"No, you must kill them,"
and I'm not so sturdy.
She's very mean to me!
And then I pass out.
There they are. Those are the ones!
-She made us do it!
Spots? I do see spots, you know.
(LAUGHING)
They're everywhere!
CRUELLA: Spot! Spot! Spot! Spot!
ROGER: There they are! It's wonderful!
They're all here!
Come now. Stop it. Stop it.
We were so worried about you.
Penny, Lucky, my darling puppies!
(BARKING)
Patch! You're safe.
We were so worried about you.
-We missed you very much, Patch.
-You did?
Of course, Son.
Mom, Dad, this is Thunderbolt.
He saved us.
I don't know how to thank you
for saving my family.
No, no. Don't thank me.
It was your son, Patch, who...
Mom! Dad! The devil woman got us.
And we were trapped
and then Patch got us out!
Yeah. And Patch made me
a trampoline!
You should have seen Patch, Mother.
He was fantastic. Just like Thunderbolt!
(THUNDERBOLT LAUGHING)
You know, they're right, kid.
Me, I'm just an actor.
But you, you are a real
One-of-a-Kind Wonder Dog!
Hey, lads, they're over here!
(PАTCH WHOOPING)
Say, "Spots"!
ANNOUNCER: Say, kiddies! ls your
dog a One-of-a-Kind Wonder Dog?
MAN: (SlNGlNG) l'm one of a kind
A one-of-a-kind dog, baby
I'm the one
Doggone son of a gun, now, baby
-I'm one of a kind
-He's one of a kind
A one-of-a-kind dog, baby
-I'm the one
-He's the one
Doggone son of a gun, now, baby
I'm one of a kind
Oh, yeah
PATCH: Wow, one of a kind!
CHORUS: Kanine Krunchies
can't be beat
They make each meal a special treat
Happy dogs are those who eat
nutritious Kanine Krunchies
THUNDERBOLT: You know, they're
right, kid. Me, I'm just an actor.
But you, you are a real
One-of-a-Kind Wonder Dog!
MAN: (SlNGlNG) l'm one of a kind
CHORUS: He's one of a kind
A one-of-a-kind dog, baby
-I'm the one
-He's the one
Doggone son of a gun, now, baby
Doggone son of a gun
I'm one of a kind
Oh, yeah
-I'm the one
-He's one of a kind
A one-of-a-kind dog, baby
-I'm the one
-He's the one
Doggone son of a gun, now, baby
PATCH: Wow, one of a kind!
That's right! All right!
MAN: (SlNGlNG)
And don't you never stop, no
So if you try that climb one more time
You might hit the top
Now if you find you're batting zero
And a legend you are not
You can still wind up a hero
if you give it one more shot
If you don't give in, you're gonna win
The only question's when
So if at first you don't succeed
-Try again
-Try, try, try again
Try, try again
-And again, yeah
-Try, try, try again
-Try again
And again and again
and again, yeah
Try, try again
Again and again and
again, yeah
Try, try, try again
Try again, yeah
(LAUGHING)
(BOTH BARKING)
(EXCLAIMS)
DIR¤ DАWSON: Oh, no, come on.
Down, boy! Down, all of y'all!
This ain't fair!