Forgive me, Mother.
I could do nothing for you.
You're sacrificing your life
for your Motherland.
What more can you do for me?
Go, son.
Long Live, India.
The General will still pardon you.
Tell him the whereabouts of
the traitors and save yourself.
I know just one traitor.
And that's you!
Long Live, India!
1 942 - 9th August
In every corner of India,
there was but one echo...
Quit India!
We'll do, or die.
As the Independence Movement spread,
...the atrocities of
the British worsened.
The man behind them
was General Douglas.
Who murdered many
unarmed men.
And hung many a freedom fighter.
But even in death,
they had but one thing to say.
''We'll do, or die!''
''1 2 dead in Delhi
in police-firing''
- They razed the whole town.
- Easy. Go on reading.
General Douglas is going back
to England on the 25th...
...on promotion!
If I had my way,
I'd hang the bloody dog!
Carry on reading.
Before that,there'll be a Regimental
Farewell Parade at Kasauni.
How long will he be there?
For a day. Just one day.
One day, eh?
There's Govind there.
And Mr Baig too.
This is the only chance
to finish him off!.
The General will go to Kasauni...
but, never return!
- Father, this is my...
- No, son.
Only one man for this job!
...Shubhankar!
You can help him. But first,
I'll go there myself.
To make the bomb.
Inform Govind today itself.
But don't tell him anything
about the mission.
Just say, I'm not keeping well.
So I'm coming there for treatment.
Very soon.
It has sprouted here too, eh?
Great! Just listen to them;
We'll do, or die.
More will die, than do, sir.
Then what are you waiting for?
Shoot them.
They too must know
the repercussions of...
...raising their voice
against the British Raj.
And this is being done because
the General is coming here.
Some trouble's brewing.
It's not the General who's coming,
but some calamity.
Let it be the General or Hitler.
What's it to you? Just shut up!
How can I? Firing in Delhi;
Curfew in Old Delhi.
Women raped by soldiers, and you
exxpect me to keep quiet?
If ever this man crosses my path,
I swear, I'll spit on him.
He'll be here nextx week.
Spit on him and fulfill your wish.
I'll do that, if your father
doesn't kill me first!
Put your tail in, eh?
Coward!
Spit on Douglas, will you?
If I had my way,
I'll kill each one of them!
This fire has been ignited
by some outsiders.
As long as I'm the C.O. here,
nobody will dare to commit treason.
It won't last...
the British Rule won't last long.
Pull that flag down.
Lower that flag.
Push them back!
Hey!
Look what's happening.
Stop him! Go, man.
What are you doing? Gone mad?
Your father's livid. Let's go.
You should be ashamed!
My son, doing such a thing?
I'll not put up with this at all.
At least think of my reputation.
If you're dying for
Independence too...
...then remove
the Western clothes.
Wear Khadi ones, and stand at
crossroads and shout slogans!
Did you hear what I said?
They are here again?
The Government has confiscated their
land and money. They'll starve.
When their son was siding with the
traitors, were they sleeping?
If you allow them in here again,
you'll be out! Understand?
What's happened?
What has never happened before!
Fights, riots, madness!
Here I am, trying to hold on to my
status and there,your darling son...
- What about him?
- Gets beaten up by a constable!
Heavens!
He's not hurt, is he?
You're alright, aren't you, son?
Hey! She's not here.
But I know where she is.
- Where?
- It was lying here.
Does this ear-ring belong
to somebody close to you?
Yes; it does.
Where had you gone
with this horse?
To find her...the girl in the bus.
- What bus and which girl?
- That bus in the Town's square.
Whose glass was stoned; that's when
I saw her and kept on staring.
I must admire your sight.
In all that riot, noise, stoning, you
saw someone, and kept on looking...
- Don't laugh; but come with me.
- How can I?
Come home tomorrow.
We'll find her by afternoon.
Our town's so small. Nobody can get
lost, even if one wishes to!
Tomorrow it is!
Come now.
Where are you running me off to?
May I ask you something?
When the whole country's burning,
how could you think of love?
If everyone thought of Love, why
would India burn at all? See this?
Great! People pick pockets. Did
you cut-off somebody's ears?
By this, you can imagine how
the wearer must be!
I could guess wrongly,
so better tell me yourself.
Very beautiful. In fact, even
that doesn't do justice to it.
When I saw her,
it was as though...
You understand, don't you?
I'll exxplain it.
- I saw her, and...
- I got that. Go on.
When I saw her,
I felt as though...
Do one thing. Think all night and
tell me when you come tomorrow. Bye!
Hey! When I saw her, it was
as though...as though what?
How come you found your way here
so early today?
You're getting worried, but he's
hardly aware of the time and duty.
You're too lenient with him.
As they say...
When a mouse finds a turmeric-root,
it thinks itself to be a grocer!
Open the door, friend.
His door may break,
but he won't wake!
Show affection to someone,
who's worth the trouble. Understand?
Let's go...
Let's go, I say.
Where are you?
- What's the matter? Let's go.
- Where to?
- To look for that girl. Where else?
- But I found her.
- Found her? Where?
- Up There.
This one? Is this the cartoon
you saw and lost your heart to?
She's Aunty!
Whom have you fallen for?
Tea, father.
- What's wrong?
- I'm alright. You go.
Have you told her?
No, I haven't.
She has suffered enough already.
And this mission is so dangerous,
she'll worry unnecessarily.
You did well.
I told my wife that you're
here to take treatment.
She got worried.
She said ask him to stay with us.
- Else, I'd have...
- No, this room will do.
I'll be coughing away here and
nobody will disturb us.
My wife wants to
go to her Mother's.
- Why?
- After 1 2 years...
...God has smiled on her.
She's pregnant.
Really? That's good news.
Congratulations.
- These books?
- They're my daughter's.
- A voracious reader. Pens poems too.
- Really?
We've a good library here.
Good!
Then she'll be happy here.
When I go to Abid Ali,
I'll drop her here.
- Coming; You're up, are you?
- What are you eating on the sly?
- Have some. It's Holy offering.
- Give some to Master Naren too.
- What's this?
- Don't get scared.
He's the driver
of an aristocrat.
Very fond ofjust one thing.
Non-stop chatter!
I'll do one thing.
I'll tell him about your illness.
By evening, the whole town will know
you're here for treatment.
Father, your medicine.
Careful, my dear friend.
Never mind the father.
Tell me about the daughter.
She must be able to support herself.
She's gone to the library.
Hold on. I lied for you for
the first time in my life.
Actually it opens at 9 A.M.
But I told him, at 8 A.M.
The watchman there is related to me.
Bribe him and he'll open it earlier.
After that, it's just you and her.
On that first meeting...
Recite a lovely couplet to her,
like my uncle had recited.
My aunt was drying her hair
in the sun, and my uncle...
Let me go, please.
No poetry.
I just knew you'd come here
in search of knowledge.
This library is a
Trove of Knowledge.
Books? These are scientific.
They tell, why the sky is blue.
And these are of literature, telling
why did Juliette love Romeo!
And these are of accounts,
that tell this is our 3rd meeting.
Yesterday, in the bus. Today morning
on the swing; And now, here.
Since we're discussing accounts,
naturally one wishes to know...
Who are you; Where you've come
from...and also what is your name!
Are you the librarian here?
Do I seem one to you?
Anyway, you at least enquired.
Now ask me, where I come from,
and my name too!
Go on, ask me.
- Let go of me.
- Go on, ask.
I have one thing of yours which you
will get, only if you ask me my name.
- Let me go.
- Ask me my name then.
What impertinence!
Let me go.
You're cross over such a small issue?
Go on, ask me.
Look at the ironies of life.
We both yearned to meet.
And when we are, it's on the sly,
like a couple of thieves!
- Nobody saw you come?
- No.
The General has a very tight
security. But one thing is certain.
He'll definitely attend the drama,
we're presenting to welcome him.
He'll be in the balcony.
It's a difficultjob, no doubt.
- Shubhankar is coming, isn't he?
- Yes.
Here's the raw material for the bomb.
And this is the map of the hall.
- Is your daughter with you?
- Yes, but she doesn't know this.
Good! Send her to the rehearsal
and send me the news through her.
- Now we'll not meet again.
- Is this a final one then?
God forbid!
- Victory to India!
- Amen!
Who is it?
Just one minute.
- Why did you close the door?
- I felt very cold.
Keep it here.
- Lovely!
- Come on now, start eating.
- You look very happy.
- It's a lovely place.
- I feel like staying here only.
- Then do.
The library's good too, I hear.
Such a library, such books...
Such people even.
Never seen before.
You had gone to see Uncle Baig.
How is he?
Fine. He's busy with a play.
Has called you for assistance.
- Me?
- Yes. Tomorrow, at 1 0 A.M.
And tell him he has forgotten to
give me the white medicine.
Good! You at least found time here,
to think of your treatment.
You'll get well here soon.
I just feel it.
- Why does aunty shout so?
- But she means well. So go now.
One soldier on that balcony
and another one here.
You on that gate, and you,
on the other.
Ten soldiers in the hall.
Four soldiers up here.
And you shall be at the gate
with your whole platoon.
- Wonderful! Don't trust me even?
- Am I mad, sir?
Do I want to invite my death
by suspecting you?
- Then why are you here?
- Just for security.
Ever since the general's arrival,
the treachery is on the rise.
Where everyone knows each other,
nobody will dare come.
You don't know their guts.
There's a revolutionary
present here itself.
What? Who?
See over there.
Here? She's a sweet, promising and
a decent girl. Acts well too.
Who'll guess she's your kid?
You teachers leave nobody!
Not even your friends.
What was that couplet you recited?
''O friend, you're my foe...''
''Any man,
whom you befriend...''
''Why should the
sky be his foe?''
Please go!
We're getting late here.
I've to go on some
urgent errand too.
Alright, my dear. See sir?
She calls the shots even here!
God bless you!
Why don't you understand?
I must go.
- She must've come. You manage here.
-Manage, my foot! Will I play Romeo?
- Where are you going?
- It's imperative that I go.
The rehearsal's important too.
You're forgetting the lines, not me.
You talk of books?
He's forgotten his name!
- Books? What books?
- The one with lines in them.
- Keep jabbering. I'm going!
- Stop him!
I can't! I must go.
- What's the urgency for books?
- You won't understand.
Go on then...
Why did you stop?
When is the General coming?
- Yes, when is he exxpected?
- Nextx week. Why?
And I'm leaving? We're doing
this for him, aren't we?
You're right. I must learn my lines.
I don't know why I forget them.
- The General will sit here...
- Baig Uncle.
- My dear! How are you?
- I'm fine.
That are you! If you help me in this,
I'll say you're even finer!
Uncle, daddy said...
- Do I put some flowers here too?
- Yes, all over.
Yes, what did he say?
He said you forgot
the white medicine.
Tell him, I'll send it today.
Take this. The actors always forget
their lines. Prompt them, please.
Put phosphorous in a medicine bottle
and give it to Mr Pathak.
- Tell him, when Shubhankar arrives..
- Is he coming?
This moon shines through you.
Shall I swear by it?
No. It waxxes and wanes.
Don't swear by it.
I believe in you.
My body, mind and life...
- What are the following lines?
- Lines?
But what's your name, dearest?
Knowing name is not knowing a person.
It's just a name, not a virtue.
Had the rose been known as a thorn,
it would still smell as sweetly.
If water had been called fire,
it'd still be cool.
Change my name, if you will,
but I'll still be the same.
I'll always love you...
what's the nextx line?
- ''Because you are you...''
- Yes.
Because you are you.
I know that it
wasn't an act.
It was your love for me.
How easily you put across
your true feelings.
And I...I don't even
know your name.
You know I wasn't acting.
It was my love. For you.
You! What are you doing here?
Go away.
- You didn't ask me my name.
- Softly. They'll wake up. Go now.
- I'll come up then.
- What the hell! Don't come up.
Don't come up, I said.
You'll fall!
Don't ever let go of this hand.
Else, I'll die.
- Don't say that.
- Okay, I won't.
Just let me look at you
to my heart's content.
Those lips; these eyes;
These eyelashes...
Leave me. Go away.
Somebody may wake up. Go!
Okay.
But promise to come early tomorrow.
- Where?
- The Rehearsal Hall.
- Okay, I'll come a bit early.
- Not a bit early; before everyone.
- Okay, go now. Someone may hear.
- How can I go?
- Why not?
- You're holding on to my hand.
- Listen...
- Yes?
- You didn't tell me.
- What?
- Your name?
- My name?
We've got a message from the H.Q.
There's a plot to kill the General.
Some are here; and more exxpected.
They also have material for a bomb.
The H.Q. have requested
the Army for help.
Call an officer's meeting at once
and arm the 2 companies concerned.
Careful.
Tell Mr Baig that
the job is done.
Keep the bomb here
in this room.
It's raining heavily.
The roads are teeming with police.
They're searching all the houses.
Our friends are exxpected. What now?
Get a hold of yourself!.
Let's go.
Carry on with the rehearsal.
I'll be back soon.
Right, Sir.
Come on, let's get on with it.
- Someone will snatch you from me...
- Who can dare to do that?
Has anyone ever snatched life from
one's body? Sleep from the eyes...
And thirst from the lips?
Time can, if it wills.
No! That's not true! I'll snatch
you from Time itself then.
- Promise me Rajjo...
- I'm not Rajjo, Naren.
It's just that...
Wait!
Please listen to me.
Forgive me, but don't blame me.
Blame my love.
Is it necessary
to flaunt love?
I wasn't flaunting.
They were my true feelings.
And I truly love you.
I can't live without you.
Will you marry me?
Rajjo was right. I'm just coming
from down. The atmosphere is tense.
I think the Army has come
to know about our mission.
- Your life's in danger. Go at once!
- And leave my work incomplete?
Our friends are coming tomorrow.
I can't leave.
I'm here. I'll manage it all.
Your life...
Don't worry about my life.
You said your wife wished
to visit her mother's place.
- Send her tomorrow morning.
- And what about Rajjo?
I'll take care of her.
- It's a riot there and you sit here!
- You! I thought it was her.
- Now scoot from here.
- Ofcourse. I'll run all the way.
But it's your turn now.
So run!
She's leaving town.
Lock, stock and barrel.
I saw her luggage being loaded.
The bus will leave soon. So, run!
I'm telling the truth.
Better hurry, and go!
I've been telling for days now.
Pack my things. But who listens?
Careful! Keep it safely.
- When will we start?
- As soon as we can.
I've to go to Nurgadh.
- On the other side of the pass.
- Sure! We'll go there too.
Hey! You won't get a seat.
The bus may go too. Come on.
If we don't get a seat, we'll have
to go standing all the way!
- And keep on eye on things.
- Are you coming with us, or not?
I thought you...
You can never leave me.
Promise me, dear,
that you'll never leave me.
What is it?
I was little late in coming.
Aunty's gone to her mother's. I had
to see her off at the bus stand.
And I thought you went away forever.
Never to return.
And suppose, I do have
to go one day?
Then I'll die.
I'll really die.
Promise me that you will
never leave me!
How can I ever leave
my father alone and go?
And what of me?
Can you leave me?
Yes, I can...
- Hey! What's wrong, dear?
- Nothing.
Then why the tears?
Won't you tell me?
If not you,
then whom do I tell?
Whom else do I have?
Has anybody broken your heart?
- Naren hasn't...
- Papa...
Why would he hurt me?
I've hurt myself.
I can't do the Juliette's role.
Why not?
I keep forgetting my lines.
Is that any reason to cry?
An army officer's daughter and
look how she's crying!
All these efforts are a waste.
I just cannot laugh today.
Perseverance never
goes waste, dear.
We both are persevering
and living, aren't we?
Else, when your mother died,
leaving a 2-month old infant...
I thought it was the end.
Look, my dear.
I can bear to see everything.
But not tears in your eyes.
An army-officer...
And see how he's weeping!
Alright.
I'll never cry again.
It's not a must that every
girl be a Juliette.
Some revolutionaries are
coming here tonight.
I'll do the patrolling myself.
Make all the preparations.
Catch him alive.
Govind, get some water and bandages
We've to dress his wound
They killed Tyagi.
- Shubhankar...wired us...
- Yes, go on.
Douglas...
He's not coming on 25th.
But 1 0 days later.
With a great difficulty...
This pistol...Shubhankar's.
My dear.
Your one more
brother has gone!
But we'll win.
We'll definitely win!
As long as we're together...
Shubhankar is not alone.
You are with me,
aren't you?
Tell me.
Surround this house, men.
Must be hiding here only.
Don't let him escape. Hurry!
Open the door.
We've to search this house.
-But I'm the manager of his Lordship.
- And we have a warrant to search.
- We've chased a traitor here.
- But no traitor has come here.
Get aside!
Come with me, men.
You go here. And you lot, there.
The rest follow me!
Didn't I say nobody's here?
Disturb us for no rhyme or reason?
- See? Nobody's here.
- Keep quiet. Let us do our duty.
We'll do, or die!
- How did things change overnight?
- We can never be one!
Forget that you ever loved
a revolutionary's daughter.
Forget that we ever met.
Don't try to meet me now.
I'm going. Forever.
Told him everything?
Didn't think of our ideals?
You told him of our revolution?
If he gets the police, you didn't
think what will happen to us?
- Go from here.
- No. I've come to your father...
For what? What do you want?
Why have you come?
To tell you whatever she told me,
will not be revealed. Believe me.
It's impossible
to trust those,
...who've sold themselves
and their souls!
I'm here before you,
and my soul's with me too!
Yes, I can see that!
No, you're not!
Now I am. So tell me.
I wanted to say that I respect
your ideals and patriotism.
I don't want to argue, but if
you try and meet her again...
You'll kill me? Go ahead.
But till my end,
I'll always say...
...that I love Rajjo and
wish to wed her!
You fool! When the country's resoun
-ding with the cry of ''Quit India''..
...you fret over
Love and romance?
- Love is not a sin!
- Yes it is! It is a sin.
A man who's not a patriot, can love
nobody on earth! It's all humbug!
That's unfair, sir.
Your love for...
...your nation is great!
And our's is nothing?
When I can understand your patriotism
try to understand my love too.
I know I'm my father's son.
I also know she can't come
into my world.
But I can leave that world
and come into yours, sir.
I'll leave that house, wealth,
money...everything, sir.
I'll leave it all. But she's mine.
You cannot separate us.
I'll come tomorrow morning. After
having taken my Mom's blessings.
I'll come and seek yours.
Why are you sitting here alone?
You seem upset.
What is it?
I'm leaving home, mom.
What!
Bring your girl here.
Don't be afraid, son.
I'll convince your father.
I've never asked anything of him.
But for you, I'll do so today.
He won't be able to refuse.
Bring her here.
She'll never agree.
I can't bring her here.
But why not?
She's a daughter of
a revolutionary.
Her brother laid down
his life for the country.
Dad will never accept her.
I've hurt you very much,
haven't I?
No, my dear. It's I who
has hurt you all.
It's always been ''I'',
''mine'', ''my ideals''.
The English didn't kill my son.
I did!
I only taught him about patriotism.
About dying for the country.
But he became a martyr...
Did you say...
Yes.
That don't cry for martyrs.
Your Mother.
I killed her too.
Bearing the load of life,
and awaiting me for hours...
...her eyes turned to stone.
My dear, because of me,
I don't want your life...
You have a full right
to lead your life.
My life is with you
Had you told me before, I'd not
have even looked at Nandu.
Let alone love him!
But now you do, don't you?
Don't think me weak.
I'm your daughter.
- Will you forget him?
- Yes.
Absolutely!
I'll never even give him a thought.
If he comes, I'll say I've
nothing to do with him.
Why should he be after me?
There are plenty of girls around.
- I'll forget everything.
- But he loves you.
Wants to marry you.
But I don't wish it.
Honestly, I don't.
Look at me and tell me that.
He's a good boy. He's willing to
discard everything for you.
If you refuse him,
I won't like it.
You're very nice...
Too good!
You're going, son? Go.
I won't stop you. Once you marry,
all will be well.
Take this.
My blessings to her.
I'll take this to her. But give
her your blessings yourself.
I'll come in the night, with her.
Don't sleep. Await us.
May I go now?
I'm His Exxcellency speaking.
I wish to talk to the Major.
- No! What are you doing?
- Get aside!
Run, my dear! Run!
He has got the soldiers.
No!
Soldiers!
Run! ...Just run!
Give this to Shubhankar and
ask him not to give up!
I'll follow you later.
Don't argue!
Time's running out.