~~ Life is a tombola.
Tom tom tombola, ~~
~~ of color and of light,
of color and of light. ~~
~~ And every one in the tombola,
tom tom tombola. ~~
tom tom tombola, ~~
~~ finds someone they can love. ~~
~~ Tombola! ~~
~~ In the tombola of the world, ~~
~~ I've been very lucky. ~~
~~ I bet all my affection on your
number. ~~
~~ I dreamed of your name,
I was waiting to meet you... ~~
~~ and the tombola of the world
rewarded me with your love. ~~
~~ Life is a tombola.
Tom tom tombola, ~~
~~ of color and of light,
of color and of light. ~~
~~ And the rhythm of the
tombola, tom tom tombola, ~~
~~ carries me to your love. ~~
~~ Tombola! ~~
~~ In a forest in China, the little
Chinese girl was lost. ~~
~~ I was lost there too, and so each
other we did find. ~~
~~ Young lady, young lady,
yesterday you were just a child. ~~
~~ And no matter what they say
you're all that a woman has to be. ~~
~~ Young lady, young lady,
you started to show off. ~~
~~ If you dress up and paint
up it's for me, and me, ~~
~~ and me alone. ~~
~~ That little girl is grown up
now and she wears stiletto heels. ~~
~~ And when she crosses the city
the boys sing her song... ~~
~~ as they pass her by. ~~
~~ Young lady that I love,
young lady that I love. ~~
~~ Young lady, young lady,
yesterday you were just a child. ~~
~~ Like a gift from life, you're
a flower, you're the sun. ~~
~~ and you're all that woman has to be. ~~
~~ You're all that woman has to be. ~~
~~ Young lady, you're all that a
woman has to be. ~~
~~ Young lady... ~~
~~ I am all... ~~
Tombola.
~~ I want the moon that illuminates... ~~
~~ your silhouette as you walk. ~~
~~ With a ballerina's steps... ~~
~~ you follow it, never looking. ~~
~~ I want you to come full of love... ~~
~~ and embrace me when you arrive. ~~
"20 CENTIMETERS"
~~ When you feel so lucky and
you laugh as you kiss. ~~
Fucking hell!
~~ I want the calm of the evening... ~~
~~ when night begins to fall. ~~
~~ It's the twilight that burns... ~~
~~ as my love burns for you. ~~
~~ I want your hand to guide me. ~~
Thanks, love.
~~ If I'm in the dark... ~~
What's up?
What's this, Tomas?
It fell on top of me, I thought it
was a coffin.
It's bad luck!
It's a cello, Marieta.
- A what?
- A cello.
I inherited it.
Inherited it, peewee?
You kept that quiet.
My aunt Rafalita.
She was very fond of me and she
died suddenly.
Rafalita?
I think you invent your family as you
go along...
so that I can't argue back.
The coffee's on, I'm going to the bank.
My ass hurts, Tomas.
I fell asleep again and I woke up out
in the country.
I felt like a bag of cement.
It's pathetic.
He saw I was out cold so he gave it
to me up the ass.
That costs more.
Recently, there are more
clients asking you to play dead.
The other girls told me.
What'll you do with something so big?
Learn to play it.
You know how much a class for that
guitar would cost?
Do you?
Not talking?
You're keeping very quiet.
It'd cost an arm and a leg.
My arm and leg.
So, things were bad enough and
aunt Rafalita didn't help.
A kilo of carrots.
A bunch of grapes for white gazpacho,
and I need some garlic too.
Hey, kiddo, you look very pretty.
She looks like a slut.
You gotta look good.
Did you want zucchini?
She says a director'll pass by one day
and put her in a movie.
You like these two?
Lovely, aren't they?
Our mother, God rest her, always said:
Garlic every day keeps troubles away.
And look at you now, a spinster with
bad breath.
My grandma peeled them and used
them as suppositories for worms.
Yeah, for everything.
If you mash them in a poultice they
cure bunions.
- And grapes?
- A bunch.
These customers are a pain in the ass.
You've just got a hangover.
Know what time she came home?
At no time.
She came straight here, didn't even
get changed.
She stinks to high heaven.
Hey, how was the concert?
Tell me about it.
Well... it was no big deal.
Like a bride's first night.
Rebecca, have you got almonds?
A-S-S.
Look at his ass!
It's like a peach.
Rebecca, that's everything.
What do I owe you?
What did you want, ma'am?
- I'm off, ladies.
- So long, Marieta.
Marieta!
Brazil!
It's all love and sex down there.
That's why the place is thriving.
- What do you want?
- The usual, love.
I'm on night shift and Paulito will
only stay...
with his aunt Marieta.
How are you, Pili?
It's hot up here.
Don't lean out too far, you'll fall
down the shaft.
Don't worry, love.
- Any word of a wedding?
- Yeah, any day!
Brazil's the place for weddings.
There's everything there.
And plenty of men.
We'd have 4 or 5 each.
It's true, I'm not joking.
The best beaches, the best cocks,
the best doctors for you, to cut off
your whatsit.
The rich get operated there.
Don't give me any crazy ideas,
or I'll start getting flaky.
Down there, even we'd be rich.
This sandwich is great.
It's got the best salami.
Hey!
Don't hang your washing now!
We won't even see the sky!
What do you want me to do?
I have to dry it somewhere.
Your sister took in those clothes
this morning,
I saw her!
You're just being nosey!
What's it to you, you fat, ugly, old hag!
Every time you and your sister stick
your heads out,
you're like Punch and Judy.
Go fuck yourself,
because no one else will!
Fleabag!
You're always bitching at us.
We'll come down and...
Stop it, Berta, you're needling them.
It cheers me up.
Naturally big!
And your son is always wandering...
Shut up, you whores!
I don't inject gasoline in my ass!
We're so sick of you.
My sister and I are going to beat
the shit out of you.
There's another one.
Bitch, what was that?
Was it your cat's piss?
We're going to strangle your dog
and hang it on your door.
Berta.
You old hag.
I'm off.
Come on, insult Candelaria a bit.
She won't feel so lonely.
You're the slut, Candelaria!
Your mother was a whore!
She nursed you on sour milk!
We're going to burn you out and
you'll rot on the street.
Sluts.
Old rat bag.
I'll bring the kid down.
It's a lot of money.
But it's a dead certificate.
That's why the initial investment
is high.
I'd have to postpone my operation,
and I'd planned
it for a year from now, at most.
No, because during the opera
season we'll get our money back...
three times over.
Let's see.
How are you going to get the tickets,
the boxes,
those season tickets?
That's all controlled.
It's taken care of.
All we need is the money so
I can start selling them.
Scalping is very tricky.
What's up, love?
Don't you like "rosbife"?
It's delicious.
Ass licker!
It tastes like rubber!
You were late and I had to reheat it!
The game is half over.
I'm going to get ready.
Mari...
Don't give me a hard time.
I have to think about it.
It's strange, I don't
know what's wrong with me,
I'm seeing you as if it were the
first time.
~~ Words again, always words,
the same old words. ~~
I don't know how to tell you.
~~ Only words. ~~
But you're the beautiful
love story I'll never stop reading.
~~ Easy words, pleasing words.
It was all too lovely, ~~
You're my yesterday and tomorrow.
~~... by far too lovely. ~~
forever my only truth.
~~ But the time for dreams is over. ~~
~~ Memories wither too when they're
forgotten. ~~
You're like the wind that makes the
violins sing...
and carries the scent of roses far away.
~~ Candy bars, sweets and chocolate. ~~
At times I don't understand you.
~~ Thanks, but not for me, you
can give them to another... ~~
~~ who likes the wind, the scent
of roses. ~~
~~ Gentle, honeyed words stay in
my mouth, never in my heart. ~~
One more word.
~~ Words, words, words. ~~
Listen to me.
I beg you.
~~ Words, words, words. ~~
~~ Words, words, words, more words
that you throw to the wind. ~~
This is my fate, to talk to you.
To talk to you like the first time.
~~ More words, always words,
the same words. ~~
If only you could understand.
~~ Only words. ~~
If only you'd listen, at least once.
~~ Magical words, tactical words,
that sound false. ~~
You're my forbidden dream.
~~ Yes, so false. ~~
My only torment and my only hope.
~~ Nothing stops you when you start. ~~
~~ If you knew how much I need a
bit of silence. ~~
For me, you're the only music that
makes the stars...
dance above the dunes.
~~ Candy bars, sweets and chocolate. ~~
If you didn't exist, I'd invent you.
~~ Thanks, but not for me, you
can give them to another ~~
~~ who likes stars above the dunes. ~~
~~ Gentle, honeyed words stay in
my mouth, never in my heart. ~~
Another word, just one.
~~ Words, words, words. ~~
Listen to me.
I beg you.
~~ Words, words, words. ~~
I swear.
~~ Words, words, words, more words
that you throw to the wind. ~~
You're so lovely!
~~ Words, words, words. ~~
~~ More words that you throw to
the wind. ~~
That's Marieta.
You scared me!
You were lying there like a stiff.
What time is it?
4:30.
Aw, shit!
I fell asleep again and
missed the fucking rush hour.
What rush hour?
When they get out of the soccer
game they're all horny as hell.
- I bet you cleaned up.
- You'd better believe it.
Three leg-overs and three pairs
of blow jobs.
Look.
You had time for all that?
You're a killer.
At your age!
I had five from
Real Madrid in one car,
and sucked them all off.
That means they won.
They were really happy.
High as kites.
I gave them a special price and did
it all in one car.
This narcolepsy is shit.
I just fucking pass out anywhere.
What is it?
A very rare disease.
I get sleepy and then I pass out
wherever I am.
That's venereal.
They said I should always have
someone with me.
Shit, I've always been so independent.
I was leaving but...
if you want I'll stay a while.
I don't want you getting wobbly.
There's Bunny.
She says she makes good money
with that routine.
Like it?
Yeah, I know you all do.
Wait, I'll get in.
Sure, you like to look, then what?
She thinks turning tricks is like being
in a play.
Hey, you know
I'm having my operation next year?
God willing.
Why? Your pecker is what earns
the money.
Because after the operation
I'm quitting the game,
that's why.
I said that ten years ago when I got
rid of Puppy.
Yeah, but you're illiterate.
Who's Puppy?
My pecker, Puppy.
Come on, calling it Puppy...
What about Carla?
She called it "Pinch", like a pinch
of salt.
What did Charete call it?
"Cochombo", like that private
detective, "Cochombo".
Yeah, but mine runs in the family.
The Carpantas have very thick, long,
hard dicks.
What's so funny?
What did you have?
A little worm?
- Something ridiculous?
- A button.
It was horrible.
Disgusting and embarrassing.
Since my operation ten years ago,
I feel nothing down there.
Neither good nor bad.
Nothing.
But you had your operation in the
Stone Age.
Things have changed a lot.
No one recovers from having their
dangler cut off.
The ones who say they feel like a
woman say it so...
as not to look stupid.
But it's a lie.
No more tricks tonight.
Sweetheart!
Are you getting wobbly again?
Are you upset?
Is it because of Puppy?
Did I scare you?
Come on!
Don't you know I'm an awful liar?
I'm illiterate, I don't know much,
so I make things up.
But I mean no harm.
What's wrong?
Having the same name as my father
and having a dick...
as big as his gives me the creeps.
What'll you do when you have a pussy?
You're an idiot.
What do you think I'll do?
Work somewhere respectable,
like a real woman.
I'd love to read the news on TV.
You have to study for that.
Then I'll study, I'm still young.
I'll take either of you, I've just
been paid.
One of us has a surprise between
her legs.
I don't care.
You go, I'm burned out.
I'm going for a coffee.
Take care, Marieta.
And don't worry, it'll all work out.
I wish every night was like this.
Hello, this is a message
for Adolfo Carpanta Orozco.
This is the Temp Agency.
Come by on Monday morning,
there may be a job for you.
Goodbye and thank you.
I need the money for the opera tickets.
What's the opera about?
It begins with a queen who beheads
her suitors...
but there's a happy ending.
That's odd.
If she beheads people, how can it
end happily?
I need it tomorrow.
Will you lend it to me?
Of course I will.
It's great, Tomas!
Things are looking up!
Putting up with this every day.
They're all useless.
That blonde over there...
She needs a good fuck.
Nobody needs a bad one.
She's a real nasty bitch.
Forget one form and she has you
shitting bricks.
- She can't be that bad.
- Oh, no?
If you get her, you'll soon find out.
Next.
It's your lucky day.
Sir!
Sir, I forgot!
Get back in line, please.
Next.
You're screwed.
Sit down.
Not there.
There.
I.D. please.
- I'm here for...
- The computer will tell me.
Let's see.
Cleaning service, night shift.
Adolfo Carpanta Orozco.
I'm sorry,
as the database says "Adolfo"...
they've assigned you a
job for an Adolfo, that is, for a man.
And?
And... your name doesn't
correspond with your appearance.
And would you be kind enough to
offer it to me?
Because,
officially, miss, I'm still Adolfo.
Just a moment.
I'll check it out now.
Adolfo?
Adolfo!
You'll have to wear a
uniform that corresponds...
to the sex that appears on your I.D.
~~ You want to change and you
can do it. ~~
~~ You're going to change. ~~
DISAPPOINTMENT STREET
~~ You can change. ~~
~~ You want to. ~~
Hold it without fear.
Like you'd hold the body of
a woman you were making love to.
Look,
Tomas, music comes from sex.
But harmony also comes from sex.
That's right, don't be scared.
Seduce it.
- I can't reach.
- That doesn't matter.
Seduce it.
Dominate it.
Make it obey you.
Hello, Marieta.
Good morning.
Who is this?
I'm Tomas's private teacher.
For the cello.
And who's paying the teacher?
I get a weekly class in exchange for
a season ticket to the opera.
So I'm paying her, right?
Is she annoyed by my pedagogy?
Don't talk as if I weren't here!
- Don't get angry.
I'm angry because I'm saving to get
rid of a spare bit of flesh...
and I'm not willing to pay for this
dwarf's fancy ideas!
So there!
The teacher has gone.
Don't be angry.
She says I've got talent.
We've all got talent, Tomas.
What we don't have is money to
develop it.
What's up?
Are you a bit upset?
I need a cuddle.
Give me a hug.
I can't be angry with you.
You can do anything with me.
What if you fall in love with that teacher?
You like older women.
I don't trust her.
She wants something.
Listen, Mari.
Don't worry.
Opera is getting really popular.
We'll make a lot of money.
I'll make sure you don't go short.
Whatever extra we earn is for your
operation.
I love it when you talk like the man
of the house.
It cheers me up.
You have to call the guard every
half hour on the interphone,
so you don't fall asleep.
A joint?
But they do a round in the middle
of the night.
Got it all clear?
Take the mop.
No, the other way round.
Don't touch the floor.
Turn it round.
Come on, keep going.
Not you, the mop.
This is...
Watch out,
it's new, very expensive.
You haven't used wax or anything.
That's good.
Make sure all the corners are clean.
That's it.
That's good.
A general clean.
Clenched fists, nervous person.
Take it easy, man.
This job will relax you.
I split up from my wife, a month ago.
I don't care.
I'm devastated.
Hello!
I'm the new cleaning guy.
- I'm calling to...
- OK.
All right.
Mop, mop, mop,
mop, mop, mop...
Hello!
It's tremendous.
The immensity.
Berta!
What is it?
- Shall I take Pauli to school?
- Yes, come up.
I'll fix breakfast for you.
Is the price negotiable?
No haggling, I'm not Moroccan.
Well, I'll think about it.
All right.
This way.
- So long.
- So long, love.
Why are you selling the furniture?
I have to.
Why?
The bastards in
the bank are repossessing the place.
You think what I earn dusting
off rubber dicks pays for the house...
and Pauli's school?
Find another job that pays you
more money.
Look, given that I'm fat and I won't
see 30 again,
all I can do
here is what the Ecuadorians do.
Clean up other people's shit for
a pittance.
This country has gone to hell.
I've got a bit of money saved,
but it's for the operation on my pecker.
Don't talk rubbish.
Maria's taking you to school today.
My hands are wet.
Come here
and I'll dry them for you, love.
Now the other hand.
What are you doing today, Pauli?
Marieta...
What?
Before I go to school, would
you show me your penis?
He's studying the reproductive organs.
The other kids have their fathers
at home.
We thought you could help us.
Berta...
Don't be so old fashioned.
Rebecca, where's your sister?
She can't come, she's sick.
They're not rotten, are they?
Back home, we give the rotten ones
to the pigs.
What's wrong with her?
They're perfect.
Nothing, women's trouble.
A kilo of cherries.
Anything else, Nicolasa?
- Weigh them for me again.
- Have I ever cheated you?
I can't see very well.
Go on, love.
See what they weigh.
A kilo, grandma.
Put it on my slate.
They always cheat us.
Yeah, and then I have to give
her credit.
What do you want?
Vegetables for a stew.
She isn't sick.
Know where she is?
She left home,
with a man who could be her father.
What am I saying?
He could be her grandfather!
He says he's a TV producer.
- You don't say!
- She can go to hell.
You spend your life cultivating
the girl,
fertilizing her, so that she'll be shiny
and colorful some day.
And the next thing you know...
...she gets plucked by the first creep
that passes.
Adolfo.
Too much!
That's you he's carrying over his
shoulder.
That's you he's carrying like a burden.
You have to get ahead in life.
You what?
You have to get ahead, suck dicks.
What?
What was that, bitch?
Enjoy yourself while you can.
You're a miserable faggot...
and a pathetic transvestite!
~~ May infinity be left without its stars... ~~
~~ or may the ocean lose its immensity... ~~
~~ but may the darkness of
your eyes never fade... ~~
~~ and may your honey-colored skin
remain the same. ~~
~~ If the rainbow were to lose its beauty... ~~
~~ and the flowers their colors and
perfume, ~~
~~ I wouldn't feel as sad as I would... ~~
~~ if I were to lose your love. ~~
~~ I care about you, and you,
and you, and only you, ~~
~~ and you, and you. ~~
~~ I care about you, and you, and you, ~~
~~ and no one else but you. ~~
~~ It's crazy but it's true,
I only want to be with you. ~~
~~ Dark eyes, honey-colored skin
that drive me to despair. ~~
~~ I care about you, and you, and you, ~~
~~ and no one else but you, and you,
and you. ~~
~~ I care about you, and you, and you, ~~
~~ and no one else but you. ~~
~~ It's crazy but it's true,
I only want to be with you. ~~
~~ You stopped and smiled at me
and asked if I'd care to dance. ~~
~~ I fell into your open arms, ~~
~~ and I didn't have a chance. ~~
~~ Now listen honey... ~~
~~ I care about you, and you, and you, ~~
~~ and no one else but you, and you,
and you. ~~
~~ I care about you, and you, and you, ~~
~~ and no one else but you. ~~
~~ There are people who like
pasteurized milk. ~~
condensed milk. ~~
~~ There are people who like milk
in their coffee. ~~
~~ And you, who the hell are you
trying to milk? ~~
~~ I care about you, and you,
and you, ~~
~~ and no one else but you, and you,
and you. ~~
~~ I care about you, and you,
and you, ~~
~~ and no one else but you. ~~
Cinderella!
So you've woken up!
What a wallop!
Are you back with us again?
Let's see how you are.
Do you feel all right?
You were fast asleep!
You were snoring so much all the
patients complained.
It's true.
Now, take it easy...
That's it, move slowly.
You're not dizzy?
Good.
Let's see.
Don't worry, we explained everything
to your husband.
I had to tell a few lies.
I said I was your boyfriend so they'd
let me in.
But that wasn't enough.
So I said we were married.
They looked at me and they let me in.
A pigeon.
You fainted when I arrived with the
strawberries.
You hit your head on a crate of
red peppers.
You were out for five hours.
But I didn't waste the time.
Here.
Hold this.
A great tune!
Mariana, look!
That is one beautiful man.
Keep the helmet.
A gift.
Tell me where you work.
In a house.
With a circle.
A clock.
A church!
No, not a church.
Trains, a station!
You work in a station?
Which one?
Nose.
Sneeze!
A-tishoo.
Atocha!
I love that game.
I'm good, I play it with my mother.
...convinced he loves her.
I doubt it.
That bike is the best ride she's ever had.
Can I see you there some day?
You work during the day.
You work at night, in the station.
Cleaning windows...
and the floor.
You work in Atocha all night
cleaning the whole station.
But she's so ugly.
And the guy is so cute.
I'll drop by some night.
- Don't look at her.
- I bet she's happy.
Act like we haven't seen.
Good afternoon.
~~ Green, how I want you green. ~~
~~ Green wind. Green branches. ~~
~~ The ship out on the sea... ~~
~~ and the horse on the mountain.
Green, how I want you green. ~~
~~ With the shade upon her waist,
she dreams on her balcony. ~~
~~ Green flesh, her hair green... ~~
~~ with eyes of cold silver.
Green, how I want you green. ~~
~~ Green, how I want you green. ~~
A fruit stocker.
His name's Raul, like my cousin
who jerked off...
with me in grandma's shed.
That's a sign.
Let the man do his thing.
Officially speaking, we're both men.
Listen to me,
this knows what's what.
Look, he's an innocent soul.
He's very naive.
And he gave me his motorbike
helmet.
And he's a musician.
That means sensitivity.
You know what?
It won't go anywhere.
After the first date, men always get
scared.
Isn't that so?
Give me five!
That's it!
Maybe I imagined it all.
I've got a lot of imagination, Gustavo.
And I can see love under every stone.
Look, if a man runs you home on
his bike,
he wants something.
If he races his engine at you he wants
to marry you.
Now I'll be seeing myself dressed
in white!
Idiot!
Hello, is Berta here?
What Berta?
A woman, kind of fat...
- She owe you money?
- No.
She left two or three weeks ago.
She took money from the Hill and
articles.
Vibrators.
Gosh!
I haven't seen her either.
People in Spain are very lazy and they
steal a lot.
Oh, fruit stocker,
with an ass like a peach,
come and see me, please.
~~ High school girl, high school girl, ~~
~~ I've fallen in love with the teacher. ~~
~~ I can't help it. ~~
~~ High school girl, high school girl. ~~
Believe me, I'm in no mood for
concerts.
The pupil isn't in.
Caress it as if it were a woman.
But I like men.
But don't you realize that the cello
is a man...
with a woman's body?
So place your head properly,
bring it close to your ear...
and speak to it.
And now imagine that the bow is
your sex...
and it's caressing his skin.
Gently.
Your head.
Keep it like that.
That's it.
What is it?
I look elegant.
I'm no good at scalping.
People don't trust me because
I'm a dwarf.
But we've spent a fortune buying
boxes at the opera.
You said you'd pay me back with interest.
- I don't know.
- What don't you know?
Tell me what we're going to do with
all those tickets.
I can't.
Do it for me, for your Mari.
She needs the money to get rid of
her peenie.
All right.
What did you say?
My dwarf is a giant!
Let me rinse your hair.
Was the teacher angry I missed
the class?
The teacher?
You creep, I was angry.
Where were you all night?
- Around.
- No, not "around".
Where?
Come with me to the nurse.
Paquita?
Some friends called me and I can't
go now.
I'm giving some injections to the
transvestites.
They're a real pain.
They're wearing me out.
Maybe one day I'll finish up and I
can go with you.
We'll go to Benidorm and have a
great time on the beach.
We'll get drunk and stuff ourselves.
I miss you.
Lots of love.
What a racket!
Hello, love.
Where's she going?
- Pili, who's first?
- You are.
That's it!
Shut up, my lovelies.
Go suck!
Be careful, Pili.
The police'll come one day and close
your business.
All those evil transvestites.
Take off your panties!
Hello, Viuelo.
Give me two today, I'm looking
very macho.
Too many hormones are bad for you.
Pili, I love that photo of you with
Ava Gardner.
That was in the Chicote.
Was she really elegant?
No!
She was a randy bitch!
A randy bitch!
Here we go.
I hate needles.
Tomas, give me your hand.
I feel dizzy.
You're such a coward.
I can't find the spot.
Find it, Pili.
Find it!
~~ Put on the mask, the mask. ~~
~~ Because everyone is in disguise. ~~
~~ Everything is fantastic, fantastic. ~~
~~ Put on the mask, your mask. ~~
~~ And it'll be your talisman. ~~
~~ I'm asking you to love me and
to tell me nothing but the truth. ~~
~~ But later, in life... ~~
~~ don't see or hear or speak. ~~
~~ And put on, put on, put on, put on, ~~
~~ put on the mask so carefully. ~~
~~ Put on the mask, the mask,
and you can be happy. ~~
~~ Because everyone is in disguise
and all the year is carnival. ~~
~~ Don't go out on the street without
your mask, mask, mask... ~~
~~ mask, mask, mask, mask, mask,
mask... ~~
Is she dead?
No way, she's snoring.
One tries to be decent.
But you,
Lord, aren't doing very much to help.
Your father made a hell of mistake
giving me those extra 20 centimeters.
Some guys would really brag if
they had that kind of...
pecker.
The word "pecker" makes me laugh.
Miss, excuse me.
Sorry, I'm talking out loud.
No, it isn't that.
The church stinks of fish.
When people come in...
It's a very big hake.
So long.
You're early.
The kid isn't in bed yet.
It's the time we arranged; 12:30.
Come up.
Berta?
Yes?
I knew you
were mixed up in something bad.
Send Pauli down to Tomas so he
doesn't see anything.
Berta, please!
I can't talk now.
I'll tell you tomorrow.
Hey!
You have to walk up, the elevator
is broken!
What do you want, love?
You got a cock?
I asked first, "bakaleti".
I want you to suck me off and my pal
wants it up the ass.
Porky likes it Greek-style, does he?
For sure!
So, is there a cock?
You want the magic words?
20 centimeters!
Cock!
No condom!
What do you think this is, the jungle?
Then you go back to your
wives with some lousy disease.
That's inconsiderate.
Don't wank off, little guy.
You're only allowed to come once.
Quit jerking off!
You'll come so fast, it's a waste
of money.
- Right.
- Take your time.
I'm coming.
Think of something else.
No.
Think of your mother.
- Yes!
- Think of your mother.
My mother...
I'm coming!
Someone's out there.
The police!
Like hell, they're whores.
I want to be a saint.
~~ I want to be canonized, whipped
and flagellated. ~~
~~ I want to levitate in the mornings... ~~
~~ and have my body covered in sores. ~~
~~ I want to be distressed, have
hallucinations and ecstasies. ~~
~~ I want stigmata on my hands,
on my feet and in my side. ~~
~~ I want to be a saint. ~~
~~ I want to be blessed. ~~
~~ I want to be martyred and to live
cloistered. ~~
~~ I want to be sanctified, to travel to
Rome and see the Pope. ~~
~~ I want that when I die my body
stays incorrupt. ~~
~~ I want everyone who sees me
to drop dead from fright. ~~
~~ I want to be a saint. ~~
~~ I want to be blessed. ~~
What, Miguel?
Fuck, man, no.
There's only one room free.
Marieta,
darling, someone's looking for you.
Who?
I don't know.
"Coppercaillie" told me.
It's Capercaillie, you dumb shit!
Shut it!
I'm going home.
Some other day!
Marieta.
Oh, Raul.
Hello.
What's up?
Not a lot.
- You're a liar.
- Why?
You said you worked at Atocha
and it's a lie.
- You went there?
- Yesterday.
I left, they didn't treat me well.
Nobody there knew any Marieta.
- They know me by my real name.
- What's that?
- Ava.
- Ava?
Like Ava Gardner, the actress.
And Marieta?
My stage name.
After Atocha, I went to the door
where I dropped you off.
I asked on all the entry phones.
They know you by your stage name.
They mentioned a few places
here and there.
I drove around for a few nights
until I found you.
You did that for me?
Yes.
- Get that!
- What?
- How intrepid.
- That's how I am.
- Are you tired?
- A bit.
Get on, I want to show you a place.
- No, I'm going home.
- Get on.
All right.
Hey, sweetheart, this isn't your patch.
What a pity.
~~ True love, oh baby. True love,
oh baby. ~~
~~ True love, oh baby. True love. ~~
~~ True love, baby. ~~
~~ True love, oh baby.
True love, oh baby. True love. ~~
~~ True love, baby. ~~
~~ True love, oh baby.
True love, oh baby. True love. ~~
~~ I've had other guys.
I've looked into their eyes. ~~
~~ But I never knew love before
'til you walked through my door. ~~
~~ I've had other lips.
I've sailed a thousand ships. ~~
~~ But no matter where I go, you're the
one for me, baby. ~~
~~ This I know, 'cause it's true love. ~~
~~ You're the one I'm dreaming of. ~~
~~ Your heart fits me like a glove. ~~
~~ And I'm gonna be true blue, baby,
I love you. ~~
~~ I've heard all the lines.
I've cried oh so many times. ~~
~~ Those tear drops, they won't
fall again. ~~
~~ I'm so excited, you're my best friend. ~~
~~ So if you should ever doubt,
wonder what love is all about. ~~
~~ Just think back and remember,
dear. ~~
~~ Those words whispered in your ear. ~~
~~ I said; true love. ~~
~~ You're the one I'm dreaming of. ~~
~~ Your heart fits me like a glove. ~~
~~ I'm gonna be true blue, baby.
I love you. ~~
~~ And now I know it's true love. ~~
~~ You're the one I'm dreaming of. ~~
~~ Your heart fits just like a glove. ~~
~~ True blue, baby. I love you. ~~
~~ No more sadness, I kiss it good-bye. ~~
~~ The sun is bursting right out
of the sky. ~~
~~ I searched the whole world for
someone like you. ~~
~~ Don't you know, don't you know
that it's true love, oh baby. ~~
~~ True love, oh baby.
True love, oh baby. True love. ~~
~~ It's True love, oh baby.
True love, oh baby. ~~
~~ True love, oh baby. True love.
It's true. ~~
~~ So if you should ever doubt.
Wonder what love is all about. ~~
~~ Just think back and remember dear. ~~
~~ Those words whispered in your ear. ~~
~~ I said; No more sadness.
I kiss it good-bye. ~~
~~ The sun is bursting right out
of the sky. ~~
~~ I searched the whole world
for someone like you. ~~
~~ Don't you know, don't you
know that it's True love. ~~
~~ You're the one I'm dreaming of. ~~
~~ Your heart fits me like a glove. ~~
~~ I'm gonna be true blue, baby.
I love you. ~~
~~ True love. ~~
~~ You're the one I'm dreaming of. ~~
~~ Your heart fits me like a glove. ~~
~~ I'm gonna be true blue, baby.
I love you. ~~
~~ True love. ~~
~~ You're the one I'm dreaming of. ~~
~~ Your heart fits me like a glove. ~~
~~ I'm gonna be true blue, baby.
I love you. ~~
I dreamed it all.
Good morning.
You fell asleep, I brought you home.
I don't understand you.
Come here.
Wait a minute.
Get off.
Go on.
Do it now.
What a dick!
- You like my cock!
- A lot, a lot.
Stay there.
Stay down there.
Let me get close!
No, that's good, that's good.
Stay up there.
Give it to me harder!
I had to sleep on the couch.
Don't make noise when you chew.
You promised not to bring clients here.
The home has to be respected.
That's what we said.
But he isn't a customer.
He's a...
special friend.
How long have you known this
special friend?
We got to know each other bit by bit.
He's been a real gentleman.
He came to pick me up from work
a few times.
What does that mean?
You'd better behave yourself.
I guess your roommate could lend
me some shorts.
Raul, this is Tomas.
That's my towel.
Sorry.
There's a Chinese robe behind the door.
It's mine.
He's good looking.
Yeah.
And his dick is as big as yours.
- Hey, don't make noise.
- I eat really badly.
Raul is a stocker.
- On the Exchange?
- Hmm?
No, he's a stocker in the market.
- Fruit and vegetables.
- Right.
Right.
Tell him what you do, Tomas.
I'm in public relations.
Don't talk rubbish, you lying dwarf.
He wheels and deals,
he's a good businessman.
Scalping pays really well.
- Explain it, Tomas.
- No.
Why not?
I don't trust him, it's my idea.
But the money is mine, so tell him.
I don't believe this.
I'll get it, otherwise I'll hit you.
It's probably the teacher.
- Berta. Not now.
- Love...
Come up for a coffee.
I can't, I'm having breakfast.
And I'm not alone.
It's important, almost life or death.
Well, almost.
I need you to look after Paulito
for a week.
I knew you were mixed up in
something shady.
But you should go away.
If anything goes wrong, they'll come
here first.
What the fuck is this?
It's best if you don't know,
for your own good.
You can't become a criminal overnight.
You have to think this over,
for Paulito's sake.
Look, if it works out,
there'll be no more scraping by.
That isn't living.
You're so right.
In any case, I can't look after him.
I'm due to have an operation.
And I'm starting a relationship.
Maria, in a week's time, Paulito,
you and I are going to Brazil.
We'll set up a business and live!
Who do you think you are?
Mother Theresa of Calcutta?
Why are you covering up for that
fat slob?
She can't even look after her son.
She's a delinquent and a bad mother.
And what are you?
Just another delinquent.
And mind what you say, Paulito is
very sensitive.
Pauli, go into the bedroom.
Well, I'm off.
Yeah, this is like a boarding house.
Well, be seeing you.
Did you think that guy would fall
in love with you?
You're so naive.
Why are you so nasty?
Always out for yourself, and
when something new happens...
to me you have to interfere,
and fuck me up.
It's for your own good, idiot.
Did I tell you how stupid it is for
you to play the cello?
No matter what the teacher says,
you can't play it well
because your arms don't reach.
Size is size.
You have to accept it.
You accept your extra 20 centimeters.
The ones you're lacking, in brain
and height!
That's a low blow.
You're a dwarf.
What kind do you expect?
- You're crazy.
- Me, crazy?
About what?
You stupid, ugly dwarf!
You're a thug!
Who could love you?
Who could put up with you?
Nobody!
You're lazy, useless, ignorant!
You couldn't find your ass with
both hands.
You know what?
I'm going out with Paulito and when
I come back...
I don't want to see you or the guitar.
The guitar is where the ironing
board used to be.
The ironing board
shouldn't be under the bed!
And the money I lent you for
the tickets,
I want it back in my account.
And you can keep the profit for
yourself, forever!
Understand?
Tomas?
Oh, no.
There are no more cello classes.
Because Tomas doesn't live here
anymore.
Where's Gustavo?
He went shopping with the kid.
- Are you Gogo?
- Yes.
Are you all right?
Shall I make you some tea?
I'll make some tea and you'll feel
much better.
Don't work today.
Let me see.
Ugly.
Marieta!
What's up?
I haven't seen you around for ages.
I've been working.
Not on the street.
- Working.
- And... how's Tomas?
Why don't you tell him to call me?
- He's really busy, love.
- He's got a girl, right?
My Tomas doesn't want a girl.
Yeah.
What's he up to?
The usual stuff.
He's doing well.
Yeah.
He's very generous.
You look lovely.
You know they're going to set up
a candy stall?
Where?
Watch out!
You'll smell of black smoke all night.
You hear the latest?
You know Trico,
the one who cut her hair?
- Yeah.
- Well...
She's passed the exams to be a judge
and she's only...
doing the street for pleasure.
This idea of doing an
imitation of the Playboy bunny.
- No.
- What are you talking about?
Imitation?
These are original.
A guy from America gave them to me.
Bunny!
Have you seen Ice Box around?
What's up?
Is she sick?
She was killed a month ago.
A truck driver beat her up.
He stole all the money she made
that night.
And he dumped her outside the city.
Why didn't you tell me?
Did you know her well?
Just from around here.
It's a whore's life.
Fuck you, Bunny.
~~ I'm a pixie. I'm a paperdoll.
I'm a cartoon. ~~
~~ I'm a chipper, cheerful free for all
and I light up a room. ~~
~~ I'm the color-me-happy girl,
Miss Live And Let Live. ~~
~~ And when they're out for blood,
I always give. ~~
~~ The man behind the counter
looks like... ~~
~~ he's got a half a dozen places
he'd rather be. ~~
~~ And furthermore it looks like he's
prepared to take it all out on me. ~~
~~ Buddy, I don't really care what your
problem is, don't make it mine. ~~
~~ Come on kids, let's all hold hands
and pretend we're having a good time. ~~
~~ Boys, boys, boys,
I'm looking for a good time. ~~
I'm ready for your love. ~~
~~ Maybe you don't like your job.
Maybe you didn't get enough sleep. ~~
~~ Nobody likes their job.
Nobody got enough sleep. ~~
~~ You just had the worst day of
your life. ~~
~~ There's no escape and there's no
excuse... ~~
~~ so just suck up, suck up and
be nice. ~~
~~ Suck up and be nice. ~~
~~ Suck up, suck up and be nice. ~~
That's lovely, Raul.
You're like a ghost, you appear and
disappear at will.
- Climb on behind.
- Where are you taking me?
Hello.
Hey.
Mom.
The extractor, mother!
How are you?
I said you're staying for lunch.
She said there's meat and vegetables.
- Do you like that?
- Yes, very much.
Good afternoon.
The walls are like paper.
Go on.
Stick it in.
Come on.
All right, but then you do it to me.
Yeah, yeah.
- Give me a condom.
- There.
Come on.
Give it to me.
It's three.
That's it.
Give it to me.
...and now the series number for
300,000 euros.
The series number is 45.
- Fucking hell, Raul.
- What?
The nosy bitch!
Your neighbor...
Don't stop.
Lower the blind.
It doesn't matter.
I don't believe it!
That's it, I'm coming!
Come on Sunday, it's my birthday.
My mother's cooking tripe.
I'll be working.
Not on a Sunday.
After lunch, you must have a siesta.
No, no!
I've got so much to do.
You look like Hedy Lamarr.
I'm serious.
Loading tomatoes and peaches has
paid for the motorbike.
And I can pay the deposit on an
apartment I've seen.
It's here, on the fourth floor.
A really nice apartment for a couple.
A bargain.
Do you like my dick?
Yes.
Do you like it a lot?
Tell me.
Mm-hmm.
Don't you think it's strange?
What?
That we're a couple and we've both
got big dicks.
Look at fags.
Yeah, but I want to be a woman.
Since I was little,
I've always wanted a huge pussy.
But you are a woman.
How can I be a woman...
with a dick like this?
I like it.
Will you like me with a pussy?
I don't know.
I don't see you as very active.
Mom didn't come to pick me up.
Come here.
Do you like the bird?
No, it's ugly.
Who is it?
Maria, it's me, Berta.
- I'm back.
- Shit, I'd forgotten!
- Everything all right?
- Perfect, we're rich, Marieta.
Listen, bring Paulito to the bus
station tonight at midnight.
- I'll wait in the washroom.
- OK.
- Did you hear?
- Yes.
I heard the dwarf was arrested.
What happened?
Tomas?
He tried to
hold up the local Chinese store.
He did it the old way,
with his finger under his sweater...
Like it was a gun.
For God's sake!
He's at the far end.
Just five minutes.
- Thanks, pet.
- See you later.
What did they do?
You look terrible.
Why rob the Chinese store on your
own street?
They know you.
I wore a balaclava.
You're a dwarf, Tomas.
How many dwarves live in the area?
Did they hit you?
Tell me...
even if they told you to say nothing.
They beat you up.
It was the Chinese woman.
She had a bat behind the counter
and she hit me here,
on the side.
She clobbered me.
You can't trust the Chinese.
They eat cats,
and cats are treacherous.
Get me out of here.
Tomas, you men are so difficult.
Why were you stealing?
Have you ever gone short?
Tell me,
because I don't understand.
I couldn't sell the tickets.
For the opera.
I only sold one season ticket to
one of my teacher's friends.
I owed you that money.
Why do you take me so seriously?
Really!
For the operation on your pecker.
Look after him until I get back.
- For the good times.
- There were quite a few.
I'll give you a fling later, my treat.
You know what I like.
It's a deal!
We're going!
Paulito, get your stuff.
Gustavo, bring the car around.
What's up?
I'll explain later.
And you, love, lend me some clothes.
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- Go left, go left, darling.
- Don't make him nervous.
- Keep quiet in the back.
- Don't make me anxious.
No, no, no, relax a bit.
~~ High school girl, high school girl. ~~
~~ I've fallen in love with the teacher. ~~
~~ I can't help it. ~~
~~ High school girl, high school girl. ~~
TOILETS
Berta!
Are you here?
Mommy?
I'm in the last stall.
Come in!
Hey.
Hello, Mommy!
Darling!
I can hardly see you!
What?
Berta, I've got a plan.
No, it's OK.
It all worked out.
Oh?
No one's looking for us.
We're going to my parents for a week.
Then I'm taking Paulito to see Brazil.
- Yes!
- Yes, love.
I'm delighted.
Look, just take what's essential.
I'll sort out the tickets.
I can't.
Here.
A gift from Paulito and me.
No, really.
I can afford it.
Go on, take it.
~~ Imagining what isn't there. ~~
Don't cry, Maria, that's what men do.
~~ You pretend to be dead...
in your own song. ~~
~~ And you know you will fall
without a safety net. ~~
~~ You will go up in the trapeze of
champagne. ~~
~~ And under your feet... ~~
- How much was the bail?
- Nothing, not much.
Want breakfast?
~~ Tears twirl around in your head. ~~
~~ There is no more wire,
there is nothing... ~~
Go on up, Tomas.
I won't be long.
All right, but hurry up.
It's my brother's birthday.
Mom made tripe for you.
I've had a tough night, pet.
I don't think I'm going to your parents
for lunch.
All right.
And I don't think we're staying
together.
You and me.
You're leaving me?
How can you leave me?
If you think you've got more right,
you leave me.
Don't you see we've got a problem?
What is it?
I want a pussy, you idiot.
And you're crazy about my dick.
That's a little problem.
A twenty centimeter problem.
~~ I want to break free. ~~
~~ I want to break free from your lies. ~~
~~ You're so self satisfied,
I don't need you. ~~
~~ I've got to break free. ~~
~~ God knows,
God knows I want to break free. ~~
~~ I've fallen in love. ~~
~~ I've fallen in love for the first time. ~~
~~ And this time, I know it's for real. ~~
~~ I've fallen in love, yeah. ~~
~~ God knows,
God knows I've fallen in love. ~~
~~ It's strange but it's true. ~~
~~ Yeah! ~~
~~ I can't get over the way you love
me like you do. ~~
~~ But I have to be sure when I walk
out that door. ~~
~~ Oh how I want to be free, baby. ~~
~~ Oh how I want to be free. ~~
~~ Oh how I want to break free. ~~
~~ But life still goes on. ~~
~~ I can't get used to
living without living without... ~~
~~ living without you by my side. ~~
~~ I don't want to live alone, hey! ~~
~~ God knows,
got to make it on my own. ~~
~~ So baby can't you see
I've got to break free? ~~
~~ I've got to break free.
I want to break free, yeah. ~~
~~ I want, I want, I want,
I want to break free. ~~
~~ I want the moon that illuminates... ~~
~~ your silhouette as you walk. ~~
~~ with a ballerina's steps. ~~
~~ You follow her, never looking. ~~
~~ I want you to come full of love... ~~
~~ and embrace me when you arrive. ~~
~~ When you feel so lucky... ~~
~~ and you laugh as you kiss. ~~
~~ I want the calm of the evening... ~~
~~ when night begins to fall. ~~
~~ It's the twilight that burns... ~~
~~ as my love burns for you. ~~
~~ I want your hand to guide me... ~~
~~ if I'm in the dark. ~~
~~ And my heart will smile... ~~
~~ full of happiness. ~~
~~ I want your mist-colored eyes... ~~
~~ that I see at times in dreams. ~~
~~ They're like a cloak of sweetness... ~~
~~ that comes to waken me. ~~