(Thunder)
# Dramatic music
(Children laugh)
# Rock music
Kevin, cut that racket!
I could hear you from Gaffney Street!
Do you have to play so loud?!
Mum! It's rock'n'roll!
Your father's favourite music
to strangle someone by
and it's likely to be both of us.
Yeah, yeah.
And I think you'll find that last chord
is an A minor 6, not a D7.
The riff doesn't take off unless
you get the chord structure right.
Yeah, I knew that.
- Moron.
- Reject.
Loser!
Margaret.
You're here early for your lesson.
Keep going.
(Plays fumbling notes)
Just touch the keys, love.
No need to pound them to death.
Just try and keep breathing.
(Continues playing badly)
MAN: Grace!
Where's my bloody baton?
I'm already late for rehearsal.
(Sighs)
Can't find a bloody thing
in this house!
Oh, hey, Dad.
Off to rehearsals then?
If there's anything left
of my hearing, Kevin.
I was just wondering
if you'd like me to drive you in?
Why would I want you to do that?
I just need the car for the arvo,
if that would be OK?
I can get back to pick you up.
The reason I have a car, Kevin,
is because I have a job.
It's an equation
that'll work for you too one day.
If you ever wake up to yourself.
Just tell him you'll take that job
down at the depot.
- Why can't he just...
- How badly do you want that audition?
Dad! Hey, Dad! Wait!
(Continues to play badly)
# Classical music
(Changes music)
# Heavy rock
# Classical music
(Gasps)
# Bold orchestral music
# Forceful marching band music
Cut! Cut!
- Stop!
(All stop playing)
For God's sakes, George,
you've got a bloody euphonium, use it!
And, Dawn, the tenor horns
are the secret heart of the band.
If you're not solid,
nothing above it makes any sense.
Look, it's the melody in the chorus
that's important
and, trombones,
you've got the counter melody
but, Derek, we still have to hear
the bloody tune.
You're all playing
like a sack of drowning cats.
(Dog whines)
Look...
You've gotta play music
like your life depends on it.
With feeling.
Focus.
Concentration and heart.
There's no bloody point otherwise,
is there? Eh?
It's about precision
coupled with passion.
You've got to touch the human soul.
Tommy, I've heard you play
like an angel.
Now, I need to hear that again.
Now, this is the first time in 20 years
we get to play in front
of the home crowd.
And this is going to be our year!
Our victory!
And nothing is bloody well
gonna stop us this time!
- Right?
ALL: Yeah!
Gino!
- Late again.
- Oops.
Sorry, mate.
(Band plays Social Currency
by Children Collide)
# So-so-social currency
Hold on!
Alright!
Whoa! Whoa!
You got a spot. I just need a few details for
the entrance form.
- Damien, is it?
- Yeah.
Uh, actually, it's my band.
I'm Kevin Flack.
- Ed Flack's kid?
- Yep. That's me.
Best electrician in town.
Did all my rewiring
when I took over this place.
Decent bloke.
Fill out all your names
and a contact phone number.
Talent quest's a month on Saturday.
I may be a little bit late for the contest,
boys, on the night.
Might be out celebrating.
Well, wouldn't miss the marching band
regionals for quids.
Not after last time.
I can still see Tommy Dempsey
blowin' mud out of his trumpet.
And his nose! (Laughs)
And George McKilty, the fat bastard,
floundering in the water
like a beached whale
with a euphonium up his arse
and your dad... (Laughs)
Yeah, alright. Alright.
That was a long time ago.
Seems like yesterday, son.
Let's eat.
I can't. I gotta go pick up my dad.
Our simple mission,
to create a lifestyle experience for our
primary target demographic -
OG1s and 2s -
as well as provide subsidiary benefits for
other secondary stakeholders
according to clearly defined short-term and
long-term strategic goals.
So what you're saying, Tracey,
is that this development
will benefit everyone in Montague.
Particularly small business.
Absolutely. What we are planning
is a total makeover of Montague,
all centring around the old cannery,
which was once McPherson's Wharf.
This will provide, in the short term,
an estimated annual income to shareholders
and local businesses,
a guaranteed $3 million in the first year,
escalating to 10 times that amount within the
first decade.
And Montague goes
from an obsolete fishing village
to a state-of-the-art tourist destination.
TRACEY: Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you stage one.
Paradise Point at Montague.
And the "pièce de résistance",
a tribute to the fishermen
of this great town.
The Montague Lobster!
Oh, there hasn't been a lobster off Montague
since before I was born!
Yes, Councillor Agnew,
that may be true.
However, I don't think we can let
a minor detail like that
get in the way of the tourist dollar.
There's just one small problem,
isn't there?
That thing seems to be standing
exactly where the Montague Band's
clubhouse is.
Hey, what's the difference between cutting
up an onion
and cutting up a trombone?
ALL: What is it?
(Laughs)
Nobody cries
when you cut up a trombone!
(All laugh)
MAM: Here's Grizzly Guts.
What's the story
with the council plans, Edwin?
They've already closed the cannery.
Our clubhouse will be the next to go.
No-one is throwing us out of our home.
Mark my words.
Legal problem?
Yes, it seems that
the clubhouse is built on land
bequeathed to the people of Montague by its
original owner.
Angus McPherson in 1927,
"for the exclusive use of the Montague
Municipal Marching Band."
Why the hell would he do that?
He was the first musical director
of this band
and it was in his will that they -
we - be allowed...
"Peaceful enjoyment
of the said property..."
"..for as long as the Montague Municipal
Marching Band..."
"..should on its own accord..."
"..and free will..."
"..continue to provide entertainment
for the good people..."
"..of Montague."
Meaning?
We can't take their land
unless they agree to disband.
(All cheer)
Well, that deserves another round.
If George hasn't forgotten to bring
his shout of the beer...again.
I bought one last week.
Oh, you did not!
You are as tight as a fish's arse!
Time to call it a day, Tommy.
Home time, everyone.
And don't forget...
ALL: Practise, practise, practise.
- That's right.
# Rock music
(Tyres screech)
The Gibson Les Paul custom!
The Black Beauty.
Triple-burst humbuckers.
Ebony fingerboard.
Pearl block inlay. Oh!
Two-tone three-way switches!
Ally stopbar.
- It's beautiful.
- It's like sex with frets!
- I've never tried it.
- What...
Sounds interesting.
- I meant, uh...
- Do you want me to plug it in?
Are you serious?
Yes!
(Feedback)
(Strums harsh chord)
(Plays rock music)
There you go.
Hey, Edwin, you want a ride?
No, no. Kevin will be here soon.
- Oh, look, there's a flying pig!
(All laugh)
MAN: Don't hold your breath.
(Seagull squawks)
# Rock music
(Horn blares)
(Tyres screech)
(Thud!)
- Ahh!
Oh, my God!
I have to go!
I was meant to meet my dad
an hour ago.
Mayor Riddick is your dad?
Yeah. I'm Mandy, by the way.
Kevin Flack. And I've gotta
pick my dad up at... Holy crap!
He's gonna kill me!
(Woman squeals)
EDWIN: Get the hell out of here!
GRACE: Edwin.
(Edwin continues yelling)
Are you the son?
Here. You'll need this.
Useless. There you are.
Where have you been?!
GRACE: Kevin! Thank God!
You won't believe it, Dad.
Flat tyre and no spare. So I...
Look what you've done!
My bloody conducting arm!
- Dad, calm down.
- Don't you tell me to calm down!
You've made a mess of everything.
Ever since you started playing
that senseless noise in the garage
day in, day out,
instead of studying to play
the kind of music you have a gift for.
- Edwin.
- You wasted all that talent!
- Edwin, there's no point...
- You're right, there's no bloody point.
(Laughs)
I would have given my right arm
for a scholarship at
the Conservatorium of bloody Music.
You had it offered to you on a platter.
But, oh no, not for you.
Not for our Kevin, no.
Edwin...
What's the point of having a gift
if you don't use it?
I'm sorry, Dad.
It's a bit late for that now.
You've destroyed everything
I've ever believed in,
fought for...
..dreamed of...
..my whole life.
Well, here's an opportunity
for Kevin to pay it all back.
Oh, no.
No. No!
NO!
# Band plays marching band music
(Music out of rhythm)
Stop. Stop!
Sorry, guys, that's terrible.
Sorry, Kevin, you're terrible.
Well, I'm only here
because Dad's in hospital.
If you think you're gonna
stand in for Edwin Flack,
you'll have to do better than that.
(Plays sliding descending note)
(Men chuckle)
Come on, guys.
What about some real music?
Something now.
Like Kings of Leon.
Arctic Monkeys?
The Red Hot Chili Peppers?
- Ooh! I like chillies.
(Men laugh)
What the hell's an Arctic Monkey?
(Sighs)
Blood, Sweat & Tears?
One, two, three, four.
(Band plays Spinning Wheel
by Blood, Sweat & Tears)
Wow!
Where did that come from?
Trouble is, your father would have
a real problem with something like that.
- Why?
- We did it once.
- It was a...
- It was a disaster.
(Voice echoes) It was 1990.
Yeah, yeah. I know all about 1990.
- Disaster!
- Your father had the same idea as you.
He wanted to play real music,
"something now".
It was musically complicated,
a challenge to play technically.
Right up Edwin's alley.
And hard to march to.
- We had to rehearse for weeks.
- Months!
It was the Regional Championships
on home ground.
We were a heartbeat away from victory.
The year before,
we'd won the gold cup.
DEREK: We were
the defending champions.
GEORGE: Edwin decided
to play something new.
DAWN: Revolutionay.
DEREK: Your dad
had just taken over the band.
TOMMY: Then it happened,
the one thing we hadn't planned on.
(Thunder)
(Dramatic music)
GINO: He took it hard -
blamed the music, blamed himself.
We went straight back to the old stuff.
TOMMY: I don't think
he ever got over it.
Every year, we go through it,
with your dad hell-bent
on winning that gold cup.
Brings out the worst in all of us.
And in Edwin, most of all.
So why do you all keep showing up?
Edwin is the best there is.
But for 20 years?!
Ever tried saying no to your dad?
(Door opens)
(Footsteps approach)
I've got something
I think you might want to see.
The legal department has assessed
the contingency risk
and will only sign off on the development if
the band ceases to exist.
So we're stuffed, aren't we?
No, not yet, we're not.
Well, there's no way that fanatic
Edwin Flack and his merry men
are gonna disband.
But they might agree to a merger.
The band might. Flack won't.
Don't be so sure about that. (Laughs)
# Up-tempo rock music
(Man sings)
(Continues singing)
# You're burning me out
You're burning me out
You're burning me ou-ou-ou-ou-out
# Look what you've done
# I'm not...
What the hell are you doing?!
Call me when you get your act together.
I can't sing to that crap.
Yeah, and it's impossible
to follow a lead who can't keep time.
Keep time?!
Is that a technical term you picked up from
your other secret band rehearsal?
- What other band?!
- It's a brass band.
(Laughs)
With a percussion section
full of false teeth and pacemakers.
- What?
- It's something I can't get out of.
While you boys sort out your priorities,
there's a hot babe just salivating
for what old Damo has to offer.
(Laughs)
Don't forget to lock up.
A brass band?!
Mate! That's so uncool.
(Novelty car horn honks)
(Tyres screech)
(Laughs) They don't call him Tripod
for nothing.
KEVIN: I can't believe
I got sucked into this.
You should see them.
Grumpy old farts waiting to die.
And the shit they play,
I'm going to look like an idiot.
I can't believe
your dad asked you to do it.
He didn't. He hates the idea.
- So why did you...
- Mate, don't ask.
(Laughs) I get it.
Your mum made you do it.
- Shut up, Simon.
(Laughs)
Oi, it's Tripod's car.
So where is dick brain?
(Laughs) Taking an aerobics class.
# Faint dance music
- Come on.
(Laughs)
Here. Here, come on.
Wow!
Where did she come from?
That's Mandy Riddick.
Oh, I'm randy for Mandy!
Yeah, I was just playing her
some of my music the other day.
(Laughs) Yeah, right, Kev. Dream on.
She's way out of your league.
Oh, and I hate to break your heart, Kev, but
Tripod's beaten you to her.
Oh!
A merger? Impossible.
I'm sorry, there isn't one of them
that comes even close
to meeting the high musical standards
required by the Diamond Vale
Marching Band.
- Mr Fyffe.
- I'm afraid it's out of the question.
We are about to embark on
a major building project for Montague
in the next 12 months.
And I see no reason why we couldn't include
in our portfolio
some major renovations to the Diamond Vale
grandstand and clubrooms.
I see.
At no cost to Diamond Vale, of course.
Well, there may be one...or two.
We do need a euphonium.
We would be in your debt.
How quickly can we move on this then?
Almost immediately.
Let's wait until after the competition.
Think about it,
with Edwin Flack's useless kid
leading them to guaranteed failure,
there won't be a voter in Montague who'll
support them.
What if they win?
We can't get rid of them then.
Win?! I have no intention
of letting them win.
Mr Flack's men don't stand a chance.
With or without him.
And with the appropriate spin, we sell the
idea to the ratepayers of Montague
that this was a necessary sacrifice,
given Edwin Flack's
unfortunate accident.
And you get your big lobster.
- Mmm.
(Laughs)
(Door opens, bell rings)
Hey! I was wondering all day
if you'd show up.
I just came back to see the guitar.
Oh. Really?
It's still there.
Um, no. Mandy!
That's not what I meant!
Idiot!
Merger, my arse!
It's for the good of
the entire community.
(Edwin scoffs)
Diamond Vale and Montague
united under one banner.
Which banner?
We know the band is due to play
at the Regional Championships
under the temporary leadership
of young Kevin, I hear.
I hope he makes a good fist of it for you.
You leave my son out of this.
And of course,
we're all behind him on that.
So to show the good faith of the council,
we have decided to support the band
through till then.
A sort of farewell performance.
(Laughs) It's the land, isn't it?
It's all about the land and a monument to
some overrated shellfish!
You thieving mongrel!
It's got nothing to do with me.
It's a council decision.
Montague has always had
a marching band
as long as anyone can remember.
But we've never farmed a bloody lobster in
this town and we never will,
so your scheme is absolute crap!
The truth is, Flack, you are in my way, you
and your bloody clubhouse.
And I can't have that.
So it's time to move over
and let progress take its course.
Well, you can't close us down.
Legally, you can't,
unless the band agree.
That's why I'll be contacting them.
Individually.
The Montague Municipal Marching Band will
never agree to disband.
That, I promise you.
In these tough economic times, Ed,
a few council concessions
can make a big difference
to those unfortunate families
without incomes.
None of this would have happened
if you had just, for once in your life,
turned up on time.
Hey, Mr Riddick. Mr Mayor, sir.
I want you to reconsider
about closing down the band.
- It's a done deal.
- Oh, please.
I know they're a bunch of old geezers but
they've got nothing else in their lives.
And everyone really likes them.
And didn't they
kind of, like, vote for you?
I don't like you, Kevin.
And I've never liked your father.
Except that he's a good electrician
and he would die for his band,
while you, well, you're not
really much good at anything
and there's not much
you genuinely care about.
You're a waste of space, Flack.
You can't close us down if we win.
OK, I tell you what I'll do.
If "we win", and I admire this new spark of
determination in you, Kevin,
if the band wins, they stay.
But if they lose, they're history.
And...you never see
my daughter again.
- Has she been talking about me?
- Not a word.
And let's keep it that way.
She's been seeing a lot of you lately.
I have big plans for my daughter
and I don't want her distracted
by the likes of you.
Oh, no, I think you mean the Tripod.
- Oh, cut the crap, kid.
- No, you see...
Now...have we got a deal?
Or haven't we?
Well, Dawn, what's it to be?
8 for continuing. 11 for disbanding.
Merging.
Right.
Well, I can't say I was expecting that.
But I guess we can't let 80 years
of history end in certain humiliation.
So, Tommy, I want you
to do one last duty for me.
Withdraw the band
from the Regionals this year
and inform the Mayor he can build
his bloody theme park on our land
because the Montague Municipal Marching
Band
has officially disbanded as of today.
I'm sorry, Edwin.
That's all, lads.
How long do you think it'll be
before he bulldozes all of our houses?
The band's just the beginning.
(Dog whines)
You could have convinced them.
Why didn't you give them
one of your speeches?
They'll do anything for you
when you crack the whip.
They'll follow you anywhere.
Christ! They've done everything
you told them for 20 years!
I think that's just the point.
Well, it doesn't take a genius
to figure out who voted for disbanding.
You don't know what I voted.
- Traitor!
- We had no choice!
Oh, well, perhaps it's just a lucky break. I
won't have to listen to you anymore.
Because if you call
what you do drumming,
I've got a 2-year-old grandson who can keep
a beat better than you can.
Probably plays a better trumpet
than you, out of his arse!
ALL: Ooh!
Well, at least he's got the wind for it.
I mean, you need a break
every 20 seconds
just to recharge your pacemaker!
I'm not the one holding up the bar.
- Hey, guys!
- What are you insinuating?!
Guys!
If you think that Diamond Vale would want a
geriatric fat bastard dick like you
backing up their brass band...
Right! That's it!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
What is wrong with you guys?
You're a great team.
You can't just give up now.
- Where's your fighting spirit?
- Right on!
(All yell)
(Elevator bell dings)
- Ahh!
(Comical marching band music plays)
Ahh!
So how did the meeting go?
Could have gone better.
I guess.
# Reflective music
(Electric guitar plays in distance)
# Melodic instrumental music
I suppose you've come back
to see the guitar.
- Uh...
- Well, it's not here.
Look, I'm really sorry about
what happened the other day, OK?
I thought what my father did
to the marching band was really mean.
I can't wait to see his face
when you win.
Yeah.
That's gonna be a little tricky
since they've all kind of given up
and gone home.
But you haven't given up.
Have you?
So, what's the plan?
- The plan?
- You're far too smart to not have a plan.
I am?! I am.
(Novelty car horn honks)
I guess that means you've gotta go.
Quick. Quick.
(Banging on door)
DAMIEN: Mandy!
Yo! (Bangs on door)
(Footsteps recede)
(Bangs on window)
Oi!
Mandy!
# We'll always be together
# Whenever we're apart
# And until you know you're mine
# Oh, baby
# 'Cause every time I wonder
# When you'll be back in my life
Oh, my God.
That was Edwin's favourite.
Put it on.
What, now?
Your father's not home.
Let's walk on the wild side.
# THE ANGELS: Take A Long Line
# He was selling postcards
from a paper stand
# A whisky bottle in his withered hand
# He put a finger on a photo
from an old magazine
# And saw himself in
the shadow of his dream
# They found him with his head
inside a tin-pot crown
# Told him his feet stank
and took him downtown
# Called him agitator, spy and thief
# Shut him up in solitary third degree
# Take a long line
# Take a long line, take a long line... #
Oh, yuck!
GRACE: I wish you'd met your father back
then.
That was the last time
those boys were really excited,
passionate.
Playing something
they really believed in.
And then it all changed.
I never knew how big it was.
To all of them.
Sometimes, my love,
one disappointment can shape
every day for the rest of your life.
Is that why you stayed?
I told myself that I had no choice.
You know, I had two kids to bring up
and was stuck in a small town
in the middle of nowhere.
Better the devil you know.
But that's not it.
It's a question of whether
you give up on someone you love.
Or not.
Mandy, I've had a brainwave.
I need something that wasn't written before
the Second World War.
So this is your plan?
If we're going to win this competition,
I need to get these old guys to play.
And the only way to do that
is to get them excited about something
no-one thinks they can play.
- Not even them.
- What about this?
A genuine 5-star classic.
"An anthem for a whole generation."
Maybe.
(Comical melancholic music)
(Dog whimpers)
I would like to ram that lobster
right up the Mayor's ceremonial ring.
I've got a proposition for you.
Piss off, Kevin! We are finished!
Debunked! Kaput!
Yeah, but...
If you don't mind, I'd like to finish this beer
and follow it up with a few more.
But I'm talking about competing...
..with a few changes.
Changes?
Yes, we go out on a high,
playing something fantastic.
Kev, we'd just make fools of ourselves, like
last time,
only worse with this material.
That was in the past.
No, can't be done.
We'd never get George back.
(Plays Flight Of The Bumblebee)
I don't know how you're
gonna get trumpets to play this
and you won't have a euphonium,
it's gonna be very difficult.
Well, you're the man.
You still doing the talent night here
with your rock band?
Yep.
You know it's on the same night?
Yes, I know.
We're on late,
long after the Regionals are over.
So, what do you reckon?
Regionals? Our way.
What does your father say
about the changes?
- Mmm...
- I see.
Look, I just wanna give it one last shot.
Yeah, well, none of us
can orchestrate this.
Actually, I've got someone in mind.
# Up-beat brass band music
Now build it up even more.
Then bring in the trombones!
This is brilliant.
And now for the trumpets
cutting through it all!
# Triumphant crescendo
(Music stops)
Hey, Mum, you're really good at this.
(Sighs)
I've always been good at this.
It's just that nobody noticed.
- Come on, you guys.
MAN: Hope everybody turns up.
Kevin, hold that, will you?
- Quick, quick.
- Shh! Come on.
(Whispers) Go. Inside, come on.
(Man laughs)
- Shh!
Blimey!
This looks hard.
(Plays trumpet)
(Another instrument starts playing)
(More instruments join in)
I want everyone in this room to swear
nobody breathes a word of this
to anyone.
- Especially...
- Edwin.
..my dad.
Anyone know why we're here?
Where is he?
Anyone know where he is?
Ooph! Who is she?
OK. Alright, everyone. This is Mandy.
(Man wolf whistles)
I've asked her to help us out
with the marching routine.
And maybe give you guys
a whole new look.
(All cheer and applaud)
# AMII STEWART: Knock On Wood
# I don't want to lose you
# This good thing that I got
# 'Cause if I do
# I will surely
# Surely lose a lot
# 'Cause your love is better
# Than any love I know
# It's like thunder and lightning
# The way you love me is frightening
# You better knock, knock
# On wood
# Baby
# Whoo hoo hoo hoo
# Whoa
# I'm not superstitious about ya
# But I can't take no chance
# You got me spinnin', baby
# You know that I'm in a trance
# 'Cause your love is better
# Than any love I know
# It's like thunder, lightning
# The way you love me is frightenin'
# You better knock, knock... #
(All cheer)
Three cheers for Kevin!
- Hip-hip...
ALL: Hooray!
(All cheer)
- Over he goes!
- No! No!
(All cheer and laugh)
TOMMY: You can swim, can't you?
Oh, my God.
I'm gonna get you back so bad!
We love you, baby.
EDWIN: Haven't seen Kevin for a while.
What's he up to?
Found something useful to do?
Oh, he's been busy rehearsing.
Rehearsing?
His rock band.
Saturday night's the talent quest.
Waste of bloody talent.
Edwin, look at me.
I've got something
very important to tell you.
And I think
you're going to be very proud.
EDWIN: (Yells) No!
WOMAN: Mr Flack!
# Classical music
- See you, Dad.
- She was beautiful, you know?
Just like you.
She was the best part of me.
I miss her too.
You grow more like her every day.
Except...she would never have
thrown her life away
for the likes of that Flack kid.
I know what you're doing.
I'll be back later.
You're stuffing up our future
and the future of this town.
What?!
The only thing standing between us
and a $50 million building project
is that bloody brass band.
Their clubhouse sits right in the middle of
what we're planning.
They're just a bunch of harmless
old guys who love to play music.
They were quite happy
to go home and die
until that idiot boy decided
to pull them back from the brink.
With your help. And why?
Kevin's doing this for his dad.
Not according to the bet
he's got with me.
What?!
A little wager he suggested
involving you.
Me?
He demanded quite a big pay-out
if they win.
And he promised never
to see you again if they lose.
I don't believe you.
It's amazing what some people will do.
And who they'll use
to get what they want.
I just don't wanna see you get hurt.
(Band plays up-beat tune)
Kevin, you need to come to the hospital right
away. It's your father.
- What happened?
- He knows.
Bugger.
You went behind my back
and hijacked my band.
It's not your band. You let them
walk out of here and throw it all away.
I won't have 20 years of blood, sweat and
tears ending up in a total debacle!
But they want to play!
How dare you drag them out there
to certain public humiliation...
No. No-one's dragging them anywhere.
OK? They're doing it
because they love to play the music.
- You leave the music out of this.
- There's nothing you can do about it.
If you change one bloody note of it,
I'll bloody well kill you!
Mandy! Dad found out we're competing and
he went ballistic!
He has no idea we changed the music or the
routine.
Mandy.
What happens if you lose, Kevin?
- What? There's no way we're...
- What happens if you lose?
Oh, shit.
You made a deal with my father.
You used me as a bet.
No, Mandy. I can explain.
Please, open the door, Mandy.
Mandy, please, open the door!
Mandy, please!
Please, open up the door.
I'm sorry!
Mandy, I'm sorry!
Please. Mandy, I didn't mean
to hurt you. I'm sorry.
(Band plays slow and sad melody)
Problem with the girlfriend, Kev?
I was thinking about dropping around
to see her later.
And I'll be giving her your love,
one way or another.
Hey, hey! Come on, guys. Cool it!
Why don't you shut up?
(Grunts)
(Drummer laughs)
We're cool, aren't we, Kevin?
Yeah, I thought so.
See you tomorrow.
Come on, don't let him get to you, mate.
He's not worth it.
Oh, no! No, no, not the guitar!
Not the guitar.
(Plays pretty melody)
(Plays countermelody)
Big day tomorrow.
# THIN LIZZY: Jailbreak
# Tonight there's gonna be a jailbreak
# Somewhere in this town
# See, me and the boys we don't like it
# So we're getting up and going down
# Hiding low, looking right to left
# If you see us coming I think it's best
# To move away do you hear what I say
# From under my breath
# Tonight there's gonna be
a jailbreak... #
This is it, men, the big day.
Get aboard, make it fast,
we haven't got much time.
- Deadly.
- You look pretty good yourself, Dawn.
- Anyone seen Kevin?
MAN: Not here.
MAN ON RADIO: As we count down
to the start of
the Regional Championships,
Mayor Riddick, how do you rate the
chances of the Montague brass band
winning back the gold cup tonight
under the leadership
of newcomer Kevin Flack?
MAYOR RIDDICK: Well, Bob,
I think eveyone in Montague
remembers the unfortunate events
of 20 years ago.
We're all wishing young Kevin
the very best of luck.
Here he is!
- Where's your suit?
- I'm not going.
- What?!
You're right, Tommy, competitions
bring out the worst in all of us.
I do not believe what I am hearing.
Will you snap out of it?!
You guys are gonna be fine without me.
Anyway, I'm supposed to
do this talent thing tonight so...
Kevin, for the first time in years,
this band feels like a group.
We all feel like a kid again.
And it's all because of you.
I haven't had this much fun since I took
Maria to see the Duran Duran concert
in 1985!
Come on, Kevin.
Come on, we can wing past your place, pick
up your suit.
Your first rock gig can wait.
We can't.
This may well be our last.
No, I can't. I'm sorry.
OK. That's it.
Come on, everybody off the bus.
Oh, what are you doing?
Well, if you're not going,
we're not going.
One out, all out.
If you stay, we stay.
(Laughs)
You know, you're all a bunch
of complete bastards.
Yeah.
Old bastards.
Now, let's bloody well get on with it!
(All laugh)
MAN: That's my boy!
To the bus!
ALL: To the bus!
Get back in that bed immediately,
Mr Flack.
You need another fortnight's convalescence
before you can go anywhere.
Now, we'll let you know the scores.
The whole ward has money on it.
Really?
That's nice.
Yes, we got fantastic odds.
2:1 on you losing.
What?! Get out of my way!
(All cheer and laugh)
MAN ON RADIO:
Ladies and gentlemen,
the grandstand's filling up
here at Montague Field,
where, in a matter of minutes,
the Marching Band Regional
Championships will begin.
Honestly, Edwin, what you're doing
is terribly dangerous.
The doctors said you shouldn't be out.
And by the time we get there,
it will be all over.
It's pathetic!
You're being completely ridiculous.
Can't you drive any faster?
RADIO: We have clear skies
and a record crowd here
for an exciting night of competition
between the best bands in the county
at the Montague Sports Field.
We're gonna win!
ALL: For all our sins
Whatever we suck
Whatever we blow
We're gonna win this great big show!
(All cheer)
Stop the bus!
- Hey, hey, hey. What's going on?
- Store's closing.
- Well...
- They're bulldozing the block.
- And I'm moving to Sydney.
- What?!
- To study law.
- But why?
- It's Dad's idea, not mine.
And I need a change.
Look, I know you
never wanna see me again
but there's something
I really need to tell you.
- What?
- The truth.
Mandy, I never
should have made that bet.
But you and I had only just met
and I didn't think
I would ever have a chance with you.
I only did it to help my dad.
(Sighs)
- Hey, Kevin, hurry up!
What are you doing?!
Look...
Tell her you love her and get on with it!
I think Tommy's right.
I think you better go.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the Regional
Marching Band Championships.
It's a beautiful night here in Montague
to mark the first time the competition's been
held on this field in 20 years.
Hi.
ANNOUNCER: Tonight's winner takes
home the ultimate reward,
the coveted championship cup.
And now,
to start off tonight's proceedings,
last year's winner and hot favourite to make it
an incredible 19 years in a row,
let's give it up for
the Diamond Vale Marching Band!
(Cheering and applause)
Diamond Vale, right and centre!
March!
(Band plays Semper Fidelis)
Still time to stop this lunacy.
No, you are not stopping anything.
You're going into the grandstand
to take your seat and watch!
Get out of my way.
Your son does have a gift
and tonight, he's going to use it.
Over my dead body!
You will sit there and shut up
and behave yourself.
And by the way,
they won't be playing your music
or doing your
old-fashioned marching steps.
What?
It was Kevin's idea.
And I supported him
because I am proud of our son
and I want to be here to see him win.
With or without you.
Right. Give us your wrist.
Yep. Thank you.
How long does it take to lose
a brass band competition anyway?
Oh, shut up!
He'll make it in time.
We should have got rid of him
months ago.
- He's so uncool!
- Yeah.
He's slowing us down.
You just can't let it go, can you?
Mandy chose him and not you.
(Laughs)
I dumped the slag weeks ago.
She's so bloody frigid.
Oh, so does that mean
she didn't wanna sleep with you?
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
(Grunts)
- Oh-ho!
Anyone else got anything to say?
Not me.
(Laughs)
Oh, shit!
Oh, man!
# Band plays
March Of The Toy Soldiers
(Cheering and applause)
ANNOUNCER:
Another great performance this year
from the Mount Stanthorpe
Marching Band.
Now we come to the last performance of the
night,
the defending runners-up.
They have placed a credible second
for 19 of the last 20 years.
Please, welcome the Montague Municipal
Marching Band!
(Dog barks)
- I can't bear to look.
- Don't be such a baby.
(Marching drum beat)
What the hell?
Wow!
Don't they look great?!
(Drumming stops)
ANNOUNCER: There is a hush
over the grandstand
as Field Marshall Hamilton
makes his inspection.
Once complete, the final routine
of the evening will commence.
Let's rock!
(Drum roll)
(Band plays Smells Like Teen Spirit
by Nirvana)
(Crowd cheers)
He did it for you.
(Barks)
(Wild cheering and applause)
ANNOUNCER: The Montague Municipal
Marching Band
has dazzled the crowd!
Ladies and gentlemen, we've just witnessed
a sensational debut
for band leader Kevin Flack,
son of Edwin Flack.
He's proved tonight
that he's a chip off the old block.
It's been an astonishing performance from
the home team.
The crowd, as you can hear,
are going ballistic!
No-one has ever heard
a marching band
deliver such a challenging choice
of repertoire
as Nirvana's Smells Like Teen Spirit.
This is a first! I wonder
how the judges will take to it.
But I can tell you,
ladies and gentlemen at home
listening to this broadcast,
if it were up to the crowd here,
this would be a win!
- Are you sure?
- Mmm.
We have the results.
Please welcome Mr Whit Bernard, chairman
of tonight's judging panel.
The results have come down
to two bands -
Diamond Vale...
..and Montague Municipal.
Yes! Yes!
Both teams played well.
In drill, Montague scored slightly higher than
Diamond Vale.
(Band members cheer)
However, Montague went over
their allocated time.
And as a result of this breach,
they have been awarded a penalty.
(Crowd groans)
I have therefore decided that a play-off will
decide the winner.
- A play-off?!
- Play-off?!
A play-off?!
Gentlemen, you have 15 minutes
to prepare.
- 15 minutes?!
15 minutes.
We're ready to go now.
(Glasses clink)
We've got nothing prepared.
Nothing but the old stuff.
- We can't do that.
- Stuffed.
Yep, we'll look like bloody idiots.
I'm sorry, guys, I should never
have gotten you into this.
What the hell was I thinking?
How could I be so stupid?
Dad is going to kill me!
OK, this has been the biggest mistake...
That was pretty impressive
playing, lads.
And very fine leadership, Kevin.
I was surprised.
And very proud...
..of the lot of you.
What are we going to do?
Well, there's only one thing you can do.
Play the number from 1990.
- You've gotta be kidding!
- What?!
Only this time, you're gonna get it right.
- We can't do that!
- We haven't rehearsed it!
Rehearsed?! (Laughs)
19-bloody-90!
How could you possibly have forgotten?
It's a memory that's seared
into all of our brains forever.
We can't play that without a euphonium!
You were robbed.
You were at least 15 seconds
within time.
Someone got to that timekeeper.
And I won't play with cheats.
And besides, I think you need my help.
Since I bet I can guess what Edwin wants us
to play next.
Even though I am...
a geriatric fat bastard dick.
(All laugh)
No, you're just a dick.
- Especially in that uniform.
- You can't go out looking like that.
Sorted.
(Mobile phone rings)
Oh, no! It's Simon.
He's in the car park
to pick me up for the talent quest.
Kevin, I don't think we can ask you
to stay with us this time.
You've done your duty by us and more.
There's nothing you can do
to help us out of this one.
I hope you knock 'em dead, son.
(Band plays The Washington Post
in background)
Oh, yeah.
Hurry, mate.
Look, I'm sorry, Simon, I'm not going.
We're not playing. Damien threw
himself into your guitar head first.
- I'm sorry, mate.
- Two minutes.
What's going on?
It's a play-off, us against Diamond Vale. I
gotta go!
(Thunder)
ANNOUNCER: Ladies and gentlemen,
Diamond Vale have delivered
an outstanding play-off number.
And now the question is
can the Montague Municipal Marching Band
reply to that challenge?
If they can only pull this off.
You know you did a really good job.
Helping Kevin with that arrangement.
He told you?
No.
I could tell.
(Crowd cheers)
(Band plays MacArthur Park
by Jimmy Webb)
(Thunder)
(Both laugh)
# Dramatic music
# Music rises to crescendo
Hey, Kev. Look.
Mandy, what are you doing here?
I thought you might need this...
for the talent quest.
You can borrow it for the night.
It's getting real ugly out there, mate.
You don't wanna look.
Mandy, will you wait here till I get back?
- Then you have a plan.
- I have a plan.
Simon, come on!
And you're a dancer, not a lawyer.
(Thunder)
I know.
# Slow, dramatic music
(Kevin plays electric guitar)
(Band joins Kevin)
(Laughs)
- Yeah!
Yeah! Rock on!
(Silence)
(All cheer and applaud)
(Dog barks)
(Mouths)
Hmm!
CROWD CHANTS: Montague! Montague!
Montague! Montague!
(Crowd cheers and applauds)
Kevin!
Kevin, you did it! You did it!
(Men argue)
You could get disqualified for that.
(Laughs)