Liberty is the happy man's due
He enjoys love and skies of blue
But then there are some
Who no worse crimes have done
It's the sad story we tell
From a prison cell
What's your problem?
Shut up!
Another day in hard labor spent
Like all the other yesterdays went
With just one horizon in sight
Iron bars morning till night
Ah, pity those who dwell
In a prison cell
In life liberty is all that counts
But man invented the prison cell
Codes and laws, do's and don'ts
Work, offices and houses as well
Don't you agree...
What life can be?
My old friend, life is great
When you're free to be yourself
So come on, let's emancipate
Fresh air is good for the health
Everywhere, if you take a chance,
Everywhere, life is a melody
Everywhere, it's wine and romance
So here's to us two and liberty!
Run for it, Louis!
Forget about me!
Thanks, Emile!
Look there we can see
It's he, it's really he.
Let us follow rapidly
This way, it's he
The finish line's in sight
Pedal with all your might
We're almost home, all right
The finish line's now in sight
Here he comes, yes it's he
He's the victor, the celebrity!
Do they fit?
Like a glove.
Excuse me, sir.
How much?
I'll let you have it...
for 8 francs.
Much too much.
7 francs 50.
7 francs.
Only because it's you.
1 0 francs.
7, 8, 9 and 1 0, thank you.
Good day, sir.
Say, mister...
Got any hankies?
New ones.
I'll go check.
Help! Help!
- I can't breathe!
- What happened?
Which way did he go?
Thataway.
Stop, thief! Stop, thief!
- What happened?
- I've been robbed.
Which way'd they go?
Thataway.
You dropped your wallet.
Thank you, it's really kind of you!
Looking for a phonograph?
Our latest model's inside.
It doesn't cost anything to look.
See for yourself.
PALACE OF RECORDS
Not at work?
Don't you know that...
Work is mandatory.
Because work means liberty.
Work is mandatory
Let me out!
There are moments when we ponder
The love we have yet to know
The lover who is yet to show
Though silently we hope him yonder
Will I meet this lover some day?
At what time, in what way?
Come, my lover to be
I've loved you since an early date
I've loved you,
though your name is a mystery
It's you I call, it's you I await
Love thrives on hope
And a touch of folly
All it takes is one look
forjoy to start
Come and erase my melancholy
Come and enchant my heart
Come, let me love you
and you will love me
Let me read deep in your eyes
Those lines of timeless poetry...
My uncle's coming.
When can I see you?
Can't you watch out?
Put your potatoes elsewhere.
Who asked you?
You don't know who I am.
That will do. That will do!
Excuse me, sir...
Out of my sight!
I forbid you to address my niece.
...walk in formation.
We will give you a job of worth
You who seek an occupation
State your name and date of birth
Leave fingerprint identification
About-face in formation
We will give you a job of worth
Where are you going?
I want to leave.
So why'd you come?
Don't know what you want, do you?
Get in line with the others.
Don't move!
- You're still here?
- Let go.
Get going, since you want to leave!
Halt!
Forward, march!
One, two!
It's not my fault, pal.
- Let me...
- I'll get chewed out.
Hold on, you'll see.
Jeanne!
Leave me alone.
Come now, child,
you have to be nice to me.
Look, miss, they've gone crazy!
What's wrong?
You're crying.
What's going on?
I don't know.
You don't know.
Did you see anything?
I don't get it.
They all jumped on me.
What d'you have to say?
I couldn't place my part...
So I ran after the belt...
What's your version?
He got in my way. I couldn't work.
What about you?
The three of 'em rushed me.
The three of them?
So you're one of them?
It was those two.
They mixed me up.
- So it's you?
- Me?
Not at all. He started it.
He started it all.
Where'd he go?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
Go on!
- Hello, old man.
- Hello, my good man.
Can I help you?
Don't you recognize me?
Not at all.
This must be some joke.
Who is this?
Don't remember Emile?
I get it.
You don't want them finding out.
- Enough!
Move along!
There's no time to lose.
Just a minute.
This fellow must have something
to tell me.
This is quite amusing.
Come with me.
I'm in a hurry. I've got to go.
There's one more thing
we need to know.
Just a minute, gentlemen.
Isn't this something!
Unheard-of!
What are you doing standing here?
Run along.
Run along, you two.
And you? Will you run along!
Get a move on!
How's this open?
What for?
- To return a hankie.
- Want to start a scandal?
- That's not it!
- Listen, Emile!
Stay here.
If you don't stop by the count of 3,
I'll blow your brains out.
1... 2... Will you stop?
3.
Come on.
You hurt yourself.
What did you expect?
Keep quiet!
Take it.
Not enough? You want more.
What are you waiting for?
Let this be the last of you.
So here's to us two and liberty!
A good likeness.
What a fool!
Not so loud.
What do you think?
Our friend looks splendid.
Simply splendid!
Doesn't he?
How does Louis look to you?
Magnificent!
Do you mean it?
This is an outrage.
While her husband works!
They're not married.
- Not married?
- She's a floozy.
And he's a parvenu.
They're watching us.
I'm so sorry, Louis isn't home yet.
But, dear Madam, we can wait.
It's late.
You must forgive him.
He works so hard.
Everywhere, life is a melody
Everywhere, it's wine and romance
So here's to us two and liberty!
Not eating?
- I am.
- How's that?
You sit there staring into space.
Like a wound is my desire
My sorrow knows no bounds
I am so sad I shall expire
You clumsy oaf!
Hold this!
You, too?
I didn't get any cake.
I didn't have any cake.
Nothing at all.
I'm so sorry, believe me.
Good help is hard to find.
It won't stain.
It's only sugar and milk.
Don't go.
That's enough.
It stopped raining.
Go on.
I'm so sorry for what happened.
I'm fed up, fed up!
Listen, darling...
It's all set then. See you tomorrow.
Say, my suit looks good on you.
As if it were made for you. Almost.
But it doesn't beat that!
Hey, you!
Who d'you think you are?
Just you wait!
If I wanted to catch you...
Your behavior tonight...
Spare me!
What d'you want, money?
Boor!
Just take it and get off my back!
Did you see that?
So you don't like it?
Wait and see.
My turn!
Watch this.
You win!
Everywhere, if you take a chance,
Everywhere, life is a melody
Everywhere, it's wine and romance
So here's to us two and liberty!
What are you doing here?
Joseph!
How are things?
Just fine.
Don't you recognize a friend?
Coming out of there?
A friend's house.
A friend?
Shall I awaken the master?
No need to.
See you soon, I hope...
Sure, but I gotta run.
Where's the fire?
Is that the mistress... leaving?
Yes, sir.
You don't say!
What are you standing there for?
Get inside!
Is this yours?
We inaugurate
our new plant tomorrow.
In the first month,
it will turn out daily
2000 models like this one.
In the second month, 3000...
What is it?
What do you want?
All right.
Gentlemen...
We'll continue this later.
He's overstepped all bounds!
Just who is that man?
This can't go on!
What did I tell you?
Will you get off my back?
Know who they are?
Now get out and stay away
from the plant.
What do you want? Money?
What then?
It's like this...
I want to stay at the plant.
You can't.
It's the one place I can't have you.
Why do you want to stay?
I'm in love.
Who with?
A girl who works at the plant.
Step up, my friend.
Sir...
Where's he going?
- I'm right here, sir.
- Not you, him! Step up.
You, too.
Is this your niece?
Yes, sir.
This gentleman wishes to marry her.
This gentleman is my friend.
Do you understand?
Perfectly, sir.
The director wants you.
Director?
The big director.
Don't worry about money.
Here's her dowry.
Thank you, sir.
Excuse me.
May I?
What is it you want?
Listen. I just wanted to tell you...
Nothing.
Would you like to get married?
Of course she would, sir.
A friend of mine
would like to marry you.
Oh, no, sir.
Only the other day, you said so.
I never said...
Please excuse her, sir.
She's feeling a bit intimidated.
- It'll work out.
- I count on you.
You needn't worry.
My friend's charming.
I know him.
I'm sure you'll change
your mind, miss.
I doubt it, sir.
Come along.
It'll work out.
I can't understand you.
The chance of a lifetime!
Come along, my dear.
Have no fear,
she'll agree to everything.
- Relax. It'll all work out.
- Thanks.
I've seen the girl.
I'll tell you later.
Isn't that so?
Of course, sir.
My niece can't wait to meet you.
I'm so glad.
If you'd care to come tonight...
Do you mind, sir?
Come tonight...
That was him!
Yes, your fiance.
Having dinner here?
No, I have my date.
And I've got guests.
See you tomorrow.
Tomorrow's the great day.
I inaugurate my new plant.
And I celebrate my engagement,
I hope.
So everything's fine?
Firmin! Joseph!
Where is everyone?
Dear friends!
What's going on here?
You thought of everything!
Going already?
Let's do some serious talking.
That's what we came for.
Will that do?
It'll do.
Don't bother!
If we blab, you lose everything.
Your status. Your fortune.
That's what you're gonna
share with us.
So that's it! Is that all?
What brings you gentlemen here?
How's that?
We received a report
on a housebreaking.
Housebreaking! But it's a practical
joke played by my friends.
You came for nothing.
Please forgive them.
But I was tied hand and foot!
I was doing my duty.
As you always do.
- What are you doing here?
- Papers!
Is this a joke?
We're done for.
He took us for a ride.
We can't get out.
Trapped like rats!
We can't stay here!
Isn't there a combination?
Things look bad.
- What is it?
- They'll blow the whistle on me.
So what?
We have to get ready to run.
- What was that?
- The police are after me.
You idiot! Shut the door, quick!
May I help you?
It's nothing, sir,
but a man's slipped into the plant.
A man?
We're looking for him.
I haven't seen a soul.
But be my guest,
have a good look.
You took the case?
The case I put here.
I just saw a guy with it!
What are you doing here?
We're friends of the director.
Sure!
We came with him tonight.
That's right.
Isn't that right?
- He's a pal.
- Aren't you?
Is that all you have to say?
If you don't speak up,
they'll arrest us.
But you'll be joining us soon.
Be seeing you, then.
Goodbye.
Here, Inspector, look at this.
We'll look at it later.
Take 'em away!
Let's move it!
In our new plant,
men will have no other task
other than supervising the machines.
The machines will do all the work.
They will manufacture
our phonographs.
"Organization and progress,"
that is our motto.
This explains the success
of our earlier factories.
It will be the same
under our new enterprise,
which will now start up
before your very eyes.
Won't you cut the garland?
Won't you cut this garland?
Cut it?
Step over here.
All hail Progress, child of Science
Which extends its hand to the future
The golden torch of hope...
It's very simple:
We introduce the materials there.
We stand back and then...
There you have it!
It guides its sister,
Human Intelligence,
Towards the sunlight...
My congratulations! It's marvelous!
Ladies and gentlemen...
On this solemn occasion,
when the Machine has proven
that if it can replace
the hand of man,
it cannot replace his brain,
allow me first to pay homage
to the brilliant creator
behind the destiny
of this magnificent factory.
This man who,
despite humble beginnings,
forged a place for himself,
and earned the respect
of his contemporaries,
whose name is forever
linked with phonograph history,
this philanthropist,
this great citizen...
This scoundrel! This riffraff!
It's him, all right.
- You recognize him?
- You bet I do.
I arrested him.
If you want to arrest him again,
you'd better hurry.
He's been tipped off.
He'll make a run for it.
All right. Get down there.
This historic moment,
when the fiery gaze of the future
Iooks back on the dazzling flame
of the present.
I haven't said everything.
Gentlemen,
the opening of this factory
is my crowning achievement.
I have nothing more to do
among you.
I am leaving you.
I hereby make a gift of my factories
to all whose
who have worked with me.
The machines will now work
for them.
Destiny beckons me to other paths.
As a great poet once wrote:
"Let us raise our souls
and our hearts
"As the mother raises her child."
These words come to mind
on this day when I wish...
We can lift our heads high
and declare
that the future destiny of mankind
seems to bear great promise.
We will soon taste the fruit...
When all things around us operate
Friends, let us enjoy our idleness
Beneath sunny skies
what a sweet fate
To laze about and sing like this
Let's indulge
in this infinite elation
It takes one kiss for it to start
My whole being finds exhiliration
In the gentle beating of your heart
You must never think of marrying
When you were born
to live on the road
While awaiting the wisdom
age may bring
Think of love as a mere episode
That's our fate
Old mate
My old friend, the Earth is round
There are women wherever you go
When we finally run out of ground
That's the time to take it slow
Everywhere, if you take a chance
Everywhere, life is a melody
Everywhere, it's wine and romance
So here's to us two and liberty!