That was a rocking act,
ladies and gentlemen.
We have two more acts to go
in the Dance Dil Se finals...
but before that...
let's give it up for such
a brilliant performance everybody!
Hello everybody!
l'm your host, Manish Paul.
And a very warm welcome to all of you.
This is no ordinary show.
This show decides
the best dancers in the country!
This is the grand finale of
most awaited Close up Dance Dil Se...
powered by Spinz!
After the break you will see...
last year's winning team on the stage.
And l can see that they are
the favourites this year too!
Yes... the defending champions.
Put your hands together for...
Jehangir Dance Company!
JDC! JDC!
Congratulations Jehangir!
The audience is already yours!
And soon the trophy will be mine too.
Why don't you go in and...
give a boost to your dancers.
l'd rather stay here
and boost the show's ratings.
Vishnu will give them a boost.
Yes, that's him!
The choreographer of the winning team.
And l'm going to meet him.
Okay, he is on his way.
Let's go!
Nervous?
Yeah!
Of course.
lt's normal.
Sir...
l've seen Lawrence's team rehearse.
They are really good.
Rhea, focus on your act.
Don't worry!
Sir, you are on in one minute.
Wow... one minute.
Are you ready?
1... 2...
Superb.
What a performance!
Mind blowing, that was.
After watching the performance
by Lawrence's team...
l'm sure it will be difficult
for ourjudges to decide.
And the winners of Close Up
Dance Dil Se powered by Spinz are...
And the winner is...
any guesses?
Come on, any guesses?
Lawrence! Lawrence!
The winner is...
Jehangir Dance Company!
JDC! JDC!
Lovely!
Thank you.
Hello sir.
Nice lipstick.
Vishnu...
We did it!
We need to talk, Jehangir!
l am sorry!
What are you sorry for?
We won.
Nothing else matters.
lt does matter, Jehangir!
We won but we are not the best.
Lawrence's team was better than us.
l don't think we'll win next time.
Vishnu... you know what...
you are...
very innocent!
Do you think...
a dance competition...
is only about good choreography?
You mean we cheated?
Well, if it's only dance...
we don't deserve to win.
Dance is not the only criteria here.
Dance is not the only criteria
in Dance Dil Se?
lt's a show, Vishnu!
The only criteria here is
what the audience likes...
and the audience loves us.
You know why?
Because l make them...
Love us!
You teach 50 students in your class.
But there is an entirely
different world outside JDC...
where l make scores of people
dance to my tune.
l know, you like winning.
You must be happy
with your work but...
l am not!
Why don't you take a break.
What?
l mean, take a break.
Since we started JDC
you've been working tirelessly.
l think you should take some rest.
ln fact, l'm going to make life
easier for you.
That's more like it!
We have won!
Okay!
But this party is not
for tonight's victory!
That's in the past.
This party is for our future.
The point is...
do you want to see the future?
Here it is.
Please join me in welcoming
a very dear friend...
all the way from New York...
Chris Donovan!
lt gives me immense pleasure...
and am utterly proud
to announce that...
Chris is going to be...
the new...
official...
choreographer of JDC.
Welcome Chris.
As far as administrative work and
other stuff is concerned...
you can rely on your dear Vishnu Sir.
Please make do in the
accounts department today...
l'll give you your
own swanky cabin soon.
Okay?
What do you mean?
What will l do in a cabin?
Administration!
l'm making you the admin manager!
There is only one
thing that l can do.
And that is dance!
Now that Chris is here,
both of us can...
No!
Chris doesn't work with anyone.
That was his condition.
Vishnu, please understand!
What?
Make him understand.
This is my studio.
Let's go...
to my cabin and talk.
Why not here?
Let's talk here.
Fine!
Vishnu, we need to change with time.
l am sorry to say...
your style is, you know... ancient.
lt's my duty to train my students...
according to the
modern international dance styles.
That's what l'm doing.
Right now JDC needs Chris, not you!
So you took this decision on your own?
This school is mine as much as yours.
What?
Can't you read?
What's written there?
Jehangir Dance Company.
JDC.
J for Jehangir.
That's me!
Standing right here.
You're here because of me, Vishnu!
l made the company what it is.
My name is on every brick
of this school.
Even yourjacket says JDC.
lt's time you realise this...
you don't work with me.
You work for me!
Worked!
l used to work here,
not anymore.
Really?
What good are you then?
Whatever you have belongs to me...
your house, car, everything.
You can't stay on
the streets of Mumbai!
What will you do?
You said it...
there's an entirely
different world outside JDC.
Do you know how
sugarcane juice is extracted?
Jehangir is like the...
machine that extracts sugarcane juice.
He squeezes the life out of people.
Before you realise it...
he's squeezed you dry
and dropped you.
That's what he's done to you.
Listen, Vishnu!
l still remember the old days.
l had once told you...
for me dance is life,
it's what water is to fish.
But l gave it up.
l mean, l was forced to.
Just because l put on
a little weight, l was fired.
Just a few pounds.
But l'm glad,
l never liked him anyway.
Jehangir's ajerk!
Now l am the master
of my own destiny.
Full respect!
Everyone knows me.
l'm not rich, but it doesn't matter.
l am very happy and content.
What are your plans now?.
l'm going back to Chennai.
Are you crazy?
lt's all over now.
There is nothing here for me.
l'm leaving in two days.
l'm staying at a hotel close by.
Hotel?
You've forgotten the meaning
of friendship because of Jehangir.
- No...
- Then?
How can you stay in a hotel?
l may not be rich,
but l have a big heart.
You're staying here, that's it!
l don't want to hear another word.
Let me get you something to eat.
Come on...
Run!
Stop it!
Get hold of him!
He's up there!
He's jumping around like a monkey!
Stop it!
Get back here...
After him!
Come on...
Grab him...
What's up, good looking?
Not now, dude!
Why don't you talk to me?
l'll call later!
Stop it!
What are you doing?
Who the hell are they?
Stop it!
Be careful...
Hey Gopi...
Who are you?
Are the cops still there?
l'm beat!
l saw her...
she looked fabulous!
The cops are still down there.
That was close!
Who is he?
Doesn't look like Gopi to me!
But where is Gopi?
How should l know?.
Gopi is here.
When l tell you to practice,
you disappear.
But you come to me
when the cops are after you.
Oh come on... you're our darling!
Enough!
Don't you act smart!
Don't lose your cool.
Calm down!
Shut up!
Whatever you are doing is wrong!
l've lost weight running after you.
All of you should be locked
somewhere to practice.
We've practiced hard.
Tell him, Sushi.
From the bottom of our heart.
Time to use your hands
and feet too!
We swear...
if we don't set the stage on fire...
then you can do whatever you want.
What a line.
l'll impress Mamta with it.
''lf l don't set you on fire...
Laugh all you want...
but if you miss a single step,
you will regret it.
We won't.
You can tell Vardha Bhai...
that we will set the stage on fire.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let's welcome Vardha Bhai...
and here he is... Applause!
Sit, Gopi.
Vardha bhai, this is Vishnu.
And this is Vardha bhai.
Put it out!
Get some water!
Vishnu!
Hey Vishnu!
The boys said that they'd
set the stage on fire...
and they kept their word.
15 days of hard work
gone up in flames.
15 days? That's it?
15 years of my life
have gone up in smoke.
That's no reason to be sad.
ls that why you got the long face?
Have a drink and let it go.
How can l let go?
15 years ago l came
to Mumbai with a dream.
Not a grand dream.
l didn't dream of flying.
All l wanted was...
to make a mark for myself.
But my destiny was paved with rocks.
But l tried.
l spent 15 years carving
a name on those rocks.
But now l've realised it
wasn't my name.
Vishnu!
Don't say that.
l know where you stand.
You have achieved a lot.
And l will tell the world
about your achievements.
You down there...
people of the world.
lt's me, Gopi...
up here.
With me, is the world's richest man.
My pal...
Vishnu!
He might not be famous.
He might not be a millionaire.
But he is rich because...
he has a friend...
me!
That good-for-nothing-scoundrel
Jehangir...
may have his name carved on rocks.
But your name will be
carved in everyone's heart.
l guarantee you.
Until your dream
becomes a reality...
you cannot leave.
Hold on...
Chennai...
sorry, Chennai!
Gopi, no, no...
please, Gopi... no...
Gopi... yes!
Vishnu, tomorrow we bid
farewell to Lord Ganpati.
Ganpati is going.
And when Ganpati leaves,
he's benevolent.
So, open your heart
and wipe away those tears.
Vishnu...
Lord Ganpati will shower
his blessings on you.
Ganpati Bappa... morya!
You jerk!
Move it!
The cops are here! Run!
Vishnu...
What's the matter?
Say something.
God made this world.
He created the plants and animals...
What's with the Biology lecture?
Listen...
God made this world.
He created the plants...
l get it.
Plants and animals.
So?
And then he gave them dance.
Leaves dance in the breeze.
Rivers flow to a rhythm.
Fish swimming, birds flying...
dance is everywhere.
Right?
Whoa!
That's way over my head.
Dance is the sign of life, Gopi.
Anything that moves
to the beat of nature...
signifies life.
Anything that is alive can dance...
the dead don't dance!
Everyone around here...
is dead.
They are like machines.
But their eyes light up with life...
when they dance.
l have seen it.
At the Ganpati farewell.
That wasn't dance.
They were fighting.
l agree...
but this fight,
this spirit of competition...
can transform their life.
Get it?
Not a word.
Tearing up my ticket was
a blessing in disguise.
l guess Ganpati wanted me
to leave JDC in order to come here.
The kids here need me more...
than at JDC.
These kids don't need anyone.
What will you do with them?
l'll tell you what l'll do...
l'll teach them dance.
Mark my words...
the kids in this neighbourhood
have a real shot at making it big.
l'm not sure about that but...
l think you're losing it...
like that character, Bhuvan,
from the movie Lagaan.
You know something...
l think you should go back home.
Sorry, Chennai,
Vishnu is coming.
Gopi!
l'm not going anywhere.
l will teach dance...
to every single one of them.
Whose boat is this?
lt's our boat.
Gopi?
Take a look.
Are you trying to burn us?
No, Vardha bhai...
lt's fireproof!
You can try all you want
but it won't catch fire.
lt's imported stuff.
Really?
lmagine... your banners,
really big...
and your name
highlighted with diamonds...
Vardha bhai!
No one dares to
stand up to your might...
but this banner is rock solid!
Hold on...
lt won't tear?
lt won't.
You swear?
Sure.
l'm impressed.
So what do you want?
Go on, tell me.
Boss...
Vishnu...
We'll clear this mess and...
get an electric connection.
We'll put a water tank there.
The rest of it is fine.
What do you say?
lt couldn't be better.
You know, l'd give
my life for you...
but don't ask for it!
The kids should be here soon.
What's up, Gopi?
You're Vishnu Sir, right?
Sir, actually l...
l mean, we recognised
you at Ganpati's farewell.
We've heard a lot about you.
You teach at JDC, right?
Not anymore.
Why not?
Did they fire you?
Bhavna!
He wasn't fired, he quit.
lt's all about self-respect!
Actually they are right...
l quit and l was fired.
Rocky, he is not with JDC anymore.
How can he help us get in?
Let's go!
What's the hurry?
Now that we're here,
let's see what he can do.
Wait a minute.
Let me handle this.
Sir, you've been a part
of JDC for so long...
l'm sure you can do something.
You know, help us get in...
Do you think you can
afford the fees at JDC?
That's the problem, sir!
Even if we pooled in all our money...
it wouldn't be enough
to cover one person's fee.
What if l teach you the same dance...
for free?
Free?
What are you doing, Vishnu?
l'm talking to them.
Hey Gopi!
l like what you've done here.
What are they doing here?
Do you own this place?
Don't get personal.
Why shouldn't l?
Enough of this nonsense.
Vishnu wants to talk to you,
no fighting in here.
Listen to what he has to say,
it's for your own good.
Vishnu, all yours...
l've seen you dance.
You dance well...
but you can do better.
You need guidance and
all l've ever done is teach dance.
l want to teach you dance...
like the performances that
you watch on Dance Dil Se.
You mean to say...
these idiots can dance like that?
Forget it, sir...
your efforts will be wasted.
Biscuit!
lf you ever call us idiots again...
l'll make sure you
crumble like a biscuit!
lt's only because
of sir that l'm silent...
otherwise...
Otherwise... what will you do?
Listen...
don't act smart in here.
l'll give you a piece of my mind.
Let's take this outside.
Watch what you say...
if l lose my temper,
you will be sorry.
And what's with the 'sir... sir...'
l can't believe how
you suck up to someone!
Let's go!
Relax Rocky,
we'll deal with them later.
Sir, l'm sorry.
That's how D and his gang are.
But we are not like them.
My team and l are with you.
When do we start?
Right now!
What?
Hello Qureshi Bhai!
Hello Gopi!
What can l get you?
One and half kilo of mutton.
Step out of your
dream and start working.
One and half kilo of mutton.
Last time the quality
of the meat was bad
You heard that?
You better give
him good stuff this time.
He's going to ruin my shop!
lt's okay.
He will learn.
When will he learn?
After l die?
He is useless.
He is always day dreaming.
He never concentrates on work.
You are right.
lf you don't like
what you are doing...
then you can't dojustice to it.
You should always
do what you like.
Right?
What's going on?
No, we are just watching...
Yeah, just watching.
What?
Look at those steps.
You want to go in?
No... l'm just saying.
Hanging around like this won't help.
lf you really want to learn, go in.
No, we are just watching.
We are not interested.
lt becomes 'new'.
Whenever you create something new...
it attracts the audience.
Sir, we are here...
to help you.
Why do you think l need help?
lt's been four days that...
you've been trying
to teach them that step.
This is how it's done.
Give him room.
On the spot, goldspot!
Out!
But sir...
Get out!
Sorry sir.
D...
there's only one teacher here...
me!
Don't ever come in
if you want to teach.
But if you do want to learn...
take a seat right now.
Boys, ready.
Positions.
What the--
Step back!
Go to your position.
Look straight.
Not bad!
Not bad, not bad...
Rhea...
you are a good dancer.
You are the lead.
You have to be better
then everybody else!
Attitude...
is the correct use of the
body to portray feelings and emotions.
Attitude gives birth to expression.
Look ahead!
What's going on?
Where the hell is he?
l won't spare him.
What's the matter, sir?
What's the matter?
lt's a narcotics raid!
Sir, he always manages
to give us the slip.
He zips around on his motorcycle and
he hangs out with Babu.
What are you talking about?
These kids are practicing dance.
This is Vishnu Sir.
And l'm his assistant.
All of them are dancers.
All of them?
Yeah, every single one of them.
ln that case... start the music.
Mayur... Rocky...
step ahead and dance.
Hold on...
not you...
you step forward...
the one behind you.
Yes, you.
Start dancing.
Wow!
This guy can really dance!
Sir...
l'm sorry...
l interrupted the rehearsal.
lt will never happen again.
Of course it will.
No, it won't.
l said it will.
Chandu...
you can deceive everyone,
even the police...
but not me.
You are always running
away from cops.
But you chose not to
hide amongst the crowd outside.
lnstead you came here
where you stood out.
Why?
lt's because you don't want to hide.
You want to display
your hidden talent!
Right?
Sir, you are something else!
l mean, how did you know?.
l'm a teacher.
lt's my job to know.
Shall we start?
Yes, sir!
l'll teach you on one condition.
Dance in itself is an addiction.
From now on you can only get
high on dance, nothing else!
Sure, sir!
l won't do it anymore.
l promise.
Wow... superb!
You were great!
lt's alright! lt's me.
Spot!
That's wonderful...
Show me some passion...
Your core needs to be strong here.
What are you doing?
lt's nothing.
Stop it!
Listen to me...
it's all right.
You need to surrender.
Stop!
Stop it!
Here wait.
What?!
Vishnu sir!
Look who's here!
Hey Poli,
where have you been?
l went there to...
Listen to me.
Sir!
Vishnu sir, hello!
How are you?
l'm fine.
l have a surprise!
A dancer!
She wants tojoin your team.
Please meet her.
What's your name?
Poli...
Poli, don't bore him!
Come to the point!
He said there is a good dancer
who wants tojoin us.
- Dancer?
- Yes.
- Who?
- Her.
- Where?
- There.
- Then call her.
- Okay.
Shaina... baby come here.
Baby?
Come baby.
She's hot!
Shaina?
Hello sir.
Not here.
Vishnu sir!
Okay.
Please give me a chance.
l won't disappoint you.
l can dance.
She can dance really well, sir.
She is fabulous.
Where have you seen her dance?
At Red Rose bar...
A bar dancer?
How does it matter?
Separate 'bar' from bar dancer,
and you have 'dancer'.
Anyone can fall on bad times.
And, not every girl who dances in
a bar is bad.
Even if she were,
she'd still be a good dancer.
And Shaina is a really good dancer...
and a wonderful person.
The rest is up to you.
All l want to say is that she is a...
very good dancer!
3...
4...
5...
6...
7...
8...
What a performance!
Hi.
Thanks Chandu!
l'll see you tomorrow.
Bye.
l'm so happy to see you Vishnu sir.
Sir, it's good to see
you smiling again.
Looks like you're doing well.
l'm a simple teacher.
l get 10 students and l'm set!
Do you have room
for one more student?
Look at him...
Forget it D...
Rhea, this is Gopi!
Gopi sir, l've heard
a lot about you.
Sir...
the guys are getting impatient.
Why don't you introduce her to them?
This is Rhea.
She was lead dancer of
JDC's winning team.
But now...
she is with us.
Today is Rhea's first day with us,
so let's freak out.
Very sweet girl... hmm?
Wow.
Okay everyone!
Great job!
l would like to give you all a gift.
Party!
New speakers.
We have to get new speakers!
Poli, come on.
Here is the money...
for new speakers.
Okay sir.
We start early tomorrow,
so no partying all night.
Go home and rest.
You're leaving?
Yeah the class is over.
Sure the class is over
but we could do something.
Like what?
You know... hang out... chill.
So, you do this every day?
No, but today is special.
Yeah!
lt's because you came into my life...
l mean... our team...
Rhea...
why don't we go somewhere?
Wow!
This is damn cool.
Look at them flirt with her.
She's cool with it.
Can't you see she's flirting too?
Guys...
We're going to 'Down Under'.
All of us!
lt's my treat!
Hey...
Shall we.
Come on.
Wow.
Hi.
What is this?
Come.
This is out of this world!
l had heard about this place
but being here is bloody cool!
This place is like an open lottery.
Superb!
We'll show them!
We don't have money to bet.
Of course we do.
Poli is here and so is the money
Sir gave for speakers.
Sir won't like this at all.
We'll double this, if we win.
And go for really huge speakers.
Today is our first day here.
We'll challenge them another day.
Please shut him up!
We have the money right now,
let's make the most of it.
Let's give them a taste of our skills.
Listen D.
Poli, why did give the money?
l was helpless.
Take this.
Hurry up!
What are you doing?
lt's okay!
Relax... trust me!
Don't worry!
The next battle is between
these new kids and Fictitious Crew!
Come D.
Did you speak?
Let me speak.
Listen...
Come on D.
Come on D!
That's Rocky.
Oh my god!
Wait.
Let them go.
Come on, guys.
Stop... okay.
Everybody... positions!
Let's do this step...
l said this step...
What are you doing?
Come on...
Don't you get it?
Why don't you get it?
Vishnu sir.
Superb performance.
Wasn't that great everyone?
Superb.
Wonderful!
Three hours ago l thought
l had a dance team...
that could compete in Dance Dil Se.
But...
no!
You can't dance.
Because you don't know
what the D in dance signifies.
D is for discipline.
lt's over!
Sorry sir...
Shut up.
Please don't go, Vishnu!
Vishnu...
let it go!
You don't look good
when you're angry.
l mean,
you don't look bad.
But if kids don't make
mistakes, who will?
No, Gopi.
lt was my mistake.
You were right.
They are good for nothing.
Please don't go, Vishnu!
Vishnu...
Sir please!
Please don't go!
Sorry sir!
Sir, it was my fault.
l shouldn't have taken
them to the club.
They should've used their brains.
lf you tell them to
walk on fire, will they?
No, not if l tell them.
But they will if you do.
Please sir...
we've worked really hard...
we painted the place,
bought speakers...
please don't go!
Sir, please sir!
We will never repeat this again.
We swear!
Please sir!
Yeah!
Hey try and be helpful.
Awesome!
lt's what every
dancer wants to hear...
But if all the dancers
on stage are good...
how will you stand out?
That's what l want to see today!
Try to impress me.
Do something which
makes the world go...
awesome!
Let me show how it's done.
Sir, we will...
We will go first.
Back off!
Not that dance.
Which one?
That's the one.
Let's start.
Oh wow.
Okay... boys and girls.
And of course, Chris!
The day you've been
waiting for is finally here.
The Mumbai auditions
of DDS start tomorrow.
And are we ready!
Yeah!
Okay.
A word of advice.
We are champions.
Obviously, we are champions.
But l want you to
behave like champions.
Others will hug each other
and shake hands...
they call it the sporting spirit.
l call it bullshit!
lt's merely an excuse...
for the losers.
You know... it's a way of masking
their embarrassment.
That's why...
Oh baby, you're so good,
you know?.
l mean yeah, hard luck baby...
sporting spirit!
But here at JDC, losing is...
never an option.
lt never was!
So your mantra for victory is...
To impress!
Whatever you do, make sure
the audience is impressed.
Take a look at me...
this hair, these lenses,
this goatee...
it's all to impress!
Your every move, every turn,
every jump, every step...
should have only one goal.
We dance to impress!
Animals dance to
impress their mates.
We must dance to...
express!
Being able to convey
your feelings through dance...
will make you a good dancer.
Excuse me!
Everybody... get out.
Confiscate all their equipment
and seal this place.
Sir, l think there's been a mistake.
We aren't doing anything illegal.
Hey...
please don't touch the equipment.
Please!
And what if he does?
ls this your ancestral property,
to set up a dance class?
And without permission!
How dare you stare at me?
Watch it!
Or you'll regret it.
ls that right?
Rushali, call Vardha bhai.
Dad is out of town.
lf he were here,
he'd take care of it.
Thank you, Qureshi bhai.
Let's go!
Well done, Qureshi bhai.
So you called the cops?
You're behind this ruckus.
You create a ruckus every day.
You know what...
this drunkard wants
to ruin our children's future.
Don't you agree with me?
Why is everyone else silent?
Tell them to leave.
Stop this nonsense.
No dancing anymore!
Please...
l understand your concern.
You want your kids to
settle down, just like you.
But ask yourself...
are you really happy
with where you are?
Are you happy with your life?
We live a simple life, Vishnu.
We spend 2.5 rupees on tea
and 5 rupees on a sandwich.
That's our worth.
We shouldn't dream about
what we can't afford.
lt's not about your dreams.
lt's your mindset
that's holding you back.
Your children can
be more successful than you.
But only if you are more liberal
than your own parents were.
l request you...
Don't you do that.
You know something...
this is how society is...
they don't want to accept change.
They are like crabs in a basket.
lf one crab tries to climb out,
the others drag it down.
They are all crabs.
Crabs!
We are earthworms.
lf earthworms were meant to fly...
wouldn't God give them wings?
Let's go!
Let's go, everyone.
Move.
Let's go!
No sense in waiting here.
We are dead.
Just relax!
Relax?
We couldn't survive Down Under.
And the competition
here is a lot better.
At Down Under,
Vishnu sir saved our skin.
But here that's not an option.
Relax... don't worry.
We are in trouble!
D is still not here.
Okay!
How long do we wait for him?
He won't come.
He will!
l don't think his dad
will let him come.
Where can l register?
There.
Guys.
Sorry l'm late...
What's up, Chandu?
D... you made it!
D...
Yes, l made it.
What's with the bags?
l was stepping out...
Dad threw a fit...
l stood my ground...
Mom began to cry...
Dad threatened...
'lf you step out,
you can never come back.'
Then?
You know, l can't live without music.
So l packed my CDs and walked out.
No worries.
We're with you.
Nice.
Well done!
Congratulations!
l'm sure you know JDC.
The next performers are
first-time participants in DDS.
they are...
DDR!
Yeah!
1... 2... 3... 4...
Ganpati Baapa Morya!
Oh no...
Bad.
What are you doing?
Why did you do that?
Have you lost it?
No, you have!
Jehangir, it's bad.
Hi sir.
Hi Vishnu.
They are very good dancers,
believe me.
Watch out for them
in the next round.
What makes you think
they will make it?
Did you see them dance?
l mean they were fighting
rather than dancing.
lt was funny!
What's wrong with funny?
l mean...
l like funny!
Of course, l shouldn't say this but...
if l were ajudge,
l would promote them.
You want to turn this into
a comedy show?.
So what?
More entertainment for your audience!
Moreover, after watching DDR's 'dance'
the audience will realise that...
real dancing is not
as easy as it appears on TV!
Think about it!
He's got a point.
The point is...
have you ever been to a circus?
Huh?
At a circus, you have these jokers...
who are there
to amuse the audience.
This show could do
with some amusement.
And DDR fit the bill.
Think about it.
Of course...
the final decision is yours.
But l really like funny.
What are you doing here, Vishnu?
Vardha bhai has thrown a party.
No partying!
Why not?
Get everyone here for the rehearsal.
Now?.
Yes, right now!
We are jokers!
We are in the second round
so that everyone can laugh at us!
Jokers!
They called you...
jokers!
Can you tell me why?
Can you?
Good.
Boys back!
Back...
boys back!
Move 4 steps to your left.
5... 6... 7... 8...
Do a wall back stand.
Turn... he is the wall.
Ready?
5... 6... 7... 8...
What the--
What happened?
l thought he wasn't ready.
Sir, l was ready...
but l don't think he knows this step.
Lack of faith!
Both of you assumed that...
the other is not ready.
That's why you failed.
You need to trust each other,
to dance as a team.
D...
whom do you trust?
Bawa!
Rocky?
Sir, Mayur.
Mayur!
Get me the blindfolds.
Blindfold them.
Tie them.
Fast.
Rocky will do the step with Mayur...
and D with Bawa.
Go back four steps.
5... 6... 7... 8...
Mayur...
did we do it.
Do you get it?
lt was trust that helped you
perform with a blindfold.
You must trust each other.
Until you don't get this step
right with your eyes open...
nobody goes home tonight.
Here.
Come on.
Come on, D.
Dammit.
What's going on?
l don't know.
Forget it.
He doesn't trust me.
Don't tell me.
lt's his fault.
D...
Have some water.
Do you remember...
you, Rocky and me
playing together as kids?
We had no worries back then.
Everyone does silly stuff
when they're kids.
You don't get it.
You're being silly now.
Tell me why you and Rocky
don't see eye to eye?
He charmed Rhea.
Rhea is not the problem.
She's been here only a few weeks.
Rocky has envied you for years.
Rocky is jealous of me?
Yes, he envied you.
Want to know why?
lt started when Bhavna
moved here five years ago.
Though Bhavna lived near Rocky...
she looked up to you
for every little thing.
Rocky couldn't bear it.
Since then Rocky and you
have been at loggerheads.
Now Rocky is seeing Rhea.
But you are still being silly...
l mean, you and Bhavna.
Says the fool that's
throwing his life away.
What the--
Shaina, guess what Chandu is up to.
Nothing...
Bhavna, come here.
Bhavna...
What is it?
D is looking for you.
- What happened?
- Nothing!
You're smoking again!
What's up?
Nothing... l mean...
Chandu is crazy.
Sorry!
What is it?
Why didn't you tell me?
Tell you what?
You know...
that you like me...
What's to tell?
Don't you know it?
Well... l'm an idiot!
How would l know?.
ldiot?
You think l have a PhD in love!
Love?
That's super fast!
l was still at 'like'...
but you've moved onto love.
Love, marriage, children...
you've got it all planned.
Stop it or else...
Else what?
No future?
Shut up!
Rocky!
Look at them man...
Superb.
Now that's what l call dance!
l didn't expect we'd make it this far.
The championship is only
two steps away from us.
Semifinals and...
Finals!
Move.
But we have to watch every step.
Yes!
Sir!
Chandu!
Chandu...
stand straight.
Step forward.
Here.
Sir, straight... attention!
You promised to
give up this bad habit.
Why did you break your promise?
Sir...
lt was a mistake.
l met Babu and some other friends.
We were celebrating...
the semifinals.
lt started with one drag...
then another... and another...
Sir...
Sir, today is not the first time
since l gave you my word.
l've been using some,
just to stay high.
l'm a dog's tail that can
never be straightened, sir!
l'm a dog's tail!
l can't be trusted.
You trusted me...
but l betrayed you.
l can't be trusted.
Chandu, l've trusted
you since the day l met you.
l still do and always will.
lf you can't give up
this addiction for yourself...
l'm sure you will
give it up for us.
l have an idea!
Chandu should be the lead dancer
in the semifinal.
l agree with Rocky.
Brilliant idea!
He will be so busy rehearsing that...
he won't have time for anything else.
Chandu...
Shaina, back...
boys back!
Get up!
Sound!
Vishnu, l promise,
l will lose weight.
And l'll give Jehangir...
Where is he going now?.
Such a loser.
Vishnu, l'll be back soon.
What is it?
Just a minute.
The semifinals of Close up Dance Dil Se
powered by Spinz will begin in a few hours!
Fans supporting their teams
have gathered here since morning.
One team here has left
everyone speechless.
Any guesses?
DDR! DDR!
This team that emerged from the
ghettos has left everyone far behind.
ln fact, this team has captured
the hearts of millions.
lf people are so excited out here, imagine
what it must be like in the DDR green room.
Biscuit, leave her alone.
Wow! Beautiful!
You look stunning.
You look fabulous too.
Anyway... where's Chandu?
He said he might be late.
Where have you been, Chandu?
Forgotten your old friends, have you?
Babu!
Chandu!
What's up?
l know where he is.
Where? Tell me!
lt's a surprise!
l'm happy for you.
l wish you luck...
and l hope you can buy more rings.
Thanks!
But l'm in a hurry... see you later.
After the performance,
Chandu will...
Have you lost it?
l have to perform in 2 hours...
and you're telling me to have a drag.
Rhea!
Look at her, she's blushing!
Have a drag...
for old time's sake!
How touching!
For old time's sake?
Friends help us live...
not die!
lf l were a guy, Chandu would've
had to compete with me.
lt's his money talking.
Think you're smart, eh?
You're showing off to us?
Let's go.
Step back!
Give me back my ring.
His phone is switched off.
We shouldn't have trusted Chandu.
We're on next.
Sir, Chandu is not here yet.
You said you trusted him.
l mean...
he has betrayed you again.
l agree with you.
Chandu is a traitor.
He has betrayed all of us.
Gopi is waiting for
us at the hospital.
We need to claim his body.
Sir, can we leave after 10 minutes?
Please?
No...
Chandu...
Who among you is family?
We all are!
We found this in his pocket.
Vishnu...
we've made it to the finals.
Mediocrity is king.
Talk some sense into him!
DDR has the public's sympathy...
they are the underdogs now.
Tell him to do what l say.
lf l lose my patience...
l will send him back
to where he came from!
Competitions... Ramp-walks...
lnternational shows... World tours...
You can have it all...
if you join my team.
But if you stay with Vishnu...
Let's assume for a minute...
that you've won the competition.
But, what next?
Think about it...
lt is your career...
right?
You can take 10 minutes to decide.
This is the contract,
that's the pen.
10 minutes...
No, sir!
We had decided that...
there's nothing you could offer
to turn us against Vishnu sir.
But we came here because...
Rhea told us that...
the look on your face when
you're screwed is priceless!
Good day, sir!
He thought he could buy our loyalty?
That was classic!
Zip!
Come on, Mayur.
Yeah!
Where do you want to go?
To meet Jehangir sir.
Okay.
Rocky...
What?
Nothing.
What is it?
l thought l saw D.
D? Over here?
Are you crazy?
Why would he come here?
You're mistaken.
Let's go!
Stop messing around.
Ready?
lmraan, lights.
Vishnu...
all set?
Leaving JDC was a mistake.
But coming back to
the competition is...
a bigger mistake.
Did you really think...
that everyone would praise you?
Huh?
You've made a big mistake...
by messing with Jehangir Khan.
The grand finale of Close up Dance Dil
Se powered by Spinz is finally here.
The dance show that has captured
the hearts of a million lndians...
and brought everything
to a standstill...
is about to begin.
The biggest entertainment
show of lndia.
Guys, you are fabulous.
Our concept is out of this world.
You think we'll win?
Of course.
Gopi!
We will win.
ln a last minute change DDR is
now going to close tonight's finale.
l guess the organizers
have realized that...
everyone in lndia is rooting for them.
So the first performance is by
Jehangir Khan's defending champions.
Are you guys ready?
Sir...
That's our theme.
They stole our entire act!
That's cheating, Vishnu.
That no-good slimeball Jehangir.
Trust me it's one of us.
And l know who it is.
l saw him at JDC.
Saw whom?
l saw D.
What?
D was here a minute ago...
But he isn't here now!
Who do you think
is doing those steps?
Dude! Did you see that?
Sir, they are doing our dance.
D is here.
lf D is here, then who is that?
Superb!
Damn good!
Wow! What a smashing performance.
JDC have proved that
they are the champions.
How could you do that?
l don't want to play
second fiddle to you all my life!
Another thing...
l'm the lead dancer at JDC.
Get lost!
You get lost!
l don't want to end
up like Vishnu sir.
Step back...
All of you step back!
Didn't you hear me?
Step back!
So Gopi...
doesn't this fighting
remind you of your ghetto?
'The only thing l can do is teach
dance', isn't that what you said?
And, what you taught...
was performed.
What will you teach your team now?.
ln 10 minutes...
So guys, what do you think
who will win?
JDC! JDC!
What's the matter?
What's with the long faces?
We have won!
JDC stole our routine.
We've already won this competition.
lt's time to celebrate.
But what do we do
for our performance?
We're up next!
You will perform the dance
that every lndian knows.
A dance that brings people together.
A dance that you can't
merely sit and watch.
lt will make you want to
get up and dance.
A dance that hasn't
changed for years...
it's performed at weddings...
it's performed when
lndia wins a cricket match...
it's performed when we
dance at the Ganpati Festival.
The only dance that
follows no discipline.
lt follows the heart.
A-B-C-D
Any Body Can Dance.
Any Body Can Dance!
Yeah!
Everybody join in.
That was a superb
classical performance!
And now brace yourself...
for the last act of Dance Dil Se...
DDR!
Ganpati Bappa Morya.
Vishnu...
You're the best.
You fixed everything.
lf every neighbourhood
had someone like you...
everything would be perfect.
Gopi...
what happened?