Hold your breath!
Now in front of
this wonderful crowd...
... the melodious voice which has
enthralled the heart of millions...
... the voice you've been
waiting to hear...
... with that
majestic voice comes...
... a great artist of our country.
The greatest singer of our country.
Subir Kumar!
Yes of course, l know
who's on the line.
Will l've to use your
name to convince you?
A bright star in the sky, Chitra.
- What were you doing?
- Nothing, l was just sitting.
Don't you've the courtesy to
stand up in front of a lady?
l am not in front of a lady,
l'm just hearing her voice.
So tell me, how did
the singing go today?
lt went very well.
lt was a sad song.
lt was a song about separation.
Separation, that's the
real tune of life itself.
Oh! So you like such songs.
Can l enquire as to who's
behind this separation?
l've kept that name in
a safe deposit vault.
So, what else did
you do today?
l helped a four year old dog
and a sixty year old man.
l saved them from
being hit by the car.
What else?
Then... l attended the silver
jubilee function of a movie.
What next?
Then l lambasted a photographer.
Lambasted! Why?
The swine, flashed his camera
right in front of my eyes.
Go to sleep now, but meet
me tomorrow definitely.
- Listen.
- Yes.
One last thing.
l'm crazy about your music.
ls that so?
Only about my music?
You make my life
worth living.
This is submitted to the
income-tax authorities. Sign it.
What were you talking about
for so long with Chitra?
We were discussing how to
start the third world war!
Yes! Do l have to
tell you everything?
No! You don't need
to tell me anything.
You may do whatever suits you.
Understood! Whatever suits you.
Why do you envy
her so much?
- A friend!
- Yes.
What friendship can a man and
woman share? lt's just like..
... a dagger and a melon,
or an eagle and a pigeon, right?
Yes. But the point here is that
she's the eagle and you, the pigeon.
- Shut up.
- No.
l've only one desire, that you
become the greatest singer of lndia.
But for that you've to be dedicated,
hardworking and disciplined.
l see you getting slowly
infatuated by Chitra.
- And she's not at all fit for you.
- What do you mean?
Look here... You know
that you can't marry her.
Why advance the relationship any
further? l don't think it's right.
And you said that an
ideal wife for you...
... would be someone
like your mother and aunt.
Someone who could take
care of you, serve you.
Mark my words, this rich
and independent female...
... will make you
dance like a puppet.
You are laughing when you should
be crying. Laugh as much as you
want to.
A day will come when
you'll have to cry.
Give that to me!
- Good night DAD!
- Good night son.
Listen, can l speak
to Subir Kumar?
Hello, whom do you want?
- You.
- Who's that you?
You, Subir Kumar.
Look here, l ain't Subir Kumar.
My name is Vishnu.
What rubbish! Your voice
is one amongst millions.
lt cannot belong to any
Shiv, Mahesh or Vishnu.
What troubles you so
late in the night?
l'll tell you that if you meet me.
Did you not recognise me?
- No.
- We met at the Haridas Convention.
My name is Radha.
Wow! A very classical name indeed.
But what do you want?
Me... l want to meet you.
But why?
l am in love with you, my darling.
Since l've heard you...
Go to hell!
Who's that?
- What happened?
- Nothing... Were you sleeping?
Do you expect me to be
fishing in bed at midnight?
You're finding it
difficult to sleep, right?
- Yes.
- lt happens.
Once you become
famous, it happens.
Go, try and get some sleep.
When will our new
bungalow get ready?
ln another two or three months.
We are quite fine here.
What'll we do in such a big
bungalow?
Do one thing. Sell it off
as soon as it is ready.
Why? What's the problem?
You look lonely, unhappy
and depressed again today.
- This will definitely happen.
- Why?
You know God, up in heaven,
he has a weird sense of humour.
He balances everything
proportionately.
He asked his secretary once, what
was given to a particular fellow?
The secretary told him that he
has been given Rupees 6 to 7
lakhs
The Lord said, ''Give him
an ulcer, gastric''...
...''and a boil in his
stomach so that he can't eat''.
Then he asked what
another fellow was given?
The secretary replied that he had
been given some land and a cloth
mill
The Lord said ''Give him
a crooked manager''
''And also make him start gambling''
Then he asked what
was given to you.
Me? A bit of fame,
a little bit of money.
-How much money?
-Around two or three lakhs of
rupees.
- What about the
one lakh black money?
- May be that too.
Then do one thing. Make him
restless for now, then we will see.
- That's a nice joke.
- You liked it, right?
So now, get up and
please go to sleep.
The same thing again.
l told you l can't sleep.
Where have you hid the bottle of
sleeping tablets? Give it to me.
Oh! You attended 4 or 5
parties.
Had a few drinks there.
And now you want sleeping tablets
so that you may sleep forever.
And the cops arrest me.
Very good!
Look here, do one thing.
Find a nice and good-looking
girl and get married.
Yes. Thus when you can't sleep...
... wake her up at midnight and
play* rummy with her for 1
rupee per point
You rascal.
Can l speak to Subir?
Yes, What can l do for you?
- How long have you been here?
- For quite some time now?
And l saw with my own eyes
how l was being dishonoured.
You were listening
to my song and dozing.
Not at all sir. l was taking your
heavenly music right into my soul.
WOW!
When a woman is sitting
with her eyes shut...
... don't make the mistake of
thinking that she's sleeping.
- ls that so?
- Yes.
- What brings you here at this time?
- l was just passing by...
... so l dropped in to say hello.*
l've a song recording.
After half an hour.
- Half an hour!
Where's Dad nowadays?
He's a busy man.
A conference in Geneva today,
Bonn tomorrow, the day after...
.. get some whisky... listen, get it
with cold water: we don't need
soda.
Chitra, l told you
there's a recording.
So what! Your voice will
become more intoxicating.
That's fine. But you
know that chap, my Dad!
- Who's that, Chandru?
- Yes.
lf he finds out that l came to sing
after having a drink then l've had
it
Yes, Chandru here.
No, this month there's no date.
Yes tomorrow is free,
but l've a bad throat sir.
Yes, if it's cancelled*
again l'll let you know.
Okay, bye.
Did you see that?
There are many problems.
- We have come with great hope.
- But what can l do?
But you have to do something.
lt's for some charity.
l understand that sir.
How're you? Did you
get Dharmendra's date?
That l have. But if l don't get
Subir's date, l'll be ruined.
Look l've got everything.
- Wait, l'd like to speak to you.
Please wait, l'll be back soon.
Vishnu! Get some tea for them.
- Does he sing too?
- No.
But he just said that
he had a bad throat.
lt means that Subir Kumar
has a bad throat.
Secretaries say such things.
ln popular lingo that's a stooge.
Come Mr. Rao.
Take a seat.
lt's just that, lt's not proper to
open your bag in front of everybody.
Can't say if somebody is from
the income-tax department.
Do you know that the
income-tax department has...
... put six inspectors
for the film section?
- ls it?
- Yes.
This is your cheque for
Rupees 2000.
And this is the hot-cash.
Chandruji, l hope
my dates are fixed.
Yes, you've made the payment...
... so they won't be cancelled.
Absolutely irrevocable.
Are you signing photographs?
Sign all of them.
There's quite a lot of fan-mail.*
Here's the six thousand which
Mr.Rao has given. Count it.
- l'll break your teeth.
- Why? Does it not hurt?
Don't l feel hurt when you
ask me to count the cash?
No, l did not mean that.
lt's money after all.
So you should count it.
l won't do it. All this
accounting is your problem.
Listen... Keep this
money for yourself.
- Myself! Why?
- Stupid question. For expenses.
You've said it once,
don't say it ever again.
l work here because of my affection
for you. Do you mind that?
At times l feel like beating you
up and making you stand in a
corner.
There are some people here from
Bangalore, l've to get rid of them.
Yes, go ahead.
l've checked the dates,
there's no chance.
Look, we are ready to pay
as much as you ask for.
That's the limit! ls he an actor
who signs any film because of
money?
But please give him this letter.
- Whose letter is that?
- lt's meant for him.
Whatever he says after reading
this is acceptable to us.
These people from Bangalore
have got a letter from someone.
- Whose letter is it?
- l don't know.
Read it.
'My dear son, Beeru'
Who has written it?
'Wishing for your well-being with
every breath, Yours, Aunt Durga'
- Your Aunt!
- Yes.
She may be my Aunt, but she
means more to me than a mother.
After the death of my parents,
when l was just one, she raised me.
- She has sent a reference.
- ls it? Then you have to go.
But, how's that possible?
The schedule is so tight.
To hell with the schedule.
l'll cancel everything.
But what about the dates
fixed for the month?
Damn the dates! l'll get the
brickbats. No problem, l'll handle
it.
Come and meet them.
- Greetings.
- Greetings, please have a seat.
Why did you not tell me before
that Aunty has sent you?
That was the one ace we held.
- But l have one condition.
- What's that?
- l'll surely go to meet my Aunt.
- Definitely, l'll have a car ready.
But l've to be back in Bombay
the next day at 1 0 in the morning
Yes, you may leave as soon
as the function is over.
- Where's Aunt Durga?
- Upstairs.
- What's going on here?!
- Oh my God!
Oh Beeru, it's you!
Wait... Let me have
a good look at you.
You've had a good look and your
eyes are filled with tears too.
You aren't yet old enough to
understand the joy of shedding
tears.
l thought, perhaps l wouldn't
get to see you till l die.
What are you talking about?
You have yet to see my marriage.
That is l'll have to live
for another hundred years.
l'm very hungry. Tell me, what're
you going to cook for dinner.
Cook! Brinjals... Cucumber Rolls
and thick bread made of gram flour.
You still remember
my likes and dislikes.
l'm not like you.
Come on, freshen up
and rest awhile.
lt's quite peaceful here.
The city is very suffocating.
l'd rather go for a stroll.
And my food should be
ready by the time l return.
- Mother, who was he?
- That's my Beeru.
Did you see how he orders
me around? As if l'm his mother.
You're back.
This is what you call soon.
- Listen, you know the temple?
- Yes.
l heard someone worshiping
the Lord... singing a madrigal.
lt felt heavenly. l've never felt
such happiness and peace before.
You must've heard brother Sadanand
and her daughter singing.
Yes. He was a teacher in
some school in the city.
He settled down
here four years ago.
There are very few
saints like him.
l don't know much about it,
but people say that...
... he's a pundit
of classical music.
And he has trained
his daughter too.
Come with me tomorrow to meet
him.
Tomorrow! But l'm leaving
tomorrow morning.
- Tomorrow itself?
- Yes.
lf you wanted to leave so soon,
then why did you come at all?
What can l do? l've to do
a lot of work in the city.
You've come after eight years
and that too for only a day.
- Aunty!
- Don't aunty me.
But where are you going?
To the kitchen,
the food is getting cold.
Aunty, l'm getting late.
Let it be, God knows whether l'll
live long enough to see you again.
- Don't spoil my mood.
- And what about me?
Remember me sometimes atleast.
Who else do l have other than you?
l'll come back and
stay here for many days.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Swear by me.
- Here you are.
Okay, l'd better hurry
or l'll miss the flight.
Visit the temple
on the way back.
Wow! You sing very well indeed.
Excuse me.
Aren't you Miss Uma?
Mr.Sadanand's daughter?
How do you know that?
l heard you and your father
singing yesterday. l liked it a lot.
l asked my aunt about it
and she told me about you.
- Does your aunt stay here?
- Yes, near that old banyan tree.
- But that house belongs to
grandma.
- Grandma!
- Do you call aunt Durga, grandma?
- Yes.
- Aren't you Mr.Subir?
- Yes l am.
Grandma always talks about you.
And whenever your song comes on
the radio, she sits right in front of
it.
l too have heard you singing.
You sing very well.
But all your songs are not good.
Some of them are just plain noisy.
Which song have you heard?
How is that good, or noisy?
lt's good. l hope you
didn't feel bad about...
No, why should l feel bad
about it? You're right.
- Even l don't like some of them.
- Then why do you sing them?
What can l do? People like such
songs, and people mean everything.
Do you sing to
make people happy?
- Then who else should l sing for?
- For yourself.
My father says, when a song is sung
for one's own self, it becomes music.
That's why your song
sounded so sweet.
- Great God!
- What happened?
Your song, and talking to you
has made me miss my flight.
l wasn't singing for you.
And you came here to talk.
Even then, you'll be held
responsible if l miss my flight.
Come on mother...
Change your clothes,
freshen-up and have your food.
- l ain't hungry.
- l know, it's because Beeru has left
Don't trouble me.
l won't eat.
Alright, then l won't eat too.
Yes, l thought you must
be crying, so l returned.
- Will you stay for a few days?
- No, only today.
Well, l'll prepare some food,
l feel hungry all of a sudden.
And then we'll go to
meet brother Sadanand.
Dad, haven't you begun yet.
The mosquitoes are buzzing around.
l'll eat it my child.
Our upanishads are a
treasure of knowledge.
You get to learn something
new every time you read it.
Alright, you keep on reading.
Keep on reading.
- What are you doing?
- Go on, read.
What's this? You're becoming more
like a child with every passing day.
Welcome sister.
Old-age makes man a child and
the daughter becomes like a mother.
Please take a seat.
Greetings.
He's my son, Subir.
l told you about him.
And he's Mr. Sadanand.
He's like my brother.
- Greetings.
- God bless you.
You are quite famous.
When did you arrive?
Yesterday. l tried to make
him stay, but he left today.
Do you know why he returned?
After boarding the plane he thought
l must be crying so he returned.
He did the right thing.
A man should have compassion.
But were you actually crying?
She wasn't just crying,
when l returned.
l saw her lying on the bed
without having any food or water.
That wasn't because you had left.
Actually l had a headache.
And when you saw him,
the headache vanished!
And Beeru, this is Uma.
You heard her sing yesterday.
Oh! Do you sing?
You don't look like
the singing type.
You too don't look like the type
to return from a plane because of
her
Let's forget it.
Why involve her in everything?
- Aunty, you said something about...
- Yes of course.
Son, he's a master of music.
Listen to me, stay back for a few
days and learn something from him.
What can l teach him? He has
already devoted himself to music.
And is treading the path
of peace and happiness.
Nature has in it's
store, music everywhere.
There's a feel to every word.
Every feeling is beautiful.
Beauty contains
sweetness and fragrance.
Everything is an integral
part of this universe.
- l didn't understand that.
- What?
What your father said.
'Every word has a feel, beauty has
sweetness and all that is integral'.
l couldn't understand that.
- lt's quite simple actually.*
Wait.
Do you hear something?
- The sound of a sparrow.
- Yes.
Don't you get a feeling that the
sounds are coming from these
flowers?
Yes. Hello, Mr. Rao.
Sorry, but your recording
will have to be cancelled.
l've received a cable
from Subir, he is sick.
Yes, he'll be back
in four or five days.
Do one thing, reschedule the
recording on next Monday.
Don't worry, he'll be here.
Listen... l saw you put some water
and bow there that day, why?
Lord Shiva resides there.
Do you know the bride and
bridegroom come here to get
married?
They don't need a priest.
They get married with God as
witness.
- What does that mean?
- lt means...
... Lord Shiva
manifested himself here.
You believe in all that.
My father says belief
is better than argument.
lf you have faith, then
it's God, else just a stone.
Here, take this.
Won't you feel unhappy
when l leave tomorrow?
Tomorrow! Will you be
leaving tomorrow itself?
- Yes.
- Why?
What do you mean?
Don't l've to work?
You didn't answer my question,
won't you feel unhappy when l
leave?
Grandma will cry a lot.
lt's you l'm talking about, not her.
Won't you feel unhappy?
Tell me.
Why will you feel
unhappy when l leave?
l don't know why,
but l'll feel lonely.
- Me too.
- The city is so crowded...
... You'll be very busy,
why should you feel lonely?
You don't know. All of a sudden
in the crowd, l find myself alone.
- Why?
- Because you aren't there.
- Beeru.
- Yes aunty.
Here, have some tea.
l'm worried about you staying
alone over there. Get married now.
Me, marry a girl!
Of course!
l feel that you'll be very happy.
Has anybody ever been happy after
marriage? Uncle being an exception.
As l said, you are quite
similar to your uncle.
Look, l've chosen a girl.
Great God! You've
already chosen one.
- Yes.
- Who's the lucky girl?
- Uma.
- Let me think it over.
What's there to think about?
l want an answer before you leave.
And it should be a yes.
Yes... l said yes.
Mr. Kapadia you've still not
finished with the Bar.
This house belongs to
an artist, not a smuggler.
And listen, l don't like the
furniture of the bedroom at all.
The size of the bed is too small.
Will he sleep on it or me?
lt's length should be
increased by atleast three feet...
... Else his legs won't fit.
You should do better with
the rest of the furniture.
Stop saying yes, and go get the
measurements. l want to surprise
him.
Sorry my friend, but you
are too late for that.
- When did you arrive and how?
- Just now, by cab.
- You did not even inform me.
- l too wanted to surprise you.
You donkey!
Welcome. Let me introduce you.
He is my boss, that's my good
friend Mr.Chandru Kriplani.
- Hello.
- He talks a lot.
And she is... Why don't
you guess who she is?
Mrs. Sinha! We met at the
function in Muzafarpur.
You've become a bit
thin and a bit short too.
She can become thin,
but how can she become short?
No she can't... Then?
Look carefully, who can she be?
Oh Yes! Miss Advani!
You stood first in the
beauty contest at Simla.
You were the judge there, right?
Haven't l recognised her!
How are you?
When did you get married?
When did you come to Bombay?
Where's your husband?
Here's her husband!
Yes... She is Uma.
Anybody there!
Get me a glass of cold water!
Don't feel bad. But the day after
the marriage was fixed was
auspicious
What could l do? There wasn't an
auspicious day for the next months
l won't consider it to be a
marriage. You'll have to marry
again.
- With whom?
- With you of course!
ls this a wedding or a joke?
Nobody knows about it.
You will have to marry again.
l'll get you married.
l'll call everybody.
lt will be a great wedding.
And lt will be followed
by a grand party.
What luck! Brijeshwarraiji is here.
Welcome! l hadn't, even in my
dreams, thought that you would
come.
Do you think in your dreams too?
When l dream, l just dream.
Listen, do l seem to be
such an insolent man...
... that l wouldn't come after
receiving your invitation?
No, it's not that.
You being an exponent of classical
music, and me a mere pop singer.
That's fine, but even your
music depends on the seven notes.
Meet Uma, my wife.
And he is Brijeshwarrai...
... considered to be the*
father of classical music here.
May god bless you.
Nowadays the custom of
paying respects is over.
But do you realise what you
have done by doing this?
You have won me over
with love and devotion.
But Subir, you said
something very wrong.
- What happened?
- This Pop music, classical music...
l wish to show you that l'm a lover
of music, so you'll have to sing.
What are you saying?
There are so many guests.
Don't worry. Nobody
over here shall mind.
Subir,lt's his order,
you'll have to sing.
- Agreed, but there's one thing.
- What's that?
- Uma will sing with me too.
- Do you sing too?
- She sings very well
- Then both of you begin.
lf you don't sing, l'll leave
without eating or drinking anything.
- The old-man has trapped me.
- You'll have to sing.
How can the reception of Subir's
wedding be complete without his
song?
Subir Kumar will be
accompanied by his wife Uma.
- Why did you ask me to sing?
- What happened?
- ln front of everybody.
- Don't worry, l'm with you.
lf you get nervous,
look at me.
And l will do this.
- What does that mean?
- lt means...
... l gave you a kiss.
Wow! What a voice!
May god bless you my child.
l pray to God that both
of you have a long life.
You've learnt classical music,
that's why you sounded very sweet.
Congratulations.
No problem Subir.
Whatever you did was correct.
l was not fit for the
position which she has taken.
What l say is true. l felt some pain
when l heard about your marriage.
lt felt like there's nothing
left anymore. l felt very lonely.
But after hearing her
sing, l feel very happy.
She's the only one
fit to be your wife.
You don't know me. l'm Chitra,
a friend of your husband.
l'm sorry, but l've to go for
a meeting. l take your leave now.
l obeyed you, now
you have to obey me.
You are elder to us, you can't
go without eating something.
- Okay, get a sweet dish.
- l'll get it, Please come.
Did you really like her voice?
l liked it very much. She must
have learnt from a good teacher.
Yes, she learnt from her father.
l've decided that from now on...
... we will sing together.
He better not make such a mistake.
- Which mistake sir?
- The mistake of singing together.
Don't you understand?
Uma is more talented than Subir.
And history teaches us that
a man is superior than a woman.
Will he be able to bear
her overtaking him?
Don't worry, they are married...
... all the music will be lost in
the kitchen and raising children.
That'll be even worse.
l must've been around ten
or eleven years old...
... one day Ramesh approached
me and told me to have a cigarette.
l refused.
He started laughing aloud
and called me a coward.
l didn't feel bad about being called
a coward, but his laughter hurt.
l felt a vigor inside me and said
give it to me, l'll have it too.
l took it and had a deep drag.
And it was all over.
l started coughing heavily.
The coughing made
me red in the face.
Meanwhile the professor
of mathematics arrived.
He stood up
and started smelling.
And l was standing
there red in the face.
A thief cannot hide
for long. He saw me.
And he said 'Hey Subir, come here'
l went near him
'Open your mouth'
He took a smell,
and caught me.
'So that's it. There's a stick
in the other room, go and get it'
Think of my plight then.
l'm about to be hit...
... and he's asking
me to get the stick.
Well, l went and got the stick.
As soon as l returned, he gave
me one hard rap on the hand.
- Enough. l don't want to hear it.
- Why?
May such a professor
suffer from fits.
Did it hurt very much?
Hey, he hit me
on this hand too.
- Vermilion
- So what?
lf someone sees it
what'll he think?
What?
l'm Radha here. We met at
the Haridas Convention.
Yes, l recognise you.
What can l do for you?
- Are you really married?
- Yes.
Where's your wife?
She has gone to
her parents' house.
Why did you get married?
Was it right to break so many hearts?
What can l do?
l too regret my mistake.
- Really!
- Yes.
l'm thinking of how to get out of
this dilemma. How to get a divorce!
Who's that?
Whose voice is that?
Me! My name is Uma.
l'm Mr.Subir's wife.
- What happened?
- Nothing, let me sleep.
- Tell me, what happened?
- l said nothing!...
... Let me sleep,
it's almost morning.
You were fine just a moment ago.
What angered you so much now?
This is what used to
happen before l came, right?
Girls calling up so late in
the night and you talking to them.
That was then,
it won't happen now.
- Really it won't happen now.
- Swear by me?
Yes l do, but you have to
agree to my condition too.
- What's that?
- Listen.
Everyday not more,
just a hundred or two...
Listen! l'll lower
it to only ten.
Uma, listen, hey!
Hey, wake up.
Wake up.
Let me go, leave me.
Keep singing, it's
such a nice tune.
How did you like the lyrics?
lf the tune is good,
the lyrics become good too.