"Love is not peace...
"Love is a battlefield."
Daddy, mummy, looky at me.
Don't stray too far.
- OK.
- Watch yourself!
"Using sincerity instead of arms...
"It is the hardest and strictest battle..."
How lovely.
"Which we should fight by
killing ourselves.
"My child, please heed this call."
- Prime Minister Nehru to his daughter
Help!
Hey, you.
You live in that big villa.
If I knew you were rich,
I'd have punched you.
AI TO MAKOTO
AKA "FOR LOVE'S SAKE"
11 years later and...
I was a senior in high school.
And Japan was in high gear.
The economy was booming and...
everyone believed they'd be rich.
Or so they thought.
Stop shitting me, you hick.
We'll show you how...
real Tokyo men rumble.
Tell me to "stop"?
Too late for that
If you're swept into
a violent love storm,
it's all over
Tell me to "stop"?
My mind's made up
Till I'm torn limb from limb
Scarred and scorched by love
If this love
can come true
I'd probably do whatever it takes
I'd maybe even
change my life for
those... jet... black
eyes of seduction
Tell me to "stop"?
Death won't stop me
Let's run to the ends of the Earth
if my arms can hold you
Tell me to "stop"?
That gets me even hotter
Till I'm torn limb from limb
Scarred and scorched by love
Heartrending sorrow
Wallowing at night
Is this the mercy of love's cruelty?
Throwing my life
into confusion
those... jet... black
eyes of seduction
Please stop!
Fighting is wrong.
- Violence solves nothing.
- Out of my way.
If you must fight, hit me then do it.
Over my dead body...
A pretentious bourgeois like
you disgusts me.
Now, scram.
You're dead wrong if you
think I'll give in...
'cause you're kinda cute.
You're fooling yourself, girl!
It's you...
Yes, you.
I won't...
I won't give in.
Fighting is...
- The cops!
- Riot police!
- Run! - Hurry!
- Run for it!
Dammit!
- Don't! Running solves nothing.
- What gives!
- Let go, you stupid bitch!
- Mend your ways! Do it for me!
Bullshit! What is with you?
Miss, are you okay?
You'll regret this!
I'm fine.
Everyone, don't hurt him.
Are you the daughter of
the Saotome family?
Guilty; I cannot lie.
Pay me no mind.
I may be bourgeois,
but I don't expect special treatment.
Take him away.
What will become of him?
That hardened bad boy will be
sent to reform school.
He can't!
Taiga Makoto...
You've been released.
Huh? Why?
You're going to the prestigious
Aobadai Prep School.
But why?
A request from Mr Saotome,
their PTA chairman.
Saotome?
- The well-to-do Saotome family?
- Exactly.
I, myself, am wondering why.
This is how it's meant to be.
Residing in Den-en-chofu,
Ota-ku, Tokyo.
A senior at Aobadai Prep School.
Saotome Ai.
I don't mean to brag,
but I'm great at sports.
As for my grades...
Sorry, I'm top of my class.
So from today,
welcome a new peer to our class.
Taiga-kun. Take off your hat and remove
your hands from your pockets.
What's with the rebellious look?
You picking a fight?
I was an Olympic wrestler, you know.
Take off your hat!
What a scar!
Just like Moonlight Mask.
Moonlight Mask = Gekko Kamen, a Japanese superhero character
who wears a turban with a moon-shaped ornament pinned to it
You look like Moonlight Mask.
Why aren't you riding your motorcycle?
Don't call me Moonlight Mask!
Stick out your hands.
Do it!
You told me to; it's your fault.
Right! You're my witnesses, right?
We're "peers", right?
Evil bastard!
What's a barbarian like him
doing at our elite school?
You, four-eyes!
What's with the rebellious look?
Got a problem, book worm?
What's all the racket?
- How horrible!
- Saotome, don't come near.
Here's that deluded
bourgeois girl again.
Don't take that tone with Saotome.
I don't care what you call me...
but I won't let you insult her!
What gives, coke-bottle eyes?
You got the hots for this chick?
Iwashimizu.
I...
It's been exactly six months since...
Iwashimizu sent a shivering love letter.
I know you met your first love,
your knight in shining armour, at an early age.
So please don't get me wrong.
I'm not asking anything from you.
So... we don't have to go steady?
No, I'm not saying that
we don't have to date.
You do wanna go steady?
No, I'm not aggressively asking that.
You're not, are you?
- So you're not...
- Yes, I am!
Honestly, I'm asking for you.
Asking for me?!
What are you asking for?
- Nothing indecent.
- You'd better not be.
We're still in high school,
you know.
Of course; I've never had
unclean thoughts.
Indecent thoughts are unthinkable.
I've never had them!
So what should I do?
Be your lovely self.
And as your lovely self...
I will live for that.
I, Iwashimizu Hiroshi...
will die for you.
I love you
oh so much
so truly
I love you
to the end of time
As long as the sun shines in the sky
You and I, you and I
We are one
I love you
As long as the sun shines in the sky
Your heart
I love you
Your eyes
to the end of time
As long as the sun shines in the sky
You and I, you and I
As long as I live
I love you
As long as the sun shines in the sky
Hey, four-eyes!
I'm talking to you.
Don't think you're cool,
you four-eyed book worm.
- Stop calling me that.
- What?
Stop calling me four-eyes.
My glasses...
are a part of my face.
That makes no sense.
I'm President of the Student Council...
I'm Iwashimizu Hiroshi.
I won't resort to violence.
But, if you demand a duel...
- to protect peace at this school,
I accept. - Make up your mind.
Makoto, trying to solve everything
with violence isn't right.
Do you know him?
I more than know him...
I'm the one who asked my father to
let Makoto attend our school.
What's going on, Saotome-kun?
I want you to lead a proper life.
Enough bullshit, Missy.
It's the truth.
The arrogance of the rich
makes me vomit.
This is...
my sincerity towards you.
Sincerity? Don't make me laugh.
Saotome-kun!
I don't care if your father asked me...
- I can't overlook his horrible violence!
- Headmaster...
I have an obligation to rehabilitate him.
Obligation? What kind of obligation?
In the past, he instigated violence
many times in Nagano and got expelled.
There's a reason why he's like this.
Like you really know me!
Actually, Makoto...
has a good heart. A warm heart.
He's hopeless scum, who can't be helped.
Why go to the trouble?
Why?
Only one reason why she'd
help scum like me...
- What?
- This Missy...
is downright crazy about me.
Basically...
she loves me.
- Fools have such wild imaginations.
- Takes one to know one. - Enough nonsense...
Turn him over to the police.
Headmaster, please stop.
He speaks the truth.
What are you saying?
I...
I love Makoto.
Since the day we pledged
to swear on our lives
such beautiful memories
have remained for me
Back then, when we saw
the same flower
our hearts both said
it was beautiful
But now our hearts no longer
reach out to each other
Bring back that loving feeling
one more time.
The sky filled with the singing of
red dragon flies has not
changed at all
Back then, we always used to
chase the setting sun forever
But now our hearts no longer
reach out to each other
Bring back that loving feeling
one more time
Like standing alone in the
vast wilderness
without knowing why,
tears well up in my eyes
Back then, even when
the wind shifted
our hearts both said
we won't change
But now our hearts no longer
reach out to each other
Bring back that loving feeling
one more time
You moved me.
You and your resolution.
Makoto-san...
you really are a kind person.
You know it. And if I'm going to lead
a proper life, I need something.
For you to rehabilitate yourself...
- I'll do anything.
- Really?
Give me money.
Your apartment and school tuition...
and necessary living expenses were
paid for by my family.
Bon app?tit.
I put two eggs in.
Too extravagant?
This plain shirt will look good on you.
Will you demand more money?
If I work part time to pay for expenses,
I won't have time to study.
You want me to be proper,
right? Ai...
What do you do?
How cold...
Father, Mother, I'm home.
Did that "problem child"
make a fresh start?
He won't change right away,
but in time...
Your father and his influence
moved political mountains.
Never forget his razzle-dazzle freed that
scum into your elite school.
That's a bit explanatory, Mother.
Let's celebrate like real bourgeois.
Cheers!
But...
The hydrangea flower,
like the palm of my tiny hand
Wiping off the tears,
we were both hurt
You showed me how to live for love
You were born
at the break of dawn
A train crossing blocking our way,
I know my way
But as it went go or stop,
I stood still that summer
It's not your first time
Live for love, love to live
Live as you are,
how strong we are
Live for love, love to live
Be as you are,
how strong we are
You got that right, so right
So, so right
The days we spent
For love, yes, for love
This world is mine
It's for love, yes, for love
Nothing can stop us,
I'm taking you along
To our future,
a beautiful rainbow
With you it's able,
the wonderful world of love
Still, I am fulfilled
And my expensive whiskey is
For love, yes, for love
And our glamorous chandelier
Heaven is where we're meant to be.
C'mon and ride with me
Blessings from God,
The wonderful world of love
Still, I am fulfilled.
You got that right, so right
So, so right
Live for love!
I can't ask my parents
for more money.
CAFÉ PURITY
There's no other way.
I'll do it for him.
WAITRESS WANTED
STUDENT HANDBOOK
My beloved Makoto...
NO PART-TIME JOBS ALLOWED
Who needs rules?
May I come in?
You're cute.
You smell nice.
This is a normal cafe, right?
What would you do...
if it wasn't?
So, it's...
It's?
It's...
- It's...
- Don't!
Saotome-kun.
Don't do it.
Don't.
Welcome!
She's up for it.
She's down for it.
Here she comes.
How cute. You new?
Yes.
- Tell me your number.
- When do you get off?
Bite the bullet.
I can take it.
Saotome-kun...
Why... why go this far?
If I'm doing this for Makoto,
this shouldn't faze me.
To make him change...
you have to taste the
same pain as his.
Who you talking to?
Sorry.
I couldn't bear the customers'
indecent behaviour.
What! It's only talk.
- You in high school?
- Huh?
Beat it, kid.
- I'm a paying customer.
- Watch your mouth.
Teach this kid some manners.
Get fucked, you yakuza wannabe!
- What the fuck, you asshole!
- You're the asshole.
Your goose is cooked!
I can't cover for your brush
with the police.
I never asked you to.
You disgust me!
Whilst you were partying...
Saotome was...
for you, she was...
- Come on, let's go.
- Now dance.
See for yourself.
She's lowered herself...
for you.
Go, girl!
Please stop.
I can't.
Aren't you going to help her?
Taiga-kun!
You wised up yet?
I'm home.
Ai.
Sit down, child.
What's with the scary face?
I don't remember raising you
to be such a delinquent.
What do you mean?
You know damn well!
Today, Taiga Makoto paid
us a visit.
What? He did?
Why?
Your daughter is working
part-time at a cafe.
That's nonsense.
How rude can you be?
What's this?
How'd these get here?
As he handed me those,
what do you think he said?
Pay me 1 million yen
to keep my mouth shut.
Pay you?
People will talk when they hear...
your daughter broke the school rules
and is working at a cafe.
- You're lying.
- It's no lie.
That boy is... evil.
Call it hush money or severance pay.
It was the straw that broke
the camel's back!
I had Taiga Makoto...
expelled from school!
Expelled? Where is he now?
We sent him to be with his kind.
"His kind"?
But why?
HANAZONO TRADE SCHOOL
Among plant life,
green-coloured plants...
use sunlight to convert CO2
into organic matter.
This new kid's got some nerve.
Tell him that...
paying his respects to me, Gumko,
is how Hanazono operates.
No baseball during class.
"Gumko"?
Did you just... laugh?
With a face like yours,
every day is Halloween!
Do you know who you're tangling with?
I got a thought...
Maybe he doesn't know
because he's new?
For your info, she's called Gumko
'cause she chews gum.
You listening?!
You better wise up!
- You loud-mouthed bitches!
- The new kid's done for!
If you...
defy me, it means you're
defying our whole gang!
Your bark is worse than your bite.
What do you think you're doing?!
Stop it!
Stop messing around.
I'll stab you!
Do it and she'll be road-kill.
He's got Gumko!
He saw her underwear!
Ask me nicely.
Another troublemaker has transferred in.
Their gang leader will have
a field day with this.
You okay?
Your leader?
You stupid or what?
I got no time for brain-dead
chicks like you.
If you resist...
you'll die.
Bring it on, anytime.
What the fuck!
Shit!
We'll bash his brains in!
What a man...
You don't know when to quit.
- There's a taboo word with
our leader. - What gives?
If you don't say it,
you might be allowed to pass.
Like I give a damn.
What? What, girl?
Eyes forward!
- What're you doing?
- You all right?
This is the boys' bathroom.
Actually, it's the girls'.
Hide.
My bad.
What blooms red is a poppy
What blooms white is a lily
But how should I bloom?
Dreams bloom at night
At age 15, 16 and 17
my life was dark and grim
No matter how grim the past was
Dreams bloom at night
Mark was yesterday
Tommy is today
Tomorrow will be George or Ken
Love is fleetingly transient
Dreams bloom at night
Neons blooming at night
are flowers of lies
Flying butterflies at night
Booze livens up the lies
Dreams bloom at night
I'm not the type to look ahead
I'm not the type to look behind
When I look away,
I see only tears
Dreams bloom at night
About anything and everything,
I was a fool
Bur I've got no regrets
All those men were unforgettable
Dreams bloom at night
Who might you be?
Takahari Yuki.
SAD CHICK
Tell me why!
Well?
I got...
a disease that makes me
look like an old man.
I don't follow.
This old man's disease is frightening...
and the disease has spread fast.
I think you might be wrong.
Gonta, you haven't changed
since the 8th grade.
I'd say you're getting younger.
Your wig is the problem.
You can tell it's a wig?
It's not your style.
I envy your youth.
What's your business?
It's Yuki.
What's happened to my Yuki?
Iwashimizu-kun!
What are you doing on my property?
Saotome Ai.
Wherefore art thou Ai?
Never thought about it.
Want to study for midterm exams?
Since you go to Hanazono, you know
your way around Kabukicho, right?
- The red-light district?
- Gimme the grand tour.
I don't know my way around. Sorry.
What's a smart girl like you
doing at a school like that?
I'm not that smart.
Why are you going to that
brain-dead school?
You calling us brain-dead?
Yo, pretty boy.
A few words, will ya.
- Makoto-kun.
- Don't worry about me.
Glad you're back to...
your normal self.
- Hello.
- Welcome.
I heard you were first in the class
for the pre-midterm exams.
To defend my position at all costs,
I must study very hard.
Ai, you'll have to try harder.
But what's the point of trying harder?
What's the point of trying harder?
So you can attend a good college.
But why attend a good college?
- Well...
- To open up possibilities.
Possibilities? What possibilities?
Ones to make you even happier.
All this for little old me?
We want to enjoy seeing
a punk like you scream.
Now we'll make him pay!
How do you define happiness?
What is it?
Well, it's...
making someone you love happy.
That's the best happiness.
I have to go out.
I've got a bad feeling that
won't go away.
Stop, Makoto-san!
Why're you here?
- No more violence.
- Shut up.
I beg you!
Don't hurt anyone else!
Get off my back!
Look at yourself.
You're hurt, too.
Don't you think you've done enough?
It's time I spelled it out...
your very existence is annoying.
Never show your face again.
- I'll take your word for it.
- Four-eyes...
never show your face, either.
My pleasure.
Let's go.
He'll only cause you trouble.
I don't blame him for hating me.
I know why you can't be real.
I know why you don't
want me around.
But I'll keep living for you.
That's my atonement to you.
Have it your way.
I never ever cry
There's no limit to my burning life
Grasping on tightly to the sun
I'm the storm that come again
Sing, Ken! Shout, Ken!
Reach as far as the sun
Swim, Ken! Jump, Ken!
Run, Wolf Boy Ken!
I'm always vigorously brave
I'm strong; you can't break me.
Never letting go of the planet
I'm the storm that come again
Sing, Ken! Shout, Ken!
Reach as far as the sun
Swim, Ken! Jump, Ken!
Run, Wolf Boy Ken!
What gives, old man!
How'd you know about my disease?
Makoto-san!
That's one scary dude.
Yuki babe!
Yuki babe...
Dammit!
My Yuki's in a tiff 'cause of you.
- No fighting!
- Let me go.
Makoto-san!
Don't!
Don't...!
- Stop!
- Enough, you bitch!
Thought you'd be more fun...
How lame.
Where are you going?
- Maybe to see Makoto?
- Wrong!
I wasn't going to visit him
in the hospital.
I don't even like him! I don't want to
miss my chance to beat him up!
She's outta her mind.
That should do it.
Oops, I'd better get to class.
Makoto-san, I'll see you tonight.
Makoto-kun, you're awake?
Do you remember yesterday?
That dude was unreal.
So he's the Hanazono High
gang leader?
I don't know about such things.
What's wrong?
Don't! You need rest.
I can't just sit here and do nothing.
At least wait until this IV is done.
Hey, Masa!
Where's Taiga's room?
Get out here!
You been messing with Yuki again?
- So what if I was?
- You're dead meat!
Makoto-kun...
Where are you going like that?
It's that famous Monkey-Crab battle.
A monkey kills a crab...
but the crab spits out some
babies before dying.
The monkey is a bad guy...
so the babies ask a chestnut, a bee,
a cow pie and a large mortar for help.
They call out the monkey
and beat him up.
Finally, the mortar crushes him.
All's well that ends well.
The monkey is dead.
But this folk story has a catch...
One of them was behind it all.
The true bad boy was...
the cow pie.
The real villain.
Of all the characters,
what would you be?
What do you want to be?
The mortar.
You for real?
The mortar?
- Gonta-san!
- What?
- I didn't say anything.
- I'm gonna kill Taiga Makoto!
Tell me why!
Cow pie!
Something wrong, Saotome?
I got a bad feeling.
Makoto's in danger.
Why don't you wake up and
smell the green tea?
Something's wrong.
I can't live happily here.
My happiness...
rests with the person I love.
What are you going to do?
Saotome!
I'm joining your class from today.
I'm Saotome Ai.
Sit down there, please.
Ai-chan.
Saotome-kun.
Why are you going this far?
If you stay in that cesspool,
you'll be in danger.
I'm joining your class from now.
I'm Iwashimizu Hiroshi.
Sit down there, please.
Iwashimizu-kun!
I can't let you be in danger.
I...
Iwashimizu Hiroshi,
will die for you...
Shut up, dork!
Pardon me.
If you're from Aobadai High, you must
know Taiga Makoto, right?
No, not really...
Actually, I do.
Leave the kid alone.
- What's wrong, Gumko?
- I said, leave him be.
So you have feelings for Makoto?
Stop joking!
Do you like Makoto?
- What?
- I'm friends with him...
- Saotome-kun!
- More than friends. To me...
he's special.
What does Makoto think of you?
He...
Makoto-san...
surely thinks Ifm his...
Makoto doesn't think anything of her.
She's my...
Hush up, four-eyes.
- Yeah, can it, four-eyes.
- Stick to studying.
Make fun of my glasses and...
they'll make you cry!
In what context?
If you think about it,
why did Makoto switch to this school?
There's a reason.
And why did he come to Tokyo?
I...
don't understand that, either.
What happened with you two before?
Could you tell me?
It's my fault he's had an unhappy life.
It's true that I came to Tokyo
to get revenge...
To make the person
who messed up my life pay.
Pay how?
The only way possible...
With violence!
And who messed up your life?
Stick with me and you'll find out.
Why are you so open with me?
Because... you seem like a sad chick.
I haven't heard that for a long while.
SAD CHICK
I thought we were compatible.
What's wrong?
I'm feeling horny.
Follow me.
Hurry up and bang me silly.
You really are a sad chick.
I need another drink.
Kill.
Gimme that.
It's cheap liquor,
but I'll take it.
What's the matter?
When men have something
they want to forget
When men feel helpless loneliness
When men are surrounded by pain
They drink to forget
Drink to forget
Wash your troubles away
Drink until you can't stand
Drink until you fall asleep
With time, you'll...
rest in peace
When women have something
they want to forget
When women feel helpless loneliness
When women are surrounded
by sorrow
They cry to forget
Cry to forget
Wash your troubles away
Cry until you can't stand
Cry until you fall asleep
With time, you'll...
rest in peace
A friend of yours?
She's a train wreck waiting to happen...
always in trouble with the law.
When she's on a binge,
the neighbourhood's at risk.
What? Don't you want
to drink with me?
- Beats me.
- What beats you?
- I'm the customer here!
- Who asked you?!
There she goes again.
Stay out of it.
Nothing good will come out
of helping her.
And don't come back!
I'll call the police!
See if I care!
Call the damn police!
She's the one who messed
up your life?
Who is she?
The woman who ditched me.
Everyone is accounted for.
Thanks for your trouble.
We brought her for you.
Show your face!
Says she's Makoto's girl.
The one from before.
No.
I love him,
but you're wrong.
You have a face that hasn't
seen an ounce of sadness.
Did Makoto do something forbidden
to our boss?
Use her as bait to get Taiga Makoto.
Yes!
And check into a bar maid...
she might be our trump card.
Yes!
Kinako, Satsuki, come with me.
He's more spineless and mushy
than I thought.
Taiga-kun!
- The shit's hit the fan!
- Cool, out, brainiac.
Saotome-kun has...
She's got nothing to do with me.
Yeah, she does.
She was abducted because of you.
The group you proclaimed war against
took her hostage, to lure you out.
- Hold on.
- What?
How'd the Hanazono girls catch Ai?
Maybe because she transferred
to Hanazono to be with you.
And me, too.
- You two... are whackjobs.
- Pardon your French!
If you and Miss Deluded hadn't come,
this wouldn't have happened.
- She wanted to help you.
- You're in a jam, not me.
True, but...
You said you'd die for her, right?
- Of course!
- Then go save her.
You'll win points with her.
More importantly, it's unwanted.
Don't leech onto me.
Watch your mouth!
She risked her future by quitting school
to chase after you.
That's what's unwanted!
She wants to make amends.
Says she's the one
who ruined your life.
So she gambled everything and
decided to live her life for you.
Get real. I don't have the
slightest grudge against her.
It's unwarranted.
I hate to admit it...
but it sounds like...
Love! Her sincere love for you.
The same love I have for her.
But she selflessly loves you.
You're out of your mind.
That love is greater than what
a mother feels for her child.
Please, don't leave.
I beg you.
Go save Saotome. Please!
You go save her.
I will die for her...
- If I die, it's worth it.
- Then go. - But...
even if I die trying,
it doesn't mean I will save her.
If I go and die,
it's mere self-indulgence.
My wish is that she be saved.
But I'm not the one...
who can save her.
But you can!
If I go save her...
she'll love me even more.
You cool with that?
My wish is not for my happiness...
it's for her happiness.
Go and save her.
Please!
- Got good news.
- What?
That bar maid...
she's Makoto's mum.
His mother?
- We could use her.
- Shall I snatch her?
- Go ahead.
- OK!
I'd like a word.
What?
I won't let anyone make fun of me.
I'll kill you.
You're not...
Are you surprised?
I'm the one who runs the show
at Hanazono High.
Makoto-san!
Why did you come to save me?
I didn't.
- Don't worry about me.
- Shut your mouth! - Oh, no! Help me!
She's a royal pain in the ass!
What do you hope to gain?
Anyone who makes fun of me...
has to pay the price.
You're sadder than before.
My personal story...
Takahara Yuki, Hanazono High senior.
When I was born...
I had no father...
Because my mother worked
at a soapland in Shinjuku.
But I...
was hardly a sad girl.
Mom only came home in the morning.
I always ate meals alone.
Stop!
Mom often came home drunk.
She often beat me.
But I learned to fight back...
and we beat each other to a pulp.
Mom started living with
a yakuza type.
He often made sexual advances...
so I stabbed him.
The police took me away...
and I lived apart from my mother.
The yakuza's boss...
felt sorry for me and cared for me.
Then, he adopted me.
I didn't want for money, but...
all my friends got scared...
and left me.
I told myself...
I'm not a sad girl!
- You think you're the saddest chick
in the world, eh? - Huh?
I'll show no mercy just
'cause you're girls.
- Makoto-san!
- Didn't you come to save her?
Thanks, Makoto!
You've done enough already.
About you being where I'm going...
- You don't have to be bashful.
- I'm not.
She's got the hots for you.
You're a pain in the ass.
Things would be easier without you.
Don't cry on me.
Oh, Makoto!
They're after your mother.
Hush up!
Forget about me;
save your mother.
She abandoned me.
Bust her up; see if I care.
- I'm sure she had her reasons.
- Stop with the sob story.
You don't know what they'll do to her.
Please go save her.
- We won't let him go.
- I won't go.
- But if you must go...
- He'll go! - I'm not going.
SULFURIC ACID
"Concentrated sulfuric..."
If you must leave, go ahead.
I'll burn her pretty face with acid.
I wasn't going from the start.
All this for me?
- I wasn't going to begin with.
- OK, then...
If you don't want me to burn her...
- then don't resist.
- You just wanna burn her, right?
Get him.
Makoto-san!
What's with you?
You'll let me burn her with acid?
I don't give a shit.
Have it your way.
How could you...
Oh, maybe if she...
if will undermine me as
a hostage and...
I'll get released sooner.
You are so self-centered.
- So that's your plan?
- No, that ain't it.
Shower me with acid anytime.
Then go save your mother,
Makoto-san.
Shut your trap!
You're messing things up!
I believe in you.
You're not the kind of man
who'd let his mother die.
Actually, you're...
a kind person.
Honestly...
Enough!
Sumire...
Give her what she wants.
Shit!
Get her.
Go!
Fuck me sidweways!
Who are you?
My bodyguard, who worships
the ground I walk on.
Not her bodyguard...
her love slave,
Zao Gonta, aged 17.
Gonta, kick his ass.
Stop!
Please, I beg you.
I'll do whatever you say.
Don't hurt him anymore.
Please!
Stop...
I don't care what happens to me.
I beg you.
Please stop.
What a good girl.
- Get off me!
- I won't leave you.
- Why go so far?
- You're my eternal hero.
To me, you're...
my knight in shining armour.
Come again?
Please spare him.
Take me instead...
I beg you, please.
What should I do, Yuki?
FIRST LOVE
Be happy in hell together.
Gonta... finish him off.
Oh man...
you look just like Moonlight Mask.
What?
Gonta!
Tell me why.
- You OK?
- I'm fine...
Compared to you,
my wounds are nothing.
Enough of your melodrama!
You'll never throw anything again.
Stop, Makoto-san.
Thank you.
Taiga-kun.
Saotome-kun.
- Get her to the hospital.
- Sure.
Where are you going?
You need to get to a hospital, too.
I've got something I have to do...
HANAZONO POLICE DEPARTMENT
Keep your nose clean.
Mind your own business.
It's her.
Gumko!
The boss and Gonta have...
- Are they hurt?
- Yes.
Only the man...
I fell in love with could do that.
It's about high time I...
Gumko!
If you spit out your gum,
you won't be Gumko anymore!
I'm going back to being a normal girl!
Until the day we meet again
Until the time we can see each other
I don't want to talk about
the reason why we broke up
For some reason, I'm simply lonely
For some reason, I'm simply empty
We both have hurt feelings
and will lose everything
Close the door together
Erase our names together
And then our hearts
will probably say something
Until the day we meet again
Until the time we can see each other
Wherever you are
Whatever you're doing
I don't want to know it
I don't want to hear it
We both have apprehensions
And we'll go back to
the way we were
Close the door together
Erase our names together
And then our hearts
will probably say something
Close the door together
Erase our names together
And then our hearts
will probably say something
I'm better off dead.
You wanna die?
Don't stop me.
I got no reason to live.
Leave me be!
Let me die!
I got no right to live.
I won't stop you.
I won't, so keep quiet.
Let's go down together.
I want to check out, too.
I'll die with you.
- You... crazy or something?
- Crazy?
My unhappy life made me this way.
Dad's going to be home soon.
Go to the bath house with him.
Are... you serious?
You might struggle,
but don't worry...
I'll hold you down.
Stop! Stop it!
I don't wanna die!
Let me go!
Hold still!
I don't wanna die alone.
- Help! Somebody, help!
- Go quietly.
I don't wanna die.
Don't wanna die.
Don't you want to die?
Help me, Makoto.
Help, Makoto!
Help me!
Your mother doesn't want to die!
You oaf!
What's with you?!
People who taste the fear of death
can never try suicide again, so they say.
Take care of yourself.
Leave me be.
My plan was to die with you...
But at the bitter end,
you called out my name.
I changed my mind... Mother.
See you around.
I can't figure out why,
but what we want
is always surrounded by worries
Your halting habits
I thought were just mine
How foolish I was
After how long?
A woman knows how to love
A man throws love away
Dreaming dreams inside a dream
and walking on
How do you feel?
How's Makoto?
Not just trying to impress him,
So many endearing things
I'm sorry, Iwashimizu-kun.
I want to fall in love
Don't know why you left me behind
He's coming.
Taiga Makoto will come.
Scout's honour.
I was arrogant and selfish
Without any light
With no end in sight
Me, knows how to love
Without any light
With no end in sight
You throw love away
Never focusing on the answers,
and drifting along
Innocent girl inside a mother
The wind unwrapping her hair
The first day he knew her name
Took a lifetime's worth of heartbeats
Speeding our love,
gentle at times
If that's your desire,
that I am with smiles
If you refuse, I'm in a fix
Dodging lies
A dying skyscraper
Sadness of a sky with no power lines
No need to cry about
Night or day, rain or sun
Autumn or winter,
spring or summer
All in a place where
Love and faith are in harmony
Ai and Makoto's fantasy
After how long?
A woman knows how to love
A man throws love away
Dreaming dreams inside a dream
and walking along
Finding love within love
You came for me.
I'm not fooling myself, right?
Hey, you.
You live in that big villa.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't cry.
What's your name?
I'm Saotome Ai.
- I'll carry you. - But...
If I knew you were rich,
I'd have punched you.
This is what the rich do.
Keep this a secret from now on.
It's uncool to get hurt saving a girl.
Tell anyone and I'll bust you up!
Satoshi Tsumabuki - Makoto Taiga
Emi Takei - Saotome Ai
Takumi Saitoh - Hiroshi Iwashimizu
Ito Ono - Takahara Yuki
Sakura Ando - Gumko
Ken Maeda - Aobadai Teacher
Masachika Ichimura - Ai's Father
Yo Hitoto - Ai's mother
Yo Kimiko - Makoto's mother
Tsuyoshi Ihara - Zao Gonta
Seishiro Kato - Young Makoto
English subtitles by Christian Storms
Yo Hitoto and Takeshi Kobayashi Songs - Lyric Subtitles by Ken Masui
Subtitles transcribed & retimed
by lordretsudo
Executive Producers: Shinichiro Inoue & Yasushi Shiina
Hiroyuki Ikeda, Osamu Fujioka, Shigeyuki Endo, Takashi Hirajo,
Toshiaki Okuno, Hiroyasu Asami, Naoya Kinoshita, Hidehiro Ito, Yoshitaka Hori
Produced by
Tsutomu Tsuchikawa & Hidehiro Ito
Producers:
Takayuki Sugisaki, Masamitsu Washizu,
Misako Saka, Mika Yamazaki
Based on the manga "AITOMAKOTO"
by Ikki Kajiwara & Takumi Nagayasu,
originally published by KODANSHA Ltd.
Planning Co-operation:
Atsuko Takamori & Fukuko Nagayasu
Screenplay by
Takayuki Takuma
Music by Takeshi Kobayashi
Choreographer:
Papaya Suzuki
Director of Photography:
Nobuyasu Kita (J.S.C.)
Lighting Director:
Yoshimi Watabe
Sound Recording:
Jun Nakamura
Production Designer:
Yuji Hayashida
Set Decorator:
Akira Sakamoto
Editor:
Kenji Yamashita
Sound Effects:
Kenji Shibasaki
Assistant Director:
Fumiaki Kato
Special Co-operation:
Hisao Maki
An EXCELLENT FILMS / OLM Production
Presented by Kadokawa Pictures, Happinet,
TOEI, TV Asahi, OLM, NTT DOCOMO,
KINOSHITA, EXCELLENT FILMS, Concept Films, HoriPro
Directed by
Takashi Miike
(c) 2012 "Ai to Makoto" Film Partners