Come and live your life.
Quench your thirst.
This moment won’t come
• again. Don’t miss it.
You’ve to make your dreams come true.
Don’t fear as your friends
are with you.
All the best.
There are joy and sorrow too.
Friends, this is the real life.
If you confront difficulties
you’ll get success.
Don’t fear as your friends
are with you.
All the best.
How are you, Mary?
—-As you see me. I
Stay like this. -Who
is it, Mary?
Mr. Chutala.
Hello, sister-in-law.I
-Hello. How are you?
Take offering. -Ok.
Wow! I’m pleased.
I always say to Mr. Dharam that
Kapur family is the best.
Where is Veer? -Veer, Mr. Chautala is here.
Take pocket money from Mr. Dharam. -Thank you. I
It's one lakh.
• Is brother in Africa or I travelling? -He’s in Africa.
He was in hospital before.
What happened to brother
-Nothing.
Acutally his empIoye .Iiedto him about...I
..his sister’s marriage
to take loan.
Actually he wanted to perform
nose job operation.
Mr. Dharam found out and broke his nose.
And then took him to hospitaI.
I’ve to go. Bye. -Bye.
Mayl go? -If you don’t go how
•wiII you come next month.
That’s true. Bye.
Sir. Sir, Insure your nose.
Why? -Did you hear if your lied is caught..
..your brother will break your nose?
Mary, without lie I can’t even
— pay your salary. Got it?
That’s right. But why lie for2 years.
Get married.
Meet madam’s father and
— get married. Simple.
What should I say to dad? Meet
struggler Veer Kapur.
He takes pocket money
— from his brother..
..Iying about our marriage.
And now he wants to marry me.
Don’t worry. Once my band is
— set, everything will be fit. —
I just need some luck.
Oh God! This won’t stop.
Oh God!Janvi.
Janvi. Janvi. HeIp.
What happened, Rachel? -This
treadmill won’t stop.
Don’t panic. It’s so easy.
No. -Come on, guys.
Careful.
Oh! -Are you ok.
This isn’t treadmill I but suicide machine
All the buttons aren’t working.
•i know. Ididn’t fix I it on purpose. -Why?
Look, you run for 3 kilometers
daily. -Yes.
But today you’ve done
4.7 kilometers.
Yes, but..
• The guideline of our gym is more you run the more you lose.
Shut up, Pinto.
Come on. Don’t lose time, lose weight. Back to the machine.
I’ll just come.
What are you thinkin sir? Join Chopra gym.
I give 2 months guarantee of
• my best fitness trainer.
But.. -There is one tagline of our gym.
Life is a cycle. Get, set, go.
Help! Help!
Very good, Peter. Do it again.
Madam, I’m going by what you’re
saying, not by what I see.
It’s ok. You sign.
Madam, handle of pulley broke.
Take one year fee from him. -Ok.
Buy a seconnd hand handIe.
Second hand handle. How many second hand things should I buy?
Even in market I’m calle
second hand.
Even second hand girls approach
me with proposals.
Janvi, help. -Look, second hand.. Pinto, help them.
Prem, where are you?
Prem, where.. -At your feet, love.
Prem, your ancestor’s out-dated
gym is running me nuts.
Now what? -Madam, even the pulley of handle broke now.
Shut up, Pinto. Go
•away. -Strange.I
It seems I married this
— old gym, not you.
Not a single machine operates properly.
Is my work to fooI
•aII my clients?
Janvi, fooling has become
part of our lives.
Look at Chautala.-Hi.-Hi.
From January to December he’s fooled every month.
You got the notch. It was the onlything Ieftto fit. ___
Wow! The car is ready.
Looking awesome, Prem.
Nice.-One minute.
You bought this cylinder with your pocket money.
I knew it. Why do you aIways spend money.. -Janvi.
Prem too has rights on
— his pocket money.
Right, Prem? -Yes.
•It was my idea to say to his brother that they were married.
Prem, you always.. -Hi, guys.
Hi. -Hi, what’s up?
Hi, guys. -Cool. -Veer.
You got it. Got the ampIifier.
Of Roland. Thanks to your
pocket money, man.
Let’s jump. Come on.
Veer, mark my words.
When Dharam will know of this
lie, it’ll be very bad.
Not at all.
Everything will be fine
as I’ve got this.
Veer, wear this. This is
•Iucky stone for you.
Are you ok?
Bring a stone for him
too. -Whatever.
1. 2. 3.
Nice tune.-But it's of no use.
We’ve no lyrics for it.
• -Romantic lyrics.
It’s very easy for me. -Car mechanic will write songs.
Time for reality check, guys.
Prem didn’t woo meIike
— this. He’s very sly.
The more I see you, I feel..
..my heart beats only for you.
I see you everywhere.
I’ll always be with you.
The more I see you, I feel..
..my heart beats only for you.
What’s my fault if my heart fell for you?
For you I’ve forsaken
the world.
You’re my love, my world.
These moment are special
as we are together.
The more I see you, I feel..
..my heart beats only for you.
Move. Please. -Hey, guys.
Entry form for Goa fun fair has been submitted. -Wow.
All credit goes to him
-Awesome, dude.
Yes. -He has good connections.
Give me coffee.-Ok.
My time got wasted
•because of you.
Veer, Chris of Aura group was also there. We’ve to be careful.
We’ve to be careful. -Forget
it. We’ll see.
Look. Think of the devil
and devil is here.
Insolent. You ruined my shirt.
I’d to attend meeting. Ar you blind? -Sorry, sir.
Uncle, she’s apologizing.
So will this get cleaned?
It won’t get cleaned if you call her blind.
Shut up! Apologize after
— kicking a dog! Wow!
You mean.. which breed, sir?
What do you mean? I’m a dog’?
I was giving an example.
It’s a proverb.
Didn’t your father taught you
how to talk to elders.
Your mother must’ve taught you how to wash clothes. S1
Let it be. He’s old generation.
Ok. So this is your generation.
These bunchs of fools.
-Take it easy.
He’s laughing like a monkey
from british era.
And it’s hard to say if he’s a boyoragirI.
He’s made in China. He’ll be ruined within 2 days.
• I don’t know if he’s holding • guitar or guitar is holding him.
And you? You’re roaming with
a beard like a goat.
You showed perform before tribals.
And now we are going
to perform for.
..you as you look like tribal.
You mean I'm tribal?-Yes.
Hi, guys. Whom are you ragging?
Look.
Daddy. -Mummy!
Veer, what have you done?
He’s my father.
Dad, I’m so sorry.
I mean, I’m really very sorry. -Shut up. I
I didn’t know your choice was so low. -You’re insulting me.
So what?
Don’t just insult me.
— Abuse me too..
..hit me, but forgive me.
God!I can't stand him.
But dad, I love him. -Come on.
Prem, everything got ruined.
You want to solve your problem.
Go to Vidya’s house
and clean it.
Clean his father’
-No, his shirt.
Pal, I don’tthinkthatl shirt could be cleanedJ
Sorry, I.. -It’s ok. You didn’t know he was Vidya’s dad.
No. Idrank your glas
by mistake. Sorry.
It's Ok.
Prem, jf I don’t get married to Vidya..
..my lie will be caught.
Brother will break my nose and take me to hospital.
You know what, I deserve
this, Prem.
Even though a step-brother, he raised him as his real brother.
He supported me at every step.
Whatdidlgivein return?
To double my pocket money
I lied to him.
I feel like a failure.
You know what, I’m a faiIure.
I'm the worst failure.
Exhausted and beaten up.
I understand.
But I’m worse than you.
I’m a worthless chap.
When I was born, people said I was so naughty and cute..
..so my dad named me ‘Prem’(love) with love.
But he forgot that surname is Chopra.
Prem Chopra.
He died and left this for me.
Chopras 1956. Ancestral gym.
Janvi got stuck with it.
She’s busy every day without
saying a word.
Veer, you know why I want to make car? —
Tell me.
To fill Janvi’s life with happiness.
It’s empty..
Life isn’t so empty, Prem.
No, I was talking about
empty bottle.
Come to eat food. -What
did you cook?
Come.-Sauce.
Come quickly.
Guys, great news.
You want money. You’ve to race?
What do we have to
— steal and run?
No, man. There is illegal car race every Saturday in Kolwa.
Participate in it. You’II
•get5O if you bet5.
For 50 we've to bet 5.
Where will we get it? -There
• isamanyou can bet5.
But I’ve already taken loan from him. He’ll give you.
Who?-Tobu.-Tobu.
Tobu, forgive me. I couldn’t repay your money on time.
Tobu says he won’t forgive.
You’ll be punished.
-What punishment?
Tobu says you didn’t
listen to him..
..so your ears will be punished.
Ear?cut his ears.
No, if you cut my ear
— I’ll become blind.
How?
If you cut my ears, how
•will I wear glasses? —
Correct.
Sorry. Cut his ears.
No, forgive me. Brother
with guitar.
Help me. -Prem, do something.
-Come, Prem.
He’s our member. The second one..
..music player, has a solid bungalow.
Tobu. Tobu, I’ll play. Doitagain. I
You’ve stolen my heart.
Don’t go away from me.
I got it.
Remix.
You've stolen..
Tobu says stop singing.
Tobu says.. what?
• Tobu says if you take 5 lakh I when and how will you return it.
Tobu, we’ll make 50 of 5 after winning the race with his car.
Tobu says, go to hell. You
• won’t get finance as..
.Tobu won’t bet money I on such junkcar.
Tobu. -What are you doing?
Mind your Ianguage!
Come, I’ll show you.
Look, special automatic
triple horse..
..power nitrogen engine car.
Tobu says where are the
rest of the cars.
Tobu this car has all
the qualities.
Come, I’ll show you.
People make formula car, I’ve made formula in car.
Look, nitro accelerator
zoom button.
When it’s pressed car will run faster than your gun.
Tobu, this car is an example in speed.
It’ll mint money once
it’s in race.
Goli, your boss is dancing in excitement after hearing it.
From head to toe..
Leg. His legs. Move it.
His Iegs!
Tobu says loan passed.
Will your nitro pump work? We’ve bet all the money.
Car will blast once this
• button is pressed.
Really? -Yes, just watch.
Ok. -I’ll organize my own
— race after this race
I’ll design all the cars of different concepts.
Good idea.
Itoo think of starting a music company.
Coffee series, like T-series. -Not bad.
Tobu, our car is in
— first position.
I’ve beat 5 Iakh from your side.
Today we’ll win jack pot. Sorry.
It’s runing smoothIy.
These donkeys turned out
• to be horses of derby.
Chris has moved ahead, Prem.
Press the button.
Ok, pal.;0]
Other cars are moving ahead.
Press the button. -I’ll.
5 Kilometers are left.
Press the button.
Not now.
4 Kilometers are left.
Prem.Press the button.
3 Kilometers are left.
1 kilometer is left, Prem.
Button.
Ok.
All the best!
Prem, really your car has blasted.
Chris has done it.
No.
Tobu says, pack your Iuggage.
But we’re not going anywhere.
You’ve to go. You’ve to
•evict the bungalow.
Why? We’ll return 5 Iakhs.
Not 5 but 10 lakh.
10 Iakh. Why?
Because of your words Tobu
• bet 5 Iakhs on your race.
And he lost.
But you bet the money.
Why will we pay?
Tobu says, you’ve to return. Or we’ll make pieces of you.
No. No.
We’ll return moneyj .in installments..l
Yes, it’s recession these days
We’ll return you 5 lakhs
in installment.
First installment, next year.
Yes. Tobu says, first installment next week.
Put ice.
It’s been one week, but we
• didn’t arrange 5 Iakhs.
Veer, tell brother Dharam to pay 5 lakh in advance.
Which lie should I say now2
— That I’ve adopted 5 kids.
Listen, sell your kidney] You’ll get 2.5 lakh. —‘
Funny. -Don’t mock him.
I’ll give you a better idea.
Goa carnival is starting
tomorrow.
We’ll make group and beg.
Foreingers will give
— alms in dollars.
-Funny. -What are you doing
Don’t worry. We got 5 Iakhs.
Wow! -What are you saying, Prem?
But for that you’ve
•toleaveyour..
..bungalow and stay in my house.
Prem, please be serious.
I’m not joking.
• You’ll get 5 lakh deposit to give this house on rent. -Rent?
No, no.;0]
If brother find it out..
Did your brother learnt about I your fake marriage for 2 years?1
But what about Chautala who comes every year.
We’ll deal later with him. Don’t worry. Just relax.
But who is he?
What is he? -Correct your question. Ask who is he?
Who is he? -Raghunandas Govardhandas Vakawale.
I asked your name, not address.
Will you’ve something.
Black coffee.
Is it in any other color? -Blue.
Chosers can’t be beggars. Get it.
Bytheway, how many peopIe
live in this society?
Sir, this is a bungaIow.
You get 24 hours water supply.
-How do you know?
Coffee, sir. -Coffe..
Sir, I know this fellow.
He lies in drain after drinking
liquor in our colony.
What are you doing here? -He’ll
stay here now, Mary.
What? You’ll work here?
You’ll get me fired.
Sir, he can’t do any work.
He’ll a scum. I’ll hit him. -Mary.
He wants to rent our bungaIow.
He has won Zee Super lottery.
He?
Slumdog miIIionaire.
So should it fixed?
I consider
-Shut up!
Raghu, 5 Iakhs.
Take 2.5 Iakh now and remaining
when I come in the house.
My question was rig ht.
What is he?
How much time will it take?
Take it. -Come quickly.
Pack quickly. SD will be here with tempo.
Great! Your one idea has
changed his life.
Right. Prem’s latest idea changed Veer’s house.
It’s my fault?
Wait..
Take this. Slit your throat.
Are you mad? -Saw?
It my work to give idea. It’s
— uptohimtoacceptit.
You point fingers at me.
Because you always interfere.
Vidya, I’ve lots of work here.
I won't be able to leave.
You attend the meeting with the sponsors of our show.
Ok,I'll.
Hello.-Is Janvi there?
Wait.
It's Pinto.
Yes, Pinto. What happened?
Madam, boat fell on a cIient.
What? I’m coming.
What happened? -Your dad’s
— boat fell on some client.
You pack. I’ll be back.
Vidya, drop me. -Sure.
come.
Wait.
What are you doing?
As per Vastu, you get good news
if phone is at north-west.
What? -For God’s sake, keep your knowledge to yourself.
Sorry. -She’s aIways..
Veer, I’m doing it for you.
And you.. Come, Janvi. -Vidya.
I don’t want to talk to you.
— -Vidya, I was kidding.
Vidya, I was kidding. -Shut up!
Darling. -Get lost.
I don’t want to talk to you.
Hello. -Hello.
Guess who?- Guess who?
'Guess who doesn't live here.
Dharam (religion).
I’m Hindu by reIigion.
Is this 2667712?
Kapur’s house. -No, this is his phone number. •
What the..
Can I talk to Veer please ? -Veer or please..
This is Dharam Kapur
Veer’s brother.
Hello.
Hello.Whos is it? -Veer.
• Brother, what a pleasant surprise? -Can you hear me.
Of course. The line
is very clear.
Long distance call.. -It’s
• not long distance. —
I’m 5 kilometers away.
I’m speaking from Goa airport.
I was going to Lusoto
• from Singapore.
Because of technical reason
I’d to land in Goa.
It’s 2 hours halt. So l’m coming to meet you..
..and specially Vidya.
Come. -Hello, Prem.
What should I say?
-Can you hear me?
Tell him you’ll be stuck in traffic.
You'll be struck in traffic.
There is one way. Come
•to airport with Vidya.
Ok.-It's disconnected
She left in anger. What will I do? Have you gone mad.
Phone her. Apologize to her and take her. Here..
Yes. -Simple. -Yes.
Hi, sweetheart. DarIing.
Are you still angry?
Sir. Sir, a lose character boy is calling me darling on phone.
What? -Yes!
You scum.
This is Vidya’s phone.
I was talking.
What will we do now? She left the phone.
Idea. Brother hasn’t seen Vidya.
No.
Take Mary as Vidya.
Prem, she’s a maid.
So what? Didn’t you
• heard the song..
shower flowers for my mer-maid.
Funny, Prem. Very funny.
Brother Dharam has come to
— Goa and you’re kidding.
What?
Sir Dharam is in Goa.
It's means he will come here.
What will he do if he doesn’t see madam Vidya at home.
What are you doing?
What will we say if he asks?
What will you say he if asks
why Gopi lives here?
How dare you race? What will you do..
..if he asks.
It’s not easy. His lie of
marriage will be exposed. -Mary.
His brother will won’t spare
us. Listen to me
All the best, sir.
Prem, think of something
or we’re finished.
Idea.-Tell me.
I’ll change get up I and become Vidya
But I’ve told brother that I’v
married a beautiful girl.
So you change get up and become Vidya.
Be serious.
Prem, think of something.
Its here-Idea!
No, airport. Right.
Prem.
One more idea!
•We’II say Vidya is kidnapped I and they want I million ransom.
If your brother pays, Tobu’s
— problem will be solved.
Kidnap? Ransom? He’ll
leave flight.
And we’ll be in more problem.
You’re giving third class ideas.
Can’t you think of something better?
I can't see but see.-Look
All the best!
Veer- Brother.
How are you? -I’m fine.
How are you?
Brother, he’s my.. -Driver.
No, my friend.
You befriended a driver.
I’m so proud of you,
• Veer. Anyway..
..teII me where is Vidya.
Brother, Vidya can’t..
You’ll say she’s missing. She’s been kidnapped.
Hey, make some other story.
I know Vidya is home and angry with me.
Yes, that’s true. Right, Veer?
Yes, she’s angry. She has all
• the reasons to be angry.
I  've not met her.
And I missed your wedding
for business.
We misssed too..
Your presence.
Anyway, let’s cut it.
And go for coffee. We’ve to
•catch up. -Yes, let’s go
Another aircraft is arranged from Singapore to Losoto.
Flight has to come from Mumbai
so it’ll take 4 hours.
We’re sorry.
4 hours deIay.
That’s great news.
Let's drink coffee -No!
We’ll go home and drink coffee
with Vidya. How’s that?
Get the car. I’N get my luggage.
Come on, boys. 4 hours
delay. What a..
He went to take luggage.
For your funeral.
Will the car come by itself?
I’ll get it, brother.
Prem, come. -Excuse me.
If brother goes home, I’ll
— end up in hospital.
Getthe car. I’ll think
• of something.
What willisay to him? -Go.
Mother. Mother, ballons.
She’s so cute. That’s the
— reason I miss India
I feel like kissing her.
It’s time.. What are you looking at?
It’s Rolex. OriginaI.
24 carats gold diamond studded.
It’s worth 2.5 lakhs.
Watches don't excite me.
Now that’s what Ical a hot super model.
What a piece!
I think it's new in market.
I never saw it before.
Bumpers are small, but headligthts are good.
I wish I could ride her.
What’s your name?
Prem. Prem Chopra.
Fantastic. It suits you.
Tell me, which fool answered
the phone at home?
I don't know.
Veer- Yes!
Which fool answered the phone at home?1
Prem.
Wait.
This is royal gift for the king of Yusoto.
Keep the luggage in.
We are finished.
Don’t worry.
Your wife will be arranged before you reach home.
How leave it me?
Go. All the best!
Chopra isn’t coming.
He has some work.
Coming.
Hello. -Hello, Mary.
Who is it? - Prem.
Sir Prem and sir Veer
went outside.
I'm Prem.
Sir, you were at airport.
Can’t I call from airport?
Sorry, sir. -Listen, wear sari.1 You’ve to become Vidya.
Veer’s wife. Brother Dharam
will be home soon.
Sir - Yes.
All the Best.
Hello, sir. Sir, I didn’t hear.
Door will open automatically.
Sorry, brother.
Sir Veer, what happened..
She’s your maid. -Yes, brother.
You can’t be wrong.
-You’re right.
I can recognize Vidya.
Vidya. -No..
Vidya. -Brother, actauIIy..
Relax, I’ll arrange your wife
•before you reach home.
Actually I.. -Actually you’re angry with me.
You should be.
Because I gave priorities to business rather than family.
I’m sorry for that.
Why are you apologizing’
It doesn’t look nice.
Actually, Vidya.. -It’s ok.
Chautala was right.
Kapoor family is the best.
Actually I’ve become
a family man.
Veer, well done. -Thank
you, brother.
Your pocket money will
be 2 Iakh now.
Just double. - Double.
Double- Double.
What happened?
You’ve a big heart. You didn’t
— give it a second thought.
I gave it a thought.
Anything for a friend.
Shower flowers on my mer-maid.
Not bad. Impressed without sari.
Brother.
Tell me, do you like the
bungalow? And how about Vidya?
Bungalow is mine.
And why should I talk to you about Vidya?
Vidya, get black tea.
Sure.
I’m talking to Vidya.
I’m talking to Vidya too.
Vidya. -Vidya.
Veer, is he cross-eyed?
He can’t see or hear properly.
She’s my Vidya.
Yes, P rem. She’s my Vidya.
She’s our Vidya.
Hey! -Leave me!
Leave me. -What’s with him’ -Brother, it’s panic attack. 1
What panic attack is it?
I think he's mad.
Mr. Dharam, it’s a disease.
He moves like wiper of car
• when he gets attack.
Brother, I’ll handle him. He has calmed down.
You.. -Sir, pIease.
I got him.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Everything is wrong. I made Mary your wife.
Exactly, your wife became my wife.
I’m talking about Mary not mywife. ‘
Yes, it happened as you wanted.
I told Mary on phone..
..to become your wife.
Prem, let this charade go on.
Brother, thought Janvi was Vidya and doubled my pocket money.
Our problems will be solved.
I don't care.
I saw how lustlull your brother
was at the airport.
Fool! He’ll do something
evil in..
..return of double pocket money.
It’s my wife. Janvi..
How could you? You made
me hyper wiper.
What could I do? He thought
IwasVidya.
So you should’ve told
him the truth.
I was about to, but he doubIed
Veer’s pocket money.
And he’s Veer. Your friend And he’s Veer’s brother. I
Look, don’t get involved! Dharam isn’t a good man.
Ok. When you spend Veer’s pocket
• money on your experiments..
..u call Veer your brother
and friend.
That’s fine, but.. -Look.
Veer has always helped us. Now it’s our turn.
It’s only for 4 hours.
Now take this tea. - No.
And behave nicely with him. Ok.
Remember. We’re doing
this for Veer.
Go now. - Now.
• Sir, sorry I couldn’t hear you on the phone. What did you say?
Iwas saying to slit yourj throat with the knife.1
Prem, go.
Why me?
Veer, tell me.. -Yes.
Why does Chopru live with you?
Brother, he has problem
of panic attack.
Doctor, told him to change
his surrounding.
So he shifted her for few days.
Listen, it’s dangerous to keep a lunatic at home.
Brother! - Brother!.
Black Tea.
Veer, who is she?
She.. she’s a girl.
I know that.But who is she?
What do you mean?
I mean, I’m Dharam, you’re
Veer and he’s mad.
Who is she?
I.. tell him she’s girlfriend.
His.
Mine.
Why is your girlfriend’s
•snap in this house?•
Can’t you control your girl friend?
I did.
But you messed everything.
-Really?
It’s surprising that even you
• can have a girl friend.
Why? Why not?
It’s possible.
Anyone can be mistaken.
Look, you’re insuIting
my girl friend.
Insult?
She was insulted when she
•became your girl friend.
Brother, leave it. Leave it.
Yes, leave it.
His girlfriend’s snap can
be in this house..
..but not Vidya’s.
It'll be somewhere around.
I’ve. Look, brother.
Veer, why is Vidya’s photo in his wallet?
Prem, how is Vidya’s photo
in your wallet?
Veer, how is Vidya’s photo in my wallet?
Dharam, this is Veer’s waIIet.
He send Prem to buy bread.
— He took the wallet. -Yes.
Give it me. What?
Yes.
You’ve no money even to buy bread. Disgusting.
Mr. Dharam, my time will also come. —
Do you see this. This
•is Rolex. Original.
You can’t get such time.
Buttell me, how did
— Vidya’s photo..
Dharam, geyser is on. Take bath.
Take bath, brother.
Yes go. on.
I'll take bath.
Veer. - Veer.
How did you like the room?
Room? This is a bungalow.
Listen, hurry up. My
•wife is pregnant.
I’ve to take to to hospital
any moment.
Congrats, Dhondu. ChiId
— is a father of woman.
Ok. Should I get the
— luggage? -Wait.
Let me put this first.
RGV. Raghunandandas Govardhandas
Vagawle.
Vagawl.
What are you doing?
This is my house. I can do anything. Who are you?•
Please heIp!
He'll kill me.
Please. How long will! you keep beating me’
Oh no! Don’t hit me. -What
happened, brother?
An idiot was putting his nameplate here.
Where did he go, brother? -Up.
You killed him.
No, he’s up there.
Prem.
You know him. - No.
It’s formal hi, hello. Hi. -Hi.
Hello. -What are you
•doing, upstairs?
This man hit me. - You!
Mr. Dharam, you’re rich so you’ll exploit poor.
This isn't fair.
No. Hey, you. -What?
Get down fool. - Don't hit me.
• I’ll explain it to • you. Come with me.
Please come.
Who is he?
Brother, Raghu is actually
mad. -What?
Yes, Raghu. Brother]
— Dharam is mad.
So we put extra sugar
in tea. -Why?
To digest bitter truth.
But how did it happen?
Once Raghu owned 6 bungalow
in this area.
He got addicted to betting
in cricket match.
Tell me.Listen.
You know the match of Yuvraj.
-Yes, 6 sixes on 6 baIls.
Brother had bet that he can’t hit six. -ReaIIy?
Then. Then What?
Every ball was out of boundary.
And Raghu lost all hisi bungalows in gambling.
And then over eneded there.
..n his madness started.
Now he thinks every bungalow
is his lost bungalow.
He chants bungalow all day.
I don’t know what he says.
It means this mad man is here, there, everywhere.
Brother, it’s dangerous.
It’s dangerous.
But doctor say that if he stays
*near this bungalow he might get cured.
Not all all. He should be sent to asylum.
That’s why we’re shifting
brother to Losoto.
Flight is in 4 hours.
But I came with the luggage in tempo.1
So shift. Rental with
— mental. Come.
Come. -No, he’ll break my denaI.
We’ll come after 4 hours.
Come. -We’ll catch up Iater.
Dhondu, God has made such
a big man crazy.
Let’s go.;0]
Where is the packing?
Where? - Don't shout.
Don't shoo me.- Where is the..
Talk softIy.
You got tempo. -Who are they?
They’re my friends.
Why did they come in tempo?
To get your luggage to airport.
One tempo for 2 bags.
So you needed 2 tempos.
Actually all these things will also go with your luggage.
Veer won’t let you go empty handed.
Whose idea was it of gifts?
Of Prem. - I knew it.
Veer. - Yes?
If you want to give me something..
..give me Vidya.
I’ll take Vidya along.
Will you come with me, Vidya?
You?
Hey!
Do you own her! How dare
•you touch her! -What?
Brother, side please.
Go from middle.Go from middle.
Uninvited guest.
Go from middle.Get Lost.
get out. get out.
What is this?. Go. Go.
You too go. -Prem. Prem.
Prem, let’s go. Prem move.
What happened to him.
Another panic attack.
I’ll see him.
You wait here.
Not even in a mall...
..so many people don’t come
as in your bungalow.
We will take him out
for shopping.
We’ll take his luggage also and leave him to airport directly.
But who will convinc
him to go out?
I’ll talk to him.-Wait. Not you.
I'll do this.
I hope Veer isn’t irritating you?
If yes then this is my personal
number, call me.
There is no need of that.
Veer is a good husband.-You
look forward.
Why? I’m not driving.
Then why are you looking back?
-I’m keeping an eye.
On what? -Cars coming
from behind.
someone shouldn't knock us.
There is rear view mirror.
But I’m free then wha
— need of mirror?
Sit properly. Don’t
— take tension.
Why? Who will take care of him?
Mr. Dharam, actually Prem
• is so attached to you..
..that he’s taking care of you.
That’s why he’s Iooking
•at you. -Oh my God!
Dindayal protects me so much.
Who is Dindayal? Your
security man?
No. My doberman.
Prem, look forward.
Coffee. -Thank you.
Prem, not coffee.. Doctor Verma has warned you. I
Dr. verma is our common doctor.
Yes.
Hello. Yes Renuka aunty.
Yes.One minute.
Call for you.
Hello. Yes, aunty. How are you?
Veer.-Yes.
Don’t you feel odd.
Odd. Why, brother?
Vidya’s phone on Prem’s
cell. Isn’t it odd?
Brother, we’re getting calls
on phone. I mean..
..itwill be odd when we get fax on phone.
Why didn’t call for Vidya came on your phone?
I think network.
-Network is full.
Full network.
This is Veer’s phone.
They’re identical sets.
— It was by mistake.
This is mine.
In Losoto military coup is announced.
There is curfew imposed.
And king Bumbata is under house arrest.
Authorities.. -King Bumbata.
Losoto’s king. My friend.
Its ok, brother, I’m sure everything will be fine.
Control yourself, Mr. Dharam.
Vidya, my friend.. -Leave her.
I mean leave this. Let’s
go to airport.
You’re right.
because of curfew in lostso..
..all flights to Losot are cancelled for now.
Now the.. -How could it happen?
How did this happen?
How will I go there? -How
will he go there?
It’s a big problem. -Yes.
Veer.-Veer.-Veer.
Janvi. I mean Vidya.
Brother won’t go. Brother.
Brother, you won’t go. -No, I won’t.•
Prem!Brother will be here.
Brother won’t go. Brother won’t go.
Brother won’t go
I didn’t knew that he loves me a lot.
Don’t worry about the expenses
of chartered plane
What! Even Charter Plane
can’t land there?
No. You’ve to do something.
You’re the captain of ship. Can’t you go to Losoto.
Sandhu transport.
Sir, by road can we go to Losoto.
Leave this.I found the route.
That's fantastic.
I’ve talked with agent.
Ferrywill take him at 6 from Kolba beach..
Losoto.
Zanzibar island.
Helicopter from Zanzibar
will take him to..
Losoto.-Wait a minute.
Tangayanaka bridge.
From there, train wiII
take him to,..
Losoto. -Wait, guys.
Goragora crator. -From there..
..he’II go to..
Now say Losoto. -Losoto.
And how many days it will take.
Yes, it will take 6 days. -What?
If we leave today.
If he’ll leave tommorow
then 7 days.
Why are you looking
— atmelikethis?..
Oh, you’re thinking that
— it will be expensive.
But what’s a big deal for him?
He's rich.
Veer.-Yes.
An astrologer told me..
..I'll kill someday..
..someone one day.
And unfortunately the victim is from Goa.
And his name’s initials
are P andIi
Who? Yes, Priyanka Chopra.
Oh. Excuse me please.
Mary.;0]
We don’t have any idea when Dharam will go.
You go to my house and bring some clothes for me and Prem.
Ok, Janvi. Ok?
Sorry, madam Vidya.
Thanks.
Don’t be siIIy.
Wait.-Hello.
Hey Red chili. -What?
Go and call your bosses.
I beg your pardon.
What pardon?
Tell them that his father
is in garden.
Look, if you give respecti
you take respect.
Ok. You give me respect..
..I'll take it.
Oh! God he touched me.
Someone help me. -What’s
going on? -Sir.
Sir, this man touched me from here to here.
Who are you ?
Me? Goli (tabIet).
Were you a capsule when
you were born?
Hey, you don’t know me.
People die when I breathe.
Then chose a good mouth fresher.
You’re mocking me.
Mummy!.
Dhondu, move the tempo.
Forgive me.
You fool.-Brother.
Goli.Brother Goli.
You know him.
Only formally. Hi. Hello.
2 minutes. We were going
to come. Take out.
Take 2.5 lakhs.
Rest of the money. -We’ll
— pay in half an hour.
What’s going on? Who is he?
They..;0]
Am I inquiry office to answer all the time. You answer him.
Brother, he came for donation
for sponsorship.
Sponsorship. -For a cricket tournament.
It’s GPL just like IPL.
GPL. -Goa premier league.
Yes. -He looks like a goon.
Don’t judge a book by its cover.
Why do you know onIy such kind of peopIe?
Sir, insure your nose.
Go. -Go. -Insure your nose.
Tobu will be banging
glass there.
How will we pay 2.5 lakhs
— within half an hour.
Tobu says..
..where is tie?
Tie on jeans and T-shirt?
-It won’t look nice.
Where is maid?-Maid.
There is a big problem
•of maid these days.
You want for small chores
or for whole day.
Tie.
Biscuits.
God! Oh mercy!
Tobu says, 2.5.
You mean 2.5. -Tobu give us some time.
Veer.
I’ve 2.5 Iakhs. Why didn’t you tell me?
I mean I’ve no money
— but something..
..which is like expect
• the unexpected.
It’s rolex. OriginaI. Worth 2.5 Iakh.
You stole my brother’s watch.
You want watch on
•your brother’s..
..wrist or heads on our shoulders. —
Heads.- Good.
It's Rolex.
Original. 24 carat gold, diamond
studded. Water proof.
300.- 2.5 Lakh.
Tobu says, remaining 5 Iakh..
..after 2 days.
If we don’t pay him 5 Iakhs
we are finished.
Think. -I’ll come up
•with something.
Trust God. -Why are
• you so relaxed?
Mary. -Sir.
Did you see my watch? -Watch?
Rolex?-Yes
Round - Yes.
Diamond-studded? -Yes.
-I didn’t see it.
Vidya, did you see my watch?
No, Mr. Dharam. -Veer.
I don’t know. -Strange.
How could it just disappear?
-Brother.—-------J
What’s the time? -How can
I say without watch?
That’s right. But what’s the time.
I’ve watch if you want
to check time.
It’s not expensive but shows correct time
Janvi, you know what?
We got sponsors for our show.
Veer, listen.
You know what?
We got sponsors for our show.
Our dream will come true.
Oh my God.
Brother.-Oh God!
What’s going on, Veer?
When did you come, 1II brother Dharam?
Didn’t you recognize her? Prem’s snap.
He’s my Janvi.
If she’s your girl friend, why did she kiss Prem?
What drama is going on?
It's about a drama.-drama?
Actually their musical group
is playing a culture.
On 26th January. She
•was rehearsing it.
She starts anytime. Let me
— say action first, silly.
But I don’t think she was acting.
But acting has to be original.
I mean she’s so talented.
-Thank God.
I thought something eIse.
Thank God. You didn’t think
of something else.
Tell me, what’s the name of the play?
Yours is mine and mine..
Yours is mine.
Lets rehearse-Ok.
wait.
Such a cheap name.
On 26th January you should
— play a patriotic theme.
Love. Sacrifice. Country. -Yes.
It has all these things.
You can see love.
His dad drinks country liquor.
And I’m making sacrifice.
I’m the producer.
He has no money to buy bread,
• but has become producer.
Anyway..
Veer, kiss was in the script.
And you kissed her.
No love, no emotions.
There should be a build up.
Brother, I didn’t get it.
No? I’ll explain.
Move.-Let it be.
Move. -It’s okay
-Wait a minute.
Brother has experience
-Come here.
Cue.
We got sponsor of our show.. -What?
Our dream will come true.
Oh my God. -What?
Anyway, let it be. Dear..
Dream shouldn’t be just woven.
Dream should make us sleepless.
That’s rig ht.
Brother.
Yes. What is it? -Your
— phone is ringing.
Where? -In your pocket.
Losoto.
Brother crossed the
— Iimitthistime.
Now you understood..
..how it feels when someone else uses your credit card?
Tell me what’s going on.
Dharam came suddenly
and thought I was..
..Vidya and doubled the pocket money.
In short, I’m Vidya now..
..and you Janvi. -Yes.
And before new problem
arise, go.
Please go. -Don’t worry.
It's 2.
And Venus is vertical. Ther
won’t be any problem.
Vidya, please. Go. HelloI
sister-in-law.
How are you, my Veer?
Brother Prem. Sister-in-law Janvi. What’s going on?
Where is Mr. Dharam?
Brother left for Losoto.
How could he?
Without any prior notice.
Mad has gone. Dhondu shift.
My prayer has been answered.
Owner is in the bungalow.
Do you get it? -ShouId
— I get the Iuggage?
Justchill.-Whoarethey?
They’re.. -Prem’s friends.
Oh! How do you do?
Well. -Ragunanddas Govardhandas
Vag havle.
Dhondu.
I’m owner of the bungaIow.
He’s psychiatrist.
He doesnot seem to be.
Should I get the luggage?
Dhondu. -Just chill. -Flight
didn’t resume.
But how could it be? Mr. Dharam..
Bye, Veer. -Bye.
Chautala.
When did you come? -Mr. Dharam..
..u are home, but they said..
..u left to Losoto.
What is this mad man doing here?
Vidya, come here.
Sir, she’s sister-in-law Janvi.
Mary, you too come here.
Sir, she’s sister-in-law Janv.
She’s sister-in-law Vidya.
Are you mad?
She’s Vidya. -Yes.
A mad man thinks everyone
else is mad.
All amd man look alike.
Sir, don’t confuse me.
Are you a riddle..
..to confuse you more.
No. WeII done, doctor.
Good treatment.
You! He’s not a doctor, idiot.
Correct.
This sofa isn't sofa and ..
..door isn't door.
This pant isn’t pant.
He’s not Ajay Devgan. -Quiet.
He's not a doctor.
I'm new man.-Get out.
Veer, get him out. Janvi, come here.
Sir, she’s not Janvi.
Should I get the luggage.
— -Just chill, Dhondu.
Sir, are you going mad?
What are you harping, ChautaIa?
That’s why you’re called, doctor..
..to treat lunatic. Right, Prem?
Veer, Veer!
Veer, he’s talking to you. Come on.
Get him out.
Come on. -Veer, tell me..
..y is Mr. Dharamcalling
Vidya as Janvi?
Mr. Chautala, you meet us
•on 5th of every month.
Yet you’re saying this. -5th.
I come on first of every month.
Chautala, what has happened to you?
You’ve even forgotten the dates?
He has lost his mind.
And she’s my Janvi.
That’s right, Prem.
And she’s myVidya.
She’s Mary. -Quiet.
Fool.
I’ll whack you now.
Fool.- Sir
He's not mad.You are mad.
I'm mad Chautala.-Yes.
I broke 4 teeth of my staff.
Ithink it’s yourturn now.
No. -Should I get the luggage?
Dhondu, just chill. -Ok.
Wait. You shouldnt’talk to doctor like this, brother.
Am I a doctor?
You’re a doctor? -You’re
•asking or telling me..
He’s telling you.
He has come for your treatment.
For your own good.
Just for your safety, boy.
Should I get the luggage?
Why does he hit me?
Sir, she’s Vidya.
I swear.
That’s what I’m saying.
She’s Vidya. -No.
I mean..- You are exhausted.
Me? -I mean you’re tired.
You need rest.
Got it.Rest.- Rest.
Look, tell me when the flight
resume. Ok? -Ok.
Go now.-Ok
Guys.
Hi, Vidya. -Hi. Vidya.
Hi. -Hi, Betty.
Hi. -Brother, she’s Betty.
Keyboard player of our band.
Hello, sir. -Hello. -Veer, we are getting late for the show.
Show. -It’s first performance
of our band.
Yes, let’s go. -Brother Dharam,
why don’t you join us?
Come. -Why not? I’d love to.
Shall we?
This rock is for you. All the best. In right pocket. —
Sovi, keep this rock
in your case.
What for? -You guys
— will really rock. —
Check the amps on stage.
I don’t want any goof ups. -Sure. -Where is Betty?
Veer.
What’s up, buddy?
Fantastic, sir.
This is a beautiful design.
Beautiful tatto for a beautiful woman.
Look at this deeds.
He’s putting tattoo as if..
..putting vermiIIion
— to get married.
Guys, get ready. You’re next.
Yes. -Veer, SD isn’t here.
What? Where is he? Has
someone called.
I tried. His cell phone is off.
Call him again.
What happened, guys?
-Brother, our drummer SD hasn’t showed up.
I’m here, guys.
SD, what the.. What happened?
How did it happen?
Chris of Auro band.
They were on car and I on bike.
They cut me purposeIy..
..and I lost my balance.
My hand is completely gone.
Without SD there is
•no performance.
I'll anounce it.
Guys, I’m afraid we..
We have bad news.
Our drummer has..
Rolling.
I want to touch the sky..
..n search for stars.
I want to shine like sun.
I want to adorn the earth.
I want to touch the sky..
..n search for stars.
I want to shine like sun.
I want to adorn the earth.
I’ll do whatever you say.
I’ll heed my heart if you say.
I’ll follow my heart
if you say.
Rolling!
Let me steal the light
of fire-flies.
I’ll spread light where there is darkness.
I'll steal color of flowers.
I’ll give them the colorlwant.
Let me steal the light
of fire-flies.
I’ll spread light where there is darkness.
I'll steal color of flowers.
I’ll give them the colorlwant.
I'll walk on air.
I’ll fly cars in air.
I’ll change days of month.
I’ll change months of years.
I’ll do whatever you say.
I’ll heed my heart if you say.
I’ll follow my heart
if you say.
Rolling!
V
And the winner is Rock..
Yes.-Yes.
Chris, your band got whacked.
Betty, I warn you.
Just cut the crap.
I’ll slap you.
You’ll raise hand on girl.
Talk to me.
SD.-Kid.
Your hand is broken.
Chris. -Want to get your leg broken?
Don’t cross your Iimit.
Tell me my Iimit.
Tell me. -Hey.
I’m Prem. Prem Chopra.
What are you doing? Threatening
or giving your bio-data.
Janvi, take him home.
Go. - Chriss.
Guys, chill.
We’re creative people
Stop fighting.
Control yourself. Come on.
Veer.
Change your name to ‘coward’.
What are you staring?
— Go home. -Come.
Play with toys.
Prem, what happened?
The way your car blew up..
..u too got scared..
— -Come, Prem.
Come.
And you know who is the biggest coward?
This - Veer's NRI brother.
Non-reacting Indian.
Do you’ve a family?
Why? -Who will take
— you to hospital? —
What? Making jokes, uncIe’?
I just got started joking.
I’m doing fighting for 30 years.
Hit him.
Oh no!- Dad is outside.
Bye, Janvi. -Ok, bye.
Wait, idiots. Don’t you’ve manners or etiquettes.
Janvi, I’ll drop you home. Veer, get out.
Dad, thank God you’re safe.
Inspector Walia phoned
and told..
..there was fig hting
• at your place.
Yes, but he was there.
He thrashed them.
They’ll be in hospital
for a month.
And the
— toMr.
credit goes Dharam.
Veer's elder brother.
The famous Mr. Dharam Kapur.
Thank you, sir.
You brought my daughter
safely home.
I’m pleased to see you.
Why?
No, I was giving an example.
An example. A proverb.
You know, dad, he dances very well.
He plays drum very weII. Mind-blowing. Superb.
Anyway, I’ll go and change.
Bye. -Bye.;0]
Ok, sir. Thank you very much. -Wait.
ldon’t know if I should say this.
But your daughter is
• going to marry.. —
..a boy who isn’t worthy of becoming your son-in-law.
You’re saying this.
What’s going on?
You’re getting criticized
because of him.
But my daughter says..
..he’s decent, upright..
..and down to earth.
You’re right. Down to earth.
He’s very IowIy.
Your daughte
— (love)
My daughter’s Prem (love)
isn’t right.
But what to do? - love is blind.
Actually, because of you..
..connection to Kapur’s famiIy..
..I thought..
I don’t blame you. Listen.
If you put horse’s shoe on donkey..
..don key won’t become horse.
If I could’ve my way..
..I’d drive him out of my house.
He’s not my own.
Step-brother. -What? -No.
Straight-forward .
I’ve seen straight-forward
man like you.
We don’t see such kind hearted man.
By the way, are you married. -Bachelor.
Oh! Muscular.
Popular. Spectacular.
And bachelor. -And I can also dance.
Why are they hugging?
Marriage is fixed. Congrats.
What are you saying?
Vidya will surely be
daughter-in-law of Kapur family.
What are you saying?
But wife of elder brother.
Good night, Veer. -Good
night, brother.
Good night, Vidya. -Good
Leave me. -Good night.
Hey! Why are you going there?
I’m scared to sleep alone.
Sleep with me. Come. -No.
I'm not so scared.
Good night. -Good night.
Come. When will this problem be solved?
God, when will my brother
go to Losoto.
Veer, Iwas thinking
• of something.
We've lied now.
But when you’ll marry Vidya..
..Mr. Dharam wiII find the truth.
Why are you scaring me, Janvi.
We'll think about it later.
Good night.
What are you doing? -Exercise
early morning..
..is good for healt -
-It’s late night.
There’s time to morning.
Late night.
What's the time?
You don’t have a watch.
Good night.
Coming. -No.
Vidya. -Prem, dad is admitted
in hospital. -What?
It’s you. -Prem, there is a problem. -What?
Vidya phoned. Her dad
is in hospital.
He got heart attack.
It had to happen. -What?
Your brother must’ve said
something worse.
Forget that. What should I do now?.
Go to hospital.
Veer, where are you going?
So late in the night.
Vi. Janvi’s father
•is in hospital.
Really? -Yes.
So he should go. Why
are you going?
Brother, if I go and Janvi’s
father sees me..
..his heart attack will become heart fail.
Correct.
You’ve said something right
— for the first time in life.
Veer, you go. All the
best. Ok? -Ok.
I’ll phone you.
Come.- Come.- No.
Meena, I’m not a rogue.
What? You’re in hospital.
Have patience, Meena.
Let me deliver the goods before
you deliver the baby.
Have patience. I’m coming.
I’m coming, dear.
Coming. -Dhondu. -What?
Tell your half-better? -What?
Just chill, Meena.
Yes. -Shut up, fool.
Dad, you can’t leave us.
-What are you doing?
No. -Dad, talk to me.
He has no problem.
He got breathing problem
because of gas.
Oh! Thank God.
Dad, you’re saved. -Help me.
I’m dead. I’ll di beca use of you.
Because of me. - This.
Move your leg from oxygen pipe.
Vidya, he’ll kill me like a fox. -Dad.
Don’t say fox. -l was giving an example.
It’s example. It’s proverb.
Dad. - Doctor.
Doctor.
He’s heart attack i
getting severe.
We need to move him
— into ICU. -What?
Get the stretcher. - Dad.
What happened? -Get out of here.
God, you scared me.
What are you doing here?
• -Icametomeetyou. I
Vidya’s dad got heart probIem.
He’s in Holy Care hospital. -Vidya.
Vidya. -God, it’s Mr. Dharam.
Open the door. -No, Prem.
You don’t worry. I’ll handle him. -Open the door, Vidya.
Coming. Coming. -Vidya.
What happened? Wh
•are you shouting?
That.. Lizard. - Lizard?
There is a lizard in room.
I’m scared of it.
No problem. Sleep in my room.
I’ll sleep here. -No.
-l won’t hear a word.
Please go. -Mr. Dharam.
Go. -Go. - Mr. Dharam.
Look who are going in?
And you rented the house yet..
..you’re with a tern po driver outside.
Do you’ve any value?
Don't talk about value.
Don't shout.
Don’t shout at this poor man.
If you’ve guts go and see what’s happening inside.
Ok. I’m going to take risk.
But wait here. -Why?
Otherwise snake will kiss.
Janvi. -Veer, how is
— Vidya’s father.
He got worse after seeing me.
What? -What are you
— doing outside?
Where is prem?
I thought he was with you.
-He’s not with me.
If not with you, where is Prem?
‘You’re Prem Chopra’.
Veer! - Veer!
Veer! -Br, what happened?
This Prem Chopra..
..hugged me thinking IwasVidya.-What?
No. -You’re blinded by his friendship.
Actaully he wants Vidya.
Brother. -Bloody rapist.
Mr. Dharam, he’s not a rapist.
He.. he has disease of sleep walking.
Yes, brother. His panic attack..
I mean, this is its
— side effects. —
Look, he’s walking in sleep.
I'll check.
..when this knife will go in his stomach..
..and come out of his back
-No, Mr. Dharam.—J
I’ll see if he’s sleep walking..
..or something else. -Brother.
I knew it.
Brother, listen to me.
Brother, this is side effect
of panic attack.
Thief.
All mad man in this house.
Don’t go inside. Gentlemen
Dhondu.
Start the tempo.
Start. -What happened?
start.
Why did you stop? Drive, Dhondu.
You’re saying to drive. But
— nobody is behind us.
You’ve made me mad. -Nobody.
Yes. Don’t laugh.
Dondu -What? - just chill.
Stop this chiII.
Now stop your drama.
I’ll see them. Even that mad man.
That.- Dondu -What?
I go to teach Vasudha as you.
And what I say as you, she
thinks I’m saying it.
I say it.;0]
But that's me.
And you’re me. I mean I’m you.
What are you harping?
Come to the point.
If my child is born without a father..
I.”kill you.
.. II
Moving to and fro from
road to gate..
..my diesel is getting over.
Who is the new character
It's beacuase of that mad man..
Don’t shout, Dhondu, just chiII.
If that mad man comes out!
..your child’s birth..
..your death will be sure.
I’ll get that mad.. -Shut up.
Don't shout.
Yes? - What?
Are you scared?
They got scared when
•I shouted, Raghu.
Why are you scared, Dhondu.
You’re standing as
— if behind me..
You’re standing as if behind me, he’s.
Let me see.
Dhondu, get the tern po.
Raghu, my brother. My friend.
Come. Let's drink tea.
Brother, you know.. -Veer.
Driving away mad man can’t
cure his madness.
We shout explain to
him. -Correct.
Brother, he’s totally mad.
What? - Mad.
Look who is taIking?
I'll be back.
Don't leave me alone.
Raghu, how many spoons?
There is only one spoon. Give 2 spoonsful sugar.
Raghu.
Have you read Geeta? -Never.
Never. -I’ll tell you.
What have you got? -Tempo.
Right. It has my luggage.
-It’s mine.
I’m talking about knowledge.
KnowIedge.
Ok, repeat.
Look, Raghu..
..in Geeta it's written.
..what was yours yesterday
is mine today..
..and what is mine today willi be of someone else tomorrowJ
Got it.
It’s not so, silly.
Don't look there. - Listen to me.
What was yours yesterday
is mine today.
And it'll be mine.
..do you understand, kid.
It’s simple. Prem.
What is it? -Take it easy.
Take it easy. I’ll expIain.
Look, even daughter belongs
to someone else.
She has to go one day.
That’s why I say..
..what was yours is mine now..
..and what is mine will b of someone else. Got it?l
Wrong.
What was yours is mine now..
..and it'll be mine.
Mad. - Fool.
Are you crazy?
Move, mad. Are you crazy?
What was yours is mine now..
..and it'll be mine.
No. - No.
Dhondu, save him.
Stop. Wait. Should I get..
..the Iuggage.
Don't hit that kid.Talk to me.
He’s hitting us. -Get out.
For the first time death isn’t
moving towards us..
..but we’re moving towards death.
Why are you driving so sIowIy?
We’ve no money. What will we say to Tobu?
I'm here. Don't be tense.
I’m tense as you’re
here. -Relax.
Stop.
Tobu, please forgive us.
We tried a lot, but we couIdn’t
arrange the money.
Please Veer.
Let me talk. - Tobu come.
We’ve no money, but..
..we’ve something to make
you our debtors.
Expect the unexpected.
Move.
This is royal gift for
— king of Losoto.
Prem.
You stole king’s gift.
What will brother say? -Veer.
You want to see this gift
• in king’s treasure..
on our Iders
Head.
Diamonds, gems.
Pearl harbour. Black Diamond.
Treasure. Everything.
Brother Prem says so you
don’t need to ask.
Everything is in it. Open it.
It’s lemon pickle.
It’s not pickIe.
Does anyone give pickle
asgiftto king?
It must’ve hidden diamonds
to evade customs.
He’s right. This belongs
to my brother.
This isn’t lemon pickle.
I said so.
It has carrot and raddish too.
Tabu says pickle is nice.
It would’ve been better if you’d brought bread too.
Not bread. We’ll chop you.
Tobu says..
..if you don’t give money
within 2 days..
..we’ll seize your bungalow
worth millions.
And for fooling us with pickle..
..we’II punish you now.
Tobu is very wicked.
He took our clothes too.
It’s because of your foolishness. -What?
Mine? - Yes.
He bought cheap shirts
and trousers.
Wefooled him of million
of rupees.
What are you doing here?
Sorry. -Run away.
It’s not about money, but your judgement.
Because of your creative ideas..
..there are more problems
in my life.
Was your dad photographer. -Why?
You always think so negative.
Don't be tense. - I'm here.
I’ve many creative ideas.
I don't care.
Why are you barking?
Dharam is there.
..who isn’t going to Losoto.
Tobu has exposed our shorts.
And now you’re barking.
Dog, you’re barking from
inside the car..
..I’II come in and whack you.
Run, Veer.
You run. - You have teased him.
Can you believe it, Mrs. Lobo?
These days a person known
as Rapist Ranga..
..is raping beautiful girl becoming half naked.
Beautiful girls. -Yes.
Then we must take care.
-Yes. -Show me.
Yes.
Ranga. -Half naked.
Run. -HeIp.
Save Us.
Help me. -Someone help us.
Rapist. -Help us.
Hello, sir. -Please.
Mary, you’re a girI.
Like a family member.
-Thank you, sir.
That’s why I say..
..from today you’ll sleep
in my bedroom..
..and I’ll be in your .bedroom. -We..
He’s saying..
I’d to say it.
Because ‘Prem’(Iove) is between us.
What? - Love between us.
Sir, I’m a servant.
Prem. - Prem.
..doesn’t differentiate between rich and poor.
He can befall on anyone.
So now you’ll be in my bedroom.
Is that clear? - Yes.
Hello, Veer.
Now Mary will give you your pocket money.
What? Our Mary.
Now she’s not our Mary.
She's madam from maid.
Your brother will be with Mary tonight.
I’ve no time to Iisten
•to your rubbish!
I’m going to change.
He's shocked.
He doesn’t know he’s not
wearing anything.
What will he change?
Prem, saw the result of your third class idea.
You’re roaming in city half naked.
And you started stealing too.
First Mr. Dharam's watch.
Then king’s royal gift.
Not royal, it had pickle.
You don’t have to yell at me.
You said that we should
do this for Veer.
And..
Janvi- It's same.
Prem, stop.
Veer.
What happened?
Prem fled with Vidya.
Get the car.
He took the car.
Come.
What are you doing?
Dhondu.
What is this?
Prem, tell him.
He broke it.
Drive properIy.
Drive sIowIy.
Dhondu, stop.
Dhondu.
Dhondu, chair.
Shut up. -I didn’tsayaword.
Dhondu.
Raghu, chill.
I’m ruined. My Meena
•is in this hospital. •
Meena.
What happened to Janvi?
-I don’t know.
He famed while talking. -Prem.
Prem, this time you’ve
gone too far.
Actually, brother..
.Vidya got seriousIy
ill suddenly.
So prem.
Vidya was ill so..
..he should have told us.
How dare you touch her!
Congrats, she’s pregnant.
Why is it so peaceful here?
Why am I dumb-struck?
What has happened..
..even the season is new.
The earth and sky is
filled with joy.
Why is it so peaceful here?
Why am I dumb-struck?
What has happened..
..even the season is new.
The earth and sky is
filled with joy.
The ambience is new.
happened, how Wh1d I tell you? —
I never thought..
..joy will come with tears.
What are these moments.
..where we are afar even
though together?
WhyamIsoIoneIy?
Why do the world seem lonely?
Everything it upside down.
What's the matter?
Life is cross with me.
The ambience is new.
happened, how Wh1d I tell you? —
Thank God for..
..not sending friends with price tag.
Or I wouldn’t have been able
to afford you, friend.
You’re very priceless.
Now you’re talking sense.
I’m sorry.
For what?-You know
I’ve decided to tell brother the truth.
What are you saying, Veer?
I’m right, Janvi.
I mean, is it worth it? My friend, my sister-in-law..
..can’t enjoy important
joy of life.
I don’t care for such money.
You did so much for us.
This time.. -But this lie is proving costly now.
And what you’re doing is..
..can’t be repaid by me.
Favor. Repay. Such words
shouldn’t come between friendsi
That’s right, Prem.
We think of other’s benefit
in friendship.
Not taken advantage of. -Veer.
It’s all over. I’m going.
Mr. Dharam, you found out. -Yes.
Chautala, told me everything. -Yes.
Veer was going to tell you what Chautala told you.
Yes, brother. Forgive me.
I'd erred!- Err?
My flight to Losoto is resumed..
..so what’s your fault?
It’s his fault, brother.
He knew your flight is resumed.
But he wanted you to stay
for few more days.
How sweet, Veer!
Chautala, book a ticket
• after 2 days.. -No.
No.
It’s important for him to Ieave.
Control your emotion,
• not your brother.
Control.
Have a safe journey.
Come, sir. It’s time]
— forthe flight.
That’s ok. But I can’t
— go without gift.
Mary. -Sir. -Did you
— seethatgift?
Gift of King Bambata? -Yes.
That treasure box type? -Yes.
Rectangular shape?
-l didn’t see it.
Mr. Dharam, that day
a thief came..
..and might have stolen
your gift
Yes, it must be very expensive.
Diamonds.
Let’s go to police to lodge a complain.
We’ll get the thief caught. -No.
It’s important for me]
to go to Losoto.
Correct. -Take another gift.
Here. This will solve
• your problems.
Who are they?
Didn’t you recognize them?
They collect donations.
Hey, what is it?
Corect the question?
—Ask who they’re?—’
He’s Tobu. Remember, GPL.
He’s head boy of GPL. He’s dumb.
Tobu says when wiII
— you pay5lakh.
5 Lakh.
Hey, are you demanding donation
or extortion money.
All the best.
Go away. I’ll pay letter. Go.
Go. We will come.
.Brother.
Tobu says..
..Tobu creates war..
..echo of this sIap..
Tobu says..
Tobu can speak.
Tobu can speak. GoIi.
Hello. 1. 2. 3. 4.
1. 2. 3. 4.
Tobu can speak.
Sage! You’re a sage.
Your slap has magic.
You can make someone deaf
•or give voice to someone.
Sage, you’re great.
You're God! -Powerfull
You’re everything.
Sage. -How much wiII
•you say in a day?
I was dumb. Let me talk today.
One slap cured me.
I can speak.
My sage has worked magic.
Tobu can speak.
I waived your loan of 5 lakh.
Which loan?
Acutally.. -Let me talk, sage.
Sage, I can talk. Let me taIk.
They came to me to
— bet on car race. —
They took 5 Iakhs from me.
But they lost.
It was good. We got to meet.
You returned my voice..
..what can I give in return?
What can I give you, sage?
But I want to give you something.
Sage, take this Rolex from me.
Original 24 carat gold..
..studed with diamond.
Sage, don’t ask me about
other watches.
It has all the quaIities.
Sage.
Sage, they gave me this gift.
I returned it to you.
First installment of loan.
Veer, Rolex. How cheap!
Cheap! It’s cheap.
Wait -Wait.
Sage, take this. Another
return gift.
Second installment.
Barn bata gift.
Veer, who gave you the idea to race? -
Prem.
And loan? - Prem
Who stole the watch?
Prem.
And king’s gift? -Prem.
Who is the root cause of all the problems? -Prem.
Prem!- Where?
Save me.
Save me from bullets.
Who is throwing stones?
Come in front.
Tobu says, who is shooting?
Who threw stones?
It’s not stone, but buIIets.
That’s what I said. Who
•is throwing stones?
Oh!
Why are you mopping now, Prem?
Mary, why is doctor Iicking
•the ground? -Go away.
New dysentry in house.
Anyhow, send your fruit
• anywhere you want
I Don't care.
Iwantmydepositmoney.
Brother Prem, now I know why you’re hiding here.
Actually it has crossed
all limit.
ldon’t want to be in this bungalow now.
Return my money to me.
Brother Dharam.
I don’t want to live here I because of that mad man.
Why are you talking as
— ifhe’sbehindme.
Who gave the idea .of rent? -Prem.
Who took deposit of bungalow? -Prem.
Who said I was mad? -Prem
Who, will I kill? -just chill.
Don't.
Move. Let me hit too. Here.
Daddy. -Yes.
I accept I told you the
— truth that night..
..but to kill your son-in-law..
..u would have killed all of us.
How?
How can I shoot?
I’m leaving on medicines.
How can this dead man
— kill someone else?
Are you ghost?
I’m giving an exampIe.
I came as my daughter won’t
answer my phone.
I was getting worried.
I thought Veer eloped
with Vidya..
..and got married.
Hey! What are you saying?
Veer and Vidya ar already married.
No.It can't be.
No, dad. -You can’t
— do this, Vidya.
Fool, she’s Vidya.
I’m his dad. She’sI my daughter Vidya
Mr. Dharam, I’m Vidya.
Yes.
Veer’s girl friend. -What
You’re a girl friend of a married man.
No, Veer isn’t married.
Then who is married?
Mr. and Mrs. Prem Chopra.
Saw? She’s Vidya.
And she's Janvi!
And you were sending
me on leave.
Got It!
Doctor, just chill.
You fool!
Veer, why did you do it?
Brother, to increase my pocket money.
And please don’t ask who gave
• the idea of fake marriage
Whose was it? -‘You’re
Prem Chopra.’
Come here, Prem.
What?
Who is he? -He’s your brothe - You’re asking me.
Sage creates miracIe.
Sister-in-law, you’re here.
Your image is there.
Sage. -What’s going on?
She’s like Mrs. Chopra.
Yes, that’s why he used
— to be with my wife.
Just chill both are different.
Shut up.
What happened? -Bambata
is Losoto’s king.
She's his sister.
I can’t understand her language. -Ok.
What happened? Meaning.
His brother are firing bullets from outside.
On brother? Why? -But why?
What happened? Meaning.
They’re firing on sage..
..as before brother has..
Meaning.
Meaning. -In Tamil it means..
..in Telugu it’s..
Tell me means
in Hindi. -It pregnant. •
Pregnant.
This is a small story.
—-Tell us,sage.
I went to Losoto 3 months ago.
It was dark night. Behind
dark valley..
..I found Kututo.
Her magic worked on me.
Lightening never strike..
..the way it did that day.
Then what happened?
After that see.
Great, brother.
Your lie has surpassed
all my lies.
Prem Chopra name suits me.
Veer.
When a kid would cry in Losoto’s village..
..mother would say, go to sleep, child.I
Or your real father will come. Dharam Kapur.
Now I know why black is
• your favorite color.
Black suitcase.Black tea.
My sir is very lowly!
I agree. Come to my
• room to sleep.
You fool!He's muscular.
Popular. Spectular.
Womanizer. Vidya, Veer
is right for you.
Veer, come. -Yes. -Take
Vidya along.
Thank you, dad.
You were sending pickles for
• the pregnant lady, sage.
As you sow so you reap.
Sage..
This man should be..
Stop.
Meaning.
Nail. -Chill. Repeat.
It means, oh my God.
No. Meaning of what he said.
They want to kill you with me.
Why? -Why?
You downloaded Losoto's life.
Why should we be hanged? -Look..
..they don’t spare witness.
Sage..
Forget it. Just chiII.
You!
Meaning.
There is only one way
— to escape. -What?
I’ve to marry her.
Then do it.All the Best
Meaning.
It means.. -Wait. I’ll tell you.
Sage, please.
It means..
All the best.