In a palanquin, the bride...
is brought to her
husband's door
There'sjoy in the heart
A thousand dreams she dreams
In the palanquin...
I had to leave my husband's house,
after I died
But I had to leave nevertheless
In tender feet...
there are boils
On thorns, I have to tread
Spring has turned into autumn
In a palanquin...
For all the tears
my eyes shed...
I have been tormented too
What has God writ for me?
May none else have
a destiny like mine
My boatman is angry with me...
who will row the boat now?
In a palanquin...
Lakhaniya, take Nandu inside.
Good Lord! At such a young age,
his mother has died.
God has been very
unfair to you, Mahesh.
Who's that?
Coming from your in-laws' house?
- Yes.
A tattered state and a sunken face.
Something surely is fishy.
But uncle, who is she?
- You know Damodar Dayal...
who was fond of hymns?
She's his daughter.
Mother!
Pushpa, how come
you are here, dear?
What happened?
Did you have a quarrel?
I'll never go back there.
I'll stay here now. With you.
Are you mad?
Tell me, what happened?
Because I couldn't conceive,
he got married a second time.
What...?
- Yes, mother. I endured it all.
I was putting up with their
atrocities and staying there.
You shouldn't have left
your house like this, dear.
Your home is where your husband is.
I wanted to die there.
But I was compelled to come here.
I don't believe you.
It must be your fault too.
My only fault was that I stayed there
and endured their kicks and abuses.
And today...
Look.
- God!
Both of them hit me
with a burning stick.
And pushed me out of the house.
My child!
If you too refuse to keep me here,
where will I go?
I am myself living at
other people's mercy, dear.
How will I feed you?
- Don't worry, mother. I'll beg.
I'll find a job. But don't ask me
to return there, mother.
Please don't.
- Don't cry dear, don't.
Come on in. Come on.
Son, this time your wedding
should be held in pomp.
What are you saying, uncle Nepal?
Had Nandu not been so small...
I wouldn't remarry.
- Of course I know, but...
How come Pushpa
came out of your house?
Wrong! Why did she come here?
- To ask for a job.
Ajob? I know her in-laws very well.
They are well-off.
Something is fishy.
- Could be, I didn't ask.
Anyway, when is your marriage?
- On the 24th of this month.
Good! A quick engagement
and a quicker marriage.
Son, don't worry about
anything.
I'll arrange for everything.
Okay, I'll leave.
Come on!
You are feeling shy of me?
As a child, you used to
sit on my lap.
Wrong again. You used to
play in my arms, remember?
You've forgotten me? Why did you
go to Mahesh to ask for a job?
When Mahesh told me
I felt very bad.
With me around, you and
your mother are in trouble?
Bad! I'll give you a job.
You!
- Yes.
I have a vast business in Calcutta.
A land, a house!
But no one to look after it.
Whenever I go there...
I sweep the floor, cook the
food.
If you handle this, it'll
be beneficial to both of us.
But uncle, I...
- I'm saying it for your own good.
Or else, is there dearth of
servants in a city like Calcutta?
No! How can I leave
an old mother and go away?
Yes, that's your problem.
But I'm in no hurry.
Think and tell me.
But yourjob is fixed at my place.
Okay, I'll think it over
and tell you.
You! What is it?
Sister Mandira, will
you lend me some food grains?
Lend? Why don't you say
you've come to beg?
Take it that way. It's not for me.
I can stay hungry, but mother...
Go away! Leaving your husband,
aren't you ashamed to go begging?
It is a sin to even
look at you. Get lost!
You had been to my place, hadn't you?
Sister-in-law humiliated you?
No. When one has no respect,
how can he be humiliated?
Don't say that, Pushpa.
Here, keep this money.
But...
- Keep it.
Keep it.
Your timely help...
- Forget that, Pushpa.
We have to help each other.
I helped you and you...
- Meaning?
It is deserted across
the lake at dusk.
Aren't you ashamed?
You are like my elder brother.
By helping me, you want
to play with my honor? Shame on you!
You saw it with your own eyes?
- Yes! Uncle held her hand...
and gave her 100 rupees.
- Really?
Come with me.
Will you tell me
what happened?
Your girl trapped my brother-in-law
and took away money.
He saw it with
his own eyes, ask him.
Tell me, did you see or no?
- Yes, I did.
Couldn't you sate
your hunger by begging...
that you called your daughter
to trap others. Lowly woman!
Shut up! Be quiet, sister-in-law.
We are not cheap.
Your brother-in-law is!
- Shut up!
You wanton, shameless,
characterless whore!
Tell me, how much money did you take
from her brother-in-law? And why?
Mother!
- Don't dare call me mother.
Why didn't I die before
hearing all this because of you?
Mother! Mother, listen to me.
Get out of my sight.
You are a whore! Which is why
your husband threw you out.
Go away! Go and drown yourself!
My brother-in-law is cheap?
My foot!
Pushpa! Pushpa!
What is this? Oh God!
You are going to
commit suicide? Too bad.
Get up! Was I dead?
With me around if you are still in
trouble, it's a shame on me!
Come, let's go to Calcutta.
I told you girls to watch
a lot of films these days.
Nowadays people prefer film songs
to classical music.
But all of you have become lazy-bums.
- Auntie, greetings.
Mr Nepal, after a long time?
Please come in.
Auntie, I had been to my village.
Pushpa, come in.
Who is she?
- Pushpa.
She is from my village.
She's very unfortunate, the poor girl.
That's very sad! Come, my
dear.
Go...
Don't be afraid. Aunt has opened
this ashram for destitutes like you.
Yes, dear. This is
my musical institute.
Girls learn dance and
music here. Can you sing?
Aunt, she's a nightingale.
Her father was a great singer.
Is it?
- He taught her to sing.
Let the teacher come,
only he can judge her voice.
Aunt, when do I come?
- After a week.
Okay Pushpa, I must leave.
- Will... I stay here?
Yes! What else? If you consider aunt
as your mother and keep her happy...
all your sorrows
will be over, right?
Yes.
- Don't worry, I'll keep coming.
Aunt, take her.
- Come dear. This is your house now.
Sir...
Should I take you
to the jewel of this lane?
To Munnibai, come on.
Get lost! Don't you see,
he's educated?
Trap someone else for Munnibai.
Sir, come here.
You must've heard about Sushma.
Come on.
- Don't touch me.
What a dirty place
you have got me, eh?
When a passenger
tells me at this hour...
to take him anywhere,
I bring him here.
Disgusting! Let's go back.
The night has passed...
and Krishna has not arrived
Sleep does not come to me...
I get no sleep
The night has passed...
but Krishna has not arrived
Hey! Mr Anand!
Welcome, Mr Anand! You?
Didn't recognize me?
Please sing.
Why have you stopped?
Sing, dear.
Sing.
Krishna has forgotten the promise
he made
Like the lamp...
Radha keeps awake
I get no sleep...
the night is passing by...
and Shyam (Krishna)
has not arrived
Torn by separation...
she's madly in love
In heart and soul,
she thirsts...
her eyes brim with tears
She can't go to sleep...
the night passes by...
and Shyam does not arrive
Wow! You've turned this room
into a temple.
Whoever you are, the pain in your
voice can soothe any aggrieved heart.
Hear that, aunt? What could be
a better compliment than this?
Know who he is? Mr Anand, the richest
man in town, my old acquaintance.
She's very lucky. The first time
she has sung, and Mr Anand is here.
No. The magic in her voice
pulled me here.
Then come here every day, Mr Anand.
Pushpa's house is your house too.
Your name is Pushpa?
It should have been Meera.
Have a betel-leaf
from my hands sister-in-law.
A look at your rosy lips and Mahesh
will even forget his first wife.
Nandu, go to your new mother.
- Come.
Nandu, come soon.
Lalu, look, a birds' nest.
- I'll place it on the tree.
Why?
On the full moon night, the
mother bird will lay three eggs in it.
And we will play with her little ones!
- On the full moon night?
Yes.
- I won't be here.
Where are you going?
- To Calcutta. My new mother said...
we will stay there now.
- Then won't you come back?
No. Father has gone to look for
a house; we'll soon shift.
The house is nice.
But if the rent could be...
Sorry. Had this house been in
another locality, it would be double.
Besides, you'll use the furniture too.
- As you wish.
When are you coming?
- On the first.
Two months' advance?
- Sure.
I had got the receipt.
Hey! Brother Mahesh!
You...?
- Didn't recognize me? I'm Pushpa.
Who Pushpa?
- Great!
You forgot me? Your
foster-sister.
Remember? I had come to ask for
a job at your place?
Oh yes! But what are you doing here?
- I... come on in.
You'll get completely drenched.
- No, I'm in a hurry.
Let the rain stop. Come in.
Please.
Is everyone fine at home?
- Yes.
And your son Nandu?
He must have grown up.
Yes.
- Sit down, I'll come.
Oh, you are still standing?
Sit down. Have some sweets.
No. I won't eat anything.
- How can this be?
We've met after a long time.
Without eating...
No, no Pushpa
I'm in a hurry.
The rain has also stopped.
I'll take the evening train.
Going to the village?
- Yes.
One minute.
Give this fifty rupees
to my mother.
Your mother...?
- Yes.
I'm very worried about her.
So I keep sending her
some money or the other.
Through whom?
That... that Mr Nepal...
because of whose favors
I'm here today.
I keep sending something
or the other through him.
I can't face anyone in the
village.
Here. Give it to my mother.
Here, keep this money.
Perhaps I've come at the wrong time.
- No.
He is a distant cousin of mine
from the village, brother Mahesh.
Sorry, seeing the money in
your hand, I had misunderstood.
This is Pushpa's money.
- I'm sending it to my village.
Oh yes. You often
send money to your mother.
Keep it, you need
not send it anymore.
Why?
- Because your mother...
died long ago.
What? She's dead?
No one told me.
You are dead for
the villagers, Pushpa.
So it's futile giving you news
about a death.
I'll leave now. Good bye.
Don't cry, Pushpa. Whatever you are
today and wherever you are...
your tears of sorrow don't mean more
than just saline water.
So wipe your tears, Pushpa.
Yes... You are right, Mr
Anand.
You're right.
Sit down.
Here.
Let this be. Let's go out
today.
Where?
- We'll look for a place...
where we won't remember anything
at least for sometime.
Neither you nor me.
Come on.
A fire...
a raging fire...
the showers put out
A fire started by the rains...
who will extinguish?
Who will extinguish it?
A garden ravaged by autumn...
is restored by Spring
A garden ravaged by Spring...
who will restore?
Who will?
Do not ask...
how the temple
of my dreams crumbled
It hasn't to do with
strangers...
it's what my own dear ones
did to me
A wound inflicted by a foe...
a friend heals
When a friend inflicts a
wound...
who will help heal...?
There's no saying
what could have happened...
or what I might have done
I live, because I drink
If I didn't drink,
I'd die
When the world makes me
thirst...
wine quenches it
The thirst wine awakens...
who will quench?
I admit, there's little
one can do against a storm
But it isn't the waves
that are to blame...
it's something else
A boat caught midseas...
is steered to safety
by the boatman
But when the pilot
sinks the boat...
who can save it?
A raging fire...
Kamla, I'm going to the
market.
Keep my clothes ready. I'll go
to work as soon as I return.
Okay.
- Father, I'll also come.
No, son.
You've got to go to school.
Take him along. If I need
anything, he can bring it for me.
Okay, come on.
Pushpa, were you fighting
with your client last night?
Not at all. He was too drunk,
I had to forcibly send him home.
Aunt! Come in.
You're a strange girl.
Do you want him to worship you?
He does that, aunt.
- Whatever! I'll tell you the truth...
whether you like it or not.
If you keep spurning him,
you'll regret it all your life.
Don't give me sermons
early in the morning.
Here... Your commission.
You are a very sweet girl.
You never trouble me for money.
So girls, there was commotion
in your rooms last night?
We've kept your money, aunt.
Come and collect it.
Let's go.
See? How they walked away arrogantly.
As if I'm begging from them.
They spend thousands of rupees
on their cosmetics.
But when I ask for money, they
make faces. I'll go now and ask them!
Father, our house.
- Yes. Don't run! Careful!
You called me?
- Yes. You stay here?
Have you rented that house
there?
Come on, father.
- Hey! This is Nandu, isn't he?
How big he has grown!
I saw him when he was so small.
Take this home, Nandu.
- Okay.
He has grown so much.
Look, Pushpa. Don't
talk to me again.
Why, brother Mahesh?
Because the filthy atmosphere you
live in, is condemned by society.
And I live in society.
Meeting you or talking to you...
could give me a bad name.
So I don't want anyone to know
that I know you.
Hey you! Why are you peeping?
Naughty boy! It is you?
Hey, Nandu! Listen.
I say, open the door!
Shankar, what is the matter?
- She's not opening the door.
What's this commotion?
All hell has broken loose.
- What happened?
Shankar is standing outside
Durga's room with a dagger.
She's not opening the door.
- Where's aunt?
Aunt has gone out with the teacher.
Shankar is drunk, he'll kill Durga.
A drunken man is a coward,
let me see.
No! I won't let you go there.
Shankar is a dangerous man.
Sometimes one has to
take risks, Pushpa.
There is no thrill in life.
Let's see.
Dagger in hand and eyes
turned red with liquor.
And this modern pose
of classical dance.
You had to come back again
on earth, my Lord?
What?
- Give me the dagger please.
Give it to me.
Shame! What a small knife!
Where have you forgotten
your trident Lord Shiva?
What rubbish is that, sir.
- Didn't you understand?
Your name is Shankar
and you are Lord Shiva.
Actually you've mistaken
your concubine to be your wife...
who'll throw
open the doors for you.
Now tell me, how can country
liquor taste like sherbet?
What are you talking about?
Open the door, Durga.
Mr Anand is here. Don't be afraid.
Not at all!
Is anyone in?
Then why aren't you opening the door?
- My child is burning with fever...
he won't let me go.
Sir, please ask him to leave
today.
I understand!
Bitch, you've shut the door again?
- You're still high, Mr Shankar?
Is the child burning
with fever, yours?
Mine? No way!
I am not his father.
Whoever his father is,
but Durga is all yours.
Undoubtedly.
- Then her child is yours too.
Yes.
- If you love her...
go and fetch a doctor,
the child is not well.
Doctor? Durga is ill?
I'll get the doctor now.
- Lord Shiva!
Yes!
- Carry your trident, please.
Oh yes, I forgot.
Durga is ill.
The show is over.
Have you some booze...?
Great!
I was scared. What if
something had happened to you?
What has to happen, will
happen.
But man should get an
opportunity to become a hero.
Didn't you see how
I became a hero?
Make a drink quickly,
my kick is wasted.
Oh! Mr Anand!
Greetings! Sorry to disturb
you.
Don't feel bad.
How can you say such a thing?
How can you ever disturb us?
You are the owner of this
garden.
After all, you committed the sacred
act of bringing a decent girl here.
Had it not been for you
then who would bring...
this flower into this
wilderness?
You are embarrassing me.
- Am I?
I won't wait for long.
Pushpa, I'm going
to the village tomorrow.
Last time your mother
asked for another 50 rupees.
Mother?
Nepal babu...
- Yes?
While grazing, the cattle
do look up in the sky...
perhaps to thank the Lord.
But you must never
have looked up, have you?
Up! The Lord above.
Don't you have any fear
of Him at all?
I don't understand.
- You don't?
Come on out, I'll explain.
Pushpa has got to know.
- What?
Including the folks in the locality.
That her mother is dead.
So drop the curtain now,
the show is over.
Where are you off to?
Take this.
No.
- Take it.
Take it mister.
When you didn't feel ashamed
earlier, why must you today?
Till you live, continue
to rob people like this.
Go, Nepal babu. Go on!
Hey Nandu!
Coming from school?
- Yes.
Mother...
- What is it?
Give me some food.
- After some time.
I'm very hungry.
- I told you after some time!
Won't you have a bath, brother?
- Yes, go and bathe!
Should I go to the pond?
- Go anywhere. Don't chew my brains.
Mother, I'm hungry.
I'll give my darling boy now.
Come to me.
Mother, I'm back.
Now give me some food.
Don't you see I'm boiling
the clothes, can't you wait?
Give me anything, mother.
I'm very hungry!
Want a beating?
Wait for sometime or I will...
Is my darling boy still hungry?
Here, eat some more.
What was that?
What did you break?
What happened? What broke?
How did it break? Answer me!
Speak up! Now you've started
stealing and eating, eh?
What are you looking at me?
Get down!
Rascal! Scoundrel! Loafer!
You steal in the house?
Don't dare step in this room again.
I'll break your bones.
Get out! Out!
Nandu Babu, why are
you sitting here?
It is so late, won't you go
home?
No! The new mother will beat me.
- Why?
I broke the pickle jar.
I was very hungry.
Oh! You haven't eaten as yet?
Don't cry, son. Eat.
Eat some sweets. Open your
mouth.
Whenever you are hungry
come to me, will you?
But don't tell anyone.
Now don't cry.
Good boys never cry.
Wow! You have worn a nice
shirt.
Father bought it?
- Yes.
Whom are these samosas for?
- No! Don't!
Give me some!
- They're stale, my son.
I love samosas.
- Really?
Tomorrow I'll order
hot samosas for you.
Eat sweets today.
Here.
Take more.
And leave now.
- Why?
It's going to be evening.
Go home and study.
I do that in the morning
and play in the evening.
But you must leave, son.
You shouldn't stay any longer.
My guests will be here soon.
- Why? What will they do?
Nothing. But you must leave,
because I'm asking you to.
Who are they? Whom are you expecting?
Your brothers?
You won't understand.
Go on now and come soon tomorrow.
I'll get lots of samosas for you.
The whole day was really wasted.
We couldn't do anything.
No, we did. We learnt that the
man who just left...
was absolutely third-rate.
A rascal! Forget that!
Tell your wife to prepare tea.
Master, madam is not home.
Never mind. Prepare two cups of tea.
- Very well.
You sit. I'll change
the cover and come.
Listen... leave the cigarettes
here.
What's all this!
This servant is good-for-nothing.
Yes, sir?
- What's all this? Pick it up!
Listen! When I call you,
why don't you answer?
How will I, sir? You call
Balram, my name is Hariram.
Oh, yes! I forgot. But Mr Hariram,
Balram was your elder brother.
Whatever, he was a very nice man.
Very brave! People feared him.
You know, at dusk even he had
the habit of drinking liquor like me.
Understood, Mr Balram?
- Hariram, Master.
I'm sorry. Mr Hariram, I want
to change my clothes...
can I have a pajama?
- Right away, sir.
Where are... my slippers?
Hariram! Where are my slippers?
The pajama is wet, sir.
- What?
It is still wet.
Do I have only one pair
of pajama, Mr Hariram?
The rest of them are in the cupboard.
The keys are with madam.
So get me a dhoti.
Sir, I can't find the dhoti.
I searched high and low.
What are you saying, Hariram?
When Draupadi was being disrobed...
you provided an unlimited
number of saris.
And not a single dhoti for me?
Very bad!
Must be in the laundry.
- First prepare tea for me...
then go to the
laundry and fetch my dhoti.
You haven't changed
your cover as yet?
Do you know when we
change covers, friend?
When people love the book.
When its new edition
is released. But in this house...
I have become an old book.
Neither anyone wants
to look at it nor read it.
Sir, it's difficult to brew tea.
- Why?
The milk has curdled.
- Repair it.
How can I do that?
Do you know where
the mistress has gone?
Yes, to the saloon to set her
hair.
Saloon...? To set her hair?
Get two cups of tea from
the restaurant opposite.
No, let it be.
Come with me to my house,
it's nearby.
You know what you'll
get with tea? Puris,...
potato vegetable and hot halwa.
And my wife makes her hair
at home.
At home?
Look at me.
I have a house and I don't.
I have a wife and still I
don't.
Anand, shall I tell you
something? Don't feel offended.
You are responsible for all this.
However a wife is...
she wouldn't want her
husband to spend the night out.
A man can work
all day like a machine.
But when he returns home,
he wants something.
When he doesn't find it at home,
he looks for it outside.
Madam? Yes, sir is home.
It's madam.
Let it be? Okay?
It was madam. She said she will
go to the party from the saloon.
She'll be late.
- See that, brother?
I'm not the only one
who comes late at night.
Forget it. You won't understand.
As I said...
Go home now.
- Aren't you coming?
Me?
Some other day.
Sir, shall I get some tea?
- Will you really?
Forget it. Fetch my clothes.
- Sir, money?
My purse is on the table, take it.
- Okay.
Anita? Who's calling?
She's not at home.
She has gone to a party.
I don't know. She will be late.
I'm her husband.
Why? You felt bad?
Good day.
Welcome.
After searching high and low
I realized that...
in life there is sweetness
only in two places.
One at the sweet shop
and the other in your voice.
I've brought hot 'jalebies' for you.
- Sit down, I'll serve it in a plate.
No.
I don't like eating sweets.
I only love to watch it.
When you don't eat,
why do you bring it everyday?
I've got into the habit.
And I enjoy it.
You love savories, don't you?
- Yes.
Salty, hot and spicy...
which go in and
reduce everything to ashes.
Go... get the bottle.
Okay.
Listen.
Get some 'samosas'
and 'kachories' tomorrow.
Will you eat them?
I won't let you drink on an empty
stomach. I'll prepare something soon.
Listen.
Do you know to fry puris?
- Puris?
A potato dish and halwa...?
Can you prepare it?
- Will you eat all that?
Sure, I will. If you sit with me
and feed me with love.
I'll get it.
Mother has sent these for a wash.
- Keep it here.
Iron father's clothes and
send them tomorrow morning.
Greetings, sir.
Mr Natwarlal, a newspaper
is meant to be read...
and you use it to
hide your face?
Mr Anand! There's danger.
- Danger?
Yes, there's this Pathan after me.
- A Pathan?
Yes. I had borrowed money from
him.
And I thought you
are hiding from me.
From you? We are two sides
of the same coin, Mr Anand.
And besides, where coming
here is concerned...
I'm more shameless than you
are.
I must leave now.
- What is the hurry?
Mr Anand, Pyari and Dulari...
- Are they waiting for you?
Go on.
You're late, son.
My step-mother had sent me
to the washerman.
Will you have some hot samosas?
- Yes.
In a moment.
Eat this.
- Who's this young man?
This is Nandu. You had
met brother Mahesh,...
his elder son.
He stays right opposite.
Nandu loves samosas?
- Yes.
Have some more.
Okay, son. Come tomorrow.
Will you give me samosas
tomorrow as well?
Sure! Go now.
You love him a lot?
Anand babu,
how many children do you have?
None.
And wife?
- Well, she's indeed there.
An ideal housewife.
So why must you leave such an
ideal housewife and come here?
You are a decent man.
The more decent a man is
the more evil he can become.
I come here only to see to what extent
I can go in becoming evil.
Do... you... really...
come here for this?
Tell me something, Pushpa.
You are an ill-reputed woman.
Then why does a decent boy
like Nandu come here?
His is a different case.
His step-mother doesn't love him.
No one loves me either.
Don't say that.
- Which is why I come here.
Don't ever ask me why again.
Make a drink.
Where did you get the samosas from?
- From there!
There? Where's that!
The one who stays opposite...
she gave it to me.
Dirty scoundrel! Rascal!
Why did you go there?
Throw it away!
God help us! You eat
at her place? Dirty pig!
Why? What is it with her place?
- You don't have to know that.
If you go there again,
I'll break your legs!
Munni, stay with him.
Come on in, Raju!
Ashok Kumar's performance
in 'Sangram' was excellent.
I'm crazy about Dev Anand. I saw his
film and I kept dreaming about him.
Ashok Kumar and Dev Anand
get to become heroes.
I bought balcony tickets for you
and I became a zero?
You're unnecessarily getting angry.
- Of course.
You are our real
hero, Mr Natwarlal.
Mr Natwarlal, what if we had meet
your wife at the movies?
Mr Natwarlal, do you borrow money
from the moneylender?
I have to, bloody hell.
To come to your house, I've got to
go to the moneylender first.
You do have a sense of humor.
- Pyari, will you have 'Pani Puri'?
Please treat us.
- Don't be so cruel.
You just saw a film.
- So what?
You like the two of us.
I'll like you more
if you make me spend lesser.
We'll have just a little.
- Come on.
Hey vendor!
Make some 'Pani Puri'.
What difference will it make?
I'm doomed anyway.
You are giving only them?
Give me some too.
I'm the one who's paying you.
No... no tangy-water for me.
I'll be done for. I have the water.
I'll add my water. Fresh water.
Give me more.
- It's all over.
Over? Never mind.
Bloody hell!
My water's also over.
How much is that?
- Fifteen rupees, sir.
Fifteen? Never mind.
Bloody hell!
My pocket has been picked.
Whatever it is,
you'll have to pay me, mister.
Sure, I will.
Is there any money in your
purses?
It's empty.
- Empty?
What is your name?
Keep this.
- I don't drink, sir.
Who's asking you to drink?
I'm pawning it with you.
I'll get the money
tomorrow and release it.
Ladies, let's go.
Look I've got 'samosas'
and 'kachories' too.
Where is your son?
Is that meant to be a joke?
You're the one who's playing
a joke, Pushpa. On yourself.
Should I get it?
- No, later.
Give it to the one I got it
for.
Hasn't he come yet?
No.
Brother, you are going there?
I'll tell mother.
Mother, he is going there again!
- Nandu, you are going there again?
I wonder what spell that
prostitute has cast on you!
That witch is not ashamed of
spoiling respectable children.
Damn it! I am fed up!
That little boy has
made life miserable.
What is it all about?
Tell me.
There! There are tears
in your eyes again?
I've told you so
many times, Pushpa.
I can't bear to see tears.
Listen...
You are heading for
a deep, dark well, Pushpa.
But your thirst will not
quench, you'll be drowned.
Now what is left to
get drowned, Mr Anand?
There is!
If there wasn't, this Anand
would never have come to you.
He wouldn't give you
money every month.
Nor would he keep
you bedecked like this.
Honestly, Mr Anand.
I never thought...
I'd start
loving Nandu so much.
Like every woman I thought
I'd have a house too.
A husband, children.
But... nothing happened.
Nothing.
Mister, aren't you ashamed to
stay here with your wife?
I'm so ashamed that I have to
come and go on the sly.
You can do that.
But what do I do?
Because of these women,
I can't even step out of the house.
People will talk
It's for them to talk
Forget it, let's not spend the night
discussing such trivia
People will talk
It's for them to talk
Let's not spend the night
talking about such things
People will say things
It has been a norm
in the world
Every dawn ended in dusk
Who are you?
And what is it about you?
Even the chaste Sita
got a bad name here
So why does what people say...
bring tears your eyes?
Tongues will wag
It's for people to talk
Let not the night pass while
we discuss such worthless things
People will talk
There are those
who taunt me
They ask me, what vice
I'm immersed in
I've seen them too...
coming secretly to
these notorious lanes
This is true,
it's not a falsehood...
tell me, isn't it true?
People will say things
It's for people to talk
Let's not waste the night
discussing such rubbish
People will talk
It's like them to talk
No, Laxmi.
I don't want to stay here anymore.
Where will you go?
Wherever you go
people will taunt you.
I've asked him to look for a house
in a decent locality.
Of course!
Mr Anand is a rich man.
He can...
- Excuse me.
Is there a woman
named Pushpa here?
That's me.
I want to talk to you.
- Yes?
Here? Which is your room?
Follow me.
This is my room. Please sit
down.
Does Mr Anand come here?
Who are you?
- Does he or does he not? Answer me!
Lower your voice.
When I don't know you...
- Anand is my brother-in-law.
And my sister doesn't want him
to come here.
So why does she let him?
- He forcibly comes here.
When she can't stop him...
- I don't want to argue.
If my brother-in-law comes here,
please ask him to go back.
How will that help?
Will you be able to hold him back?
Besides, I'm not the only
one in this big city.
I care a damn for
how many of you there are.
I'm here only to tell you
to stop him! That's all!
I can't.
Why don't you say that
you suffer a loss?
You don't have a brother or a
son.
How will you understand
my sister's sorrow?
Money is your only....
- Hey you!
Why are you talking nonsense?
Who are you?
Mr Anand's relative.
With whom do you want
to form a relation here?
Mind your tongue!
- You mind your tongue!
He is shouting at us
in our house only!
Get out! Out!
Out!
- What are you doing, aunt?
Please go away.
I promise you...
Mr Anand will never come here again.
- I'll be highly obliged!
What have you done? At his
behest, you'll desert Anand?
I gave worrying about
separations...
...the day I came here, aunt.
- Why be so mad?
You won't understand, aunt.
Why are you crying?
For you.
Where were you yesterday?
Father and mother stop me
from coming here.
They say only dirty people come
here.
No one will come now, son.
I won't let anyone except
you here. No one!
Why is the door closed today?
Open!
Your lover is at your doorstep.
Open the door.
Please leave, Mr Anand.
Leave? What for?
Don't ever come here again.
What's wrong with you?
Open the door.
No. Go back.
To your wife.
- There!
She's the one I leave and come,
and you want me to go back to her?
I don't come to go back,
Pushpa.
Then wait outside!
Hey! Hello, Mr Anand!
You, on the road?
The door is closed.
Is there a festival today?
There's a crowd everywhere and
a queue before every room.
Which queue are you
standing in Mr Natwarlal?
I don't believe in queues.
My principle is...
when one door closes,
another one opens.
Which is why I love
two girls at a time.
If not Pyari then Dulari. Come on.
- With you?
Hey, don't worry.
I have this
country-made stuff with me.
Mr Anand, sometimes one should
enjoy country-made liquor too.
Come on.
First lift your left leg.
Look who is here!
Mr Anand. You?
We are so lucky!
Whose face did we see
early in the morning?
Mine, of course.
You forgot?
A donkey praises its own tail.
Please come.
- Sit down.
Please sit down.
I brought you here and you're
the one who's being pampered.
A glass for me
and a glass for Mr Anand.
Why are you quiet?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Of course there is.
Don't lie to me.
Tell me. Go on.
- Natwarlal...
what do I say to you?
- Tell me what happened?
Must I?
What has happened...
how did it happen
and when?
What will I tell you
What has happened...
how did it happen
and when?
It happened when it
had to happen
Forget it. Let's not talk about
it
What has happened...?
how did it happen
and when?
It all happened when
it had to happen
Forget it. Let's not talk about
it
Why must I complain anyway?
I'm heart-broken.
But how does it matter?
It was a fragile toy...
something had to happen to it,
and it happened
What has happened...?
how did it happen
and when?
It all occurred
when it had to
Forget it... let's not
talk about it
Do you understand?
That which I saw and heard...
how will I describe it to you?
It was a beautiful dream...
it had to end
and it did
What has happened...
how did it happen
and when?
It happened when it had to
Let's not talk about it
I'll drink to my heart's content
and sway in these streets
I had to lose my heart here...
and get a bad name...
I did
What has happened...
how did it happen
and when?
It happened when it had to
Let's not talk about it
Welcome, sir.
What's the time?
- It's two.
Two?
You haven't slept as yet?
- No, sir. Nor has madam returned yet.
When your master got tired
waiting for your mistress...
...why are you awake,
Mr Balram?
Hariram, master.
- Oh, the younger brother?
Go to sleep.
Lock the door and go to sleep.
Pushpa didn't do the right thing
by sending Mr Anand away.
She doesn't know what's good for her.
Why talk about her, auntie?
Here comes the devil!
Naughty fellow!
Hey! What are you doing there?
Nothing!
- Nothing!
The Prince! Pushpa has
unnecessarily pampered him.
Hey Gopal! Only three days are
left for the festival.
The idols aren't ready as yet.
You haven't brought clay from
the dancing-women's courtyard.
I don't understand something,
uncle.
Why is their impure mud mixed in the
idol of goddess Durga?
Who knows?
It's an old custom.
Without mixing that clay, Durga's
idol is not placed for worship.
Get on with your work.
I'll go and get the mud.
When will you paint the idol?
- In a day or two.
Where did you get this
blooming dale sapling from?
From the opposite garden.
Plant it in your house;
a lot of flowers will blossom.
Really?
- Of course.
Go quickly, or else it
will wither away. Go on.
What will you do with this
clay?
It'll be used in an idol
for the Goddess.
Is this clay very nice?
- It is sacred, son.
Then can I plant this here?
- Sure, why not?
Okay, ladies.
Thank you very much. Good day.
What are you doing?
I'm planting the dale sapling.
- Oh!
When it grows, a lot of
flowers will blossom on it.
What will you do with them?
- I'll pluck them for you.
Me?
- Yes, because you pray.
You know, when it grows...
a bird will come and
build a small nest in it.
I see! What will happen then?
Then? On the full moon night...
the mother bird will
lay three eggs in it.
Great! On the full moon
night...
the mother-bird
will lay three eggs,...
who told you all this?
- Lalu did.
Who Lalu?
- My friend who stays in the village.
Have you ever been
to Madhavpur?
We used to stay there earlier.
Near the lake below the tree,
there was a huge nest.
Lalu picked it up and
placed it on the tree.
And said the bird will lay three
eggs on the full moon night.
Aren't you listening to me?
I am, son.
- Look.
I have planted it here.
Don't let it wither away.
No, son.
I'll never let it dry.
Never.
You!
Yes, I remember. You had stopped
me from coming here.
So why?
To know...
why I can't come.
Your wife doesn't want you
to come here.
No wife in the world would
want her husband to come here.
Then what will you
gain by hurting her?
Happiness.
The little joy that I got,
I got it right here.
My marriage is the biggest
curse of my life, Pushpa.
But she's your wife.
- Yes. That is her trump card.
My house is a house of cards.
Every time I try to build it,
it collapses.
I wonder how she is who cannot
be happy with a man like you.
Forget her.
You also don't want me to
forget my sorrows for sometime.
Mr Anand.
Did you water my plant?
Plant? What plant?
- The blooming dale.
Nandu has planted the blooming
dale in our courtyard.
What I was here to ask you,
I got the answer from Nandu.
Nandu there will be
flowers in your courtyard.
Blooming dale flowers.
I'm so unfortunate...
Don't say that.
- There's no harm in speaking the truth.
If I come here, this plant
will wither away.
The blooming dale will wither away.
- No.
You don't know how
much faith I have in you.
How much I like you!
You do?
- Yes.
So I don't want you to come
here.
If you don't want me to,
I won't come.
Perhaps we won't
meet each other again.
But still...
if you ever need anything,
please don't hesitate.
I'll leave now.
Mr Nandu, I'm going.
But before going I bless you...
may a lot of flowers
blossom on your tree.
Will they?
- Yes, plenty of flowers.
The fragrance of your flower
will spread far and wide.
Your life will be
filled with joy, Nandu.
May I go?
So long, Pushpa.
Hey, Nandu.
You are in bed early.
What is it, son?
I have a severe head-ache,
father.
God! You're burning with fever.
Listen! Nandu has a high fever!
Why not? He roams around
in the scorching sun.
He doesn't listen to me,
now let him suffer.
Call the doctor
and look after him.
I don't have the time.
I've got a lot of work to do.
Where are you going?
- To the temple.
Sister Pushpa, where is
your son nowadays?
I don't know. His parents don't
approve of him coming here.
Perhaps they have stopped him.
You didn't come for two days.
What happened to you?
Fever.
- Fever?
Where is your step-mother?
- She's sleeping in the next room.
My sister is awake
if she sees you...
she'll wake mother,
And mother will scold you.
Go away. When I'm all right,
I'll come to you.
No, come when you
are completely cured.
Here, drink this.
Why did you leave it?
- I don't like sago.
Will you eat sweets in fever?
Will you drink or not?
- No. I won't.
God!
Is he an enemy of mine!
Come Raju, let's go.
Let him go to hell!
Hey, Nandu!
How are you feeling now?
- My fever is not subsiding.
Why? It has been so long.
Doesn't the doctor come here?
He does.
Why didn't you call
a senior doctor?
Their fee is high and my father
doesn't have the money.
Look, I've got some grapes
and apples for you.
You want it?
- Yes.
Eat.
Hey, Nandu! Whom are you
talking to? Who's there?
No one, mother.
You go to sleep.
Go now. Mother will get up.
Greetings.
- Greetings.
Mr Anand has sent this letter
for you.
Look, please ask Mr Anand
to see me once.
Very well.
- Tell him it is urgent.
Ask him to come this evening.
- Okay.
Brother, does your head hurt?
Yes, Raju.
Just don't worry.
Dr. Ghosh will reach there.
Here.
What for?
- It is yours.
Give it to the doctor.
At least let me be help
in something so small.
Keep it.
And listen, brother Mahesh
shouldn't get to know...
that we arranged for the doctor.
- I understand.
That you are kind-hearted...
I always knew.
But today I learn how
big-hearted you are.
The more I meet you,
the more I like it.
Please call a senior doctor.
- A senior doctor?
Yes. The case is getting
complicated.
Looking at the child's condition
you can only depend on doctor Ghosh.
Yes.
- But his fees will be very high.
Yes. I hear he doesn't
take a penny less.
Yet, he is a known
specialist.
Who?
Doctor.
- You are Mr Mahesh?
Yes.
- Your son is ill?
Show me your tongue, son.
- Nandu, your tongue.
Some more.
Enough.
Okay, give me a piece of paper.
- Here it is.
What's his name?
- Nandu.
Send for this medicine
from my dispensary.
There's no need to worry.
Everything will be all right.
See you, doctor.
Doctor, your fees?
Don't worry about that.
Send for the medicine first.
I'm must leave,
I'm in a hurry. Good day.
Anand?
You are still here?
I thought I'd ask you and go.
Nothing serious I hope?
It would be, if I'd been late.
It's para-typhoid.
Nothing to worry about, I hope.
- Nothing to worry. He'll be okay.
Doctor, don't worry
about the expenses.
Here's 200.
- Money from you?
It's not mine, but
on behalf of the mother.
Oh! Tell me, what relation do
you have with Nandu?
Relation?
When someone is very dear to you
inspite of not being related...
isn't it a wonderful relation?
You won't understand.
You won't.
Nandu, now you have
become completely all right.
When can I start eating food doctor?
- Wait for two days.
Then eat to your heart's content.
- All right.
I'll leave now.
Mr Mahesh...
- Yes?
There's no need to change the medicine.
Continue with it for two days.
Doctor...
Will you tell me something?
- Go on.
You've been coming here
for so many days.
Neither did you take your fees
nor money for the medicine.
I don't understand this.
But I do understand.
- What?
That you are a simpleton.
- Meaning?
The child's mother gave me
money in advance.
And you don't even know?
My dear man,
besides your office...
don't you know what's
happening in your house?
I don't understand this.
Who gave so much money?
God knows.
Even I don't understand.
It's amazing.
I'll find out at the clinic
while returning from work.
Listen, we must fix
the date to leave.
I've applied for leave
it'll be done soon.
I'm going to the village
after so many days...
I don't even have a nice sari.
Bring me one, please.
I'll get my salary today
I'll buy one.
My Nandu is absolutely
all right, isn't he?
Absolutely.
Give him sago even today.
He can eat anything after two days.
- Very well.
We don't owe you any
of your fee, do we?
No. Now tell me something.
You've paid my fee...
why doesn't Mr Mahesh know about it?
- Well... actually.
I am not Nandu's natural
mother.
Pushpa, listen!
I made a grave mistake
in understanding you.
You have not only paid the doctor's
fees and money for the medicine...
you have given Nandu
a new lease of life.
I didn't have the
capacity to treat him.
I can never repay such
a big favor of yours.
I have misunderstood you.
Forgive me for that, sister.
Brother!
- Yes, sister.
Apart from respect and worship,
I can give you nothing else.
This is an ordinary sari.
The day-after-tomorrow is
Bhai Dooj (Brother's day).
Wear it on that day
as a remembrance of this brother.
Hey!
My son!
Now you've become
absolutely all right.
Yes.
I've got a box of
biscuits for you.
But before that I'll
bring an amulet for you.
Whose amulet is this?
- The Goddess's.
I prayed to Her to cure you
soon.
Always keep this tied
on your arm.
You'll never fall ill.
- Is it made of gold?
You are my gold.
My darling boy.
Wait, I'll get biscuits for
you.
Where are you?
Where is he?
Krishna sure is
a mischievous boy...
what will Mother Yashoda
do about it?
Krishna sure is
a mischievous boy...
what will Mother Yashoda
do about it?
Her eyes look for him...
where is Krishna hiding?
He flew away...
like the easterly winds...
what is Mother Yashoda to do?
What is Mother Yashoda to do?
Krishna sure is
a mischievous lad
You are the only dream
I have had in life
Anyone who sets his eyes on
you...
takes you for his own
Krishna, everybody loves...
for He plays the flute
what is Yashoda to do?
Krishna is certainly
a mischievous boy...
what is Mother Yashoda to do?
You know, we are going away
from here after two days?
Going away? Where to?
- To the village.
You'll leave me and go away?
- What do I do?
Everyone is leaving.
I'll have to go too.
You'll never meet me again.
- Why not? I'll come to meet you.
Just watch.
I'll surely come. May I go now?
Go, son.
Don't untie it!
- Let go!
You got that filthy woman to
tie an amulet on you?
Scoundrel!
Bindiya! Hey Bindiya!
Yes, madam.
- Return this to Pushpa!
And tell that witch!
She's a sinner anyway!
Why is she casting her spell
on children with this amulet?
Throw it in her face.
Listen, Nandu.
We'll be going after two days.
If you go there, I'll break
your bones, got it?!
Madam Pushpa! Madam Pushpa!
Yes?
- Here's your amulet.
Kamla, are you through?
Yes.
- So are we. I'll go and get the cart.
Nandu! Come in!
You've cut your leg.
- That's okay.
I'll apply some lime,
it'll be all right.
No, I'll fetch some medicine.
- Hey, Nandu... it's okay!
Mother, brother is back.
- Is he?
What are you doing?
Where had you been?
What's in your hand? Show me!
Medicine? Who's hurt?
- She is!
You're now stealing
medicines for her?
Yes, I'll go! Leave me alone!
- Give it to me.
You talk back at me!
What audacity!
Just come back, I won't spare you.
What are you doing, silly
boy?
You brought medicine for me
and bandaged my wound?
So what happened?
- What happened?
You won't understand.
I'll never forget this day.
Will you go today itself?.
- Yes.
In a little while. Father has
gone to fetch the cart.
Then you won't meet me again?
Why not? When I grow up,
I'll come to meet you again.
To take my amulet.
You keep it carefully.
Certainly, son.
I surely will.
Okay I'll go now.
Otherwise mother will beat me.
Go on, son.
Hey! What is this!
Being a Brahmin's son,
you touch my feet?
You love me so much.
Then shouldn't I bow to you?
Go, my child.
May God keep you happy.
Go on.
Mother, brother is back.
You are back?
Rascal! Devil! Shameless wretch!
You went there? You bit me and
went to give her the medicine?
She means everything!
I'm nothing to you!
I won't spare you!
Never!
I'll skin you alive.
Answer me!
It's my wish! I'll go.
- You'll go there!
Yes, I'll go!
- You back answer me!
I won't spare you!
Will you go there?
- It's my wish! I'll go!
Please don't beat him.
It's not his fault.
Here! Here!
- I'll still go there.
He'll never come to my house again.
Please stop it.
You want to go there?
Go and die!
Why did you come?
Why did you come to my place?
- You had hurt your foot.
So what?
You should've let me die.
Tell me. Will you ever
come to me again? Tell me!
You will also stop me
from coming?
You also don't want me to come?
I won't come!
I won't ever come!
No, son.
How can I stop you?
But... but what do I do?
Go away from here! We'll be
leaving in a short while.
Before leaving, we don't want to
see a cursed woman's face!
Mother...
Pushpa, do you know
your Nandu is leaving?
I do.
Are there many cars in Calcutta?
- Yes, many.
Double-decker buses too!
Huge ones.
Really?
- And many delicacies too!
Samosas, jalebies, kachories.
Kachories? How are they?
- Absolutely delicious.
Your father used to
treat you everyday?
No.
- Then your new mother?
No! She gave it to me.
- Who's she?
She was so very nice.
She loved me so much.
Hey! Nandu babu!
You!
- Don't you recognize me?
Why will you recognize
your village friend?
That too, a matric-failed
Chander!
Sorry, I couldn't recognize you.
You've changed completely.
You expect a man to survive in
150 rupees and still not change?
What do you do?
- A sales agent of a fraud company.
I sell spurious oil and
toothpaste.
Forget it and tell me about yourself.
I've heard you've become an engineer?
Five years ago, I was in Patna.
I got transferred only last week.
And your family?
- They're still back there.
I'm looking for a house.
- Oh I see!
But how come you are here
early in the morning?
I was passing by. Suddenly
I stopped looking at this place.
Something special about it?
- Yes.
Look.
The sewage of the entire city
flows through this gutter...
into the holy Ganges.
After that, it no longer remains dirty.
It becomes holy water.
This place reminds me of someone.
- Who?
There was a lady.
Her life was also
like this gutter.
But her heart was as pure
as the holy Ganges.
But who was she?
- No relative of mine.
But the love she gave me...
perhaps my own mother
wouldn't have been able to.
I am glad to meet you.
Okay, I'll leave now.
I'm getting late.
I've got to go and sell oil.
See you again sometime.
Look for a house,
I'll drop in for tea someday.
Sure.
- Okay, bye.
Hey, dunce!
Why are you shouting?
Is mother Ganges deaf?.
- Of course.
I've been worshipping her
for 14 years.
What did she give me?
Ajob to sell oil...
that too, after screaming
at the top of my voice!
Being a Brahmin's son
he sells oil, poor fellow.
Destiny! I must see his
horoscope someday.
Brother, read my hand. I got
you with great difficulty today.
Look, I've washed my
hands clean with soap.
What's this?
You used my soap?
Give it to me! Now go away!
You are not a conjurer...
to make me dance anywhere.
Hey, old hag!
Are you deaf?.
The man in room number 7 is
asking for water, go quickly!
I'll go.
- And these vessels?
Damn it! You haven't
washed them as yet.
It's time for the boys to
leave, when will I cook?
God! Wonder how my horse lost?!
His father had won two derbies.
- Forget it, Shamu.
When our forefather's
didn't leave anything for us.
What will the poor horses do?
- Who will win the match?
Mohan Bagan?
- East Bengal.
Is there a ghost behind you?
- Sorry.
Put some water.
- Water? Please give this.
Here you are.
Hey Ramu, son-of-a-gun!
- How can I become a father, sir?
I think serving you day and night,
I'll die a bachelor, Mr Pundri.
Not Pundri! Pundri Katch!
- Sorry Pundri Katch!
Where were you?
- Where wasn't I?
I'd gone to fetch
rasogollas for Mr Ghanshyam.
Tobacco for that fatso Maharaj.
To polish Sitaram's shoes. And...
- Shut up!
I told you to fill
my earthen pot at night.
If I don't get water in the morning,
I get an upset stomach.
Go and get it.
- At once.
Give this water to the gentleman.
- But it is for room no. 7.
Forget room no. 7.
Mr Pundri will drink it first.
Otherwise he'll have an
upset stomach, get it?
Sir, please read my palm and
tell me when will I get married?
When you die! Rascal!
Making fun of my art!
It's 9, will we be late?
- Yes, even if we...
You!
Here!
I want to ask you
the same question. You...
here?
I work here.
Are you okay?
- Wrong.
You should ask whether
I'm happy or not.
What is it, Anand?
Was the servant...
What's this?
You see me after so many years
and you start crying?
You forget....
Wipe your tears.
I have seen many ups
and downs in life.
I thought, nothing would
surprise me anymore.
But I am, after seeing you
today.
But this place is better
than the place...
where I previously was,
isn't it?
Wherever you stay,
you won't change.
First you cleanse dirt
from people's hearts.
Now you wash
their dirty vessels.
By touching the dirt in this world,
you purify it.
You know...
I met you after so
many years...
but I never felt
I was away from you.
Come on, Anand.
Mr Chatterjee is waiting for us.
A penny for your thoughts.
What's the matter?
This servant Pushpa...
is it an old affair?
You are a share market broker.
You won't understand.
There are things in life
which one enjoys...
when one deliberately
suffers a loss!
You won't understand.
Come on.
Okay, Ramratan I'll leave now.
I've got to take the 8.10 train.
Look after him, he's very
ill.
Here.
Who are you?
I... I am the new maid here.
Where is Ramu?
- I don't know.
I was so very thirsty.
Because I'm blind...
I can't even take
water on my own.
Sister-in-law!
Brother has got a second wife!
What?
He has brought her along.
Think her as your younger sister and
mind you, she should have no problem.
But... without telling me?
- It was not necessary. Come on.
Here you are.
Have you left?
If you see Ramu around,
please send him in.
I have a splitting headache.
Very well. I'll send him.
Looking for something, sir?
- Yes.
Many years ago Durga, Jharna
and many girls stayed there.
They left long ago.
Some even say Jharna is dead.
And in that house lived
a girl called Pushpa.
There's no news of her.
She left long ago.
Is that opposite
house vacant?
Yes, go and take a look.
Talk to that watchman.
Thank you.
- Good day.
Come, let me embrace you...
may no one cast an evil eye
at you
let me hide you in my heart
Come, let me embrace you
Lest someone casts an
evil eye at you...
let me hide you in my heart
The world is the scorching
sun...
and a mother is soothing shade
What is Mother Yashoda to do?
Krishna is indeed
very mischievous
You are the only dream
I have had in life
Everyone who sets his
eyes on you...
takes you for his own
Krishna, everybody loves...
for He plays the flute
What is Mother Yashoda to do?
Krishna is indeed
very mischievous
Send for this medicine.
- Okay.
If necessary, I'll give
an injection later.
Doctor, your fees?
- Four rupees.
Four rupees?
I only have two.
And I have to renew
the monthly pass too.
Should I give some?
- You?
I have some.
- You'd better inform his relatives.
His relatives? He has no one.
Which is why I brought him here.
He had two wives.
He left the first one.
And the second one
committed suicide.
Here you are.
- Here you are, doctor.
May God help you.
Keep these two rupees.
No, you've to buy
his medicine too.
That's right. There's milk near the
stove. Warm it up and give it to him.
I'll fetch the medicine.
I'm already late for work.
I won't go!
- Out, I say!
I won't leave this
house and go away.
Why won't you?
Listen carefully.
Either she stays here or me?
Barren-woman!
Throw her out!
Will you go or not?
- No! Kill me! Cut me to pieces!
But I won't leave you.
- You won't?
You won't budge like this.
Pick up your clothes
and get lost!
Here.
Samosas?
- Yes, brother-in-law got it.
You love them a lot?
- A lot!
Madam.
Madam, he's been crying
a lot today.
He has fever, I think.
Yes.
Don't worry.
I'll bring the doctor.
Enough!
Nothing to worry about.
It'sjust a common fever.
I'll prescribe medicines for two
days. Everything will be all right.
With your touch, certainly.
Perhaps you don't
remember, doctor...
you had cured his father too.
When his father, that's me;
I was 8 years old then.
What's your name?
- Nand Kishore Sharma.
Remember?
Yes, now I remember.
Great!
After all these years?
I was in Patna; recently
I got transferred to Calcutta.
Oh! What do you do here?
- I'm an engineer in the corporation.
Here, send for this medicine.
Nothing to worry about.
If need be, send for me.
- Sure.
Bye.
What is it, Ramu?
- The man in room no 7 is dead.
Mr Ramratan?
- Yes.
Doctor...
- Yes?
Write a death certificate.
- Come with me.
I was shattered at heart
first...
I break my bangles
in widowhood now
All my dreams
lie shattered
There blew a string wind...
which ruined my world
My right to look beautiful...
my right to look beautiful
is now no more, God
In a palanquin...
I've been brought
to my husband's house
Anand! Come on in.
Where have you been?
Sit down.
Are you okay?
Can't I come to visit you
unless I'm ill?
I felt like catching up
with all old acquaintances.
So I'm here. I have no problem,
neither physical nor mental...
I'm happy and peaceful.
Peace and happiness in today's world?
What formula have you found, sir?
Open the doors to your mind.
And peace and happiness
will blow in like a wind.
Take me for instance. I always
kept the doors of my mind shut.
I used to visit brothels,
I was a heavy drinker.
And I thought I'd find happiness
in these things. I was wrong.
And from the time I've
well-ventilated my mind doctor...
I stopped everything. I found peace
and happiness on my own.
How can you stop drinking?
- I just did.
And my wife too.
- Wife too?
No, actually I put it
wrongly.
Actually my wife left me.
It was a dilemma for her really.
On one hand was the hubby,
on the other were the parties.
Which party?
Forget it. You tell me
about yourself.
How are you?
- I'm fine.
But I never imagined
you'd change so much.
Such a drastic change?
- It happens, doctor.
The course of life is
not always smooth.
There is a turning somewhere.
You forgot, Pushpa?
How can you?
Pushpa! Whose foster-son
you had treated!
That very Pushpa ventilated
my heart and mind.
I see. Look at the co-incidence.
That boy Nandu...
is an engineer in
the corporation here.
And stays right here in this locality.
- Really? He must have grown very big.
What's more, his son recently
fell ill and I'm treating him too.
Here he is! Come, Nandu.
Greetings.
- We just mentioned your name.
You'll live a hundred years.
- What is the use of just saying that?
There should be someone
to give me this blessing.
Why not?
I'll bless you! May you
live a thousand years.
You...?
- Don't you recognize me?
When you were small, you'd
come to Pushpa's house.
I would bring samosas,
kachories and sweets for you?
Remember?
- You!
Mr Anand!
- Remember now?
Did your son get fever again?
No.
- Then stop the medicine.
Okay.
Is the blossoming dale tree
you planted, still there?
Yes. I've bought a flat
opposite that very house.
Really? Are the flowers blossoming?
- Many!
I want to see it.
Will you show me?
Come on.
- Let's go. Okay, doctor.
Do you know where she is?
She?
Pushpa?
You are longing to see her?
- Very much.
Do you want to meet her?
- Yes.
Let's go. Take a look at her.
Good bye, doctor.
Hey old hag!
What are you doing?
Wash that big vessel soon.
Look who is here.
Look!
Recognize him?
Or must I tell you his name?
See? You're just staring in amazement,
but Pushpa sure recognized you.
I never ever forgot.
Can this face ever be forgotten?
Talk to your son.
I'll just come.
Come, son.
Let's sit there.
You've grown taller than me.
But you haven't changed at all.
The same big eyes,
the same innocent face.
Come.
Sit down, son.
What have you done to yourself?.
But you're okay, aren't you?
I remembered you only yesterday.
I once cut my finger while
chopping vegetables, remember?
I've preserved the bandage
you had tied.
You have something else too.
My amulet. Remember?
I had told you I'd come
back for it.
Yes... I remember.
Will you give it to me?
For your grandson.
My grandson...?
Your son?
Yes.
I was going to take him to
the Goddess' temple today.
And I found you.
- Wait, son. I'll go and get it.
Good Lord!
Where the hell is that woman?
Hey old hag! Who'll wash
all this? Your father?
Wait, I'll do it.
What? The bloody shirker!
I'll find a new maid today!
It's a sin to employ these
whores at work! Great sin!
Here.
Look, I've got samosas
and kachories for your son.
Give it to him.
Eat, son.
Not only me...
Even Mr Anand remembers everything.
- You remember, Nandu?
You loved to eat this
as a child.
It's hot, it'll become cold.
Eat it up.
Hey Queen!
What are you doing there?
Come and wash these vessels!
Is he a man or a beast?
Hey! Tears in your eyes?
Mr Anand...
how do I explain it to you?
I understand everything.
You don't have to tell me anything.
Wipe the tears.
Have you washed them? Are you blind?
Look, how greasy it is!
My finger is cut, perhaps...
- Your finger is cut!
Hey delicate darling.
If that's the case, leave thisjob.
Go and dance somewhere.
- Shut up!
This is great!
Who are you to shout at me?
- Mind your tongue.
What happened?
- Look! Wonder how they came here?
I was scolding my servant
and they got angry.
Who are you?
- An old flame of this whore!
One more word against her
and I'll break yourjaws!
I won't say a word.
Sir, you are supporting
our maid a lot?
What is so special about her?
- There is, son. There is.
Doesn't she remind you
of your mother?
This is the time to
repay your old debts.
Debts? What debts.
The debt of motherhood.
Of being a child once.
This is the time, Nandu.
Take your mother home.
No.
Mother.
I won't listen to you.
Today you'll have to come with me.
Today is the festival of Durga.
On this day, devotees take
the Goddess Durga home.
If my mother does not
come to my house today...
I'll think that love, affection,
attachment... is all a farce!
But... but...
- No buts today.
Your son is taking you home,
go on!
Come on, mother.
- Yes, yes Pushpa.
Go.
Rickshaw... stop.
Get in.
That's okay.
Bless you, son. Go on.
What's this?
Tears in your eyes?
Tears...? In my eyes?
Oh yes!
But how did they flow?
You who always wiped
people's tears...
is there no one
to wipe your tears?
Let them flow, Pushpa.
They come with great difficulty.
I didn't know crying is such
a pleasure. I'll never say that...
Really, you didn't get
anything in life.
You didn't take anything from anyone.
You only gave, only distributed.
Go, Pushpa.
Your son is waiting for you.
I'm going.
I got so much from you...
but couldn't give you anything
in return. And today...
while going, I'm taking once again.
The dust of your feet.
On reaching home look
at the blooming dale, Pushpa.
A lot of flowers have
blossomed.
Take your mother away, Nandu.
Go on.
This is Immortal Love