Spice for the front page, isn't it?
- All you can think of are...
headlines for the front page.
- Oh, drop it!
Here comes Judge Raghunath
Such a gentleman! Why on earth
did that goon want to kill him?
Here comes your friend
ls the jury in place?
Yes, my Lord. Present
ls the accused present?
- Present, my Lord
Who is the counsel for the accused?
Have you no lawyer
to defend your case?
ln that case, the government...
My Lord
l'm the counsel for the accused
l do not wish to defend myself
l promised to defend you, if
you're ever arraigned. Remember?
Does the accused give his consent?
Yes
Raj, you have been accused of
a murderous attack on Judge Raghunath
You may plead your case
l swear to speak the truth
Judge Raghunath, can you tell us
why the accused tried to kill you?
Did he have any enmity with you?
Yes. The grudge that a born felon
bears against the judge...
who sentences him and
grants no reprieve
Could there be no other reason
for such animosity?
None. How else could l
relate to him?
l have no further questions
Defense may proceed with
cross-questioning
Judge, you are senior to me
lf in the course of questioning,
l happen to affront you...
do forgive me. Someone's life is
at stake. And you have taught me...
to ignore all relationships for
the dispensation of justice
This is my first interrogation.
Please give me your blessings
What do you mean when you call
the accused a born felon?
He has been a tramp and a hoodlum...
ever since he was a child.
His record says it
This penchant for crime has surely
been transmitted congenitally
Judge, do you have any children?
No
But how is this question relevant
to this case?
Most relevant. Think again. Are you
certain that you have no children?
No. But l reiterate. This question...
- Can you recount the circumstance...
when you threw your wife
out of your house?
My Lord, am l to be forced to reply
to such meaningless questions?
Ms Rita, you may ask questions
relevant only to the case
We wish to know whether or not,
the accused attempted murder
lf yes, then why?
Enough! Stop it! l'm a murderer!
Hang me if you will!
Proceed with your questioning
The accused does not deny having
assaulted Judge Raghunath
But, as you said just now,
the question is why he did it
This interrogation is meant
to reveal the answer...
if you my Lord, and Judge Raghunath
repose your trust in me for a while
You may proceed
l repeat my question.
Can you recount the circumstance...
when you threw your wife
out of your house?
l beg your pardon, Judge Raghunath,
but this question is very important
And not only for the accused.
For you too
The cause of whatever is happening
today, lies rooted in your past
Remember...?
Can you tell us? Why, when
and under what circumstance...
did you throw your wife
out of your house?
24 years ago...
l was practising law in Lucknow
l was the black sheep of the family,
because l opposed social norm...
and l had married a widow.
My father was a big gun
and was away in Bombay most of the
time. He was unhappy with me
But under no circumstance,
was l willing to leave Leela
She was so good to me.
She was such a good woman
And l was in love with her
But once, on our way from
Kanpur to Allahabad...
little did l realise that
like a boat in midstream...
my life too was to be caught
in cross currents
''Cross currents in the midstream''
'' Beware''
''ln the current you will sink or sail''
''The open skies''
''Careful sailor''
''Your boat is headed into a storm''
''Restless flow the deep waters''
'' Beware''
''Twigs are carried away''
''Steel sinks''
''So what do you think?''
'' Beware''
Aren't you feeling sleepy?
What are you thinking about?
- Why do they sing '' Beware''?
They say, these parts are dangerous.
Jagga the bandit. He's from these parts
Bandits...?
- Yes, but don't worry
As of now, he must be fast asleep
in some prison
Go to bed. l'm feeling sleepy
ln case you're afraid,l can come over
- No
No! The lady is with them!
Leave me!
You heartless bandits!
Where's your chief?
What right have you to terrorise
women from good families?
Aren't you ashamed?
- Ashamed?
Shame is for good folks,
not for bandits and robbers
As for me, my grandfather was a bandit,
my father was a bandit! But l wasn't
And your husband went and made me one!
- My husband...?
Who are you?
- Jagga. And l was innocent
But without a shard of evidence,
your husband framed me...
just because my father, my grandfather
were bandits
He framed me for rape
and he sent me to jail
So l've decided to prove
your husband right
Coward!
See what's wrong with her
Has she come to her senses?
No, she's still in a swoon
Let her go, Chief. She's pregnant.
She's going to become a mother
Touch her, and you go to hell
Pregnant? With a baby?
Her husband said that children born
of good folks turn out good
And children born of bandits...
turn out to be bandits. Always
Now let's see what the lawyer's son
turns out to be
Send her back once she recovers
Good are those born of good folks!
And of bandits are bandits born
You should make me a gift.
- What's the occasion?
Not any occasion.
The lady is back
What did you say? The lady?
Why is it dark in here?
Lights! Tonight we celebrate!
lt is you who lights up my life
Now that you're back,
even the lights seem so bright!
Give me the wick
But Leela, how did you escape?
l hope you weren't in danger?
Your love was with me.
How could anyone even look up at me?
You are tired. Change.
l'll bring you your dressing grown
These last four days
The last four days were
like a lifetime
l took the police and l looked
everywhere for you
All the while, l feared...
l feared you were in grave danger!
But how did you escape?
And who was this bandit?
Some Jagga. He said that you
had convicted him
So he escaped to get even with me!
lf he has done anything to you...
l'll see to it that he hangs!
- At heart, he's a devil
But God saved me at the last moment.
Thank God!
Tell me something
Ask
Does a bandit's son necessarily
become a bandit?
Yes, it's bound to happen
But why do you ask?
Just like that
Let's see what comes first.
Your becoming a magistrate, or...
Why? ls someone expected?
A new guest
Now l don't have any chances
of becoming a magistrate
Why? What happened?
Whatever... let's talk
of something else
How do you like this?
Nice
Listen...
Are you annoyed with me?
Annoyed? No
Why should l be annoyed with you?
Have my lunch sent over
What's the matter?
Where are the servants?
God knows! Maybe they're all dead!
l have to do all the chores
Let me help you.
- You'd rather tell her all this
She's sitting around like a queen!
Not to be cross with Leela.
l told her not to strain herself
You know the condition she is in.
And in a few days from now...
She's going to bear the fruit
of her sins!
What are you saying?!
- What everyone else is saying!
For four days, she lived with a bandit!
And Jagga at that!
Don't you remember what
he was convicted for?
Do you enjoy making someone unhappy?
The jaundiced eye sees all yellow
Do you think you're beyond scrutiny?
Don't you forget...
women have had to stand the test of
chastity. Because society asks for it
Bhabhi!
(Sister-in-law)
Forgive me Bhabhi,
your pot is broken
lt's only an earthen pot. But remember,
a woman's honour is far more fragile
Once disgraced, her honour
can never be redeemed
Just answer my question!
Did you not know that your wife
was seeing her lover on the sly?
The villagers used to say that.
But l didn't heed what they said
You haven't yet told the court
why your wife deserted you
You know it! Women are adulterous!
l know what that means!
Raghu, how can you lose
your cool in court?
l'm afraid your chances of
magistrateship may be clouded
Chances of a magistrateship?
That's out of question now
Can a lawyer whose wife is under
suspicion ever become a magistrate?
The whole town is agog!
- What are you saying?
Aren't you ashamed to talk like this
about your wife?
l'm just saying what
everyone is saying
Let them say what they want
You're right. That's what l decided.
But how do l get rid of the suspicion?
lt's like a leech sucking on...
some dark corner of my mind!
- What now...?
Where's everyone?
Send Bhabhi over to me
Oh, l'm so afraid!
Why isn't someone coming to me?
That's my husband. Please,
send him over to me
Look Raghu...
l'm telling you again! That baby
isn't going to be born in this house
lf she wants to have her bastard,
let her go elsewhere
l'm not going to let the honour
of my family be tainted
l'm going to throw this
wanton woman out!
No! l'm not going anywhere!
No one can take me away from here!
He knows that l'm innocent!
He trusts me, he trusts me!
You're here! Now l'm afraid of no one!
Have you heard? They want
to throw me out!
They say l'm a wanton woman!
They say, l've no right to be here!
But now you're here.
No one will dare anymore
Tell them l'm untainted!
Tell them you trust me
Tell them l'm mothering your child
Why are you so quiet?
Have you fallen for what they say?
You're the one who told me...
''l don't care for the baying dogs''
lf you desert me, who else
in this world can l turn to?
Tell me... tell me that you trust me!
''Do you think you're above scrutiny?
Don't you forget...''
''women have had to stand
the test of chastity''
Why are you quiet?
Speak... speak!
You can see the state l'm in.
l'm afraid... afraid!
l'm going to become a mother
... the mother of your child
Have mercy! This is your baby.
This baby is yours!
Get out!
Get out of here!
''The most chaste of women''
''Were banished''
''Why is not the earth rent asunder
in sorrow?''
''Why are not the skies torn apart?''
''So suffers the girl her father
raised lovingly''
''Her father raised her lovingly;
her husband loved her once''
''Now she goes from door to door''
''Oh such games The Lord above plays''
''ln the oyster
He makes the pearl blossom''
''ln murky waters
He makes the lotus bloom''
''Strange are your ways, Lord''
Congratulations, Lawyer!
A son has born to you.
Son of a decent family!
Born in a filthy gutter!
Do you not know what your wife
and your son went through...
after you shut your doors on them?
- No
Nor did you try to find out
But l can tell you
To get out of your way,
your wife left Lucknow
And your innocent son grew up
in a Bombay slum
One day...
Police! Scram!
Hey Nathu...
Hello, Constable
What are you up there like a monkey?
Why don't you go to school?
At school, the master asks for fees
My father hasn't the money
to send me to school
Look at Leela's son, Raj.
He lives in this slum too
His mother is worse off. Yet she
sends her boy to such a big school
What did you say? He isn't a boy.
He's a sissy!
Ma, why do you put oil in my hair?
- Oil keeps the hair soft
But why do boys in the neighbourhood
call me sissy?
So what? How do they
compare with you?
You're a good boy
who goes to school
You'll grow up to become
an educated man
And those wayward boys
will go to jail
Ma, what's wayward?
The ones who just tramp around
Those who think that whatever
belongs to others, belongs to them
Those who gamble and drink
instead of going to school
And they have fun!
Ma, when l grow up,
l'll become wayward too
Nonsense! You'll become a lawyer
Then a magistrate
And then, a judge
You're sitting here?
Everyone's out there buying chocolates
l don't have money
Why, doesn't your mother
give you money?
Daddy gives me a whole Rupee
every day!
You're rich. And l'm poor.
Eat this
No, Ma says never ask
for anything to eat
lf she told you not to ask,
go ahead and snatch it
No!
You're coming to my place
this evening, aren't you?
Why, what's happening?
- My birthday party!
You must come! lt's going to be fun!
You know, Daddy has ordered
such a huge cake!
Let's go and eat ice cream
Raj, aren't you giving me a gift?
l didn't have money to buy anything.
l'll give you some other time
Must you only buy something
to make a gift?
You can give me a flower
Really?
Here you are
Someday, l'm going to make
lots of money
And l'll buy a gift for you.
Something better than all this
Do that
But can anything be better
than this flower?
Come on Raj, meet my father
Ritu, say hello to the Judge
Hello, Judge
Bless you
You've grown up in these four years
You must've forgotten me.
Happy birthday
l've just arrived from Lucknow.
l owe you a present
As of now, l can give you a flower
Here you are
Let me put it on your hair
Someone has already put a flower
over there
Raj has given me this flower
Daddy, this is Raj.
He's in my class
l see
- Hello
Hello
God bless you, son
Raj says that he will become a judge
when he grows up
Very good!
Your father must be a real gentleman
What does your father do?
l don't have my father.
l have only my mother
Has he passed away?
- No! Don't say that!
My mother says he is alive.
But...
He doesn't live with you
... and you haven't seen him either?
Your father is a strange man.
- Not a word about my father
Else... else...
How can you let your daughter
play with boys like him?
Go to play, Ritu
Why, what's wrong with the boy?
l like him
He doesn't even know his father's
name, and you like him?
l'd say he's just a wastrel
- Forget it.
Must you hang on to
those rotten old ideas?
What was the Bandit's name?
Yes, Jagga
l remember you saying the same
at his trial
That a bandit's son
always becomes a bandit
l still stand by that principle
Principles, principles and principles!
lt's because of these blind dogmas...
that you lost someone
as precious as Leela
And because of your principles,
you never married again
The dry parched desert that
your life is, is your own doing
So much so that you would rather
destroy a friendship...
between two innocent children?
Why, what has the poor child done...
to bring you to harm?
Not this boy. But it was...
someone like him who destroyed my life
... and brought me to disgrace
Maybe today, he too says
what this boy just said...
''l'm only my mother's son
... l have no father''
ln every urchin l see him...
the one whom my wife bore,
the one who isn't mine
My wife's, yet not mine
Rita looks good in that photo,
doesn't she?
But Ma, why do you work so hard?
This is why you fall ill
l'm not going to let you work
anymore, you understand?
You mad boy! lf l don't work,
how are we going to eat?
l'm a man. l'm the one
who is going to work
From tomorrow,
no going to school!
You won't go to school?
Won't you?
How will you become a gentleman,
unless you educate yourself?
Wayward imp!
Without schooling, how can you become
a lawyer, a magistrate, a judge?
lf you say so, l'll go to school
... and l'll work too
But l won't become a judge.
At Rita's l met a judge
l didn't like him
''Are you out for a good time?''
''Hey Mister, Hey Babu,
Hey Mr White, Mr Black''
''Out on the streets
we're waiting for you''
''We, the merry boot-polish boys''
Good morning, teacher.
Sorry, l'm late
l work, you know. l work
What's all this?
Brush, wax... l give you a good polish
Your name has been struck
from the rolls
What?
- You can't study here anymore.
But l've brought the fees too! lf you
say so, l'll stop polishing boots
So l can't study here any longer,
can l?
No
For a minute, can l talk to Rita?
l have a gift for her
Rita's father has transferred her
out of this school. They have moved
Why did you kick my ball?
Forgive me, l stepped on it
by mistake
How dare a boot-polish-boy?
- Hit him!
You're just a boot-polish boy.
You dare take me on?
Hit him!
His coat... strip him!
My Ma is ill.
Let me go to my Ma
You can hit me some other time.
My Ma is ill. Let me go to my Ma
Your Ma is ill?
- Yes
His Ma is ill!
Run! Uncle Jagga is here! Run!
Get up. Come with me
Where to?
Wherever l go. From now on,
you go wherever l go
That's what your father wanted
You know my father?
- Yes
l knew him
Whatever l am today,
is all thanks to him
l owe your Dad an old debt
Then you'll surely help me
find a job somewhere?
Job? What job?
- Whatever! l'll do anything!
My Ma is sick! We haven't anything
to eat! Give me any job!
l'll clean the dishes, sweep floors,
carry luggage... l'll do anything!
Just give me a job! Give me a job!
You fool! Only fools work
You're a smart boy.
And you talk of working?
Unless l work, how will l eat?
How will l feed my mother?
Steal
Steal?
Stealing... no!
Yes, yes, yes!
Steal! Steal! Steal!
Pick pockets, locks,
rob, kill
You took so long, son
You've been hungry all day.
Go on, eat food
Food? Have you cooked?
- Yes, why not?
lt's over there, under the plate
The bread is warm.
l even cooked potatoes
Take some. lt's on the shelf
Have you found it?
Yes Ma, l found it
The bread, and potatoes too
The potatoes are delicious
Eat it then. Give me a bread too.
l'm very hungry
Very hungry
Bread...?
Yes, Ma. l'll get it right now
Right now
''Yes, yes, yes!
Steal! Steal! Steal!''
''Pick pockets, locks,
rob, kill''
You thief!
Stealing bread?
- Excuse me, my Ma is hungry
She hasn't had anything to eat
in three days
Son of a gun! Off you go to the cops!
What's your name?
l asked you what's your name
Father's name?
Ma has never told me
my father's name
Where does your mother live?
l asked you where your mother lives
l won't tell you. l won't
lf you don't, who pays for your bail?
You'll go to jail. You know that?
Where are you running?
- Don't send me to jail!
My Ma is hungry.
Don't send me to jail!
Afraid, son? Don't be.
This is just your first step
The road ahead is very long
Hey, are you mad?
Why are you laughing at your bread?
This bread...
you know this bread?
She makes you dance
What do you mean?
- She made me dance!
Outside the jail twelve years ago,
had l found her...
would l be here time and again,
for her sake?
You've had enough for free.
Come on, the jailer is calling you
Your time's up. Find yourself
some other hotel
Time up?
- Yes
l don't think l like the food here
anyway. From now on...
it's Hotel Taj Mahal for me
lf you want to eat at
the Taj Mahal Hotel, stop thieving
Stop picking pockets
And do some honest work
- Sure. l'm going on a pilgrimage.
''l'm a tramp''
''Whether l'm rising or falling,
l'm always a star''
''l have no family, no home''
''l have no one who loves me''
''l don't have a lover waiting for me
across some river''
''For me the city is empty city
The unknown path is all l love''
''l'm a tramp''
''l'm not rich''
''l'd rather stay a pauper''
'' But the songs l sing
are merry songs''
''My heart is full of wounds''
'' But my eyes are always
full of smiles''
''Oh this world''
''ln this world, maybe l'm doomed''
''l'm a tramp''
'' But whether l'm rising or l'm falling,
l'm always a star''
Raj! You had me scared
Come on, give me a hug
Hey, are you talking English?
- This time in jail...
l came across one of the politicos.
l thought l'd make the most of it
And got to talk some English.
l could use it
Tell me, what news of Ma?
You told her, didn't you?
Yes, a long time ago. She thinks
you're away on a long business trip...
with your boss. When you go home,
you must go home in style
l have it all fixed.
- First, tell me...
have you been sending money to Ma?
- Of course! On the 1st of every month!
Say, you'd need some money,
wouldn't you? Keep this
Looking for this thing?
l guessed it was for me.
So why not take it for myself?
Want a ten or a twenty? No...?
Bravo, my boy! You'll make
your guru proud someday
And someday, l'll ask your father what
the gentleman's son grows up to be
Raj, l've been dying to see you!
This time, it has been a whole year!
Where has this boss of yours
been taking you to?
This time, l've been
to London and more
London?
On my way back, l even stopped
at Arthur Road
My boss is into import and export.
- What's that?
You don't know import-export?
You're so naive
Your son is about to become a big
businessman, and you don't know...
what import-export is?
Listen to this, Ma
lmport-export means moving the money
between here and there
But mostly, it comes in this way
How would l know?
You've even started talking English
Sit, l'll get tea for you
What are you looking at?
l'm a thief
A lying thief
l've sinned
Why did you turn that photo over?
Whenever l look at it,
she seems to be staring at me
She brings back childhood memories.
Why don't you admit that?
Where could she be now?
Why don't you try to locate her?
Childhood days, and childhood friends
... do they ever come back, Ma?
l'm going out
- But your tea?
Forget it. l've got to see a friend
My son he is! Silly boy!
''This is a colourful season''
''Men think it's exciting
to see me tonight on the sly''
''Exciting!''
''This youth is so exciting''
''Your girl is mad about you''
''Why do you refuse me?''
''Why do you look away from me?''
''Look here, the world is yours''
''Why are you afraid of love?''
How much did you make today?
- Ten thousand five hundred
Why only fifty-fifty?
You can have many times more
How?
- Tomorrow morning...
a bank is being inaugurated.
Say, how's the opportunity?
A sleight of hand, and there's
a hundred thousand or so going
All you need is a car.
- Car?
A good car.
- For me, that's a sleight of hand
Eleven tomorrow. l'll tell you where
Good! Someday, you'll surely
make me proud
lt's late
You have to make it by eleven
First class car!
Car? Where?
Out there
Who's driving it?
- No idea
A girl just got down
and walked into that shop
Keys?
- With her, maybe
That one?
Can't you see?
No keys here
Return the bag.
- What for?
lt will make things easier.
We'll make it work.
How will you return it?
What happened?
- l've been robbed!
Who did it?
- l didn't notice
He was with you!
l had it a moment ago
- You didn't notice who robbed you?
Had l noticed, l would've caught him!
You...
Yes you!
- Who me?
Look, there goes the thief!
Stop! Thief!
He jumped over the wall!
Wait here
Come on, help me
There you are! Hiding!
Aren't you ashamed? Give it to me.
Else, l'll beat you to pulp
l'm going to kill you! Give me!
You dare stare at me like that?
Hey... knife!
Are you running away? Coward!
Coward!
He ran away
Anyway, here's your purse
Keep it
You've been through so much
trouble for my sake
No trouble. l've taken more
l should apologise. You risked
your life to get my purse back
And l suspected you
Not your fault
lt's just my looks
Sometimes even the police
are mistaken
Bye
How was the show?
- No use
We'll find a car. Why worry?
Get over to the place
l'll join you after a change
of clothes
Hey Romeo! You tear your clothes
no sooner than you see a girl!
Get lost
Get going
Stop! Thief!
Where are you going?
lnside
lnside? What do you want?
- Strange question
Your boss is the one who called me.
And you ask me what l want?
The boss, or the lady? Who called you?
Yes, the lady
So you're the one
who fixes the piano?
Yes! The piano fixer!
ls the piano in there?
- Are pianos kept outside?
No! lnside. Come on in,
else l'll get into trouble
Looks like a billionaire's palace!
The mantle!
What a lovely mantle!
What a grand mansion!
What kind of a joke is this?
Here's the piano
This piano is in bad shape.
Badly damaged
Rotten! lt'll take me time to fix it.
Go on, get back to work
l'll fix it
Who's playing my piano?
You...?
- You...!
l'm mistaken, once again
l thought it must be a thief
That's what l am.
- What?
l mean, who else but a thief
would come in uninvited?
No, it's good of you
to have come
You did me a favour.
l should've called you over
But l didn't know your address.
How did you find out my address?
No, don't ask me that.
lt's a secret
Let's say, it's luck that has led me
to your doorstep
Please be seated
No, thanks
Matches
Madam, he's the piano-fixer...
- Piano fixer?
Your servant thinks l'm here
to fix the piano
But you said...
Never mind, take the call. Go on
Strange fellow. He took you
for a piano mechanic
Not his fault.
lt's just my looks
lnspector sahib, no thief
came in here
Please wait here
What brings the police here?
Excuse me, l'll be back
A car thief has sneaked into one
of the houses in this neighbourhood
Have you seen anyone?
- No, no one came in here
She's wrong about
no one coming in here
l happen to be a visitor.
Would you be looking for me?
No... how could this be?
Come
Grand house
Yes. lt belongs to the Judge
Judge...?
- Yes, he's my guardian
Like the guard on the train
... signalling red and green?
No. After my father passed away,
l have been his ward
For the sake of my education,
he left Lucknow and he came to Bombay
l am much obliged to him
Do judges sport such grand houses?
He must be making a pile on the side
What a thing to say!
The judge is very principled
He never spares criminals
l hope God spares him!
Not to worry. lf you're ever arraigned
in his court, let me defend your case
You... lawyer?
- Yes
l took you for a schoolgirl
That was a nice one. A couple
of months, and l'll be an advocate
Would you like to see my degree?
A judge lives here. And a lawyer too.
Leaves only one to make a full court!
Yours truly. And here l am.
- And what are you up to?
Thievery
Stealing, picking pockets, locks,
ladies' purses, like yours...
that's what l'm up to.
- You're joking again. Be seated
You don't think l'm a thief?
- No, l think you're a gentleman
This is the new world order!
The thieves, the hoodwinkers...
they all dress in first class suits
like l'm wearing, and we take them...
for gentlemen. But those who work hard
for an honest living and dress shabbily
... are labelled tramps and wastrels.
The capitalists, the blackmarketeers...
the profiteers, the usurers...
who are they? Thieves, like l am!
You sound like a stock broker
or a banker
You might say that give and take
of money is what l'm concerned with
As far as banks are concerned,
l visit banks regularly
Be seated
Tell me your name
Tell me, whose photo is this?
- Mine
You...?
Yes, when l was young
lt's a birthday photo
Your name?
Rita. Why?
Ms Rita, would you like to come
to my house?
l'd like to show you
something unique
My mother would be very pleased
to meet you. Come
You...?
After twelve years
You've changed!
You haven't changed at all
Where have you been, Raj?
Looking for you
And at last, l've found you
- And when l saw you...
l took you for a thief
Not your fault.
lt's in my looks
''Ever since my lover
has come home...''
''my heart leaps with joy''
''His heart said
something to mine''
''And the old days returned''
''Our days have returned again''
''He brings so much of happiness...''
''my heart leaps with joy''
''My heart he could win
through my eyes''
''l could lay the stars
at his feet''
''My hopes soar...
my heart leaps with joy''
''Ever since my beloved
has come home...''
''my heart leaps with joy''
''We are young
and we are in love''
''He is the one who
makes my world''
''My heart leads him to me...
my heart leaps with joy''
''Ever since my hero has returned,
my heart springs to life''