My mother is very sick, Doctor.
Bring her here.
I'll examine her.
No, she can't come here.
She's unconscious.
She doesn't speak anything.
Please come, Doctor.
All right, my boy.
I'll come right away.
Doctor, what's happened
to my mother?
You don't have to worry.
Come to the dispensary in the morning
and take the medication from me.
All right.
Doctor, I hope the poor
woman will recover.
Nothing can be said for certain
since she's not ailing from anything.
In fact, she has suffered
some great setback.
You are right. May the Lord not
let anybody suffer such a setback.
Also remember that it's important
for her to have enough of food.
If she doesn't eat enough,
medicines won't be effective.
Mother... mother!
Drink the medicine, Mother.
Eat it, Mother.
I know that you always eat
after you have fed me.
But I have already eaten.
I'm telling you the truth.
Please eat it...
Don't cry, Mother.
Why are you weeping?
The one who has made us weep
will have to shed tears.
Mother!
Look what's happened to
the little girl!
Hey! Aren't you ready yet?
Come on, get ready quickly.
I will serve breakfast.
I'll come right away, Auntie.
Where's Ajay?
Mother looks so pretty today.
Come on, Mother.
Let's have breakfast now.
Aha! It's a sweet dish!
Open your mouth, Mother.
Now feed me with your own hands.
Did you feed milk
to the little girl?
Yes, Mother. The little girl
has drunk the milk.
And father has gone out
to fetch the medicines.
As soon as he returns
with the medicines...
...we will give the medicine
to the little girl.
Do you know... the little girl
has become very naughty!
She doesn't obey anyone.
Let's go.
I should be leaving now, Mother.
No, Ajay.
You are a son who would
make every mother proud.
You have done so much
for your Mother.
You should be happy that your
Mother has begun talking.
Your efforts have borne fruit.
You too care for her so much.
You have done so much for us
despite being a neighbor.
Not even one's own relatives
don't take so much trouble.
That's enough. You appear to have
become very wise, is it?
I should be leaving.
Stop please... stop!
- It's you?
- Yes. Where are you going?
I was on my way to Bombay.
But I missed the bus.
Is it? I am also heading
towards Bombay. Come in.
We are meeting after many years.
How are you?
I am fine. How's your mother?
Mother is absolutely fine.
How about you?
I went to Pune several times.
But I couldn't meet you.
I am living in Bombay now.
In fact, I travel a lot
between Bombay and Pune.
Ever since my parents have died...
...l've had to take on the
business responsibility.
Your parents passed away?
In the plane-crash two years ago
at the Bangalore airport...
...all the passengers were killed.
My parents were two of them.
Tell me, why are you
going to Bombay?
- In search of someone.
- Searching for whom?
In search of success.
Wait, fatso. I will
pick up the phone.
I am the head servant of
this house. Understand?
Why do you answer the phone?
You are unable to remember anything.
You speak however you like.
And then I have to bear with
the abuses of Mr. Chopra.
Go away from here. Go and wash
the utensils in the kitchen.
I don't remember anything?
How can he say that?
I am Mr. Bajodia speaking
from Ahmedabad...
...who deals in boxes, buckets
and tumblers. Who are you?
I am Babulal, the head servant
of this household.
You see, I've to come to Bombay to
discuss about my son's marriage.
You hand over the phone
to Mr. Chopra.
Just a minute.
Fatso, who's Mr. Chopra here?
Mr. Chopra is our employer.
Just hold on. I will
go and find him.
If daddy telephones,
tell him that...
...I will go straight to the
health club from the college.
- All right?
- Yes.
There's nobody around, and the phone
has been kept off the instrument.
If I am not around for a day,
what would happen of this house?
- How are you, Sir?
- I am fine.
I telephoned to ask you when I should
come to see the girl.
You may come whenever you like.
Tell me, how's your business doing?
Potatoes and onions have
become just too expensive.
Even the tomatoes, chilies
and ginger too!
- Who's this speaking?
- I am Babulal, the head servant.
- What's wrong with you?
- You should've told me so.
You're giving me a hard time.
I want to speak to Mr. Chopra.
Give me the telephone.
Mr. Chopra has left
for the college.
Mr. Chopra still studies
in the college?
She's arrived! Here I go.
O Lord Hanuman! If she looks in
my direction lovingly...
...I would make an offering of half
a coconut at your temple.
Move away.
- Have you brought my history notes?
- Yes.
And I have brought your love story
which was kept inside it.
- Love story?
- Come over here.
I'll show you. Look!
I can understand that it's your heart
that has been targeted.
But whose arrow is it which
has wounded your heart?
Not now. I will tell
you at the right time.
All right.
- Let's go to the canteen.
- You'll miss the psycho lectures?
I won't attend any class today.
I will tell Ravi when he comes.
Did you see? You remembered him
and he came over to you.
Is that all? I will copy
all the notes of psychology...
...and hand it over to you.
You need not attend the lecture.
I knew that you are the only one in
college whom I could depend upon.
Where did it go?
What kind of a lover are you?
You've returned after so many days.
Today, you should have been waiting
anxiously for your darling to arrive!
Whereas you've your eyes
fixed on this book!
At least they don't
make you wait!
- Are you angry?
- Yes. I am very angry.
Do you know that you've been late
by six-and-a-half minutes?
- Please forgive me.
- No! No forgiveness.
All right, then.
Punish me.
Your punishment is that till
I continue to read the book...
...you should continue to
kiss me ceaselessly.
I mean... sit quietly till then.
- I don't like to meet secretly.
- I too don't like it too.
But what can be done?
We are helpless.
You see, at this stage, nobody should
know what's going on between us.
If your daddy gets even an
inkling that...
...you love an unemployed
and ordinary boy like me...
...he would never forgive you,
nor would he ever accept me.
Don't feel sad. Trust me.
The day is not far when you
will become mine for ever.
And then...
But there's one thing... I don't like
your habit of coming late.
Let me see your watch.
My sister was to have come
today from Simla.
I had to go to the airport too.
It's too late now. She must've
even reached home by now.
How many of you
Is their, Babulal?
I am only one, Sister Gabbar.
I mean how many servants are
there in this house?
I will tell you right away.
- Three.
- And you?
- I am a man.
- You mean you are not a servant?
Boss is always so concerned
about me that...
...I forgot that I am a servant.
You even forgot that the car
had to be sent to the airport?
Why does one have to send
a car to the airport?
There are airplanes at the
airport, aren't there?
Did you hear?
- Where's Daddy?
- He's passed away.
What?
He was travelling in a helicopter.
He was feeling chilly.
So he switched off the fan
in the helicopter...
...and then he vanished
from this world.
- Whom are you talking about?
- About my father.
- How are you?
- How are you?!
I am fine. But I am
very angry with you.
Why didn't you come to
receive me at the airport?
I had extra classes today.
All right. But at least
daddy could have come!
You know how daddy is.
He is fond of just two things.
One is to expand his business.
And second is to race cars.
He must be busy in one
of these two activities.
I don't want to hear anything.
Our company's production should
increase at all costs.
Yes, Sir.
- Speak on, Mr. Mehta.
- The workers have appealed...
...to the management that they
should be allotted houses to live.
The company gives them employment
for which they receive salaries.
Besides this, they won't get anything
else. You may leave now.
Mr. Girdharilal's factory is
in our control now.
Go and take charge.
Henceforth, this company will be
known as Seema Garments.
A lot of telephone calls have been
received from your residence.
Miss Seema has returned from Simla.
How is my daughter?
- How are you?
- I am fine.
- But I am in a foul mood.
- Why is your mood foul?
- Why did you take so long?
- Because of urgent work at office.
I have bought a new garment
factory for Seema.
Now Seema Garments' name will become
a rage in the whole of Europe.
And what about me?
You? What do you want?
That's all! A sports car?
All right, you will get it.
- What is this?
- It's a soup.
This is a soup?
It's a finger bowl.
One washes one's hands in it
after eating the meals.
What have you done?
You've placed here something which
is used after meals are over.
What if the boss had gulped it
down thinking it to be a soup?
Quiet! Go and bring soup now!
You may also go!
You won't go anywhere tomorrow.
You will stay with us.
No! Instead, both of you will
come with me to Madras.
I'm going to participate in
the car race for the final time.
- But how can I come?
- Why?
- I've my practical exams tomorrow.
- Oh yes!
Your exams are important. But...
It would've been great fun
if you had come too.
Why do you think so? Take it from me.
Think of me to be close to you.
Just see, father. Like always,
you'll win the race this time too.
I hear this is the last time
you're participating in this race?
Yes. Till I continue to participate,
nobody else will be able to win.
Till the number one doesn't make way,
how will number two get the chance?
That's fine. But it
might happen that...
...number two gets the chance
this time itself!
There's a new boy named
Vicky Malhotra.
I've seen him practicing.
His timing is amazing.
He's the one with whom you'll
have a stiff competition.
- Where's he?
- There he is!
Whether it's a car race or
a race in real-life...
...I don't lose ever.
- Yes!
Whether it's a Icky,
Micky, Licky or Chicky...
...they are all pale in
comparison to my dad.
What say, Dad?
Mr. Madan Chopra is participating
in the race for the last time.
On one hand is Madan Chopra's
experience...
...and on the other hand
is Vicky Malhotra's confidence.
Madan Chopra... his car is
nearly close to him...
Now Madan Chopra is attempting
to overtake him...
Vicky Malhotra's
self-confidence is...
With full control over
his vehicle...
...Vicky Malhotra has
overtaken Madan Chopra.
Both, Vicky Malhotra and Madan Chopra
take the leads alternately.
Looks like Vicky Malhotra will
set a new record...
...and Madan Chopra will have
to concede defeat.
I had nearly lost my breath!
It was only when you raced ahead
at the last minute that...
...number 32 was left wondering
about who he is dealing with.
I want to meet the driver
of car number 32.
Was there some technical
problem in your car?
- No, Sir.
- Then how did you lose?
I've been your fan since years.
I look upon you as my guru.
I didn't want you to lose
the last race of your life.
It means you lost deliberately?
One has to lose something
to win something.
What do you want to win?
Your blessings.
I like your style. By the way,
where you do hail from?
From Bombay. Car racing
is my hobby.
And it's my profession
to deal in racing cars.
I've been on the look-out for a
sports car for my daughter.
Let me know if there's
some nice car.
I am reaching Bombay
day-after-tomorrow.
I will show her a car
the moment I reach there.
I want to click your picture
next to your car.
Just a minute. I'll join you.
I'll be in the club-house, daughter.
Excuse me...
- My name is...
- Priya Chopra.
And you want to know why
I lost the race!
For your sake.
Didn't you say that all these Icky,
Micky, Licky or Chicky...
...will prove to be pale in
comparison to your dad?
And if this Icky, Micky, Licky
or Chicky were to win the race...
...you would have
been heartbroken.
And how could I break the heart
of a beautiful girl like you?
That's why I said that to win
sometimes, one has to lose too.
And one who wins after losing is
known as 'Baazigar'(a juggler).
- What is such a person known as?
- A 'Baazigar'.
Look! Your dress has
become so wet!
You're talking of my dress.
But I've become so restless.
Why? What's happened to you?
Don't ask me anything. You may assume
that I've lost for the first time.
It was daddy who took part in the
race. Then who defeated you?
- The one who was defeated by daddy.
- Whom did daddy defeat?
- The one who won me over.
- And who won you over?
The one who lost with daddy though
he was on the verge of winning.
Gosh! Did daddy win the
race or lose the race?
Daddy won the race though he was
on the verge of losing.
But I lost.
You're talking in such
a confused manner.
Why don't you tell me clearly
what exactly happened?
It was a scintillating
competition.
His gaze was like an arrow
which straight hit my heart...
...and I was wounded.
Whom are you talking about?
What's happened to you?
I've fallen in love.
- Gosh! You've fallen in love?
- Yes.
And if you look at him, you will
fall from the 20th floor.
I'm prepared to jump
from the 20th floor.
- But let me have a glimpse of him.
- Not just a glimpse...
I will even introduce you to him.
He's coming tomorrow to
show me a sports car.
- I will bring him to your college.
- All right. But bring him early.
Tomorrow, I've to attend a
friend's birthday party too.
Daddy will become mad when
he sees this car.
I have also turned mad.
If you like this car so much,
why are you giving it to daddy?
Who's talking of the car?
Is this the age to love cars?
This age is meant to fall in
love with beautiful girls.
Seema will be glad to meet you today.
We have to meet her at college
at one o'clock.
I've praised about you
to her so much that...
...she just went berserk.
I've told her that...
...you're very handsome and that
you love in a unique style.
How many cylinders does
this car have?
Eight.
It must be great fun
to drive it, isn't it?
- Yes, it is.
- Shall I drive it?
No, you can never drive it.
- Stop the car.
- What happened?
What happened?
- So much noise for an ice-cream?
- Please fetch me one.
- Ice-cream is not available here.
- In that case, I want coconut-water.
All right. I will fetch
it for you right away.
Please give me one ice-cream.
I mean... coconut-water. Hurry up.
- I am going on a long drive.
- Yes, I am bringing it.
- There's a girl behind!
- Don't let her overtake.
Why did you block my way?
Come on! Move aside.
You were driving the car
so excitedly, weren't you?
Does the road belong
to your ancestors?
Her speech is very spicy.
Let's see how she tastes.
Where are you running away?
Let's catch her!
How did you fall down?
What happened? Did
the girl hit you?
Not the girl... that boy
in the jacket hit me!
What're we waiting for?
Let's get him.
- The water is finished.
- Is it? What do you want now?
The cream.
As you wish!
- The cream!
- Yes.
There they are!
Come on!
How come you're in this condition?
Why don't you take something?
Sometimes you jump from there,
or from here, or from up above...
Look... this is a
place for love.
You've come to love. And we have
come to take out your procession.
I see... so you play
musical instruments!
- Yes... no, of course, not!
- Why didn't you tell me earlier?
Darling... these people
enjoy playing music.
Why don't you sit
here for a while...
...and let me take
care of them?
Where did he go?
Why don't you come too?
Take this file to the court.
Can I make a phone call
to Commissioner Uncle?
Are you the Commissioner's niece?
Let me make a phone call first.
Then you will get to know.
You've made the Commissioner
your Uncle to impress a constable?
It's you, Karan!
You look smart in the uniform!
This is Karan. We studied
together in Simla.
- I was going and these crooks...
- I've understood.
They must've surely
teased you.
I'll deal with them later.
Please come in.
Some other time. As it is,
we've been delayed.
You'd better hurry up. Seema must be
waiting for us in the college.
It's 3 o'clock already. She was to
have to gone to her friend's party.
She must've gone by now.
Come on... open your mouth.
A little bigger.
Just a little more...
I cannot come.
I cannot leave them
and come to you.
Why don't you call him inside?
- Whom should I call in?
- The one whom you are signaling to.
I was only calling Charlie
to dance with me.
He got the connection
with great difficulty.
I am coming over.
Tell me something. Why didn't
you come inside the party?
You know that I don't like to mix
with your affluent friends.
I came up to the door
only to inform you that...
...l'm going home
for a few days.
What? What will I do all
the while you are away?
Oh yes!
Yes! You make do with
that Charlie!
Why are you angry?
I was only joking.
Come on... let's go and treat
ourselves to some delicacies.
I'm warning you strictly.
The boy who was supposed to have
come to see Miss Seema...
...he has already arrived.
But you lowly people shouldn't
come in his presence.
Besides the Chopra house, even my
image will be ruined. Understand?
And today, I will be making
a special tea.
Special tea for special occasions.
After drinking it, the boy will give
his consent for marriage immediately.
And it will be me who
will make that tea.
Has your father ever
made tea?
Don't mention my father.
He used to make coffee.
Get me the hat.
Today, I will make tea
flavored with saffron.
It's not saffron.
It is turmeric.
You are in a great hurry.
Shut up, fatso!
He's making a mess of things here.
Over there, the guests are waiting
for the tea to be served.
You see... I've only one son.
Whatever I have belongs to him.
I've three factories. I make all
kinds of plastic items.
If you ever need buckets, mugs
or tumblers for bathing...
...let me know immediately.
- Wait, Babulal.
- Shut up!
And none of you should
come outside. Understand?
He has taken boiled water
to be served.
He didn't even mix tea leaves.
Instead, he has mixed salt.
He's my son.
He's my only son.
Mr. Singhania has telephoned.
- Please drink tea. I'll be back.
- Please go. Business comes first.
If Mr. Singhania needs
buckets or tumblers...
...do suggest my name to him.
Make tea quickly.
My son has studied in
the United States.
If you wish, you may speak to him
in English and assure yourself.
My son!
- What is it?
- There are no tea leaves in it.
Affluent people make such tea.
Drink it quickly.
Tea leaves!
Please come.
Did you drink tea or not?
The tea of your home is like
nectar. What say, Son?
Seema has come!
Come, let me give you a surprise.
- What surprise?
- Come along first.
Come, Seema.
She's Seema, my daughter. And he's
Mr. Bajoria, and this is his son.
Hello, daughter.
Both of them make a good pair.
Now just give your nod for marriage.
All right. Let's hold the engagement
ceremony sometime next week.
Try to understand my problem.
You know, don't you, that I don't
have any status or position...
...that I can come over to your dad
and speak about marriage with him.
I don't know anything. If you
can't, I will speak with him.
I will tell him everything about
you and convince him.
- But...
- We have just one week left.
Daddy has fixed my engagement
for next week.
All right. Meet me tomorrow.
I will find some way out.
You may marry wherever
your Daddy wants you to.
What are you saying?
I've given it a lot of thought.
We've no other way.
I don't want any way.
I want the destination.
And you are my destination.
I cannot live without you.
In that case, we have
just one choice left...
...which can unite us forever.
What's that?
- Suicide.
- Suicide?
Are you willing?
If death is the destination
of our love...
...then I am prepared
to die gladly.
I, Ajay Sharma, am writing
this in full consciousness...
I, Seema Chopra, am writing
...that without any coercion,
having been fed up of life...
...I am committing suicide.
- Nobody is to be blamed for this.
Sign it now.
What happened? Why
are you laughing?
Because you've passed.
Yes! I was only testing you!
I was testing your love,
your faith.
What about this suicide note?
Only cowards commit suicide.
And I am not a coward so as
to give up so easily.
You reach at the Registrar's
Office at 1 o'clock sharp.
I will wait for you there.
Are you happy now?
Closed between 1 and 2 p.m.
See? You were delayed and
it is lunch time now.
How would I have known that...
...everybody in this office
feels hungry between 1 and 2 p. M?
What should we do for half an hour
now? What if somebody sees us here?
What can we do? Let them eat food.
We will go for a walk somewhere.
Our marriage is so strange!
Neither is there any procession,
nor any celebrations.
Listen... tell me something.
What is the gift that
a husband gives...
...to his wife the first
thing after the wedding?
What is that?
I knew that you would forget.
That's why I've brought it.
Look what's inside it.
It's very beautiful. Just like you.
- Is it?
- Do you know, Seema?
I feel like placing you on
the top of the skies.
Like this!
Hey! What are you doing?
I suffer from vertigo.
I feel dizzy to look
down from heights.
Please take me down.
I am feeling scared.
Now that you've held my hand,
why do you have to feel scared?
I'm mad that I am taking
you away from your world.
Every girl has to start a new life
after leaving her own world.
And the girl walks on these
beautiful feet...
...and liberates herself
from her old ties for ever.
I am freeing you.
Please forgive me.
Leave me. Leave me.
Please leave me.
Leave me.
I am sorry about Seema's death.
Can you spare some time
in private?
Yes, please come.
Till now we believed that Seema
fell from that building...
...or she was pushed down.
But the truth is that...
...she committed suicide.
Seema committed suicide?
How can it be?
Do you recognize
this handwriting?
This is written by Seema.
But how can it be?
On that day,
she was so happy!
And if she had any grief,
she would've surely told me.
I am her sister. I know her well.
Seema cannot do this.
Seema can never commit suicide.
Seema cannot do like this.
Seema cannot do it.
I think there's no
scope for any doubt.
If you wish, we will
continue the enquiry.
Otherwise, we will
close the case.
You may do as you please.
I've already lost my daughter.
- Why doesn't it enter inside?
- Keep on trying. It will go.
This nail doesn't belong to this
wall. It belongs on that wall.
What is it?
- Is there someone at home?
- What a question!
You blind man! Just put this on!
Who am I here?
- Who are you?
- I am Prem Nath.
So shall I start dancing then?
We've stopped giving charity.
Get lost from here.
I wonder where from
these people come from.
Why are you screaming?
What happened?
I wonder where from they come
to ask for charity.
- I threw him out of the house.
- You did a wise thing.
Greetings. I've come from
Bhimchand Jewellers.
Is Miss Seema here?
Tell me, what is it?
I am her sister.
She had come to our shop
a few days ago.
- She has to pay for some bills.
- What for?
She had bought
a mangalsutra necklace.
- A Mangalsutra?
- Yes.
Looks like you're mistaken.
But she had given the
address of this place.
Look, this is the bill.
- What?
- I was telling you...
...before itself that Seema
didn't commit suicide.
Looks like the boy she wanted
to marry has murdered her.
Please request the Commissioner
and start the enquiry again.
No... there's no need
for an enquiry.
If Seema has been murdered...
...would you let go the killer
without him being punished?
The killer would be
punished much later.
Have you ever considered what
punishment we would go through?
It's such a shameful thing
that Madan Chopra's daughter...
...used to love someone secretly...
...that she was planning to
marry someone secretly.
This story is published
in the press...
...if everybody talks about
it in a juicy manner...
...I would lose my face.
Who would marry you?
Have you ever given it a thought?
No... Seema is dead.
Let the pain of Seema's death
remain in your heart.
We cannot let it spoil
our reputation.
No, I won't come up.
I feel scared.
What's there to be scared of?
It's just six feet high.
No. I feel dizzy when
I look down from heights.
What's the matter? Why
did you call me here?
Seema didn't commit suicide.
How can you be so sure...
...though you've seen her handwritten
suicide note yourself?
Because she had purchased a
mangalsutra necklace.
Yes. And a day later,
Seema fell down from here.
And there's a marriage bureau
in this building.
It's possible that she must've
come here to marry some boy...
...and that boy proved to be
a cheat and he pushed her.
Let's assume that the
boy pushed Seema.
But the question is... why did
Seema want to marry him secretly?
Secondly...
One needs to apply one month in
advance for a registered marriage.
I've already checked the register.
There's no application in the name of
Seema Chopra at the marriage bureau.
And thirdly, we didn't find any
mangalsutra in Seema's purse.
Now you tell me, did she come here
to marry, or to commit suicide?
If she wanted to commit suicide,
she could've shot herself...
...or consumed poison. But she could
never have jumped from a height.
Because Seema was scared of heights.
She used to feel dizzy
when she saw from a height.
She couldn't even jump from a height
of six feet in a swimming pool.
The enquiry is over. I cannot
help you in any way now.
Help me to track down
Seema's killer.
Nobody is helping me
at this point of time.
All right. I cannot do
anything officially.
But I am prepared to help
you in my personal capacity.
Now do as I say.
You'll have to first ascertain
who all Seema met.
I had even asked Seema about the
boy who she was in love with.
But she put off the
question saying...
...that she would tell me
at the right time.
But there is surely someone
who she was in love with...
...whom she wanted to marry.
Do you suspect any one who
could have been her boyfriend?
I don't know about outside
the college.
But within the college,
she was friendly with Ravi.
- Who's Ravi?
- He's our classmate.
Can you tell me where
I can find Ravi?
You will find him at the
library in the evening.
You are suspecting me needlessly.
I did love Seema. And I also
believed that she loved me too.
But my misunderstanding was
cleared the day when I saw her...
...in some other boy's
company in the garden.
Other boy?
- Who was he?
- I don't know him.
Yes, I had clicked some photographs
on Anjali's birthday party.
He is there in one
of the pictures.
- Where is that photo?
- In my hostel.
- I will get it for you tomorrow.
- No! I want that photograph now.
You stay here. I will go upstairs
and get the photographs.
- I will come too.
- No!
This is a boy's hostel.
So you can't come upstairs.