BEACH PARTY
We got an early start
We're gonna have a ball
We're gonna ride the surf
And that ain't is all
Nothing is greater than
the sand, surf and salt air
Unrack our boards
just as soon as we get there
Stack 'em in the sand
while they're breaking' just right
Yeah, we're surfing' all day
and we're swinging' all night
Vacations is here
Beach party tonight
- We're chalking' our boards
- Chalking' our boards
- While we're in school
- We're in school
- Now we're waxing' our boards
- Waxing' our boards
At Balboa, too
Nothing is greater than
the sand, surf and salt air
Unrack our boards
just as soon as we get there
Stack 'em in the sand
while they're breaking' just right
Yeah, we're surfing' all day
and we're swinging' all night
Vacation is here
Beach party tonight
Nothing is greater than
the sand, surf and salt air
Unrack our boards
just as soon as we get there
Stack them in the sand
while they're breaking just right
Yeah, we're surfing' all day
and we're swinging' all night
Vacation is here
Beach party tonight
Well, there it is, honey,
and it's all ours.
Just you and me all alone.
Exactly.
- It's just like we're married.
- Exactly!
There's nothing like the beach
early in the morning.
It's so quiet and peaceful
and mysterious.
- Come on. Let's get the stuff inside.
- Right now?
We've waited a long time.
You know, the only thing
I've studied this semester is you.
Well, I hope you don't flunk.
There's always summer
school, you know.
Hold it, Dolores.
We've got to do this right.
It's like there's nobody else
in the whole world.
That's right. Nobody else.
Just you and me.
- Just you and me.
- Exactly.
Hey!
- What's going on here?
- Deadhead! What are you doing here?
Sleeping. Good night.
Now, you get your big carcass out
of here before I pick you up...
- You're gonna wake everybody up.
- Who's everybody?
There's just me and Ken...
Tommy y Big Boy.
I guess about all of us.
- Gee, what a wonderful surprise.
- Yeah.
I wonder who thought
of this wonderful surprise.
This is such a big house, and
I didn't want you to get lonely.
She's all heart.
Well, you know it's more fun
with the whole gang.
- Not what I had in mind!
- Frankie, that's just it.
I don't trust myself
when I'm alone with you.
- You really put me on.
- Frankie...
"Just the two of us. Nobody else in
the whole world. Like being married."
You're not going to get away with it.
I'm going to get rid of all these guys.
Then there's going to
be the two of us...
rattling around this
great big house together.
Frankie!
- Hey. Wall-to-wall girls.
- What are you doing here?
Get out of here.
You get out and stay out!
- Take off.
- Thanks for the invitation, Frankie.
Where'd I go wrong?
Hey, you're gonna rub a hole
right through it.
Hello, there.
Hi, there.
Come on. Let's go.
All right. You can go now.
- What do you mean?
- Get lost.
Well! I can see
the headlines now.
"Famed Anthropologist Dr. R.O. Sutwell
Arrested as a Peeping Tom."
My dear young woman,
at this moment, I'm concentrating...
on developmental biology
in human beings.
- That's what I mean.
- Marianne, I'm no match for your wit.
Here. Take a look, please.
Not me. I blush easily.
I'm a Philadelphia girl.
But tell me about it.
I presume you've guessed.
It's my new book.
By the way, how do
you like this title?
"The Behavioral Pattern
of the Young Adult
"and It's Relation to
Primitive Tribes."
- I've got a shorter title.
- What's that?
- Teenage Sex.
- You know, Marianne,
it's absolutely fascinating
how similar the behavior patterns...
of these young people is to
the other tribes we've observed.
Oh, come on, Professor,
these are just normal American kids.
American, yes. Normal, no.
Marianne, they're a
true subculture.
They live in a society as primitive
as the aborigine of New Guinea.
Now, listen to this, quickly.
- Dis you dig his action?
- His action?
He was hanging ten, when
he tried to shoot the pier,
and dinged his board
just when he took the air.
- Maybe you've got a point.
- You bet I have.
I'm gonna need reference books All of
Max Jacobson's works on puberty rites.
Murchison's studies of the Aztec
fertility symbols at Spanish Key.
Coming of age.
That sort of things.
Marianne, this book will
be my triumph.
And you'll never get
it through the mails.
But hang on the
picture rights.
American International
will snap it up in a minute.
- I take then that you won't help me?
- Have I ever said no?
Come to think of it,
you never have.
I'll help.
Thank you, Marianne.
- On one condition.
- Yes? What's that?
After you write this
book on sex...
Yes?
Read it.
Rhonda, what are you doing?
Watch. They come all unhinged.
See, it works every time.
At the present time
I am secluded approximately...
37 to 40 yards from the subject group.
Did it ever occur to you
that there's something else in life...
besides getting a boy?
- Like what?
- Love.
Here's something now.
Here's something coming in.
What's your problem? Frankie giving
you the cold treatment or something?
Deep freeze would be more like it.
You can't really blame him.
He brought you down here alone, and you
turn the place into a teenage flophouse.
Well, at the last minute
I got cold feet.
If somebody had wild plans for me,
why stop him?
Rhonda, I want Frankie to think of me
as more than just a girl.
- There's something else?
- Yes! A wife
Wife? Dee Dee,
you're not even a woman.
But I'm close.
And I'm not getting any closer
until I'm a wife!
Dolores, come here!
The music you hear in the background
they're playing...
Oh, brief footnote on comparison
to Haitian voodoo ceremonial.
Well, along the coast past Malibu
I make it every day
after school is through
My secret surfing' spot
where only I know
- The gremmies and the hodads never go
- Never go
I said the gremmies
and the hodads never go
Incredible.
Well, I'm hotdogging on my board
till the sun goes down
I jump into my woodie
and I make it back to town.
My secret surfing' spot
where only I know
- The gremmies and the hodads never go
- Never go
I said the gremmies
and the hodads never go
Never go
My secret surfing' spot
is the talk of the school
The Samoan puberty
dance all over again.
My secret surfing' spot
where only I know
- The gremmies and the hodads never go
- Never go
I said the gremmies
and the hodads never go
Yeah, I'm hotdogging on my board
till the sun goes down
The mating dance of
the whooping crane.
My secret surfing' spot
where only I know
- The gremmies and the hodads never go
- Never go
I said the gremmies
and the hodads never go
Never go
Absolutely impossible.
I'm hotdogging on my board
till the sun goes down
I jump into my woodie
and I make it back to town
My secret surfing' spot
where only I know
They're now concluding
their ceremony.
And they're collapsing
exhausted in the sand.
That was great.
By use of the directional
audio phonic microphone now,
I shall attempt to pick up
some of their more secret yearnings.
Gee, girls are pretty.
- You just found that out, huh?
- Well, I mean when they move.
- Right, Frankie?
- Come on, knock it off, huh?
- What's bugging you, Frank?
- It's Dolores. She racked him up.
Deadhead, you've got the
biggest mouth in the world.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Well, he's right. It is Dolores.
Fellows, how would you like
to have plans for a girl
and end up with a surfboard?
If you're smart,
you'll dump her.
- He's right.
- Yeah.
She's not gonna get away with it.
I've been building for
this scene all year.
- Then you're gonna dump her?
- Well, I would in a flash.
- Except for one little thing.
- What's that?
- I love her.
- Never say that!
Man, you want to ruin
it for the rest of us?
- We'll throw you out the union.
- What am I gonna do? I'm hooked.
Look, you're been building all
year for this scene, right?
- Okay, so you build someplace else, huh?
- Yeah, right.
- Yeah. Put her down.
- Right.
You know what happens
when a chick knows you dig her?
What?
- She walks all over you.
- Yeah!
Well, I'll show.
I'll dig somebody else.
- Another chick?
- If I were Dolores, I wouldn't like that.
That's the point, goo-goo. Put her down.
But who? Who can I...
- Hey, is she still there?
- Who?
The one at
Big Daddy's, you know.
- The cream puff.
- You mean, Ava.
- Yeah, Ava.
- Man, she's something else.
She's got everything, huh?
Well, I'll tell you,
if she hasn't got it,
it's only because
she hasn't got room for it.
- Big Daddy's tonight.
- You're on!
And now,
a poem
by our beloved teacher...
Cappy Caplan!
A poem dedicated
to Big Daddy!
D is for Dallas.
I may not go there.
A is for, "Ah, ah, ah."
D is for Nicholas.
Long may he wave.
D is for D-Day or maybe Day D.
Y...
- Why not?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Put them all together,
the spell Daddy!
He's been a mother to us all.
Yeah. Yeah!
Dance, swing, live, kids.
Remember that tomorrow may be
the day after today.
Swing, live, dance.
I will walk among you.
Well, I looked at the heavies
They were rolling' in fast
I knew I'd better make it
'cause they just don't last
I'm surfing'
Surfing'
Swinging and surfing'
Oh, the sand and the sea
is the only life for me
I'm surfing'
Yeah, and I'm surfing'
I'm hotdogging on my board
Gonna have me a ball
Caught a good ride and that was all
I'm surfing'
Surfing' and a-surfing'
Oh, the sand and the sea
is the only life for me
Just surfing'
Yeah, just surfing'
Well, I looked at the beach
There was nothin' but chicks
Rode a breaker in
Gonna get my kicks
I'm surfing'
Surfing' and a-surfing'
Oh, the sand and the sea
is the only life for me
I'm surfing'
Yeah, and I'm surfing'
Just surfing'
I met a little blonde
and I asked her if I could date her
She said, "Come on, honey
You can wash your board later"
I'm surfing'
Surfing' and a-surfing'
Oh, the sand and the sea
is the only life for me
I'm a-surfing'
Yes, just surfing'
Yeah, surfing', baby
Just a-surfing'
Oh, the sand and the sea
is the only life for me
I'm surfing'
Just surfing'
Surfing'
Come on, I'm surfing'
Well, I'm surfing'
- There she is. What do you think?
- Hey, man.
- Yeah!
- Yeah, she's some chick, huh?
Yeah!
- Is this what you wanted?
- It sure is.
- I'm sorry!
- Here. I'll help you with that.
Oh, would you?
I always spill things.
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah!
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
Say, listen, maybe when you take a break,
we could kind of dance a little, huh?
Oh yes.
I break very soon.
Well, here. Let me take you tray.
I'll take this for you here.
You done it again, boss.
You stupid.
Fix it.
MICE - RATS
Just what we needed,
the black plague.
Out!
Hold this.
Any moment I shall try for my
first contact. This is always difficult.
- Hey, Dad.
- I thought maybe you'd skip us this year.
I like you. And when Eric Von Zipper
likes somebody, they stay liked.
- Yeah, thanks a lot.
- Yeah, and I like it here.
- He likes it here.
You see, I told you.
I like it here.
- I get the message.
- Yeah.
Look, just don't make
any trouble, huh?
Who me?
Aggressive. Definite aggression.
Something's about to...
Definite jungle reversion.
Well-executed, too.
Keep a-moving' and a-grooving'
Don't stop now
Keep a-jumping' and a-stomping'
Whoa, baby, when
you shake so fine
I get the fits and chills
up my spine
What you're doing' is getting' to me
Don't stop now
Wind up and let it go now
Don't hold back
Whoa, baby, when
you shake so wild
You make me feel
like a motherless child
What you're doing' is getting' to me
Don't stop now
Little girl, I can tell
by that look in your eye
You got a kind of pleasure
making' my temperature rise
Let me tell you now
That's all right with me.
Long as you never let
it drop a single degree
Keep a-saying' what you're saying'
Don't stop now
Yeah, keep a-saying' what you're saying'
Whoa, each time
you twist your hips
Somethin' inside goes
a- flippety flip
What you're doing' is getting' to me
Don't stop now
Little girl, I can tell
by that look in your eye
You get a kind of pleasure
making' my temperature rise
Let me tell you now
That's all right with me
Long as you never let it drop
a single degree
Keep a-saying' what you're saying'
Don't stop now
Whoa, every time
you twist your hips
Somethin' inside goes
a- flippety flip
What you're doing' is getting' to me
Don't stop now
Yeah, yeah, what you're doing'
is getting' to me
Don't stop now
What you're doing' is getting' to me
Don't stop now!
Don't stop now
- Hey.
- Oh. Oh, please, excuse me.
What's the matter, baby?
You got a problem?
Yeah, that oversexed maniac
with that girl.
- Well, don't think about him no more.
- What?
- Eric Von Zipper likes you.
- Who's that?
Me!
- Well, you've done it again, boss.
- You stupid.
I'd better go now.
Hey, baby. Girls fall for
Eric Von Zipper.
- I didn't fall. I tripped.
- Tripped, schmipped.
What's the difference?
You're here, and you look good to me.
Yeah, I'm here with friends.
Yeah, well, he found a new chick.
- You'd better let me go.
- Hey! I like you.
And whatever Eric Von Zipper
wants, he gets.
No! No! Don't!
Excuse me. Excuse me?
I'm R.O. Sutwell. I'm sorry to intrude,
but you're molesting this young lady.
What are you, her grandfather?
To be perfectly factual,
I've really never met her.
Now, if you'll be so kind
as to unwrap her.
Look, nobody tells
Eric Von Zipper nothing.
Yeah, that's right.
No one tells Eric Von Zipper nothing.
- Couldn't... Who are you?
- J.D.
That's short for
juvenile delinquent.
One moment. Before you do
something you may regret,
I think it only fair to
caution you that I practice...
a most potent oriental
physic-psycho philosophy.
Yeah, and he looks
like one, too.
Well, I'm gonna give you
something new to practice.
- Wait just a moment...
- Like pain.
Excuse me. Would you
hold this for just...
I'll have to send for another one of these.
Could you hold these parts for me?
Hold these, too, please, will you?
And watch the battery.
They're very hot. Be careful.
I don't think they
manufacture this model...
- I'm sorry.
- Hey, I'm gonna rip you for that.
The Himalayan time
suspensions technique.
I think it would be...
Hey, what'd you do to him?
It's very simple. A complex
pressure point and applied force.
You see? Now he's in the clutches
of what we call time suspension.
Hey, boss?
You're fantastic.
Just wonderful!
Thank you very kindly.
May I escort you home?
Thank you.
I appreciate so much your
holding those parts for me.
Thank you. They're very
precious to me.
- Hey...
- The battery, yes.
But, listen.
What about him?
Oh, yes. Fortunately,
the force was light.
He'll come around in a few hours.
Just keep him warm and comfortable.
My dear.
Dolores.
Where do you think you're going?
I'm being escorted home
by this nice, old gentleman.
- Okay!
- A-OK!
He done it with his finger.
One lousy finger. Zap!
And look at him.
He don't even move. No nothing.
- He said he slipped a clutch or something.
- And he's in time suspenders.
I don't care what he's wearing.
Get this stiff out of here. Out!
Hey, gently! Gently!
Don't break him.
Careful.
I just can't get over how
great you were.
I mean, the way you saved me
from that storm trooper.
That was nothing, Dolores, nothing.
But thank you. Thank you just the same.
Oh, say, you don't mind
my calling you Dolores, do you?
Oh, not at all, if I can call you...
What is your name?
- Sutwell. Robert Orwell Sutwell.
- Orwell?
Yes, I'm sorry. That's always
been sort of a problem with me.
- I'll just call you Robert, okay?
- A-OK.
Dolores, I've got to
confess something to you.
You've suddenly
become very important to me.
And I'm interested
in finding out more about you.
- Oh?
- You see, I'm an explorer.
I explore.
You understand?
Yes, I understand.
You're my first contact.
Really? At your age?
Yes, and to a man of my age,
first contacts are terribly important.
I know. Contact's the
most important thing...
in the whole world.
Well, I wouldn't exactly say that.
- You wouldn't?
- No.
You're so right. I guess old men
always seem to know so much more.
I don't know. We old codgers
make mistakes, too, you know.
- Not very often, I'll bet.
- Well...
You're so distinguished.
- And you study people.
- Yes, that I do.
Are you a doctor,
like Dr. Shootser?
- Well, when I... Dr. Shootser?
- Yes.
Wait a minute.
Don't you mean Dr. Schweitzer?
Is that his name?
Yes. I think he's still
using it. You see...
- And you're so exciting.
- You think so?
- You're not at all like...
- Like Frankie?
You'd like Frankie
to think of you...
as something more than a mere girl?
Wouldn't you?
That's right.
You'd like him to
consider you as a wife.
- That's exactly what I said to Rhonda.
- I know.
I mean, I knew that that's
the way you'd feel about it
Dolores, now that we've met
and sort gotten together...
Well, I guess you could say
that we've made contact.
It's funny that with all you experience
that I'd be your first contact.
Yes...
- May I say something to you?
- Oh, yes, please do.
You may be my first contact, too.
Dolores, dear, could we just go
past contact for a moment?
It isn't contact I want so much
as your help.
- Me help you?
- Yes, with my research.
You see, I want to find
out all about you.
How you live, where you live,
your friends, what you like to do.
Anything you want, Robert.
Now, now, somehow I don't seem to...
You know, I think it, would be better
if we talk this over at my place.
- All right.
- You mean you will?
Yes.
Tomorrow then.
- Tomorrow?
- Yes, say about noon?
Oh, Robert, you even know
when a girl shouldn't be rushed.
Dolores...
Now, steady, old man.
You have the age but not the experience.
"You even know when a
girl shouldn't be rushed.".
Who said old?
- Gee, what do you think of that?
- I think he ought to grow a beard.
- Deadhead, you've got a flabby mouth.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I didn't say nothing.
Boy, this has been some night.
You can say that again.
Professor!
Oh, yes! Oh, yes, Marianne!
I'll be there in
just a moment.
Just a second.
Hurry!
Oh, yes.
I'm sorry.
There's your old Fitzhampton
and Murchison and...
- Thank you.
- ...Jacobson.
Thank you.
My, you've done this swiftly, Marianne.
Marianne, would you believe
that last night I made contact?
From the looks of your eyes,
I would believe it.
Imagine. Contact in just two days.
Marianne, incidentally,
I want to ask you something.
Would you say that
I'm an old man?
- Older than what?
- Well, older than young.
Do you know what
you're talking about?
- You know you're a very pretty woman.
- You're not bad yourself.
Thank you.
In a bearded,
academic sort of way.
Yeah, that's what I thought.
You know, all those
young people out there,
with their squirming tribal dances...
Strange. All the years
I spent in the jungle,
I never took time out
to learn to squirm.
You think maybe
you missed something?
Maybe not all of it.
But mostly with me,
it's been a spectator sport.
I've never really played
on one of the teams.
Don't you think it's time
that you got off the bench
and into the game?
Robert?
Ah, hi, Rob...
There's one of your teammates
here for batting practice.
Oh, yes, hello.
Good morning, Dolores.
You asked me to come by tomorrow,
so there I am today just like you wanted.
Oh, yes. Dolores, I think it might be well
if I got dressed for the beach
and met you down there.
All righty. Don't be long.
All righty.
No wonder you feel old.
Marianne, that's my first contact.
It's pure research. It's business!
- Lolita business.
- I'm not the...
Ava, I love you!
Thank you, darling.
Hey, Ava.
- Hi, I look for Frankie.
- He's coming in off the curl.
- You coming surfing tonight?
- If he takes me.
Well, if he doesn't take you, I will.
Frankie.
- Oh, hello, Ava.
- Hi, darling.
What's the matter?
Don't you like me?
Yeah, sure, I like you, honey,
but alone, not in front of so many people.
Now, you're going to
take me surfing tonight?
Well, I...
I just might.
Come here, baby.
- Tell me you love me.
- Yeah, yeah, I love you.
Where are you going?
What you think you're doing?
- Robert.
- Oh, yes, right here.
Good afternoon or good morning.
No, it's afternoon.
- Something wrong?
- Oh, no, there's nothing...
Where did you get
those banana boats?
Oh, yes. I'm very proud of these.
I brought them back from Africa.
How'd you get them
away from the witch doctor?
No, no. They weren't his.
They belonged to the Chief.
- Robert, they've got to go.
- Do you think so?
Well, all right.
They're very comfortable.
- What is this?
- Oh, yes. I'm very proud of this too.
This was present to
me by another chief,
the Chief of the
Tokyo Fire Department.
The firemen wear them to fires.
It's fireproof, also waterproof.
It's sort of a conversation piece.
No one around here converses
in the Japanese firehouse talk,
so take it off.
All right.
A bathing suit?
Yes, I've had it
for quite a while.
It was presented to me
by the Hong Kong YMCA.
- With a skirt?
- Yes, that's part of it.
I'm afraid that's going
to have to go, too.
No, no, no, I'm afraid this
will have to stay. This is it.
- Well, maybe you could...
- Maybe I could, but I'm not going to.
I'm just fine as I am.
Thank you very much.
Well, in that case, here.
Put this back on.
Very well.
My... I'm terribly sorry.
Oh, no. Actually, I think
you're kind of cute.
Sort of a walking United Nations.
Thank you very much.
You know Dolores,
I don't get to the beach very often,
so I really wasn't prepared.
What does she see
in old beaver puss anyway?
I don't know. If he had a twin,
he'd make a good cough drop.
- You get what you pay for.
- Deal!
Hey, pops!
Where'd you get that crazy kimono?
It just so happens it was presented to him
by the Chief of the Tokyo Fire Department.
Wonderful! If my rickshaw ever
catches fire, I'll know who to call!
Come on.
- Isn't it a hooting day?
- Yes, is it...
A hooting day?
- The sets are so glassy.
- The sets are glassy?
- The waves! They're just like glass.
- Oh, I see.
Tell me something?
Hooting?
Now, as I see it, it means a sort of
a cry of pleasure from the word "to hoot"?
Oh, yeah, Robert,
You´re so intelligent.
Hey, come on.
Let's skeg him.
I think you're just perfect.
Hooting, hooting.
- What about Dolores? She likes him.
- She's Frankie's girl. Come on.
- And stoked? Now, stoked means happy?
- Right.
Hi, Dolores, we thought
maybe we'd like to meet your friend.
- Not now, Ken.
- Stoked to meet you.
- You talk like a real kook.
- Thank you. You're very kind.
Robert, I think we'd better
go to the house.
How are you on the board, beard?
I can do a swan dive
and a fairly goof jackknife.
- No, no, no. The surfboard.
- Oh, that, no. I've never done that.
Must be fascinating. I'd like to learn.
It seems fairly simple.
Oh, it is, it is.
How about right now, huh?
- Hooting! Hooting!
- Oh, no, Robert, no!
We'll just try it right here first.
Right there. Just lay right down there.
That's the first step.
I see.
That's it. Right on your face,
and paddle like this.
What, like this?
- You see that wave out there?
- Oh, yes.
Okay, now, you sneak into it.
The first thing you know,
you're up on your knees.
- Like this?
- That's it, that's it.
Now you're to shoot that wave...
You're building to it.
- Shoot it?
- Yeah, catch it.
- Oh, catch.
- Right. And you stand up.
- Nothing to it.
- That's great!
- He's a real hotdogger.
- Say, do you...
Hotdogger?
- A good surfer.
- Oh, really? Thank you.
- You ride it right in.
- Yes, ride it right in.
- What do you say we give it a try?
- You know he doesn't know how.
- Now, now, please.
- Robert.
It's very, very simple, Dolores.
All right, I'll go right...
Don't you think you'd better
take off some of your equipment?
Oh, yes. Thank you very much.
My Perkins reminder watch.
Would you hold this please, Dolores?
Oh, and my glasses.
There we are.
I guess I better take this off, too.
Oh, boy, they just don't make
those bathing suits like they used so.
No, no, I'm very attached to this one.
I wore it when I swam the Hellespont.
I like it. I think it's
substantial looking.
Thank you, my dear.
All right.
Say, beard, you're gonna need this...
when you jazz the glass.
Jazz the glass?
Oh, that's very good.
- You got that?
- Yes, I've got it. Thank you.
Robert, don't!
Now, now, now, please. I told you,
I think is very simple, Dolores.
Wait a moment.
I'd like to do a few calculations
if you don't mind.
Let see me. The standard
sea level pressure is 29.92.
Ought to be 30 inches to the...
Oh, what is the weight of the board?
Twenty-six pounds.
Twenty-six. Thank you very much.
Twenty-six...
That's 2.6, averaged over X,
times the natural buoyancy.
Now, all submerged, it's 43.
Let's see here. Saltwater.
Saltwater is 7.2 over 0.4.
Yes.
There we are.
I'm ready.
Oh, no wonder.
I forgot to carry the two.
Excuse me.
- Excuse me.
- Go away. We're closed.
- Zen?
- No, I'm asleep.
I'm sorry.
Please forgive me.
Wait a minute. Hey, I know you.
You're the guy who put the finger...
on Von Zipper.
I've been trying to
figure you out for a long time.
Come on. Squat. Sit down.
What's your racket?
- My name is Sutwell. R. O. Sutwell.
- R. O.
And I'm here to ask questions.
- You're a cop?
- No.
Don't worry about them.
They're asleep.
No, you see,
I'm a developmental biologist,
social anthropologist
and an explorer.
- You're joshing.
- No, I'm doing research...
on post-adolescent surf dwellers.
I'm writing a book.
- It's called "The Sutwell Report.
- How about that?
I'm studying rather
primitive behavior patterns.
You came to the right cat.
If there's anything you want to
know about these kids
I can tell you the whole thing
in two words.
- They're nuts.
- They're nuts?
You see?
You noticed it, too.
What do you think they do all day?
Run all around the beach.
And they only got one
thing on their mind.
Each other.
That's sort of usual, isn't it?
That starts in...
I know, but they got so much energy.
They don't know what to do with it.
- They need a reason, a cause.
- A cause?
Yeah, that's why I hired him.
Big Daddy. He'll give them the reason.
He'll give them the cause.
- What cause? He's asleep.
- So he'll give them a sleepy cause.
What's the difference?
He's a real weirdo. I found him
on the beach one day walking around.
He had a couple of pigeons
or seagulls on his shoulders.
All these kids were gathered around him,
waiting to hear the word.
- What word?
- We don't know yet.
You know, you're a
very remarkable fellow.
- I think so. I like you, too, Professor.
- Thank you.
- Hey, one thing. Will you level with me?
- All right.
What's with the duster?
You think it moves the chicks?
No, as a matter of fact,
it usually works the other way.
I don't dig.
You don't want to level with me, right?
Yeah, all right, I'll level with you.
I was the youngest professor
at the university.
In fact, I was so young it was sickening.
Every time I opened my mouth,
my students laughed.
The other professors laughed.
Even the janitors laughed.
Well. I knew it couldn't go on
for long, so one date at lunch,
I presented my problem to
an old professor friend of mine.
And without even glancing
up from his soup, he said,
"Buy yourself a pair of glasses
and grow a beard. "
So, you see, all of this is just 18 years
of professor window dressing.
Amazing how our lives parallel.
I mean, you got the... And...
- You know how I happened to raise this?
- No. Why?
I got a dimple in my chin, and I didn't want
anybody mistaking me for Kirk Douglas.
But you don't look
anything like Kirk Douglas.
Yeah, you see?
Cappy, any help you can give me
with my research
will be deeply appreciated.
Well, you're going to need more help
than with your research.
Somehow I don't dig.
It's that Eric Von Zipper.
He's looking for you.
He's mad, real mad.
Whoops, there she goes.
I better go over and wake those girls up
before they freeze like that.
It once took me three weeks
to unwind one of them.
There goes the other one.
All right, come on, girls.
Up, up, everybody up.
Well, I guess I'll just have to
turn them over.
They sleep better on their head.
Come on, come on, up.
Thank you, Cappy.
I want to talk to you about Dolores.
- I'm Frankie.
- Oh, yes.
- I know who you are.
- You do?
You're the guy who's been
cutting in on my time.
Now, please. Just a moment...
You're brainwashing her with your beard.
Brainwashing her with my beard?
Why else would she be crazy
about someone like you?
- Now, that I resent...
- I mean, you're an old man.
Now, just a moment.
If you're so wild about Dolores,
why are you running around
with this Hungarian goulash?
Because she's my girl!
- Who, goulash?
- No, Dolores.
Oh, I see. Yes.
Make her jealous. Put her down.
Typical aborigine attitude.
I suppose you'd like to drag her off
on your surfboard by the roots of her hair?
Yes, I would.
I love her.
Look, I know how you can love her, too,
because she's lovable.
But I'm telling you this. I'm not going to
let any overage, fuzzy face
take away my girl,
not if I have anything to do with it.
And believe me, mister, I do!
By the way,
how you fixed for blades?
Boy, that kid's really got a chip on
his shoulders. I think it's his head.
- Can I ask you something, Professor?
- Yes.
You studying these kids' sex life,
or are you getting involved in it?
See you.
Involved.
- Hi, Sue. Have you seen Dolores?
- Dolores who?
Dolores Del Rio. Now, come on!
Where is she?
Help yourself.
- Oh, it's you.
- Yeah, me.
Well, there's nothing we have
to say to each other.
Yes, there is. Plenty.
Now, look, this time
has gone on long enough.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Oh, come off it! You and old pig bristles...
It just so happens I love him,
pig bristles and all.
Have you gone right
out of your mind?
Maybe, but I'm not crazy enough
to stick with you.
- Not even if I loved you?
- Not even if...
What did you say?
Not even if I loved you?
- Do you, Frankie?
- You know I do.
But you never said it like that.
Oh, honey.
What is going on which
I am included out?
Ava.
- There's something I have to tell you.
- Tell me outside in the dark.
- No, Ava, you've the wrong idea.
- Frankie, you promised.
- "Frankie, you promised."
- Dolores, I was just...
- I'm waiting.
- She's "waiting."
- But, look... What I'm trying to say is...
- I want to hear you say it again.
- Say what, Ava?
- How he loves me.
Did I say that?
Dee Dee, I was only trying to...
Where'd I go wrong?
Ava will kiss and make
it feel better.
You bet she will.
Come on. Let's go.
Where did I go wrong?
Treat him nicely.
That's right!
Well, maybe.
Treat him nicely
That's what you should do
I was such a fool
to treat him so cruel
He found someone new
Treat him gently
And to him be true
I was so unwise
Told him little lies
I lost him to you
So I ask you to
always take care of him
Maybe it's because I know
I still love him
Treat him nicely
With his love be kind
Had a listened to
advice I'm giving you
He might still be mine
Had a listened to
advice I'm giving you
He might still be mine
Had I listened to
advice I'm giving you
He might still be mine
Professor?
Yes, Marianne, I'm dressing.
I'll be right there.
Don't bother.
I'm just lugging in the
rest of your library.
Oh, I see.
Still upset with me?
Upset?
Why should I be upset?
Oh, I don't know.
I got that impression.
By the way,
how did the game go last night?
- Any home runs?
- No, but it wasn't exactly a shutout.
I went shopping today.
How do I look?
- Like a South Sea island village.
- Oh, thanks.
- Waiting for the volcano to erupt.
- Yes, that's a dramatic image.
- It sort of blends with your beard.
- Tell me, what is this with my beard?
I've heard more about my beard
in the last two days...
than in all the years since I grew it.
Maybe this tribe is more hip
than the Hari I knew of Japan.
I swear... Oh, hey, speaking of tribes,
I'm gonna mingle tonight
and get the inner workings of this tribe.
Now, I want you to follow me
with the directional here
and get it all down on tape.
- I'll get all the good stuff.
- You know, I'm really enjoying this.
Scratch you later, chick.
"Dig" you later.
Dig. Oh, yes, yes.
Yes, I must work on that.
Well, I looked at the heavies
They were rolling' in fast
I knew I'd better make it
'cause they just don't last
I'm surfing'
Yeah, swinging' and surfing'
Hello.
Robert, I thought you'd
never get here.
Well, if it isn't King Kamehameha.
Hooting, hooting.
Who gave you the hat?
Lily Dache?
No, no, no. I bought this
especially for tonight.
Yeah. I want to be one of the gang.
It's part of my research.
- Robert, I love being your guinea pig.
- Oh, thank you, thank you.
Old pig bristles.
Don't you worry about him.
No.
Put your arms around me.
- What's the matter? You cold?
- Yes.
Well, say maybe I could
put some more wood on the fire.
- You would.
- What?
More wood on the fire.
That's strange,
I'm not the least bit cold.
As a matter of fact,
it seems very toasty here to me.
- Robert!
- What's the matter?
- Your hat?
- What's the matter with it?
- It's on fire!
- What?
Here, pops!
You may catch cold.
- We're all here
- Yeah, we're here
The time has come
The tide is out
Yeah
- So what do we do?
- We keep warm
- How do we do that, brothers?
- We hold tight
- What do we hold sinners?
- Girls!
Yeah!
Where have they all gone?
If you don't know that,
you must've flunked biology.
Come on. Let's go.
This is nice,
isn't it?
Robert, you know I
like you very much.
- I like you, too.
- Thank you.
But I just can't stand by...
and listen to what they're saying
about you behind your back.
What are they saying?
They're calling you awful things
like "Hair Mattress",
"Old Billy Goat," "Pig Bristles"
and "The Finger."
"The Finger"?
Robert, the whole thing,
it's got to go.
It won't take long,
and you'll hardly feel it.
- Look, I've brought Deadhead's razor.
- Dolores...
You're not suggesting
I cut my throat?
No, silly! This.
Oh, that.
Oh, yes, yes.
No, no, Dolores,
I really shouldn't.
- No, I might not look too good under here.
- I'm willing to take the chance.
- Well, I'm not.
- Robert, be courageous like me.
No, you don't understand.
We're old friends.
We've been together for years.
And you can't just mow down
an old friend like that.
- It isn't...
- It's a shame, Robert.
- What?
- You have...
such young eyes and
such an old chin.
Young eyes?
I'll come back after
you two have parted.
Dolores...
Dolores, wait a minute,
I really...
The moon
Promise me the moon
And every little star
that shines above
The world
Promise me the world
And every dream
I'm dreaming' of
The moon
What would the moonbeam
I don't want the moon
A moonbeam,
a moonbeam
Deadhead, how can you be hungry
at a time like this?
Man can't live by love alone.
The world
I don't want the world
To own a real dream
- But please
- Promise me anything
Give me love
- Cool it, Ava. Now, just... Wait!
- Oh, come on!
You promised!
- Now, just one second.
- Come on, darling, don't tease me.
- Ava, down, girl. No, just... No, no, wait.
- Baby, come on.
Robert, Robert.
Robert?
Robert.
Robert, I am so
disappointed in you
Don't you have...
Robert? Robert,
you look positively...
Robert...
May I call you Bob?
- Why not?
- You know something?
You're whole new you.
- Only on the outside.
- I just can't resist you now.
Bob, it's no use.
I'm yours.
- No, Dolores.
- Bob, are you afraid to be alone with me?
No, no, it's not that.
It's just that...
I just don't trust myself,
now that I have my pig bristles gone.
Good! Them let's go someplace where
we can be alone. Let's fly to the moon.
Dolores, could you help me
with my research now?
- I have lots of questions to ask.
- Just anything, Bob.
Now, surf dwellers.
Tell me, what´s is
this irresistible magnet...
that draws and holds
this tribe here to the beach?
Well, it's fascinating. It's exciting.
The mystery of it all.
And the little unexplained things.
Like, just the other night, a fisherman saw
a little ghost plane with blue lights
land right here
on the beach.
And when they went to investigate,
the plane had just disappeared.
Like magic.
Real spooky.
You know, we might blast off
in that little ghost plane...
with the blue lights
even though they're
red and green.
You see, Bob?
Now with your pig bristles gone,...
even you are beginning to feel
the thrill of the beach.
Come on. Let's go find
the little blue lights and fly to the moon.
- Bob. it is an airplane!
- Yes, it is.
Oh, Bob, I've never been in an airplane!
Could we go for a ride?
Quiet, quiet, please.
All right. I'll take you.
But it'll have to be in the middle
of the night when the beach is deserted.
Now, promise me something.
You won't breathe a word of this to a soul.
- My lips are sealed.
- Good. Just keep them that way.
I'll tell you what.
You go home and get some sleep...
and meet me back here
at 3:00 in the morning.
- Bob.
- Yes?
You're just the coolest coolest.
I never been so
insulted in my life!
Hey, what...
Oh, it's you, Ava.
I thought you were with Frankie.
I was.
- Well, what'd he do?
- Nothing. That's the trouble.
Maybe he was hungry, too.
Marianne.
Marianne, come take a look.
I've shaved...
I'VE HEARD ENOUGH
Marianne, jealous.
Well, why not?
I'm a whole new me.
- Which one is it?
- It's one of them there.
You're a big help.
Hey, what's that?
Looks like a chick.
I could see that, you stupid.
Let's go.
Oh, it's you.
Yeah. Yeah, it's me, Von...
And what you doing here?
It's a secret. We got a
surprise for that Sutwell guy.
- I love secrets.
- Oh, yeah?
We'll tell you all about it
as soon as we give it to him.
Which one of these is he in?
I don't know.
I'm stranger in this country, too.
- Are you alone?
- Yeah. I'm looking for someone.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Come on, Zipper.
Let's go get him.
Yeah.
Stick around, chick.
You'll see Von Zipper in action.
All right, I stick around.
Now, listen. The only thing
you gotta watch for are this fingers.
Now, he's only got two of them,
one there and one here.
Now, there are seven of us
and only two of them.
You and you each grab a finger,
and then I'll hit him.
- Got it?
- Yeah!
You stupids!
But which house is it?
You stupid.
That one.
Let's go. Will you...
Will you...
You stupids!
I can't see nothing!
- Don't holler!
- Help!
- You're hitting me!
Dolores.
Help!
Hey! Do you hear a scream?
It's just Dolores and that man.
Help!
- Excuse me. I'm sorry. Excuse me, please.
- Help me!
What's...
Zipper! It's the finger!
Let's get out of here!
You...
- Quit! Quit! I'm going!
- Get out of here!
Oh, I'm terribly sorry I...
You all right?
Here, I'll help you.
There we are. That's it.
No, no. No, this way.
Yes.
- Oh, Bob.
- Dolores.
- What happened?
- I've been so frightened.
- What?
- I don't believe it.
We... I mean, she...
- Frankie...
- They...
They seemed a little restless,
Frankie and the rest of them.
They didn't seem to believe
that I was saving you from that...
You mean that
carbon-monoxide commando?
Yeah, that's the fellow.
They seem to think
that it wasn't just an accident.
How'd you learn to fly?
Oh, I don't know. They lifted me
out of my wheelchair into a Cub,
and somehow I made it.
- That was before the war, of course.
- Which one?
Spanish-American.
Oh, you're teasing.
I'll bet it was World War I.
You know...
You know, Dolores,
incredible as it may seem to you,
it was a World war II,
and I was an instructor
of combat aerobatics.
What does that mean?
Well, that-s the art of getting
the opponent off your tail...
without being shot down.
Could you show me
how it works right now?
Yes. Yes, I could.
What was that?
Oh, that was just primary stuff.
A simple loop. Did you like it?
It was simple enough, I guess.
- Did you enjoy it?
- I loved it.
But before you do it again,
let's get an opinion from my stomach.
- You know, when... Your stomach?
- Yeah.
- I'm terribly, terribly sorry.
- That's all right.
The analgesic for your stomach
is the Chinese Eight.
- Bob?
- Yes?
- You all right?
- Sure.
Isn't this a sensational
curriculum though?
It was designed for the Air Force by
a friend of mine, Colonel Wyatt Johnson.
Are you sure it wasn't Wyatt Earp?
Isn't this a great little plane?
It'll do anything.
Will it land? That'd be fun.
You don't want land.
You don't...
Oh, yes, I guess you do.
Right away, Dolores.
Right away.
There we are.
- You're all right?
- Oh, I'm fine.
Oh, no. Look, I'd better
help you home.
No, no, there are times
when one must be alone.
Will I see you tomorrow?
Only if they allow me visitors.
Oh, fine. Blasting off to the moon.
Sitting on a bed. A likely story.
Marianne, I tell you, it's not my fault.
I didn't plan it this way. It just happened.
Just because you no longer look
like Father Time, don't get ideas.
- It's later than you think.
- Listen, you've gotta help me.
I've got a problem.
- You're so right.
- Dolores thinks she's in love with me.
Your problem is you're too
young for her, mentally.
Look... Oh, Marianne.
You criticized Fitzhampton
for going native.
Look at that outfit.
What's wrong with it?
It's part of my research.
Marianne, look, please help me.
Look, if I can make her believe
that there's something...
- between you and me then I could...
- Use me.
If you want a pinch hitter,
call Mickey Mantle.
Oh, please, don't put it that way.
That sounds so uncouth.
Just like you've always done.
"Save me from the aborigines. Help me
with this report, with that report. "
I'm...
I don't know why I've stuck with you
all these years.
You're never even noticed that...
That I've...
been around.
Oh, hello. Hello, Dolores.
Sit down. Relax.
I'll be right with you.
You beast!
Beast? Oh, you mean this.
Please don't let this worry you.
Marianne's very understanding.
- I'm sure you are, too.
- Understanding? Bob, what do you mean?
Well, I mean, after all
the years that we...
Well, naturally, you didn't think that...
We're very cosmopolitan.
You know.
You shave off a red beard
and become a bluebeard!
- I think she's gone.
- I think it worked fine.
- Professor? Professor?
- Please, call me Bob.
Bob.
- You could stop now.
- I could.
You know, I've suddenly
discovered something.
- You have?
- Yes. I... I'll tell you later.
Oh, the rocking' goony bird
is seldom ever heard
Even in the reaches
of his jungle home
The beast! He's a beast.
Dee Dee, what's the matter?
Don't you dig Father Time
without his pig bristles?
Shut up! Can't you see
she's had a traumatic experience?
I think it's about time that
somebody gave that hairless Chihuahua...
- a little trauma of his own.
- Yeah!
- Come on!
- Let's go.
- Hey, where you going?
- Over there.
- I'm going with you!
- Can I go?
You stay here.
After I've finished with him,
I'm coming back to
Seattle with you!
- I wanna talk to you.
- Yeah. Yeah!
- Make it quick. I'm busy.
- Okay. Are you gonna marry her?
- Well, I hadn't really...
- Dolores, I mean!
Dolores?
For heaven's sake,
me marry Dolores?
That's right. The ring, minister,
ceremony, the whole bit
Who's she?
- She happens to be...
- His girl.
Boy, for an oldie,
you really move around.
- He takes vitamins.
- If you...
Hey, Frankie, what's this?
Oh, for heaven's sake, would you
stay away from these instruments?
- It's expensive electronic equipment.
- I know what he is. He's a spy!
- A spy?
- What's this?
- Give me that.
- Back off, cowboy.
"The Sutwell Report".
I told you he's a spy.
Well, that accounts
for the phony beard.
Oh, for heaven's sake,
this is the most ridiculous thing...
- Fellows, listen to this.
- Please...
"And post-adolescent surfing societies
are primitive in origin,
similar in most ways
to pre-civilized..."
Hey, what's that mean?
It means he's using
us for case studies.
- Me and Dolores and all of us.
- Yeah?
- He's putting us down.
- Yeah!
"And as to their sexual
activities it seems..."
Hey, I'm not finished!
Hey, they're gone. Give me that.
Come on. Let's go!
Pies and beer.
I like it.
Go away.
Leave us alone, will you?
Cappy, thank you.
Thank you very much.
Cappy...
What's going on here?
Listen, is there anyplace
that you can hide us?
- Who are you?
- Sutwell. R. O. Sutwell, remember?
- Old pig bristles?
- I came...
Yeah. What'd you do
with the face mop?
- He's in disguise.
- Marianne, please!
Cappy, I'm in trouble.
Big, big trouble.
That figures. You probably got
involved with that Dolores Chick.
- We want Sutwell.
- Marianne, I... What's that?
Look, hide us. Put us in...
Now I know how
General Custer felt.
Now, here he comes.
Singing Bull.
Blast off.
So this is what you
think of us, huh?
Yes, it is!
And if I ever get a chance to finish it,
it'll be an unusual scientific achievement.
You used us.
You used all of us!
You made Dolores fall in love
with you for an experiment.
Oh, for heaven's sake,
this little girl doesn't love me!
She was pretending
to make you jealous, right?
That's right, Frankie.
I tried to tell you that.
Gee, I don't know
what you're all so upset about.
You were doing the same thing
with that Hungarian goulash over there.
You know what you need?
You need a leader.
- Somebody to show you the way.
- Way to do what?
- If you...
- Shut up, goo-goo.
Yeah, shut up, goo...
And what's more...
There ain't no more.
Eric Von Zipper said he'd be back.
He's back.
With an army.
- All right, where is he?
- He who?
You know I'm talking about.
Where is he?
- I don't know.
- What, what, what?
- That's him.
- That's him? You stupid!
- The brush is gone.
- The...
You know, I liked him better
with the jaw warmer.
Don't you get this?
This is the Samson bit.
Without the hair,
he ain't nothing.
Dick!
Hey, let me through!
Ring around the rosy
Keep Professor cozy
We will break your nosey
With a rubber hosey
Keep Professor cozy
We will break your nosey
With a rubber hosey
Ring around the rosy
Keep Professor cozy
We will break your nosey
Fellows, please, I don't
want any trouble.
Ring around the rosy
Keep Professor cozy
We will break your nosey
With a rubber hosey
Ring around the rosy
Keep Professor cozy
We will break your nosey
With a rubber hosey
Charge!
But watch the fingers.
Look, kids, take it easy,
will you?
Take easy! Big Daddy
hasn't given us the word yet.
Onward. Onward!
Told you to watch the fingers.
My hero.
Yeah.
That does it.
Oh, you...
Professor!
Onward!
Onward?
- I like your style.
- Thank you. Look out!
- You stupid.
- I'm sorry.
I got an army of stupids.
This way, folks.
Just step right this way, please.
Now we have Big Daddy's.
A favorite spot of the teenagers
to gather and have fun,
good, clean fun.
Of course, there's a teahouse
across the street...
Be gentle.
Who do you think
you're playing with? Kids?
My army.
Look, wreck the
joint if you wanna,
but whatever you do,
watch out for Big Daddy!
Look out!
Give me one of those pies!
Honey, I'm sorry. I didn't mean it.
Honey, I didn't mean it.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean it.
Listen to me, honey. I didn't mean it.
- Too late.
- I'm sorry.
Too late for what?
Sluggish nervous system.
Professor?
Yes, Mr. Von Zipper?
I wondered if we could
talk for a minute.
- Do you mean like a palaver?
- We could do that, too.
All right, Mr. Von Zipper.
- Watch him. You can't trust him.
- Thanks.
Look, professor...
Could we be friends?
Why not?
Look, Professor,
now that we're buddies,
I wonder if you could
learn me something.
Oh, yes. I know what
you want to know.
The Himalayan time
suspension technique.
Yeah. Could you teach me that?
It's possible.
Good. Because see, that way,
I wouldn't need a army.
'Cause, anyway,
they're, you know...
I thought so.
Yeah, so if you could teach me that,
then I couldn't need a army.
I could go around to anybody
if I didn't like them
and I could take the
fingers and press...
Please, may I tell you that
I only teach this to people...
How do you like that?
Big Daddy's waking up!
He's waking up!
He's gonna give us the word!
Well, come on, Big Daddy.
Give us the word.
The pit.
Bring me my pendulum, kiddies.
I feel like swinging.
Well, I looked at the heavies
They were rolling' in fast
I knew I'd better make it
'cause they just don't last
I'm surfing'
Swinging' and a-surfing'
Well, the sand and the sea
is the only life for me
I'm surfing'
He still hasn't come out of it.
You know, I kind of
like him this way.
- Say it again.
- I love you.
Oh, that sounds so wonderful.
Well, I guess my research
is just about finished.
It almost finished both of us.
You know, Marianne,
you won't believe this,
but my next trip is going to
be to the Mariana Islands.
- Oh?
- Yes.
And I'm looking desperately
for an assistant.
You are?
Someone who can keep me
from getting involved,
with the natives, that is.
I think I know someone
who could keep you uninvolved...
with the natives, that is.
I'll be back.
Just you wait.
Eric Von Zipper will be back!
Hey! Wait for me!
You stupid.
THE END...
ALMOST
Keep a-moving' and a-grooving'
Don't stop now
Keep a-jumping' and a-stomping'
Whoa, baby, when you shake so fine
I get the fits and chills
up my spine
What you're doing' is getting' to me
Don't stop now
Wind it up let it go now
Don't hold back
Wind it up and let it go now
Whoa, baby, when you dance so wild
You make me feel
like a motherless child
What you're doing' is getting' to me
Don't stop now
Treat him nicely
With his love be kind
Had I listened to
advice I'm giving you
He might still be mine
I got an army of stupids.
Well, I looked at the heavies
They were rolling' in fast
I knew I'd better make it
'cause they just don't last
I'm surfing'
Surfing'
Swinging' and surfing'
Oh, the sand and the sea
is the only life for me
I'm surfing'
Yeah, and I'm surfing'
Just surfing'
We got an early start
We're gonna have a ball
We're gonna ride the surf
And that ain't is all
Nothing is greater than
the sand, surf and salt air
Unrack our boards
just as soon as we get there
Stack 'em in the sand
while they're breaking' just right
Yeah, we're surfing' all day
and we're swinging' all night
Vacations is here
Beach party tonight
- We're chalking' our boards
- Chalking' our boards
- While we're in school
- We're in school
- Now we're waxing' our boards
- Waxing' our boards
At Balboa, too
Nothing is greater than
the sand, surf and salt air
Unrack our boards
just as soon as we get there
Stack 'em in the sand
while they're breaking' just right
we're surfing' all day
and we're swinging' all night
Vacations is here
Beach party tonight
- We're here at last
- Here at last
- Time's just right
- Gonna try to have
A beach party tonight
Nothing is greater than
the sand, surf and salt air
Unrack our boards
just as soon as we get there
Stack 'em in the sand
while they're breaking' just right
Yeah, we're surfing' all day
and we're swinging' all night
Vacations is here
Beach party tonight
Vacation is here
Subtitles: Kilo