Bingo.
G-48.
Bingo!
Bingo.
- Man, Bonehead's really swinging!
- I do believe.
Well, if it's all that good,
let's give it a chance.
I don't think that's it.
A shot in the mouth?
That's exactly what Dennis Frank...
Do you have a headache?
The answer is Witch Doctor's Aspirin.
Beach blanket bingo
Beach blanket bingo.
That's the name of the game
Take a blanket made for two, now
Add a boy and a girl
That's a game for
me and you, now
Yeah, let's give it a whirl
Beach blanket bingo
That's the name of the game
- Every lad and...
- Every lassie
Playing down by the shore
- Looking smart
- And looking classy
Yeah, they're learning the score
Beach blanket bingo
Beach blanket bingo.
That's the name of the game
When a lad just meets a lassie
And he asks for a kiss
Then he finds the lassie sassy
- Right blanket!
- Wrong miss!
Beach blanket bingo
Beach blanket bingo.
That's the name of the game
Play the game like
you should do, now
That's the start of the fun
When you find the
girl for you, now
Bingo! You've won!
Beach blanket bingo
Beach blanket bingo.
That's the name of the
That's the name of the...
That's the name of the game
Bingo!
Hey, look!
"Hear Sugar Kane's... "
We can read, Goo Goo.
Hey, look at that!
Remember, as close
to the boat as you can.
I'll land in the captain's lap.
- You do, and I'll...
- Bye-bye!
- It's a girl.
- It figures.
Somebody must have
left the door open.
That's what I call a high dive.
Hey, it's a free fall!
- Hey, look at that! That's great, huh?
- That's wild.
Boy, that's out of sight!
It's too much. Wow!
- Do you think that's a publicity stunt?
- Well, sure it is.
Man, that's sure some stunt.
Well, what if she's in trouble?
We should help her.
Oh, look, don't panic.
You see that rich boy's canoe out there?
He'll pick her up. Boy, are you gullible!
See, what'd I tell you?
Dee Dee, a smart promoter
could sell you Grant's tomb.
Oh, no. I've got sense enough
not to buy that again.
Gosh, I wish I could do that.
You just did, kiddo.
Now get out there and take the bows.
Gee, I'm a little scared.
Look, somebody paid a lot
of money for this stunt.
Don't louse it up now.
- Well, isn't it kind of cold?
- Only on the top.
They didn't pick her up.
What's the matter with those guys?
I don't know. Let's go find out.
Hold it. If they passed her up,
I have a feeling we should, too.
Come on, Bonehead.
Come on, you guys, let's go!
- Come on, you guys!
- Let's get her!
Perfect.
Earl, take a look at this.
And now it's our move.
All right, men. This is one of my big ones.
Oh, hi, girls.
I can see the headlines now.
"Singer saved by surfer. "
Perfect.
There's a pearl for you, Earl.
Yeah, I wish I'd said that.
Oh, you will. It's all yours.
Anything for the column.
Sugar's out there.
- Hey, what's going on?
- You'll see.
Put your arm around her, boy.
- Hey, what is this?
- Don't be a problem. Perfect.
Hey, look, if I put my arm
around someone, I like it to be my idea.
You're a hero, boy.
You just saved a beautiful young girl
from the jaws of the deep.
Got that, Earl? "Jaws of the deep. "
Yeah, I'm gonna keep
that one for my wallet.
- I have a feeling she didn't need saving.
- Yeah, but Frankie might.
You kids know who this is?
It's Earl Wilson, the famous columnist.
- Who's she? The BW?
- What's a BW?
Well, in Earl's column,
it always means his beautiful wife,
only this one isn't.
- Beautiful, yes, but wife, no.
- Haven't you ever heard of Earl Wilson?
Oh, you'll have to excuse Bonehead.
He hasn't even heard of President Wilson.
Well, Mr. Wilson has come all the
way out from New York
just for this one interview, right, Earl?
- You might say that.
- I just did.
Is she somebody or something?
"Is she somebody?"
Where you been living, in a cave?
You're close.
Come along, now,
and let's get out of these loose clothes
and slip into something tight.
I'd like to see her slip
out of something tight
and into something more comfortable,
like my arms.
Just think of me as your father.
Now I think we're ready.
Now, that's what I call a healthy girl.
Sugar Kane doing
her first free fall...
in honor of her album of sky songs,
Come Fall With Me.
What's up, boss?
Shut up. I'm thinking.
How long will that take?
Until I get it thunk.
Perfect. Oh, we need our
little hero in a picture.
I can make it on my own.
- I didn't catch your name, boy.
- I didn't throw it.
That's pretty tacky, boy.
I didn't want us to have
a language barrier.
That's enough pictures.
Don't want to tire her.
Let's dig this groovy chick.
Come on.
How far did you fall
before your chute opened?
- How does it feel, falling?
- Hey, where'd you learn the free-fall bit?
At Big Drop's Skydiving Club.
It's just over the hill.
- How do you know when to pull the cord?
- Before you hit the ground, Goo Goo.
Yes. Well, it's sort of hard to explain.
You see, when you're
falling, it's like...
Well, I get the feeling
I'm somebody else all the time.
I think we'll be more comfortable
up at the beach house.
And I'll get Sugar to sing for you.
Excuse me.
Little Sugar's too excited
to talk right now, fellas,
and Earl's waiting to interview her.
But I'll tell you what.
Keep in touch.
Here, have my card.
Take one. They're free.
Now, that's pretty tacky.
Oh, a smartnik.
But tomorrow, boy,
look for your picture in the paper.
Come along, sweet.
Sugar lives right up the beach.
You're all invited anytime.
Come on up and hear
her latest album.
- Bye.
- Frankie.
- Bye, Frankie.
- All right. Come on, dear.
"Bye, Frankie. "
Looks like Frankie's done it again.
Yeah, and he struck
a real gusher this time.
You stupids!
I'm through thinking.
Now, what I'm thinking is,
that poor little Sugar Kane
is mixed up with undesirables.
Well, Eric Von Zipper's gonna protect her.
I think I adore her. She's nifty.
- That skydiving looks like fun.
- Like to try it, boss?
Eric Von...
Eric Von Zipper thinks
cycles is better.
- Right?
- Right.
We go!
Eric Von Zipper ain't gonna
get left behind this time.
Jerome, you... Me...
It's a wiggy beach.
Okay, ready?
It only hurts when I cry
Go, Donna!
You ask me if
I ever long for him
Since we said goodbye
Sure, I get sad
But it's not too bad
It only hurts when I cry
You see,
I hardly even think of him
As time goes slowly by
I just go on like
there's nothing wrong
It only hurts when I cry
Sure, I remember our first kiss
The way I loved him then
Sometimes I think a love like this
Could never happen again
So please don't worry
if I sigh for him
You know that I'll get by
I'll just pretend that
it's not the end
It only hurts when I cry
It only hurts when I cry.
Sure, I remember our first kiss
The way I loved him then
Sometimes I think a love like this
Could never happen again
So please don't worry
if I sigh for him
You know that I'll get by
I'll just pretend that
it's not the end
It only hurts when I cry
- Dee Dee, I've been thinking.
- About what?
- About Sugar.
- Oh, really?
No, I mean about skydiving.
Boy, it'd be a new thrill up there.
Just imagine that feeling.
Yeah, like a bird.
When do we start?
We?
Well, sure. It'll be
a new thrill up there.
Yeah, for me,
but not for you.
A girl's job is in the kitchen,
at least until she learns
how to cook a hot dog.
Dinner was burnt.
Women have a few rights,
in case you haven't heard.
We can even vote.
- Yeah, that's the real American tragedy.
- Very funny.
Okay, play your little game.
But when the time comes,
I do the jumping and you do the watching.
Come on, let's turn in.
We'll want to get an early start.
- Hi, Butch.
- Hi.
Bingo!
Well!
Mark Anthony and Cleopatra
have returned.
You know something, Bonehead?
You remind me of the ocean.
- You mean I'm so deep?
- No. You make me sick.
I think I'm sorry I asked.
Hey, fellas, what do you say...
we hit Big Drop's tomorrow
and make the skydiving scene, huh?
Yeah, that's a good scene.
- How about you, Bonehead?
- I ain't gonna jump out of no airplane.
- I may be dumb, but I'm not...
- Bonehead, don't put it to a vote.
I'm going with Frankie tomorrow
to try the skydiving bit.
- Any of you girls with me?
- Sure!
Hey, you girls are crazy.
- Why? You fellas are gonna do it.
- Yeah, but boys are different.
I've noticed, and I'm glad.
Now, that's my kind of people.
You girls are so anxious to jump,
why don't you jump down here?
I'll guarantee you a happy landing.
I'd rather jump out of an airplane
without a parachute.
Either way you get to heaven.
Hey, that's a good-looking kid.
- Yeah, she's not bad.
- I wasn't talking about her.
See? You're crazy about him.
One look at a picture in the paper
and you're nuts about the guy.
Oh, come off it, will you?
Hi, kids. Welcome to Big Drop's,
where everything is sky-high
but the prices.
- Hi. What's up?
- Hi.
- I'm Big Drop.
- Big Drop?
It's just a nickname.
They used to call me Big Droop,
but I had it shortened.
Seems to me
I've seen him somewhere before.
That's Buster, my helper,
and Bobbi, his helper.
Looks like she could use a helper, too.
It's just good, clean fun.
Keeps him out of pool halls.
Come on in and look around.
Look around you, gang.
It isn't much,
but we like to think of it as our home.
This is Bonnie and Steve.
They help me run the place.
- Hi.
- Hi, gang.
Hello, there.
These kids want to learn
all about skydiving.
Free fall and everything.
Of course, free fall isn't really free,
but it's cheaper than expensive.
I assume you children
want to learn all about skydiving?
- This child does.
- This child's from Wig City.
I buy that.
All right, I'll leave you kids
with Bonnie and Steve.
If you brought money,
I'll see you in the office.
I saw your picture in the paper
this morning.
It didn't really flatter you.
- It was my bad side. I was facing front.
- That's cute.
We really do want
to learn skydiving.
She has some crazy idea
she wants to try it.
Why not? Bonnie's made over 100 dives,
and she's still in one piece.
You can say that again.
Why not? Bonnie's made over 100 dives,
and she's still in one piece.
- I mean, I'm sorry.
- You don't have to apologize.
He does to me.
Best way to learn is to watch.
Bonnie and I'll show you a double free fall.
Well, maybe first you ought to explain
some of the dangers involved.
The only dangerous part
is driving to the airport.
- Come on, I'll show you.
- Let's go, guys.
- And you can show me.
- My pleasure.
- Hey, ladies first.
- Go.
There she goes!
Oh, look at that!
It's beautiful! I can't wait.
Look, Dee Dee, Bonnie is an expert.
I learn fast.
Look at that!
Hey, there's Bonehead.
Perfect.
- What happened?
- Well, he was surfing, and...
She saved him, that's what happened.
This poor boy was out there
floundering helpless,
and Sugar swam out
and pulled him in.
- She's a heroine.
- Bullets, I...
Sugar, don't be modest.
We all know what you've done.
Just rest your head
back on Sugar's lap, boy.
Sure.
All right, everybody watching?
Sugar, cry a little.
Perfect. I've done it again.
Tell me your name, boy.
Well, everybody calls me Bonehead.
- Oh. Well, what do your friends call you?
- Stupid.
This calls for a celebration.
Tomorrow night, supper at Sugar's.
How about it, kids?
- Separate checks?
- Aren't you getting shorter?
Don't be late, kids.
Come along, Sugar.
Up, boy. We got the picture.
You know something?
I just don't know.
With your luck, you don't have to.
Well said.
You tired? Chalk.
Whoa! Got an itch?
You know, the name of
the game is pool, bubby.
Now, you gonna play it or not?
You know, I shaved twice
since you last shot.
Von Zipper plays
when Von Zipper is ready.
Cue. Powder.
Will you... Will you...
Not here, here.
Let me know when you're
going to play, bubby.
Hey, boss. Come here.
Out! I'll murder you
at the zoo tomorrow. Go.
All right. Later, daddy.
- Did you lose this, boss?
- Oh, stupid.
- What? What is it? What?
- Read this.
- Look at the picture.
- What does that say?
"Skydiving singer saves surfer. "
Read me more.
Slow. Read slow.
"Di-min-u-tive
"Miss Sugar Kane is enter-training
"the local surfters and...
At a diner tomorrow at her beach home.
"Also, plans will be disgusted
"for Sugar's new album
and concerning the surfters. "
That does it.
Them rotten surfers
ain't gonna get away with it this time.
Us good guys are gonna save Sugar
from them beach bums what don't work.
- Boss...
- Our work is never done.
Our work is to protect
the weak and the innocent.
Fall in!
What are you... Will you...
Why... Why do you put...
If there's a battle to be fought
Go to the battle then we ought
And so
Let's go!
Follow your leader
He is his ideal
He has nerves of steel
With my muscles,
I'm impressed
Not to mention all the rest
Follow our leader
I am my ideal
Them rotten surfers
we must fight
- Wipe out them surfers, ain't that right?
- Right!
And so
Let's go!
Follow your leader
He is his ideal
He has Rat appeal
Look at these two fingers now
We'll give them the finger now
Follow our leader
I am my ideal
Follow your leader
He is his ideal
He is a big deal
I'm the greatest, I admit
I've got class, I'm full of it
Follow our leader
Follow your leader
- He is
- I am
- His ideal
- My ideal
- Right?
- Right!
All right, kids,
and I guess you always will be
for the rest of your lives.
Old Bullets has a real
treat for you.
Miss Sugar Kane doing a number
from her new album, Come Fall With Me.
New love
He's my new love
He understands
When I hold his hand
And say
I feel so blue today
True love
That's my new love
He's there by me
To tenderly just say
I love you more each day
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
I've noticed you noticing.
Professionally.
Singing, you know.
New love
He's my new love
He'll always be
So close to me, I know
I love my new love so
True love
That's my new love
I know that he will always be
My new
New love my whole life through
I know that he will always be
My new
New love my whole life through
So glad that he will always be
My love
That's it, fellas.
Crowd around, crowd around.
Smile, Sugar.
This could be the cover
for your next album.
Stop the music!
Stop the music! Stop the music!
Stand aside, everyone.
I take large steps.
Well, looks like the carbon monoxide
commandos are back.
Look, fellas, don't make me
call the pest control.
I am Eric Von Zipper,
and I come here to tell you
that these beach bums is bums,
and ain't nobody
making no album with them.
They can make it with me and my cycles.
You could call it Come Cycle With Me.
Oh, perfect.
You'll hear from us. Next.
I got one more thing.
Eric Von Zipper adores you.
And when Eric Von Zipper adores
somebody, they stay adored.
- That's stupid.
I am my ideal,
but you are my idol.
Hey, Von Zipper.
Why don't you crawl
back under your rock?
Leave him talk.
He ain't through.
Thanks, J.D.
That's short for Juvenile Delinquent.
From the looks of him,
you wouldn't think he'd ever make it.
Oh, it wasn't easy,
but I helped him.
And these is my two mice,
Puss 'n' Boots.
- I am pleased...
- I am sure.
I thought up them names myself.
You know something?
I believe you.
My idol used to be Marlo Brandon,
but he did a moving picture about cycles.
He made them cycle guys to be bad guys,
so he ain't my idol no more.
You are. I could teach
you how to cycle.
- Well, thanks, but...
- Not too close, Sugar. He's a carrier.
Oh, yeah. I could carry her on my cycle.
It's a nice, healthy sport,
out in the wide open spaces,
just like us. It's nifty!
Now, if you hurry,
you can find lots of wide open spaces
just off the premises.
Him, I don't like.
You, he don't like.
Can I depend on that?
I am even thinking
of giving you the Hima...
- The Hima...
- ... layan.
The Himalayan suspenders treatment.
The Himalayan suspenders?
There's definitely a language barrier here.
It's sort of a judo thing.
Professor-type fella taught it to him.
Oh, yeah, there's really
nothing to it, see.
- All you do is you take your finger...
- Watch it, boss.
Oh, I ain't gonna do it,
not to me, I ain't.
- Is this right?
- That's...
- He done it again.
- Only different.
- Yeah, she gave him the finger.
- By remote control.
Oh, I love this game.
Can you move it out of here?
Come on, let's get him out.
Careful, careful.
Don't break him.
He's fragile. Careful.
Eric Von Zipper will return.
Oh, we can't wait.
Crawl in anytime.
Tooty-toot, Mouseketeers.
- Have you seen Bonehead?
- No. Who looks for Bonehead?
Well, I'm worried.
He hasn't been himself lately.
On him, that should be
considered a piece of luck.
Come on, let's sneak away
and talk about us.
- You came out to look for me. I'm glad.
- Hey, you're the one.
But when I came to,
Sugar was there.
I knew something was fishy.
That's very funny, what you said.
Well, what I mean to say
is thank you for saving my life.
You don't have to thank me.
- Do you live around here?
- Yes, I live around here.
- Well, can I come and see you sometime?
- You're seeing me now.
Well, I mean...
Hey, swim in with me and meet the gang.
- No, I'm sorry.
- Well, can I see you again?
Tomorrow at this same time.
There's a cove
about a half a mile down the beach.
I know where it is. I'll be there.
Oh, I don't know your name.
- Lorelei.
- Lorelei. That's pretty.
- Is there a last name?
- Just Lorelei.
There is something else
you should know about me.
- Yes, what?
- I'm a mermaid.
Some of my best friends
are mermaids, Lorelei.
See you tomorrow.
You know something?
You really are one.
I told you I was.
Well, I knew something was different
about you, but not this different.
- Do you still want to meet me tomorrow?
- Gosh, yes. More than ever.
I've never known a girl with a...
I mean, I'll be the only boy in my block
that knows a real, live mermaid.
- You know what I think?
- No, what?
I think
You think
Love doesn't mean a thing
- I think you think...
- I've got news...
- ... I think...
- ... For you
...Love means a wedding ring
- I think...
- You know...
- ... That...
- ... You think...
- ... It's true
- ... I think
Love's just a runaround
- You...
- I think
- ... Know that's...
- ... You think...
- ... Not true
- ... I think
It's time we settled down
- With all this thinking going on
- It really seems to me
- I've been thinking a lot about you
- And you've been thinking a lot about me
- Well, I think
- You think
- Why think?
- Let's get together now
You know
- I love you
- You know I love you
I think
You think
Love doesn't mean a thing
- I've...
- I think
- ... Got news...
- ... You think...
- ... For you
- ... I think
Love means a wedding ring
- I think...
- You know...
- ... You think...
- ... That...
- ... I think...
- ... It's true
Love's just a runaround
- You...
- I think...
- ... Know that's...
- ... You think...
- ... Not true
- ... I think
It's time we settled down
- With all this thinking going on
- It really seems to me
- I've been thinking a lot about you
- And you've been thinking a lot about me
- Well, I think
- You think
- Why think?
- Let's get together now
You know
- I love you
- You know I love you
You know
- I love you
- You know I love you
You keep your feet together,
knees slightly bent,
rolling to the right or left,
taking the force of the impact
on your hips and your shoulders.
Do not look down.
Keep your eyes horizon-level at all times.
- Now, you want to try?
- Okay.
Bend those knees.
There you go.
Very good. Not bad.
Did you see the roll?
- Frankie.
- Yeah?
- You want to give me a hand with this?
- Sure, if you'll show me how.
- Oh, it's easy. Just hold onto it.
- All right.
Now give me your hands.
Fasten the chest strap.
- It's right here.
- All right.
- Is this right?
- Yeah, nice.
Looks like your friend and my friend
are getting pretty friendly.
Now hand me the leg straps.
Good.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
Looks like Bonnie's friend
is just a little jealous.
And you're not?
You're darn right I am.
I'm so mad I could jump.
Be my guest.
- Excuse me.
- Oh, hey, we're not through.
Maybe you're not.
- Hey, you're doing all right.
- Yeah, so are you.
You mean...
Oh, lay off, will you?
- Dee Dee, I love you.
- Don't you "I love you" me.
What?
Hey, Bonehead!
You missed a real kick.
I was right.
Bonehead's really left the scene.
Yeah.
Let's see if we can put
him back in focus.
Bonehead.
Hey, Bonehead.
- Bonehead! Remember me?
- I got something to tell you.
- Tell, Bonehead. We're all ears.
- Her name is Lorelei.
- Whose name is Lorelei?
- This girl, the one who saved me.
Butch.
Bonehead, the girl who saved you,
her name is Sugar. Sugar Kane.
No, that's what everybody thinks,
but it isn't so.
Her name is Lorelei,
and she's a mermaid.
Boney! Boney, are you there?
Hey, I think I've got it.
If anything will pull him
out of a trance, this will.
Be right back.
Bonehead, is there anything you need?
Anything I can get you?
Just Lorelei.
Yeah.
Now, all you have to tell him...
is that he asked you
to the pavilion tonight.
He did?
At the party at your house.
That's what you tell him.
But I remember he didn't.
Well, look, I know he didn't,
but say he did as a favor to me.
I'm trying to pull him out of a trance.
If it's for you, Frankie, I'll do it.
- Thank you.
- Besides, he's kind of cute.
- Bonehead?
- Sugar says it's A-okay for tonight.
- For tonight?
- Yeah, at the pavilion.
You asked me to go.
- I did?
- Well, sure!
And she's all set,
aren't you, Sugar?
I hear you're a real good dancer.
I just can't wait.
Well, swell.
You mind if I talk to Frankie alone
for just a minute?
Go right ahead.
You know this stuff about Lorelei?
It must've been
one of them mirages or something.
Sure. We all get them.
- A mental mind is a terrible thing.
- Man, you know it.
And, Frankie, please, don't say anything
to anybody about the mermaid.
My lips are sealed.
Thanks for coming along, Earl.
I know this isn't
a fancy New York nightclub,
the kind you're used to,
like the 21 Club.
Hi, honey. You look great.
And I'll put you right on.
I've got good news for you, Big Drop.
Don't tell me. Let me guess.
You're leaving?
Now, you gotta stop
making me laugh.
I've got Sugar Kane here with me,
and she'll sing for you.
Who needs girl singers?
Not Big Drop.
I'm in an echo chamber.
For your information,
I've also got Earl Wilson here with me.
Who needs girl singers?
Big Drop.
Tell Miss Kane it'll be our pleasure.
- Perfect. I'll go tell Sugar.
- What is she gonna sing?
Don't worry.
The group's got her music.
Earl? Earl!
There you are. Right over here, Earl.
Sugar, here's Earl again.
And this is... Oh, forget it.
Welcome, kids!
Welcome to the pavilion.
I want you to know
that sitting in our audience right here,
one of the greats.
So great, Earl, I get the chills
every time I mention your name.
One of the greatest writers...
He's cute.
One of the greatest writers of our time,
a sweetheart of a fella, Earl Wilson.
Let's hear it for him.
You're great, Earl.
It's nice to see you.
And I want to tell you
something as a friend.
Somebody tell you you're 11?
Get rid of that hairdo.
You know what I mean?
You don't need the crew-cut haircut.
It's a little embarrassing,
because at your age, Earl...
Please, believe me.
You act as though
you were in the sandbox and you flunked.
You know what I mean, kid?
Frankie and Dee Dee.
Hi, Frankie. Hello, Dee Dee.
Stand up and get sick
for the audience.
You two 43-year-old yo-yos
skipping around the house.
Grow up!
You're a man already, Frank.
How long can you stand
in the bathroom in front of the mirror
going "samba, samba, samba"?
You're 43, Frank.
You're old and wrinkled.
Did you ever hear yourself sing, Frank?
I bet you scare trains.
You sing, Frank, you sound...
I'll be my...
You're old. Let me hear
you say one note. Say...
Wrong! You see what I mean?
That's what I mean! This kid cannot sing.
And I want you to know
one other thing, Dee Dee.
I never liked your personality.
You know what I mean?
You're too short for this type of work.
What are you, a seal?
You're Bonehead, right?
Bonehead, I'm a friend.
I spoke to the Board of Health.
You're gonna be condemned.
Do yourself a favor. Try this.
Spell "pussycat. "
Smart as a whip, huh?
But I want you to know something.
I have nothing against kids.
I don't mind...
I don't mind kids as a whole.
In a group, they annoy me a little bit.
So we're in for a big treat.
Right, Hondells?
Right.
We have a marvelous singer here,
and she's Miss Sugar Kane.
So here she is,
Miss Sugar Kane and the Hondells.
Fly boy
Fly boy.
I want to tell you
about a friend of mine
I love him so he drives
me out of my mind
- She's gonna be a big star, right, Earl?
- Yeah. She's very good.
The biggest. Big with the kids, too.
Flying in his flying machine
High in the sky
now we're making the scene
He's like an angel
well, you know what I mean
They shouldn't be dancing!
Boy. Big Drop!
He's my fly boy
Up in the sky on top of the world
We're in heaven above
He's my guy and I'm his girl
What a way to fall in love
I bet Dee Dee
would rather be dancing with you.
And you'd rather be
dancing with Frankie.
- I didn't say that.
- You didn't have to.
- How'd you guess?
- Oh, it was fairly easy.
You're nuts about the guy.
You can't take your eyes off of him.
Well, I was never a subtle type chick.
Okay, you want games?
I'll go along.
We're up in the sky
on top of the world
We're in heaven above
He's my guy and I'm his girl
What a way to fall in love
What a way to fall in love.
Now I know he's got
me under his spell
- Did she maneuver this?
- Sort of.
You're not doing her any favors
by letting her get away with it.
He's my fly boy
Fly boy
My fly boy
He's my fly boy
And Earl just thinks you're great.
Tell her, Earl.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
You're in, honey.
- Come on, Bonehead. Let's go.
- Go? We just got here.
I don't mean just go.
I mean go, go, go, like dance.
Oh, sure!
Did you ever do anything
like that, Earl?
Once back in Ohio,
when I got caught in a swarm of bees.
- Bonehead, you're just not with it.
- I guess you're right.
Would you like to take
a walk along the beach?
Sure!
Oh, isn't it wonderful?
The water's so beautiful.
Yeah, it sure does cool off
our dancing dogs.
Yeah, it's real cool.
- Do you hear that?
- Hear what?
Music, real soft and pretty.
I hear the music from the pavilion.
It's pretty, but it sure isn't soft.
Well, I've been wrong before.
Something bit me!
I'm getting out of here.
It's a people bite!
Well, what do you know?
I'm late for a date.
Hey, Frank.
I was only kidding before
about your singing.
I know you can sing.
Come on up here and prove it.
These are
The good times
While we are young
No chance untaken
No song unsung
These are the good times
Life goes your way
Loving each moment
Of each new day
While the meadows are green
Free as the wind are we
Sharing a dream
Living our destiny
These are the good times
Long as you care
All of the good times
We'll always share
I'm gonna give him a bravo.
He's terrific.
- Oh, you think so?
- Yeah.
Sugar taught him everything he knows.
Sharing a dream
Living our destiny
These are the good times
Long as you care
All of the good times
We'll always
Share
He sings like a bird.
Yeah? Well, let's see
if he can fly like one.
Hey, Frankie, you'd better turn in early.
Tomorrow you make your first jump.
Nice of you to let me know.
Don't let him push you, Frankie.
You're not ready.
Frankie does all right
at everything he tries.
- I've noticed. I think he's ready.
- You're cute. Like a cobra.
I'll see you tomorrow at Big Drop's,
and if you're late, I'll start without you.
- Now get lost.
- Sure.
Are you gonna let him
tell you what to do?
- What would you have wanted me to say?
- You're not only stubborn, you're stupid.
You know, she's got a point.
Lorelei?
Lorelei!
- Frankie, this is wrong, and you know it.
- She's right, Frankie.
- Let's hope not.
- He's so full of pride and integrity.
Yeah, he's full of it, all right.
Look, Dee Dee, I'm not gonna chicken out.
If Steve thinks I'm ready, I'm ready.
- Steve, is he ready?
- It's up to Frankie.
Let's go.
Well, looks like I'm on.
What are you waiting for, chickie baby,
to lay an egg?
So long, Stevie!
There he goes!
Hey, that's way out.
Too much.
That kid's got no guts.
I told you he was chicken.
Frankie, you were just great!
I couldn't have done it better myself,
if I could've done it.
- Which I wouldn't.
- It was wild!
Hey, where's the plane?
I want to do it again.
Hello.
Oh. I made it from the parachute I found
on the bottom of the ocean.
Does it please you?
Well, it's not that, Lorelei.
Oh. Well, mermaids can have legs
for a short time on land.
- I thought that would please you, too.
- You were sure right about that.
- Can we sit and talk?
- Sure.
There's lots of stuff
I need to know about you.
You sure have pretty legs.
For a fish, that is.
- How come you speak English?
- Well, mermaids speak all languages.
We've helped sailors from all the ports
of the world for thousands of years.
I'm not a sailor,
but I was a Sea Scout.
- And I'm sure glad you helped me.
- Well, so am I,
because in all my 300 years,
I've never met a human I really liked.
You're 300 years old?
- Gosh, you sure don't look it.
- Well, I suppose I never will.
You mean you'll always look like this?
Wow!
Well, that means... Just wow!
- How long can you keep your legs?
- Until midnight.
- Then what?
- Well, then I return to the sea.
- You ask too many questions.
- Just one more.
Will you go out with me tonight?
And I want you to meet
a couple of friends of mine. Okay?
- But you won't tell them I'm a mermaid?
- Believe me, they wouldn't believe me.
- I've got to buy you some clothes.
- Clothes. I'll never understand why.
Neither will I.
What size do you wear?
Size?
Well, I guess we'll have to
work this out by hand.
Now, let's see. Bust.
- About like that.
- Do that again. I like it.
Please, Lorelei, I'm busy.
Now, waist.
About there.
And hips.
Well, that ought to do it.
Oh, no. Shoes.
Exactly two for one.
Now, you wait here, Lorelei,
and I'll bring you everything you need.
Bonehead, do that first
thing again, please.
Well...
Lorelei, do you know
about the birds and the bees?
No.
Well, I better get out of here,
or you're gonna find out.
- Wish me luck, Frankie!
- Look, Dee Dee, this is crazy!
I was only putting you on
when I said you wouldn't jump.
Oh, get buster here.
Women can't do anything.
They can't jump.
They can't fly.
Be my guest. I'll show you.
Okay, I'll go.
Just to make sure she doesn't jump.
She'll jump! She's all heart.
I'll show you I'm all heart.
If her chute don't open,
she don't owe me a cent.
Look, Dee Dee,
you don't have to prove anything.
I believe you want to do it.
I believe it, too,
and that's what I have to prove.
I wonder if I'll ever get
the nerve to do that.
I wouldn't advise it.
You'd have too much to lose. Me.
Okay, Dee Dee, step outside
and get some fresh air.
Dee Dee, you're not gonna
go through with this.
You can stop me if you want to, Frankie,
but please don't.
I have to do this for me.
Do you understand that?
- Her chute didn't open!
- She's gonna do a free fall.
Pull it.
She made it.
When a girl makes up her mind,
she gets anything she wants.
- Now we're gonna talk about you?
- Us.
- Somebody's got to drive this thing.
- It's on automatic pilot.
- Now, Bonnie, listen. I...
- You listen.
Here we are, all alone,
way up high.
Just the two of us.
- Yeah, but somebody down there likes me.
- Well, somebody up here likes you, too.
Bonnie, you may have turned it
on automatic pilot,
but I'm not on the same switch.
You don't get all your kicks
from surfing, do you?
Well, of course not,
but this is ridiculous.
It's really wild up there.
She's got the plane on automatic pilot.
- But why?
- It's hard to fly with your arms full.
- No dice, Frankie?
- I'm not even in the game.
Well, I just dealt you in.
Steve won't like this very much.
Look, Bonnie, you're a nice kid.
You don't need all this phony jazz.
I'm not used to having people
say no to me.
Well, that's the trouble.
If more people said no,
you wouldn't act like this.
I'm gonna break him in two.
There's something you should know.
Frankie's small, but he's wiry.
Steve!
Oh, Steve, I just can't tell you
what happened!
I can.
It was terrible, and there I was, helpless,
all alone up there.
- I suppose he put it on automatic pilot?
- Steve, he forced me.
- Come off it, Bonnie.
- Hey, why don't you wise up?
Keep out of this.
Nobody makes a monkey out of me.
Now, wait a second. You listen to me.
This whole thing is your fault.
If you'd get off
the jealous kick with Bonnie,
she wouldn't be looking around.
It's not me she's interested in,
or anybody else. It's you.
That's right. You.
She just wants proof you care about her,
and this is her way of getting it.
So if you really care,
you ought to let her know it
and knock off the silly games.
- Maybe he's right.
- He may be right, but he's gonna be sorry.
Nobody makes
a monkey out of Steve but Steve.
Well, I hope it fits.
The lady in the store
was real nice about making sure.
Okay.
- You like it?
- Wait till the gang sees you.
Let's go!
High heels.
You shouldn't wear them
in the sand, anyway.
Here.
You will have to forgive me.
It's my first time, you know.
Yeah, I know the feeling.
I remember the first time I wore shoes.
It was about a year ago.
They go a lot of places
And they have a lot of fun
Hill climbing in the mountains
Or for a desert run
And when I get a little bike
Now, you can just bet
I'm gonna be a member of the cycle set
I'm gonna take my money
And I'm gonna put it away
And bank every paycheck
when it comes to payday
Dance.
I'm gonna pay it up in cash
So I won't be in debt
Then we'll ride my bike
With the cycle set
Of the cycle set
I saw a little bike
and the price was just right
So I'm gonna take my money
And I'll pick it up tonight
And I'm with a real pretty chick
That I just met
We're gonna ride together
with the cycle set
Come on, Dee Dee, let's dance.
- Let's go, Lorelei.
- Bonehead?
Gee, I don't feel like a bonehead with you.
I feel different.
Tell me more about the
birds and the bees.
Well, it's like when
you get a certain feeling coming over you.
- You mean, like falling in love?
- Yeah, that's it.
And I'm beginning to get it now.
Maybe we'd better dance.
I'm gonna ride my cycle
With the cycle set
If that's dancing,
I'm afraid I can't do it.
Well, when this is over,
I'll ask him to play something slower.
We're gonna ride my cycle
with the cycle set
Earl, I don't know
why you're so crazy about this place.
I just want to do a
little more research.
- Which girl is it, Earl?
- Oh, come on now.
They must've raided the place.
We'll sit over here, Earl.
That's indecent.
They're touching each other.
I knew there was something
about it I liked.
Why me?
Why me all the time?
It's a shame there wasn't soap in it.
It would've been his first bath.
Hey, that was nifty, boss.
You see anything funny in that?
- She likes it.
- What?
It's the Black Plague.
Do you find this type
of fun relaxing?
Start the music!
Where's Sugar?
Where's my idol?
- She ain't here, boss.
- Yeah, we been looking around.
Later we will go get her
'cause I adore her.
Hey, boss, look!
I seen his pictures in the column
in the newspaper I read to you every day.
That's Earl Wilson.
You know, Earl's Pearls.
Oh, sure!
Hey, Earl, how about tossing a pearl?
Before swine?
That's good.
Right like that, he... Him, I like.
You just lost a lot of points, Earl.
Please, do not destroy my mood.
Tonight, I even like you.
Oh, perfect.
I'll save the next dance for you.
I lead.
Come on.
Let's go find my idol.
- It's almost time.
- Oh, yeah. We gotta be going.
Do you have to leave so early?
We're just getting acquainted.
Well, I promised Lorelei
I'd get her home before midnight.
What, does she turn into a pumpkin
or something?
Something like that.
It was nice knowing you.
I hope to see you again.
- Thank you.
- It's nice meeting you.
- Nice meeting you.
- Oh, come on, Goo Goo.
Good night.
- Good night.
- Bye.
- She's a nice girl.
Yeah, but there's something
strange about her.
I don't know. She just seems out of place.
Like a fish out of water.
Okay, now, everybody quiet.
I don't want nobody to wake up my idol
until I wake her up myself.
'Cause I adore her.
- Right?
- Right!
Quiet, will you?
You stupids! This ain't no way
to run a kidnapping.
Sorry, boss.
Do like I do and you
will learn things.
Jerome, fix it.
Follow your leader.
My hat. Where's my hat?
My hat.
Be quiet. Quiet.
Next time I bring you stupids along,
I will go by myself.
My idol fell asleep with the TV on.
Marlo Brandon never
looked like this.
Get her some clothes.
I don't want no idol of mine to freeze,
'cause I adore her.
What are you doing?
I'm glad you asked that question,
because I, Eric Von Zipper,
am putting the snatch on you.
Snatch?
Yeah. I'm kidnapping you,
only it's more romantic, like eloping.
- Did Bullets think this up?
- I, Eric Von Zipper, thunk it up.
- I think it's marvy.
- Nifty.
- You need any help, boss?
- No!
I'd rather do it myself.
Whoa. I may... Gee, she's...
Help me. Help me!
I've always worn this.
Now I want you to wear it.
Bonehead, I love you.
You said what I was gonna say.
Only, why so sad?
- Because we have to say goodbye.
- Goodbye?
I'm sorry.
If I didn't love you,
it would be easy.
But if we love each other,
why can't we take what we have now?
Don't tempt me.
The memory of it would haunt
me for the rest of my life,
and for me, that's a long time.
You know I'm right.
You are what you are,
and I am what I am.
We just don't belong.
Lorelei.
Please don't.
I'm going home now.
Easy, easy. That was good.
This time you even hit the white ball.
See? You're learning.
I bet you them beach bums
ain't never been
in a decent pool hall in their lives.
Are we playing pool, bubby,
or is this all a lousy dream?
There happens to be a lady present.
- I apologize.
- That's nice.
And after you learn pool,
I'm gonna learn you how to cycle.
You're gonna become
Eric Von Zipper's progidy.
- It all sounds marvy.
- Yeah, nifty.
Hey, how would you like a malted?
Sounds super!
Well, why are you standing here?
The lady wants a malted.
Get her a malted!
And make it a double!
A double!
All right, out with it.
What did you do with her?
I didn't do anything.
She went under this wave,
and that was the last time I saw her.
He drowned her.
This brute drowned Sugar Kane!
- Sugar? Who's talking about her?
- Sugar's missing?
I missed her at 8:00 a. m. bed checks.
She's gone!
Know anything about it, Bonehead?
Just 'cause I was burying clothes
doesn't mean
I know anything about Sugar.
Burying clothes?
It is kind of a coincidence.
You have to admit that.
Those were Lorelei's clothes.
Lorelei, the mermaid.
- Mermaid?
- Oh, Lorelei's a mermaid.
Sure. She took her clothes off
and went back into the ocean.
I didn't know what to do
with her clothes, so...
- Oh, what's the use?
- What's the use?
Relax, Bullets. It's all my fault.
Sugar and I cooked it up
between ourselves for a publicity gag.
Drowning as publicity?
- Even I wouldn't do that.
- Look, nobody drowned anybody.
Headlines. "Girl singer disappears.
Found by boy surfers. "
Good for you and
good for us, right?
Perfect.
I should've thought of it myself.
Now, where is she?
Give it a few more hours,
and you'll have her back. I promise.
She'll be on the beach this afternoon
right after Frankie and I do our free fall.
She will?
I mean, she will.
You know something?
You're a good kid, kid.
I'll get right to the papers,
and if anybody asks,
I did think of it myself.
- All right, Bonehead. Now, where is she?
- Well, I thought you said you knew.
I only made up that jazz
to get rid of Bullets.
Now, come on. Let's have it.
Look, Frankie, I'm being honest.
I don't know anything about Sugar.
I took Lorelei home last night
and we said goodbye.
Bonehead, Frankie is only trying to help.
He's your friend.
- He's not even listening!
- Listening? Sure I am.
- Don't you hear it?
- Hear what?
So long.
- See you later.
- Wait a second.
Don't forget what we told Bullets.
This afternoon, she'd better be here.
"Von Zipper?"
That's it.
And with my help,
you're gonna be the best lady pool player
in this entire pool room.
Marvy!
- Before the Rats come back...
- The mice want to play.
- We could kill that kid.
- That's the idea.
Leave it to old Slim. I got ideas,
and they're all vile, baby.
- Marvy!
You're a regular Minnesota Fats.
It's all right, Sugar, I'm here.
- You stupid! I was here first.
- And you're gonna stay here.
Why me? Why always me?
Let's go, Sugar.
You're gonna stay here,
too, bubby.
Come to your daddy.
I'm gonna take you to
my bubby house.
There you go, baby.
I think I'm gonna need some help.
- Anything new with Bonehead?
- Nothing, and I'm worried about him.
It's you two I'm worried about.
Steve's still wigged about Frankie.
Well, why don't you take us up?
I already suggested that
to Steve. No go.
- Oh, what can he do?
- There's a lot he can do.
Hey, here they come!
Frankie, I'm worried.
Do you think
Bonnie might have been right?
My girl's worried.
Any reason she should be?
No reason at all.
Or for you, either.
First one down's a rotten skydiver.
Look at that! Too much.
Oh, out of sight!
We gotta try it.
- Open! Open those chutes!
- What's the matter?
At the speed they're falling,
that water's like concrete.
That's groovy.
Not so groovy.
They opened too late.
Come on! Let's go! Come on!
Lorelei.
Lorelei!
Hey, Frankie, skydiving's groovy,
but let's stick to surfing.
Yeah.
You know something?
A kiss is worth more
than a thousand words.
Then why don't you stop talking?
- All right, where is she?
- Where's who?
You know very well who.
I mean, I brought Earl here
because you said...
Frankie, I found Sugar.
They've got her at that pool hall.
- Who's got her?
- Von Zipper's got her.
Von Zipper?
The Rat Pack social director.
And you promised me...
And I'm gonna keep my promise.
Okay, you guys, let's go!
Cowabunga!
- "Cowabunga?"
- I don't know, Earl, but let's go.
- You know, I've been thinking.
- Watch it, boss.
Where is my idol and South Dakota Slim
and my two mice, Puss 'n' Boots?
First you win the game for me, boss,
and then when
you're nice and relaxed, I'll tell you.
Oh, okay.
Watch this.
There they are.
Let's rack them up!
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
What are we fighting about?
You've got Sugar!
Where is she?
- I ain't got Sugar. Where is she?
- I was gonna tell you, boss.
I got a hunch South Dakota Slim
took her to his bubby house.
- You mean the old sawmill?
- Yeah.
Sawmill? Why, it's right out
of The Perils of Pauline.
It's Pearl White revisited.
We'll see you later.
Follow me. Whistle, whistle.
That's Earl, brother.
Yeah, Earl, while there's still a door.
- Whistle.
- Get them, guys!
Why me?
Why me all the time?
Tasty.
Now the show starts, bubbies.
Fine. Fine! Fine!
You know, the name of this
game is murder, bubbies.
Oh, fine.
This is gonna be good.
I seen this in my favorite picture,
The Perils of Pauline.
I don't think this is very nice.
No, I think it's kind of mean.
Hold it!
No one can criticize old Slim.
I'll show you old Slim
hasn't got a mean bone in his body.
I'm gonna apply
the anesthesia to you, darling.
I've got hasenpfeffer.
I've got a little bit of...
There she is.
This anesthesia works
every time, bubby.
Come on, Sugar, let's go!
Yeah, we may be rotten, Sug,
but we're not this rotten.
It works every time.
What are you doing
with my bubby there?
Step aside, ladies.
That's my Sugar, bubbies.
- You give me back my idol! Right?
- Right!
- Bull's-eye.
- Hey, boss!
Come on!
Sugar, your daddy's gonna
take you to his new lab!
Come on, my little bauble.
- Come here!
- Boss?
Nobody takes my Sugar!
Now you've got yours, bubby!
Why, you...
I'm the king bubby around here!
Come right up and get me!
Where's my little Sugar?
You watch your daddy
operate now, Sugar.
Come on, bubbies!
Hey, bubby!
Here's your daddy!
Come here!
Come on, now! Come on, man!
Why me?
Why me all the time?
I'm gonna give you a little
entertainment. Yeah!
Sugar.
- You all right?
- My hero!
I do all the work and he
gets all the credit.
Well, that's life.
Why are you hitting? Stop hitting me!
Will you let go? You stupids!
Okay, let's go.
What a story.
Surfer saves singer. Singer saves surfer.
Surfer saves...
I'll let Earl string these pearls.
Bonehead,
about that mermaid...
I was kidding.
There never was any mermaid.
The girl who pulled me in this afternoon,
she asked me to give you this.
Oh, here comes Boney.
- Hi, Sugar.
- Hi.
This is so romantic, Bonehead.
It's like we were brought together
by some mystery of the sea.
I knew he was stupid,
but sickening, too?
Was there really a mermaid?
Is there a moon? Is there a sky?
Are there dreams?
Subtitles: Kilo