Treguna, Mekoides
Trecorum Satis Dee
- You, there. Which way to Pepperinge Eye?
- Couldn't say, sir.
It said on the wireless to paint out
the signposts in case the Nazis drop in.
I'm not a Nazi.
I'm a British officer.
That's what you'd say
if you was a Nazi, isn't it, sir?
Drive on, Corporal.
- Sorry to give you so many,
but you do have six bedrooms.
- Oh, no trouble, my dear.
Anything to get the poor things away
from those terrible bombings in London.
Come along, love.
Dear, scoot.
Hey, what about us?
- Oh, yes. What is your name, please?
- Rawlins, ma'am.
Rawlins? Rawlins.
Oh, yes, here we are.
Carrie, Charles,
Paul.
You're for Miss Price.
I'm expectin' her in.
Halt! Who goes there?
I won't be a moment.
Please don't touch anything.
Blast it, fellow!
Put down that ridiculous thing!
Bit of rust comes from
standing in the cellar.
How should I know you is
a British officer?
- Now, what's all this?
- They've just seen Fifth Columns around here.
Claims he's lost,
asking suspicious questions.
Madam, will you tell this man
that I'm Captain Ainsley Greer,
attached to army headquarters
at Tidbury,
and I'm not to be menaced
by that grotesque object!
- Please be calm, Captain.
- I'm exceptionally calm,
if one considers,
as we stand dithering here,
our country is
in the grip of crisis.
There's an immediate
prospect of invasion, however remote,
but dash it, anyway, I choose
this godforsaken part of the country!
Captain, we may have been out of things
for the last few hundred years,
but we pride ourselves on
the history of this village.
May I remind the captain,
during the eighth and ninth centuries,
the marauding Danes frequently
came ashore in this precise area.
Fascinating. Now may I inquire,
who is in charge here?
I am postmistress and chairman
of the War Activities Committee.
Oh, you don't also command
the Home Guard, do you?
I do not. That is
General Sir Brian Tiegler,
late of His Majesty's
Royal Northumberland Fugleliers.
Call out the navy
Call out the ranks
Call out the air force
Call out the tanks
From the Cliffs of Dover
Call up the gulls
And don't forget
the loyal territorials
But who's digging in here
Who will defend
Every inch of England
no matter what they send
Who's standing firm
in our own front yard
The soldiers
of the old Home Guard, that's who
of the old Home Guard
For we wrote the story
of the old brigade
We know the glory
of yesterday's parades
Who's standing firm
in our own front yard
The soldiers
of the old Home Guard, that's who
of the old Home Guard
Parade, ready. Halt!
Permission to dismiss
the parade, sir!
Carry on, Sergeant.
Parade, dismissed!
Captain Greer, sir,
from headquarters at Tidbury,
here to check military
preparations in the area.
Tell them Pepperinge Eye
has matters well in hand.
But nevertheless, I...
What on earth is that?
Good morning, General.
I received your message, Mrs. Hobday.
I assume that my parcel
has arrived.
- It's in the office.
- Ah, lovely.
- Who is that?
- Miss Price. Splendid woman.
Her late father
served with me at Vimy Ridge.
What does she burn in this thing?
It smells a bit like sulphur.
Ridiculous. One can't make
motor fuel out of sulphur.
Here we are- another object
from Professor Emelius Browne in London.
Thank you.
- Is it what you expected?
- I imagine so.
Professor Browne sent you
a cat last time, did he not?
Yes.
- Professor Browne is well?
- I haven't the faintest idea.
Are we to have the pleasure
of meeting him?
I very much doubt it. I don't know
Professor Browne personally.
- Was there something else?
- As a matter of fact, there is.
Would you come this way?
- Well, I'm very anxious
to get home, you know.
- Come along, please.
Get down, Charlie.
I want to ride!
Stop it this instant!
Children, this is Miss Price.
- Carrie, Charles and Paul Rawlins
all the way from London.
- How do you do?
- How are you, miss?
- Hello.
- Hi.
The government are trying to evacuate
as many children as possible into the country.
- Very sensible of them.
- Today they sent us 45.
And I've had to find homes
for all of them at very short notice.
These are the last three. All right,
children, pick up your things.
You're not suggesting that I should
take these children into my house?
- Exactly.
- Oh, I'm sorry, but that's
quite out of the question.
Children and I don't get on.
I believe you, miss.
Come on, back to London.
- Hooray!
- Be quiet!
- Besides, I have work to do.
Very important work.
- Uh, Miss Price.
You do have that
entire house to yourself.
And according to the order of the ministry
of civil defense, you have no choice.
I see. Very well.
If that is the case, I shall take them
into my house with the understanding...
that you find a more suitable home
as soon as possible.
Fine. Come along.
- Uh, good morning, Miss Price.
- Good morning.
There they are! Miss Price,
what a charitable thing you are doing,
taking in these poor unfortunates
from the city.
- Hold this very carefully.
- I wonder, Miss Price,
if I may drop by later this afternoon.
- Why?
- We have their spiritual needs to consider now.
That won't be necessary.
They won't be with me for long.
Ooh!
Upon occasion, one does feel
alarm for Miss Price,
alone, unprotected,
living in that desolate lane.
One does admire her
so tremendously.
One also admires
Miss Price's sturdy house,
the four acres of desirable land and
the fine prospect overlooking the sea.
Does one not?
I shall be frank.
One needs an anchor
of domesticity,
a feeling that one has
a cozy place to return to...
as one fares forth
to do heaven's work.
Oh, how is the vicar?
His wound is better, thank you.
Oh, how marvelous for the vicar...
to be struck down not
in his gathering old age,
but on the field of battle,
bringing in the wounded
and the helpless.
Will you be taking his place?
In the army, I mean.
Alas...
if I only could.
My quinsy, you know.
My parcel, please.
Bring your things inside.
Bit murky, ain't it?
Yeah. Not another house
around here for miles.
Wipe your feet.
Big place, this.
Who else lives here?
I live alone.
It suits my purpose.
All right.
Come along, everybody.
Sorry, miss.
The cat startled us.
No need for alarm.
You just frightened him, that's all.
Yes, scared to death.
You can see that.
- What do you call your cat?
- I don't believe in giving
animals ridiculous names.
I call him Cosmic Creepus,
because that's the name he came with.
You will sleep in here.
This was my father's bedroom, and I want you
to be very careful of everything in it.
- You boys take the bed there.
- All right, miss.
- What was your name?
- It's Carrie, miss.
- Carrie, you sleep on the sofa in there.
- Thank you, miss.
- Is that all you brought?
- We ain't exactly burdened down with frillies.
Travel light, that's us.
Well, I don't think
this arrangement is going to work,
but it seems that
I have no alternative.
- We'll do our best, miss. Really, we will.
- Thank you, Carrie.
The bathroom is along the landing.
Supper is at 6:00.
- You will wash thoroughly-
- Wash?
You will wash yourselves,
otherwise there will be no supper.
Is that clear?
- A house of horror,
that's what we've come to.
I'll get his clothes, okay?
I'll get your clothes.
Please don't bother to whisper.
I am exceptionally keen of hearing.
You are planning
to run back to London.
If you have any more plotting
to do, please do it elsewhere
where I shan't have to listen.
I want you all to sit down after
supper and write to your parents
and tell them that you are well.
- We has no parents, Miss Price.
- Who do you live with then?
Aunt Bessie.
She took care of us.
Still, she wasn't even
a real aunt, was she?
But don't you know anything
about your own parents?
I don't remember anything. Aunt Bessie
knew once, but she don't anymore.
Why is that?
Three nights ago, the bombs
were gettin' a bit close,
so I took Charlie and Paul...
down to the underground
to sleep.
Aunt was working late, and she got home
the same time as one ofJerry's bombs.
I'm sure your aunt
was a very kind woman.
Yes, ma'am, she was.
I'm afraid I don't know much
about what children eat.
You'll have to make do as I do.
Is there anything particular
that you fancy?
Sausage and Mash. Bubble and Squeak.
Toad in the Hole.
Fried fish.
Oh, anything at all.
I'm afraid you won't find
any fried foods in this house.
- No fried food?
- No.
- How do you keep your health?
- What's all that?
Cabbage buds, rose hips,
glyssop seed, elm bark, whortle yeast
and, uh, stewed nettles.
And in the pot there,
mango wuzzle jam.
Mango wuzzle?
Yes, very nourishing.
For what we are about to receive,
let us be truly thankful.
"Dear madam,
with this shipment,
the Emelius Browne
Correspondence College of Witchcraft...
sends you its heartiest
congratulations on qualifying...
for the first degree
of your chosen calling.
You may now call yourself
'apprentice witch'.
Yours faithfully, Emelius Browne".
My first broom.
Time to go.
Everybody up.
Wake up, Paul.
We're going back to London.
Now, let's see
how we fly this thing.
Here we are.
"Clasp the broom
with both hands".
Yes, of course.
"No, never astride the broom".
"Technically a witch
is always a lady,
except when circumstances
dictate otherwise.
Take an easy, graceful,
sideways position".
Of course.
That's much better.
An easy, graceful,
sideways position.
There we are.
How's that?
"Now, to start up the broom,
your basic formula-
Lakipo, Nikrif,
Scrumpet, Leetch!"
I wasn't ready.
"Lakipo, Nikrif, Scrumpet, Leetch".
Now watch this.
Here we go.
Lakipo, Nikrif,
Scrumpet, Leetch!
It's going to be
a little different this time.
All right.
I know it's not ladylike.
Lakipo, Nikrif,
Scrumpet, Leetch!
- Cor!
- What's the matter?
- How does she do that?
- 'Cause she's a witch.
- That's the sort of thing witches do.
- Oh.
She don't fly good, do she?
She's crashed!
Come on!
Now's our chance to hop it.
- Suppose she's hurt?
- Go on! You can't hurt a witch.
Look out!
She's proper cross now.
Let's get away from here.
Hang on.
I'm havin' a bit of a think.
A witch she is, says you.
Then let's use
the old loaf, says I.
- Let's get back to London.
- What we have here is an opportunity.
She don't want anyone
to know she's a witch, does she?
- Not ruddy likely.
- That's the opportunity.
And I intend to
make the most of it. Come on.
- Bran porridge.
- Thank you, miss.
Very healthful, I'm sure.
Hurt your foot, Miss Price?
Oh, just twisted my ankle.
- Sorry to hear that.
- Thank you. It's nothing serious.
Lovely weather
for flying last night.
Why did you say that, Charles?
Game's up, Miss Price.
We know what you are.
I see.
Don't worry, Miss Price.
No one's gonna peach on ya.
Thank you.
I should be most grateful if you
didn't tell anyone in the village.
Of course, there'll have to be one
or two little changes made around here.
I mean, I'd like to see
an occasional sausage on the table here,
a bit of strawberry jam.
- Charlie!
- Let me handle this.
And another thing, Miss Price.
There'll be no more of this
wash, wash, wash, morning and night.
Anything else?
Now you mention it,
I could do with
a bit of lolly.
Lolly?
Cash. Cold, hard cash.
You must have buckets of it.
For your information,
the most accomplished of witches...
can't make money
out of thin air.
Have you ever heard
of a rich witch?
Be that as it may,
you don't want us to blab, do you?
Have you considered
what danger you might be in?
I am a witch, you know.
What will you do, turn me into a toad?
Lovely.
A toad with pink eyes.
I might just do that.
- Go on, then. I dare you.
- Very well, Charles.
- You shouldn't have said that to her.
- She don't frighten me.
She can't even ride
a proper broom.
Excuse me, Charles.
"Filigree, Apogee,
Pedigree, Perigee".
Oh, Charlie!
That's better than a toad.
That's a rabbit!
Bother! I never seem
to be able to manage toads.
Stop! Leave him alone!
- Don't let Charlie get hurt.
- Oh, not to worry.
My spells don't last very long.
I'm just an apprentice witch,
you know.
Look out, Charlie!
You flaming brute!
I'll teach you
to do that to me!
Let Cosmic Creepus alone.
It weren't his fault.
I'm afraid it's my fault. Bad enough
not being able to manage a broom.
I can't perform
a simple, basic spell.
You dared her to do it.
I don't see why we can't all be friends.
- Maybe she's not a wicked witch.
- Of course I'm not.
- See?
- If only I could trust you.
You see, the work I'm doing
is so important to the war effort.
- How do you mean?
- I mean exceptionally important.
Most secret.
What do you say, Charlie?
We can keep a secret.
Yeah. If someone
made it worth our while.
I don't follow.
Simple-you give us
something valuable to seal the pact.
Oh, Charlie,
don't try to be clever again.
It's for her own
protection, ain't it?
If we broke the pact, we'd have
to give back the valuable object.
I think it's an excellent idea.
I wonder what
I could give you.
Would you settle
for one of my spells?
Bet that's not worth much.
Come with me.
I like you better
as a rabbit, Charlie.
- Shut up, you.
- Well, I never had a rabbit.
This is my workroom.
No one has ever seen it before.
Come along.
It's all right.
Careful what you touch in here.
Rum sort of place, ain't it?
When I signed for my witchcraft course,
there was a free bonus...
a certain marvelous traveling spell,
if you paid promptly in advance.
- I think I'll give you that one.
- Is it valuable?
Certainly.
Poisoned dragon's liver?
Poisoned dragon liver.
You mean, you poison the dragon
or just the liver?
Well, it comes prepared.
It's part of the school equipment.
Ah, here we are.
The traveling spell.
All right, everybody,
gather around.
All right, now, let's see.
Does any one of you have a bracelet
or a ring or something...
that you can twist?
- No, Miss Price.
- What about you, Paul?
Always carry a few things
around with me.
Never know when they
might come in useful.
Piece of blue glass,
lovely bit of string.
Horseshoe nail.
- What's that?
- Knob come from the bed upstairs.
- It twists, don't it?
- Yeah, it twisted right off.
Yes, I think that
will be all right.
Carrie, turn the light
down a little bit, will you?
Hellebore, Henbane, Aconite.
Glowworm fire, firefly light!
There. Isn't that pretty?
Is that all we get?
This knob will now work
the famous traveling spell.
And what's the famous
traveling spell?
How does it work?
Well, you take this knob
and put it back on the bed upstairs,
then turn it smartly
a quarter turn to the left.
Then in a firm, clear voice,
tell it where you want to go,
and the bed will take you there.
- Go on!
- Miss Price, will it, really?
Well, I see no reason
to think otherwise.
Oh, thank you
for the lovely gift.
Oh, I'm sorry, but it does belong to Paul.
He's the only one who can work the spell.
- Me?
- Yes.
That's right.
Mine, weren't it?
- That's the way the spell works.
- Nice mess he'll make of things.
Oh, bother.
You children run upstairs.
But mind you don't try anything
with the bedknob until I get back.
Good morning, Miss Price.
I was just admiring the sound
workmanship of your lovely house.
- Yes?
- I was in the village...
and as I was taking
my morning constitutional,
Mrs. Hobday asked if I might...
deliver this letter to you.
Oh, and I must say I did welcome the opportunity
of having another chat with you.
- I always find them so refreshing.
- Thank you very much.
Dear Madame,
it grieves me to inform you...
that due to the war we have been forced
to close down our college of witchcraft.
This means that we shall not
be sending you the final lesson...
in which you expressed
so much interest.
We were wondering what was keeping you.
- I've had some very bad news.
- Is there anything we can do?
No. No, thank you.
Yes.
- Yes, there is something that Paul can do.
- Me?
Paul, I need the bedknob back.
I must get to London immediately.
No, I want to go
to the jungle.
- Oh, I know, but-
- Wait a moment.
- I'll handle this.
- Charlie, be careful.
What you're saying, Miss Price,
is you now wish to take the object...
which you gave
to an innocent child...
and get him mixed up
in some kind of witch's hanky-panky.
Well, yes, in a way, but-
Well, a few odd shillings
might fix matters up, as you might say.
No, Charles.
Money has got nothing to do with it...
and, as a matter of fact,
neither have you.
Come with me, Paul.
Now, Paul, ridiculous as it
may seem to have to explain
this to a six-year-old child,
- but I do need your help.
- Go ahead.
I was expecting
a very important spell in the mail...
from my teacher, Professor
Emelius Browne, and it hasn't come.
What's that got to do
with my knob?
I must go to London immediately
and see Professor Browne.
With his help, we may be able
to bring this war to a successful end.
That is why I need the knob.
What is your decision?
Thank you, Paul.
I brought this for your hair, Carrie.
It may be windy.
Thank you.
Oh, it's ever so nice.
Paul, have you been
to the bathroom?
- Twice.
- Good.
Charles, you better put on something
warmer. The bed may travel quite fast.
I'm not going.
I'm staying right here.
But why, Charlie?
All that rubbish about a traveling bed.
It won't work.
- That's why.
- Carrie, help me to pull the bed out.
We don't want to scratch the wall
when we take off, do we?
Now, how's a ruddy big bed
like that gonna get out of this room...
with those little windows?
I don't know, Charles.
There's a great many things
about magic that I don't know.
We'll just have to find out.
Lovely. Just so's
you leave me out of it.
I don't fancy
making a fool of myself.
What's come over you lately, Charlie?
You're no fun anymore.
Help me to tidy up the bed, Carrie.
We don't want to go to London
with an unmade bed.
- How old is Charles?
- Eleven, going on twelve.
I see. That's what my father used
to call "the age of not believing".
What's that supposed to be?
When you rush around
in hopeless circles
Searching everywhere
for something true
You're at the age
of not believing
When all the make-believe
is through
That's Charlie to a "T."
When you set aside
your childhood heroes
And your dreams are lost
upon a shelf
You're at the age
of not believing
And worst of all
you doubt yourself
Throw that
into the wastebasket.
You're a castaway
where no one hears you
On a barren isle
in a lonely sea
What's that supposed to be,
poetry?
Where did all
the happy endings go
Where can all
the good times be
Everyone on the bed
who's going.
You must face the age
of not believing
Doubting everything you ever knew
The knob, Paul.
Until at last you start believing
There's something wonderful in you
Lovely sentiment,
I'm sure.
- Are you ready, Paul?
- Yes, Miss Price.
Now, when I say go,
tap the knob three times
and turn it a quarter turn to the left.
- Left.
- That's it.
Now, we better hold on tight.
The behavior of the bed
is something I'm not quite sure of.
Here, let me breathe a little.
All right, Paul?
Ready... go.
One, two, three.
Nothing happened.
- That's very odd.
- I told you it wouldn't work.
Of course.
How stupid of me.
We didn't tell the object
where we wanted to go.
Now, Paul, repeat after me.
Take us to Professor
Emelius Browne.
Take us to Professor...
- Emelius Browne.
- Very good.
Headmaster,
Correspondence
College of Witchcraft.
Headmaster,
Correspondence College...
Of Witchcraft, London.
Now, go.
One, two, three.
- Is this London?
- Of course it is.
- Can't you smell that lovely sooty air?
- Marvelous, ain't it?
- Well, Charles, are you convinced by now?
- Not yet, I ain't.
- I don't see no Professor Browne.
- Neither do I, in point of fact.
You children look after the bed
while I make inquiries for Mr. Browne.
I told you this flaming bed
wouldn't work.
- Oh, Charlie, don't start that again.
- It didn't work proper.
- This bed was supposed
to take us to Professor Browne.
- Look!
Professor Browne.
Come on.
Oy, wait a moment.
We can't leave the bed there.
Push.
- Which way did he go?
- I don't know. Let's try this.
- Push!
- Hurry up!
Ladies and gentlemen, gather 'round,
please! Ladies and gentlemen!
Please note the name, ladies and
gentlemen- Professor Emelius Browne.
I am here to divert,
to amuse and, yes, even to help you.
How can I enrich your lives?
My humble talents
are at your command.
Ah, madam,
what have we here?
- You said you were stony broke.
- I don't keep money in me ear.
- It's a trick.
- Yes, madam, a trick.
Or to use a kinder word,
an illusion.
But what isn't,
in these troubled times?
We live in a world
of fakery and false images.
There he is!
It is not what things are.
It is what they seem to be.
Is that not so, madam?
That ain't the kind
of professor I expected.
I'm not sure it's the kind of professor
Miss Price expected either.
You see, it really doesn't matter
what I do, what I do,
as long as I do it...
with a flair.
What effect
a little smoke is.
With a dash of hocus-pocus
and the scent of burning-
And the scent of burning
sulphur in the air.
I'm a fraud, a hoke
a charlatan, a joke
- But they love me everywhere
- Thank you!
Thank you!
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
for my next trick,
may I draw your attention to this
solid piece of ordinary window glass...
framed in an ordinary
unprepared frame.
May I also draw your attention
to this perfectly ordinary steel nail.
Now, I shall place
the framed glass...
in this brown, unprepared- unprepared,
mark you, ladies and gentlemen...
unprepared brown paper bag.
I shall now attempt to drive
the steel nail through the glass...
without breaking the glass.
"Impossible,"I can hear you say.
We shall see.
He ain't very good,
even if he is a professor.
And it really doesn't matter
what I say, what I say
As long as I say it
with a flair
First I rattle off
a ready stock
Of gibberish
and poppycock
And fix you with my best
hypnotic stare
With my moans and groans
and soporific tones
They have cheered me
everyone
For it really doesn't matter
what I say, what I say
I sell it when I tell it
with a "seemus alabeem"
The magicians' nursery rhyme
Abra... cadabra!
You succumb- ooh- to it
every time
Wave a stick
And each trick
Will mystify and disarm
In fact, to coin
a fitting phrase
It works
Ooh!
Like a charm
So it really doesn't matter
what I brew, what I brew
As long as I brew it
with a flair
Though I've never
cast a magic spell
I make the motions
very well
My showmanship
is far beyond compare
I'm a rogue, a rake
a mountebank of fake
But I do
whate'er I dare
What a waste of fresh eggs.
They ain't fresh. Smell.
For it really
doesn't matter
What I do, what I do
You buy my charms and poxes
'cause they come in fancy boxes
To improve your ugly daughter
I've a vial of colored water
And my magic incantations
can be framed as decorations
Though there's really nothing to it
and, of course, you all see through it
You love me 'cause I do it
With a flair
Now, friends, I tell you
what I'm going to do.
I'm going to offer you my entire stock
of magic- No, ladies, please don't go.
The prices are so low,
you will never cease to marvel at them.
Don't leave now and regret
lost opportunities later.
You, young sir, would you care
to warble like the storied nightingale?
With this inexpensive device,
you can charm the very birds
down from the trees, like so-
- How much?
- For you, sir, one penny.
One copper coin of the realm.
Carrie, I'm very surprised at you
wandering off like this.
- We found him for you, miss.
We found Professor Browne.
- Don't work. I've been cheated.
- Is that Professor Browne?
It is, indeed, my dear.
How may I serve you?
Would you be interested in the mating
call of the Brazilian Matouacan bird,
known as the bird of love?
Very useful, eh?
You are the headmaster of
the Emelius Browne Correspondence
College of Witchcraft?
The late headmaster.
The college, alas, is now defunct.
Professor Browne,
I am one of your pupils.
My dear lady, you are, indeed,
an ornament to the college.
- Splendid.
- Not at all.
I was shocked and dismayed...
when you closed down the college
without that most important last lesson.
I'm sorry, my dear. No refunds.
Look at your contract.
But I must have the spell
that comes with the last lesson.
The matter is closed.
I bid you good day.
I have an appointment
at my club for squash rackets.
The matter is not closed.
Don't let him get away.
Righto!
- I got him!
- Leave go of me. Would you mind-
- Would you mind letting go of my leg.
- Flush him out!
Will you get this child off my leg?
Would you get this child-
Filigree, Apogee,
Pedigree, Perigee!
Cor!
Now I trust you'll behave
more like a gentleman.
Look out!
Well, there goes
another rabbit.
- What was that all about?
- I changed you into a rabbit
with one of your own spells.
My spell?
From my school?
Not one of your best spells,
in point of fact.
It doesn't last very long.
Some of your others are much better.
But I don't understand.
My spell?
They were just nonsense words
that I got out of an old book!
Well, they work
perfectly well for me.
They work for you?
Good woman, some kind of destiny
has brought us together.
You got the words for these spells
out of some old book, you say?
Well, more or less.
I changed them around a bit.
I gave them a bit
of my own style, as it were.
The old sorcerers did have
a bit of a tendency to waffle on.
But, dear lady, I never thought
I'd meet somebody like you.
What a treasure.
Mr. Browne, will you please
stick to the point.
I would like to see
this book immediately.
Certainly.
It's at my new townhouse.
Would you care to join me
for luncheon?
We can discuss my ideas
at the same time.
Thank you.
We'd be delighted.
We? Do these three jackals
belong to you?
Well, not exactly.
However, we shall all go together.
- On the bed?
- On the bed, Paul.
Come along.
You go 'round the other side.
I always travel on the left.
Will you give the address
to Paul, please?
May I ask how we are going
to get there on this bed? Fly?
My dear Professor Browne,
with your own traveling spell,
the one you gave
with the course as a bonus.
My traveling spell?
That works as well?
- Just give the address, please.
- 8 Wynchfield Road.
Bed, take us
to 8 Wynchfield Road.
Madam, is this vehicle safe?
Oh, perfectly safe.
A bit theatrical perhaps,
but then most good spells are.
Well, we're here.
I would never have believed it.
You must have given us the wrong
address. You don't live here, do you?
In point of fact, I do.
Temporarily, at any rate.
I found the front door open,
the house was deserted.
Everyone has left
the neighborhood.
Now, why should they do that?
This probably has
something to do with it.
Merciful heavens!
I should think you'd be terrified
at the very idea of living here.
You'd have thought so. I am, by nature,
well, a little bit of a coward.
But then I pondered,
as I often do.
In the perverse nature of things,
this diabolical object...
is probably the best friend
I've ever had.
It enables me, for the first time
in my life, to live like a king.
Shall we go in?
Rothchild '26-noble,
worldly-wise,
but with a charming touch of innocence,
wouldn't you say?
Mr. Browne, the book-
where is it?
Dear lady,
you are relentless.
The book is in the library,
and we shall proceed there after
finishing our cheese and wine.
Why do you keep
the curtains closed?
So that we may enjoy
the gentle glow of candlelight.
More likely so's a copper don't peek in
and catch you hidin' out here.
Now, why don't you young things
have a look around the house?
- I want to have a chat with Miss Price.
- May we?
Yes, run along, children.
But mind you don't touch anything.
Remember, this house
does not belong to Mr. Browne.
Mr. Browne, where is that book?
I must have that spell
on substitutiary locomotion.
What is it, a toy shop?
No, it's a nursery.
Ain't you ever seen a nursery?
No. And neither have you.
And what is
substitutiary locomotion?
Substitutiary locomotion
is the ancient and mystic art...
of causing objects to take on
a life force of their own.
Why are you
so interested in that?
Because I know that it
can only help the war effort.
- I must see the nature of the spell.
- Precisely, my good woman.
But now you must
hear my ideas.
What are you reading?
Isle of Naboombu.
- Can't be no such place.
- There is too such a place.
These pictures prove it, don't it?
Bit weird, though, ain't it?
Animals wearing hats and things.
Oh, I like it.
Uh, would you
hold this, please?
What do you think of that?
Well, I don't know
what to think.
Miss Price, just think
how successful I could be...
with an assistant
who can really do magic!
- Oh?
- Dear lady,
have you ever considered entering
what some of us call "show business"?
The what business?
The theater! Pantomimes!
Village fairs, the seaside.
Brighton, Blackpool,
Follies on the Prom!
Mr. Browne, I have
very important work to do.
Listen to me.
We could make a package.
Let us strike a bargain
You possess a gift
But I can speak the jargon that will
give your gift the needed lift
- Oh?
- You possess the know-how
And I command
the show-how
Oh, how successful
you could be
With me
- I'm afraid we're wasting valuable time.
- What's your name?
- Miss Price.
- No, no. Your first name, my dear.
- Eglantine.
- Eglantine?
Eglantine
Oh, how you'll shine
Your lot and my lot
have got to combine
Eglantine, Eglantine
Hark to the stars
Destiny calls us
The future is ours
As the shine sells the boot
and the blossoms the fruit
All you need to succeed
in your plan
Is the proper ally
upon whom to rely
And I'm your man
For I have an acumen
that's nigh superhuman
I sell things
that nobody can
So I humbly suggest
you accept my behest
I'm your man
- Eglantine, Eglantine, oh, how you'll shine
- Mr. Browne!
- Mr. Browne, will you please stop it?
- Your lot and my lot
- Have got to combine Eglantine, Eglantine
- Mr. Browne!
- Do you hear me?
- Hark to the stars
- Destiny calls us, the future is ours
- Mr. Browne, I'm warning you.
With my expert pantomiming
The proper taste
and timing
I'll introduce you
in the manner grand
I'll whet their appetite
for you
I'll set the scene
so right for you
We'll have the beggars
eating out of your hand
As the words
sell the tune
And the moonbeams
the moon
All you need to succeed
in your plan
Is a champion
reared with a flourish
And a flair
And I'm your man
Do stop prancing about.
There's serious work
to be done.
I have always had a bit
of a knack for witchcraft
Common spells and simple charms
came naturally
So when the war began
I conjured up a plan
To do my bit
in the national emergency
I enrolled in your
Correspondence College of Witchcraft
And I slaved at every lesson
as it came
But the spell I counted on
is the lesson that is gone
It's disappeared
and you're the one to blame
Your suggestions are rash
and your manner is brash
And I've no time to waste
Mr. Browne
If I am to proceed
it's that book that I need
Don't let me down
But if you'll see me through
I'll discuss it with you
Though I've no taste
for playing the clown
If I meet with success
then I might acquiesce
I won't let you down
Eglantine, Eglantine
Oh, how you'll shine
Your lot and my lot
have got to combine
Eglantine, Eglantine
Hark to the stars
Destiny calls us
The future
Mr. Browne, I'm warning you!
I warned you, Mr. Browne.
Now, where is the book?
Well, where is it?
At last, Mr. Browne!
The Spells of Astoroth.
Of course.
Oh, here's the traveling spell.
This is where you got it.
Does one's nose
have to twitch like this?
Oh, you're back,
Mr. Browne.
Miss Price, a word
about your tactics.
I don't mind being changed into
a hawk or a tiger or something
with a bit of dash to it,
but always a fluffy, white rabbit-
it's intolerable!
Ah, here we are.
Substitutiary locomotion.
"The ancient art of..."
etcetera.
"The spell which creates
this force...
is five mystic words.
These words are..."
But the rest of the book
is missing!
Now you see why
I closed down the college.
- But where are the other pages?
- I haven't the foggiest.
- Listen to me, Mr. Browne!
- I'm all ears.
You will be if you don't pay attention.
Where did you get this book?
Oh, I bought it from a chap
in the street market.
There was a bit of unpleasantness,
as a matter of fact.
He claimed that I'd given him
a dud coin, I ask you.
There was a sort of scuffle.
The book tore.
He got one half and I got the other.
- Where's the other half now?
- Oh, it's probably been thrown away.
- But if it still exists, there's
only one place to find it.
- Where is that?
Portobello Road
Street where the riches
of ages are stowed
Anything and everything
a chap can unload
Is sold off the barrow
in Portobello Road
You'll find what you want
in the Portobello Road
- Rare alabaster
- Genuine plaster
A filigreed samovar
owned by the czars
- A pen used by Shelley
- A new Botticelli
The snippers that clipped
old King Edward's cigars
Made in Hong Kong.
Two bob a dozen, would you say?
- Waterford crystal
- Napoleon's pistols
Society heirlooms
with genuine gems
Rembrandts, El Grecos
Toulouse "Lautrecos"
Painted last week
on the banks of the Thames
Very interesting.
But where do they sell books?
There's a little place
around the corner.
Portobello Road, Portobello Road
Street where the riches
of ages are stowed
Anything and everything
a chap can unload
Is sold off the barrow
in Portobello Road
You'll meet all your chums
in the Portobello Road
Lovely to see you.
Good-bye.
What I want is the other
half of this book.
All in good time,
my dear.
There's pure inspiration
in every creation
No cheap imitation
Not here in me store
With garments as such
as was worn by a duchess
Just once at some
royal occasion of yore
You look charming, my dear.
In Portobello Road
Portobello Road
The fancies and fineries
of ages are showed
A lady will always
feel dressed a la mode
In frillies she finds
In the Portobello Road
Burke's Peerage, The Bride Book
The Fishmongers Guidebook
I'm looking for
the other part of this, thank you.
A Victorian novel
The Unwanted Son
You don't understand.
I'm not interested in that book.
- The History of Potting
- The Yearbook of Yachting
The leather bound
Life of Attila the Hun
Portobello Road, Portobello Road
Street where the riches
of ages are stowed
Artifacts to glorify
a regal abode
- Are hidden in the flotsam
in Portobello Road
- Here!
Who do you think you are,
the Queen of Sheba?
Tokens and treasures
Yesterday's pleasures
Cheap imitations
of heirlooms of old
Dented and tarnished
Scarred and unvarnished
In old Portobello
They're bought and they're sold
Tokens and treasures
Yesterday's pleasures
Cheap imitations
of heirlooms of old
Dented and tarnished
Scarred and unvarnished
- In old Portobello, they're
bought and they're sold
- This good lady is looking...
- for the other half of this book.
- It's called The Spells of Astoroth.
I don't keep no torn
or damaged books here.
What do you think I am,
a ruddy waste paper merchant?
You can eat like a king
in the Portobello Road
I think, if I'm right, there's
another bookstore along here somewhere.
Grandpa, you don't expect
to sell a piano like that, do you?
Let me have a go, my dear fellow.
- Oh!
- Portobello Road, Portobello Road
- Yeah! Go on!
- All kinds of things are happening
in Portobello Road
You feel like a ballerina
when you're hopping like a toad
When you kick your heels up
down in Portobello Road
- Come on!
- Oh, yeah!
Go around the drum now. Yeah.
Yes, play the drums.
Come on!
Oh!
You missed me.
Come on, dance.
Come on, girls.
Lovely.
Closing time!
Closing time. Closing time.
Closing time.
Bye.
- Bye.
Portobello Road
Street where the riches
of ages are stowed
Anything and everything
a chap can unload
Hey, governor. Oy, tosh. Somethin'
for the lady friend? Nylons?
- No, thank you.
- Petrol coupons?
- Chocs for the little ones?
- No.
How about one of these, mate?
Fell off the back of a lorry.
- Do be a good chap and run away.
- Would you fancy this, then?
Ah. Now you have my undivided attention.
What can I do for you?
You are to get over to the Bookman
straightaway. He wants to see you.
- You too.
- Who is the Bookman...
and what right has he got
to order me about?
Under the circumstances, we better
ask questions later. Excuse me.
Half a mo- Why am I pushing
this here flaming bed?
Because, my friend, this magnificent bed
once belonged to the Duke of Wellington.
- You see?
- I ain't sure I do.
It is extremely valuable, and I wish
to give it to the Bookman as a present.
- All right, all right.
I'll push the blasted thing.
- I thought you would.
- Who is it?
- I brought the woman.
- And him as well.
- Well, send 'em in!
- In you come.
- Right. In we come!
Sorry, gov.
No one told me about the stairs.
Why didn't you just
bring Scotland Yard, Swinburne,
and half the household
cavalry as well?
- What's the bed for?
- It's a present for you. That's what he said.
Nothing of the sort!
The bed belongs to me.
Except for this knob,
which is mine.
Be that as it may, Bookman, there's
been bad blood between us long enough.
Let this glittering gift
begin friendship anew.
- Draw the curtains and lock the door.
- You'll be snug as a bug.
Mr. Browne, isn't that
the section of the manuscript
that we've been looking for?
- Who is this person?
- Miss Eglantine Price,
a charming young woman
of my acquaintance.
Miss Price, I've been looking
for this other bit a long time.
Mr. Swinburne told me you were
in the market making inquiries.
And here we are.
I don't mind saying,
to see it all together at last,
there isn't much I wouldn't do.
Or haven't done, for that matter.
Right, gov?
You'll close your mouth,
Swinburne! Is that clear?
It's all rather like a jolly
detective story or jigsaw puzzle,
isn't it?
We're both after
the same spell.
You have one clue,
I have the other.
Yes. In that case,
the sensible thing seems to be...
for us to cooperate.
Yes. I'd rather cooperate
with a cobra.
Would you prefer
that I ask Swinburne...
to take the book from her?
Here, you.
None of that.
- Bookman.
- Yes.
I assume you're looking
for the same thing I am.
May I?
This is quite a moment
for both of us.
"Substitutiary locomotion,
the lost miracle of the ancients".
And so on and so forth.
Ah! Here we are!
"The spell which creates
this force is five mystic words.
These words are-"
"Engraved on the star
that was always worn...
by the sorcerer Astoroth".
But where are the words of the spell?
I assumed they'd be in
your half of the manuscript.
But I thought they'd be in yours!
Once again, a dead end.
I shall never know
the secret.
Isn't that old Astoroth?
And there's his star.
It's a pity it's so small
you can't read the writing.
- But why the animals?
- Towards the end of his life,
Astoroth kept animals in cages
and searched for the spells...
that would make them
more like humans.
The legend is that finally
the animals rebelled at the experiment,
killed Astoroth and stole
many of his powers.
- Including the star with the spell on it.
- Possibly.
They found a ship, sailed away
and were never heard of again.
However, there's a final notation
in my half of the book...
saying that
in the 17 th century...
a shipwrecked lascar
was taken from the sea,
half mad with thirst
and exposure to the sun.
Before he died, he swore he had seen
an island ruled by animals.
- Where?
- There is, I regret to say,
no such island.
I looked for it
in every chart.
The Isle of Naboombu
does not exist.
Oh, it does too!
Got me own...
- What is he trying to say?
- Nothing.
When he don't say nothing,
he mumbles.
I wish the child to speak!
Now you've done it.
There is too such a place.
Got me own book. There.
Real pretty letters, ain't it?
Let me see it.
You're not interested, Bookman.
It's just a simple children's book.
- I'll be the judge of that. Give it to me.
- No.
Please don't annoy me.
- Give me the book, boy.
- Not likely.
Bit of a stalemate,
isn't it?
If it's all the same to you,
I'd rather use me own.
Sentiment, you know.
Come along, Paul.
I believe it's time to go.
Go? How, my dear?
The door is locked.
Observe the fundamental weakness
of the criminal mind.
- You will believe in no one or anything.
- I understand. The knob, Paul.
- Right.
Of course you do, my dear.
Do you realize we can
tell them the complete truth?
They will believe nothing!
- He's up to something, you know.
- Bookman!
Before your very eyes,
I shall cause this bed and all
the occupants upon it to disappear.
Disappear? I should like to see
a cheapjack tenth-rate entertainer...
do a trick like that.
Cheapjack entertainer?
Now, that was naughty.
- All right, Paul.
- Where to?
To the Island of Naboombu.
I'm very curious about that place.
Good. Bed, take us
to the Island of Naboombu.
Enough of this nonsense.
Get the book.
Beastly climate.
I never did fancy the sea.
- Where are we?
- Naboombu, of course.
I ain't never seen no island
like this before.
I'm afraid we may have
fallen into the lagoon.
That's right.
Here we are, on page three.
Hi, Mr. Codfish!
Hello, young fellow.
Welcome to Naboombu Lagoon.
Now I'm hearing things.
Fish don't talk.
Not too bright, is he?
- He's me brother.
- Oh? Sorry.
Mr. Codfish, where is
the Island of Naboombu?
You mean the land part?
Oh, that.
Straight up.
You can't miss it.
None of my business, of course,
but I shouldn't go there if I were you.
- Having troubles, they are.
- Troubles?
He's right, you know.
A lot of trouble.
Well, trouble or not,
we should be getting along.
- I wish to see who is in charge.
- What's the rush?
It's really rather splendid down here.
For you, my dear.
Oh, thank you.
How pleasant-
Bobbing along, bobbing along
On the bottom of
the beautiful briny sea
What a chance to get
a better peep
At the plants and
creatures of the deep
We glide
Far below the rolling tide
Serene
Through the bubbly
blue and green
It's lovely bobbing along
Bobbing along
On the bottom of
the beautiful briny sea
What if the octopus,
the flounder and the cod...
think we're rather odd?
It's fun to promenade
Bobbing along
Singing a song
On the bottom of
the beautiful briny sea
Look!
It's lovely
bobbing along
Bobbing along on the bottom
of the beautiful briny sea
What a chance
to get a better peep
At the plants and creatures
of the deep
It's grand
When you're dancing
on the sand
Each glance
Bubbles over with romance
It's lovely bobbing along
Bobbing along
Through the water
where we get along swimmingly
Far from the frenzy
of the frantic world above
- Two beneath the blue
- Could even fall in love
Bobbing along
Singing a song
On the bottom of
the beautiful briny sea
Bobbing along
Singing a song
On the bottom
of the beautiful briny
Shimmery, shiny
Beautiful briny sea
Bravo! Bravo!
Most exciting!
You've won the Ruddy Cup.
Help! Help!
Uh-oh. Oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
This time I really
got a whopper!
Whew!
People? People?
Oh, no!
What scurvy luck!
- My goodness!
- I'll deal with this, my dear.
- Don't you know that...
- Good day, Captain.
I used to be a bit of
a seafaring man myself.
Many's the time
I've shipped out of Portsmouth.
Delighted to meet
a fellow mariner.
Oh? Now, stow it, mate!
- Oh, really!
- Can't you read readin'? Huh?
Uh, it says, um,
"No peopling allowed".
No peopling allowed?
Ridiculous.
Don't antagonize him,
Mr. Browne.
That means I got to ta- ta- ta-
throw you all back,
that's what it do!
Wait a minute! It says here
that anybody can see the king.
And that's the law.
Where do it say that?
Here, in me book.
So it do.
What?
Da- Da- Da- But if you people
know what was good for ya,
- you'd get yourselves all-
ta- ta- ta-
throwed back!
The king don't like people!
Nonetheless, we must see the king
on an urgent personal matter.
Please lead the way.
But just don't say
I didn't warn ya, see?
Uh, follow me.
You're all from some clipper
that flies the black ball
To me, aye-yaye
Blow the man down
I'm a peace-lovin' sailor
and that sure ain't all
Blow, blow, blow the man down
Get out of here!
Yes. Yes.
What can I do for you?
I, uh, caught some people
down at the Sea Lagoon.
They want to see the king!
Really? Well, we can't be bothered
with that sort of thing now, can we?
I don't know that I fancy this.
His Majesty
is in a frightful rage.
Excuse me, sir.
As an all-around entertainer of sorts,
I am considered not without talent.
Perhaps I can cheer him up.
No, no, no, no, no.
You don't understand.
As everyone knows,
His Majesty is the world's
greatest soccer player.
But due to a technical problem,
the Royal Cup match
cannot take place today.
And His Majesty had so
set his heart on it.
Throw these...
oh, creatures
back into the sea.
Aye, aye, sir.
Just a moment.
I can help.
Do you really think so?
I'd be most grateful.
Do you know soccer?
Do I know anything
about soccer?
Why, I was captain
of the Totnum Hotspurs for two years,
three seasons
with Manchester United.
- Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes. You'll do.
- Before that, I...
Come this way, please.
Mr. Browne, are you certain
you'll be all right?
Now what?
Not an ideal person
in many respects,
but Mr. Browne
is a very brave man.
Do you think he's done for?
Do ya think so?
Ar, can't tell you
how I appreciate this.
For some reason,
we have great difficulty...
finding referees 'round here.
If there be one thing we like,
it's volunteers.
Eh, birdy?
Har! Har! Har!
He's a proper king.
Look at his crown.
What's he got 'round his neck?
What a magnificent...
ornament, Sire.
Ar, yes. Well.
Wouldn't be without it.
Been in the family for years.
The Star of Astoroth.
You're to sit
in His Majesty's royal box.
No littering, no chewing, no fruit
or wrappers from boiled sweets, please.
Rise, please.
Loyal fans,
this is official!
We have a volunteer referee!
Let the match begin!
He's still wearing it.
Right. Dirty Yellows,
let's have a nice, clean game.
Right. True Blues,
best foot forward.
Weird sort of game they play here.
Hurry up!
Get rid of it!
Gracious!
You're doin' fine, matey.
Move it around. Move it around.
Get on with the match!
Ya-hoo-hoo-hoo!
- Foul! Foul!
- They're only animals.
That's no excuse
for dirty football.
Ohh!
Ref, are you blind?
Be quiet, Charles.
Don't forget who the referee is.
Ooh!
Don't they have no rules?
'Course they do. The king
makes them up as he goes along.
Poor Mr. Browne.
Do you think he's all right?
Well, he's moving.
Steady, matey.
Move it around.
Tsk! Oh, he almost
had it then.
Looks like he's done for this time.
Don't just stand there!
Hit it in!
Stop... that... ball!
Goal!
Ha-ha!
Game's over.
I win!
Ah, let me give you
a hand, matey.
That's quite all right, Your Majesty.
Thank you so much.
Oh, please, let me help you on
with your robe.
Why, yes. Thank you.
Thank you. Yes.
Can't have you catching cold,
Sire, can we?
Why, no, no.
Have you ever heard of something
called the "gypsy switch"?
No. Can't say that I have.
Remind me to tell you
about it sometime.
I can't tell you
when we've had such a good time.
We'll carry the memory of Your Majesty
in our hearts for a long while.
I think it's time to leave.
Aye. Must you go?
We must be dashing. Marvelous game.
Lovely to see you. Good-bye.
- Good-bye. Come along, children.
- Good-bye.
Good-bye.
Friendly lot.
Hee-hee-hee.
Don't mind them visitin'.
Wouldn't want 'em livin' here.
- Come along, children.
- Come on, children. Hurry up.
Oh!
Stop gibberin'!
What's the matter with you?
Your royal star!
They've stolen
your royal star!
Har, har, har, har!
Don't be ridiculous.
What do you think this is?
Why... didn't you...
say... so?
All right, Paul,
put the knob on the bed.
At last, the magic words:
"Treguna, Mekoides,
Trecorum Satis Dee".
I'll keep it.
Women always lose things.
- Hurry, Paul. The knob.
- It's stuck.
- I suppose I better do something.
- Please, do. Quick.
Got it.
Filigree, Apogee, Pedigree-
Oh, bother!
I do hate shoddy work.
I don't suppose I shall ever
get used to this thing.
Children, will you push
the bed back into place, please?
I think we could all do
with a nice cup of tea.
Oh, no time for that. I've gone to
a lot of trouble to find this spell.
I'm going to try it immediately.
Mr. Browne, kindly let me
have your shoes, please.
My shoes?
Oh, fine.
- What's the shoes for?
- Really, Charles,
if you'd been paying attention,
I should think you'd be aware
that substitutiary locomotion...
is the art of causing inanimate objects
to take on a life force of their own.
Obviously, I must have
inanimate objects to experiment with.
Makes sense, don't it?
Stand back, everyone.
I need plenty of room.
I want you all to be
absolutely quiet.
- Mr. Browne, you have
the Star of Astoroth, I believe.
- Oh, yes.
It's in my nice, clean hanky.
It's all right, Mr. Browne.
I should have realized
that it would be quite impossible...
to take an object
from one world into another.
If only I would've had the sense
to remember the words on that star.
- I know the words, Miss Price.
- Don't bother Miss Price. She's thinking.
Charlie, why don't you and I nip down
to the village and get something for supper?
And I might conceivably
call into the pub for a pint...
to steady my nerves.
- Trebonna-
- I do know the words, Miss Price.
Come along. How can you know
the words when Miss Price doesn't?
Fre- Frebunna.
- You wish to put this
on Miss Price's bill?
- That is correct.
I don't believe we've met.
Oh, allow me
to introduce myself.
I am Miss Price's teacher,
Emelius Browne, from London.
Professor Browne.
Of course!
Oh, how many times I've seen your name
on your packages to Miss Price.
Oh, extremely masculine
handwriting.
I should have known.
Professor Emelius Browne.
- The very same.
- I'll confess somethin'.
Such was the nature and frequency
of your correspondence with Miss Price,
I ventured the hope there was somethin'
of a personal interest between you.
If there only were.
Miss Price is a fine woman.
I most heartily agree.
We're very fond of her here.
- I'm sure.
- In point of fact,
how many times
I've said to myself,
"Oh, fortunate is the man
who can secure Miss Price for a wife".
Well, one could
say that, yes.
You yourself
are not married?
Alas, no.
These are strange and fearful times
in which we live, my good woman.
Who could ask someone
you cherish...
to share such
an uncertain future?
Very well. Don't say I didn't
warn you, Professor Browne.
One of these days-you mark my words-
someone will come riding out of nowhere
to seize and carry off Miss Price...
- before your very eyes.
- I shouldn't be surprised. Charles.
Good morning.
And who was that,
may I ask?
Professor Emelius Browne
from London.
He's come to see Miss Price.
A very good friend, I understand.
Oh. Indeed.
- That Mrs. Hobday seemed to fancy you.
- Shh, shh, shh!
- I consider her a very dangerous person.
- What, her?
Mrs. Hobday is that most dangerous
of species: a matchmaker.
Troop movements and massing of barges
in French and Dutch channel ports.
The prime minister has told the nation
to be on the alert...
for signs of a possible invasion.
That was the news-
To think I might have been able
to do something about all this.
It's out of your hands now, my dear.
If only I could've remembered
those words. It's maddening.
Why don't someone ask me?
Come off it, Paul.
You can't remember those kind of words.
You mean like
Treguna, Mekoides,
Trecorum Satis Dee?
Treguna, Mekoides, Trecorum Satis Dee?
How do you know that?
Easy. Says so
right here in me book.
You mean it was there
in your book all the time?
Yeah. But nobody
ever listens to me.
Treguna, Mekoides,
Trecorum Satis Dee.
Nothing happened!
Am I doing something wrong?
Well, to tell you the truth,
it does seem a bit old-fashioned.
- After all, we are in the 20th century.
- What do you suggest?
Well, it needs rhythm,
tempo, music.
As I always say,
"Do it with a flair".
- Do you mind if I have a go?
- Oh, of course not.
Now, come along, you lot.
We need all the help we can get!
Treguna, Mekoides
Trecorum Satis Dee
- Treguna, Mekoides and Trecorum Satis Dee
- Substitutiary locomotion
- Mystic power that's far
- Treguna, Mekoides
- Beyond the wildest notion
- And Trecorum Satis Dee
- It's so weird, so feared
- Treguna, Mekoides
- And yet wonderful to see
- And Trecorum Satis Dee
- Treguna, Mekoides
- Substitutiary locomotion
- And Trecorum Satis Dee
- Come to me
Shh! Now.
Treguna... Mekoides...
Trecorum Satis Dee.
Cor!
Treguna, Mekoides
and Trecorum Satis Dee
- I don't want locomotiary
- Treguna, Mekoides
- Substitution
- And Trecorum Satis Dee
- Or remote
- Treguna, Mekoides
- Intransitory convolution
- And Trecorum Satis Dee
- Only one precise
- Treguna, Mekoides
- Solution is the key
- And Trecorum Satis Dee
- Substitutiary locomotion
- Treguna, Mekoides
- They must be
- And Trecorum Satis Dee
Treguna, Mekoides
and Trecorum Satis Dee
Substitutiary locomotion
Lovely substitutiary locomotion
You've made
substitutiary history
With Treguna, Mekoides
and a little help from me
And Trecorum Satis Dee
Lumme!
Mr. Browne,
what is going on here?
I haven't the foggiest.
How do you do?
Oh, shall we?
- That's my nightgown!
- Is it really, my dear?
Yes, and I'm not responsible
for its behavior.
Obviously not, my dear.
Paul, what on earth
are you doing?
Havin' a jolly good time,
that's what.
- How can we stop all this?
- Must we? It's really most agreeable.
Yes, but we must do something.
Didn't I give you my all-purpose
cut-off spell? Lesson number eight.
- Number eight!
- Yes, number eight, I think it was.
Oy, me Sunday trousers!
Buzz off, old chap.
Find your own dancing partner.
Be careful, Carrie.
Slow down!
Charles!
Mr. Browne,
will you please control your shoes!
Dear lady, I very much fear
that we have nothing under control.
Do you mind?
Now, who would like some more
of my lovely Sausages and Mash?
- Oh, no more for me, thank you.
- Oh. Carrie?
It was very good,
but I've already had two helpings.
- I'm full.
- Me too.
Well, at least
somebody wants some.
Cheer up, my dear. This should be
something of a celebration.
I'm sorry. There doesn't seem
to be much to celebrate.
I still haven't mastered
that spell.
Of course you have. You just need
a little more practice, that's all.
- Do you really think so?
- No doubt about it.
Meantime, there's nothing to liven the
spirits like a little masterjuggling.
- Right, Charlie?
- Go on then, gov! Give us some juggling!
Very few better than me at this.
All you need is 20 years practice
and a touch of genius.
It's never happened
to me before.
I don't usually juggle
with cats under my feet.
Look, she's laughing.
Oh.
Oh, Mrs. Hobday, do come in.
I can't stop, my dear. I've just
come by to bring you the good news.
- Good news?
- Yes, yes. Mr. Bissethwaite
who brings the milk, you know?
Well, he's promised
to take the children in.
He and his wife have got that farm.
Just the place for growing children.
Put a bit of color
back in their cheeks.
Why, what's the matter?
I thought you'd be pleased.
You told me yourself that you
were much too busy, you had
no time to take care of children.
Well, circumstances
have changed somewhat.
That's right.
We got a dad now.
- Mr. Browne.
- Paul.
Miss Price, is this true?
Of course. You do want him to stay
with us, don't you, Miss Price?
I suppose I hadn't
really thought about it.
What about him?
What do you say about it, Mr. Browne?
Well, it's all rather sudden.
I don't quite know what to say.
Oh, then I'll leave
you two to talk it over.
Oh, I'll come back in the mornin'.
Yes, good night.
- Good night.
It is true, Mr. Browne. You are going
to be our father now, aren't you?
Well, uh, we...
We are rather rushing things,
aren't we?
Perhaps Mr. Browne has other things
besides you children to think about.
Yes, well-well, as a matter of fact,
I should've left ages ago.
I must get a train
back to London tonight.
It's, uh- it's rather an
important matter, as a matter of fact.
I'd like to tell you about it,
but it's, uh, a little bit hush-hush.
You know, sort of a secret.
Well, uh, if, uh...
If I've been any sort of help
to you, I'm pleased.
You've been immensely kind.
Thank you.
And I've enjoyed
being with you.
Perhaps it's been good for all of us.
Will you be coming back?
Someday, my dear.
I, uh, certainly hope that
we shall meet again someday...
when all this war business
is over.
I see.
And then, perhaps, I shall
realize my fondest dream-
Eglantine and Emelius,
illusionists extraordinary.
Just think how that'll
look on the poster, huh?
Uh, the children
are going to miss you.
- You really think they will?
- Yes.
Well, I shall miss you-
all of you.
If I don't go now,
you might never get rid of me.
Good-bye, Carrie.
Must you really go?
Yes, I- I think it's best
for everybody. Good-bye, Paul.
I still think you
should be our father.
Good-bye, Charlie.
- Do you want me to come down
to the station with you?
- No.
No, you stay here
and look after everybody.
- Good-bye, Miss Price.
- Good-bye, Mr. Browne.
No one to miss
if he's gone too long
No one to comfort
if things go wrong
That's how
I want it to be
Nobody's problems for me
No one who needs me
to ease his pain
No one to call me
his ball and chain
Nobody's problems for me
And that's how
I choose it to be
No troubles and strife
in this life that I lead
No tempers to humor
No hungers to feed
No one to warm
when the winter's cold
No one to pamper
No hand to hold
And that's how
it always will be
No
Nobody's problems
For me
When is the next train
to London, please?
Lord bless you, sir.
There ain't no train.
Nothin' 'til milk job,
4:00 a. m. tomorrow morning.
- Mind if I waited here?
- You suit yourself. Good night, sir.
Good night.
Out you go, Cosmic.
Hello? Hello!
Hello!
Hello?
Emelius Browne, do you know
you could be warm and cozy...
in that house
at this very moment?
For once in your useless life,
you really seem to have been needed.
You're a failure, Emelius Browne,
and a coward.
No, fraulein, this is not the invasion.
Just a little exercise.
A minor raid to induce panic
and to spread a little mischief.
When you English
get it through your head...
that the German forces can land at will
whenever and wherever we please,
perhaps you will consider
a reasonable peace.
Not bloody likely!
Go on, Miss Price.
Do it to him.
I must say,
it's very tempting.
Colonel, how would you feel about
being turned into a nice, white rabbit?
I said, how would you feel about being
turned into a nice, white rabbit?
Be quiet, please!
Filigree, Apogee, Epigee-
Not again!
Your memory, Miss Price.
Charles, would you kindly fetch
my notebook from the workroom, please?
Righto.
Let go of that child this instant!
Silence!
Fraulein, we have work to do.
I am sorry, but I must send
all of you someplace...
where you will no longer
be a nuisance.
As the words sell the tune
And the moonbeams the moon
All I need to succeed
in my plan
Is a champion rare
With a flourish
and a flair
Oh.
Eglantine.
Where's the spell for rabbits?
Easiest of all, she says.
Confound it. Can't women ever learn
to file things properly?
Ah, here it is.
"Filigree, Apogee, Pedigree, Perigee".
That's it.
Filigree...
Apogee, Pedigree, Perigee.
Now, come along, my boy.
Just for once in your life,
you've got to believe in something.
That's it.
Good lad.
Filigree, Apogee,
Pedigree, Perigee.
Now, what's the use of putting the children
and me in that drafty castle?
It's quite chilly, you know.
Because, fraulein, the colonel believes when
the British female decides to become a nuisance,
she can become
the greatest nuisance in the world.
And I'm inclined
to agree with him.
You need a lesson in manners, Sergeant.
If I only had my notebook,
I'd make certain you'd learn a few.
Jumpin'Jehoshaphat! MoreJerries.
- Take it easy, can't you?
- Try holding your breath.
I am holding it.
We could strip him down
and grease him with soap.
No, it's no good.
He can't do it.
I could've told you that
in the first place.
If we can't get Paul out to give the alarm,
we'll just have to think of something else.
- What about that spell that
makes things move about?
- Oh, but I need weapons.
How 'bout all these things?
I'm afraid they're
a bit ancient.
Where did this come from?
It's Mr. Browne,
that's who it is.
Oh, he's on his way to London.
Mr. Browne?
If you are Mr. Browne, would you be
kind enough to get down off my lap?
It is Mr. Browne!
It is you!
You didn't think that
I could do that spell, did you?
Oh, I am glad to see you.
But what about all these Germans?
Well, as Charlie says, "What's wrong with the
substitutiary locomotion spell?"
- That ought to be useful.
- No, but it isn't ready yet.
- You saw what happened this afternoon.
- Well, we have to chance it.
We can't let these so-and-sos get away
with their beastly little raid.
Mr. Browne, won't you get up
off the floor, and we'll go to work.
Herr Oberst!
- Jolly good luck, my dear.
- Thank you, Emelius.
- Let's hope you haven't
forgotten the spell, Miss Price.
- Oh, not this time, Charlie.
Found this in the castle.
Probably not a magic broom, but it
might make you feel more at home.
Well, thank you, Carrie.
That was very thoughtful of you.
Come now, children.
Let's get out of Miss Price's way.
Treguna...
Mekoides...
Trecorum...
Satis Dee.
Look!
Sound the advance!
Just in time for the kickoff.
Steady on the left.
Victory for England
and St. George!
It's like a Lord Mayor's show.
Pikemen, hold your distance!
Treguna, Mekoides
And Trecorum Satis Dee
and Trecorum Satis Dee
Fire!
Blimey!
- Where's it coming from, Sergeant?
- Sounds like the sea road, sir.
- Come on, lads, after me!
- Come on! Fall in, lads.
Good shooting, bowmen!
Well caught, sir!
Very good!
Knock his block off!
That's it!
Mr. Browne, make those children
take cover this instant!
Are you still there, Colonel?
I thought you'd be
on your way by now.
You see? Things may not
be so easy for you after all.
Good-bye, Colonel.
Eglantine.
Oh, Eglantine.
Dear Mr. Browne.
Miss Price, we thought
they'd damaged you.
See? No one
can hurt Miss Price.
There they are, lads!
I sensed something was afoot.
All right!
Drive them into the sea!
Firing positions, you fellas.
Both sides.
All right, men.
Hold your fire.
I think we've taught
the Hun a lesson.
He'll think twice
before coming back here again.
It's tragic.
All your spells, your equipment-
all gone.
Still, I was able to perform
some small service first.
That mean you ain't
going to be a witch no more?
- Never?
- No, Paul.
I realized some time ago
that I could never be a proper witch.
When was that? Was it that first
magic moment when you laid eyes on me?
No. It was the day
my poisoned dragon's liver arrived.
I knew then that anyone...
who felt the way I did
about poisoned dragon's liver...
had no business being a witch.
- You're certain you're doing the right thing?
- Well, I think so.
The way things are, it's
much too dangerous being a civilian.
- Take care of yourself, gov.
- I'll do that.
And I'll be back
before you've grown an inch taller.
- We'll be together again.
- Sounds like you have an escort to the station.
Parade, halt!
Well, here we go.
- Permission to move off, sir.
- Carry on, Sergeant.
Parade, by the right.
Quick!
March! Left! Left!
Left, right, left!
Suppose that's it.
We ain't gonna have
no fun no more.
Well, still got this,
ain't I?
Call out the navy
Call out the ranks
Call out the air force
Call out the tanks
From the Cliffs of Dover
Call up the gulls
And don't forget
the loyal territorials
But who's digging in here
Who will defend
Every inch of England
No matter what they send
Who's standing firm
in our own front yard
The soldiers of
the old Home Guard, that's who
The soldiers
of the old Home Guard
I don't mind saying,
to see it all together at last,
there isn't much I wouldn't do.