Summer's here, it's a holiday
School is out,
now it's time to play
Just get the schoolbooks
out of reach
We're gonna go
to Bikini Beach
That's it, that's right
That's where the fun is at
All the chicks are bikini clad
Oh, yeah!
That's it, that's right
That's where the fun is at
All the chicks are bikini clad
We're on our own,
we're on our way
The gang's all heading for a holiday
A lot of girls and
a guy for each
Come on let's go
to Bikini Beach
That's it, that's right
That's where the fun is at
All the chicks are bikini clad!
That's it, that's right
Keep the short shorts
out of sight
That's it, that's right
Gonna be, who needs short shorts?
Beach party tonight
That's right
Come on. Let's hit it!
Come on, let's go.
This should keep the wolves
away from our door.
Hey, isn't there some way
we can lock this thing?
From the inside or the outside?
What's the matter, Animal,
don't you trust the boys?
It isn't that. I don't trust me.
Hey, Candy, who do you have
to know to get into girls' town?
I'm available.
I bet you this is what you
had in mind. Huh, Animal?
Okay, Candy, put him down.
That Candy really has the power.
Dee Dee?
There's a moon out there
and it's calling us.
I don't hear anything.
All right. The moon isn't calling
but the waves are.
We can go sit by them
until we get the message,
while the children sleep.
Frankie, you go listen
to the moon and the waves.
Until I hear wedding bells,
I’m children too.
You win some.
You lose quite a few.
- Oh, Bixby's Bird Farm!
- Oh, Cora, will you...
Oh, all right, all right.
Holy hot curl!
Girls, come here!
I wanna show you
something. Hurry up.
Wake up, you guys.
Wake up, hurry up.
- I wanna show you something.
- What is it?
Throw your eyes at that!
The Sheik of Araby
has pitched his pad among us!
Might be a mirage.
Let's go give it the
double “O,” huh?
Hey, what's a double “O”?
Once over, Goo Goo.
Come on, you guys.
It's the Potato Bug!
He's here!
They've all gone beetle
over a Potato Bug.
That ain't no mirage.
Dee Dee, I think we associate
with a very unstable group.
Come on. It won't do any harm
to have a look.
Don't tell me you've flipped over
that crumpet eater.
Well, they say he's
very nice, personally.
Personally, I can live
without finding out.
Well, I can't.
I must insist you be
as quiet as possible.
His eminence is sleeping.
His eminence?
- Are you his girl or something?
- No.
My name is Yvonne,
but I am called Lady Bug.
I am the Potato Bug's bodyguard.
Oh, yeah.
- Who guards your body?
- I do.
What if some big handsome brute,
and I'm not naming names,
figured he'd make some
time with you?
Why, you and I, we could make some
beautiful music together.
Why, just come on
into these arms, baby.
- Hey, that's something!
- It’s called Savate.
- Sa-who?
- Savate.
In French, that means
the art of foot fighting.
You know something?
She can do with her feet
what Candy can do with her...
- Giant ground swells!
- ...hips.
Wake surfing!
- This is it, huh, Dee Dee?
- Sure, it is, for now.
Our forever is right now.
- But what about tomorrow?
- Tomorrow is the day after today.
Frankie, there's a real tomorrow.
You gotta think about that.
Sure, I'll think about it.
Tomorrow.
You know something?
I got a feeling
somebody's watching us.
I get the strangest feeling.
Something's wrong around here.
Yes, indeed.
You gotta have a
rhythm when you dance
When you gamble,
gotta take a chance
But when you wanna
try a little romance
Then love's a secret weapon
Well, Clyde, they're doing your dance.
Take a little chance
and look him in the eye
All you gotta do is give it a try
Yes, love's a secret weapon
So come on and take my advice
You'll find...
Clyde, Clyde, watch the paint.
Clyde, stop.
It’s time you started to believe
That's how Adam was
won by Eve, oh!
That's the secret of
the whole affair
Give a little love
and tender care
If you're gonna get him
and keep him there
Then love's a secret weapon
So come on, take my advice
Well, you'll find that
love is kind of nice
It’s time you started to believe
That's how Adam was
won by Eve, oh!
That's the secret of
the whole affair
Give a little love
and tender care
If you're gonna get him
and keep him there
Then love's a secret weapon
Yes, love's a secret weapon
Yeah!
Hey, there's a monkey!
Hey, hey! Look!
I thought the Potato Bug was taller.
Hey, I was right.
That monkey was watching us.
Clyde. Come along, Clyde.
Give them back their ball.
All right, Clyde.
All right, Clyde. Clyde!
- Hey, Tarzan! Where's Jane?
- Let's go check.
Clyde, come on.
Clyde, Clyde, Clyde.
Come along. Come along.
Come along, Clyde.
Clyde. Clyde, come here.
Clyde!
Now, may I ask whose board
this happens to be?
- It’s mine.
- Oh, really.
- Well, may I use it?
- Be my guest.
- Clyde?
- Hey, hold it, now. No, no.
Son, just step back.
Watch, please.
I assure you.
Everything is all right.
Look at him.
- Oh, come on. What is this?
- No way. No way.
Well, he's paddling
at least. Not bad.
You gotta be kidding!
- He made it!
- Hey, look at that!
- It’s fantastic!
- Great!
Hey, look at him!
Look at him turn! The bottom turn!
- Hey, Deadhead, he's better than you!
- Better looking, too!
Yeah!
- A headstand? That's it.
- No more. That's it.
Marvelous, yes.
- Did you enjoy Clyde's performance?
- Oh, yeah.
He's a real sharp chimp.
Well, I’m afraid you're missing the point.
You see, the point is not
whether Clyde is sharp.
The point is that the intelligence
of you young people has fallen to his level.
What's he talking about?
I’m determined to prove that you
young people are borderline cases,
leaning toward feeble-mindedness,
with an abnormal
preoccupation with sex.
- Well, yeah!
- That's all right.
The only display of knowledge
being of a carnal nature.
Would you mind repeating
that in English?
Quiet, Goo Goo.
You photograph quite well, Clyde.
Well, that's rather good,
don't you think?
- That's not bad. It’s kind of cute.
- Yeah, it's cute.
- Well, who are you, anyway?
- Harvey Huntington Honeywagon.
- I'd keep that quiet if I were you.
- The Third.
Oh, you got the old folks' home
down by the beach.
Sea-Esta by the Sea
is a resort for senior citizens.
And your irresponsible
behavior has...
been a blemish on
that fine community.
And I intend to do
something about it.
- Hey, Frank, put him in his place!
- Wait a second! Wait a second! Look.
This is a public beach.
And just what do you think
you're gonna do something about?
Well, you read tomorrow's paper,
under this picture.
Those of you who can read, that is.
Hey, man, I went to school.
Come on, Clyde. Come on.
The nerve of that clown!
Yeah, he looks like something
out of The Twilight Zone.
Imagine, comparing us to monkeys.
Deadhead, you might
be the missing link.
Oh, I say there!
Over here.
- It’s the Potato Bug!
Look at him! There's nobody
in the whole world like him!
- Oh, I wouldn't say that.
- I would.
Yes. That was a jolly good show.
Yes, jolly good indeed.
That simian creature, most amazing.
Positively remarkable!
Did you come here
for surfing, Mr. Bug?
Oh, no. Crumbs, no.
Not enough speed, really.
Oh, yeah? Did you ever
see a real hot dog...
hit the big wild ones
at 80 miles an hour?
I’m afraid I don't
quite understand...
your Yankee-type
colloquialism, old chap.
A hot dog is a surfer, Potato Bug.
A hot dog's a surfer.
I thought you all spoke English
here in the colonies.
- Oh, it's not required. It’s an elective.
- Oh.
I mean, 80 miles an hour
really isn't very fast at all.
Oh, well, what would you call fast?
I don't know. Two hundred.
Two hundred and twenty.
That sort of thing.
Where it's a teensy-weensy
bit frightening,
with a spot of danger involved.
Yes. Well, I'd be delighted to show
you chaps tomorrow if you'd like.
Just come over to the drag strip.
- Hey, you got a rail under there?
- Oh, quite.
Little hobby of mine, you know.
Jolly good fun. Yes.
But you 80-mile-an-hour chaps
might find it a bit too devilish.
You might just find
we can be pretty good.
Hey, let's get off this kick.
Maybe the Potato Bug
will sing something for us.
Right-o. Just a few measures.
Ooh, I don't wanna
be the richest man
Ooh, yeah, yeah!
All I wanna do is hold your hand
Riches won't buy you everything
I just want what love can bring
Ooh, give me your love!
I don't want what
money can buy
Ooh, yeah, yeah!
Come on, little girl
and I'll tell you why
Ooh, yeah, yeah!
Money won't buy you happiness
All I need is your sweet kiss
Ooh, give me your love
Now that you know what
I’m searching for
Ooh, yeah, yeah!
Say you'll be mine forevermore
You know I gotta
find a love somehow
Say you're gonna
make me happy now
Ooh, give me your love!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
There now, that ought
to be sufficient.
I'm really not one of
my fans, you know.
I knew we had something in common.
Something in common?
Oh, yes! Quite humorous.
If you want to take it that way.
It's time for your midmorning tea,
your eminence.
Oh, yes.
For the days when I was just plain old
Peter Royce Bentley of Sussex.
Oh, well. That's the price
one must pay, you know.
Cheerio, cheerio.
Let's go, lassie.
To the office, Clyde.
Watch where you're going, Clyde!
Charlie, tell me I didn't see
a monkey driving that Rolls.
I’m not gonna report that to headquarters.
They'll think I’m crazy.
I’m not gonna report it.
Captain will think I’m
back on the sauce.
Let's take another look, huh?
It’s a monkey all right.
Sarge?
Sarge, you're not gonna believe this.
But Charlie and I are tailing a Rolls-Royce
that's being driven by a monkey.
No, no, Sarge, by "monkey",
I don't mean some kind of punk.
I mean a real, live, furry...
Right, Sarge. Right.
Okay, Sarge. Right.
What'd he say?
Promised not to tell the captain
if we'll go get some black coffee.
You know, that monkey drives better
than my mother-in-law.
Come to think of it,
he's better looking too.
Just because he pushes a rail, big deal.
Any grease monkey could learn that.
- Even you.
- Yeah, even me.
Great. Now you've really found
a sure way to kill yourself, drag racing.
Speaking of drags, I have the
feeling I’m with one right now.
Frankie, if you want to learn something,
why don't you learn to get yourself a job
now that school's out,
or learn to settle down?
Oh, you're suggesting a slow death.
No thanks. When I go,
I wanna go in a hurry.
Me, too. Goodbye.
- Oh, I say there. Having a spot of bother?
- Oh, it's nothing.
Oh, bit of a row with
your frankfurter, eh?
What seems to be the problem, love?
He's got suicidal tendencies.
He wants to be a dragster.
Bit of a sticky wicket, what?
I mean, a chipper filly like you
shouldn't be a poor widow.
Oh, I agree.
What would you say
about being a rich one?
What do you mean?
Well, I wouldn't mind
having you for my bird.
- Bird?
- Girl.
You're no different than he is.
Oh, fiddlesticks and rubbish.
I’m rich, you know.
- Money isn't everything.
- It is to a widow.
- Yeah.
- Come along, duck.
Let's have a spot of tea, eh?
- Well, why not?
- Yes.
"Why not?"
- Eighteen million!
- Yes.
Bit of a slow day.
Oh, well. Carry on. Come, love.
Great. A Potato Bug, a chimpanzee
and now this.
My cup runneth over.
"Today's teenager true sub-culture."
"Youth of today leaves
no hope for tomorrow."
"Yesterday, in broad daylight,
in a place illegally called Bikini Beach,"
"we were witness to scenes
of wild perversion"
"and abandonment that defy description.
"The solution is for the county
to condemn the surfing area."
"By making this facility unavailable
to these potential delinquents,"
"we could persuade them
into more useful endeavors"
"than studying each other's anatomy."
"It might be fitting to warn
responsible parents"
"who grew straight and tall by
building our character on the three R's,
"that our children have progressed
to the three S's,
"surfing, speed and sex,
not necessarily in that order."
I do turn rather a handsome phrase.
I’m sorry, sir. I tried
to stop her but she...
How dare you break into my office!
Don't you "how dare" me.
How dare you print this vicious article
against these vacationing kids.
It’s untrue and I demand
to speak to your publisher.
Madam, I am the publisher.
Please identify yourself
and explain this outburst.
You may go now, Miss Simms,
and please go gently.
This editorial has no basis in fact.
Now, who are you?
And why do you get so wrought up
over these juvenile delinquents?
- They're not juvenile delinquents.
- I resent that.
And I resent these lies.
Look, I’m a schoolteacher
and I know these kids.
Those surfers are building
strong, healthy bodies,
and together with
the boys who build the dragsters,
they'll be responsible
for tomorrow's rockets to the moon.
Well, now, that doesn't auger too well
for the future, does it?
Well, what's wrong with physical fitness?
You should try it sometime.
I do not deplore physical fitness,
but I do deplore half-naked young ladies,
if they may be called that,
running around in these scanty bikinis.
Imagine, boys and girls
sleeping on the beach,
side by side, unchaperoned.
Now, what kind of a society is it
that would allow such a thing?
And what kind of a mind is it
that's always ready to believe
there's something wrong?
You need an education, madam.
Well, it's miss. Miss Clements.
Are you willing to devote an afternoon
to seeing the truth?
Is that a challenge?
In that case,
it would be a pleasure.
Very well. I shall take you
to a teenage haunt known as
Big Drag's Pit Stop.
Ball.
Quiet, or you'll wind up on the menu.
Ball three.
Ball too high.
One more crack out of you
and you'll be today's special.
I just call them as
I see them. You bum.
What a mess.
Answer the door.
I’m closed.
I’m Harvey Huntington
Honeywagon III.
In that case, I’m open.
- What do you think this is, a zoo?
- One would assume so.
- That's Frieda, my bird.
- Oh, and this is Clyde.
- How do you do?
- And Miss Clements.
- Hello.
- Oh, rather unkempt, I should say.
- I've been cleaning up.
I always clean up in the daytime
because I always clean up at night.
Oh, then I assume you are
the person known as Big Drag?
Yeah. That's me, Big Drag.
Pleased to meet you.
Oh. Oh, excuse me.
I also dabble in the arts.
Well, Mr. Drag, we're on a mission.
A crusade, you might say.
Well, I don't think there's enough room
in here for a crusade.
Did you read the paper this morning?
Particularly an article
about the youth of today?
Sure, first thing.
Right after the comics.
Won't you sit down?
We're closed, but
I guess we're open.
So, why don't somebody buy something?
Well, I’ll have a martini.
We don't serve booze in Big Drag's.
Notice there are no cigarette
machines around either.
This is strictly for kids.
Beer and soft drinks.
I’m with you, Big Drag.
Make mine a beer.
And I shall have a soft drink.
Straight or over the rocks?
One beer.
Mr. Drag, I understand you're quite
an authority on the youth of today.
You mean kids?
I see them all day at the drag
strip and all night here.
Well, then you shall
be able to help me.
That article you saw
in the paper this morning
was one of a series I’m doing on the
depravities of the youth of today.
What depravities?
Did you ever see the kids
at the drag strip?
Certainly not.
- Did you ever see the kids that come here?
- Of course not.
Then the authority I am, you ain't.
My dear sir, I am not accustomed
to being treated so cavalierly.
Nor was my father,
H.H. Honeywagon II,
nor his sainted father,
H.H. Honeywagon I
You sure come from a long line
of Honeywagons.
In other words,
you have nothing to say to me.
Not in front of everyone.
Oh, Clyde.
Yes, I do have one thing to say.
don't like the way your Clyde
is looking at my bird.
Well, I don't like the way your bird
is looking at my Clyde.
Stop playing with my bird.
Now, come along. Come along.
Come along, Clyde. Come along.
- Stop it!
- Good day, sir!
Clyde.
I should stay closed.
It’s better for business.
Hey! My paintings are
not for sale, sir.
There's part of me
on those canvasses.
It hurts me to see anybody look
at them like they might buy them.
I’ll get it.
Who was that?
He's a famous art dealer.
He's been after my stuff for a long time.
But I won't sell.
Big Drag is for the ages.
Someday when I’m gone,
some proud collector will say,
"Look at this! It’s a real Drag."
My place!
- Done it again, boss.
- You stupid. Fix it.
Hey, you. Stupid. Fix it.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- What do you want?
What's going on here?
What is that... What is that all about?
What's going on?
You'll kill somebody!
Will you guys watch it?
You're gonna hurt somebody.
Hey! Eric Von Zipper likes you!
And when Eric Von Zipper likes
somebody, they stay liked.
Hey, I think I heard about you,
the creature from the black lagoon.
- You, I don't like.
- Yeah. You, he don't like.
- And who are you?
- J.D.
Yeah. That's short
for juvenile delinquent.
Later you will get the Rats' revenge.
Right now, I wanna talk to you.
You are my idol.
I seen your picture in the paper
and I read your article.
J.D., he read me your article.
But I loved it.
Look who's on your side.
I seen your picture, too.
Clyde, quiet!
You know, what you said
about them surfers is right.
They are bums.
And we are gonna
stamp them out together
'cause the surfers is the natural
enemies of the Rats and Mice.
- Right?
- Right.
- Surfers is giving us a bad name. Right?
You and me, we're a team,
and we're gonna destroy them.
Together, with violence!
Well, I had in mind something
of a more legal nature.
You see? Everybody likes you.
You got friends,
and we're gonna stick by you.
What is that bit about
water seeking its own level?
Birds of a feather and all that.
Sir, I consider you a member
of the lower classes.
You're right.
How'd you know that?
You know, I went all the way
through the third grade.
You are my idol.
And you know something?
The Rats and Mice are behind you.
And now, Eric Von Zipper is hungry.
- What would you like?
- I don't know.
Like, maybe a bird sandwich.
No! I’ll get you salami.
it’ll be 70 cents.
Hey, I don't think
you understand me.
Eric Von Zipper don't buy.
He takes.
That's not nice.
I think I’m closed.
You are push me too far.
Now you get the Rats' revenge.
- No, but wait. But, but, but.
- No buts!
- You gonna hit him, boss?
- Yeah, I’m gonna hit him.
But, but, but!
No, no! Help!
Are you...
Hold his mouth, too.
Now, you hold his bird.
Well?
He's got a very nasty bird, boss.
- Well, then, just forget it.
- That's some pal you have.
Just hold him now.
Just hold him.
- What, what, what?
- Unhand this man, sir!
Tell your Rats I don't want
this gentleman molested.
Release him this instant.
You may be my idol, but nobody,
nobody tells Eric Von Zipper nothing.
You see, as long as
the Finger ain't here,
Eric Von Zipper is the king.
Who is the Finger?
- There was a fellow here last year.
- Professor-type fellow.
- And he made with the finger.
- Called it a technique.
- Yeah. Something like the Hima...
- Layan.
Layan. Himalayan
suspenders technique.
Very potent type of
Zen karate thing.
Yeah, what he used to do,
he used to take his finger, see?
- And he would put it by my head...
- Watch it, boss.
Don't worry.
I ain't gonna do it.
See, he would take his finger,
but you had to have a special kind
of brain for this. See? And I have one.
He would take his finger and he
would put it alongside my brain,
and then he would push it and...
The boss did it again.
He gave himself the finger.
- I think he stripped his clutch again.
- Hey, boss.
Get this stiff out of here.
When Big Drag speaks, he commands.
Away, away!
Frieda, are you all right?
Gently, gently. Don't break him.
And stay out!
Von Zipper will return with an army!
- I think I'm gonna like you, Harvey.
- Why?
With him for a friend,
you don't need me for an enemy.
They call that drag racing?
I don't see them dragging nothing.
Man, you sure you wanna
go for this bit?
Yeah, Johnny. I’m gonna go for this bit.
I’m gonna go all the way.
The winner, Dave Wilkins
in his scalloper.
Time, 8. 10 seconds
at 188.66 miles per hour.
It’s the Potato Bug! Hi!
He acts like he owns
the whole world.
Hey, there! What time do
you leave for the moon, Bug?
Oh, jolly good.
Your frankfurter has come
to see me perform.
He's a chipper sport, he is.
Must be a bit of English
blood there, I say.
I have the feeling he's here
to check on my performance.
I wonder what she sees in that
fugitive from a barbershop.
Those rails are all
smoke and noise, man.
Hi there..
It’s a great honor to
have you here, Mr. Bug.
Sorry I couldn't meet you, but
I thought I'd clean up a bit.
I own this place.
I’m Big Drag.
Well, it's a pleasure
to know you, Mr. Drag.
- Absolutely top hole.
- Yeah.
Well, you can call me Big, Potato.
- And you can call him Mr. Bug.
- Oh.
The reason I’m here, old chap,
is that I want to try out my new rail
and have a shot at your
world record, you know.
What is that?
It’s England's revenge
for the Boston Tea Party.
Well, are you about set, Potato?
I mean, Mr. Bug.
I’d be crackers if
I weren't, old boy.
Be at the ready at
all times, you see.
Carry on regardless and
all that sort of rot.
He sure looks good
in that silver suit, though.
Yeah. I wonder how he'd
look in that ambulance?
Then, we're off and sailing, eh?
Yeah. I’ll go shine up a trophy.
Ladies and gentlemen,
your attention, please.
As a surprise attraction,
Peter Royce Bentley,
better known as the Potato Bug,
will attempt to break his world record
for the quarter-mile drag.
It’s a bird.
It’s a hunk of iron.
Anybody could handle that.
Friends, gang! Listen to this!
The time, 7.9 seconds,
202.3 miles per hour!
A new world record!
Here's your trophy, Mr. Bug.
See where I signed it? Big Drag.
Oh, jolly decent of you, Big.
- Here, ducks. It’s all for you, love.
- But I didn't do anything.
You might have to.
That's a loving cup, you know.
Well, that sounds like a good idea.
Only it should come from him.
Good, oh. Good, oh.
Congratulations,
and I’d like to challenge you.
You josh.
I wouldn't if I were you.
I’d simply carry on
with those surfing sticks
you frankfurters are so fond of.
I mean it.
When I’m ready, I want to race you.
Good show. I like
that sort of spirit.
Simply toss me the gauntlet
when you're ready
and we'll have a go at it.
You see?
Will everyone please
clear the track?
We have a new contestant,
a mystery driver.
Oh, well, it's off to tidy up a bit.
Later, ducks, eh?
Ladies and gentlemen, the Potato Bug's
record has just been broken!
The mystery driver set
a new record!
Time, 7.1 seconds at
203 miles per hour!
Now, Miss Clements,
one moment please.
Excuse me.
I have something I
wish to show you.
I’m not so sure
I want to see it.
You are the new champ, sir.
I got that feeling again.
There's a monkey suit
with a real monkey in it.
Hold it. Hold it.
Hold it.
There you are.
It’s like Frankie said,
anybody can learn to drive one.
What were you trying to do?
Make monkeys out of us?
You think we ain't got honor?
You think we ain't got dignity?
Well, no offense, sir.
I’m just trying to prove a theory of mine.
This is an insult.
Would you like to have
your picture taken, sir?
For the front page of the newspaper?
- For the paper?
- Yes.
- A picture of me?
- With him?
- Yeah.
- I’ll buy that.
- Oh, that's fine.
Now, just you put
your arm around him.
Very friendly. Oh, boy, that's right.
Oh, that's wonderful.
There we are.
Well, my dear.
What do you think now?
So you taught a monkey to drive.
But he didn't build the machine.
He didn't create anything.
But I did.
I created the impression
that teenagers live in a simian world.
And I believe I created some doubt
in your mind. Isn't that right?
Only of your sanity.
Excuse me, but I’d like to talk to
someone about getting myself a rail.
That's me. Big Drag.
You better ask him about learning
how to drive one of those things, too.
- Yeah. He wants to be a drag, like you.
- You've come to the right place.
- How much money do you have?
- 100 bucks.
100 bucks?
I can let you have
this for 100 bucks.
- Well, maybe we could fix it up.
- Oh, I don't know.
Well, I gotta be fair about this.
Something I should tell you
before you buy it.
The brakes pull bad to the left.
The steering wheel's loose
and the clutch slips.
And you need two new rear tires.
And you shouldn't pull
out the choke.
- Why not?
- Because it releases the parachute.
Now, look.
Doesn't anything work on this car?
The radio's kind of nice.
Maybe somebody could loan me a
rail or I could rent one.
Hey, you look like a
fellow I used to know.
- His name was Jack something.
- Yeah. I used to be Jack Fanny.
had a string of musclemen
whose muscle was mainly in their heads.
But I got out of the fanny business.
That's all behind me now.
I can show you a model
over here you might like.
This is a rail.
It’s not a rail
like you think a rail should be.
It’s a rail because
it's the principle of motorocity.
Now, let me give you a few
of the basic principles of motorocity.
Which is the wheel?
The wheel is round, as you see.
The reason the wheel is round,
is that round wheels are round,
and the rounder the wheel, the better.
They're the best kind, you know.
Since a long time ago,
we discovered that square wheels
didn't work well.
So you see, squares are squares
and wheels are wheelers.
Now, when we think wheel,
we think round.
- Have I made myself clear?
- Yeah.
Well, how come they call
that thing a rail?
You don't understand
English, do you?
All that greasy kids' stuff
has softened his brain.
- Would you like a demonstration?
- Yeah.
Come on.
Roll it out.
It’s the wrangler stretch!
Oh, I say, this is
a jolly good show.
The entire establishment is leaping!
- Is that how one puts it, my dear?
- You're close.
The translation is,
"The joint is jumping."
Oh, yes. Oh, yes.
Good show. Good show.
- Clyde likes it.
- I’m happy for him.
And now I take great pride
in proudly presenting The Pyramids.
Looks like a bug,
laughs like a hyena.
Well, they all stand up
as he idles by
Gonna cheer him on
for the record try
Best rails here from
every state now
Everyone knows
the competition's great now
Record run, record run
Pardon me, lady.
Miss Bug?
Would you care to hit the boards
with little old Deadhead?
Merci, Monsieur Head.
It seems to be one of
your native dances.
You will have to teach me.
Yeah, yeah. I’d just love
to go native with you.
Record run, record run,
record run
Enjoy. Enjoy, love.
Hurry back.
The music of the youth of today
is straight out of the jungle.
The tree is green
there isn't any doubt
We're gonna see...
The savage music that stimulates
their post-adolescent
preoccupation with sex.
You sure love that three letter word.
Record run, record run
These children
are nothing more than animals.
Come off it, Harvey.
They're having fun.
"Fun", now, that's a three-letter word
I bet you never heard of.
- Come on, let's join them.
- I’m here strictly as an observer.
I have a feeling
you've always been an observer.
Let's not be vulgar.
I think I’m gonna ask Clyde to dance.
At least he's enjoying himself.
Well, of course he is.
Everything here is down to his level.
If he's having such a good time,
maybe we should give him a real treat.
I bet he'd go ape at
the Coconut Grove.
Hey!
Well, you got no worries now.
Eric Von Zipper is right with you
to protect you
in case them beach bums
give you any trouble.
I don't know how you
got so lucky, Harvey.
Yeah. Oh, by the way,
I want to apologize.
I’m sorry I was not out at the
drag strip to protect you today,
but I just woke up
from that Himalayan suspenders trance.
- Really? How can you tell?
- Oh, it's easy.
See, every time
I give myself the finger... Oh!
I better not, 'cause I gotta keep
my mentality on the alert to protect you,
'cause you are my idol.
What? Oh! Hello, Clyde.
Nice to see you again.
You know something, Clyde?
I could get to like you
'cause you're my kind of people.
You shouldn't have said that.
He's very sensitive.
Oh. Oh, I... I'm sorry, Clyde.
Well, nothing to worry about.
I’ll be right over there with my rat pack
in case you need any help.
You are my idol.
Beach bunnies, surfers and dragsters,
it gives me great pleasure
to give you great pleasure.
Big Drag is proud to say
that right here in the middle of our midst
is a famous, well-known celebrity.
I guess you all know
who I’m talking about.
We want Potato Bug!
By George, this is jolly good of you.
Makes me feel super, don't you know!
This is an unexpected pleasure
we didn't expect, Mr. Bug.
I’ll put it in my memory book
if I don't forget.
Thank you, old sport!
- Ooh!
- How about that?
- Hey, you've got lips
And those lips they
need kissing
Hey, little girl,
how about kissing me? Ooh!
- You got love.
- How about that?
And your love I’ve been missing
Hey, little girl,
how about loving me?
- How about that?
- Ooh!
I’ve been waiting a long,
long time
For a little girl like you
Now at last you're
gonna be mine
Tell you what I’m
gonna do, ooh
- I love you
- How about that?
All my love I’ll be giving
Hey, little girl,
how about loving me, too?
- How about that?
- Ooh.
Ooh
How about that?
I’ve been waiting
a long, long time
For a little girl like you
Now at last you're
gonna be mine
Tell you what I’m gonna do
All my love I’ll be giving
Hey, little girl,
you're the girl for me
How about that?
Hey, little girl,
you're the girl for me
- How about that?
- Ooh!
Hey, little girl,
you're the girl for me
How about that?
- How about that?
- Ooh
Good girl. Good girl.
Yes. Quite spunky.
He's got a head like Gibraltar.
Yes, quite stylish, too. Yes.
So don't worry, Frankie
A guy like you,
you get another chick like that.
- Yeah, that's right.
- Not at this table.
Look, Johnny, I don't
want another chick.
- I don't want anything.
- Hey, I’m with you.
That way you don't have to
take a chick to dances.
You don't have to find
a place to smooch.
And you don't have to think about
what we're always thinking about.
Hey. What am I saying?
Would you two like to be alone?
Look, here comes creep.
Frieda, keep a civil
tongue in your beak.
How many times do I
have to tell you, sir?
My art has no price on it.
I mean, it's priceless.
- Ain't this spiffy?
- Yeah.
I think I’ll lower the bridge
on London town.
Hold it. What he's doing,
you can do better.
- Yeah.
- But if I’m wrong, don't blame me.
Thanks a lot.
- Dee Dee, I want to talk to you.
- Go ahead and talk.
I mean alone.
Sorry, old chap. But I’d
like to take Dee Dee home.
Oh, I think it would be a spiffing idea
if you two were to reconcile.
Though I must admit I’ve become
quite attached to your young lady.
Double drats, I believe
the word is "poultry."
You mean, "chick."
Are you sure it's
all right, Potato?
Oh, first names.
Oh, it's top hole.
Only sporting thing to do.
Give the young man a chance
to display his charms.
Test them against mine,
that sort of thing.
Yeah, yeah, come on, Dee Dee.
Let's get out of here..
He's a rude bugger, he is.
It’s Watusi time!
Now, Clyde.
I got you where I want you
I want you where I got you
You're never gonna
get away from me
I want you where I got you
I got you where I want you
There's no one else
around but you and me
We got plenty of time
They won't be home until nine
I got you all to
myself until then
Clyde's people
invented the Watusi.
Sure, they were the
original swingers.
I got you where I want you
I want you where I got you
You're never gonna get
away from me
I want you where I got you
I got you where I want you
There's no one else
around but you and me
Now, wait. Hold it.
Stop the music! Stop everything!
Now, wait a second. Wait a second.
This has got to stop.
What kind of a place
do you think I’m running?
Well, I’d rather not
answer that, Mr. Drag.
Would you like to have your
picture taken for the newspaper?
- Again?
- Yeah.
- Oh, I suppose you need the circulation.
- Would you like to...
- No, no. We won't need you.
There we are. Here you are, Clyde.
That's right. Thank you, sir.
Come along, Clyde.
Oh, excellent, Clyde. Excellent.
Time we went along, my dear.
Tomorrow morning's editorial
is going to be an eye-opener
for the entire community.
I’m waiting for your eyes to open.
He's a sweetheart of a guy.
It’s beautiful, isn't it?
You know, this is the first time the day's
been quiet enough to hear the waves.
I’m sorry I took you
away from your date.
I didn't mean to.
You didn't?
All right, I did. But I don't
blame you for liking the Bug.
- For one thing, he's famous.
- Yes.
- And he's rich.
And all the girls go ape
when they see him.
- Then why are you walking here with me?
- Because you're you.
Every time you hold me
I know it's real
My heart once told me
How it would feel
Why?
Just like you told me
Each time you hold me
Why?
Because you're you
Every time I’m near you
Stars from the skies
Somehow appear to
Shine in your eyes
Why?
They just appear to
Each time I’m near you
Why?
Because you're you
Every time we kiss now
It’s plain to see
So sure of this now
You were meant for me
Why?
So sure of this now
Each time we kiss now
Why?
Because you're you
Well, I’m glad everything's settled.
Things are back to normal,
and we can just forget about drag racing.
Hold it. Who said anything
about forgetting it?
I can't back out of that race.
A man's got to stand by his word.
I told him I’d race him,
and that's the way it's gotta be.
Well, then he'll back out of it
because I’ll tell him to.
You stay out of this.
Anything you say, Frankie.
And so I say, the best way to go forward
is to borrow from the past.
Return to that steady, reliable course
charted for us by our forebears.
If it was good enough
for our fathers,
and good enough for our grandfathers,
then it follows
that it must be good enough...
I’m sorry, Mr. Honeywagon.
I told her you were tied up.
Tied up is too good for him.
He should be locked up.
She never listens, Miss Simms,
but thanks for trying.
I just finished today's article.
Would you like to read it?
I didn't even read yesterday's.
I put it on the bottom of my canary's cage.
- I resent that.
- He hated it.
Harvey Honeywagon,
I’ve been doing some digging.
And I found out why you're putting
the knock on these kids.
For purely moral reasons is why.
For purely commercial reasons is why.
You're trying to buy up
that beach property
so you can expand your OFH.
- And what is "OFH"?
- Old folks' home.
It is not an old folks' home!
It is Sea-Esta by the Sea!
You mean, "Fee-esta."
The fee is the only thing
you're interested in.
I am interested in protecting my residents
from an evil environment.
Sea-Esta by the Sea
is a resort for senior citizens,
and I’m going to see to it that they get
the peace and quiet they so richly deserve.
Well, they're getting it,
all right
It’s more of a last
resort for them.
All they do is sit and vegetate.
Honeywagon's vegetable farm,
that's what you're running.
Now, that's really an insult.
All I’m trying to do
is help these poor people
who have been forced into retirement.
You're helping them into their graves.
Why don't you furnish shovels?
I’m only doing what I think
is proper and right.
Harvey Honeywagon,
you listen to me.
You're holding a
double-barrel shotgun.
Killing off the old folks while
you kill off the fun for the youngsters.
I guess it never occurred to you that the...
beach is a place to live, not to die.
- Have you quite finished be...
- I’ve finished!
And don't ask me to leave.
I’d rather it was my idea.
You know, for a while there,
I was beginning to like you.
Now I wish you'd take a room
at the vegetable farm and retire.
I’ll get the kids to take up a collection.
We'll send you a shovel.
Well, I’m just going to have to appeal
to the Potato Bug's sportsmanship.
I bet he won't be as
stubborn as Frankie.
Well, what's wrong with drag racing?
I think it's kind of groovy.
Aren't surfboards fast enough
for you, Animal?
No, and neither are the surfers.
Would you trade that beautiful
ocean for a dirty old rail?
Well, there's room for both.
Not in my life.
Wish me luck.
- Okay.
- Okay, bye.
A little short in the back.
- How do I look from the front?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You're the buggiest little Bug
I ever saw, from the front.
- But don't let her get behind you.
- Okay.
There she is.
Well, wish me luck.
- Good luck, Potato.
- Yeah.
Hi, Potato.
Oh, I say, this is a spot of luck,
by George, don't you know.
Out for my evening stroll,
that sort of thing, and here you are.
A bit of luck, indeed.
Ripping, actually.
I was just on my way to see you.
Oh, by George, and rather!
A girl and her frankfurter
soon parted, so to speak.
And one is quite flattered,
don't you know.
Potato, do you feel all right?
Oh, all right? Oh, yes, yes.
A touch... Touch of sinus,
you know.
You know, the sea.
And a stiff neck as well, yeah.
Well, I was really coming over
to ask you for a favor.
Now, what is it, love?
Potato, I want you
to cancel the race with Frankie.
Good heavens, girl, you josh!
You can't ask that!
No. No. You can't ask an Englishman
to bend his word.
And there's a bit more
to it than that, you know.
I wouldn't mind having you for my bird.
Well, you don't have to win the race
to win everything.
Oh, yes. Yes.
There are other things.
Indeed, there are.
And, ducks, you're making me feel,
shall I say, frivolous.
You know, fogging up the old glasses.
- Potato, then you will cancel the race?
- Definitely not!
A challenge is a challenge!
But here we are all alone, and...
Can't you just forget about
everything else?
Well, one is tempted, my dear.
Especially when one is aware
of our proximity.
- It’s you I love.
- Yeah.
Are you really aware of that?
Well, Englishmen are
not made of wood, my dear.
We are well aware of the opposite sex,
have been for centuries.
I’d just die if anything
happened to you
Yeah.
Well, you know, you can always
go back to your Frankie chap.
It can't be all that bad.
He's really quite a good catch.
And he sings better than I do,
actually, don't you know.
You're just being gallant.
There's only one Potato Bug.
Oh, well, I don't know that.
My word, ducks! You seem to be wrong.
There appears to be two Potato Bugs.
By Jove, I don't believe I’ve ever known
a wicket this sticky!
I think I know which wicket
is the stickiest around here.
Now, love. Now, ducks.
You see, only our hairdressers
know for sure.
To think that you could stoop
to such a low-down trick!
I never want to see you again!
I should say not,
after those things you said to me.
I mean, to him.
Did you mean all that love junk?
- Wouldn't you like to know.
- Yes.
I say there, you two.
Stow it, won't you?
I have no idea what this is all about.
But one must cope.
Be civilized. Stiff upper
lip and all of that, you know.
You keep out of this,
you beetle-eyed bug.
You're just as bad as he is.
Both of you are always trying to find
new ways to kill yourselves.
Well, I hope you both make it.
- Where did we go wrong?
Hey, so let's play
already, huh, daddy?
Eric Von Zipper plays
when Eric Von Zipper is ready.
You stupid...
Would you mind?
Boss. Hey, boss, read this.
- You stupid?
- Oh, I’m sorry, boss. I forgot.
I’ll read it to you.
It’s by that fella, Honeycart.
Honeycart, he is my idol.
I adore him.
You wait till you hear this.
It says, "This is a retro-action."
- What does that mean, boss?
- Oh, that's when it's...
- Keep reading, stupid.
- Oh, yeah. Okay.
"This is a retro-action
of everything I have said,"
"and an ape-ology from the
farther-est reaches of my heart."
That's my friend.
He sure writes beautiful.
"I... I consider my actions
almost mani-acle"
"and want to tell the public
that all the young surfers"
"make our beaches ring
with joy and laughter."
That's the worst stuff
that was ever read to me!
What a fink!
And I thought he was a good guy!
Hey, daddy, are you gonna play
this pool game or ain't you?
Yeah, I’m gonna play pool.
Dirty pool.
Out! Out!
Now my friend gets the Rats' revenge!
- Oh, I’m sorry, boss.
- You stupid.
How are you fixed for blood?
You want to play a game
before the moon comes out?
All right. Just take it easy.
Cool it, daddy. I’ll play by myself.
"And the presence of these young people
is a fond reminder to the older generation"
"that they were young once
and perhaps still are."
Eric Von Zipper has been betrayed!
The good guys of this world
has been betrayed!
And all because of one fink, you!
I must ask you and your
curious conglomeration to leave my office.
- What's he trying to say, boss?
- It don't make no difference.
We leave when Eric Von Zipper
says we leave.
You used to be my idol, but you turned
into a regular Arnold Benedict.
And all because of a woman.
A woman's work is never done,
but this one done it.
Then teachers is the worst kind.
You know what this is?
This is a regular Delilah and Simpson bit.
I must ask you to leave these premises
before you arouse my ire.
- What's that mean, boss?
- It means keep out of my office!
That does it! Now you will
get the Rats' revenge!
That'll be a pleasure.
You can let him go now
'cause Von Zipper does not like violence
in front of broads.
But Von Zipper will get his revenge
'cause Von Zipper always uses his head.
He done it again.
He gave himself the finger.
Come on, let's get
him out of here.
Eric Von Zipper will get
his Rats' revenge!
Harvey, I never realized.
Well, deep down inside,
all we Honeywagons are full of...
Well, much more than one would suspect.
Well, fellas, what do you think?
Are you kidding? It’s the greatest!
Come on. Look, I know it's not much,
but we can make it something.
Well, when do we start?
- Yeah.
- When?
Well, it isn't gonna be easy,
but we can do it.
We can make this rail
faster than anything on the strip.
But it's gonna cost us
every dime in our pockets.
So, what's money?
What we can't buy, we'll scrounge.
We'll turn this into something so fast
you can't even see the smoke.
The only one who'll see the smoke
is the Potato Bug.
- Smoked Potato Bug, you get it?
- Yeah. Well, let's start.
Hold it! Hold it!
Hold it!
I guess you guys didn't get the message
when I told you about motorocity.
One of the most principled principles
of motorocity is generosity.
That's why I, Big Drag,
am going to loan this rail to him.
- Hey!
- Thanks a lot! Thanks, Big!
Gee, that's big of you, Big.
Another principle of motorocity is
that more people want to come
to a grudge race than any other kind.
But I wouldn't want to mention that
because some people might think
we're trying to commercialize
in a sport that deals
strictly for funds.
- I mean, fun.
- You're a good guy, Big.
Look at it, Dee Dee.
Right now it's just wheels and rails.
When that flag drops,
it becomes 1,000 horses.
And that's a lot of power.
It’s an 80-foot wave
and you ride close to the crest.
No. No, there's a difference.
The ocean, its wild and it's free.
It’s something you can't change.
But this, this is an engine,
a machine.
It can be controlled.
It scares me when I think about it.
It’s like you want to take
every chance there is.
Dee Dee, that's the way we've got to live.
That's what it's about.
You ride your 1,000 horses, Frankie.
I’ll be betting on every one of them.
Would you like
to give it a trial run, Frankie?
- You bet.
- Come on, fellas.
Come on, boys. Move it out.
This time it's love
I can see it in his eyes
Though it should be no surprise
I’m like a little child
All starry-eyed and wild
This time it's love
This time it's real
I have found the boy for me
The way I feel
I know it was meant to be
I’ve always known somehow
The way it would be now
This time it's love
How wonderful to know
that your dreams come true
someone cares for you
Oh, this time it's love
And I know each time we kiss
This time it's love
Suddenly I’m sure of this
I have that certain glow
That only lovers know
This time it's love
I have that certain glow
That only lovers know
This time it's love
You stupids!
Now, here's how we
get the Rats' revenge.
Tomorrow is the grudge race, right?
Right!
Whisper! Whisper! You stupids!
Now, we put the fix
on the Potato Bug's rail.
Now comes the race.
The Bug's rail goes powie.
And the Bug, he gets
hit with the flit. Right?
Right.
Now, everybody thinks that Frankie
done it account of it's a grudge race, see?
So everybody will see
that the Von Zipper is right
and that the beach
bums is bums. Right?
Right.
Any questions?
- Yeah.
- What? What?
How do we put the fix
on the Potato Bug's rail?
Listen to the Von Zipper
and you will learn things.
First, we amputate the eliminator.
Then, we eliminate the amputator.
And from then on, it's simple.
Let's go.
Sorry, boss.
Thanks, boss.
Which one is it, boss?
That one.
Hey, it's kind of groovy, boss.
- Cycles is better.
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah, boss.
By the tire. By the tire!
Get a screwdriver.
I’ll loosen this nut.
Becca, what in the world
is a drag strip?
I haven't the faintest, but I’ll bet it's...
gonna be more fun than the mausoleum.
Oh, I’ll bet.
Ladies and gentlemen, we're about to
blast off with the preliminary race.
You're right, Becca.
This is more fun than the mausoleum.
You just listen to me,
Florabella!
The winner is Fordney Allen
in his Mighty Malibu!
Time, 8.2 seconds at 198.3
miles per hour.
Clyde!
You've got them living
again and loving it.
Oh, I’m quite big with
the older types.
You're quite big with me, too.
Everybody go over to Big Drag's Pit Stop
and wait for me there.
Where we will have
the victory celebration to prove
that Eric Von Zipper done it again.
- Ain't you gonna go with us, boss?
- No, I’m gonna stay here for the kill.
Out! Out! Out!
Hey, wait!
Your attention, please.
The next event is the one
we've all been waiting for.
The match between England's champion,
the famous Potato Bug,
and Frankie, our own local surfer.
Potato!
Good luck, and I mean it.
Oh, yes, and may the better man
emerge victorious, old chap, don't you see.
Don't worry, Dee Dee.
It will all be over in a few seconds.
I wish you wouldn't put it that way.
You two all right?
That was my best rail.
I’ve been sabotaged.
I told them to fix the Potato
Bug's car. Those stupids.
Von Zipper.
It was, like, a mistake.
You know what I mean?
- Von Zipper did it.
- I did?
It wasn't me. There was a...
There was a group, see?
I told them to fix the Potato
Bug's car. Those stupids.
Don't go away. I’ll be right back,
see, 'cause I know the kids who did it.
So, you stay there,
and I’ll be right back.
How do you start it?
How do you stop it?
Somebody, stop it!
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
You're in the way!
Get out of the way!
Look out! Look out!
Look out! You're in the way!
Everybody back into the bus!
Follow those cars!
Look out!
Hey, look out! Move over!
Move! Move! You're in the way!
Look out!
Howdy.
Howdy?
- Deadhead, watch out!
- Watch out for what?
Can you believe this?
- Shall we get some black coffee?
- No, I’m going back on the sauce.
Oh, that's stupid!
Well, you made it, boss.
Sort of.
I knew I shouldn't have had
that door fixed.
You! You sabotager, you!
You rail derailer!
They told me there'd
be days like this.
Now, stop that!
Don't, Harvey!
There he is!
There's the fink
that ain't our idol no more!
Our side needs all the
help we can get, my dear.
Clyde! Clyde!
Pyramids, play something!
Play something!
- What?
- You've done it again, boss.
Candy!
Come on. Give them your bit.
There!
My place, they're ruining it.
Oh, they really are ruining me!
Oh, jolly good! Yes!
Oh, hi there, ducks.
Sorry I’m late, but I had to stop
for some petrol, don't you know.
Oh, my word, ducks.
ln England, one would call this
a spot of the old nasty, yes.
But in France,
we would call it an election.
Oh, bit of a near thing, that.
Oh, good show! Liked that!
- Oh, I say, ducks. Isn’t he one of ours?
- Oui.
Yes. Excuse me, old boy.
Not very sporting, lad.
I don't want you to see
what's gonna happen to you.
Thank you. It’s called
karate, old boy.
Oh, he's all yours, ducks.
Hey, your shoelace is untied.
Now, stop it!
Thank you, my dear.
Now, please repair to a safer place.
Are you all right?
Which do you prefer, love?
- Him.
- Good-o.
Good show! Good show!
Enjoy! Enjoy!
- Excuse me, old boy.
- What? What? What?
Why you rotten little bug!
I’m gonna squash you!
What's all that?
Most peculiar, that. Yes.
Hold her still!
You stupid...
- Parcheez!
- What is that, "parcheez"?
That's what it is, "parcheez."
I want to say...
Now cut that out, Clyde,
or I’ll rent you a room at the zoo.
If I didn't own this
joint, I’d sue me.
You stupid...
No! I’m too young to die!
Now, put that back.
That's part of my wall.
- That's part of his wall.
First my wall, now my art.
How many times do I have to tell you?
My work is not for sale.
One of them is a masterpiece.
I’ll take it.
It is? You will?
That's the one!
But, but, but, but.
Have it sent to my place and there'll
be a check for $1,000 waiting.
I must tell Vincent Price
about this place.
Oh, what monsters.
- Come on, Miss Florabella!
- All right.
- Oh, come on! We've got to go.
- All right
Well, come on!
Hi, Clyde.
Hey, you guys, the battle's over!
Von Zipper's stoned again!
All right, you Rats, get him out of here!
Get that creep out of here!
Come on, boss. Wake up! Wake up!
- He's back in those Himalayan suspenders.
- Yup, he's done it again.
Let's get him out of here.
The great Von Zipper will return!
Well! Can you believe that?
I tell you, Becca, this is the most fun
I’ve had since Berry's Nut Farm.
Well, how'd you make out, Potato?
Oh, it was a wonderful sport.
Splendid really.
I must tell them about this upon my
return in London town, eh, ducks?
We're gonna miss you, Bug.
What are your plans?
Oh, jolly good, I should say.
Lady Bug and I
have come to an agreement.
Wedding bells and all that
sort of rot, don't you know.
Hey, congratulations!
I hope you two don't fight
as much as Dee Dee and I.
Oh, I should hope not.
I abhor fisticuffs.
Or, in your case,
my dear, "footsicuffs."
I made a deal with him.
He does not raise his voice to me,
I do not raise my feet to him.
Welcome to Big Drag's Pit Stop.
Come on in, folks.
Come on in and join the kids.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Clydes and birds, and all you kids,
it gives me great pleasure
to present to you Little Stevie Wonder.
- Dance and shout, work it on out
- Come on
- Everybody, oh, yeah
Come on, everybody
and follow me
That certainly isn't
the bunny hop they're doing.
Come on, clap your hands
and shout with glee, yeah
Just take off both
of your shoes
Now that's the way to
lose your blues
You get a happy feeling
when you dance and shout, oh, yeah
- Come on everybody dance
- Dance and shout, work it on out
I want to know what
you got to lose
- Come on and take a chance
- Dance and shout, work it on out
'Cause everybody's doing fine
Come on, everybody
Come on and form a line
You get a happy feeling when you
dance and shout, work it on out
Dance and shout, work it on out
- Isn’t this the living end?
- Not for me, Florabella.
It’s only the beginning.
It isn't the end at all.
- Dance and shout, work it on out
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, now that's the way
- Oh, yes
You know we've got a dance
that's here to stay
Dance and shout, work it on out
Because everybody's doing fine
Come on, let's rock it
one more time
Because you get a happy feeling
when you dance and shout, oh, yeah
- Dance and shout, work it on out
- What did you say? Oh, now I got it
- Oh, yeah! Oh, yeah, yeah
I got you where I want you
I want you where I got you
You're never gonna
get away from me
I want you where I got you
I got you where I want you
There's no one else around
but you and me, yeah
We got plenty of time
They won't be home until nine
I got you all to myself
until then
My mom and my dad say
the traffic is bad
Maybe they won't be
home until ten
Oh, yeah
I got you where I want you
I want you where I got you
You're never gonna
get away from me
I want you where I got you
I got you where I want you
There's no one else around
but you and me, yeah
I got you where I want you
I want you where I got you
You're never gonna
get away from me
I want you where I got you
I got you where I want you
There's no one else around
but you and me, yeah
We've got plenty of time
They won't be home until nine
I got you all to myself
until then
My mom and my dad say
the traffic is bad
Maybe they won't be
home until ten
Oh, yeah
Subtitles: Kilo