Government Officer Mr. Laghu Duo,
l'm Vilas Pardesi aka Billu.
Village Budbudha,
Lala Lajpal has visited here,
Have you seen my Billu Saloon,
and if you seen then it's good,
because l'm writing this letter on
the behalf of this shop, my shop's
condition is same as your government,
ln the name of asset l have
somethings,
like a chair what my naughty children
calls Swinger,
some day it will be break and it will
break customer's butt,
a scissor who never cuts anyone,
A comb who looks like an old man jaw,
it's one teeth is here and one is
there,
So l am requesting you for loan to
purchase new accessories,
l'm sure you will think that why l'm
directly not talking to you.
l came here, and l'm counting bees
sitting outside on broken bench,
But l've heard government files doesn't
move without weight,
And l don't have any idea about bribe.
And l don't want to mess it all,
that's why l am asking you in written,
that will you take bribe,
lf your answer is yes then l'll tell
you l don't have money,
And if your answer is no, then you
call me inside,
Your upcoming customer,
Billu.
An idiot is sitting outside,
Send him inside,
Greetings! Team DUS Jay78
May l come in?
Please come,
Mr. Gandhi,
Mr. Dharam Raj,
How could they come,
they are gone, they are died,
l came alone,
that's why l am respecting you,
All those great souls are gone,
But it's my pleasure to meet you,
Directly ask to Government Officer,
that will you take bribe or not,
Amazing!
A man of principles like you is
eligible for praise not for loan,
No, lf that bribe line hurts your
feelings,
then l'll cut that line,
Abuse is like a children's ball,
that you through it on the wall and
catch it back,
Go you great soul,
You won't get any loan,
Pandit Jee, something for that
rolling chair,
You will always wander,
but you won't get loan,
Thanks!
for what?
You should never ask straight to
any government officer
will you take a bribe,
You have teach me this lesson,
Out!
Why you people are sitting outside,
Electricity is not coming or what.
That's why we put the lamp, electricity
department have cut our electricity,
Okay,
No problem, it's a good thing,
Big people like Mahatma Gandhi,
were study in lamp light all night,
so what they did in days,
They went to school,
They helped their parents for work,
Yes, even Mr. Abraham Linkon studied
in street lamps,
From tomorrow l'll go to street,
You don't understand anything,
Where is your mom,
She is gone to get some oil.
Naughty, you're talking about your
mom,
She is really gone for get oil,
To our neighbour Mina Mosi,
You didn't brought the grains,
No, l came out from shop but entire
market was closed,
Tell the truth, nobody has come for
hair cut,
No,
l had some customers,
l paid our house rent,
Now happy,
Very happy,
Now give him another good news,
Which one,
Principle has called you school
tomorrow,
Why?
lt's a good news,
Greetings,
Bindya was saying that if today....
fees won't be submit then you will
restigate them,
Out, office is outside,
go and submit your fees outside,
l couldn't bring the money,
Have you brought your memory,
Look, last time you beg to me that's
why l made you a promise,
Today l fulfill that promise,
One month's fee hasn't come that's
why l restigate your childrens,
But how it worth?
We will see what it worths?
Sister, if you will restigate children
from school then there will be 2 things
First, your school fee will be stuck,
because how money will come to me,
Second, children's studies will be
stuck.
You can save one thing to stuck
between both of them,
Which one?
Studies.
What?
l swear, l have broke my all piggy
banks,
look, l've got one rupee,
Now when l went to sell my goat then
my wife shouts,
then let your childrens teach from
goat,
Shall l send my goat here,
First you will teach my goat and then
goat will teach my childrens,
Then you will ask goat's fee,
You're making me fool,
Who started that?
Get out from here,
You were walking with heavy feets
in school.
like you have a lot of money in your
pocket,
and you will pay our school fees,
But l told you l'll arrange soon,
l am happy, l don't have to listen
your same speech daily,
Bring first number,
But l buy you all the books,
What if they take you out from school,
Learn outside from the window,
Then what is the need to come school.
We can study at home,
To wash same uniform mom's back
won't pain,
But you have to go school for exams,
Why you came to my shop every
morning,
Listen what happened today this
dharmendra has lost today,
He will give me a crore,
What?
Whose hand he will turn?
Not turn, idiot crore,
lt's one crore,
These losers are playing of crores on
street and don't have a single penny,
But it satisfies our selves,
You watch your empty safe all day long
That's why you are always upset,
Can't you find another place for play,
Where we will find a batter place than
that, nobody comes here,
This peace is embarassing for me,
Today l have oil then shine your self,
But from tomorrow, no oil for you,
and there is no guarantee from
tomorrow,
And this is the last trick, after
that you hold my ship.
How ship will reach to corner,
This Modern Madan is a problem here,
Since Modern Madan's shop has open,
Billu's scissors are stopped,
Nowadays, it's a trend of exposure,
Madan has made his shop like
Rakhi Sawant,
And his shop is like old Neerupa Rai,
All budbude's hair has cut in that
saloon,
Do something, Billu Bhai.
Pagla (Mad)
Hey!
Hold your tongue,
l said next,
l have many customers here, l don't
have time for waste,
Next!
Hey!
Look!
Old Rate, New Rate.
Cutting rate from fifteen rupees to
ten rupees,
What is this billu's next trick?
Don't know it is the cheap price of
billu,
or nothing,
Shut the engine,
Petrol is very expensive,
Then totally it is 2750,
What he is doing here?
Call him up here,
Hey, Billu!
come here.
Mr. Dumchand is calling you.
How many times l told you damchand,
don't you understand once,
What should l do?
l didn't kept your name that's why....
from today write daily for 101 times,
damchand, damchand, damchand,
and still you can't call, then don't
come on work from tomorrow,
Greetings!
greetings!
Your saloon has closed now you will
cut wood on my body,
l needed a new chair that's why....
Oh! your time has changed,
Your busniess is running good,
Where?
But planning is necessary in life,
that's why l understand the estimate
of chair,
From today l will save my money
then l will order,
So, you don't need a chair and you
don't have money,
No, l don't need it right now,
l don't have money,
Then why did you break my legs,
Do you think l am a fool?
Billu!
lt's a matter of timing,
Those people's business is running
good,
they all took money on interest from
me, but you didn't...
that's why your business is not
running.
Look, don't worry,
Get some cash and forget the timing,
Just give me interest.
lf l ain't get yet then how l will
get now,
My life will ruined because of your
interest,
Leave it,
then what are you doing here?
Take him out,
No, you don't need it,
l will go,
Give me the wood,
get lost.
Don't have a single penny in pocket
and watching colorful dreams,
lt's super hit Sahir Jee,
You write it down,
First let him write the rest of the
story,
then write down the fate of film,
Jerry!
Film's flow is good till here,
but what next,
Sir, We have seen a view of one
brother who lived on sky,
then he came out to search his
twin brother,
And real film starts from here.
And the search should be the soul
of the film,
Because every man is searching for
something,
Someone is searching for name,
someone is searching for fame,
someone is searching for money,
and someone is searching....
....for some moments of peace.
You know....
...if this journey of search
we can make it interesting then we
will enjoy the film.
Otherwise in the story of twin
brothers meeting and take apart
what is the new idea?
Sir, locket!
Locket's idea is new,
Very original.
Since childhood a locket like remote
is tied on both brother's neck,
and if one brother touch that locket
then it sounds beep in another's neck
Yes. sir.
We have kept some feeling of technology
ln the climax with that sound of beep
they both search each other.
Do people will beleive on that,
l am sure they will.
l must appreciate your confidence,
and for your courage too.
So much security.
What is this new conspiracy.
Not at all.
Like every successful man l'm paying
for my successful life,
To watch my last picture some
polititions become against on me,
and they become anger on me,
They said....
that we took the side of one community
and neglect their community,
l took a stand and tell them watch the
picture and tell me where is the
mistake, nobody has no answer, even
one politition start telling me
that Mr. Sahir we are like magician
like they brings things from empty
hat and we bring the problems, and
this time l was their target.
lntelligence told me that it could be
dangerous for my life, so it started,
By the way where these twin brothers
are going to meet.
ln the village, that's why one brother
is belong to the sky and other one is
from village, that's why l kept the
movie's title ''Aasman ka Farishta
aur khoon ka rishta''.
You've become so commercial.
By the way in which village you are
going to shoot.
Let's see.
We will find it,
Shoot it in Budbuda Village.
Yes, Sir.
Budbuda!
l've heard it's a nice village.
Bindiya!
Yes!
You came to borrow grain, you made a
promise and disappeared,
You told me that you will give goat's
milk daily, what happened.
What should l do?
Her child drunk all the milk,
then tie them seperate.
l can't tie them seperate, they both
can't live without each other.
lt's just a child,
Just wait for a week,
l'll send you the milk,
This couple is like this, Man carry
money and wife carrys stuff.
Drive slowly,
You don't need to drive fast.
Stop right here.
Carefully!
Some postman was looking for me,
Nobody never finds you,
Not today l've never seen anyone
searching for you.
Why are you laughing?
Someone is dancing naked here.
They laugh unnecessarily.
My poet has print in Gazal Sagar.
and l was expecting it's money order.
Where did you get these flowers?
Did you get married?
Where is the bride?
l've left her hospital for delivery.
You jusy play your games,
Government gave me respect,
For what?
They held up a programme for Gas,
l narrate them such a nice poetry,
people were clapping for me,
You should watch if you would be
there.
l'll narrate you too just order for
tea.
You narrate your poetry in Madan's
shop then l'll get you tea,
Atleast few of them will come from
there.
Tell, whom l have to beat,
Shut up!
Look! what's written on there?
Message, Shave, Cutting.
l'll get everything.
Mr. Damchand, you just got cutting
few days before, let them grow.
but if he will high his prices then...
l'll get more short hair,
and l don't have to spend money soon,
And will he cut proper?
Why he won't?
that day you insult him,
think! your neck is on his chair.
Scissor on his hand, to take avenge
if he cut your ear and throat,
and say sorry then.....
So what?
l'll break his legs.
What is the worth to beat him when
he cut my ears.
then we will beat him first and then
let him allow for your hair cut.
You dumb!
You want me to slap you.
Billu! from today it's your
responsibilty to cut my hair.
Look, l have come here....
Carefully!
What happen?
He broke my chair's tyre,
and his back too.
Let's take him to the hospital.
Don't take me their he suck money
not blood,
Take me to another hospital but
cheaper.
Do you have red paper, alapeno,
Why are you abusing me?
Not abuses these are the vegetable's
names,
l think we have to order them from
city.
Lot of vegetables here,
don't you like them.
We need all of them,
Listen!
Vegetable Men,
For next month don't sell these
vegetables,
then what villagers will eat,
Are you giving a party?
Shooting!
shooting has going to start here,
ln our village!
ls any grossery store here?
Cinema has come to our village,
come on.
lt's the only largest godown of the
village,
lt will take rice, flour for 400
people.
your shop is like a matchbox,
We will bring neighbourhood's
godowns and they will give us,
Nobody has seen shooting here before
english were ruled here,
Who is the hero?
who is the hero?
We will tell you everything.
Come,
Sir.
He is the police commissioner of this
area.
We didn't left anything for your
security,
Police will keep away the public from
your shooting area.
We hope there will be no disturbance
in your work,
l think you announced my programme,
l thought we will shoot in village
away from people,
but same here,
lnspector, Collector, DSP.
They come everywhere.
He is the owner of this guest house,
Come, come come.
l have brought new sofas,
brought new fridge here.
come,
Bedroom is here and bathroom
is here.
No shower in bathroom,
l've send plumber from mumbai,
l have removed that shower from
plumber,
He was fixing, but l refused him,
Animals take standing bath,
you are the prince of the film,
you sit and take bath,
What it is Chobay?
what l told you and what you did?
stop..leave it..
chobay sir will make fix shower..
His intention was good..
look how intelligent is your boss.
police,milatry,artist,star,
Your people who came here..
So we have arraged for thier living
The water is purely
fine which is for bath...
You have arraged for our deluxe
a lot..thanks for it..
l'm little tired..
l want to relax ...
You just go..
and tell me if somethings is for me..
lf you asked me so l want you
to give me chance for acting..
You do acting?
yes l do
l played in ram lila drama..
when l float on the water..
so l got applauses..
okay..l'll see what l can do!
Please dont forget..
Not at all.
lf you need anything so peep your
head out from window and yell my name.
l'll be appear..
Okay you may go now..!
not at all..this is the way of love
of the villagers..
lts strage..
should l act once..
Why are you standing outside..
you'll get your fever high..
come inside!
l was inside since 3 days..
l met with priciple medam..
and l begged her on week time..
This time they almost gave me threth..
That lts last time..!
where are you coming from?
from the market..
l bought the stuff for home..
How is your fever?
l was wanting to have chicken pox..
But lt might have little fever.
from when your shop is closed?
will come home to cut hair
My hair got long..
have you hair for cutting?
what did you say?
He said l'll come to you.
Your tounge skip like scissor in fever.
Shooting people has come..
And you know who is hero?
your friend sahir khan..!
ohh lord..
an super star in our village?
Lets go for meet him..
l want to snap with him..
snap and autograph... we have
to meet him before someone else
Stop...
let him cured...
Till then they will gone..
so should we call him at home?
Look at our house..
change the cloths..
Tell me when will you make us
meet with sahir uncle..?
when you'll get summer vication.
lf you'll not bring us there..
so l'll kill you..
We have cute kids..
Will take me with them?
yes to all!
yes along with our mammals..
Sahir uncle takes bath with full of
roses in the bath tub..
You forgot the heroins..
he always surrounded with them.
l saw on t.v.!
ls that true that sahir uncle
wears one dress one time.
Who knows..
did you pee before sleep?
What he do after wearing one dress?
same as we do...
to use in cleaning dust.
and shoes?..he has big room.
he'd wear shoes once..
What he do with old shoes?
he do boil and eats in the break fast,
just be silence and sleep.
l'll wake you up early morning..
for learning maths..
Drink this tea..
Your fever is down..
l think we could manage to
meet with him.?
l'll not go for meet with sahir khan..
Why?
l met with him many times ago..
lt passed many years..
dont know with how much people he have met.
He'd be forget me..
You want me to tell him that
you recognize me?
He'll get rid after recognize me.
He'll see me and judge me
by my situation.
lf he recognize me so he'll
be degreted ..
after long time l goes for meet with him..it
looks like ant is going to stick with honey.
l'll not endure it all..
so you lied to us..
So why you promised with kids..
How can l explain this to kids?
lf i'll get rid with kids..
so time will be pass..
My poor kids..
the are hoping for non..
My father is friend of sahir khan..
They'd be room mate?
No at all..
He'd be cuts sahir's hair!
he'd be an sevent on
sahir's banglow..
lt would be not friendship..
just an knowing..!
Super star sahir khan ln
the village..
our village name ls on the new paper
lt seems that everbody
got the jack pot..
He thinks himself as sahir khan..
lets go father...
You promised us that you'll
make us meet with sahir khan..
now dont change your intention..
What ls day today?
sunday.
We cant go today...
there'd be so crowd on shop..
At your shop?
dont excuse us...
Today will not let your tail off..
We will come with you at shop..
now lets go..
One minute..
where is shooting going on?
lts on our village...
but where ln our village..
at the lake,on the roof,where?
so lets go..
we'll find everywhere..
We cant find everwhere like that.
we'll got fever in the sunlight..
l got fever to meet sahir uncle..
What'll happen for your saying.
l have to take you to the doctor..
Wait..
l'll do something..
You just stay at home..
l'll ask to sahir uncle...
he is big star,lf we dont ask,
so lt looks bad..
l'll tell him that our kids
want to see shooting..
yes with wife..
so when l can bring them?
So he'll say that..
get them today..
So in evening..
of which kind of flour he eats..
its shining..
He dont eats flour you fool,
but eats nuts ,almond etc,etc.
These are gems..
but an wrestler..
His dog eats almond and
nuts in early morning..
ice cream ln lunch..
ln evening ,ghee..
Means..not only sahir is rich
but even his dog is rich..
Yes..
dog ls so lucky..
Why dont became his dog.?
To beget like dog you must have
the right time..
And you borned in the misery time..
l'll tell you the
truth after few days...
so how?
l'll write his song of films..
l just want one chance..
Talent ls exceed ln me..
lf he'll hear my song..
so he'll go away from the village..
Dont show me your teeth..
remember one thing..
Where no one can reach ..
l can reach there ..!
shooting is started..
We want to see the shooting!
he's our namchandjee.
We want to invite mr.sahir..
no one can talk with sahir sir..
if you want to see shooting..
So see it from far away like
other people..
Take me to the hospital..
Listen...
where are you?
Principle medam has come..
She'd be worried about
the fee of kids..
Tell her l'm not at home..
no l dont lie..
to saying lie for saving husband,
wife's got virtue..
lts saying..
now tell her..
How are you?
ls your husband at home?
its okay..we came to give
an good news..
The school commitee has decided
that your kids fee will be paid by fund
Thank you very much..!
lts our duty..
Come inside..
you just have to debt on us.
we are poor people but we'll do
anthing for kids which is possible.
her class teacher tells me..
But l informed whole school that..
no one can get to know outside..
Billujee is very hiden person..
a lot of time he came to
school in teacher meeting..
While talking about fee, never revealed
that he is friend of sahir khan.
He just have to bring him on
the school ceremony..
Medam,,l cant do that...
You said that he's not at home..
l came from behind..
l appoligies with you.,
i cant bring sahir khan here..
He's not my friend..
You'd have to say it...
l told that billujee
will say like that..
Sit down..
l'll explain to you..
My shops chair always moves..
And we all are shocked..
We just asked you for some time..
we'll not teach our kids for free.
We'll pay the fee..
dont worry about fee as medam said.
You just to sahir khan..
Cant bring!
Why you cant bring him
in the school..?
atleast it about our
kids future!
When we'll meet him..
so we'll talk about the school.
dont heed him..l promise you
we'll definetly bring him.
l'm satisfied with your promise.
we are going..
good bye..
Just think its done..
at which hope you promised her,
l cant bring him..
They are taking our kids back in
school,,so understand something.
lf you cant do that..
so l'll go by myself..
l'll say to him that
l'm your friends wife
you have to obey your
sister-in-law..
l'll do something..
Everone will have money.
you had a lot of bomb..
but you didn't explode it ever.
Bomb...?
the friend of sahir..
And shop with bad condition..
okay...
this is the matter..
So it is the ordinary thing?
So why dont you show us..
lf l have something inside..
so l can show you..
From since you have friendship
with sahir khan?
l want open the shop...
back off please..
You are reknowed personlity
of our village..
You are not that in
our sight which you was
l'm still the same..
and will remain tomorrow..
l couldn't sleep whole night..
ask why?
Mosqueto was biting you?
No!
Because l was writing,pen was
wrinting and singing for you..
Everybody thinks you are
too good..
As same is my new poetry..
l'm sahir khan..
Everywher ls sahir..
whole village is singing about him.
an super star like sahir,
friendship with billu uncle..
But where they became friends?
ln the college.
Billu went to college.?
he teachs kids the science..
How he became friends..
billu jee pumped his scooter on him,
they have to operate..
lt was big accident.,
he gave him the blood.
Therefore he is saying,
that sahir has his blood..
He called him to bombay,,
for working on films..
l denied ...
why?
These all heroes grabs the
heroins hands..
and hug them,,
l dont like it..
And now a days they
makes tatto on hands..
l'll cut his both hands..
How much money they
earned in cinema..
call us when he comes..
sahir uncle want to meet us tonight,
because he's busy in shooting in day.
Sahir uncle dont like it..
He'll come to school..
so see him there..
Father is coming..
dont heed him...
Bravo..
you turned your face when see me.
What kind of kids are you,
you should get punished..
Cause of you its been spread
like fire in whole village..
say like electric..
electric runs faster than fire
There is no peace..
priciple medam called me..
l'll tell her that l dont know any
sahir khan,,l cant bring him..
hence we'll not talk with
each other..
lf you say that you'll not bring
sahir uncle to school..
So you'll see that we'll
not go to school anymore..
For all of us..
means not only for school.
lts very proud for us that sahir khan's
friends kids learns in our school.
But billjee..you puts us in very
suspence..
You didn't gets any message from
sahir khan yet..
ls he coming or not?
after 10-12 these film maker
will go back
lf he's coming so...
we have to prepare..
Did you talked with him?
yes!
l said to him...
and he said..
no!
My shooting is going on whole
day so what l do?
So stop the shooting for
half hour..
Does it effect anthing?
lt'd be the time for lunch
in the shooting?
So he can have half hour
from that..
He's big man...
he'd be busy a lot..
lts your friend..you can force him..
We made your kids fee
for free..
lts from our fund..
Look,get the sahir khan..
or your kids will be out from school..
Dont talk like that..
so you bring sahir khan..
l'll snatch you beared..
Billu jee you just say something..
l'll try my best..
you just try your best or break.
and promise us that you'll bring
sahir in our school ceremony..
Yes l'll bring him..
l was thinking that you
are very self confident..
Now l came to know..
you just one self confidence..
There is lot of poor people..did all
runs away to see thier rich friend?
may i have some tea?
l'll give you tea...
but dont ask why l didn't put milk
why goat stop to gave milk?
Goat is giving milk a lot..
So many peoples comes for get
inform,,it spend on it..
l cant take a free moment.
Tell all of them there's no sahir
khan is coming..
Then no one will come..
just like before our house will
be detain in some corner..
l'm not going to say it..
remember it..
people turns thier face when see us before
and now they see us,
want to see us again..
ln whole this problems he
only give us the peace..
why l refused it..
people getjeoulous..
l feels so good.
you gone mad..
Kids too.
Whole village is gone mad..
only you are remain genius.
lf you are genius..
so why are you hiding...
go to meet with sahir khan..
he'll not eat you..
how many time l told you,,
he'll not recognize me..
Are you an astrologer...
you cant say without meeting him.
They couldn't find any other village..
When these film maker came here..
My destiny goes ruined..
lt was shining before...
Will he recognize me or not..
just sit silencely..
you'll come to know the truth
after meeting him...
lf he'll not recognize you so it
all right. if yes so you are lucky
he is good friend of yours..
call to guest house..
Which guest house..where sahir
khan is stayed?
Okay l'm calling.
l want to talk with sahir khan..
ls sahir sir speaking?
No..l'm yeshwant..
his secratary...
Who are you?
give the phone to sahir sir..
l cant give him the phone
without knowing you..
Who am l?
l'm an barber..
What's the matter?
give him the phone..
he know me..
give him..
Dont you have any work..
You idiot if you tease us again.
so l'll complain in police..
you understands?
you idiots..
okay...
what okay you sold your mind?
Okay l understand..
What you understood?
lf you call here again so
l'll make you arrested..
Okay carry on..
what carry on..
hang on the phone..
cant you understand...
hang up the phone..
you idiot..foolish...
Tell me..
what sahir khan says?
l want to talk with him..
He said...
he is taking bath..
l'll come to your house..
He's taking bath...
if he is so how he could talk?
Your mustache looks good...
l dont need it...even he dont want it.
Just pick it up..
will billujee pick it himself?
Get it inside..
get it..!
Look over there...
Greetings Billu brother..
Give me..!
Put it down...! what is it?
An wheel chair..!
First time in life boss
bought this expensive thing!
what else..will he buy cheap thing
for the billy brother?
Now dont say that l bought
lt worth of 25000!
No...no..When did l told
to buy this expensive chair?
you got the jack pot..!
What l do with this old chair.?
Thorow lt ln bin.!
This chair?
This ls your chair!
Get the stuff out quickly!
Remove all this rubbish..!
Look at that..new
gel,new powder,new spray
New after shave,new rezor..
and new sceizor..!
And this is windy...
and just do open ceremony of it..
No..l dont need it..
what ls the motive of your mercy!
What ls so mercy..
lts an brotherhood!
what ls the cost of brotherhood?
zero!
l seeing an world's 8th wonder!
come to home...
l'll show you 9th wonder!
you dont even let me take breath.
what's the matter?
what do you want from me?
l'm not telling you to move an mountain.
You just introduce me with him..
l want to invite him for dinner at home.
lts not possible..
l cant do that..
Listen to me..
just stop..!
Not now...but anytime you want.!
Listen to me..!
l'll not now...lets go.!
what are you staring at?
lets go!
l cant payback..!
Why are you yelling?
let him go now..!
The business is going good.
handle your work!
They came to you themself!
You didn't ask someone anything.
The peoples are yelling..!
but you are..!
lf this matter is true or false..
you'll not be prove as liar..
Listen, to get rid of people's sorrow
god takes many getup..!
you just consider it that
he came to you as sahir khan!
No..l'm not talking about
illegale promise..!
But now a days good days
has came..
Get rid of your credits..!
And thorow on his face..!
Cinema pepople will go in few days..
untill your money will resolve!
lf someone ask you..
so dont say yes and even no!
what's it is?
is that wedding your funeral?
there is more customer than
us on billu's shop!
now they will come more..
we have new stuff...!
l heared that he met with
sahir khan!
really?
he said i'm friend of billu!
sahir came to know while
talking that billu is poor man!
Then?
then sahir pitty on him...
after all he is his friend.
He said to his man for
buy some stuff for billu from city.
And he sent all stuff to
billu's shop..
l was shocked that how miser
man became an rich..
l heared that..
he'll have new A.C ln a week.
What his a.c will do?
He dont know hair styling like me.
lf sahir ls with him...
so he'll hire 100 people like you.
the employee will work for him..
and he'll handle the cash counter.
money can buy you everthing.
yourjitinder will go away from here.
You just go away from here.
l'm massaging you..
and you'r provoking me..
Mom..!
Look what father brought for us.
he didn't brought anything for me.
what happend?
the sahir khan on stairs..
l saw him..
My sleeping is has been ruined..
and night too.
Now what?
lts true that dreams comes true?
lf it'd be true so l'd be rich.
Now go to sleep.
Childs?
they are stuborn..l thread them.
lf you'll not get them on shooting
on this sunday..your food will be stop.
they are your blood..
if they decided so can do anything.
How many times l told...
he yelled at me many times..
But you never told me that
your sahir khan's friend..
people are calling me and saying
l'm sahir's father speaking
He dont listen the phone..
no one calls him..
lf we just got little money..
so will you smoke on it?
villagers gave me...
Can l ask you something..
answer me after thinking..!
should we hide from here.
And what about our goat and chickens?
We will cut them when hungry..
And if we'll come back so how
can we live?....by hiding face?
Dont know how much promises
we made. they will kill us
So you why distribute it,
l even cant see its nail
l have an idea for it!
mina was saying, Cinema
people needs the villagers
They want the mob for the festival
You know mena went to festival,
she got some money..
And she even touched sahir khan..
Crazzy fellow...
She was washing cloth with one hand.
lts good she didn't hug..
or she'll not take bath.
look...l have told you
the way which l knows..
lts your desicion to meet with
them or not.!
Where your mammals will go away.
lts not the shooting road.
The are admitting the villagers..
Tell to sahir khan that...
he'll meet you later..
We'll make you meet later..
now you go ahead..
l'm the manager of guest house..
Yes l know you..!
But lts prohabited to going inside.
yes l'm listening it since childhood.
Sir..you forgot something..
He's the manager of guest house..
What happend mr.chobay..
What l forgot ln guest house?
You forgot me..
You were giving me chance for acting.
Your promise gone away
just like the wind..
l'm an good actor...
l have played in dramas.
So you played the role of fat boy..
And in the story..
the floating stone..
You did double role ln drama..
please that inspector role..
He is the director...
Greetings..
Lets go fast..
dont move anybody..
Hide the water bottle..
you can open umbrella while hot.
Dont move anybody..
Wao..bravo chobayjee.
l'm ready..
you remember dialouges?
When l say action..
you narrate your dialouges.
What is his dialouges?
why this donkey is jumping around.
pleas take the shot without clap,
and take close up, l'll wait for it.
that holy locket..
What ls the further line..
please tell me..
Your line is..
l recalled..okay..
That holy locket..
Dont cut...
l'm recalling it..
This man is swinging..
Mother...the holy locket..
l remembered everting..
in meantime of you birth
God said...
Mother you are an prey..
God didn't say that..
l know..!
Mother said you both are star of God.
while your birth mother tied holy
locket on the god's neck..
And said you are and harmonium..
How can she tie holy locket on
gods neck..?,,,,,l know ..l know.
in thier birth mother said you
are an sent star from God.
Mother said to him
after tied holy locket.
How can She tie on ?
l know..l know..
of both kids...
after tieing the locket on mothers neck.
how can tie locket on mothers neck..
how mother....?
she said after tied both on
gods neck...
l know it...
One minute..l'll be come..
Take it...
lts coming..!
After having brith of you the
start chokes the holy locket..
One minute..
lts coming...
Someone stick the chobay's mustache..
Otherwise he'll look like
the twin brother of inspector..
After birth of god mother tied
both of them..
And set on neck with holy locket..
You begets...
Then my mother get marriade
again..
and after marriage of mine
and my mothers..
You deaf.. lf you'll not say
it properly..l'll bury you
What happend?
he cant get sahir khan
and even his shoe..
But medam its been spread on the lane..
That sahir khan will come in our school
lots of people will come
to see him..
lf he'll not come so our
commitee will be degret.
Look..l tried my best..
now you just try your best..
lf you did'nt blow the coconut.
so blow it on my head..
l said him...
remember always... Damodhar
dobay never accept defeat.
My man are on higher authority..
l know an party and his
M.L.A..
its P.A ls my friend.
l have to do something..
And lts the matter of school.
lf l couldn't angual school
by shir khan's ..so burn my alive.
lts hurting?
No l'm enjoying..!
l didn't said thatjust climb on tree.
You'd send the message to
sahir khan by the police.
lt will be chao there..
Whole province will be ruined.
ls'nt there any another way?
To inform that you lived
on this village..
l should hang my self on
the tree of guest house..
Sahir will pass from
there..he'll ask who is he
People will say that he is billu
You heared that?sahir khan will
meet with orphans tomorrow.
its arraged an lunch..
This chance is gone..
lts our baojee..
Everthing has limits..
turn off the car..
petrol is too expensive..
l cant wait anymore..
When l thought about meeting
with sahir khan..
l see him everywhere while
sleeping,eating,even in wife.
When you'll make me meet with him?
Be patient...
l'll do it soon..
ln my house everyday we
cooked for sahir khan..
And l daily sold lt on cheap price.!
till how l spend my money like water..
l heared only few days are
remaining for shooting!
What?
just few days?
He came with wind..
and will gone with wind..
You said a lot...
And just do something for me..
Pick it up...
and put on the jeep..
And get me to the shoot of
sahir khan's..
Dont start the car..
let him put it first..
Who said? l dont know him..!
l never seen him and heard about.
There is non of my friend like that.
We came from the school.
We want to meet with sahir khan..
We have talked with minister..
Let them come..
l pray to god cordially.
That you people do good deeds..
and become good human..
Now l talked a lot...
l'm hungry...lets eat..
we came to meet with sahir khan..
did you have permission?
we cant let you in..?
what kind of permission in friendship..
he's billu the friend of sahir khan.
Respect him..
So go to guest house..
guest house manager send us here.
you are teasing us...
open it..
l dont know you..
you people cant meet with him..
So we should go..
why we should go!
tell them billu is here...
Listen...greetings..
We came from the school..
yes manister called me..
Sit down please..
l'm an principle..
and he is member of our community.
he must given him my
introduction on phone.
We were friends..
before he became minister.!
l told him..
and sahir sir said yes.!
Will you have something?
confirm?
yes!
lts our goodness that we meet you.
We all are your fans..
Kids are waiting for you
in school..!
Sahir khan will come..
he'll come..
The village environment has been
change being having you.
But no one could see you..
yes but...what we do?
lf we'll allow everyone..
so our work cant be done properly.
its only enjoyement in seeing movie..
and these shootings are too boring..
You are saying right..
l and minister went to see the shooting
and thatjumping actor named
abhay kumar...
l minister were sitting..
and he set between us..
l never heed him..
he thinks he is big item bomb..
l have read about you in the
film city magazine...
l heared the you have a lot of mess
khan's are fighting with each other..
l just read it..
What did you tell me your name?
Dubay...
You are saying as you know all
film stars very well..
our film industry is
just like an family..
An family..
we have fraternity...
As in every it happens..
we loves with each other and fights..
But all this is so personal..
you know personal..
But there is one in you exceed..
That is money,pride,and the
warmth of the popularity..
And you all thinks that..
there is world because of us..
we came for the purpose of
school..so give it up all rubbish..
Sir..will you come in the ceremony.?
He'll definetly come..
because minister says..
He dubay..
l'm not the pupet ..
this film industry would be an
fiction for you..
But its work for us..
hard work..
The whole unit working here..
They didn't came for
the party or function.
Medam..please dont take it wrong..
l want meet with your kids..
and with my fans..
But..
So lts not possible..
l beg you pardon ...
no...you didn't any mistake..
lf there is like that..
we'll call some other khan..
You have misunderstanding...
about the films star..
ln real life we are local people..
We likes little things..
we got happy with little things..
We got anger with little things..
So miss principle..before l slap him
under his ear..get him out from here..
one minute dubayjee..
l'm shamefull..
You get him out from your class..
What we can do.?
there is some people like that.
You may find this kind of nuts..
peoples are yelling only for
one reflect..
Kids are not coming in school.
they are running after your
shooting on the road..
dont break everbody's heart
cause of this uncapable person.
our villager will see you in peace..
Dont say no..
Ok all right..
l'll come but...
keep that idiot away from me..
l'll come at last day of
my shooting for few hours.
l told you cant meet with sahir khan..
who are you to saying it?
are you his uncle.?
Why are you asking..
pump him..
catch him..!
easy..!
You villager people know somthing?
That how big crime you did!
Zed security is for big peoples..
And you mob is coming inside
by breaking it..
you'll be go to prison
for attemting murder..
We just went to meet with him..!
For what?
Do you want make film?
you just went with permission
or you went with your cain sticks..
not permission.
but an special person...
Who special one..?
Billu!
The corner man billu.!
You people of clay..
use your mind..
How can an corner shop man
make you meet with sahir khan?
Because billu is best friend
of sahir khan..!
Who said?
whole village said!
Who said to village..
And what is the proof?
What is the proof?
Of what?
about what?
about friendship!
Of friendhsip?
What is the proof?
What?
Did Mr.Sahir has gone his shop to
meet him,
did he called him up?
Did he got a photo with him?
You sat him on your head to call
him Billu Bhayankar.
Now where your billu has gone?
25000,
l bought a chair of 25000 for that
bastard,
l'm still paying for that chair,
And some scissors,
Denim powder, polish boxes, cream
and mirrors too,
And little plastic comb,
who will remind about that,
After listening your talk it seems he
was making fool entire village,
Yes,
l am telling you since long,
Money, Land, Jewellery,
even their meals too,
don't know what he was saying,
His house was empty now it looks
like palace,
He took 2000 from me,
and from dhallan too,
Yes, he took 700 from me,
Then why don't you do one thing?
Why don't you file a police complaint
against billu.
l'll lock him down in fraud case,
You just give us the pen and paper,
We will sign it,
Pick up the stuff and put into the
jeep.
You want me to beat him,
police will do thatjob,
Pick up all the stuff,
pick up that chair,
What is this drama?
Bastard!
When police starts beating then
you ran away,
l am a friend of Sahir khan,
Call yourself his friend you make
fool entire village,
Pick up everything,
Not even leave a soap,
l've never seen a cheater in my
life,
What did you think?
You will be safe,
He is more poisonous than snake,
Have you got haha hawai,
l've got it, but he finished powder
and cream boxes,
Write down,
write down in accounts, we will get
something from his house,
l'll see how you will do business
in this area,
Check in safe,
get everything.
Yes,
We will deduct from interest.
Your entire life will spend in jail
to shave prisoners.
He is a thief,
He is a traitor,
He even seen hair of Sahir khan,
you don't need to step in his shop.
You go home and take rest.
After closing your shop, l will
drop keys at your home,
Who is Billu Villas Pardesi.
What happen?
Are you billu?
No, l am not.
He is billu.
Let's go to police station,
What have l done?
Why dehli thug,
You cheated the people,
you made them fool and now you're
asking what have l done?
Come to police station,
l ain't do nothing,
Don't talk much,
l'm sure villagers have some confusion.
Every confusion will be away,
Tell everything to DSP.
Look billu!
No hard feelings,
don't think much,
Lawyer's fee has arranged,
Just...
....think
-to suppose it bad act-
and forget it as a nightmare.
Look, who is standing here,
Sahir khan's sister in law,
Why are you running?
Show me how liar's faces looks like,
Your brother in law has come,
we didn't see him,
He miht be came in night,
Tiwari Sir!
Yes!
Flowers are ready,
Yes,
Light speakers are tested,
twice,
Crackers,
l gave them to peon,
Okay, and childrens band,
they are in que,
Sahir's secretary has said that he
will leave at 5,
lt mean he should be here at 5.30.
Mom, quick quick,
enough.
Big people will come there,
Just dress up well.
Give me some money,
lf l want to eat something,
Ask your father about money,
lf you have then give me,
otherwise leave it.
Why? can't you talk to your father?
No,
Come dugu, everyone has gone,
Everyone is going to see him,
May l ask you one thing,
Do you really know Sahir Khan,
l know him or not,
lt doesn't matter on our lives,
l've seen his many films,
l feel that l would see him once,
lf you say then....
Go!
Stop!
Many people will be there,
don't go alone,
Sahir Khan has come,
not yet,
lt means we are on time,
Go and tell school people what l
thought,
Our boss damchand is here,
so what should l do,
he is saying if you insist him,
then he will give a speech about
sahir khan,
That will be a big pleasure for us,
But there is a condition,
You have to sit him next to
Sahir Khan.
Why next, we will sit hip up on
his arms,
Get lost from here,
Are they agreed?
No,
What did they say?
May l?
Tell!
They said that tell that idiot, crazy
dog,
that stay on some corner,
Did somebody hear that?
No!
lf someone will know in village
then l won't spare you.
Mr.Sahir is on the way,
And water bottles and....
Come on,
Move,
Hey! When l wear flowers to Sahir
khan,
you just take a snap immediately,
l don't want any excuse.
And both faces should seen clearly,
lf sahir will see on gate then he
will go back,
Madam!
you don't worry,
Go,
l will handle him,
Move!
Mr. Dube!
What are you doing here?
That Sahir khan thinks himself a
big thing,
he would be,
We are paying our duty here.
When he will come here,
l will put these flowers on his neck,
Mr. Dube! if you will stay here,
then who will give a speech on
stage,
What?
Who? Me?
What are you saying?
l didn't write anything,
How could l gave speech?
Speech is ready,
you just have a look,
Read it on stage,
lt's not an exam,
then what should l do with this?
Wear it after speech,
Listen! do as l said,
We have a space here,
Who will sit behind,
l will on front,
Come, Mr. Dube!
l'm reading speech,
but when l will speech then l don't
want any interference,
Listen!
Hey! open the door,
Get up!
Don't you listen, get lost,
Don't send them there,
close this way,
Gullu!
don't look there,
dumchand is calling,
Our respected Mr. Sahir Khan,
respected people of budbuda village
my colleagues of school and students,
don't be confuse,
l am not going to speak much,
because what's going on here,
that's a dream or truth.
l ain't understand yet,
Nobody of us didn't imagine that,
ln a small village like budbuda a
great celebrity will come,
and it will come face to face,
To listen Mr. Sahir's name in front
of our eyes all those moments come
what he played in his different roles,
Mr. Sahir is the biggest star of our
country.
and l don't need to issue any
certificate of that thing,
Move fast,
My greetings to everyone,
and lot of love,
this film's shooting has suppose to be
in some village,
and unfortunately l called up your
village name,
Budbudha,
l've heard in childhood that your
village is a nice place,
Principle said it right,
l really never thought to come between
all of you people,
l'll become a part of your land,
Actually, what human thinks about
his life,
it's not necessary that God has also
thinks the same,
that's why someone has said,
lf you want to make laugh God then
as a joke
tell him your future plannings,
Anyway, first of all,
l'm appologizing you from the bottom
of my heart,
that you people couldn't see our
shooting properly,
Actually, my last movie was little
bit controvercial,
and because of that government gave
me much security,
Just because of this security what
problems you people faced,
Believe it, l'm facing problems more
than that,
that's why l to leaving all those
things away l came near to you.
l have been told that l should give
speech to childrens,
lt's such a big word,
Forgive me, respected principle,
but l can't speak big things,
But l would like say one thing to
my little friends,
Childrens, your childhood are the
beautiful and finest days of
your life.
So, sitting there chunny will say,
that sahir l've lost my teeth and l
am feeling pain,
here bunty will say that teacher
punished me today,
some children would have a fear
of exams,
then these are not beautiful days.
Yes, l am believing you that
these are the most beautiful days,
because bunty when you will grow up,
and your shave will like this man,
Chuny, when you will become a pilot
and when you'll have tension to fly
a plane then you all will die for
these days,
But then these days and these moments
won't come back,
Today, your heart is true,
lt's noble,
lt's shining gold,
Today, what relations you will make
with your heart,
what friends you will make,
Friends like, Relations like,
will never make in life,
Today, to see you people,
l lost in my childhood,
You have nice clothes for wearing,
Good books for reading,
Nice food for eating,
and may be to see me here you people
don't beleive,
that in my childhood,
l didn't have it all,
My childhood was so decent and poor,
l wasn't filmstar sahir l was
just sahir,
My father was a poor man,
we had nothing,
but in everyone's childhood there is
someone,
who left his deep effect on our
little souls,
He became a partner of our mischiefs
and our troubles,
he became our friend,
he became our partner,
l had a partner in my childhood,
My support,
My God's light,
Billu!
My friend,
l remember,
during the break in school,
childrens ate food from their tiffon,
l put my hand to tap
and l drunk just water,
then to touch my shoulder,
raising his tiffon to me,
Billu!
My friend,
My hair were long like girls,
but to cut them l didn't have a penny
in my pocket,
To get an advantage of his father's
absence on shop,
my hair cutter,
billu!
My friend,
When l was sad to missing my mom,
then stealing money from his
father's safe,
he took me for movies,
billu!
my friend,
When we returning our homes in
evening,
to gave me greed of peanuts,
he made me perody of film characters,
Those evenings,
in the journey of those streets,
Billu found out my inside actor,
l didn't believe on myself,
as much billu was believing on me,
One day.
to sold his gold earings,
he gave me mumbai ticket,
and kept the rest of money in my
pocket,
l hold his hand and asked him how
l'll return this money,
then he told you don't need to return
them,
Just any poor man,
and remember me,
that's enough,
then l came to mumbai,
To see this running life,
l became filmstar sahir khan from
sahir,
l went back to our village to find
my friend,
but he didn't meet me,
Someone told me that he felt in
love with some girl,
and she was not from his community,
Villagers were against him,
So saving his life
he ran away from the village,
l would like to tell you the truth,
Today l have everything,
Name, Fame,
Wherever l go, millions of people
came after me, calls my name,
Every place surrounds from my name,
But still today,
in those millions of voices,
l always search one voice,
You never told me anything,
You sold your earing,
that tiffon's matter,
but he remember everything,
Yes!
Even l didn't thought that he....
....will remember everything,
l can live my entire life with that
happiness,
that sahir still misses me,
l don't need anything from him,
His heart,
is very big.
and see where he reached,
what happen?
programme has finished,
then why did you came home,
We feel cry,
so we came home,
Forgive us father,
We made a big mistake,
lf l would be on your age then l
would said the same,
Whatever you said,
l heard everything,
l was wrong about you,
that you will become a big man,
so you will forget everything,
l forgot everything,
l searched you alot,
but you didn't meet my anywhere,
But you can find my address,
You never felt to meet me,
When l ran from village then l met
many problems,
Empty hands, responsibility,
new place,
to standing this house and business
much time has spend
And you rise very quick then....
l make plans but....
You are gone so far,
then l lost my hope,
to meet you,
My condition is very bad, and l don't
want you to see me in this condition,
Leave it,
lt was my self respect,
it was my shame,
Shame?
from me,
l felt,
Forgive me,
Bindiya!
Yes!
Come here,
What are your names?
Gunja and he is dugu,
Dugu?
My name is ronak,
very nice,
This is my first visit,
won't you offer me something,
l'll bring sweet for you,
Billu!
l have to go now,
but l will be back soon,
We will go to our village together,
and if possible you stay there,
that we should live our memories
again,
He is my uncle,
and others are neighbours,
Sir, l have write a poem,
l'm a friend of billu,
Just listen once,
l will be very greatful to you,
lt's nice,
l'll use it in my next film,
No, it's enough,
Now nobody offers me these kind of
songs,