- Hi, Maile.
- Hi, Eddie.
Are you mad at me? I haven't had
to chase you for a week.
This time you're not
going to talk me out of it.
But I'm in a big hurry.
How many times do I have
to warn you? Fly now, pay later.
Please, no lectures.
I'm late. Chad's coming home.
- Chad? Home from Europe?
- His plane's probably landing now.
Follow me.
Let's not keep the soldier waiting.
Thank you, Eddie.
Thanks, Eddie! Bye!
- Hi, Wahilla.
- Maile. You got passengers arriving?
- Just one. Chad's out of the Army.
- Chad? Here, with my compliments.
United Airlines flight now
arriving at United Airlines ramp.
Wahilla, I think I'm scared.
He's been gone for two years.
What if he's changed?
Just be patient with him.
Some boys need time
to get adjusted to being back home.
- Some of 'em get it right away.
- Hi, Maile. Hi, Wahilla.
- Hi, Chad.
- It worked. She's jealous.
She should be.
Please, come along.
Get going, will you? Move along.
- He's been in the service overseas.
- For two years.
I did three years, but all I got when
I came back was coffee and donuts.
Excuse me, sir.
- Thanks again.
- Thank you.
- Maile.
- I'm not speaking to you.
- I was only having some fun.
- I saw you.
You knew I'd be waiting for you.
- How could you kiss that girl?
- It was easy. I mean...
You call that a kiss?
That's a kiss.
My French blood tells me to argue and
my Hawaiian blood tells me not to,
and they're really battling
it out inside of me.
I've never seen a more
beautiful battleground.
All right, soldier. You win.
- Yeah.
- Welcome home.
I wonder where he took
his basic training.
In Hawaii.
Sure you don't want to drive?
It's still your car.
I'm fine right here. And you
sure kept them both in good shape.
- Both?
- Your body and my car's.
- "Pupule".
- I'll show you who's crazy. Hit it!
- What are you doing?
- I'm not going home now.
"Wikiwiki" - to the beach.
- I missed you, Maile.
- I missed you, too.
What were you doing all that time
while I was missing you?
- Being true to you.
- Always?
- Almost always.
- You mean to tell me...?
Hi there!
What are we waiting for?
Got your bathing suit?
- I brought you one from Paris.
- But I've got a job!
- Today's a Hawaiian holiday.
- It is?
- You never heard of hooky-hooky day?
- Hooky-hooky!
Come on.
The old shack.
The boys really kept it up.
I used to think a lot
about this place.
I was afraid it might change,
but it's still beautiful.
- This is for me.
- You're not going to stay here.
I got a roof over my head,
a cot, a stove...
But you've got a beautiful
house in Kahala, and a family.
Let's get this over with.
All the time I was overseas, I got
a letter from my folks every week
reminding me of my beautiful future
in my dad's pineapple business.
And the more they reminded me,
the more I knew I couldn't come back
with my life laid out for me.
It's too easy to fall into that
setup. I got to do this myself.
- Can't you tell them that?
- I will!
- Good!
- When the time is right.
Please don't take too much time.
I don't know how long I can wait
for you to grow up.
You're a pretty fresh kid.
I think I'll let you have one.
Why, you little...!
- What's so funny?
- I bought it to welcome you home.
- It's the first time I've worn it.
- On you, wet is my favourite colour.
- Hi.
- Hello. Where'd you come from?
What's the matter?
Cat got your tongue?
- Could I play with you?
- You're too young for this game.
If I get a girl, can I play with you?
He's not as young as I thought.
The game's over, pal.
Maybe some other time.
- Bye.
- Let's go for a swim.
- Might as well.
We can't dance.
The suit's in this bag.
- Ready?
- Almost.
- Did you really buy this in Paris?
- First three-day pass I had.
- How's it fit?
- You tell me.
And wow.
Don't you think the sleeves
are a little long?
I used to dream of you in a muu-muu.
If my grandmother saw this, she'd
sew me up in a muu-muu for life.
- Don't ya like it?
- I love it.
And I thank you for thinking of me.
I wasn't thinking of you.
I was thinking of me.
- Now can I play?
- Can he play?
Sure, kids. Later.
- You said I can play.
- Later.
It's Chad! Maile!
- Hello, Chad! Maile!
- Hello there!
- Chaddio!
- Ho there!
- When did you get back?
- Today, brother.
- What did they feed you in the army?
- Lead, man. All lead.
Hey, Chad.
- We sure missed you, brother!
- I missed you, brothers!
Good to see you!
You guys are
still travelling light!
Sarge, what happened
to all your medals?
This is it. This is all I got.
- Look at Duke!
- Look at Duke! He missed you, too!
- He looks great.
- But he's still as stupid as ever.
Lay off! You know Duke's sensitive.
You'll hurt his feelings.
Ito, your chest slipped
from here to here!
- Paul, you still slaphappy?
- Yeah!
Shave and a haircut, two bits!
Where is it?
- Maile, you coming in soon?
- I'm not ready to come in!
Let her swim, Chad.
Chaddio, tell us about Naples.
How were those cool,
crazy Italian chicks?
I picked up this little number.
- You really want to hear about it?
- Yeah!
- No engagement rings?
- Come on. Let's hear it.
- Maile, come on in, will you?
- Not yet!
Dig this crazy seaweed.
That's no seaweed. That's the top
of Maile's bathing suit!
Maile, just stay right there!
Maile! Don't come out!
Just stay there!
He's bringing a shirt out to her.
I told you.
That dog is just plain stupid.
Quiet! He's sensitive.
He can't hear me
way out there. Can he?
It's all here, what time
your plane leaves and lands in Maui.
- Thank you very much.
- Have a nice time.
- Thank you.
- Come back and see us.
- Hello, Mr Gates.
- Hello, Maile.
I'll come right to the point.
Is my son here?
- Chad? Here?
- I hear he's been home for days.
If this is true,
I know that you've seen him. Well?
That's good enough for me. Chad's
mother doesn't know about this.
I want him home before she finds out.
If he doesn't consider my feelings,
he owes consideration to her.
I leave it to you.
- Goodbye, Maile.
- Goodbye, Mr Gates.
- Hi, O'Hara. Don't you take judo?
- Man don't live on muscles alone.
You got any ketchup in that bag?
No, but I have
some lipstick. Same colour.
- Lipstick fattening. I'm on a diet.
- Oh, yeah.
- Where's Chad?
- Back in the briny.
Even though there's no surf,
he's right back in the swim.
He's about to be beached.
- It's about time you got here.
- I left half an hour early as it is.
The fellas are having a "luau"
at the outrigger. I said we'd go.
Can't. The whole family's
meeting in Haleiwa.
- At your grandmother's?
- It's her birthday. She's 78.
That's something
to celebrate. Am I invited?
- You're hiding out, remember?
- Not from your folks.
Yours, either.
Your father came to see me today.
He knows you're back.
- You've got to go home sometime.
- Why?
You can't spend your life
on a surfboard.
Yes I can. The GI bill of rights
says I get my old job back.
- This is my old job.
- Like I said... Yankee, go home!
Wait a...
Hey, wait! I'll get you!
It's certainly nice to have you here.
Here we are.
Daddy, let's drink
a toast to your boss.
Every time I come here,
I feel like a prize fool.
I saw the latest company statement
raising the dividends.
You're no fool, boss.
Then how come I moved you here
and kept myself on the mainland?
To your glorious Hawaiian winters.
Mr Gates! Mr Gates!
Mr Gates, guess who here!
He's home!
Just drive up in car, from Army!
- Who?
- Our boy Chadwick!
Chadwick! Daddy! Jack! It's
Chadwick! My boy's home from the war!
- Sarah Lee, there wasn't any war.
- Well, don't just stand there!
Chadwick, my boy!
- Hiya, Mom!
- Welcome home, Son.
Hi, Pop. Jack!
Didn't expect to see you!
Just checking up on your old man.
- You're looking good.
- Thank you.
- Ping Pong, shut off that water!
- Don't get wet.
Hello, Mr Chadwick.
You have swinging time in Europe?
Pingo, the swingingest, boy.
How are you, boy?
Doesn't he look marvellous?
Go get the camera.
Later, Sarah Lee. Later.
- Come in.
- I have to get my bags, Mom.
Don't worry, Mr Chadwick.
I get bags...
I got it! I got it!
Tell cook we'll let her know
when to serve.
- We want to talk to our boy.
- "Oui, oui", missy.
We must give a welcome-home party for
Chadwick. It could be for Jack, too.
Forget about me.
Just invite Chad's friends.
Those nasty little beach boys? No.
I'm sure Chadwick's got
all that foolishness
out of his system, after the war.
Sarah Lee, how many times do I have
to tell you, he was not in a war.
I know, Daddy, but if I don't
tell myself there was a war,
I have a most depressing feeling
Chadwick's just wasted two years.
Chadwick, sweet boy.
- Feels good to get into civvies.
- Why'd you take off your suit?
You looked just like
Stonewall Jackson.
- You got some sugar for your mama?
- How about a drink, civilian?
Give him
some of your pineapple juice.
- Missed it, boy?
- Yeah.
You should try
the new rum drink. Jack...
Chadwick's a growing boy,
and I don't think it proper
- to give him intoxicating libations.
- I'd like to tell you...
- We were talking about your party.
- What party?
Your coming-home party to celebrate
your return from the war.
We can have the Wilsons
and the Pomfrets. They're a must.
They get absolutely
hilarious at parties.
They get absolutely stoned,
is what they get.
Yes. Chadwick, I think
it would be much impressier
if you wore your uniform
with all your medals.
I didn't win any medals, Mom.
Of course you did.
What were they on your suit?
- Just marksmanship and good conduct.
- You see, Daddy?
You just have to hit a target
instead of an officer.
You remind me of my great-grandfather
on my side. Captain Matthew Polk.
He was one of the bravest men
in the war between the states.
The daring deeds that man
performed, his bravery under fire.
His courage on the field of battle
made us all proud to be Polks.
It's such a shame Captain Polk
was a damn Yankee.
Chad, which one do you want?
- Let me see.
- You need it, boy. Take your pick.
I'll stick
to the straight pineapple juice.
We must decide on the orchestra
for the party.
If you'll excuse me, I'll freshen up
a little before dinner. "Aloha".
- Orchestra? How about my friends?
- You mean those native boys?
- The swingingest group around.
- They are not musicians, Chadwick.
- They're just beach boys.
- They've turned professional.
How do you know that?
He corresponded with them
while he was in Europe.
Chadwick, we might as well have
an understanding right off.
You've come home to stay and
your life's going to be different.
You'll associate yourself with
the finer elements on this island,
and you're gonna have
a responsible position
with the Great Southern
Hawaiian Fruit Company,
marry a girl of your own class
and be a gentleman like your daddy.
Do we have to discuss this now?
I don't want you
wasting your precious time
on those beach boys
or that native girl.
Sarah Lee, the boy just came home.
I think he should know
what we expect of him.
I know what you expect of me.
I thought I could come back
and do what you want me to.
- Now I know I can't.
- How? You just got back.
- I've been back for five days, Mom.
- Five days?
I've been living in my shack
and dreading telling you.
I'm not gonna work for the Great
Southern Hawaiian Fruit Company.
- Sarah Lee.
- Yes, Daddy?
Let's talk about it tomorrow, Son.
Home five days and he didn't
even come to his mother.
Mom, it's time I started
doing something for myself,
like making my own decisions.
Your mother hasn't finished,
and you haven't had your dinner.
All of a sudden,
I'm not hungry. Good night.
He didn't even give
his mama any good night sugar.
Sarah Lee, there are times
when I could wring your fool neck.
- Good evening, I'll take your car.
- Thank you.
It is a pleasant surprise, Chad.
We were not expecting you.
I came to pay my respects
to Maile's grandmother.
We have a visitor.
He dropped by to pay his respects
to your grandmother. Excuse me.
- I thought you were going home.
- I did. I'm out on good behaviour.
Your father
said he was glad to see me.
I'm glad to see you, too.
Come wish grandmother
a happy birthday.
Grandmother, you remember Chad.
I am delighted to see you again.
Welcome back from the Army.
"Aloha!" And Happy birthday!
I brought you a gift from Austria.
Thank you. But the light you kindle
in my granddaughter's eye is enough.
It's a music box.
It plays a European love song.
It's the same in any language.
- That's lovely, Chad.
- And so are you, Grandmother.
Sure beats lunch in town, doesn't it?
You don't get this view in town,
either.
And it was easier
to get a reservation here.
Your grandmother
packs a pretty picnic.
The way to a man's heart.
She's making sure I reach yours.
Especially after last night.
She loved the music box.
I'm glad. She's a wonderful lady.
The difference between
your family and mine!
We're not our families, Chad.
We're what we make of ourselves.
You're right.
If I'm gonna make anything of myself,
it's time I took hold of things.
While you're in the mood
to take hold...
Maile, I've got to get a job.
And not in
your father's pineapple plant?
No, ma'am. No red carpet
where everybody knows who I am.
"He's the boss' son. Be nice to him. "
That's not for me.
Hawaii has a big future.
I wanna become a part of it.
- I'm young, healthy, not too stupid.
- You're wonderful!
This place is growing. More tourists
come here than any other state.
- That's it! You thought of it.
- What?
- Tourists! Your business is booming.
- Getting bigger all the time!
I know the islands.
I'd be a good tourist guide.
You'd be great!
I'll put a word in with my boss.
No, you don't.
This mission is strictly solo.
You're coming in loud and proud.
I got to see your boss!
I've wasted too much time already.
- Haven't you forgotten something?
- Oh, yeah.
- What about me?
- Oh, yeah!
These are not only decorative,
but they keep my neck warm.
Let me see. Where were we?
We were somewhere, weren't we?
I was telling you of my two years at
university before I joined the Army.
The Army?
That's a lovely organisation.
And you say you've
lived here for 50 years?
50... No! 15 years. Since my father
was transferred from Atlanta.
That's where Chad was born. Atlanta.
He was. Yes.
Where is the Crouching Lion?
That's a rock formation on a cliff
just north of Kaaawa beach.
It used to be
a native fishing shrine.
Well. That's good. That's very good.
That's excellent.
I'm testing you, you see.
Have to be on your toes
to work for a man like me.
- Yes, sir.
- Yes, you do.
Now, I am a tourist
from Chillicothe, Ohio.
I want to see night-blooming cereus
blossoms. Where would you take me?
- I'd take you to the Punahou School.
- You would? That is good.
Yes, well... That's splendid.
This young man knows, Miss Duval.
I think he might do. He might.
Well, I'll think it over.
- When will you let me know, sir?
- When I know, of course.
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you, Mr Chapman.
Thank you, Mr Chapman.
Beautiful. Beautiful!
That's Mr Chadwick.
Quick, cover it up, Ping Pong.
I don't want him to see it.
Everything looks so festive,
doesn't it, Daddy?
- Where's Chadwick?
- On the telephone.
- Straighten your tie. Is he dressed?
- He was the last time I looked.
Fetch me a mai tai, Ping Pong.
We got more bar glasses?
- I'll check.
- Do that. Parties, parties!
Mr Chapman didn't promise anything.
Something came up unexpectedly
and he needs you.
- It's a new client, a schoolteacher.
- Teacher?
- She wants to meet you.
- Now?
It won't take long. Meet me
at the Hawaiian Village Hotel.
I don't have much luck
with teachers.
- She'll like you. Don't be late.
- I'll pick you up.
- Pick who up?
- 10 minutes. Goodbye.
I have to run out for about an hour.
You can't!
Our guests will be arriving soon.
Cocktails at seven and dinner
at eight thirty. Who was that?
- Maile.
- Chadwick...
I agreed to ask your beach boys
to provide music...
If you want me back in time,
don't start anything now.
Chadwick? Fix your tie.
She's supposed to meet us here.
- Have you met her before?
- No, I haven't.
We shouldn't have any difficulty
in finding a schoolteacher.
I could spot one a mile away.
Good afternoon.
I'm Miss Duval from the Hawaii
Tourist Service. This is Mr Gates.
How do you do? I'm Mrs Ingersol.
- And I'm Abigail Prentace...
- How do you do?
...the schoolteacher.
Sure. You can spot them a mile away.
- Won't you join me?
- Certainly. We beg your pardon.
- I'm terribly sorry.
- That's all right, Miss Duval.
I didn't expect a guide dressed
like Mr Gates. He is the guide?
Yes. These aren't my working clothes.
There's a party tonight.
Mr Gates comes from one
of our finest families.
That's certainly in his favour.
I must be very careful as
I'm chaperoning four teenage girls.
It's a great responsibility.
I get along well with teenagers.
I used to be one myself.
And not too long ago. Frankly, Miss
Duval, I was expecting an older man.
As part of the service, I promise
to get a little older every day.
If you would prefer another guide,
I'm sure the office
could arrange it for you.
We like to keep
our customers satisfied.
Mr Gates,
do you think you can satisfy
a schoolteacher
and four teenage girls?
I'll sure try, ma'am.
I'll do all I can.
What I mean is, this is
their first trip to the islands,
and the girls are curious
about the local activities.
Like surfboard riding.
Can you arrange instruction?
- I'll teach 'em myself.
- You?
I grew up on a surfboard. Outriggers,
catamarans, I can handle 'em all.
- How wonderful!
- He used to be an expert at sports.
- Used to be?
- Before he went in the Army.
He's been gone for two years.
He just got back.
I'm afraid he's a little rusty.
I'm afraid Miss Duval doesn't realise
how well-oiled I kept my machinery.
- What time do we start tomorrow?
- Nine all right? Here?
We'll be waiting.
Thank you for coming.
It's a pleasure meeting you.
- And you.
- Thank you.
Maile?
They didn't build teachers like that
when I was at school.
She's all right,
if you happen to like older women.
If she's older women, the rest
of the group are in big trouble!
You can drop me off at my house.
Drop you off?
We gotta celebrate my new job.
- What about your mother's party?
- I'm the guide now.
Do be careful, Daddy. Those
mai tais can be mighty powerful.
- Thank you, Daddy. Hello, darlings.
- Hello! This is a lovely party.
Thank you. Try the dip.
It's an old Carolina recipe.
My grandmother brought it from
Charleston to Savannah. Delicious.
- Hello, dears.
- Good evening.
Isn't it delightful?
It's all so festive.
Ping Pong, make sure Mr Karnibad's
glass doesn't get empty.
- Oui, oui.
- That's French. He's learning it.
So nice of you to come to my party.
There you are, Admiral Anthony!
I see you have met Admiral Anthony.
- General Anthony, Mrs Gates.
- You may be only a general now,
but it's only a matter of time
before you're an admiral.
- Hi, Chad. Hi, Maile.
- Hello, everybody.
- Daddy?
- Excuse me. Yeah?
- Look.
- Good, Chad's here.
- Look who's with him. That girl.
- Yes. She's very attractive.
- Aren't you forgetting yourself?
- I'm trying, Mother. I'm trying.
- Nice to see you again.
- Thank you.
This is my mother. It's about time
you met. Mom, Maile Duval.
Very glad to meet you, Mrs Gates.
Chad's talked so much about you.
He has? That's nice, Chadwick.
He's talked about you, too.
- Yes. We've both talked about you.
- Yes!
Looks like Maile's on the rack.
- Are you staying for the party?
- I'd like to very much.
- Let's get her off.
- Yeah. Let's rock!
Daddy, I'm going to have a headache.
A dreadful headache.
What was that?
Something we have to get used to.
It's called the sound of youth.
- Good morning, Miss Prentace
- Miss Duval.
- Girls, Miss Duval.
- Morning, girls.
- These are "alohas" for you.
- How lovely!
Thank you.
- How wonderful.
- It's very nice of you.
Good morning.
Well! You look more like a guide
this morning.
- You don't look like a teacher.
- Girls, our guide.
Shall we start
with the pineapple fields?
I hate pineapples.
Let's go there first
and get it over with.
- Are you going with us?
- I have to get back to my office.
- Can we give you a lift?
- No, it's just a few steps.
Thank you.
I hope you don't mind
being this crowded.
Not at all.
- Would you close the door, please?
- Have fun.
Girls, this is the island of Oahu.
Honolulu, our capital city,
is the largest island.
- Anybody know the population?
- Population, population...
Last count, 500,409.
Correct. Give the young lady
a 5lb box of broken records.
- Call me Beverly.
- I'm Patsy.
- I'm Selena, but call me Sandy.
- And what's your name?
You may call me Miss Corbett.
You'll interested to know
that since 1778,
we've been welcoming "malihinis"
from all over the world.
- Welcoming what?
- "Malihinis". That's us.
- I thought we were "wahines".
- You're both.
"Malihini" means newcomers.
"Wahine" means female.
- We're "wahine malihinis"!
- Big deal.
Patsy, must you?
- I did it! I'm bored!
- That's quite rude, Ellie!
It's OK, Miss Prentace.
Make it louder, duchess.
All right, everybody out.
This is a small pineapple field!
- What are those women doing?
- Picking the ripe fruit.
Conveyor belt hauls it to
the trucks, then to the factories.
Why do they still pick them by hand?
Before you pick them,
they gotta be ripe.
- The human eye decides that.
- That's interesting.
And nobody's come up with
a better way to break them off.
- That doesn't look so tough.
- No? Try it.
- Be careful.
- It bites!
See? They're tricky.
Full of sharp little edges.
Can you get us a pineapple, Chad?
I think that could be arranged.
Cold slices of pineapple.
- A little stand over here.
- Pineapple?
- What did you expect? Bananas?
- Ellie, don't you want some?
- Hello, Mr Gates.
- My friends would like pineapple.
- Certainly.
- I bet it's delicious.
- I need something cool.
- Have you tried it with salt?
- Salt?
- It's real good.
I'll take this to Ellie.
- I thought you might like some.
- I don't.
It's good. Why don't you try it?
Thank you!
That's pretty rude.
Are you always so bored or is it me?
Life is a bore, I always say.
- Already?
- I've had 17 years of it.
That's the fun part.
Wait till the next 17.
Don't you start that
child psychology bit. I'm no child.
I'm no psychologist.
I believe you're being paid to show
us a good time. When does it start?
- The others are having fun.
- They're drips.
- Why did you come with them?
- It wasn't my idea.
I've got two mothers
and three fathers.
You must come
from a very rich family.
- You're a very funny man!
- I'm sorry...
Don't be. Just find some action.
Got a match?
- I don't use them.
- It figures.
- What's your idea of action?
- What's yours?
You're a funny girl.
Just wait and see.
Yes, Mr Chapman?
- Miss Duval, come in here, please.
- Yes, sir.
Yes, dear, but...
Well, I certainly will, dear.
All right, eight thirty sharp.
All right, dear. Goodbye.
My wife. I promised to take her
to the concert tonight.
I must remember that, too. Concert.
Miss Duval, what is it you want?
- Mr Chapman, you sent for me.
- I did? Well, what is it I want?
- Has it anything to do with Chad?
- Chad who?
- Chad Gates, remember?
- Yes. He's a fine-looking boy.
He's bright, too. We should hire him.
He's been working for you
for two days.
He's the guide
for Miss Prentace's girls.
Girls? Wait a minute. Look here.
I don't want guides
carrying on with girls.
- There's no hanky-panky here.
- He's showing them the local colour.
Tonight he's taking them
to a "hukilau".
A "hukilau"?
Well, that sounds like fun.
My fish.
Well, you should enjoy that.
I'm not going. He's taking
Miss Prentace and the girls.
Miss Prentace. She's a lovely woman.
They make a handsome couple.
- Yes, young Gates and Miss Prentace.
- They do?
Yes. She's quite taken with the boy.
She's even extended her tour.
Now that's hanky-panky
from where I stand.
What? Excuse me. Please sit down.
No, Mr Chapman, that's all right.
I don't need a seat.
I do. I'll take two for the concert.
The concert, that's what
I wanted to speak to you about.
Could you take my wife
to the concert tonight?
I'm afraid I can't. I've decided
I'd better go to the "hukilau".
To the "hukilau"?
If you can't make it,
I'll have to go to the concert
by myself.
Yes, Mr Chapman.
"Hukilau". My fish. I... Yeah.
Yeah. Come on, boys. Come on.
You girls, too. There.
- Can I help you?
- No, we're OK. We'll talk later.
Girls? Patsy? Beverly? Sandy?
Come on.
Chad, can you go get
some firewood for dinner?
- Firewood? You'll eat anything!
- Watch it, man!
- Isn't this a beautiful spot?
- Lovely. Look at the palm trees.
- Do you want some help?
- What?
- What are you trying to do?
- I did it.
- Congratulations.
- Didn't you like it?
- You'll get us in trouble.
- Do you want to kiss me again?
- I want you to behave yourself.
- Why? Afraid you might like it?
I don't rob cradles.
Did you ever see anything like this
in a cradle?
Come here, Ellie. Hold out your arms.
Close your little eyes.
Take this to Ito.
- Come on. Catch the fish!
- Come on, let's go! "Hukilau"!
Who needs group fishing?
If you don't pull the net,
you don't eat the fish. Let's go.
The men need help! Come on!
Boy, am I full!
Lto, this is the best fish
I ever tasted.
Positively delicious.
- I've had enough.
- We all have!
- Good! That leaves more for me.
- You've had six already, man.
Ernest, counting is not couth.
Ito eats like teeth
are going out of style!
- Slice some sand!
- Yeah!
The last few days I don't know
what time that boy's gotten in.
It was after one last night.
I woke up when I heard our dog bark.
I thought it was Chadwick coming in.
Then I realised it couldn't be,
cos we don't have a dog.
- Are you listening to me, Daddy?
- Oh, yes!
Ping Pong, my eggs are cold.
Take them back and warm them up.
- Oui, oui. Morning, Mr Chadwick.
- Hi, Ping.
- You want some cold eggs?
- No, thanks. I'll stick to juice.
Thank you. Good morning, Mom, Pop.
Morning. You got some sugar
for your mama this morning?
- You're up early this morning.
- Have to, Pop. I got a job.
A job? Working?
I've been an employee of the Hawaiian
Tourist Service for three days.
- How could you?
- I thought you wanted me to work.
Not as a common employee.
Why be a messenger boy for tourists
when you could follow your daddy's
footsteps, and be vice president
of the Great Southern Hawaiian Fruit?
I fail to comprehend you.
I like my job. It's fun, interesting
and I meet a lot of nice people.
Nonsense! Tourists aren't people.
They're... They're tourists.
- Easy, Sarah Lee. I'm sensitive.
- Morning, Jack.
Tell me, Chad, where does another
tourist meet these nice people?
Try the Island Inn.
They're having a "luau" tonight.
I'm late. I'm meeting
with the Grievance Committee.
- Want to sit in?
- Not me! I'm on vacation.
- Can you drop me off?
- Sure.
- Where's your car?
- I can drive the company car.
- Bye, Mom, Jack.
- See you tonight.
Land! My son driving tourists
around like a chauffeur!
It's a disgrace.
I don't know. When you married
Fred, he was a chauffeur,
driving bananas
around in my old truck.
I'd rather drive girls than bananas!
- Right this way, folks.
- Right after you, boy!
You girls really shake that grass!
And you wanted me to go to Chicago
and visit your mother, Enid.
- Beautiful song.
- It was lovely, Chad.
They taught us that corny hula stuff
in school when I was three.
You were never three.
It's good. What's it called?
A mai tai. You finish this one,
I'll order another. Miss.
Another of these tummy-warmers.
We got some real pretty company
over here.
Howdy, ma'am. I'm Tucker Garvey.
This is my wife Enid. Say hello.
- We're from Tulsa, Oklahoma.
- Allo! I am from Paris, France.
What you know? I sure
like a pretty little French girl.
Say some more of that talk
for me, Fifi.
Je suis filet avec sole. Oui, oui?
Chateau Frontenac... Big boy.
So sorry! I make ze big mistake.
I thought it was a pig's knuckle.
- Take it easy, Frenchy.
- You are very brave, big boy.
Well, Fifi!
Parlez-vous francais?
Let's dance. Come on!
Come on, Frenchy. Let's dance.
- Wait a minute!
- Let me go!
- Let's dance.
- I don't want to!
- You wanna dance, don't you?
- No!
You're going to dance. Come on.
You're stepping out of line.
- That's my business!
- It's my business, too.
Thank you, duchess.
That was wonderful, young man.
How about dancing with me?
We haven't finished eating yet.
Come on, handsome.
Garvey, tell him to dance with me.
- Go and dance with Enid.
- You dance with her.
Not me. I've been dancing
with her for 15 years.
I'm gonna dance with Frenchy here.
Excuse me, Mr Garvey. I think you
should go home and sleep it off, sir.
You watch who you're calling names.
You're gonna wind up
sleeping it off. Get lost.
- We can settle this...
- I said move.
Chad, please!
Go on. Turn him loose, sis.
Turn that tiger loose.
Thump him, Garvey!
Garvey! Get up, Garvey! Get up!
Chad, look out!
Hit him for Fifi!
Emergency! Emergency! Police!
Hey, you! Cork up the wailin'.
I said cork it up!
Wait a minute...
Beautiful. You guys sing beautiful.
I hope you get life with me.
- Dad, I know how you feel...
- I posted your bail. Let's go.
- What about the others?
- They'll be out soon.
They all have sympathetic fathers.
- I'm very upset, Chad.
- I couldn't help it.
I thought this guide idea
would teach you responsibility.
There he is! I'll fix you!
Mrs Garvey,
I'm sorry about your black eye.
There he is! I've got him.
Lieutenant, arrest this man.
But he's just been released.
Released? That's not right.
Not at all. He's a violent boy!
Just a minute. I'm this boy's father.
If it runs in the family,
he may strike again. Mrs Garvey!
Mrs Garvey knows how wild he is. She
told me all about it. My goodness!
You should never wear green
with that eye.
- Who is this character anyway?
- This is my boss, Dad.
Your ex-boss. You're fired!
He was only protecting your clients.
You can't fire him.
Yes, I can. I'll do it again.
Just watch me. You're fired! See?
Let me explain what happened.
I don't want an expla...
Just the money. $700.
- Why?
- For the damages your son caused.
- What a mess it was.
- I haven't got $700.
- Then your father will pay it!
- I will not!
- The newspapers will be on my side.
- What newspapers?
The ones I gave the story to,
one of your guides had a fight
and everybody went to jail.
That's good, huh?
Yeah, that's good.
No! That's very bad for business.
I'll sue the newspapers.
That's good, isn't it?
- Yes. That's good.
- I'll waive the release.
No, you won't. He can't do that!
He's going to ruin my business.
I demand, Lieutenant,
that you release...
- Send him home. Just send him home.
- He's free to go.
- Come on, Chad. Let's go.
- Maile.
Miss Duval,
I'll see you back at the office.
- No, you won't, I just quit.
- Quit?! You can't do that!
Yes, I can. I'll do it again.
Watch. I quit! See?
My baby!
My baby! My baby's home
from the big house!
Will you forget those old movies?
You are all right, aren't you?
They didn't grill you under a lamp?
No. No grilling, no lamp.
I'm just fine.
I do hope this doesn't get back home.
There hasn't been a Gates in jail
since your moonshinin' uncle
was caught squeezin' corn.
He was your uncle. He was a Polk.
Mom, I'm sorry,
but it wasn't my fault.
I know that, dear.
It's your friends.
Mostly that Duval girl.
She's the one to blame.
- Maile had nothing to do with it.
- She was there.
You work in her tourist place.
Who else can we blame?
- She's pulling you to her level.
- I won't listen to this.
Then listen to this.
You tried your way and messed up.
Now try our way. No more beach
friends and no more harebrained jobs.
- Understand?
- Yes. But no promises.
If you stay in my house,
you'll go along with it.
You just made the decision for me.
Chadwick! Think of who you are.
You come from a fine family.
You'll do enough remembering
for both of us, Mom.
Oh, Daddy!
What did we do wrong?
Offhand, I'd say we got married.
- How do you like being unemployed?
- I don't.
- How would you like to be married?
- You asking?
Not till I know what the answer is.
One more setback and it's a record.
First man to lose a home, a family,
a job and a girl in one day.
You were right in what you did.
Chad, don't quit. Bounce right back.
- There's so much you can do.
- Yeah. I can be a tourist guide.
Miss Prentace thought you were good.
I saw her at the office.
She really blasted
Mr Chapman for firing you.
She cancelled the rest of her tour.
She thinks a lot of you.
I'm sorry about the tour.
I think she was enjoying herself.
- I know she was.
- Is she taking the girls home?
Unless she goes to another guide.
But I'm more concerned
about your plans.
- You're a wonderful girl!
- I am?
- And pretty! And got a brain.
- I'm so glad I was able to help.
- Take care of my board!
- Where are you going?
To see Miss Prentace.
We agreed to continue the tour.
If you'll follow through.
"Plane reservations
and hotel accommodations at Kauai. "
I'll do what I can.
By the way, congratulations.
Was she hard to convince?
No. She was all for the idea.
That's right. Three days.
When I come back, we'll celebrate.
Goodbye, honey.
OK, girls, let's go inside.
Follow your luggage.
- It's beautiful.
- Look at the palm trees!
- And the bridge!
- It's nice.
I'm going to like it here.
We'll meet in the lobby
in half an hour, girls.
Beverly, we're rooming together.
Put on your riding clothes.
I'll arrange for the horses.
- This is for dinner.
- I'm starved. I could eat a horse!
Please, make it mine.
- Shall we go in now?
- We have to wait to be called.
Who's gonna call us?
That's the traditional Hawaiian way
of announcing that chow's on.
- Pretty impressive.
- Indeed.
- Shall we, ladies?
- Yes.
Duchess? Dinner is served.
- This one and that one.
- Did you tell Chad you were coming?
No. I want to surprise him.
Are you sure Miss Prentace
is at the same hotel?
I made the reservations myself.
You're as anxious
to get to the hotel as I am.
- I have business there.
- So have I.
- Hi, Chad!
- What do you want?
- Off limits. Back to your room.
- I couldn't sleep there.
You can't sleep here. You...
That perfume!
You ought to take a bath.
On second thought,
take a cold shower.
I'm lonesome.
I want someone to talk to.
- What about your roommates?
- They're sleeping.
That's where you should be - in bed!
I am in bed.
- Hello?
- This is Maile. I just got in.
- Maile. You just got in where?
- Here at the hotel.
I thought it would be a surprise.
Surprise? It is. I mean,
I'm glad you're here.
- Are you receiving visitors?
- I was just getting ready for bed.
- It's been a rough day, I'm tired.
- Am I getting the brush?
No. I'll meet you in the bar
in five minutes.
Well, then. That's better.
At least we have five minutes.
I have five minutes,
Miss oversexed and underaged.
I spent one night in jail cos of you.
- That's when I knew.
- What?
When you fought with Mr Garvey,
I knew you cared.
I wasn't fighting over you.
Don't you think
I'm worth fighting for?
I think you're a mixed-up kid
that's too big for her breeches.
I don't wear breeches.
You're getting out of here,
Miss no-breeches Bardot!
- Chad, do you think I'm pretty?
- I think you're pretty stupid.
Would you rather hold me
than Abigail?
I'd like to hold you
over a barbecue pit.
Who is it?
- Patsy...
- And Sandy!
What is this,
game night at Coco Palms?
We've got to see you.
- What are you doing here?
- We're looking for Ellie.
- This is my room. Out!
- And that's my perfume!
You're ruining my sleep!
- That dirty sneak!
- Who's a dirty sneak?
- You! You stole my perfume!
- And my peignoir!
Keep quiet!
Ellie was just leaving.
- I don't care what she's doing.
- Don't you dare!
Go back to your room.
Go back to your rooms
and settle this.
I trust you'll explain what
you were doing here. Everybody out!
- Yes?
- Abigail Prentace, may I see you?
Just a second.
Girls, in the bed. No, no!
Hello. I hope I didn't disturb you.
I've never been more disturbed
in my life.
This is irregular,
I know, but may I come in?
Sure. Come on in.
We're having open house tonight.
I was so restless,
I went out walking in the moonlight.
Moonlight in Hawaii is intoxicating.
- I know.
- I had to talk to someone!
This is the night for it.
Chad? I'm not as young
as you might think I am. Not old!
But a little older than you. Not
that that should make a difference.
No. It doesn't make any difference.
I've taken a vacation every summer,
looking for, well, romance.
An attractive girl like you
should have no trouble.
Thank you.
I'll get quickly to my point.
When Miss Thackery asked me
to chaperone the girls,
I accepted eagerly.
I thought it would insulate me
against this frustration.
- But instead, Chad, it's happened.
- What's happened?
- I've found romance.
- You have?
I just can't keep it a secret.
- This is most unexpected.
- To me, too, Chad.
- Excuse me.
- Open up!
Ellie's gone! She stole the Jeep!
- What?
- She drove off like a maniac!
- Which way did she go?
- Out the front gate.
Crazy kid. I'll get a car
and see if I can catch her.
She went so fast,
we couldn't stop her.
- Leave me alone! Let me go!
- Stop it, Ellie!
- Let me go!
- I'm trying to help you!
- Let go! Let go of me!
- Stop it!
Listen, Ellie.
- Stop this! Stop it!
- Why did you have to stop me?
Nobody cares about me.
Whether I live or die.
Nobody seems to care because you
don't seem to care about yourself.
If you like yourself,
others will, too.
There's nothing to like.
There is if you don't try to be
something you're not.
It don't work. You better find out
now and save yourself a lot of grief.
- Everybody hates me.
- Nobody hates you.
No? Then why do my parents
always send me away -
to school all year,
on trips every summer?
And you... You threw me
out of your room.
You didn't throw Abigail out.
Do you know what you need?
A good spanking.
Maybe I do. Nobody ever cared
enough about me. Even for that.
All right. If that will prove
that somebody does care...
- You wouldn't dare!
- Wouldn't I dare?
I got a feeling this will
make both of us feel a lot better.
These hot cakes are good.
- Pass the guava jelly, please.
- Here, Bev.
- Thank you.
- Gesundheit.
See how many friends you got.
Sneeze and count the gesundheits.
Hope you didn't catch a head-cold.
No, ma'am. Just the opposite.
You haven't touched
your breakfast. Aren't you hungry?
- I don't have much of an appetite.
- Are you feeling all right?
As a matter of fact, I'm not.
I didn't sleep very well last night.
I had a restless night myself.
You should get some rest
instead of coming riding.
We'll meet out front in 20 minutes,
and don't be late.
We'll be there. We promise.
- Chad, I'd like to talk to you.
- About last night?
Yes. I didn't finish
what I was telling you.
I'm not the guy you think I am.
I snore and everything.
Abbie! I've been looking
all over for you.
I didn't want
to disturb you last night.
This is what
I've been trying to tell you.
- You mean you and Jack?
- Yes!
Congratulations! Both of you!
- Thanks.
- It's great.
I got my girl, but you've got
a few things to straighten out.
- Where?
- She was headed for her bungalow.
- I missed you.
- You don't know how great it is!
He's a nice boy.
I hope things work out for him.
He'll have to take care
of his girl himself.
Maybe I can give him a hand
with his other problem.
Operator. You look wonderful.
Operator,
get me Mr Fred Gates on Oahu.
Great Southern
Hawaiian Fruit Company.
Hi, honey!
You're in the wrong room,
lover boy.
I'm sorry about last night.
I got tied up...
With Miss Prentace! I saw you.
I could explain what happened,
but nobody would believe me.
I love you. There's nothing
between Miss Prentace and me.
Of course you deny it. But I know
that look, and she's got it.
That look is for Jack.
He's got it, too.
Mr Kelman and Miss Prentace?
You can do better than that.
You must think I'm a fool!
- Look, Maile...
- Don't touch me! Get out!
- Men! You can have them!
- I don't want them! I want you!
- Lonnie, three mai tais.
- Yes, sir.
- What are you doing here?
- Hello, Son.
It's time you two got things settled.
- Settled?!
- Sit down.
You mean you dragged
me all the way over here just...
- Why are you here anyway?
- I'm here on business.
That's a welcome change.
What kind of business?
Dad, you've wanted me to work
for the company. Do you still?
Yes. Your mother and I
both want that very much.
- Jack?
- Nothing would suit me better.
That leaves me. What do I want?
I want independence,
a chance to stand on my own,
which seems to rule out
working for the company.
But I figured a way to do both.
Work for the company and Chad Gates.
- How many salesmen do you have?
- 317.
- Scattered all over the States?
- And Canada.
Every year you have an annual
sales meeting in Atlanta.
Have you ever thought of how much
they'd enjoy a trip to Hawaii?
Bring 'em here, show them how we
do things, get some Hawaiian sunshine
and they'd go back and sell
like never before.
- I think he's got something.
- And incentive trips.
Any salesman who goes over his quota
gets a holiday here.
That's a crackerjack notion.
I'll put you in charge.
No. I wanna go in business
with Maile. That's my independence.
I wondered where I fit in.
- Maile, sit down.
- Hello, Maile.
I'm giving Great Southern this idea.
I expect them to give us
the tourist business.
My partner will figure
out the costs, OK?
- You've got a deal.
- Chad, I'm proud of you.
Lonnie, four of those little
tummy-warmers over here.
- How do you feel, partner?
- Proud and happy.
"Gates and Duval Travel Service. "
Has a nice ring to it.
It's too long. Simple.
"Gates of Hawaii. "
- Don't I get any billing?
- Gates is plural.
In case you didn't know, that's a
proposal, and that has a better ring.
You're sure?
I could be romantic about it,
but you'd say yes anyway.
- You're pretty sure of yourself.
- Isn't it about time?
- Mr Gate on line for you.
- Merci beaucoup, Ping Pong.
Hello? Hello, Daddy?
Pack your things.
You're coming over to Kauai!
- Kauai? What on earth for?
- Don't argue with me, Sarah Lee!
You better hurry over here
or you'll miss your son's wedding.
Hello? Hello?
Everything OK, Mr Gate. Missy Gate
just taking nap, s'il vous plait.
And did you know that
my daughter-in-law is of royal blood?
She's a descendent
of King Kalaniopoopoo of Hawaii.
- Kalaneaupuhuu.
- Yes. Our southernmost island.
- Yes, I know. I am her grandmother.
- Here they come.