'If Lost Look Back To Where
You Came From'
African Proverb
The Autobus By RMC
Get going, you idiot!
They scorn it
but they don't know its true value
Move on, move on
In 1943, it was one of a kind
Your father bought it
Its chassis was made in England
Its design in Italy
And its engine made in Germany
Good as gold
Runs 1 70 km/h with 30 passengers
Come on, move!
You need to pee on the wound to heal it
You're joking, right?
Water will do the job
This is pure juice
This will get it going forever
This isn't going to work pal
It broke down
Do you have any more of your brilliant
ideas, you and your friend?
Push, will you, just push!
Easy guys, this isn't going to work!
That's it, I'll get off and help
You step out, and just watch how it rolls
It's only stopped because you're so thick
The show is a few hours away
and here we are, with a battery full of piss!
Never loose faith, son!
jeez, where's the state?
Don't worry kids
This bus is going to change your lives
Alia!
Three Weeks Earlier
Where do you think you're going?
This wreck still works?
It's not a wreck. It's a piece of art
What's your name?
I'm looking for the cafeteria...
Hungry I suppose?
How about a shawarma sandwish?
Go on, out!
You said you're looking for the cafeteria?
Follow me!
There's nothing left...
You won't find what
you're looking for in the cafeteria
Let me make you some coffee
It has just been grinded, Kamal Maffousse!
I've known you since you were this high
You didn't recognize me
Must be my new look
You look so much like your father
may he rest in peace
Mr. Nabil, a real gentleman
Come here give me a hug!
- It's Vola's fault
- No, it's Arze's fault
You're the one who fell!!
Whoever's fault it was, it was a disaster!
- Good morning
I have a package for Mr. Nabil Maffousse
Dad! A gift for you!
- From who?
- From...
From me!
You know I am the only one to care for you
I thought you were practicing so you wouldn't
get embarrassed all over again!
But you're responsible too
I told you yesterday the stage was slippery
So why is it that the kids didn't fall?
On stage everyone!
Let's show Mr. Boss here
who we were, who we are now
and who we'll always be
Number one!
What a great example for future generations!
I'm counting on you Alia
Don't worry! It's you I'm dancing for
You are making fun?
I promise I will show you
Stretch more Khalil
- I'm all stiff
- You need some greasing
And you, you have a doctor's
note saying you can't warm up?
Do you have to be such a pain in the ass?
He can't be any other way
Kamal, darling, I'm here to make you famous
Not to sweat on your 1 and 2 and 3
The interview is supposed to be with
the whole group, or just with you?
Honey, when there's icing on the cake
you don't look at the rest, no?
Now, take close ups on the faces
We all know that all you've done is a bit
of dubbing. So get started will you!
So. That was the opening of a tights
store in the Armenian neighbourhood
Look, this is my teddy
Can't sleep without him!
And this is my first music video
It was a big hit
I was the big hit!
Where's your cameraman?
Why isn't he filming us?
Your time's up!
Excuse me miss
But if it's our troupe
(get lost!)
you're interested in
this album is probably much better
These damn stilettos, they break my back!
How am I supposed to dance like this?
Why don't you wear tennis
shoes like everyone else!
Flatties? Right, that should
be a real cock-teaser!
You're not filming are you?
Guys! Don't you see it's our last chance?
It's easy for you to preach
You have no idea what you're talking about
Did you hear? I think it's our turn
Alia
Don't worry! It's you I'm dancing for
- My name is Arzé
- Pleasure
I, too, used to dance with them but now,
there's only room for the skinny! awful, huh?
Even my boobs dropped!
Look, this was when we just started out
That's when we got our first prize
- Who's this?
- The one handing the prize?
That's Nabil Mafousse, Kamal's father
God rest his soul
It's true, he was always strict with us
But we loved him
He didn't know much about dancing
But he was a genius, a real pioneer
You know, our school wasn't just any school
It was an idea
He wanted a school without any social
gender or religious differences
Look here
NATIONAL DABKEH FESTIVAL OF ANjAR
Who are these people?
The Utopia College of Aley?
Is this a joke?
It is the name of our old school, mister...
Oh the dropouts' school, right?
If you please, many are waiting their turn
May we know the reason?
This isn't a dabkeh
You have no right to call this a dabkeh
This is a mix of sufi, eastern, western
It is imported from I don't where
You sir, are using the glory
of your past to make it glittery
Is that enough of an explanation?
No, it isn't
How arrogant!
You disregard your identity
and you don't even care!
There is a limit to this cultural invasion!
No Lebanese speaks arabic anymore
And our girls are all blonde!
And you sir, you dare attack
our last cultural heritage
The dabkeh?
Lebanese, does this word
mean anything to you?
- Stop it!
- Get out, before I call security
It's all my fault, I knew I shouldn't come
Let's go Kamal
Let's go!
- I hate you Kamal, I hate you!
- Let it out honey
Use my padding as a punching
ball if it makes you feel better
He was right! This ducks' dance
of yours is no dabkeh!
We've been through this enough already
This is a contemporary dabkeh, a modern one!
Modern! Fusion, world!
Hummus, soy sauce, tabbuleh!
- Whatever, but it certainly isn't dabkeh!
- Honey, it's your stomach that's gone global!
Maybe my stomach is a dump
But not my ears!
I don't mean to intrude
But I have to tell you, you were great!
Auntie?!
My darling, you were 100% magnificent!
just splendid
See!
Great or not, I'm not buying this
I have a question for you sir
Who do you think you are
to tell me how I am supposed to think?
Your tie, where is it from?
Italy, or Taiwan?
Or did you get it from your
so-called heritage Mr. Barakat?
In what supermarket can we
get some of this heritage?
The dabkeh, sir, is alive, just like us
it breathes, evolves, adapts
You're still hanging on to a bygone
Lebanon And there's no turning back
The road is blocked
So why this longing for something
that's been ravaged and killed?
How can it work out?
Each within a private struggle
Locked in lies
Hidden, secluded
Even love falls apart
Too scared to open up
Too scared to move on
How can it work out?
This man worries
Wakes from sleep in a sweat:
He knows the past can't
Be forgotten or laid to rest
Locked in lies
Hidden, secluded
This man won't take chances
Except through his dancing
And here my friend
It's doomed to end
Locked in lies
Hidden, secluded
Between two take-aways
This man's life is fading away
He's gonna get white hair
And his daddy still won't care
Locked in lies
Hidden, secluded
Here's Vola, Sweet Vola...
Why did you stop?
I don't feel it
Maybe I can raise the pitch higher
No. It was good
Are you sure?
Yes
Take it again, but please, don't stop
Locked in lies
Hidden, secluded
That's it
What?
You got the the right tone
Alia, can you take it again, same level?
Ok
Let me drink first
What's funny, is that I've been working
on this music for 15 years
And it's only now that
I found your voice for it
Maybe if you clean up this place a bit
it will Help you tie all
the loose ends you left hanging
The only thing missing was your voice
So I'm your muse now, Mr. Mafousse?
Shall we go on?
If you don't want to continue, just say so
Are we back to the same old story?
We've been practicing for two months now
We're all exhausted
All we're asking for is
one week to take a break
Is that too much to ask from the boss?
You want a week?
You got it
Here's Vola, sweet Vola:
Reaching for love
Playing her life as if on screen
Trying to fulfill her dreams
Weaving endless illusions
To hide her deceptions
Here's Vola, sweet Vola:
Reaching for love
Hi sweetie
How are you?
So, how long before your
Mrs. calls her pet back home?
45 minutes maximum
You know what?
I've had it with your timing shit
A woman like me
you have to appreciate her
How many times did I tell you
I don't want to see his face
It's my father, and this is his place
I take it you haven't changed the locks either
Afraid your best friend might catch us?
It's high time you turned the page
You don't even ask me how it went?
What happened?
What kills me most is that
there won't be anymore rehearsals
It's over
Oh, the dabkeh!
Don't tell me you were planning
to stay with these idiots
Come now, sit here darling
Pack your stuff and leave
Because I'm not in the mood
Not today, not tomorrow, not the day after
just get the fuck out
Locked in lies
Hidden, secluded
Nothing improves:
We're tired of being broke
Sick of this legacy
That makes our lives a joke
All for illusions of past glories
just for once let's sing out
And through us let there be joy
For once let's sing out
And through us, let there be joy
I thought I could get out of this rotten prison
When my father sent me to study abroad
I thought I was free
After two years, I thought I could tell him
I came here for one week
just to do that and then leave again
At the time, I was doing fine
I had a three-year contract
with a big German danse company
But as soon as I got here
The war broke out in the South
It was really ugly
The German embassy wouldn't renew my visa
I showed them my med school papers
They rejected me four times!
I tried France, no way!
England, don't even think about it!
And the US, they didn't even
look at my passport!
Omar
The name itself is a crime
Whatever brought you back here, Kamal?
Everyone here wants to go away, and you
You come back rubbing salt on old wounds
Don't worry
It will be fine
You don't realize what you're asking
What's it to you?
If it works, all the better for you, but if it
doesn't, you just go back to your country
- You got the citizenship, right?
- Yes
Lucky you!
What about the others?
How are you planning on winning them over?
I have a surprise for them
This is the CD
I might use it for my story
You know, my grandma's name is Isabelle
Really!
I used to get such beatings from her!
I like beating men too
Would you like to come in?
No thanks
Maybe another time
As you wish
She got invited to this TV show
And you know her, the minute she hears
the word TV she goes all nuts
So she goes to the doctor
and gets her lips stuffed with silicone
- Stuffed with what?
- Silicone
- No way!
- just imagine what she looked like after!
That's why she cancelled the show!
She said she had a running fever
Well done, she's always lying anyway
- Well, well look who's finally here
- How are you auntie Haifa?
How are you?
Your cousins called. We are all going together
to pay our condolences for your great-uncle
Tomorrow at five
I told them ok
Unless you have other plans?
No, mum, don't worry
I don't have plans anymore
Good night
How old is Alia now?
30, 31
Kamal, Kamal
This was the first time
we saw each other in 15 years
As if he had never left
She looks innocent
You think so?
Isabelle, where's your story?
Hello boss...
I haven't finished it yet...
I'm working on it the way you told me to
Don't forget to show it to me
before it goes on air
Yes, sure
That's his girlfriend, right?
Besides Omar and you, all the others quit
Why did you stay?
Why?
Well first of all, Alia hasn't decided yet
And second, I like his music
and he's my friend!
That's it?
There's no other reason?
- When I become a star, you'll find out
- Meaning?
Meaning, you make us famous with
your story and then you'll see
What if there's no story?
Then it will remain a secret
This 100% Lebanese company was excluded
from the Anjar festival this year
Blasted for prejudicing
Lebanon's cultural heritage
Molly! Molly! I am on TV!
Of course, madam is a madam!
They don't seem to think you're a disaster!
I want to live with my time
not in a bygone past!
Bygone past? Man, you're way off!
Once more, this year we did our best
to respect our traditional values
We believe that there can be
no evolution without roots
Alia, Alia, come see your sweetheart on TV!
Mum! Mum! You're on TV!
It's the Lebanese public that should decide
whether our dance is popular or not
Not a senile jury
Thank God we have TV to tell us
What's going on in your life
It's true I'm not all that young anymore
but this dabkeh is just amazing!
In fact, I invited them
to dance here in Baalbeck
What, what, Baalbeck?
He's gone mad!
I have to call them
Hello
The dancers haven't given up. And like
the Phoenix, they have dusted off the ashes
And decided to go on a tour across
the Lebanese regions
Arze, it's for you!
So they want to show Mr. Mahfouz Barakat
That they can go to the people
Instead of the people coming to them!
It will be an itinerant festival
the troupe will be dancing
In Rachaya, Baalbeck and even junieh
That's history
Come on, dinner's ready
He's playing it smart all right
What's this, can it be right?
He's either bold or just thick
He's a pusher, he's real slick
No, no, no, no
If he thinks he can go on
Doing things that can't be done
Television, Television
I have my name to protect
This is something I can't accept
No, I can't. He's making fun of me
This tune, I can't hear no more
It's eating you to the core
You keep singing it to me
The world is changing, can't you see
Stop sighing for these lost wars
And this dabkeh that's grown sore
This tune, I can't hear no more
It's eating you to the core
No, no, no, no
Since the end of this damn war
You don't see your way no more
There is more than the dabkeh
That's worth living for, I say
I can't
Don't want to
There's nothing you'd like more
You can't hide it anymore
Even your daughter is dancing
To Trance, hip hop and Samba
Tomorrow you'll stop your sorrow
Your friend's word you'll follow
Lend an ear and take a cue
Take it slow and think it through
You'll come back
tell me that you'll come back
You know why Kamal
wants us to meet here?
To make us feel guilty!
Stop it, school memories
are much harder on him
We really fucked this place up!
Look...
You remember that silly game
we used to play?
- What was it called again?
- Dodge ball
Oh yes, dodge ball
I also remember when I was on the other side
of the mountain, on the mortar
And I was ordered to fire
I totally screwed my childhood!
Did you see the cafeteria?
1 7 years of war, and not one bullet!
Not even a scratch!
Number 1!
That's the one I used to take
This bus is blessed by the heavens
Nothing happened to it during the war
Mister Na..m says we can do whatever
we want with it. Is that right?
The bus belongs to the school
meaning to your father. So?
So now this thing is supposed to take us to
Baalbek, the land of the dabkeh?
They're going to grind us to bits
and throw us to the lions!
Why did you come then?
Katia doesn't agree, and she is not here
What's your problem?
If you really want to know
I don't agree either
But I'm here for your father's sake
For the pledge we made to him
Dancing at a wedding, that's all we needed!
- The television will be there
- TV? Oh my!
Isabelle, the reporter, will be doing a 2-minute
report on us every day for the evening news
It's thanks to you, you know
I told you! Icing on the cake!
So what story did you make up
for Isabelle to get on prime time?
The hurt, misunderstood artist
or the uprooted martyr?
I said I know how to make pretty girls dance
And our beauty queen here
is she still running?
No it can't
But if you fill her up
she'll take you to the Indies!
What are you planning to do
if Katia doesn't show up?
- Can we dance without her?
- Toufic, I have the solution
Stop worrying!
I don't believe this!
Oh you better believe it!
She's right. Plump dancers spice up the show
Even Bill T. jones had overweight
dancers in his New York City show
This is Arab City, honey, not New York City!
There is no way that Arze is going to dance
- Why not?
- A bit of practice...
And she'll blow us away!
Well?
THE ANjAR FESTIVAL
- THE AUTHENTIC RECAPTURED -
Alia!
- Mum, I'm not going to school!
- Home-cooked food is healthier
Good morning Mrs...
Morning Sir...
Oh my Lord! What is this?
Dad, this is Kamal
Kamal Maffousse
We were together in school, remember?
Kamal yes, yes, of course
Do you still live in France?
I'm back now
I'm warning you Kamal
if anything happens to her
Don't worry. Alia is like a sister to me
Thanks. One brother is a handful already
Dad, don't worry, I'll be back soon
I know she can be a pain
Don't worry about me. Have fun
I thought she was over him
My mum actually thinks I'm in
the mountains nursing an old woman
You had the guts to tell them!
Mine thinks I'm on a set with Omar Sharif
I'm dying to see their face when they see
me on TV playing the wedding entertainer
Bye bye
Grandiose culture
Crude and rotten, Bye bye
All around pictures of chicken
Platters of food deep-frozen
Bye bye
Brand babes, so sexy
'Tabbuleh in cans- Falafel-makers'
Paradise, as far as the eye can see
We're out of here, you and me
Thought these smiles were for me
Bye bye
Highways of national unity
You peoples free and selfish
Bye bye, bye bye!
RASHAYA- MOUNT HERMON
Off Anjar is an alternative festival
that takes place across the country
So with Anjar, it's out
and with Rashaya, it's in?
In short, it means that
we'll be dancing here in Rashaya
And we need the keys to grandfather's
house to spend the night
Dance huh? And you're going to dance!
And you mister, are you dancing as well?
- No, but...
- Well, good for you!
I wish Omar wouldn't dance either!
35.000 US$ to send him
to Germany to become a doctor
Please dad, not this story again
35.000 US$, in those days
we had to take a loan!
Once he would get his diploma, we thought
he would pay it back double, triple even
Dad, please!
Go on, pour him a third cup
Kamal is family!
Thanks
So you want the keys
to your grandfather's house?
Yes
So you can wiggle?
So we can dance
Go find yourself a hotel will you!
Go!
This is your grandfather's house?
What a shame!
- Don't worry
- This is the last time I set foot in this house
We had agreed to share all the expenses!
Don't complicate things. I don't want to!
What's going on?
Omar's father doesn't want to take us in
And Omar here is playing Great Gatsby
If we can't stay at my grandfather's house
I'm going to pay for the hotel!
It's my money, and I'm free to do
what I want with it!
- Why are you insisting?
- You're in my village!
And these are our traditions! Don't embarrass
me any more than I already am!
What are you watching?
I'm just zapping
I'm scared about tomorrow
I didn't know you were so popular!
The whole town and their mother are here!
You really think they're here for me?
It's the Diva they're here for!
No, no, no!
I've said this a million times, this only
comes at the second musical phrase!
It's set, everyone's here! Even reporters
But not his highness of course
Omar, I told you he was coming
So, how many dances are we allowed?
Only one!
After all, we're only appetizers
for the great Diva
Put the electro version!
I thought you said it wouldn't work
with the mentality over here
I didn't want to, because of my father
But since he isn't here
Put it on, I like it better
Kamal, we're on
OK, I'm coming
This is the second time!
Baalbeck would really be the end!
Toufic, enough already
You were very good! Not one wrong step!
Particularly you Omar, you were excellent!
Omar, you know they are a bit conservative
here, but that doesn't mean they didn't like us!
My father didn't want me to dance
Neither did my mum
But I did
I struggled, but for what?
Nothing
What have I achieved? Zilch
I need them! They're my family!
At least, you stood up for your choices
You, get off my back!
What is it to you?
If it doesn't work
you just return to your country
My country?
My country is here!
I am Lebanese, just like you
It's this country that is estranged, not me!
They're here! They're here!
Welcome! You came from so far, just for us!
We won't let you leave with empty stomachs
Please feel at home
Welcome, welcome
I have only these flowers to offer you
You're very generous. Thank you!
Kamal!
The jar is heavy, but the scent isn't
Why don't you give these to the pretty girls
For me?
Are you sure?
Welcome to Rashaya
We're glad you're here, because
we always enjoy shows like these
Well, well!
Look who's here! Welcome!
I won't bother you
Sprinkle some of your glory on me!
Oh I see. You get prickly seeing
so many men around me
Not at all. I love crowds too
I can't help it. They're fans
Sure!
Considering that you're so prudish
You don't like it?
Sure I do
But I like it alone
without the traffic
It's all a matter of fate
Maybe if we had stayed together
I'd be cooking and scrubbing right now
It wouldn't have worked out anyway
With the war and the roads
to your house blocked
Oh stop it will you! You were afraid
of marrying a Christian girl that's all
Oops! I forgot
We're not supposed to mention this...
What about your family?
They treated me like some low-life!
Don't get mad darling
You made your decision
Come on, smile
and let my splendor shine upon you!
Toufic!
Why did we stop here?
Get a grip darling!
Loosen up!
Go ahead, he's waiting!
Can you believe it, he went mad?
Saying that no one understood the dance
Omar, come on, he came to see you
You should be grateful
I've been dancing for ten years
and he never even tried to see me
He went too far!
Maybe he went too far
but at least, he's still alive
Go hug him while you still can
You should have said
that you became a dance doctor!
Was it you singing?
Yes, why?
What were you singing?
A lullaby my grandma used to sing to me
I don't know
It just sounded familiar
It felt strange, as if it were calling me
But I didn't expect it to be you
Kamal
You're knocking at my door in the middle
of the night to talk to me about lullabies?
What do you want?
Nothing...
You want to come in?
No. Tomorrow is a hard day
You should rest
As you wish
Good night
Dad wants to check how I'm sleeping?
On my belly!
Mum, go baby him for a change!
Yes mum, I told you Omar Sharif
but I could've said anything
Because you don't care anyway!
Yes, mum, I hear you. Everything's all right
Are you taking your medicine?
Take care, I love you
All we need now is another
embarrassment in Baalbeck!
Don't worry
This ain't really anything
It's a mix of everything
It's a mix you old fool
This is hummus, that is fast food
This is dabkeh, ain't it neat
Dabkeh on a techno beat
We don't have to do this
THE 'OFF' ANjAR FESTIVAL
THE AUTHENTIC (RECAPTURED ) 'MODERNIZED'
BAALBECK
This itinerant festival is a first in Lebanon
Its success can be attributed
to Kamal Maffousse
A composer and choreographer
One of the brilliant minds that lives in exile
Who decided to leave France
and return to serve his country
It's a bit over the top, no?
I'm not doing this for your pretty face
It's a special request from the boss
You see this van you're in?
My boss only uses it for the hot news
Meaning?!
Your group is certainly not hot news
At most, you make a good cultural report
But he still gave me the van
Looks like he likes you!
Watch this!
The dabkeh used to have its own heyday
In Baalbeck, Baakline
and all those festivals
Now the dabkeh has almost disappeared
just like our tradition...
The show was very nice. It's new to us
I really liked the Dabkeh, it was really nice
Do you feel how tense I am?
Did you enjoy it?
I loved the edit!
During our tour, we came across
this billboard for the Anjar festival
- Look guys, check out the pasha on TV!
- 'We asked Mr BARAKAT what he thinks...'
These billboards are an insult to our
festival and we cannot remain silent...
This case does not end here
We shall sue these criminals!
Your friend, my boss, must be very happy
Girls, the groom says he can
only give you two bedrooms
You need to share
No way
Obviously. Stars like you don't share rooms
All the better, that will spare us
the symphony of your snoring...
Ms. Bach!...
Good evening ladies and gentlemen
and welcome
Tonight, we have prepared
a surprise for our newly weds
Who are sitting here, without a clue!
This is going to be an exceptional evening!
We want to sing...
Dance and clap
And we want to love each other
Oh God, everyone knows me here!
There's no way I'm going in!
What did you think pussy cat? You're
just a cabaret dancer now, nothing more
If you're afraid, pray, like me
Pray! Whom to? Your God or mine?
Everyone prays for his own God
that way we'll have them all on our side!
Enough already Toufic!
We were all brought up
with the same principles
There shouldn't be any of this between us
Fuck your school values
Politics in this country
They feed it to us in the bottle at birth!
Will you stop your bullshit now
We need to focus on the dancing
Please welcome Toufic and his fellow dancers
DIGI DABKEH!
I swear, I can't
This is Baalbeck guys!
You're already in too deep!
If I were you, I would just dash right in
What if they actually like the dance?
And you're not with us
What would your friends say then?
No balls!
Come on!
Louder, Louder!
All right, but let us first start
with the regular Dabkeh
At least to show them
that I'm a real dabkeh dancer
If it makes you feel better
If it weren't for your father, Kamal
Oh jesus, Mary!
Help us God!
Oh Lord!
What an ass!
You are one bastard!
Viva Travolta! The King of Dabkeh!
You were incredible!
Why did you do that?
Didn't I do well?
No
What are you waiting for
to carry me sweetpie?
I talked to my boss. I told him it was great!
He wants to add a minute to the report
See?
She's saying it was great
I would like to thank all those
who are here today for this great party
May God bless you!
If you enjoyed the dabkeh so much
I suggest we open our dabkeh club
that has been closed since the war
And if our dear Toufic agrees
We would like him to run it
Thank you, thank you!
This offer couldn't have come at a better time
Because I'm looking for a job anyway!
But I need to make one thing clear
I hate techno music
And all these noises they call music
It is the real dabkeh that I like...
The dabkeh of the young man standing there!
If you want me to repeat this mascarade
you just saw...
Then I'm sorry, but I cannot accept the offer
But if you want the real dabkeh...
A school of authentic dabkeh
that comes from the heart and soul
Then I'm your man!
We want dabkeh! We want dabkeh!...
- I missed you so
- So did I
I would have liked to offer you more...
Thank you. It's very nice!
I'm the one to thank you!
I was so afraid my wedding would be dull
I love hip-hop
I can see that
And your husband, he likes the same things?
I have no idea. We don't talk much
when we're together
I think I intimidate him
How long have you known each other?
Not long...But he's a good person
Sorry Toufic, I can't
Why? Is there something wrong?
I can't do this to your wife
My wife? You know her?
All my life I dreamt of being her!
It's as if I knew her in a way
Are you playing around with me?
Toufic...
If we sleep together...
You'll be like all the others
You'll leave your wife and daughter
And you'll become like a toy in my hands
Then I'll dump you like an old shoe
I don't want to do this to your daughter
I don't want her to be hurt
like I was when I was a kid
Because of a bitch
And you, how many children do you have?
Let me find the husband first!
But, how old are you?
A little over 30
There haven't been any suitors?
No, there have been many
But I guess I...
I just waited too long for prince charming
Will you wait for me?
Don't worry, I'm here
It feels so good!
Did you sleep well?
Not a wink. You?
Same here. The beds are expired!
I can't resist the smell of butter
in the morning
Oh, you're so kind!
I'm not so sure you deserve this
So, who's the best dancer?
You are! The best dancer of all!
- And who's the most generous of us all?
- You are!
- What are you doing?
- What do you mean?
You are stuffing yourselves
while I prepare a knefeh for you!
Come on guys, let's eat!
Hand me a plate
Hand me the syrup
What are you doing?
What about morning practice?
Why don't you relax for a change? join us!
You're going to need five days
to be able to dance after this
Come on. Come sit next to me
And enjoy this knefeh
How come we're still taking orders from you?
If you think you can stop dancing just because
you got a couple of claps yesterday, you're wrong
We need to make Mr. Barakat
be sorry for what he said
Is there something wrong?
Bless your soul! Are you ever wrong?
Come on Kamal!
How could we
Let heaven slip away
The Knefeh: a gift from God
So relax and do as we say
Won't you quit shaking your head
You're not eating cheese and bread
It's a blessed meal you're eating
Like a secret passion or lust
What's hidden, you need to feel
You can't touch it, it's unreal
The Knefeh: a gift from God
Relax my friend, and do as we say
Eat up!
Rule number 1:
Dabkeh dancers must form a circle
Dabkeh should be hand in hand
The first one in line meets the last
Here, there is no first nor last
What does this mean?
They are just jumping
This is no Dabkeh!
We invented this legacy!
Today we're here in your town
Dancing dabkeh all around
Your town, your pride, your mark, your land
So don't trade in
Coz you got it all here
Here, come see what you have
Coz this sure is the place to be
So won't you please quit being down
just see what's going all around
Come here see what you've got
Ain't no secrets, ain't no Anjar
Ain't no fuss
If you want
We have no problem if you go
Now throw your tie far from here
Get focused and ready
Keen and intense
For the party
At the Utopia College of Aley
A big group will be dancing the dabkeh
A group that has style
Strange a bit, but real cool
At the college of Aley
You men are lucky!
This country is blessed by God!
Blessed by God and ruined by its people!
Ruined by its people?
We are its people
You and me
What's this about dancing at the school?
Are we back to the same old story?
Our heritage is under threat!
Don't live in caves
See my belly, see
Watch how it sways
Come dance with me
Vola's in town
Move closer, move
Better than on screen
A quick dance to go
Don't live in caves
See my belly, see
Did you know about the show at the school?
No more than you!
Did it come to you just like that
like a revelation?
Mr Mahfouz is starting to feel the itch
And we have to make him eat his heart out
By taking us back to the cafeteria
And hitting on the sensitive nerve!
That's blackmail, Kamal
We need to come full circle
Listen Kamal!
I dance to forget my pain
I can't keep reopening the wound
Stop playing with your nightmares, Kamal!
Don't you see that it is hard on us too?
We haven't forgotten either
No one can forget!
The thing is we just gave in
End of story
Oh Oh! there's trouble
Move over!
- Good morning
- Move over I said!
Stop the car on the right
Prepare your camera
Your story doesn't make any sense
A bus from 1943 and you want me
To believe that it's in order?
Please...
Not once did I pay the license tag late
Even when the bombs were pouring down!
It says here that it's blue!
But this is a blue touch!
Have you found anything?
Nothing so far, sir
Captain...
My name is Khalil Daoud
I have this letter from the Minister...
Pursue the search!
Come on...
Throw the bags!
I'm telling you boss
they are all being held at the checkpoint
- Get yourself arrested
- Arrested, me and the cameraman!?
Of course, film everything, everything you hear
And try to be on your worst behavior
But you realize that if they get arrested...
I don't need to hear your explanations!
just listen to what I'm telling you
And do exactly as I say
If they arrest one of your clowns
I can't do anything
But if they arrest a member of my team
I can bring hell down on them!
There's nothing sir
No spray cans, no paint bombs
It's for you, Captain
Go ahead. You have nothing to lose!
Hello, yes?
Yes sir
One minute and we'll be free!
Yes...
But Colonel Assaad told me...
Yes sir
I am so grateful!
You still don't know the real value
of Isabelle Morcos!
Yes Sir
As you say, sir
What a country!
Our savior Isabelle!
Stop here please
I'm leaving before I start hating you
Alia!
I said, go!
This girl:
Trapped in her worries
Wakes from a dream
To find her past constantly reset
She must move on
But can't let go
Where do you come from my friend, where?
Where are you heading, where?
My heart betrayed, I drift away
The face I loved, erased
Where do you come from my friend, where?
Where are you heading, where?
My hair is now long
But your voice is weak
My heart is in pain
And won't heal
Where do you come from my friend, where?
Where are you heading, where?
Can you learn to let go
Of the weighted past?
Learn to love after the pain?
I can't find my path
I've strayed too far
Longing for the past, lost to time
The image I had of you was so strong
Now it fades and your voice has gone
jUNIEH
That is all that is left
of our beautiful sand beaches
What do you want to do Kamal?
We can't dance without Alia
Vola will replace her
No way! There is no way I can replace her
I'm already out of place!
Without Alia
You can't do anything
Katia left, and now Alia
There's no troupe anymore
What are you saying?
You want to cancel?
OK, Go say this to Khalil's uncle
who opened the place just for us
Go say this to his folks
All of junieh is here to see him dance!
Our relatives have seen us dance
and that's what counts
You know I can do it
You know what that means?
Anyway I've always wanted them to know
Now I'm giving them a chance to applaud
I am sure it will be all right
WELCOME TO THE ''OFF'' TROUPE:
THE DIGI DABKEH
You deserve every clap you got
It's all thanks to you
I've got great news for you
The jury's president Mahfouz Barakat finally...
Agreed to let you participate in the contest
Anjar is opening its doors to the DIGI Dabkeh!
- My boss just told me
- Really?!
Finally!
Come over here
Tell me, your boss, can't we meet him?
I'm sorry, I don't get it
What made Mr. Barakat change his mind?
Kamal, it's all about money
between Barakat and my boss
Our network always had an exclusive
to broadcast the Anjar festival
But these days
Mr. Barakat set the price too high
So let's say your tour
was a way of putting some heat on him
So we were just an excuse
to get a better rate?
What's it to you? What matters is
that we're finally going to dance
Why don't you go get Alia
instead of asking stupid questions!
No, I'm glad, but if I get this right
You were playing us from the very beginning?
Don't be so dramatic!
It's business, that's all
They had to fill up the grid and they did
And you don't give a damn about our dabkeh!
No my dear, I won't accept it!
What do you mean?
Kamal, I really don't understand you
I thought you would be happy
Wouldn't you rather be in Anjar aired
on TV and seen by the entire country...
Than dance in ruins before
a couple of people?
You're right. But we would rather dance in
ruins infront of a couple of people as you say
This is ridiculous!
You don't get it, do you?
The off is more important than the in
It's better to be out than in
The greatest revolutions happened from
outside. Nothing happened from inside
What revolutions are you talking about?
Even if you're right
We have no choice but to go on, together
Listen Kamal Mafousse, Vola Andraos
is dancing at the Anjar festival
Whether you like it or not
And anyone who loves me, will follow me!
I don't understand you anymore Kamal
Kamal, what are you doing?
You get what you want and you check out?
Congratulations
You played us perfectly!
I tried warning you Kamal
But you were...
Too self-absorbed to listen
Well anyway, thanks, really
That's all you have to say to me?
You too, you want to go with them?
Where shall I take you?
I thought you were asleep
No
Where are we going?
You said drive, so I did
Here you go, I'll stop
What have I done?
All I wanted was to bring them
back together around the same tune
A music, that would help us bury
all the dead things in us
It turns out I am unable to bury anything!
And here I am
Like a fool, being driven in a bus
I wish I were outside all this
I wish I could go far, but where to?
Out far, it is void, there is nothing
Nothing
This bus was nothing before you returned
But nothing is everything
What would have happened to it
If we had left it?
Nothing
A blank page
Nothing is everything!
You knew my father well
What would he have done in my place?
You should ask yourself that question!
Go on Kamal
The cafeteria is right there
Go in, ask him
You are making fun?
I promise I will show you!
There's no way to know in a country like this
It is all of us and yet non of us was in it
They even handed weapons to children
They didn't want anyone to understand
They abolished thinking
So, do you want that coffee or not?
Yes
Come
If I come back
It'll be for you
Yes...
What, you came to see if I'm singing
Or if I'm dancing...
for you?
Or did you come to say good night?
I'm not dancing and I'm not singing
Neither have I been sleeping
Kamal
You come and go and you're still
in the same place
We all tried helping you get over your father's
death, but you're not willing to
Alia, I understand
But, I can't take seeing you
Sad and hurt anymore
And I keep missing you
This is a music I've been working on lately
It's not techno, nor dabkeh
It's a Lebanese mix!
He won't stop, will he!
It's a five
Not a 6 and not a 4
It's a new beat that we did
1, 2, 3, 4 and 5
Do that again, will you?
Unbelievable!
He doesn't limp when he dances!
You can dance!
Maybe if he does, he'll quit harassing us!
Not in your wildest dreams!
Seriously Kamal, show us again
CNBS Presents
The National Dabkeh Festival Of Anjar
We live in an era driven
by a race for evolution
Arrogance and vanity are the prevailing traits
The new generation will tread
the same path we took:
Everything they feel passionate about today
Will be discarded by the next generation
Objects of our own desire could
well become objects of disgust
So what is the solution?
Thank you
To hell with television!