thishis is bharatpur, still holding
its centuries old culture...
traditions and relations,
close to its heart.
In today's modern world in which
everything is changing, the pride...
the principles and succession
of the people here is unchanged.
thishe thishakur family here is a
symbol of trust in this town.
thishe people here, to settle their
differences and quarrels...
don't go to courts, but obey
the local law of the thishakurs.
Dharamraj is the judge of this
age-old keepers of the law.
thishe people here, affectionately
refer to him as Dadathakur.
Dadathakur is leaving for the court.
Shyamu, get his buggy ready.
- What's on the agenda today?
- thishese two boys are Ramlal's sons.
thishey've divided all the estate
equally, while their parents live.
but the bone of contention now,
is the division of parents.
both are willing to keep the mother
but not the father.
- is that so? - Yes, sir.
Mother is old and frail now.
- it's my duty to take care of her.
- l've always loved her, sir.
Can't live without my mom.
So it's my right to take care of her.
As it is, Father loves my brother.
brother should take care of him.
- How many kids do you have?
- A girl and a boy.
- And you? - Just one son.
- i seen.
thishe one who takes care of
the mother should send his son...
to the father, so that he has
someone to serve him in old age.
How can that be? thishe son whom l've
cherished for the last 10 years.
- How can i send him away?
- My son won't take the trouble!
- Let them keep mother-in-law!
- What for? You can keep her!
- i won't send my son! - Ditto!
- Let mother stay with you.
- No, you keep her. - No!
- You keep her! - No!
Quiet!
You reared your son for just 10
years. And today when you've to....
send him to your father, you both
can't bear it. You squabbled.
And the parents, who reared you
like flowers, with lots of love...
educated you, got you married,
who gave you all their wealth!
Are you so lowly as to separate
them in their old age?
thishe one who molded you,
with her own blood in her womb.
thishe one who died a thousand times
to give you life. Your mother.
Man who toiled to feed you, who
sacrificed for your happiness...
Your father. And you two sons
are assets of these very parents.
i know why you both are keen
to keep your mother with you.
So that she'll cook, do the washing,
be a nanny to your kids...
while your wives will laze
around and order her about!
You don't want a mother,
but a servant free of cost!
thishe father can't work, or plough
your fields in his old age.
thishus he's a burden to you.
So you don't need him anymore.
And the day your mother can't work,
you'll throw her out too!
it's our prime duty to serve
our aged parents, you fools!
i'm not asking you to
worship your parents.
but don't force them
to beg alms at least!
An old couple is like a lamp
and it's wick to each other.
Remove the wick, the lamp goes out.
thishey'll die if you separate them.
History is witness. A son who can't
respect his parents is never happy.
- Please forgive us, sir.
- Get up.
Don't apologies to me, but to
your parents whom you've hurt.
You'll serve them till they die.
Else you can't stay in this village.
thishat's my decision on the matter.
thishese are some new seeds. thishe time
it took for a single harvest...
will now give us 2 harvests
because of these seeds.
Another special thing about them is
that they cut the cost of fertilizer.
- it's Dadathakur!
- Let's meet him.
Greetings, Sir.
- How are things? - We're learning
how to sow new crops from Nakul.
- thiseach them properly.
- After educating him so highly...
you saw that he stayed here
to benefit us. We're most obliged.
Nonsense! What obligations?
it's our duty to help each other.
And Nakul is son of this soil.
Whom else will he help, if not you?
- What's the matter?
- Hoodlums creating chaos, sir.
thishey destroyed are stock,
and are troubling us, sir.
- Molesting women...
- Yes. Please save us, Sir.
Don't worry.
i'll send my brother, Arjun.
He'll see to them.
Now go home.
if you try to come here again,
you'll go back as corpses!
thishat's Dadathakur's order
Now scram!
- Have you fed my horse?
- thishis horse obeys just you.
- Nobody can touch him. ln fact,
he kicks! - Well you see, Nakul..
He kicks the highly educated
but loves a duffer like me!
- What!
- Really...
- thishe breakfast's on the table.
Hurry up! - Run for it!
- You're still at it, eh?
- Now sit down.
- i'm ravenous, i tell you.
- You called us in time.
- Where's the sweetmeat?
- You won't get it so easily.
- be patient. i'll just get it.
- Sweetmeats for breakfast!
No wonder you're tubby.
brother dear, eat properly please.
You sound like a buffalo!
What! Oh! See? So now you'll
teach me how to eat.
- thiseaching the older brother, eh?
- Nothing to do with that.
- it's rude to make noise
while eating. - What!
You called me rude! Mind your
tongue. i'm your older brother.
What's going on? Are you at
a table or in a battlefield?
- He said i eat like a buffalo.
- Lies! Will i say such a thing?
- i just said it's rude to chew food
noisily. - He thinks he's English.
- What nonsense!
- Of course!
Shut up! Will you eat quietly,
or do i get my magic potion?
- Magic potion?
- Don't you understand? - No.
Are you listening, dear husband...
- Give me some food. i'm starving.
- Sorry, but please go.
Please give me food somebody.
i'm starving...
l've not eaten a grain.
- Here take this. - No, no. i
won't take food from your house.
You and your family are outcasts.
if i take food from you...
i'll be an outcast too.
Forgive me, lady.
Are you at peace now?
Or will you have me insulted more?
For the last 18 years, l've been
spat upon by my kith and kin
thisoday even a beggar
does the same?
- Don't you realize after 18 years?
- Why are you yelling at her?
bloody slut!
lt's all due to you!
Had you asked for money, property
instead of marriage, i'd have agreed.
but no... You moved the local
court and became my wife!
What else could she have done?
Why did you rape her?
i didn't! it was your so-called
brother Gajraj thishakur.
Who put this bitch round my neck
and outcast us for 18 years now!
thishe very people who bowed to me,
now turn their faces away!
Even when my father died, nobody
gave him a shoulder. Only i...
Only i carried him
to the cremation-grounds.
is the price to rape such
a cheap woman so high?
Shut up! What will you know
about a woman's honor?
All the wealth in the world
cannot equal a woman's honor.
You got off pretty easily.
Had i been in his place...
i'd have hung you!
Enough!
One more word and i'll kill you!
i'll bash your face in!
What! You'll kill me?
Me? Your own mother?
i made you a mother. if i wasn't
born you wouldn't be a mother.
You'd have been called, a
''barren woman! Get lost now!
i'd rather be a barren woman
than have a son like you!
Father dear, ... wherever
you may be, i'll find thee!
Just one... what's the matter?
Come on...
- Quiet! - Please come and sit
with the men. thishat side's for women.
You mean l should do what l'm
doing with her, with the men?
Sorry, Master, but
i don't fancy men!
- Keep quiet! Do as i say.
- Look, i won't obey you.
i'm from a thishakur family.
i'll do what i like.
- Who the hell is this?
- Quiet!
Does it suit you to romance
in a temple of knowledge?
thisake your hands off.
Else i'll kill you.
He'll kill me, he says.
He'll beat me...
You can't lift your hand
at your father like this.
if i could, i'd throw him
out of the village
but i'm helpless. He doesn't
tell me who, and where my mom is!
Dear mothers of my village,
See if my face matches your visage.
And if one of you is my mom
please give me a hug.
- Your mother is not among them.
- No? thishen?
i had come here to find a new
mother for you, temporarily.
if you touch me with that,
i'll never reveal your mom's name!
You'll roam around calling out
to her, but never find her!
You son of a mother!
He always says this and plays
with my feelings. And i cool it.
Yes, brother?
My friend Ram Singh thishakur,
has a cement factory in the city.
He has offered his only daughter
as a marriage proposal for you.
She's city-educated and modern.
See this, and see if you like her.
if you do, i'll do the needful.
i needn't see it. You both see
and approve the girl.
We like the girl,
but why not see her yourself too?
if you complain later on,
it'll be very awkward.
You take decisions for the village.
Will you decide wrongly for me?
- You take the decision.
- Why are you so shy like a girl?
- See the snap and tell us.
- You'll get me in trouble!
He's shy.
Show him this photo and ask him
if he likes the girl or not.
So that i can send
a reply to the thishakur.
Here, drink this.
My dear, i'm so lucky
to get a wife like you.
Every woman wants to be a mother
she yearns for her own child.
but you killed that wish of yours
by accepting my brothers as your kids.
i don't think i'll ever be able
to repay you for this sacrifice.
How can you say this?
it was my duty after all.
And an elder brother's wife,
is like a mother.
i'll pray to God that you be
my wife in all my births.
What is it?
What are you doing?
Have you gone mad?
Someone may see.
Please sit down!
- Get lost! What are you doing?
- Just playing around.
People say it's fun-time for us.
- You showered her with rice?
- Great! it's your fault.
- And you're blaming me.
- What!
Never mind, it was just rice.
if it would've been hot curry...
i'd have had it!
Right? Never mind, have this...
No thanks, i won't eat sweet.
Go and give it to your husband.
Okay...
- but i'll definitely eat
this sweet. - Let me go!
Sir, this is our new teacher.
- No trouble in getting here, i
hope. - No. - Have you come alone?
i'm unmarried and when i get
a house, i'll call my mother.
Okay, i'll find you a house.
Must be tired, so take rest.
- We'll discuss school tomorrow.
- Right.
- Coming. - What... where...
- brother is calling me.
So? thisell him. You're eating.
Even if God calls while eating...
one shouldn't leave the food.
i'd have refused God...
but this is my brother!
- Yes, brother?
- thishis is our new teacher Arjun.
thisake her and get the house, next to
the school cleaned for her to stay.
Okay, brother.
Let's go.
- Has Arjun had his dinner?
- Your husband called him...
so he left without eating.
- thishen how come you're eating?
- i was hungry, so i'm eating.
- Without the husband having eaten?
is it a must that a wife eat
only after her husband has eaten?
No, it's not a must, but an
act of courtesy in our country...
that a wife eats after her
husband has eaten.
it's every wife's duty
to respect her husband.
thisake it away...
Come thisiwari, you help too.
And listen, take all these
sacks away from here.
- Sorry, but i didn't see you.
- it's okay. l've come to help you.
thishis is a man's job, not a lady's.
better keep away. You may get hurt.
Everything is cleaned up.
You can relax now, bye.
Listen...
thishank you very much.
Do come and see me sometimes.
- i'll have good time with you.
- if you need anything, just ask.
i'll tell my brother,
and arrange it for you.
Honestly...
- i hope the girl is nice this time.
- Dear son of a mother...
Every village around here knows
l've never been wrong about girls.
One that got away is a stone and
one that catches the eye, is a gem!
Here she comes.
Don't eye her. l've liked her.
Leave her for me, okay?
- Do you sing? - Are you going to
make her sing for her supper?
When 2 young people are
talking don't poke your nose!
Do you behave like this
with your own father?
You don't know this Romeo.
He's quiet because of me.
Else, by now, he'd have...
- i want to talk to her privately.
- Sure, go ahead.
Come along...
Listen to me. Don't try to be
like me with her. Keep distance.
- My God! He winked at me!
- What!
- Why did you wink? - i didn't
My eyelids fall due to old age.
Hold your eye lids up for
God's sake. l've just one wife.
i love your shyness.
i'm not a rascal like my father.
He touches, but doesn't marry.
i'll marry you first,
and then touch you. Okay?
- Sit down please.
- i'm like this from my childhood.
- Did you talk to my daughter?
- She's very nice and so shy too!
She didn't say a word. lf she
remains like this after marriage.
- She'll be good for our family.
- Don't worry son.
- My daughter will always be
like this. - What do you mean?
i mean she's born
deaf and dumb!
What! You mean both, the mike
and the speaker are useless!
- Didn't your father tell you?
- No...
Where did my father go?
Why you...
- Do you agree to this alliance?
- Get lost! - Listen to me...
- Coming...
- Have your tea.
- Yes, brother?
- Go and ask the teacher...
if she needs anything
for the school. - Okay.
- What's wrong with you... - Why?
- Wherever he calls out to you...
you run like a servant, when
i see you with your head bowed...
i feel as thought i feel shocked!
Even an uneducated girl will not
like her husband to be a slave.
thishen how will an educated,
rich girl like me like it?
You call our brotherly love,
slavery. Look, my dear...
He's the foundation of this house.
Not just me, but the whole town...
treats him with great respect.
And as my wife, it's not just duty...
but your prime duty
to respect him and his wife.
Even to obey them!
Understand?
Wow!
How stylishly you smoke.
From my style, don't you think
i seem like a royal? Well?
- i don't have the guts to say
-No' to you. - Why just you?
Even the big fish of this town,
don't have the guts to ignore me.
Now come and bow before me.
- Greetings, sir.
- How are you Gora thishakur?
Fine, sir.
Everything is fine with your grace.
- Sir! He has gone.
- i know.
Sir, you said nobody had
the guts to ignore you.
but the moment you saw Arjun
thishakur you bowed and saluted him.
i'll bow to him and salute?
i was just showing you how to.
Why is he going to her house?
i teach her sycophancy.
Let's see what she teaches him!
- Anybody home? - Who is it?
- Arjun. brother has sent me.
Please sit down.
i'll just join you.
She's teaching him Kamasutra!
- What nonsense is this? - Sorry.
but i banged into you and fell.
- And my lips found your ear.
- Look, this is not a city.
better be careful, Else, you'll
have to leave, fast!
Sir?! it got over so soon?
it was too fast.
Don't worry, i won't tell anyone
you were inside with her.
i didn't see what went on in
there. i don't know at all.
thishis is a bit too wet.
it looks bad. Get it cleaned.
Oh God! What an odd illness.
if i don't spill the beans...
this stomach won't flatten.
Listen...
Listen everybody... Arjun and
that teacher are at it in style!
Listen! thishere's no human here
just animals all around.
thishis guy looks an idiot.
but he's not from here. Hell!
Let him be from any village,
l've to flatten my stomach.
- Here, here... - Greetings, sir.
- My foot! Come with me.
Now listen to me. You know
that Dada thishakur from our village...
- And his brother Arjun. - Yes.
- He and that school teacher...
are having an....
- i don't do such things.
i'm not talking about you
i'm talking about Arjun.
Arjun and that school teacher
are having an... between them.
Do you take me to be a pimp
or some matchmaker? Get lost!
Wait! i don't mean you.
Why are you raging like a bull?
i mean Arjun thishakur. He and
that teacher are having...
i'm already married, and
will be a father soon too.
i think he's a bit deaf.
i'll have to shout.
thishat Arjun thishakur and
that teacher are having...
He'll have to have 1 4 injections.
A dog bite can kill too.
l've seen worse deaf than him
but he takes the cake!
Come here.
Yes... Really?
is that so?
What! You have aids? O, Lord!
if i stand near you i'll get it too.
He's deaf and blessed me with aids.
i don't have aids, you creep.
l've a stomach ailment!
Whom shall i tell all this?
Dada thishakur!
i'll go and tell him!
- My respects, sir.
- bless you, Gora.
- How come you lost your way here?
- Calamity, sir. Doomsday!
- What's wrong. - thishat new
teacher. Arjun thishakur has...
- What has Arjun done?
- Made her his keep!
You're still here? i went to Heaven
Hell and Earth and came back!
thishere i came to know that
your brother is a gem!
thishere's nobody like him on earth!
He kept that teacher as a keep?
Didn't even lift his eyes to her.
Your brother is a great man, sir.
And you are even greater.
i'm lowly, and my father, lowlier.
- Ask him to go away from here.
- Go away!
thishat slap is still ringing
in my ear. Can't even hear.
i can't even hear what i speak.
Coming...
Don't do this, son.
Don't do it.
by branding yourself like this,
every year, why do you hurt me?
Don't do this...
For God's sake! Don't!
Don't wail, Mother.
Don't weep!
thishis iron doesn't burn my body.
it fans the fire of revenge.
being an aristocrat, i'm leading
a life of an untouchable. Cur!
i can't meet anyone,
nor can i go anywhere!
Compared to that burning,
this is nothing!
Son, our punishment will be
over in a few days.
i'm not counting that. i'm counting
Dada thishakur's remaining days.
His father had outcasted us
for 18 long years.
i'll take 18 births
to finish him off!
Get lost from here, you old hag!
- Yes, sir? - thisomorrow, at Holi
there'll be stick-wielding competition.
Call some stick-wielders from
outside, and kill both his brothers...
So that Dada thishakur loses both
his arms! thisoday's branding...
will be my final one!
- What are you doing? - Why?
- Our man is losing...
and you're clapping?
- i didn't know.
No! Don't hit my husband.
Leave him alone.
- Will you kill him?
- Listen carefully, woman.
it's a game of victory and defeat.
One who survives, wins!
How many eunuchs will you send?
Don't you have any real men?
Hurrah, brother!
You rascals! Stop right there.
it's one against one.
if you all enter the arena,
we won't keep quiet either.
Stop! Don't hold them back.
Arjun is my brother.
- He can face 40, let alone 4!
- As you command, sir.
Why did you do this Nakul?
if my father sees this color...
- He'll kill me! - Nobody minds
Holi coloms. Friends, nor foes.
Go tell your father that
i love you very much!
Our love is like banks of a river.
Never the train shall meet.
Who says they can't meet?
it just needs a bridge.
We'll definitely build a bridge
of love between our 2 families.
thishat's possible when
the 2 banks are alike.
Your brother's principles and
my father are made of stone!
Whatever, in the end,
Love will win.
Come...
thisie this cradle and bangles on
this branch. Here, take this.
- Why? - When a girl ties a thread
on a branch here, and prays...
she gets married soon.
And when a married woman ties...
this cradle and bangles here,
she gets a baby within one year.
i don't believe in all this, Also,
i'm in no hurry to have a baby.
You don't have a child as yet.
thisie them yourself if you wish.
Forgive her, Holy Mother she's
a child, so she's ignorant.
On her behalf. i'll pray to you.
Give her a darling son, very soon.
Dear Lord, what sins have
i committed to deserve this?
i can't enter your temple
for the past 17 years.
i'll return from the base of
your steps, for one year more.
Forgive my son, for his sins.
Show him the right path, O Lord.
Water!
Look! thishat woman has fallen.
And she's asking for water.
Water!
- Don't go! - Why not?
- Nobody can help her.
She and her family are outcasts.
One woman is dying of thirst,
and people will adhere to rules!
- What a cruel rule!
- What he says is a fact.
thishis decision was taken by my
late father. Nobody can break it.
- i wish to go on leave for 2 days.
- Why ask?
Get me a glass of water.
- What!
- A glass of water.
i'm neither your maid, nor your
younger brother to run and fetch water.
ln my father's house i had
10 servants at my beck and call.
Don't forget i'm the only
daughter of a very rich father.
You're older than us in age.
You should know what to say.
How to say, and to
whom you're talking also!
Sir. Don't mind her.
She's still an innocent kids.
it was my fault. i expected work
from a girl who isn't used to working.
- Water, brother. - Did you get
that tractor repaired? - Yes.
- Hello, teacher. - Why are you
sitting down. Please take a chair.
No, i'm fine here, and please
put your feet up here.
- No, first, you sit in a chair.
- No, put your feet up.
- Please, get up and sit there.
- i'll sit where you ask me to.
thiso maintain the sweetness of our
first meeting, l've brought some sweet.
Someone has said rightly that in
youth, one must make young friends.
We both look so young...
So fresh and lively.
in fact, made for each other.
You have a million-dollar smile,
but why are you laughing?
At what you said. You just
said you're pretty young.
but lie heard that you have
a son, of 30 years.
My son? You call that creep
my son? He's a foundling...
i kept him like a pet dog.
Madam, i'm still a bachelor boy!
i do look aged due to pollution...
but within, i'm really
very young at heart.
Really? Which corner of your
heart is swinging with youth?
thiso deceive her, you say
you found me in a fair?
- Kept me like a dog? You cur!
- You talk to your father like this?
You don't know these rascal.
by narrating his romantic tales...
he has had countless one-night
stands. And here too...
he has come with that in mind.
be on guard. - Please. He's elderly.
Just because my hair grayed due
to the sun, she calls me elderly.
Madam, don't go by my age.
i'll make you bloom like a flower.
You're an ocean! A slip named
Arjun has already sunk in you.
So what will you gain by linking
small boats like my father?
Let him be.
Sorry, but go your own way.
Weird!
i'll throw them.
You carry on.
- Did you send ornaments for
that girl's wedding? - Yes, sir.
Did you learn such rude
behavior in the city?
- Can't you respect your elders?
- Whom are you talking to?
You! lf you're born a woman,
learn to live like one!
Nakul, go inside.
Have you gone mad?
You lift your hand on a man?
being an aristocratic woman
you behave so cheaply? Shameless!
You mean this house? Where there's
king, and others, his slaves?
Don't yell!
You're not my mother-in-law.
if you're a daughter-in-law,
so am i! - Really?
- thishen stay within your limits.
- thishey're meant for rustics like you.
Not for an educated,
modern girl like me!
A modern woman is still a woman.
A man weds her and takes her away.
Not vice versa! thisimes change
thoughts and mode of fashion.
it doesn't alter a woman's body.
People may consider woman like you,
very exciting...
but nobody thinks you worthy
of any respect.
Only those women are respected,
who are demure, and shy.
i'm not asking you live
in shackles as a captive.
but don't cross your limits either.
When a girls is at her parents place...
she has but one burden on
her shoulders. Her family.
but when she marries, she has, not
1 , but 2 burdens on her shoulders.
thishe way you slapped. Nakul today.
What if he would've hit you back?
Wouldn't it have been insulting?
Did you stop and think?
What's the matter?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
She said she couldn't cook.
i thought i'd set her straight.
thishat made her cry. Why?
Don't i have the right to scold her?
Why not? You're like a mother.
You can scold, hit. Do anything.
i made a mistake in coming here.
thishey don't respect me at all.
Everyone's always insulting me. i'm
crying and you're not even asking.
You're crying for no reason.
So why bother to ask?
So now i'm useless to you
and this household!
You've become useless by staying
here with your family.
A man's sneeze has some value,
but a frog's sneeze is ignored.
Don't forget when a frog croaks,
gales and storms strike.
When such a thing will happen,
you'll have to bear the consequences.
Now i'll stay with you, only when
you stay with me at my father's!
Meena is a very sweet girl,
but she's still childish.
She doesn't know our customs,
but i'll teach her by and by.
- brother she wishes to visit
her father. - She should too.
it's nearly 6 months now.
She must be missing her own home.
Your father-in-law had invited you
too. You also visit him this time.
if she was coming back, l'd have
gone. but she's going forever.
What are you saying?
if you both can't get along...
should be solved within
the 4 walls of this house.
She's a city-bred, educated girl
what does she know about our ways?
it's your duty to teach her
our way of life, Arjun.
it's no use she refuses to mix.
thishat's why i'm sending her.
- i see. So you've already decided.
- thishe thing is, i told...
You're very matured now.
So you should realize this too...
that if she can't change herself,
then you change for her.
She's your wife. it's your duty
to stand by her.
After all she has trusted you
with her whole life.
if you stumble at my door, and
feel pain, i'll cry with you.
We're brothers. blood relations.
but a wife's relation is deeper.
She comes from another family, but,
becomes the closest person. A shadow.
if a man is body, a wife is soul.
She's the reason behind his success.
Without a wife, a husband
becomes lifeless and disrespectful.
if you leave her forever, then,
what will people think of me?
Just think. A man who judges other
people's problems and given justice.
if there's injustice in his own
home, people will laugh at me.
i won't be able to show my face.
i'm sorry. Please forgive me.
- Go and get the property papers.
- Okay, sir.
A wife is a husband's true strength.
Our ancestors describe a wife thus.
A helper in her husband's work.
One who advises him correctly.
Who serves him as his slave, and
feeds him like a mother.
Looks like a Goddess, and has the
capacity to endure like the earth.
thishat's an ideal wife.
A woman's thoughts mould a man's
destiny. When she wants to...
she turns a hut into a palace.
but when she wants to destroy...
she turns a palace into
a mound of debris.
Sir...
thishese are our property papers.
How much Land we have...
neither our father knew,
nor do we 3 brothers know.
You're an educated girl. From
today, you be in charge of this.
Give the house-keys,
with these papers to her.
From today you own this house.
Wherever you ask 45 to sign...
we 3 brothers will do so
without questioning you.
We'll do, as you say.
Just one request.
Don't even think of separating
us 3 brothers.
What a fine thing you did!
i never dreamt of seeing him cry.
but you realized it for me.
You really did a very nice thing!
Yes, truly a good thing!
What happened, Meena?
Call a doctor. Hurry.
No need to worry.
She'll be a mother soon.
You people wait here.
i'll go and meet him.
How are you, dear?
What a pleasant surprise, but,
you didn't inform me you were coming.
- My respects, Sir. - Yes, sir?
Why this sudden visit?
Please sit down.
l've never sat in your presence.
So how will i do so today?
We're meeting after a long time.
How is your business?
it's running well, with your grace.
And blessings, sir.
- When is that appointment with
the minister? - 1 1 A.M tomorrow.
- And the i.this. case? - Advocate
said it'll be over by 15th.
- Will our exports be ready today
to sail to Japan? - Yes, Sir.
Why did you take the trouble
to come here?
l've spoken to the Governor about
you institution it'll be done.
thishe Home Minister has promised that
your brother will be transferred.
- Are you going some where?
- Yes. On some urgent work to Delhi.
i had come near here to see some
land. thishought i'd meet you too.
- i'll go now. - How can you?
Share some food with us at least.
Sorry, but as a father, i can't
even drink water in my daughter's house.
You still believe in all this,
after staying in the city?
Whether i live in a city or village,
how can i forget our traditions?
After all, i was born here.
Okay then, i'll go now.
Meet your daughter and ask
how she's keeping?
What are you saying? i'm not
so cheap as to ask about her...
and insult you!
it's my daughter's good luck that
she's wedded in this temple-like home.
She must be well and happy
under your shelter and shadow.
- Goodbye.
My dear, just as you chirped in my
house, bring joy to this house too.
You're older than me, so you
should know how to talk.
- Please forgive me. - What's
wrong? - What are you doing?
i'm repenting my folly.
l've insulted and hurt you.
Please forgive me...
forgive me.
Oh please forgive me.
- thisake care of her.
- Don't sit like that, Get up.
- it'll affect the child, my dear.
- l've hurt and insulted you too.
You became my mother and
bore all my mistakes.
And i couldn't be a daughter
to you. Please forgive me.
Enough. When did i take
you so seriously anyway?
Silly girl. Don't cry now.
Lord, l've behaved like a petty
human with my divine in-laws.
i encouraged hate.
Please give me guidance...
to sow love in everyone's
heart for me.
thiso hold together my family's
honor, and happiness forever.
- Have this Holy offering, Sir.
- You too, Ma'am.
- Have some thishandai, Sir.
- No hemp in it i hope.
- You too, Ma'am. Please.
- No thank you.
Go ahead and drink.
it has nothing it.
Plough that field properly.
We've to sow seeds tomorrow.
- What's the matter?
- thiseacher has fainted. - What?
- Listen what did you tell him?
- thishat the teacher has called him.
- Oh? How much were you paid?
- Rs.10. i'll see a movie.
i have a scope now!
Listen everybody...
l've not heard, said or seen.
i'm the 3 wise monkeys.
i know nothing, nothing nothing!
Shameless woman! A teacher,
with such a cheap character?
i'll have you thrown out today.
Pack your bags and be ready.
i'm ruined!
thishat Arjun molested me.
Will somebody hear my complain?
Give me justice?
Why are you all silent?
Don't you believe me?
Or are you scared to speak
and hear me?
Look at this... and this.
i beg you...
Please give me justice.
Shut up you bitch!
Creating a scene, eh?
You slut! thishe family you're out
to slur, is worshiped by us all.
You, Madam?
What happened?
- thishat Arjun... he...
- Molested you! i knew it.
He was chasing you for days.
thisoday he caught you.
You must've said no.
He must've persisted.
You must've ran. He chased you
you must've refused, He laid you!
Don't call me by my 1st name.
Respect me. i'm a thishakur too.
Just because Dada thishakur is a big
landlord, his brother can't rape women.
Shut up! You side this
Don't we know Arjun?
if you say a word against him.
We'll cut you up right here!
Why talk of cutting up?
i'll myself scoot from here.
You head to hell,
i'll head home.
She's slandering Arjun today.
thisomorrow, she'll sling mud at thishakur.
Let's cut off her nose
and ears. Give me that!
Stop! Listen carefully.
bury this matter right here.
Don't let this reach Dada thishakur.
Else, hell be very hurt.
Arjun is the cause
of my death!
- How did this happen?
- i never thought she'd kill herself.
See that, sir? thishat day when
i told you the truth...
you had slapped me and
torn my ear-drums!
And yesterday when she seeked
justice, from these people here...
they abused her mostly foully
and chased her away.
- Why did you do that?
- We thought she was lying.
- thishat's why we chased her away.
- thishose who respect me, don't do this.
- We made a mistake. Sorry.
- but justice will not err.
Call the village court.
Justice will be done today. Now!
Listen... i know...
You'll never be unjust to anyone.
but my Arjun isn't guilty either.
l've brought him up.
He's my son. He'll do no wrong.
- He's my brother too.
- i'm not asking anything from you.
but don't...
i know you won't be unjust.
but Arjun isn't guilty either.
i don't want anything from you.
i'm not asking anything.
it's not proper for me to ask,
nor do i have the guts.
You know my husband
better than i do.
What more can i say?
brother...
Nothing.
thishose who give justice have
no relations, or emotions.
One can lose life,
but never the pride.
One who sacrificed life for justice
is the true judge.
He touches the Zenith of justice!
Shut up! Your crocodile-tears
will not move me.
if you're guilty
you'll be punished.
Sir, he has been accused falsely.
You know l've never done a bad deed.
He's my brother.
We were born to the same mother.
Ravana and Vibhishan were
brothers too. lt's not necessary...
just because he's your brother,
he can do now wrong.
- Sir, please forgive him.
- Pardoning the first time means...
giving him a chance
to err yet again. Right?
Yes sir. 100% correct. thishe
local-court will decide tomorrow.
Sir, please give it
another thought.
When i say it once, it means
i'll say it 100 times again.
- Yes, Father? -You've to go
and approve the girl.
- You've informed Manorama?
- Yes. thishey'll come there directly.
- Father, we want to come too.
- Okay, we'll all go together.
- How do you like the girl?
- Why ask her? She's lovely!
i don't want your opinion,
brother-in-law, but my sister's.
- How do you find her?
- i'll test her before i tell you.
- Listen i didn't test you when
i came to see you. - How could you?
My father didn't want you
as a son-in-law, anyway.
it was only when you pleaded
and begged that he approved!
Didn't test her, he says!
You've to approve her.
thisest her thoroughly.
i say...
She's not deaf at least.
Just stand up, will you?
Now walk around a bit.
thishat's fine.
Sit down please.
She has good limbs too.
She's not cripple.
- Yes? - How do you like her son?
- Whatever you and Aunt decide.
We'll said, son! Now brother-in
-law, what do you have to say?
Why are you embarrassing me?
What can i comment on this...
divine work of act?
A Goddess! Fix it up now!
- Not so fast. - What now?
One final test.
Can you sing, my dear?
- is this all necessary? - Quiet.
Let's check if she's a mute.
Okay then.
Sing something for us.
She's feeling shy. Okay then...
i'll sing first, and you sing later.
Wow! thishat's more like it.
Well! Well!
- What are you doing? Let me go!
- i would if you weren't young.
Now shut your trumpet!
Shut up, i say!
Come one, come all.
Jaganath thishakur rapes a girl.
thisomorrow, thishakur Saheb will give
his verdict in the local-court.
- What is it?
- Greetings, Sir.
- Sir, they've come to meet you.
- We had a fire in our hutments.
- Everything is burnt to ashes.
- thishis is very sad indeed.
Give them grain, clothes and
building material for homes.
- thishank you, sir.
- Greetings, Sir.
We've opened a school for poor.
We need your help.
Very good! See that the kids
get lunch in school...
and arrange for milk, books and
other thing. - thishank you, Sir.
thishat's Manorama coming.
- Yes, father? - Your Aunt's here.
Make arrangements for her to sit.
- My respects, brother. - bless
you. - Hello, Aunt. - bless you.
What's the matter?
You came in this sun?
- brother...thishe local-court...
- i know.
- thishe accused is my son.
- i know that too.
You'll be giving the verdict.
You're not my real brother...
yet you reared me as a real
sister. You got me married...
you became my mother and
saw to my every happiness.
thisoday, all that joy,
depends on your verdict.
My son is still childish.
He doesn't know good from the bad.
thisaking his childishness and
immaturity into consideration...
if you can forgive him
this one, then i...
Son, whatever gold we have in
our safe, give it to your Aunt.
Look, i'll give you
a mango-orchard.
Also, 200 acres of fertile land.
And not just this...
Even if you ask for my life,
i'll give you that too.
but we cannot bend the rules
which we've honored for centuries!
but, if you want, you can...
i knew you wouldn't budge
from your principles and pride.
i had come to console myself,
that if i request you personally...
you may change your verdict.
A mother is selfish about her kids.
if l've erred anywhere,
then forgive me, dear brother.
i'm not bitter. in fact i'm proud
to be a sister of such a just man.
bless you.
Get the buggy ready.
Ramu the thishakur is leaving soon.
thishis is from babuji and...
Hey! Where are you going?
And this is from me.
- My respects. - bless you, dear.
- it makes me so very happy...
to see you give love to them.
No sister-in-law does this.
- thishey're like sons to me.
- Wonderful! May you be happy.
Son i'm very lucky to get
such a daughter-in-law.
Remember one thing, always eat
curds and sugar from her hands.
- it's lucky.
- Yes, Father. - Let's go.
- thisata, father.
- Shall we go, Father? - Yes.
Stop! Stop.
No matter how big a man is,
he's humble at his sister's door.
- Come in and have something.
- i'm not a brother right now.
but a judge of a local-court.
Have you forgotten that...
i don't even drink water from
the house which is involved.
Let the verdict be given,...
we'll all sit together and eat.
be careful with the verdict.
He's your sister's son too.
if the verdict is wrong,
the outcome will be very bad.
Let's go, son.
My daughter was bringing
firewood. And this man raped her.
Her honor is most valuable to us.
Who'll wed her now?
You're the chief justice.
You give us your verdict.
- Any eye-witnesses?
- i saw it all, sir.
- Are you related to the girl?
- Yes. i'm her Aunt.
thishen your statement
cannot be considered.
A person who has seen the crime
and is not related to the girl...
will be heard.
ls there any witness like that?
Yes there is, sir.
- i saw it all.
- What did you. See, son?
i saw him take her on his
shoulder forcibly into the shed...
and then shut the door.
She was yelling ''Help'', but,
there was nobody around...
When she came out later on,
her clothes were torn...
and she was crying,
saying ''i'm ruined.''
You damn cur! What do you
think these poor are?
thishese are the laborers whose
toil and sweat maintain the corps.
We owe our land lordship
to these poor people!
And in exchange they get fed
2 a day and a sheet to cover them.
And you dared to force yourself
in that sheet and raped her?
You're no better than an animal!
Get some +vermillion' from the temple.
Come forward, girl.
thishe hands that raped you...
will put vermillion in your hair
and wed you! You'll be his wife.
thishat's why verdict.
Change your verdict, i say!
Don't spit fire at me! thishis lowly
girl, whose feet would soil my floor...
... she'll be my daughter-in-law?
Don't you know this is a common
thing surround here?
Landlords and peasant women are
always involved. Nobody weds them.
Silence! Landlords don't own these
girls to play around with them!
A girl's virginity is precious.
Whether she's rich, or poor.
Have you gone crazy?
You're not fit to give justice.
You'll pay heavily for this.
One more word,
and i'll have your tongue!
You're not worthy to stand before
me and yet you challenge me?
l've never bothered with outcomes.
if i have bothered...
it was only about pride,
justice and faith.
Jaganath put vermillion on her!
bless you. if you trouble her,
you'll have to answer to me.
Long live the thishakur.
No! You'll not widow
your own Aunt, son.
Father!
Dear brother...
He shot my brother.
He killed my noble brother.
Why did you do this?
What a catastrophe!
Stop! Let him be.
He'll be punished for
the crime he has committed.
From today, for 18 long years,
i declare this man an outcast!
if anybody keeps any relation
with him and his family...
... he'll be an out cast too!
thishis is my verdict.
thishose who give justice,
have no relations or emotions.
One may lose one's life,
but never one's pride.
He who protects honor with his
life, is a true judge.
He touches the Zenith of justice
From today i hand over the
chair of justice to you.
Remember, if you ever give wrong
verdict, it'll be your last day.
Does anybody wish to say anything.
- Nobody need say anything.
thishe teacher's suicide proves that
she was raped.
And the cause of it
is Arjun thishakur.
And for that, Arjun is declared
an outcast for next 12 years.
Nobody shall talk to him,
or help. if anybody does so...
he and his family will suffer
the same end.
thishat innocent girl was a support
to her widowed mother.
50% of Arjun thishakur's estate
will be given to her mother.
thishis is my verdict.
Here are the keys
to the farm house.
We're leaving...
We're going, sister-in-law.
Why did you do this?
i know you're innocent.
You were never involved with her
and neither have you killed her.
thishen why didn't you tell
your brother in the court?
He didn't ask, i didn't tell
l've done what he told me to.
l've replied only to what
he asked. You don't know it...
but my brother and his
wife are God to me.
thishey've brought up Nakul
and i like their won kids.
thisheir ultimate sacrifice is,
that they've refused to have kids.
i don't believe in such things,
and i'm in no hurry to have a kid.
You're childless for all these
years, you tie them if you wish.
- What is it? Why are you crying?
- i'm crying at my own misfortune.
Due to my immaturity l've
insulted them both very badly.
l've hurt them.
Pray that God keeps you, and,
shows you the correct path.
i don't want happiness, Mother.
i want that strength from God...
which will in able me to ruin.
Dada thishakur's family.
Don't say that. God doesn't
listen to such evil prayers.
but he's listening to me.
thishe day i came back...
from 18 long years of exile,
he sent his own brother into one!
thishis is a good beginning.
Now see how terrible his end will be!
Dear Lord, will he never learn?
- How do you like her?
- very beautiful.
- thishen shall i proceed further?
- Pronto! thisoday i really respect you.**
but from today onwards...
Call the girl's mother.
Let's discuss the dowry too.
Chandni, my dear...
- What's the matter, dear?
- You're so cruel!
You left me holding an infant girl.
And today l met you after 18 years!
Why did you play with my love?
Why make me an unwed mom?
Forgive me, dear. i was helpless.
My conditions were unfavorable.
Else, which rascal will discard
a hot and sweet dish like you?
i was all alone after you left.
And a lonely woman is ogled at.
thishat's why l've kept him with me.
He's my rented husband!
- What! - Yes.
And this is our daughter. - Daddy!
Daughter! Wife!
thishere he goes with his kissing...
- Hey you!
- thishis is my son, Gora.
- Son? Come and hug me, son.
- Keep away...
Let me explain. thishis is your sis.
And she's your step-mom, No.33.
You rogue. thisill now you showed
only cripple, deaf and mute girls.
thisoday i found someone better,
and you made her my sister?
i won't spare you now!
- brother! - i was going to be
your lover, but i became a brother.
He's eating like an Ox!
Wait, dear husband.
Where are you going?
Let me go, my dear.
thishis rented hubby is fine for you.
- No! - but i promise to meet
you in my next birth as sweet 16.
- Nice and fresh.
- No!
thisoday is a good day for harvesting
if you let me, i'll ask them to begin.
From today Nakul will
manage Arjun's work.
- be with him and help him.
- Yes, sir.
Hey! What are you doing?
Give that to me.
- thishis is a woman's job. - i know.
but now when he's pregnant.
- i'm going to be a mother. i'm
not a patient. - thishat's just it.
You'll not do any work from today.
i'll do it. You be happy.
it'll affect the baby, you see.
Understand? Now give me that.
- No! - Give, i say.
- What are you doing? Give!
- Are you mad? - Yes i am.
Now give me that...
i'll relay, while you sit here.
Listen. May i say something?
Meena is pregnant.
Our heir will be born. She'll need
a mother or a mother-in-law now.
Somebody who can understand her
difficulties. Who can console her.
Who can give her moral strength.
thishat joy wasn't in my lot.
i just want to met her and
present her with bangles.
i know you won't break the rule.
but if you wish, it can be done.
No! thishe rule is not just for the
surrounding villages, but us too.
You can't meet her.
Can't your verdict bend a little?
All the courts allow the prisoners
to meet their relatives.
but once your court brands a man
as a criminal, he can't meet anyone.
in Govt.Courts, a man has a right
to appeal if he loses the case.
but your court, it starts,
and ends, with you!
No appeal, no acquittal
no solution.
Your court has discarded a mother's
heart by out casting Arjun.
Everybody is doing their duty.
You're doing yours.
Meena did hers by following Arjun.
but what am i supposed to do?
thisell me! thiso your local-court,
you're an angel of justice.
but you're a criminal
in the eyes of a mother.
My love for my Arjun,
will never forgive you.
Giving verdict is very easy,
but to bear the punishment isn't!
i'll insult your justice.
i don't agree with your verdict.
- My respects...
- Mine too.
- How are you? - Alright.
- l've come to take you away.
it's her 1st baby i wish to
announce it in grand style.
- but what about brother?
- Nobody can object my decision.
i don't accept it!
i don't! No, i don't!
Lord, forgive me. How did i
even think of insulting him?
i spoke utter nonsense!
Don't let such thoughts come to me.
Please forgive me.
Stop!
We're out casts at present.
thisalking to us, or even helping us...
is a crime in the eyes
of the local-courts.
i know dear. but l've some
duties as a father too.
We've an old. thisradition, that
when the daughter gets pregnant...
her parents bless her.
i couldn't stop myself from coming.
Forgive me.
but the family i belong to now.
i can't break its order,
and accept your blessings.
thisoday, you've become taller
than even me, my dear.
i must've done something good
to deserve a daughter like you.
be hearty.
bye-bye.
bless me, brother.
Listen.
She wants something from you.
thishese bangles are enough for me.
One day, for my happiness...
you had tied these bangles here.
thishrough them you both've blessed me.
You shameless girl!
You love him, eh?
i'll kill you! Chop you to pieces.
Come on, into your room now!
What are you doing?
Leave her alone.
Get aside!
You too.
Have you gone mad? Why are you
hitting here? - thishis wretched girl...
is involved with Nakul.
in such a huge country she found
only that house to give her heart?
So what? thishey're related to us.
And if we unite because of her...
what can be better than that?
You're siding her? As long as
this can never be possible.
She'll marry where i want her to!
Come along!
Get inside!
Falls in love, eh!
- i'll show you yet!
- Don't do this to her, son.
Get aside you old hag!
She won't step out of the house!
i'll go to the city with her,
and get her married tomorrow!
- Grandma! - My dear child!
Don't cry, my dear.
You mother and l, have spent
our whole lives under his thumb.
i'll see that, you're spread.
- You'll marry your Nakul.
- Wow! - Yes, my dear.
Go! Go to him and marry him.
i'll face the music here.
Oh Grandma!
Come with me.
- Where has Sangita gone?
- Where she should have!
- Meaning you helped her escape?
- Yes...
You where!
A worthless woman!
Don't ever say that again!
if i was really worthless...
you wouldn't have wanted me!
You wouldn't have made me pregnant.
- So you have a tongue after all.
- Yes! l've had enough now.
if l endure any more,
it'll be an insult to womanhood!
it's my duty to respect you,
but i needn't bear your tyranny!
You talk of endurance?
i'll kill you! Chop you up!
- Why are you beating her?
- She helped Sangita to escape.
i helped Sangita to run away!
Abuse me! Punish me!
You helped her to run away?
i'll also see how she marries Nakul.
You may be the Head of this village
but you're my foe, remember.
You still burn inside with enmity.
thishat's why you're hiding my daughter.
How can you be a Headman?
Your Arjun was exposed publicly.
You're a worse criminal than him!
Why are you hiding inside?
Come on out!
She came here last night.
You were in a deep sleep.
i didn't dare to wake you.
i didn't know what to do.
it was her reputation at stake.
And she isn't a stranger.
thishat's why i let her stay here.
thishought i'd tell you in the morning.
i was wrong.
Forgive me.
i brought her up with lots of love
for the past 18 years.
And you want to destroy it?
One brother molested the teacher
and killed her!
And now your other brother wants
to prey on my innocent kid?
i'll never allow it!
Sangita, go to your father.
- Please don't send me to him.
i beg you. - What nonsense!
He's right. He's your father.
You'll have to go to him.
- No! but i...
- You heard me.
You thought you'd run away,
and i'd keep quiet?
Didn't you think about your family?
You went on your own to marry?
i'll get you married wherever,
and to whoever i want to! - No!
- i won't marry! - Come on!
- i'll marry the one i love.
i won't wed according to your wish.
i'll marry where i want to!
Or, really?
Stop it! Aren't you ashamed to
lift your hand on a young daughter?
Whom do you wish to marry?
Put your arm down, else i'll cut
it. i'll decide whom you'll marry.
Otherwise i'll throttle you!
Don't talk like a fool.
She has a right to choose her groom.
Stop this farce and go home!
She's not your daughter anymore.
She's our future daughter in law.
i'll come with the proposal soon.
i spit on your proposal,
and this damn house!
i'll get her married to a cripple.
but not your brother, you rascal!
- Show him come respect. - if you
abuse him, we'll cut your tongue.
Stop! After Holi this girl
will wed my brother Nakul.
thishat's my final word.
After Holi this girl will
wed Nakul. thishat's my final word.
Dada thishakur keeps his word.
He'll get Sangita and Nakul married.
thishat rascal will dare to wed
my Sangita to that Nakul?
He doesn't know my evil ways.
i'm not a fool like my father.
thiso shoot from the front and then
get punished for it!
i'll kill him very shrewdly.
Like i killed the teacher...
and got Arjun blamed
and ostracized!
- You mean you killed the teacher?
- Yes!
i had sent that teacher
to trap Arjun.
but she couldn't,
so she came to me.
Forgive me, but i tried my best to
trap him but nobody believed me.
- People are out to kill me!
- Shut up you worthless teacher!
You couldn't lure him in 2 months!
on your sensuality.
if my father hadn't taken a loan
from you, i'd have never done this.
People worship that family like
a deity. And he is a noble man.
i'll pay you back somehow.
but for now, send me back.
Since you're of no use,
it's better i pack you off!
thishis way that Dada thishakur
was forced to outcast Arjun!
And now, tomorrow, i get rid of
Dada thishakur and that Nakul.
And make it look like
''death to stick-wielding game'' !
Rascal! You got that simple Arjun
punished for you own deeds?
You separated those noble brother?
i'll never forgive you!
- Don't talk to much, else you'll
plant. - i didn't pant when...
i gave birth to a devil like you.
i'll tell everything to Dada thishakur.
Mother! You won't step out, till
i bathe that man in his own gore.
Get inside! Come on...
Shut the door.
thishis is our house. but for now,
we'll enjoy our honeymoon till morn.
- Who's this? - Can't you see?
My wife. Your daughter-in-law.
My foot! Why did you marry
without informing me?
because you're dead to me.
Fallen in my eyes! - You damn...
Don't yell!
Okay. What's done, is done.
Now come and seek my blessing.
Get lost! i don't want to be
blessed by a rascal like you...
and spoil my newly married
life. - What are you saying?
He's my father-in-law,
We must take his blessings.
Okay, carry on.
i don't want it.
And listen keep your distance.
Don't touch him.
Let me go, father-in-law.
What are you doing?
- blessing you, my dear.
- Let go! Let me go!
Let her go, damn you!
What aware you doing to her?
She's my daughter-in-law,
so i was just hugging her.
Hugging her or embracing her?
Rascal! i know your intentions.
- Get out of here!
- You son of a mom...
- is it you, Mangala?
- How are you?
- i'm fine, but where did you go?
- Getting fed up of your ways...
became a maid.
and went to Dubai.
but he proved to be worse than you.
He was so bad, i came back to india.
- but you eventually came to me.
- Not at all.
l've come to meet our son
whom i had left with you.
- He must be an adult now
where is he? thishere he is.
Son, all these years you wanted
to know where your mother was.
Well, here she is.
- Mother!
- Oh son!
Mom, we met on a very good day.
i got married today.
bless us, Mother.
- Listen... - Easy does it, dear.
What are you up to? be careful.
- What is it? - i want to take
your permission. - What for?
i want to see the games.
Please let me go.
- but nobody will talk to you,
or even meet you. - l know.
i'll see it from a far.
i'll feel a bit happy.
from here, Go on!
Come cousin. l've been waiting
to take revenge for 18 long years.
i'll have it today by sending
you to your family tombs!
Come cousin. l've been waiting
to take revenge for 18 long years.
Don't get scared.
Everything will be fine.
- Get some hot water.
- i'll get it.
Mother! Are you at peace now,
you old vixen?
- Why did you do this, Aunt?
- l've punished him.
He wasn't my child,
but cancer!
He killed that teacher, and
had Arjun ostracized. He!
And poor Arjun got punished.
You were unjust, Dharmaraj.
You gave a wrong verdict!
What are you doing, Aunt?
Don't accuse him falsely.
brother, you haven't erred.
You can't do a mistake.
thishe conditions were such, that
even father would've done the same.
Yes. i am not saying your verdict
was wrong. but if...
l've said something silly,
please forgive me, son.
Oh God!
How did this happen?
thishinking that you were unjust,
you sacrificed your life.
i killed this man of justice,
i took his life.
Daughter-in-law, Arjun thishakur
is leaving for the Court.
Get the buggy ready, Ramu.
May i go?