You've returned to the village
after 2 years, Shekhar.
l can't keep myself from telling
you about what have happened here.
- Can't you just shut up?
- But listen to me...
You know Godu, the wrestler...?
He looks like a regular bull.
- He used to be all brawns earlier...
- Are you crazy?
And the sweetmeat vendor's wife
has eloped with a neighbor!
- They met at the movies...
- l could slap you for that!
The washerman's wife has delivered
a baby-girl again; their sixth one.
But he's still as virile as ever!
You can never say.
We had a good monsoon last year.
Our crops were saved,
but otherwise...
You swore never to step in this
house and went away to Bombay.
But you have come back.
- l could leave this instant.
- Sit down.
- You still have a temper.
- l've got that trait from you.
l mean... l've inherited
that aspect from you.
Have you at least been studying well
all those miles away from home?
He has passed with a First Class.
So you've passed, all right.
What do you intend to do now?
What do you intend to do
after your education?
He has found a job in Bombay.
He will work, and pursue
studies in journalism.
You hear that, don't you?
What's that ''ism''
you're going to study?
Whatever it be, you will
need money for the fees.
Who will pay that?
Money doesn't grow on trees.
l've got a job as a proof-reader.
l will use my salary for my studies.
Which means you don't need
your old man's help, isn't it?
You want to stay in Bombay and
never return here! lsn't it?
You don't plan to marry
a girl from Bombay, do you?
- That will never be.
- Good.
We are a widely respected
and cultured family.
l won't tolerate it, if you bring
home a bride from another community.
Better remember that.
And go ahead and eat now.
Have l come home only to escort you
to weddings and functions?
- ls it that much of a bother?
- Welcome, dear...
This is Narayan Mishra's son.
Didn't Dad say that a sister
is a brother's responsibility?
What can he do, except talk?
- Hasn't your father come?
- He's away in town.
Remember me, Shekhar?
l used to teach you Hindi?
Why, of course!
DrGDrGDrGDrG
This isn't right, Shekhar...
Listen to me!
They won't spare you, if you go
ogling around in their locality.
- But we're just standing here.
- Exactly! And that's wrong!
Here comes Chitti Miyan!
- Hold on...
- Why are you guys standing here?
- Greeting, sir.
- Greetings.
He went away. But they'd behead us,
if they knew we're here for a girl!
- Let them do it.
- Why must l lose my head for you?
There she comes!
We've had it! We will now have
to face the Village Council!
- Which one of them is her?
- How would l know?
There's still time! Let's scram!
- Could you recognize her?
- No.
And you still take all the trouble?!
Let's get out of here!
A veil has flown off the face
of one of those women, Shekhar!
- The red bag!
- What?!
- He's trying to woo you.
- Shut up.
Don't pretend. l know everything.
What's your name?
Why are you standing by the door?
- There's so much to do, Shaila.
- l'll join you in a moment.
Well, lady? Are you crazy?
You're mad!
My father will never sign
this progress report.
l won't be coming to school
from tomorrow.
- Give me your bag. And take mine.
- What for?
Don't argue. Just do it!
Why did you give me your bag?
- Listen...!
- Who's that?
lt's you... with the red bag!
Now l know why!
Here he is!
One moment, please... l don't know
how to tell you what l feel.
But l'll tell you, for sure.
Hey! Don't cry...
why are you crying?!
l've said nothing to you!
Who are you?
This red bag!
l thought it was her...
Come in.
l want the Chemistry notes.
Wait a minute.
Laxmi has gone inside.
Here you are, Bano.
Don't forget to bring it
to class tomorrow...
They'll cut off your hand
if you're caught, Shekhar!
Why are you getting into trouble?
l'll find you a nice girl!
- You can marry her yourself.
- l'm not talking about myself!
l beg of you, Shekhar...
Please don't!
Zeenat? Hurry up!
- ls that Zeenat?
- Who else? lt's her of course.
Look at her swaying her hips!
Watch your step!
The earth might split!
Why say that? She's not the
only one in town, is she?
Careful... l hope
the boat doesn't sink.
This is the limit!
Zeenat is not so bad.
Didn't you say you wouldn't
be coming today?
Has your father signed the report?
Why aren't you
carrying your bag?
How will you study
without the books?
What's up, Bano?
Have you seen a snake?
- Hold her firmly, Zeenat.
- lt's okay...
- Hold her, l say.
- Yes. Or she'll fall in the water.
Go ahead... hold her!
l could give up everything for you.
Could you do that for me?
l could die for you.
l'll wait for you at the old fort.
Do come over, if you love me.
- l've brought the kerosene, mom.
- You're late.
There was a big queue
at the provision store.
Look at the winds...
l think it's going to rain.
Help me with the stuff we're
drying in the courtyard, Bano.
Zeenat's looking for you, Bano.
DrGDrGDrGDrG
My name is Shekhar.
l'm Mr. Mishra's youngest son.
l know that. Please sit down.
Ask someone to fetch
some tea, Shamim.
lt's okay. Don't bother.
How can that be, son?
You've come visiting us.
l work for a newspaper
in Bombay.
l'm also doing a course
in journalism.
l'm a small-town man. l wouldn't
know of all those things.
l...
Your daughter Shaila Bano and l
want to get married.
Get out!
D'you realize whom you are
talking to, you swine?!
l've just said my prayers! Or l'd
have hacked you to pieces right now!
Do you hear him? He's asking for
our daughter's hand in marriage!
l haven't come to ask for it...
We just wanted to inform our elders.
- Father!
- Leave me alone!
- Father...!
- Go inside!
Provoke me anymore and you
will be a bundle of pieces!
How dare you?!
Who are you? And who are we?
Even our blood is different!
They can never be one!
Show me your hand.
We will certainly be one!
- Where's the young master?
- He's inside.
How did you suffer this
injury on your palm?
lt's nothing. Just bandage it.
Shivram of Palanpur has asked
for Shekhar's horoscope...
...to match it with that
of his daughter's.
Just tell him that.
Hear that? lt's Shivram's
daughter for you.
- Why isn't he speaking up?
- Tell them we're not interested.
Your father's coming in.
For how long will you live on the
food of restaurants in Bombay?
Tell him that they're a good family
and the girl is nice, too.
She'll soon be a graduate. Ask him
to go and take a look at her.
l don't want to.
- Why not?
- l know when and how l'll marry.
This is a new one...
but what is it all about?
- l've found the girl l wanted.
- l see.
Wonderful... but where is she?
ln Bombay? Does she belong
to another community?
This is precisely why l didn't
want him to go to Bombay!
She's from our village.
Really? Who is she?
Tell me who she is!
- You'll kick up a fuss, if l...
- Tell me who she is!
lt's Shaila Bano.
Bashir Ahmed's daughter.
ls it Bashir... who owns
the brick-kiln?
Hari... where are you, son?
- What is it, dad?
- Let's go.
Call Bashir... tell him Narayan
Mishra is here to see him.
There will be bloodshed if your
daughter meets my son again, Bashir!
l'm a poor man, but l have
my self-respect, mind you!
lf anyone plays foul, both our
families will be wiped out!
You thought you can ensnare a rich
and educated man, did you?
Who wants your wealth or him?
- l'm satisfied with my respect...
- Am l not respected then?
- Don't put words in my mouth.
- You can't handle your girl...
...and you dare back-answer me!
l send the girl to school and you
guys follow her like hungry dogs!
- Whom did you call a dog?
- You're lucky...
...l let your son walk away
without a scratch!
l'll see who harms whom!
Give me that sickle...
l'll hack this guy today!
lf you guys start a riot, the matter
will go the Village Council...
...and both families will have
to leave the village!
Let's see how anyone throws us
out of the village!
Give us the nod, sir!
We'll chop these guys to pieces!
Try touching us, if you dare!
And see what l'll do to you!
Stop it! What are you guys doing?!
Stop it, l say!
What are you up to?
This is between the two of us!
And why are you crying murder?
Go away!
Please go away.
This isn't right, Bashir...
lt's simply not done!
Don't do this to me.
Are you satisfied now?
My respect has been brought to dust!
Are you happy?
- What's wrong, father?
- What could be worse?
Has there been a day when we have
not visited the temple? Tell me.
l have been a trustee of
the temple for 20 years.
The management dare not take a
decision without consulting me.
That's the kind of
respect l command.
lt's our house the deity is brought
to first, during any festival.
But how and why will the deity
be brought here anymore?
My son falls in love
with a Muslim girl...
...and her father goes around
threatening to slaughter us!
What the hell is all this?
l give up! l surrender to
the educated young man!
Shaila Bano is a good girl.
She studies in the same school...
Shut up!
lf he marries her, who will
accept you for a bride?
We can find a Muslim for her, too.
l could knock your teeth
out with a slap!
l let you go, because
you have grown up.
- lmpudent rascal!
- ls it wrong to love a Muslim?
Are the Muslims our enemies?
All right! Marry her...
after l'm dead.
l can't wait for you to die.
What did you say?
What is this chap saying?!
You are the son l begot
after a lot of prayers.
You will take my advise, if
you have any love for me.
lf you must marry
that Muslim girl...
...you might as well
mourn my death first!
How can you say such things?
Shekhar!
Seek your father's forgiveness.
l'm going away to Bombay, father.
l will never return.
How are you, grandma?
- Where's Bano?
- There she is.
Bano! Where are you?
ls what your mother saying true?
Speak up!
Has Narayan Mishra's son been
writing to you from Bombay?
Answer me... !
Do you want me in a position where
l can't face anyone out of shame?
l'll hack you to pieces!
And you women! Can't you
take care of a single girl?
Don't you cry! Shut up!
You were born, when l returned from
a pilgrimage of the Holy Mecca.
Whom am l slogging and working hard
for? lt's for you, isn't it?
Haven't you ruined everything
by doing all this?
Promise me... that you will
never make such a mistake again.
l'm going to get you married
in less than 10 days!
l will have my way!
How about going and
getting married?
- Listen...
- What is it?
Are you scared?
Why is my heart beating so fast?
But l won't cry.
l won't cry, will l?
Please hold my hand.
Sit down.
- ls your name Shekhar?
- Yes. Shekhar Mishra.
- Have you got the certificates?
- Sure.
l got our names registered
a month in advance.
Do you have the witnesses?
Yes. There they are.
- Who are they?
- My colleagues at the press.
- Aren't you from Bombay?
- Not at all!
We're both from Malanpur;
it's on the coast.
Actually, my forefathers
are from Hyderabad.
We're both from the same village;
but he's been here for 2 years now.
l've arrived only this morning.
lt's your turn next.
- Did l say something wrong?
- No.
Then why did you stop me?
The sooner you stop talking,
the sooner he'd have left.
And the sooner he had left,
the sooner we'd get married.
And the sooner we are married,
l'd be able to give you a kiss.
- Your name?
- Shekhar...
- Your father's name?
- Narayan Mishra.
- And what is your name?
- Tell him your name.
Shaila Bano.
Well, Shekhar?!
Who's that girl with you?
You've ditched me, haven't you?!
You've ditched me and married
her, haven't you, darling?
l couldn't help it! Her father held
a knife to my throat...
...and threatened to kill me if
l didn't marry his daughter.
- So l married her.
- Please don't believe him.
...like a true maiden!
But you mustn't let him loose!
Hold him tightly...
...or the guy will flee!
- Who's that?
- lt's me.. Shekhar.
Mr. Malgaonkar... This is my
wife; we got married today.
- Greetings!
- Greetings.
Congratulations! Do you hear?
- He has got married.
- You didn't even tell us.
- And what is your name?
- Bano.
- Yes, l'm a Muslim.
- Have you already married?
- Just keep quiet!
- Why? Shouldn't he have told us?
How can we say our prayers
with the girl around?
Just come with me... Come on.
They have guests from Solapur, whose
kids will stay in our room for 3 days.
ls that all?
We're having a great
nuptial night, aren't we?
lt's not just tonight... it's going
to be like this for a few more days.
- What did she say?
- Shut up and go to sleep.
There he is... let's go.
The groom is back at work!
- How's everything, Shekhar?
- His eyes are red!
What's wrong?
Aren't you feeling well?
How did it go?
lt was fun, wasn't it?
Didn't you sleep
all of last night?
This is no time for jokes!
Please leave him to his work.
Your eyes are red, Shekhar...
You look tired.
You mustn't have slept
all night, l guess!
''Dear Mother,
l have got married...''
''...without an engagement
or any other ceremony...''
''l have got married, even though
my parents were not present here''
''l have eloped to get married...''
''...please forgive me for that''
''Do find the right time
to talk to father''
''Despite the anger
he has against me...''
''no one can deny that
l'm his daughter''
''l'm very happy here, Mother''
What is it?
Didn't you say you wouldn't
arrive before 10 tonight?
l have yet to embrace
my bride even once...
...and how...
...how can l study journalism
in this state of mind?
You used to earlier; you must
continue in the same manner.
- l wasn't married then!
- So what if you're married now?
Let me go!
What if someone sees us?
So what?!
We got married just yesterday!
Wait till we get to our room!
- lt's full of brats!
- You should be patient!
How can l? Thousands must have
been married after us!
And by now, they must have...
lt's for you.
Madam! l'm extremely sorry!
Please forgive me!
There's a letter for you.
There's a letter from your folks.
Yes. Dad has written to me.
- Won't you read it?
- l'll read it later.
l won't be able to concentrate
on what l'm cooking.
l'll keep trying to figure out
what he has written to you.
And we'll have a fight
if l read it right now.
No way! That will never happen.
- He has sent some money.
- That hasn't made me angry!
ln the name of Shiva...
''l've given you up for dead, but
your mother cannot forget you''
''Your brother took your mother
to the doctor.''
''She has High Blood Pressure;
you know why''
- What kind of a girl is she...
- Go on.
''She's a shameless girl to desert her
family and run away with a stranger''
''Her parents are no better who have
forgotten their daughter and...''
My parents are not so bad!
Which is why l didn't
want to read it.
They can call me what they wish!
Why bad-mouth my parents?
Have l ever said anything
against your folks?
lt's what they have written.
How can l help it?
Read what else is written.
- l know she's a good girl, but...
- Don't fabricate things!
Read what he has written!
l'll return his money right now!
''l can understand why you were
in a hurry to marry her''
''l'm sending you a thousand
rupees with this letter''
''Take her to a good hospital and
abort the bundle of your sins...''
''...and send her away
to her parents''
Tell her that l'm sorry.
- Tell her that he's sorry.
- Say sorry to her.
- Say sorry to her...
Tell him it's okay.
Ask her if l must
change my religion.
- Pardon me?
- Must l embrace her religion?
Must he change his religion?
- No. He shouldn't.
- He shouldn't.
You shouldn't, she says.
Say ''l love you'' to her.
''l love you'', he says!
You promised to marry me
and ditched me, didn't you?
No way! l will marry you
the next time l am born.
- How about me?
- l'll marry you, too.
Looks like an old involvement.
Know what? He says
''l love you'' !
Shut up, fatso!
The landlady approves of you.
She has sent the relatives away.
What are you up to out here?
This is no railway platform!
Go to your room!
DrGDrGDrGDrG
- You ?!
- Who else could it be?
l forgot where l was.
l was startled.
What's this?
l had a daughter who
is now dead.
l don't want people coming here
as her relatives.
Never in this birth will l come here
for that relationship.
l've come here for bricks.
Ask him if they're available.
We need a truck-load in U.P.
Why come to me for bricks
in Uttar Pradesh?
He's talking nonsense. What will it
cost and when will he deliver them?
Tell him that a truck-load
will cost him 2,000 Rupees.
This is the advance.
l want the name of Lord Rama
inscribed on every brick.
- What did you say?!
- l want the bricks...
...for Rama's temple in Ayodhya!
l am sponsoring the bricks
from this village!
- Not more than 3 Rupees for this.
- No, madam. l can't afford it.
Pay him 3 Rupees.
You fleece people the moment
you see someone gullible!
Can l take my wife away
for a moment, please?
l've been promoted!
l'm a reporter now!
l'll get a salary
of 2,000 Rupees!
You have brought me luck!
l know it all! l know how
you have left me pining!
- Not at all...
- You're a wicked man!
l'm not a wicked man, Maniben!
Later...
- May l tell you something?
- Not now.
What could l do, if
the cooker went off?
lt fell down,
because l panicked.
lt's you who always has me
running scared.
l only asked for a minute.
l had to tell you
something important.
By now, l'd have
told you everything.
lt's difficult to keep such
a secret... it's a burden.
What is it?
What did you want to tell me?
How will we manage?
Allah will...
Our children will have two Gods;
They'll manage it for us.
My master is here to see you.
Your daughter has
written a letter to me.
- She is not my daughter.
- That's what l thought, too!
We don't mean anything to them.
They ran away and got married.
And they're now having a baby.
A baby? Thank You, Almighty!
She wrote to convey that,
without telling my son.
Don't use this excuse to forge
a relation with me, okay?
Who'd want you for a relative?!
Just don't drag the baby
into our enmity!
l'm leaving now.
And just remember; the child
will follow my religion.
Why will he follow your religion?
lt's the father's religion that
the children follow!
No way! lt's the mother's religion
the children must follow.
The child will be a Hindu!
Not a Muslim!
He will follow our religion!
He will be a Muslim!
Try as you may, he will pray at
the temple, not in the mosques!
l'll make him a devout Muslim
in the mosques!
l'll teach him the Texts in the
wee hours of the morning!
Let's see how you do it!
As if l'd let him touch the boy!
He's always bragging.
Wait there... Whom did you ask
before bringing all that here?
This is a custom the bride's
parents must perform...
...before their daughter
delivers the baby.
No thank you! You'll kick up
a storm! Please go away.
ls it okay to send them away, when
they've come to perform a ritual?
- l thought you wouldn't...
- They aren't doing it for us.
lt's for the baby.
Take them inside.