l love you.
These two simple words...
Who knows who were
the first to use them?
Whom did he say them to?
Whenever these words of love...
... were uttered by anyone...
The beautiful, innocent were
attracted like crazy magnets.
Work fast or you'll
never complete in time!
- The stage isn't ready as yet!
- lt will be.
We'll have flowers there
and chandeliers in the center.
Don't ruin the flowers.
What are you doing?
You take the flowers
and give this to me.
Brother is coming today.
Has somebody gone to the station?
l've sent Anand.
Guess who this is.
One who can't be seen
in the daylight.
My moon like daughter.
The Chandni (moonlight)!
Why did you have to guess so easily?
Till the daughter is at home,
she is recognized.
But when she gets married
and belongs to somebody else..
Every relation ends.
l've come for Neelu's wedding
but you're getting me married off!
- l'm not getting married...
- After putting the frills...
- How are you aunt?
- l am fine.
But why are you so impatient?
Why have got applied this paste?
Should we get you also married?
My foot will get married!
- How are you dear?
- Very well.
- Where is Neelu?
- Upstairs in her room.
Couldn't you come earlier?
There was so much work at home.
- He should get leave.
- Some excuse always.
- You've come like a guest.
- Let go!
- Just 2 days before the wedding!
- l'll answer when you leave me.
You're hugging the dust and
grime of the journey and my clothes!
Does the moonlight ever
get dirty because of dust?
Good God! What was that blast?
- That's his style of coming home.
- Who is it who comes like a bomb?
He's Anand's best friend, Rohit.
Who has put rags
in place of canopy?
- That was me sir.
- You?
This darned and sheet put up for
Rohit Gupta's sister's wedding!
Sir, now you won't
see them anywhere.
Remove them fast! Quick!
Have the flowers arrived?
Check if my bags have come up.
And give me a dress to wear.
We didn't meet for a year and
you've learnt yours and mine!
All my clothes are yours.
- Where is Chandni?
- Must be loafing somewhere.
l was feeling cold.
Want to warm up my hands.
Warming up your eyes or your hands?
Come on. Go away.
Do you know why it turned dark?
So that it would only be
bright enough for me to see you.
And you see only me.
When the Maker must have made you..
Even he must have been
swayed at least once.
Maybe you don't know
how beautiful you are.
So beautiful that the word
beautiful falls short.
People have a tendency
to beat around the bush.
But l speak the truth
and to the point.
l love you as much as nobody
must have ever loved another!
By now maybe you
too love me that much.
Yes or no?
Let me tell you another thing.
We Delhites can rule the
country as well as the heart!
We will win the heart!
Nobody ever spoke to me
like this in Shahjahanpur.
l was only my mother's daughter.
My heart would beat there too.
But in Delhi l can hear
my heart beat!
l came from the village.
When the time came to leave,
l started howling.
l kept crying and held my
grandmother and said..
l know nothing.
What will happen? l know nothing!
Come dear. You too
listen to this story.
No teacher can teach you this.
Come and sit with brother.
Aunt you were telling us
about your honeymoon.
ln our days, we had
a room of cow dung.
l fell asleep waiting.
Only then did your uncle come in.
Now only he and l were in the room.
Seeing me asleep,
he pinched me hard!
What's wrong with you?
l was pinched 55 years ago.
And you're feeling the hurt today?
Nothing aunt.
The romance has just begun.
Then slowly your uncle
caught my hand.
- Let go of me!
- That's just what l said.
- Then what happened?
- What would happen?
- Then he lifted me up.
- Then? Answer..
l know you are very impatient.
But nothing happened.
He turned that way and slept off
and l turned the other!
Does that mean that...
nothing happened?
For 6 years we did nothing.
The deed was done when
l turned 16 and he was 18.
These days everything is hurried.
Everything is instant.
What do you say?
lncidentally everything is instant.
But when an accident takes place...
We say, seasons keep changing
but spring has just arrived.
Yes or no?
You've got the right note.
Hopefully the tune will be good.
Yes or no?
Come on answer, yes or no?
- Will you serve or just ask?
- Serving!
Henna is being applied to my palms
but the color is on your cheeks?
This color is like a rainbow.
lt is seen but can't be caught.
lf the bride to be places her
hennaed hand in a spinster's hands...
She'll get engaged
and married right away.
But if a boy holds a girl's hand...?
Then they fall in love. lsn't it?
Why are you pouncing on them?
The bride has gone but the
photographs aren't running away.
Your wife is running away. She
insists on leaving by evening.
Are you all leaving today?
- lt's a matter of my job.
- Dad, wedding photographs.
Chandni has leave. Neelu has
gone to her husband's house.
lf she stayed back,
she'd share our loneliness.
Has the goddess of wealth and
a daughter ever stayed in one place?
She may stay if she feels like it.
At least now come and help me pack.
Yelling won't help pack. Here.
Will you stay?
- Yes aunt.
- Are you happy?
Yes l'm very happy.
You're my favorite. That's why
l'm keeping you back to love you more.
Does she only know how to
take love or even give?
lf there's a tiny bit
of place in her heart...
l'll send in an application.
When you fool around, you don't
care if there are grown ups around!
Coming.
Don't the people in
Delhi have any shame?
lf l feel shame, l'll be waving
a flag atop Qutub Minar all my life!
Only if l be shameless
will l climb astride the horse.
- Yes or no?
- You clicked even the horse.
But kept flashing lights at me!
- There's no picture of me!
- First answer yes or no.
- lf l say no?
- l won't come on a horse.
Will you sit on a donkey then?
l will...
No! l'm frightened!
l'm with you!
- l will die! - l won't
let you die before you answer!
- l will fall off!
- Then come closer.
- l am scared.
- Then hold me tight!
Yes or no?
- Yes or no?
- Yes!
- Louder, l can't hear.
- Yes! Yes!
When will you come again?
-When you call me.
- Give me your address. l'll write.
- lf mother finds out...
- l'll write at some friend's address.
Letter! A letter from your lover!
Give it to me! Don't trouble me!
First l'll read it.
lt came to my address.
l have a right to read it.
According to our deal, l will
read it and you will hear.
- Just hold this.
- Cheat!
l'll show you when
the next letter comes!
Should l call you the
breeze or the desire of time?
The beat of my heart or
the fragrance of my breath?
Flowers bloom when l think of you.
When dawn breaks it feels as if
you are tossing your hair in dew.
And l'm kissing your eyes.
The golden afternoon feels as if
the moonlight has come to earth.
The setting sun adorns you
with orange blossoms.
And your fragrance reaches me.
When night spreads
her cloak of darkness...
l swear l miss you a lot!
The full moon stops in its'
orbit to admire your beauty.
l shut my eyes and
Chandni enters my heart.
Yours and only yours.
What do l write?
Time has come to a standstill.
Time, night, breeze, fragrance,
everything holds its' breath and...
Waits for me to write something.
But how can the feelings
of the heart form words?
All your favorite things are present.
Jasmine flowers, a smiling flame
and your Chandni.
l wish you were here.
But how can you be here?
But you are here.
ln my heart and its' beats.
Soon our hearts will beat like one.
My parents will return tomorrow.
l'll talk to them about our wedding.
You want to marry a girl
you saw in that crowd?
A girl who is not of our standing,
who is not from our community!
You want to make her the
daughter-in-law of our family?
What are you talking about?
l'm not the first man to do this.
When we buy furniture we first
check if it matches in our house.
The girl l love is
furniture for you?
This word, love has been used
so often that it has lost meaning!
Why do you forget that she
will get married and come here?
- We'll have to adjust with her!
- Understand one thing mother.
l'm not marrying her for you.
Neither do l believe in caste,
community and society norms.
l haven't come to ask you
nor to take your permission.
But only to inform you that
l am marrying her.
You only have to decide whether
you will bless us or not!
Stop him. lf she comes to
this house as a bride...
What face will l have in society?
Which society are you talking about?
Where your bank balance
decides your reputation?
That girl won't come to our house!
You can't darn silk with rags!
That was done the day l came
to this house as a son-in-law.
And how will you stop him?
He's a man of today, your only son.
Someday he'll leave everything
and walk off. Think about it.
Try to understand, weddings
are between people of same standing.
We have to live in this society.
The society that has accepted me
will accept her tomorrow.
Actually he knows he is our only son.
We can't go against his wishes.
He's exploiting this fact.
- Talk to Shivsagar..
- What are you...?
But remember one thing.
The wedding should be
worthy of our position.
They treated us very well!
This boy has dishonored us!
The daughter-in-law is the honor
and shame of the family, the house.
She remains behind curtains
and maintains her distance.
With her around we'll have a ball.
We'll see dances everyday.
The neighbors too won't get bored.
l still say break the relation.
lt's not too late!
She didn't want to dance or sing.
Your darling son forced her into it.
ln saving your reputation,
you may end up losing your son!
They will come tomorrow.
Rearrange your facial expressions.
- What did he say?
- Nothing.
Congratulations!
Happiness and joy!
Take our picture.
Mother you are forgetting
the bride-to-be.
- Live long son. - Today is also
the girl's day. Bless her also.
Always be happy.
Our love and blessings are in
this ring. Be happy son.
The beauty of the ornament lies
in the wearer and love has no value.
The beauty also lies with
the person putting it on.
- Here put it on her finger.
- Yes.
Won't you give her any gift?
How can l forget my
future sister-in-law?
l thought she's very fond of dancing
so what could be better than this?
l am fond of dancing but..
On this auspicious occasion
only you could give such a gift!
The brother will always remember
this gift of his sister!
What's the matter?
Why are you upset?
l'm thinking of the future. Chandni
will be stifled in that house!
l didn't know they
would behave like this.
What do they think of themselves!
They belong to a rich family.
lt's the arrogance of money!
We didn't go begging to them!
- We are happy as we are!
- What's the fight about?
Think about Chandni
and her happiness
l am confident Rohit
will look after her.
And l know nobody can be angry
with my daughter for very long.
Once they get married,
she'll win everybody's hearts.
l hope this happens.
Are you mad?
Did you get frightened?
Close your eyes.
What will you do to me
with my eyes closed?
What can a poor girl do to you?
- How can l trust you?
- Oh! Can't trust me now?
Today l'm going to get raped!
- Will you shut your eyes?
- But why?
Open your mouth.
Taste this and identify it.
This is barfi from Ghantewala.
Now let's see. What is this?
What is this? Laddu.
Now let me see.
Don't open your eyes.
Chilli !
You didn't say what it is.
Can't you eat one
single chilli for me?
l can consume poison for you.
What did she get!
Chandni! Where are you running?
Come and sit here.
We won't stay here for
one day after we get married.
Because your family, my relatives...
They will bore us! Call us for
meals and ruin our nights!
So what do you want?
l want to take you away from here.
Where there is nobody
but you and me!
We'll have our
honeymoon in Switzerland.
What's wrong? Where are you?
l can spend my whole
life with your love.
- Come here.
- Why?
Come on. l feel like kissing you.
- l couldn't hear.
- Don't ruin my romance!
An old joke. A fat man wants
to make love to a pretty girl.
The girl says, if you can
catch me, you can love me.
So fat man, won't you kiss me?
l am dead. l can't answer you.
l will bring you back to life.
Move and l shoot!
Please don't. l'm the only husband
of my wife. What will happen to her?
Give me all the cash in your pocket!
- Fast! Don't try to run.
- Just a minute. Absolutely.
l have just 3 francs left over.
You can have them.
Comes to Switzerland
and carries only 3 francs!
l don't know anything.
l want to go shopping!
Aren't you tired of shopping?
l'm carrying these bags like an ass!
Let's go to the hotel and romance.
All the valuables!
Come to the hotel.
l'll give you everything.
Okay. Hold this.
- Let this be.
- For ice cream.
Get lost! Wants real stuff
for threatening with a toy gun!
May l taste it?
- May l ...?
- No way!
Had half of mine and
won't give hers!
Dropped my ice cream!
Give me a bite!
Tonight... yes or no?
- No, no.
- Come on, say yes or no.
- No mischief in this cold.
- What else can we do in the cold?
lt's very cold today.
We'll do one thing, go to
the hotel, l'll give you cognac.
Cognac is brandy. Meaning liquor.
No. Cognac is not wine.
- Cognac is not liquor?
- No, cognac is not liquor.
- Good heavens! Cognac...
- ls not liquor.
What else is it?
Romance, love.
Youth. lntoxication. Wow!
Romance, love, youth,
intoxication, wow!
Cognac is not liquor.
We'll have a ball tonight!
We'll stay awake all night.
Talk of love.
While talking of love,
we will make love.
Making love again we'll make love!
Cognac is not liquor!
She is finished!
Cognac is liquor!
- What are you doing?
- l was sleeping.
- Give me a kiss.
- l'm sleeping now.
No, l won't give.
You woke me from a dream.
Fast give me a kiss.
Aunt has come!
From where do these aunts land up!
Where were you? You took
ages to come to the phone!
- l was in the bathroom.
- What were you doing?
- Please tell me.
- Having a bath! What else!
What's the matter?
l'm dripping with water!
- What are you doing?
- Talking to you.
What were you doing before that?
Looking in the mirror.
How did you find my Chandni?
- l love myself today.
- And not me?
Why don't you understand?
l love you.
That is why l like myself.
When you call me yours...
l feel proud of myself.
Now what is it?
l want to meet you this evening.
- But where?
- On the terrace of your house.
- Our terrace?
- l'll wait for you.
- All right. l'll come.
- But as my Chandni.
- What do you mean?
- ln milky white clothes.
From head to toe.
Up here!
You are mad!
What are you doing? Are you mad?
This is my style.
Careful.
Come back please!
Ramesh here.
Rohit met with an accident.
While landing. He's in the hospital.
What happened?
Don't worry. Everything will be fine.
- Where is he? Can l see him?
- Not yet.
Not now? What do the doctors say?
- Nothing can be said.
- What?
- ls he very serious?
- He's being operated upon.
Do you know how this
accident occurred?
- How?
- Because of her!
She is very fond of flowers.
To pamper her Rohit bought
flowers from all over town.
He was showering her with flowers
when this accident took place!
This happened because of you!
What do you want from us?
Why don't you go away from here?
l can't leave before meeting
Rohit, without seeing him.
No! You won't meet him or
see him! Go away from here!
Just once mother.
Let me see him just once.
Then l'll do as you say.
Let me meet him just once.
Rohit has gained consciousness!
You looked gorgeous from that height.
What's the matter?
What's wrong? Tell me.
My right arm and leg aren't moving.
- What's wrong with me?
- Your right side is paralyzed.
Will l be able to walk?
Will l ever get well?
Of course you will but you have to
use your determination and will power.
You have to get well.
God has saved you for me.
Now your life is
a trust meant for me.
Welcome home smiling face, dark hair.
Take me to my room.
One thing is for sure,
Rohit brought joy home.
Tell you something? The nurses
in the hospital were very pretty.
Had l stayed longer,
l would've had an affair.
l was in a hurry to get back.
Why did you become silent?
Hearing voices from the past l feel..
Time has stood still.
Don't hold back time. Let it go on.
Will those days ever return?
Yes, those days will return.
l have full faith.
Your faith is my life.
And your life is my life.
Today if l ask you for something,
promise you won't turn me down.
Do you expect me to refuse?
Every word of yours is my promise.
From now onwards whenever l open
my eyes, l should see you before me.
Today onwards my morning
will begin with your smile.
And night will set under
the darkness of your lashes.
What are you doing here?
Can't you see mummy?
She's making breakfast for Rohit.
Are we no more that you will
make breakfast for my son?
She's establishing her
rights before marriage.
She comes here every morning.
She's really shameless!
Not shameless, very clever.
She thinks if she can win Rohit's
heart, all the wealth will be hers!
Are you listening to us?
She thinks she can pull us away
from Rohit by doing all this.
The world will laugh, not yet
married but always around my son!
Do whatever you want, you cannot
become the mistress of this house!
Go away from here!
Keep the tray back.
Don't you dare step
in my kitchen again!
Don't cry for every little thing.
Your tears will dry up but
they won't appreciate them.
You've lost so soon.
You have major battles to win.
What do l do? Mother gets
angry at every thing.
And Pooja always hated me.
Actually they want you
to get fed up and leave.
Don't they want Rohit to be happy?
They do but they want him
to be happy in their choice.
And you're not their choice.
lf Rohit sees tears in
your eyes, he will break down.
So bear everything, put up with it.
Take everything with a smile.
For Rohit if not yourself.
For his happiness.
You are right.
She dropped brother! Come fast!
Good God! What happened to my son?
What do you want to do? Kill him?
- Nothing happened. - Of course,
you fell because of her carelessness!
She's always dancing and singing!
Why don't you find another house?
- Do you know what you're saying?
- She is right.
Since the time she stepped into
my house, my son has been ruined!
- She's cast a spell on him!
- What are you saying?
- Listen to what l have to say.
- Son, you are unwell.
- You need complete rest.
- Pooja has accused Chandni..
l want peace in this house!
-But what's her fault?
- You keep... - Daddy...!
Unnecessarily Pooja...
You must rest son.
Pooja take him in.
No need. l'll go on my own.
Listen to one thing carefully.
Rohit is my only son.
l don't want to lose him
because of you.
Very shameless girl! Standing here
after listening to all this!
Please be quiet. This is enough!
Now go home.
They won't let you live.
Are you angry with me?
No.
l've brought something for you.
Shut your eyes.
l'll put it in your mouth
and you must identify it.
- Why shut my eyes?
- l won't give you chilies!
Feed me like this.
Don't you trust me?
l don't trust myself.
- You did till yesterday.
- There's a lot of difference today.
- What difference?
- Yesterday was a dream.
Today is real.
Real, dream, yesterday, today...
l don't understand...
Why don't you understand?
l'm not the man you loved!
With whom you sang and danced!
How long will l amuse myself
with memories of the past?
Why are you being so emotional?
Emotions are all l have now.
Everything else is...
All the dreams have crashed.
They haven't crashed.
Our dreams will come true.
How? With this handicapped,
cripple, helpless Rohit?
You can't use these words to
describe yourself when l'm here!
lf you could revolt against your
parents and society for me...
Then can't l become your legs?
l'll be your better half in
the true sense of the word.
l'll be your hope, your strength.
Your belief.
Why don't you try to understand?
Who did all this?
l did it.
- You?
- Yes.
l don't need the
memories attached to them.
Don't say that. Our love is
tied by very delicate threads.
That is pity not love.
And l don't want to
live with anyone's pity.
What is wrong with you?
What made you change in one night?
There is no place for
your love in my life.
lt's not so easy to erase love.
l'm not lifeless
like these pictures!
l'm a living girl.
ln whose chest beats a heart.
l have feelings, a brain that thinks!
By removing the pictures,
the symbol of our love...
You've white washed the walls but
put the color of hatred on our love!
Those pictures reminded me of
the moments that l can't forget!
Your beauty, your smile,
your youth makes fun of me!
Your singing to
please me stinks of pity!
You want me to be dependant on you.
No! lt's better to die
than live like that!
Don't say that.
Your life is more precious to me
than anything in this world.
l know today your heart is
filled with hatred not love.
Yet l ask you one question.
lf l was in your place and you
in mine, what would you have done?
l would have left you much earlier.
l feel sorry for your pettiness.
You don't know the meaning of love.
Love is a gift of God not charity!
You're talking of the girl who
was your heartbeat, your breath!
- Your love!
- What has that love given me?
You got everything!
Family, name, wealth!
And l have got venom!
Defamation! Restlessness!
lt snatched away
the peace of my life!
The girl you talk of made me a
cripple instead of giving me life!
What? You too accuse me?
l made you a cripple?
Yes! Till yesterday only my
family and the world said this.
But today even l say you
crippled me! ln body and spirit!
All right. lf like your family
and the world, you too believe..
That l crippled you.
l have no right to live in this house.
Nor any right on you.
l'm taking your gift of love with me.
You may live with hatred.
l will live with my love.