Nair, good news.
Your town tender has come to us
Rs 200 crore contract on a
mere 3 lakhs bid difference
Our Ganesh construction has got it
A Rs 200 crore road contract
and we missed out for a mere 3 lakhs...
to Ganesh constructions
We need that contract,
no matter what it takes
Boss, from this moment you may
think the contract is ours
He should not be allowed
to enter this town
Bash him and get me that contract
Where is your boss?
Who are you all? What do you want?
I am engineer Kumar speaking.
Someone has intercepted our
staff vehicle and are threatening us
Who are they? What do they want?
I don't know who they are
and what they want
Come soon sir!
Where are you now?
- 15 Kms from our place
I'll be right there
Catch them! Don't spare them
Saravanan, you!
Are you alright?
I'm fine
When did you come from U. S?
How did you come here?
I was coming from the airport,
I saw thugs chasing women
How could I ignore that?
So gave them few thrashings
How come you are so trim?
If I am obese it may not look nice.
If you are thin it won't look nice
My company staff. I got a call
saying they had a problem
But you rescued them before I did
- Had he not come in time...?
Now that he's back
it's gonna be great!
Where is your beautiful wife
Ganga Senthilnathan?
She is here
Ganga...? Where is she?
She was right here
Scared me
Last year you introduced her to me
as your love
Wasn't she a reserved type?
So mischievous now?
It's her mischief
that I like
Come, let's go home
- Go on, I'll come in my car
Mother is not happy with our marriage
nor with our Vettayapuram trip
You must reason with her
I'll go and see father
Sir, I am a psychiatrist
only because of you
You brought up this orphan as
your own son. I can never forget that
Though you are not with us
you will always live in our hearts
Mom, greetings
Come Saravanan...
so you find time to visit us?
After your last year visit
you didn't even make a call!
I don't care if you are
a great doctor
Don't worry, I am not going to
leave India for quite sometime
I will make you all happy
and I will also remain happy
You will make all those here happy.
But who will solve my problem?
I will do it, don't worry
How did you say, what I had in mind?
That is his speciality
Looking at your face he would say
what is in your mind.
He is not a mere doctor,
he is also an expert mind reader
How else can he treat
confused psychiatric patients?
Shut up
Not a big deal. There is nothing
that cannot be achieved by practice
What makes you think that the people
there will cause problems for Senthil
in his construction work?
- What do you know?
I wanted to reunite his father's family
by getting him married to his cousin
But if they find out that he had
a love marriage like his father...
they might do anything to this girl
You think it's funny?
None of you know about Akilandeshwari
Even her brothers are frightened of her
She is such a terror
She would surely harm
Ganga and take her revenge
I am not going to stay in their house
Then where?
I have bought the Vettayapuram palace
I am going to stay there
What, mother?
- As a kid...
I heard lots about that palace
That is a dangerous place.
For nearly 50 years
no one came forward to buy that
Are you mad to buy that palace?
Don't worry about Senthil or Ganga.
I will ensure nothing happens to them
I shall leave for Vettayapuram today.
My first task would be...
to meet your relatives and console them.
I'll also check the palace thoroughly
Later I will decide whether these two
should stay there or not
'Akhilandeswari House'
Dear, dear!
Have you ever called me lovingly?
You always alarm me! What is so urgent?
- Look! People and cars!
They are coming here
Come on in, sir.
He is a big textile businessman
They have come to seek
your eldest daughter Priya
My sister Akilandeswari takes
all decisions in this house
Though Priya is our daughter
she was brought up by my sister
I'll come after consulting my sister
Kasturi married my fiance, but now she
has forgotten the 30 year animosity...
and seeks my daughter for her son
So I have decided that he will be
my son-in-law
Okay sister.
Where is that businessman?
- They heard what sister said
All the cars have taken an about turn.
- Is it?
It is 8 years since we are married.
In all those I have not seen...
anybody from your uncle's family
- These families parted ways 30 years ago
This wedding will reunite them.
You'll see all of them
Come soon, come
Oh Lordl
Lord of the seven hillsl
Look at us
Our folk, s hearts are diamonds.
Come on burnish it
When all the powers are harnessed...
this earth would turn a heaven
Oh Lordl Lord of the seven hillsl
Look at us
Think for a while
The tiller would smear legs in mud...
so that we can lay hands on our food
If those who clean the drain...
go on leave for four days,
the town would stink
If we don, t have hairdressers...
will we look handsome?
If there is no one to wash
clothes in river water...
will the dirty linen get brighter?
Which ever job you do,
work is worship
Pattukottai said so in his song
When all the powers are harnessed...
this earth would turn a heaven
Oh Lordl
Lord of the seven hillsl
Look at us
Let people say
anything about you...
just listen through one ear
and push it out through the other
Even if the cloud floats
or the crow flies...
the sky won, t get dirtier
Even if a ball is immersed in water
it would float...
Even if you are sidelined
come on up brother, like a ball
Can the crescent
changing to a full moon...
be prevented by glow worms?
When all the powers are harnessed...
this earth would turn a heaven
Oh Lordl Lord of the seven hillsl
Look at us
Our folk, s hearts are diamonds.
Come on burnish it
Our folks hearts are diamonds.
Superb
When all the powers are harnessed...
this earth would turn a heaven
We don't know when and
how son-in-law is coming
Who let that bullock cart in?
Who is that?
Stop, stop! I say, stop!
You don't pay heed to
a respectable man!
Don't I look like a man?
- No, no
Who are you?
Why did you bring in a bullock cart?
We are expecting our son-in-law
From Chennai. Kasturi madam's...
- Son-in-law!
We expected you by flight. And here you
come in a bullock cart, like a simpleton
Look, I'm not your son-in-law
Right. Not before the wedding
Are you joking?
I'm not your son-in-law. Well...
- Well, you are here now
Oh, how do I explain?
I'm Senthilnathan's friend Saravanan
Before I could explain over the phone
the line got disconnected
Your mother called us and told us
to expect such excuses from you...
because you would be embarrassed
to stay in our home
My sister has taken Priya to the temple
Son-in-law, stop lying now
Oh! You useless fellow
What are you looking at?
Burn the crackers!
Where is son-in-law?
My wife is also missing!
Excuse me! I am scared of crackers.
- Me too
Where is she?
I feel you are like my sister.
- I also feel...
you are like my brother
What bloody feeling?
She is not the girl
you are going to marry
I have already married her
and she lives with me
It is true we have been married
for 8 years and have no children
So don't shift your feelings
towards him, Swarna
What? You and Swarna don't
have children even after 8 years?
He read my mind!
Good Lord!
Simply gorgeous
Enough. I am telling you once again,
she is my wife
Son-in-law, if you talk to your uncle
he would talk for the whole day
Come here
I burst crackers for him,
but he drops a bomb on me
He is praising her too much.
- I will praise her!
Son-in-law, the bullock cart journey
must've been tiring
Go take a shower and rest
What, what is this?
- Brother, let us not have him here
For what?
- We don't need him here
If you allow him to enter, we may
lose many valuables. Be careful
Don't blabber.
- Am I blabbering?
He is calling me over...
did he hear what I just said?
You don't like me
staying here, isn't it?
On my way here, I asked many people
about Vettayapuram palace
Everyone was scared and
no one was prepared to help me
So?
- Lf you take me to the palace...
I won't stay here, otherwise...
- Otherwise?
I will stay here.
- Oh no! I will take you there
But you should do what you say.
- I will say only what I do
Both are same. Shall we go?
Go inside, go!
Even the gate gives me the creeps
This is the Vettayapuram palace.
Now that you have seen it, let's go
Take off your hands.
- Why? Do you want to ride in?
Come inside.
- Where?
Come on!
- Buddy, I'm not going inside
I won't go inside, I swore to you!
It's not fair to force an elderly person
Had I told you, you wouldn't have come.
That is why I'm forcing you
So informal?
- Right
No good showing respect
to a cowardly old man
I won't go, even if you abuse me!
- Who stays here?
I won't tell.
- Swarna!
A gardener and his grand daughter!
- Really? So why are you so scared?
They don't stay inside palace.
- But we're going in
You may go in! I'll go back home.
- Why is that rope and log hanging there?
Painting work is in process.
- Then, are there painters inside?
Only one guy named Gopal.
He has been painting for a month
A guy staying here alone for a month,
but we both are scared to go in?
But he is from another village.
Had he known he would've fled
It is so dark in here
even in broad daylight
Murugesh, do you know the
history behind this palace?
Does STD mean history?
Inmates of this palace fled 50 years ago
Now some fool has bought it
and is having it painted
They can't hide what is inside
by painting the outside
Let us go now.
- OK, let us go
Not inside but outside.
Look, an elephant is lying dead here
That is a buffalo, Murugesh.
- Buffalo?
What do you think there is inside?
- Ghosts, they say
Fools.
- Evil spirits, they say
Cowards.
- A 30-feet snake, since 30 years!
That is why, that Gopal...
- A snake, really...?
He doesn, t work here beyond 4 p. M
One day he boldly worked after 4 p. M...
And that day, things strangely
started breaking suddenly
Ever since, he leaves the palace
by 4 to 4:30 p. M
Why should a guy with
so much fear work alone?
Groom is missing?
Groom!
He ditched me! Oh God!
He left me alone.
How will I go out?
I've to go 1 k.m. From here.
Gopal, take me along. Where are you?
He came with me,
and ditched me, murderer
A lion!
Brother Murugesh, look at me
Say something... please
Didn't I ask you not to take him there?
Just look at him
He looks like one of those big shots,
frozen with a smile while being arrested
What to do now?
Sister...? Why is there a crowd here?
What happened?
Greetings, I am...
- not the groom
Where is my prospective son-in-law?
When they said, you came by bullock cart...
I knew that you were not my son in law
Because his son wouldn't come like that.
- You said it right
I tried to tell them
I am not the groom...
but they don't believe me
But you've understood it on your own
The groom has decided to buy
'Vettayapuram Palace' in this village
He has sent me for that. I am his friend.
I've been brought up in his house
My name is Saravanan.
- Impossible!
I won't allow him to buy
the 'Vettayapuram Palace'
lt'll be dangerous for him to buy that
For my daughter too,
who will marry him
Well, lady...
I don't know how to say this.
His marrying your daughter...
There he comes
He resembles his dad
You? Son in law?
Priya, come here.
You wanted to see your fiance
He has arrived. Come and see him
Who's that?
She is Ganga
My wife
His mother wanted him
to marry your adopted daughter...
but due to certain circumstances,
Senthil had to marry Ganga
What is this? People from big families
asked for my daughter's hand...
but I didn't agree,
but you have deserted us
Marriages and alliances are decided
by destiny. How can we control it?
What a knowledge at such an young age?
You have Avvaiyar's brain. Shake hand
Let it be
My marriage definitely would have
hurt you
But I've come here only to see you all.
Pardon me
We shall leave now.
- Where?
I've bought 'Vettayapuram Palace'.
We shall be staying there
You mean THAT palace? Please don't
Why?
- I went to see it, and I got a shock
If you buy it,
you'd be inviting trouble
Uncle, you are all elderly,
this is what you believe
Listen to me. Just like my uncle,
you also married an outside girl
However, I won't allow you to stay
in such a dangerous place
Uncle, before coming here
Ganga and I visited that palace
Nothing is scary over there like he said
Don't mistake me, I've been a gardener
in that palace for 40 years
Even I've not gone inside that palace.
Please think and act
I've bought that 50-crore worth
property for 5 crore rupees...
I know that people believe that
it has some problems
But I don't believe it. I want my wife
Ganga to be the owner...
of a palace instead of just a house.
That's why I bought it
In case of any problems, we'll deal
with it. You don't worry
Go stay there
You may go and stay in that house
Why do you stare? I stood against buying
that house. Are you wondering...
why I am asking him to stay there?
Not only them, but all of us
are going to stay there...
until his contract gets over.
- Oh God!
If both of them go there alone and
something happens to them...
his mom will mistake me thinking that
since he didn't marry my daughter...
we had sent him there
despite knowing everything
Hence all of us will go and stay there
until everything is solved
Correct.
- Nice of you. Let's get her blessings
No, Senthil
- Why?
Not now
Complete the contract,
then we all can get her blessings
All these poojas won't be
effective in this palace
I've come along only to see your end
Now that you have come,
just watch what happens
Senthilnathan, we are not staying
just because sister asked us to
I don't want you two to stay alone and
get into trouble, that's why I agreed
We would stay here till the end
only on one condition
Tell me, what is it?
- On no account...
should anyone go to the stairway behind
Specifically no one should go to
the room in the southern corner
You have decided to stay with us with
your family. Won't I do atleast this?
We shall stay away from
that place for sure
Now I am happy
Oh God! What would I do?
Why do they buy trouble
and decorate it nicely?
I shouldn't stay alone in the house.
I should always be with the others
Murugesa!
Such a beautiful name. Why do you
call it in such a scary manner?
Why do you create trouble?
- I have a sore throat
I forgot to ask, what is
your zodiac sign?
Why?
Just tell me
Leo.
- Leo, really?
Only one in a lakh will
have this zodiac sign
You are lucky
Ghosts love that sign!
Does it take so many people
to lift one cot?
This is not any ordinary cot?
It is an antique
Made of Burma teak. It takes
more than 2 people to lift it
Bring your wife and come quickly
We are going to visit the family deity.
It's your dad's temple
In a bullock cart with the groom
Why all of you are
coming in a bullock cart?
Sir is a doctor in the U. S, he likes
to go only in a bullock cart
Mercedes Benz is fine, but
the bullock cart has its own charm
Well said
- Gardener, what are you doing here?
My grand daughter is flying kites
with all the kids
So I am here with her
- Who is she?
That girl in a white sari
with black stripes
I did kite flying at a very young age
- Yes
Are you ready?
- Readyl
Crane, fly fly
Hen fly fly
Myna fly fly
Peacock fly
My Kite, fly away
Fly across the sky
Oh my soull Fly
No bounds fly
This kite leaps and flies,
it will fly splendidly
This is super star, s kitel
Our kite
If you see Goddess Meenakshi...
Pray to do away with money lending
at exhorbitant interest
If you see Sri Renganathan...
Ask Talaicauveri to come often
Don, t know about Yesterday or
tomorrow. But today is present
Fly and dance as you wish
The wind is now favourable to us
Our kite is not a butterfly
but an Eagle
The sharpened kite flying thread...
will duel with anyone
This kite leaps and flies,
it will fly splendidly
This is super star, s kite, our kite
If the ladder is kicked
gratitude becomes meaningless
Nod your head to the wind...
thank the kite flying thread gently
Have not gone to schools,
have not gone to college...
but got degrees
Not even books
teach lot of lessons...
kites teach and kite is a teacher
Who can fence the air?
Let us fly like kites
Crane fly fly
Hen fly fly
Myna fly fly
Peacock fly
Oh My kite fly
Fly sky high
Fly across sky no bounds
Fly fly
This kite leaps and flies,
it will fly splendidly
This is super star, s kite, our kite
Priest, this is my nephew Senthilnathan
He has bought the Vettayapuram palace
Everyone is scared when a mention
is made about the palace
What is there? What happened?
About 100 to 150 years ago...
King Vettayan lived in that palace
He used to make a peculiar noise
when he arrives
He would do anything to attain his goal.
He was such a brutal man
Once when he had gone to
Vijayanagaram in Andhra...
he met a dancer called Chandramukhi
He was lured by her beauty and
wanted to make her his mistress
But Chandramukhi did not agree
Because she already loved
a dancer called Gunasekaran
Even after knowing that, the king
abducted her against her wishes
Chandramukhi without the knowledge
of the king...
made Gunasekaran stay in
a nearby house and met him stealthily
The King came to know about this.
On a Durgastami day...
the king killed Gunasekaran
right in front of her...
in the banquet hall of the palace,
and he burnt her alive
Chandramukhi had an untimely death
not doing anything wrong
Her soul wanted to avenge the king
The king knew about this and brought
all sorcerors from all over the country...
and conducted prayers and sealed
Chandramukhi's ashes in a pot
He kept the pot in a room at the southern
corner of the palace and locked it
After some years the king also died.
But Chandramukhi's soul...
is still waiting in that room
to avenge the king
It is said that there is a
king cobra there too
Nobody knows how much of this
is true and how much is not
12 o'clock? This is the time
at which the ghosts come out
They have all left me alone.
Is it a bedroom?
It looks like a big ground.
I accepted not knowing this
Now my heart throbs while I sleep here
Who is that?
Oh God
I didn't do it, I didn't do it
It is me, Murugesan
Why did you come at this time?
- Could not bear my wife's snores
At nights she walks like a devil,
she lies down like a ghost
From the day I heard the
priest's story I have lost my sleep
Let us hug together and sleep here
No.
- Expected. Are you not a doctor?
Please clarify my doubts.
- What Murughesan?
Do ghosts exist?
Have they ever seen one?
Should I believe it or not?
I want to know this
Why do you turn so often?
It seems the priest is better than you
Do ghosts exist? Is there any
indication of a ghost coming?
There are typical indications.
- Like?
A dog howls at a distance
Really, I can hear the sound there
Did I ask?
- No
The breeze blows wild,
the trees sway...
the windows rattle...
I can hear this sound there
Did I ask?
- No
A faint smell of jasmine...
Jasmine!
- Why are you shouting?
Ok, the wind will carry jasmine smell
Yes I can smell the jamine fragrance
Did I ask?
- No
Just hear the story, no cross questions
If you do... what is this?
- Adam's apple
I will pluck it out
Then...
What?
- Anklet
Oh God I hear the anklet sound also
Did I ask?
- No
Then a smoke like image in
white attire comes up
It's showing up!
Where?
- There
Why do you laugh like a woman?
- Not I. The ghost is laughing
Where?
- There
It's gone
You have mistaken my grandpa's dhoti
swinging in the wind for a ghost
Have you not learnt anything?
- Me scared?
Me?
- Yes
Murugesan and I were rehearsing
for a drama. What is you name?
Why?
- Just to know
Durga.
- Goodness me
What?
What an arrogant girl.
I will take care of her later
It's all because of him
He damaged my image
before a beautiful girl
Having done all this
see how he is sleeping
Stop it!
What is this?
Early morning can't you find...
any other place to teach music?
It has become a big nuisance with you
At nights you walk with anklets,
laugh frighten us, and ruin our sleep
Early morning you sing and wake up
all the those who are sleeping
This is not right. I came here
to rest, I have lost my peace
Kids, why do you scream like this?
Go, watch good movies in TV
Look here, Darga...
- Durga!
If you want to teach music,
go to a temple...
or a hall or river side
don't do it here
My friend has bought
this palace shelling out crores
Is this palace meant for you
to teach music?
No, change your location tomorrow.
If I hear the sound again...
I will drive you and
your grandfather away
Look, what ever you do, the
music classes will be held right here
From tomorrow it would be more noisy
If you have decided to go
from this house what can I do?
If I am to forgo my music
I don't want to live in this place
She's an orphan. A bit short tempered
but doesn't take anything to heart
Until you leave this place I will ask
her not to conduct classes here
I beg of you
Don't
You may be a modern girl and
would like to see what's up there
But in such matters
you should listen to elders
Come downstairs
Who is that?
You?
What are you doing here
at this time?
I couldn't sleep so I thought I'd
come here for some fresh air
Love?
Are you in love?
- How do you know?
It is evident from your face
The day your dad asked you
to come and see your groom...
you were unperturbed and calm.
I knew then itself you were in love
Tell me, who he is?
Viswanath. Dance professor.
He lives there
I see. Good selection.
- Do you know him?
I know him, I also know who
made him stay in that house
Have you expressed your love?
- Yes
What did he say?
- He asked my dad to come
Didn't you tell him about it?
- I am scared
Then how will your love succeed?
What's your dad's name?
Kandaswamy
Your daughter is in love here,
and you are sleeping?
Hey Mustache!
Oh God
Why are you here at this hour?
- Nothing, just came for some fresh air...
Fresh air? Get lost
What are you doing here at this time?
- Alliance
Alliance?
- Ok, research
Research?
- Love
First this doctor should be
driven out of the house, isn't it?
I told you this that day itself.
You are late
He is interested on that girl.
My wife is saved
A bachelor has one worry, whereas
a married man has thousand worries
Look here
1001st worry
He's just so accurate...!
Grandpa, it's 9 o'clock and yet
no one has come
They won't come.
- Why not?
Bommi is here.
Where are the others?
The uncle who scolded you yesterday,
gave us money...
and asked us not to come for classes.
He asked us to go and watch a movie
Until he goes back it would be better
not to conduct music classes
Durga
Because you don't like me
teaching music...
you stopped them from
attending the classes?
You can only give them money
and send them for movies
But can you buy music
with your money?
I have already bought it
My harmonium?
- I bought all these instruments
Except this box. Your grandpa
gave me this trivia, free of cost
Music is like Saraswathy
It's in the blood by birth
Arrogant people like you will not
understand its importance ever
You will never...
understand! You...
- Look here Darga
Don't curse me, it might come true.
Not for the sake of this box!
You may take it.
- This one?
I won't touch the harmonium
used by you
The Civet hill does not dance.
Bommi dances...
This is a lullaby by God.
Hear it, Bommi
My music enthralls, Bommi
lt, s His song that pervades
I have sung the song
bestowed by Lord Shiva
Through the song
I captivated millions
Circular buds bloomed...
when the breeze caressed
Buds...
gently attunes melody
Music must make one dance...
and swing
Music must make one hear
and captivate
Hearing this music the earth
would always orbit
Tying little cradles a mother, s
lullaby is also music
Man and woman on cot
attuning melody of desires...
is also music
Oh mind, get appeased
Who is the mastermind here?
Check what you know
Gather what is not there
There, s no one who knows everything,
who comprehends everything
The Civet hill does not dance
Dancing Bommi, this is
a lullaby by God
Hearing my song mind
would jump in joy
Is there a place
where His song is not heard?
I have sung the song
bestowed by Lord Shiva
Through the song
I captivated millions
Fantastic! You were wonderful
You have made us dance.
- He does everything nicely
What do you think of my friend?
At a time... he can answer 10 different
questions posed by 10 different people
He's not an ordinary man.
He's extraordinary
What are you watching?
Go inside
Why do you look there?
- Super dress
A wiseman does not require advice
A capable man does not
require advertisement
Through your song
you have taught me a lot
Forgive me
A message for doctor Saravanan
You've got an e-mail
What happened?
- One of your patients is serious
Wants you to return.
- Is it a bad news?
Is it not? You said you will
stay here for a month
But within 6 days you
have been called back
Senthil, a doctor can wait
for the patient...
but a patient should not
wait for the doctor. I'm leaving
What Saravanan?
Saravanan will appear
Sir, I am leaving.
- Really? Take this
Now I am happy. Happy that
you're leaving so soon
Go ahead.
- Correct
You are happy that I'm leaving so soon
But I have finished
a 6 month's job...
In...?
- In just 6 days
The other day we talked about love.
Have you informed your dad?
Love?
Doctor, you left your specs in my room.
- In your room?
I'll take that later.
Let me talk about Priya's love
How dare you talk about
my daughter's affair to me?
Who else should I talk to then?
Do you want me to say it all...
to all the magazines and press?
How can you fall in love with
a complete stranger? How dare you!
Don't get excited. I said she was
in love. Did I say with me?
Priya is in love with
dance professor Viswanath
Yes. Viswanathan is a good boy,
a right match for your daughter
The other day I was talking
only about this to Priya
Next day I talked to Viswanathan.
With your consent...
he is prepared to marry Priya,
he said. So think about it
Don't lose a good alliance
on false prestige
However hard you try you may not
get such a good boy
Once the marriage is fixed
send me an invitation
If required, your second daughter...
- I'll surely invite you. Please leave
Really?
- Really
I forget someone... yes, Swarna
I won't allow you to talk to my wife
even at the risk of my life
Look at his dress.
He is wearing the shirt inside out
lt'd be better to tear it to pieces.
- Is it your dad's property?
It's my money, it's my dough
I may tear it, may not tear it.
What will you do?
This maid has such a sexy hip.
Bad timing! Not when he is around
What will I do? Tonight, somehow,
I am going to get her
This is too much
- What?
Too much. Swarna...
The chicken...
- He asked for chicken, I didn't buy
So he wants to complain about me.
- You see...
Sir, Rajathi Raja, Arunachala
Padyappa, Thalapathi, Manna...
you may leave! Don't break
a happy family
You may leave
What did he say?
- Nothing. He wants us to eat chicken
What?
- A small story
Tell me and leave
This guy cannot even stand up...
but he likes to have 9 wives
Wait
Ganga, I forgot to tell you
I was leaving
You said one month, but you are
leaving in 6 days. Liar
You think disease comes with a notice?
What is this?
For you, to eat on your way.
- All this?
Yes, eat nicely
Do you know what is
the best medicine in world is?
What?
- Food
If you eat to a limit it is medicine.
If you over eat it is poison
Wherever I am, I keep people
around me happy
I did the same thing here also
but I was little excessive to you
If you feel so, forget it
But don't forget me
Bye. May I...?
Sorry... bye
Durga come here,
want to talk to you in private
What Madam? - No formalities.
Call me Ganga
Ok Ganga, tell me what is it?
I have a lot of old books with me.
I want to keep them in...
some room upstairs in the building.
Will you accompany me?
My God! Even my grandpa
doesn't go there
He has also asked me not to go there.
Because Chandramukhi's room is there
Old people have that fear.
Why should we fear? Am I not with you?
Let's go
Ok, you need not come, I am going
What about the people at home?
All have gone to meet Viswanathan
regarding the alliance with Priya
In that case I will come
I didn't love your daughter
for her beauty or status
I lost my parents at a young age
But I wanted to live in a joint family,
so I accepted your daughter's love
That is quite understandable.
I also like the groom... you too like...
We have only seen the groom
Shouldn't we finalise the auspicious
dates for the ceremonies?
Sister, today is a good day,
we can finalise them today itself
My daughter's engagement should
not be held in a tiled house
It should be done in the fort
and in a grand manner
I am glad that you have agreed
Coming 16th is an auspicious day.
Let's do it your way
I think this is the room
Why are there so many amulets?
150 years ago, prayers were
conducted here
Chandramukhi's spirit
is locked up here
Do you believe these stories?
Whatelse?
I think this room has valuable
jewels and diamonds
To prevent theft, these stories
must have been floated
If I get the keys to this room
I would open and show it to you
This room has no key,
it has been lost
But my grandpa told me once... that the
key's mould is available with a blacksmith
We will ask the blacksmith
to make the key immediately
You own the house.
You tell him
If you want, I will bring the key
after it is made
I will order right away
What?
- Here, the key to Chandramukhi's room
- Please don't open this door
What happened?
- The guy who made the key...
has died vomiting blood
If this is the end for the guy
who made the key...
what would happen to me,
who brought this key?
I'm scared.
- Yesterday when I placed the order...
he was drunk. A guy who drinks 24 hours,
would die whether he makes a key or not
It's good he died
after making the key
Don't confuse yourself, be brave
You say the old man died because
he made a key for the southern room
But Ganga who went into the room
is perfectly alright
You are right.
Trust me. The old man
died of a rotten liver
I may sound funny... don't know, what
more is going to happen in this house?
Hoil? It's a marwari festival, right?
Please call the ghost gently or else
it might harm us before it leaves