Welcome to your favourite
programme...
In which we introduce you to
famous people
Today we'll meet the famous
industrialist
And owner of Malhotra group
of Industries
I'll take you to his fabulous
bungalow near Delhi
Now,we'll introduce you to
Mr.Kailashnath Malhotra
Greetings
Today we want to talk to you
about things -
Which the World doesn't
know
If they could be told publicly
I'll definitely tell you
Firstly,we want to know about
your family
I have a very big family
I have a son,daughter-in-law &
a grandson
And there are some relatives
who stay with us
I'll introduce you to them
come,Come...
Sit down
This is my son,Ranjith
Greetings
She is my daughter-in-law
Asha
Greetings - Greetings
And he is the brother-in-law of
Ranjit,Mr.Pankaj - Greetings
And his wife,Kanchan
Greetings
Is it - Rest are my Staff
-Greetings
Mr.Malhotra,generally there is
discord in joint family's
What is the secret of harmony
in your family?
It's very simple
My son looks after
the business
His brother-in-law
helps him in it
Home front is taken care by
my daughter-in-law
And Kanchan helps her
And I take care of
all of them
I mean,I get every household
work by 1 phone call
I've access to the
top people
Every Central Minister & Secretary
are very close to me -
I'm not bragging
He doesn't call a mechanic to
repair the T.V in the house
He phones directly to the Minister
of Information & Broadcasting
He is Pappu
Son of our Old Manager
He has been brought up here only
since his childhood
He is like my son
If you have any work with the
Minister tell me -
I'll get it done
in a jiffy
Don't misunderstand him,This
is his habit.
He is right.
Is any Tv serial's shooting
going on !
Only the Villian was missing,
sit down,sit down!
He is Dr. Balaraj
He's my childhood friend
But he's no less than my enemy!
He has put restrictions on
clarified butter,sugar & salt.
And has left pappu here
as his spy!
If I hadn't restricted,you'll be dead
as of now,you've so many diseases!
What are you talking
camera is rolling
Alright alright I am looking
alright,isn't it?
Alright Mr. Malhotra,
one last question.
Your family is so happy,your life
is so successful
Do you have any other desire
which you want to fulfil.
I am waiting for a
companion.
Are you contemplating marriage
at this age!
Marriage?!?!
Oh no! I'm waiting for my
great grandchild.
Who will be my toy!
Who'll become my support
instead of this stick!
And He'll keep my name alive
even after my death!
And when'll this waiting
come to an end!
When my grandson Raj agrees to
get married
At the moment he has gone to
attend his friend's marriage.
Please leave me,-no no...
-Please go...
Go back
Please come
You've dazzled all the guys!
-really?
What?
You danced very well in
the function.
You were saying something?
Yes. Your child is very sweet.
Just like you.
All say like this only
No son.
Sister-in-law,take your son.
What was he saying?
He! He was saying that
''your son is very sweet''.-
Just like you.
He thought he
was my child.
Ay chotu,water is not coming
in this pipe.
What are you talking?
What's heppening?
Not working,you're gossiping?
We're not gosping
Pappu brother.
Water is not coming in this,
some blockage is there.
Go & mow the lawn.
Water is not coming?
I am an orphan,if there's anyone
in this world,its you!
Whom are you phoning?
I'm phoning the irrigation
minister-why?
Water is not coming in
the pipe.
Phone the plumber.
Why call the plumber
for such minor jobs?
What's the irrigation minister for?
-For irritation.
Only he appriciates me in the
entire family,water.
Did you,I just dialled & the
water came. this is called power.
Again the water has stopped
Brother pappu water has stopped.
Do I've to phone repeatedly am
I your father's servant?
Mother.
Your life'll also change,Just
say''Yes'' for the marriage.
How are you? My son
-fine!
How was your friend's
marriage!
Mother his life has changed.
Sister is right,you agree
to get married.
I'm not going to be trapped so soon
-Did you see?
How are you son?
How are you?
Blessings-
How was your trip?
Good you've come.Go to singapore
immediately-
And find out out why our ship hasn't
started from there
Our dealer's are bothering
us a lot here.
What type of a
father you are?
Son has just returned & you're
sending him out again.
You always want to send him out
of the country.
Dad,somebody has to go.
Then send some one else.
Pankaj you go.
But who'll attend to the
work here?
Did you bring it?-yes
Suppose our theft
is detected.
One who is caught
is a thief.
Conspirary between grandfather
& grandson!
There is something fishy.
Now take it out
Grandpa,only one-yes only one.
Oh! lovely sweet.
They are sweet like your
affection & soft like my heart,.
Don't be poetic. Eat quickly
It's a risky matter.
You may lock the door but I've
the master key.
What's happening?
Eating sweet steathlty.
You have advanced
diabeties-That too 320.
Uncle,it's a sin for you to even
touch sweets.
You're taking medicine
and sweet also.
And I'm scolded that I've eaten
all the sweets.
Dad,if you're not thinking about
you.Atleast think about us.
Enough. All of you have ganged
against a sick old man.
At least ask me why
I got the sweet?
One wrong girl'll come &
nullify everything.
Why did you get the
sweets?- why?
Because Raj has said yes.
He has said yes.
For what?
For the marriage.
What're you doing? He is tired
let him take rest.
I'll talk to him & tell you
everything later.
Take the sweets and all
of you eat it,go....
What sort of a Grandpa
you are?
Why?
To save yourself you've
put me in a soup.
And what sort of a
grandson you are?
To save the prestige
of their grandpa-
Grandsons sacrifice their
lives also.
And you are not agreeing
to get married also.
Listen sorry,If you don't
get married.
How'll the malhotra
dynesty subsist.
Grandpa this family
is like this
Everyone loves each other
immensly.
Do you think I'll bring
such a girl?
Still,I won't get
married.
Are you telling sorry?
I am your grandfather. I'll see
how you don't get married.
And I am also your grandosn
Give it.
Open your mouth.
It doesn't mean that I've agreed
to get married.
And this sweet is also
sugar free.Eat it.
How nice you look!
Miss Baructha,how many times
have I told you..
Yes. Had I married,I'd have 2
small children also.
But I'm not married yet.
I'm also not married.
And understand this.
Until I get a nice handsome boy
like you,I won't get married.
And don't get married
miss Barucha.
What are you seeing.
do your work.
Son Raj,I am doctor
Balraj speaking.
Yes doctor uncle.
Son you come to my
nursing home immidiately.
Your Grandpa is slightly
unwell.
Not slightly but
very unwell.
Yes Yes,he is very ill.
But he was alright in
the morning.
In this age one can get unwell
at any time.
Okay I'm coming.
He is coming.
Mother was there any
phone from doctor uncle!
He was here only.
He did the routine
check up of Grandpa!
And Then both of them
went for a walk.
But why are you asking?
Nothing mother. Okay, Bye.
Act in such a way that
it should look real.
You don't worry Kailash
You know that I used to come
1st in college in acting.
Grandpa,Raj has come,
lie down,lie down.
After giving you 2
Injections also!
Your pulse is not becoming
normal
What is your worry after all?
You still have 1 years life.
In 1 year all the wishes of a man
can be fulfilled.
What's that? You tell me I'll
fulfill his wish.
I've only one wish.
To see the face of my great grand
son before,I die.
But Raj doesn't love his grandpa
but he loves his freedom.
Open your eyes kailash
Raj has come
where are you,Raj?
I am here,Grandpa
With a suit on,You're lying on
the hospital bed.
I had to lie in emergency-
And You had to act
also in emergemcy
Doctor uncle you also joined hands.
What could I do? Your grandpa made
me to do all this.
Grandpa,why are you doing
all these things?
You know how valuable you
are to me!
I'm valuable,isn't it?
Then fulfil my wish.
Tell me when'll you come to see
the girl? come on tell me!
Whenever you say.
Priya,it seems they've come.
Come come Mr. Malhotra.
Greetings Mr. Kapoor.
Mr. Kapoor,he's my
grandson Raj.
May you live long.
He is the same person who I had
met in Suman's marriage.
I understood the situation,when
I saw you both there.
That's why we've asked
for this alliance.
I've already liked
your daughter.
We wanted Raj to see
her today.
Come daughter,come.
Greetings
God bless you,sit down!
How do you like her!
Grandpa,don't you find
her age a little more.
What are you talking
I've
seen her horoscope.
Her age is perfect.
It seems grandpa has seen the
horoscpe without glasses.
Her cheeks are so fat
That is the symbol
of rich people.
See her beautiful smile
How beautiful!!
The girl next to her
looks better.
She is the mother
of a child.
This girl looks like the
mother of 4 children.
What are you talking? She doesn't
look like that at all.
Son if you wish to ask
her anyting then go ahead.
Yes,Yes,if you want
you ask her.
Me! I have studied upto
7th standard-
But she is a double
graduate.
She is an expert in
domestic chores-
All these savories & sweets are
prepared by her.
That means she doesn't
know anything.
She knows all these
what else do you want!
Why is he asking these
questions to me?
He is still looking at you
Be ready. He'll ask
one more question..
What are your hobbies?
These are all her hobbies.
she always praises others.
She herself is a gold medalist
in ''KABBADI''
IN KABBADI!
Now child I also want
to ask you something.
Tell me what's most important to
keep the family happy?
It is love
Let the number of members
be more or less
But if eveyone loves each other
then the household becomes heaven.
Very good. What noble
thoughts!
Why bother about her
noble thoughts?
Ask her noble thought
Why do you want to know the noble
thoughts of her sister-in-law?
Sister-in-law?'' - Yes
Don't cry child. Madam your
son was crying?
Come,Come,my son.
Congratulations Mr. Kapoor
Raj has liked the girl.
From our side the alliance
is confirmed.
Now you fix the marriage date
-Sure,have sweets
Doctor Uncle,There's no differnce
between love & photograph
How's it?
Both are developed in Darkness!
Shameless fellow!
Hey! look at Raj's photograph!
Who had taken it?
Look....Look at this!
Mother,I had taken this photo!
Raj was unaware,when I took
this photograph!
I feel you both have liked
Switzerland very much!
If that's true,why don't you & Raj
settle there for few years!
Absolutely no,they both are
not going anywhere!
Till now,I was worrying for son
after sending him abroad!
Now,even Daughter-in-law
no way!
When I sent you to Oxford
for Higher Studies!
You cried mad!
You too father!
Grandpa,You could've told me!
...I would've talked with foreign Minister
and opened a Oxford's Branch we!
You donkey! You were not even
born at that time!
This is our country's
ill fortune!
Okay!......one second!
I'll call you later,okay!
Whose phone was it,that you had
to move away from me!
Come on tell. what's
the matter?
You're correct!
First,I thought I'll hide
this from you!
..But these things never
remain secret!
If you come to know...
...That there's someone else to share
my love with you!
What will you do then?
I'll kill myself!
Raj,do you love anyone else?
I haven't done it,I think
I'll start now...
What?
Doctor had called!
Report's are positive!
Priya,You're pregnant!
What? Am I going to become
a Great Grandfather?
Long live happily! Long live...
God Bless you...god bless you....
What's it? Big boss
Take this and distribute it
among poor!
Okay sir!
Daughter-in-law,Asha
-yes father!
Congratulations!
You're going to become
a GrandMother!
And I am going to became
a Great grandfather!
Today I am very happy!
Oh! the god has fulfiled
my wish!
Longlive my child,Longlive!
What happened,father?
Ranjit,you're going to
get my position!
You're going to become a grandfather
and I,great grandfather!
...Congratulations!
Pappu,I am going to become
Grand Uncle!
I'll become Grand Pappu!
I'll become Grand Uncle!
Grandpa,congratulations!
For the first time I've seen so
much of happiness in this house!
..It's all because of you!
Kailash,congratulations!
Congrats!..congrats!
Today,I'll make your day! look
I've brought sweets for you!
I'll eat to my heart's content and
I'll make you also eat...
...No...Balraj..No...
From today it's no to sweets!
Now,I want to live longer!
Hereafter I don't have any
need for this!
...Now that my walking partner
is coming!
Hereafter I'll follow all your
instructions!
Hey! Chotu,look,after years
Big Boss is going for a walk!
..That too without a
walking stick!
All this is the Magic of
the daughter-in-law
Grandpa,when talks were on for
my marriage in this family!
I was scared!
-why?
I had once seen your photograph
in the Newspaper!
I thought,one who had such
menacing Monstache!
He'll definitely be strict and
will be like Hitler!
I've to be scared & put
the veil!
But after coming here,I came to
know that you're very Modern!
Now,I feel that you're not Raj
but my grandfather!
Madam,this time,we had a
great crop this reason!
Each branch bearing
100's of Mangoes!
Hey! were you plucking mangoes
or counting it?
Hey! Stop this fight and carry
on with your work!
This will go to Sharma's,keep
this in that basket!
And sister-in-law,this is
for kumar's!-Please give!
Put into that basket!
Madam,please take this!
Oh! My child,how many times I had
warned you not to lift heavy articles?
Take away those unripe mangoes!
Where did you go early
in the morning?
I went out for shopping!
What for?
For Maharana Pratap!
....I mean for the photo
of Maharana Pratap!
Why?
Because if a six months pregnant woman
whatever she watches more!
..The child will imbibe
those qualities!
If we keep this photograph
in Priya's bed room!
Then the coming child will also be
courageous like Maharana Pratap!
Have you gone mad?
If he becomes like RanaPratap!
...He'll be fighting with a sword
all his life in Jungles!
We must make the child a
great cricketer only
What will he do becoming
a circketer!
Unnecessarily he will get trapped
into match fixing!
Our child should become a
great leader!
...One who'll march this
nation towards progress!
So,In the bedroom of Priya...
What happened?....
Have you slept?
...I am thinking about which leader's
photograph should I hang there?
Can this humble man suggest
a thing?
Come on tell?
It can solve the problem of
all the three!
Keep some film Actor's
photograph in her room!
He can do,Leader's role cricketer's
Role,& even Rana Pratap's Role!
How good had it been
if you were quiet?
Leader's photograph-
Leader's photograph!
Why are you unnecessarly
fighting anmong yourselves?
Yes,my child,come on tell!
Why are you getting tensed
up for me?
I've already hanged the photograph
which I like the most!
what?
Oh!
Catch it!
Oh! I've broken my back!
What's this Bansi?
How can it be out,Grandpa!
this was a six!
Out means ...out!
What's this?
Mother,Grandfather's cheating!
My dear,It's our family Rule,one who
crosses beyond the bundary is out!
Now,give me the bat!
Oh! Tell me that,you want
to do the bating!
Yes...Yes...I want to bat!
You go and bat,I'll do
the umpiring!
Anyhow,you'll be out at the first ball
why are wearing a cap?
I've seen many who had
dared to bowl me out!
How fast you're bowling?
Before I could lift my bat the ball
whizzed part me,I am not out!
Hey! come on give him out!
No....No! it's out!
Hey! What are you saying?
It's definitely out!
What an umpire you are?
Father's certainly out!
Hey! You're not my friend!
you're a Traitor...Traitor!
What did we fix
earlier between us?
What could I do? when all of them
joined together,I had to give out!
What do you mean by saying
that you had to give out?
Fixing matches even in family!
I'll telephone and inform
sports minister! Right now!
Let it go my friend,
I'll not bat!
Now,its my chance to bat!
Okay....Okay...give me the ball!
Welcome...Welcome to bat!
Don't know to play cricket,still
wanting to keep Tendulkar's photo!
Watch,how I am going to
hit a six next ball?
Hit a six!?!
Daughter-in-law!
Not able to understand
anything!
It's already 2 hours,why doesn't
anyone tell me anything?
This Balraj also went inside,and
still hasn't come out!
What happened,uncle?
Everything's alright
isn't it?
She had miscarriage! The still born
died in the womb only!
,.....And priya!
-She is alright
.....Out of Danger!
God's great! Thanks!
...That our daughter-in-law
is safe!
Can me meet priya now?
It isn't good to disturb her
for 7-8 hours!
I feel,we all go home!
Since the accident no body's
peacefull!
You all go home I'll
stay here only.
No,Aunty! you go home,we
both will stay here!
Mother,I'll stay here!
But,son!
As soon as priya gets consious
I'll give you a call!
Come on.....Come.....come....Come!
A mother losing her child is
a great Disaster!
...doctors's calling you!
I'll come back soon!
Come Raj! come....Sit down!
Son!
In the accident priya's womb got
ruptured and became sceptic!
Because of which,priya can never
become a mother in future!
Even the Modern Technology can't
be of any help to her!
Son,you've to keep this as a secret
form your family!
If your Grandfahter comes to
know about this!
He already had two Heart attacks
He'll not be able to bear a third one!
But can I tell this to priya...
..That we'll keep away the
tears from us!
Shall we go?
Children have come!
I don't want any cries
& Cadoleaves!
Everyone will behave as if
nothing has happened?
Undersatood!?!
-Yes!
Go...Go back to your
normal work!
Welcome...Welcome my children!
What a long life my daughter-in-law
has been blessed with?
Think of her, & she's here!
Long live my child!
Watch out in a year owr house
will reverberate with a child's cries!
Be happy with family
and kids!
Enough!....No....
priya...no...
No...My child! please
don't cry!
Why this sorrow for a still born?
Cool on down!
Oh! My child miscarriage is
an ordinary matter!
My friend too had a miscarriage
But now she's mother to 4 kids!
What? In this time of family
plannings 4 children?
Pappu,register a complaint aganst
her friend with the police!
Why police,I can now call family planning
Minister and put her in jail
Hey! Her husband himself is
the family planning minister!
You can't touch him!
Call the Prime Minister!
Where will he be?
Why are you laughing? I can call
even Bill Clinton
What's happening here? why are you
talking own problems? busy with your
No body's concerned about daughter-in-law
she has just come out of Hosiptal!
Yes my child,go
and take rest!
Today,I'll prepare all your favourite
dishes! Come,sister-in-law!
Pappu,make a provisions list
-certainly!
Don't you want to
go to office?
Definitely!...come...come..
Daughter-in-law,you go to your
room and take rest!
Raj,take her!
What happened?
Did you see the eyes of
your family members?
There's an expectation
in every eye!
...That in the near future,I'll present
them with a heir to this family!
One day they'll definitely come
to know that...
We have deceived them! What will
happen at that time?
You don't worry about that
I've a plan...
Come on tell,how do you feel
if we adopt a child?
Look! Father always tells me to
go abroad to look after business!
If you agree,we'll go abroad
for a year or two!
We'll adopt a child there!
Okay?
And,I'll explain everything
to Doctor uncle!
We've been left with no choice!
Grandpa!
Come...my child...come!
My respects to you grandpa!
Bless you my child!
Come sit,my child!
Were you crying?
No!...these are tears of
happiness,my child!
While reading the newspaper
I fell asleep!
...And in that sleep I had a
very nice dream!
...That I've become
great grandfather!
A small child was playing
in my lap!
...And was laughing!
Exactly like Raj!
Similar eyes...similar smile!
As I bent my head to
fondle the child!
..that rogue caught
my monstache!
In that happiness tears
rolled out of my eyes!
Do you know my child,the morning
dreams will always come ture!
I'll give myself entirely to
my husnabd only!
Look will you give if I
ask you anything today?
Why do you ask?
Everything is yours!
If I wish to give it to some one
else which is mine!
Give it what's
the problem in it?
You marry again!
What?!!
Today,grandfather dreamt of a Raj
a replica of you! Playing in his lap!
He doesn't want anyone,he wants
your progeny only!
Now you only tell!
How can we play on their sentiments
by calling an adopted as your son!
I am at the disadvantage!
I can't become a mother!Raj
But you can become a
father,isn't it?
Agree to it. Raj.please!
The accident which you had,
If it had happened to me!
Would you've married again?
Look!
Raj. I want to meet
you immediately!
What's the matter?
I can't tell it on phone!
Do one thing come to lndia Gate
I'll also come there!
Alright,I'll come!
Read this news!
How lucky that woman would've been
who was like me,but now has a child!
The only differece is that the womb
was of a different woman!
You mean test tube Baby?!
No,our family is so famous that this
test tube matter will never be a a secret!
That's means you
want me to.....
Yes Raj,if we get a girl who
could give birth to our child!
Look,If I wanted to beget a child
from some other woman!
Why would I have refused
for the marriage?
Why would I have talked about
adopting a child?
Because,I love you so much!
..And I don't want to share
it with anyone
Raj! We'll get difficulties
freely!
For your child I am ready to share
your love with other woman also!
Priya,even if I accept,where would
we get such a woman?
If It's written in my fate
to become a mother!
We'll definitely find a woman!
The contract which you entered
with your  friend...
Will she help me?
..This is your Air Ticket
to Mumbai
What happened? You seem to
be very disturbed!
Nothing Ms.Bharucha! -
Please sit down! A small problem!
You tell me your problem,I'll
solve it,just like that!
Ms.Bharucha,this problem can't be
solved just like that
It'll take minimum 9 months!
What?
-yes!
One of my friend needs
a girl
Is it? Is he handsome
like you?
Yes he's handsome,Rich and ready
to give everything!
...A house, a car,everything! But,all he
needs is just a child!
First let them get marry,I'll have
a cricket team ready
Problem is that he's
already married!
...And he doesn't want
a second marriage!
What?
...A child wihtout marriage!
Any problem?
You've mistaken me!Am I
so cheap?
No...No...Ms. Bharucha
You've mistaken me!
I am not that sort of a guy I was just
discussing about my friends problem
that's all!
Let your friend and his
problem go to hell!
Understood ?
Till now our relationship was
restricted to freindship!
But from today,it has entered
even in our business!
I am very happy to announce that
all products of Raj's companies!
...Will be exclusievly marketed
in Europe by Mr. Ajay sharma!
The first product to be lauched
will be discussed with Raj
Will she help me?
Mr. Raj,I know about
your problem?
I am ready to help you!
You're very nice!
Priya will be very happy
to hear this!
Raj! Mrs. Kapoor is asking about your
opinion in the product!
Yes! sir,I was asking,which product
should be launched first?
Actually,I was thinking
something else!
Can we discuss it in
next meeting?
Where do you want to go?
Straight!
Take a left from here!
Please,Stop here!
Switch of the light in the vehicle
and start here itself!
Is your house here? I don't
find anything here!
Why do you need a house?
What?
It's an Ac car It'll be
most exciting
I generally take as Rs.1000
a night
But,If you wish,you can pay
Rs.100-200 less also!
You've mistaken me...Seeing you...
I just gave you a lift
I was escorting you to home!
You mean?
Mean......I mean....my problem
is something different!
I've freind who needs a girl
to stay with for a year!
I don't even know to
count
For a year?
Outwardly saint,but from
inside a Demon!?!
This story is not of your friend's
its yours,isn't it?
Yes!
Look sir,I've two children,no father
to look after them!
Then,I can't come!
But,there's a girl,who dances
at Deepa Bar!
Go & meet her! her name
is Madhubala!
your work will be done!I'll
phone and inform her!
...One second!
...Keep! this!
Didn't even touch me,
but still paying money?
This is not for you,but
for your children!
I'll pary to God,that whatever be
your wish,may it be fulfilled!
Hey! Hook that smart kid!
Hey! Hero,will you
come with me?
No...No...I'll not come!
-Hey! you stop!
Come on,give me
all the money
So much was thrown on you
where's rest of it?
Take it,this is your
commisiion!
What money?
Will you give it by yourself or
shall I take it out?
Hey! Don't touch me!
Come on take it out!
Take this!
Hey! Meena get away
from him!
...I'll go...I'll go...Any how
he is useless!
Case,PowderRani,don't know from
where all these people come?
Vijayanthi told me over phone
that you'll be coming here!
Come on tell,what
do you want?
Did she tell you anything?
Madhubala,are you coming
with me?
Hey! Prawn! get lost man!
Hey! Today you're acting
too smart!
Come on tell,Sir!
I can't talk here,can we go out
and talk some where else?
Okay! but it'll
cost you more!
Okay!
Let's go!
Come!
Sir,why did you bring
me here?
We'll go to chandni! There's
a Bounty for customers!
There,you'll get with room
towel, soap, Beer free of cost!
My room's here!
Come!
I think I've hit
a Jackpot!
You go to the lift,I'll
get the Keys!
Oh! why this sandle always
opens up?
Hey! Pigeon! Why
are you laughing?
Are they new ones? Fatso!
Shall we go?
Hey! Don't tip him?
Madam! is a very large
hearted woman!
Is it? He's very clever
tip him,Sir?
Take it!
Hey! Fatso,half of it
is mine!
..come...Come...please come sir.
Wow! What a spacious room?
I've heard that Hotels have
very large rooms!
But sir,this is very large!
You have a TV also?!
Is it your's sir?!
No,it's Hotel's!
Do yo want to watch it?
Sir,is it mobile phone?
No,its Remote control!
Oh! sir,I totally forgot!
There's no necessity for that!
why?
Are you not in mood?
No,I want to have a small talk
with you!
It'll cost you double!
Sir,I was just joking!
I'll take Rs.700-800!!
Sit down....Hey! come and sit!
How can I refuse you sir?
If I go out I'll take
more money!
But,you've brought me to
a nice place!
Behaved nicely with me!
You're handsome too!
I'll ruin you! I'll take Rs.1000 from you!
Okay,now tell me,how much you'll
take for a week!
Rs. 3000!
For a Month!
You have impressed
me a lot!
Okay, make it Rs. 15000
a month!
One year!
One year?! I'll cost
you dearly!
30,25,35...It'll be rupees onelakh
sir..one lakh!
How much is that?
Two lakhs!
T.W.O. L.A.K.H.S.!!!
I've never seen so much of
,money in my life!
Sir,I'll not do any
Wrongful jobs!
You're not going to make
any blue film,isn't it?
Don't worry!
I am a married man! And I
love my wife very much!
It's seen!
We have eveything!
...Except a heir!
I want a child from you!
Child? why? Is your wife
a barren woman?
I can't stop my laugh!
Then,why did you come
to me?
Because,I want a child
from you!
I am ready to pay any
amount for that!
Tell me,how much can
you pay!
Rs. 5 lakhs...10 Lakhs!...
10. L.A.K.H.S.!!!
-Hey! What Happened?
Are you alright?
-10.L.A.K.H.S.?!
10.lakhs...10 Lakhs!-What happened?
I was waiting for your
phone call only!
I'll give you just a child and
you'll pay me Rs.10 Lakhs!!
sir,you'll not cheat & leave me
on streets after making me pregnant?
l can pay you full
now itself!
No...no...I've confidence
in you!
A child of street girl like me
if you give it to your wife?-
...what will the society
talk about it?
The society will talk only if it
comes to know about it!
So! everything secretly!
Oh! My hard earned money!
It's wonderful,sir!
Till today I was earnig
for my stomach1
But now my stomach is going
to earn for me!
But,sir, remember
one thing!
I too have only one principle
in my life!
I'll nrver give anyone
a lip to lip kiss
I've found out the girl who's going
to give you the child!
How nice girl she would be
who has come to help us?
10 lakhs...10 lakhs....10 lakhs
She's innocent.
But priya..
I've understood! She's from a poor
family!That's all, isn't it?
She's.....
If she has good culture that's
more than enough for us!
10 lakhs.....My hard
earned money!
Listen,tomorrow,buy
yourself some good clothes!
Take this Rs. 50000!
Buy such clothes that
cover your body
Why? Don't you like
my figure?
It's very nice,but keep
it covered!
And inform your family that
you're with me for a year!
Okay! Go and sleep!
Then,come!....I am ready
since long time!
Oh! No! ...you sleep here!
I'll sleep there!
What?
You sleep here!
I'll sleep there!
No...no...I want my 10 lakhs
very quickly!
..You'll get it...You'll get it!
sleep!
Don't know,when will I get
my Rs. 10 lakhs?
Hey! What's the cost of
this dress?
These me not meant for you
- why?
Is the cloth of bad quality or
the colour will fade?
It's costly,you
can't buy them!
What are you speaking?
Look I've money!
Come on,get out!
Why should I go out,I've money
I've come to buy clothes!
I've told you once,isn't it
Please get out!
Telling me to get out!
you filthy man!
Do you think,am I beggar?
I can buy your entire shop!
understood?
Neither I want to sell my shop
nor any clothes to you!
Hey! Oldy! does decent people's
money have anything distinct?
Yes sir!
Don't touch me!
Do you consider me so cheap?
Hey! Oldy! I'll not spare you!
I'll not spare you!
You've such a large shop,but still
don't have even basic courtesy!
Idiot...fool!
Showing faces to me....
move!
Threw me out of the shop
can't even recongise Humans?
But can reconigse Dress?
What's it?
Where are you going
-upstairs!
Who are you to ask me?
Look Madam,I am the
general manager here!
Whom do you want to meet?
My boss is there!
-who?
The handsome one
with big eyes!
Yesterday night only he brought me here!
His room is also up there!
I don't know all that?
The room from which,the sea
is also seen.
Look Madam! there are many rooms
here from where sea is seen.
Hey! come with me,I'll
show you!-You can't go
Hey! Baldy! don't act smart!
If my boss comes to know!
Hey! Leave my hand..
leave my hand!
..Hey! fatso! come here,come here
you know me,isn't it?
Tell this white moon that
you know me!
Do you know her?
How can he Forget
he only took me up!
Sir, She was with
Raj Malhotra!
The thing is that,I wasn't
at duty last night!
...I made a small mistake!
...That you'll forgive this small mistake
That you'll not tell this to Mr.Raj!
Who's this Mr.Raj?
-With whom you've come here!
So,my handsome's name
is Raj Malhotra!
Now,are you also going to come with me?
-No..No
Come on move...What are you looking at?
-Yes...yes madam!
Where's my handsome?
The first product to be lauched
lnternationally will be.
MY friend....my business partner
Ajay sharma!
...Will be promoting it through
his American Companies!
Whatever technical details needed
I'll come there and give it!
According to market survey,our
products have good scopein Europe!
Come here!
The money which you gave me
that shop owner told me.
..He refused to sell the clothes
for girls like me!
You go to the room?
I'll came back!
No,I'll eat with you!
Go to the room and
order the food!
Idiot,you can eat with
these people!
Raj,Who's she?
-She's a friend!
She's a friend,but is she
a time pass?
She's a good girl!
She's a good girl! But she's
a street girl,isn't it?
Who's not a street smart man here?
Are you not a street smart man?
I too....
What was the necessity for
you to come down?
What was that urgent work for
you come and disturb the meeting?
If you're ashamed of me,why didn't
you warn me to come down?
You could've locked me up in
the bathroom?
That shop owner also called
me a cheap!
He refused to sell,saying that he'll
not sell to girls like me.
why are you staring at me? I don't
show my anger on food!
If you want
go and get it!
No,I don't want!
Which shop man?
The shop on the other side of the
street,that big shop
What did he say?
He misbehaved and called me cheap!
Now..even you too!
I had forgotten that you've come
from a different world!
I didn't come,you brought
me here!
Leave that and take this!
Keep this!
Come with me!
-where?
To the same shop to buy
the clothes!
I'll not come there!
What happened?
Only today someone has talked
with me so respectfully!
Come lets go!
She's with me!
-you?
You've come to our shop,
It's a great honour for us!
I haven't come here for shopping
she has come!
She has come with you..
Attend to this madam!
No,sir,you'll
attend to her!
..come...Madam..
please come!
Madam...please take this!
..No...NO..
Please have soft drinks madam
I've brought soft drinks for you!
Till then,you see these dresses!
I'll arrange for same shoes & sandals!
..Hey! Get them quickly!
...Let's try this!
Look at this do you
like this?
No?!
I had come here decided that...
...I'll buy your entire shop!
But,your shop doesn't have
anything like that!
Which will look beautiful
on her!
And you like anything?
Shall we go to some
other big shop?! come.
You're too hot! Have
this cold drunk!
Oldy,don't do anything
like this next time!
What are you doing?
This too!
This is small bottle!
This small bottle will make
a big hole in the liver!
Give it to me!
Look,madhu,my wife should
never know about your past!
Alright
-Okay!
Hey! what are you doing?Are you
going to make me skin head?
How am I going to repay
your gratitude?
Oh! come,leave it!
Only a woman can understand
the sorrow of a woman!
I was right isn't it?
Very nice but with a little love!
That's alright when will I
meet priya madam?
Tomorrow,we are going
to Switzerland!
I'll introduce you to her at
Delhi Airport!
Till then reherse it
25-30 times,okay!
With love?
Only a woman can underastand
a woman's sorrow.
Alright?
Brother Bansi! come quickly!
otherwise plane will fly away!
Long live my son!
Keep phoning and take good
care of yourself!
I've intimated Zunch office
They'll come to receive you!
If driver doen't come,telephone me
I'll get the pilot
Take this! As soon as you
get pregnant wear it!
It'll safe gaurd the child
-yes!
Long live,take care!
Don't worry'I'll take care
of everything here!
Okay I'll go!
Take care! give me a call!
Longlive my child! Take care!
-take good care of her!
Raj where is she?
I told her to meet me
here only!
Madhu,This is priya!
I am totally speechless!
The gratitude is such big that
I can't even say a thanks!
Only a woman can understand
a woman's sorrows!
Come Madhu
My cousin & his wife
are coming
She's Madhu,she was in the same
flight,she stays here only!
Oh I see!
I just phoned your Daddy
yesterday
He said that you people're
coming to Switzerland
Last time you came on Honemoon &
I didn't disturb you
But this time you'll have to
stay with us
This time also we'll have
to stay seperately
Because office is very close
to Banglow!
And there is plenty of work in
the office this time
Okay but.....
My son's head shaving
ceremony is there
And both of you will have to stay
with us for a week
Come,I'll drop you
No my car has come
Okay,I'll take you upto
your car..come
Madhu this is our house,we're
going to stay here
Wonderful,house between
the hills
I'm thrilled to
see the hills
Seeing the snow
I've melted
Mr.Teacher
You've taught all this?
I tried a bit
Doesn't matter,I'll teach
her the rest
Come Madhu
How did you like the house
-it is fantastic
This is my room
And this is yours
Madam
Madam,this coat has
got stuck
Okay,I'll take it out
Don't call me Madam,call
me Priya
Oh God! how can I utter
your name?
The way I utter your
name
There is no sir & Madam
here,okay
Oh God! you've such a big
swimming pool in your room
We can swim whenever
we want
If you like it then you stay here
I'll go to your room
I'll bring my things
Madhu liked this room,so I gave it
to her I'll stay in the guest room
That's right
We've already seen
this room
Let's see the guest room also
let's go
Not like this
The way I brought you
to this room
Same way I'll take you to
the guest room
This is my room,not yours
that's your room
I know it,but my wife
is here
You're mine,isn't it
Yes-then
Oh God! Fruits,Vegitable,Groceries
slippers all in 1 shop-yes!
Madhu you take whatever
you want,Okay-yes
Just now,they've announced that
heavy snow fall is likely
And all roads'll
be closed
Raj is coming to pick us
up shortly
You do one thing
You understood what you've
to do,isn't it?
You bought things for the
whole year,Oh!
Where is Priya,still
shopping?
No,she went away home
What! doesn't she know there is going
to be snow storm here
She knows
She had to buy certain things from
near the house
That's why she went away,by now
she must've reached home
Keep the trolly,come
I'll do it!
From there,that side
Madhu phone is ringing
Yes Priya
Where are you?
In the church
Stay there I am coming to
pick you up
How can you come? all roads are
closed because of snow fall
But you don't worry about me
I've many people here with me
As soon as the roads are clear
I'll come
You've closed the paths
Take it that way
But if you two are
not alone
How'll we get rid of
our lonliness
I am sorry,I had mixed a little
Vodka in coca cola
It is very cold outside
that's why....
I love my wife
immensely
You've become mother
She has become mother
Ten lakhs-ten lakhs!
Congratulations Raj
Bless daughter-in-law on
my behalf
Listen you take the 1st
flight & come here
No no grandpa,that is
not possible
Because according to doctor,Priya is not
allowed to take a long flight
Alright don't come!
Don't bring the
daughter-in-law at all
But look after daughter-in-law
over there
What's happining grandpa?
Here talk to your mother
Son Raj-yes mother!
Raj,congratulations may God
give my life also to you
Give phone to daughter-in-law
I won't give,one second!
Wish you a long happy life
don't lift heavy things
Yes yes
And the Charan that I had given you
tie it on the wrist
Tie it on your hand
And take care of
daughter-in-law
Congratulations,kept
the phone down
What's this? It has
sacred flowers in it
Mother-in-law has given me for
the protection of the child
Always keep it on your hand
It'll protect the child
See it's months,there is no
bulge on the stomach
It won't come in 3 months only
after 5 months it'll show
When I was expecting last time
I was also worried like you
Mother-in-law had told me
Mother-in-law! she's a
dangerous creature!
No,my mother-in-law
is not like that
She is very nice,she loves
me a lot
And grandpa of Raj...
He doesn't consider me as daughter-in-law
I am the grand daughter to him
Who else is there
in your family?
Grandpa's friend,
Doctor Uncle!
Uncle,Auntie &
one Pappu brother
He has very high contacts
If any phone goes out of
order in the house
He won't phone the mechanic
He'll phone the telecome
minister directly!
And his winking habit puts every
new person in a quandry
Your inlaws place would be very
interesting,isn't it?
Day must be passing off
very quickly
It was like that earlier,but
since that happened with me
But those days'll
return again
Congratulations Raj!
Our company has crossed the sales
of 10 millions
It's nothing,It'll cross more than
10 millions,100 millions
Hello sister-in-law,how
are you?
I am fine
She's my friend,Madhu
And he is Ajay,friend of Raj
and a businessman
Come Madhu
Yes Madhu,you are our VIP
Hey son,come here!
Raj,Vicky brother
has come
Brother,sister-in-law
hasn't come
Day after tomorrow,my son's head
shaving ceremony is there,isn't it?
That's why she is busy there
but I've come,isn't it?
And I've come to remind
you people
That both of you must come for the
ceremony day after tomorrow
I was thinking for a long time
as to where I had seen you
Wonderful
What a great change
has come over
After seeing you nobody can say
that you're a prostitute
Who told you?
There is no secret
between me & Raj
I also appreciate good things
If the commodity is good
I don't bother about money
As soon as you're free
from Raj,come over!
What ever Raj is paying you
I'll give you double than that
Why did you come away
from the party?
I don't want to stay here
I'm going back
What happened? did any one
say something?
All rich people like you
are alike
You play so many games
for your selfish ends
First you gave me so much respect
elevated me to the sky
And with one jerk you pulled me
back to earth
You wanted only a child
isn't it?
That I would have produced on
the road also
What was the need to mature me
for your society
When you had to tell your friends
that I'm a prostitute
I never felt so cheap,when I was
in the proffession
The way I am feeling
today
Did Ajay say anything
to you?
Madhu,I haven't said anything
to anybody
Ay Madhu,where are
you going?
I am going back,he told
his friend that I....
That I am pregnant
Ican't dance
Madhu Raj & I are your friends
your well wishers
We'll never say anything
that'll hurt you
You want to dance,come..
I don't want to dance
A person who thinks someone
as his own
He get's hurt by trifles
Priya,I didn't tell you one thing
about Madhu
I know,I have heard
everything
You did the right thing by
not telling me this earlier
May be after knowing the truth
I might not have accepted Madhu
But today,I can say
To give birth to our child
There couldn't have been a
better girl than Madhu
Isn't it?
How is Madhu?
I'm just coming from her room
she's still angry
If we both go for the head shaving
ceremoney without her
Then she'll feel very bad
Then we'll also not go
No..No..Vicky brother will be offended
We'll do onething,I'll go for the
function,you stay here
I'll give the excuse that you couldn't
come because of business compulsions
Okay,pack your things,I'll drop
you at the station,come
Drink this juice
Cigarette is healthy to your
and child's health
Madhu I know you're upset
But,when you came to
the Bombay confrence
The way you had dressed up
the way you had behaved that...
Ajay was also present there
When I didn't tell this to
my wife Priya
Then why would I tell
it to Ajay?
Even then if you feel I've
made a mistake
Smoke the cigarette
You were bathing?
Raj is not at home,he has
gone to the office
Yes I know Raj has gone
to the office
And,he'll come back late
And Priya is also not at home
she has gone to her cousin
That's why I've come!
From the time,I saw you at
the party
I couldn't control myself
That's why I came here at the
very 1st opportunity
I've enjoyed with
every type of Girl
But,the attraction that you have
nobody else has it
You please go away
from here
Yes,I have understood
You're in contract with Raj that's
why you're in tension
There is no problem between
me and him
He is not only my business partner
but my childhood friend also
He'll have no objection
You cheap prostitute
you slapped me!
Come on,get up...get up
over here..
You're pretending to be
very decent,isn't it?
I'll smash your decency
Raj I had thought,that....
What did you think?
That,you'll rape her?
you'll rape her?
Raj,what are you doing you'll rape
her?listen to me
Raj listen to me
You'll rape her
Raj,listen to me
Raj,what are you doing for a cheap
prostitute you're beating me
Does she look a cheap
prostitute to you?
I don't find her that way
How did she look like
that to you....?
Raj for such a girl you're beating
your childhood friend
Childhood friend!
Even if you were my brother
I would have killed you
Raj for her you're endangering
partnership worth 500 crores
Why 500 crores for her
For her,I'll forsake the entire
wealth of the world
Do you know,why? because she
is priceless for me
You're my friend,isn't it? that's
why you leave from here
Otherwise I'll kill
you,understod
Go..go..
I'll bring medicines
If you need anything
call me
Madhu,take this
What were you thinking?
I was remembering my
childhood
When I was a kid
My mother always used to
tell me a story
That,there was a poor girl
Oneday a prince came to her
on a white horse
And took away his bride
And then,all her dreams
came true
Even I used to see this same
dream all the time
When I grew
Instead of white horses many
white cars came
Many princess got down
from them
But nobody came to
take me with him
All came to purchase me
Then I realized
That it was a fairy tale for
children in their childhood
It doesn't happen like that
in reality
Raj & Priya will be shocked
to see us
Ay Chotu,take down the
luggage quickly
How can I take
down so much?
Come with me
Priya,grandpa has come with
the entire family
What?
Is that your family?
Priya,it'll be a catastrophy,they think
that you're pregnant
One second
No no,it'll be too big!
This....
Yes,this is alright
Wear this charma also
But there are sacred
flowers in it...
Yes yes,I know,give her the flowers
and you wear the charm
Yes
Daughter-in-law,we have
come
Where are you,you'll be
overwhelmed
Oh Grandpa,Mother
Grandpa
May you live long
Mother....
-we surprised you,isn't it?
God bless you,my son
You came without
informing
We couldn't wait to see Priya,so
we have come-where is Priya?
She is tying the pillow
Tying the pillow!
Tying the pillow! what did
you all hear?
What did you say?
She is changing her dress
Come my child,come....
My child....
Blessings mother
God bless you,you have given us the
entire happiness of the world
No..no child don't bend
down,God bless you
Let me stop the evil eye
falling on you
Oh! Grandpa...
How are you my child?
I am fine
How are you,Pappu brother
Hai! Uncle
How are you Priya child?
Didn't I tell you that you'll
be pregnant within a year,isn't it?
What mother,why did you all
give us such a surprise?
What happened?
what happened?
She is the wife of my
friend,Madhu
Her husband generally stays away
for business
There is no one else in the house
that's why she stays with us
I see....
You did the correct
thing my child
At this time you shouldn't
live alone
Come...come here
Blessings....
Always be happy
I'm Priya's mother-in-law
I know
Priya daily tells me
about you all
You are auntie,you are uncle
and you are Pappu brother
And you're grandpa
Blessings
Don't bend down
blessings
And you are the father
Grandpa won't you take away
the evil eye frome me?
Why not,may you live long
and married
It's not surprising why our
dark hero Mithun stays in Ooty
So that,he looks fair among
the people who stay there
Grandfather....Biscuts
Madhu my child,what is
your Husband's business?
He!....
He is into Import & Export
Yes grandpa,that's why he is sometimes
in UK,Austrlia!....
He's always out of station
I see...
Whatever it may be business
will anyways go on
But in such times,a husband should
necessarily be with his wife
Daughter-in-law,no problem
Like the way,we'll take
care of our Priya
In the same way,we'll
take care of her too
After listening to this God Vishnu
started crying after becoming a child
And after seeing that beautiful
face of him
Tears of affection & happiness rolled
out from mother Kausalia's eyes
They say,if the description of
God Rama's birth
Is heard by a pregnant woman
Even her child likes it
You just feel and watch
There definitely would be some
movement going on inside
Madhu child,why are you
standing there,come here & sit
Come....come...sit
Listen,at the time of
God Rama's birth
The condition of
his father Dashrath
Because,the amount of happiness which
the mother undergoes in delivering it's child
The father feels
twice of her
Child,what are
you thinking?
That your husband is not
with you,isn't it?
He definitely would be
helpless about this
But he always would be thinking
about you & your child
Poet Tulsidas said....
Priya,my child
-yes mother
Child,this is that
spicy sweet
Do you remember?
I have brought it for you
from Delhi
Madhu come...
Mother has brought for me spicy
sweets from Delhi
You'll really be benefitted
if you eat it..eat.....
It's spicy,isn't it?
Last year,when I was expecting even
I found them very spicy
That's why mother forcibilly made
me eat,making me sit infront of her
Will you have one more?
Mother is coming,don't say
that I had it
Yes mother
Oh! you are here,I was searching
you in your room
I was sitting with
Grandpa
What's the matter,you
are crying?
No...I was watching a melodramatic
film,that's why
Come with me
Sit down,carefully....
Madhu child,these are
spicy sweets
After eating it,both the mother & the
child are benefitted a lot
Come on eat it....
Mother,no I'll eat it later
No....not later,you'll have to eat it
before me,otherwise,you'll not
No...mother.-I know it's a little
spicy that's why
Come on,open your mouth
open...good-No...
Madhu,there's a lot of
swelling on your feet
I had told the Doctor about it
but he said,it's quite normal
It definitely happens,but a
lot of swelling is not good
I'll apply oil on your feet
made of 7 herbs
It reduces the swelling
Yes madam
Bring that oil made
of 7 herbs
I'll get it
Keep it
Show me my child
No..No mother,I'll not like
you touching my feet
But,I'll like it
Once,that I have adressed
you as my daughter
I also mean it
from my heart
You are my daughter
isn't it?
Who all are there in
your family?
Mother,I have no one
There must be someone in
India,isn't it?
I have no one
in the world
Hereafter,don't ever say,that
I have no one in the world
From now,this entire
family is yours
Greetings Mr.Priest
how are you?
Yes one minute
Grandpa...it's Mr.Priest's
phone from Delhi
What's the number of
the facility Minister over here?
Yes Mr.Priest...greetings
Whose phone is this?
What was he saying?-I don't know
Alright we'll do exactly
as you say
You make the arrangements
yes.. okay...
Grandpa, what
arragements?
Raj, Mr.priest has chosen 18th as the
date for priya's lap filling ceremony.
Congratulations.
We''ll go to Delhi tomorrow itself,
okay
Raj, how can we go
back to India?
Even Madhu has to be with us,
isn't it
Because,18th has been fixed as
priya's lap filling ceremony
You go along with Raj to the
office, call for a board meeting
And make everyone understand
-yes father
Grandpa,is it not possible,if
you call Mr.priest here itself?
And acomplish the ceremony
here itself.
Why?
Because, Priya's delivery date
is also of this month
And ...,the medical facilities
over here are also very good
What are you talking
about facilities?
I'll make one phone and get
all the facilities transferred to Delhi
There is no facility of a
minister itself over here
I see..., Bihar is a
better place than this
Raj my son. We''ll get all the
madecal facilities in Delhi
And such a ceremony is done
at that place
Where there are friends,
relatives etc.
Mother, you are right.
We''ll all go to lndia.
Madhu, I had promised
your husband.
That I'll take
care of you.
But,we are all going to India
for the lap filling ceremony
Because, your's of Priya's delivery
date,fall on the same day.
And I can never go
against Grandpa.
But, I'll do all your hospital
bookings etc
And whenever you get the
labour pain.you yourself go.
Have you gone out of
your brains?
How will this poor go alone to the
hospital in such a condition?
Grandpa, she does'nt have
any other alternative also,isn't it?
Who is with her,and she also can't
come to India with us.
Why can't she come?
You had promised her husband
isn't it
Yes, I had
Everybody listen,this is
my decision,
That, Madhu will come
to Delhi along with us
Greetings...
He is my father, and they
are my brother & sister-in-law
What have they brought?
An auspicious offering
In the lap filling ceremony,
the pregnant woman.
Wears clothes brought only from
her parent's house
Great..., Is this such
a big ceremony?
Blessings...
Come... come...
Greetings... come
Pappu,Just listen, Mr.Priest
is asking for rice
Please make the
arrangement
should I call the
food minister
Tell me,how many bags
you want?
Oh god,for a handful of rice,
will you call up the minister
Handful..
Bring it from the kitchen
Allright
Have you seen Bhati uncle
somewhere?
I haven't,but,what's
the matter?
Are you immitating me?
Did your mother ever come & go
at fathehpur's red bungalow?
Fathepur's Red bungalow, No,
my mother never went
My father freequently
visited there
Father always used to say
that son,you have one sister
Father...
Priya, your auspicious dress has come,
now soon get ready
Mother, you go down, I'll
make Priya get ready
No Daughter, you can't
come down
Look,I wanted both of yours
ceremonies to be performed together
But Mr.Priest said,that two
pregnant women together
Can't participate in
this function
Allright mother
And Priya my child,today get ready
exactly like a bride,fully decked up.
Allright
This ceremony is a very important
event in any woman's life
Because a woman does'nt have
one birth,but she has 3 births
The first when she becomes someone's
daughter & comes into this world
The second,When she becomes
someone's wife.
And the third,when she
becomes a mother
And why this ceremony is performed bofore
a woman becomes mother is because
That the forthcoming child gets
so many blessings & prayers
that its birth is not
with pains
But its with
happiness
Now, soon get ready & come down
the time for the ritual is nearing.
Allright
Raj,you here,now don't
involve priya in your talks-
She has to get ready & come down
allright
Raj,I can't come in this
function
Why?
Mother said, that this is
not any ordinary ritual-
All these prayers etc are for the
well-being of our child
Madhu should sit in this
ritual instead of me
But,how is this possible?
If madhu wears my
Bridal dress-
The veil would be there
isn't it?
And nobody will come to know
that she is Madhu
Madhu,will you wear the
auspicious dress?
Allright
Sister-in-law,just see if priya
has got ready or not?
Bring her at once
Allright sister
Aunty,I'll go & see
-mother,I'll go
Saw,allright,you
itself get her
Who's it?
It's me
Has madhu got ready?
Yes
Girls...
The auspicious thread...
I forgot
Listen.. I'll make her wear
you go
Alright,I'll go that side
make it fast...
The one who is going to furnish
my clan with a heir,I salute you
May God let your child
live forever
And the way, how sun shines
the entire world-
In the same way,your child
should shine my entire generation
May god, my age should add
to your child
And he brings so much
happiness in your life
That no happiness of the world
can match against it
Priya,Great,the color of heena has
blended so thick on your hands-
This means,Raj loves
you a lot
We have to take a family
photograph,come everyone come
Yes, take the photograph
Mr.priest, you start
the prayers
Allright
What is the name of the
child's great grand father?
May this great grandchild receive
all the happiness of the world
What is the child's
grandfather's name?
May this child receive
all the fame
What is the child's
grandmother's name?
May god bless this child
What is the child's
father's name?
May god make this
child live forever
Mother...
Today's function was great
isn't it?
Excellent, what was
the best among it?
Great grandfather's Dance,
what do you say?
What stromy winds are blowing
I'll get these windows closed
Look,it's too late,
you go and sleep
God bless you
Did you see Madhu
anywhere?
What?
Madhu,where are you going?
This child's mother is not
Priya Malothra,its me
This is my child,I'll not give my child
forgive me,I can't give this child
Madhu, don't say like this
For the last 9 months I have
undergone penance for its birth
Everyday I have weaved one new
dream for this child
At this time, not
only me or Raj-
But our entire family is counting
days for the childs birth
Madhu,all our happiness
is linked with it
I'll kill myself,but I'll
not part with my child
Madhu, you don't lack anything
unlike me,you can get married
You can again experience
motherhood
But I... I am incomplete,
I can never become a mother
Madhu,I beg of you,please
give me this child
In return of it,I'll give you
what ever you want
Allright,I am prepared to
give you my child
Can you give me
your husband?
After all,you showed your
true colour
I thought even a prostitute
was a woman
But you've proved that a prostitute
can never do good to anyone
She can only destroy
houses
I asked you your
husband from you
You made me remember
my status
You are asking form
a mother,her progeny
Mother,whether she is
a prositute
Or a daughter-in-law
of a house
Mother is only a mother
I'll not... I'll not give
you my child, I'll not...
Raj,she is refusing to
give us our child
Priya,but first look
at her condition
Immediately call up
doctor uncle
Everthing wil get allright
Madhu's scanning is
in progress
In a very short while,we'll
come to know the complications
It's mother's phone..
Yes mother
You,priya,Madhu all the
three of you are not in house?
Where are you all?
Mother,we're all
at the hospital
Madhu and priya had
developed labour pains-
So,I've brought them here
We all are reaching
the hospital
No mother no,you come at ease
okay,doctor uncle is with us
Oh god! I am
just coming.
Doctor has called you in.
The child in the stomach
has turned around-
That's why the child is not
at it s normal position.
All right,go ahead.
But,the condition
is serious.
I can either save the mother
or child in this operation
We'll have to take the decision
at the earliest
Doctor,you save
the mother.
Make arrangements to take
her to the operation theatre.
Nurse,take Raj's signature
-okay
Take her in,
careful....
This happens very rare,the
operation was sucessful.
Both Madhu and
child are safe.
Congratulations,its
a boy baby.
How sweet child it is.
You wanted to save the mother
Isn't it.
Even the mother
got saved.
And your child too.
I got carried away for a while
and became selfish.
You are this
child's mother.
He is only yours.
Give me my Grandson...
Look....Look I am your
Great Grandfather.
Oh yes,what about our madhu
a boy baby or a girl baby?
That poor girl's child
at its birth....
No child,don't get
disheartened.
Think that it was
not yours.
The same thing happened
even with our priya-
But did you see,in 1 year's time
god blessed her with another child.
Yes daughter
Madhu,don't go I'll disclose
the truth to my family members.
When two Brother's can stay
together,under one roof.
Then why can't two
sister's stay?
I have got my complete
family here.
I only lacked
a sister.
Today,I even
got that
Let this sister remain
as sister.
Don't make her
a co-wife.
Otherwise,no woman would ever
have belief on another woman.
Only you have rights on
this family,and on Raj.
My rights are only on those
remembrabces,which I got here.
What more do
I want?
Madhu,you have been checked-in
This is your boarding pass.
Your bags have been sent
into the luggage.
In this,there are keys
of your new house-
And some blank cheques
on your name.
The deed which you have done
for me and for priya.
For that,even if I give you
my entire wealth-
Even then,its less.
Just consider this to be a
small gift from me & priya.
I have taken my gift,
look at this-
I am taking my entire
family along with me
Other than this,If I take
anything else,it'll look as though-
A mother has taken a price
for her child.
But Madhu,you....
I'll not return back to that world
from where you had brought me.
You had touched me once,here after
no one else can touch me!