Namwon town of Honam Province
Was known as Dae-bang
region long ago.
On the east is Chiri Mountain.
On the west is Chuksung River.
Water flowed southwards
with high mountains above.
Full of spiritual energy,
Namwon bred many pretty people.
With endless graves of loyal
officials,
can unswerving loyalty
not exist?
In King Sukjong's early reign,
there lived the only son
of a local governor.
He was 15 years old.
Since he was handsome and righteous,
he was a great man.
On one fine day,
he called his servant Pangja...
Hey Pangja!
Yes master.
I've been here several months,
but I've yet to go sightseeing.
Do you know of any good places?
Why does a diligent student
like you need to know?
You're foolish.
All the greatest scholars
have visited famous sights.
So tell me now.
As you wish Master Lee.
Out the north gate, Kyoryong
Fortress is a good place.
Out the west is Sonwon Temple,
and to the east is Kwan Mausoleum.
To the south is Kwangharu Arbor,
Ojak Bridge and Yongju Pavilion.
They say they're the best places
to visit in the south provinces.
From what you said,
Kwangharu seems the best.
Go get the horse ready.
But your father forbids this,
and we'll get into trouble.
I'll just get permission.
Go mount the saddle!
He mounted the horse,
and Pangja leads the way.
a fan shaped like a
crane's yellow wing,
he flips it open and blocks the sun.
As he travels down the South Road,
the breezy dust from each trot,
flutters in the air
with the scent of peach flowers...
The governor's son is out.
"I traveled from afar
to see Kwangharu's beauty."
Juksung Mountain in the morning
is still covered by late fog.
The river water reflects
green willows and flowering trees.
The spring wind blows gently.
The beautiful columns
soar high into the sky.
The purplish-red tower
embraces the sunlight
and shines radiantly.
In old Wang Bal's poem,
the palace where immortals lived
must be Kwangharu.
Kwangharu is beautiful,
but Ojak Bridge is better.
If it is really Ojak bridge,
then the legend of
Gyunwoo and his love Jiknya
I'll be the Gyunwoo star
on Ojak bridge,
but who shall be my Jiknya?
- Pangja.
- Yes, master.
Today, we'll drink as friends
not as master and servant.
Who is the oldest of you two?
Master, he's a few years older.
Then you have a drink first.
Take this drink.
Today's your day.
such a beautifully written poem.
"I didn't recognize spring's arrival."
"But everywhere, peach
flowers blossomed already."
"A pair of butterflies
left the peach flower,
but they returned missing it."
White and red flowers.
White and red flowers
from the flowery forest,
an angelic girl appears.
Like the sun or moon,
this beautiful girl appears.
She arrives together
with a girl about her age.
The long twisted ropes,
she grabs them
with her delicate hands.
She leans once,
and swings up.
She leans again,
and swings back.
If she flies higher,
she'll meet the Sowangmo angel.
If she flies lower,
she'll meet
the ancient Yoji empress.
She is a girl,
but also an angel.
One moment she's far away,
the next she's very close.
Her swings are in and out
like a swallow's springs
Her lovely motions
put Mongryong in a spell.
Hey, Pangja.
Yes...Yes, master.
Look over there.
Where?
Where my fan is pointed idiot.
Oh, the wrestling match we passed by.
Look carefully.
Can't you see that girl
swinging in the forest?
Looks like a fair maiden
on a swing. Let's go inside...
You think a fair maiden
would be out here on a swing?
You fool.
You should even recognize a
passing dog in your hometown.
Oh, her name's Chunhyang.
She's an old courtesan's daughter.
Looks like her maid
Hyangdan is with her too.
A courtesan's daughter...
This is good.
- Pangja.
- Yes, master.
Go and bring her here.
Please, I can't...
Pangja!
She won't come.
Even though her mother's a courtesan,
Chunhyang is arrogant,
Well read, and writes poems.
She's like a noble's daughter.
She's a courtesan's daughter.
So can't I ask to see her face?
- Bring her to me now.
- Oh master...
Many officials, penniless rakes,
and even nobles of Namwon
tried endlessly to seduce
her, but they all failed.
That's nonsense.
The world's precious beauties,
are destined to have an owner.
So go and get her.
Pangja obeys and runs for Chunhyang.
A fast, chic, and charming Pangja.
Yet a flippant, fluttery,
and sly Pangja.
Like a blue bird delivering
a letter to Sowangmo,
a clever and quite cunning Pangja.
He wears an ox felt hat with silk straps,
a fake jacket and linen pants.
With a stick for a pipe,
and the front end of his
garment tied to his back,
he takes one step,
and takes another.
Step, step, step, step away.
He breaks a branch,
and plays around
with his staff.
He picks up a stone,
and throws it at a willow tree
to scare the birds away.
After his childish play,
he runs to the forest swing
and yells as loud as he can...
...Chunhyang!
Oh gosh! You fool!
My lady almost had
a baby on the swing!
What?!? A baby?
Can you believe it?
A virgin gave birth!
I meant she almost fell,
you idiot.
Chunhyang, there's a big problem.
What is it?
The governor's son came
to visit Kwangharu.
He saw you on the swing,
and wants to meet you.
So let's go.
How come the governor's son
is interested to meet me?
Chunhyang is this...,
Chunhyang is that...
Pangja, you must've
squealed everything about me.
Chunhyang.
If you're a fair lady,
then you should've swung
in your front or backyard.
Tie a rope to your tree,
and make your own swing.
But in this open field,
you flaunt your bare ankles,
tease us with your raised dress,
pretty smile, and giddy laugh,
no wonder he fell for you.
Let's go!
I may be a lowly person,
but I'm not a courtesan.
As a fair lady, you can't
just drag me to any man.
So go alone.
Chunhyang, wait!
Do you want to get into
serious trouble?
The governor will torture you
for being rude to his son.
Is that what you want?
Then tell him this.
"The wild geese desire the sea,
the crabs desire their holes,
and a butterfly desires a flower."
You idiot!
I didn't tell you to chase her away.
I didn't do such a thing.
She cursed me in words
I didn't understand.
And told me
to repeat them to you.
What words?
She said, "the wild geese
desires flowers..."
...or was it the other way.
Really?
They're not insults,
but a proverb with deep meaning.
Like the wild geese desire the sea,
the crabs their holes,
and a butterfly's flower,
she wants me to come
to her.
Let's go.
Now?
My father granted half a day,
so we've got to go back.
Studying in nature
is one of the scholar's ways,
but you're forgetting
to balance your body and mind.
Don't forget to follow the 'six
exercises of a scholar,'
such as archery and horseback riding.
Don't forget to do these things.
If you get sleepy reading
old classics,
read this book to stay awake.
Young Lee sits at his
desk under Chunhyang's spell.
He sees the six officials and
Pangja, and it's Chunhyang.
His mother, and it's Chunhyang.
And his father, it's Chunhyang.
Shapes of the 'Gwon'...
the shape of a sphere, a cube,
Chunhyang's shape,
my shape, the shape of lovers...
they sleep together,
and make a baby's shape.
Master Lee,
what kind of book is that?
- 'The Book of Changes'.
- No, it's the 'Book of Lovers'.
Is there anything about my shape too?
No. There's nothing
about lowly servants.
Bring me the
"Book of 1000 Characters."
Why read a beginner's
book to study for your test?
Because each character
has profound meaning.
The sky was created on the first hour.
Before four seasons existed,
in the empty space lies the 'sky.'
The earth was created
on the second hour.
Since it's composed
of minerals, wood, water, and fire
everything is born and raised
by the 'earth'.
The profound and delicate color
of the North God is 'black'.
The color symbolizing the first
of the five musical scales,
and the center
of four sides is 'yellow'.
We can see thousands of miles away
on the large and high 'pavilion'.
Through the past and the present
is the infinite and endless 'space'.
Go see how far the sun has fallen.
It hasn't set yet, master.
Why is it moving so slowly today?
It seemed to run so fast yesterday,
but today it must have a boil in its foot.
The guard shouts...
Close the gates!
Young Lee is ecstatic and says...
Let's go to Chunhyang's house.
Pangja leads the way.
On the way to Chunhyang's home,
a wide, dusty road leads into a trail,
while the moonlight seeps
through the clouds.
And with the green willows
between the flowering trees,
the night is so lovely.
When they arrive at
Chunhyang's home,
on the left are green pine trees,
on the right are green bamboo trees.
The wavy pine trees stand calm.
What shall we do now, master?
Call her.
Sir, I think it would be better
if you call her yourself.
Just do as I said. Call her now.
Chunhyang! Are you awake?
My master is here
so come out this instant!
Is this some prank?
It's me Pangja.
What are you doing here?
I've brought the governor's son.
What?!?
The governor's son? You fool!
You should've told me
earlier he was coming.
Look at you.
You're better off worrying
about your underpants instead.
Oh gosh!
Hyangdan!
Go open the gate for them.
Master Lee, it's an honor to
have you at our humble home.
Please do come in.
'Lotus Pavilion...'
The writing is refined and graceful.
Who wrote this?
It's a girl's clumsy writing.
Although a lotus blossoms from clay,
it's clean and enchanting,
and its scent travels for miles.
The farther a lotus scent
travels, the fresher and purer.
Your scent fills my room,
and intoxicates me.
Instead of the lotus, you're
the best flower, Chunhyang.
A painting of the famous Minister Kang.
Did you draw this too?
You're making me blush, Master Lee.
While fishing with no bait,
he waits forever to meet King Moon,
and later fulfills his dream.
While avoiding a disrupt world
and becoming a hermit,
it's an ambitious life
that understands patience.
Your wish to meet a good husband
is shown in the painting.
Did you come here thinking
I was an easy courtesan?
You're a talented writer,
and so am I.
Don't you think its fate
that brought us here together?
Hyangdan...
He's fallen for Chunhyang
so you have to serve him well.
If things go well, all of
Namwon might be Chunhyang's.
Wolmae...
Part of the reason why I
brought him here is for me.
So put in a good word for me.
Come on Wolmae.
It's time for me move up,
so I can brag about myself.
You're out of your mind.
- Don't steal my part of the gold.
- Wolmae...
Wolmae?
Just shut up,
and pull out the chicken hairs.
Master Lee, this is my mother.
It's my honor to meet you.
Good evening.
If I knew you were coming,
I would've greeted you formally.
What brings a noble young man
to our house this evening?
Please come in and sit comfortably.
Thank you.
A few days ago,
I saw Chunhyang at Kwangharu,
and I instantly adored her like
a butterfly desiring a flower.
How would you feel if I took
Chunhyang's hand as my wife?
You're the son of a noble,
but Chunhyang is of a low class.
If the butterfly just came to
pick the flower and leave,
our world would be miserable.
So please stay and just
have a drink with us.
I know this is informal,
but I think this is fate also.
I'll be a good husband,
so give me your permission.
When her father was
the governor of Namwon,
he picked me as his
courtesan for one night,
and so she was conceived.
He promised to take us to Seoul,
but he passed away suddenly.
So I raised her all by myself.
And I did it with the utmost care.
Since you're so insistent,
I could give you my approval,
but it's not my decision.
Chunhyang, what do you think?
Since Master Lee is so intent,
does a lowly girl have a choice?
But...
Since the future is unforeseeable,
please vow...
...your eternal love for me.
"Like the sun and the moon,
my love will never change."
...Mongryong Lee
Chunhyang, my child.
Every woman does it.
Don't be scared and do what he says.
Also...
Lay this on the floor.
He has to know you are a virgin.
So don't forget to show
it to him.
Chunhyang, come here.
The night is late.
Let's sleep.
I don't want to.
Listen to me and come here.
They say for a married couple
ever-lasting happiness
depends on the first night.
But if you grab the wife's hand,
they say it's bad luck.
The moon is bright.
Oh yes, it is bright.
The moon is brighter than ever.
My wretched moon is bright.
The reflection from
Chunhyang's room is bright.
When I was young,
I was known as
"Bright Moon" of Namwon,
but I am bright no more
as my face grew old.
As one day, two days,
and several days pass,
the young lovers'
shyness disappears,
and they grow fondly intimate.
One day,
as they hug and roll around,
they enjoy the 'Love Song.'
Come here,
ride my back and we'll play.
Love, love, love, my love.
What a love, my beloved.
Yes...my love.
Oh...my love.
What would you like to eat?
A poked round watermelon
poured with sweet white honey.
Take the seeds out and taste
a juicy red piece.
Savor it all in one big bite.
No, I don't want any.
Then what would you like to eat?
What would you like to eat?
A short, thick, and oval
sweet cucumber,
eggplant, or melon?
No, I don't want any.
Then what would you like to eat?
What do you like to eat?
Would you like cherries or grapes?
A taffy or tangerine candy my dear?
Then my love...
What would you like to eat?
What do you want to eat?
How did they find out?
Who's the bastard that told them?
When the morning cock cried,
the governor suddenly came and
demanded your whereabouts.
Forgive me, I had no choice.
Since your father knows
already, don't try to lie to him.
Tell him you won't leave anymore
and you'll concentrate on the exam.
Okay?
My love, my treasure, my joy.
Oh yes...you're my beloved.
When you die, become a flower.
A peach flower
that blossoms in the spring.
When I die,
I'll become a tiger butterfly.
On a beautiful spring day,
if I dance around you,
then recognize it is me.
If the flower withers,
the butterflies don't visit anymore.
So I don't want to be a flower.
Then there's another after you die.
You become the Bell of Chongno,
and I'll be the hammer that hits it.
In the night,
I'll hit it 28 times,
In the day,
I'll hit it 33 times.
When I hit you,
recognize it is me.
I don't want to be a bell.
Then there's another after you die.
You'll be the Yin,
such as the 'earth',
'shade,' 'wife',
and 'woman'.
I'll be the Yang,
such as the 'sky',
'sun',
'light',
'husband',
and 'man'.
We will live happily forever
when we become 'one'.
Hey Hyangdan.
Oh my! You're bad.
Master Lee.
Master Lee!
What are you doing here?
Where have you been lately?
Were you too busy to study
and hear the good news?
What sort of news father?
I've been appointed
to the King's cabinet.
I'll finish up here
so take your mother
to Seoul ahead of me.
Master Lee is here.
My son-in-law is home!
But why are you here so early?
Well, I'm glad.
I just sewed an autumn jacket
for you. Come up and try it on.
Why did you walk here without Pangja?
Why do you look so worried?
Did your father scold you?
Please say something.
I don't smell any alcohol.
...no fever.
What's wrong?
My father has been appointed
as a minister in Seoul.
What great news.
That's a high rank in the government.
But why aren't you happy?
I have to leave for Seoul tomorrow.
Are you worried I won't follow you?
A woman follows
her husband wherever he goes.
There's nothing
in Namwon if you're away.
My mother said if people
discover our marriage,
I'll be disowned,
and forbidden to take the state exam.
So she insists I don't mention
our marriage to my father.
Are you saying we must separate?
Only for a little while.
All I can do is come back for you later.
Oh my husband!
Is what you said
a quirk, a joke,
a mistake, or nonsense?
Watching me kill myself...
Is that what you want?
When we met the first time,
what did you say?
We swore to the
mountains and the ocean
with the sun and the moon
as our witnesses...
Until the mulberry field
becomes the sea
or the sea becomes the mulberry field,
we will never part.
Not even a year has past,
and you're saying farewell?
There is the cloud you swore on.
Speak to me.
You begged me
to be your wife,
but now you ruined my life!
My husband, take this drink.
While you travel to Seoul,
think of my love for you
when you see the blue river.
Our enemy is not a person,
the enemy is the class that divides us.
Chunhyang, take this mirror.
My love is as pure as
the mirror's reflection.
Cherish it and think
of me when you use it.
Take this, my husband.
My unchangeable love is the
same as the color of jade.
Think of me when you see it.
After Namwon,
there's Osu and lmsil,
and then Chunju
which is famous for its fans.
After Yusan, which is known
for its fur and leather,
there's fine honey
and ginseng in Kongju.
Then there's Chunan,
which is famous for its carps.
Then Suwon and Kwachon,
which is 32 km from Seoul.
Bandits in Seoul are so territorial,
country people start to shiver
when they pass Kwachon.
Chunhyang...
When I pass the exam,
I'll send a royal palanquin for you.
So wait until that day.
A royal palanquin is only ridden
by high-ranking officials.
Do you think this day will come
before I become an old hag?
Meanwhile,
his mother prepares to leave.
Double palanquins...
Single palanquins...
Horses and soldiers are busy.
Nervous Pangja
dashes with Mongryong's horse.
Ring...ring...ring...ring...
He arrives at Chunhyang's home.
Master Lee there's big trouble!
Master Lee! Master Lee!
There's big trouble!
Your mother asked about you,
and I gave her an excuse.
We must hurry.
Mongryong has no choice,
but to mount the horse's back.
Farewell Chunhyang.
Farewell mother-in-law.
Farewell Hyangdan.
Chunhyang is speechless.
On barefoot, runs, runs, runs...
...she grabs the bridle with one hand,
and with the other,
she grabs Mongryong's leg.
Oh my husband!
Oh my husband, please take me!
Pangja pulls the bridle,
and whips the horse.
It bolts like a flying tiger.
Green mountains and blue rivers
he passes it one by one.
Like the mandarin duck
that lost her lover,
Chunhyang is heart-broken.
As she sees her husband leave,
she sees this much of him
and that much of him,
like a distant moon,
like a distant star,
and then like a butterfly...
I long to go.
I long to follow
my lover,
for one thousand miles,
for even ten thousand miles.
Where the wind rests,
where the clouds rest,
where all animals rest,
even a wild falcon,
where they all rest
at Dongsul's high ridge.
But I will cross it over
to follow my love.
The Jiknya star in the heavens,
even when the Milky Way blocks it,
the Gyunwoo star
can always see it once a year.
The place where my beloved stays,
what Milky Way is blocking him,
that makes me see him no more?
I want to die,
and become a spring swallow,
so I can fly above my beloved's roof
and build my nest under the eaves.
I'll meet him
in the middle of the night,
and make love to him till dawn.
their hats are pulled up and...
they arrive in the forest and...
Chunhyang! Come out
Madam, two soldiers
are looking for Chunhyang.
Oh no, I forgot about the
courtesan roll call...
Welcome. Please, come in.
It's been a long time.
The new governor
demands to see Chunhyang.
Since I haven't kept
my promise to buy you a drink,
were you disappointed?
It would be a lie if I wasn't.
- I'm sorry I was so busy...
- Chunhyang, come out!
We're good friends so
don't let it get to you, okay?
Please have a drink later.
- Stop it.
- Take it. Don't worry.
Hey Kim! We scored.
Chunhyang.
When the new governor headed
west Pyongyang for two years,
he awarded
his courtesans a lot of money.
Also, as the Governor of Unsan
he gave his courtesans much more.
So be nice to him, okay?
Chunhyang.
We'll take care of
you so don't worry and come with us.
Look after her, okay?
Chunhyang has arrived!
Chunhyang is here, my lord.
You're very pretty.
Yes, indeed.
I chose Namwon
among many other places
to see you for myself.
But...
Are you really married
to the old governor's son?
Yes, I am.
But how can
a young woman like you be alone?
You must have
another man who cares for you?
Please tell me.
Because I'm married
to the old governor's son,
I'm devoted to
no other man except for my husband.
You're well intended.
But he'll probably marry
a noble girl when he passes the exam.
And he'll forget all about you.
You will serve me from now on.
So go clean
yourself up and wait for me.
I'm not listed as a courtesan,
and lived my life as a fair lady.
That gives you
no reason to do as you please.
By law and custom,
it's natural to serve
your new governor.
Stop your nonsense
and get ready for him.
If my husband never returns,
I'll be chaste until I die.
So please reconsider.
A chaste courtesan's
daughter is ridiculous.
My mother would faint if she heard this.
Be it your mother or I,
fidelity is the same.
But does class make us different?
What?
A governor is loyal to one king.
A wife is loyal to one husband.
But would you fall on your knees,
and serve two kings, governor?
How dare you!
You will die for that!
Drag her outside!
We've got her outside my lord!
If your mother is a courtesan,
then you're a courtesan by law.
As a lowly courtesan,
you disobeyed my orders.
So you deserve to die!
Did I steal food?
Did I disobey my mother,
or cheat my fellow brethren?
If not,
then why are you punishing me?
You must be ignorant of our laws.
Then tell me what law I've broken.
Chief Penal Official!
Yes, sir.
Tell her every sin she's committed.
Listen carefully.
One who commits high treason,
or disobeys the governor
is punishable by death.
Then what does it say about
raping a married woman?
She's the wicked daughter of the devil!
Make her confess her crimes in writing!
Chunhyang, write as I say.
As a lowly courtesan,
I disobeyed the governor,
so I deserve to die for my crime.
"One Love"
Chief Executioner!
Yes, sir.
Beat her till her organs burst!
If you don't,
you'll be the one to die!
Yes, sir.
Look at the way
the soldier is walking.
He lifts an armful and brings the clubs.
He throws them to the floor...
He sorts through the stack.
He grabs one and tests it.
He grabs another and tests it.
He picks a large one with a good grip.
Move an inch!
and your bones will be broken!
Beat her hard!
Chunhyang's mind
and body is scorching with pain,
but she never shows it.
She moves her head in a
shape of a 'one',
stares into Hakdo's eyes
and cries out...
One and only one!
My love is only for one man!
So why are you doing this to me!
Just kill me!
Hit her harder!
Yes sir!
Two can never be!
What's the difference
between loyalty to a husband,
and a minister's to a king?
I know a woman's duty,
so how can I serve two men?
This is impossible
so I can't accept two!
After the third hit...
In our three lives,
in my three obligations,
I'm loyal to my father,
my husband, and my son!
I'm not a whore!
So just kill me!
After the fourth hit...
A noble governor like you,
do you not know any justice?
Even if you tear me into four pieces,
and hang them on the four gates,
I still won't accept you!
After the fifth hit...
You rode with five horses.
So keep this country's five ethics!
After the sixth hit...
I have six organs,
and my love is in each one of them.
So it's useless
for you to tear them apart!
After the seventh hit...
If you raised a seven-foot sword,
and cut off my head like a horse,
it's no use!
After the eighth hit...
Try as many as eight hundred times,
but my love will never change!
After the ninth hit...
You're the King's official!
So stop your corruptive ways!
My intestine has nine curves.
My love flows deep in them!
After the tenth hit...
Ten cries for my love!
Move away!
You bastards! Let me in!
My daughter's dying!
My daughter!
Why did this happen to you?
Is beating innocent people
the new governor's way to rule?
Is being loyal
to your husband a punishable sin?
If she dies,
then kill me also!
Please save my daughter!
Move away!
She'll die like this.
She needs medicine.
Pangja, let her down here.
Oh, Chunhyang...
Oh, my daughter...
Bring some water!
Chunhyang wake up.
She's crazy.
Is she doing this out of some
spite against Chunhyang?
What is she doing?
In Chinju, a courtesan
named Uiam died for her country.
In Pyongyang, a courtesan
named Wolson killed an enemy general.
The people in Andong
worships the shrine of lljinhong,
who fed her husband with
her flesh to save him.
In Chungju, they honor
Hwawol for saving the king,
and now in Namwon
a new courtesan Chunhyang
will be next to honor...
Meanwhile in Seoul,
Young Lee studies hard.
He reads night and day
countless pages of Korean classics.
His knowledge broadens
and he becomes a skillful writer.
The state exam takes place
while the country stood silent.
The Royal Teacher
comes forth with a scroll in his hand.
His assistant takes
the scroll and hangs the question.
"The past spring of
this garden is the same as the present."
The question hangs tall.
Mongryong reads the board,
He thinks for a moment.
He grinds the stick into the
ink stone, and dips his brush.
His brush strokes are equal
to famous calligraphers.
He's the first to complete
and hand in his answer.
The Royal Instructor
looks at it and compliments him.
Your words are perfect
and have spirits in them.
Each character
is as genuine as a jewel.
They post the top score.
Mongryong Lee!
The crowd is amazed
by the announcement.
Handsome Lee walks proudly
towards the court terrace.
After he wears his formal gown,
He receives a token
and is escorted to the King.
He kneels before the King,
and graciously accepts
his three cups of wine.
He bows to the King,
and walks down the steps,
wearing a flower cap and blue gown,
with a jade emblem
and red scroll in his hands.
After he became the ethics official,
the King secretly makes him
his emissary to inspect Cholla Province
and gives him his assignment,
with a symbolic ruler and royal insignia.
He bids his family farewell
and leaves for Cholla Province.
He leaves the South Gate of Seoul,
and crosses Han River
and several streams.
Then he passes
many small villages like
Mirookdangee,
Kolsagunae, and Ssangyoochon,
and many marketplaces,
like Dukjum and Ohmu
and many towns like Sosa,
Kwangjung, and Morowon,
He finally arrives at
Yusan town.
- First Deputy.
- Yes, sir.
Go to the west provinces.
Start in Yusan and lksan.
Then Kimjae and the rest.
We'll meet at Kwangharu
on the 15th of next month.
Yes, sir.
- Second Deputy.
-Yes, sir.
Go to the east and
check Kosan, Kumsan,
Muju, Yongdam, and the rest.
- Meet on the same day too.
- Yes, sir.
Hey, you dear farmers,
listen to what I say.
Listen to what I say.
Drop by drop,
your sweat turns into fruit.
Chop by chop,
your grain turns into gold.
Come here. Eat with us.
No thank you.
I'm just a vagabond
headed to Namwon
to ask a favor from a friend.
So how is this town now?
- The town is full of demons.
What do you mean?
The governor is a drunken devil,
his confidant is an old zombie,
the chiefs are gambling trolls,
and we're all grumbling ghosts.
- This town seems to be cursed.
Do you think that's all?
For the governor's birthday,
each family
has to give three sacks of rice.
He's robbing the people.
I've heard the governor
adores a courtesan named Chunhyang,
and enjoys her every night.
Is this true?
What?
You bastard!
How dare you insult her!
It's just what I've heard!
Why are you angry?
Who the hell told you that?
I'll rip his eyes out!
And tear his ears off!
Catch him! Get him!
How much farther?
How far to Seoul?
Where do I sleep today?
Where do I sleep tomorrow?
My fate is unlucky,
so I have to go.
But Chunhyang's fate is worse.
How much farther, how far?
Hey you, come here.
- Come here.
-Why do you call me?
I'm a busy person, you know.
- Because I'm from Seoul.
- From Seoul?
Who are you visiting
at such a far place?
I'm delivering Chunhyang Sung's
letter to Mongryong Lee.
- Let me see the letter.
- Are you serious?
Reading a man's letter is forbidden,
but you ask to see
a woman's letter in public?
You don't recognize me?
Look carefully.
I can't believe this!
Oh, Master Lee!
It's a blessing to see you.
Are you and the family well?
Why are you dressed like this?
Pangja, give me the letter.
"To Mongryong Lee of Seoul"
After you left,
three years have past
and I've yet to hear from you.
Are you too intoxicated by
Seoul's beautiful spring petals?
Or is your mind taken away
by pretty brothel women?
Or are you going to marry
some noble lady in Seoul?
I'm living with
these worries day and night.
After the new governor arrived,
he asked me to court him,
but I defied him
and he beat me severely.
I will die soon
at the governor's birthday feast
when he beats me on the death chair.
Vicious bastard!
When I get hold of him...!
Why do I feel such a fierce wind?
Could it be a fierce wind
to save poor Chunhyang?
My master can't really
be a beggar, so could he be...
- ...an...an emissary?
- Pangja! Don't be foolish!
Well, it's good we met.
I want you to deliver a letter
to my home in Seoul.
When the sun is about to set,
he arrives in front of Chunhyang's home.
In the back of the garden,
is a silent cry.
He's drawn to the sound
to take a closer look.
He sees Chunhyang's mother
at a small altar in the backyard.
To the Great Dipper,
with lit candles
and a bowl of clean water
set in front of her, she prays...
I pray...I pray...
...to the gods of heaven and earth,
and the gods of the sun,
moon, and stars...
Please come and help me.
Please make my son-in-law
a royal emissary
or a lord of Cholla Province.
Either one will be fine.
Please let him
save my daughter's life.
I passed the test...
But I owe it mostly to their prayers.
Is anyone home?
Come out!
May I help you?
Go and tell your madam to come out.
Who is it?
Someone is asking for you madam.
He looks like a beggar asking for food.
What?
Are you deaf?
Haven't you heard?
My daughter is in jail and about to die,
and you ask us for food?
We have none! Get out of here!
I've arrived!
It's Mongryong Lee from Seoul!
How can this be?
Is this true, or is it a joke?
Hyangdan. Bring the lantern.
Is my son-in-law really here?
What took you so long?
Let me see my son-in-law.
This can't be...
The son of the ex-governor.
Look at the way he's dressed!
Chunhyang's dead...
She's dead for certain.
I prayed day and
night you'd return as a high official,
but you come back
as this country's filthiest beggar!
A crisis struck our family,
so I couldn't take the exam.
Our wealth is all gone, and
I've been begging since then.
To remember old times,
I came back to Namwon.
That was delicious!
Must be your job to stuff your face.
Your appetite reflects your living.
I was so hungry
before I could barely think.
But since I'm full now,
Chunhyang comes to mind.
- Bring me to Chunhyang.
- Chunhyang's dead!
Let's go.
She's dying because
of me so can't I see her? Let's go.
You can't go now.
The governor is so strict
no man can bring food to her.
Even a male dog can't go there.
If they catch you,
you'll be killed.
When the last bell strikes,
you can see her then.
Oh, my poor baby...
The first bell, the second,
the third, fourth,
and fifth bell strikes.
The time has come.
Hyangdan leads the way.
and the beggar son-in-law follows them
to Chunhyang's decrepit cell.
The night is dark and gloomy,
not a person in sight,
the echoes of a warbling bird...
running water...
wailing ghosts...
the wind blows...
...like trembling ground.
Heavy rain is falling...
Ghosts in twos and threes
come together and cry...
Guard.
Damn guards are busy gambling again.
...Nine.
- Three pairs.
- Damn it! It's not my day.
Prison keeper.
Who is it?
It's you again.
We can't let anyone in until the
governor's birthday tomorrow.
Go back.
Don't be stubborn.
Take this, okay?
Hey Dukbae!
Open the gate idiot!
It's some food for my baby.
Give her this later.
Anything else inside?
- Oh, come on...
- Go in.
My baby...
Chunhyang...
Wake up. It's your mother.
Mother,
what are you doing here this late?
He's here...
Who are you talking about?
The one you've waited day and night for.
Be it your husband or a beggar,
he's here. See for yourself.
Is this true?
Hyangdan, raise the lantern.
Chunhyang, it's me.
What happened to you?
Oh, my husband.
What took you so long?
What happened to your face?
He can't save you,
and you still call him your husband?
Chunhyang.
My husband.
Tomorrow at the new governor's
birthday feast, I'll be executed.
Don't let anyone touch my body.
Take me to Seoul and bury me
in your ancestors' graveyard.
Then prepare a simple altar for me,
and say these words...
Chunhyang,
cherish the drink I pour for you.
If you do this,
I can rest in peace.
Young Lee is disheartened.
Don't cry.
My love Chunhyang, don't cry.
When the day is bright tomorrow,
either the death carriage
or the fortune carriage,
no one knows what you'll ride.
Even when the sky collapses,
There is a hole to escape.
If I said don't cry,
then please don't cry.
On the next day,
the birthday feast takes place
in Kwangharu Pavilion.
It's a spectacular sight.
The red pavilion stands
tall in the blue skies.
Surrounded by large shades like the clouds.
Covered by silk curtains on all four sides.
Red and blue candle lanterns
are hung on the open road.
Crowded with courtesans, musicians,
performers, and passerbies.
Town magistrates of other counties arrive.
Here comes Lord of Unbong town,
the Lord of Soonchun town,
the old Lord of Goksung,
the handsome Lord of Soonchan,
the lucky Lord of Damyang,
the chic Lord of Okgwa,
the Lord of Nampyung,
and the lazy Lord of Kwangju.
When all the lords enter,
another palanquin arrives.
Firecrackers crackling.
Sun umbrellas bumping.
Palanquin bearers' shoulders colliding.
Servants searching for their masters.
It's out of control.
Take this, take this,
take this drink,
and live one thousand,
ten thousand years.
Thank you for sparing your
busy time to come today.
...Chunshim can still twirl well even
with twins in her belly.
I heard the officials of Kumsan
were caught for embezzlement.
It was well taken care of.
Forget it and have a drink.
Look here, Soonchun.
Seems like this feast will go on all night.
- Are you staying till the end?
- Of course.
After the feast, Chunhyang will be flogged
to death.
I won't miss it for anything.
Our henchman can kill a person with one blow.
I'm sure there's someone here like that, too.
Why do you think there
are so many people outside?
There are so many people!
Looks like all the beggars around Namwon.
Two cows, fifteen pigs
and all the chickens in Namwon.
There's got to be something for us too.
Halt! You can't go in!
Step aside.
I said you can't enter!
Get out of my way!
I'm a nobleman too!
Step down!
Move away!
Can't you recognize a noble?
Step down!
You're tearing a poor noble's clothes!
What's all this noise?
- Let go of me!
A noble who looks like
a beggar insists we let him in.
- Governor Byun.
- Yes.
Although they're outworn,
he wears the clothes of a noble.
Just seat him in the corner,
and send him away after a drink.
If you desire Lord of Unbong.
Let him in.
You may enter.
Take your shoes off first!
Look here.
I look at your table and mine,
and it makes me angry.
Since you're late, it seems
your table was hastily made.
You may take
anything you'd like from mine.
Here, have a drink.
Lord of Unbong.
Yes.
There will be a big
meeting in Goksung this winter.
Please come.
Of course.
Look here.
You say you're Lord of Unbong town.
Yes I am.
Then call
a courtesan to sing for me also.
Sing for this guest.
He demands a singing courtesan too!
If you drink this wine,
for thousands of years
you will beg.
Since I cannot beg
for thousands of years alone,
why don't we all have
a drink and divide these years.
What a rude remark.
For your hospitality,
I'd like to improvise
a poem in honor of the new governor.
Governor.
Since this boy has no manners,
his writing will be poor.
Just send him away after he writes it.
Two words.
If you can't write a poem
with them, you will be clubbed.
Good.
Then give it to me.
Lives and feast.
Sure, he must know
they go in the second and last line.
It's not very good
so please correct it if it's wrong.
I apologize for my disturbance.
How tasteless...
"This wine in golden vases is
the blood of a thousand people.
The food on these jade tables
is the flesh of ten thousand lives.
When the candle wax drops,
tears of starving peasants fall.
And the people's complaints get louder
to pair this noisy feast."
This poem is laced with poison!
This is foolish.
Something has come up.
I must be going.
- I have to leave also.
-Why are you leaving?
My wife is very ill today.
I have to care for her quickly.
I have some urgent matters too.
Why are all of you worried
over some beggar's poem?
Please sit down.
Look at Mongryong,
He worries everyone might run away.
He runs out to the terrace,
and flicks open his fan.
Hidden in the crowd,
the envoy sees the signal
and storms out of the crowd,
They brandish their clubs,
raise the royal medallion like the sun,
thrust into the gates and shout...
In the King's name,
you're all under arrest!
You're all under arrest!
In the King's name,
you're all under arrest!
As if the heaven
collapses and the earth trembles,
hundreds of spectators
scatter like gushing streams.
What can be more frightening
then the thunderous roar
of the royal envoy?
Who can bear this whirling wind?
When the governor's
guests are panicking all over,
look at their servants'
ridiculous movements.
Food is stomped on,
and vases are broken,
Drums are split into two,
gongs roll off the pavilion
to make their own sound.
Harp strings are crushed.
Courtesans pin chopsticks in their hair.
Musicians lose their horns,
and blow from their hands.
Soldiers lose their guns,
and shoot from their mouths.
Some bump their heads,
and bleed from their nose.
Some fall on their face and cry,
passers by also run and shouts...
Oh no!
Our town is in trouble!
Namwon has the richest rice supply.
But you stole from it,
impoverishing the people.
You're supposed to keep
a close watch on the governor,
but you fattened
your pockets while lying to him.
You ignored the sick and
desperate peasants who live in misery.
Divide what they stole from
the poor and gave it back to them.
Release all the innocent people in jail.
And bring Chunhyang to me!
Chunhyang, we're here!
All of Namwon's
widows will stand by your side!
So don't worry!
Untie her!
Yes, sir!
Chunhyang, hear me out!
As a courtesan's daughter,
you disobeyed the governor!
How do you expect to live?
Serving two husbands
is the same as serving two kings.
So what injustice have I done?
Since you refused the
governor, will you refuse me also?
I thought the king
sent you to help the people,
but you're just like the
governor and other officials!
Stop humiliating me,
and just kill me!
Give this to Chunhyang,
and tell her look up at me.
He said to take this,
and look at him.
Don't just stand there!
Bring her to the main chamber!
Move away!
Chunhyang!
Chunhyang, wake up.
Why did you do it?
If you had told me,
I would've slept peacefully.
But I stayed up
all night worried about dying!
Chunhyang.
Don't cry.
The King forbade me
to give away my secret.
Don't cry.
Are the gates still closed off to me?
This belly bore Chunhyang!
I'm the mother-in-law
of the emissary!
People of Namwon,
listen to what I have to say.
Don't try to bear a son.
Bear a daughter like Chunhyang.
Raise her with tender and utmost care.
When a man from Seoul comes,
take him in as your son-in-law!
Oh...she's my daughter!
Oh...he's my son-in-law!
When you came last night,
I already knew everything.
So that your secret
doesn't get revealed,
I acted like that on purpose.
You were mad, weren't you?
Don't hate Governor Byun.
Without him,
how could my daughter
be a loyal wife?
You'll be sent to
Cholla province prison.
If you have any
objections, then do it there.
Adoring a pretty woman is natural.
But don't you think what you
did to Chunhyang was too harsh?
Class has a definite order.
A daughter of
a courtesan becomes one naturally.
She didn't disobey just me,
but she disgraced
the law, and committed treason.
It wasn't injustice...
it was her will to be a human being.
Later...Mongryong
goes from town to town,
and finishes his investigation.
He returns to Seoul,
and reports what he had seen.
The King compliments him...
You saved the country
from great worry.
You're a national hero.
Another official tells the King
about loyal Chunhyang of Namwon
and the King bestows on her
an honorable award for loyalty.
As for the people of Namwon,
the King lifts the taxes.
They all live in peace,
but who knows
what will happen after this story.