"The Love Boat"
(1967)
Luau, let's have a luau
Hear me world
you must know
I'm dropping everything
and falling out
Who needs to worry and strife
Life can be a party,
I will change my way of life
Luau, let's have a luau
Search more lights
bright city
is where you will find me,
having fun.
I need this
to be free
I choose and take
the life you want
This is the life for me
Luau, let's have a luau
"WELCOME TO FLORIDA
STATE HAPPY "
"Workshop on Ernie, Automotive Services"
"Carburetors, brakes, ignition
Hey buddy, can you answer?
Sure.
How may I help you?
Fill the tank as
get something to eat.
It will be a pleasure young friend.
And then go out with me
today or not?
At his motorcycle? Forget it!
Ham sandwich
and coffee, please.
Yes, it does not take offense
I say ...
... Is driving a nice car.
Glad you like.
Ham sandwich and coffee.
That is your bike?
Oh yeah, well ... almost, left
three more payments.
I have an equal at home.
I'm Scott Hayward.
- Tom Wilson.
- Hey, young friend!
Can not find the tank.
Show where he is.
And the radio, would swear that touches
as a phone.
That's a phone.
Must have a very long thread!
Just a moment, I have
a link for you.
Scott, are you?
Elie, how did you find me?
I tried all seasons
Mason furniture line - Dixie.
His father is enraged.
Wait a minute.
I have Scott on the line.
Gimme that phone!
Hello Scott?
Here is your father speaking.
Tell me son,
where the hell are you?
At the moment,
Hayward at a checkpoint.
A step in the right direction ...
... I hope you have a good
reason for leaving here ...
... Like a scared rabbit
the pack.
Sorry for leaving
without warning.
You were very
busy and I ...
... Just wanted to disappear
for a while.
Disappear?
Or run away?
And the poor child,
his bride ...
... That you almost
abandoned at the altar?
I thought it was
for real this time
Me too, until I found out
was not me she loved ...
... But your money!
Scott does not understand?
The money is for that ...
... To buy all the good things
that make you happy.
There are more things that
father in this life.
More than money?
Scott, get rid of these ideas
silly and now return home now!
The position of vice president
the company expects.
A father, I'm just
Duster Hayward's son.
Thanks to this, I have so many
oil wells that do not know.
This means that deserve
be vice president?
It is enough for me son.
But not for me
father does not understand eh?
I want to do something for
own, bye dad.
Bye? Scott what ...
It has a beautiful ski there.
Thank you, listen ...
... You go to Miami,
Hotel passes the Shores ...
... And I look at the Ski Shop,
I will be the new teacher.
We'll have a party,
many girls ...
... the boat race.
If I go there,
yes I'll do it.
We do not currently have
plans, only problems.
Problems ...
Sure, I could not
to listen, really ...
Duster Hayward's son ...?
Yeah!
It has quiet life, what kind
problems have?
Lord! Your sandwich is
ready and waiting.
I'm inviting the cat
to leave me for one hour.
She looks at her car ... and melts!
Exactly.
- A look at my car.
- So what?
Once wanted
was on me ...
... Not in my car,
nor my money.
Call this problem, huh?
It's the kind of problem
I would like.
If you want to switch places,
just enough to say.
I'm on the right track
to many kisses
So those greenbacks
I do not will be missed
All good things
life are free
Who needs money?
I do not
Cash or
credit card, no matter
Since my bills
continue getting fatter
The easiest way
is my favorite avenue
Who needs money?
I do!
Poor millionaires
can never relax
Because they are always
concerned about taxes
Why waste time
with higher loans
I prefer to spend it
looking for romance
So what if my pockets
are empty?
Who needs money?
I do not
Some guys keep
others lend
As for me,
just want to spend
Give me some green
my sky will be blue
Who needs money?
I do!
Stocks and bonds,
I understand that
Profit,
I do not care
Who wants to sit
in the lap of luxury?
Who needs money?
I do not
I want a big yacht
so I can walk
The kind that girls
please enter
All I need
are one or two million
Who needs money?
I do!
When a girl
starts to flirt
Now that I am a hard,
I know for sure
What is behind my
personality that she is
Who needs money?
I do not
Poverty is the only thing
that money can not buy
Therefore, poor or rich,
pays to get G-R-A-N-A
A girl loving
is what I love
Clean money,
I want stacks of them
Let my income
net overflow
can not take it with you
when moving to another
So?
Who needs money?
This adorable   money
Who needs
- Of money, not me.
- Of the money, I do!
Welcome to Hotel Shores, sir.
Thanks, now ...
... Let me see if I can
out of his grasp here.
I can turn.
I should imagine.
It's hard to drive this cart
with these spurs ...
... But I feel naked without them!
At that time, need
a reserve ...
Yeah! The name is Hayward.
- A reservation is required ...
- Is Hayward!
Oil Hayward.
That Hayward!
Yeah!
I thought it would make a
small difference.
Absolutely!
I'll take care of your car,
being careful.
Look for the manager, I am sure that
he will arrange something for you.
Thanks mate.
Hey you!
I?
Yes, you! Can not stop
that thing there, in the passage.
Get out there!
Mr. Hathaway?
Guess who just arrived?
Thanks, muitoobrigado.
Excuse me Miss, I hope
not have hurt you.
Spurs tangled!
Naughty!
Mr. Hayward, I presume.
Yeah!
Welcome to Hotel Shores, sir.
Oh .. Well you know me huh?
I do not remember
meet you sir ...
Hathaway, sir.
Hello sir. Hathaway,
pleasure to meet you.
Look Mr Hathaway, my bones are
breaking through to know?
I need a soft place
and nice to stretch them.
Well, I think we
you find something appropriate.
Very good!
Excuse me!
Hello! Everything under control?
Mr. Wayward ...
Oh yeah?
I think we found
a place, sir.
Ordinance!
Follow Mr. Hayward
the presidential suite.
Presidential suite?
Well, how did reservations ...
... Will have to serve.
Very nice, Mr Hayward,
I say, Mr Hathaway.
The bleachers were full ...
and you could feel the
electricity in the air.
Well .. it was the most exciting thing
what ever happened to me.
I'll show you,
can handle it?
Yes
Thanks.
Now, just imagine, here
... we're four.
Okay ... well at the start,
accelerates a guy ...
... E. .. bam!
It's out of the race.
Now we are only three ...
only three ...
... And suddenly ... bam!
one of the boats go flying ...
... And there we were, just us two ...
... Just the two of us in the race ...
... Now I know it's time
to leap ...
- Mr Jameson?
- Yes, Charlie?
I put the new propulsion and already
put in the water, waiting for you.
Okay, I'm already there.
Well, ladies, I hate
having to leave them ...
Do not go, finish the story.
Well .. to shorten the story ...
I won!
And I have also established
a new record.
But now my passion, this is
race so if you'll excuse me ...
... I'll take to Lady Scarlet
North Point and will regulate it.
And tightening may be
anyone else that fits it.
Any takers?
I like to go.
Mr. Jamison ...
... Love getting tight.
Me too.
- Yes?
- I'm Tom Wilson ... Wilson.
Sorry Mr Wilson, we
completely full.
I'm not looking
quarter.
- Good!
- I am the new ski instructor.
Wilson! The input
service is back there ...
Excuse me, Mr Hathaway.
- Is the new ski instructor?
That's right.
Want to make an appointment for a
class tomorrow, Miss Carter?
Not tomorrow, now!
Mr Wilson only begins
to work tomorrow.
Mr Wilson, as a special favor,
could start their classes today?
I think so, I just have to
find my room and leave it there.
Great! See you on the platform
Ski-... 5 minutes?
- In five minutes?
- Unless you arrive before!
Mr. Hathaway ...
Exactly where ...
North Point is?
Are you sure you need lessons?
Ohh yeah ... yeah.
I figured it would lose
balance this time.
Yes I was lucky.
- She's a beauty.
- Yes it is.
Someone who knows?
Not yet.
What are you trying to do?
I can teach you
anything else?
And then?
I was teaching you to keep
balance and suddenly ...
... This boat and it appears
begins to juggle ...
... As if one of profissisonal
Cyprens Gardens.
Where did you get that?
There is too much?
I knew that I would like ... 20 bucks!
Twenty bucks?
Never paid for it ...
- For a tie in my life!
- Until today!
The next time you want a
tie, let me choose.
After all, the
reputation is mine!
Yeah! Dude, I enjoy myself here.
Tonight, for example ...
... I have a meeting with a
millionaire named Jamison.
May know,
he is the jammies.
- What?
- Jammies.
You know, the parts
girls wearing ...
.. And say they are sleepwear.
He is in them!
- He uses them?
- No! He who manufactures them.
The "Jammmies?
Is it once a year
just come for the race.
And won the last three ...
... Which is no surprise,
considering the boat he has.
It must be worth a fortune.
Does he have more
money than me?
A red boat, great
with tailpipes up ...
... And exiting the water ...
- Is the Scarlet Lady?
- Yes, you saw him?
This is the boat for which
Dianne was showing off.
Understood, it also
is behind him.
So tonight
I am concerned ...
Your little joke ...
this week it went nowhere.
Jamison jammies and I
made other plans.
- Arrange the tie.
- Okay, thanks.
Sure, try it at home.
If you need anything,
call room service ...
... And can sign on my behalf.
Thanks! Get out!
Mr. Jamison!
Hello Paul, the usual please.
J J Special right?
I was waiting.
Hey, Mr Jamison ...
... Want to ask something,
Here comes the year, right?
You know my wife is
filling the bag, whatever you play ...
... You could get something from
Jamie settlement jammies?
I hate to ask, but you know ...
- His wife ...?
- Yes.
- Sure ...
- My wife, actually.
- Really?
- Yes!
Of course .. of course Paul, I ... I take care of it
so back to New York.
- Thanks.
- Actually ...
... We have a new
coming this year ...
... So soft, they do not know where
Jammies and just get the girl.
Forget it.
I already have six children, not
need one more, right?
Ahhh ... it is!
How about something in flannel?
Flannel?
Yes ma'am, what will it be?
What is that?
What?
A J J Special.
Sounds interesting, or would
better to say dangerous?
Depends on your mood.
It may be interesting or
dangerous, or both.
Ohh .. I see.
In your case, I think
would dangerously interesting.
"I'll take one.
- It's coming out.
Forgive my curiosity, but ...
... I have not seen before?
This afternoon, for example?
I doubt, I was skiing
this afternoon.
So it was you!
Remember the boat race?
The Scarlet Lady?
- That was me.
- Really?
Was doing some
maneuvers very good.
That was nothing.
Well .. I'm James Jamison,
and you're ...
- Dianne Carter.
- How are you?
Hi friend!
Excuse me.
Gloria, this is J J Jamison.
- How are you?
- I am doing fine, sure.
J J Come, let us leave here and find
something more exciting.
You're ready to go?
Ready, eager e. .. available.
Be right back.
We'll see.
Here we are.
- Hi
- Waiting for someone?
Not anymore.
Well .. if so ... can I?
Yes
Now, on to lesson
ski this afternoon ...
I think I owe you an apology.
Okay, just do not do it again.
This is the first time
I'm in Miami.
The first night, and you,
the first girl I meet.
I thought of a ride
around, you come with me?
Why not? This seems
it will be fun.
I paid, we'll see ...
- ... So if you switch.
- I switch?
Sure, pants are best
to ride bikes.
Bike? You must be kidding.
Sorry, but this
is your problem.
- Okay, see you ...
- Five minutes.
- Five minutes?
- Unless you arrive before.
Touché!
- How's it going?
- Very good.
Hey, come on!
I must be getting old.
Hey look, leave tomorrow
work at 16 ...
... How about a boat?
- And there's this restaurant that ...
- No.
Tom, do not miss
your time with me ...
... I am not rich, and my
family is not rich.
- How so?
- Look, I understand ...
... You guys, come
here for the season ...
... Housekeepers, lifeguards,
Ski Instructors ...
... All hoping to find
a girl ... very very rich.
I understand, I was so obvious?
Ohh no ...
No. ..
... Is that one is able to
recognize the other.
We are of the same type, you
think I'm doing here?
For years, I've saved and
I saved up ... I pledge ...
... Half of my clothes are
lent, and the other half ...
... Put labels Sack's, everything
to be able to come here e. ..
And find a millionaire.
Okay, I admit ...
... I do not know why
telling you that.
No wonder why he left me ...
... That's not in their plans.
I think it's because
I like you.
Besides, who knows, they may
to let him jealous.
"He" is Jamison?
Yes
Maybe you need
more ski lessons.
- Will you help me?
- Why not?
How you pay
I can repay the favor.
And who knows it ...
may have a sister?
They say that, looking
deeply a bonfire ...
... Sometimes, if you can
see the future.
Well .. what you see?
I can see you now
Living like a queen
In a house that has it all
Anything but Love
Crystal chandeliers
Limousine chauffeur
Yes, you'll have all the same
Anything but Love
I see diamonds and furs,
sapphires and pearls.
as the image name
poor little rich girl
sitting alone
Counting her treasures
and your tears
Better a shack
Where two people like each other
Than a house that has it all
Anything but Love
I see diamonds and furs,
sapphires and pearls.
as the image name
poor little rich girl
sitting alone
Counting her treasures
and your tears
Better a shack
Where two people like each other
Than a house that has it all
Anything but Love
I think we'd better go.
Is.
It is better that engine speed,
he is very cool.
That boat was
second last year.
Will not get anywhere
this year, if it continues.
Listen to him.
You have a great ear.
- Am Burton Sam Burton.
-Tom Wilson.
I guess I never
seen around here before.
I am a ski instructor from the hotel.
The way he spoke I thought
were of any team.
No.. Just curious
I like boats.
We lost the last one
race in south bend.
What happened?
It was an experimental model
he was working on ...
... When it came to 140,
began to vibrate ...
... The 150 began to unravel ...
... I could not handle it
and entered into a pillar.
What a pity, perhaps
better luck this year.
I'm not running this year ...
... Costs a lot to rebuild it
with little hope ...
... That we can find
what went wrong ...
... If you know of someone who wants
buy a boat damaged ...
... Very cheap, have
to my shop in Miami.
- And what would it be?
- Burton Boat Company.
Ohh! Sam Burton is that you?
- Nice talking to you.
- My pleasure, Mr Burton.
- Go with someone else?
- Hi
Come on, just to see our friend
J J going to the beach.
In this case, it is best to move.
But this time I'm riding.
- Are you ready?
- Accelerate.
Hey! Who is she?
- Funny ask ...
- Forget it, I'll find out.
Come on.
Quick, quick!
Let's reach.
Let's follow that boat!
- Take the girl!
- Go, go.
- Hi you guys!
"Hi honey, wait a minute!
Turn! Turn! Turn!
Wait for us.
Closer!
Hold hands!
Come on!
Easy! Easy!
No. .. no ...
Look!
Come on!
Are you okay?
No! Turn the other way!
- What is the problem?
- I lost the top!
Ohhh timing perfect!
Jamison has been swimming here!
Come back! Please come back!
Go away! Go away!
It was a really good trick
who tried to ski.
There was a trick.
I lost my balance,
can go away please?
Not only was the balance
she lost!
This is what you seek?
Give it to me please.
No. .. not unless they promise will
a drink with me at the hotel.
Okay, I promise! I promise!
Right.
- Thanks.
- Sure.
Look, can I help you?
No. .. you can let me
I turn myself thank you.
Turn around please.
Himself together?
- Yes, all right now.
- Come, let's get back on my boat.
- Okay.
- You could launch a new fashion.
- And what would it be?
- Water skiing, "topless" will go.
Can not blame a girl
for wanting the finer things.
Scott, wait for me!
Come on! Was it something I said?
It's a long way back!
Here Flipper! Here boy!
The funny thing is that she thinks
I'm here ...
Speak louder Scott
I am a bit flooded!
The funny thing is that she thinks I'm
here for the same reason she.
Pump and dump!
If she is so
interested in money ...
... Why did not
over me?
-Lots of competition.
- I think so.
It will be interesting to see how
she will deal with the old J J. huh?
Of course, with Jamison
there is only one way.
What's wrong?
Does it bother you?
No, that's his problem, not mine.
Hey kids!
Calm down children!
Quiet! What's the matter little girl?
They think I'm
fear of slipping.
Why not show
they are wrong?
Because I'm afraid.
Come on, try.
- No.
- I'm right here and you get caught.
I can not.
I would be surprised by things
you can do, just try it.
When everyone thought that
the world was flat
Colombo said:
"It's round"
He made history
And America was discovered
Because he had confidence
A little thing called confidence
No job too big
when you have confidence
a "C", an "O", "N"
an "F", an "I", an "A", a "NCA"
Join   everything, and what you have
Trust
Remember the tortoise and the rabbit
What   bet that famous race
Where the rabbit fast
ended nowhere
the lazy turtle
took first place
Because she had confidence
A little thing called confidence
No job too big
when you have confidence
will be surprised by what
can do, just try it
knows he can not guide
a rainbow in the sky
will be surprised by what
can do, just try it
All you need is
- Confidence.
- A little thing called ...
Trust
No job too big
when you have confidence
- With a
- "C"
- And a
- "O"
- "N"
- And a
- "F"
- "I"
- And a
- "A"
- "NCA"
Join   everything, and what you have
Confi ...
Trust.
Ice cream for everyone "
It seems to have a knack for
dealing with children.
I think it's the opposite.
Wilson, the handle of my
skiing needs adjustment.
Fix it please? I think that
compensate for the job.
I did think the Scarlet Lady
for a ride.
We still have a luau that night.
I wonder, how you want to compete
how all that money?
- One way would be to race.
- We temosum boat?
We have three ... but all are in Texas.
And with your salary, is
precisely where they will stay.
Moreover, with the
your bank balance ...
Hold on buddy, is not
trying to prove something to yourself ...
... Without using your money?
Thanks, let's forget all that.
I just had an idea, I know where
I can get a boat!
- For 10 bucks?
- Ten thousand would be more appropriate.
Still, I would not have time
to fix it for the race.
- We can see the boat?
- Sure, come on.
But I mean a
thing to you guys ...
... Spent a lot of time and
money on this boat ...
... The conditions in which it is now
I think just praying no way.
All he needs is
reconstruction and a new engine.
Much money for you Tom
Unless your friend
Here's sponsor.
Well .. my checkbook
is right here.
Just say, that I fill it up.
I'm tempted, but ...
no thanks.
Why so sure ...
that can solve the problem ...
... When my engineers
say it is a hopeless case?
Not sure but ...
I would try.
You know, it has less than 2
weeks until race day?
Of course I know.
And yet both
do it yourself?
Is.
I admire that.
The Orange Bowl regatta has
$ 10,000 as a prize ...
... If you win, we divided
half and half, is that fair?
No kidding, are you?
No son, I'm not.
Hey, what about that buddy?
Okay, where would
working on it?
Well .. at ...
... In store for skis
hotel is good.
Okay, it's all yours.
- Thanks Mr Burton.
- Thanks.
Hey let's move it.
Maybe you can get
before the luau.
- What is the problem?
- You said the magic word.
Luau?
Yeah!
Attention everyone!
Help yourselves while it's hot!
Lobsters, seafood, chicken, shrimp.
And bikinis too!
Luau, let's have a luau
mama's boy
loves a luau
also loves a luau
mama's boy
loves a luau
also loves a luau
Hear me world
you must know
I'm dropping everything
and falling out
Who needs to worry and strife
Life can be a party,
I will change my way of life
Luau, let's have a luau
Search more lights
bright city
is where you will find me,
having fun.
I need this
to be free
I choose and take
the life you want
This is the life for me
Luau, let's have a luau
mama's boy
loves a luau
also loves a luau
mama's boy
loves a luau
Search more lights
bright city
is where you will find me,
having fun.
I need this
to be free
I choose and take
the life you want
This is the life for me
Luau, let's have a luau
mama's boy
loves a luau
also loves a luau
mama's boy
loves a luau
also loves a luau
Luau, let's have a luau
Luau
Hi friend, get a trunk
and join us.
- Still have a lot of food there.
- I can not stand any more.
Hey, tell me one thing.
I saw the boat towing
Burton to the hotel ...
... Will turn it into a ski boat?
Not exactly, I think of
fix it up for the race.
- Are you kidding me!
- Really?
Yes! That thing does not
endured when she was young ...
... And do not improve with patches
made by an amateur.
Well .. what I meant is that he is
doing a bit of his post.
Why do not you do
only you know?
You mean, do not mix.
You could say that.
Well .. thanks for the warning, but
if you please do not follow.
I do not care, it will be good
for laughs.
What about going
a treasure hunt?
- Treasure hunt dear? Where?
- Do not know?
Outside, a pirate ship
sank with many ingots ...
Chocolate?
Gold!
Sank during a hurricane
some 100 years ago.
And still there?
They say that on clear nights,
today, we can even watch it.
They say ...
- You can not ...
- Come I'll show you.
Right.
Hey! This is a good idea.
Why not let us
search for treasure?
Okay.
You should get a girl.
Ask him
has a sister?
Hey come on!
Hello Mr Burton.
I see you are working
more than usual tonight.
Can not help it if we want
those earning $ 10,000.
I would not mind ...
... Put much hope on that boat ...
... After 10 years of trying ...
... Thought I'd get to
drawing that could win.
I think I got the error
is not in the drawing of him ...
What do you mean?
The hull broke because
protective covering gave ...
... Pressure, look, you can
break it with your hands.
And it will happen again.
This is the best resin
I know.
There is nothing more
robust market.
Mr. Burton, do me a favor?
Sure.
Hit as hard as you can.
- Crash?
- Sure, go ahead, knock!
O well!
What happened here?
It's called "GOOP"
this is the abbreviation.
The technical name is longer.
Where'd you get that?
In a place where I worked,
I studied engineering ...
... And worked in a lab
after I graduated.
Helped develop
this hardener.
If it's so good, why
is not in the market?
Not so good.
If exposed to water, turn gelatin
is that exposure time is.
So what's the idea?
The company gave him, not me.
Mr. Burton?
Can I use your lab
for some experiences?
I will work at night, so
I will not disturb anyone.
You. .. think you could
work on it?
I do not know, but I would try.
My wife died long ago
while we have had children ...
... Always felt for
not having a son ...
... I do not feel much.
Just make sure you locked all
before leaving, go to bed.
- Thanks Mr Burton.
- Good evening.
Coffee?
Need more cream and sugar.
What do you call that thing?
- Swingarm.
Distribution.
Carburetor, swingarm.
I know.
I suppose I have to find
Sally on 10 minutes.
- I'd better go.
- You can go.
- Thanks for the help.
-Let it go mate.
I think that from time to time, all
rich man must come down ...
... And work side by side
with their workers.
Very decent of you.
You look kinda tired.
Why does not rest
the rest of the day?
Hey ... listen, I met a beautiful redhead ...
... Would save it for me
but anything for a friend!
No thanks, I am very
laboratory work.
You can check whether
the package arrived yet?
First thing, if you're there,
te mando quickly.
Or in French ... "done."
Hey buddy, there are only four
day for the race.
Yeah, I know, thanks buddy.
- Hi Tom
- Hi Di.
I just saw Sally in the hall
looking for you.
My goodness, this woman
do not leave me alone!
And I love it!
Hi
- How's it going?
- How are you and Jamison?
Okay, I'll find it
docks in a few minutes ...
... And a boat trip to
the club where we will dine.
Sounds pretty romantic.
Elee very romantic.
But its proposals do not
include a marriage.
Do not worry about it.
On a recent night, instead
going to the club ...
... He's gonna ask
to his room.
Will put some soft music ...
... And serve a perfect dinner.
Pheasant caramel ... of course!
And wine.
And dessert, let's see ...
Cherries Jubilee.
And after that ...
... Get there, you're in chat.
Tom, what's the problem?
Nothing.
Okay, I'll see ya.
Come here.
Clean.
Unless Jamison is blind ...
... Maybe he sees the trees,
rather than the forest.
Thank you.
You reached for me
said hello
I could hardly speak
My heart was beating so much
anyone can say
You think you know me well
But I do not know
You do not know that
Who dreams of you tonight
want to kiss your lips
want to hug her tight
I'm just a friend for you
is what will always be
But you do not know me
never met
the art of love
My heart ached
in love with you.
Afraid and shy,
I let the chance go
The chance of you
I also love
You reached for me
said goodbye
I saw you walk away
Beside the lucky guy
never find out
Someone who loved her so much
Now, you dont know me
As director of research
and development ...
... Is a function of my office to explore the
advantages of diversification ...
... However, acquisition
to diversify ...
... Is not a profitable venture.
Therefore, it is my strong recommendation ...
.. Accept the generous offer of
Allied Chemical's ...
... And surrender all searches,
complete or not ...
... Formulas and data
Our ill-fated search ...
... By phosphate oxioctanóico glycolic.
You mean the "GOOP"?
Yes sir, was the
what I meant.
If what was meant, then say,
do not confuse me!
Ohh ... yes sir, no sir.
Mr Hayward ...
... Will return the
bottles you asked for?
I include them in inventory.
You confused me again?
What bottles?
Remember? There are two
Ellie had days ...
... Get the formulas in which
Scott worked before ...
... To leave.
Those ...
Did what?
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Come here and sit,
I want to talk to you.
Do you know where my boy is?
Answer me woman!
Do you know where is my boy?
It's Friday night then you
remain until after midnight ...
... Can not ski all day
and work all night.
I think I'm more
tired than I thought.
I met his friend at the hotel ...
... He told me he was
waiting for that package.
Thanks.
He himself would bring, but
her hands were busy ...
... I think in a Sally,
and in another era, Ginger.
They are the latest formulas when
was working in Hayward.
He worked in Hayward?
Do not remember what I said about the
employment in the lab?
Ohhh yes.
Why she left there, if
do I know?
No, okay, I quit,
at least I think so.
I understand.
I mean, I really do not understand.
One day I'll tell you.
Fair enough, how's it going?
I'll know better when trying to
... a little of that.
Good luck.
- Oh hello Mr Burton.
- Hello Tom
It seems that
need a hand.
- Need 10!
- Where do I start?
Get there in the front.
Just slide the brush,
because it is quite easy to apply.
- This is it.
- Yes it is.
- Do you think this will work?
- I think it will do.
Think? You mean
not tested yet?
I had no time takes 24
hours to harden.
We do not have much
time before the race.
Neither spare time
that could be wrong.
As I said the other day,
must have confidence.
Hello gentlemen, as
everything is going?
You know what time it is?
Partner does not pass inspection.
... Look mate, you had to
be here two hours ago!
Something about "I promise to help"?
Hayward never return
back on his word.
Your obedient servants!
Ladies, line up, I
show what to do
This boat will sparkle like
diamond when finished
By the numbers, not
have much time
Let's start a
assembly line
You get the sandpaper
You take the bucket
Take the hammer baby.
You take the nails.
You take the ink,
you get the brush.
Let's take that
special touch
We have a magic potion
that will help us win
I do not know how to spell,
but only apply
Phosphate oxiotanóico glycolic
is the latest discovery.
But okay, girls,
might call "GOOP"
Stir this   sandpaper,
hammer that nail
Wet   this brush,
Pass the bucket
Get the rhythm
nice and easy
Let  , rubbing and
sanding it is easy
Okay girls, we end
I'll say what we
we do
Let's foot
and have fun
'll kiss you all,
one by one
Cigars ... cigarettes?
Cigars?
Can I help you sir?
- Well how are you ma'am?
- How are you?
- Okay.
- I asked if I can help you.
Ahhh! Yes ..
I suppose I like
some of these cigars here.
I may be wrong, but you
must be the father of Scott.
Hit on the fly!
Of course I am!
You know my boy?
Everybody knows his son.
I see that the two
smoke the same brand.
It is ... what?
My boy has never smoked
a cigar in his life.
He is my best customer.
Ohhh really?
So can you tell me where
it was at this time of day?
I'd say ...
... In four minutes you can
meet him at the bar.
I'll wait for it to pass.
At the bar?
Buying drinks for everyone.
The Florida weather makes things
very strange to people.
He's ... uh ... smoke ...
... And drinking?
Anything else?
It seems that I got
just in time.
Here's sweetness.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
It seems that the father is
always the last to know.
Cigarettes
Cigars?
- How are you?
A lady there in the south wing
said I'd find ...
... A young man named Scott Hayward
Here setup, you know?
She spoke the truth,
is his friend?
We can say that.
Then choose a drink,
on his behalf.
For friends of Hayward,
booze!
What a beautiful phrase.
But it is not uncomfortable, just want to
a dose of your best whiskey.
We can expect
Mr Hayward together.
I know you?
My name is Burton,
the Burton Boat Company.
In three years, his company wanted
swallow mine, remember?
Of course! I remember now.
What happened? Thought
had an agreement.
We had, until his hard head
beat with my stubbornness.
My boy loves boats,
then wanted to give him ...
... As one of its
birthday.
I do not know what he would do.
You appear to have
all it needs.
Money to burn women
lives only for today.
Wait, Mr. Burton,
one minute please ...
... What's wrong
with everyone here?
You know who this is?
Why, certainly, is not
describing my boy.
Seeing is believing.
Well. ... Well and if I knew what
there is to see, maybe I believe.
- Your boy Scott, right there.
- Where?
There! There he is!
- Excuse me.
- Wait a minute ...
... That mean ...
boy is your son?
You bet ... sir.
He is the hotel's ski instructor,
His name is Tom Wilson.
I have no idea what is
drinking cup in there ...
... But one thing
I ceretza ...
... I know my own son.
Mr Hayward, I'd better
a little chat.
After Mr. Burton, if not
I want to care ...
No, now!
It's about your boy.
Let ...
Partner ...
was waiting.
I want to meet someone.
This is Gigi.
Gigi, this is "monsieur" Wilson,
is my best friend.
Although it is poor.
- How are you?
- Enchanted "monsieur" Wilson.
She speaks no English, I
teach you everything I know.
- Oh really?
- About English.
Please join us, Tom
Yes, sit down, we are
very democratic.
Thanks.
- Want to dance?
- Yes.
What says Dianne?
You will love the view
in my suite.
and put a pretty mellow song,
serve a J J Special ...
- ... A breast of pheasant ...
- Caramel?
Sure! And a good wine.
And then, of course ...
... My favorite dessert.
Cherries Jubilee.
How did you guess?
Women's intuition, I
get my purse.
Well, good night all.
See you tomorrow.
If you'll excuse me,
I'm saying goodbye.
Wait a second there.
You know what that means?
Yes, it means "goodbye and good
luck to my head. "
- Tom
- Mr Burton.
- Collecting up early?
- Is.
- Have a good night and sleep well.
- I will try.
- It's not going to check it out on the boat?
- I checked a few hours.
One last time will not hurt.
Never know what you can find,
if very meticulous.
You better take a look,
do it for me.
I'll look.
He knew that entered this
boat race tomorrow.
Father!
- Do you think wins?
- I hope.
One such said Sam Burton
who will share the prize, right?
It's great to see you, Dad.
Do not jump to conclusions.
He also said he did
all the work yourself.
- Is it true?
- Almost all.
Do you think he will
hold this time?
I think.
He is eager to take chances,
go there tomorrow ...
... Maybe kill himself, to find out?
It is, to find out.
Finding out about myself,
see if I can.
You know what Dad?
I would trade all that has
gave me for one thing.
- Why trust me.
- What are you saying son?
I've always trusted, just tried
facilitate things a bit.
That father, do not want to facilitate.
I make my own
errors and fix them ...
... Before you press the shutter button
panic, as it did in the factory.
Well ..
... Enough of this chatter
emergency button on ...
Trust ... and stuff!
Now I will hear a second
young fellow!
His firm spent,
from night to day ...
... 1 million dollars in "GOOP" or
"Gook," or what you call ...
... And we could not
make it work.
And now tell me who will leave
with this boat tomorrow ...
... Win, lose, sinking,
stand if this thing ...
... Then have gone ahead
eprovado something?
That's right!
Let me tell you something,
whether you like it or not.
I want you to know that ...
... I'm so proud of you
as a father who has never ...
... Botado both feet in
that was freaking my God. "
Thank you father.
I think we've solved
this very well, no?
I'm feeling
a little tired.
How about with me
back to my hotel?
We will be glad father.
What a beautiful room!
Very exotic.
Have to be.
It is called the Sultan's suite,
I get it every year.
Where guarding his harem?
Where did you get a
idea like this?
As we ...
I agree that I have acted
middle playboy ...
- Just a little.
- But it's over.
Now .. I need is ...
... The warmth of fellowship ...
.. Escape from loneliness ...
... The simple beauty
What a girl ...
... The right girl can offer.
James ... there's someone knocking at the door ...
Mr Jamison laundry.
- Excuse me for hours, but ...
- Thank you.
I called, but ...
Now ...
- Where were we?
- Escaping loneliness.
Yes, esca ... escaping the loneliness ...
... The simple beauty of a girl ...
... The right girl
can offer.
You've said it.
Here, 26D, Duster.
Am I right?
That's right.
Well son, I will be with
you every step you take.
- You know that right?
- Now I know father.
Thanks.
Good night.
- I need to breathe.
- It's not the reason.
No, it is not.
Dianne .. I mentioned this?
- What gift?
- What should I give you.
It's a little something to ...
use this finger ...
... With about 5 carats.
I'm asking
marry me.
If I knew how
I waited for this moment ...
James, please!
James will have a
big day tomorrow.
And a great night tonight.
- What is it?
- He brought his ski.
- What?
- Get your ski ...
- ... And I would return it.
You know what time it is?
Sure! Gave me 10 bucks so
I thought it would hurry.
James, I'll let it go.
No! N.. N.. No!
Also ...
- I gotta go.
- Go? Why?
- We were just ...
- Just going to say goodnight.
Ohh! Forgive me, I hope
not have come at a bad time.
Actually interrupted.
No Tom, all right, James
and I were just ...
No matter, it will
the first to know ...
Tomorrow we will get a ring ...
... A double celebration ...
... For first win
the race, and second ...
... Will announce tomorrow
our engagement.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
- Thanks for the evening.
- Sweet dreams baby.
You know something?
It has a very bad timing.
Of course we always have losers.
Look, if you're talking about the race ...
I'm talking about putting your
nose where it is called ...
I hope you know ...
take care of itself.
I call it karate!
Shut up!
The girl who never loved
never know I care
All my dreams with her
They are dreams that
never share
I want
And I need her
I know it could have been
But just
Long before you begin
The kiss that never got
Another guy will win
plans ever did
Another guy will do
I'm lonely, so lonely
Why is it that
I'm thinking
But she will always be the girl
What ever loved
never loved
- Hi
- Hello
- I thought you went to bed.
- Well, I was going but ...
Knew it ...
able to sleep.
Is it a surprise, because as Mrs.
James Jamison should fall asleep easily.
Tom .. I mean ... not James
I can marry him.
Anyway, I would
to thank you for your help.
Always at your service.
Well .. good night ...
... And goodbye.
Goodbye?
I come home tomorrow ...
... After the race.
Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen ...
... here is Sam Riddle, giving them
Welcome to Marine Stadium ...
... in beautiful Miami, Florida, where
wait for a test ...
American Association ...
Boats to race ...
... one of the biggest races in the country.
trophy Governor, and yet
$ 10,000 to the winner ...
... The great Orange Bowl regatta.
The teams completed ...
... The latest reviews, all
boats in the water now.
... that means not missing much
now. The fans are coming ...
"Monsieur Hayward!
Grab the popcorn!
Put butter?
Now he wants to calm down?
If my child said
that the "GOOP" Whoa ...
... He can stand.
I would be so
so sure.
Me too!
Hey! Dianne're here!
- One class, one, two, three, sit!
- Thanks.
And now, ladies and gentlemen ...
... is coming to the pilots
the formation lap ...
... approaching the great
bleachers, the Vapor Trail ...
... the boat number 96
Fred Whiting is ...
... and right back at Bad Boy,
Number 13 is Lucky Hugues ...
... then comes James Jamison,
Lady in Scarlet, numéro D3 ...
... this boat is that we should be
eye, ladies and gentlemen ...
he won the last ...
next three events ...
... and is the favorite today ...
... following  Jamison, The boat's Pet
Terry, number 52, with George Gergo ...
... George was second
last year ...
... following  GERCO
Paul Jerrow have ...
... and there's Tom Wilson in
Rawhide, number 99 ...
... is the same boat not
stand the impact of last year ...
... to pressure those hooves
racing is awesome ...
... he literally fell to
pieces to reach 150 km / h. ..
... and the question is whether this shell
experimental reconstructed ...
will hold the same kind ...
impact today ...
... because it seems that new records
Speed will be set ...
Excuse me, I'll be back.
Sure would not linger.
Following is  Glenn Peters
number 77, in Redball Express
Hi Mr. Burton! Good luck today,
I know it will win.
Binoculars Sorry sir, I believe
not have seen this gentleman before.
Then it's time to know,
because you have much in common.
Ahhh it? You're rich too huh?
Well, how are you?
My name is Hayward ...
... Scott Hayward am
of the oil business.
Is it? Very pleased Mr Hayward,
that honor to meet you ...
Also deal with ...
oil is not known.
Take a cigar.
Okay, thanks,
what about taking a mine?
Well thank you ..
for his kindness.
Funny you know ...
... I think I met your daddy.
And you? Know Daddy?
How wonderful!
A great gentleman,
what's your name sir?
My name?
Lord ... I ... I do not believe
who has heard his name.
Ohhh yeah ... Hayward.
Duster ...
W. Hayward ...
Son!
Are you alright boy?
I swallowed my cigar?
Never mind, here
Get one of mine.
No, no, no, you
Duster Buster smoke ... ...
... Get it, I
some cigars ...
... Take all, keep it!
Ohh the race, gotta go!
Bye dad!
Be careful, now
the engine is running!
Now the helicopter
race is coming ...
... is positioning itself for
end of the warmup lap ...
... just missing some
seconds for the race.
Pass me the popcorn.
The last driver ever
positioned for the start ...
... and there they are
Ladies and gentlemen ...
... the cream of hazardous
boat racing ...
are holding the positions ...
4 km past us ...
... and nearing the start,
the director is in the helicopter ...
... so the boats
are positioned ...
... it will trigger the signal
who will start the test.
And there it is
... a clean start
Ladies and Gentlemen
Cobra  wide in front ...
... George is  Gergo
right behind him ...
... and Fred Whiting, in 1996, will
pasted on his back ...
are in the first round and
Cobra maintains its leadership ...
This is Jeff  Cassey, number 15,
trying to force the excess ...
... think about Copper Rourke
and comes right behind Roy Bubbles ...
... approaching ...
and here comes J J Jamison
He can overcome
4 at a time
It comes with everything ...
... surpassed Roberts ...
... is now in fourth place ...
And now the third
... and is coming close to Whiting ...
... and beyond
now tries to ...
near Snake ...
... and does! Lady Scarlet
leads the way
Undoubtedly, J. J. Jamison more
since the emphasis is
The other boats are well
together, no challenge in sight.
There goes the  Rawhide!
Tom Wilson is firm
You float through the ...
... and now out of the turn ...
... he cuts the right and
tries to overcome Whiting ...
... and there it goes!
Rawhide is third
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Come on, come Rawhide!
One more lap and Scarlet Lady
is still in the lead.
Cobra  second ...
Rawhide keeps coming
Let Rawhide!
appears that Jamison wants
sure you do not pass.
will reach the limit.
Wilson goes on
Cobra now.
Will try to
overtake on the straight.
Wilson  decreases the distance ...
... closer ...
closer ... and beyond
Wilson is now in second,
behind Lady Scarlet.
The last lap
exceeded 150 km / h.
same speed over
Rawhide with last year.
The question is: will
history repeat itself?
Jamison keeps
same speed.
Wilson continues
on his back.
Come on!
Wait a minute! It seems that Wilson
is having some kind of problem.
Scarlet Lady  increases your advantage
Rawhide is located on the front and back.
Cobra takes second place.
Wilson seems to have
solved the problem.
Recovers your speed now.
will exceed the Cobra.
back into second place
Beware! Jamison should
be about 160 kph!
It forces the boat to the extreme
and Wilson want to stay with him,
must impose the same pace.
Remember, it is the same
hull broke ...
last year with ...
much less speed.
Can the hull reconstructed
stand this year?
Backing,
Ladies and gentlemen ...
... if Rawhide withstand pressure ...
can handle everything ....
The question now is: can he
achieve Scarlet Lady
there are less than two laps
Entering the final lap,
Jamison continues to lead.
Come on Tom!
Rawhide, go, go!
are exiting the last corner,
the banner is ready.
Come, come friend!
Come on, come on!
And he does!
Rawhide wins
We have a new champion
Ladies and gentlemen ...
... a true champion!
Tom Wilson in his first race ...
... steals the victory of the man who
won here the past 3 years
Congratulations to Tom Wilson!
The award
will be tonight ...
... In the great hall of the Hotel Shores.
You did it!
Got it!
Man that boat!
To see you ripping up the last curve,
I swore that you were born for this!
Time of celebration!
Yeah!
His father is really proud.
Need to see it distributed cigars
as a first-time parent ...
... And bragging.
And Sam Burton said ...
... The "GOOP" will be the most successful
market, since their bikinis.
- Your health friend.
- On your own, buddy.
Something wrong?
No, I'm just
expecting a call.
You may have to receive
trophy at dinner tonight.
Now wait a minute!
No sir, no! You won
the trophy and will welcome you!
He proved what he wanted, it's time to
back to being what we are.
Also, I wonder if
Sally loves me for who I am or ...
... For your money.
I know what you
I mean, friend.
She's ready to go now!
Thanks Harold, to hold there.
Give me the keys.
- What's happening?
- I'll explain later.
- Now wish me luck!
- You are desired.
Thanks buddy.
Harold can please hurry?
I need a taxi.
Never been to Connecticut?
No, a taxi!
Does it have to go? A taxi?
- There it is!
- Taxi Miss?
Jump up, take you where you want to go,
courtesy of Scott Hayward.
Wish you did not
go away today.
In these circumstances I think is better.
And I expected to get
help to spend the prize.
Thanks, but should retain
money and not spend it with me.
Too late, already spent!
Tom!
Tom Wilson you have to
return this ring to the store!
Does that mean
marry me?
I mean, not
we, I mean ...
... This ring would pay the rent
a year plus expenses, plus ...
So you're saying that
marry me?
Of course I'll marry!
Dianne, I must confess something.
- About what?
- About my family.
I'm marrying you,
not with his family.
Well .. about me being
ski instructor.
Look dear, listen ...
... With winning and with the
I win, we'll be okay ...
... Just can not afford
stuff like this ring ...
... The more I
wished we could.
You see that
oil field there?
Got a tenfold
when I was 21 years.
Ten times?
You see that yacht?
I won one just like the
my last birthday.
You know what I think?
I think I drive the car of Scott
're doing you have delusions.
That's what I'm saying.
- What?
- It's who I am.
Who?
I'm Scott Hayward.
And I'm Fiegledopper Hortense,
wants to talk seriously, please?
Look .. see for herself.
Well, it all started on the way here,
I stopped at this restaurant ...
... Where I met Scott ...
Tom, Tom the real ..
Dianne ... Dianne, are you okay?
Sorry to be rich.
If I said something that hurt you.
I swear I can explain everything.
Like I said, I stopped in
one of my posts ...
I mean ... our posts ...
... And while I fill the tank,
I went to get coffee and a sandwich ...
... That's where I met Scott,
or rather, Tom ..