What to do for land?
Your son is with us
Bring 10 lacs and come to
Verma factory
this boy name is manish gupta and
he is a son of chetan gupta
kidnappers has asked 10 lacs
ransom money
this city is strange
what happen?
Its a mess
they did not find anyone else
except chulbul to transfer here
brother did not get transfer,
he took transfer himself
what big works?
You are crying because of your father
he is taking time in bringing money
what are yous saying?
We are workers of chulbul pandey
sir will come from that side
my name is chulbul pandey
government give me job to maintain
laws
its between you and me
recommend me some idea so that
boy will also enjoy
first i take your kiss and
then i beat them
what is your father name?
Chetan gupta
you are sitting here?
Dont worry about chulbul sir
our sir is Kung Fu Panda
who is calling?
Its looking old.
Give it to chaubay
you can give it to killer but
you cannot give it to saver
he is not lazy like you
you can hire a detective for me
but you cannot hire bodyguard for son
he is robin hood pandey
I can also see it
so that they will not run away
how is your son?
Give my love to him
I think you like Kanpur
I'm police officer's wife,
I have to manage everywhere
some other people also come with
us from Laal Ganj
is everything ok?
This news disturbed me
I got 10 lacs as a award. I gave 2 lacs
to police and 8 lacs is for me
I have bought peanuts for you
what?
You were sleeping?
I disturb you
why you always disturb him?
Yes but after 4 whistles
control your feelings
she will not come
I told Nirmala brother got transfer in
kanpur come with us
she said I will stay here for my
father
I said why?
I will take care of my father
I have bought zeus phone for you
thanks.
Now I can contact you
let me listen this song
are you forgetting something?
I'm prajapati pandey
we have to go to SP sir office
he wants to meet you.
He is a funny guy
you are spoiling reputation of police
lets see how funny is SP
I love pizza
I eat pizza atleast 2 times in a week
company says if delivery is 30 mins
late then delivery is free
my officer engaged him for 10 mins
I'm happy from your kidnapping case
if anyone do good work then I like it
thats why I'm doing less work
and saving more money
you eat sir
you dont worry we are not
scared of anyone
I will come for hearing
why you are in hurry?
Please forgive us
make me your lover
your work is done
for few days you go out from
this city
they decided to send me to jail
new inspector is very famous
he saved childrens from gangsters in 3 hours
he killed cheddi.
We are lucky that we are saved
he is less inspector and
more business man
he has come to city to increase
his business
yes we are playing game
they are so many cases on them
your publice is so weak. Because of
bacha brother we cannot arrest them
we should kill them
they are disturbing us and
civilians since 5 to 6 years
you were getting hernia operation
what about it?
You will not welcome me?
What police will say for accident?
Sharma got a call that some people
are planning for robbery
our sir is very kind hearted
we covered them and told them
to surrender
what do you want?
Our police officer could have died
what are you thinking?
If police will decrease then who
will take care of you?
I know this police officer,
there must be a plan behind it
you have become headline of this city
tell me 1 thing both shooters were bacha
brother's man and they killed shiv bala
why you did not tell this to media?
My experience is also same
but atleast bacha would get
some pressure
who is the MLA?
What happen?
You did not sleep?
You also think I miss Nirmala
then you have to prove it.
I ask you a riddle, you have to give answer
who come back?
Its a difficult riddle, it will take time
its a very hard question
chulbul asked you riddle,
why I give answer?
I will never do mistake again
he will get bail
I think he is gone.
Bring biryani for him and beat him
what happen?
Why are you creating wild environment?
Go there. If I teach you then
you will get big loss
I remember 1 thing,
chunni is a male name or female name?
Then why are you doing this acting?
Marry someone and make
him daddy
for our children's bright future
from chaubay
now chulbul pandey will entertain us
give me chance to serve you
by letting me win this election
he is saying to serve people and
here is gangsters are forcing to give vote
he is a old criminal
he teach peole politics
he is chulbul pandey
i messed with 4 police officers
i thought lets listen to you too
SP and chulbul pandey both are coming here
if any problem then go into his house
and kill him
tell him my name then he will
know who M I?
Before going to bar,
we find out who is dancer?
Your father has done 3 mistakes,
including you
your father died from dengue
and your mother died from its
happiness
further knowledge is secret that
I cannot reveal
why are you going in
that deep?
Its not a small thing
when everyone will be bigger than us,
then how we will survive?
Thats why I'm here since 15 years
I have decided to kill him
if you cannot sleep then
tell me
I met your mother in a wedding
she dropped tea plate on me
I was staring at her
then I talked to your Patna aunty
she talked to your mother then your
mother agreed
after marriage when you dropped me at
aunty's home, which movie you went to see?
Respect your mother
mother was right there is no
enjoyment in sleeping with you
hey my love
you will not leave this?
You are my wife,
not a slave
when I give you orders,
take actions against it
where are you going?
Come in car
we serve old people
we will drop you at home with respect
your son chulbul pandey
he has created problem for us
my brother is not doing anything
what is urgency?
You are not alone police officer
bacha should not do anything
to our family
my brother money is transferred
this time its transferred very fast.
Last time it took 5 days
leave my way
i have heard you are doing
wedding drama at home
wild dogs has increased in money
let me complete
she is getting married and a person
said he will kidnap her. His name is genda
I say sorry for this
in which war you participated?
Your fight worked for you and
for me too
why you stop music?
Groom has come
why you have come?
Chulbul pandey has come
do you know who M I?
Here everything is me
I'm behaving very calmly
he cannot control his emotions
why you want to die?
You will slap my father?
Happy marriage
you are upset since 2 days and you
are giving me tension
I dont like it to make you sad.
But I have to do in police job
if you want then I will
leave this job
this is called crime
my brother is killed and
i want revenge
i will investigate about it
I come here to say I
will take revenge
I'm not cheddi singh,
I'm bacha singh
you will regret why you got
transfer in kanpur?
I dont know about me but you will regret
why I got transfer to kanpur
eat all
do you work or not?
You dont sleep
every wife has complaint that her
husband sleeps
and you complaint that her
husband never sleeps
then I will go to my father
your father died for your happiness
now you have to take care of her
I want to ask you a personal question
you are shivering
I want to talk to you
I have put a request for your transfer
I know bacha very well
you have family and now you
are becoming a father
if anything happen to you then
what will happen with them?
Please sign here
i have done my insurance and
you are my nominee
I do police job. Anything can
happen to me. Why are you saying this?
I can beat 100 bacha in 1 time
genda's soul is still not in peace
and we are discussing here
you are not understanding
control yourself
I call media and tell chulbul is great
tell them my brother deserve this?
I respect police action
no matter he is a brother of
MP or CM
it means pandey is right
i want to congratulate pandey
its not my political benefit,
its for my soul peace
i have done my insurance,
you also do it
i dont understand this game.
An officer kill our brother
i cannot do this
my father came in my dream
what are you thinking?
I had a dream you give me respect
your wife still not come back
and you are thinking of her
who has come?
Give some food to him
your cousin is same like nirmala
you have engaged yourself
somewhere else?
I have come back from jungle
did you get any problem?
Why you come only for 2 days?
What you will do with teacher training?
I will do job and earn money
you only love me
i also want to do something
i want to join police and make
name like you
i have lots of guts
i will not give you chance to
complaint
do something.
Any doubt?
I enjoyed it
any special plan for tonight?
Send payment in the evening
you did not go in funeral?
He was your brother
what you have done?
You love us alot.
We never missed father
if father would alive today,
then pandey would be dead
you did not come in sitting,
if you cannot manage then leave it
resignation?
It will take time
go for work later
first drop me to temple
i did not marry with makhi,
everytime you say go with makhi
i will come after lunch
what you have asked?
Make me uncle fast
he said he will come on time
he killed my brother and
increasing his family
pandey your wife has given a birth
to beautiful baby
he killed our baby
I'm badly hurt
do really bad with him so that he will
remember what he has done
i promise from today they will
never become father
today you will realize why i should
not get transfer to kanpur
pandey is very dangerous
you think i will leave pandey?
We will cut him into small pieces
you sit and watch drama
he will think why he come
to this world and fight with bacha?
Did you get hurt?
I told you pandey is very dangerous
hit as much you can tolerate
why are you killing him?
If he will alive then he will be famous
give me handcuffs
its for few days only.
I will come back
i remember 1 thing,
you hurt my wife
what you have done?
Atleast inform me
who has done holes in you?
Bring him to hospital
and ask him where is money otherwise
make 2 more holes in it
now kanpur will be in peace
i want holidays to bring my wife overseas.
I want to make you uncle
open eyes I'm your father
you scared me
he also dont like your compliment
i have a family now.
And a grand son too
you are having tea alone?
Last night mother came in my dream
she told me to call you verbatim
she said if you like her then
marry her
thank you
you eat it.
I go and kill him