- Kashiram!
- Yes Madam!
Have you packed
Prince's bags?
Did you pack his warm clothes
too? It must be cold there.
Don't worry!
I've packed everything!
Check the things carefully!
Alright, Madam!
It's time for the Tilak
and Ravi hasn't come yet!
Munshi! Call the station master
and instruct him to hold the train.
He's so undisciplined!
You cheat! You pretend to
love me as you're leaving now!
Please apply vermilion
on his forehead!
His face bears
a special radiance!
That's the reason
he's popular!
- I'm late, shall we go?
- You must...
Take care of yourself
on reaching there.
I don't trust you.
Out of sight, out of mind!
The whole house wears a
deserted look in your absence.
In that case I won't go.
I'll cancel the show!
lf you care for your mother,
get married soon!
Brides aren't available
in the market, Mom!
She is a doll as far as
this house is concerned!
- When will you bring her?
- During this trip, perhaps.
- In a wink!
- I hope so!
But you must promise me not
to faint after seeing her.
I promise...to faint!
- You take care of yourself too.
- Bye!
Uncle has come too!
Where are you heading to?
To Sundernagar!
Bless me, Uncle!
- God bless you!
- Bless me, aunty!
I've got to perform at a concert
there. I take your leave now.
- Bless me, sister-in-law!
- Bye, son!
- Narendra! - Yes.
- Get those files! - Sure!
Ravi is the crown prince!
He has to manage this
huge Empire, right?
But he seems to
neglect everything!
Music doesn't suit
our family, sister-in-law!
Ravi is immature yet!
He will understand
everything gradually.
Moreover, music is
only his hobby.
But our honour is at stake!
Calm down, brother!
You've got to sign
a few documents!
- I see! - These documents
pertain to the Jungle!
These are details of the
material we've supplied!
And these are the new tenders
that have been passed recently.
I trust you.
Where do I have to sign!
- Please read them at least once.
- You must read them, aunty.
Else, Papa may transfer all
the property to his name.
It will only prove beneficial,
even if I do so.
- Sign here! - I look
forward to Ravi's marriage!
I'll go on a pilgrimage once
Ravi settles down in life.
Ravi will
automatically take...
Wealth is fascinating indeed!
One is never content!
He craves for more and more!
You've involved me too
in this sinful deed!
If Queen Mother learns
of the truth, we'll be doomed!
You know that I fear
death, don't you?
Don't worry, Chintamani!
Anxiety is as good as a pyre!
But I'm making
arrangements for...
...that old woman and
her son's funeral pyre.
As it is all the properties
are being transferred...
...to my son's name,
gradually.
Once the formalities
are completed...
Mother and son
will be finished!
I am only her step
brother-in-law after all!
You don't know how one feels
when one is a step-brother.
I've tolerated
all the injustice!
I shall avenge every insult!
I shall ruin the entire family!
Thereafter, I shall
rule the Empire!
I shall rule the Empire!
He was the Queen's
faithful servant!
He died an unnatural death!
I think jovial people like you
reside in Sundernagar!
Thanks for the compliment!
But only an artiste can
recognize another artiste!
- Are you an artiste too?
- Yes!
I'm Devdas, the all rounder!
I write lyrics and compose
music for them and sing as well.
Hear me folks
You have a sweet voice indeed!
Shall I sing a song for you?
What have you done?
Be careful!
I was engrossed in your tune!
Strange!
- Had the vehicle skid...
- There would be a program...
...but of a different type!
Please proceed
to the guest house!
Strange indeed!
I've unloaded your luggage!
I think I must beware of you!
How long will you
beware of me, Sir?
I've transformed my wife
from Paro to Chandramukhi!
Are you a magician as well?
Maidens living here tend to cast
a magical spell on people around!
- Are you married? - No! - You
can't escape their clutches then.
- What do you mean?
- Don't meddle with these things...
You mind only your business.
You'd better not venture out!
lf you move out, a pretty maiden
will cast a magical spell on you.
Are you explaining to me
or scaring me?
Are you trying to understand
or are you scared?
Your rest house is very
comfortable, Mr. Devdas!
Amitabh Bachchan too said
the same thing!
I'll come to fetch you
at 7:00, sharp!
You may relax,
I take your leave now!
I'll come at 7:00!
Seven friends
standing in a row
Demanding tickets
I told you that tickets
aren't available!
Kajal! You won't gain anything
by jingling these anklets!
People are quarrelling for tickets
as though there's an election!
May you be cursed!
Why do you say so?
- She's your only niece, right?
- I'm her only uncle, right?
- What's the connection between
the 2? - They're connected.
You claim to be
an influential man,...
...can't you arrange for
a few tickets for her sake?
- Aren't you ashamed?
- Why should I be ashamed?
Do I have to arrange for
tickets to prove my identity?
I said that tickets aren't
available and I mean it!
I can't arrange for the tickets
even at the cost of my life.
I'll kill you!
Hey devil! Have you
taken it seriously?
Calm down! I shall
try my best!
I shall arrange for the tickets
at the cost of my job!
Oh uncle!
I won't hesitate even to resign
for the sake of your love!
I shall form a Drama
company instead!
But promise me, you will
work for me, won't you?
- Promise me!
- I suspect foul play!
My name is Chandramukhi,
after all!
And you're the cause
of my miseries as well!
I'm in a dilemma...
...whether to
accept you or not
Should my heart throb
for your sake?
You're the girl of my dreams
and sweet memories
l shall certainly find you
You're a fragrant flower
You're a poet's delight
You bear an innocent face
You resemble the moon
You are worthy of praise
Your looks are bewitching
You're the epitome of beauty
The day I catch sight of you
l wonder what it will lead to
l shall hold you in my eyes
And in my arms as well
l shall make you
the queen of my heart
My heart craves for you
Please make way!
Please excuse me!
What should we do, Kajal?
Don't worry!
I'll do wonders!
I'll kill him!
Oh God! I'm dead!
Stop!
Who are you?
What have you come here for?
- Speak up, else...watchman!
- I'll kill you.
- Will you kill me?
- Why did you threaten me then?
What have you come
here for then?
It's a good way
to get an autograph!
l attended your show as well,
but people surrounded you, so...
What's your name?
Is it the kohl women
apply in their eyes...
...or the one that's used to
cast the evil spell away?
- Both!
- Both!?
- What should I write?
- Anything nice!
Happy?
When you come the next time...
What happened?
My leg is sprained.
- Sprain?
- It's paining me!
- How will I get back home?
- Home!?
I'll take you home!
Come on! Take care!
Take care! Where do you live?
- There! - Where? - Near the
hillock, next to the big tree.
Below Choturam's house and
next to Moturam's bungalow!
My maternal uncle, Devdas'
home is situated there.
- Mr. Devdas!? - Yes.
- Oh I see!
So, you're Devdas'
niece, right?
Everyone in Sundernagar
is like that, right?
- Like what?
- Foolish!
- Shut up!
- Guide me to your home!
I'll get a heart attack.
He was so close!
- Now he's gone so far.
- How lucky she is!
One need not look
into the mirror
It reflects one's age
- Uncle!
- What's the matter?
- What's wrong with my child?
- What happened, Kajal?
Will you have mercy on me too?
Guide me to her room so that
I can lighten this burden!
- I'll kill you.
- Don't threaten me!
- Show me!
- What should I show?
- Her room.
- Follow me!
Please come!
Please put her on this bed.
Please put her on this bed!
Will you tell me
what the matter is?
I went on a stroll to
the hill-top and slipped...
- I hope you aren't hurt!
- I am hurt!
You've done what
Vibhishan did to Sudama.
Not Vibhishan, Sudama!
- That's what I meant!
- You chat while I serve tea.
Hurry up!
It's your picture!
Kajal is your ardent fan!
She sings songs
composed by you!
You must take good care of
yourself for a few days!
I'll take care
of my reflection.
It's very difficult, dear!
- It costs a fortune!
- Is anything left?
What's wrong with me?
My neighbour answers me...
...when I question my wife.
And now that I ask Kajal,
you're answering me instead!
- Was that a joke?
- No!
- Please have tea.
- Did you prepare only one cup?
- You may...- You have it,
it's special.
How long do you intend
to stay here?
My mother says that witches
reside in hilly areas.
- Hence, I plan to leave
tomorrow. - Not possible.
You may come whenever you please,
but you can't leave as you please.
- Right? - Right!
- Absolutely!
Only an artiste can recognize
another artiste, right?
Am I right?
Remember, whenever you look
at yourself in the mirror,...
...someone else too
is looking at you.
`You're my desire!'
`l wish to hear my name
from your lips!'
`l wish to breathe through
your fragrant hair'
`And I wish to see my picture
in your kohl filled eyes'
`I've gathered the courage to
write to you now. Yours, Ravi'
`My dear Kajal, you're
the light of my eyes'
`You're the fragrance
of the night...
...and the brightness
of the eve'
When will you see me?
When shall we meet?
When will you address me?
I've booked Ravi's ticket
thrice and cancelled them too...
...Ravi doesn't seem to
intend leaving the place.
l must say, this place
is mesmerizing.
I too was trapped by you
in a similar manner, right?
- May you be doomed! - Where
are you heading to, Bahadur?
- Sir!
- What's all this?
- A love letter!
- For whom? - For Madam!
What nonsense is this?
A fragrant love letter!?
What are you up to, Chandramukhi?
Are you bent on
tarnishing my image?
What nonsense are you talking?
Are you out of your senses?
- My reward! - You want a
reward, don't you? Take this.
I'm doomed! My image
has been tarnished!
- I'm doomed!
- What are you blabbering?
Why don't you read the letter
first? Who will write to me?
You're right! Hold this!
Who will write
a letter to you?
It's time for you
to get a telegram.
Am I right?
What are you laughing for?
Whose letter is it?
You won't understand!
I'll explain to you.
Where are you, my dear?
My dear child!
Do you love Ravi?
Is this true?
What's the truth?
- Who's opened a flower
shop here? - Is it true?
Answer me!
- Hey!
- Why don't you answer me?
I'll answer you, dear!
Ravi loves Kajal!
Kajal too loves him!
But this isn't a suitable pair.
They're rich while we're poor.
- I don't approve of it!
- You're so narrow minded.
Only one artiste can identify
another artiste!
- Am I right?
- Yes.
- I'll kill you.
- I'm dead!
Listen!
`My songs are incomplete
and so is my breath'
`My life is meaningless'
`l long to see you'
`Please have mercy on me'
My love!
Stop!
My eyes are filled
with tears of joy.
They're drops of
nectar and not tears!
They're glittering
like the dew!
You're the apple of my eye.
My heart yearns for you...
...it longs to see you
Oh my love...
...I love only you
Oh my dear...
...you are dear to me
as well
l love only you
l dream not anymore!
Now that you reside
in my eyes
You are by my side
every moment
You reside in my heart
l trust your every word
You're the one I dreamt of
You're my heart throb
I'm your admirer
I'm lost in the world of love
You mean the world to me
What did you ask for, Ravi?
- You tell me first.
- You say it first.
You must say it first.
I...asked...
Love knows no religion.
Nor does it crave for words.
I know what you asked for.
You're my present
and my future as well.
I'll follow your
footsteps blindly.
Your destination will be
mine as well.
I grant my love to you today.
- Sonu!
- Say it again!
You must address me
by that name always!
lf you address me as Kajal, I'll
think that you've disowned me.
Where had you been
for so long?
I was at home as my leg
got sprained.
- Was your leg sprained or your
heart? - I'm saying the truth.
- But your eyes reflect
a different story. - What!?
You're in love
It's not fair on your part
to have forgotten us!
- Whom are you talking about?
- Your guest will preside...
...our Annual Function.
And Kajal will dance
in his presence!
- That's right. - I won't
dance in his presence.
And why should he
be the Chief guest?
Won't he heed to his
dear sisters-in-law?
Won't our brother-in-law
heed to us?
- Where were you?
- I was waiting for you.
- Why didn't we meet earlier?
- You never thought of me so.
My eyes reflect your love.
- And your face.
- That's a lie.
- How can I reside in your
eyes? - Don't you believe me?
- Look into my eyes then!
- Oh God!
You're right! I do
reside in your eyes.
What sort of a magic is this?
Initially, I too
was surprised,...
...but I realized it the
moment I got close to you.
In that case, we'll remain
close to each other, forever.
Close, right!?
What are you up to?
Stop! Where are you
heading to?
I won't spare you!
- I'm trapped!
- What's the matter?
- They're approaching us.
- Who?
My friends are approaching us.
Please don't heed to them.
Please refuse
to heed to them.
She's gone!
Our Annual function is
scheduled for today...
...and fortunately,
you're here, so we wish...
...that you grace
the occasion.
- We'll be honoured!
- Actually...
- Didn't she mention this
to you? - No!
- Haven't you understood yet?
- How could l?
She dances to your tunes,
doesn't she?
Your darling is about
to arrive.
Am I right?
How will I dance without
my spectacles?
I can't see him either!
`One doctor and a
hundred patients!'
We've been eagerly
awaiting your arrival.
You shouldn't have entered
through the back door.
l wanted to meet you all, first.
I wanted to surprise you all.
I heard that you're
a good dancer.
But I thought you made
others dance to your tunes.
Then I consoled myself saying
that one who makes others dance...
...will create a sensation
by dancing herself.
Won't you say something?
A restless soul can rest
in peace, only when...
When you cast a magical
spell by your dance!
Look, your anklet
understands my language.
But you fail to understand!
Oh these anklets!
Take me along, dear
Hold my hand dear
Oh these anklets
Your anklets are
noisy...
...and mesmerizing
Oh your anklets
My anklet sings a song
...and draw you close to me...
Your dream filled eyes
and your words...
...make my day, but
disturb me during the night!
How will I narrate
my plight to you?
l remember not weeks,
months or years
It's a bond of love
The jingle of your anklets
sound like my heart beats
My anklet bears your name
You mean the world to me
l wish to take the place
of these anklets...
...and have the privilege
of adorning your feet
l dread this sight
I'm nervous
Serve some steaming hot Rotis.
- I'm coming.
- Hurry up!
What's the matter, Kajal?
- Answer me!
- Did Ravi say something?
He's leaving!
You're responsible for
everything!
You don't have a foresight.
Why did he get involved with her
if he intended to cheat her?
How will she live
in peace now?
You consider life a stage too!
You take life for granted.
You don't bother about
the consequences.
l take your leave, Devdas!
I wanted to meet you and thank
you for all that you've done...
...before I could leave
I shall be indebted
to you forever!
I'll leave now!
Kajal is not to be seen!
- I wanted to meet her too.
- Mr. Ravi!
What more do you have to say?
Have you come to inquire...
...about her after
having hurt her?
Have you come to see
whether she is heartbroken?
Why did you make a promise when
you didn't intend to fulfil it?
I didn't expect you to do this.
She has been weeping
the whole night!
Why are you punishing us
for no reason at all?
I'll kill you!
Uncle! Make arrangements
for our marriage.
I shall take Sonu
along with me!
I told you that only an artiste
can recognize another artiste.
You suspected Ravi
unnecessarily.
- There's lots of work to be
done. Let's go! - Let's go!
How would I go without you?
You seem to be
extremely happy today!
Bangles adorn my hand!
You must wait for
a while, dear
- Hello Mom!
- Hello Ravi!
- It's so long since
you left home. - I'm fine!
I'm bringing home a gift which
will take you by surprise!
- I'm hearing, son! - I've
got a surprise gift for you.
It's a suspense! The lines
are bad, bye!
I know what the gift is!
I'm your mother after all...
...no one can understand you
better than me!
Munshi! Prince is bringing home
a surprise gift.
Kajal! My dear child!
My dream has been fulfilled!
Ravi! You must fill my dear
Kajal's life with joy!
Welcome, daughter-in-law!
Madam! Daughter-in-law
has arrived!
- Don't uncover your face!
- How will I see then?
You may look through my eyes!
I'll shut my eyes then!
Come!
May God bless you!
You've filled my life
with happiness, son!
I wish to shower all
the wealth on you?!
Invite one and all. Let people
witness this sight!
Congratulations Sir!
- What's all this?
- Prince is married!
You won't succeed in your plan!
You scoundrel! You gladly
announce a bad news too!
What are you doing?
Let him go!
People are watching!
Look dear! I'll immerse
this ring in the water and...
...the two of you
must try to recover it.
One who wins this game will
be a winner all his life.
- Try you best, son!
- I'll win, aunty!
- Are you ready?
- Yes!
What's this? This is unfair!
Alright! You may play now!
Pick it up, daughter-in-law!
Bravo! She has won!
Congratulations!
To you too! Welcome!
- I'm annoyed with you!
- Annoyed!? With me?
Of course! You've taken
a major decision...
...without even consulting me.
You've alienated me, haven't you?
- You're annoyance is justified
but Ravi is the culprit!
- Bless me, uncle! - Bless him!
- God bless you, child!
He is your uncle!
Seek his blessings!
God bless you, child!
May you lead
a prosperous life!
Sister-in-law!
I'm extremely happy!
I'm relieved!
I wish brother was alive!
We've endured joy
after a long span!
Let's celebrate!
Let's have fireworks!
I'm engrossed in your thoughts
I'm lost in your memories
I've entrusted my life to you
I've accepted you
Love happens only once
l love only you, my dear
l owe my life to you
I wonder from where the
scoundrel has brought that scum.
But you blessed her too, Papa!
You blessed her with a
prosperous life, didn't you?
One must add fuel to the
fire to keep it burning!
The house can be set aflame
with the help of the fire!
I too have flicked a spark
from that fire!
All I'm waiting for, is
the right opportunity.
All my efforts
have been futile!
I'd planned to ruin
the entire clan.
But they're planning
to continue with it!
Papa! A rotten fruit
is always discarded!
I too shall tarnish her image!
She will be relieved of it
only after death!
I've to send a few
documents to Mumbai,...
...you must sign them
immediately.
Thereafter, I'll visit
the temple.
- Do we have to leave at once?
- Yes, I've fixed an appointment.
But I wanted to take
Sonu to the jeweller!
You may take her later!
I haven't stopped you!
I'll take you
the moment I return!
Hello brother-in-law!
Brother-in-law!?
Who are you?
Where have you come from?
With whose permission have
you entered this home?
Will you reign this palace?
Will you bear a child?
No one will come
to your rescue today!
You will bear my child
and not his!
This very moment!
Sonu, you!
What happened Sonu?
Brother-in-law
misbehaved with me.
What?!
Till today, no one dares
to see our daughter-in-law...
...and you tried to touch
her with your dirty hands.
Ravi, beat him!
Virendra Pratap,
take him from here.
I gave shelter
to this venomous snake.
He tried to misbehave
with our prestige,...
...I would have killed him,
if you have not served for us.
Take him from here.
I should not see him
anymore in this city.
Why did you spare this rogue?
Why?!
Why didn't you kill him?
How will I face the world?
At whom mercy I was
living all my life...
...what did you
gave them in return?
Which family do you hail from?
Move! Tell me.
You scoundrel!
Get lost from here.
Oh God!
How cruelly they had beaten you!
Is this the way
to beat anyone?
It's good that you came on the
right time or else...
...your chapter would
have been come to an end.
Chapter is now going
to begin, Chintamani.
Ravi has not raised
his hand on my son.
But he had provoked my anger.
He had sparked the fire
which was doused.
She was about to kill my son,
now I will ruin all her family.
Now you can see
the real destruction.
Please hurry. Now you
are married to me...
...it's enough getting ready.
Why are you in so hurry?
Your train is not going to leave.
Take care of yourself.
I will take good care
of myself and her too.
I will show your daughter-in-law
our whole estates...
...and will be back
before evening.
- Don't worry about us.
- Okay.
We take your leave.
- Hello mother!
- Ravi!
Mother, I am calling
from farm-house.
Weather is very bad,
it's raining very heavily.
Ravi speak louder,
I can't hear you properly.
I am calling from farm house.
Here weather is very bad,
and it's raining very heavily.
We will be returning
till tomorrow morning.
- How is my daughter-in-law?
- She is very fine.
Ravi, I feel very scared.
Thank god, for this weather,
so that she will embrace me.
- I will kill you.
- Then, come on kill me.
Because of this gestures,
l fall in love with you
When you embraced me,...
When you embraced me,
l got relived
Because of this gestures,
l fall in love with you
This wet weather...
This romantic nights...
Only your name on my lips
Fire in my heart,
and it's very cool outside
l am going crazy
l see only you and your
fragrance everywhere
Your beauty has enhanced
for the first time
Because of this gestures,
l fall in love with you
When you embraced me,
l got relieved
Because of this gestures,
l fall in love with you
The weather is...
...very romantic
The evening too...
l had engraved your
images in my heart
l feel like loving you
l will love only you,
and I can't live without you
First time I got
this beautiful moments
Because of this gestures,
l fall in love with you
When you embraced me,...
l got relieved
Because of this gestures,
l fall in love with you
- Because of this gestures,
- I fall in love with you
T ell me one thing, Sonu.
Why do girls take
so much time to get ready?
We men get ready very fast.
Wear shirts and pants and ready.
And why do you girls take...
- No!
- No...!
Come on, chase them.
Ravi, are you alright?
Sonu, you please go from here.
I will stop them.
No Ravi, I can't leave you
in this condition.
- Don't be stubborn.
- No.- I said go.
No.....!
Father!
Who?!
Who is there?
Daughter-in-law, what happened?
Where is Ravi?
Why don't you speak?
Speak dear!
I am asking you where is Ravi?
Killed him.
Everyone killed him.
Yes.
Are you in your senses?
Do you know what are you talking?
Are you in your senses, dear?
No, Ravi.
You can't leave me and go.
You can't!
Oh god, you can't do this to me.
Don't you feel pity to
snatch a widow's son?
You should bring my son alive.
You should!
See!
She is just got married.
She hasn't seen her
married life.
O my dear!
You sinner! Do you
think that you can escape?
I will say the
truth to the world.
You can only say when you can
escape from this palace.
I have just seen my
son's corpse.
This palace has
seen many celebrations.
Many celebrations!
It will face a downfall too.
There will be a disaster.
I will light your pyre.
Take them and lock them.
Virendra Pratap, remember one thing
one can't escape from God.
One day you will pay
for your sins.
You will pay for all your sins.
Pardon me, sister-in-law.
Forgive me.
Forgive me!
Lust of money got me
involved in this sins.
But, they will kill him...
...I didn't expect that
they will kill the prince.
What had happened
sister-in-law?
Hurry up.
Let's escape from this city
before any calamity happens.
Hurry up.
Come on, daughter-in-law.
Come on.
We will go far
away from this city.
Search every nook and corner.
That three lives
shouldn't escape.
Sister-in-law, this big
tragedy had happened...
...and you didn't inform me?
What to tell Sharmaji,
Our ancestors palace has ruined.
You trusted
Virendra Pratap blindly.
What would I have done?
Ravi was a child that time.
I thought that he will take
the responsibility when he grow up?
But...
Time snatched my son from me?
Don't worry, sister-in-law.
I will have Virendra Pratap
punish for his sins.
No, brother. I've to protect
whatever I'm left with.
Remember one thing,
that you are not alone.
I am there to help you.
l laughed a lot. See, tears
have come in my eyes.
These are not merely tears,
they are tears of joy...
...that are shining like
dew on your cheeks.
You are my life.
Ravi, I am feeling scared.
Thank god, for this weather,
for bringing her close to me.