We won't leave this place.
It's not just a jungle.
It's our home.
I have lost my papa.
Now I don't want to lose my home.
Time please, dad. Time please.
That's it. Give up?
- No chance.
Exactly. You stand no chance.
I will hit once.
But it will be a severe blow.
Oh, God! But, son, you only
know how to say dialogues, right?
After all, he is like his father.
I was crazy about these charms.
When...when..
When I decided to make you my wife.
Wow! Well said, son.
Another dialogue.
And I will smack you both on your bum.
Wow! You are a poet, mom.
Very funny. You be quiet.
And you stop fighting.
Do you intend to make
my Yuvi Rambo in a day?
I was teaching him self-defense.
I am making him a man.
Exactly. He is not a man.
He is a cub.
Mom, please chill.
- No, I am not going to.
What if you get hurt?
And what do you know..
What a mother goes through!
- What a mother goes through!
Fine! Do whatever you want!
Don't come to me crying.
I think tonight you will
have to sleep outside the cave.
Don't worry, son.
I know how to placate your mother.
How?
- With a song.
You are my world.
I am speaking the truth.
Believe me.
Why are you upset?
With me.
Understand my plight wordlessly.
Your anger is fake, fake, fake.
It's not real.
It's not good to hurt
and torment me, beloved.
O beloved.
Don't skirt eyes. Smile.
Adorn my dreams.
I will keep both my worlds.
At your feet.
I don't want to live without you.
Don't want to live.
I am wherever you are, beloved.
I will go away from your world.
You can't influence me.
Don't flatter me.
You know how to entice.
I have come back to you, defeated.
Withered flowers of
love will blossom.
O beloved.
Sultan!
Yuvi!
Papa!
If papa had been alive,
and one of us had been shot..
..would he have left this place?
There is a huge difference
between your papa and us, Yuvi.
We are not strong like him, son.
But he always considered
all of you his strength.
If he is not there, we..
- If he is not there,..
.. then we can't do anything.
Today he was shot.
Tomorrow we might be shot.
As it is, what difference does it
make if we live here or elsewhere?
If we go somewhere else,
at least we will survive.
Yes! True! Absolutely right!
- Absolutely right!
All of you are cowards.
Real cowards.
So what if the King is not there?
His commander is
with all of you, right?
Those who have
encroached on our home..
..we will teach them a lesson.
We will beat them black and blue!
Like this.
There are two soldiers in my ape army.
On my signal they will attack.
Attack.
- Attack.
Attack. - Oh! Shut up!
What's your problem, chimp?
You are ever ready to fight.
Discussion. Every problem
can be solved with discussion.
You know that, dear?
You mean you will go to humans.
They will say good morning
and tell you to have a seat.
You will say, Uncle bulldozer,
don't snatch our home.
They will say sorry
and offer you coffee.
Their bulldozer will take a u-turn
and they will leave the jungle?
O ignorant fellow,
they are humans. Humans.
They don't even pity their people.
They will shoot you dead.
Completely.
Hey! Listen, chimp!
All of them must not be like you.
A few must be like me.
We can talk, chitchat, discuss.
Fine. I agree. I agree
that they will listen to you.
But who will talk?
Is there anyone among us
who knows human language?
Is there anyone?
- Yes, there is.
Who?
- Who?
Who is it?
- Who is it?
Secondly.. - Fool, first
say what's the first thing?
First? Yes. That's what I was saying.
I know someone who can help us.
Because he knows not just our
language, but also human language.
And his name...
his name...his name is..
His name is... his name..
What is it?
Just now it was on my mind.
Name! Name! Name! Name!
Rajni. Ghajini. Kalpana. No.
Vijay Dinanath Chauhan.
Shut up!
This is not your film shooting.
It's life. Life.
They will heed only action.
Not words. No. - Enough.
It's enough, Bajrangi.
Now we need neither words nor action.
The decision has been made.
We will leave this jungle in two days.
'Parinda' (Hindi movie).
Uncle Hawa-hawai.
Who knows human language?
You? Who are you?
I am Yuvi, uncle.
- Yuvi?
Your friend.
- Friend?
Ditto. Same to same.
Secondly, you also pack your
bags and leave this place.
But where will you go?
I will go. I will go. I..
Where will I go? My home..
- Is here, right?
His name is Alex. He is film
director Vikram Khosla's parrot.
His wings are weak. He can't fly.
But what a parrot! Hindi.
English. Punjabi. Gujarati. Marwari.
He knows all languages.
But why are you asking me all this?
I have a plan.
Anger means sin, ego.
And this will be your end.
I am telling you. If you
want to be a big leader..
..you have to
swallow your small anger.
Like a milkshake.
So my darling monkey,
whenever you lose temper..
..stop right there.
Take a deep breath.
Now exhale.
- Not so deep.
And remember my mantra.
One. Two. One. Two. Three.
Stick out your right arm.
And then your left next.
Twirl around tummy.
And move your butt like this.
We do the hugging and
hug the little monkey.
And start from the clock again.
We do.. - Magical hug.
I have seen this scene before.
Secondly..
First shall we talk about
the first thing, uncle? - Yes.
That's what I was saying.
I don't know about films.
But here, everything
depends on your acting.
Is that so?
- Yes.
Okay, uncle. Ready?
- Yes. Ready.
Action!
Not possible.
- It's possible.
It's out of the question.
- It's not.
These are just words. Merely words.
You don't know my uncle Bajrangi.
Uncle Bajrangi.
What's the matter? Any problem?
Look, uncle Bajrangi.
I am telling him
that there is nobody..
..as strong as you
in the entire jungle.
You are right.
- But he doesn't believe me.
Is that so?
So I will make him believe it.
Why?
- No. No. No.
I have waged a bet with
him that uncle Bajrangi..
..can defeat two in arm wrestling.
But he says...but he says..
Not possible.
Is that so? So this is the matter.
Does anyone in the jungle have
the courage to come forward?
I am not talking to you.
Barela! Marela! Come here!
What happened?
I know your mother's lover.
Something is fishy, boss.
I don't think his
intentions are good, boss.
I even told him that uncle
Bajrangi can shake any tree..
..and drop all the
fruits down in a jiffy.
But he says..
Impossible.
So see this.
They are flattering you.
- Coconut tree.
If you fall,
you will break your bones.
You should at least get coconuts.
I am dead!
So many of them.
What else did you say, pigeon?
Not pigeon, uncle. Alex.
Alex?
- Yes.
I even told him that
only you can release..
..Alex from Vikram
Khosla's captivity..
But he said..
- lmpossible.
Enough. Where? Where is Alex?
I am your parrot.
You are my birdie.
Why don't you listen to me?
Your youth is tantalizing.
I don't know what
spell you have cast.
My heart is smitten.
It murmurs sweet nothings.
Hurry up.
Come. Come. Come.
Yuvi, hurry.
Your youth is tantalizing.
I don't know what
spell you have cast.
Welcome to Khosla's home, baby.
Wow! Nice house, Mr. Khosla.
She is hot.
Alex! What a cute little parrot!
- Come, baby.
Let's go to the poolside.
Why poolside? - That's where
your opening scene will be shot.
The opening scene will be in a bikini?
But I want to do acting also.
Cool down.
We need bikini to sell the movie.
My character will be exposed?
Full exposure. Full exposure.
A long role and short dresses.
I will make you a top heroine.
You are serious,
aren't you, Mr. Khosla?
Very serious.
Silence!
Mummy, please. Listen to me..
- Quiet.
Bagga, he is small. But you..
He is small.
That's why I went along with him.
Aunt, come on.
He needed someone responsible.
You think going to a human's house..
..and putting everyone's life
in danger is a responsible thing?
And you, Bajrangi.
You were against talking to humans.
So why did you do this?
You see...you see, Yuvraj..
- Flattered you.
And you got flattered.
- And you fell down.
Flat on your face.
- Bad. Bad.
Very bad.
Ma'am, you were saying something,
weren't you?
Ma'am, speak.
- Ultimately.
Not even once did you think
how dangerous that place is.
What if something
had happened to my son?
How is that possible?
I swear on Lord Bajrangbali.
As long as I am there,
no one can even touch your cub.
That's what Sultan also used
to think. But what happened?
In front of my eyes humans
snatched him from me.
Neither he nor I could do anything.
I am sorry, mummy.
I shouldn't have gone
there without your permission.
But I didn't want somebody else
to suffer the same fate as papa.
In fact, during the meeting
papa himself came and told me..
Your papa is dead, Yuvi.
And those who are dead,
they never come back, son.
It's the story of every family.
It's every family's story.
I mean, enough of this family drama.
Cut this family drama
and drop me back home.
For God's sake.
Drop me back right now.
Look at this.
If he doesn't harp on the same thing..
..who will call him a parrot?
Shut up, you ape.
I don't talk to LS ones like you.
You..
- Chimp.
Secondly, why do you want to leave
the fresh air of the jungle..
..and freedom and go
back to that prison?
Freedom my foot! You call this
thing freedom? Think again, dude.
It's so hot here.
Khosla has AC, TV, DVD, internet.
Whiskey and cashew nut.
And most importantly, this
irritating nut is not there.
What did you say?
- Chimp.
Listen, you are also one of us.
You are also a wild bird.
Won't you support us
in this fight, darling?
Chill, dude. This jungle
is your home. Not mine.
I checked out of this
place a long time ago, man.
Why are you giving this
parrot so much importance?
I suggest we still have an option.
My monkey army is fully prepared.
I suggest...I suggest attack..
- You say it.
You say it.
- Who is fat?
Me.
- Fine. I will say it.
Attack.
Bajrangi, that's impressive,
man. What an army!
They will fight with humans?
You have lost your mind!
- Get lost.
Don't hide behind her.
Don't you dare! You pauper!
You...you backward monkey!
Come out. Come in front.
Come in front.
Did you know kidnapping is
a crime under section 364A?
What nonsense are you talking!
We are very, very sorry,
Alex. But you are our only hope.
You will have to help us.
You will have to take
our voice to the humans.
Have you lost your mind?
Take it to the humans?
Today you will say
talk to the builder.
Tomorrow minister.
Then chief minister.
If things still don't
work out, you will say..
..Alex, come with us to Delhi.
Delhi?
What is Delhi?
Unbelievable! You don't know Delhi?
It's the capital of
our country, bonehead.
NDTV. CNN. IBN. BBC.
Fights. Shoes. Mike.
Trust vote. Bundles of notes.
Parliament.
- Parliament.
Oh, no. It's parliament.
People who sit there,
they run our country.
You know ministers and all.
- Ministers?
Damn! Ministers
control the government.
They listen to complaints.
You mean, they will
listen to our complaint?
Yes. They will surely listen.
No. No. No.
Now don't say that
I should come to Delhi with you.
I am not going anywhere. Got it?
I mean, even if the earth rips
apart or the sky falls down.
Alex!
Run!
'lf papa had been alive, and
one of us had been shot..'
'..would he have left this place?'
It's here that papa taught
us to live together, right?
His memories dwell
in this jungle, mummy.
We will have to convince Alex.
We will go to Delhi.
Delhi? What Delhi?
D for going to Delhi.
P for meeting people.
B for begging.
B for bad, bad, bad.
S for shame, shame, shame.
That's why, that's why I am the boss..
..and both of you are my henchmen.
We will go to Delhi.
But we won't reach there.
On the way, as soon as I get a chance,
I will get rid of Alex.
If the parrot is not there,..
..there won't be any
discussion with humans.
And there will be only action.
Because this land
always belonged to monkeys.
And it will belong only to monkeys.
And we will rule over it.
Glory to Lord Hanuman.
Oh, God.
Come. Come along with us.
Get lost. Give me breathing space.
Give up. Give up your obstinacy.
Give me way.
Come. Come along with us.
Get lost. Give me breathing space.
Give up. Give up your obstinacy.
Give me way.
Neither earth nor sky.
We are going on a mission.
We have vowed today.
Our promises are true.
Our resolutions are strong.
Come on. Let's go there.
We take a step in front.
You take a step and follow us.
Let's go to Delhi. Delhi safari.
We take a step in front.
You take a step and follow us.
Let's go to Delhi. Delhi safari.
Our breaths are smoldering.
Our eyes are fiery.
Our feet have the zeal to walk.
And there is zest in our heart.
Whatever difficulties we might face.
We won't back off.
We have to live together.
We won't be divided.
Help. Help. Go away.
Don't bore me.
Don't eat my brains.
Use all your power.
Confront us.
We won't lose.
Ever.
Attack!
We take a step in front.
You take a step and follow us.
Let's go to Delhi. Delhi safari.
We take a step in front.
You take a step and follow us.
Let's go to Delhi. Delhi safari.
Delhi safari.
A cheetah!
Cheetah! Where is the cheetah?
There. In the compartment.
- Come on. Come on.
Run! Run! Run!
Oh, darn, we are going to die.
What's the problem, Alexander?
They have found out there
is an animal in the train.
How did they find out?
We are hiding inside.
It all happened
because of this monkey.
Bajrangi, did you go out?
- No.
Big job.
- No. - Small job. - No.
'Vada Pav' (lndian burger)? Banana?
Don't you..
Don't you have any sense?
I swear on Alex.
I was guarding this place.
They are coming here.
Somebody is at the door.
Check in which
compartment the cheetah is.
Check that compartment.
- Check.
Mummy.
- Yuvi.
Where have they gone?.
- Open and see.
Check. Check.
- Come here.
Look here.
What are you doing?
Open it.
- Open it and see.
Is the cheetah here?
It must have escaped from there.
It must have fled.
- Let's look ahead. Come on.
All this happened because of you.
How did you reach here?
I was not coming, mama.
But as soon as I closed my eyes,
papa came in front of me.
Yuvi, you again dreamt of your daddy?
I am speaking the truth, uncle Bagga.
Papa came to me. And..
Mummy, I am not lying. He came to me.
The trial of life.
We are together.
Everybody embrace each
other and say sorry.
End credits roll.
But I object, My Lord.
My Lord, I want to show
you a short flashback.
When this innocent and
sweet parrot was tortured.
My lord, exactly at 3:.37,
before the train stopped..
..and after the brakes were jammed.
This monkey was standing before me..
..with a big knife.
Can he tell me what he was up to?
I need an explanation.
Baj, is that true?
The rascal's falsely accusing me.
Why is he always after me?
Objection, my lord. He is lying.
King Kong,
why be scared if you've done it?
Why don't you say it clearly..
..that you were trying to kill me.
I don't need to try to kill you.
I can blow your brains out right now!
Enough! If you two keep fighting..
..then we will never
succeed in this mission.
Bajrangi, not a word from you.
And you also listen
to me carefully, Alex.
We cannot make it to
Delhi without you.
And you cannot get
to Mumbai without us.
So, it's better that
we help each other out.
Fine, fine. I will go along.
But ask this monkey to
leave behind his weapons.
As long as he doesn't do
that I won't budge. - No.
These weapons are my pride and glory.
Oh yes, but you're brave,
you're strong..
..you don't need these damn weapons.
Come on, throw it down.
- No! No! No! No! No!
There you go.
I'll just go relieve myself.
You're already relieved, Bajrangi.
Look at him.
He looks so weak.
Quiet! Speak.
Thankfully I secretly hid two weapons.
Boss.
Plan no.2 has completely failed.
You were asking about following him.
You should've signaled us
while getting down the train, fool.
Fool?
No, I am the fool.
Boss, we also heard that..
..they took away all your weapons.
It must have been painful.
And that's why.
That's why I am your boss..
..and you are my henchmen.
So what if they took my weapons.
You two have your weapons.
We left ours back home.
- No.
No. I've brought mine.
So wait for my signal.
And as I give the signal..
- Attack!
Slowly.
How will we go to Delhi now?
Only the train knew the way.
That's why you're there and I am here.
Where was the train heading?
- Delhi?
So where will the tracks go?
- Delhi.
Where are we headed?
- Delhi!
Common sense.
Follow me.
What's this?
Common sense.
Nonsense!
Monkey brain wanted
to follow the train.
Take my advice and take a u-turn.
At least we'll be back
to where we started.
What now, uncle?
When all paths lead to dead end..
..then the solution
comes from up there.
Batman uncle.
Not Batman, but take my advice.
Raju's my name and
showing the path's my game.
You want to know the way to Delhi,
don't you?
How do you know?
Not just Raju Guide,
but every animal in this country..
..knows about your mission.
It's the age of internet.
Here's Delhi.
Delhi! Delhi!
Do you have another map
to understand this map?
I can fill haters with love.
And sing a song that
will get to Delhi soon.
Come friends.
Come, let me show
you the way to Delhi.
Come friends. Come, let me show you
the way to Delhi.
Head straight.
Don't be scared, have courage.
There'll be a patch
of lush greenery.
The forest will be dense.
No, no, no, no.
Humans raided that dense jungle.
All they left
behind was a dead tree.
Go straight from there.
Don't repent on what happened there.
Where the current's strong.
You will come across a river there.
No, no, no, no.
The river that used to flow.
Has now turned into a drain.
Don't ask what the
humans have done to it.
Just travel a little further ahead.
Be weary of humans.
A place that's lonely and quiet.
You will come across the desert.
No, no, no, no.
The group of gypsies are lost.
The fun's gone.
Those beautiful sand dunes..
..have turned into highways.
Everyone's prayers
have been answered.
You can see
the Parliament from there.
Don't stay quiet in the Parliament.
Tell the humans.
Listen cruel humans.
Listen to what it's trying to say.
Nature's trying to say..
..we co-exist because of each other.
If you annihilate us.
You will be eradicated as well.
Guys. Guys, please.
I cannot travel any longer.
You want me to order
an aeroplane for you.
Keep walking otherwise.
- Otherwise what?
You will kill me,
right. Please kill me.
Kill me. Kill me.
Has this parrot lost his mind?
Yes, I've gone mad.
I've gone mad. I've lost my mind.
Look. Look. I am not strangling him.
He's making me strangle him.
Bajrangi. Alex. Calm down you two.
Kutch is not too far now.
My clarinet says
My drum says
Welcome, welcome, welcome.
To my home.
Here come the guests.
Welcome, welcome, welcome.
To my home.
Who's the mightiest of all...
...soon everyone will see.
I am above all.
The world will be mine.
Anyone locks horns with me,
will be reduced to ashes.
I will blow away my competition.
Come, O traveler.
Welcome to my home.
Welcome.
Come, O traveler.
Welcome to my home.
No problem's ever
been too big for me.
You've no idea of what I can do.
The world bows at my feet.
Even winds change
path at my command.
Come, O traveler.
Welcome to my home.
Welcome.
Come, O traveler.
Welcome to my home.
Welcome.
Come and face me bravely
if you can. - Come on.
Don't turn your back and run.
- Come on.
I will show your place.
Don't be scared of me.
- Don't go.
Careful.
Escape while you can.
Front, back, up, down, right,
left, escape from where you can.
Come, O traveler.
Welcome to my home.
Welcome.
Come, O traveler.
Welcome to my home.
Welcome.
Come, O traveler.
Welcome to my home.
Welcome.
Come, O traveler.
Welcome to my home.
Welcome.
These two are finished.
Yes, but that's okay.
The dance is finished as well.
Yes, yes, but our journey
to Delhi is not finished.
And what about these two?
Don't worry.
Give them a whiff of
onions and they'll be fine.
Kalpesh, this isn't a serious problem.
They just felt dizzy while dancing.
Yes, dear.
But I feel..
- I feel they just need rest..
..and they will be fine.
Just tell us the way ahead.
It's too late now.
Spend the night here.
In the morning we
will tell you the way..
..and spread this news to the
rest of the birds and animals.
But remember one thing.
The area beyond that
black banyan tree..
..belongs to Kaaliya.
Don't even wander that way.
'The area beyond that
black banyan tree..'
'..belongs to Kaaliya.'
Thank God, papa, you're here.
Speak slowly, son. Everyone's tired.
But I want to wake them up.
I want to tell them that you're there.
Nobody believes me, papa.
I will call them right now.
Yuvi. Son, there's no point.
They won't be able to see me.
But, papa..
But why is that, papa?
Why can't they see you?
Because they think I am far away.
Only you know how close I am to you.
But why can't mother see you?
Of course she will.
But when the time comes. Okay.
I am just here to tell you..
..that you've to stay alert
for the mission you are on.
Because problems don't
always come from outside.
Sometimes our own kin create problems.
Now Kaaliya will kill you
and no one will doubt me.
Papa.
Bajrangi, uncle.
What are you doing here?
Where am l?
- Bajrangi, uncle.
What's going on?
Why is Alex..
This is Kaaliya's area.
Oh my, God. We'll have to
get out of here quickly.
Come on, Bajrangi uncle. Quickly.
You're a little late.
It's useless now.
Who are you?
I am the uncrowned king of this area.
Kaaliya! Kaaliya!
Kaaliya! Kaaliya! Kaaliya!
Bhairav!
- Yes, boss.
What's on menu today?
Boss. Parrot kebabs.
Lion-curry.
- Is it?
And roasted Monkey.
My mouth's watering.
Look, Kaaliya. Don't think I am alone.
On my signal..
Brother, don't speak.
I don't see the rascals..
Tandoor nights.
- Kaaliya uncle..
..we mistakenly
wandered in these parts.
Please let us go.
Fine. Fine.
You can leave if you want.
But first you've to fight us.
Defeat us.
And then you can leave.
Very simple.
But how will you fight us.
I've fangs.
I've claws.
I've courage.
I've an army.
What do you have?
I have my mother.
Mother!
Mother! Mother!
Save me.
I am going to die.
Please, please.
It was a mistake..
I will teach you a lesson..
Kaaliya. Why are you running now?
Rascal. Wanted to turn
me into a roasted monkey.
Thank God you're safe.
If anything had happened to you..
..then I could've
never faced the Sultan.
Forgive me.
And your highness..
- Bagga.
Ask him to leave right now.
I don't need his apology or him.
The savior is greater than destroyer.
But you will never understand this.
Alex is much better than you.
He's going to Delhi as our voice.
As long as he's with us..
..our voice will
certainly reach Delhi.
Our voice will never
reach Delhi, mother.
Alex has lost his voice.
And I think he can never speak again.
What have you done, Bajrangi uncle?
What have you done?
It's a serious matter.
It's serious.
Alex has become completely dumb.
No, no, he's just lost his voice.
One and the same thing, Kalpesh.
By the way, this often
happens in our stage-shows.
Remember, Rasik in our
stage show in Chicago.
Dear, you're just..
That was Glasgow and not Chicago.
Whatever, but he did lose his voice,
didn't he, flamingo?
Yes, but it did come back as well.
Do you want to argue
or find a solution?
Solution. They want it.
Do you have a cure for it?
Tell them. Tell them the cure.
Yes. Here's what you do.
Give Alex guava, ginger and basil..
Don't give them the solution..
..give them the whereabouts to
the 'Jari-buti Baba' (physician).
'Jari-buti Baba'.
On the path leading to Marwar..
..there's a huge river.
And his cave is on
the shores of this river.
It's so peaceful here.
I feel the peace here will
be broken by Alex's voice.
Just watch. As soon as
we meet the physician..
..Alex will start blabbering again.
Guru.
Sir.
Baba darling.
Baba.
Is that the Baba?
Oops. No parking.
I will take a look.
- No, no, no.
He'll die sooner if you do that.
I will take a look.
Guru. Guru.
There's no bell here.
I think I'll have to enter directly.
Hail Lord Hanuman.
Who is it?
Who is calling me
from his inner voice?
Baba darling is here
that mean that's..
Baj. Do you need a torch?
I swear. Even Mumbai
isn't that polluted.
Baba, this is Alex.
He lost his voice last night.
Alex, open your mouth.
He...he..
- Will die?
- Cream candy?
He's got no ordinary disease.
It's a royal sickness.
But what's wrong with him.
T...T..
- Tumor.
TB.
- T...T..
Tension. Hyper tension.
Stress.
High BP.
His cure M... M..
- Machine gun.
Cream candy..
Is going to be hard work.
First we need to C...C..
- Cut throat.
Slap him.
Apply sandal and
jasmine paste on his neck.
Get fresh yellow rose
jam and mix it with mud.
And then feed him that jam everyday..
..with fresh, red, guavas.
But who...who...will do this job.
Leave that to me.
Where is it?
Medicine.
Let me rub these two together.
Looking hot, chimpo.
Quiet.
Stubborn parrot.
So many thorns.
What did he say?
Yes.
This one.
Yellow.
Red. Red. Red.
Yellow. Red.
Red.
Here you go.
Is that fine?
No.
Let's see.
Here you go.
Is that fine?
No.
No way. I won't go that far.
That's not possible.
What are you doing?
Got it.
Here you go.
No.
No. Hail Lord Hanuman.
Pump up the jam.
Who was laughing?
- Who was laughing?
Get something to eat.
You'll get sick trying to cure him.
I won't drink a drop of water.
I swear in everyone's presence..
..until Alex doesn't
regain his voice..
..I will look after him.
He can't be our boss.
We can get beheaded
but never bow down!
Yes, that was our boss.
But today seeing
your head bowed down..
..it seems like..
Seems like..
We should take a headache pill, right.
He can't be...our boss!
- And you can't be my henchmen either.
I see. - Where were you
two when I kept signaling..
..and Kaaliya was
smiling at me with his fangs?
Where were you two when
I was wandering around..
..for Alex's cure?
Shame on you.
Eklavya cut his thumb for his Guru.
And you two...
are pointing fingers at me.
Shame on you two.
I don't need you.
Get out of my sight.
Get lost.
Did they really leave?
Who the hell is it? Coming. Coming.
Bagga uncle,
Alex will get back his voice before..
..we reach Delhi, right?
Don't know about that.
But if this continues..
..Bajrangi will lose
his voice for good.
He has been Alex's
bell boy since three days.
Have you seen the movie Bal Hanuman?
So many demons attack the poor
little Hanuman's back at once.
But Lord Hanuman,
without losing his courage and might..
..kept forging on
chanting Lord Rama's name.
The number of times he was faced
with troubles he uttered...
Wow, what a chick!
What nonsense!
No. Before that.
No. No. After that.
I won't spare you today.
What's happening, mama?
Is this called BP is rising?
I have no idea.
Can you make out whose
is high and whose is low?
Bajrangi!
Not just your voice.
Today I'll fail your entire system.
Stop, Bajrangi.
Bajrangi, listen to me.
I won't spare you. Alex!
I went hungry for you.
I kept serving without
having a drop of water.
I became the bad guy
in the eyes of everyone.
And you. You betrayed me.
What the hell!
Betrayal in the army of apes.
What the hell.
What? Have you done dumb?
Blurt something.
What did little Hanuman
say when faced with trouble?
Hail Lord Rama.
Yes. So hail Lord Rama.
What have you done?
Soldiers, attention.
- Yes sir.
The enemy has woken us up.
I repeat. The enemy has woken us up.
Put him to sleep for good.
Why aren't we running? Run.
Hail Lord Rama.
Ghosts and spirits stay away from you.
When you chant Lord's name.
I say. Evil spirits stay away.
I am confused, Bagga uncle.
Who is running after whom?
Oh no. There is no confusion.
Someone is running after them.
So what should we do?
Let me think.
Actually we must also run. You know.
The enemy has back up.
The enemy's second
unit is joining them.
What's their position?
20 degrees east. And 400 feet away.
Roger. All units alert.
All units alert.
Attack the second unit.
Artillery ready?
- Ready, sir.
Aim
- Yes, sir. - Fire.
All hail Lord Hanuman.
Quick.
Run. Run.
Come. Come.
- Everyone, come here.
Fast.
Run. Run. Run.
Go. Go.
- Quick.
Mummy, look here.
Everyone get into this.
Yes. Come. Come.
Here. There is safety here.
There is safety here.
You should be ashamed, Bajrangi.
Not just Alex. You
have cheated all us again.
I swear.
- Oh shut up, Bajrangi.
I don't trust you or your swearing.
You don't understand me.
I am saying that..
Don't say anything. Shut up.
- You shut up.
See. He can talk. He can talk.
You can talk, Alex.
Yes. You also want
me to talk, isn't it?
I will shut up you.
Don't let the enemy
get out of here alive.
Yes sir. We won't let the
enemy get out of here alive.
Target in sight.
All this is happening
because of this parrot.
Me. Of course.
It's all because of me.
I told you to touch the beehive.
I did.
I told Mr. Bagga to use his back side.
I said that let's go to Delhi.
Oh no!
Get down, Yuvi. Quick.
Aunt, he can get down and hide.
But what all do I hide?
Waiting. Waiting?
Be my guest.
Bajrangi.
Mummy.
- Madam. My leg.
Brother Bagga.
Bajrangi. Alex. Jump.
I am coming. I am...
Follow the main culprit. I repeat.
Follow the main culprit.
Bajrangi, my leg.
Is it stuck? Great that is stuck.
You cheated me. You cheat of a parrot.
Bajrangi, don't
leave me alone. Please.
Do something yourself or die.
Bajrangi, please.
There is no time, Bajrangi. Go. Jump.
Leave me and jump.
Stop staring at me. And jump.
Darn, crossed the border!
Should we follow them?
No. Unfortunately
that's not our territory.
Let's go back to base.
Tell the troops.
Roger. Back to the base.
They have gone.
Thank God they didn't spot us.
All that's fine, Mr. Bagga.
But where must Alex and Bajrangi be?
I don't understand
why on earth they didn't jump.
Why didn't you jump?
Why didn't you jump, brother Bajrangi?
The savior is greater
than the killer, isn't it?
This is what madam always said.
She was right. She
was absolutely right.
I was being so stupid.
I was upset with you for
snatching me from a human's house.
But I forgot that humans have
snatched the homes of all of you.
But still, at every stage
I kept avoiding helping you.
I am sorry, Baj.
Why are you saying sorry?
It is my fault.
You came here to help me..
..and l...started
thinking of getting you killed.
But to tell you the truth.
To tell you the truth.
I enjoyed saving your more..
..than I enjoyed
thinking of getting you killed.
Alex and Bajrangi.
I was this parched when
I stole the smoking pipe from..
..the hideout of dacoit Laakhan.
Actually Bajju,
normally I only drink Bisleri.
But today I am so thirsty
today that I will compromise.
Come on.
I'll get water for you.
No, sir. Let me bring the water.
Come on, dude. Are you my best
friend or am I your best friend?
You are my best friend.
So you must listen
to your best friend.
Understood?
Water. Your color is always the same.
You take on the color of
anything you are mixed into.
I am not a tiger.
No. No. Don't kill me.
- I am not a tiger.
Don't kill me.
- I am a cat.
- Don't kill me.
Don't kill me.
No. No. Don't kill me.
Bajrangi. Thank God
Begum madam you are here.
Or he had almost eaten me.
I am thirsty. I...
Brother Tiger.
Let me go.
I am not a tiger. I am a cat.
Brother Tiger...
If humans have their way,
they'll kill all the tigers one by one.
I didn't want to die.
That's why I started leading
the life of a cat to evade them.
And in calling myself a cat,
I forget how to live like a tiger.
I know that you must be
thinking that I am a coward.
Yes, I am a coward.
And perhaps I haven't
become some hunter's trophy..
..until now because I am a coward.
You aren't a coward.
You are only trying to save your life.
As I was by looking for
excuses not go to Delhi.
But now I have understood.
This mission isn't
for one single jungle..
..but for every animal that
is living in fear in his home.
You are right, Alu.
So convey our message to them.
We are not going to Delhi.
No one's going to Delhi.
We had gone mad that we were
thinking of teaching humans humanity.
We were going to complain
about one human to another human.
All of them are the same.
Cruel and heartless.
They won't spare anyone.
You. Me. This...
I won't let anything happen to Yuvi.
I am taking Yuvi and going away.
All of you also run away.
We'll not go to Delhi.
No one's going to Delhi.
'I'll have to call someone.'
'He is the only who
can make mummy yield.'
Look mummy. Papa.
He has come to meet you.
As I used to say that he will come.
See. - There is no one there,
Yuvi. Stop it.
Your father never did
come nor will he ever come.
No, mummy.
Papa is here. See. Can't you see him?
No. I don't see anyone.
But I can see him clearly.
Aunt, see. I can see Sultan.
Yes. Yes.
Aunt, I am telling you. See.
But not there. Here.
In Yuvi. Don't you see?
In his courage.
The courage that
brought all of us this far.
I see Sultan in the friendship of
Alex and Bajrangi.
A friendship that has
left animosity behind.
I see Sultan in you, Ms. Begum.
In your love for your son.
This courage, friendship, this love.
These are the things that
made Sultan, the Sultan.
Who says Sultan can't be seen?
Sultan is with us even today.
Yes. He is right here.
I myself didn't know
why I am on this journey.
Why am I needed here?
Only to joke and fool around.
Now I know. Perhaps I was needed
here so that not just this kid..
..but all of us are
able to see Sultan.
Sultan.
- Begum, Delhi isn't far now.
Keep forging on.
Delhi isn't far now.
Our courage says that
we'll stopover here.
I was mad and crazy.
I didn't realize my mistakes.
I have now accepted my mistakes.
We won't turn back now.
We'll just forge ahead.
This is what we have decided.
This is what. Just this.
Attack.
I will take a step.
And you follow me.
The caravan of love
is heading for Delhi.
I will take a step.
And you follow me.
The caravan of love
is heading for Delhi.
Here you are. Delhi has arrived.
And parliament.
Yes. Yes. But what do we do now?
It's impossible to get in.
I have a...
- I have.a plan.
Okay. You say. You first.
No. No. Go ahead.
You first.
- No. You first. - No way.
- No. Just say it.
You first.
- You first.
I am saying you first.
Oh shut up the two of you.
We'll miss the bus in
deciding who goes first.
Aunt, you must have a plan.
No.
- No! What?! You don't have a plan.
Oh God! What are we going to do?
We'll have to come up with something?
It's not going to happen
that we open the truck's doors.
Step out on the street.
Create a racket.
And the media will come
rushing to us with their microphones.
And ask us. Hello, Mr. Bugsy,
why have you come here?
'Mr. Bagga, you are a genius.'
Move that car..
..out of the way.'
Animals. Animals.
Don't let them escape.
Hit them.
Yuvi!
Mummy!
Baj, today for the first time I feel
that you should also have a gun.
You are right, Toto.
I also feel only gun can do
the trick. And not talking.
Cover them.
Get to the side.
NDTV. CNN. The entire media is here.
The entire nation is watching us.
Alex, talk.
Go. Go. You were the only one missing.
What happened, Alex?
Why don't you say something?
Stage fright, dude. Give me a minute.
Stage fright. You?
Remember? You are an artist. Come on.
Look at them.
They have run away from the jungle.
They have woken up after
leaving the shade of trees behind.
They have come here
evading all troubles.
Risking their lives.
I am afraid they might get lost.
These animals on earth.
He has definitely
had some green chilies.
That's why he is singing
out of intoxication, brother.
'This is great. They have reached.'
'They have reached Delhi. Attention.'
I was cent percent confident.
Who gave them directions?
You.
I have lost my peace.
Get your eyes off me.
These jungle creatures
are getting ruined now.
So that their hopes are
not dashed. Please come.
Please come. Please come.
My brother from the parliament.
What the hell.
He sings great even when he is drunk.
Great!
He is still singing drunk, brother.
These are trained animals from circus.
Send him to lndian ldol.
A monkey who looks like Guru.
- Where?
On TV.
- That's no monkey.
That's Guru himself.
I had said that Guru will get there.
When did he say that?
- When you didn't hear.
Toto. Toto, what are you doing?
Remember Huggy Waggy.
To hell with your Huggy.
And to hell with your Buggy.
You are making fun of us.
People are making fun of us, Toto.
What are you doing?
- He is right, Alu.
Why are you weakening our
mission by putting on this act?
Guys. Guys.
You guys must first trust me.
If I had given a serious lecture..
..the people of lndia
would have disappeared.
Understood?
Enjoyed?
Hearing a parrot singing.
You laughed to your heart's content?
Everyone laughed at my singing.
But did anyone hear what I sang?
Did anyone realize how a parrot,
a monkey, a leopard, her cub..
..a bear reached
Delhi's parliament? And why?
What problem dragged them this far?
Or no one could stop
laughing to understand our pain.
So you tell us why you have come here?
I will tell you. But only when
someone from this parliament..
..who is capable enough and has
intentions of helping us shows up.
Right now the entire country wants..
..to know the story of these animals.
And there has been
a lot of commotion inside..
..the parliament house right now.
We are seeing that here is
chaos in the parliament.
Even the trust vote supposed to
happen today has been stopped.
I repeat. The trust
vote has been stopped.
Instead of watching the daily soaps..
..every mother-in-law
and daughter-in-law..
..are keeping a close eye on
these animals gathered outside..
..the parliament.
We have been here for many hours.
And we have been waiting
outside the parliament house..
..only to know whether someone
from the parliament is actually..
..going to hear these animals out.
- I have got breaking news.
It is rumored that
the prime minister himself..
..is coming out to hear these animals.
TADA and MODA had been
the topics of discussions until now.
But now a bear, a monkey,
two leopards and a parrot..
..are the talk of the town now.
Back up. Back up.
Tell me. Tell me what you have to say.
Talk, Alex. Talk.
Convey our message to every human.
We've come here to tell you that...
That every human's life is in danger.
Crores of animals are going to
attack your homes and families.
What is he saying!
Your house, your family and your
life. Everything will be finished.
We will kill everyone one by one.
Now a war will ensue that will
wipe out the human race. - Oh my God.
Kill. Kill them. Kill them.
Shocked? Got angry? Got
scared for your lives.
For your homes. For your own.
Perhaps you must've realized a
little what we have been through.
Because we aren't attacking
you but you are attacking us.
Not since today. But since ages.
With guns, bulldozers. With pollution.
By cutting down jungles.
By killing animals.
You have dogs, parrots
or cats as pets so..
..that you can play with them.
But kill crores of
animals for their teeth..
..skin and various other parts.
Isn't our home a home?
Aren't our children dear to us?
Is our life worthless?
What is this fault of this cub?
That his father was killed.
The age at which he should
be laughing and playing..
..he gathered all of us and
brought us to Delhi to save his home.
So that we can plead to
humans for our friends and jungle.
But when we reached here,
we were welcomed with guns.
With shouts of Kill them.
Kill them.
We have come from jungle.
But you humans are animals..
..whose first reaction
to anything is action.
When we left home
Delhi was very far away.
But all of us didn't come to
Delhi this far just for reaching it.
But we came to reach to your hearts.
And if we've managed to
reach there even slightly..
..then stop deforestation.
Stop fighting.
Today together let's wage
a war against war. Against hatred.
Not just for one single jungle.
But for the entire world.
Attack. Attack.
Attack.
Attack. Attack. Attack. Attack.
Come on!
Attack. Attack.
Attack.
Rock on.
The happy day has arrived.
There is no worry now.
Come, let's have a party.
Let's have a grand celebration.
The happy day has arrived.
There is no worry now.
Come, let's have a party.
Let's have a grand celebration.
Let's eat and meet.
Let's have some drinking.
Let's have some disco and singing.
I want to lose control.
There is rumble in my heart.
No war. Jungle rules.
No fight. No war. Jungles rules.
Come on. Shake it and have fun.
Come on.
Let the entire neighborhood rock.
Come on. Shake it and have fun.
Come on.
Let the entire neighborhood rock.
I saw. You saw. He saw.
The peacock danced in the jungle.
Who saw?
I saw. You saw. He saw.
Look. Look. Jungle rules.
No fight. No war. Jungles rules.
Why put on make-up?
You look beauty cutie.
I am crazy about your look.
I am at your service.
Celebrate. You have holiday today.
Do whatever you want.
I won't be upset.
I love you madly.
You have driven me crazy.
No fight. No war. Jungles rules.
Come on. Shake it and have fun.
Come on.
Let the entire neighborhood rock.
Come on. Shake it and have fun.
Come on.
Let the entire neighborhood rock.
No fight. No war. Jungles rules.
No fight. No war.
Look. Look. Jungle rules.