Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
[Harmonica]
Hey, what did the blue jay say
To the little sparrow
on the fence one day
Say, you'll never guess, so I
Will tell you what I overheard
while passing by
The blue jay said " How do you do
Mr. Sparrow, how are you"
The sparrow said " How do I do
I do just as I please"
and then away he flew
Hey, what did the blue jay say
To the little sparrow
as he flew away
Say, nobody ever heard
Because he didn't get a chance
to say a word
The blue jay didn't notice
That on the fence
there was a cat
The sparrow flew
but the blue jay sat
And now he's just a little
bird on Nellie's hat
- [Music Stops]
- [Applause, Cheering]
Hey, hey! Beautiful, beautiful!
That performance touched my heart!
I, for one, will contribute a dollar.
Er, gentlemen? Yes.
That's... fine.
[Girl]
Thank you. Thank you.
Come on, fellas!
Help! Help! Help! I got robbed!
I've been robbed! Help!
- I've been robbed! Help! Help!
- The professor's at it again.
Come on, fellas.
We gotta meet the professor.
Not me. The rest of youse kids
can wind up in jail, but not me.
We're not going to jail.
We're going to Washington Square.
- What's the matter? What's up?
- It's the professor.
- He's picked a pocket again.
- You take that back!
You can't inflect
on my grandfather like that!
- Take it back!
- All right.
You don't think the professor would
take anything that didn't belong to him?
That's just the trouble
with the professor!
He don't seem to know what
belongs to him and what doesn't.
The professor's one
of the "honestest" men in the world.
And, besides, he's reformed.
Ah, my pupils.
[Chuckles]
- Professor!
- Yes, what is it, my little tuberose?
Tell them you didn't take
anything from that man.
What do you mean, steal?
Why, who suggested such a thing?
- [Together] We did!
- Oh, you did.
Well, now I ask you,
is this gratitude...
after all I've done for you boys?
- I'm ashamed of you.
- You see?
Yes. As a matter of fact,
I just learned of a big party uptown...
where, if we hurry, we can pick up
a penny or two playing for the guests.
Come along.
[Chuckles]
- Come on.
- Well, maybe he is honest,
but if it happens again...
[Chattering]
Come on, boys. Sit down!
Skinny, would you please sit over here?
Cunning, aren't they?
Especially the little one.
Tsk! The hats!
Can't you see you're in a swell house?
Wouldn't it be amusing to have
them play at our wedding reception?
We could dress them up and...
Allen, you're not listening.
Huh? Oh, our wedding.
Yes, yes. Of course.
- Allen.
- What?
Never mind.
- Come on, boys. Tune up.
- [Harmonicas Tuning]
Stop sniffling like that.
Here, use this.
- [Grumbling]
- [Chuckling]
A sad thing to say at best.
Thoroughly disapprove of it.
- [Grumbling Continues]
- Stop mumbling, Jasper.
I can't understand your nephew bringing
these filthy little street Arabs here.
They'd steal your hoops
if they could get their hands on them.
I'll thank you
not to get personal, Jasper.
He was a dandy
Yes, he was a dandy
and she was a belle
She wore a bonnet
with blue ribbons on it
And he wore a flower in
His coat lapel
He was so handsome
And she was oh, so fair
While strolling on the avenue
Folks would stop and stare
For he was a dandy
Yes, he was a dandy
He was a dandy
and she was a belle
She wore a bonnet
with a stuffed tomato on it
And he wore a flower in
His coat lapel
[Woman Screaming]
[Confused Chattering]
We've been robbed.
All our furs, everything.
A burglar's been in
and has stolen everything!
- What did I tell ya? He's done it again.
- He did not.
- I know he didn't!
- Just the same, I'm through! Come on.
He did not! He did not!
- [Man Shouting] Police! Police!
- [Chattering Continues]
Police! Police!
[Grunting]
I'm caught!
- Somebody broke in the window.
- What?
I haven't any doubt these ragamuffins
are part of the scheme,
sent here to divert
our attention from the thief.
- Will you stop mumbling?
- They've caught one of them.
- Leave me alone. I didn't do anything.
- We'll take you right in.
- I don't know nothing about it.
- We caught this one in the balustrade.
I trust you weren't injured
in the struggle.
- Why, no, ma'am... not a scratch.
- [Scoffs]
Come here, dear.
Don't be afraid. You and Jasper...
take these gallant officers upstairs...
and get a description
of the things that were taken.
Give my apologies to my guests and
assure them I will replace everything.
- But doesn't this one go to jail?
- Oh, don't be an idiot.
Come, dear.
I didn't do anything.
Honest, I didn't.
- I'm too little.
- [Chuckles] Are you?
- Won't you let me go?
- Where would you go?
- Home.
- Where's home?
- With the professor.
- The professor?
- Who's the professor?
- Oh, don't you know him?
Why, everybody knows the professor.
He's a fine gentleman
and an "aristocrack."
Oh.
- Is that cake?
- Suppose you find out.
Help yourself, my dear.
- Hey, Professor, wait a minute!
- What is it?
Professor, they got her!
The police. They got her!
- They got who? They got Dimples?
- Yes, sir!
Oh, uh... Here, uh...
Say, the professor's
awful strict with his students.
He watches 'em very close
so they won't do nothing bad.
And he scolds them
if they're naughty.
But singing and playing in the street?
Isn't it rather odd...
for a music teacher to permit that?
Aw, that's just practice.
If they practice at home, the neighbors
throw bottles through the windows.
[Laughing]
Which do you like best,
chocolate or vanilla?
I like chocolate and vanilla.
I wish the professor was here.
He likes vanilla cake.
Help! Stop thief!
[Professor Groaning]
Oh, he got away.
The thief got away.
- Are you hurt, sir?
- [Coughing] Oh, he was a big fellow.
Too big for me.
I'm not as young as I once was.
- What's going on down there?
- This gentleman almost caught the thief.
- He got nearly everything back.
- Wonderful!
Won't you come in, sir?
I'd like to see you.
Oh, thank you, madam.
I'd be delighted.
Well, I did no more
than my duty as a citizen.
[Coughing]
Ah, and not unlike the home
of my childhood.
[Chuckles]
Dimples, my darling.
- You're all right.
- I knew you'd come.
- It's the professor.
- Ah, delighted.
Do you see? If anything's been stolen,
always send for the professor...
and, generally,
you can get it back.
[Chuckles] Uh, yeah. Well,
I wouldn't go as far as to say that.
You've rendered me a valuable service,
sir. I can't thank you enough.
Oh, madam. I, uh, I was passing...
in front of your, uh... cottage...
when the culprit emerged
from the bushes.
I seized him and grappled with him,
but he was young and I am not
the Eustace Appleby that I was...
when I stroked the Yale crew
to victory.
If it wouldn't embarrass you, I'd like
you to accept a little something.
Oh, no, no, madam.
Thank you. Not for me.
Any American would have done the same.
But, of course,
if you'd like to, uh,
remember the child
with a little something...
- Oh, no.
- Eh, no.
Just a little souvenir. $100 or...
[Clears Throat]
Perhaps 75.
Is there anything
you'd especially like, dear?
Well, there is one thing.
- Yes.
- What is it, dear?
If it's not too much,
I'd like another little piece
of that chocolate cake.
- Of course, child!
- Oh, dear.
How big a piece do you want?
A big piece or a real big piece?
Give her all the cake
and some of the cookies.
[Clock Cuckooing]
[Woman]
Here you are, dear.
Now tell me, where do you live?
- In the rookery, in Cherry Street.
- [Woman] The rookery?
Just sort of camping out...
the Depression, you know.
[Chuckling]
Oh, yes. Good night, my dear.
- Will you come and see me again, soon?
- Yes, ma'am.
I'd like to.
Do you always have chocolate cake?
I will, whenever you come and see me.
[Chuckles]
Well, come, my little rosebud.
It's passed our bedtime, you know.
Au revoir.
[Professor Sighing]
Oh!
- Cicero!
- Yes, sir.
Yes, I wasn't sleepin'.
I was just restin' my eyes.
Well, this is hardly what a gentleman
expects of a gentleman's gentleman.
A flne way you choose to welcome your
master home after the day's commerce.
There should be a blazing fire,
hot punch.
Yes, sure would be nice.
- But...
- I was never without my nightcap.
I never knowed you had
but the one cap, Mr...
I have put up with your
perpetual unconsciousness!
I've overlooked your careless
treatment of my establishment!
But no one can remain
on my domestic staff...
and speak slightingly
of the Appleby wardrobe.
I am known
as the beau of Cherry Street.
As for you, Cicero,
I have come to the conclusion...
that this apartment is not
big enough for both of us.
Uh, maybe we can get
a bigger apartment...
- Out of my sight! You're flred!
- [Mumbling]
If there's nothing I can do about it.
Nothing! Nothing! Absolutely nothing,
Cicero. Our paths part.
No, now what time you want me
to be back in the morning?
Oh, I should say 7:45, Cicero,
as usual.
That's all right.
I hope you find your cap.
- Professor.
- What is it, my little apple cheeks?
- Why did you take that clock?
- Clock?
W-What clock would that be, my sweet?
I remember no clock.
The one you put your hat over.
I saw you.
Why, of course not.
You ought to know that I wouldn't take
a small clock like that.
I mean, I wouldn't take
any clock, large or small.
After all, my dear child,
I'm a musician, not a thief.
[Clock Cuckooing]
All right, Professor.
All I can say is that...
this is a coincidence
that leaves me embarrassed...
and nonplussed.
I wouldn't convict a dog
on circumstantial evidence.
And, yet, it's as broad as it is long.
I admit that, now and then,
I'm tempted...
to pick up some small article
that doesn't belong to me.
But, on the other hand,
I'm just as likely...
to leave something behind
that's mine.
I didn't leave my hat
at Mrs. Drew's, did I?
L... Oh, no.
I have it here.
Well...
[Sighs]
Would you like me
to give you a birdcall or two?
Maybe the whippoorwill
at twilight to help you to go to sleep?
No!
[Horse Approaching]
Why, child,
back so soon and so early?
- I brought it back.
- Brought what back?
- Your cuckoo clock.
- Why?
What on earth are you doing with this?
I, l... Well, I stole it last night.
- Well!
- It's a funny thing about me.
I'm so wicked. Isn't it awful?
- You stole this?
- Right under your very nose.
I really don't know
what's to become of me, I'm so bad.
Professor says he doesn't know.
He says I'm gonna wind up
in the "pinchitentiary" if not in jail.
Are you sure
someone else didn't take this?
Oh, goodness!
You don't mean the professor, do you?
He wouldn't take it. He's too honest.
He made me bring it back.
Are you, are you going
to have me arrested?
[Laughs]
Well... I really believe I should.
But I don't imagine
you're a very hardened criminal.
- [Knocking]
- Come in.
Colonel Loring and Miss Betty
to see you, ma'am.
- The Lorings?
- Yes, ma'am, and the colonel...
is ravin' somethin' awful, Mrs. Drew.
- Well, don't stand there, Rufus.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Tell him I'll be right down.
You wait here, darling.
I want to talk to you.
Hey, what did the bluebird say
[Humming]
Well, if it isn't Miss, uh... Miss...
Appleby. Sylvia Dolores Appleby.
- They call me Dimples.
- [Clock Cuckooing]
Do you like that cuckoo?
Us Applebys know all about birds.
Someday I'll have the professor come
over and do some cuckoo calls for you.
He can cuckoo even better
than the cuckoo can cuckoo.
Mmm, quite a talented family.
Oh, yes.
We Applebys are very talented.
Why, even the professor used to be
the best actor in the world, he says.
I suppose you want to go on stage too.
Someday I'm going to.
I'm going to play Macbeth,
just like the professor did.
[Chuckles] Wouldn't you like
to play a younger part?
Say, a little girl like yourself?
Well, maybe...
just to begin with.
I'll tell you what you do.
You have your grandfather take you to
the National Theater to see a friend...
a beautiful young lady.
Here. I'll write her name down for you.
- Is she an actress?
- Yes.
Are you in love with her?
- Why, l...
- [Rufus] I beg your pardon, sir.
- Your aunt wants to see you.
- Thank you, Rufus.
- Well, come along, Dimples.
- Your aunt told me to wait here.
- Allen, maybe you can explain.
- Explain what, Aunt Caroline?
- I want to break our engagement, Allen.
- Oh.
- Is that all you can say?
- I'm sorry it had to happen this way,
but I think Betty is right.
It would be the best thing
for both of us.
But why? I don't understand.
- You see, Aunt Caroline...
- I'll tell you why.
It's common gossip that Allen
has become involved with an actress,
that he spends most of his time
with these low people of the theater.
He's even talking about putting up money
to produce a play for this creature!
I regret that I had
to tell you this, Caroline,
but it's time you knew.
Oh.
Allen, it isn't true
what he said about the actress, is it?
I'm afraid it is, Aunt Caroline.
Of all things, an actress.
Allen, how could you?
You know how I hate the theater
and all that it stands for.
- I love her, and we're to be married.
- Married?
Alan, you can't do it!
I won't let you ruin your life!
My mind is made up, Aunt Caroline.
You're an ungrateful,
disobedient, shameless boy.
And as long as you stay in my house,
I must insist
that you observe my wishes!
In that case, I'll have to look
for another place to stay.
Allen.
I'm sorry, Aunt Caroline.
I'd hoped you'd understand.
If you leave this house,
you need never expect
to come back to it...
as long as I live.
I'll get my things.
[Squeaking]
[Squeaking Continues]
Child, are you hurt?
I don't think so.
Nope. I feel dandy.
Oh, well, you frightened me.
Oh, that was nothing.
Once I fell off the roof
of McGuire Saloon.
- Good heavens! Were you hurt?
- No.
- I fell on Mrs. O'Casey.
- Mrs. O'Casey?
Yes. She's fat and very soft.
[Chuckles]
Once I was leaning out of a hayloft,
and Skinny waved to me and...
[Sobbing]
What? You're crying.
Oh, no, child.
Is it because he's going away?
Yes. I'm going to miss him.
He was all I had.
Now he's leaving me.
Sometimes I wonder if men
are worth all the trouble they give us.
[Kids Shouting]
Hello, Mrs. O'Casey!
Hello! Hello, Dimples!
How are you, Mrs. O'Casey?
How's Mr. O'Casey?
That's Mrs. O'Casey.
She's the lady I fell on.
[Chuckling]
- Hello, Skinny!
- Hello, Dimples!
He's not really skinny.
We just call him that.
- Won't you sit down, Mrs. Drew?
- Thank you.
And Cicero. Cicero!
- Yes, sir. I was just outside.
- Oh, there you are.
- Yes. A little tea for Mrs. Drew.
- Tea?
Spread the table. You can pour.
- Pour what?
- Uh, no. No, thank you.
- Oh, you're quite sure?
- Yes.
Well, then Cicero,
you can get on with your marketing.
- Market?
- Let me see.
I think I'd relish
a nice flllet for dinner.
- We ain't never paid...
- Cooked in your own inimitable ways.
[Both Chattering, Indistinct]
[Chuckles]
Yes.
There's a quiet splendor
about the aboriginal servant, Mrs. Drew.
Which, unfortunately,
is not always shared by their masters.
- [Clears Throat]
- [Stammers]
Professor, your granddaughter
is a remarkable child...
an appealing child.
As briefly as I've known her,
I've become... very fond of her.
Yes, that's easy to see, Mrs. Drew,
and quite easy to understand too.
In fact, I'm so fond of her,
that I want to propose
something to you...
something for her good.
I'm going to ask you to let her
come and live with me...
and let me do all I can for her.
You mean that l-I
should give Dimples up?
Well, this sort of life...
isn't what a child should have.
You understand that.
For all your love and devotion,
you aren't helping Dimples.
You're hurting her.
You may even ruin her whole life.
But l-l-I... I love Dimples.
I know that.
That's why I'm asking it of you.
It wouldn't mean a complete separation.
You could see her whenever you wished.
- And perhaps I could help you too.
- How?
Perhaps I might ease your life,
provide you with a sum of money,
say $5,000.
Five thousand dollars for Dimples?
Five thousand,
if you let her come and live with me.
Oh...
- [Clears Throat]
- I must run along, Professor.
You give a lot of thought to what I've
said. I'm sure you'll agree with me.
Good-bye, darling.
I'm going to see you again soon.
- Good-bye.
Please don't sell me, Professor.
- Please.
- Why, bless your heart.
I wouldn't sell you
for all the money in the world.
I thought you might want the $5,000.
Oh, my sweet, sweet child.
There's nothing in the whole
world that could take you from me.
Nothing.
I... I love you, Professor.
I'm gonna make myself worthy
of that love.
When somebody loves somebody
Everything and everybody
Makes life
A happy song
When somebody has nobody
Birds won't sing and that somebody
Finds life without a song
If you want to see a picture
Of the whole world upside down
Just picture me
Without you
And you without me
Just close your eyes and you'll see
How Ionesome we'd be
Stars would fall, dreams would all
Crumble
Down for good
Castles would tumble
There'd be no me
Without you
No you without me
And yet nobody could be
As happy as we
Smiling through, clinging
Together
What would I do
Without you
And you without me
It's all for the best, Allen.
You're free now.
Of course.
I just feel sorry for Aunt Caroline.
She's done so much for me.
If she knew I'd actually gone
into the theater business,
well... I believe she'd change her name.
That's better than what you
thought she'd do...
cut you off without a cent.
- Oh, she did that.
- She did?
Yes. But I have some money of my own.
That's how I made Le Douve play.
All the same,
I hate having to hurt her.
You've made me happy.
Isn't that important too?
So important that I'm glad
I gave up everything else to do it.
I'm going to have my name on the bills
and a star on my dressing room door?
- A dozen stars.
- [Footsteps Approaching]
[Professor In Next Room]
Remember now,
we start to leave the minute
I refuse his first offer.
That, uh, sounds like Professor Appleby.
I sent for him
to talk about his grandchild.
She'd be perfect
for the part of the little girl.
It's mighty shrewd of Drew
to send for me.
An actor of my reputation
can't hurt him. After all...
- Well, I knew it was you. Come in.
- Ah...
[Chuckles]
Yes. Yes.
This is Professor Appleby
and his granddaughter, um...
Sylvia Dolores Appleby.
But they call me Dimples.
Oh, yes. Miss Cleo Marsh.
- Oh, I'm greatly honored, Miss Marsh.
- Hello.
Miss Marsh has the leading role
in our new play.
Ah, opposite me, I suppose.
[Chuckles]
There's nothing I like better than to
get my teeth into a good romantic role.
"But soft! What light
through yonder window breaks?
"It is the east
and Juliet is the sun.
Arise..." Uh.
- "Arise..."
- "Arise, fair sun,
and kill the envious moon."
Yes. "Arise, fair sun,
Isn't he simply wonderful?
[Chuckles] I was quite
a matinee idol in those days.
I still get letters from ladies
in the towns where I played.
- Yes.
- Landladies.
- Eh, oh, oh, no.
- No. L...
- Well, uh,
Shakespeare isn't exactly
what I had in mind.
- Oh, no?
- Well, do your birdcalls.
- They're beautiful.
- Yes, yes.
Mr. Drew, you'd better close
your windows.
- Your room will be full of birds.
- Oh, I don't mind that.
Oh, very well.
Eh, let me see, uh.
Uh, yes. The, uh, the, uh, the robin
calling to the blue jay.
[Imitating Birdcall]
[Both Laughing]
The blue jay responding.
[Imitating Same Birdcall]
- [Chuckles]
- Isn't that simply wonderful?
But they sound the same to me.
I can't tell any difference.
Aha, but the bird can.
[Laughing]
- Yes.
- Well, I wanted to talk about, Dimples.
Oh, you want her too?
Well, you're shrewder
than I thought, Mr. Drew.
My granddaughter and I
make an excellent team.
Just watch us. Cicero,
"The Fling."
[Harmonica]
[Band]
That's a charming dance,
but we couldn't possibly...
- We can do jokes too.
- Yes.
Professor, I sent for you
because I wanted Dimples...
for a part in the new play
I'm going to produce.
I hate to disappoint you,
but I wanted her, not you.
Oh, well, that's flne. Fine.
Couldn't you flx it so the professor
could do it instead of me?
I'm sorry,
but the part is for a little girl.
Then you'd better get
some other little girl.
I wouldn't be any good
without the professor.
Your grandfather could work
right along with us, if he wanted to.
- Yes.
- The theater business is new to me.
I could use a helper,
sort of an assistant.
Sir, I've never been
an assistant in my life.
- Oh, I'm sorry and...
- I'll make an exception in this case.
- Splendid!
- Yes.
L-I congratulate you, Mr. Drew.
No Appleby has ever been
associated with a failure.
And with us in your organization,
your play is a success already.
- [Laughs]
- Didn't I tell you he was wonderful?
Quite.
You're going to do
a beautiful play, Dimples...
a play that's never
been produced before.
It's about a little girl named Eva...
who tries to help
the slaves down South...
and an old colored man
who loves her named Uncle Tom.
The gospel train is a-comin'
- [Humming]
- I hear it just at hand
I hear the car wheels movin'
and a-rumblin' through the land
- Oh, get on board, get on board
- Little children
- Get on board
- Little children,
there's room for many a more
- Choom, choom, choom
- I hear the bell and whistle
a-comin' around the curve
She's playin' all her steamin' power
and strainin' every nerve
- Oh, get on board
- Get on, children
- Get on board
- Little children, there's room
for many a more
The fare is cheap and all can go
The rich and poor are there
No second-class aboard this train
no difference in the fare
- Oh, get on board
- Get on, children
- Get on board
- Little children
- Little children, there's room
for many a more
She's there and now the station
Oh, better don't be late
But come and get your tickets
and be ready for this train
- Oh, get on board
- Get on, children
- Get on board
- Little children
- Little children, there's room
for many a more
- Oh, get on board, children
- Children, get on board
Get on board little children
There's room for many a more
You gave me $40...
to pay for the tickets.
I had them printed for $37.50.
That leaves you a clear profit
of $2 and a half,
and here it is to the penny.
- Yes, sir, to the penny.
- Fine. You've done an excellent job.
Yes. And now I'll need
$95 for advertising.
As long as you're paying the bills,
I think it would save time
if you handled all the money.
Uh... oh.
Here it is. About $800.
It's all I have left and just enough
to finance the rest of the production.
Uh, uh, all right.
You trust me with this?
Yes, of course.
Well, thank you very much,
Allen, for your faith in me.
I'II, uh, I'll handle this money...
just as though it were my own.
[Kids Shouting, Playing]
- Professor?
- Yeah?
What does that sign say?
Uh. Oh.
It, uh, it says, uh...
Oh, yeah, it says,
"No Smoking Allowed."
Well, then why don't you stop smoking?
Well, l...
- Uh, oh, yeah.
- [Man] Well, I'll give you $600.
Sir, do you realize
this was Napoleon's watch,
given to him by Josephine
the night before Waterloo?
Why it's worth $ 2,000
if it's worth a cent.
I'll put it up to a stranger.
Ah, there's a gentleman...
who looks like he might know
something about antique jewelry.
He wouldn't know anything about jewelry.
I, sir, am a recognized authority...
which leads me
not to recognize your remark.
My good man, what would you say
a watch like this is worth?
Uh, oh, that's a superb antique.
I, uh, I had one just like it myself.
There you are, and I never saw
this gentleman before in all my life.
I'll give you $700 for it.
I haven't the money here,
but if you'll come to my bank with me,
I'll give you $800 for it.
I'm sorry, gentlemen.
Yea, it grieves me,
but my boat is departing
for the Orient in half an hour.
And, well, I guess I'll
have to give it to Richards.
- You're a very lucky man, sir.
- J-Just a minute.
- Can I talk to you a second?
- Oh, yes. Of course.
I hate to see Richards
get a bargain like that.
- I don't like him.
- I detest him.
If you could get ahold of that watch
and come up to my bank in Harlem,
I'd take it off your hands...
and I'll give you $10 for your trouble.
Oh... could you make that $15?
- You drive a hard bargain. I'll do it.
- Heh!
- There you are, sir, $700.
- I'll give you $800 for the watch.
But I haven't got any more money.
You said it was mine for $700.
- Oh, no. This gentleman gets it for $800.
- Thank you very much.
I consider this a great favor.
[Chuckles]
But look here, that's hardly fair.
I came here with $700 to buy a watch,
and you give it to someone else.
Here. Here's the watch.
- Watch? What watch?
- Why, it's Napoleon's watch.
You have the wrong man.
I'm not Napoleon.
Uh, you're not... No.
But you said... You told me...
- [Stammering]
- I never saw you before in my life, sir!
You ne... Why, here... Uh...
Uh! Oh, eh, eh, eh, eh...
Don't you see that sign?
- Well? Who's smoking?
- Huh...
- Well, seeing you're a friend of mine...
- Yes?
I'II, uh, give you a dollar
and a half for it.
A dollar and a...
You don't understand.
- This watch belonged to Napoleon.
- It did, eh?
- Yes.
- Well, that makes it secondhand.
Sec...
Ah, Tom, my boy,
the whole world is empty as an eggshell.
I know it, massah, I know it.
- It seems to be given...
- Ah, there you are, Professor Appleby.
- We've been waiting for you.
- Yes? Well, to what do I owe that honor?
Well, we supplied you everything
for your play.
We're the creditors, one might say,
and Mr. Drew told us
you would give us our money.
- Money? What money?
- The money Mr. Drew owes for scenery.
- And the costumes and the...
- Oh, yes, that money.
You're surely not suggesting that
Mr. Drew and I intend to defraud you.
Mr. Drew, you told us
that he would pay us our money.
Yes, of course.
Pay them, Professor.
Well, I, uh...
I don't like their attitude, Allen.
I never heard of people
doing business this way.
- Why argue? Pay them and get it over.
- Uhh...
Yes, well, the truth is,
I flnd myself a little short.
Short? How much?
Well, it's around $800.
That's all the money I gave you.
- It wasn't my fault. I was cheated.
- That's all the money I had!
I was stupid enough to trust a scoundrel
like you. You blundering old fool!
The professor said that you'd pay us.
Now, what about it?
I'm sorry, but you heard what he said.
You're going to pay me.
Nobody's going to put anything over
on Emery T. Hawkins.
And you're not through
with me either.
That's what I get for giving credit
to a bluffing upstart.
- Let's haul this stuff out.
- I'm gonna send a wagon for my stuff.
[Chattering]
Take it out and put it on the truck.
Well, I guess that ends everything.
I didn't mean to do it, Dimples.
- Do you see?
- You broke your promise to me.
But the man swore to me.
He gave me his word.
You told me you
wouldn't steal anymore.
But what I really meant...
I mean, l-l-l...
I didn't buy the watch
for myself. L-l...
You said you were
going to be honest.
Uhh. Well, I guess I'm not much good.
Maybe you'd be better off without me.
- But I thought you had money, Allen.
- I did have...
enough, anyway.
I guess I didn't
take care of it very well.
Well, uh, what are you
going to do now?
I suppose I can get a job somewhere...
and maybe save up
enough money to do the show.
That needn't change
our plans about marriage any, Cleo.
I don't suppose money is very important
to people who are really in love.
You can say that
because you've always had money.
- Perhaps.
- I'm afraid this changes everything.
Then you're not really
in love with me.
Oh, you mustn't say that, darling.
I'll run along. Good-bye, Allen.
[Allen]
Good-bye.
I'm awfully sorry, Allen.
Look here, Drew.
It's all right for the rest.
They can take their things back
and sell them.
These costumes have been made
to fit your play.
They're not worth a penny
to anybody else.
How am I going to get
my money out of them?
- Sorry, but there's nothing I can do.
- We'll see about that!
Somebody's going to jail for this!
Mrs. Drew,
do you still think I'm worth $5,000?
You're worth ever so much more, darling.
And do you still want me
to come and live with you?
I can't think of
anything I'd like more.
All right, I'll come.
Have you got the $5,000 with you?
[Laughing]
I'll be right out!
It won't take me more than a minute.
So you're really going.
Yes, Professor.
Well, I knew it was
the best thing for you,
but l-I didn't think
you'd want to go.
Well, it's like Mrs. Drew said,
"A little girl shouldn't be raised
in this kind of'envinoment."'
Yes, you'II... be much better off...
in that nice, big house.
Of course, it'll be Ionely.
There'll be no children to play with.
But I gotta think of the future,
Professor. That's what Mrs. Drew says.
Yes, and she's right.
And she'll see that you get
the right kind of food too.
Plenty of carrots...
maybe three or four times a day.
Of course, you won't be able
to go fishing with me anymore.
But I guess it's the best thing.
Fishing isn't any too good
for little girls.
I like fishing fine.
But I guess it isn't good
for little girls.
No, l... I guess it isn't.
- [Knocking]
- Come in.
- Well, I think I'll be going.
- A note from Miss Drew, sir.
- Are you ready, miss?
- I'm ready.
- Ahh...
- Good-bye, Professor.
Good-bye, my little angel.
You'll come and see me sometimes,
won't you?
Of course I will.
And you're gonna take good care
of yourself like you said you would?
I will.
And you'II... be good too?
Uh, yeah.
[Knocking]
Mr. Professor, there's a man without
a policeman, Mr. Hawkins, to see you.
- I'm not here. Tell him I'm not here.
- Yes, sir.
- Mr. Hawkins, he's gone...
- Not here, eh?
Listen, Appleby, I've come here
to give you one more chance...
to pay for those costumes.
If you don't,
I'll have you in jail in an hour.
L...
You'll have your money tonight.
I might've known you'd try that.
I should've sent the law.
I made a mistake coming here myself.
You certainly did,
Mr. Hawkins, and if you don't get out,
I'll be tempted to pull off one of your
arms and beat your head in with it!
Professor, I didn't know
he was gonna start nothin'!
The professor used to dance
and sing for me after dinner.
But, of course,
the dinners weren't good for me.
Last night we had wieners...
four a piece!
Can you do birdcalls?
[Clinking]
[Clears Throat]
Professor Appleby to see you, Mrs. Drew.
- Oh, yes. Come right in, Professor.
- Oh, ho.
- I see you got my note.
- Yes, thank you.
I, uh... I guess it's better
for everyone concerned.
Dimples will be happy,
and my debts will be paid.
And as for me, l...
I guess I ought to be glad to know
that Dimples has such a fine home.
You won't be sorry for this, Professor.
I wonder if I might see Dimples
for a minute, just to say good-bye.
Oh, yes, of course. Rufus,
take Professor Appleby to Dimples' room.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Ah, thank you.
Why, my darling.
Oh, Professor!
Oh! Why, what's wrong with
my little girl? Aren't you happy here?
Oh, yes, yes, I'm very happy.
I hurt my finger.
Where? Are you sure?
Of course.
There. That's better, isn't it?
[Chuckles]
There we are.
And you can see
this lovely dress Mrs. Drew got me.
Yes, it's beautiful.
Must've cost a lot of money, huh?
And she's gonna buy me
some dolls too... three of them.
Ah, you're a very lucky little girl,
and I'm happy to know that
you've got such a nice home.
It isn't every little girl who can have
such a good "envinoment." [Crying]
Oh, my darling.
I'm gonna take you home.
No, Professor. Mrs. Drew says I'm gonna
have a lot of advantages here.
Yes, but no place is nice for
my little girl when it makes her cry.
You're going home with me.
But if I stay here,
you won't have to go to jail.
You can give Allen back his money.
[Chuckles]
I won't go to jail, sweet.
Mrs. Drew, l... I'm terribly sorry.
It was in a moment of great weakness
that I took this money.
- Oh...
- When I saw my little girl crying,
I realized there wasn't enough money
in the world to compensate me for that.
You saw her crying? I don't understand.
Don't you like it here?
I do, but I get so Ionesome
without the professor.
[Chuckles] I was willing to give her
up, knowing all you could do for her,
but I see now that...
Dimples needs me
as much as I need her.
Oh! I guess I was
foolish to imagine...
the child could ever become
as fond of me as she is of you.
I admire your honesty and respect you
for declining the money.
- Oh, thank you, Mrs. Drew.
- And I thank you too.
You know, I wouldn't go away
if the professor could live here too.
Mrs. Drew,
why don't you marry the professor?
[Laughing]
Why, my dear child...
Then your house wouldn't be so Ionesome.
Professor's lots of fun.
- [Coughing]
- I'd marry him if I was grown up.
Course, he hasn't much money,
but you've got a lot. [Giggles]
Yes, well, I, uh,
think perhaps you'd better
run along, darling, and get your things.
- I'll be with you in a minute.
- Good-bye, Mrs. Drew.
Maybe you can come
and see us some day.
At our house,
you won't have to eat any carrots!
Oh!
Heh, heh!
Well, good-bye, Mrs. Drew,
and thank you for all your kindness.
Of course, you realize, Mrs. Drew,
I was only doing this
to save our poor little home.
Why, yes, of course.
But thanks to a kindly providence,
I still have means of getting the money.
Of course, it will mean that I'll have
to sell my one remaining heirloom,
something that's been in the family
for generations, but I'll do it.
Oh, that's too bad.
I wouldn't mind so much if I didn't have
to sell it at such a great sacrifice.
But it seems a pity that these
money-grubbing jewelers...
should get the watch for $1,000...
when it's easily worth
five times that much.
- The watch?
- Yes, yes. Napoleon's watch.
- Oh!
- Eh, Josephine gave it to him,
and he gave it to
my grandfather at Elba.
Hmm, poor, dear Grandfather.
If he'd ever guessed that I'd
have to sell Napoleon's watch...
to a money-grubbing jeweler...
- Is that it?
- Yes. Isn't it a beautiful thing?
- Is there anything I could do?
- Oh, no, no, Mrs. Drew.
I couldn't take money from you.
But, uh, perhaps...
perhaps you'd let me give it to you.
- Why...
- I'd like you to have it.
You're very kind,
but I couldn't take it.
Of course, you could give me the small
pittance that the jewelers offered,
and someday when fortune smiles on me
again I'll buy it back from you.
For Dame Fortune is a fickle gypsy,
always blind and often tipsy.
[Chuckles]
- A thousand dollars?
- Yes, dear lady.
- Oh.
- You'll take care of it, won't you?
- Yes.
- Now I know just how Napoleon felt...
when he had to give up
this beautiful trinket.
Oh, thank you.
Good night, Mrs. Drew.
Good night.
- What a lovely hand.
- Why, Professor.
- Oh ho! Pardon me. I forgot myself.
- Oh!
- I didn't realize my position.
- [Laughs]
But after all, Mrs. Drew,
I'm only human,
and your charms are irresistible.
[Both Laugh]
Good night. Good night.
[Crowd Chatter]
Uh, 35 cents for one ticket?
Well, opening night prices
are a little high,
but those are
the best seats in the house.
[Clears Throat]
Well, Allen's play opens tonight.
I'm afraid Betty
is still fond of Allen.
- I've forbidden her to see him.
- Have you?
Yes, the theater's ruined
that young man.
- Can't we speak of something else?
- Hmm? Yes, of course.
[Chuckles]
Oh, by the way,
I thought you might be interested...
in an old emerald ring
that I picked up at auction.
Five hundred years old. One of
the finest things in my collection.
Mmm. I know so little
about these things.
By the way...
I have something I think
might interest you...
the watch Josephine gave Napoleon.
- Oh!
- Professor Appleby had it
in his family for many years.
Oh.
Mm-hmm.
Mm.
Well,
if that watch belonged to Napoleon,
it was given to him
20 years after he died.
- What?
- This thing is tin. An obvious fake.
But I gave the professor
a thousand dollars for it.
Then you were robbed.
The watch is worthless.
And after I helped him.
I kept him out of jail. I trusted him.
I believed all the kind things he said.
- The man has made a fool of you.
- He hasn't yet!
I'm going to show him that
I can be just as merciless as he can!
Get your hat, Jasper.
We're going to the police station!
- Can you see her?
- Who, darlin'?
Oh, don't pretend.
I know you're looking for Betty.
I don't see her.
I don't suppose she'll be here.
I'm just a doorman, miss,
and orders is orders.
That's all right, Spike.
We're expecting her.
- You're expecting me?
- As if you didn't know! [Giggles]
- Did you flnd her yet?
- No. I didn't think she'd come.
Betty.
I think I'd better go
and rehearse my lines.
- This is the nicest surprise I've had.
- I came to wish you good luck.
This is good luck, Betty.
I didn't think you'd ever look at me
again after the fool I made of myself.
I'm willing to forget all that, Allen.
But Father never will.
If he knew I'd come here,
he'd be in a rage.
[Man]
Ten minutes!
- Come with me, and I'll get you a seat.
- Ten minutes!
[Applause]
[Orchestra]
[Continues]
[Laughter]
Oh, Topsy, Topsy.
You've been very bad again.
- We want to see Professor Appleby.
- You'll have to wait here.
I'll see if I can find him.
Don't you think all of this can wait
until tomorrow, Caroline?
- You know how I loathe this place.
- No! He must be arrested.
It wasn't bad enough
that he robbed me of the money.
He also had the insolence to put the
money into this foul venture of Allen's.
Mr. Appleby! Mr. Appleby!
- Yes?
- Do you happen to know two policemen?
- Two policemen?
- Yeah, policemen.
- What...
- They're lookin' for you.
Oh...
[Stammering]
Yes, I know 'em!
[Pants]
I do like you, Topsy.
I like you because you've never
had any father or mother.
I like you, and I want you to be good.
- I want you to be good for my sake.
- [Laughing]
Lord, missy!
I'd be ashamed to be good!
[Laughing Continues]
Oh, Topsy, Topsy. I'm sorry for you.
Have you kids seen a suspicious-Iooking
character around here?
- [All Laugh]
- I beg your pardon!
[Whispers]
Dimples!
Hey, you! What are you duckin'
in and out of the place for?
Are you tryin' to hide?
- Who, me?
- Yes, you!
Why, I was sitting there
tending to my own business.
If you don't mind, I'll go back
to attending to my business.
Uncle Tom on stage.
On stage, Uncle Tom.
- On stage, Uncle Tom.
- [Policeman] Hey!
- I thought you said you were Uncle Tom.
- Yes, you're quite right.
- I am Uncle Tom.
- You're supposed to be on the stage.
Uhh, on the st...
Uh, yes, I am. Thank you very much
for calling my attention to it.
I, uh... Heh heh! I was going to make
my entrance through the exit.
[Chuckles]
Stupid of me, wasn't it?
[Clears Throat]
[Man]
On stage, Uncle Tom.
[Dimples]
Oh, Uncle Tom! Uncle Tom!
- Eh!
- Oh, Uncle Tom! Uncle Tom!
Aha! Here I is, Miss Eva.
Well, here I is, Miss Eva.
[Laughter]
[Whispering]
Professor! Get off! Get off!
- Eh, well, good-bye!
- Bye!
- You're under arrest!
- Oh, but I is Uncle Tom.
You're Uncle Tom? You're Professor
Appleby! I knew all the time!
- Oh, no, I'm playin' in the show here.
- No!
- Will you come with me, Uncle Tom?
- Yes, Miss Eva.
My only duty is to tend to you.
[Applause]
- What's the matter?
- Everything's all right, darling.
L... I just want to talk for a few
minutes with these gentlemen.
Never mind that. He's under arrest
for stealing a thousand dollars.
- He stole...
- But I didn't take it for myself.
- I wanted to pay Allen back. Really.
- Oh, come on!
You leave him alone!
He didn't steal anything from you!
I'm sorry, darling,
but you'll be better off this way.
There isn't much time, Dimples.
You'd better hurry for the last act.
- I'm going to jail with the professor.
- Please, Aunt Caroline.
- This is my affair, Allen.
- It's painful, but it has to be done.
The man is a thief.
No, darling.
You've gotta stay and finish the play.
I can't do it, Professor. I can't.
- I can't! [Whimpering]
- Now, listen.
No Appleby ever quit a show.
We've always been troupers.
When you get to be a little older,
you'll know what that means.
You've got big scenes to play, darling,
and I want you to play 'em
just as though you thought...
I was out here to watch.
She'll stay. Won't you, pumpkins?
If... If you want me to, Professor.
That's right. And you'll give a good
performance too, won't you?
I'll try.
That's my little girl.
I'm proud of you.
And I'm proud of you too.
Well, l... I'm ready to go now.
Oh
Swing low, sweet chariot
Kindly sit down in this box
until the scene is over.
Young man, are you suggesting
that we witness this foul exhibition?
- We will not sit down!
- The show is on. Sit and stop talking.
- I will not!
- We are not degenerates!
Officer, can't you make these people
understand? They'll disrupt the show.
Very well, Jasper. Let's not make
a scene. It'll only last a minute.
Comin'for to carry me home, oh
Swing low, sweet chariot
- Betty's here! Shh!
- Comin'for to carry me home
[Humming]
Well, you're looking much better, dear.
In a day or two, you're going to be
as strong as a lion.
No, Papa.
You needn't pretend, because I know.
You know what, dear?
That I'm going away, and very soon.
Oh, my baby,
you mustn't think those things.
I wouldn't be surprised if you were out
of bed by tomorrow, playing with Topsy.
No, Father.
The angels told me.
They told me last night...
when my head hurt so.
They're going to take me to Heaven.
Now, you'll feel more cheerful
when you've had a nap.
I am cheerful, Papa,
because Heaven is beautiful.
But... But I'll miss you.
You're not going to leave me,
my pet... not for a long, long time.
And there's something else
that makes me sad.
Can't something be done
for Uncle Tom and his people?
What do you mean, dear?
They love their children
as much as you love me.
Uncle Tom loves his children.
- Please do something for them.
- Anything I can, dear.
Eva?
You'll give Uncle Tom his freedom,
won't you, Papa?
I will, dear. I will.
Eva? Eva?
I can see those great gates.
They're made of pearls!
And they're opening wide.
And there are angels.
They're calling for me.
I'm coming.
I'm... coming.
Eva! Eva!
She doesn't hear.
[Sobbing]
It's over. Praise the Lord, massah.
It's over.
Oh, swing low
Sweet chariot
Comin'for to carry me home
Oh, swing low
Sweet chariot
Comin'for to carry me home
- Bravo! Bravo!
- Bravo!
Well, I guess we better go now.
Yes, I guess so.
Obviously you haven't a heart.
Who'd think of taking that lovely child
away from her grandfather...
after he helped Allen produce
this beautiful play?
Well, I thought you said
the theater was a bad influence.
I'll thank you not to interfere
with my affairs! Let him go.
Oh, thank you, Mrs. Drew.
You're a woman of great character
and discrimination.
- [Applause, Cheering Continues]
- May I?
- [Applause]
- Wait! Don't go!
We have a treat for you tonight.
The entire company,
headed by our charming little star,
has prepared a celebration for the first
anniversary of Uncle Tom's Cabin.
Out of the South has recently come
a new form of entertainment.
Our company wishes to be
the first to present it in New York,
- if it is your pleasure.
- [Applause]
[Orchestra]
[Fanfare]
[Applause]
[Chorus] The Louisiana moon
is shining down from starry skies
Above, mm-mm
The Ionesome
Ionely old and breaking heart
Just needs a lady love, mm-mm
While the shades of night
were falling, falling
You could hear him softly calling
Dixie-Anna, oh, Miss Dixie-Anna
Don't keep me waitin'
Ain't you gonna come out tonight
Full moon shinin'
and my heart a-pinin'
Come out and meet me
in the moonlight
Can't you understand
Love is in the air
Lovers hand in hand
strolling everywhere
Dixie-Anna, oh, Miss Dixie-Anna
Don't keep me waitin'
Ain't you gonna come out tonight
Glowin' and shinin'
and my heart a-pinin'
Come out and meet me
in the moonlight
Dixie-Anna, oh, Miss Dixie-Anna
Don't keep me waitin'
Ain't you gonna come out tonight
Moon a-shinin'
and my heart a-pinin'
Come out and meet me
in the moonlight
Can't you understand
Love is in the air
Lovers hand in hand
strolling everywhere
Dixie-Anna, oh, Miss Dixie-Anna
Don't keep me waitin'
Ain't you gonna come out tonight
Moon a-shinin'
and my heart a-pinin'
Come out and meet me
in the moonlight
Mr. Bowes, why is it a fireman
wears red suspenders?
Well, I'll tell ya, I don't know.
Say, how come a fireman
wear red suspenders?
Well, the reason a fireman wears
red suspenders?
To keep his pants up. I don't know.
Full moon shinin'
and my heart a-pinin'
Come out and meet me
in the moonlight
Oh, Dixie-Anna
don't you keep me waitin'
You know that ain't right
Dixie-Anna, oh, Miss Dixie-Anna
Don't keep me waitin'
Ain't you gonna come out tonight
Moon a-shinin'
and my heart a-pinin'
Come out and meet me
in the moonlight
Can't you understand
Love is in the air
Lovers hand in hand
strolling everywhere
Dixie-Anna, oh, Miss Dixie-Anna
Don't keep me waitin'
Ain't you gonna come out tonight
Moon a-shinin'
and my heart a-pinin'
Come out and meet me
in the moonlight
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org