Prologue.
Steady, steady.
Thank you.
There are news.
Picnic is worthless, since
they have their plan.
- What for?
- To ignore us.
They think that we want
to engage them...
and agreed to send us to hell
til we stop our love life.
- I think that is not possible.
- Of course not.
So then?
In spite of their pact, I'm going to
talk to your sister, I'm sure to win.
What's your tactic?
I'll see in time...
And you?
I'll pretend to be
indifferent...
and then I'll propose her
a platonic friendship.
That never fails,
they always fall.
- Well Chayo, are we done?
- Yeah.
Don't change your mind,
- and don't betray.
- Don't worry.
OK, let's go.
Let them find us.
- Hey Pedro.
- What?
I'm taking Rosario fishing
to the fall.
And I'm taking Maruja hunting.
Remember that she's my sister.
Come on, don't you know me?
That's why I say so...
Country smell
that in the trees,
the breeze wraps
with it's song
of a marvelous rythm.
Miraculous God
is going to glow.
The country is a nest
of inexpressible things.
The song of the river
and the cry of the lark.
Mighty torrent
the moonlight kissed me.
Rocking of a cradle on the blue lake.
Country smell
that in the trees
the breeze wraps
with it's song
of a marvelous rythm.
Good God
is going to glow.
Why are you so quiet?
Mmm, ah.
I was just thinking.
Is it something that you're
going to tell me?
Yeah.
Just tell me.
Many times I've been tempted
to ask you to be my girl
but I haven't had the guts.
And now you did.
Now...
I want to tell you...
That I'm glad not
to have done that.
Why?
Because I have reached
the conclusion
that you and I should
be only friends.
That's what we've always
been, haven't we?
Yeah, but we have to glorify
that friendship.
Beleive it or not.
There was a tieme when I dreamed
to hold you in my arms.
To touch your hair.
To see me in your eyes and
to kiss you vigorously.
But you have put it very delicately
that this is not
the kind of love that
you want from me.
Nor I from you.
So you will get married,
maybe will l.
We'll grow old.
And we'll always be
very good friends.
Don't you think it's
a beautiful love?
Yeah, so beautiful.
You have taken the bait!
Why do you say so?
For that little trout. Lend
me the net. Look at it!
Lend me the net!
Have you thought about it?
Yeah!
And what dou you say to me?
No.
Just let me warn you that I'll marry
the first lady that I'll find.
Hey "Perico", don't
you fright me.
But babe, I can't find
a way to convince you.
It'll be enough to well behave.
And do I behave badly?
No, very good! Deny me that you
are courting the Gutierrez.
Ay, how can you be like that?
The Gutierrez. Anybody who
hears you might thing
that I'm courting the four
of them, only two of them.
The other two are for Jorge, and they're
not any longer, we finished.
And Martha, the telegraphist?
We lasted less than..
An urgent message.
And what about Juanita,
the post office girl?
Maybe a night delivery?
It better was immediate
delivery.
Shameless! And Enriqueta,
the funeral parlor girl?
That one is dead!
Tha's why you attended the service
along with the San Juan district girls.
Here we go again!
Those are only girlies, you
have your right place!
Fortunately. So, the farther
you and I are, the better.
Ay babe!
Hey Jorge.
You have somewhere a
girfriend, don't you?
Admit it!
Didn't we agree to
be great friend?
Friends make confessions
and advice each other...
Come on, tell me, do you
have a girlfriend?
I don't know what to tell you.
But what do you think of Genoveva,
General's daughter?
She's pretty...
She dresses well,
plays the piano...
and is your girlfriend?
Not yet, but I'll talk to her.
Don't talk to her. She's not for
you. You deserve someone better.
Well, that is my opinion.
Now I want to know yours.
What do you think of
Ricardo Del Paso?
He's a great guy, elegant...
formal and speaks english...
and has no love affairs.
Never drinks an he confesses
every Sunday.
And never speak bad words.
He's eligible.
He's bald, but a
wig will make it.
He has no converstion
an he is so stupid.
But stupids are the
best husbands.
So he's for you. When are
you getting married?
Do you want me to
be your best man?
Go to hell with your friendship.
Friends... What happens is that you're
in love, so you don't need me...
- But Rosario.
- You loved me a lot. Don't deny it.
So what about Ricardo?
I don't mind Ricardo. I just wanted
to see if you cared about me.
But you don't care.
"He's so stupid.
He's for you."
There are other more stupid. Those
who orginized a picnic to court...
and finished with a
platonic friendship.
Leave me alone! Don't
get closer.
But we're friends.
Well, I don't want
to be your friend.
So you prefer...
Yes Jorge.
No one can love you like I do.
But say nothing to your sister
until she has accepted Pedro.
And now let's go because
it's late.
- So you detest me.
- Just like that.
Then we end here.
We're finished.
Ok. Give me my
stuff back.
What stuff?
My sighs, the sleepless
nights thinking
about you, the kisses
that I've given you.
You have given me?
Well, in thoughts.
I don't want you closer
not even in thoughts.
Then I don't know what I'm
doing here. I'd better go.
As you wish.
So you getting rid of me?
Ok. I'll go.
- Good bye.
Don't you think that we have to
say good-bye as good friends?
Of course. Good bye "Perico".
Have a nice day.
Won't you give me a kiss?
Are you crazy? I'm not
one of your girlies.
A kiss of friends.
Friends don't give kisses.
OK. A kiss of
brothers.
Neither.
And if I steal it?
I don't think you'll dare.
Why?
Because I'd break your head.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah.
There it is.
Now break my head.
Jorge, come here! Pedro fainted!
The hell! You gave
me such a fright!
I thought you were dead.
Almost.
Look, you broke my head.
- I always keep a promise.
- I see.
What happened?
Your sister broke my head.
- But Maria.
- Ask him why.
What did you do, Pedro?
Don't look at me like that.
I only gave her an innocent
kiss on the cheek.
Hey siste, it was too much
for a kiss on the cheek.
Imagine if he had given me
the kiss on the mouth.
I'd be taken out the ammunition
from his belly.
You were right, buddy.
Today was your day.
Your lucky day!
It was just for you to learn,
so you behave well.
Babe.
Two Serious Guys.
- Hi Chucho!
- Hi Jorgito. How do you do?
Working.
I'll leave her.
Washed, greased and cleaned, ok?
Do you want us to
lend you a horse?
This is really a first class
service, but I'd rather walk.
What is Mr. Jorge Bueno
doing these place?
Hi Tiburcio! Let's start
not calling me mister.
...and call me just
Jorge as usual.
God forbid! You're a very rich man and
I don't want to be disrepectful.
Look Tiburcio, forget that.
Money is just to spend, not
to show off among friends.
- Hey buddy, I'm so happy to see you.
- Me too.
Well, now you can tell
me what is the
purpose of the visit and
what can I do for you?
I want some cattle. Do
you have some to sell?
Only that on my head.
Listen, but I can
sell you my ranch.
- Let's see it.
- Right away.
Do you smoke?
No, thanks.
If you want it we can pick
your friend Pedro up.
- Is Pedro here?
- Yeah, didn't you know?
First time I hear it.
- It's been a year since I saw him.
- Ok, let's pick him up.
No Tiburcio, I came here looking for
cattle. I don't care about morons.
So this is Jorgito,
always joking.
Terrific!
You got on my nerves!
Why? - I don't know what
I don't know what kind
of feelings you've got.
Only God knows how is suffering
my little daughter...
...and you, the husband,
so easy.
So if I worry, the baby
will be born sooner?
Of course not, but you'd demonstrate
that you love your wife.
She's a girl. You
can come in.
Your first-
born, son.
Can you see father-in-law?
We didn't need that scene.
Let see, where is
my newborn rose?
Ups, she's so ugly!
This rose is not even a spine. She
has the face of his grandfather.
She's like dad, isn't she?
She's his living image.
But who says that she's ugly. She's
as beautiful as a Lebanon flower.
We're going to call her as
my grandmother, Latifa.
No, don't spoil her
with that name.
Ok, she's going to be
Rosario, like me.
Oh God, I haven't seen you.
You're so ruined, Chayito.
Yeah, look at the state you
have left your mother.
Aren't you ashamed? She's
totally rambling.
Where's the color of her cheeks?
Those eyes so beautiful.
Those red lips, where are they?
You ate them, didn't you?
You are just born and you are causing
a lot of damage, like the scourge.
Don't hate her.
It's the first thing
his going to do.
He who is a bad husband,
a bad father will be.
Men like these shoudn't
have children.
Hey father-in-law, don't spoil the
moment. Well, I think I'm leaving.
- Good bye, Chayito.
- Where are you going?
I'm going to invite my friends
a drink, because of the birth.
We have to celebrate, don't
we? Excuse me sir.
Hey my little girl, you were so wrong
getting married to this cheeky devil.
All men are equal.
As long as he respects
me, leave him have fun.
My "Perico" is not responsible
for his luck with girls.
But that is not luck,
is to abuse.
Whatever. I'm not going to lose
my husband for being jelous.
He loves me so much
and I do too...
That's enough for me.
Ok. I have a clear
conscience,
because you got married
without my permission.
You've got a new baby
I'll tell you later when she's
going to be baptized.
And while I find my
child's godfather...
...I invite you to drink...
have a drink, since
here is your father!
The father of the child,
don't misunderstand.
Look at the mob this guy has.
Get in and don't let
our child go out.
Honorio! I invite the
drinks to my friends!
And get ready to dance!
I've got a partner
for all of you!
Hey Perico don't mess around, what
a way to celebrate a birth!
What's wrong?
My house is for families.
Aren't we in familiar spirit?
Yeah, familiar, and..
. Bring Mrs. Matilde.
Of course. With all her daughters,
everything is in family!
Don't play with me, you
want to catch me ruined.
But Mr. Bueno,
don't be bad.
Give me at least $40,000.
No Tiburcio. I have
told you that I give
you no more than $25,000,
and that's final.
Hey kid, two cold beers.
Yes sir.
The other night I went
partying at Julia's.
The family was present.
Mary Pepa congratulates
Luz and Otilia.
And Camila was the
joy of the reunion.
And while Lupe fed her baby.
Mrs. Cleta ask for
a drink to Celia.
She lined the intimates
on two rows
and we drank charanda
from Morelia.
After that Amelia
played a grammophone
and we danced all together.
There was a cadet
who was jelous of Chelo
but she was dancing with Gaspar.
Come on and dance Mrs. Matilde.
They gave us jelly sandwichs.
Punch to some of them, and
Coca Cola to the others.
As the maid was serving so steady.
I went to the kitchen with my tray.
I found there Ofelia's friends.
Who have passed their
tequila hidden.
And we drank behind the sink.
And Amelia almost caught us
then they ask Lola to sing.
And we suffered "Here goes my
farewell". After that auntie Cleta
played the pianola.
And we applauded a lot so
s he couldn't complain.
Do you play?
What?
Do you to play?
Oh yeah, sorry, I was absent-minded.
Not that much, you killed
my double-six.
I'd like to kill someone else.
Double one?
No, someone else.
Listen to me.
That one singing is Pedro
Malo, isn't he?
Yeah. And don't say
that I abuse.
Ask him the value of the ranch
I'm offering to you.
I give water to Pedro
and others...
But Pedro has properties here.
Those ones I showed you.
If it weren't for my spring, he
woudn't crop a single corncob.
Life on those properties depends
on the ranch I'm offering you.
Ask Pedrito and you'll see.
I'm going to ask him.
Wait for me.
I had the guts and sang you a
song to Eufemia.
That I sang out of key
and they made fun of me.
I faced him, but Eufemia
stopped me.
Otherwise he'd be standing
on line at the Limbo.
But the jelly was
already digested.
Beacause the lady of the
general joined us.
And nosy Carola goes gossiping.
And the husband comes and
the quarrell started.
The row started.
He pull out his gun.
I hid myself behind the pianola.
The police came
as Carola called.
And we went to the jail all together.
Come on girls, party is
alright, but some order!
Go fooling around,
but decent, ok?
Look at your luck with girls.
It seem so Mrs. Matilde, but all
that glitters is not gold.
I'm not lucky with them.
Don't say so.
That's true. No woman
takes me seriously
because they say I'm dating
a lot of girls.
And I have to date many because
no one takes me seriously.
You can't complain about us.
I'm talking about women.
And what are we?
You're... girlies.
- But your woman.
- My woman has his own place.
Jorge.
How seriously happy
I am to see you.
Yes.
You've got to be
seriously happy.
That's how I speak.
You're a swine.
You're right.
I was telling the
girls about that.
I'm so unhappy.
At least you accept it.
Well, yeah.
- How did you know that I was here?
- By chance.
We have to met some
day, don't we?
Of course.
What about talking in there?
Let's talk.
Come in.
You first.
I just came to make a complaint.
Tell me.
Why didn't you invite
me to your wedding?
I'd gladly have gone.
Well, err.
Everything was so fast.
Besides, you know the way that
I am and how I proceed.
Yeah.
Now I know how you are and
the way you make things.
Crawling like a reptile!
Betraying friends and
cheating on women.
Aren't you?
You married my girlfriend knowing that
I loved her and I pretended her.
Of coures, you don't dare
to face me, that's enough!
My sister knew better. She didn't
believed in your wicked love!
Because she could
forsee your kind!
And I was stupid enough helping
you in good faith...
for you to be my
brother-in-law.
Such a nice worm I was going
to include in the family!
And don't think that I'm hurt because
you marry my girlfriend.
If a woman cheats on you...
forgive her and that's it,
ultimately she's a woman.
But when you're betrayed by who
you think is your best friend...
Ah Chihuahua, it hurts!
And you're still laughing?
Answer me, answer me!
You won't say nothing...
being such a coward.
The comedy of my love.
- Have you talked to Pedrito?
- Yeah.
What did he tell you
about my ranch?
Your ranch?
Oh yeah, he told me that it was
a good investment. I buy it.
In $40,000?
No matter the price! Let's
go signing the deed.
OK.
Grease those spings that
creak like new shoes!
Don't worry
Mr. Elias.
Clean it well with oil.
Work well so I can
give you a tip!
Good luck, Jorgito.
Thanks buddy.
Am I dreaming or am I saying
hello to Mr. Jorgito?
How do you do
Mr. Elias?
Why are you so serious
with your friend?
You used to hug me in the past.
You have said so,
in other times.
You seem to be mad at
me. Yes, you're angry.
But you're wrong. I alwas wanted
you to be my son-in-law.
Look Mr. Elias, we'd better
not talk about it.
Yeah, I've gotta talk, 'cause you think
I was responsible, but I was not.
I know nothing that happened. I
wash my hands, as Pilate did.
You can say that I'm a fool, but
I can't understand what happend.
Now tell me one thing..
Why did you argue, my daughter and
you, if you were getting married?
Things that happen,
Mr. Elias.
Maybe you remember that last time
I saw her, about a year ago...
there was a fair at town, and she didn't
want to go because of a headache.
I remember.
Then I was confident that she
woudn't go, I invited a girl.
You understand, don't you? One of
these friends bachelors have.
My dark lady, it seems that
it's time for a huapango...
While she swings in her hammock,
I'm watching her...
And whe she shakes, I ask
her what's up, when.
What's up, when?
That lady in a wrap
has been sighing...
if that charro doesn't love
her, we're ready...
And because I don't want her so
sad I ask her what's up, when.
What's up, when?
And though I'm not new to love,
I'm not exceeding myself.
I'm like a bread that becomes
softer on any mouth..
And when I see her alone I dare
to ask her what's up, when...
What's up, when?
On the banch of an holm oak
a goldfinch is whistling...
What a beautiful olive-skinned
girl to join us...
And with all respect
I ask her...
What's up?
When?
What's up, when?
That charro and that lady are
just staring at each other...
Forget the papers and
you can do it...
And to avoid being indiscreet,
I ask them what's up, when?
What's up, when?
A nice colt whinnies in the
stable from time to time...
Ah, but you were here?
Tell Jorge to come.
- But we're going to..
- Tell him to come or I'll go for him.
Alright, I'll go. Take this,
baby. I'll be back.
...sighing.
And first of all, I ask
her what's up, when..
What's up?
What's.
What's up, when?
Hey buddy...
With Victorita's permission,
can I talk to you?
- Yes sir..
- Where are you going to?
I'll be back in a minute...
Let's go...
Hey, Rosario is there..
- Here?
- Yeah, here.
- She told me that she wasn't coming.
- But she's there.
Mmm, she's keeping watch on me.
You'll see how fast
I work this out.
Take care of this one.
Listen to me, I've got mine.
Just for a moment.
- Just don't go too far.
- Hey Jorge, I'm surprised..
Yeah, but I don't want
to be surprised.
What's up Vitolita?
What's up, when?
Easy Perico.
What's wrong, we're almost brothers,
and besides I'm the substitute.
It doesn't matter.
Are you so decent?
- Well,
- Well what?
Is there a way.
...this glass?
What?
What's your play?
Weren't you ill?
You can see that I wasn't. I just wanted
to catch you with that woman.
I'm glad that you found me this way,
so you'll get rid of this habit.
Is that all you can say?
Aren't you ashamed of been seen
everywhere with that woman?
I can tell you that not being my wife,
you don't have the right to tell me this.
How?
I gave you your place
by inviting you first.
You didn't want to come,
it was up to you.
Well I'm here. Leave that
woman alone and let's go.
I can't leave her.
- Why?
- Because I invited her to come. OK?
Jorge, try to understand that I'm right.
What's wrong leaving that woman?
I won't make a fool myself.
No matter who she is, I'll be a
gentleman and I won't leave her.
And you leave me standing up?
Have you forgot who I am?
I'm your girlfriend.
I'm not a tart.
In fact because you're my girlfriend,
you shouldn't play this comedy.
I don't want you to do
this again. Come on!
Go home, I forgive you.
How can it be? Now you're
the offended.
I'm the offended.
Then I don't beg you.
I demand you to leave that
woman and come with me.
Otherwise, we're finished.
- Is that you're last word?
- The last one.
Wait for me there.
What happend?
Nothing buddy. I
sent her home.
See her bright idea.
She came to order me to leave Victoria
stand up to go with her.
Can you imagine my position?
What did she think?
- And what was the result?
- We're finished.
- No man.
- Yeah, but it'll be just some days,
You know, she'll be forgiving
me, as all girls do.
That's true. The've got no
choice but to forgive.
While they're are our girls,
they can't do anything.
- See you later.
- Bye.
I confess that I felt guilty.
But when I wanted to see
Rosario to apologize...
I found out that you were away.
Now I understand why my daughter
came in that night...
saying "Dad, please don't mention
Jorge again. He's dead to me".
And where did you go?
To Mexico City. She wanted to forget
about you no matter what.
Some two months later,
cheeky Pedro came...
and all of a sudden, I learnt
that they were married.
Well, as long as she's happy.
I don't think so. She can't be happy
with that bad, unloving father.
Do you have a grandchild?
A very beautiful, nice girl.
- In fact, she was born today.
- Today?
- And this bastard is...
- Say it, partying...
He's been like that since
he got married.
- What a bastard!
- Do you realize my tragedy?
I feel sorry for
you, Mr. Elias.
And you should be sorry for him.
Because you pay the price forthese
things sooner or later.
Your car is ready, sir.
Bye Jorgito.
Goodbye son, have a nice trip.
Goodbye Mr. Elias.
Goodbye Chucho.
- Goodbye Jorgito.
- Goodbye son.
- Hi! I want you to fix that tire.
- Leave it there.
But you're going to lend
me a horse, aren't you?
A horse...
That's for those with a car. If you
want it, you can take that donkey.
- Three kings.
- Not useful. Run.
Hi buddy, how do you do?
Fine buddy.
And I'm not lucky at all, I don't
know what's happening..
That's why!
Look at it..
What an eyesight you have!
Why don't you go somewhere else?
There are sights that are
worse than a fly...
I knew a peasant that by seeing
his neighbour's cornfield...
...he'd dried it out.
- A hundred!
- Ok.
Losing all the time.
We open with a ten.
Once again the same bad luck!
What's up, Jorge?
Now I see.
One of those who can dry
out a plant has arrived.
Where do you come from?
What's up, Tules?
The lost has appeared.
What's up buddies?
- What brought you this way?
- Just to say hello to friends.
Have you got one left?
Well, those who were...
and besides to talk
to you, Jorge.
You can tell me when.
Right now!
Just speak in front of me, so
ypou don't give me bad luck.
A card to the center.
Give me two.
No, no, this way.
Over there, lean on that column.
Ok.
What's all about?
I wanted to talk about the ranch
you bought by my property.
- The one with the spring, right?
- Yeah.
It's open.
- I'm ready.
- Give me four.
- So then?
- You know that several farmers...
...use water from that spring, and l...
I pass!
- $300 more.
- I can't.
$300 and what's left.
I can't either.
You was telling me..
I want to work this out,
so I won't lack of water.
- I pay.
- Three aces.
I don't need'em. Pool of kings.
Terrific! And in four cards only.
- Well...
- How lucky.
Sure. You can see where he is.
So...
what about the water?
How much is it going
to be for irrigation?
Oh..
...being for you,
$5,000 a month.
$5,000?
But all the rest of
us pay $200 a year.
You've said so, the
rest of you...
It's $5,000 for you.
If you like it, and if
not, forget about it.
I don't know if it's
woth to tell you..
That all my hopes are
on that harvest.
If you don't give me water,
I'll lose everything.
Hey man.
I'm glad to know that.
I'm glad!
So you bought that
ranch to ruin me?
To ruin you?
Do you think that I can do that?
To you, being so good,
honest and loyal...
Such a good friend!
Alright Jorge, no way!
Gentlemen, you learnt
how it goes...
My property in such conditions
is worthless...
but in some other hands,
it's a good business.
Does anybody want it?
Let's make it easier. Give me a $1,000
pesos credit to play with you...
and if in 1 hour I don't give
them back, you can keep it.
Don't bother the gentlemen...
Good friends are for such times...
Do you want a rope to hang you?
I'll gladly give it to you.
Here are $1,000 pesos.
No, I didn't make
my offer to you.
Since surely I'm going
to lose, well...
...I want my property
in better hands.
What do you say, gentlemen?
I think you should accept.
I won't take it the
wrong way, come on!
$250 each one!
- There are mine.
- I even leave my place to the man.
No, you can stay.
I give you the chance to give
me the coup de grce.
What's up?
I accept.
- Give me the chair, buddy.
- Ok, you'll see.
$100 pesos to beguin.
- You go.
- Cut!
Let's see.
Well see.
The first to speak.
Do you start?
- You?
- No.
I start wit $200.
My turn.
$200.
- And $500 more.
- No man, that's a lot.
Don't play like that.
No, I don't risk.
- It is not that good.
- Neither do l.
You'll understand that my
shot was not against you.
- I want to catch my friend.
- Thanks.
What you deserve...
Your turn, buddy.
$50. It starts.
Here they are.
Give me some good ones, ok?
Let's see.
It's good.
There isn't.
I'll see if I'm lucky...
I start with $200
I pass
$200...
...and your rest.
There isn't.
This time I can't
run. I go.
Do you have a triple?
Yeah.
Did you bring the deed
of your property?
Yeah.
I was well prepared.
Give me two cards.
Well gentlemen...
after finishing here...
you go to the notary's office
to sign the deed.
And as my gift.
Water is free for you.
My cards face up.
Ah, a full.
To finish it.
A full, three aces
and two kings.
Now you've seen, buddy.
Have a better game?
A two.
Well...
At last!
At last? What?
- The other four.
- Poker on four!
What a lucky guy.
What a game he had!
- Terrific!
- What a luck!
The Hell!
What a luck!
What a lucky guy.
You won us...
Gentlemen...
...we have five minutes
left for the deadline.
Here's your money. Thank
you very much.
Not even in two years of good harvest
I could have won so much.
You had luck.
It is true that rascals
have luck.
- Good evening, gentlemen.
- Good evening.
Wait Jorge!
I give you all that I won
in exchange of water.
Water is all that I want.
- Really?
- Nothing else.
Hey man, you could have said so.
- Chucho!
- Yes master?
Bring this gentleman a
big bottle of water.
Here you are, master.
Here you are.
Thank you, sir!
Are you leaving again?
No, I'm staying as a tourist.
To see if I can take
from Jorge...
something else besides
his money.
Have many days like today...
Thank you, Madam.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Ok, let's go walking.
Your dress is so beautiful!
Do you like it?
It was dad's gift.
One of them, because you haven't
seen the main one.
This aftenoon's party. Such a
big party to be remembered!
- Isn't that Jorge?
- General, as everything you organize.
Well, I leave you beacause I have
to go to the station to pick up...
a very special cognac. Excuse
me, good afternoon.
See you later General.
My good frieng. I didn't
expect you here!
How do you do, General.
I'm at your service.
Listen Pedrito. I expect you by 6 in
my house. It's my daughter's bithday.
I guess Jorge and his family
will be there, don't they?
Of course.
- You must be there!
- Of course general.
I'm not used to miss
such events.
- Count me on.
- Ok, see you later.
Pedro.
- Come here.
- Damn!
- What are you doing here?
- You're surprised, aren't you?
Last time we argued, I said
you were a bad man...
miserable tyrant of my daughter,
I said everything!
And to repeat that, you
bother yourself to come!
Let me tell you everything I've gotta
say, and then you speak, ok?
Ok.
The problems have with
your father-in-law...
...are not for you to abandon
your wife and daughter!
Oh shit! Why do you say that
I have abandoned them?
Isn't it abandonment to desert without
conset and stay a far away?
No sir! I have to work out
an urgent problem here.
It is also very urgent to
meet your family's needs!
That's why I brougth Rosario
and the baby this way!
- They're here?
- Yes sir!
Damn! Why did you
bring them here?
Because you musn't show off as a
bachelor. You're married, sir!
No sir! You're going back
to town right away!
You're wrong son! From now
on, wherever you go...
even to hell, your wife and your
daughter will go with you.
No, no, no sir!
- You'll see, uncle.
- I'm not your uncle.
Unfortunately, I'm
your father-in-law!
You don't seem so. You seem
to be a nosy mother-in-law!
Oh yeah? That's what
I look like for you?
Tomorrow I'll go to Veracruz
to take a ship...
and I'll go to my homeland. You
stay here with your wife,
...and we'll se how you
manage with her...
Will anybody look after her like me?
I have even neglected my business.
It's up to you! Do you want the
nosy mother-in-law to leave?
Don't do that uncle, don't go.
What will Rosarito
do without you?
That's what I say sir.
If you're a good boy with a great
heart, why don't you well behave?
Behave well with my daghter, and
you'll have everything with me.
Not money, but lots
of friendship.
Why do you have to be arguing
with me all the time?
Let's go to you hotel to check
out and we'll go home.
What home?
Have you forgoten, Pedrito, that
we have our abandoned house here?
Ok. Let's go home, sir.
More respect for your
father-in law, Pedro.
You're so funny, really.
We'll go in a minute, doctor,
don't be impatient.
- I'm not in a hurry, Josefa.
- Anastasia!
What happend with my tie?
- What's up doctor.
- It's here!
Do you know who arrived at noon?
- Who?
- Who else can it be? Rosario.
She's not that young.
She has a baby.
- Is she married to Mr. Pedro?
- Shut up!
Anastasia, you musn't mention
those names in this house!
- This shall be the last time!
- Yes Madam.
You still love her, don't you?
- No, I don't.
- You don't fool me.
You're still in love
with Rosario.
Not in love.
I'm ill.
It's a chronic illness that goes and
comes back when you least expect it.
There's a song for that illness.
A spoon of oblivion...
and drops from another love.
Yeah, my prescription is
a wedding with Genoveva.
Let's see if insted of
a spoon, it's a rub!
You'll go to the doctor's.
I'll meet you there.
We have a beautiful baby here.
...tha beautifil baby we have
here. Look at the pigeons.
Look at them. Don't you
want to see them?
We have more pigeons
here baby...
See you later, Chayo.
Won't you stay for lunch?
I have to go with some friends.
Business lunch.
- See you tomorrow, Mr. Elias.
- See you tomorrow?
Does it mean you're
coming back at dawn?
Or by day. You
can nver know.
Have you seen, baby?
You cannot keep your mouth closed
with a man like this.
He's a carouser, shameless.
But to avoid your grandpa been
called a nosy mother-in-law...
We put on my lips a patch.
And we can deal with
the carouser.
There you go again, dad?
I'm saying nothig, but talking
to my grandchild.
See you tomorrow
Pedrito. Do well.
Son of my heart.
Try not to come back
late, Pedro.
I don't want my dad
to start talking.
Don't worry for your
husband, Madam.
Pedro!
Jorge!
Aren't you ashamed to see me?
I don't think so!
If you were ashamed, you
wouldn't have come.
Jorge, please.
I feel sorry for you.
When a woman like you and a man
like him are join by betrayal...
they always finish the same.
She cheats on her husband.
And him, abandoning her!
It never fails!
You are, darling...
who got me in ecstasies..
Why should I deny that
I'm in love with you?
From your sweet soul
that is full of feelings.
With those black eyes with
a strange shining.
That control me and demand
me to love you.
You're my delight,
you're my illusion.
I know that glory...
is in Heaven...
and is to mortals...
the hope when they die.
I bless God because having
you in lifetieme...
I don't need to go to Heaven.
Yes darling,
you're the Glory...
Sorry to be a little
late. Good afternoon.
Don't worry. You're
just in time.
Please come in.
We'll drink a cognac that is not
a cognac, it's a Heaven's gift!
- What are you doing here?
- I was invited.
Sponger!
Ladies and Gentlemen...
I want to officialy announce...
my daughter's engagement
to Mr. Jorge Bueno...
who has honored me
to ask her hand...
and I will tell you that
I congratulate myself...
because without offending
those of you here...
I wouldn't find a
better son-in-law.
Bravo! Good!
Now you pay compliments
to the happy couple.
I was ready for it!
Ready guys!
Let's start!
People honestly say...
in every wedding
bridegroom always love her,
but to have his funeral...
this bride has no sorrow, because
she 'll have a good husband.
Jorge Bueno is a good thing,
at least his last name...
Jorge Bueno is very good...
son of Bueno too...
and his grandfather, very good,
that had his name.
Play for me, but a little higher.
I'll try to be as good
as my last name...
let him drink his poison who
has demanded a funeral...
Pedro has a bad last name.
I'll answer to his verses.
He only wants to show off,
because he isn't bad, is...
hopeless.
Pedro Malo is very bad...
bad by destiny...
and his gandfather, uy!
What a bad guy...
we got to buy him a lion.
On a sunny morning...
sombody clouded the landscape...
there were a crow and a parrot
tearing out their feathers.
You've got to forget the past,
if luck is guilty...
Good and Bad mixed...
turn out mediocre.
I'm bad, don't deny it...
but I'd like to mix Good
and Bad to see...
if you get something fair.
Please do something. Those
guys are going to fight.
Easy you scaveger scorpion...
you were visiting an apiary...
to see if poison could
be removed with honey
and goodness is not for evil...
with honey and his poison,
today he's...
purged!
Let him be understood,
who can understand him...
if he can be understood...
and if he can't understand...
he's got to be forced to understand.
I'm going to tell the
orchestra to play.
Why?
It is clear to you that I'm
not a fool like you...
has showed...
Not a fool, but a meddler...
for your hunger...
of friends.
I always calm my hunger
with my friend's food...
Beggar, but a beggar who
steals his friends...
You say so.
I stand for it!
Don't be tired...
- Don't avoid it!
- I avoid it.
Then this song is over!
- Do you dance, Jorge?
- Later.
Let's dance, please.
Later.
They're so playful.
Maruca!
Why don't you say hello?
Who are you?
The same "Periquito" who loves
you more everyday...
Oh yes...
That Perico who got his
head broken for liar.
I would say that I was
sent away, wasn't I?
But you found your cage...
Not that much. Just ask me to
go, and I'll go with you.
Look, don't start
with that crap!
What crap, you got me spinning.
You're not free.
Remeber your status...
But now I'm free.
Well, quit bugging me,
or you may have your
head broken again.
I don't care!
I love you with all my heart.
They're going to break
you in pieces!
So go away...
If you haven't leave the
town by tomorrow...
wherever I find you,
I'll kill you!
Take care, mom...
Are you sure you won't
need more money?
No, I have enough.
Don't restrict yourself, eh?
Remember that I want the
best trousseau available.
You'll see.
Watch the sharp bends.
Hey sir!
What's up?
What happened to Pedro?
He didn't go. He's
at the casino.
The fifth!
Here's the ace.
Double!
Hey Pedro, just think the
next play and we'll win.
He loses anyway!
I pass.
This is the good one.
Well, I won.
This game was well...
but I think it's the last
one of your life.
Step away, gentlemen!
This guy is going
to die right here!
I promised him!...
take your gun out and
defend yourself!
I don't have it.
- What a coincidence.
- It's not a coincidence, it's deliberately.
You wouldn't shot
an unarmed man.
You know me so well...
but it won't make a difference.
Lend me this!
Defend yourself!
I can't shoot my best friend.
Friend?
How you dare to say such word!
Well, in other words...
I can't shoot the brother of the woman
I love the most, do you undestand?
Gentlemen, you are witnesses.
This guy is a coward and
wants to die as a hero.
- That's why I'm going to please you.
- One moment...
I'm the one who's gonna please
you, as you want it.
Just the two of us in
the private room.
All right!
- Good bye, gentlemen.
- Goodbye.
It was so close!
Here you are.
- Hey Chucho, bring me a mariachi fast!
- Yes sir.
Woman, open your window...
So you can hear my voice...
the man who loves you is singing
with God's permission...
you brighten my life...
and for that, dear woman...
I'm singing to you tonight...
that's why I'm here to steal...
a small ray of your light...
Wake up.
My love, my goodness...
What I'm sorry for, my love...
is to come here to make
you lose your sleep...
But wake up...
Wake up my love.
And listen to my sad song...
That your lover sings
that your possessor sings...
and it's for your love...
A t moonlight nights...
blossom perfum
a starry night
and a warm breeze
behind the grille,
covered with flowers
the fiance is waiting...
shaking...
of love, yes.
When I see those eyes
that nervously wait, white
stars loved their light.
Breeze scatters a better aroma
and all the flowers
sigh in love.
For a...
glance of those beautiful eyes,
the stars and flowers...
are jealous.
The breeze...
sighs, the sky..
Fades out...
and in the heart..
Wanders...
the jewell...
of love.
Well guys,
Share it, ok?
Ok.
- Your cooperation.
- And remember.
I never came to sing
this serenade.
- Let's go.
- Ok sir.
Wouldn't you, baby?
I knew that you had
to come down, love.
Good evening,
mr. Elias.
How are you, sir?
Could you tell her to come down,
please. I want to talk to her.
Isn't it the same to talk to me?
Of course not! What would they think
if the see me making love to you?
Do you mean that you want to
make love to my daughter?
Keep away, sir.
My daughter has an owner.
- I'm going to be her owner.
- You're drunk.
Besides...
Once upon the time you wanted me to
be your son-in-law, and here I am.
Yeah. I wanted you to be my son-
in-law, but fair and square.
And this way, behind the
door, you can't be.
My daughter is married.
But I'm not a jealous guy.
But I am.
My daughter has a daughter.
We send her to the orphanage.
Oh yeah? And should we send her
husband to the orphanage?
The husband...
Hey Mr. Elias...
What a pity that I can't
tell you some matters...
But I can tell you to go with
you music somewhere else.
You don't have the right...
to come bugging a person for
no reason. Go away, please!
Ok, sir. I'm
leaving...
but tell Rosario
that I love her!
You want me to tell you that?
And want about if
I don't do that?
It doesn't matter...
she's listening to me
upstairs... Rosario!
I'm leaving because your
father throws me out!
But I want you to know...
that I love you,
I love you a lot!
But I don't love you,
and I can't love you.
You're responsible for that!
Do you remeber how much I begged
you and how you despised me?
That's why you married Rosario?
And besides being the girfriend
of your best friend...
she was your cousin?
As you ignored me, it
was the same for me...
Well, it doesn't surprise me coming
from you. You're so shameless.
But she, how could she have
accepted to be your woman?
If you grew up together,
you were like related.
It's like if I were married
to Jorge, how awful!
Putting it you way you
do, it seems awful.
But you can work this out.
Can I?
Just tell me that you love me and you'll
see how fast I untangle this...
- Oh yeah, is that easy?
- Sure!
You're so cynical and lazy!
Alright.
But you're the woman I've
loved the most in my life.
And you're the man I despise
and hate the most!
I swear you dad that I haven't give him
a reason to be offended this way.
I told you darling,
Jorge's drunk.
But most important is that
Pedro doesn't learn this.
Heaven help us, they might
shoot themselves!
Tomorrow, when he's sober,
I'll talk to Jorge.
You'll see that he won't
bug you again.
And the only responsible
is your husband,
that never spends
a night at home.
It's clear that he
doesn't love you.
He loves me with all his
heart, and me too.
Don't blame Pedro!
Sure he's to blame!
It is not fair that I have to take care
of his duties, while he's out there...
fooling around. Bastard!
When are you going to stop
being so miserable?
When you do the same.
Watch out your words!
Watch out your questions.
You're so tricky and shameless!
What a coincidence, I thoght
the same of you.
- What are you talking about?
The music you played
Maria last night.
Do you realize the scandal
you've made?
A married man with children...
loving my sister and singing
a serenade in my own house?
Why do you make me
play the fool?
Don't talk that much!
Didn't you sing serenade
to my woman?
Well, that's different.
Sure it's different. Imagine
what they think of me.
When I left home this mornirng there
were some kids playing bullfight..
And one made fun out of me...
such a laugh that I
became suspicious.
If I'd known that you would react, I
wouln't have told you what I said-
I think you told me that
so I gave you the water.
- Do you think I'd do that?
- Sure!
You're so cunning and lazy!
Jorge, I'm tired
of your insults.
You made a coward out of me.
But that's it!
If you got something
against me...
let's knock the shit out
of us to kill ourselves!
- Are you so brave?
- Yeah.
- Come on.
- You first. Don't you have it in for me?
Come on, you idiot!
Take a look at this.
Can you see? You'll die by
hitting you with this rock.
- Go ahead now!
- I'm not that despicable!
I've already told you
that I can't kill you.
But I can.
Look!
You bastard! Would
you have shot me?
I would if you hit
me with the rock.
- What a bastard.
- Oh yeah.
Well.
Shall we continue
or shall we stop?
- As you wish.
- No, you decide.
Let's put an end to it.
Well. It's
alright.
Well, what we're here for...
I urgently need to
talk to Rosario.
It's not my business.
You've got to tell her.
One moment sir, we didn't agree
that I was going to procure her.
- No?
- Of course not!
We have the right to crawl,
but not that much.
Alright...
Just let me tell you that you won't have
water and you won't see Maria again.
Damn you!
When do you want to talk to her?
Tomorrow night.
- Where?
- In my place.
What! To take my woman
to your place? What...
Why not?
There's a party. I invite you
and you go with your wife.
It's the most common thing!
And what are we celebrating?
Tomorrow is the 23rd...
It's my birthday, don't
you remember?
Buddy! Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- I hope you die...
- What's up?
- I hope you die in many years.
You interrupted me.
Alright!
Girls, look who's coming.
How do you do, Pedrito?
How do you do, baby.
Is your wife fine?
She's fine, thanks.
And what about your
friend Jorge Bueno?
Is he good?
Well.
Pedro!
What's up General? What
are you doing here?
- Waiting for you.
- Here I am, please come in.
No, I'd rather stay here. It's
a very delicate matter.
You know that Jorge is
engaged to my daughter.
Yes sir.
You know that I made public
the engagement.
Yes sir.
And you know the banns
are being published.
Yes sir.
But what you don't know,
because in these matters the husband
is the last to know...
is that your great friend
Jorge Bueno...
has dishonoured you...
- Hey General.
- That's the word, sir!
Dishonoured!, because there's no
other way to name the fact...
that he sang a serenade
to your wife!
Shit! That was
really wrong!
Very bad done, General.
But since they were friend, maybe
it was just for friendship.
What friendship, like
hell you will!
He shouted at her
like a mad man...
I love you, I love you. Everyone
in the neighbourhood heard him.
What a shame!
Imagine my daughter's state.
To have such an offense on
the verge of the wedding!
She's been humiliated,
deceived and vilified.
It's like being kicked
in the teeth!
Well, general..
You know a man like me has
no other way but the arms.
I picked up my gun and I was ready
to wash the infamy with blood.
But thinking about it carefully,
I concluded...
That I shouldn't shoot Jorge.
That's a wise decision, General.
It doesn't worth it.
I'm not going to shoot him.
You will!
- Me?
- Of course!
Even though I'm deeply
offended...
I admit the sacred right to punish
that miserable belongs to you...
- You're right, I'm going to kill him!
- Right!
He's going to have
the worst death.
- Civil death.
- What?
In these matters oblivion is the best
thing, General. Please excuse me.
No sir! That's no
men's attitude.
- No?
- It's of cowards.
- Yes.
- And you're not a coward.
- No.
- Then, kill him!
That's the only honourable
way left!
Yes sir.
It's the only one.
Jorge surely dies!
- See you later, General.
- Where do you think you're going?
I'm going to take a shower.
No my friend, you must clean
your honour first...
and then you take whatever
you want. Let's go
Genoveva,
I think you know about that serenade
everybody's talking in town...
and I must explain my
behaviour telling you frankly
that when I asked for your hand I
sincerly believed that I was cured...
from an illness that
deeply affected me...
Unfortunately that illness has
struck me again so seriously...
that I think it has no cure.
I think you know it's name.
I don't want to offend
you repeating it.
General, would you excuse me?
I'll be back in a moment.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going er...
- To pick up my gun.
- There's no need.
Here's mine.
Take it.
- I can't accept!
- Why?
- I implicate you.
- It's best.
It's going to be a
joint revenge...
You'll pull the trigger and my
bullets will kill him. Take it!
Well, we'll take joint revenge.
By the way, do you want some
soda, General, I'm thristy.
I'm also thisty, but
of revenge. Let's go!
I'm not worried because I think your
father will understand and even say.
Don't worry, Jorgito,
it happens to all men.
He'll hold my hand as usual,
and he'll invite me to drink.
Yes sir, Jorge is at
the Post Office.
- Hurry up!
- General, shouldn't we think it twice?
It's been analized and solved,
the offender will die!
Well, and if there
is another guilty?
How can it be? Do you have
doubts about your wife?
- Oh no, not at all.
- Then?
Maybe I was wrong. Jorge
did it with my approval.
- No.
- Yes.
Then, the first who's gonna die
it's you, for being yielded!
- Give me my gun back.
- Please wait, General. Let me explain.
- There was a reason.
- I'm waiting to hear.
- Why do I tell you, you won't beleive.
- Come on!
- It was to save Genoveva.
- My daughter?
- From what?
- Of getting married to Jorge.
- It's not for her.
- And what is your business here?
Because my affection is great,
for her and for you...
and I had to prevent her
to marry Jorge somehow.
- But why?
- Because he's...
- got some kind of illness.
- And illness can be cured. Let's go!
- Not this one!
- How can you know!
Science's advanced, and there
are medicines for everything.
This one can't be cured.
You've got to beleive me.
Well, if it is a leprosy,
or something like that.
You've got it! It's not leprosy,
but someting as bad.
- No...
- Yes.
Imagine the disgrace for your
daughter and for you.
Having grandchildren ill-
fated, hunchback..
Without eyes, or a head this size.
No, what an atrocity.
Who would have thought that
on a healthy looking guy.
It's what he inherited from
his carousing father.
Well, and what does it have
to do with the serenade?
Everything! Jorge had kept the secret
and thought to be cured...
but after the engagement to Genoveva,
he realized that he was ill again...
and what to do? To tell
you about it? Never!
You should talk about these things
only to a physician...
then what to do? To imagine an
affair to dissapoint Genoveva.
What woman would do
the favor, General?
Only a friend. We talked to my wife
and Jorge sang the serenade...
and you know the rest
of the story...
I see. It was strange taht you
defend the lover of your wife.
- Of course.
- Yeah, everything is clear now.
But not the disease.
I don't beleive it!
- Hey General.
- Let's talk to Jorge!
- Why do we need to embarrass him?
- Let him get embarrassed!
I have to clear up this matter.
And if it is not true this story
about the incurable disease...
I swear on my father's ashes
an my militar honour
that I'll shoot you like
a dog. Let's go!
Jorge!
I'm here to speak as men do.
Here I am, General.
What's all about?
It's about an illness that...
Well, we have to be clear.
- Of that disease that you have!
- My disease?
At least that's what
your friend said.
And why are you talking
about what you shouldn't?
I demanded it.
Well General, in the end I had
to talk about it with you.
There is the first contradiction. You
said he wouldn't talk to me about it.
Well, he's changed his mind.
Well, besides you would
have known by this.
Letter to Genoveva where
I explain everything.
- May I read it?
- Yes, why not?
Hey General, I think it's no good
to learn what friends write.
Silence!
I think you know about that serenade
everybody's talking in town
and I must explain...
When I asked for your hand I sincerly
thought I was cured from a disease...
that depply affected me.
Unfortunately that illness has
struck me again so seriously...
that I think it has no cure.
I think you know it's name.
I don't want to offend
you by repeating it.
No, my daughter musn't
know this.
She had to know someday.
Maybe she knows it.
You're so cool about this
embarrassing matter!
But this is something that happens
to everybody sonner or later.
General, haven't you been
in such situation?
Heaven forbid! I'd
rather shot myself!
General, that's what one says...
but in the end there's
no shooting, and
you stay there. It's true
that it makes suffer.
But when it works, you enjoy it!
- So you like your disease.
- Yes sir, a lot!
There is no accountog
for tastes, general.
You shouldn't speak,
your're like me.
- You too?
- But I'm not as sick as him.
God, the world is upside down.
Do you have a good physician?
A physician?
No, General.
These things are not for doctors.
Either they go by themselves
or they distroy you.
I don't understand how
can you be resigned.
How can't it be. Since I was
a kid I have it in my heart.
You mean in your blood.
In my heart, blood, soul,
even in my bone marrow.
You're right. He's
in the final stage.
But if in spite of all this you
demand that I keep my word...
I marry your daughter.
No, no, no. There's no need to
disgrace innocent people...
ill-fated, hunchback, without
eyes and bigheaded kids.
Give me your word that you will
never think about my daughter.
Well, I promise, General.
Keep up with your plan with Rosario.
I'll make sure that Genoveva will see it.
I'll take her to your party. There
you can be a little shameless
so she'll be disappointed, and
I'll have no hard feelings,
On the contrary, I'll
be very grateful.
Hey! Why didn't he
shake my hand?
- Don't push it, buddy don't push it!
- You've got to explain everything!
Hey man, please, I'll
explain everything.
Then what, please say
yes, Chayito, please.
It's clear, Jorge handles
you like a puppet.
It's like you had a ring in the nose,
and pulls as you pull a, a...
- A bull?
- Or an ox, it's the same.
- Chill out, don't be so evil minded.
- You innocent!
He wants you have another woman, so
I could cheat you with him. He said so!
And listen, I could cheat you with
every man, but never with Jorge!
Every man?
Wll, I meant no-one, and
even less with Jorge
I only want to make peace, so we
can be friends as we used to...
- Yes...
- Come on Chayito, please me.
No!
Well alright, I'll go to his
party, but I don't want to.
Shit!
Hurry up, you're going
to be late to the party.
Wait, I've got to lock the car.
Because everyone is honest,
but you never know.
Hey girl, here comes Mrs. mmm,
mmm's wife and his father.
Who are mmm and mmmm?
Those who can't be named
in this house.
Mmmm.
Rosario and Pedro are here,
what are we going to do?
To serve them.
I invited them.
Jorge!
They say they're going
to close my paths...
They could close the paths.
But my love.
..when?
- What's up Jorge.
- What's up buddy.
- Congratulations buddy.
- Thanks buddy.
Hey buddy, it was very
hard to convince her
but there she is. Don't
exceed yourself.
- No, buddy, me?
- What did you tell Maria about me?
Nothing came to my mind. Let's
see how you can fix it.
What do I have to tell her?
- Go talk my sister, we'll see if it works.
- Ok.
- Congratulations Mr Jorgito.
- Thaks Mr. Elias. You look very happy.
Yes. Today is the first time my son-in-
law is taking his wife to a party.
Listen, do you promise
no to get drunk?
- Sure Mr. Elias.
- Ok.
Congratulations Jorge.
This far? What about
a hug to your friend.
Why not?
Don't start, don't exceed.
Behave well, please.
Chill out, Mr. Elias.
Marujita.
I just want to tell you that Periquito
can't fly any longer.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Since I never earn your love,
I want your friendship.
I made peace with Jorge. Now
I want peace with you.
We're in peace.
Do you want to dance
with your new friend?
Why not?
I just want to ask
you something.
Have you ever loved me?
Are you starting again?
No, it's only curiosity.
Did you ever love me?
I don't have to answer.
Mr. Elias, would you like to eat a
sandwich, a taco, do you want a soda?
No thanks, I'm not hungry.
Rosario...
- Do you want to dance?
- Yes Jorge.
- I've got to talk of an urgent matter.
- Listen Jorge...
Please don't interrupt.
If you're going to speak about...
what I think, it's better
to keep quiet.
I'm only asking to be heard.
Jorge, if I came is because Pedro told
me that you wanted to make peace.
- Let's be good friends.
- No!
If you love like I love you, we've
got to be more than friends.
- What do you mean?
- I talked to Pedro...
Pedro told me everything.
Everything.
But I don't care.
You marry me and I'll love your
daughter as if she were mine.
It's up to you.
It cannot be. Imagine
the scandal in town.
- We clear off!
- Your mother wouldn't allow it.
- I convince her.
- No Jorge, how would be our life?
- And your sister's hate.
- We'll work that out immediately!
- You talk to her and tell her everything.
- That's impossible, I don't dare.
- You tell her or I will.
- No Jorge, please.
Of course!
Well, since you want to know
it so bad, I'll tell you...
yes, I loved you.
When you got married
I suffered so much.
You can't imagine how I cried.
Then, why did you denied it?
Because I didn't want to share your
love with all those girlies.
You know how women are..
I thought you love me very little, I was
forcing you to love me more and...
And you forced it that much
that it couldn't resist...
- No, you couldn't resist.
- But we're in time to fix it.
Do you want to fix it?
No, I'm not destroying a family,
and less if there are children.
Children. She's only
one little girl.
- Maria! Rosario wants to talk to you.
- I don't want to.
But I do.
Jorge, please.
Desperate ills call for
desperate measures.
- Do you want a drink?
- A drink for this anger.
We've got to take advantage of my
mother's absence, and go to the city.
And from there?
You get divorced, I got married,
you got married and...
We go to the United States!
And if general discovers that we
fooled him with your disease.
No buddy. How
can he know?
Talk to the doctor. I know
he's looking for him.
We've got to go before
the fair time arrives!
And you, silence.
- Sure.
- Ok.
I think this is not going
to work. I feel strange.
No buddy, you've got
to be optimistic.
- What are they looking at my head?
- Your head?
God! This outfit
goes after me!
- Hey Pedro.
- I want to talk to you. Excuse me.
- What happens uncle?
- I'm not your uncle.
Take your woman, we're
leaving right away.
But why?
Because I'm ashamed.
Don't you realize?
While your dancing
with Maria Jorge is
courting your woman,
isn't that enough?
Uncle, there certain things that
can't explained to you...
What the hell, he told
me the same thing.
- What happens, Mr. Elias?
- It happens that I'm tired of...
of your bad bahavior with my daughter.
I'm taking her right away!
Please keep cool.
Let's go somewhere else that we're
telling you the whole truth.
- The truth? Is there something wrong?
- No, please come.
You're going to tell me everything.
Why do bring me here?
- Sit here.
- Please tell me the whole truth,
tell me at once what's
all about.
- Can you see that hole in there?
- Yes.
- Sure?
- Yes,
- You don't fit there.
- Listen to me!
Listen to me, you bastad,
why do you bring me here!
Hell!
The General will arrive anytime. If
he speaks to him, we're in hell.
- We've got to get rid of him.
- I'll fix it.
- Jorge, Jorgito.
- How do you do doctor, are you fine?
I was resting in Guadalajara, when
I remebered it was your birthday.
- I came very fast!
- Didn't you have problems on the way?
Not at all, in spite
of the speed!
- How are you?
- Sweating, doctor.
- The heat?
- No, but I'm sweating.
- Because of today's excitement!
- It must be.
Doctor, please go quick
to Santa Fe ranch,
a horse fell on the steward
and he's dying!
I tell you, I just have arrived and I
must go to do some emegency healing!
Go on and carry out your duty.
- Doctor, I found you at least!
- How do you do, General.
- Very bad, and I'm offended!
- Why is that?
Because you didn't tell me
about what you know...
I mean, professional secrecy
must be kept behind.
What are you talking
about, what secret?
- Come so we can speak.
- No I can't. I must go..
- The wounded is dying, doctor.
- You see, General. See you later.
- Hi General, nice to see you.
- I'm very upset!
Why General?
Are you asking yet? Genoveva
didn't want to come...
but I managed to convince her.
I came ahead to make a plan.
She wants to hear your explanation,
but we must avoid that.
Desperate ills call for
desperate measures.
What do you want to do?
To attack! When she arrives, let
her see you very close to...
this sir's wife.
- And that's it. So let's get started.
- Don't worry General, I'm coming.
I value all that you do for your
friend, and thanks for my part.
You're welcome, General.
Very generous your action.
But there's a gossip about you!
I advise you to leave the
town as soon as possible.
We have thought
that. Excuse me.
I've got to go out of here,
even at my life's expense!
Bastards! Open,
open.
I'm still thinking that
you're two shameless!
But very generous.
Pedro...
I retract half of
what I said to you
but we talk the other
half later...
- Brother..
- Mmm.
I'm pride of your big heart.
You know how to love.
My daughter has arrived. Dance
or do something, but do it!
We dance!
- Come my girl, please come.
- No please.
Take me out! At least they open!
I'm going to see that bastard.
- Disobedient children!
- What happens Mr. Elias.
General, come this way.
- Please lend me your gun.
- What for?
To see if Jorge respects me.
Look at him, dancing cheek
to cheek with my daughter.
- I'll kill that bastard!
- Easy, don't spoil the plan.
- What plan?
- There are things that can't be said.
- You too?
- Me too what?
It seems that you have
an understanding.
Sure. The four of us have
I'm going to explain, look.
- Excuse me.
- You're welcome.
Hey,
Aren't you Pantaleon,
Santa Fe's steward?
Yes sir.
Weren't you dying because
a horse fell on you?
Hey doctor, someone joke on you.
What a funny joke!
Get back.
If someone looks for me,
I'm at Jorge Bueno's.
What a hapiness to have
you like that...
my darling
feeling the beat of your heart
drinking anxiously your breath
burning myself in your look.
There are people who die from pain
jelous for not being in love
it doesn't matter that people
if God has brought you to me.
God's will be done.
What a hapiness to have
you like that...
my darling
feeling the beat of your heart
drinking anxiously your breath
burning myself in your look...
Dad, give him back his ring,
I want nothing from him!
My daughter, Genoveva, wait...
die..
Jelous for not being in love
it doesn't matter that people
if God has brought you to me.
God's will be done.
Dinner is served!
Mr. Elias, it's time
to speak honestly.
Don't worry to explain, Jorgito,
I'm not that dumb
I know that is for
everybody's good.
Everything turned out as planned.
Here is your engagement. Goodbye.
Good heavens! Why do you say
that everything's over?
Because he has humiliated me,
ridiculized me, with a married woman.
Married? He inherited that
from his father, I'm sure.
Many problems with married women
I had with my deceased husband.
No my son, please
explain. The.
General says that everything
is because...
he doesn't want the children of Genoveva
to receive that heredity..
What heredity and whose are
the children of Genoveva?
But Jorge's!
- Jorge?
- I'll explain later...
- Good evening, General.
- Madam, I'm very sorry
to let you know that the wedding
has been dissolved.
And I'm also sorry to let
you know the reason.
I know the reason.
What can I do?
I'm ashemed. My deceased husband
suffered the same...
problem and Jorge inherited it.
- Then you knew!
- Of course.
And why didn't you warn me?
I didn't know you wanted a perfect
husband for your daughter!
No, but with such a disease,
it's a tragedy.
No, no, it's a common
thing to all men!
Madam! What do
you insinuate?
Come on, General, you may
have something to hide.
Madam, you're very wrong...
General, all that we speak
is not to be needed.
Good night.
Hey, now the family is complete.
How do you do madam?
- What are you doing here?
- I came to visit.
- Where is the rest?
- At the dinning room.
- And Jorge?
- Jorge is with Rosario.
Jorge with Rosario?
Strange indeed? But it's only because
the children Jorge has with Genoveva
won't be inherited.
What?
I'm telling you what
the General tod me.
Neither Pedro nor
Jorge told me..
Whe I ask, they only say "There are
things that can't be explained".
Is that ok?
I'll take out a truck without being
seen. I'll wait for you at the door.
- I'm taking out our stuff.
- We'll go through the front door..
Pick up my daughter
and God be with us!
- Is everything ready?
- Yeah.
- No, there's one missing thing.
- What?
This!
Yeah!
What the hell happens here?
A husband holding
the other woman.
And her brother kissing the
husband's wife in his face?
Mom, there are things that
can't be explained.
I told you so.
Now you will explain
or you'll know me.
One moment.
We're going to explain
everything.
No, you won't confuse me,
nor this one. Out of here!
- But mom.
- Out, I said!
- They told me that!
- They fooled you. I swear, yeah.
Jorge is a healthy guy, I know!
- Are you willing to testify it?
- Even with doctors, if you will.
- Alright! Come with me.
- Let's go.
Nobody is making a fool of me!
- Wait General.
- You're going to hear me!
- Let's talk like people.
- You shut up!
First I'll fight a duel
with you, then with you!
General, there's no need
for such killings!
It's late to explain.
On your way!
- But General, a little bit of..
- Shut up, or I'll fight a duel with you!
Yes general...
In spite of everything,
Jorge still loves me.
And Pedro loves me.
There's no doubt that
tragedy is after us!
That's why everybody's mad, this
poor arab in first place.
I'm no longer an
arab, I'm asian.
- Why?
- Because they took me for a ride!
Stop joking!
I'm not agree with these
crossed marriages.
Josefa, come here!
A terrible tragedy. The boys and the
general are going to shoot themselves!
- We must avoid that killing!
- God heavens!
- That's enough!
- Let me go!
I've got to punish
those bastards!
Let them finish the party singing,
and then you'll kill them!
No sir, I'll kill them firs, then they
can sing as much as they want!
Easy general, that I'll
explain everything!
- No darling, this can't be!
- Please daddy, you're so nice, say yes!
- Is our happiness, Mr. Elias.
- But look at the tangle of relatives!
I'm father-in-law and
uncle of Pedro.
As Jorge and Pedro
are like brothers,
Jorge is getting married
his sister-in-law.
And my poor grandaughter
will have two
step-fathers, and will
be of two uncles!
That mean that I'm not fater-in-law,
but fater of Jorge and Maria.
Maria marries a nephew,
then Mrs Josefa..
Is my woman and my sister
at the same time.
What a family salad!
Please stop, if not, I'm going to be
Pedro's mother, and I won't marry him.
Now tell me that Jorge, loving Rosario
as he does, wouldn't forgive?
Any woman can have
such a disgrace!
A country girl goes to the
city go to a ballroom
and there she's made high,
she can't be responsible!
What a villainy!
Why didn't you go after those
criminal, to be punished!
She's was thinking only in her
disgrace, snd how to suicide.
Pedro is very generous!
To marry Rosario just to
give a name to the child.
That was it!
Because they were legally married,
but they have lived like brothers!
Now I understand.
But Pedro, how he fooled me!
- What a bastard!
- Excuse me?
- Music!
Let's forget our pain!
The party has started
everybody comes to the party
to enjoy yourselves
girls are so beautiful
dressed up to the nines
with he earrings
and their patent leather shoes.
Ah, so many sherbert
and orgeat stands
the fresh lemonade and
jamaica water...
we also have melon and
strawberry water..
We have delicious tepache
water from red watermelon,
but of pineapple..
Many adorned stands
with little flags and ribbon
and beautiful ladies serve in there!
Hot lard, chili
and sweet tamales
brown doughnuts and gorditas
there they play lottery
and throw the dice
two lovers married.
A maricahi is playing there, and ..
A charro and a lady are dancing.
Our parties are so beautiful.
Everything is hapiness,
candies, music and color.
Lots of dark eyes with
glittering of stars.
Are looking for a open ranchero.
They're the stamps of my land
they're dressed in colors,
songs and love.
A singer in sequin...
that reflect on its shine
the glittering of my stars,
my sky and my..
My sun.
The End.