Famed industrialist Vijay Kapoor's
companies and factories...
are already mortgaged. Now the court
has ordered the auctions
We tried to find out
Vijay Kapoor's reactions
But he isn't talking
to the press or the media
Medicines cure these ailments. But
for wounds, there are no cures...
not for those inflicted upon you
by ones who are your own
Relationships... I heard
they fraught fraternities, Pratima
Mine... oh they have broken me
so completely
"The king..."
"the queen..."
"oh, they are young,
and they are rich"
"What's left to ask for?
This is all Destiny's doing"
"It's what your love
has done for us"
"What's left for asking?"
"My home is my temple
you are my God"
"You are my prayer answered"
"Who else would love me so much?"
"Who else would give me
so much happiness?"
"At your feet, I wish to stay"
"In your arms, I want lifetime"
"What else is left for asking?"
"Like blossoms,
that gift of nature..."
"are our parents to us"
"Every day I have prayed for you"
"And every dream of mine
comes true, at last"
"These relationships
are to be nurtured"
"And once my prayers are answered..."
"what more will be left to seek
out of life?"
"There is a king,
there is a queen"
"They are mementos
of your love"
"This is all Destiny's doing"
"It's all His doing; everywhere,
His blessings abound"
"What more is left
to seek of life?"
Three imperatives for the successful
management of any enterprise
The ownership, the management,
the worker
Workers are known to have
grouses against companies
There are owner-worker problems,
management's and workforce don't gel
But it is the ownership which is
responsible and answerable
In situations like these,
once a month...
if owners were to make the workers
and the management's meet...
to talk out things, then
a relationship is struck...
between ownership, management
and workers. That is when...
the entire establishment is organized,
woven into a strong family
And as far as I know, no family in
the world has ever suffered a strike
Therefore I am confident
when I say this...
The legacy of strikes, this problem
of sick industries...
will be rooted out
once and for all
You were in there, weren't you?
- Yes sir
You didn't like what I said?
- While the others listened...
I was entranced by what you said.
By the time I came around...
the round of applause was over
All my life I had seen you only
in the pictures. I keep collecting...
your articles, your interviews.
Do take a look, please
What's your name?
- Rajesh Purohit
I have an MBA from
Allahabad University
Yes! Same university as yours
What have you been doing of late?
- I'd rather tell you...
what I wish to achieve. From you,
the one who propelled...
Kapoor Industries to such heights,
if I could learn something...
about achieving, then I will consider
myself a very successful man, sir
Why not see me in my office tomorrow?
- Yes sir! Thank you sir
Sir, you wanted the list
of textile mills
Papa, I'm stuck at the crosswords!
- My child, I'm at the office
The clue is "Commerce, business".
The answer is in four letters
Four letters?
"Ro-z-ga-r" (Wage)
Papa, I could browse whole
dictionaries, but this one...
I'd never find. You want the clue?
"Greens, out of farm"
Four letters, this one.
- Five...?
"Tar-o-ta-za"
(Fresh)
Yes, "Tar-o-ta-za"
One minute, Preeti!
- No please! Last, last
Rajesh, why don't you go over and
help Preeti solve her crossword?
Give me the file
Come on in. Papa sends you?
Yes.
- Come on, sit
Rajesh, you want to solve crosswords?
All right, let's test you
Five empties to fill
The first, is two letters
The second, three
Third, four
Fourth, five
Fifth, six
Each ends with "Ri"
Start?
- Yes
First clue, "Woman"
- "Na-ri"
Second, "Small vessel"
- "Ga-ga-ri"
"Government-related"
- "Sa-r-ka-ri"
"Small-time trading"...?
- "Du-ka-n-da-ri"
Last word. "Lawless city"
- "An-dh-er Na-g-ri"
All the answers, pat! And I thought
no one in the world...
is smarter, more intelligent than Dad!
You seem to be even more brilliant
No Ms Preeti, answering 5 crosswords
doesn't make a Vijay Kapoor
And what a magnetic personality
Hear him, and you want to meet him.
See him and you're drawn to him
The truth is, I worship your Daddy
When you aren't, I pine.
When you are with me, I'm restless
I have decided. I want to marry you.
- No! I'm not worthy enough...
to even consider this! Mr. Kapoor
has done me a great favor
Am I to repay him like this?
And let him berate me?
What are you saying Rajesh...?
- To me, he is an ideal
I can never do anything
that might hurt him
He will have my resignation tomorrow.
I should be leaving
Mr. Vijay, are you expecting a guest?
- Someday, one's daughter leaves
The boy is coming today.
- To meet our Preeti
Just watch this, dear brother-in-law.
Wedding's happening in no time
But which family? Who's the boy?
This is my home, not office, Rajesh.
A guest invited to dinner...
isn't expected to ask for permission
to come in
Papa! How did you get to know...?
It's your happiness I cherish
Be seated, Rajesh
Your parents... your family... why
is no one else here from your side?
I'm an orphan, sir.
I'm the only family I have
So what? When Pratima and I
got married, all we had...
were a pair of dresses each.
And by and by...
by dint of my efforts,
I built this empire
And throughout this journey,
all I had were Pratima and God
One bad decision.
Hey, you're getting married!
- Such is the jet age
Discussions aren't under way yet,
and here's a wedding on the cards
But this wedding isn't happening
without Ajay
Rajesh, Ajay is my son. He's away
vacationing after his final semester
As soon as he's back, we'll just
pack the two of you off
"My wild heart
is looking for a beauty"
"But who she is..."
"I don't even know"
"Someday she will come to me..."
"someday, she will bring love"
"I will kiss her"
"I will embrace her"
"I'm the pretty dream in her eyes"
"Oh, I'm so eager to see her"
"My wild heart
is looking for a beauty"
"But who she is..."
"I don't even know"
"My wild heart
is looking for a beauty"
"But how do I describe him?"
"Oh, he's a wild one"
"He's one-in-a-million,
he's my lover"
"In my dreams he flirts with me"
"Oh what a darling"
"Someday, I'll surely get him"
"But who she is..."
"I don't even know"
"My wild heart
is looking for a handsome man"
"Hey beauty, what's your name?"
"None of your business"
"Hey, you're stuck-up. Slow down"
"You're insolent. Get lost"
"Don't you show me your temper.
- Don't you try to flirt"
"You won't give in so easily?
- I know your type"
"You're drunk!
- But I think..."
"you're quite helpless.
Who are you...?"
"Who you are, I don't even know"
Hey, I'm still single, I swear
My dark little, darling sister
How's my son?
- I'm fine
Look at her! Time so soon for
my little blossom to get married?
Looking so pretty... and the henna
on your hands too?
May God bestow upon these hands
all the happiness, forever
Where's Papa?
I'll find him.
Stay put
No sir, please! This apartment,
this car, servants...
this sudden payhike, for no reason,
oh please don't be so kind to me
I promise, I'll make Preeti
very happy, I'll pamper her
But I want to be a self-made man.
I don't want to compromise my ideals
Look Rajesh, had Preety married into
a big family, I would've liked them...
to care for her like a daughter. Not
as a son-in-law, more like a son...
can you not live in our house?
Like a member of our family?
Come, share our joys, our sorrows
Why is God sending so much happiness
an orphan's way?
Parents, brothers, sisters,
relationships...
for me, they were mere words.
Meanings, I never even knew
All this for me, in this very
lifetime? I can't believe this!
Couldn't be a better man for Preeti,
not in this world
And you, Mummy-Papa's choice,
Preeti's paramour...
are my friend
Welcome...
oh hello...
hi lady... welcome
Welcome... welcome...
this smile is giving me a jaw-ache.
This was one offer I couldn't refuse
How about a kiss?
Don't make me pine
What...?
- You're my heartthrob
My heart goes out to you.
- You lazy laggard
Roadside Romeo! Savage!
Beast! Blackheart
O'heartless one, your every torment
I shall bear. But I swear by you...
you I have given my heart to!
- Uneducated loafer!
You're insane! While you wait,
someone will whisk me away
No!
This no filmi plot
And I'm not insane
This is no love triangle
Just a simple straight love story.
A tale of twosomes...
like Romeo and Juliet,
Laddoo and Sweety
Moron! The legendary lovers
never married in the end
The committed suicide, or they were
killed. Spare me, I don't want to die
Something is stirring in my heart.
- And then...?
I'm in love
Love is never defeated.
- And then...?
I'm no less a man!
I'm your prince charming!
- And then...?
The lover will carry his bride away!
Still stuck at "then"...?
All superhits films, no?
- So...?
Coming for a long drive?
- First get me a drink
For attending my daughter's wedding,
for receiving my guests...
I don't want to thank you. Because
your debts I can never pay off...
with thanks.
- Sir, why embarrass us?
Can we ever forget your debt?
- What a thing to say
At weddings, we fathers have only
given our daughters away
The rest of it, you have
always shouldered
The one who is getting married today
is our daughter. Let us do our bit
I'm thankful.
- Farewell
Best wishes.
- Thanks a lot
I've just concluded
a major responsibility
But you still have
your responsibilities
You have always had my best wishes.
One word of friendly advice
Tell me.
- This is a grand wedding
But you know the business community,
more enemies, than friends
Your competition might be enthused.
- At chess, they can't checkmate me
Can they checkmate me in business?
You...!
- You...?
What are you doing here?
- That's what I want to know
It's my best friend's sister's wedding.
- Both, my sisters
A savage? In such a good family?
- Such God willed
Talking about savages, ever taken
a look at yourself? At your flaws?
None that I see
First, you're stubborn.
Second, you have a temper
Third, you're brainless. Fourth,
you love to flaunt your Dad's money
Five, you haven't a dressing sense.
- And you? Ever considered yourself?
Flaws are all you'll see.
- Can you count out a couple?
Count.
- Go on
One, you think you're oversmart.
- Because I'm intelligent, brilliant
Besides, fools think I'm oversmart.
- You don't have manners!
Let's have that announced. I you
can find anyone else who says that...
I won't ever talk to a girl
ever again, I swear
You're too tall.
- Inherited that
Not to get worked up.
- Wait, I'll tell you
Give me some time
What does he think of himself?
Not a flaw?
Which I am
What's come over you?
- Your brother...
what does he think of himself?
- Why, what happened?
He's out of his mind.
Says, I have a temper
Which you are.
- You...
You have this temper, don't you?
- I'm stubborn, I flaunt my Dad's money
I'm brainless! And no dressing sense!
- He said that?
Those words!
- What a wonder...
That's why I'm telling you. The flaws
I never noticed in all these years...
Ajay makes out, he even tells you!
Now that the education is over,
what about the future?
I've picked up an IT major with MBA.
Maybe I'll get into IT business
The government is promoting it too
What are the Big Three discussing?
Dad makes it a Big Four.
- We were discussing IT
Ajay want to get into IT business
Business is a fine thing
Ajay has just...
finished studying about IT. He doesn't
have any business experience
What did you say about experience?
- Look son, without experience...
one stands to lose.
I'm not against business
But I will always oppose
an amateur effort
In IT, experience isn't necessary.
And how does one gain experience...
without working?
- Experience is what you need...
while taking decisions.
A successful businessman...
is one who has the guts
to take decisions
Books don't contain experience.
Books tell you about experience
Ajay isn't out of his knickers.
You want him to don a suit?
Preeti, you don't know a thing.
Ajay is a big player
Tell me, what's your game?
I'm fixing all your matches
Not match-fixing, this is about
girl-fixing
Is our Ajay in love?
- All that I don't know.
But nowadays...
- Clam up
He's adept in finding flaws in girls!
- Hush!
Ajay found all of five flaws
in this friend of mine, Nisha
This is too bad! You ought
to flatter pretty girls
I only wanted to make her presentable,
to help her understand...
how to conduct herself
before her elders...
You think he's joking?
- He sounds serious
Papa! Nice opportunity to get him
married. Talk to Mr. Thapar
No way!
The girl's father comes asking
for an alliance
You talk of alliances after she
and I have a nice relationship going
And as far as rituals
are concerned...
I have my family right here
with me
That's Vijay Kapoor's son
Welcome son
That's your chair
A father's dreams
By dint of your hard work, you will
prove yourself worthy of that chair
Two premises to the argument.
If you want...
you can just walk over and sit there.
But I would like you to make it...
by dint of hard work
and your own capabilities
Son, the tree that has struck its
roots deep, isn't swayed by storms
I'd rather you applied yourself
to work, and climb step by step...
till you get there
If you want a business of your own, by
all means, yes. But your prime duty...
is to manage this company.
- Yes, Papa. Where do I begin?
What are you upto? I told you
to go and get me a beer. Go on
But Mr. Harry Singh, my machine
is running. How can I leave it?
Machine stopped? Go, get me a beer.
Go on, what are you staring at?
Chilled beer
Your magic is working.
- Why what happened?
Nisha is completely changed!
She doesn't know what a temper is
What's being stubborn? She doesn't
even know! She's so demure
She has even changed
the way she dresses
Only traditional Indian clothing
The churidar-kurta,
the salwar-kameez
She looks great!
- Lovely little sister... sit
How about doing something for me?
- Want to meet Nisha? Say it
When is she going to come?
Hi Nisha! Come, sit
You're looking great
All credits to you
At least I've had an effect on you!
Even the same-same colour
I'd like to come to the point.
Nisha, I want to marry you
I've changed. I don't want
to let my past shadow my future
Great! Past is best forgotten.
- That's what I want to tell you
You belong to my past. So I'd like
to forget things like you
I'm no "thing".
- Oh Ajay! You don't understand
Now I can find a better boy
for myself
What if I find someone else?
- Willing to lose anything
Him
Him...?
He won't even talk to you!
The girls are all over him
See...?
- Right over here...?
Shall we be friends?
Has she gone mad?
Ajay takes girl out, speaks his mind.
Girl goes out with Ajay...
talks her heart to someone else,
and makes a jilted lover out of him
Can't woo a girl! How can he manage
such a big company?
Does my son know
what experience means?
Takes time to grow that hair.
- Then you find it has greyed already!
A perfect solution! Just set up
an "Institute for Reforming Girls"
Girls will come to be reformed. Then
they will walk away with someone else
Enough of jokes at my expense
Ajay Kapoor knows only how to win
Priya, do you have her numbers?
- She has! They keep chatting
Rani, don't interfere
I have her number. Let me dial her up.
- Fast
But you got to do your talking
Go on Ajay.
- I'd like to see you
Consider this urgent.
- No time tomorrow
I'm out picnicking with Sunil.
- Any place in particular?
I'll tell you, provided
you don't disturb me
What happened?
She's going to dreamworld
with some actor, Sunil
But I'm going there.
- To do what? Guess...?
What...?
- He'll play marbles
I can woo girls, I can run companies.
I'll prove that to you
Bravo son! But I'm coming too.
- What will you do there, Ma?
No picnic without me!
- If you go, I go too
Me too!
- Me too
No one is going anywhere
All of us are going for a picnic
Here we are, Dreamworld.
Now declare your war for love
You're looking the wrong way.
Look, how your dove is necking away
Sally forth, like a brave!
Slap him twice, take his place
I'd like to talk to Nisha
Yes go on Ajay.
- So you see Nisha...
even the hues of our lives match!
What I mean to say is...
you won't find anyone better than me.
- Such vanity...?
Please marry me.
- Stubborn too
Nisha, try to understand!
- Has a temper too
What am I lacking in? I've everything!
Houses, cars, money! Everything
Flaunts his Dad's money?
- Ajay, all my bad habits!
You've inculcated all of them.
Please change yourself
Else, no girl is ever
going to like you
We're having a small picnic
This is going to be real fun!
This Vijay! My son has a heartburn!
And he's bringing her right over!
Ajay must win Nisha's heart. Else,
her heart will stay with that Sunil...
even after she has married Ajay!
- Shut up
What use such a marriage?
You'd rather weep and get over it now
You think my nephew can't live without
her? No way! Come, let's square her
How much more am I to eat?
I'm bursting at my seams
Listen, we're playing a game.
- Funtastic! Cricket, football
Gentlemen here will flatter
the women they love
Yes, we're always finding faults with
our ladies. Who ever flatters them?
Token of appreciation
from the lady will be a kiss
Silence, silence! Let's play.
- I begin
Tresses as black as a buffalo's!
- Shut up, Laddoo. Mr. Vijay first
I behold in her poetry personified
She's flirtatious, whimsical,
she enlivens
Without her, my evening are empty
She is my life, my hope, my desires
The keeper of my secrets,
she is my very heartbeat
She is the smile on my lips,
a mother, a lover...
from her flows forth
every relationship...
she is the fountainhead
The lady ought to give a kiss
All right
I flatter you and the mirror gets
the kiss? What do I do with that?
Please, my turn now. My turn!
- Go ahead
First I'll flatter Sweety. In return,
she will give me a sweet, sweet...
Flattery first.
- To that bracelet on your arm...
my heart is stuck.
- To her bracelet? Brilliant
Don't shake that arm,
it'll break my heart
Watch that heart, wear my bracelet.
- Give me a kiss
Why should I? You were flattering
the bracelet
Lucky for you, you didn't
flatter her slippers
Mr. Sunil, whom will you flatter?
- Nisha
And Ajay, you...?
- Of course, Nisha
Winner takes my heart
Get started. Let's decide right away
"Your eyes, like lakes"
"In you, the magic of fountains"
"One look at you..."
"and I am restless"
"There are those who talk of
lakes, fountains and love"
"I call you my goddess of love"
"Gods will bow before this beauty"
"Before my love, no one can stand"
"This is no love"
"The fellow-traveller
isn't the lover"
"Those in love tread upon thorns
and brave the fires"
"Oh why do you not trust my love?
Were it not for true love..."
"this world would never be"
This is too bad Nisha
The contest isn't over yet.
If Ajay can do what I can...
he wins.
- I can do whatever you do
You want me to show you?
- Go on
Think it over.
- Done
Nice act
"The winds, the clouds are saying
what a wonderful sight this is"
"But only a heart will ever know
what a heart has to say"
"The winds, the clouds are saying
what a wonderful sight this is"
"But only a heart will ever know
what a heart has to say"
"Love calls out to love,
oh so lovingly"
"When my eyes met loving eyes,
I fell in love"
"But only a heart will ever know
what a heart has to say"
"When my eyes met loving eyes,
I fell in love"
"When I saw the pining,
I wished I'd die for love"
"In my lover's arms,
my love will be requited"
"In love's embrace,
even love loses itself"
"My love..."
"you are the one I aspire for"
"Your youthfulness has swept me
off my feet"
"Oh how I've spent all these moments
without you"
"Love calls out for love,
oh so lovingly"
"With love, let me etch my name
in your heart. It's Love"
"Nothing's greater than love,
all I want to do is make love"
"Look at love, ask for love,
with love"
"If love ever deserts me,
speak to me of love"
"This promise,
let never be broken..."
"let us never part"
"Your love I treasure
more than my life"
"You, I hold in my heart"
"Love calls out for love,
oh so lovingly"
"The winds, the clouds are saying
what a wonderful sight this is"
"But only a heart will ever know
what a heart has to say"
"Love calls out..."
"To love...
"oh so lovingly"
"With love"
Pack up.
- Hey who are you to order us around?
Cut out the informality.
- You bloody...
Hari Singh! One minute!
Ajay, please! Let me talk
Hari Singh, what's this attitude?
He's the boss' son
At home, maybe. Here, he's a worker.
And I'm his senior
True, but the sight of gambling in
the premises can rouse tempers, no?
Let him complain to the supervisor.
I'll do what my supervisor tells me
Times when we'd bow like slaves before
the King-in-waiting are gone
No, that's not the case...
- Idler! I'll break your face
You don't know who I am!
- What are you waiting for?
Come on, break my face!
- One minute! Ajay please
Hari Singh, just forget this.
- This isn't going to be forgotten
This is going to be decided.
Here and now! And you stay out
You stay out! Get that?
- I won't budge an inch
Because you're the union leader, you
expect everyone to lick your boots?
Hey son-in-law-about-the-house!
You think you own this factory?
Let go of him!
You're going to kill him
Ajay! Stop! Please!
No getting away with this!
- Ajay, listen to me
I'll put an end to this leadership!
Booze and gambling!
You're going to kill him!
- It's over! Once and for all! Let go
He won't ever touch anyone
What does he think of himself?
He can do whatever he wants?
I sent you to the factory to learn.
Not to teach anyone
Workers are paid to work,
not to gamble
Your principle, maybe. But you
have no right to impose yourself
Then why just four of them?
Tell all the workers to gamble
Those four hold 4000 at ransom.
Workers are brainwashed into...
thinking that if anyone
is concerned with or capable of...
ensuring their welfare, it's the only
the unionists. But the truth is...
these unions have contributed to
nothing but poverty, hunger, larceny
Ever seen the sheep being herded
by four dogs?
They Mr. Ajay Kapoor, are our ones
Meaning, you knew everything?
- Yes. And though I'm in the know...
I have to pretend ignorance
Not in 25 years, have workers ever
gone on strike in this factory
Reason wherefor is the way
I use the union
Hari Singh assaulted Rajesh,
but he didn't retaliate
Because he knows it's not in the
interests of the factory. But you?
The vigour of your youth
makes you oblivious?
Look Ajay...
I don't wish to be a subject of
ridicule for the business community
I want you to apologise
to that union leader right now
Okay, Papa
For the sake of the workers,
Hari Singh can take a beating
But betray the workers,
I never will
We aren't slaves, are we?
He said something in English?
But English, I don't know
Had I known English, would I be
a worker? I'd be a manager
For our sakes, let's hear you speak
in Hindi whatever you said in English
Go on, are you shy?
Forgive me
What did he say?
Anyone heard that?
But only yesterday, you ripped
the shirt off my back in public
You stripped me. Now King-in-waiting
speaks in hushed tones? Speak up
Come on, say it. In public
Yesterday...
I assaulted him
It was my mistake
Therefore, I beg his forgiveness
For the first time in my life, I've
bowed before a man who has wronged
Because you told me.
- You shouldn't regret apologising...
for what was your mistake.
- But I can't bring myself...
to bear the pain I am suffering
...the rage within. Accepted...
your experience count more than mine.
But the way you think differs...
entirely from the way I perceive
things. A difference of a generation
So I have decided to start up
the IT business on my own
The business I want to get into, needs
no experience. Education is enough
Do you have the capability
of managing a company?
Look son... you don't learn swimming
sitting ashore
Without knowledge of good and bad,
rights, wrongs in business context...
you can't get into business.
You'll end up ruining your company
In the IT business,
you don't need packdogs
It takes educated, capable people.
- Do you imply that...
ones who are educated, capable,
do not deal with unions?
Big-time politicians are involved!
- The American solution is hire-n-fire
No, that'd be oppressing your workers.
- What about what I was forced to do?
You do not see that? Papa, you want
to use the union to control workers
I want the remote control in my hands.
Between you and I...
maybe, therein lies the difference.
- Not differences, son
Differing points of view. I think
experience is more necessary
For you, education is more important.
These views aren't reconcilable
They never were, they never will be.
- Meaning whereby...
that I cannot expect you
to support my venture?
Brother-in-law! Where are you?
We've been disgraced! Ruined!
- He's very busy
What is the matter? Tell me.
- Ajay has disgraced us
Read this paper! Everyone in
the market is laughing at us
Don't let him hear this.
- What's this hue-and-cry?
For the sake of the family!
- What is the matter?
What's left to be said?
Read this
Look at what Ajay has done
Borrowing from the market?
What's all this? How much do you need?
Ten million? 20...? 50...? 1 00...?
More? Want a billion?
Just fill in this cheque
But never again make the mistake
of borrowing from the market
You're financing me to protect
your reputation on the markets
More than your son, you care for your
prestige? That's what you care more
I'll never accept what's given
in contempt. Take that cheque back
Your father's name, you have already
maligned. Go, pawn my name if you will
Ajay, he's hurt very deeply.
I'm telling you all this...
because I'm your elder in years.
Take what he's giving you, please
Just let me liquidate your loans.
What's wrong with us investing?
This investment is free of interest.
You bring home all your profits
And outsiders don't have a say.
- Rajesh, enough
Leave me alone
Ajay, I'm not leaving you all alone.
Just listen to your father
Go away
What's up? Going somewhere?
- We're leaving this house
Why...?
I don't wish to be a burden on ones
who have no respect for my husband
I'll make do with whatever
my husband can provide for me
I prefer hardship to life lived
in disgrace. Your teachings, no?
But who misbehaved with your husband?
- Preeti, say no more
You must tell me the truth!
What's going on?
Ajay has ordered him
out of the house
What happened?
- Today, no one interferes
I'm still alive, Ajay. I still breathe!
Who gave you the right...
to tell Rajesh to leave this house?
- I didn't ask him to leave
I only asked him to leave me alone.
- You should have the guts to own up
It's fear of your father
that makes you lie
Papa, I revere you.
I'm not afraid of you
Yes, I see that you have begun
to suspect my truths
Are you so frustrated that you try
to make a lie sound like the truth?
And because you cannot take it out
on me, you unleash yourself on Rajesh?
If you think I'm frustrated with life,
you are completely mistaken, Papa
I'm educated, I can seek solutions to
every problem. Frustrated, I won't be
Trust me.
- This confidence in yourself...
is misplaced. You think these loans
you raise were given to you...
because of your capabilities? Wrong!
In the market...
not even the unknown beggar is given
alms. And you are known to be...
Vijay Kapoor's son. Because of this
singular virtue the markets lend you...
knowing, that even if you cannot
pay interests...
Vijay Kapoor will go to the extent of
selling himself to pay back every cent
Papa, why are you so arrogant?
What makes you think that...
even the air I breathe
is thanks only to you?
Look son...
once the son has grown up, he takes
his father's pride to be vanity
And the father...
the father pities his son
for his inexperience
I don't need certificates from
my family to prove my knowledge
Once differences in perceptions have
cropped up between the generations...
the two should go their separate ways.
- You tread your path at your own risk
I shall... I shall leave.
I surely will
Ajay, I'm the root cause of all
the trouble. Please, say no more
Let him speak, Rajesh.
He has forgotten decorum
You force me to speak.
- As I forced you to borrow?
After you refused me, I had no way out.
Maybe you doubt my capabilities
In that case, would I have sent
you abroad for studies?
Would I have given you this lifestyle?
Would I have left the company...
in your hands? And you tell me, that
I doubt your capabilities? Ingrate
Papa, are you reminding me
of all you have done for me?
How could you think... a father would
remind his son what he did for him?
Sir, you mean...?
- Ajay, please say no more!
Rajesh, I didn't mean to push you
Listen...
Please, don't get worked up.
All this was unintentional
Ajay didn't push purposely.
I know my son very well
Such a mistake, he'd never do
Pratima, that shove was meant for me,
not for Rajesh. Directed at me
This house is mine. In this house,
my every spoken word is the law
I am ordering Ajay
to leave this house
Ajay, what are you doing?
Must you take to heart your
father's word spoken in anger?
Didn't you hear what Papa said?
Here in this house of his...
his spoken word is the law.
The law-breaker is a criminal
In your eyes, a criminal I will not be.
- Don't go away
Nor will I be my father's criminal
Please! Don't go away
Ajay, please! Stop
Let him go. Father and son are like
water-drops separated this moment...
flowing together tomorrow
You I have loved, not your status,
nor your family
Come with me. Take a word of advice
from my Daddy
No, I can never let my daughter
marry a man who has been...
disowned by his family.
- Disowned I may be
But I will leave nothing wanting
for the family I will raise
No! I'll have nothing to do with you,
nor will I let my daughter marry you
You may leave
Your every decision I have respected
and abided by. When I took...
the most important decision of my life,
I expected your acquiescence. But...
you've insulted the man I love.
And this I cannot tolerate
I shall never forgive you
for not giving me away
"Shattered I am, but
I will always love you..."
"and leave you, never"
"I swear by my love"
"I will fulfill my vows"
"The eyes that look up at you
with love..."
"the heart that warms to you..."
"is filled with love"
"The eyes that look up at you
with love..."
"the heart that warms to you..."
"is filled with love"
"It's my heart"
"For your sake, I have left
everything behind"
"I have broken all bonds,
every tradition"
"Let me open my eyes only
to gaze at this beauty"
"Let breathe only
to feel her breath"
"The one who has drowned
in your love..."
"the one who seeks you within..."
"is a heart"
"It's my heart"
"I'll reach out to the stars for you"
"My wild lover, all my life,
I will be yours"
"In your arms,
I have forgotten all else"
"In your love,
I have found everything"
"The one in your dreams..."
"yours for a lifetime..."
"is a heart"
"It's my heart"
"The eyes that look up at you
with love..."
"The heart that warms to you..."
"Is filled with love"
"It's my heart"
You haven't been to the office
for quite sometime now
A lot of work is pending. So I brought
the papers for your signature
Rajesh, I haven't been keeping
too well
Priya's wedding is coming up shortly,
got to take care of the wedding too
Sir, you need strong shoulders
for support...
why don't you ask Ajay
to come back?
Priya's wedding has been finalised?
- Yes Ajay. Just come home
Everything will be all right.
So momentous a decision...
and folks at home
never even informed me
Am I so estranged...? You tell me,
am I a stranger?
No Ajay, actually everything
happened so fast
Just come home, and everything will be
all right. Don't take this to heart
Here's the wedding invitation.
Do take a look
Papa hasn't even mentioned
my name on the invitation!
Stop
Brother
My little...
darling
One request, sir
Ever since we married, I have
never taken Preeti for a vacation
She would be happy if I did
Why not, Rajesh? Just let me know
your programme
Actually, we wanted
to leave this evening
But there's a very important
business meeting tomorrow
I you could take of the meeting
that'd be fine
Very well, Rajesh. Go on.
I'll take care of everything
Mr. Kapoor, granted that in Rajesh
you have a very responsible hand...
taking care of your businesses.
But I would rather that...
you sank your differences
and called Ajay back
They are here
Yes, Rajesh was told me about
this business meeting
What's this...?
- A notice, Mr. Kapoor
We're here to collect the 500 million
you borrowed by raising mortgages
You are overdrawn. Worse, your
cheques bouncing one after another...
jeopardises our reputation too.
- Your factories and residences...
are all pledged. Those are the papers.
Liquidation is the only way out now
Such a big deception?
The financial markets are in a tumult
Rajesh
Only aim in my life
was to make it rich
No matter how much I earned,
all I could've afforded...
was a middle-lass existence like
millions others. So I think it over
And I target Mr. Vijay Kapoor.
I win him over, get myself employed
There I come to know that his biggest
weakness is his daughter Preeti
I present myself to Preeti so as to
make her fall in love with me...
the path that leads right into
his home. Mr. Vijay Kapoor wanted...
to give me a car, an apartment,
everything. But I wasn't begging
He takes it for a sacrifice,
and takes me in, like a son
My first victory.
- Now the biggest hurdle in my way...
was Vijay Kapoor's son Ajay. I hear
father and son conversing...
and I realise that their approaches
to life are entirely different
When Vijay Kapoor sent his son to
the factory to learn the ropes...
I played my next card. Hari Singh,
what man will stand by and watch...
his brother-in-law getting bashed up?
- No one
Ajay loses his temper, he beats up
Hari Singh. And this rascal...
he takes it without a whimper.
Then he calls for a strike...
which unsettles Vijay Kapoor so much
that he forces his son to apologise
And the way I did it to him!
It was like a lashing in public
Then what happens? Holy war
between father and son begins
Ajay asks his father to finance
his business, he refuses
In the heat of the moment, Ajay
borrows money on personal bonds
And I publish the news in my paper.
- Mr. Khanna, your news was like...
adding fuel to fire. Yes, Vijay Kapoor
is infuriated, he offers his son...
to name his price to buy him out.
I rub the salt into his wounds
I incite him upto the point when
he asks me to leave him alone
I confront Preeti with the analogy
that I'm no better than a dog...
in her brother's home, in her father's
home. Son is son, dog is dog
I incite Preeti till she decides
to walk out that moment
Mr. Vijay Kapoor was raging already
like a wounded lion. Our departure...
was like a stab in his wound. For one
last time, father and son quarrelled
And unwittingly, Ajay pushes me.
I pretend to stagger and fall
That provokes Vijay Kapoor to throw
his son out. My second victory
Now I wanted to ensure that
father and son re-unite, never
Opportunity arises in Priya's wedding.
I had one wedding invitation printed
One sans Ajay's name.
Then, I seize opportunity when...
Vijay Kapoor is moping over his son.
I got him to sign in my favor...
a power of attorney.
The beginning of ruination
I mortgaged all his factories
and all his estates
For half the market price. Papers
were drawn up for full market value
A relationship made a pauper out of
Vijay Kapoor. And I have used...
my relationship to emerge
a successful businessman
That's my success story
This court hereby permits
Dalal Financiers...
to auction off Mr. Vijay Kapoor's
estates to recover their dues
"Yesterday's truths
are today's legends"
"Homes plundered
brick by brick"
"In moments, friends
become strangers"
"Memories are so dear"
"Ruination, long shadows of sorrow
are all that remain"
"And empty, tearful eyes"
"What's left of life?"
"Oh, what's left of life?"
What will happen now, Ma?
This isn't just a house.
This is Papa's honour
I won't let it go under
the hammer. Never
"Don't punish me for loving you"
"Don't betray my love"
"I'm yours, you're mine"
"You are lost in my eyes"
"Trust me"
"I'm madly in love"
"Madly in love with you"
"I pray for you"
"I desire you"
"I'm in love with you"
"Don't ever stop loving me"
"Promise me"
"Don't make me cry"
"Don't punish me for loving you"
"My heart beats for you"
"My lips speak your name"
"You, I thirst for"
"I don't want to be taken away
from you"
"You are my hope"
"Don't destroy my world"
"Don't punish me for loving you"
Why are you so late Ajay?
I've been worried
I had been home
What home...?
- My home
To Mummy-Papa
And I...? You took such a big
decision all by yourself?
I need no one's permission
to go home
Where were they, when you
were being thrown out?
were devastated deep down inside...
when you needed someone to take care
of you? Tell me Ajay. Then...
no one came by to even care! What is
this sudden surge of sentiment?
They are worse off than I am.
My Papa is sick
His factories, his residence
is going under the hammer
In that state, I can never desert him.
That's my religion, that's my duty
Your every loyalty begins and ends
with me. When they deserted you...
I was the only one who stood by you.
I too had my Daddy
Towards him, I had my loyalties too.
But for love's sake...
I spurned everything, to be with you.
And today, in this condition...
when it's you whom I need the most,
you want to leave me?
Who wants to leave you? I have never
stayed away from you. Nor can I ever
You are a part of our family
They will love you. They never
dismissed you as a stranger
Why should you estrange yourself?
- With you, I've vowed to stand...
in joy and in sorrow. But partaking
only a portion of your love...
is not acceptable to me
Where are you going?
Listen... listen to me Ajay!
Don't leave me today
I must go
If that's the imperative,
then at this moment...
you will decide whether to cast
your lot with your parents or with me
For the sake of our relationship,
you want to break other relationships?
Nisha, it's your wish. To stand by me,
or not, the decision is in your hands
Daddy, take me away from here
Ma, how are you?
Where's Nisha? You didn't
bring her along?
Ma, you're about to become a grandma.
So I left her in her father's care
Such good news!
And you didn't inform us...?
Pratima, I need no one's sympathy,
no one's charity
Vijay Kapoor is down but not out
I still have the strength enough
to fight my battles... to win
Papa, listen to me...
- Tell him I wish to speak to no one
Your Papa hasn't been keeping well
of late. He has become irritable
Don't mind him, son.
- No Ma, not his fault at all
It's all my fault
Ma, I still remember crawling
quietly onto Papa's lap...
whenever he was angry with me.
He'd scold me at first. Then...
he'd shower me with love. I don't
even remember the awakening of my ego
He told me to leave, and I left.
Had I only embraced him...
would he not have forgiven me?
He would, wouldn't he, Ma...?
Yes
My ego has ruined this house,
destroyed everything that was mine
I have made everyone so unhappy,
made you unhappy too, Ma...?
No...
- Forgive me, Ma
I could cope with you growing up.
But you've become magnanimous...
I see for the first time
Papa
Anger, pride, leads man on
the path of self-destruction
And often one misunderstands
the one's own benefactor
That error committed,
one loses his benefactor
Vijay, you are committing
that very mistake
By the time you realise, regret...
I fear it may be too late...
to repent. This is the only reason
why I'm stopping you
Don't misbehave with him
Give him your love, be gentle.
Don't give him a prize, if you won't
But at least, don't insult him
Who is it?
Why don't you speak?
What kind of a joke is this?
Who is this?
Who's speaking?
- Ankit Dalal of Dalal Financiers
Yes go on, I'm his son Ajay.
- Mr. Ajay, by now...
you should've arrived at a decision
whether to you pay me or not. Else...
I shall proceed with the auctioning.
- We won't let it be auctioned
Nor will I tolerate men
of your ilk calling up
Mr. Dalal, stay within your limits.
- Why take it out on me?
I'm just a businessman. You ought
to talk to your brother-in-law
He is the one who pawned your house
Ajay, would you like a cup of tea?
- I'm not here, your guest. Tell me...
did Papa make a mistake in giving
you a job? He gave you a new life
Was that his mistake? He loved you,
gave you respect. Was that his crime?
Why did you deceive my Papa?
You have ruined my home, robbed us
of our peace, our happiness. Why?
Ajay, you want justice? Go to court.
Levelling allegations against me...
won't make me a wrongdoer. I cheated
no one, deceived none. I used my brains
I did business with a family of
weeping fools. And I made my money
The relationship ties my hands.
Else, you'd weep tears of blood
And you'd come walking home to us
to return our money
Old adage, Ajay. The sister's husband
is more precious than most by far
I can be charitable. A five, a ten,
twenty, fifty, hundred...?
Not in millions. Units.
Proffer that hand, supplicate
Never have I stood in supplication.
If ever, that'd be a slip on my part
But it will cost you dearly.
- You will raise your hands...
on your brother-in-law? Ajay, I won't
tolerate fools and madmen for long
Open the door
Open up
Police station? There's an arsonist
in my house! He's wreaking havoc
Hurry up and come over.
Yes, write down my address
Ajay! Stop
Leave him!
- Preeti, he has ruined us
He mustn't be spared.
He ought to be...
Ajay! For my sake
Are you all right?
- Where's the goon?
Mr. Rajesh, where's the goon?
Arrest him
He's the arsonist!
Give me a medical examination.
Frame him! Make sure...
he doesn't even get bail.
- You...
Hey you goon!
- You saw that?
He accosts me in your presence!
- What's your name?
Behave yourself. I'm Ajay Kapoor,
Vijay Kapoor's son, get that?
You're Vijay Kapoor's son?
- Yes
Son, why all this? You end up in the
cophouse. He has a case against you
Stop eyeballing me
Get lost.
- Where are you taking him?
What's all this going on?
- You end up in the lock-up
What are you up to?
Sign this
Show him out. Let decent folks be
Come on out
Never in my life have I ever been to
a police station. All because of you...
I was forced to sit in that hell
for hours. Of this violence...
what can be the outcome?
Come on, tell me. God forbid...
if something happened to Rajesh,
you would've made Preeti a widow
All your life you'd be in jail,
and we'd be the worse off for it
D'you think violence will solve
your problems? Don't you forget...
Rajesh is my son-in-law.
If he is as much as touched...
it's our Preeti who will suffer.
Easy task that was for me
The worst of goons in town, kiss
my doorstep. In minutes, it'd be done
Preeti is trying to reason with Rajesh.
She's trying to change him
A miracle might happen
Rajesh, you are my husband.
It's my duty to tell you
It's not too late. Return Papa's money.
Apologise to him. You have my word...
Papa will respect you even more.
- As long as the money is mine...
my clout I have. I needn't go seeking.
- But the money isn't yours, Rajesh
My family has never wished you ill.
Instead, they embraced you
Believe me, had you asked Papa for the
money, he would've given it to you...
with a smile.
- As in alms?
You wanted me to beg of your father?
- Instead, you deceive him, rob him?
I deceived no one! I did business,
I used my brains
Had I sourced it from elsewhere,
you would've had a splash, enjoyed it
But you sermonise me, because
I made it off your father?
I'll-gotten gains, be it from
anywhere, I would never touch
Rajesh, money made this way
lasts all of a very short while
And the rest of your life
will be a punishment
Please Rajesh, return
these wages of sin
Preeti, you have no right
to disabuse my efforts as sin
And don't you think that because
I love you and I respect you...
I will go on listening to whatever
you have to say
Don't meddle with my business
Our laws are fabricated
around loopholes
Isn't there any way
to prevent this auction?
Mr. Malhotra, can't we procure
a stay order...
so as to give us at least
some time to think...?
Consider the stay order granted.
I will get hearings postponed...
by four, maybe six months.
The appeal will be filed tomorrow
Look at that.
- The car's turn to con us
Make yourself comfortable on the bench.
Let me look for a mechanic
Back in five minutes
Sahib! You don't recognise me?
I'm Rameshwar... sandwich-man
I used to vend sandwiches
outside your factory
What a business I had!
Roaring, rip-roaring
What evil eye was it?
Factory closed down...
Sahib, I hear talk of the factory
being pulled down for highrises...?
Sahib, the poor workers worship you.
For them, you are the breadwinner
They have faith, the Sahib won't
let them starve
Your faith, your prayers will
surely help us save the factory
Sahib, one request. Before you leave,
do eat one of my sandwiches
No, let it be.
- Go on Papa, have one
You've never broken anyone's heart.
Don't break his
Make us a sandwich.
Lots of peppers
Coming right up, sahib.
- Make it fast. I'm hungry
Thanks
Have a bite, Papa.
- No, go on
Have one piece, Papa.
- I want nothing
Since when did you start eating
so much peppers?
You remember feeding me on your lap
when I was a baby? It was so bland
Not even a dash of pepper. And you'd
eat that bland stuff with me. But...
you loved eating peppers,
pepper was your weakness
So I had this sandwich spiced up,
to enjoy your kind of taste
Papa, ever since my childhood,
whenever I stumbled, whenever I fell...
it was you who has been helping me
up on my feet. Today...
when you falter before a storm,
can I not support you?
Why will you not
let me hold your hand...
Papa...?
Am I the one on your mind?
Every moment, I've been missing you
Let's put an end to
this missing each other
Ajay, it was my mistake!
I fought with you for no reason
Forgive me, forgive me Ajay!
Without you, I can't live
Knowingly, unknowingly, if I ever
committed any mistake, forgive me
I love you so much
All dressed up and going where?
Today's Brothers' Day. I'm going...
- You aren't going anywhere
You aren't feting any brother
For all you're worth,
try stopping me today
To our relationship, I've given in.
But not to slavery
You cannot force me not
to fete my brothers
What brother? Don't forget,
that brother raised his hand...
against your husband.
- Not against my husband
He raised his hand against a traitor,
a thief, a fraud who looted my father
I, a thief? A fraud? Rather than let
you go to see that scum...
I'd tie a lodestone around your neck
and throw you into the sea to drown
Don't you try to force your way
into my house
Who broke down this door?
- He! Once again. Arrest him
Today's Brothers' Day. And he
wouldn't let me see my sister
Now I get everything!
Listen here...
what are you, man? No power on earth
can keep a brother from seeing...
his sister on Brother's Day. And till
date, no law's for holding a brother...
because he wants to see his sister
on Brothers' Day... hey, are you mad?
Ajay, this day every year, a sister has
the right to ask her brother for a gift
Tell me Sister, what do you want?
- The vow of protecting your sister
Today, I ask you to protect me.
Take me home
Take me away from here, forever
Fool, who saves your day now?
As long as she lived in your house,
she shielded you. Now she's gone
Now brother, who saves you?
God help you
Forgive me! The entire family
is paying for one mistake of mine
Paying...? What do you mean?
Look at me
It's just happenstance. You aren't
the only one who was mistaken...
about Rajesh. I was mistaken,
your mother was mistaken...
others in the family went wrong too.
You know how man differs from God?
It's human to err in the judgement
of men. God doesn't. Thus He's God
As far as relationships are concerned,
yes men are deceived at times
One who breaks off, loses everything
Ones who conjoin, thrive forever
For parents, the greatest happiness
is the joy of their children
Today, the entire family
has again come together
Who could be as lucky
a mother as I am?
Now let's celebrate Brothers' Day
Ma, aren't we missing someone? Nisha?
- Yes, Nisha
Ajay, why don't you bring Nisha home?
- Tonight you bring her home
Must have a look-see at my friend,
now that she's my sister-in-law
Priya is at her father's. Let her rest.
- No more Ajay. We'll see to it...
that she gets more comforts
than she has at her father's home
Wonderful! If a useless fellow like me
lives off the lay of the land...
why can't the bride?
- And we have yet to give her...
her fertility rites.
- Our prime duty is to protect our turf
Fertility rites can wait.
- Why? We might be going...
through trying times.
But her ritual we will give her
Even the poorest who can't afford it,
will put a lamp at their doorstep...
to celebrate the Festival of Lights.
- Not another word. Bring her home
We'll start preparing
for her fertility rites
You can take Nisha with you,
provided you sign these papers
Very well sir, let me take her home
I'll have these papers
sent back with Nisha
Nisha, I have a request. Please don't
let my folks get to know...
how things are between us
"Your coming lights up my home"
"Blessed is my home,
I adore you"
"Oh, we're all so happy"
"My nights were so stark
So stark my days were"
"How do I tell you, how I lived
through the separation"
"You're back,
and my home is all lit up"
"Blessed is my home,
I adore you"
"Oh, we're all so happy"
"You called out to me,
and here I am"
"My lost life,
I've found again"
"In you, I have found
my every happiness"
"The chasm is bridged,
our home is all lit up"
"Blessed is my home,
I adore you"
"Oh, we're all so happy"
"Tears of joy fill my eyes,
I cannot hold my tears back"
"What else have I to say?
My tears have said it all"
"Look, how smiles bring cheer"
"Blessed is my home,
I adore you"
"Your coming lights up my home"
"Blessed is my home,
I adore you"
"Oh, we're all so happy"
I will make do with whatever we have,
every sorrow I shall bear
But I don't want to leave you Ajay.
I don't want to go away
I want to be here. With you.
Once we held hands, we swore
to be together for a lifetime
But today, you're about
to leave me forever
Ajay, I want something from you.
- I know. Here you are
What's this?
- Divorce papers
Divorce...?
Your father is waiting for you.
Come downstairs
Daddy! Take me home Daddy.
- Yes my child
What did he have to say
about the stay order?
It has been dismissed
Not to worry. Today or tomorrow,
Brij is arriving from London
I'll have the money once he's here.
Find out when he's expected
What if he doesn't arrive in time?
- Then you and I are going somewhere
Friends, I come before you to plead.
All that was in my power...
to save the factory, I have done.
But I don't think I will be able...
to save the factory. The relationship
we shared, I wanted to nurture...
as long as I lived.
For this lapse...
if you can, forgive me
What did Uncle Brij have to say?
- He's right here, in town
But for our family,
he's away in London
Papa made friends with a businessman,
but his friendship was a trade-off
It's best for Papa not to know this.
He was Papa's last hope
He won't live through the shock of it.
- Oh, what is to happen now?
Get a hold on yourself. I still have
faith, everything's going to be fine
Stop! What's going on?
Let go of him, I say
Are you out of your mind?
For 2 months the factory has been shut!
- We're starving to death
We have no future left!
And he's enjoying himself
He's living it up!
Drinking everyday!
Having girls... having fun!
No sparing him! Burn him alive
This is wrong! He had no hand
in closing down the factory
Go, and try to share with them
their sorrows
Share a joy, and joy abounds
Share a grief, and its burden
is lessened. Take care of them
You saved my life... why?
Why this mercy, unasked for?
Why mercy to a criminal?
Why make the workers feel for me?
You don't know! I took you on
at the factory for a purpose
I disgraced you by forcing you
to apologise to me
But I wasn't like this always.
Time was when I'd die for my employer
What my employer has done for us,
I knew. Food, clothing, housing
He even built a school
for our children
But for just a little money,
I forgot it all
I even forgot that unless the machines
work in the factory...
our kitchen fires will not be lit.
My employer I have betrayed
After this day, no employer
will ever trust his employee
Never will workers
trust their leaders
A beating, they might forgive
But I have deprived them
of their livelihood
For the grave crime
that I've committed...
their families are paying. I forgot!
No worker can ever prosper...
once his employer is ruined.
Sahib, my loyalties lie nowhere
Not with my employer,
not with my fellow-workers
My loyalties lie nowhere!
Kill me, hack me to pieces
I have no right to live
No Hari Singh, get a hold
on yourself
You have repented,
and that is enough
No! I shall atone
I shall
Come, let's stake our lives!
Don't let our employers come to harm
One fight we have lost,
but this war we shall win
Too late Hari Singh
Too late now
We haven't the time
to put together so much money
We've lost our home, our factory
I'm his wife, and a married woman will
never take off her wedding necklace...
till her husband is alive. This is the
mark of the woman's faith in her man
It's in faith that I entrust you
with this. Keep it
This can never be! I appreciate
your feelings. But the truth is...
this won't be enough to pool the money.
- It'll be done. It will be done
Our homes... they are yours
These four thousand homes, for you
Mortgage these. But save your house,
save our factory
Our dreams, our tomorrows, our future
are all tied to you
Say, we're with you
We're with you
If I have your prayers,
your blessings, your sacrifices...
then this war we'll surely win
Begging from beggars to buy back
the house and the factory?
Mr. Khanna, you will bid for me when
the bungalow is being auctioned
The factory we'll buy out
at cost-plus
Did you have to pay in
the earnest money...
for the bidding without
as much as a thought?
You expect Rajesh to leave anything
to chance? And where comes...
the rest of the money from?
- No matter how much Rakesh bids...
but we'll save this house from falling.
Uncle will bid for us
This mansion was mortgaged
for 500 million
Not a cent in my pocket,
and here I am, bidding
I will go on raising the bid.
But do you have the money?
Just keep upping the stake
Businessmen and the workers
are both bidding
The floor price is 500 million
51 0 million
600 million
61 0 million
700 million
71 0 million
800 million
Come on gentlemen, bid
81 0 million
Bid 900 million
900 million
91 0 million
1 billion
1 billion from Mr. Khanna
Look like no one is going
to cross a billion
No more voices?
The bidding seems to be over
1 billion... one... two...
1.25 billion
Back out
Anyone bidding more?
1.25 billion... one... two...
Three. Sold
Do you realise what papers
you have just signed?
The transfer deed?
- No. Undertaking to the government
Unless you deposit 1.25 billion in
2 days, you've lost your earnest money
This moment's victory is meaningless.
This is a far worse insult
When the court attaches
the earnest money...
the world will laugh at us.
- Trust me. I'll organise everything
The money isn't exactly raining.
Nor have you found a treasure
Where will you find so much?
- We're going to have it
"I'm new in town.
Give me a hug"
"And slake your thirst"
"Look at me, my wild ones"
"Such beauty you will never find"
"Come and look me up"
"For that which comes to mind"
"Don't give me that light flutter
in my heart, it makes me pine"
"Don't desert me,
after those promises"
"Don't let the wait
rob the opportunity"
"Just make love to me, once"
"Ask me out, wherever you want"
"Drown your sorrows,
come to me"
"Look at me, my wild ones"
"Such beauty you will never find"
"Come and look me up"
"Talk your hearts out"
"Give me thirst in my eyes, the colour
to my cheeks, the welt on my lips"
"Take from me the colour of my tresses,
my blush, the throb in me"
"Let me have the first taste Spring"
"Snatches of a night together,
but give me all the fun"
"I'm more tender than a blossom
Take me in your arms"
"Hold my fragrance
under your breath"
"Hey wild ones..."
"Such beauty you will never find"
"Come and look me up"
"For that which comes to mind"
There's an arsonist in my house
Can't hear... louder
Bad line
This one is a really bad sort
Don't take the call if the phone rings
Let the folks tear him apart
No! Ajay, forgive me!
For Preeti's sake!
Forgive me
From Hinduja Hospital
You've fathered a son
What are you doing? Put my baby down!
He's crying
You hear him crying, but you couldn't
hear me weep for my parents?
I don't want to hear
that malicious crap
You have ruined my life,
taken away my happiness
You have no right to that baby!
You have divorced me
Because that was what you wanted
Lies... lies
Lies? Ask your Daddy.
Divorce was the condition...
he laid down for letting me
take you home for the ritual
Daddy would never do anything as evil!
- Ask your Dad
And if you weren't part of it,
you can come home whenever you want
I'm taking my son.
- Where are you taking my son?
Don't take my baby away
He's taking my son away
Why doesn't someone stop him?
Taking a child away from
its mother is a grave sin
I beg of you! Ajay, don't take
my baby away from me. For my sake
Don't take my baby away. I won't
live for a moment without him
I'm going to die
You'll die? You'll kill yourself?
For this child one-day-old child?
What about the son...
you wanted to take away from parents
who reared him for 25 years?
For them, he is their hope.
Wouldn't that separation...
from their son, kill them?
Sir! Save my life, sir!
They're going to kill me!
At a word from you,
they will turn away
I beg you for my life!
I'm your son-in-law
I married your daughter, sir!
You need not tell me what
your relationship is with me
This house you did not enter
seeking a relationship
You came here to do business
You know what makes a businessman?
A businessman is applies himself,
his skill, his time diligently...
this is what he trades,
in recompense wherefor...
he earns
You are n businessman.
You are merely an opportunist...
who cunningly shrouded his ambitions
in the cloak of a relationship...
to deceive people.
You are a cheat
And you could con me only because
I trusted you
And you poisoned my trust
Even snakes sometimes
spare their prey
But snake in the grass, that
you are, you spared no one
You engaged me in a game
of snakes and ladders
At every opportunity,
you climbed a ladder
You ruined the very ones
who reposed their trust in you
Then you forgot all about
the snake at 99...
that takes the player
all the way down...
to where there's no chance
of a climb again
Where did you take your education?
Where were you taught...
this triumph of the evil?
Not one story tells you that
How then, did you expect the outcome
of this story to be different?
Did you expect to pen a new novel?
How could you imagine that?
Now I'll teach you
how to do business
Now you will say in your own words,
what price that life of yours?
1 00,000, 1 million,
1 0 million, 50 million?
You have time till the workers
break down that door and barge in
No hurry
Here I sir, relaxed
But the price to your life,
you will have to name
Come out
Out
Kill him
I'll return everything!
Everything, sir!
All of it
Sign it
I grew up a motherless child.
I was never told that once married...
a woman makes her husband's home
her only home. Forgive me...
as you'd forgive your daughter
You see son, in cases of certain
relationships, one has to forgive
And I think, the others in this family
will forgive you too
Where's Preeti?
- This is for you
Rajesh, members of my family
might have forgiven you
But I will never forgive you.
Because of you...
my family has suffered. If ever any
daughter forgives a husband like you...
that day, come back to me
One minute... wait
Life is all about relationships.
Those who break away...
Iose those dearest to them.
Those who conjoin...
will even reach