SANTA:
This is Christmastown in the North Pole.
One of the things you need to know
is that everyone who lives here...
is happy all the time. Really happy.
I mean, really, really happy.
Honestly, sometimes it's a bit much.
But happiest of all was Buddy the Elf.
Well, he wasn't really an elf,
but we'll get to that later.
(SINGING) Christmas elves enjoy themselves
By donning gay apparel
Or by singing songs in Santa's shop
Fa-la-la, la-la, la-la-la
Of course, I always like it
When they sing a Christmas carol
I like it even better when they stop
Night and day, they dance and play
They never sleep much either
Would some peace and quiet be a crime?
Fa-la-la-la, la-la-la-la-la
Of course, I love each one of them
But Santa needs a breather
Because they're just so happy
all the time
- They're oddly
- Happy all the time
- Ungodly
When they sing until they're bluish
Santa wishes he were Jewish
- 'Cause they're
- Happy all the time
- I swear they're
- Bizarrely happy
- All the time
SANTA: But there's an elf called Buddy
Who makes them look apathetic
ALL: If he were any sweeter
We might end up diabetic
SANTA: He's everybody's buddy
But he'll leave your eardrums ringing
ALL: 'Cause everywhere he goes
He has to tell the world he's singing
I'm singing
It's almost Christmas and I'm singing
And I love Santa, so I'm singing
Buddy, you're standing on an elf again.
I thought the floor felt squishy.
Sorry, Ming Ming.
That's okay, Buddy.
(SINGING) My spine will heal
Because I'm happy all the time
Okay, elves, you've got toys to make.
Yay! Time to go to work.
ALL (SINGING): Happy all the time
Happy all the time
Making toys is so appealing
That I spend each morning squealing
True, he's happy all the time
- Who knew? I'm happy all the time
- Happy all the time
He's unnaturally happy
All the time
Happy all the time
(CLATTERING)
Oh, no. I made a big mess again.
It's okay, Buddy.
Why don't you just say it?
I'm a cotton-headed ninny-muggins.
(SOBBING)
(ELVES SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(WIND WHISTLING)
I break everything I touch...
I keep stepping on Ming Ming.
And yesterday,
I only made 400 rocking horses.
Sometimes I don't feel
like I'm an elf at all.
(SIGHS)
Well, Buddy, let me tell you a story
I should have told years ago.
A story.
Whoo-hoo! I love story time.
Holy moly! My legs! My legs!
- Aah!
- A story about your legs?
I love it already.
No, Buddy. Just listen.
Once upon a time, on a Christmas night,
I slid down the chimney of an orphanage.
While I was putting presents
under the tree...
a baby crawled, unseen,
into my toy sack...
and I brought him back here by mistake.
Never having stolen a baby before,
I didn't know what to do.
So the elves took him in
and raised him as one of their own.
And as the years went on,
he grew bigger and bigger and bigger.
Oh. So I'm a giant elf.
- No. Buddy, you're...
- Wait.
I thought this was a story
about your legs.
No, this is your story.
The story of Buddy the Elf.
- Well, actually, Buddy the Human.
- Human?
Your mother's name was Susan Wells.
Now all you have left is your father,
who never knew you were born.
His name is Walter Hobbs...
and he lives in a strange land
called New York City.
And he works right here
in the Empire State Building.
BUDDY: In there? Ha-ha.
Why, he must be teeny-tiny.
Hello, Dad. Dad!
No, don't be scared. I mean you no harm.
This is just a snow globe, Buddy.
Well, of course.
I bet he's the world's greatest dad.
Yeah, about that...
So, what's the world's
greatest dad like?
I mean, does he prefer candy canes
or peppermint sticks?
Uh, he doesn't like either.
Well, the world's greatest dad must have
a top-of-the-line, one-horse open sleigh.
Well, then how does he dash
through the snow?
You see, like a lot of people these days,
he's just lost the Christmas spirit.
But Christmas spirit
is what makes your sleigh fly.
And every year, it's tougher
to get this old girl off the ground.
I guess it could be worse.
- At least he's not on the Naughty List.
- Well...
Can you imagine the world's greatest dad
a Naughty Lister?
I mean, with their beady little eyes
and their naughty little hands...
always grasping for presents
they don't deserve.
Buddy.
(SIGHS)
Let's just cut to the chase.
Your father's been on the Naughty List
for over 50 years.
(GASPS)
Well, this is it. I'm all set to go.
Now, Buddy, are you sure you wanna
go through with this?
New York City can get a little rough.
I've made my mind up, Santa.
I've got to get my dad off the Naughty List.
Well then, good luck, Buddy.
- Farewell, one and all.
- ALL: Bye.
Now, do you remember the way
to New York City?
BUDDY: Sure do.
I go through the Cotton Candy Caverns,
brave the Gumdrop Ocean...
trek through the Candy forest,
then straight on to New York.
- Bye-bye.
- Good luck.
See you later, Buddy.
Good luck finding your dad.
Thanks, Mr. Sea Serpent.
I'm coming, Papa.
(SINGING) We'll make angels in the snow
Till the snow begins to blow
Then we'll run inside
and start a tickle fight
And if it's too cold to sled
We'll eat gingerbread instead
And then cuddle
till he tucks me in at night
And we'll have our pictures taken
For the Christmas cards we're making
Him and me in suits of matching plaid
And when people see us walking
They'll be Google-eyed and gawking
At Buddy and the world's greatest dad
So I'm gonna try my best to be
Everything you'd expect of me
And I promise that I won't stop
until I'm done
So someday you can say
I'm the world's greatest son
Ooh! Sorry.
Wow!
It sure is a big city.
How am I going to find Walter Hobbs?
Walter Hobbs!
Excuse me, have you seen Walter Hobbs?
(COOING)
- Walter?
- My name is Walter.
Dad, it's me, Buddy. I love you so much.
The Hobbs family
is finally back together again.
- My last name is Franklin.
- Oh.
My name is Hobbs.
Then you must be my father.
You're everything I imagined.
I can't believe I found my dad,
Walter Hobbs.
It's Jerry Hobbs.
This is gonna be harder than I thought.
Are you Walter Hobbs?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Ooh! Sorry.
Excuse me. Are you Walter Hobbs?
Is that man shouting your name, Walter?
Of course not, Emily.
He's obviously delusional.
Is your name Walter?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Why is that guy dressed up
like a giant elf?
Christmas always brings out the weirdos.
Son of a nutcracker! My leg feels
like a shattered candy cane.
You know what would be fun?
Let's pick out a Christmas tree tonight.
Brilliant idea. Let's put a dead tree
in the living room.
Come on, Dad.
Where's your Christmas spirit?
He's right. You're turning into a grump.
Besides, we never do anything
as a family anymore.
You know I'm too busy
for all that nonsense.
Hey, why don't you get
your Christmas gift early?
Uh, look, I gotta get back to work.
I'll see you two later.
Michael, you know
your dad's a very busy man.
Hey, I have an idea. Why don't we write Santa
and tell him what we want for Christmas?
I don't believe in Santa.
All I know is what I don't want.
MICHAEL (SINGING): I don't want a check
That's made out to cash
Or a corporate regift
from some secret stash
I'd like a day with my dad
- EMILY: Just a day?
- MICHAEL: Make that two
If you can do that, Santa
I'll believe in you
MICHAEL & EMILY:
Even though it's been years
- Since you heard from me
- I thought it was worth a shot
If it's true that you're magic,
I guarantee
- We could use all the magic you got
MICHAEL: I can get you some cookies
If that's what it takes
I've heard stories and I know the deal
- You just slide down the chimney
- And fix our mistakes
- Now, if only I thought you were real
If you were real
EMILY: I guess that's our list
Our letter is done
Is it really a list
If it adds up to one?
MICHAEL & EMILY:
Make him part of our lives
- Not just passing through
- If you can do that, Santa
- I'll believe in you
- Yes, if you do that, Santa
- So good luck, Santa
- Here's hoping you come through
Signed, Emily
And Michael too
Ooh.
Hot dog.
Mr. Hobbs, you're gonna love this idea.
It's about an outcast reindeer whose glowing
antlers help Santa through a bad storm.
Yeah. We call it
Tony the Lite-Up Antlered Reindeer.
(BOTH SNICKERING)
That sounds awfully familiar.
Uh, then what about this?
It's the story of a grouchy green grouch
who hates Christmas, and then he...
Let me stop you right there,
my brilliant writers.
Greenway Press needs an original story,
and we need it now.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
- What?
- Mr. Hobbs...
I think someone sent you
a Christmas-gram.
Oh, I love the holidays.
(GASPS)
It's him.
Oh, all right, let's get it over with.
Go ahead.
Get what over with?
Aren't you gonna sing
some dumb song for me?
Sing? Yeah, anything for you.
(SINGING) I'm here with my dad
And we never met
And he wants me to sing him a song
And, um, I love you
I love you, I love you
Huh.
Security.
Oh, hello. Does everyone
in New York hug this tight?
GUARD: Merry Christmas, weirdo.
(MOUSE SQUEAKING)
SANTA: Buddy's first meeting
with his father didn't go so well...
but his luck is about to change.
(BELL RINGING)
(JOVIE HUMMING "JINGLE BELLS")
Huh?
(HEART BEATING RAPIDLY)
(HORNS HONKING)
(CONTINUES HUMMING)
(GASPS THEN TIRES SCREECHING)
BUDDY: Unh!
- Sorry.
- Are you okay?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
That car wasn't as big
as the last one. Heh-heh.
It's so nice to meet another human
who appreciates elf culture.
Who doesn't love itchy tights, right?
I'm Jovie. You must be the new guy.
First of all, you don't need to try
so hard on the costume.
I sewed it myself.
Uh, cool. Also,
they'll want you to sing...
but no one checks in on you,
so you don't have to.
But singing's the greatest.
Santa always says:
"The best way to spread Christmas cheer
is singing loud for all to hear."
Deck the halls with... Come on.
Boughs of holly
Where's your Christmas spirit?
Nope. Sorry. I don't sing.
You should. I bet your voice is prettier
than the call of an Arctic Warbler seal.
- JOVIE: Oh. Um...
- Ooh, ooh.
It's Santa Claus. I know him.
Do you wanna meet him?
- JOVIE: Uh...
- Come on.
- JOVIE: Aah!
- MAN: Here you go.
Santa. Santa.
- You mind? I'm on a break.
- But it's me.
Santa Claus, Santa Claus. Hi.
Ah, great.
Well, hello there.
Ho, ho, ho.
Wait a second.
His stomach didn't shake...
- Oh, boy.
- ...like a bowl full of jelly. Who are you?
What are you talking about?
I'm Santa Claus.
No, you're not.
- You're a fake.
- I'm fake? Ha-ha.
Hey, buddy, how'd you like
to be dead, huh?
I don't know how you know my name,
but you're not really Santa.
- Look, everybody.
- Aah!
- Fake.
- Argh!
Everybody, listen. He's a fake.
Fake, fake, fake. This guy's a fake.
Fake-o.
This guy's a fake.
Fake Santa.
Fake, fake, fake.
(GROANS)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
(GASPS)
Fake.
Come on, Buddy, the cops are coming.
Are they like the guys
who hug you out of the building?
What? Just go.
When can I see you again?
Uh, after work, I hang out at the ice rink
at Rockefeller Center.
Uh-huh. I have no idea where that is.
Just look for the giant
Christmas tree. Go.
I love Christmas trees.
(TIRES SCREECHING AND BUDDY SCREAMS)
(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
BUDDY: Oh. Uh-huh. Stocks and bonds.
Five percent interest...
(GIRLS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
THEN BUDDY GASPS)
BUDDY: Becky said what? Oh, my gosh.
(DOGS YAPPING)
(BUDDY BARKING)
(PANTING)
- What?
- Oh, uh...
I didn't see you there, Dad. I love you.
Would you stop with that dad stuff?
What do you want?
There's no easy way to say this.
You are on the Naughty List.
(NAUGHTY LISTERS WHISPERING)
Look, I don't believe in Santa Claus
and I don't believe you're my son.
Now, leave me alone! You got that?
But Susan Wells was my mother.
Susan Wells?
Wha...? Uh, you have
another son, Walter?
He may or may not be my son.
Unfortunately,
the facts are pointing towards "may."
Then, until we get this sorted out,
he needs to stay with us.
Yay!
But he thinks he's an elf.
No, I was just raised by them.
It's almost Christmas
and there's no decorations in this house.
Oh, do you wanna decorate the apartment?
WALTER: No way. No decorations.
All that Christmas-spirit stuff
is a scam.
Dad says, "The holidays are a time for us
to make money, not spend it."
No wonder he's on the Naughty List.
Yes, that's right, Michael.
And if I don't come up with a new book idea,
I'm not gonna be making any money.
Come on, Dad. For once, can you
please let us put up some decorations?
- Yeah, please. Please, please, please.
- Please, please, please.
Fine. Just don't go overboard.
- Oh, thank you! Yes!
- Yes! All right!
(SINGING)
There's a saying we have up north
That helps us put our best foot forth
If you wanna deck the halls for Mr. C
Make sure
they're sparkle-jolly-twinkle-jingley
What's that supposed to mean?
When a room is gloomy
And its atmosphere has called it quits
Then you must remember
That December is a time for glitz
Never stop until each limb
On your Christmas tree
Is sparkle-jolly-twinkle-jingley
Pick up every ornament
That's sitting, waiting on a shelf
While you're busy decorating
Why not decorate yourself?
Soon you'll bring a smile
To every person you see
- I'm sparkle-twinkle-jolly... What?
- Close enough.
(SINGING) And if you're at a loss
Remember the phrase that says
To thine own elf be true
For when it comes to Christmas displays
Look inside and you'll know what to do
MICHAEL: You'll know just what to do
ALL: Put some cheery folderol
On every wall and every nook
Tinsel up each corner
Till it's Christmas everywhere you look
Give the world a holiday
That's bright as can be
Make it sparkle-jolly-twinkle-jingle
Shiny-showy-cheery-Kringle
Razzle-dazzle, ring-a-lingle
I can't lie, it makes me tingle
ALL: Sparkle-jolly-twinkle-jingley
- Wow.
- Cool.
SANTA: So Buddy did his best
to spread Christmas cheer.
But it would take more than some tinsel and
lights to get Walter off the Naughty List.
Can you please pass the maple syrup?
I'm sorry. I didn't set out any syrup.
It's spaghetti.
That's okay. I think I have some.
Cool. Hey, me next.
Ugh. I think I'm gonna
stick with coffee.
- BUDDY: I knew it.
- Knew what, Buddy?
I have the world's greatest dad.
Aw, look up, honey. Mistletoe.
Oh.
We've been tinkering with the story
of a snowman that comes to life...
named Freezy the Snowman.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. We even have a song.
(SINGING) Freezy the Snowman
He was made from balls
of snow, and then...
Okay, okay. I've heard enough.
(KAZOO HONKING)
Psst. Dad, Dad,
do you wanna hear me play the kazoo?
Buddy, enough with the kazoo!
I'm sorry. But my boss, Mr. Greenway,
gets really cranky when he's upset.
GREENWAY:
What kind of an office is this?
Doesn't anyone do any work around here?
- I ought to fire the whole lot of you.
- Shh.
GREENWAY: I've never seen an office
as poorly run as this one.
- WORKER 1: Good morning, Mr. Greenway.
- WORKER 2: Good morning, Mr. Greenway.
Zip it. You're fired!
- Buy some cookies?
- You're fired!
You're fired!
Fired! Fired! Fired!
Fired!
What am I paying you for?
Get back to work!
Oh. When my boss is having a tough day,
we bring him milk and cookies...
and sing Christmas carols
so he forgets his troubles.
Buddy, you're a genius.
We distract Greenway with tinsel and eggnog,
and all that other holiday nonsense...
make him feel that Christmas spirit...
and he won't notice
how lame our ideas are.
Oh. I can help decorate. And we can all
dress up like gingerbread men and sing.
Uh, that's okay, Buddy.
We can handle it from here.
Why don't you take
the rest of the day off?
Thanks, Pop. You're the greatest.
(KAZOO HONKING)
Uh, where's Rockefeller Center?
- BUDDY: Hey, Jovie!
- Huh?
You weren't kidding. That is a big tree.
Yeah, my mom used to take me here
over the holidays as a kid.
It's kind of fun watching skaters
fall on their butts.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- Let's go skating.
- Mm...
I'm not very good.
Well, neither am I.
I was the worst skater in the North Pole.
They called me the triple klutz.
Now, please, don't laugh.
Okay. Do you need to hold onto me?
Huh?
- Uh, oh, yeah, Buddy. You're terrible.
- I know.
The final rotation of my octuple salchow
wasn't very clean. Oh.
Anyway, so who's your favorite reindeer?
Mine's Dasher, followed by Comet,
but he can be a little messy.
I wish I could still get as excited
about the holidays as you.
I always say the best way
to spread Christmas cheer...
is singing loud for all to hear.
I don't sing, remember?
(SINGING)
Come on, Jovie, singing can be easy
Please, stop.
It's fun, it's free,
and best of all it's...
- Totally cheesy?
- Come on.
(SINGING) All you have to do
Is move your voice much higher
High, low, high, low
High
It's just like talking only you sustain it
And make it sound pretty
No.
Just sing a Christmas song
It's like magic if things go wrong
Just spread some Christmas cheer
By singing loud for all to hear
- But when I sing, people stare.
- That's the point.
(SINGING) And if you're short on cheer
Think about that year
You woke up to find
A brand-new snow had fallen
The ornaments you made
Way back in second grade
Untangling the Christmas lights
Took your father several nights
Your mother claimed that she had proof
There were reindeer on the roof
Remember who you were back then
Let those moments live again
Come on, Jovie. Try it for me.
(SINGING) Just sing a Christmas song
That's it.
It's like magic if things go wrong
Keep going.
Think of the joy you'll bring
- If you just close your eyes
- And sing
Aw, shucks.
- CHADWICK: And so...
- Freezy, the green grouchy snowman...
with the light-up antlers
flew through the terrible storm...
and delivered the presents
to the Whys of Whyville.
Merry Christmas, everyone.
You know, maybe it's the eggnog talking,
but this is the best idea
I've heard all year.
Thank you, Mr. Greenway.
We put a lot of work into it.
Dad, Dad, Dad.
I'm in love! I'm in love! Love!
(SINGING) Just sing a Christmas song...
(BUDDY GASPS)
You didn't tell me
you had elves working here.
Is, uh, this part of the presentation?
Heh-heh.
Very funny.
No, this is...
Oh, no. Did you leave your uniform
at Santa's workshop?
That's okay, I have a spare.
If this is supposed to be putting me
in the Christmas spirit...
it's not working.
Okay, arm through here.
Stop squirming, stop squirming.
Ouch. You got me in the eye. Ha-ha.
These are too big.
You must have the smallest feet
in the whole North Pole.
Tiny feet.
Look at your little tiny fee...
Aah! I have never been so humiliated
in my life, Hobbs!
And I can't believe I almost fell
for your song and dance!
Your story was terrible!
Sir, have a little more eggnog? Please?
Tomorrow night,
you'd better bring me an original idea!
Tomorrow night?
But that's Christmas Eve.
I don't care! You're gonna give me
the best Christmas story ever...
or you're fired!
- But...
- Fired!
Get out of my way, you pencil-necks!
BUDDY: Wow.
- He's an angry elf.
- Buddy!
- Do you realize what you've just done?
- No.
Get out!
- Out where?
- I don't care. I don't care! Just go!
You're not an elf! You're not my son!
SANTA: It was Christmas Eve...
and Buddy had never been more unhappy
in his entire life.
Because of those terrible things
Walter said to him...
he left their home and wandered alone
through the streets of the city.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Give me another.
I think you've had enough, buddy.
I'll tell you when I've had enough.
Just keep the syrup coming.
(SIGHS)
How can a city so big
have so little Christmas spirit?
It's getting worse and worse every year.
At least you're an elf. You don't have
to listen to kids telling you you're a fake.
Well, you are fake.
You're all fakes.
Fakes.
We're just trying to spread
a little Christmas cheer.
And what do we get in return?
Bruises on our thighs
in the shape of kids' butts.
Years ago, kids would light up
when they saw you.
Now they just sit on your lap
and text each other.
No respect at all.
(SIGHS)
(SINGING) Used to be
I'd stand on the busiest corner
Ring my bell
And make the people smile
Nowadays, they pass me by
And who knows why?
Could it be that old St. Nick's
Gone out of style?
Well, nobody cares
Nobody cares
Nobody cares about Santa
They read their list
Then you get dismissed
'Cause nobody cares about Santa Claus
Is this all a sign?
Is this all an awful sign?
Of a sad decline?
A miserable, sad decline
I never knew such disrespect
Could ever have existed
No wonder this whole city
Has been naughty-listed
I kind of get that feeling too
Well, nobody cares
Nobody cares
Nobody cares about Santa
The bringer of bliss
What kind of world is this?
Where nobody cares about weary
Fed up
Ready-to-hang-the-sled-up
Santa Claus?
Ho, ho, ho?
No, no, no
(ALL SCREAMING)
(BUDDY GROANS)
- EMILY: Buddy, we're home.
- MICHAEL: Buddy.
EMILY: Where is he?
We have to find him, Mom.
WALTER: Okay, Mr. Greenway, we've come up
with a couple quite original ideas.
- Dad. We need your help.
- Wha...?
Michael, Emily, what are you doing here?
- I told you I have to work tonight.
- Buddy ran away, Walter.
What's going on here, Hobbs?
Sorry, Mr. Greenway.
It'll just be a second.
Please. This is a very
important meeting.
What's more important than your family?
I'll tell you, snotnose.
Money is what's more important.
Please, don't speak to my son that way,
Mr. Greenway.
Well, someone has to,
or else he'll turn out like your other kid.
I hope I turn out like him.
Buddy cares about everybody.
You just care about yourself.
Come on, Mom. Dad needs to work.
Yes, thank you.
You've wasted enough of our time.
Now, go ahead, Hobbs.
Uh, yeah.
Emily? Michael? Wait.
You'll wanna hear this too.
Here's the story.
It's called:
I Quit.
Excuse me?
That's right, Greenway. I quit.
You wanna spend Christmas
on the unemployment line?
No, I wanna spend Christmas
with my family.
Singing, drinking eggnog,
and opening presents.
All right, Dad.
Oh, Walter, it's about time.
Let's go find your brother.
(GROWLING)
Oh, look, another fake Santa.
You're not fooling anyone
with your flying sleigh.
I can see the strings.
You're a big fat fakety-fake fake.
(SLEIGH SPUTTERING)
Whoa. That's the real Santa.
His sleigh doesn't have enough
Christmas spirit.
He's gonna crash.
I'm coming, Santa.
(CRASH)
Sorry.
(SLEIGH SPUTTERING)
Buddy? Buddy?
Where could he have gone?
We really need a Christmas miracle
right now.
Did you see what I just saw?
(SINGING) I saw a tiny sleigh
Make its tiny way
Right across the sky
There wasn't time to think
There wasn't time to blink
Before it zoomed right by
And everything I knew, I knew
And everything that you knew too
Is absolutely now untrue because
Without a doubt there is a Santa Claus
I didn't see Santa Claus, Michael.
EMILY (SINGING): It's hard to be sedate
Or keep your head on straight
When fairy tales come true
Though I can't complain
'Cause if I'm insane
That means you are too
So why don't we make a pact
A solemn pledge to be exact
That Santa's real?
In fact he always was
I know I've had my doubts before
But now there's proof I can't ignore
So why deny it anymore?
- There is a Santa Claus
Come on. If that's Santa,
Buddy can't be far behind.
SANTA: Now, we all know Santa's sleigh
is powered by Christmas spirit...
but there aren't so many believers
these days.
So guess who's about to have...
- an emergency landing.
- Aah!
EMILY: Buddy?
- Buddy?
There's no way Buddy's out here.
Buddy.
- MICHAEL: Hi, Buddy.
- Hi.
- Buddy. Oh, we were so worried.
- I knew we'd find you.
Buddy, I'm glad you're okay.
I have something I need to say to you.
And I have something to say to you.
It can wait. This is important.
But mine's really, really,
really important.
- Then go ahead.
- Santa's sleigh is about to crash...
- because there's not enough Christmas spirit.
- Okay, that can wait. Listen.
Ever since you showed up...
you've brought this family closer
than it's ever been.
You've filled my heart
with Christmas spirit.
This whole elf thing is a little weird,
but I know you're my son, Buddy...
and I love you.
I love you too, Dad.
Okay, that's enough.
Whoa, cool.
Ho, ho. That was a close one.
Hello, Buddy.
Who's this?
Everyone, I'd like you to meet
my really good friend, Santa Claus.
Walter, I'm very proud of you.
You've rediscovered
the true meaning of Christmas:
Your family.
Congratulations.
You, sir, are officially
off the Naughty List.
Yes!
Santa Claus!
Nice to meet you, Michael.
I can't believe this.
Now that you're off the Naughty List,
Walter...
But this is crazy. How is this possible?
Just open it, Dad.
Is this what I think it is?
The skateboard I asked for
when I was 5 years old?
Of course not. What are you going to do
with a skateboard?
It's a shirt.
Ha-ha-ha. It's a skateboard.
You're real.
Santa Claus is real.
Wow!
(SLEIGH WHIRRING)
MICHAEL: Whoa, what just happened?
Your dad's Christmas spirit
just made my sleigh fly.
But we're gonna need a whole lot more
to get it back in the air.
(NAUGHTY LISTERS WHISPERING)
Oh, no. I was worried about this.
- What is it?
- Is it who I think it is?
SANTA: Yep. Naughty Listers.
Yeah, and we're here
for the presents, jerk.
Mr. Greenway?
Don't be so surprised, Hobbs.
Of course, I'm on the Naughty List.
Time to give up those presents, fatso!
No way, José.
Go spread as much Christmas cheer as you can
and we'll get that sleigh off the ground.
Go, go, go.
Get those presents!
All right, Buddy.
Lock and load.
Let's do this.
There's too many, Buddy. Hang on.
Hyah! Hyah!
MICHAEL:
Okay, let's spread some Christmas cheer.
We can't let Buddy down.
Buddy? Buddy the Elf?
How do you know Buddy?
He's the one who told me...
the best way to spread Christmas cheer
is singing loud for all to hear.
A song. That's a great idea.
We should go out there and sing.
Uh, I don't like singing
in front of people.
Oh, where's your Christmas spirit?
Buddy needs us to do this.
Walter, if she doesn't wanna sing...
If Buddy's in trouble,
then I wanna help. Let's go.
Come on, Jovie, you can do this.
It's for Buddy.
(SINGING) All you have to do
Is move your voice much higher
High, low, high, low
High
Just sing a Christmas song
It's like magic if things go wrong
Just spread some Christmas cheer
By singing loud for all to hear
Just sing a Christmas song
And keep on singing all season long
Think of the joy you'll bring
If you just close your eyes and sing
Give me those presents!
Buddy, I don't think we can outrun them.
BUDDY: We just need
a little more Christmas spirit.
Come on, Dad. Sing.
Show some Christmas spirit.
(SINGING) Just sing a Christmas song
And keep on singing all season long
Just sing a Christmas song
SANTA: Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
ALL (SINGING): And if you're short on cheer
Think about that year
You woke up to find
A brand-new snow had fallen
The ornaments you made
Way back in second grade
Untangling the Christmas lights
Took your father several nights
Your mother claimed that she had proof
There were reindeer on the roof
Remember who you were back then
Let those moments live again
Live again
BUDDY: Whoa!
(GRUNTS)
I'm okay.
SANTA: Good job, everybody.
Santa's got his mojo back.
Ho, ho, ho, ho.
You want a ride back to the North Pole,
Buddy?
No, thanks, Santa. I'm happy here.
This is Jovie.
I think she's my girlfriend.
Heh, heh, heh. Hi, Santa.
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Oh, no.
I don't have any presents.
ALL (SINGING):
Just sing a Christmas song
It's like magic if things go wrong
Think of the joy you'll bring
If you just close your eyes
SANTA: Now, that's the spirit.
Merry Christmas to all,
and to all, a good night!
ALL (SINGING): And sing
This is the most amazing
Christmas Eve ever!
Yeah. I don't even care
that I quit my job.
I quit my job.
What are we gonna do?
We'll just cut back on some things.
- You still got each other.
- And one heck of a story, Mr. Hobbs.
(GASPS)
A story. That's it.
(SINGING) Page one
Fresh out of toys
Santa makes his way back
When he hears a small noise
From inside of his pack
A sound that's not unlike a baby's cry
It's enough to leave
the jolly guy perplexed
And?
(SINGING)
Come on, Buddy, what comes next?
Page two
Back from his ride
Santa gathers his elves
ELVES (SINGING): He gathers his elves
BUDDY: And they quickly decide
They'll raise the baby themselves
The North Pole
Isn't made for humans, though
And soon the phony elf
Begins to grow so tall
- He
- Learns he's human after all
ALL: It's the story of Buddy the Elf
It's the story of Buddy the Elf
It's the story of
WALTER: And the books
will fly right off the shelf
ALL: It's the story of Buddy the Elf
And maybe Buddy helps his dad
In a setting much like this
(TIRES SCREECHING)
And maybe his father learns
A son is something he can't dismiss
They might learn that they need each other
Much more than they know
Maybe the point of the story
Is it's never too late to grow
It's never too late to grow
ALL: It's the story of Buddy the Elf
It's the story of Buddy the Elf
It's the story of
And the books will fly
right off the shelf
It's the story of Buddy the Elf
- SANTA: I love it, I love it, I do
- ALL: The elf
- I love it, I love it, I do
I love the story
Love the story, love the story
ALL: It's the story of Buddy
And that's it.
That's the story of Buddy the Elf...
which has gone on to become the
best-selling children's book in the world.
And it probably
won't come as a surprise to you...
that they all lived happily ever after.
Read it again. Read it again.
Baby Buddy loves this story.
(GIGGLING)
(SANTA SIGHS)
One more time.
"This is Christmastown
in the North Pole..."
(ENGLISH - US - SDH)