- Is that him?
- Yes.
Doesn't look like a killer.
Your timing's bad, pal.
I'm off on holiday later.
With this weather...
I need a bit of sunshine.
Name?
Pigoil.
- First name?
- Germain.
They call me Pigoil.
Place of birth?
The Faubourg.
Which one?
The Faubourg. There's only one.
A unique show in Paris. Unique!.
On the Faubourg
and at the Chansonia tonight.
An unforgettable
New Year's Eve spectacular!.
Songs, magic,
laughter, pretty women!
Starring Line Andrieux,
Réjax and that lady- killer...
...Tony Nightingale!
All for 4 francs in the stalls...
...and 3 in the circle.
Hurry, it's starting!
You're not interested?
Are you sure?
Roll up, it's a wonderful show!
Pigoil, you're late!
- I know.
- You're never late.
- Seen Jojo?
- Not yet. How's my new jacket?
- Ugly.
- Ugly?
I wanted to wear it for my debut.
Yeah, do that.
It won't be long now!
I'll be the prince of imitators!
Why not the king?
Evening, Pigoil.
They're looking for you.
Milou's caused a rumpus again.
Surprised?
Get the program!
- Not much of a crowd.
- It's not bad.
- Hi.
- All right?
Hey, Blaise, tonight.
Don't you "Milou" me.
We're sick of it!
- Let me speak.
- ls Dorfeuil dreaming?
- I'll talk to him.
- He thinks we're rolling in it?
We get paid tomorrow and no later!
Or we'll go on strike. We all agree!
No, we don't all agree
and you know it.
People, we're running late.
Think of the audience.
Tomorrow and no later!
Here we go.
- Honey, seen Jojo?
- No. Why?
Mind my makeup.
I have a surprise for you both.
- Am I beautiful?
- You bet.
Welcome to the Chansonia.
This evening, a dazzling show...
...designed to enchant.
New Year's Eve...
...a program by Louis Dorfeuil...
It looks bad
when you contradict me like that.
- Your politics wear us out.
- My politics?
It's about workers' rights.
I've been here 35 years,
six days a week, 60 hours a week.
I never complain.
- You're proud of that?
- Yes.
- Milou, get into place.
- All right.
Us others love this dump too.
His name?
You'll guess when I say...
...he sings like an angel.
All men envy him...
...and all women are mad about him.
Yes, it's him...
...Tony Nightingale!
I wait till her street is in shadow
And every door has been closed
Until all the stars have faded
Into the collusive sky
Beneath
Beneath M\aria 's balcony
I wait for M\aria to see me
If she sees me
Evening, Dorfeuil.
Stop!
This isn't nice!
I hate hurting others.
I can't, Galapiat.
Not right away. Give me more time.
Take your time if you want.
But not mine.
Pay me back by midnight
and I'll tear this up.
If not, the Chansonia is mine.
Curtains. Everyone on the dole.
Demolition, reconstruction.
Prime real estate.
This theater is my life.
I won't wish you a happy New Year.
It's bad luck before midnight.
- Seen Viviane?
- No.
I wait for M\aria to see me
Come in, silly.
If she sees me
Why
- You knew it was me?
- Why are you here?
- And you?
- Tony is letting me change in here.
You're modest now?
I have a surprise.
I went to the travel agency.
Look, the sea.
We'll go for a week with Jojo.
Let's talk later.
It's me, my love!
Sorry.
Germain...
...we need to talk.
What?
- With Nightingale?
- Yes.
The slut.
I don't believe it. What a slut!
What's wrong?
- You almost seem jealous.
- I am.
I mean...
...jealous for your sake.
Excuse me, l- -
Viviane and Nightingale?
Any connection?
They've been connecting, all right.
- Never.
- What about Milou?
Are they at it too?
See, it looks better here.
It's more an indoor jacket.
My wife sleeps around
and only your jacket matters?
Where's Pigoil?
- No idea.
- He has to do the curtain.
Pigoil!
What's up?
You go fast, Jojo. Very fast.
Much too fast. Start again.
Three times slower.
Is that you, son?
- Where were you?
- At Radio Man's.
Again? Stop going there.
You know he's...
- He helps with my homework.
- No reason.
Why are you out here?
I needed some air.
- Can I go and see Mom?
- Yes.
No. Wait.
And...one!
Goodbye, 1935.
Nine!
Three!
Six!
Nineteen thirty- six!
Happy New Year!
PARlS 36
The results of the election
of M\ay 3, 1936...
4 MONTHS LATER...
...are a resounding victory
for the Popular Front!
M\r. Léon Blum
is forming a government...
...to carry out
unprecedented social reforms...
...bound to create further tension.
M\ore than a turning point...
...it's a revolution for workers.
These are times of hope.
FOR SALE
Dad?
- What is it?
- Your breakfast.
- What time is it?
- Eight o'clock.
- You're not at school?
- I'm going.
Off you go.
Thanks.
Long live the Popular Front!
Come and see. It's heating up.
All comrades must stand united
for a common cause, the strike!
An immediate strike!
Here and now!
Easy to call for a strike
when you don't work here.
But I'll be here.
Every day...
...with the union to back you.
Who's for?
Well?
Yes.
Come on, vote.
- Strike!
- Yes, comrades!
A unanimous vote.
I need your help, Mr. Galapiat.
The union has sent Emile Leibovich.
I'm seeing red, literally.
What will you do?
Come on, let's go.
With two bottles of red...
...that makes
22 francs and 52 centimes.
Tell me, Crouzet.
I've known you a while now.
Why give only me credit?
I trust you, Pigoil.
- Jojo doesn't suspect anything?
- Nothing.
We've never had debts before.
Like I told you,
it's between you and me.
Have a good day, Crouzet.
- Here we go.
- Not too fast!
Let's get rich!
This kid Jojo is gonna go far
His fingers as swift as a shooting star
With a memory that nothing can mar
This kid Jojo is gonna go far
One day when he's a true champion
A leading brand of accordion
On its goods will carve his name
To ensure his everlasting fame
Thank you!
Jojo and Clément will be back...
...same time tomorrow.
You're a lousy singer.
Who cares? It makes them laugh.
Next spot.
We did well today.
Come and see.
When I was in the Red Army...
...I lost a lot of comrades in battle.
The strike suits you.
I'm Emile.
Milou to the ladies.
Are you Leibovich?
In person.
- To join up, fill out a form at the door.
- A comedian.
You commies have five minutes
to get out.
I smell Yid.
Come on, kids!
What's going on?
Don't just stand there! Run!
Fascists!
Bastards!
Fascist bastards!
Keep away from the laundry.
Strikes aren't for kids.
They're for idlers.
Milou's no idler.
Milou? He's the king of idle slobs.
The Chansonia closed four months
ago. Seen him work since?
I haven't.
He's always chasing skirt...
...stirring up trouble in factories...
...yelling about strikes
and occupations.
I can do that too.
You don't work either.
I wanted to ask you.
Why don't you and Milou
speak anymore?
Is it because of Mom?
Sort of.
Do you miss Mom?
Do you miss her?
No. Do you?
Me neither.
Liar.
Liar yourself.
Eat while it's hot.
Is it good?
You impressed us at the laundry.
You didn't waste time, old chap.
The one with the ball is pretty.
Too bad.
You certainly deserve
a role worthy of you.
- When?
- Once we take power.
Blum is already up the creek.
He'll fall like rotten fruit.
And we'll be waiting.
Heading the militia contingent
is a good start...
...but with the support I give you- -
150,000 francs since January.
- - I hope for other responsibilities
in your party, my dear Grevoul.
You'll have them.
But you must calm down.
"Soft pedal," as you people say.
Explain, Tortil.
Your boys overdid it at the laundry.
One worker, a father of four,
is in a coma.
I may not be able
to cover you next time.
Enough idle chat.
I hear you have
some new goods in stock.
- Top- quality.
- I'll vouch for that.
If the inspector vouches for it...
You spoil us, Galapiat.
- Let's see.
- Always ready to serve France.
Blimey, true as
my name's Fernandel...
...I remember
the conscription officer told me:.
"You're short of breath,
you need a bigger chest."
I told him,
"My sister got all the chest."
I've got him down pat, right?
I'll fit it into my act.
My one- man show,
as they say on Broadway.
They'll go wild.
How many auditions
these last four months?
Around 10.
Maybe a few more.
And always turned down?
You're so naive. Can't you see...
...established stars block the way?
Sure.
A guy like me puts them
in a blue funk.
Give it a rest.
You're wearing us out, Jacky.
Just find a job. A real one.
With real pay!
Thanks for helping Jojo.
Only natural.
It changes nothing.
I haven't forgotten about Viviane.
Have a drink and make up.
I don't drink with traitors.
I don't drink at all anymore.
What?
Lovely! Good payers
are hard to come by these days.
Just carry on like this.
Give him all he wants,
but he mustn't know.
You're a complicated lot.
Don't worry, it's between us. Here.
You're two francs over.
Here.
Where's this from?
It's a gift from Crouzet.
A gift? From Crouzet?
I swear.
Lying to me now.
We Pigoils never steal!
I didn't steal it.
Consider this a gift too!
Jojo, come back!
Here they come!
This kid Jojo is gonna go far
His fingers as swift as a shooting star
With a memory that nothing can mar
What are you up to?
How old are you?
He can't even play the accordion, sir.
I'd like to help, but...
All right.
Sit down, Mr. Pigoil.
Your son is engaged in begging.
You're no longer capable
of raising the boy.
He'd be better off in care?
Who mentioned care?
He has a mother.
His mother's gone on tour
with her lover boy.
She's back.
She admits she was wrong...
...and has been here
to tell us she wants her son back.
I have agreed to that,
for a trial period.
Seriously?
Until you've found
regular employment...
...you won't be able to have him back,
or even see him.
But she walked out on us!
Months without a word!
Your ex- wife is now involved in...
...a model relationship with a retailer.
A retailer?
A spirits merchant.
Calm and honest.
In a small country town.
Ideal for your son.
Pigoil?
We forgot to give him this.
Chin up.
The Great MAX
- Yes?
- Open up.
Recognize this?
Come here, bastard!
Stop! I don't want to go out!
You taught him to beg!
That was his homework. Why?
Down, Aristide!
"The sea, the sea."
It's all you talk about.
Talked about.
He wanted to make enough
to take you.
Why didn't you tell me?
It was a surprise.
And I never see you anyway.
Of course, you haven't been out
for 20 years now.
Thanks to my radio...
...I know the world as if I did go out.
You're not missing much.
Look what the world's made of me.
What's going on?
Who opened the place up?
Jacky. He's lost his mind. Look.
He's told everyone to come.
Galapiat will be hopping mad.
It looks good.
Well? Can't you guess?
Make an effort.
I'm sure you know this voice.
What on earth is this masquerade?
Order, gentlemen! I want order!
So? Who is it?
Hitler?
Inspector Tortil!
Get out of here!
Who goes there?
This looks bad.
Get down, idiot.
Get out! It's private property!
Out with you.
Don't you speak French, you clown?
Ever heard of manners?
You say hello when you turn up.
You shouldn't be here.
Wait till Mr. Galapiat finds out.
I'm scared.
We can still have a laugh here.
Your Chansonia's dead, moron!
Not yet!
This is our place.
We've given it our lives.
We'll take something back now.
We're occupying it.
- What?
- We're occupying it!
Yeah, we're occupying.
What's up, guys?
You can't improvise a revolution.
I don't care about your revolution.
I just want a steady job.
Chansonia occupied.
You said it.
Just a second.
You think you can restore everything...
...set up a new show,
run a business.
All that...
- ...in my place?
- Well, yes.
We're professionals.
I admire your passion for work...
...but private property
is a sacred right in France.
We'll pay rent. With luck,
we'll buy the place one day.
How? By singing for your supper?
In any case...
...you have no choice.
Tomorrow, the whole country
will be on strike.
The times are changing.
Stop it, please.
Enough, Pigoil.
I'm sick of their smooth talk.
The workers are taking back
their work tool.
Bravo, Comrade Leibovich.
A true democrat. With men like you,
France is in good hands.
You leave France be.
She doesn't need schemers like you.
What are you implying?
Can I have a word with you? Alone.
What is it?
- You remember Charles Vl?
- What?
Charles Vl, son of Charles V...
...whom he succeeded in 1380.
Enough, Triquet.
Watch your tone with me.
His peaceful nature
endeared him to the French.
They called him
"Charles the Beloved."
What the hell do I care?
You heard Tortil.
If you're harsh,
you may lose everything.
Stay discreet, show trust.
You already rule the Faubourg.
Become its Beloved.
Galapiat the Beloved.
- Morning.
- Hi, Pigoil.
Veal stew "Chansonia"
So you're with us, are you?
Isn't it obvious? You fatheads.
Guys.
Galapiat gave us a month.
A month to succeed, Jojo.
The Chansonia is in a bad way.
We'd never have managed it all
on our own.
Nearly there.
Time to eat!
They're all back, happy to work,
even for nothing...
... until the first receipts.
Even your pal Clément came.
I think he misses you.
Careful, lads. I get vertigo.
So don't look at us.
You play the accordion.
I hope you'll play me
a tune or two soon.
I miss you so much.
Lots of love. Dad.
I'm not accusing anyone.
I'm just saying this mill worked well.
So buy a new one.
It's only 15 years old.
Mom, can you post this for me?
We have to go every day.
They have to see it's my place.
They mustn't forget that.
That's why monarchs
put their heads on coins.
Enough!
- Philippe le- -
- Enough!
- Stop!
- Philippe le Bel.
Excuse me.
I'd like to see Mr. Dorfeuil.
That's terrible.
He was desperate.
He begged me to buy his theater.
I didn't quibble.
Friendship is priceless.
But fine gestures
aren't always enough.
Why did you want to see
dear old Dorfeuil?
He was the last person
Mother knew in Paris.
Knew? Why? Is she...?
She's dead. Two months ago.
You poor dear.
- I'm not your poor dear.
- Just a way of speaking.
I see you with your little suitcase...
...your little dress,
your little tears.
You're very sentimental.
Not always.
There's your pretty smile.
- I have to go.
- What? So soon?
I'll make the rounds...
...and do auditions.
Auditions?
- I want to make my debut.
- Debut in what?
The music hall, of course.
Well, I never... It's not easy.
You need contacts.
I'm not scared.
Thank you for your welcome.
- Mr. Galapiat told me to help you.
- I'm all right.
Mondain.
My chauffeur.
He'll take you where you like.
Mr. Triquet, my accountant.
Mademoiselle.
Douce.
That's sweet, "Douce."
Do you have family here?
Where will you sleep?
I'll manage.
I've got my wits about me.
- Do we have a room left?
- I'll check.
- I'm all right, really.
- Allow me to insist.
In memory of Dorfeuil.
You'll be safe with me.
I'm Félix Galapiat, real- estate agent.
I do business too.
Do you know what they call me?
The Beloved. Galapiat the Beloved.
Allow me to show you why.
Pigoil, we're sick of it.
You say we're all in this together...
...then you hire sluts
once our backs are turned.
You see evil everywhere.
What else are Galapiat's floozies?
What choice do we have?
Let's start.
- What are those for?
- To look cold.
You don't show what you think.
You look like a fly.
I can't see either.
You're hired.
- You'll be paid from the takings.
- What?
It said so in the ad.
- You'll only be paid if it's a hit.
- What?
Gentlemen...
...I'm leaving.
Goodbye. Next!
Blaise? Why are you here?
I'm out of work too.
- We can't pay you at first.
- Do I get meals?
- Yes.
- Beverages too?
- Count me in.
Next!
Love me
It's what you do best
Honestly!
Don't you have another pianist?
Cut it out.
He's good.
Be careful what you eat
Not too salty nor too sweet
You only have one stomach
Be careful what you drink
Not too fizzy
Nor too still
Or you'll need to pee
M\y belly aches
Too late, it's time to go
Bravo!
- He's hired.
- Yes, he's good.
Next!
It's the girl Mr. Galapiat sent.
- Here we go.
- What can this tart do?
Who knows?
Back to the knocking shop with her.
Hello, young lady.
- What's your name?
- Douce.
- I'm sorry?
What can you show us?
Her tits.
Whatever you like.
I can sing a song.
No, thank you.
We have singers for that.
Stick to what you do best.
I can recite a commercial, then.
A radio commercial.
Keep on wasting your time.
Milou.
Recite your commercial.
Be it by the fire at home...
...or for a night on the town...
...for my sweet lover alone...
...or for a crowd in my gown...
...I use Simon cream
to make me attractive and pretty.
Like every girl in the city.
I thank Simon cream
Simon cream
Announcer?
We'll have to see her pins.
Right.
May we see your legs?
- Not bad.
- You're hired.
The Chansonia is looking so fine
Because Faubourg Paints
Has colors divine
Good. The second one.
Jeanne and her hair styles
Are the best anywhere for miles
It's good thanking our partners.
- Sure.
- It's true.
He's in his Sunday best!
How's the ventriloquist doing?
Ace, like your suit.
Pigoil, isn't it time to eat?
That's all you think of.
- Your musicians?
- They're free.
- Are they good?
My costumes?
See Milou about that. Milou!
Pigoil!
Very funny.
Take her to Paris- Costumes.
Send the artistic director.
I have to rehearse.
Ask about my new jacket.
You handle the money, so see to it.
I have a reputation here.
- You go.
- I can't.
- Got a cocktail party?
- An appointment.
A romantic one.
You understand what I'm after?
Songs about walks in the park.
Merry and joyful ones.
Manager of what, exactly?
The Chansonia. I've taken it over,
with my partners.
Allow me to offer you
two free invitations.
Come anytime with your wife.
- Are you getting paid?
- Yes.
Well, no. But I soon will be.
So come back and see me soon.
I've stopped drinking.
Sorry, I have a lot of work.
I know Mr. Galapiat very well too.
Is that a threat?
You're barking up the wrong tree.
No, I didn't mean anything by that.
This is for my son.
Since I can't have his address,
can you forward it to him?
I'll see what I can do.
Thank you.
Look at this one.
All silk with sequins.
Look at the finish.
How much?
Two thousand a week.
You think we're suckers?
Don't move, I'll be right back.
Shopping with you is a joy.
We're not the Folies Bergère.
- It's the union's money.
- Spoilsport.
Well?
Common.
Nouveau riche. No good.
I know why you're so mean to me.
You're attracted to me.
I'm attracted?
And you can't bear the idea of it.
Here we are.
Twelve hundred. Will that do?
It's the cheapest I have.
Why don't you ask your protector...
...to dress you at Lanvin?
He's not my protector.
All right. I can be more vulgar.
Well...
...this show has to be worth seeing.
What's your problem?
Beware of reds.
You're heading for a fall.
- Reds?
- Yes, reds.
For instance...
...the one you were with today...
...is a real red.
An agitator ready to sell France
to Moscow.
And to abuse young orphan girls.
- Are you jealous?
- Absolutely.
I have a right to be.
I watch over you. I worry.
That's very kind. Thank you.
But I never asked you to.
You make me suffer, Douce.
You're so distant. It hurts.
Where?
Here.
There.
Let me help you reach the very top
as you deserve.
Good night.
Take me home.
- I'm in bed!
- It's Emile.
- Good evening.
- I could have been with a client.
Sorry about earlier.
It's not like me to...
I know you're not a...
I apologize, okay.
Come on in.
No, I don't want...
Don't be afraid.
I'm not afraid.
I didn't pick the decor.
Glad to hear it.
- Where did he take you?
- Who?
To his cabaret, the Arabian Nights.
You know it?
No.
I don't go to rich folks' clubs.
So where do you go?
Shindigs, dance halls,
places where workers go.
That's where I come from.
I'm from Lille. Well, near there.
I didn't know.
What do you know about me?
That you're pretty.
And Galapiat's friend.
- Not again.
- I know how to flush out the enemy.
I was in the Red Army elite corps.
Real tough guys,
nothing like Galapiat.
Watch your step with him.
He's scum.
Funny, he said the same about you.
He did?
Who'll you believe?
I don't know.
I'll think about it.
And now, Monsieur Fernandel.
Maestro.
I don't know, I don't know
I don't know if Raymonde is blonde
Under her arms, left and right
The hair is black as night
On the day we finally wed
After the party, we were in bed
I had a revelation
She wasn't blonde
What deception
Bravo! Excellent, Jacky!
Thank you. Come back anytime!
Thank you.
Sorry.
Magnificent.
It's not quite ready.
Have you seen
my young protégée anywhere?
She's gone. To try on costumes.
Something sexy.
You see what I mean?
- Not alone?
- No, with Milou. Emile.
He knows all about skimpy dresses.
Can I buy you a drink?
Frankly, I'm worried
about the Chansonia.
Apart from you and Douce,
the others...
You've noticed then?
No, no.
Thank you.
I'll tell you something.
I'm what they call a star turn.
Precisely.
I'll offer you a deal.
Fill me in on everything...
...the problems, who's doing what.
Be my right- hand man, in short.
And I'll help you with your career.
- How?
- A big stage.
Just for you.
Can I really say stuff like this?
It's humor, Jacky, a caricature.
Your talent will make it work,
believe me.
Our old Gallo- Roman homeland...
...now governed
by a naturalized Jew.
Since all of us here in SOC...
...Iove our dear France...
...it is our duty to raise a wall...
...a patriotic rampart
to keep out all the rats...
...who come to eat
our fine French cheeses!
Long live France!
Long live SOC!
Do you recognize me?
Try hard.
They call me the Yid.
"Kike" to my friends.
Fear not, I don't mean you any harm.
I love France!
As long as she fills my pockets.
Seen my carpet, my friend?
Nice and cheap.
Cheaper than Léon Blum!
What do you think of it?
Remarkable.
I wrote it.
Yeah, boss!
No problem, boss!
We go out picking that cotton!
Charge, sergeant!
I hear it's an excellent film.
Paris. In these troubled times
of strikes and factory occupations...
...the unemployed
of a neighborhood have united...
... to revive a music hall...
... with imagination
and staunch determination.
Stagehands, cashiers, usherettes
and even sandwich men...
...all jobs that need filling.
All the local businesses
support them...
...from the café owner to the grocer
while waiting for the artists.
It's good to see
the French stand united.
An example to follow!
A fine example.
Where are you going?
Jojo, come back!
Hold my bag.
- Where are you going?
- I'll be right back.
You think I feel nothing?
I've made blunders.
But I came back for you.
I'm doing all this for you.
You've made a lot of progress here.
Don't worry about your dad.
He has all he needs.
Come back in now.
I got us the best seats.
All right, we're coming.
You're my sweetheart.
The Chansonia reopens tonight!
Free admission for all!
See the Five- Man Quartet!
Romance with Roger Nizza!
The escape artist, Fred Kraft!
And only at the Chansonia,
the Prince of lmitators, Jacky Jacquet!
- Where were you?
- I forgot the time.
Are you kidding? He forgot the time.
Everyone's here.
Not only. Look at the third row.
The cream of the press is here.
Even the radio has come.
- Here we go. Mazel tov!
- Don't screw up.
Showtime!
Good evening.
Welcome to the Chansonia.
It's an important evening
for our music hall...
Break a leg!
...run by Mr. Pigoil.
Over to you.
Show them what we're made of.
Remember what I said, keep smiling.
Your paper!
Ready?
Here we go.
Go on.
Good evening
and welcome to the Chansonia...
...for its gala reopening.
This is a big night for our music hall...
...now run by Mr. Pigoil...
...and his friends.
Strip!
Only after you do.
We wouldn't be here
without everyone who believed in us.
For fresh produce every day
One address, chez Crouzet
For his cooking and fine wine
Take a table at Célestin's
And thank you to Mr. Galapiat
who made this possible.
No need to overdo it.
And now...
...the man known
as "The Prince of lmitators."
Yes, the one and only...
...Jacky Jacquet!
Perfect!
- Really?
- lf the manager says so...
Get the next announcement ready.
Jacky, we're right behind you.
Bravo, Jacky!
Thank you.
Thanks to Jacky,
the Prince of lmitators...
...we're taking flight.
Here come the planes.
You can picture the plane.
He's priceless.
Thank you.
Now let's go fishing.
It's a sunny day.
Look up. What do I see there?
Ducks!
Ducks, ladies and gentlemen.
Do you see them?
The daddy duck.
The mommy duck.
The ducklings.
Ducks, ladies and gentlemen.
We can't leave this fabulous place...
...without hearing the frogs wake.
Here come the frogs.
It takes some doing.
He's alone up there.
It's not easy.
- He's not funny.
- Try doing the frog for this crowd.
Thank you.
Bravo!
They're a bit cold tonight.
I'll warm them up.
You've been waiting for him.
With special permission
from his sergeant- -
A song!
Yeah, a song!
- - our greatest comic troupers.
You know who I mean, Poupart!
A song!
- What's wrong?
- She has to sing.
- You have to sing.
- What?
They want a song.
You must know one.
No.
- Not very well.
- lt'll do.
- What about me?
- Later.
Go on.
It won't work.
Whenever I'm far from Paris
M\y lungs can't catch a breath
M\y heart is filled with tears
And my body feels exiled
The furthest
I ever went was along the M\arne
To follow a little crush I had
But as soon as all the din fades
I'm bored for silence doesn't suit me
Paris, Paris
You're my only family
Only with you is my heart free
If I don't see you again tomorrow
Paris, I'll die
Eaten up by sorrow
You bewitch me with your charms
I'll lie naked in your arms
If I don't see you again tomorrow
Paris, I'll die
Eaten up by sorrow
You realize?