Hey, listen, if you and your
nautical nitwits...
...are gonna give the girls their
big break, better shove off.
- We've dropped anchor.
- We have?
Say, will you guys let me forget
I was once a hoofer?
It sure seems swell to be getting back
where the women talk your own language.
You bet. it's gonna be great
to be able to talk to a dame...
...without using your hands.
Hey, you been holding out on me.
I didn't know you had a girl in your act.
- Give me that.
- Wait a minute.
That's why you joined the Navy.
You thought a torpedo would be easier...
- ...to dodge than a shotgun.
- Don't be funny.
- I asked that little girl to marry me.
- What?
Yeah, and she turned me down.
Imagine a guy asking a dame to marry.
Say, what's become of her?
Oh, I heard from her
when we were down in Manila.
She's working here in Frisco.
Well. Maybe she's got a friend.
Let's go see her.
No, we're all washed up.
- Say, give me that picture.
- What do you want it for?
I thought you said
you were all washed up.
Oh, I just kept it
because I came out so good.
Lay aft for the 4:00 liberty party.
Boy, I hope I pick
something good this time.
I'm always getting schoolteachers.
Why not?
You got a lot to learn yet.
I want something with spangles on it,
like that ex-partner of yours.
Say, let's find her.
She probably wouldn't
even speak to me anymore.
The last letter from her, she said she
was working in a high-class spot...
- ...where all the money goes.
- Yeah? Well, that's the way it is.
Listen, you mugs, don't forget
that liberty expires at 12:00.
We've got our orders.
Needn't wait up tonight, Mother.
We're going to Paradise.
Six admissions, please.
- Do you want any dance tickets?
- Dance tickets?
- How much are they?
- Three for 25.
- Give me one.
- one?
Yeah, to see if I like it.
What's the matter?
Don't your friends dance?
They're underage.
I hold them on my lap.
- Hey, Bake, where's Bilge?
- He stopped off to buy the beer.
He knows a place where you get
3 cents back on the bottles.
Hi, tiny.
I'll see you fellows. I gotta look
up a party in the telephone book.
Hello? information?
Look, I want to get the number
of a Miss Sherry Martin.
She lives at 610 Hyde Street.
Yeah, all right.
Sorry, miss,
it's the rules of the Paradise.
No girls are allowed in without escorts.
I see. Women aren't even admitted
to paradise without a man.
Yeah.
Oh, there you are.
Don't bother. Your hands are full.
I'll get the tickets for us.
Two, please.
I'll explain to you when we get inside.
Did you bring your lunch too?
Thank you. You see,
I wanted to get in to see my sister.
She works here, and they wouldn't
let me in without an escort.
I thought you were trying to frame me.
Oh, no. You see,
I've never been here before.
My sister's asked me to come down.
I've never been able to.
I've always been so busy, but, well,
tonight I just felt like a little spree.
Well, I hope you find it.
I've sort of been playing hooky
all day today.
I spent the afternoon
watching the fleet come in.
Oh, gee, it was exciting.
If I were a man, I'd be a sailor.
Yeah, I know just how you feel.
They're pretty, aren't they?
I'll bet you're used to seeing
pretty girls all over the world.
I never give them a tumble, sister.
Women don't interest me.
I'll bet you dance beautifully.
No, not a step.
Well, I gotta be shoving off. So long.
- Come to Papa.
- You sure work fast, Bilge.
- Yeah, we're the slow ones.
- Lay off me.
Where did you pick up
that awful-looking crow?
She picked me up.
I think she's screwy.
She must be
if she tried to pick you up.
- Well, what will you have?
- Six clean glasses.
- Who is it?
- Connie.
Oh, Connie, come in.
I'm glad to see you. How'd you get away?
What about your music lessons?
I didn't feel like giving them,
so I just called up and said I was ill.
I guess it's just a touch
of spring fever.
This is a funny time to be having
spring fever, in october.
Well, things usually happen
to me out of season.
Connie, why don't you admit it.
You're lonesome.
Some men aren't half bad.
I don't know why.
I just seem to frighten them away.
You look too darned intelligent.
It isn't that gentlemen prefer blonds...
...it's just that we look dumber.
Maybe that's it.
It used to end up by my saying
I'd be a sister to them.
Now it begins by their saying
they'll be a brother to me.
That's the difference between us.
I make them say uncle.
Well, I can understand that.
You're attractive.
Connie, women weren't born
with silk stockings on, you know.
Well, I wear silk stockings.
And no one looks at them.
Well, men haven't x-ray eyes.
Though sometimes I wonder.
Gee, you must look lovely in this.
And so could you, if you wanted to.
Things have got to be
dolled up nowadays.
That's why they put brass on battleships.
Why don't you let me try to fix you up?
You'll be amazed how much
better it'll make you feel.
Even though I'm not a blond,
I could be dumb, couldn't I?
And you'll probably do all right too.
It takes a lot of brains to be dumb.
Let's try it.
Hey, Kitty!
Connie, this is Kitty Collins.
Kitty, this is my sister.
- How do you do?
- Hiya.
Will you fix her up?
Well, I'll do what I can, Sherry.
I've got to go on.
I'll be back after the number.
And remember the old saying,
"Clothes make the man."
Do you have to wear these?
Oh, no. I just wear them
to impress my pupils.
I'll bet they're impressed.
Nobody'd ever take you
for Sherry's sister.
I guess not.
I've spent most of my life up the coast
in a little town called Bellport...
...while Sherry's been here.
Sherry!
- Bake!
- Sherry!
Well, what a surprise seeing you here!
Yeah. I'm kind of surprised
to see you here too.
Gosh, I'm glad to see you.
I'm glad to see you too.
Say, you better do something
for that cold.
Oh, this isn't a cold.
It's tears because
I'm so glad to see you.
I'm glad to see you too.
Thanks.
I've missed you, Bake.
I've missed you too.
A little bit.
Gosh, I'm glad to see you.
Same here.
I worried about you for two years
until I learned you'd joined the Navy.
Didn't you ever get my letter?
Oh, sure, I heard from you, all right.
Telling me about how well
you were doing and everything.
Why didn't you write to me?
I didn't think you cared
about hearing from me.
Especially after that last time
we saw each other.
Well, all I said was
I didn't want to marry you.
Yeah, I know.
It all seemed very important at that time.
But it doesn't make any difference now.
Doesn't it?
No. As you said, marriage
would have ruined your career.
Well, I found out I was wrong.
No, maybe you're right.
If you'd married me, you wouldn't
be working in a chop-suey joint like this.
Well, I don't see
any admiral's stripes on you.
I like to go incognito,
just to mingle with the boys.
Order, please.
I want a Coke.
And Miss Martin will have a chocolate
sundae without whipped cream.
With whipped cream, and plenty of it.
Gosh, you're glad to see me.
Well, you sure look different.
Don't I?
I'm beginning to feel different.
Kitty, there's a sailor I want to meet.
How do I go about it?
Are you kidding?
No. I mean, are there any rules?
Well, yes and no.
"Yes" before you meet him...
...and "no" after.
Gosh, Sherry, how'd you
ever get in a place like this?
Well, it seems I didn't mean
much after we split up.
For some reason, they're not
interested in a girl dancing alone...
...unless she's got a fan.
Well, a fan doesn't cost much.
Gee, it's swell being with you again.
Friends?
- Friends.
- Let's kiss and make up.
No, let's just make up.
That'll give you something to work for.
Why don't you guys take a walk.
Hiya, baby.
Hello, sailor.
- So you know my name.
- Sure.
Haven't we met before?
That's what I should have said.
No, but haven't we?
Not a chance.
Think I could forget a face like yours?
Well, I must have been mistaken.
But we're meeting now.
Wanna dance?
Oh, I was under the impression
that you didn't dance.
Who, me?
I'm the heavyweight
dance champ of the fleet.
You've got me up
against the ropes here.
Maybe we better sit this one out.
Sure.
This is a lucky night for me, baby.
You're just my type of girl.
Oh, really?
I thought you were the kind of man
who never gives girls a tumble.
You've got some
very funny ideas about me.
Oh, I admit I've been around.
But I've never met one like you, baby.
No, I guess you haven't.
Hey, what's the idea?
It's a line of defense.
Well, watch my maneuvers.
You can't beat the Navy.
All right, sailor. I surrender.
Unconditionally?
Well, I'm willing to discuss terms.
Okay, baby. Let's get out of here.
Let's find someplace where we can talk.
I'll go ransom my hat
and meet you at the back exit.
And don't walk out on me.
- Where's Connie?
- Dropped in a minute ago...
...and said she was leaving,
for you not to worry.
Poor kid. I'll bet she was scared
with all these sailors around.
Thanks.
All right, everybody.
And now, as you know...
...the Paradise Club holds its popular
Saturday night dance contest.
Mr. Weber will tap the shoulders
of the eliminated couples...
...and as usual, your applause
will decide the winners.
I thank you.
- Kind of neat, huh?
- Kind of.
Listen, my enlistment's up in the spring.
Then we'll pick up where we left off,
only this time you'll ask me to marry you.
The Navy must be a wonderful institution.
It produces such a modest,
shrinking type of man.
Yeah, doesn't it?
Go away.
How do you like that?
On my dime, he wants to cut in.
The village cutups.
Wait a minute.
This is the dance contest.
- Is it?
- I'm not supposed to be in it.
- Why not?
- Because it's for guests.
Well, I'm a guest. Ten cents' worth.
No, I don't think I'd better.
Maybe you're right. You probably couldn't
keep up with me anymore anyway.
You think not? Well, I'm not so
sure you could keep up with me.
Gosh, you've kind of taken
the wind out of my sails.
There aren't any sails these days, baby.
Just steam, full steam ahead.
Come on, let me get you
something to eat.
- Don't tell me you can cook too.
- oh, yes.
You don't know the kind
of person I really am.
Well, you've given me a faint idea.
Oh, boy.
Say, I haven't seen the inside
of an icebox since I left home.
Where is your home?
Texas.
I've been back once or twice
to see my mother.
- She never knows when I'm gonna turn up.
- Don't you ever write her?
I'm no good at writing.
Don't know what to say.
You could say you love her.
What's the use? She knows that.
Custard pie.
- Now, don't tell me you made this too.
- I made it.
Sweetheart, you've got everything.
I knew it from the first minute I saw you.
- Bilge, I've got to tell you the truth.
- About what?
Well, the first time you saw me,
you acted as my escort.
Remember the funny-looking girl
with glasses who bought your ticket?
- Yeah.
- Well, that was me.
Well, what was the getup for?
It wasn't a getup.
Until tonight, those were the kind
of clothes I wore. That was the real me.
Well, how do you like that?
But that doesn't make any difference.
I'm nuts about you anyway.
Say, Connie, what are you?
A teacher.
I knew it.
Yes, a music teacher.
Well, that ain't so bad.
Oh, Miss Martin, I want to speak to you.
Mr. Weber, I want you to meet
Mr. Baker, a friend of mine.
Mr. Baker is a guest.
- Oh, how do you do?
- How are you?
Mr. Weber owns the Paradise Club.
Is that so?
Not a bad little spot
you got here, Mr. Weber.
It isn't right for Miss Martin though.
She's used to working
in a nicer atmosphere.
Oh, you don't like this atmosphere.
It's all right for some people...
...but not for Miss Martin.
And who are you?
Me? I'm her manager.
I see. Well, I think you'd better
go manage her somewhere else.
Beginning right now.
Pick up your salary
in the morning, Miss Martin.
Good night.
Well, I fixed that.
You fixed me.
I did that on purpose. I don't want you
working in a place like this.
I'll take you to see Jim Nolan.
I'll get him to put you in his show.
- He'll do that.
- It might have been better to wait...
...until we were sure.
Now, I'll take care of everything.
That's exactly what's worrying me.
Bilge, how long are
you going to be here?
We're having war games.
We don't know.
- Maybe in a week. Maybe tonight.
- oh, no.
Don't you worry.
We'll be back in the spring.
The night the fleet arrives
you and me have got a date.
- Honest?
- The minute we hit port.
- Soon after that, I'm out of the Navy.
- Really? What are you going to do then?
Gonna stick to the sea.
Oh, I love the sea too.
My father was a sea captain.
You know, that's what I want to be.
I'm taking my chief petty
officer exams now.
Then I'm going to try for my master's
papers in hopes that I can get a ship.
Bilge, I've got a ship.
- What?
- Yes, come here.
Here it is.
It's a model of the real one.
It was my dad's ship.
He died of a broken heart when
she ran aground off the north coast.
I wouldn't want my ship
to run aground either.
Dad left my sister Sherry
what little money he had.
And he left me the ship because
he knew how much she meant to me.
Boy, she's a beauty.
I've always had dreams of sailing on her
again as I did when I was a kid.
A steam schooner,
just the kind I like to feel under me.
Baby, I'd like to be captain of your ship.
I wanna sail under my own steam to
China, India and those spiggoty ports.
So do I.
I've always wanted to sail on her
to all those spiggoty places...
...with my husband at the helm.
- Holy cat.
- What's the matter?
I gotta be going.
Gotta be back on board by 12:00.
- Oh, gee.
- Sorry.
Well...
Hello, Connie. ls Sherry home?
Not yet. She's a
little later than usual.
What's happened to you, Connie?
You look swell.
May I present Mr. Smith. A friend
of my sister's, Mrs. Manning.
How do you do?
- I'm sorry to have broken in like this.
- oh, no, that's all right. Don't go.
Mr. Smith was just leaving.
He has to be back on ship by 12.
I can't stay. I have an engagement,
but tell Sherry I dropped in.
Good night, dear.
Good night, Mr. Smith.
Good night.
I wish you didn't have to leave, Bilge,
but maybe you'd better.
Yeah, I guess so.
If you're still here tomorrow night,
will I see you?
Will you.
- Tell the admiral not to go away.
- I'll do that. Good night, baby.
Good night.
Mr. Smith.
Hello.
I'm going that way anyway, so I thought
I might drop you off at the dock.
Thanks, that'll help me out a lot.
I'll be up to get you
the first thing in the
morning and we'll go see Nolan together.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Can't you come up for a while?
I'm sorry, Sherry. I've only got a minute.
I've got to be back on board by 12:00.
Good night.
Haven't you got a home?
Turn in all liberty cards.
All liberty has been cancelled.
We have immediate sailing orders.
Turn in all liberty cards.
All liberty has been cancelled.
We have immediate sailing orders.
Sailing orders? Listen,
I've got to get ashore.
I've started something
I've got to finish.
Yeah?
Maybe you're lucky we're sailing.
Put it in.
I've got to go to bed, Connie.
I can't keep my eyes open any longer.
Yes, it's late.
Sherry, how much does
a chief petty officer get?
Whatever he told you,
just cut it in half.
Give me a chance. Let me talk
about Bake for a while, will you?
Excuse me, darling, you go right ahead.
Of course, he would make more as
master of his own ship, wouldn't he?
I'll bet he's by far the
best dancer in the Navy.
Yes, that's what he told me.
Who?
You're talking about Bake.
It's swell, Sherry, isn't it?
Isn't it?
- What's the matter?
- Bilge must have been right.
About what?
Well, he said they might
have to leave anytime...
...but it's sooner than I expected.
Who has to leave? What? Where?
The fleet.
The fleet?
Why, the dirty, double-crossing...
What's going on?
Dance team.
Stand clear, fellows.
Give everybody a chance to read it.
Well, where is Bake?
Professor Baker will commence
dancing class just as soon as he...
...finishes painting the mainmast.
When you weren't back
by 2 this morning...
...I had to think up some alibi.
I told the quartermaster you stayed
with your mother who was very sick.
When the officer of the deck
asked me where my mother was...
...I said she was home in Texas.
Well, how did I know you
were going to be so dumb?
I can understand them making you do this,
but why do they have to pick on me?
What kept you out so late anyway?
A very charming young lady,
with loads of dough.
She was in show business
too, before she got married.
But her husband didn't understand her,
so the poor kid had to go to Reno.
Poor kid. I bet the chorus miss her.
She still sees them.
There's nothing snooty about her.
What about that teacher that was going
to make you captain of her ship?
She's a swell kid too,
but she's kind of serious.
She's sappy like you.
She wants to get married.
I beg your pardon.
One, two, three.
one, two, three. Try it.
One, two, three. one, two, three.
one, two, three.
Now the left arm up.
Right arm around the lady's waist.
one, two, three. Now smile.
One, two, three. All right.
Let's see if you can
remember what I told you.
Now, you fellows get over there.
You're the dames.
Dames? What's the big idea?
You asked me to teach you
how to dance, didn't you?
All right then, you're dames.
You fellows are their partners.
All right, music.
Now get together.
Come on, get together, get together.
One, two, three. one, two, three.
one, two, three.
Don't be bashful. Grab them tight.
One, two, three. one, two, three.
That's better. one, two, three.
Hey, Bake, nobody will dance with me.
That's too bad.
Keep it up, fellows,
while I dance with the wallflower.
Hey!
You know, there's a difference
between dancing and wrestling.
In dancing, the main idea is to keep
your partner's shoulders off the floor.
I was taught to dance collegiate.
Oh, that's different.
Let's cut in.
Hey, Marines.
May I have the pleasure?
Dancing class dismissed!
What I can't understand, Miss Connie,
is why you want a floater.
A girl can't handle a ship herself.
No, but she may be able
to get a man to do it for her.
Well, I went over the ship
like you asked me to, and...
There's lots to be done.
It'll cost quite a bit.
Well, I've saved up about 600 dollars.
And I'll add 400...
...which I got convoying the Navy around
the dance floor on my feet.
Even at that, I'm afraid 1000 dollars
would hardly be enough.
But I'll tell the company
what nice girls...
...my old friend Captain Martin's
daughters are...
...and we'll see what we can do.
Thank you, Captain Hickey.
If you don't mind my saying so,
I think he's a very lucky young man.
Actually, Captain Hickey, I consider
this whole thing a business proposition.
Don't you believe it, Captain Hickey.
Little Red Riding Hood rides again.
I hear the old man is entertaining
a party of big shots this afternoon.
- That's the reason for the dress whites.
- Yeah.
Hey, Bake.
I just got word I passed my exams.
No kidding, Bilge!
Gee, that's swell. Congratulations.
- Thanks.
- I knew you'd make it.
I know you don't care to be taken on
a tour of inspection, Courtney.
But I'd like to have you
glance over the ship...
- ...and look at our men.
- We'd love to, Captain Jones.
If it won't trouble you, Jones,
we'd enjoy it immensely.
Mr. Gilbert, my party
will look about the ship.
See that attention is sounded.
Have the band play a march.
Aye, aye, sir.
How about breaking up this sewing circle,
and getting into a jam session?
Are you ready?
- Your men are very smart, lieutenant.
- Thank you, sir.
- Mr. Gilbert.
- Yes, sir.
Have that jazz band
stop playing at once.
Aye, aye, sir.
Silence!
Baker, are you aware the captain is
showing some guests around the ship...
...and that attention has been sounded?
I'm sorry, sir. We didn't
hear the call. We were playing.
Captain, the orchestra was playing
and none of the men heard the call.
I'm satisfied, sir, they intend
no breach of discipline.
- Thank you, Mr. Gilbert.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Captain Jones. Would you think it a
breach of discipline if I asked you...
...to let them play for us?
I do so adore American music.
Not at all.
Bugler, sound carry on.
Division dismissed.
Baker, please carry on as you intended.
Thank you, sir.
Come on, boys, as we rehearsed it.
Captain Hickey, I'm so happy.
- The great day is dawning.
- Yes, they're just outside the gate.
- They'll drop anchor tonight.
- That's not what I mean.
Nolan's back from New York.
He's giving me an audition tomorrow.
- That's marvelous! But what about Bake?
- That's all I want.
To show him I can get that job
without his magnificent management.
- And then what?
- And then...
...I'll be satisfied.
So the Connie Martin is about
to have a new master, huh?
- Well, good luck, dear.
- Thank you.
Oh, gosh, it's nearly 7:00.
I've got to be going.
I hope this is the last night
I have to take a substituting job.
What time will you be back, dear?
We won't be through until about 1 or 2.
Don't worry. I'll make
a lot of noise with the key.
- Good night.
- Night, darling.
- Say, what are you gonna do with Mike?
- A little peace offering for Sherry.
Every time she looks at him,
she'll think of me.
There is a resemblance.
I wrote and explained what happened...
...but I never had an answer
to any of my letters.
Bilge, you don't think by any chance
she could be sore at me, do you?
I'd advise you to phone first
and find out.
Maybe you'd better phone for me.
You're so masterful with women.
You'll swab your own decks tonight.
I got a heavy date
that I made last october.
Hello.
- Hello, Bake.
- Is Sherry there?
Oh, she's working. Good.
Then she's not sore at me.
Oh, she is?
Well, I'll be right up then.
Well, I wouldn't, at least until
I've spoken to her. Where are you?
Who, me? I'm...
I'm dining with a friend of mine.
Yes, well, you can tell her she can
reach me at this number.
It's Franklin-4321.
All right, I'll tell her.
She may be a little late. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Mike, don't ever fall in love.
Connie.
Oh, hello.
I must have fallen asleep.
Can't I get you a cup of coffee?
No, thanks. You have one.
You see, I never did write him.
I wanted to keep the boat as a surprise.
So I really can't blame him.
It's my fault.
I think we better get to bed.
Don't forget I've got to sing
at Iris' tomorrow night.
- We can use that 50 dollars.
- Yes.
Oh, I nearly forgot. Bake called.
He left a number where you can reach him.
He's waiting to hear from you.
Let him wait.
Good morning, Nolan Enterprises.
Just a moment, I'll connect you with him.
- Good morning. I want to see Mr. Nolan.
- Mr. Nolan is in New York.
Good. I'll wait.
- Thank you, that's very nice.
- Thank you, Mr. Nolan.
We'll be ready to hear you sing
as soon as you've rested.
- Well, how is she?
- She's a great little dancer.
If she can sing too,
she's the best bet we've had.
Better get a contract ready. Nolan'll
be yelling for one if she delivers.
Okay.
Hi, Sullivan.
Hello, Baker. What's the idea
of the outfit? Is it a new act?
- Yeah, an act of Congress.
- So you joined the Navy.
So long as you don't want a job,
I'm glad to see you.
I want a job for somebody else.
She's just what Nolan's
been looking for.
You're too late.
He's got somebody in there
he's interested in.
Yeah? Who is she?
I don't know.
Just some girl who came in.
- May I have a drink of water, please?
- Why, certainly.
Yes, Mr. Nolan, right away.
Take a glass of water to the young lady.
She's gonna sing now.
- You better take that contract in.
- All right.
- Glad you dropped around.
- Thanks.
There's nothing like
water for the voice.
No, there isn't.
- That's what I always say.
- Yeah.
Well, so long, Sullivan.
I'll be seeing you.
So long.
Thank you.
All right, Miss Martin.
Yes, sir.
- Pretty dull party, isn't it?
- Why, yes, it's dreadful.
How about sneaking away
to find some excitement?
I'd love to, but I can't.
You see, I'm the hostess.
Really? I'm so sorry.
I didn't mean to deride your party.
It's all right, brother.
That's what parties are for.
- Hello, Sherry.
- oh, hello, Iris.
Connie says she's singing in your place
tonight, that you're not well.
- What's wrong?
- Well, I don't know.
I've been feeling
a little peculiar all afternoon.
That's too bad.
Why don't you try a little
bicarbonate of soda. That might help.
- Hello, hello, hello.
- You like?
This reminds me of the Paradise.
- I wonder where you buy the tickets.
- Remember where you are, son.
Poor kid, she had to go to Reno.
I'll see you later.
Don't worry,
I'll take care of everything.
- What are you doing here?
- I came with my pal.
You're not gonna hold it against me
for the rest of my life, are you?
I waited all last night
for you to return my call.
- I wanted to explain about Jim Nolan.
- Don't bother.
I was there this afternoon
and I fixed it all up for you.
- At Jim Nolan's?
- Yes, and it wasn't easy.
There was a girl
he was about to sign up.
As she was getting ready to sing,
she asked for a drink of water.
What do you think I did?
- What?
- I put bicarbonate of soda in it.
- You what?
- Yeah, bicarbonate of soda.
Can you imagine
the expression on her face?
Bake Baker, I'll get even with you
if it's the last thing I do.
I must have said something.
Bilge.
- Connie Martin.
- Why, yes, of course.
Well, well, how are you?
You're back. it seems
a long time, doesn't it?
Yes, when you come
to think of it, it does.
I was sort of expecting you last night.
And when you didn't show up, well,
I thought perhaps you'd forgotten me.
Forgotten you?
No, I had to stay on board last night.
I realize that. it was silly of me.
Of course,
somebody has to stay on board.
Oh, Bilge, I was so excited,
I didn't notice you passed your exam.
- I'm so glad.
- Yeah, I am too.
I've so many things to tell you,
I don't know where to start.
That's swell. I'll be glad
to hear them some time.
- Well, I'll see you later.
- But, Bilge...
- What?
- Yes, sir.
- Hey, can you imagine that?
- What?
I'm trying to drown my sorrows.
I down a quart of the stuff...
...and the guy tells
me it's grape juice.
Let's get out of here.
What's the rush? Maybe the grape juice
will make me feel happy anyway.
- Remember that teacher?
- Yeah.
She's here, and she was
expecting me last night.
- Did you forget?
- No, I lied to her.
- I told her I had to stay on board.
- Why?
Oh, I don't want to wake up
some morning and find myself married.
Acted as cold as I could. A dame like that
always makes me feel like a heel.
She brings out your finer instincts.
Come on.
- Where have you been, Bilgy?
- oh, I...
I want you to meet
my shipmate, Bake Baker.
This is a friend of mine, Mrs. Manning.
How do you do, Mrs. Manning?
How do you do?
I'm always happy to meet
a friend of Bilgy's.
Yes.
Sometime when I'm having a party
I'll invite you to come.
May I have the next dance? Thank you.
I've been waiting for you, Bilgy.
Why aren't you wearing your uniform?
It's a custom of the Navy.
Officers seldom wear their uniforms
ashore unless we're on duty.
Then how can one tell the difference
between an officer and a civilian?
We have our academy ring.
Oh, isn't that lovely.
Mind if I borrow this for a moment?
- I'd like to show it to a friend.
- Certainly.
Thank you so much.
I'll bring it right back.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
What is it?
You men are all alike.
Oh, Sherry, honestly,
I didn't know it was you.
That's not what I'm talking about.
Then tell me what's the matter.
No.
If I only had someone to protect me.
What is it? What is it?
I've never been so insulted
in all of my life.
Who did it? What did he say?
Oh, I couldn't repeat it.
Who was it? Point him out to me.
That man over there near the pond.
I don't like his face.
Listen, landlubber, I know your type.
You can't get away with that.
He's lucky I slipped.
- Let go of me.
- Take it easy, buddy.
Let go of me.
I'm awfully sorry
this had to happen, lieutenant.
Thanks so much for the use of your ring.
Return to your ship at once.
Aye, aye, sir.
What's the matter, Bake? You look sick.
Can I get you some bicarbonate of soda?
Sorry you're leaving
so early, Miss Martin.
I have to get up early. I'm looking
for my sister. Have you seen her?
- She was on the terrace a moment ago.
- Thank you.
What's the matter with
you tonight, Bilgy?
Nothing. Why?
- You're acting so funny.
- Am I?
Why, I don't mean to be.
That's more like you were last night.
This is tonight, baby.
And remember the date for your diary.
Now, remember what I told you.
Well, look who's here.
Thank you very much.
Where did you come from?
That's all right, son. You did your best.
I know. She treats me that way too.
I don't often try to apologize
because I seldom make any mistakes.
I thought we were
all even after last night.
Gosh, Sherry, I didn't know you took
this whole thing so seriously.
- Don't flatter yourself.
- It's Connie. She's going back home.
Why, what's happened?
Like a sap, she fell
in love with a sailor.
Well, look at you.
I don't consider you a sap.
Save that for the high-class
patter and genteel dance act.
Connie won't listen.
If she goes back to Bellport...
...she'll just eat her heart out.
Tell me who it is, and I'll bring him back
if I have to drag him to her.
She wouldn't want him that way.
Who is he?
Well, with the usual
lack of imagination a sailor has...
...he told her his name was Smith.
The call him Bilge.
Bilge Smith? He's my shipmate.
I might have guessed it.
No, seriously, Bilge is a swell guy.
I'll talk to him.
Bake, you don't understand.
Connie wouldn't want him
if things had to be explained.
He's stuck on that Iris Manning.
Say, what's she like?
Anything in a uniform.
There, don't you worry about it.
I guess maybe I can
take care of this matter.
Captain Hickey, did you guarantee
this whole thing personally?
No. Not exactly.
I did tell them I sailed
under your father.
And if the amount isn't met, you're
in danger of losing your job, aren't you?
Well, I'm kind of sick
of being a landlubber anyway.
Don't you worry about it, child.
Goodbye, Miss Connie.
Ahoy, Captain Hickey.
Ahoy, Miss Sherry.
- Well.
- I want you to meet...
...the United States Navy, Bake Baker.
- How do you do, Mr. Baker?
- Captain Hickey.
So this is the young man
you've been moping about, eh?
- Well, fair weather.
- Thank you, sir.
Well, I don't suppose you can
make it any worse than it is.
You see what you can do with her.
- Hello, Bake.
- Hello, Connie.
Sherry tells me you're leaving.
Well, that's probably
the wisest thing to do. Run away.
All this stuff about fighting for your man
makes things so complicated.
If all girls would just give up
and run back to Bellport...
...then we'd see the end of family life.
Little Junior would remain just an idea...
...and every man would burn
his own toast. I thank you.
Well, I'm not leaving.
Staying right here.
There, you see? I told you I'd fix it.
Why, Connie, that's swell.
What happened?
Well, I've been talking to Captain Hickey.
He's about to lose his job
for what he's done for me.
I've got to have 700 dollars
by Saturday.
Seven hundred dollars? We earn that
in a week, but they don't pay it to us.
There, Mr. Baker, is something
for you to manage.
What do you say?
I don't know, Baker. if Nolan
ever found out, he'd fire me.
All I want is a loan of some scenery
and costumes for the one night.
Now, how will he ever know?
Well, let's see.
We had a show called Mum's the Word
that folded in four days.
Those costumes were pretty cute,
but Nolan never liked them.
You can have those.
Thanks.
And if you ever need a battleship,
you can have mine.
- So long, boy.
- So long.
- Hi, Bake.
- Hello, Bake.
You know, rehearsal
was called for four bells.
Say, Bake.
Is there going to be some dames
in this show with us?
If it's the fairer sex you're
referring to, the answer is yes.
- Hello, Sherry.
- Hi.
Lookie there.
How about that, huh?
- These kids offered to help out.
- oh, gee, that's swell of you.
I wish that tall blond angel
would adopt me.
You ain't fooling, either.
Hello.
How was heaven when you left?
Tell me, little boy, did you get a whistle
or a baseball bat with that suit?
Bomber and his blonds.
Thanks, fellows. I can see
you guys don't appreciate high art.
What's the matter, Sherry?
It's Connie. She says she's going back
to Bellport after the show, anyway.
I wish there was something
we could do for her.
That Manning woman.
Maybe something can be done.
Let's not worry about it now.
We ought to run through the new number.
We haven't been through
the dance though.
Let's take a crack at it anyway.
There isn't much time.
Come on, fellows, let's
have it, will you?
A flat, fellows.
That's it.
I'm moving my gear
up to the chief's quarters.
Mind getting that riveting machine out
of the way so that I can get to my locker?
Don't bother me, son.
The show must go on.
Why?
Why? I don't know why,
but that's what they always say.
I hear you're putting on a show
with the Martin girls.
Yeah.
What are you doing tonight, Bilge?
I've got a date
with Mrs. Manning at 10:00.
Well, I'll be seeing you.
"Was I long, darling?"
Was I long, darling?
"And every hour away from you
seems like a day."
- Mr. Bake Baker.
- Yes.
Mr. Baker, I'm so
happy to see you again.
Oh, thank you.
It's so thoughtful of you
to ask me to join your show.
- I see you have the part I sent.
- Yes...
...it's short order to learn by tomorrow
night. I spent the afternoon studying it.
- I think I know it quite well.
- That's fine.
I just thought I'd drop in
to run through it with you...
- ...since we haven't much time.
- Mr. Smith isn't here yet.
Oh, he'll be here.
Shall we start?
Well, now, I thought we'd make this
a sort of a dress rehearsal.
Oh, dress rehearsal?
I'm supposed to wear a negligee.
Yes, it's very important to the scene.
This is going to be a
lot of fun, isn't it?
You'll be surprised.
I'll rush and slip one on.
It'll be more effective
that way, won't it?
Oh, definitely, yes.
Yes.
Mrs. Manning is waiting
on the porch, sir.
Thank you, Benson.
I know, it's Bilgy.
What are you doing here?
Who, me?
I'm here at Mrs. Manning's
special invitation.
Have a cigar.
I'll call for a drink for you.
Hey, Max!
What's this all about?
Oh, my being here?
Iris and I have developed
a very close friendship...
...ever since the night of her party.
Listen, how far has this thing gone?
Well, you know, Bilge, you and I
are both men of the world.
Don't make me laugh.
You wouldn't like to make
a little bet or anything, would you?
Any amount you say.
Ten bucks?
All right with me.
You wait out there,
and keep your eyes open.
Okay.
Was I long, darling?
Every minute seemed like an hour, babe.
And every hour away from you
seems like a day.
You're not expecting anyone, are you?
Well, I was.
But when I heard you could come
I told my servants...
...I wasn't home to anyone
but you, Bakey.
And to think we've only
known each other these few days.
Of course, there have been
other men in my life...
...but they all seem like such petty,
unimportant people since I met you.
Yes, I understand.
Tell me, have there ever been
any other women in your life?
- You're the first.
- oh, my darling. You make me so happy.
There, there.
Sorry if I'm interrupting anything.
And you're supposed to be my pal.
How dare you enter like this.
What right have you to come prying,
forcing yourself into my private life?
- But I...
- Understand this.
I was only playing with you.
And you, poor sap, fell for it.
Will you leave,
or do I ring for the butler?
Don't trouble yourself.
Well, how was I?
You were swell. Nobody could've
done the part as well as you.
I was confused at the end. Bilgy didn't
say his lines the way they were written.
No, but he got the general sense of it.
Isn't Bake here yet?
The boys say he didn't leave
in their boat with them.
No one knows what's happened to him.
I might have known. A little thing
like this show's just slipped his mind.
I bet he's telling the admiral
how to run the fleet.
If he doesn't come,
we'll just have to return the money.
Without Bake, we'll have no show.
And without a show, we'll have no Bake.
Why did they let the rest of the men go
and keep me?
I've gotta get to that show.
All I know is that orders are
your liberty has been cancelled.
I'll bet you did this to get even
with me for last night.
Well, if you think I did it,
go ask your executive officer.
Okay, admiral, I'll do that.
Seaman Baker to speak
with the executive officer.
Just a minute.
Seaman Baker requests to see you, sir.
Permission granted.
Here's Baker now.
- Executive officer will see you.
- Thank you.
Yes, Baker?
I beg your pardon, sir.
I've changed my mind.
Just a moment.
We've been talking about you.
Lieutenant Williams came aboard
to discuss you with me.
I'm sincerely sorry
about the other evening, sir.
I didn't know you were an officer.
I realize that, Baker.
Lt. Williams has been very generous
about the whole thing.
He's just been interceding for you.
Thank you, sir.
May I go ashore now, sir?
Your name is on the report.
The captain will probably scratch it
tomorrow at mast.
But until then, you must remain aboard.
- But, sir, I...
- That'll be all, Baker.
Aye, aye, sir.
Well, wise guy,
did you get your liberty pass?
Where are you going without liberty?
- Where do you think?
- Wait.
- You crazy?
- I'm not crazy. I'm going.
You know the orders.
I don't care what
the orders are. I'm going.
Cut it out, will you?
Gee, kid, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
I forgot myself.
Come on, Bake, hit me.
Hey, water taxi. Stand by.
Bake!
What is it, quartermaster?
It's a man jumping ship, sir.
- Do you know who it is?
- Yes, sir.
It's Seaman Baker.
Smith.
Get a detail of men and arrest
Seaman Baker immediately.
Aye, aye, sir.
You've gotta be ready by the third chorus.
Get your clothes on. Hurry, kids.
- Is he here yet?
- No.
Here I am.
- Hello, Sullivan.
- Hello, Mr. Nolan.
Glad to see you taking
so much interest in scouting talent.
Yes, Mr. Nolan.
If I'd known you were coming...
- ...I'd have changed my plans.
- oh, that's all right. Glad to see you.
Let's sit together.
Baker sent a note telling me he had a
Monte Carlo idea when the fleet was there.
I'm anxious to see it.
Might be able to use it.
- He's a smart lad.
- In more ways than one.
Sullivan...
...look at that costume.
That's the kind we should've
used in Mum's the Word.
Yes, sir.
- Shore patrol coming aboard on duty.
- Aye, aye, sir.
You men patrol the docks and
see that he doesn't get off the ship.
Wonder what this is all about.
Hello, Connie.
It's you. What are you doing here?
I've come to arrest Bake.
Arrest Bake? Why?
He jumped ship.
My orders are to bring him back.
Well, couldn't you wait
until after the show?
If I don't bring him back right away,
it'll cost me my stripes.
Well, I guess you'd better
make your arrest then.
He's in there.
Thanks.
Connie, I've been wanting
to say this to you, but I...
I don't know how.
Can't we start again,
like at the beginning?
I'm afraid you missed the beginning.
This is the end of the show.
You're under arrest, Bake.
I guess I didn't hit you hard enough.
Come on, we gotta get back to the ship.
You win.
You may as well know, that thing with
Iris Manning last night was a gag.
What?
While you were running around
with a bottle of peroxide...
...you were passing up a girl
you were nuts about.
That's my business.
Tried to make up.
She wouldn't look at me.
I don't blame her.
Do you know why
this show's being given?
To help Connie pay off this ship.
Is this the Connie Martin?
It ain't the Joe Doakes.
She didn't tell me she salvaged it.
She salvaged it for you, you sap.
She knew I was going to arrest you,
and she told me where you were.
That's the kind of a girl she is.
You go on with this show.
What about the patrol?
I'll stall them off
until you get through.
Oh, no, just because I'm in a jam,
there's no need for you to get in one.
Those are orders. Do as I tell you.
Maybe they won't be putting us
in the same cell together anyway.
Okay, chief.
And we'll sail to China and India,
and all those spiggoty places.
With your husband at the helm.
Hey, Bake.
Here's a note for you and Miss Sherry.
It's from Nolan. I told you I'd fix it.
Oh, he asked me to get an answer.
Tell Mr. Nolan we'll be happy
to consider his proposition...
...as soon as Mr. Baker
gets out of the brig...
...which is one
thing he can't fix.
- Okay.
- Wait a minute. one condition.
That is that Miss Martin
asks me to marry her.
Well, will you?
You'll have to ask Father.
Get your uniform on.
I can't stall the patrol any longer.