Some folks say "If you want to really see
the country, take a bus or hop a train. Ride a bike."
Me? I'm an old-fashioned kind of guy, stick
to what I know. Snowflakes.
I know it's not for everyone. But so long
as you pack light.
I mean, and wear at least 3 layers of undies,
it's a lovely way to spend a winter.
If my calculations are right we're about two
seconds from landing in Beansborough.
Nice little town.
Plenty of parking space and lots of cocoa.
Ah uh. There's nothing like the first snow
of the season.
And believe you me, nobody loves it any more
than the folks at Beansborough.
They've got this annual carnival, you see,
and I've been coming to it since I was knee
high to a snow cone.
So when I heard it might not happen this year
well I... ohhh...
I'll catch up with you later, alright?
There's seven inches of that fluffy stuff
on the ground already and you know what that means.
No school! Woo! Alright! C'mon let's go! Woo!
I love when the clouds burst open like one
giant pillow fight.
You stick out your tongue to taste 'em, the
snowflakes so soft and white.
I can't wait to make some angels or construct
an icy fort.
You need something to hide in especially if
you're wide and short.
We love the snow! Oh no not snow! We love
the snow! Who needs the snow?
Better than rain. That causes such pain. The
rain you can throw!
When the pipes begin to freeze and everybody
greets you with a sneeze.
What the heating bills will cost! The time
it takes us to defrost!
Oh, I could live without snow!
Holly, why aren't you playing outside?
Wasn't invited.
Neither was I.
But it's excellent packing. Let's go outside
and make a fertility goddess.
Maybe later. Right now we've got to rehearse
for the Winter Carnival.
Not again.
Charles, if I'm going to perform for the whole
town every trick's gotta be perfect.
What's that for? Put it on and get in the
box.
Hurry. I want to saw you in half.
Charles, do you want to help or not?
Of course I do. But I'm a scholar, not a meatloaf.
Charles, please. I just want to warn you,
I am very ticklish. You won't feel a thing.
That's why it's called magic.
There's no such thing as magic. Everything
has an explanation.
The proper term is science.
Now don't wiggle. Just close your eyes and
relax.
Relax?!
It's just your basic everyday cut off your
head in 3 strokes hand saw.
Now, you ready?
Can we at least crack a window? I'm roasting
in here.
Woah!
My hat!
Woaaah! Does this thing have brakes?
I'll be right back Charles. I've gotta get
my hat. Holllly!
Oh I'm sorry. I... I...Miss Carbuncle!
Is this how you spend your day off young lady?
Organizing a game of tackle the teacher?
No. You see, I...I was practicing...
Why don't you save your story for tomorrow's
composition?
Right now Miss Carbuncle has a sidewalk to
plow.
Before you know it this darn snow turns into
slush
and where's there's slush there's ice, and
where there's ice there's broken hips,
and where there's broken hips there's substitute
teachers!
Miss Carbuncle. If you should see my hat...
Not that I don't like the snow.
Just prefer it in it's proper place like on
mountain tops and poetry and songs by Bing Crosby.
Goodbye Miss Carbuncle!
It's no winter wonderland when your skidding
into a telephone pole!
(Narrator humming)
Huh?
My hat!
Oh no you don't!
You wanna take something? Take the tie!
Unless you think I need it.
How do you well dress for this Winter Carnival anyway?
I mean...I don't want to under dress.
But if I could get away with a tank top or
something more "caz".
Who are you?
The name's Frosty. And yours?
Uh, I'm Holly. Holly DeCarlo.
Nooo. Not the Holly DeCarlo?! The world-famous
magician!
Yeesh. Imagine that.
First person I meet and it's Holly DeCarlo.
You must be thinking of somebody else. I'm
not famous.
And not a very good magician.
That's not what your friends say.
I don't have any friends...except for Charles.
One friend is a lot different than no friends
kid. One friend is plenty.
But we always fight. Charles only talks about
science.
He doesn't believe there's anything in the
world that can't be explained.
Huh? Like say, uh, a snowman doing a cartwheel?
Or singing Puccini? Or maybe dancing a mean
mambo?
Holly? Well, there you are!
You locked your best friend in a box and just
ran off.
Now how are you gonna feel when poor Charles
grows up and has to join a support group.
I'm sorry Mom. I ran out cuz...
Here! Take one of these cans and start spraying.
Uhh...Mom. This is Frosty.
Well, I'm sure he is.
OK. Now make sure you aim right at the snow
and hold the can at least 12 inches away.
What is this stuff?
Well, it's the greatest invention since microwave
pancakes.
It's called Summer Wheeze. Watch this!
And you thought you were the only magician
in the family, didn't ya? Huh? Didn't ya?
Lille, how did you get that sidewalk of yours
so clean?
You won't believe this Merle, but I never
had to lift a shovel.
You're kidding. Watch this.
Yeowwwww!
Incredible. So, uh, what do ya say we find
a safer place to talk. Say Siberia?
Removing snow's a breeze with one blast of
Summer Wheeze.
Hmm. Catchy isn't it? I want those words painted
on buses, billboards, large dogs!
I suggest we hang a banner at Saturday's Winter
Carnival.
By Saturday there should be a can of Summer
Wheeze on every shelf.
I'll go to that carnival a guest but I'm going
to leave it a king!
A king, sir? You heard me.
I'm about to give this town the greatest gift
ever...a winter with no shoveling!
No slush! No frostbite! Clean streets and
dry sidewalks.
By this weekend snow tires will be ancient
history. And in return they'll make me their king.
That makes you prince, tuna breath.
But sir, what about the environment? This
product may cause...
Bones! Hit the button!
Ahhh!
Any other objections? Good. We'll let the
fun begin!
Oh no! Don't get upset Frosty.
Upset?!
Upset is waking up and finding out somebody
forgot to give you a belly button.
Upset is finding out somebody stole your nose
to play foosball.
This ain't upset kid! This is panic! I'm two
squirts from being history!
Holly didn't sleep a wink that night. Neither
did Frosty.
Beansborough had suddenly become a scary place.
At least to a happy-go-lucky guy like Frosty
who thought wearing no socks in January was
living dangerously.
Holly knew she had to do something fast if
she wanted to protect Frosty.
Yes!
You gotta be kidding me!
Shhh! Hurry!
Holly! You're gonna miss your bus!
Holly!
I'm going Mom.
Holly's plan seemed to flow without a hitch
until...
Holly! What is that sticking out of your desk?
It's just my lunch...turkey.
Don't you think you should cook it first?
(children laugh)
That's enough! Young lady. A school desk is
no place for poultry.
Unless you choose to present it as a science
project.
I do.
Well then you'll have to wait until Charles
is finished.
Continue Charles.
Thank you Miss Carbuncle. Now where was I?
Oh yes. (clears throat) Snow plays an important
role in our environment.
It is a major source of fresh water for the
earth and without it life on this planet would
soon disappear.
Isn't that right Miss Carbuncle?
Miss Carbuncle?
(Miss Carbuncle snoring)
Any questions?
Yeah. I don't think snow's so important. My
dad says it causes heart attacks.
He must have snow confused with chili dogs.
Any other questions?
I think it should only snow one day a year
for the Winter Carnival.
After that I wish it would melt so we could
have ten months of summer vacation.
(children cheering)
An attractive but dangerous theory.
Ten months of summer and a beach party in
January.
A picnic!
A volleyball tournament!
That's right. No more snow.
Do you realize what you're saying?
Yeah. We want summer.
No more snow. No more snow! No more snow!
No more snow!
Hey! Simmer down now! Where do you think you
are? MTV?
Charles, have you finished?
Yes, Miss Carbuncle.
Fabulous.
Let's go Holly! Bring on the bird!
Holly?
Frosty! What are you doing out here? This
is dangerous.
I couldn't sit in there anymore Holly.
I started getting a cramp then I got this
freezer burn.
You shouldn't be out here. If one of those
trucks comes by...
Nah. I think I've finally found a place where
the snow is here to stay...an ice castle!
Won't be there for long.
What are you talking about?
I just came from my school.
All the kids there were screaming "No more
snow! No more snow!" It was terrible.
What did you say?
Nothing.
I was too scared.
Whenever I try to talk my mouth gets all dry
and my hands get all clammy.
I let you down, didn't I?
You know kid, maybe it's time you tried a
different approach.
Sometimes when the words just fail you. You're
scared but you know they're wrong.
I found that I get much further when I turn
my thoughts to song.
You know why you love this season. The joy
that the snow can bring.
So why should you stop to reason? Just open
your heart and sing.
Let there be snow! Let there be snow!
Need I remind you, the autumn's behind you,
let the wind blow!
This is the time of year to make figure-8's
across the lake.
Such a magical sight when the world's dressed
all in white.
Wooah, let there be snow!
The days may grow short and grayer.
The cold may nip at your nose.
But once there's a six-inch layer, those
soft flakes beneath your toes,
you can't help but want to taste it or jump
in a snowy pile.
Why not build a fort or igloo or find a window
to print your smile?
Woah, let there be snow! Let there be snow!
Close down the schools and let's act like
fools, there's parties to throw!
I thought once you made your fortune, you
could sit back and count your loot.
But now that I've conquered Beansborough I'm
ready to trade this suit.
I want a crown that fits me. I want a cape
that flows. Six yards of fur and velvet.
Right down to my crooked toes. There's no
more snow! There's no more snow!
Look how they love me! The clouds up above
me couldn't compete with my dough!
Let mother nature try to win, I'll give her
blizzards quite a spin.
Just try and stop me. No one can stop me.
Let me kingship begin!
Let there be snow! Let there be snow!
This kind of weather brings people together
so friendships can grow!
Why should we sit around and wait for summer
days to celebrate?
Such a magical sight when the world's dressed
in white.
Oohh let there be snow!
Hey Charles. This is Frosty.
Nice to meet ya.
I take it he doesn't dance.
Doesn't blink much either.
What are you looking for?
Batteries.
Heh heh heh. Lighten up kid. Some things just
can't be explained...like rhythm.
C'mon. Don't make me dance alone.
Hold it! Stop the car! Stop the car! And stop
the music!
That snowman is flaking on one of my sidewalks.
Bones!
Who is that frostbitten clown? Must have come
from the park.
There's probably dozens of those snow critters
in there just waiting to soil my sidewalks.
Don't just sit there you overgrown bag of
lint. Get them!
Phew. I think we lost them. Well? Did you
spray him? Tell me the truth bones.
There's a tuna casserole in it for you.
They're leaving. I think we're safe.
Not all of us.
Frosty, what happened?
Looks like the work of Summer Wheeze.
Oh no! There's hardly any snow left on the
ground. How are we going to help Frosty?
You better think fast guys or I'm going back
to the North Pole in a bowl.
Sometimes it pays to have a man of science
on your side.
Most of us panic in a time of crisis.
Me? I reach for a cup of cocoa. Helps me focus.
But a kid like Charles, well he looks at a
problem as something to solve.
Just when Holly was about to give up Charles
remembered something.
What's that? Snow. I was saving it in the
freezer for an experiment.
But I figured Frosty needs it more than me.
Gee. This place is starting to look drier
than Miss Carbuncle's knees.
Mr. Twitchell's trucks drove through while
you were gone.
C'mon, we better hurry. Holly and Charles
went right to work.
They padded. They puffed. They packed. They
patched.
And by the time they were finished they had
no feeling in their fingers.
But there was plenty happening in their hearts.
But their smiles didn't last when they checked
out of that castle they realized
there was no place for Frosty in a snowless town.
This is terrible. Don't worry Holly. Frosty
will last. At least until tomorrow.
What's tomorrow? The Winter Carnival.
Without snow?
Gee kid. If there was ever a time we needed
magic, this is it.
That's it! C'mon.
Well...will that crown fit me or not?
I could always have the crown stretched or
have my head shrunk.
What is it? A snowfall. Don't fret pussycat.
That's exactly what we need for that carnival.
We are gonna make an entrance. Heh heh heh.
Welcome one and all to Beansborough's annual
Winter Carnival. Heh, Um...
Before the festivities begin I would just
like to say...
Greetings neighbors.
Who says you need snow to have a carnival,
eh? Heh heh.
It's hard to believe that we suffered for
so many years.
The slush.... the frozen pipes... the icy
streets...
It's now or never, Holly.
Summer Wheeze is not the kind of magic we
look forward to every winter Mr. Twitchell.
Call security!
Your product is dangerous. What's convenient
for today isn't always safe for tomorrow.
We need snow just as much as we need rain
or sunshine or clean air.
Little girl, I think your hat's too tight.
Now as I was saying...
I'm not finished, Mr. Twitchell.
And unless you've got a spray that makes little
girls disappear you're gonna have to listen.
You've made your point small fry.
And I can assure you there is nobody here
that finds anything magical about snow.
Don't be so sure Mr. Twitchell.
The best kind of magic that only winter brings
comes in a big snowy bundle that dances and sings.
(Audience gasps)
May I?
Now, can somebody give me a B-flat?
Let there be snow! Let there be snow!
This kind of weather brings people together
so friendships can grow.
Why should we sit around and wait for summer
days to celebrate?
Such a magical sight when the world's dressed
in white!
Woah, let there be snow!
The days may grow short and grayer.
The cold may nip at your nose.
But once there's a six inch layer of those
soft flakes beneath your toes,
you can't help but want to taste it or jump
in a snowy pile.
Why not build a fort or igloo or find a window
to print your smile?
Wooah, let there be snow!
Watch it fool!
Let there be snow! Let there be snow!
This kind of weather brings people together
so friendships can grow.
Well I don't think we even need to vote this
year neighbors.
There can only be one king in this crowd.
Why should we sit around and wait for summer
days to celebrate?
With such a magical sight -- when the world's
dressed in white.
Oohh let there be snow!
Mr. Twitchell.
What do you want?
I want you to know I was just helping a friend.
You got your snow back, Missy. So why don't
you leave me alone!
Any chance you'd want to take a toboggan ride
before you leave?
On the royal sled.
You only live once.
Frosty! Where are you going?
I think it's time to move on kid.
Visit another town. Make some new friends.
But you've got friends...here.
Well, at least one friend.
One friend is a lot different than no friends.
One friend is plenty.
You're right. Especially when it's you.
Don't leave Frosty. Don't worry kid. I'll
be back.
Give me some time to find me a new bowtie.
This time no polka-dots.
Maybe something in a nice blue, not too busy.
Or green.
I like green. Brings out my eyes.
C'mon Holly!
And so the folks at Beansborough got their
Winter Carnival after all.
A tradition was saved.
Summer Wheeze was permanently canned and Mr.
Twitchell decided to make sleds instead of trouble.
He should have known he was no match for mother
nature or a little girl like Holly.
Next stop. Winnipeg. Nice town. Plenty of
parking space and lots of cocoa.
Frosty the Snowman was a fairy tale they say.
He was made of snow but the children know
how he came to life one day.
There must have been some magic in that old
silk hat they found
for when they placed it on his head he began
to dance around.
Frosty the Snowman had to hurry on his way
but he waved goodbye saying don't you cry
I'll be back again someday.