Where to, Mr. Churchill?
Some large, bright, gay place
with hundreds of beautiful girls.
- Some large, bright, gay place.
- With hundreds of beautiful girls.
Yes, sirree.
Isn't that a coincidence,
on the right there?
- Thank you, Jeeves. Thank you, Jives.
- Mr. Churchill, hold it, please.
- Thank you.
- Here we go.
- Evening, Mr. Churchill.
Good evening, Marcus.
Why, Mr. Churchill,
you're quite a stranger.
Not to the people that know me.
Girls?
Good evening. Hello, fellows.
- Hi, hey.
- How are you?
- Why, Mr. Churchill.
- Thomas.
- We certainly have missed you.
- Well, thank you.
You couldn't have picked
a better night.
- Really? Why?
- Tommy Dorsey's opening.
- Hiya, Tom.
- Hello, Dan.
I've always been considered
Quite a delicate child
Watched over by a governess
And nurse
To say I've led a sheltered life
Is putting it mild
I promise you it couldn't be much worse
Mother always called me
Her hothouse rose
And all the dates I had
Were with hothouse beaus
But now that I am old enough
To cast a few votes
I'm going out and sow a few oats
So
Treat me rough, muss my hair
Don't you dare to handle me with care
I'm no innocent child, baby
Keep on treating me wild
Treat me rough
Pinch my cheek
Kiss and hug and squeeze me
Till I'm weak
I've been pampered enough, baby
Keep on treating me rough
Treat me rough, muss my hair
Don't you dare to handle me with care
- I'm no innocent child
- No innocent child
Keep on treating me wild
Treat me rough
Pinch my cheek
Kiss and hug and squeeze me
Till I'm weak
- I've been pampered enough
Baby, keep on treating me rough
Can't get enough
Treat me rough
No one can
Don't you dare to handle me with care
I'm no innocent child, baby
Keep on treating me wild
Treat me rough
Pinch my cheek
Kiss and hug and squeeze me
Till I'm weak
I've been pampered enough, baby
Keep on treating me rough
When I was born
They found a silver spoon in my mouth
I had a barber just to curl my hair
If winter came
The mater carried me to the south
The point is that I had the best of care
Women and headwaiters fawned on me
Life was just a bore till it dawned on me
That if I'd ever want to be a man
Amongst men
I'd have to be manhandled now and then
So treat me rough
Muss my hair
Don't you dare to handle me with care
I'm no innocent child, baby
Keep on treating me wild
Treat me rough, pinch my cheeks
Kiss and hug and squeeze me
Until I'm weak
I've been pampered enough, baby
Keep on treating me rough
Danny Churchill.
Silly, isn't it, Dad?
- Son.
- Yes, sir?
You're living in a world
of weekend whimsy...
...and growing up to be
a rich man's son.
Surely you don't believe what's
printed in the papers?
"Publisher's son is crowned king.
Danny Jr. "
"Publisher's son stops show. "
Why, it's incredible.
Dad, you know how reporters
like to exaggerate.
Any mention of Danny Jr. Winning
academic honors at Yale?
- No. Or even a spelling bee?
- No.
The next thing you know,
you'll be sponsoring a beauty contest.
- It isn't really that bad.
- Now look, Danny.
None of this stuff is actually bad.
But if it keeps on,
you'll get to be known as a character.
The first thing you know...
...why, you start living up
to the write-ups and that is bad.
And we're not going to let
that happen, are we?
You're right. I'm sorry, Dad.
I'll leave for New Haven today.
No, Danny, you're not going back
to New Haven.
No, you're going to Cody.
Cody? What's that?
Cody College of Mines and Agriculture.
It's out West.
It has fresh air.
And it is not coeducational.
Dad, you can't be serious.
Why, a guy would go daffy out there.
Well, there's a bare possibility
that it might make a man of you.
And another thing,
just so it won't be a shock to you.
There hasn't been a woman out there
since the Civil War.
Well, that doesn't make any...
"Codyville. Two thousand,
eight hundred and fifty feet. "
Hey.
Hey!
- Where's the hotel in this town?
- Ain't none.
Well, where do people live?
There ain't none.
Well, could you tell me
where Cody College is?
Down the road, about eight miles.
Well, are there any taxis in the town?
Oh, no, don't tell me. I know.
There ain't none.
- Well, good night.
- Good night.
"Cody College.
Eight miles. "
Hey.
Hey!
Having a little trouble?
Why don't you leave it out here
for the buzzards?
Well... Well, I'll be.
Hello.
- I said, hello.
- That's what I thought you said.
Well, what do people out West say
when somebody says hello to them?
Look, stranger,
why don't you just go away?
Oh, that isn't very nice.
I've been lying under that jumping jack
for a half an hour.
- I'm not in the mood for small talk.
- Oh, excuse me.
I just happened to be in
the neighborhood...
...and I thought I'd drop by
to tell you...
...that you're the best-looking
automobile mechanic I've ever seen.
Traveling salesman?
- What are you laughing at?
- Nothing. I'm just happy.
- You're sure it isn't the sun.
- No, no, it's something about my father.
He sent me out West to get away...
To get away from the girls.
And I find you right out here
in the middle of the desert.
I think it's very funny.
- You do?
- Yeah.
Would you go ahead and have
your own private little joke.
I've got things to do.
What are you doing down there?
Grinding coffee.
May I?
Won't talk, eh?
Well, it looks like Hattie here
isn't gonna be very sociable.
Well, I don't know
what I'm gonna do.
There's nothing left for you to do
but to sit here...
...and give me the story of your life.
If I'm not at school in 10 minutes
I'm gonna miss the mail train.
You mean Cody?
You don't mean to tell me
that you're a student there?
No, I carry the mail.
Government's making a big mistake.
They ought to put your picture
on the postage stamps.
Well, I can't waste any more time here.
Wait a minute, would you?
Let me try it once more, please?
- Well, that's it.
- Wait a minute. Where are you going?
Out West, when we're in trouble,
we walk.
It's the same in the East.
I'll go with you.
My name is Danny Churchill.
I'm from New York.
Free, white and lonesome.
- Danny... Did you say Churchill?
- Churchill Jr., yeah.
- The playboy?
- Well, I...
- What's so funny?
- Oh, goodness gracious.
I don't get it.
Oh, yes, indeed.
Fancy meeting you here?
- I don't get it.
- They tell me that you're...
That you're quite a hand with the ladies.
I hope I'm as good a hand here
with Hattie.
- As you think you are with the ladies?
- All right. All right.
Hey. Hey. How about me?
- Hi. Are you Danny Churchill?
- Yeah.
Well, I'm Henry Lathrop.
- Glad to know you.
- How are you?
I'm sorry about jumping over you.
We didn't see you.
Well, that's all right.
We'll show you where to register
and the dean's office...
...and the mess hall
and then to your room.
- Swell.
- Come on, let's go.
Hi.
This is Danny Churchill,
just got in from New York.
This is Bud Livermore,
you're roommate.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Hi.
Big day tomorrow.
See you in the morning, about 6:00.
Yeah.
Did...? Did he say 6:00?
- When do you sleep?
- We hit the hay pretty early.
- At about what time?
- All lights out at 9:30.
That's a quaint little hour.
Yeah, and the hay feels pretty good
about then.
- What do you sleep on around here?
- These.
- No mattress?
- Yeah, right here.
You unroll them. I'll show you how.
I can see we put them down ourselves
but who puts them up?
You put hooks on the side of the wall...
...and this room can become
a nice little closet.
You get used to it.
They keep you so busy,
most of the time you don't even notice it.
I'm curious.
What does a fellow do around here?
Well, you're up at 5:45.
Roll your cot, clean the room...
...and you're in the mess hall by 6:10.
On the days you don't wait on tables.
- Well, how about do you ever...?
- Then you're back in your room at 6:45.
- Until 7, your time's your own.
- Well, do you ever get...?
Then you go to classes until 10 minutes
of 1, dinner until 1:30.
Then you have another 15 minutes
to do anything.
Like playing 18 holes of golf.
Then in the afternoon,
you work in the laboratory...
...or in the mine shaft or with the
livestock, depending on your courses.
- Don't you get...?
- Until 5:45.
Then come back to your room
for supper.
After supper, you study till 9:30
and then you go to bed.
In a wheelchair, no doubt.
- So you see, it's a pretty full day.
- I'd say so.
Except Saturday, we have
the afternoon off from 3 till 6.
Oh, goody, goody.
And at night we see movies,
sometimes talkies.
Talkies?
Well, that sort of rounds out
the whole week, doesn't it?
Yeah. I'll go take a shower now
before I do anything else...
I forgot to tell you...
...the showers are out back,
there aren't too many of them.
You have to write your name
on a slip of paper...
...and put it in the box in the hall.
The monitor checks it
when you can use them.
The best day is Saturday.
Good morning.
Hey, come on.
Hey, you gotta get up.
- Up and at them.
- No, no, no.
- Come on.
- Look. I'll tell them. I'll tell them.
- Fine. When he gets here, I'll tell them.
- Come on. Come on. Up you get.
Yeah, 48 states in America and
I have to wake up in a bureau drawer.
- What was that?
- The gong. You get used to it.
- Yeah. Like hanging.
- Come on, will you get up there?
- Fine. I'm up.
- Come on.
I jump right out of bed, see?
Okay. Fine.
What, no Indians?
- Hi, you lads.
- Hello, Bud.
- How are you?
- How did you sleep?
Sleep? I hardly yawned.
Well, wait till you get your lungs full
of some of that good fresh air.
- Here you are. Climb into these.
- What are these?
We're going on an all-day ride.
Do it every two weeks.
- Well, where to?
- Nowhere in particular.
We ride up into the hills
and spend the night...
...and we come home in the morning.
Well, if it's all the same to you fellows,
I think I'll just sit this one out.
- No, you don't.
- Come on.
Come on, Dan. Come on, Dan.
Come on, fellows, let's go.
Hey, wait a minute.
Wait a minute, will you?
How do I look?
You look great, old man.
Yeah, well, if you bump into
Buffalo Bill, tell him not to worry.
That's a good one.
Hey, where'd everybody go?
Hey, who's riding that buck?
- Good morning.
- Hello, Rags.
- Ain't you coming along?
- As soon as I finish the mail.
Hurry. There's no point to these rides
unless you barbecue them steaks.
I'll be there.
What's holding everything up?
We're waiting for Park Avenue
to mount Whitey.
Oh, fine. I gotta see that.
I hope you fellows have a spirited
animal for me...
...because I'm a guy that likes a horse
with plenty of zoom.
- I think we can arrange that.
- Well, where is he?
There he is, Whitey.
Well, I'll see you later.
Why, you'll love Whitey.
He's as meek as a lamb.
Hey, what's that?
The new guy from New York.
He's riding Whitey.
Wait a minute.
You want me to climb up on that?
Why, sure.
All right, boys, let's go.
Whitey.
Hey, Whitey.
Whitey, please.
What have I done?
Hi there.
Can I give you a lift?
Anything you could give me
would be an improvement.
You're that young fellow
from New York, ain't you?
No. No.
I'm that old fellow from New York.
- Who are you?
- I'm Rags, New York City.
Checker Cab Company, Class of 1933.
Yeah, you haven't got
a checkered cab with you, have you?
No, but I got a buckboard.
I can take you up to the camp in that.
- What camp?
- With the boys.
Hey, where's Whitey?
Whitey?
Oh, Whitey hit the road.
He'll stop when
he gets back to the corral.
As far as I'm concerned, he can keep
going until he hits Connecticut.
- Well, you ready to ride?
- Yeah.
If I can sit on my stomach.
What else do they do around here
besides play cowboys and Indians?
The boys work pretty hard...
...especially since they threatened
to close the school.
- Yeah? Why?
- I don't know.
Something about the legislature
couldn't get enough unenrollments.
If it hadn't been for Armour
and his granddaughter Ginger...
Ginger? Say, is that the girl
that delivers the mail?
That's her. She's coming out
to cook supper for the boys.
Tell me about her, will you?
Ain't nothing much to tell
except that she's just wonderful.
- Everybody loves her.
- Are you sure it's just everybody?
Yeah. Especially Henry Lathrop.
Is he the fellow that goes around
acting like he owns the place?
That's him.
I knew there was something
about him I didn't like.
- Hi, Rags.
- Hey, you lost a tire.
Hey, Danny. Where's Whitey?
Who's that cowboy with you?
Did you enjoy the ride?
Yeah. I haven't had so much fun
since I was shot out of a cannon.
Some fellows like to tiptoe
Through the tulips
Some fellows go on
Singing in the rain
Some fellows keep on painting skies
With rainbows
Some fellows go on swinging
Down the lane
But
I'm biding my time
Because that's the kind of guy I'm
While other folks grow dizzy
I'll keep busy
Biding my time
Next year
Something's bound to happen
This year
I'll just keep on napping
I'm biding my time
Because that's the kind of guy I'm
There's no regretting
When I'm setting
Biding my time
I'm biding my time
Because that's the kind of guy I'm
Beginning on a Monday
Right through Sunday
Biding my time
- I'm biding my time
- I'm biding, biding
Cause that's the kind of guy I'm
That's I'm
Chasing away flies
How the day flies
Biding, biding my time
Yahoo
Stranger so long
I'll just go along
Biding
My time
This Western air certainly does
bring out harmony, doesn't it?
It brings out a lot of things.
Ginger.
- Yes, Henry.
- You'd better be getting back.
- It's exactly 8:14.
- Yeah.
You know, the astounding thing, that
in exactly 24 hours it'll be 8:14 again.
And just think, you'll be the first
to know.
Come on, Corky, let's go.
Good night, fellows.
Good night, Ginger.
See you tomorrow.
Come on, fellows, let's turn in.
Hey.
What's so funny?
The strange things you see
when you haven't got a gun.
Me. Me pay you for ride home.
Thank you very much.
The pleasure is all ours.
See you later, buddy. Home.
No, sir, it's not like that.
It's not the place.
The place is beautiful,
but it just isn't for me.
You mean, it's the kind of a school
you'd want to send your son to.
Yes, sir. That's it.
No, I'm sorry. I beg your pardon.
I didn't mean it quite like that.
That's all right, Danny, I understand.
It's kind of too bad, though.
Pardon me.
You know, your grandfather and I
were roommates here.
Hello. Yes.
It's the registrar.
He wants to know if you're gonna
start classes today.
Well...
Hello, Ed. No, he's going back.
Too much fresh air out here.
I don't want you to get
the wrong impression, sir.
I have nothing personal
against the school.
That's all right, son. I'd probably
be just as unhappy in the Stork Club.
Say, your dad's gonna be
kind of unhappy too, isn't he?
Take unhappy and multiply it by furious
and add a little belligerent...
...and I think you've just about got it.
Come in.
Gramp, there's a friend of yours outside.
The maybe-maybe girl from
never-never land, Ms. Polly Williams.
Hi, Grampo. Here I am C.o. D., F.o. B.,
and M.U.G.
Come on, honey, hang one on.
- There. That didn't hurt a bit, did it?
- Polly, I'm glad to see you.
I'm glad you said, "I'm glad to see you,"
because I'm glad you're glad to see me.
- Hi, neighbor.
- Excuse me, Danny.
- This is my grandchild. Ms. Ginger Gray.
- Yes, we've met before.
Yes. And this is my cousin
Ms. Polly Williams.
Mr. Daniel Churchill, Jr.
Hi, Church. How's your steeple?
Say, you know, junior, you're cute.
- Well, I...
- That's all right, junior.
I know just how you feel.
Here's some mail for you, Mr. Churchill.
Channel number five.
There's something loose in here.
Well, I think I'd better get going
so I don't miss my train.
Danny, Ginger's having a big birthday
party tonight. You better stay over.
I'd like to very much,
but I've already wired my father.
You're missing some mighty fine
singing.
Yes, sir.
Ginger's got plenty of snap.
I'm sure Mr. Churchill would find it
rather dull.
Would you like me to drive you
to the junction?
I don't...
It will be a pleasure.
I don't want you to miss that train.
- Thank you very much.
- Don't mention it.
It's very nice of you...
So long, junior.
See you in the pool room.
Just ask for Polly.
So long, Polly. Watch your crackers.
Nice day, isn't it?
Nice day yesterday.
What do you think the chances are
for tomorrow?
Say, you by any chance aren't related
to Harpo Marx, are you?
There's something I have to tell you.
And if I don't tell you,
I'm gonna hate myself.
I'll bet you'd be the only one.
You are the most precocious,
overconfident, spoiled young man...
...I've ever had the misfortune to meet.
- I think you're cute too.
- As an added attraction, you're a quitter.
Why, you've been eating ice cream
with a silver spoon...
...in a nice fat college for a long time
that when you get out here...
...with plain people, you run for cover.
Wait a minute. Now it's my turn.
Did anyone tell you
that you've got a face...
...like a two-week vacation with pay?
Did anyone ever tell you...
...you've got a nose cute enough
to write a song about?
Did anyone tell you when a girl like you
starts talking about a fellow like me...
...it means only one thing, that
you're falling madly in love with him?
Did anyone ever tell you
that a fellow in my state of mind...
...is apt to kiss a girl
in your state of mind?
- I dare you.
- You what?
- I double-dare you.
- Double?
- You did it.
- I did?
Why, it's funny.
I didn't even notice it.
Have some pity on an Easterner
Show a little sympathy
No one possibly could be sterner
Than you have been with me
Now, there's a job that I'm applying for
Let me put it to you thus
It's a partnership I'm dying for
Mr. And Mrs. Us
Now, before you file it on the shelf
Let me tell you of myself
Oh, I'm the chappie to make you happy
I'll tie your shoesies
And chase your bluesies
Oh, lady, would you?
Oh, lady, could you use me?
Now, I'd shake the mat out
And put the cat out
I'd clean the garret and feed the parrot
Oh, lady, would you?
Oh, tell me. Could you use me?
Oh, do you realize what a good man
You're getting in me
I'm no Elk or Mason or Woodman
Who gets home at 3
The girls who see me
Grow soft and dreamy
But I'm a gander who won't philander
Oh, could you use me?
Because I certainly could use you
There's a chap I know in Mexico
Who's as strong as he can be
Eating nails and drinking Texaco
He is the type for me
There is one in California
More romantic far than you
When he sings "Ha-cha-cha-chornia"
I often think he'll do
But as for you, sir
I'm afraid you will never make
The grade
For you're no cowboy
You're soft and how, boy
I feel no muscle that's fit for tussle
I must refuse you
I cannot use you, excuse me
No night life for you
The birds would bore you
The cows won't know you
A horse would throw you
You silly man, you
To ask me, can you use me?
Though at love you may be a wizard
I'm wanting to know
Could you warm me up in a blizzard
Say, 40 below
Your ties are freakish
Your knees are weakish
You're not a spender, you elbow-bender
Though you can use me
I most certainly can't use you
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Ginger
A happy birthday to you
A happy birthday, Miss Ginger
Happy birthday to you
oh, thank you.
- Make a wish.
- Come on, Ginger, make a wish.
All right.
- One.
- Two, three.
Come on. Come this way.
Here it is.
For you, Miss Ginger.
"To Ginger, from all her fellows. "
- And that includes me.
- Go on, pull it.
- What, this?
- Sure. See what's in it.
All right.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Go on. Play something, Ginger.
And it plays.
Dozens of boys would storm up
I had to lock my door
Somehow I wouldn't warm up
To one before
What was it that controlled me?
What kept my love-life lean?
My intuition told me
You'd come on the scene
If you'll listen to the rhythm
Of my heartbeat
You will get
Just what I mean
Embrace me
My sweet embraceable you
You irreplaceable you
Just one look at you
My heart grew tipsy in me
You and you alone
Bring out the gypsy in me
I love all the many charms
About you
Above all
I want my arms about you
Don't be a naughty papa
Come to baby
Come to baby, do
My sweet
Embraceable
- You
- Embrace me
My sweet embraceable you
Embrace me
You irreplaceable you
In your arms
I find love so delectable, dear
Doo-doo-doo
I'm afraid
It isn't quite respectable, dear
But hang it
Come on, let's glorify love
Ding-dang it
You'll shout encore if I love
Don't be a naughty baby
Come to papa, come to papa, do
My sweet embraceable
You
I love all the many charms
About you
Above all
I want my arms about you
Don't be a naughty baby
- Come to Tommy
- Come to Georgie
- Come to Harry
- Come to Johnny
- Come to Bobby
- Come to baby, do
My sweet embraceable
You
Henry, do you think
the night is this beautiful...
...just because it's my birthday?
Oh, I don't know. I'd say it was
more or less of a coincidence.
Oh, you would?
- Ginger.
- Yes, Henry?
- Ginger, I'm a man of few words and...
Well, after approaching the subject
from every standpoint very objectively...
...I think it would be to our mutual
advantage if we became engaged.
- Engaged?
- Yes.
And after a respectable period of time,
I think we should be married.
Henry, this is so sudden.
Well, you know I like to put my cards
on the table.
Yes, well, I think you could
have taken out the joker.
Well?
- Well, what?
- Well, I'm waiting for an answer.
- Well, that's pretty complicated.
- It's really quite simple.
You're young, attractive, intelligent
and I'm young and intelligent.
And all we need is a meeting
of the minds.
Meeting of the minds?
Look, Henry, I think you're
an awfully nice boy...
...and I'm very fond of you.
But you just don't ask a girl
to marry you...
...like going to the hardware store
to buy a coffee grinder.
You don't come up
to a girl and say:
"The humidity's high for this time
of year. Will you marry me?"
Well, I just didn't want to get romantic.
You just didn't want to get romantic.
What are you saving it for?
I thought we were above
that sort of thing.
Well, Henry, maybe you are.
I hope I'm not.
Very well, Ginger, I'm not discouraged.
Shall we go back?
No, you go ahead.
I'm going to stay out here
and just look at everything.
As you wish.
What are you doing here?
I just got to thinking
about what you said in the car...
...and I got to thinking
that you were right.
Besides, I heard you were getting
married...
...so I came back to offer my services.
- In what capacity?
- Best man.
Well, I'm not getting married.
I didn't think so.
I just said, I didn't think so.
Oh, you didn't think so.
Have you been listening all the time?
No, really, I was trapped there.
He certainly does pack a terrific wallop.
- Who?
- Mr. Put-Your-Cards-on-the-Table.
He's a very nice fellow.
Yes, he's a very nice fellow.
Just the guy to get
Juliet off the balcony.
Well, there are other things
besides making love.
Wait a minute. Don't start knocking that.
Are you going to be staying...
...around?
Yes.
I'm going to be staying... around.
I thought you hated it here?
Not anymore.
Well, what made you decide to stay...
...around?
Well, it could be the climate...
...around, but it isn't.
Or it could be my love
for the great open spaces...
...but it isn't.
And again,
it could be that I just like you.
Yeah. Yeah, it could be.
- Were you always out of your mind?
- No, no, no, just lately.
And gosh, it's wonderful.
- I think I'd better get back to the party.
- Oh, wait a minute.
- Here, I've got a present for you.
- For me?
Sure. My grandmother gave it
to my father, and he gave it to me.
It's lucky.
It's beautiful. My.
That's me, before and after.
- You haven't changed much.
- Only I dress better now.
I can't take it if it's your lucky piece.
No, go ahead and keep it.
I won't need it now.
Now that you're around.
Gosh, first a piano and now this.
It's quite a birthday.
Would you do something for me?
Well, remember the kiss
that I gave you this afternoon?
Would you mind giving it back to me?
Oh, well, if that's the way
you feel about it.
- Happy birthday.
- What?
Happy birth...
Come in.
- Hi, Rags.
- Hi, Mr. Churchill.
- How are you feeling?
- Well, great, as long as I don't sit down.
Mr. Churchill, I knew you wasn't
gonna walk out on us.
You did? How?
I wasn't one of those taxi jockeys
in New York for nothing.
You ain't the kind that'll hop out
of a cab in the middle of traffic...
...just because the meter's gonna jump.
Thanks, Rags.
- Will you do something for me?
- Anything.
- Will you send this telegram for me?
- Sure.
I'll phone it in from
the post exchange.
Thanks. Here's something
for your trouble.
- No, that's all right.
- Why not?
Oh, no, I never touch the stuff.
Money's just like women and popcorn...
...the more you get the more you want.
I ain't had change
for a quarter in 10 years...
...and, boy, am I a happy guy.
- Hello, Rags. How are you?
- Mr. Lathrop.
- Would you do me a favor, please?
- Sure.
- Send this before the station closes.
- Well, there's the telephone right there.
Well, I can't go around
reading other people's mail.
Have a sandwich?
Oh, no, thanks.
Had too much birthday cake.
"Mr. Daniel Churchill Sr.
New York Union,
Times Square, New York City.
Dear Dad, have changed my mind. " Stop.
"Am not leaving Cody. " Stop.
"This school has as much personality
as a cup of cold cocoa...
...and I still think
the place is pretty snerpy. "
- Excuse me, I made a...
- Go ahead, Tom.
"And the students here play
cowboys and Indians...
...but you know a Churchill never quits. "
Stop.
"There's something about this place
that fills a fellow with plenty of ginger. "
Stop. "I would appreciate check
by Pony Express.
Love, Danny Boy. " Thanks, Ed.
Cowboys and Indians?
Come on, fellows.
- What's going on, Henry?
- I'm calling a mass meeting tonight.
What for?
To discuss the dismissal
of Danny Churchill Jr.
- Why?
- Read the telegram he sent his father.
"Dear Dad, changed my mind.
Am not leaving Cody. "
Danny Churchill or no Danny Churchill?
He won't change the school to his liking.
The student council will take care
of this.
Come on.
- Did you put this up on the board?
- I did.
I think you and I better step outside.
You know, this Western air fools you.
It makes you feel extra brave.
All right, so you're taller than I am.
- I think that we'd...
- No, I'm all right.
- I can take care of myself.
- Well, all right.
Why, Henry here is the boxing champ
of the school.
Do you want to step outside or not?
Mr. Churchill, Mr. Lathrop, the dean
wants you in the office.
- Do you know what he wants?
- No, I don't, but he's steaming.
- Good day.
- How are you, sir?
Little excitement going on here?
- Yes, sir.
- What seems to be the trouble?
- It seems...
- We found...
From left to right, please.
- It's about this telegram.
- I've been informed of its contents.
This is my fault.
Those are my sentiments.
I'm sorry I feel the way I do, but I do.
I feel as though I've caused enough
trouble here.
I think the best thing for me to do
is resign.
Young man, you are the resign-est
fellow I ever saw.
- Yes, sir.
- All you've done since you arrived...
...was unpack, pack and resign.
- Yes, sir.
- Would you tell me something?
Just what is the meaning
of the word "snerpy"?
Well... Well, a snerp...
...is a looging with a belt in the back.
Sometimes referred to as a diljo.
- A diljo is a...
- Never mind. I have a rough idea.
- Henry Lathrop.
- Yes, sir?
What prompted you put that notice
on the board?
- The student council had a meeting...
- A meeting?
Every time a cow coughs,
that council has a meeting.
Where's my glass?
We felt if that was Mr. Churchill's
opinion, he didn't belong here.
You did? If you'd been minding
your own business...
...you wouldn't know what people are
saying in private telegrams.
If you didn't know that,
there wouldn't have been a meeting.
- Sir, we were only...
- Would there?
- No.
- Supposing we forget all about it.
- But the student council...
- Hoot on the student council.
There's my glass.
- Lf this young man thinks we're a...
- A diljo?
A diljo, that's his privilege.
- We're still in America, aren't we?
- Yes, sir.
Well, that gives him a right
to call us a diljo.
As for you, supposing you stop
unpacking, packing and resigning...
...and start learning something
around here?
Yes, sir.
Well, get going, both of you.
Oh, just a minute.
There's another American custom.
Well, don't stand there like
Ike and Mike, scoot.
- Hi, boys.
- Hi, dean.
Hello, Gramps.
Ginger, have we a slang dictionary?
What's your problem?
What word do you want?
Looging.
- Looging?
- With a belt in the back.
Flash. The legislature today...
... in conjunction with
the new education bill...
... has ordered Cody College
to be closed next year.
Reason given by legislature:
Applications for enrollment
have fallen off to an extent...
... that they decided
to withdraw school's charter.
The bill awaits Governor Tait's
signature.
What does that mean?
The school closes.
Well, that's impossible.
- Did you know about it?
- Yes.
Well, they can't do that.
- Let's do something about it.
- I've done all I could.
- Lf he signs that...
- Don't worry.
After all these years...
Gramp.
Well, I just can't stand here.
I better call a meeting,
tell them about it.
What will you do if you lose
the school?
Oh, I'll find some other kind
of business, I reckon.
I'm getting kind of tired of the boys,
anyhow.
- Hi there.
- Hello.
Any mail for me?
No, not today.
Ginger, about forwarding my mail...
Here. You can fill that out.
Well, I guess now that the college
is closing, all your problems are settled.
Look, Ginger, I'm not gonna be
a hypocrite and say:
"I'm sorry the place is closing,"
because I'm not.
But I am sorry about leaving you.
Hey, come on.
Things aren't really that bad.
I'm sorry, but poor Gramp.
All his life,
he worked so hard for the place.
Why, every boy that came in there
was just like his own.
Here, blow.
Blow. Blow.
Ginger,
I'm not going back to New York.
- You're not?
- No, I'm gonna stay right here.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm not getting sentimental.
I don't care about the school.
As far as I'm concerned...
...it's just a place to look at
from an upper berth.
But, well, I...
I do care about you.
- You do?
- Yes, I do.
What they need here's a less cheering
and more operation.
You bet.
Let's go to the dean's. We'll give him
something to cheer about.
- All right.
- Are you through with that?
- Yeah.
- Thanks. Come on.
- May we ask you a question, please?
- Why, certainly.
How many applications do you need
for next year's freshman class?
Oh, about 125.
You mean if 125 applied for admission,
that you'd get the appropriation?
- That's right.
- It's very simple.
What made Dartmouth famous?
The Dartmouth Winter Carnival.
What put Southern California
on the map?
The Rose Bowl.
What made Notre Dame
a household word?
Football teams.
Every college in the country
was made famous by some event.
What's the springboard
for Cody College?
A Western rodeo.
Once a year we'll bring back the West.
- Daniel Boone.
- Jesse James and Buffalo Bill.
- Beautiful girls.
- On horseback.
- Glorious costumes. Happy. Carefree.
- Gay.
Once a year,
we'll choose the most beautiful girl.
We'll make her Queen of the Rodeo.
Sure. Little kids will be begging
their mothers to send them out here.
Well, it's fantastic.
All we want is your permission
to see the governor.
Well, I've lived through three blizzards,
an epidemic and four wars in my time.
I guess I could stand
a hundred beautiful girls.
- On horseback.
Danny, I give you the governor.
Hey. Hey. Egghead.
- Ma'am.
- You took the wrong road.
So I did.
Yes, I'll call you as soon as I can make
an appointment with the governor.
Not at all. Thank you.
"Governor's daughter
makes debut tonight.
Marjorie Tait, season's popular deb,
official hostess at inaugural ball. "
- She's a pretty girl.
- Domestic, isn't she?
What time is it?
Four o'clock.
- Excuse me, sir, but don't you...
- I'm sorry...
...but the governor is still busy
with a special committee.
And besides, he's seeing no one today
except by appointment.
Not even a Republican?
What are we gonna do?
Stand up, Ginger, and let me...
Let me see that dress.
Will you? For a minute, please?
Stand up and let me...
Let me see your dress.
My, my.
It's awfully pretty. Blue is nice on you.
Yes, sir. Very, very pretty.
Yes, you...
...certainly, certainly look nice.
What'd you write on that...?
Would you take this into the governor?
I hate to bother you like this.
"Dear Bill, in town for the day.
Could you see me a minute?
Regards, Dan. "
Now, young fellow,
we can't have any of that.
Please, take it in. I'll bet he'll see me.
- What are you trying to do, get me fired?
- No.
- The governor has a broadcast here...
- Please, if he doesn't see us, we'll leave.
- Yeah.
- Well, all right.
- Can we leave the equipment here?
- Yes.
The room we'll use for the broadcast
is down the hall.
I'll show it to you.
I don't think we're gonna get to see him.
Oh, sure we will.
Here we are at Forest Hills...
...bringing you the tennis matches
between Covas and Lopez from Mexico.
Miss Covas is about to serve.
It's an excellent serve, cross-handed.
Back-handed cross-court.
Miss Covas outside.
It's 40-love, match point.
Miss Lopez is about to serve now.
She asked that everybody in the gallery
be silent.
It's an excellent serve.
It's cross-courted back-hand.
There's a volley.
Out.
We're about to bring you the main
event between champion Joe Louis...
...and the contender, Johnny Paycheck.
As yet, both boys have not come
into the ring...
...but we expect them at any moment.
And here's Harry Bellows
announcing in the center of the ring.
Introducing the main contestants
of the evening...
...15 rounds of boxing...
...for the heavyweight championship
of the world...
...from Des Moines, Iowa,
weighing 187 and a quarter pounds...
...wearing black trunks,
Johnny Paycheck.
Stand up, Paycheck. Take a bow.
Okay, okay.
And his worthy opponent, considered
the greatest heavyweight of all times...
...from Detroit, weighing 202
and a quarter pounds...
...wearing purple tights, Joe Louis.
Stand up, Louis, take a bow.
Hello, Joe. Here's the bell for round one
and your announcer, Clem McCarthy.
Good evening, thanks very much.
Louis stalks him with a left hand.
It's the same old Joe Louis
that we've seen time and time again.
He tries with a left hand to the body.
Paycheck bounced away.
He didn't like the blow at all.
Louis caught him with a left hand.
Paycheck is down.
The count is one, two, three.
Ladies and gentlemen,
referee Arthur Donovan...
...has stopped the bout
and it's Louis, by a knockout.
Stick around. We'll try and get
a few words from the champion.
Pardon us. Can we get through?
Hey, Joe. Joe, Joe, Joe.
Ladies and gentlemen,
here's Joe Louis.
Tell us about the fight
as long as it lasted.
Joe, did he hurt you in the first round?
Joe Louis.
Thank you very, very much,
ladies and gentlemen.
It was a tough fight. If I fight him again
maybe I'll still keep the championship.
- That's very funny.
- Yeah.
Well, don't you think you better stop
shrieking with laughter?
I don't feel like laughing.
You're getting to be
a regular problem child.
Even worse than that kid I used to
know, the kid with the electric leg.
- Electric leg?
- Yeah.
A fellow I know stepped on
a high-tension wire.
Oh, we saved his life, but from then on,
his leg was always magnetized.
What? Is he all right now?
I don't know.
I haven't seen him lately.
But you shouldn't let a situation
like this aggravate you.
After all,
worrying never solved anything.
Remember what Shakespeare once said:
"He jests at scars that never
felt a wound.
But, soft! What light through
yonder window breaks?
'Tis the east and Juliet is the sun. "
Do you really think
we'll get to see the governor?
I take an oath.
- What if he turns us down?
- Oh, he hasn't got a leg to stand on.
And neither have I.
Now we present George Armour Allan,
and the news.
Take it away, New York.
Mr. Churchill.
Mr. Churchill?
Oh, excuse me.
The governor will see you
immediately.
- This way, please.
- Oh, thank you. Thank you, sir.
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
- Yes.
- Remember our bet.
- Hurry up. Hurry up.
Mr. Churchill.
Well, it's certainly good...
Why, what is it, young man?
Well, what can I do for you, son?
Well, who are you?
What's your name?
Really now...
Mr. Governor,
my name is Ginger Gray...
...and this quiet fellow here
is Danny Churchill.
Dan Churchill?
- That's impossible. L...
- Junior.
Junior.
- Are you Dan Churchill's son?
- Yes.
- Yes, sir.
- Hello, Dan.
- How's your dad?
- Well...
- Sit down.
- Thank you.
What's on your mind?
This is Ginger.
She's the granddaughter of Dean Armour.
Dean Armour? Really?
I talked to him on the phone.
I know. That's why we came to see you.
I'm a student there.
You are? I didn't know that.
I am. Mr. Governor,
you can't close down that college.
I'm afraid I have nothing to do with it.
The legislature passed the bill.
I know, but the bill's no good
unless you sign it.
I know, Ms. Gray, but I have to sign it,
I'm afraid.
Suppose you gave us more time.
Suppose a lot of applications came in...
...then you won't have to sign the bill?
- But what makes you think they will?
I have a feeling a lot of boys will
wanna go to Cody College next year.
- Yes, sir.
- Just what do you me want to do?
- Give us 30 days.
- Yeah.
And if nothing happens within that time,
then go ahead and sign the bill, sir.
I'm a reasonable man.
All right.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
I won't even ask
how it's going to be done.
You're on the air in five minutes, sir.
Sorry, I have to run.
My daughter's giving a big party.
Would you like to come?
I can't.
I have to get back, but Danny can go.
Oh, well, thanks very much
but all I have is this pinstripe suit.
- Wish I could wear one.
- You go ahead.
- I don't really feel as though I...
- Go on.
You know. Go on.
- All right. Thank you, sir, very much.
- Fine.
- Say hello to your grandfather.
- I will, thank you.
- I'll see you later.
- All right, sir. Goodbye.
Danny.
- For you, John.
- Thank you, sir.
- How do you do?
- Hello.
- How about it?
We've got the governor
in the palm of our hands.
Great. Set the capitol
right on its dome?
- Oh, get in, will you, Polly?
- Don't forget to see the newspapers.
- No.
- And call the newsreel men.
- Don't forget the photographers.
- I'll swamp them.
Please be sure and ask
the governor's daughter down.
I'll get her. Don't worry.
All right. Here, I wanna give you
something.
Oh, what's that for?
Well, you're going to need
an awful lot of luck.
All right.
Say, you gonna be busy
on Sunday, say, in about 50 years?
No, I don't think so.
Would you like to help me celebrate
my golden wedding anniversary?
I'd love to, if you don't think
your wife would mind.
All right, Rags.
Well, come on around.
All right, get going.
And no shortcuts.
- Hi, Tommy.
- Hey, Danny. I'm glad to see you.
What are you doing here?
I heard you're looking for a short
piano player.
- You can sit in anytime.
- How long will you be around?
We play a theater
and at the Upton Hotel.
- Are you doing anything on the 17th?
- Seventeenth? Not that I know of.
- Then you've got a job.
- Swell.
- There you are.
- Hello, Marjorie.
Do you think you have time
to meet 12 beautiful girls?
Not more than six at a time.
- I'll dig you later, Tom.
- Solid.
I think you're one of the most
beautiful girls I ever saw.
You do?
I wouldn't be surprised if you were
chosen Queen of the Rodeo.
That would be really exciting.
Oh, well, I can't make any promises,
but I could go to work on it.
Oh, that's so sweet of you.
You know, I think you're one
of the most beautiful girls I ever saw.
Oh, that's a rather big statement.
Oh, I've seen an awful lot of girls.
And my picture will be in all the papers?
- After all, my father owns 14 and...
- oh, Danny, you're so fascinating.
In a small way, but fascinating.
I think you're one of the most
beautiful girls I ever saw.
Do you really?
Yes. I've got books at home to prove it.
Oh, Danny, let's do sit the next one out.
We certainly all shall. Come.
Do you think the boys
might choose me queen?
I'm chairman of the committee and
I've got an awful good ear for music.
- Excuse me. I'm sorry.
- Danny, you're delightful.
Oh, I'm sorry. Here.
My, what a lovely locket.
- Did a girl give it to you?
- No, I've had it for quite some time.
- Precious. Do you mind if I try it on?
- I'd rather you wouldn't, because I...
- May I?
- Well, I don't know.
- Certainly, darling. Excuse me.
- Yeah.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
with your kind permission...
...presenting the music of that great
American composer...
...Mr. George Gershwin.
Our own arrangement
of "Fascinating Rhythm. "
All right, everybody.
The polls are now open.
Step up and vote
for the Queen of the Rodeo.
- Come on, everybody vote.
- Only vote for one at a time, folks.
- Polls are now open.
- Ballots right here.
Get your ballots.
- Hi, Church.
- How's your steeple?
How did you know? Fine. Say, are there
really going to be 100 pretty girls here?
You bet there are.
I can see I'm in for a very quiet
weekend.
Wait a minute.
Listen, have you seen the dean?
- Yeah.
- Is he still happy?
He's happy, but getting older.
Hey, Mr. Danny,
I sure hope Miss Ginger wins.
Are you crazy? She better hadn't.
Who better had?
The governor's daughter.
Wait a minute. I thought you told
Miss Ginger she'll win.
Oh, I've told a lot of girls
they're gonna win.
- Why?
- We need the publicity.
I think she's wonderful...
...and I'm terribly in love with her...
...but she just isn't news, Rags.
Mr. Danny, that's a lovely pair of boots
you got on, but I'd hate to be in them.
Hey, Danny.
Hey, Dan, come here.
- Where have you been?
- Been counting up the votes.
- You're in the biggest trouble I ever saw.
- The junior league wants me for murder.
Oh, tornado coming.
Oh, Bud.
- Have you seen him yet?
- Who?
- Danny Churchill.
- Oh, Danny.
No, I haven't.
I think he went to sleep.
To sleep?
Yeah, he's got a pretty big day
tomorrow.
Girls, I think I see Danny.
- Where?
- Inside.
Oh, thanks.
- Where is Ginger?
- She's inside.
You're gonna get fat if you don't stop
eating all those bananas.
When you look like me
from the neck up...
...from the neck down is no problem.
Do you really think I'll win
the crown tonight?
Are you kidding?
The rest of those dames aren't
even on the same floor with you.
You know what you ought to do...
Hey. Hey, Ginger. Hey.
Oh, that's fine, card tricks.
What is it, Danny?
Ginger, you like me quite a bit,
don't you?
I think we're safe in saying that.
Well, I think you know
how I feel about you.
I think so.
Remember once you told me
that about 100 years ago...
...an Indian pushed that rock
from the other side of that mountain...
...just to prove to a girl
that he was on the level...
...and she was the only one
he cared about?
That's right.
Well, I want you to know that no matter
what happens tonight or anytime...
...I'd move that rock on the other side
of the mountain, any day, any night.
It's a pretty tall mountain.
We've got them taller than that.
Come on, let's go back to the dance.
- The crowd's wonderful, isn't it?
- Yeah.
I guess the good-luck locket's
really working.
Danny, could I have it back now?
I mean, just so that maybe
I could win the crown tonight.
Well, Ginger, I forgot to tell you,
but I lost it on the road.
- Hi there.
- Hi.
Hello, Gramp.
Well, what do you think of it all?
Well, I kind of lost track
of the whole thing miles back.
- Isn't it nice? Danny, you really...
- Ginger.
Would you care to dance with Ginger?
Go ahead. It's fine.
- Well, Danny...
- Have fun. Dance.
- Would you like to get some air?
- I'd love to.
Danny. Danny Churchill.
Wait a minute, that's you.
Why, they're calling you.
- Well, go on up.
- Danny.
Oh, Danny.
- Attention, please.
And now,
the high point of our little jamboree.
Mr. Danny Churchill will crown
the most attractive...
...the most popular,
the most everything girl...
...Queen of the Rodeo.
You're about to see a man buried alive.
Ladies and gent...
Ladies and gentlemen.
I want to thank you all
for coming here tonight.
Especially the ladies.
There's nothing
that I'd rather do than this.
Thank you, Tom.
Looks a little nervous, doesn't he?
- He's a study.
- Yeah.
In suicide.
There have been so many sensational
girls here tonight...
...that it's been quite a problem.
But it had to be done, anyhow.
And I thought
that the voting was so close...
...that you should meet the two girls...
...who came down the stretch together.
The delightful and talented...
...and lovely, Miss Ginger Gray.
And now the gracious...
...and lovely daughter of the governor...
...Miss Nancy Tait.
I mean Miss Marjorie Tait.
And now...
...for the queen.
It's with great pleasure...
...and honor...
...on behalf of Cody College...
oh, I can't look at this.
...to award the crown to...
...Miss Marjorie Tait.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
I'm very happy...
Lost it on the road?
What's she doing, hitchhiking?
- Ginger, I can explain everything.
- Danny, wait, the crown.
There.
Where do you want me to ship the body?
Ginger, listen to me.
Remember what I told you
about moving the rock.
I wouldn't believe you
if you moved a mountain.
Ginger.
Miss Ginger.
Oh, Miss Ginger, you can't do that.
That's for kids.
Oh, Rags, I feel so miserable.
Oh, Miss Ginger...
...you know I've known you
since you were that high...
...and I saw you fall off horses
and get run over...
...but, gee, I never saw you cry.
- You know what I came out here for?
- What?
You remember one day
you told me that...
Well, if ever I felt lonesome...
...that you'd sing me a song
just for me?
Well, I feel lonesome.
Old man sunshine, listen you
Never tell me dreams come true
Just try it
And I'll start a riot
Beatrice Fairfax, don't you dare
Ever tell me he will care
I'm certain it's the final curtain
I never want to hear
From any cheerful
Pollyannas
Who tell you
Fate supplies a mate
It's all bananas
They're writing songs
Of love
But not for me
A lucky star's above
With love to lead the way
I've found more skies of gray
Than any Russian play
Could guarantee
I was a fool
To fall
And get that way
Heigh-ho alas
And also lacka-day
Although I can't dismiss
The memory
Of his kiss
I guess
He's not
For
Me
Rags, what's the matter?
I feel so much better now.
Oh, Rags, don't cry.
Ginger.
Who's going away?
I am.
Where?
Back East with Polly.
Back East?
Why?
Lots of reasons.
When?
Pretty soon.
Ginger.
Ginger, look at me.
I'm looking.
I'm sorry.
You're not looking at me now.
I'm really sorry about your grandfather
and the school...
...and about your not winning the crown.
You're not angry with me really,
are you?
No.
And you know that I'm really sorry?
Yes.
Will you...?
Will you write to me?
No.
Why not?
Because I won't have anything to write.
I will, though.
- You will?
- Yeah, lots of things.
About how I fell in love with you...
...under an old transmission...
...and how I felt
like cutting off my right arm...
...after I gave that other girl the crown.
Oh, I... I don't care about that.
You're not looking at me.
Ginger.
Wait. I want to tell you about the locket.
- I don't wanna hear about it.
- Well, here it is.
Why, I don't want it.
- I don't even wanna touch it.
- Take it, please?
Every time I'll look at it, I'll hate
myself for the rest of my life.
Oh, won't you, please?
Did you ever...?
Ever kiss that debutante?
I take an oath.
Did you ever want to?
Never mind, don't answer that.
Ginger.
- We tried to make a three-ring...
- Hallelujah. Excuse me.
- Hallelujah.
- What's the meaning of this?
- Cody comes to life.
- You keep out of this.
- No, sir.
Why, hello, Dad.
Do you know this school
isn't going to close?
- It isn't?
- No. Look at this.
- Applications for admittance.
- To this school.
- Next year.
- Over 200 of them.
- The governor can't close the school.
- He can't?
Now, get yourself all set now.
Are you ready?
- Ready for anything.
- Yeah.
These applications are from girls.
- From what?
- Girls.
Why not make the school coeducational?
- Oh, no.
- Didn't I tell you girls had a future?
I always said you were girl crazy.
I was wrong. You're just crazy.
- Wait a minute.
- I don't feel that way. It's a good idea.
No, not you.
Get me the governor.
You heard me, the governor. Yes.
- And reverse the charges.
- Oh, Gramp.
- Is everybody having fun?
- Yeah.
That's only the beginning.
Now, the golden voice of the golden
West, our own Ginger Gray.
Singing "I Got Rhythm" accompanied
by Tommy Dorsey and his orchestra...
...and that ain't hay.
Days can be sunny with never a sigh
Don't need what money can buy
Birds in the tree sing
Their day full of song
Why shouldn't we sing along?
I'm chipper all the day
Happy with my lot
How do I get that way?
Look at what I've got
I got rhythm
I got music
I got my man
Who could ask for anything more?
I got daisies in green pastures
I got my man
Who could ask for anything more?
Old man trouble, I don't mind him
You won't find him around my door
I got starlight
I got sweet dreams
I got my man
Who could ask for anything more?
Who could ask, who could ask
- I got rhythm, I got music
- I got my man
- Who could ask for anything more?
I got daisies in green pastures
I got my man
Who could ask for anything more?
- Old man trouble, I don't mind him
- You won't find him
Hanging round my front or back door
I got starlight
I got sweet dreams
I got my man
Who could ask for anything more?
I got rhythm
I got music
I got my man
Who could ask... ?
Who could ask
For anything more than daisies?
Starlight, sweet dreams
Hanging round my front door
Hanging round my back door
Hanging round my side door
- I got starlight
- I got sweet dreams
- I got my man
Who could ask for anything more?
Who could ask for anything more
Than music and rhythm?
I got rhythm
She's got rhythm
He's got rhythm
We got rhythm, yeah
They got it
We got it
Rhythm
- Who could ask for anything
- More?