Gone are my blues
and gone are my tears
I've got good news
to shout in your ears
The long lost dollar has come
back to the fold
With silver you can turn
your dreams to gold
We're in the money
We've got a lot of what it takes
to get along!
We're in the money
The sky is sunny
Old man depression you are through
You done us wrong!
We never see a headline
'bout a breadline today
And when we see the landlord
we can look that guy right in the eye
We're in the money
Come on, my honey
Let's lend it, spend it
send it rolling around
We're in the money
I say, we're in the money
We've got a lot of what it takes
to get along!
We're in the money
Look up, the skies are sunny
Old man depression you are through
You done us wrong!
We never see a headline
'bout a breadline today
And when we see the landlord
we can look that guy right in the eye
We're in the money
Come on, my honey
Let's lend it, spend it
send it rolling around
We're in the money
Come on, my honey
Let's lend it, spend it
send it rolling around
- Hey, who are you?
- You'll find out.
Come on, boys.
Might as well begin right here.
Get out of here.
Hey, you, go take them clothes off.
Go on. Come on, you punk, get out of here.
Come on,
get these music racks out of here.
Wait a minute. What is this?
- Well, who are you?
- I'm Barney Hopkins...
- producer of this show.
- Oh, yeah?
It's tough luck, brother.
I'm from the sheriff's office.
Legal attachment to collect for the credit.
- Corpus delicti, or seize the body.
- What, again?
- Don't you dare.
- Don't worry, sis, this will look nice...
in the sheriff's office.
- What's the excitement?
- It means they close the show, dumbbell.
Give me that costume.
- I beg your pardon.
- Well, we've got to take it back, actress.
Well, that's as far back as it goes.
Sorry, miss, they got to have that top.
- You can at least give me car fare.
- What for?
This is our dress rehearsal.
We got a great show.
It opens tomorrow night.
You can't do this to me
just because I don't pay a few bills.
- When the show opens, I will pay up.
- Tell it to the sheriff.
This is the fourth show in two months
that I've been in of and out of.
They close before they open.
The Depression, dearie.
I can remember
when that alarm clock used to ring.
Those good old days
when you had to get up.
Come on, let's get up and look for work.
I hate starving in bed.
- Name me a better place to starve.
- Your stomach.
Let's get up and get dressed.
I thought we might try the flea circus.
Maybe they got something for us there.
- What can we get at a flea circus?
- Fleas.
- You can get those here.
- All right. Come on, let's get up.
One, two, three.
- How about some nourishment?
- Yeah, what's on the menu, Trixie?
We'll see what the neighbors have to offer.
- You guys cut the bread and set the table.
- Have we any bread?
Yeah, have we any table?
What neighbors?
I can remember not so long ago
a penthouse on Park Avenue.
With a real tree, and flowers,
and a fountain, and a French maid.
And a warm bath with salt from Yardley's.
And a little dress that Schiaparelli ran up.
And a snappy roadster,
and a ride through the park.
Now stealing milk.
That's all right.
The dairy company stole it from a cow.
Just about a year ago this time,
I was on my way to Havana.
The birds were singing
and the sky was blue.
And I said to the big mug in the next pew,
"I need $200, big boy."
And he said, "In my pants pocket."
You know, I reached over and I took $500
out of his back pants pocket just like that.
And all I got left are his pajamas,
and I'm a milk snatcher.
Guess we got to give it back.
Maybe it's the piano remover.
- Fay!
- Who'd you think it was, the wolf?
If it was, we'd eat it.
Why the blue spectacles, grandma?
So the landlady won't recognize me.
I'm obligated to her
for a little item called rent.
If you've come to make a touch,
the bank has folded.
Your millions are safe, Trixie.
I came to tell you gals good news.
Barney's putting on a new show.
- Barney?
- Barney Hopkins?
- Rehearsals start in two weeks.
- He must have found an angel.
Come on, let's go over and find out.
That's right. As soon as the mob finds out,
they'll all be after him.
- Come on, let's hurry.
- We can't all go.
We haven't got enough decent clothing
left to wrap around one of us.
Yeah, and if one doesn't look modish
with Barney, it's thumbs down.
Let's see if we can scare up enough...
to make at least one of us look,
as you say, modish.
- Who's to go?
- Let's match for it.
- Taxis.
- Yellow.
- Checkered.
- Red top.
Black and white.
- Checkered!
- Carol wins.
- Gee.
I look much better in clothes
than any of you.
- Lf Barney could see me in clothes...
- He wouldn't recognize you.
Say, what happened
to your lovely mink coat?
Uncle's got it. Uncle's got everything.
We've even hocked our inlays.
Honey, you'll have to give me
my stockings back.
- Sure, there they are.
- Fay?
You got to give Carol that dress.
Don't, I'e got to go back to the drugstore.
We'll give you something good enough
for a drugstore.
I know, but the dress belongs to them.
I'm a hostess there.
- Stand still.
- So am I a hostess.
I've got to entertain Barney
with the idea of putting us to work.
Don't forget to stand in the light, Carol,
when you're talking to Barney.
They certainly know what they're doing...
when they dress
their hostesses in that drugstore.
- Well, you don't look bad.
- Now, take these papers...
get through the enemy's lines,
and ride like blazes.
- Taxi fare.
- Lots of luck, Carol.
Thanks.
Here we go, laughing and wondering.
Say, watch yourself in the clinches.
Don't forget that dress...
belongs to the drugstore.
I'd like to meet that druggist.
Now, the best comedian on Broadway
will proceed to make beds.
Well, I'm going to get a glass of milk.
In the shadows
let me come and sing to you
Let me dream a song that I can bring
To you
Take me in your arms
and let me cling to you
Let me linger long
Let me live my song
In the winter, let me bring the spring
To you
Let me feel that I mean everything
Love's old song
Will be new
In the shadows, when I come and sing
To you
Dear
In the shadows
When I come and sing
To you
You can't turn these sheets anymore.
They've only got two sides.
Polly, will you quit mooning over
that good-for-nothing songwriter again?
- Now where's that going to get you?
- He's wonderful, Trixie.
- Honey, he's a songwriter.
- So is Irving Berlin.
- What's wrong about being a songwriter?
- How long have you known him?
Two weeks?
What do you know about him?
I knew everything I wanted to know
the minute I met him.
- Maybe it's Carol.
- Oh.
Hello.
It's true, it's really true.
He's putting on a show.
It's true. Barney's putting on a show.
We're coming right up to the apartment.
Be there in 10 minutes.
Phone all the girls.
Phone Fay and Ruth and Mary and Gwen.
Phone them all. Tell them to come
right up to the apartment.
- He hasn't cast yet, no.
- Hurry and don't lose him.
- They're coming up.
- Who?
Barney and Carol. Phone Fay.
Phone all the girls. We're all set.
No, you phone them.
I've got to dig up the old sex appeal.
The way I feel this morning
I'll need a steam shovel.
Half a mile, four, eight...
Step on it, Polly.
They ought to be here any minute now.
Almost ready.
Gosh, to think that we're going to have
real jobs again, earn money.
Yeah, and I've been
off the gold standard so long.
It's them.
- Come on in, Barney, and meet the girls.
- Hello, Mr. Hopkins.
- Howdy. Howdy.
I've seen that face before.
Well, if it isn't Barney.
Good old, smiling, big-hearted Barney.
- Barney, we hear you're putting on a show.
- Yes, I'm doing a show.
You sound more enthusiastic than usual.
Does that mean it's good?
You said it's good.
It's the finest thing I ever had.
Come on over here and sit down
and tell us all about it, Mr. Hopkins.
Well, I've figured it out
from every angle, kids.
And I can't see
how it'll run less than six months...
or gross less than half a million.
That's figuring on $30,000 a week.
At the Broadhurst we could do $40,000.
- We'll do $40,000 with this show.
- Gosh.
- I remember you.
- Do you?
You were in the chorus.
Someday you're coming out of the chorus.
- Thank you, Mr. Hopkins.
- Could you use me, too, Mr. Hopkins?
Sure, I'm going to use all the girls
I used before.
Carol, here, will be featured...
and Trixie as comic.
I got some ideas
for song numbers for you, honey...
that will drape them over their seats.
- Something new, different.
- What's the show about?
- It's all about the Depression.
- We won't have to rehearse that.
Now, it's my idea...
- Who's that playing?
- Some palooka songwriter.
I don't know that number, what is it?
It's his own. He composes music.
Shut the window
and let's get on with this.
Wait a minute.
That's not bad.
Ask the fellow to come on over.
Brad.
- Hello.
- Come on over, quick.
All right.
You know,
that number's got a great feel to it.
- The boy's got something.
- Yeah, a piano.
What's he done?
He hasn't had a chance to do anything yet,
Mr. Hopkins.
- But he has genius.
- Yeah?
Well, the show business
could stand a little genius.
Barney, what's the idea of wasting time
with a genius...
when there's hard-working girls like us
to worry about?
- What is it, honey?
- Come on, I want you to meet somebody.
This is Brad Roberts, Mr. Hopkins.
- Mr. Hopkins is our producer.
- Never mind that. Sit down and play.
- Play what?
- That number you were just playing.
- I know, but l...
- Don't be afraid, you're among friends.
- Go on, Brad.
- Well, all right.
I beg your pardon.
Say, what's this all about, anyway?
Go ahead and play.
Sing it if you got words.
All right. Here goes.
I've got to sing a torch song
For that's the way I feel
When I feel a thing
Then I can sing
It must be real
I couldn't sing a gay song
It wouldn't be sincere
I could never croon
A happy tune
Without a tear
I have my dreams, but one by one
They vanish in the sky
I try to smile and face the sun
But romance passes by
I've got to sing a torch song
To someone far apart
For the torch I bear
Is burning there
Right in
My heart
That's great. I like it.
- You got anything else?
- Yes, I have a couple of things.
- Well, play them. Play them.
- All right.
Hello, Mr. Hopkins.
Charming to see you again.
Sit down.
No, I don't like that, son. It's too dull.
What is this, a piano lesson?
Or are we going to hear about this show?
Say, have you got something with kind of
a march effect, march rhythm to it?
Yes, I have.
I have something about a forgotten man.
- But I don't have the words to it yet.
- Play it, play it.
I tell you,
I just got the idea for it last night.
I was down on Times Square,
watching those men in the breadline...
standing there in the rain,
waiting for coffee and doughnuts.
Men out of a job, around the soup kitchen.
Stop!
Go on.
That's it! That's what this show's about!
The Depression, men marching,
marching in the rain.
Doughnuts and crullers,
men marching, marching...
jobs, jobs, and in the background,
Carol, spirit of the Depression.
A blue song.
No, not a blue song, but a wailing.
And this gorgeous woman singing
this song that'll tear their hearts out.
The big parade. The big parade of tears.
That's it. Work on it.
- I'd like to do a specialty.
- Sit down. You'll do a blackout.
I'll cancel my contract
with Warren and Dubin. They're out.
I want you to write the music
for this show, and the lyrics.
- Can you write lyrics?
- You bet he can.
I've got it all figured out,
and I want your stuff, son. It's great.
- I definitely want it.
- Mr. Hopkins, you can have it...
on one condition.
Yeah?
If Miss Parker, Polly,
has a principal part in the show.
She's helped me a lot,
and she's really great herself.
You're telling me? I'm telling you.
And I'll tell you something else, too.
You got a swell voice
and a great personality.
You're different. You've got class.
I want you to sing in this show.
Thanks a lot, but that's impossible.
Now listen, you and Polly would make
a swell team, like the Astaires.
You'd be a knockout
for the mushy interest...
- I'm sorry, but it's impossible.
- But, Brad, why not?
I can't, honey, for a lot of reasons.
Let me get in on this. Isn't there
going to be any comedy in this show?
Plenty.
The gay side, the hard boiled side, the
cynical and funny side of the Depression.
I'll make them laugh at you
starving to death, honey.
- Be the funniest thing you ever did.
- Did you ever see me ride a pony?
- When do rehearsals begin, Barney?
- Rehearsals?
- When I get the money.
- Get the money?
Money?
That's always the way it is. I got the show,
I got the music, I got the cast...
I got the theater, all raring to go...
and it's the old, old story. Money.
- No money at all?
- Not even the old shoestring.
- But you said... You let us think that...
- What did I let you think?
I told you I had a great show, and I have.
But you said it was all set.
It is set. It's been set for six months.
Every time I get an angel to put up
the bankroll, something happens.
I had one yesterday.
Only today, he came to me
and said he and his wife...
who was suing him for divorce,
had become reconciled...
and she didn't want him fooling around
in the show business.
And here I am, holding the bag.
You've got your nerve, Barney.
What about these girls?
They've given up jobs
just because you said that...
You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
Gee, it's tough enough
without you making mugs out of us.
- We counted on this, all of us.
- Wait a minute, kids.
I'm not going to let you down.
I've got other irons in the fire.
Two men are due here tomorrow
from out of town.
- Texas cattle.
- Yeah, Texas cattle.
How can they sell cattle?
Who eats meat anymore?
- All I can say is...
- How much do you need?
- $50,000.
- There isn't $50,000 in the world.
Not to put a show on with, anyway.
All right then, who needs $50,000?
Make it $40,000, $25,000.
If I wanted to chisel,
and I know how to chisel...
I could do it for $15,000, but...
I'll advance you $15,000.
Say, what does he use? I'll smoke it, too.
Quit joking, will you?
It isn't smart to make gags
when girls are starving.
Brad, this is too serious a matter
to all of us.
Honey, I mean it. I'll be glad to do it.
Where can you get $15,000?
He means real money,
not streetcar transfers.
Remember, one condition:
Polly is featured.
Anything you say.
Nope. I can't give you a check
for certain reasons.
I'll give you cash tomorrow.
Is that all right?
- You fell for it, Barney.
- He did. He fell for it.
That's what's commonly known as a gag.
It's not a gag. I mean it.
Tomorrow I'll be in your office at 10:30.
You have my word for it.
I'm going to go work on that number
a little, so I'll see you later.
Goodbye, honey.
- Brad.
- Yes?
- Brad, this is cruel.
- What, honey?
- To kid about a thing like this.
- I'm not kidding. I'll give him the money.
He'll have it in his office
at 10:30 tomorrow morning.
- Where are you going to get $15,000?
- Well, honey, I'll tell you...
See this ring? I just give it a little twist,
make a wish, presto.
- Brad.
- Trust me, will you, honey?
- And I'm not joking.
- That's just the trouble.
- I do trust you.
- Oh, honey.
- What?
- No, I won't say it yet.
I have an idea, and I want to get
to the piano before I lose it.
See you later.
He meant it. Really, he did.
I'd stake my life on it.
Faith, hope, and charity.
You have faith, Barney hopes,
and we all need charity.
Wait a minute.
Listen.
He's got it. Just what I want.
Don't you hear that wailing? Wailing.
Men marching, marching,
marching in the rain.
Jobs.
Gee, don't it get you?
- Well?
- There's no answer...
at Mr. Roberts' apartment.
Now Trixie can say, "I told you so,"
but I won't. It hurts too much.
Come in.
Gigolo Eddie always shows up
at the wrong time.
Hello, Barney. Heard you got your mitts
on some dough to open a show.
Thought you might want to celebrate.
Fresh off the boat.
Well, you heard wrong. Pull up a coffin
and lie down with the rest of us.
Business is so tough that nobody
even wants to owe me anymore.
- You can go.
- But you hired me for the day.
I thought I was going to need a secretary.
Well, you'll pay me for the day,
or I'll make a complaint to the agency.
I wish there was somebody
I could complain to.
- Who are you?
- We're the Zipky Kentucky Hillbillies.
- Who?
- The Kentucky Hillbillies.
- Singing.
- Dancing.
- Music.
- Wisecracks.
- Do you know Your Old Kentucky Home?
- You said it.
Scram right back there.
Your old mammy's waiting for you.
We get it.
I better lock this joint before the acrobats
and midgets start flocking in.
- Good morning. You're early.
- I'm sorry I kept you all waiting.
- Yeah?
- I got a new idea for a number...
and I lost all track of time.
Got a piano? I'll play it for you.
Hey, listen, kid,
I'm the comedian around here.
We've had enough of your gags.
They're not funny.
Please stop it, Brad.
There's a limit to everything.
I'm going to lock this office.
Get out of here, all of you.
- Don't you want the money?
- Don't kid me.
There you are. $15,000, cash.
Brad, I always knew you were on the level.
Rehearsals start at 9:00 in the morning.
Fresh off the boat.
Pettin'in the park
Bad boy!
Bad girl!
First you pet a little
Let up a little
And then you get a little kiss
Pettin' on the sly
Oh, my!
Act a little shy
Aw, why?
Struggle just a little
Then hug a little
And cuddle up and whisper this
Come on, I've been waiting long
Wait a minute. Hold it.
Hold it, girls. Gordon, listen, you've got
to put some life into that song.
- Yeah?
- You got to sing it with some pep...
and some feeling.
You got the whole thing wrong. Listen.
Play me the first chorus, will you?
Here's the way it goes. Now come on.
Pettin'in the park
Bad boy!
Bad girl!
First you pet a little
Let up a little
Then you get a little kiss
Pettin' on the sly
Oh, my!
Act a little shy
Aw, why?
Struggle just a little
Then hug a little
Cuddle up and whisper this
Come on
I've been waiting long
Why don't we get started?
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
What am I doing that's so wrong?
Well, listen, you do this
right in the middle part.
Come on, I've been waiting
That's not the melody. Here it is.
Come on
I've been waiting long
Why don't we get started?
All right. All right.
Now, let me tell you something.
I've been a juvenile for 18 years...
and you're going to tell me
how to sing a song?
Come on, fellows, let me down, will you?
I want to get a glass of water.
Come on, girls and boys,
show me that dance chorus.
Come on, snap into it. Hit it now.
Come on, let's go. Give it to me now.
Listen, Brad, why don't you do
this juvenile part yourself?
You've got it over Gordon like a tent.
Reconsider. Give your songs a break.
Barney, I told you, I can't do it.
You say you can't,
but you don't tell me why.
You've got a voice. You got personality.
You can do it, but you won't. Why?
Barney, will you let it go at that
once and for all? No public appearances.
- Hi, sweets.
- Hello.
Listen, honey, you've got quite a yen
for that boy, haven't you?
I like him, of course.
There's something awful funny about him,
something very mysterious.
Listen, did he ever tell you
where he got that $15,000?
- No.
- And why he has to live on $25 a week...
when he can go out and come back
with that much money?
Now, look.
"Toronto bank clerk took $20,000...
- "from bank and disappeared."
- I can read.
That's quite a coincidence, I should say.
- What's a coincidence?
- And look.
"New York police asked to check up
Broadway nightspots."
And here's the description of him:
"5'9", dark hair"...
That could describe anybody.
It couldn't describe me,
and it couldn't describe you...
and it does describe him.
He is about 5'9"...
and he has got dark hair,
and where did he get that cash?
Well, don't be ridiculous, Trixie.
You're letting your imagination
run away with you.
Listen, honey, I don't want to see
you fall in love with a guy...
who's going to get you
into a lot of trouble.
I know, but I'm sure.
What are you sure?
What do you actually know about him?
Does he ever talk about himself?
Does he ever mention his family?
You remember that he wouldn't give
Barney a check, it had to be cash?
And he won't go out there
and play Gordon's part. Why?
Because he's afraid that newspaper...
Now, listen, don't talk,
and don't come back here. You promise?
I said I wouldn't, didn't I? So long.
Don't say anything to anyone,
will you, Trixie?
On stage.
Stage, lady. Come on.
You know, this stuff is just as good
to rub with as it is to drink.
It penetrates.
Show me the spot.
He's been rubbing me for an hour,
and he says, "Show me the spot."
- What's this?
- It's his lumbago.
- Get up.
- I can't, I tell you. I can't.
You can't get up, can't you?
No, don't. Please don't.
Straighten up, you permanent juvenile.
I can't, I tell you. I can't.
You don't suppose you're going out there
and singing a love song...
with your back doubled up, do you?
What kind of a love song
do you think this is?
You've got to straighten up.
You've got to stop being a baby.
Mind over matter.
I can't, I tell you.
I got a show.
I spent weeks and months getting a show.
I've worked. I've slaved. Opening night.
We open tonight, and he's got lumbago.
Go out and announce the show
is postponed. Give them their money back.
Tell them our juvenile man's
dying of old age.
Listen, kid, now it's up to you.
Now you've got to do it.
- You've got to go on in his place.
- I can't do that, Barney.
Why can't you do it? The curtain's
going up. The show is going on.
Your girl's in it. Your music's in it.
Your money's in it.
You've got to go on and do it.
- There's a reason why.
- There can't be any reason.
- All right.
- Well, what is your reason?
Now, listen, I don't care if you have
to go to jail after this performance...
you ought to forgot about yourself
and do this anyway.
Do you know what it means
if this show doesn't go on?
to the girls in this show?
Those poor kids who gave up jobs...
and will never be able
to find other ones, these times.
Those kids
who've been living on nothing...
starving themselves the six weeks
we've been rehearsing...
hoping for this show to go on
and be a success?
Well, they're counting on you.
You can't let them down. You can't.
If you do, well,
God knows what'll happen to those kids.
They'll have to do things I wouldn't want
on my conscience, and it will be on yours.
Now, you can go out and sing
Gordon's part, and put this show over.
And if you don't, well,
I don't care what your reason is.
She's right, Brad.
I hadn't thought about it in that way.
- Yes, of course. I'll do it.
- Great, kid. I knew you would.
Walter, get Gordon's dress suit.
Get him a dressing room.
He's not on for seven minutes.
They won't have to hold the curtain.
- Right. Come on, kids, we've got to...
- Oh, boy.
Get him ready.
Gee, if anything happens to him now,
we're responsible.
There's more to that kid
than I thought there was.
He has nerve. He's regular.
He belongs in the show business.
He's risking going to prison for us.
I like that kid. If he goes to prison for this,
I'll visit him there, I swear I will.
I want to see him and let him know
that I know what it means.
- Brad.
- Hello.
Put your ear close to the door.
I want to whisper something to you.
All right, honey.
Brad, it's wonderful of you
to take this chance tonight.
- It's courageous.
- It's not courageous, exactly.
Say, but how do you know? Do you know?
But don't think about it, Brad.
Just think about, I love you.
And I always will,
no matter what happens.
Gee, that's swell, honey.
After tonight, you can tell me all about it.
I'll understand, and maybe I can help.
After tonight?
Hurry, Miss Parker. Hurry, Mr. Roberts.
- Wish us luck, sweetheart.
- I do. I wish us luck.
Every night a body should relax
After all the wear and tear
Get that oxygen your body lacks
Get it in the open air
Go and find a little rendezvous
Underneath the starry skies
Take someone who's sweet along with you
For a little exercise
Pettin'in the park
Bad boy!
Pettin'in the dark
Bad girl!
First you pet a little
Let up a little
Then you get a little kiss
Pettin' on the sly
Oh, my!
Act a little shy
Aw, why?
Struggle just a little
Then hug a little
And cuddle up and whisper this
Come on, I've been waiting long
Why don't we get started?
Come on, maybe this is wrong
Well, gee, what of it?
We just love it
Pettin'in the park
Bad boy!
Pettin'in the dark
Bad girl!
Whatcha doin', honey?
I feel so funny
I'm pettin'in the park with you
Pettin'in the park
Pettin'in the dark
Let up a little
Then you get a little kiss
Pettin' on the sly
Act a little shy
Struggle just a little
Then hug a little
Cuddle up and whisper this
Pettin'in the park
Bad boy!
Pettin'in the dark
Bad girl!
Whatcha doin', honey?
I feel so funny
Pettin'in the park with you
Pettin'in the park
Bad boy!
Pettin'in the dark
Bad girl!
First you pet a little
Let up a little
And then you get a little kiss
Pettin' on the sly
Oh, my!
Act a little shy
Aw, why?
Struggle just a little
Then hug a little
And cuddle up and whisper this
Come on, I've been waiting long
Why don't we get started?
- Come on
Maybe this is wrong
But, gee, what of it?
We just love it
Pettin'in the park
Bad boy!
Pettin'in the dark
Bad girl!
Whatcha doin', honey?
I feel so funny
I'm pettin'in the park with you
Pettin'in the park
Bad boy!
Pettin'in the dark
Bad girl!
First you pet a little
Let up a little
And then you get a little kiss
Pettin' on the sly
Oh, my!
Act a little shy
Aw, why?
Struggle just a little
Then hug a little
And cuddle up and whisper this
Come on, I've been waiting long
Why don't we get started?
Come on, maybe this is wrong
- But, gee, what of it?
- We all love it
Pettin'in the park
Bad boy!
Pettin'in the dark
Bad girl!
Whatcha doin', honey?
I feel so funny
I'm pettin'in the park with you
Pettin'in the park
Bad boy!
Pettin'in the dark
Bad girl!
Pet a little
Let up a little
And then you get a little kiss
Pettin' on the sly
Oh, my!
Act a little shy
Aw, why?
Struggle a little
Then hug a little
And cuddle up and whisper this
Come on, I've been waiting long
Why don't we get started?
Maybe this is wrong
But, gee, what of it?
We just love it
Pettin'in the park
Bad boy!
Pettin'in the dark
Bad girl!
Whatcha doin', honey?
I feel so funny
I'm pettin'in the park with you
Who is the boy?
Brad Roberts,
according to the announcements.
And the program says
he did most of the music, too.
Smart kid.
There's something familiar about him.
I've seen him.
Not in the theater, either. Wait a minute.
- Let me have a nickel.
- Yeah.
I'm going to find out.
Listen.
Why, I can't believe it.
The description, and I knew
I'd seen him someplace before.
Let's go back
and get Barney to tell us the truth.
What a front-page story that will make.
Come on back with me.
- Polly, look at this.
- What?
Look at it.
Oh, gosh.
I can't believe it.
I never dreamed of such a thing.
I always knew that kid was somebody.
You can't fool me much.
Why, Trixie Lorraine, you thought I was
a fool to have anything to do with this.
You don't know when I'm kidding, do you?
- Mr. Bradford?
- He's over there on the lounge, sir.
Thank you.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Robert.
- You're late.
- Not much, am I?
Seventeen minutes.
- Hello, Peabody.
- How are you, young man?
- Sit down.
- Thank you.
I'll come directly to the point, Robert.
Your family is greatly disturbed
over what has occurred.
I hope you appreciate the fact
that I flew here this morning...
in uncertain weather.
As trustee of your estate
and your elder brother...
I represent the family...
in saying that we cannot have you
mixed up in this theater business.
- You know how we feel.
- Your mother is greatly concerned...
and every member of your family.
I cannot begin to describe to you,
my dear boy, the extent of the shock.
I'm sorry
everybody in the family is shocked...
but I'd better come
directly to the point, too.
Music is my career, you know that.
- Music, yes...
- Well, I mean the kind of songs...
that's sung in shows,
and over the radio, and on record.
I don't mean the kind of music played
by the Boston Symphony Orchestra.
You have to be half dead to compose that.
I want to write this other kind of music.
This show was my big opportunity.
The show clicked.
I've got my start, and I'm going on with it.
As to appearing with the show,
I know how you feel about that.
And I did the best I could to stay out of it.
But an emergency came up,
and I had to do it.
Now I can't let them down.
Besides, I like it.
Much as the family regrets
that one who bears our name...
should go in
for this sort of sensational career...
in preference to banking...
nevertheless, we've agreed
not to oppose you.
One thing, however,
we must and will insist upon.
And what's that?
This girl, this showgirl
whose name is linked with yours...
- Polly Parker.
- Well, what of it?
- What of it? Simply this...
- Listen.
Before you say anything about her,
you better know this.
I'm in love with Polly Parker,
and I'm going to marry her.
- Lf she'll have me.
- What?
I'm going to complain
to the House Committee.
Just what I said.
- You'll marry this cheap little showgirl...
- Wait a minute.
That's pretty much
of an old-fashioned idea.
Families don't interfere
with love affairs nowadays.
And if they do, it doesn't mean anything.
If you marry that girl,
you'll get not one cent of income.
I don't have to remind you
that until you're 30...
I have the absolute legal right
to cut off your income.
I understand,
and if that's all you have to say to me...
you're just wasting your time.
I've got more important things to do.
I shall certainly complain
to the House Committee.
- I can't understand him.
- It's the girl.
I know these showgirls. They're just
little parasites, little gold diggers.
- I don't doubt it.
- I remember, in my early youth...
I trod the primrose path
on the Great White Way.
There I learned the bitter truth
that all women of the theater...
were chisellers, parasites.
Or as we call them, gold diggers.
I remember...
well, one experience I had
with a woman of the theater.
It was the day of the big Harvard game.
We all came down.
A stout company of young blades
eager to learn about life.
I met this girl at the stage door
of the old casino.
We went to Rector's for a bite.
I had a cold bird and a bottle.
She nibbled at a steak.
Her name was Eunice.
She called me Fuffy.
I don't know why she did,
but she called me Fuffy.
I'm going to see her.
I don't know where she is now.
That was 30 years ago.
No, I mean this Polly Parker woman.
I wouldn't go if I were for you.
You're only putting yourself
into their hands.
I tell you, they're all blackmailers,
gold diggers, parasites.
I resign.
- No.
- Yes.
When I feel a thing
That I can sing
It must be real
I couldn't sing a gay song
It wouldn't be sincere
I could never croon a happy tune
- Come in.
- Hey, shut the bathroom door.
I will, Trixie.
Without a tear
I have my dreams
Come in, come in.
They vanish in the sky
I try to smile and face the sun
But romance passes by
Well, who is it?
I am J. Lawrence Bradford.
Yes?
I've come to see Miss Polly Parker.
Oh, yes?
I'm the brother of Robert Treat Bradford...
whom you probably know as Brad Roberts.
You're Brad's brother.
- Sit down, I'll be dressed in just a minute.
- Don't bother, Miss Parker.
- I can say what I have to say...
- But you see, I'm not...
Please, Miss Parker.
I've just spoken to my brother.
He tells me he wants to marry you.
You're making a mistake.
- Lf you'll let me explain...
- Don't bother to explain.
I've told him if he disgraces the family
by marrying a showgirl...
the family is through with him.
Did you say, "Disgrace the family
by marrying a showgirl"?
I said exactly that.
Showgirls are reputed to be...
parasites, chisellers, gold diggers.
Showgirls are excellent in their way...
attractive creatures, even fascinating...
but hardly fitted to shine
in the upper social circles.
This is not directed
against you personally, Miss Parker.
No, I understand that, not personally.
All showgirls are parasites,
chisellers, and gold diggers.
Exactly.
- And now...
- You better let me tell you...
Just tell me how much?
- How much what?
- What is your price?
How much do you want to release his
brother from his promise to marry you?
- Well, this is very funny.
- I see nothing amusing in it, Miss Parker.
Please, don't let's waste time. How much?
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry?
No price on me.
But I insist, Miss Parker.
You must have a price.
I'm inclined to be generous in the matter.
After all, I realize
that Bob is a headstrong boy.
But I'm in charge of him,
and I feel I know what is best for him.
I've had about enough of this.
If you don't mind...
I beg your pardon, but am I interrupting?
No, not at all.
This is Brad's brother,
J. Lawrence Bradford.
I'm charmed.
Beware, Trixie's a showgirl.
Who is this distinguished looking
young man?
- I don't know.
- I'm Faneuil H. Peabody.
- Faneuil?
- Faneuil.
When I know you better,
I'll call you Fanny.
Have you got a cigarette?
Gold.
My error. Have you a light?
Your hand is shaking.
What an unexpected pleasure.
Now, come along,
let's sit over on the other side of the room.
Come on. Come along.
You know, I used to know some Peabodys,
but I think they came from Texas.
Sit down, now. Come on, sit down.
There.
Mr. J. Lawrence Bradford
tells me I must give Brad up.
He also says we're chisellers and
gold diggers, and wants to know my price.
Well, have you told him, Polly?
I was about to tell him where to head in.
I wouldn't be too hasty.
I'd at least discuss it further.
After all, we're grown up, sensible.
You're a woman of the world.
I'm a man of the world.
We ought to have a conference.
Isn't that what businessmen always have
when they're away from home?
Conferences?
I know a new speaky. It just opened.
Their liquor is good,
and do I know good liquor.
It's right around the corner,
and we'll be with you in just two minutes.
I'll just slip into something.
I beg your pardon.
- What's that?
- My slip.
Come along, Polly, dear.
Let's not keep them waiting.
Here's something for you to read...
Mr. Bradford.
And...
here are some pictures for you to look at.
Now, you amuse yourselves, won't you?
We'll just be two minutes.
Fanny.
Peabody, you're disgusting.
I'm going to tell them the truth
and kick them out.
After what he called you? A parasite?
Say, what is a parasite?
You better resent it.
He did get under my skin.
Stuck-up snob.
They've had their turn. Let's have ours.
We'll take them for a ride.
Use the bathroom while I use the phone.
Endicott 2.
Hello, Madam Minnie?
This is Trixie Lorraine.
Say, you know the hat with the...
Yeah.
No, no.
The expensive one.
Did the buzzer buzz?
What's that?
A COD for Miss Polly Parker.
$75.
$75 just for a little hat?
But she'll look adorable in that, won't she?
Yes, she will.
Now let me see. What does COD mean?
That means you've got to pay for it.
How inconvenient.
Well, you'll have to take it back.
Oh, dear. She'll be in such a bad mood.
- Who will?
- Polly.
She did so want to wear that hat when
she went out for lunch with you today.
Oh, dear. When she doesn't get
what she wants, you just don't know Polly.
Oh, so disagreeable. She's no fun at all.
Just sits there.
She won't agree to anything you say.
She probably won't even want
to go with us.
We three will just have to go alone.
There you are, boy. Take it back.
Here, wait a minute.
- How much is it?
- $75.
$75 for a hat?
Sure, that's what the ticket calls for.
Here.
- Leave the hat.
- You darling man.
Polly's just going to love you for this.
Polly, this sweet big brother of Brad's...
has insisted upon paying for your hat.
- But he mustn't do that.
- But he has.
- But I couldn't.
- But you must.
That looks adorable on her, doesn't it?
Doesn't it?
Yes, now all you need is a corsage.
I think lilies of the valley and gardenias.
I guess I'll need orchids.
- Shall we send out for some?
- Yes.
Let's be going.
I must get a 4:00 train to Boston.
I'm very sorry, Mr. Bradford.
But I just couldn't leave the room
without a corsage.
And I wouldn't let Polly.
I couldn't let her go out that way.
We'll buy you a corsage on the way.
- But let's hurry.
- Isn't he a darling?
You're just so generous.
Polly, I wonder if you would answer that.
I'm going to powder my nose.
Well, what's this?
Looks like another hat.
We have a hat, my lad.
- But I was...
- You must have the wrong address.
Oh, no.
- Who's the hat for?
- A Miss Trixie Lorraine.
It's for Trixie. Let me see it.
Look, isn't this ducky? Look.
- How much?
- It's somewhere...
Let me see the bill.
Bill. Yes, sir.
$75.
Do all hats cost $75?
Now, you dear, sweet man. You are not
going to pay for that. You're not.
Trixie. Come on in, Trixie.
I'm very much afraid I haven't the change.
- How much do you need?
- $5.
You just keep that. Buy yourself a yacht.
But I get so seasick.
Well, thanks.
- Trixie.
- Did you call me, Polly?
Isn't this darling?
Handsome bought it for you.
You sweet lamb.
He shouldn't have paid for it.
Oh, dear. Now he'll think I'm extravagant.
But what a pretty hat.
You do like me in it, don't you?
You know, I think we ought to take a stroll
on Fifth Avenue and look at the shops.
You'd be surprised
how reasonable things are these days.
Come on, J. Lawrence.
I'm a busy man, Miss Parker.
I cannot afford to waste more time
in coming to an understanding with you.
I've been wanting to ask you a question.
Are your eyes hazel?
My eyes?
- Please, Miss Parker.
- They are hazel.
And such nice eyes.
Such a good, kind expression.
- Miss Parker, please.
- Now don't be so formal.
Didn't you promise to call me Polly?
- Polly.
- Thanks.
- I beg your pardon.
- That's all right, Fannykins.
I've got to have another cigarette.
Platinum.
Hello, everybody.
Get her. Just when I was
beginning to have a good time.
Introduce me, won't you?
I thought you'd left.
- Miss Fortune, Mr. Bradford.
- How do you do?
- Charmed.
- You didn't introduce me.
Miss Fortune, this is Mr. Peabody.
- Mr. Peabody.
- Miss Fortune.
My good fortune.
My good man,
are you by any chance punning?
I'm quite a punster.
I get it. I suppose you were a stroke
on your college punsing team.
That's funny. That's very funny.
Miss Fortune, won't you join us?
I'd love to. I'm just in the mood.
- Some champagne?
- Indeed, my doctor recommends it.
- Did you have a mother?
- What?
Whose name was Eunice?
No, I don't think so.
I did have a mother.
Whose name was Gertrude.
- You look like Eunice.
- You do look like Eunice.
What's the matter?
Fay has an attack of chiseling.
It's chronic with her.
Another look at him with those
bedroom eyes and I'll break your leg.
Excuse me for whispering.
Fay and I have so much in common.
Can we have some more champagne?
A quart.
Now I tell you,
there's only one thing to do.
We've got to spend more time here.
We've got to see more of her.
I don't wish to see any more of her.
What I've seen convinces me.
We absolutely must make her think
we're an easy proposition.
- Suckers, you might say.
- What are you shaking your head for?
I'm thinking of the consequences.
I believe...
I can make this girl transfer her affection
from him to me.
- What?
- Don't misunderstand me.
Nothing personal in it.
This girl is smart.
Now what are you shaking your head for?
Are you afraid?
- Afraid of what?
- Well, I confess I'm a little afraid.
That girl is very fascinating.
But we're not boys, are we?
- Well, hardly.
- We're men, aren't we?
And we needn't succumb
to that sort of feminine allure.
- Need we?
- Indeed, we needn't.
- Just because they want something...
we don't have to give in, do we?
No. Not at all.
- Let me have a light, please.
- A light? Certainly.
A light?
Yes.
Where's your lighter?
My lighter?
Where'd you get the lighter?
Fanny gave it to me.
Fanny? This is marvelous.
This is wonderful.
Who's Fanny?
Fanny is Faneuil H. Peabody.
The kind of man I've been looking for,
lots of money and no resistance.
Old Peabody's the family lawyer.
This is great.
Well, I don't think it's so funny.
We must tell Brad's brother the truth.
The truth about what?
The truth about Carol not being me.
No, you've got to go on with it.
He thinks he's pretty darn smart.
Take him for a ride.
You said it. Let's go on playing this game.
Gee, it's for prizes.
Look what I got already:
Gold, platinum, animals.
That's nothing compared to
what I'm going to get out of Fanny.
Well, I don't think it's right.
- It's going to cause Brad more trouble.
- Hey, listen.
I could do something that'd make him
come to Polly on his knees...
and beg her to marry Brad.
- I've got an idea.
- That's right, honey.
"Use well before shaking."
We're going to have
a lot of unnecessary trouble.
But I'd marry Polly
with or without his consent.
- I want to get even with him.
- I want a chauffeur with a car.
I want a chauffeur
with buttons and a uniform.
And I want a dog.
I want a dog named Fanny.
Buy the little doggie for Trixie.
What do you want the beast for?
Then I'll have something
to remember you by.
What name do you wish to engrave
on the collar, madam?
Fanny.
It's not that kind of a dog.
His name is Fanny. It's a pet name.
Every time I look at my dog,
I'll think of you.
Then I'll have two little Fannys.
Here, hold him while I powder my nose.
- Shall we dance?
- Certainly. Why not?
I thought this was my dance.
Sorry, Bob. Why don't you dance
with this nice young lady?
Thanks. I'll dance with whom I please.
- Shall we indulge?
- Why sure, what can I lose?
My brother's jealous.
He has no reason to be.
I am not prepared to say that.
Well, then, I'll say it for you.
You're as light as a heifer, a feather.
You know...
I'm much more
the sort of man for you, Polly.
Yes, you have your good points.
Let's dance, honey.
Don't look at me that way.
He may see you.
Am I registering jealousy or am I not?
No, you're wonderful.
Watch it. Look jealous. Here they come.
Come on, honey. Let's dance.
I bet you think it's bolder,
dancing this way.
I think it's delightful.
- I'm a clumsy soul.
- You're a dear.
- I'm getting old.
- Aren't we all?
Say, I'm a little bit old myself.
You, old? Why,
you're the very personification of youth.
Thanks, but honest,
I don't know what's the matter with me.
I have a yen for a little house
in the country...
and the fireside...
and carpet slippers for the old man.
Who's the old man?
You'd run if I told you.
I couldn't run very far. I'm very fat.
Say, can you imagine me
getting sentimental?
The most hard boiled dame
on the Dirty White Way.
You're not hard boiled.
That's just on the surface.
Underneath, you're...
Say, what do you know
about me underneath?
I mean...
I know what you mean, you old sugar.
You watch out. I'm falling in love with you.
Hello, boy. When love comes at my age...
Guess who?
- It's little Fay.
- Yes.
It's little phooey.
Fay, darling,
I have something to show you.
- Will you excuse us, please?
- Surely.
- Can you see that?
- See what?
Can you read where it says exit?
- Exit.
- You said it.
You start walking, and you keep walking.
And if you ever come near him again,
I'll break both your legs.
- I could easily resent that.
- Scram.
Did little Fay cry out?
No, that must've been
the cornet you heard.
Pardon me, but I think this is my dance.
- I'm so sorry.
- Quite all right.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Yes, beautiful.
You know,
I've been watching you and wondering...
You're so obviously a girl of breeding.
- Who are your people?
- My father?
My father was an official
in the government service.
Her father was a letter carrier.
Mother was an invalid.
Her mother could have
licked John L. Sullivan.
Then how did it happen?
What are you doing in the theater?
Well, you see, it was like this.
I was at finishing school...
when my parents died.
- And they left me...
- An orphan.
Yes, an orphan.
I had to find something to do, earn money.
And all I could find was...
Well, you see?
I do see.
You're the sort of child who...
the sort of girl who...
Not cheap, not vulgar.
Not at all like people in the theater.
You know, you are the girl
my brother should be interested in.
- Well, I don't like that.
- Neither do I.
So we're all too vulgar
for J. Lawrence Bradford.
- No. Not at all.
- All except this nice little girl.
- I'm too cheap and vulgar.
- No. I didn't mean that.
I'm going home. I'm not going to stay
and be insulted like this.
Polly.
I'm getting lonesome.
Polly, you misunderstood me.
I think you're...
Here I am, honey.
I want to make you understand that...
I wouldn't offend you
for anything in the world.
Let's forget it. How about another drink?
Here.
I'll forgive you.
Bottoms up.
I want to say...
About you...
Like me?
Like isn't the word.
It goes deeper than that, Polly.
I don't understand it myself.
- I love you, Polly.
- You're drunk.
- No, I'm not...
- Yes, you are. You're drunk.
I love you, Polly.
You don't mean a word you're saying.
You're just playing, aren't you?
I am, you know.
Stop it.
Oh, you are drunk.
- Who is it?
- It's me, Trixie.
- Where's your key?
- Here it is.
I can't manage it,
my fingers are frostbitten.
- Where'd you leave Fanny?
- I left Fanny behind. He's waiting.
Well, what's the matter with him,
sleeping sickness?
He passed out.
Well, he doesn't have to pass out
all over our lounge.
- Say.
- Say what?
Have I an idea? Ask me, "Have I an idea?"
- Have you an idea?
- Listen.
- We'll stick him into bed, your bed.
- Oh, no, you don't.
Don't get excited. You'll sleep with me.
Then, when he wakes up in the morning...
will we have him where we want him?
Will he do just what we want him to do?
- Ask me, will he?
- I don't like it.
You want to get even with him, don't you?
Yes, I do.
Can't you see,
when he wakes up in the morning...
what will he ask himself?
What would anyone ask himself?
"What has happened?" he will ask himself.
"What am I doing in this girl's bed?"
He will ask himself.
And how many answers are there to that?
You tell me.
Oh, but nothing will have happened.
Of course not, nothing will have happened.
- You said it.
- But he'll think...
Say, you know what he'll feel like?
He'll feel like, what do they call them?
Oh, yes, a cad.
- It's a bet. I'll do it.
- You take his head.
No. You take his head, I'll take his feet.
I don't want to look at him anymore.
Say, you know, I thought you were
getting kind of stuck on him.
Don't be stupid, Trixie.
I was just putting on a good act.
A very good act. You certainly fooled me.
Okay, dearie, here you go to bed.
There, now, my little man.
If you think I've fallen
for that apple-cheeked boyfriend...
I've been chiseling.
Say, you'd be surprised
what plans I have for him.
And will he be surprised.
Say, I'm going to take him
like Graham took Waterloo...
or whatever he took.
And when he
Wakes up in the morning
When he wakes up in the
What's this?
- It can't be. It isn't.
- It is.
- How did he get there?
- He passed out, so we tucked him in.
This is wonderful. This is marvelous.
- I'm afraid we've gone too far.
- Gone too far?
- Yes.
- No, this is only the beginning.
I have to run.
I've something important to attend to.
I'll be back in an hour.
So, my dear brother,
you'll cut off my income, will you?
Won't let me marry Polly, will you?
Well, listen, old fellow,
you don't know it yet...
but you're going to wake up
a kinder and a wiser man.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
- How would you like your eggs?
Where do you think you're going?
Do you think you can do what you did
last night and get away with it?
Ruin a young girl's future
just because she loves you?
I don't know where I am,
or what you're saying.
That's too bad. I'll tell you where you are.
I know where I am, all right.
I mean, figuratively speaking,
I'm confused.
- I don't know what happened.
- Well, I do.
Plenty, brother, plenty.
Tell me...
- now what do you want me to do?
- Sit down.
- How much is it worth to you?
- Worth? What for?
Call it payment for a night's lodging,
if you like.
You don't mean it.
- Polly doesn't know...
- Listen, what do you think Polly is?
I never would have believed it.
But why not? What else could I expect?
You said it. What else?
I know what you need, a pen.
$5,000, is that satisfactory?
What do you think this is, the Mills Hotel?
$10,000, then.
And that's all I'll do.
Well, don't feel generous. It's not so much.
- That's your opinion.
- The pen?
And now, have you any objection
if I go on my way?
Objections? Let me open the door for you.
- Thank you.
- Come back when you can't stay so long.
I've got it.
- Got what?
- Rest your eyes on that.
- What's the matter, isn't it enough?
- I don't want it. I don't want any of it.
Say, what's the matter with you?
I knew it.
You are carrying the torch
for that Back Bay codfish.
I'm not. I hate him.
Sure you do. Why he's got
no more feelings than a hyena.
He has, too.
Don't you talk that way about him.
Why? We've just been playing him
for a sucker. He's just a chump.
He's not a chump.
He's kind, and he's good.
Sure, you hate him, all right.
No, I don't. I love him.
I've never felt so happy in all my life.
I've got a confession to make.
Well?
Well...
Last night...
I told Miss Lorraine, Trixie...
that I cared for her deeply...
and she admitted
an equal affection for me.
For the first time in my life, true love...
real love, with a real woman.
Look. Look at that.
- I've been tricked.
- You certainly have.
That's the girl.
That's the girl
Robert planned to marry all along.
The one I intended to save him from.
There's no doubt about it.
They've certainly made a fool of you.
- What about you?
- Who, me? Well, I...
Did you know?
If you knew, why didn't you tell me?
What do you think
I brought you along for, anyway?
To heave ponderous,
ridiculous sighs at that giraffe?
Who are you calling a giraffe, sir?
- I've a suspicion it's the woman I love.
- You love.
You give me a pain.
You're coming along with me.
- I'll show them I'm not such an easy mark.
- Where to?
To that woman's house.
The one who posed as Polly Parker,
who led me on.
I'm not going with you. I can't.
- Why?
- Well...
I have a dinner engagement.
- A conference.
- All right, I'll go by myself.
But I'll show her.
But I never said
your brother wanted to marry me...
and I never said my name is Polly.
- I took that for granted.
- You take too darn much for granted.
- I'll ask you to return my check, please.
- Your check?
That's on exhibition
over there on the wall.
I knew you'd probably stop payment on it.
- I'll take the necessary steps...
- You'll do what?
Listen, you made a sap out of yourself...
and you tried your best
to make a sap out of me.
Now I never want to see you again,
understand?
And as for your check...
Well, you don't think I hold myself
as cheaply as all that, do you?
- Cheaply? $10,000?
- That's your estimate of me, not mine.
That check is framed, not cashed.
I put it there to remind me...
never to get mixed up
with your kind again.
Now get out, will you, please? Get out.
No, I will not get out.
- You must.
- No, I will not.
Not until I've told you what I think of you.
Don't you dare. Get out.
I was drunk the last time. I'm not now.
I mean it. I love you, Polly.
- My name's not Polly.
- Whatever your name is.
Carol, that's my name.
Cheap and vulgar Carol.
Daughter of a Brooklyn saloon keeper
and a woman who took in washing.
Carol, the torch singer at Coney Island,
cheap and vulgar.
Every time you say cheap and vulgar,
I'm going to kiss you.
Cheap and vulgar.
I didn't mean to fall in love with you.
I was only playing a game.
I didn't mean to fall in love
with you, either.
I was trying to play
a little game myself.
You're going to forgive Brad and Polly,
aren't you?
- No, I'm not.
- But you must.
- Lf they're married...
- They are.
- They phoned me from the city hall.
- I'll have their marriage annulled.
- But you said...
- I don't care what I said.
I was confused, upset.
Maybe you're confused about us.
No, that's one thing I'm sure about.
But their marriage is off, definitely off.
Well, then so is ours.
- You mean you won't marry me?
- I certainly do.
- I'm late. The show. Sorry.
- Polly...
- See you later.
- Carol.
You haven't told me.
We've got to settle this. Carol.
Shadows on the wall
I can see them fall
Here and there
Everywhere
Silhouettes in blue
Dancing in the dew
Here am I
Where are you?
In the shadows
let me come and sing to you
Let me dream a song
that I can bring to you
Take me in your arms
and let me cling to you
Let me linger long
Let me live my song
In the winter
let me bring the spring to you
Let me feel that I mean everything to you
Love's old song will be new
In the shadows
when I come and sing to you
let me come and sing to you
Let me dream a song
that I can bring to you
Take me in your arms
and let me cling to you
Let me linger long
Let me live my song, dear one
In the winter
let me bring the spring to you
Let me feel that I mean everything to you
Love's old song will be new
In the shadows
when I come and sing to you, dear
When I come and sing to you
In the shadows
let me come and sing to you
Let me dream a song
that I can bring to you
Take me in your arms
and let me cling to you
Let me linger long
Let me live my song
Let me bring the spring to you
I'll mean everything to you
- Love's old song
- Will be new
In the shadows
when I come and sing to you
In the winter
let me bring the spring to you
Let me feel that I mean everything to you
Love's old song will be new
In the shadows
when I come and sing to you, dear
In the shadows when I come and sing
On stage.
Hurry up, boys. Snap it up, will you?
On stage, Forgotten Man number.
Forgotten Man number,
everybody on stage.
Come on, girls, make it snappy.
Forgotten Man number, on stage.
- All right, girls, on stage.
- Forgotten Man number.
On stage, Forgotten Man number.
All right, Miss Carol,
Forgotten Man number.
- Congratulate us. We are man and wife.
- You're not.
- I ought to know, I'm the bride.
- Trixie, I'm so glad.
- We're married, too.
- My heartiest congratulations.
- Same to you, Peabody.
- Isn't it wonderful?
- At my age?
- At any age.
Come on, honey.
- Hello.
I got him signed, sealed, and delivered.
Good girl. Keep him close to home.
Here, wait a minute.
I understand you two are married.
- I'm going to have it annulled.
- You can't annul our marriage.
Not yours, stupid, his.
- You can't do that.
- Yes, I can.
You've interfered enough. We're married,
and we're going to stay married.
Today you asked me to marry you.
- He did?
- Yes, he did.
Yes, I proposed, and I was sincere.
If you do this to Polly and Brad...
I wouldn't marry you
if you were the last man on Earth.
I told you that once, and I meant it.
Much as I love you,
nevertheless, I am determined...
to look after my brother's interests,
whether he likes it or not.
Arrest him. You have a warrant. Perjury.
Falsification of age
in obtaining a marriage license.
You can't hold me on that.
Technically, we can,
pending an investigation.
Brad, what are we going to do?
What's holding up the show?
Do you want to ruin me?
My brother just had me arrested
for getting married.
Arrested? Where's the cop?
Here he is. Detective Jones.
Detective, my eye. He's a ham actor.
That's no way to speak of an artist.
Why, I've played with Sir Henry Irving...
George Arliss, and David Warfield.
Scram. You're a washout.
You've been playing cops on Broadway
for 25 years.
- Snitch.
- Get out there and do your number.
Is everybody nutty?
- Here.
- What's this?
I'm sure Carol will endorse it to you
for a wedding present.
$10,000. What a brother.
You mean, what a sister-in-law.
You mean, what a Fanny.
I don't know
if he deserves a bit of sympathy.
Forget your sympathy.
It's all right with me.
I was satisfied to drift along
from day to day...
till they came and took my man away.
"Remember my forgotten man
"You put a rifle in his hand
"You sent him far away
"You shouted, 'Hip, hooray! '
"But look at him today!
"Remember my forgotten man
"You had him cultivate the land
"He walked behind a plow
The sweat fell from his brow
"But look at him right now!
"And once he used to love me
"I was happy then
"He used to take care of me
"Won't you bring him back again?
"'Cause ever since the world began
"A woman's got to have a man
"Forgetting him, you see
"Means you're forgetting me
"Like my
"My forgotten man"
Remember my forgotten man
You put a rifle in his hand
You sent him far away
You shouted, "Hip, hooray!"
But look at him today!
Remember my forgotten man
You had him cultivate the land
He walked behind a plow
The sweat fell from his brow
But look at him right now!
And once, he used to love me
I was happy then
He used to take care of me
Won't you bring him back again?
'Cause ever since the world began
A woman's got to have a man
Forgetting him, you see
Means you're forgetting me
Like my forgotten man
We are the real forgotten men
Who have to lead this life again
We sauntered forth to fight
For glory was our pride
But somehow glory died
Remember your forgotten men
You've got to let us live again
We came, we marched away
To fight for USA
But where are we today?
And once, he used to love me
I was happy then
He used to take care of me
Won't you bring him back again?
'Cause ever since the world began
A woman's got to have a man
Forgetting him, you see
Means you're forgetting me
Like my forgotten man
English