We can't remain locked here.
You have to let us out.
You know very well we were supposed
to be jailed for just one night
and we've been
here three days already.
Well, yeah. But what do you
want me to do?
The mayor is the only one
who could release you.
And now there's no way.
He's away visiting the oil fields.
So until he's back,
you'll have to stick around.
If he went to the oil fields,
he won't be back.
Well, who knows.
My brother-in-law
has been there a month now
and he's making a lot of money.
In his last letter
he says the oil companies
pay $20 to $30 dollars a day.
No way.
Did you hear that?
$20 to $30 dollars a day.
We should've been there three days ago,
making that money.
I know that song by heart, already.
Stop saying it.
I'm the one to blame.
But where have you ever seen
that saying something nice
to a woman is a crime?
Saying something nice is not a crime.
But punching her husband in the eye
won't make the town
embrace you as a son.
Go to bed now.
You won't rot in jail after all.
You have to hurry up.
I should leave you here. That'll teach
you not to get us in trouble.
You're always complaining.
Now listen boys.
Soon we'll all be out of here.
It's best not to want to escape.
It's best not
to want anything.
You just go with your friend. I hope
soon you'll get wherever you want to go.
But you have to come, too. Or they will
accuse you of aiding us to escape
and throw more jail time at you.
Even better. Where else will people
feed you for doing nothing?
Well, you may be right, Tubio.
Okay, now everybody
mind their own business.
Let's go.
Hey, you think we
will fit there?
I will. Let's see if you can.
I'll wait for you at the oil fields.
See you later.
THE NATIONAL
HELP WANTED
- Mr. José Enrique.
- What's up, Heriberto?
Nothing, boss. I just came to see
if you had any job for me.
- Nothing, as you can see.
- Jesus.
If I was you, I wouldn't let those
assholes do what they want, boss.
If you need me,
just let me know.
Thanks, Heriberto.
If I only had
a few resolved men,
you bet the oil wells
of The National would be producing.
Ay, Chihuahua.
When it rains, it pours.
Last time I got paid was on
my saint's day, wasn't it, boss?
Jesus, how slowly
a whole month goes by.
- Aren't we in dire straits?
- Worst than dire straits, boss.
Here's a few dollars.
- It may help you a bit.
- Thanks.
I wish I could walk into Rayado now
with all his white guards,
to see who's the man.
I'll see you later.
Now I'm very busy.
Little Rayado,
he can no longer walk
Because his father,
because his father...
I see you're happy, my friend.
What are you doing here?
Just passing by.
Make sure you're not passing
with a couple of bullets. You hear me?
Just let me go. I'm a man of peace.
I don't want no trouble.
You know that working here
is forbidden?
Working? I just came
to say hi to the boss.
Okay. But nobody mocks
orders by El Rayado.
Understood?
Is José Enrique there?
Yes... yes, Mr. Fabio.
But he's very busy now.
Good morning,
Mr. José Enrique.
Hello, Mr. Fabio.
I was in the neighborhood
and I thought I'd come and greet you.
And to insist that I sell you
the oil wells, right?
Look, Mr. José Enrique.
I come here as a friend
in order to help you
get out of this tight spot.
The National will never work.
Stop deceiving yourself and sell those
three wells once and for all.
They're doubling the offer and
that's a lot of money, Mr. Enrique.
So you're advising me to sell.
Naturally. You and I
are both practical men
and we both know who's
the real boss.
Yes, they're tough.
For a month now they've not allowed
anybody to get hired here.
It must be that no one
wants to work here.
Workers make
too many demands now.
Enough of this, Mr. Fabio.
See those wells? I'm ready
to blow them up
if I'm not allowed to work.
Aren't you overreacting a bit?
No, sir.
I've made my decision.
Nobody will make me
change my mind.
Tell it to whoever sent you
here to threaten me.
All right, Mr. José Enrique.
You know what you're doing.
I already did my part
as a friend.
Goodbye,
Mr. José Enrique.
I hope you find workers.
The ball is spinning.
All bets are off.
Red 27.
Ay, Chihuahua.
When you're having bad luck,
better to start selling beans.
Don't lose heart.
I once won
after losing all night long.
How did you do it, Nanette?
After I lost everything,
- the casino burnt down.
- Jesus.
Everybody ran away.
I took the money.
It was a Friday the 13th.
I remember it perfectly.
13? Then, I'll play the 26,
because it's two 13s.
Let's see if the casino
burns down meanwhile.
All bets are off.
Leave it, blondie.
I saw you.
Jesus, Nanette.
You never change.
You're the worst thief
in the oil fields.
A thief, no. The doctor says
I have an illness
called "kleptomania."
"Keptomania"?
"Kleptomania".
Whatever.
I'm so broke and you're so sick.
Okay, we'll leave it as it is.
- Thank you, my friend.
- You're welcome.
I was just standing here, so...
Let me buy you a drink.
Heriberto Malo.
Gerardo Ramirez, nice to meet you.
He's my friend...
- Demetrio Garcia.
- Nice to meet you. You're invited, too.
- Thank you.
- Here, take these two chips to play.
And find a cure for that ugly
"keptomania" of yours.
I like to see you with
so much energy, Heriberto.
I like energetic men.
The ball is spinning.
Have you been long
here at the oil fields?
- Two days.
- Two days that seem like 20.
Why?
Because we spent
all four dollars we had
- to pay for our first and only meal.
- Jesus.
The ball is spinning.
Three rums.
To think that we believed
that bums became millionaires here.
And we haven't found
even a miserable job.
Do you know of any work
we can do around here, my friend?
Anything.
We have no pretenses.
What a coincidence.
My boss is looking for workers.
He's from Argentina
and a wonderful man.
But his wells are not working.
Now, the job has its risks.
But... it's legal, right?
Legal and very legit. But they are
threatening whoever works there.
Oh, yeah? So, what he needs
is to find more workers.
Well, I'll take care of that
and let's see who says otherwise.
Jesus. If that happens,
my boss will be so happy.
- And what can you do?
- I'm a mechanic.
A mechanic. A man.
And another man,
if I may say so.
Jesus, my friends.
You've made your fortune already.
- Bottoms up. Cheers.
- Cheers.
Remember what you told me
this morning, Mr. José Enrique?
Well, here's what you need.
These folks are looking for a job.
They know what it's about
and they're ready to
do anything.
With me, you already have
three men to start the work,
even if it's little by little.
Take a seat.
Where were you before
arriving at the oil fields?
You say before arriving
at the oil fields?
Well, we went
to several places.
Last place we stayed
was a jail.
What? It's true.
Nothing we can do about it.
Nothing significant.
You know how boys are.
After all, I'm in no position to ask you
for recommendation letters
and I trust you.
I like your honesty.
- Naturally.
- I have to warn you:
whoever works at The National
is under threats.
This is not like any other job.
If you want, while I prepare the pumps,
Gerardo can go out to hire more people.
If it's no more than that, I'm ready
to fight anybody.
- I've been in worse situations before.
- You risk your skin here.
It will last me until it's
time to go.
Then, go ahead.
Now everybody
go mind their jobs.
Let's play with all our hearts.
Now you're talking. A man has to do
what a man has to do,
as they say in my country.
You'll see, Mr. Enrique.
Together we'll be unbeatable.
The National
Don't ask for employment.
No more jobs available.
Next.
Ready.
For the success of your efforts,
Mr. José Enrique.
And for all the help
you've given me.
Well, I think they won't be able
to stop us now.
How furious they must be,
because we hit them really hard.
Remind me to telegraph my sister
tomorrow, to cancel her trip.
Yes, boss.
I didn't know you had
a little sister.
Is she coming here?
Yes. She tells me in this letter
she'll arrive in eight days.
As soon as her contract ends
in Mexico.
Her contract?
What does she do?
She's a performer.
If she comes,
you won't be so lonely.
That's what I thought, too.
But in this situation, it will be crazy
to bring her to live here with me.
You've already seen
how many difficulties we've had
and the risks we've taken.
How long has it been since
you saw her last?
When I left Buenos Aires,
she was just a kid.
I thought of bringing her
to live with me some day.
I established myself here
and put my mind on the job.
Her letters to me
never stopped,
always written
with the same affection.
Listen to this one.
"I'm so happy that I'm going to see
again that brother
who seemed to exist
only in my imagination.
You can never forget the land
where you were born, Mr. José Enrique.
No, you never forget.
Sometimes I feel as if
I never left it.
As if I can still smell its air.
It's a natural thing.
Leaving your land far behind
makes you love it even more.
Yours must be a great country,
isn't it, Mr. José Enrique?
From the distance, it seems to me
the greatest of them all.
Well done, Heriberto.
I think you had a good idea.
Well done, Gerardo,
well done.
Thank you very much,
Mr. José Enrique.
I'll keep you in mind
next time.
Well, if we want to pump oil tomorrow
at 8:00, we better go back to work.
Yes. That's the most important thing:
that the wells start producing tomorrow.
But don't forget tonight you're invited
to celebrate our success.
I can't, Mr. José Enrique.
I have the night shift.
- If you want, I can...
- You stay here to help me.
Some other time, then.
Gerardo will come with me.
He has nothing to do here.
We'll pay a visit to
Mr. Fabio's casino
and see what kind of face
he makes when he sees me.
Lucky at gambling,
unlucky in love.
Didn't I tell you?
Mr. José Enrique is
very drunk already, boss.
Hey, my friend,
bring us more champagne.
You'll have to forgive me, Mr. José
Enrique, but I can't drink any more.
We have to be happy, Gerardo.
After so many bad days,
you need something
to look forward to.
Do as he says, Gerardo.
You only live once.
- José Enrique.
- Camelia.
I thought you wouldn't
remember me.
I always remember you.
I'm glad you could come.
Take a seat and have a drink.
My friend, Gerardo Ramirez.
Camelia, the nicest of all dancers.
Nice to meet you.
- You used to visit me more often.
- You know you're my favorite one.
A great success for you
and some room in your heart for me.
Not just some room. If you knew
how much I like you.
And how much I like you,
José Enrique.
The 11th commandment:
you should not intrude.
I'll buy you a drink at the bar.
Thank you, Gerardo.
How nice.
I notice something strange
about you tonight, Camelia.
Strange, what?
I don't know. I saw it in your eyes
when you came to the table.
Well, I don't want you
to get emotional.
The important thing is that we're
together and we'll be very happy.
Right?
- Get her out of here.
- Throw that old woman outside.
- The Northern Song.
Brutes.
They prefer the worst song
to that beautiful waltz.
Everybody likes only
what moves them inside.
It's true. But I just get
moved by romantic things,
very romantic things.
Yeah? Well, whenever
you feel romantic, let me know.
Heriberto. What a cute name.
I like him because he reminds me
of a great love of mine.
A cook in the foreign legion,
in Morocco.
Have you been in Morocco?
He looked so much
like Heriberto.
It was his fault I got fat;
he made me eat at all times.
One day, we went out on a date
and he said to me,
"Nanette, you're
the most virginal
of all women."
I couldn't resist
and I cried.
When I met him, I was single
and didn't have any money.
He said, "Nanette, you're
the most beautiful
of all women".
What could I do?
I ran away with him.
He looked so much
like Heriberto.
On a July 14, I went to Argel
with a captain.
And the cook found me
on the train.
I didn't want to do it,
but the captain convinced me
saying we had to celebrate
the storming of the Bastille.
But the cook was not
into parties.
He looked so angry, that I felt
like covering him with kisses.
He said, "Nanette, you're the
most wretched of all women".
Well, he didn't exactly put it like
that. He just told me I was a...
C'mon boys.
Time for you to go home.
- Let's go.
Let's sleep it off
somewhere else.
Excuse me, my friend, have you seen
Mr. Jose Enrique Irigoyen?
From The National?
He left a long time ago.
- Nanette.
- Gerardo. You're still here?
Give me back my tie jewel.
What's a tie jewel?
What you stole from here
a while ago.
- Gerardo.
- Give it to me.
Well, don't be like that.
It was just a joke.
Yeah, but between jokes
I've already lost many.
That's why Heriberto says
you have an ugly "keptomania".
"Kleptomania".
Good night, blondie.
Nobody knows anything.
Keep looking for him.
He must be somewhere.
The earth
didn't swallow him.
What a coincidence. The very day
we were going to start pumping oil.
Maybe he was so drunk, he's still
sleeping it off at some hotel.
We have to find him,
wherever he is.
Hey, boys.
Let's move. Search for him
in the oil fields.
- Yes, sir.
- And you, check all the hotels.
And you boys, go across the river.
Who knows if you'll find him there.
- Okay, sir.
- Let's go.
- We're going to the police.
- The police? What for?
In the oil fields there's no more police
than the white guards.
We'll go, anyway.
You stay here just in case.
Let's go, boys.
- Sorry to bother you.
- Not at all. Tell me.
It's about Mr. José Enrique.
He's nowhere to be found.
We just went to the
police to make a report.
Impossible. He must
be somewhere.
Or maybe he went out on a trip.
He couldn't just disappear.
Well, yes, but the fact remains that we
looked everywhere and he's not there.
He was last seen
going up to your room.
Yes, but he later went home.
He was too dizzy.
- So, you don't know anything either?
- Absolutely nothing.
I assure you I'm very
upset now.
Please let me know
if you have any news.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
DISAPPEARANCE OF MR. JOSE ENRIQUE
STILL A MYSTERY
Believed to have suffered an accident
when he couldn't be found
What's wrong with you?
Are you polishing my boots
or reading the newspaper?
- I'm already done, boss.
- "I'm already done, boss".
What happened?
Since he has been
missing for eight days now,
the police gave up
the investigation.
What about the other thing?
They've just read
Mr. José Enrique's will.
- Oh, yeah?
- And he named a sister living abroad
as the sole beneficiary.
Do you know what he did
while he was still alive?
He appointed a temporary manager
to run the oil wells.
A temporary manager?
Who?
Who do you think he is, boss?
Demetrio. Isn't that funny?
- The mechanic?
- Yes,
the one who talks like this.
Poor guy. Anyway, I'm sorry
for him because this one doesn't care.
What the heck
could The National mean for him?
- As if he was its owner.
- Let's go, Jeronimo.
Heriberto. Come here.
Here. Read this.
I don't know what we are going to do.
"I arrive today. Mexico train.
Kisses. Mercedes."
The boss' sister.
She's chosen the worst
time to come.
Mr. José Enrique didn't want
her to come.
Yes, but the boss didn't have time
to send her the telegram.
We have to take care of her.
She's the boss now.
Gerardo, you know about women.
You'll have to welcome her.
- I have work to do.
- Me? I don't even know her.
It doesn't matter. Tell her what
happened to José Enrique.
She must understand
this is no place for her.
And how the hell do you
expect me to know who she is?
It's very easy, brother.
You know she's from Argentina.
You just pay attention,
and when you hear
"Che", well that's the one, brother.
Look what I get.
"Che", not even one luggage
carrier in this station?
- I was looking for you.
- For me?
- I don't think we know each other.
- I don't have the pleasure yet,
but I've come to welcome you.
- You're very kind.
- I should have started by saying
I'm here on behalf of
Mr. José Enrique.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yes. He couldn't do it himself.
- Follow me, please.
- Hey.
Well done, Raquela. You just got here
and made friends already.
Did you see that, Mercedes?
He thought I was you.
- Who's that man?
- I don't know.
Your brother sent him.
How strange that José Enrique
didn't come himself.
- Surely you'll see him later.
- Yes, something must have held him.
Let's go then. That nice boy
is waiting for us.
When will you be able to see
a man without losing your head?
Move.
Here goes the cart.
- This girl comes with you?
- Yes, she's with me, she's my friend.
Ms. Raquela Ortiz.
Gerardo Ramirez,
at your service.
Please, follow me.
This one is the largest one
and it has a view of Main Square.
You've been lucky
to find a room available.
It's easier to become
a millionaire in the oil fields,
than to get a room in a hotel.
- Oh, it's here.
- This is the other one, miss.
Can I have a word
with you, miss?
I didn't dare to tell this to
Ms. Mercedes. I'd rather tell it to you.
- What is it about?
- I'll explain it to you.
Come in.
You were saying?
Mr. José Enrique has been
missing for eight days now.
Missing? What are you saying?
- We don't know where he is, miss.
- Impossible.
Unfortunately, that's the way it is.
All our efforts to find him
have failed and
we fear the worst.
If that's true,
what are the police doing?
The police don't know
anything either.
It's impossible that
no one knows anything.
I assure you we did everything
we could, miss.
José Enrique.
And who are you?
We are kind of his heirs now.
Well, not the heirs exactly.
The people in charge of the business,
that's what I meant.
How could this have happened?
A man can not disappear
in a city, like a suitcase.
How did he disappear?
Where?
We don't know. Last time
I saw him was in Gulf's casino.
The Grand Casino. He was a bit drunk and
he went up to Camelia's room.
Camelia?
Who's Camelia?
She's a dancer at the casino.
I met her that night,
and I don't know anything else
about her.
I saw them going up the stairs,
and since then
Mr. José Enrique became
invisible as the eyes of an ant.
Mr. José Enrique had decided
his sister wouldn't come here.
You haven't even
been informed.
Because my friend's brother wanted
to bring her here to live with him.
For her own good, convince her
to get away from the oil fields.
Why are you so interested
in seeing her leave?
Me? You're wrong, miss.
I'm not interested in having
her stay or leave.
Tell Ms. Mercedes
that I'm at her service.
And yours, too.
Who can get mad
at a such a pretty woman?
What's wrong?
Mercedes, what happened?
José Enrique is missing.
Probably he got himself killed.
Killed? Are you crazy?
That man just told me that.
- What did he tell you?
- That he has just disappeared.
Ah, that doesn't mean
he was killed.
Calm down, Mercedes.
We have to think straight.
Think straight.
We have to do something.
First, we have to confirm it. And if
it's true, it will be better for you
- not to stay here.
- How can I leave after learning this?
We could see later
what can be done.
No, no, Raquela. You go. Your ship
leaves tomorrow and you can't miss it.
I'll stay here.
You can't stay by yourself.
You don't know anybody here
and you can also be in danger.
In spite of everything, I'll stay.
That man mentioned
a dancer from the casino.
He said José Enrique was
with her before he disappeared.
I'll go see him and
get the truth out of her.
Whoever she is, she won't be
so stupid as to implicate herself.
Do what I say, Mercedes.
They'll know you're
José Enrique's sister
and you won't find anything.
You made sure nobody
knows who I am.
Can we talk to
Ms. Mercedes Irigoyen?
Mercedes Irigoyen?
Let me check.
Oh, yeah. One of the
two Argentinean girls, right?
- Yes.
- They both left already.
You mean they left the oil fields?
Yes, sir. They said they will board
the South American ship.
The one that left 2 hours ago.
Well, that's the best
that could have happened.
- Could I see the boss?
- Mr. Fabio won't be late.
Thanks. I'll wait for him.
- What?
- That's not the right lyrics.
I'm sure it's the way I sing it.
The cook from the
Foreign Legion was in Argentina
and he used to sing this song.
Whatever. But the song
says another thing.
- It says what I sing.
- It does not. The lyrics are different.
The lady is right.
It should be "caracanfunfa".
I was sure it said that.
You've been to Argentina, right?
- I'm Argentinean.
- Anyway, you sing it horribly.
Are you going to teach me
how to sing an Argentinean tango?
Let's hear what she thinks about it,
since she's from there.
- You know how it goes, right?
- Yes.
- Are you a singer?
- Then, show us how it goes.
- No, not now.
- Why not?
- Because I'm waiting for the boss.
It doesn't matter. Sing it.
Leave her alone. She doesn't look
the type who sings tangos.
Maybe she just knows
how to sing in church.
You think so?
Please, maestro,
play it for me.
Very well, miss.
You sing it wonderfully.
I'm the owner of this casino.
Nice to meet you.
Raquela Ortiz.
Did you come to the oil fields
to work as a performer?
I'm just passing through. I'll be here
only a few days, but I'd like to work.
Consider yourself hired,
Miss Raquela.
Thanks.
I'll assure you my customers
will be happy to see you,
when they see you
and listen to your singing.
- Don't worry about the conditions.
- You won't regret it.
This is what's best
about the oil fields.
- Where do you come from?
- Now, from Mexico.
But I'm actually in a tour
out of Buenos Aires.
Hey, Camelia. Camelia.
- What do you want?
- Take this girl upstairs, to number 9.
- All right, Mr. Fabio.
- I believe you'll like the room.
- Let's go upstairs.
- Make yourself at home.
Camelia will tell you
all you need to know about it.
You know I'm the kind of man
that when I say, let's work, I mean it.
But tonight is tonight.
It seems to me
the new manager of The National
gets drunk even with lemonade.
That man doesn't exactly
look like a genius.
The National gets
worse every day.
Good evening.
Would you be so kind as to have
a word with me, Mr. Demetrio?
Listen, Gerardo.
Don't you think
Mr. Fabio is onto something?
Yes. But some people
don't always get what they want.
- What would he want Demetrio for?
- I don't know.
But don't worry.
Demetrio is not a kid.
We'd talk better inside.
You tell me here
what you want to tell me.
I've heard you'll start
working tomorrow,
and I just wanted
to give some advice.
Don't be a fool.
Mr. José Enrique thought
he was better than the rest of us.
He didn't heed the warnings
of his friends.
You're a man of experience.
What do you get by getting into trouble?
Take advantage of this opportunity
and sell those wells.
Did you finish already?
I want you to understand,
Mr. Demetrio.
I have nothing to do
with this matter.
But I wouldn't like to see you
getting a headache over this.
Look, Mr. Fabio. Where I come
from we have a saying,
we can tell the kind bird
from afar.
So, you see.
If you're interested,
we'll start pumping tomorrow at 8:00.
Nice to see you, Mr. Manager.
Why so serious?
To hell with business,
let's have fun, okay?
I'm afraid I drank too much.
What you drank without me
doesn't count.
So, clean slate,
let's start from scratch.
- What's your name, doll?
- Camelia.
- Are you Camelia?
- I like to be with a serious man.
And so handsome.
- Would you dare?
- Let's go, then.
- Where's Heriberto?
- He's trying his luck at the roulette.
Let's see if he hits the jackpot,
like I did.
- You two talked a long time.
- Yeah.
- What did he want?
- Nothing.
Stop drinking now.
You had enough already.
This is a new countdown.
Don't you see Camelia and I
are having fun?
Leave him alone.
He's not used to drinking.
Didn't you hear
what the kid said?
That's envy. Show him how you
can drink more than all the boys.
Sure. I'll hold more
than him, at the very least.
I liked you since the first
time I saw you.
How lucky I am I came
to the casino tonight.
You had to come, because
someone was expecting you.
I finally learned how
they sing in heaven.
I imagined you would be far
from the oil fields by now.
- And Ms. Mercedes?
- She left.
So you've been left here alone.
What a pity.
Would you join me at my table?
After all we're old acquaintances,
you could say.
- What are you thinking about?
- That I'll accept your invitation.
- What do you drink?
- Thanks, nothing for me.
As you wish.
Since last night it seems as if
you have something against me.
- Why, Raquela?
- I hardly know you.
I assure you I have no other intention
than to take care of you.
Besides, I like you.
That's the truth.
Last night you told me you were one
of the people in charge of The National,
- right?
- Well, the one in charge is Demetrio.
- He's the General Manager.
- Manager?
Who named him to manage
what is not his?
Whoever that was, it doesn't matter.
Let's talk about something else.
About you.
I'm asking you who
appointed him.
Every time I see you
I like you more.
Don't be a spitfire and let me
show you that I am your friend.
You're all by yourself here,
and that's not good.
Do you know why you remained
in the oil fields?
Because it was God's will
that we met.
Would you come
to my table, Raquela?
I believe the lady is with me.
We haven't finish talking yet.
And I won't leave the casino
without telling you all
I have to tell you.
What are you doing here?
Get out or I'll call someone
to throw you out.
- Please, be quiet.
- I told you to get out.
- Look, miss, please...
- Mr. Fab...
Raquela?
Raquela.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I thought you were alone.
Angered I like you even more,
I tell you.
Enough.
Now you're gonna listen to me.
You're under arrest, son.
Raquela.
I knew something was wrong.
Calm down, take it easy.
Calm down. Calm down.
No, miss. Not you.
He's all mine.
What are you doing, stupid?
I've told you many time
I don't want any trouble here.
Okay boss.
I'm just a simple man
doing his job.
That cretin is not worthy
of a single bullet.
Throw him out in the alley. If he shows
up again here at the casino,
kill him like a dog.
God help you if I see you again.
You're a dead man.
Get out or I'll shoot you even
if the boss doesn't want me to do it.
Please, Raquela, calm down.
I beg your forgiveness.
It was all my fault,
for not taking precautions.
I should have known sooner
or later some cretin
would try to bother you.
A wretch like that. And I believe
he's even more than a wretch.
Unfortunately, there are plenty
of bandits and killers here, Raquela.
Make no mistake,
he's one of them
and he came here
just looking for you.
That's what I thought at first, too.
But now, I'm not sure.
Everything seems very odd.
Anyway, I'll say it again:
this won't happen again.
Excuse me, I'll go now.
Have a good rest.
Thank you.
- Any more news, Rayado?
- Nothing, boss.
But since I'm on my day off,
I decided to check with you, Mr. Fabio.
You know what I mean.
Yes. Go see the cashier
and get your money.
- What about that guy?
- We kicked him out.
He's certainly stubborn.
I'll have to be alert.
- He won't go far.
- We should teach him once and for all.
We'll see. If he ever again sets a foot
in the casino, he'll regret it.
Won't he try to turn on
the Argentinean's oil wells?
Well, who knows.
What if we play the same joke on him
that we played on Mr. José Enrique?
The same one we just played
on the other guy from The National?
Okay, boss, I was just saying.
What happened last night
with Gerardo?
They told me he came
into your room and got out of line?
- He seemed so nice.
- Do you know that man?
Yes, a little bit. I suppose
he got fresh with you.
Who is he?
I only spoke twice with him.
He's a close friend of Heriberto.
Well, I know something else.
I think he likes you.
He told me so himself.
Also, Mr. Fabio is almost
in love with you.
If you put your mind to it,
he'll be putty in your hands.
- Nanette, excuse me for a second.
- Heriberto, what happened to you?
- Where's Camelia?
- Camelia is not here. She went out.
- See you later.
- Heriberto.
Come. I wanna talk to you.
Demetrio was murdered here last night.
We're completely sure of that.
We haven't seen him since.
- Killed here, in the casino?
- Yes, here.
The same way my boss Mr. José Enrique
was killed here before.
And the same way
they'll try to kill Gerardo,
for being the new General Manager
of The National.
If he's so dumb to get inside
this cave of thieves again.
Are you sure of
what you're saying?
Look, miss, you better
shut your mouth.
Heriberto.
It's hard to believe that behind
this angelic face hides so much evil.
Last night, you stopped Gerardo
from saving Demetrio
and surely you knew he was getting
murdered somewhere inside the casino.
Upstairs. What else would you expect
from an intimate friend of Mr. Fabio?
Heriberto, wait.
Wait, Heriberto.
Leave me alone. If you were not so
stupid, you could be of some use.
Get out of my way.
Tell the boys to go home.
Just keep the guards here.
Okay, Mr. Gerardo.
You take turns
every eight hours.
Anybody tries to get close,
you shoot them.
Yes, sir.
Everything is ready to start
pumping oil tomorrow at 8:00.
Poor Demetrio, he won't see the black
geyser springing up from these towers.
And we probably won't either.
We ran out of dynamite, and we're just
halfway through the field, Mr. Gerardo.
- Okay, you two go get more dynamite.
- Yes, sir.
Go with them, Heriberto.
What are you going to do?
You have to be careful, Gerardo.
What needs to happen
will happen.
Listen, if I'm not back by 5:00 am,
blow up the wells.
How am I supposed
to wait until 5:00 am
doing nothing,
knowing you're risking your life?
- Let me go with you.
- You'll do as I said, Heriberto.
At 5:00 am,
if I haven't come back.
I'll see you later, and if you want
we can leave the oil fields.
Leaving the oil fields? Look,
Gerardo, you know how much
I respect you and how
fond I'm of you,
but I'd rather stay here.
I was born here, and I don't think
I could live anywhere else.
In case we don't
see each other again...
Now go fetch the dynamite.
There's a lady in the office
who wants to talk to you.
With me, a lady?
Who?
- She didn't tell me her name.
- That's odd.
What are you doing here?
What do you want?
You better leave immediately.
Listen to me. I'm here because I have a
serious matter to talk about with you.
Now I know I was wrong. And I beg you
to forgive me for suspecting
you were responsible for the death
of my brother.
- Your brother?
- Yes.
I'm Mercedes Irigoyen.
You?
What kind of trick is this?
It's not a trick. You confused
my friend with me
and I took advantage of that
to stay here incognito.
That's why you treated
Mr. José Enrique's friends so poorly?
I already told you
I didn't know.
I just found the truth last night.
- What truth?
- About Mr. Fabio and everything.
I still don't get why you let all those
thugs jump on top of me if you knew it.
I learned it after they
threw you out.
It's okay. In that case,
there's no need for explanations.
And I'm the one
to ask you to forgive me.
Now I know how much I owe you.
I can't thank you enough.
You owe me nothing, miss.
All this is yours and you're my boss.
I'm at your service.
Dynamite?
Your brother ordered us
to blow up the wells
before giving them away
to that gang of thieves.
I was ready to execute his will.
Now, you tell me.
You do whatever is best.
Poor José Enrique.
I was so eager to see him again.
- You were old friends, right?
- Not exactly.
We knew him a few days
before it happened
and we became very
good friends.
If we could read it in the eyes
when someone really loves us.
Sometimes it's hard to know when
something unites us.
I should have understood
it all after you first talked to me.
And I should've tried to make
you understand.
We are both a bit guilty, right?
We were both walking on the same
path without realizing it.
I couldn't have imagined
before coming to the oil fields
that I would be involved
in all this.
And that I'd meet you.
Me neither. I came to see my brother,
to get together with him,
and now you see.
Here we are, you and me,
like arriving by night
to places unknown.
It feels as if fate
had everything ready
just for us to meet.
It smells like kerosene,
doesn't it?
Crude, we're sitting
next to an oil well.
Well, this is the end.
Pretty soon the
jungle will devour
even the last traces of what
José Enrique built in this corner
- of the Gulf of Mexico.
- What are you planning to do?
I'll go to the city and leave this
situation in the hands of justice.
Yeah?
My justice doesn't wait that long.
Tonight Mr. Fabio will pay.
You mean you're going
back to the casino?
Your life is in danger and these people
don't mind more killing.
Death comes at its own time,
don't you think?
- Are you set on that?
- Absolutely.
In that case, I'll stay, too.
No, Mercedes. Not you.
Leave the oil fields.
I've been cornered and I don't want you
to get mixed up with that.
It's not your problem only.
I beg you, Mercedes.
Get out of here.
When I left the casino
to come to see you,
I thought I would never
return to it.
Now I've decided to stay
and help you.
- Help me?
- Yes.
I don't know what you propose to do,
but you won't be alone.
You see, Gerardo,
our paths
are still the same.
- Did you see?
- What?
That one just walked in.
Get him.
Move.
- The Northern Song.
- Calm down, calm down.
Since they don't pay attention to us,
I'll sing it for you.
I'll dedicate it to
my good friend, Mr. Fabio.
And be aware that I'm actually
saving you from a tight spot.
Because if it wasn't for me, tonight
they would have destroyed your casino.
That's the way to sing.
Now come have fun with us.
I'll be back in a moment.
Wait.
Very good, very good.
Last night I was thrown away from the
casino just because I came to see her.
How can you blame me
for liking my darling so much.
I'm here to see
if you throw me out again.
You're planning also to visit her
in her room tonight?
Maybe I'll do it.
Very well said, my friend. But now
come have a drink with us.
- Let's go then.
- And you know you're not alone.
- Because men get along with men.
- That's true, always.
- Come with us.
- I was out-numbered last night.
Those white guards,
they just grabbed me and...
Nothing will happen, Raquela.
Don't worry.
You can go up to your room,
whenever you feel like it.
Perhaps it will be best to finish
this matter once and for all.
That's right. Another drink
and people to say 'cheers'.
To the honor of having
you with us.
To good friends.
Cheers.
Excuse me. I'll drink
double later. I'll be back soon.
This is going better
than I expected.
Mr. Fabio set everything
up for me.
He set it up for me,
'cause he's a good friend.
And he realized
how much I liked you.
I swear, tonight is the biggest
night of my life.
And now, sugar, we're alone at last.
Let's see who dares to throw me out.
I missed your kisses.
And I won't die without them.
You understand?
Come here, sugar.
Where are you going?
C'mon, Rayado.
Drop the package.
See who that is.
We're here for the package.
- There's no package.
- No package?
- No.
- All right, honey, don't get mad.
They changed the orders.
It's better if we don't have
a dead body tonight.
Let's go.
You're a bit nervous.
Did anything happen?
That's the way
I wanted you, murderer.
I knew that one of us wouldn't
survive the night.
Your time has come
and you're gonna pay.
I'm sorry, Mercedes. I know you'd rather
not see your brother's killer again.
So you tried to use as bait
no less than
José Enrique's sister.
Listen to me first.
Listen to me.
Listen to me, miss.
I'm not the one responsible
for your brother's death.
I can prove it.
What would I get from it? I'm just
a working man, without enemies.
- I just followed orders.
- Orders? Whose orders?
I can't tell you that.
Have mercy on me. I'll give you
everything I have.
I'll make you rich. It's not my fault.
There are others who are responsible.
- Who? Speak.
- It's very hard to explain. Others.
- Speak.
- No.
The ones responsible
are... the trust, the company people.
The company people? What about
the orders, who gave them to you?
- Van Eckerman.
- Van Eckerman?
And who's that person?
The CEO of the company.
Everybody knows him.
- Where does he live?
- In the house at Main Square.
The yellow house.
- Who's that?
- Ms. Raquela, your number.
Go, don't worry.
Besides, you won't be
able to escape.
My signature will
be useless to you.
But before that, I'll pump all six
bullets from my gun in your head,
if you don't write me
that paper.
Don't go away. It will just take
a second. It's for the publicity.
Please, just one moment, miss.
Right here. Good.
It's a photo for the news.
Open the door or we'll shoot.
Open or we'll shoot.
I'll be the one shooting.
Stay where you are.
Don't move or
I'll shoot you.
He's here.
Now, Rayado
got scratched all right.
What's going on?
We captured that guy.
He's in your room upstairs.
Mr. Fabio was shot
and I'm going to get the doctor.
And what did you do
to the man who shot him?
Nothing yet, in case Mr. Fabio
wants to talk to him
before sending him out
to the next life.
And that will have to wait
until he regains consciousness.
Excuse me.
Good evening, Miss Raquela.
Take me to the house
of Mr. Van Eckerman.
To the house of Main Square?
- Take me to Mr. Van Eckerman's house.
- Go.
What?
What's happening?
A lady wants to see
you, urgently.
- A lady?
- She says she's Mercedes Irigoyen.
Owner of The National.
- The National, you said?
- Yes, sir.
It's okay, go.
Take a seat, miss.
Thanks. I'm all right standing.
- So, tell me.
- You know who I am, don't you?
I'm the sister of Engineer
Mr. José Enrique Irigoyen.
The new owner
of The National.
Nice to meet you.
So...
I'm perfectly aware
that my brother was murdered
because he wouldn't yield
to the threats of the oil companies.
I also know that last night another man
was killed for the same reason.
I don't understand a single word
of what you're saying, miss.
Excuse me, you're a bit upset
and I'm very busy.
Just one minute.
You have to hear me first.
I just came here to ask you
for your help
to save someone who's in danger.
Only you can do that.
Someone... Who's that?
Gerardo Ramirez,
temporary manager of The National.
I don't know him.
He also tried to confront
the oil companies.
Another naive man who believed
that the weak can fight the strong.
An old stupidity that has caused
much pain in the world.
Let's talk slower, miss.
You seem to be
an intelligent woman.
Let's sit down.
Doesn't it seem absurd to you
that some people are willing
to bump their heads
against the wall?
- Absurd, at least for now.
- For now, you say?
Yes. Just for now,
because you have the power.
A power that
changed into civilization
the wilderness of
these places, miss.
A power that brought hatred
and desperation to the world.
I think you're exaggerating, miss.
Anyway, what's the reason
for your visit?
You're interested in The National,
and I'm here to sell it to you.
Why do you want to sell it?
Because only in this way can I save
the man who I want to save.
Aha. I understand, miss.
Your proposition could be
of some interest to my company.
In this case, we could get together
here again tomorrow morning
- to discuss the deal.
- No, it has to be done right now.
Do you understand?
He's held at the casino
by the same thugs who
killed my brother.
I like you, miss.
So I'll solve this matter
as my gift to you.
That's why they say women
are the salt of the earth.
- Bring me the file of The National.
- Yes, sir.
There are still
a few more formalities,
that we can resolve tomorrow,
the next day or
whenever you want.
You understand,
business is business.
- So, please, sign here.
- What about Gerardo?
Who can guarantee nothing
will happen to him?
You're right. Go to
the casino and bring here Mr...
- Gerardo Ramirez.
- Right away.
TRAIN SCHEDULE
NORTHBOUND
Let's go.
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
- Did you hear that?
- Yes.
- The wells.
- I had forgotten
- they were going to blow up.
- I didn't.
That's why it was so urgent for me
to close the deal with Van Eckerman.
But you did it knowing they
were going to blow up?
That's not good.
We won something out
of our defeat.
- I did.
- Me, too.