All right Mr. Raju, congratulations...
for your release
Jailer sir, thank you
so much
Raju, look over there-
Your city, your house, your life,
your happiness, your memories.
Mother, quickly serve food for me,
I am feeling very hungry
What's this, eat properly like
humans, first go freshen up
Mother, the vehicle is coming
The vehicles will keep coming
and going-
Come lets see how fast this taxi
takes us to the station?
Are you going to think about
the shop or not? -
You've given it in the hands
of the boy he"ll ruin it
Poor father, toiled and died after
leaving a shop for his son-
And he is head over heels
of becoming a Guide
Mother from Delhi, Calcutta, Bombay,
Madras, Singapore, London, Rome & Hongkong
Any tourist after getting down at
the station, what he asks is
Where is Raju guide, where is...
I am coming...
Mother, its for
Gafoor
Raju, again...
Enough. Enough. Enough...
Friend, the throat of the car will
get choked, here take your share
Come on my love
take us fast
Sir, eat this betel, the nuts are from
Mysore & the leaf is from Calcutta-
The catechu is of Bombay, and
the calcium is of Bikaner
It doesn't look like a betel leaf
looks like National Unity
Raju listen, you extract a lot
of work from my son-
And you pay him
very less salary
I give him Rs 10 he will not
get a penny from outside-
Instead I should get some
thing from you
That I have provided your vagabond
son on a job.
I see...
s
Raju sir, now a days people
purchase very less-
But they ask more for the
address of Raju Guide
Dilip, my dear, there is a lot
for you to learn from life
You must be wondering that leaving
all those beautiful places-
Why have I brought
you all here?
The Poets wrote poetry on
the streets of Paris
They fell in love on the bylanes
of Rome & Venice
Poet Zauk has even said-who will go
leaving the streets of Delhi-
Wow! What a beautiful
thing it is
Brother, now come here
with me
Come let's go
I'll show you an
excellent thing
Show me
Look at this, each and every part of
this is made of a different stone
Touch it and see
Great, Wonderful, what an
excellent workmanship
Raju, think once again
The same city, which oneday bowed
before you
Should not ridicule
you today
The same streets, where you
roamed like a King
Today, those shouldn't think you
to be a robber
Mother, Uncle, Rosy, friends, you made
everyone shed tears in their hearts
And then today, you have been
released from the Jail
There is nothing other than
insults in this city
Leave this city, lf you can settle
settle your life somewhere else
Greetings
After so many years, the fortune of
this temple has blossomed
What's the name of
this village?
The name of the village is Rampuri
and my name is Bhola
Where have you come from and
where will you go from here?
Friend, coming and going is not
always in our hands
A person thinks, I'll
go that side
But the destiny catches him by his
ears and drags him that side
He thinks, I'll go that side, but
the nose drags him to that side
Your words are irrevocable
After getting fed up, one day I
called the destiny near me
And asked, afterall, what
exactly do you want?
I see...
She said, leave your will and
catch hold of my finger & come
I said, alright
as you please
So brother look, today I am here
tomorrow there
Don't know where I'll be
day after tomorrow
Very true, very true
Standing near the bank of the river
I was thinking
That, I give up my life, by jumping into the river
Then suddenly
I saw you
And I heard Bhola whatever
said and done
The God has sent this nobleman
after listening to your cries
Friend, right now, I don't have a
penny, which I can gave you
But yes, you can take this cloth
If it can help you in any way
You are a very generous person
but my worry is of something else
Noble man, I am in
a great difficulty
They say, difficulty and life go
hand in hand till the pyre
Very true
But the entire fault
is of my father's
Yes, my father
married thrice
I was born to the first wife
A totally mentally retarded boy
was born to the second wife
A girl was born to the third wife
Not a girl, she was the root
cause for all the difficulty
Well, whatever it may be, a sister
is anyway a sister
Only God knows, how I
brought her up
But in return she...
Does she refuse for her
marriage?
Look... I had searched a
very good groom for her
But the day, when I fixed
her marriage
Do you know
what she did?
She ran off from
the house
Ran off
What is concealed from you, for 4 days
I kept searching her empty stomach
And I found her very far
in a fair
And now, she remains, closed
in a room
Neither she eats, drinks nor
talks to anybody
She keeps crying, crying
and crying
I am preplexed, my wife is preplexed
the entire village is preplexed
If she dies tell me who'll be
responsible for that sin?
Friend, well what
can I do?
Lord, there is a lot of force
in the advice of Saints
Once if you...
Alright, bring her here, probably
this Saintliness plays some miracle
Greetings, greetings
Lord, I have brought some
fruits for you
She wasn't coming, I said a great
nobleman has come
He'll fulfil all
your desires
She has come in the greed
to have your glimpse
Bhola, there was a time, when I
had totally lost faith on Humanity
My heart used to cry & the
entire world looked as an enemy
But there is no cloud, which
will not get scattered
There is no sorrow, which
has no remedy
Lord's magic
This earth, this sky, this air
that mountain, this temple, me, you...
Everybody are Lord's magical
play isn't it?
Yes may be
But Maya, the fact is that the love
which one can get from her husband
Can't be got from 100 step brother's
or even from 500 step sisters-in-law
Did I say a lie?
- No
Then take this, eat thinking it
to be the divine offering
God will bless you
Oh God! Oh God! Oh God!
Lord, lord, lord, this is a small
gift for you, please accept it
Brother, what's
this for?
Lord, even after knowing everything
you are still being sarcastic
I have fixed even her
marriage date
Maya's marriage, has
she agreed?
Come come... come come...
Lord!
Why have you
stayed back?
You yourself come and request
Lord to stay back till the marriage
Felt shy...
There is no doubt, that he
is some Great Soul
Who has come here for the
betterment of this village
What nonsense are you talking
are Great Soul's carrot's or a raddish's
Which can grow in
all the farms?
The wisdom of these illitrates
have gone to dogs
Listen to what
we say
It's a great sin to consider any
Tom, Dick & Harry as Lord
The Lords have a
character
It can be understood only by those
who have full knowledge of scriptures
Thank you, thank you, I thank you my
village thanks you
Bhola, again the
same thing
No body should touch his feet
he doesn't like it
Alright, alright...
Come... come... come fast...
What's all this drama? What lies
have you spread about me?
Lord, I haven't told anything, I
haven't spoken a word
But tell me, when the sun rises
can anybody hide it's rays?
Come... come... move
make way...
Vacate the place
for the Lord-
What are you doing? Simply
standing over here?
Blow the fan...
Is there anyone, listen go send
the girl, let her take the blessings
Why are you all marching forward?
Be patient, be patient
You must have heard that
native Doctor's are created falsely
Have you ever heard, that even
Lord's are created falsely?
Do you go to school?
There is no school
in the village
Priest, carry your divine vessel, and
march forward towards the forest
Priest, what are you saying
come with me?
Let us, the knowledgable person's
also go on a Holy pilgrimage
Lord live long...
- live long
What good name did you
say was his?
Priest sir, what will you do
after listening to the name?
Haven't you heard don't ask the
caste of a Sage, ask for his wisdom
Value the sword, and
not the scabbard
Wow! Great, excellent...
Keep quiet, we have come here only to
enquire about your knowledge
But, please be seated
When great people like
you are standing-
Then how can this worthless
dare to sit
Wow! Great...
You have obtained a good education
priest, sit down
I'll arrange an another
cot for you to sit-
This is Lord's place
Bhola, don't act like a fool
First, know who deserves the
respect and who doesn't?
Lord, give us the meaning
of this Hymn?
Why couldn't understand?
He can understand, only when he
knows sanskrit, isn't it?
Excellent!
Priest, you didn't understand
Teacher, you? No
How can you? You can understand
only if you know English, isn't it?
Lord
'Live long'
Greetings mother
Welcome... Miss Nalini, today what
made you come here?
Today it's the day for Raju to
get released from the Jail
I suppose, even his mother
has come for that
Greetings mother
Greetings
It's been months, since he
has been released
But how is this possible that Raju's
imprisonment was reduced by 6 months
Oh yes! You had gone
to London
But, How didn't he meet
you till now?
I returned only today from the
village, greetings
Greetings
So, was your trip to
Europe succesful?
There was a lot of news about
it in the papers-
When did you return, please come
in have a cup of tea
Please permit me to go
Mother... mother... l'll not
let you go by walk
Rosy, move away
leave me
If you don't listen to me, I'll catch
your feet, infront of everybody
What drama are
you playing?
Then please come
come...
Several times, I had tried to come
you & voice my sorrows
And to make you realise, that I am
not that as bad as you think
I don't want any
explanation
How can I forget, that I had
only one son in the entire world
But the moment, your shadow
was cast him
Neither, he remained mine
nor of the world
I fail to understand
That, when you were not determined to
stay with your husband
Then, why did you
get married?
Why did I marry?
Do you want to
know?
Then listen
My mother was
a prostitute
She had only one ambition
in her life
That somehow she wanted to keep her
daughter away from that atmosphere
Whether, I went to
school or college
I always stayed
in a Hostel
But still, I couldn't kept
myself away from dancing
Get out from
my house
Lakshmi Bai, I'll go but drainage
water can never become Holy water
Get out
Mother, what's the matter?
Nothing
Aunty, what's the matter
tell me...
I had brought a
message for you
One Banwarilal, was ready to give
Rs 2000 PM for you
And your mother is out
of her brains
Look at this
But mother, I don't want to
get married right now
I want to earn a name by
dancing on the stage
The one, who doesn't have her
father's & husband's name
And whose mother
has a ill-fame
Under what name can that
girl acheive fame?
Daughter, once you get away
from this atmosphere
Get married to some
respected person
Then, whatever you do, nobody
will dare to raise a finger on you
I like your daughter
Then have sweets
Even you take
Mr & Mrs Marco, I happily acknowledge
this consent of your's
And legally register your
marriage
Mr. Marco, congratulations
Thank you
There is a difference in my house
and in your mother's house
Do I have to make you
understand this?
Mother...
Daughter...
Daughter, what's
the matter?
Mother, now what can I
make you understand?
Just think, there will be no child
born in this house
Sir, listen you seem
to be a local
Yes
Can you tell me where can I get the
address of Raju guide?
Why not? You can ask any child
passenger, porter
Instead, I tell you to ask it
from the engine of the train
Sir, I am asking you
Who are you?
How does it
concern you?
If you are asking a decent man
then ask decently
Have I asked you to
interfere in between?
Let the guide go to hell, I can
carry on the work even without guide
You can carry on, but
what about me?
I know, you are coming with me
you would become a burden
If you know, then why did
you bring me along with you?
I did a mistake, I did
one more mistake
Writing a letter to this bloody
guide was a total fiasco
You... are you
Mr. Marco?
How does it
concern you?
How did you come to know
my name?
I beg an apology
I am Raju Guide
I should have recognised you
after seeing you itself
Well tell me, have the arrangements
for the Hotel been made? -yes
And taxi?
Taxi is also arranged, Porter
Mr. Bearer
What's this?
If anything breaks again, I'll
adjust the cost from your pay
Go go go...
I had written to you that the
purpose of my visit here
To search the ancient caves
Do you see the dak-bungalow
on that hillock?
Yes
Behind that in the jungle are the
caves that you're looking for
Alright I'll freshen up & go
Right now its impossible -
It'll be night fall when we reach
there and then how'll we return?
To go there, one has
to go early morning
That means today is wasted
Sir, what's this, if a day gets
wasted then why am I a Guide?
Here there are beautiful
places to watch
I've no time to waste I've
come to see only the caves
You are forgetting that
I'm also with you
And I may be interested in
them besides the caves
Is there any good
library here?
Yes it is there
Then drop me there &
show the town to Madam
Madam won't go alone
- What?
If I was fond of going alone
on excursion -
I would'nt have come with you
But Rosy you know...
If you won't come with me then
I won't go
Why does man get married?
That means you don't care
about me at all
Think that way, I don't care
I don't care...
I am going
Coming Madam
Show the town to Madam
Mr. Marco won't come
Shall I write & give you that
he won't come
Gafoor, show the town to Madam
- Yes sir
Where should I go first?
Go to hell, but go
If they had to go to hell why
people would come to Udaipur?
We think this place
is heaven
You're right, Raju, but
keep quiet at the moment
This is the library of
our town
Stop the car only when you
are told to
Understood Gaffoor?
Yes, I understood but
you keep quiet
But I didn't understand
If you're such a tourist who doesn't
want a guide to talk -
Then, here is the car, Gaffoor
& this person
Is going...
Listen...
Is there any hamlet of
snake charmers?
Where the lady snake charmer does
snake dance
lt'll be better if Mr. Marco doesn't
know about this
He wouldn't
know
If you didn't come with me then why
should I come with you
Don't come
Then go
Yes I am going
Go
Where to?
- To see the caves, where else?
You'll go alone?! - Why?
Is it the custom there?
That without the wife man is not
allowed to go in
It could be late night when you
return and she is alone...
So? When she doesn't want to
come what can I do?
What was that?
What happened?
The jungle is getting very
dangerous, animals come inside
Open the room & get the
food prepared
I'll do it immediately
Raju keep these Rs.200 &
give me an account
You have a wash, then we'll
go to see the caves
Oh you hunter
If you'll throw away the rat then
what'll you have for breakfast?
You haven't had breakfast eat it
- What's this nonsense? -
Will you bet Raju
I am sure that there should be
atleast one more cave
Then search it, I didn't find any
You'll see it when I
search it
And I am capable of
finding it
I may have to dig
the earth
Arrange for some labourers & for my
stay in the dak-bungalow
You go to town immediately and
bring these things
I feel that you should go
to town yourself...
I can't waste this valuable
time
But your wife is there alone
Oh yes! I forgot that, What
the hell is this?
You haven't married isn't it?
Here I have the most important job
of my life & there...
Madam Rosy open the door, I am
Raju guide...
I have a message for you
from Mr. Mathur
Raju, its of no use...
We're tired of doing the same thing
since morning
Do you have any such key which
can open all doors?
I have the master key but why open
somebody's door -
Take it out, I take full
responsibility give it
As you like it, take it
Oh God! I am scared what'll
happen now?
See Raju, I had told you
its poison isn't it?
Call the doctor immediately
Joseph, What's this?
You've made wonderful
arrangement
Enough... Enough...
Give pills every 4 hours
with coffee
Don't leave the patient alone under
any circumstances
No... l'll bring her husband
immediately
Raju have you gone mad?
It takes 10 hours to
Go & come -
And is my car a bullock cart that you
run it with a whip -
And in the jungle there is neither
road nor light, I won't go
Then what shall we do?
Look Raju I can't take any more
responsibility than this
I'm lucky that my heart
didn't fail
You do what you like
Either take the patient
from here
Or you take the responsibility of
looking after her
Do you want anything?
Run, rocks are
falling
You got up? How're
you feeling?
What are you doing here?
I was doing my job
& serving you
Where is he?
- He? There only
He didn't come in the
night also
Some important work cropped up
That work was more dear to
him than my life
He doesn't even know that you...
He thinks that I give
empty threats
Whatever I say I can't do it
That means you had told
him that you...
But he is not bothered
If I had died it would have been
good riddence for him
It would been better had
I died
You didn't listen fully you
didn't ask, why I came back
When we reached there he was
feeling sorry & missing you
What beautiful jungle, caves &
dak-bungalow and this Joseph!
Cooks so well only one
thing is lacking
If you bring Rosy it'll be work
and picnic both -
Here it is romantic, seclusion -
It would've been better
if Rosy was here
Believe me it was he who
said all these
You think I am lying
And you think you're telling
the truth
Here is the medicine I'll
send tea
I don't need it
You do need it, I'll come back
Now she is alright, continue
the medicine
You give her the medicine because
in the morning her cup of tea
Was used for washing
the clothes
I'll take it myself
Doctor there is no problem
if she travels
Because this lady is
going to her husband
No problem, it is better
Who told you that I'll go?
You didn't say, but I am worried
about Mr. Marco
He didn't come yesterday & you
took the pills
If you don't go today
he may take pills
If my husband would make me laugh like this I
wouldn't have defied him
And are you are defying me just
because I am making you laugh
Are you married?
No, so far God
has saved me
Why?
She'll be happy
with you
Madam, this is your thought
I am a very strict man -
I'll make her cook food take service
from her make her press my legs -
And I'll also slap her, if she
behaves like the way you behaved yesterday
Along with it will you love
her or not?
I'll definitely have
to love her
Then her life will be blessed even if you
make her to do whatever you said earlier
Raju, I'll not go -
But promise me, till the time
he asks anything about me -
You'll not say anything
about me
I am surprised that how could these
caves be hidden from the World till now?
The World which values
Ajanta, Ellora & Khajuraho -
How can I allow this treasure
to be concealed under the dust?
But Raju do you know why didn't
any assayer came here till now?
Because, I was destined
to do this job -
I was left to discover this
to understand its real worth -
To bring it to the limelight
which it really deserves
But Raju don't worry even your
name will be mentioned in the Book -
And it'll be definitely
mentioned
Because you are that man, who
has brought me till here
Aren't you forgetting anything?
- What?
For example, what the
time is and...
I thought probably I was forgetting
something about this cave
Sir, look in the city your...
I have brought your luggage from city
This idol definitely would have been
made during those times
Mr. Marco! Your luggage has been
brought back from the city
Oh good! Look Raju, right now
don't trouble me -
You go and serve food, I'll
just come back of you
Don't you want to ask
anything from me?
Didn't I say you go, I'll just come
I've to write some important notes
What I have to tell you, is
definitely more important
Oh God, so you'll not leave me
come on tell, what do you want to say?
If you don't have to ask me anything
then I don't have to say you anything
What a stupid
man he is?
Mr. Marco!
Raju, what's
the matter?
Don't you have to ask me about
your wife's condition?
Oh yes, what happened, has she
come here or has she gone?
Rosy, consumed poison
Look, she'll not believe
my words -
You yourself say that I couldn't
come last night because of this taxi
You are standing perfectly
allright
Aren't you happy?
But Raju had said
something else...
Rosy look if you are allright
and can commute -
Then instead of calling me here
you could've easily come there
Neither did I call anyone here
nor did I want to come there
Oh God, why don't you understand
that I don't have time even to breathe
Who is responsible for my time
that got wasted in to & fro
If your time get's wasted
to see your sick wife -
Then who is responsible for my life
which is getting wasted by staying with you?
First tell me, the reason behind
consuming the poison? -
What was the reason behind insulting
me in this new city?
What is that thing which
my money can't buy -
And which I have
deprived you with?
But still, you want to show
that I torture you a lot -
And you aren't interested
in living
Although I know, that you consumed
poison only to trouble me -
To show that I torture you
to take revenge on me -
Otherwise you should've consumed
2 more pills
So that you would've really
got relieved from me -
But you never
wanted this
Allright, accuse me, that
I don't want to die
Why don't you clearly say
that you want me to die
Raju, she's gone
Leave me, Leave me
Leave me...
Leave me... Leave me...
Don't follow me
Didn't I say you go now
I'll not do anything
Didn't I say, I'll not go even
If you come along with me
Do you see that small Island
there's a tomb of a dog
Of a dog?
It was Tajmahal's dog, he was
the pet of Maharana
A dog is better than me
Should I tell you
one thing -
The person who keeps cursing
his own destiny -
Even the destiny keeps
cursing that person
Come, Mr. Marco would be
waiting for you
Don't know how many days would
I spend in the caves -
If you intend going home
you can go
I have kept Rs 1000
in the envelope
Raju, will I get anklets
somewhere here?
Anklets why not?
How much?
- Sir Rs 10
Come
Let me atleast take
the change
The money is mine
or yours?
But the price of this
is only Rs 10
Today these are priceless
for me
Come, come
Sir...
What are you seeing?
Raju, where did you bring
such a sample from?
Rosy, for god sake, remove
these anklets and walk
Why?
What do you mean
why?
If you feel ashamed, then walk
on the other side of the road
Allright, even you'll remember
Now atleast help me
He is Raju, Guide, isn't it?
- He is the same
What is he doing here
along with this girl?
Probably he has
quit his job
Look...
Ay Guide, now show me
around -
Show me such a place that
my heart gets pepped up
How far is Chittor?
It's very far, and the
car is not there
What's the use of that Guide
Whose work stops because of a car
My mistake, I swear I'll never call myself
as Guide let's get back to hotel -
Otherwise people will think, that
I am walking with some drunkard
Don't you watch while driving?
Or you a human?
Will you not speak anything what
sort of a Guide are you?
I don't understand till yesterday
you looked as a 40 year oldwoman
Who has lost all her happiness, desires
& hopes on the middle of some road -
And today you look like a
16 years old girl -
Innocent, ignorant, full of
childhood mischief
Do you know, why?
- Why?
Madam Rosy, you are
a wonderful dancer
Really... Really...
Why did you give up dancing when
you have so much of talent?
What should
I say-
Marco thinks, singing & dancing is
the profession of prostitutes
How did a man with good thoughts
meet with a cheap dancer like this?
There was no other way, mother
was a traditional dancing girl -
How could she take her daughter
out from that atmosphere?
But look at my destiny
Marco came in my life
He favoured me by
accepting me -
He obligated me by making me
the daughter-in-law of his house
Such a big house, so many servants
so much of money -
So much of rest
so much of fame -
And so much of love
Yes, so much of love
Rosy, the times are no more
the same
When the woman was considered
as a prostitute of the house
Used to cry, used to palipitate
used to bear -
But she never used
to complain
The times are also no
more the same -
That one was considered cheap just
because he was born in a low caste -
And is born
in a low family
If I had the rights, I could
have proved to Mr. Marco -
That how high
your caste is
Mine?
Artiste's are not
bloody buffoons -
Today even respected people
respect the art -
How did Udayashankar earn
fame in the World?
Because of his nose -
And Shantaram, Saraswathi and...
Raju take such renowned names
that my destiny starts fluttering
You have never made
an attempt -
Otherwise who knows even after
listening to your name -
People's destiny would
start fluttering
No... I don't have
such a destiny
Destiny?
Make yourself so strong, that
before the destiny -
The God himself asks, tell me
what is your desire?
If you have the strength, dedication
talent & an interest -
Those which are impossible
should come infront of me
Why don't I talk to
Marco for once more
Raju, listen -
Why so much
of delay?
Even sir is very angry, there's
a lot of trouble inside
Rosy, I don't think this is the
right time for us to go in
Why?
Don't ask too many questions
we'll come tomorrow
Raju, I am not
a child
Is sir inside?
No, yes... No, No...
Come Rosy come...
Raju did you see, this
is what happens
If one drives a motor on the
road meant for bullock carts
Bloody, the road
attains the glory -
But the vehicle has to
look like this-
Only I know, how
obstinate this is-
If it refuses to move in
the middle of the night
Then, I can't even scold it
infront of madam
Bloody... Oh God!
Oh my friend, take half
of the cloth
Ay Raju... Raju just
get up and see
Had I been in
her place
I would have spit on that son of
a gun & would have told 3 times
Divorce... divorce... divorce
What's the matter?
You look over there
I'll see over here
Raju over here...
Raju, look over there
There is no way even from
that side
Hold this, and give
me your hand
Alright, Be careful, place
your feet carefully
If this is only
your courage
Then every woman will
feel ashamed on your life
Then, ls there no other way
to make a shelter?
If husband doesn't
give happiness
Can't one get it anywhere
else in the world
Marco is also fed up of you
But even he doesn't break his
head against the wall
He feels happy with the stone
idols in the caves...
Just because he
is a man
And you keep palipitating yourself just
because you are a woman
Rosy, it's wrong
absolutely wrong
Today the state in which you
are because
You haven't learnt to rebel
with this state
Or you swear that, the
one who kicks you-
You'll keep flattering him for
the rest of your life
And if not-
Then, there is no sin in demanding
your rights & making yourself stable
The sin is in keeping quiet
& bearing the torture
Ths sin is in losing the battle of
life living in suffocation
The sin is in committing suicide
committing suicide is sin...
Rosy, it's a sin
sin sin...
Nobody is anybody's slave
nobody is indigent on anybody
The word helplessness is only
a whim
While asleep everyone
is helpless
And when he wakes up the strength
automatically comes
And I have seen this strength
even in you the day when you... you
Had tied these
Even after this, lf you feel
yourself to be helpless, weak
I have no remedy
for it
I'll only regret, that why
I kept saving you form dying
That's because, there are
certain cowards
Who should get drowned & die
in a few drops of water
Then I'll feel ashamed, that at some
point I had a relation with you
What's it?
Where is sir?
He is near the Bank of the river
what are you doing here, go...
Rosy I had thought
That in this regard, whatever
discusion had to take plase
Has been over
And we had come down
to a decision
Marco, but it's not necessary that
all your decisions are mine too
But it was your
decision
That you wanted to leave the
profession of your mother
And wanted to earn a
respect of my name
Your name?
Now I have started finding more
respect in my mother's profession
Than in your name
If you want to gather a crowd by
the noise of Anklets, Tambourine & Lute
Then I don't have to remind you
that it's not possible in my house
Marco, there is atleast a little
difference in me & in these stone idols
They don't trouble me
They don't trouble you
because they are stones
And they are stones, that's why
they don't trouble you
You inserted a stone
in my heart-
Once you insert a heart
in these stones
Then you see, each & every idol will
shout & say, Marco I want to live...
Aren't you alive?
If forsaking all interests and then
living is living, then I am living
But, you have your work with
you what do I have?
What does a woman have
her house
A house is complete with husband
and children
What's my fault in this what do I
do when the God himself doesn't want
Marco, I am not blaming you, but
then in which hope should I live?
What dreams should I see
sitting the whole day?
What should I keep thinking by
staying awake the whole night?
If I don't have the happiness
of children come in my life
Then atleast let a little happiness
come in my life
Happiness... happiness...
happiness...
If all the happiness was left
only in dancing & singing
Then why the hell did you
leave your mother's house?
I left mother's house, so that I
would go to my husband's house
But how could I know, that over there
neither there'll be a husband nor house
What do you want?
Leaving all my work, I should keep
decorating flowers in your hair
Why did you marry, if you had
an aversion towards the flowers?
Not an interest, I married because, I
had an interest to invite trouble forever
Not an interest, it
was your neccessity
What cheap talk are
you speaking?
I am speaking it because
of your cheap acts
You call my love
to be lust?
And you call your
lust to be love?
You don't require a wife, you only
require a woman may be however she is
That's why your bed is more
dearer to you than me
Because it doesn't demand anything
after it subsides your lust
You are not a man, you
are a bloody Barbarian
Where are
you going?
How does it
concern you?
Without my permission, you can't
do any stupid act
Afterall, I have some
rights on you
May be?
How can you forget, on what
all I have done for you
The same, which I am going
to become
I'll not let
this happen
Any rowdy, vagabond or hooligan
by throwing 25 paise,50 paise or 1 Rupee
And after that, he ridicules me
and dispects me, I can't see
You can't, no problem, nobody
is forcing you to see
Whose conspiracy is this, who has
put this idea in your mind?
Who has instigated you?
What new thing has happened, that
leaving this comfortable life
You don't have the fear of
wandering from one street to another?
I was asleep
I woke up
Is there no other reason, tell me
I want to know
Have you found
another man?
May be, it's possible
What... you mean to say
you have someone else
Marco, lf I become unfaithful
I'll do it openly
Not by giving an excuse of work
doing it secretly in some dense forest
So?
You are suspecting me
you are insulting me
Don't think, that by falsely
accusing me
You have got an excuse of
becoming characterless?
Anything more?
If you really what to listen
then listen
Even for a day, I didn't forget
what blood flows in you
I married you under the pretence
after knowing everything
That I am buying you
for my necessity
If women like you have
a notion
That you are worthy of becoming
a wife of some respected person
Then, there is no stupid person
more than you
Listen one more thing, I hate
you, I hate you, I hate you...
Even If you go, there'll be
1000's coming like you
Go, get lost from here
Raju, will you give support
to a helpless woman?
Bring the luggage in, I'll make
you meet my mother, keep it here
Mother, look we have a guest
at home, her name is Rosy
Don't have a wrong estimate of
her religion with her name
Her pet name
is Rosy
You make some tea or coffee
I'll make her get freshen up
After that we'll
go out
You ignited a spark in me
I burnt down my entire house
Raju, I am totally ruined
I have no one in this world
You're lucky, I was worried that
she may get angry...
When I look back, I only find
ash, & ruins around me
In the front a long a deserted
lane, whose destination is unknown
Rosy, in those ruins look a
guide is standing
You are looking at the path
but not the co-traveller
I had asked your support
for a few days
I never intended of transferring
my burden of my life on you
Trust me, this burden will definitely
reduce the worries of my life
Raju, I am blemished
If you are blemished, then
I accept this blemish fully
No... No Raju this is not possible
I had never even thought of it
It was a sin of thinking it till
yesterday, but today its different
It was a sin of telling it till
yesterday but today its different
Rosy, I want to see dreams for you
and I want to make them a reality
Give me the permission
I can't give you anything I can't
promise you, don't put me in a fix
My shadow may
ruin you
Will you listen to me patiently
you are not making any promise
I want to place your hand on my
heart and make a promise
Who is she, where has
she come from?
Mother, she is a tourist, I had
met her at the station
How did she come alone
why did she come?
Not alone, her husband
was with her
Is she married?
Mother she is a
destitute woman
What is that marriage, where there
is no body & soul involved
There is not much time
left even in the divorce
So, she has left him and
has come to you
Mother, she has not come to me
she has come to you
If you want to drive her away
do it now, later don't blame me
What are you saying?
Go to sleep
I am only thinking about the
neighbourhood, what's my problem?
Brother Raju, sometimes
even call us
Or you watch the private
show all alone
You must be having mother
sister at home
Otherwise, I would
have told...
Yes, we have mother's & sister
But we don't have some
dancing beauty
You are dead...
Come down, I say come down
come down
Now, only this was left
isn't it?
What happened?
Who is asking for oranges, I am
asking the address of Raju Guide
Didn't I say that Raju Guide
no more comes here
He has eloped with
one dancer
Today is your last day
but you never came all these days
Are you going, or should
I kick you...
No, I'll not go & who are
you to kick me out?
And this shop is not yours
what did you say?
Father...
You son of a father, where
are all the goods
And what's this cash box
doing here?
It's my first
month earning
What are you talking to the child?
Talk to me
Your son has snatched
my shop
First thing, this shop is
no more yours
Master make him understand
Every passenger complains
that you'r not available at the station
So your contract has been
cancelled from this month
And a new contract has been awarded
to Banwarilal
This shop was of my father
now it is mine
Let me see, who dares to
push me out from here?
So this is the matter, come here
I'll make you understand
Ramu, come here
Gaffoor, come fast, they are
hitting Raju
Raju, this is all happening
because of me
No Rosy, No...
Here take this brother
take this
And sister, these vegetables
are from own farm
Add salt to these bitter gourds &
then fry them in mustard oil
I tell you, lt'll be
very tasty
Alright, you sit, I'll make
tea for you
I went for a hearing, when I
returned I got your telegram
Greetings uncle
May you live long
Mother, you didn't tell me that you
have sent a telegram to uncle
She didn't tell you
Sister, you must consult elders
in such matters
I've heard a lot of
rumors about you
I'll punish you
severely
Here take tea
- Give it
Continue the practice
This is my house, I'm not scared
of anybody
Dance, dance practice
So you're busy in this
There wasn't a person in
our family
Who'll make the she monkey dance
Bring a tabot
Enough Rosy, rest for tomorrow
Hey you girl... ls this your
father's house?
Your brother's house, your
husband's house?
If not then why are
you here?
We don't keep dancers
in the house
Come this side, uncle
Why're you shedding
crocodile tears?
I am talking sense
understand that
Take the train to Delhi and go
away from here
I'll buy the ticket for you
Had you not been my uncle I would
have told you -
That you don't know how
talk to girls
Things have reached to that pass
In my house before you scold my
guest you'll have to deal with me
You dare to talk back to me
dogs child
By abusing my father you are
giving good respect to your sister
For a prostitute
- Uncle
Do debauchery outside this house
- Mother
Tell your brother to hold
his tongue... otherwise...
What'll you do? Let me
also know
Now are you happy?
You're contended, isn't it?
Mother
Don't dare... Mother
How peaceful it is now...
You didn't feel offended?
Raju, I've decided that
I'll go
I've also decided
- What?
That you'll not go
Enough, I don't want to hear
anything else
Only 1 hour is left for
train's departure
Passenger is ready