Mr Sohanlal!
Inform the police.
Go on!
This is Khanna speaking.
The work is done.
You must keep another
death certificate ready.
Send the will to
its rightful place.
The will shall reach you
by morning. Do the needful.
Dear Asha, your uncle
has met with an accident.
And he is dead.
No! It can't be true!
This is true.
My heartfelt condolences
are with you...
You?
Today is the Silver Jubilee
of the Princess Club.
On this joyous occasion...
the club has presented you
with a variety of programmes.
But the most interesting programme
will be presented now.
We now present the winners
of the lucky draw.
The winners will be sent abroad
on a chartered flight...
on a 2-week complimentary
holidary abroad.
Here are their names.
Barrister Rakesh!
Mr Dharamdas!
Mr Kishan!
Miss Kitty!
Dr Acharya!
Mr Madhusudan Sharma!
And Miss Asha.
They are the seven
lucky winners...
who leave for a foreign holiday.
I hope this is the best
vacation of their life.
This is Captain Bhatia
speaking to you.
Due to a technical snag in the
engine, we will have to force-land.
Do not panic and
fasten your seat belts.
We are doing our best
to land safely.
It will take us 2 hours
to repair the engine.
You can take a stroll
till then, if you wish.
It's a nice place.
What if they can't
fix the engine?
Well...? - How will we go?
We've had to force land
because of the snag.
We will leave, once it is repaired.
I have nothing to do with this.
I know nothing.
It's very late.
And Anand hasn't returned yet.
We've been wandering around
for so very long.
When we couldn't find a place
to live in, how can he?
Even if he does find a place,
do you think he'll return?
Why don't you believe me!
Anand is responsible for all this.
We will soon know.
There he is!
Any success?
- No. No trace of human life.
What shall we do now?
- Rest.
Let's leave it to the one
who brought us this far.
By then I'll starve to death.
I'm so very thirsty.
Then drink this.
- God! You want to corrupt me!
You're joking instead of
finding some shelter!
In this dangerous jungle...
- You folks are far more dangerous.
Sit here.
I'm leaving on my own.
Don't worry.
She'll return on her own.
Has the entire
entourage arrived?
I've been waiting for you
for a whole a week.
Which means you knew about
our arrival.
Old man, what nonsense
are you talking?
Who else but you
could've arrived?
I've made all the
arrangements for you.
Arrangements?
Who are you?
I'm the cook.
I am the butler.
And shall take care of
all your comforts.
Come, doctor.
- Wait!
How did you know I'm a doctor?
- I'm not a fool.
Well, Mr Sharma?
- You know my name too.
I know everyone. You are
Mr. Sharma and she's Ms. Kitty.
Aren't I right?
And he is Mr. Dharamdas.
He is omniscient.
Is he human or a ghost?
Why are you so apprehensive?
This note contains everything.
Why are you snatching it?
It doesn't include your name.
So tell me your name.
I'll make arrangements
for you too.
Where will you, now that
you are here? Follow me!
C'mon upstairs!
What are you doing there?
They all seem nice and healthy.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven...
And now the eighth one too.
I'll have to make arrangements
for him too.
Why are you staring at me? Haven't
you ever seen a handsome man?
All said and done,
he's an interesting man.
He has taken care of
all our comforts.
There are enough of
groceries too.
Mr. Sharma, do you intend to make
us stay here all our lives?
My intentions differ slightly.
Now stop arguing,
and start eating.
Get some mutton for me.
- Tomatoes and green chillis for me.
Listen... bring vegetables for me.
- Okay.
Bring yogurt for me.
Do you have some pickle?
- Only bitter gourd. I'll get it.
I think we must help him.
- Sure.
Each one has a different choice...
chicken and mutton indeed!
I'm confused.
One wants raw tomatoes another
asks for tomato sauce.
If I'm not mistaken,
you are Mr. Sohanlal's niece?
Yes... but what makes you ask?
- Only casually.
The food is delicious and you
are a fun person too.
Madame, do you want to
devour me too?
Who's interested in living anyway?
- Then why don't you die?
What is this?
An account of the spices?
Where are the vegetables?
What are you reading so intently?
This dairy bears the names
of the travellers...
who have reached the end
of their lives.
This is for those who were
strangers to each other...
but now are companions in
this last journey of life.
By now, you must've realised...
that you are all victims
of a conspiracy.
Do you recollect that someone was
a victim of your conspiracy too?
All of you have been deliberately
brought together today.
You are all murderers,
criminals and culprits.
And you've been brought here
to be punished.
And the punishment is death
for all of you, but in turns.
What nonsense is this?
- Don't kick up a fuss.
It won't help. There is no way
you can escape this ordeal.
Just as you smilingly
committed the crime...
so also you must accept
the punishment smilingly.
We won't tolerate empty threats.
Who is behind this conspiracy?
Why doesn't he face us?
Does anyone else stay here too?
- How would I know? Could be.
Who was singing this song?
- Maybe my mother!
Put the knife away. That song
is coming out of my ears.
This is the hit song of the hamlet
and is heard every where.
As if there is a wandering
soul in this hamlet.
What?
- Who else will stay here?
I don't believe this.
He must be lying.
Someone must be staying here.
- Madame, today is the first night.
You will understand everything
by and by
Atleast finish your meal.
Hearing of spirits makes
them lose their appetite.
If they encounter a live spirit
they'll die!
You seem to be quite smart.
Since they've wasted all this,
I'll feed them for breakfast.
I've told you, Rake.
I like alcoholics but not alcohol.
Why'd I force you
to drink?
This is something which is offered
willingly and had willingly, too.
Isn't it, darling? I'm sorry to
address you as darling, darling.
That doesn't mean I'm drunk.
Your eyes intoxicated me,
otherwise I'm quite sober.
Have a sip.
- Please listen to me.
Okay, I'll drink it myself.
Just come over, if you're scared.
I'm in the room next door.
Why should I be scared? The protector
is scared, not the destroyer.
What can anyone steal from me?
Don't say that... they could
do so much to you, darling!
There! I've got used to
calling you darling.
Open the door slowly.
- I can't help it, sir.
If I work slowly,
how will I finish my work?
Sir, what is this?
- This is a "doorbin" (binocular).
"Been"? (a pipe)
Let me use it to charm snakes.
This is used to see
faraway things closely.
Oh, I see. Can you see
the pavements of Secunderabad?
Prepare me a cup of tea.
- No, sir. I bring the tea.
It's for you to make it...
That's all!
Give me a call...
I'm young at heart!
Where are you, Madame?
- I am here.
How will I talk to you if you
remain standing in there?
Come out and see, I've brought
a cup of hot tea for you.
Come before it gets cold.
What is it?
- How much of sugar, Madame?
I don't want tea now.
I'm going for a swim.
What?
- For a swim.
Do you intend to swim
across the ocean?
Everyone wants me to prepare
some tea for them; but I refuse.
And she refuses me!
Are you going for a swim?
A pain, sir?
Then drink some tea.
Instead of tea, bring me
some fresh lime-water.
Do you suffer a hangover?
- You are very smart.
Are you going for a swim?
- Yes.
Go ahead!
I too will join you later.
You are fond of swimming and
I love catching things that swim.
I mean fishing.
- Then come on.
How she walks!
- And how are you?
Is breakfast ready?
- What a hog!
Didn't you get your fill
ogling at her?
Go and get my breakfast.
First brush your teeth;
your mouth is stinking!
The first time I ogle at a girl...
and I get caught.
You're fond of taking
pictures, aren't you?
That's right.
You must be fond of
stealing pictures too.
If the picture were good,
it'll remain etched in my heart.
Where is my photograph?
- Your photograph?
Perhaps in my eyes.
- I talk of my uncle's snap.
You uncle's snap
must be in your heart.
You are insolent!
Insolent is one who crosses
the limits of decency.
Is your uncle's snap really missing?
- D'you think I'm lying.
I'm sorry, but there's no
police station around.
Otherwise I'd have accompanied you
to lodge a complaint.
Thanks!
- Please listen.
What is it?
- Thanks!
Had your uncle been here,
I'd click a new picture of him.
Thanks!
- Thanking doesn't end the matter.
I want to tell you something.
- What?
That this place and our
companions are so strange.
I can see that.
- Say what you want...
but remember, there is danger
lurking at every step.
If there is anyone who can
protect you... it's your truly.
May I go?
- Sure, but don't venture out alone.
Our destinations may differ.
- It could be the same. Try it out.
If you hurt your foot,
it will be difficult to walk.
Life with you in a few days
will be difficult anyway.
It's my life that has
become difficult!
Welcome, Dharamdas...
Fond of fishing, aren't you?
And what interest
brings you here?
I've been watching Miss Kitty
spend a long time in the water.
She's calling you!
- Me? No. It's you she's calling.
The water is very cold.
Spend a little more time here
and you'll be an expert at swimming.
We'll have to stay here, because
there's no way out of here.
Our tormentor has wisely
chosen this place.
Come here! Quick!
I've spotted a ship!
The wielder of the knife and the
fisherman are both missing.
And Ms Kitty has a stomach-ache.
Am I a machine to cook for
so many people?
It's late.
They should've returned by now.
There they are.
Now sit for dinner.
I'm sorry to be late.
- Better late than never!
Where is Kishan?
- Wasn't he with you?
No, I went aone
and came alone.
Didn't you even see him?
- No.
Then where could he be?
We must look for him.
He went of his own volition,
he'll return on his own.
If he's careless,
we mustn't follow suit.
I'll go and take a look.
Better lay the food.
Can't you see all this food?
You ought to wear glasses!
I've fried the fish you caught.
You?
- Didn't you say...
that danger lurks
at every step.
Let's go together.
- You want to accompany me?
In search of Kishan.
- Still better.
Why did you laugh?
It was not me, Anand.
That voice, then?
The butler was right.
There is a spirit here.
Come, let's go.
He's not here either.
- I wonder where he has gone.
Let's look there.
I found this letter near
Kishan's body.
I thought of reading it in
everyone's presence. It says...
"do not mourn Kishan's death
because he was a murderer"
"He ran over a man
with his car..."
"who was a victim of
your conspiracy"
And his name was Mr. Sohanlal.
Dharamdas, why are your hands
shaking? Did you know him?
I know him.
He was my uncle.
It's so ironic that till this morning
Kishan was with us...
and now...
- I can still visualise that scene.
When he stood atop the
mountain to wave at the ship.
Who knew death would
claim him so soon!
As far as I think, none of us
saw him after this morning.
And we found him dead at night.
It means he was murdered
in the evening.
Dharamdas too returned late
for dinner.
You misunderstand!
I've done nothing!
Where did you find the dagger
with which Kishan was killed?
Dharamdas always keeps it
under his pillow.
Isn't it, Dharamdas?
- This is a lie.
It means that dagger was yours?
You killed Kishan?
You are a murderer.
- This is a lie.
I'm innocent.
- Prove it.
I think we'll give him time
till tomorrow evening.
But why don't you believe me?
I have killed no one! It's a lie!
It's a lie!
One is gone.
You toil so much...
- That is my job, mister.
Listen...
- What?
Who realises his duties
nowadays?
Do you realise your duty?
Had you realised it,
you'd have tipped me.
Here you are.
- How reluctantly you give!
What will I have to do
for this tenner?
By God!
You are a very smart chap.
Why drag God into this?
Give Him rest for a while.
Only God will save me here.
- Is that so?
Tell me, who killed Kishan?
- How'd I know about who...
How can I tell you that?
But I sure know that
Lord Kishan had killed Kamsa.
Not that Kishan; our Kishin.
- Allah!
I don't know but everyone
was hinting at you.
I did not kill anyone.
Don't cry...
just prove it otherwise.
Do you think the fish
will testify for me?
What are you trying to do?
- You say...
What?
- That we were together.
Or else they will kill me.
Don't shift the blame
on my shoulders.
My life is more precious to
me than yours.
In which case, I value
this tenner more than you.
He's going to die... surely die!