''Every man has dreams
of the woman he wants''
''Some will tell you...
some will hide it''
''lt's a strange situation
to be in''
''Every girl dreams of
the boy she wants''
''Some will tell you...
some will hide it''
''lt's a strange situation
to be in''
''How long will anyone
travel through a lonely journey?''
spend a lifetime in loneliness''
''She will come some day...
my love will''
''How long will l remain lonely?''
''How long will you remain lonely?''
''He will surely come some day...''
''My love, will''
''Somewhere, someday...''
''you and l will meet''
''Every man dreams of the
girl he wants''
''Love...''
''l'll fall in love''
''Mischief, l will be up to too''
''She's the one l dream about.
She's the one l desire''
''Every moment, l wait for her...''
''She's the one l pine for''
''He'll come with
the bridal headgear...''
''the bridal procession,
he will lead''
''He'll take me away as his bride''
''Every girl dreams of the
boy she desires''
''Every man dreams of the
woman he desires''
''Some will tell you...
some will hide it''
''lt's a strange situation
to be in''
Praise Lord Shankar
You're Shiv. And l'm Shiv too
But you're God.
And l'm an ordinary human being
Lord, l'm starting a new life today.
You must've seen the newspaper.
l wonder how many people saw
that ad on the second page
They want an Executive Manager.
One post, many aspirants
But make sure You bless only me
Lord, when will this devotee of Yours
find a job? When will l make money?
When will l have a wife and kids?
When will l tell stories to them?
Our little family will then
come here and sing praises to You
Praise Lord Shankar
Just get me this job, Lord... please
And don't You think
of anyone else. Okay?
No matter how much
anyone prays to You
My obesiences, Goddess Parvati
l will say nothing to Shivji.
He won't listen to anything
A woman has to struggle so much
in a man's world
We've got to get pushed around
so much, try so many tricks to make it
Now for today's headlines
Look at the speeches they make
And women would have said the
same things with so much of compassion
But some people just won't listen
Let's see the second page.
Maybe l'll find some justice here
A job! There is a vacancy!
For the post of Executive Manager!
''Gender, no bar! The same status
for both, men and women''
l could make it. l'm so qualified...
l just can't lose out.
But You know who will be
the obstacle. Men again!
lt's up to You now, O Goddess
Please accept my humble plea
And please get me this job
You must win, Goddess.
Not Shivji. At least not this time
Going to eat? Go on
Will you have some water?
- No
Tea?
A cigarette then?
- No
Like to chew some tobacco?
How about meeting
You have no vices.
You're going to get this job
How come?
- True. This Hyderabadi...
can understand what your heart says.
l've been doing it for years
You're absolutely right, you know.
l'm No 1 ! l have all the degrees
- Really?
No power can stop you then
l'm Dil-phenk Hyderabadi. You?
- My name... Shiv. Shiv Kapoor
Shiv Kapoor? Do something, Pooja!
Or you're going to lose this job
Think of something. Go on!
What destiny! What luck, my boy!
Don't you forget me.
- How can you say such a thing?
As if l'd forget you! Don't worry.
- Dil-phenk, come here...
and stop chatting. Come on.
- The gentleman is calling me
He gives me great respect
Don't you forget me
- Don't worry. Go on
Who are you?
What are you here for?
Sit down. Sit
Okay, stand up....
Never mind. l'll sit down
What's that in your hand?
- Certificates of my qualification
For a job in Papa's office?
- Yes, well...
they issued that ad in the newspapers
for the post of Executive Manager
And so, l...
Why? What happened?
- This morning at breakfast...
Papa received a call from a
very influential man
Your job is gone.
- Gone? How can that be?
He receives a call and l lose my job?
Where is your Papa?
Calm down... sit
You want to go very far
in life, don't you?
All right then, trust Papa's daughter
and please go away. Okay?
You're such a rich man's daughter
and yet, so compassionate
Only my name won't impress him.
You must show him l'm capable too
Only then will he agree.
... when should l meet you again?
You don't have to meet me.
l'll meet up with you
l have your name and address, right?
- Right
So please leave now. Or l won't be
able to help you. Go on!
What is it now?
- You haven't told me your name
Beautiful name.
My name is Shiv Kapoor
Please don't forget
Damn it!
Thanks for living up
to Delhi's reputation
You've rammed into my
beautiful car, haven't you?
Your beautiful sister has
rammed into your beautiful car!
Brother! l've found a job!
- Great news!
Which means...
keeping me up all night with you
has finally helped!
l can now personally shoulder
my responsibilities
Here you are. Keep the change
and just get lost!
Great affection brother and sister
are showering on each other!
l'll give you news that will
brighten up your mood too, sis-in-law
Come on, brother. Let's tell her
Great news, sis!
- Sis? My foot!
Sister-in-law!
- Let go! What are you doing?
He's already panting.
- He's panting out of happiness
l've got a job as Executive Manager.
- Thank God!
You'll stand on your own two feet.
- Here l am. On my feet!
You must stand up too.
- What for?
For not having to cook tonight.
l'm treating you to dinner
Where?
- At Delhi's Number One restaurant
Wow! Do we get to eat like this every
day, or is this a one-time treat?
My sister has a large heart, Kittu.
She would do so much for us.
That's okay. But Pooja hasn't told us
how she got such a big job so easily
Want me to tell you the truth?
Or just fib?
You're always fibbing.
So tell us the truth this time
Very well then. Here goes.
When l got there...
it was as if all the doors
were open for me
There were many Toms, Dicks
and Harrys before l got there...
but who could have possessed
my kind of personality?
Oh yes.
- When l moved further...
the staff were so impressed,
they got up to salute me
They rolled out the red carpet
for me, leading to the boss
Guess what the boss said,
when he saw me?
Go on.
- He said, ''My child'' !
Such abilities, talent, confidence
and personality? ln this nation?
''Where were you all
these days, my child?''
You ought to have told him
that you were with us
Pooja, the boss called you ''child'' ?
- Oh yes, brother
And l started calling him ''Papa'' too
l'm sure it's divine intervention.
- Oh yes
All thanks to Goddess Parvati.
l wonder how She got Shivji to agree
Poojaji...
- Who's that?
Shiv. The one with the
high qualifications
Who are you?
- l'm Shiv... Shiv Kapoor
l see. And what are you doing here?
- l'm drowning my sorrows, Poojaji
lt's my friend's second
wedding anniversary
l had to come,
he dragged me here.
Or l was only thinking about you.
- What? Who's this, Pooja?
Shivji...
- Shivji?
Right. Shiv Kapoor. And you folks?
- My brother and my sister-in-law
Hasn't Papaji come?
Papaji?
- Yes. Papa
Have l said something wrong?
- Not at all
Didn't l tell you, brother?
Papa=Boss; Boss=Papa...?
That's just it
Okay, l'll do it for you
Very well then...
- l see. Very well then!
How can you leave like this?
You're Pooja's friend
You must eat with us tonight.
Pooja has ordered so much! Look
So much of food...?
What are you celebrating?
Celebrating the job, of course!
- Job?
Jobs, of course! lsn't it
my duty to get employment...
to every poor man, where l am?
- You'll give me a job, won't you?
Yes, l will. Good bye...
- All right... good-bye
Don't forget it, okay?
- What are you doing?
Amazing! Your first day at work
and you're already employing others!
l said my sister has a large heart!
This is how you must always be Pooja!
He's a good boy, although he's poor.
You must certainly give him a job.
Oh sure
God! He's driving me up the wall!
l'll have to do something about him!
The bloody hanger-on!
Sir, l've finished my work for the day.
Even the work for tomorrow
l've even sent that
detailed fax
ls this all?
l have something to discuss.
- Speak
l have a friend, sir.
He's very highly qualified
He stands first in sports.
And he has no vices at all
Well? What am l to do?
Sir, could you give him a job?
All right. Send him here right now.
l'll employ him
What job are you
going to give him, sir?
l'll fire you and hire him instead.
- What?
lt isn't even a week since
you've joined this office...
and you're already finding
other people jobs
Work sincerely, if you wish to.
Else, l'll have to show you the door
l'm late! lt's 9:00 already!
- lt's 9:00 ! l'm late!
Why don't the two of you wake up
early, if you don't want to be late?
You are both just the same!
Where's my key now?
- l'm getting very late, brother
Please drop me at the office.
- Are you mad, Pooja?
My office is in this direction,
yours is in that! No way! lmpossible!
Greetings, sir.
- Bhiku Singh? What're you doing here?
Running an errand for the boss, sir.
- For C.P. ? l see
Who's this?
- lt's my boss's car.
He's going in the same direction.
Ask him to give me a lift
Can you drop my sister at
Connaught Place, Bhiku Singh?
Go on. Hurry up
Pooja...?
Poojaji! Listen to me!
One moment, please!
One moment!
Listen to me!
One minute!
At least roll down the window!
lt's Shiv Kapoor!
l met you at the office, remember?
Thank you, Bhiku Singh.
You may go
Where did he spring from?
l've been calling out to you and
you wouldn't even look back at me
l've been following your car
on my bike
Really?
- Oh yes. And how would you listen?
lt's such a big car.
Fully air-conditioned
Your windows were shut.
How can you be blamed?
Well? What is it?
- Have you seen today's newspaper?
Have you?
- What does it say?
Your office has advertised again!
How could they, when you're around?
Your Papa will once again get a call
and l'll lose my job, won't l?
You're so naive.
You just don't understand
To remain in circulation! One has
to do it to fool people. See?
l see
But why must you worry?
l'm very much here
l've spoken to Papa.
Your job is confirmed
Confirmed? May l meet him then?
- Meet Papa?
Yes. l have an interview with him.
- Really?
Listen, be very careful
during the interview
Nobody must know that
l have recommended you.
Or you'll lose the job.
Not even my Papa, okay?
Go on now.
- May l?
Be very careful
You? What are you doing here?
How did you get here?
- l found you at last, didn't l?
Laddoos, Poojaji.
- How did you know l was here?
When will your friends help?
Those Anju's and Sush's...
you have an amazing friends' circle!
They were only too happy to tell me
Laddoos...?
- Come to the point. What is it?
Okay, where is your hand...?
- Let go! What are you up to?
Ever since you shook
hands with me...
my life has changed for the better.
- What happened?
Your Papa has taken your advise
He has employed me as
the General Manager!
What? What are you talking about?
Why're you so surprised?
You're the one who did it
Have some laddoos, Poojaji.
Made with clarified-butter
l bought them from Bengali Market.
Have some
That's enough.
- Enough? Have a whole laddoo
No, l don't have a whole laddoo.
- No? And l swallow half a dozen!
Give some to your brother and...
- No. Not them!
Why not? Give them some, too.
- Don't disturb them!
Give them some...
- l've heard you talking, Shivji
This is just what l
expected from you, Pooja
You've got this capable boy
a job at last
See what a large heart my sister has?
And you...
Not just large-hearted...
she's a magnanimous Delhi-ite!
Know what? You do have
a beautiful sister!
Shut up, feller! And put
those laddoos away!
Let me watch Aishwarya Rai!
- Don't be angry, Sardarji
l've got a job today.
Have some laddoos.
Congrats! l'll have two laddoos.
- One for me...!
Congratulations, General Manager!
This Hyderabadi will now treat you
to the most delectable food!
Thanks a lot, my friend
lt's only after l met you that
l embarked on this lovely journey
Had you hung around the other day,
you wouldn't have got this post
You'd have been hanging,
lower down in the ladder
True. lt's all thanks to Poojaji
As long as l live,
l'll worship only Pooja
Pooja? Pooja who?
The manager?
Come on! You're giving the employer
the status of an employee?
This is the limit! Thanks to her,
so many poor guys have found jobs
Take my case. Hadn't she put in a word
for me to her father, the employer...
could we have been chatting in
this posh, air-conditioned office?
What a shame! You're making
my head swim with rubbish
That girl has made
a sucker out of you
She got rid of you the other day
and snatched your job. That's it!
What does that mean?
- l mean, she's just...
an executive manager. Nothing else!
Which means, the boss
isn't dear papa at all?
Chopra, the old fossil,
is a rotten old fig!
And he's still a bachelor!
You mean Pooja didn't
recommend me at all?
My dear naive boy!
Recommend you? She's been
cutting you out all the way!
Really? So she took me for a ride!
- Yes.
And took me all over Delhi!
- Oh yes!
She has turned out to be
quite an actress!
Dil-phenk, call her immediately.
l'll fix her
l'll call her. And you
must teach her a lesson
lt's your right.
You're the General Manager!
Let her come. l'll show her
l'll teach her such a lesson, she'll
never think of conning anyone again
Do come
My word!
Sit down. Why're you standing?
- How can l sit in your presence?
You have done so much for me
You took my destiny into your hands
and made my life
You've recommended me to your Papa
at the breakfast table!
l do that very often.
- ln a flying Mercedes car...
you weren't thinking about yourself.
You thought of me
lnstead of the Executive Manager,
you made me the General Manager!
You're such a great person.
lt's amazing, Poojaji!
Would you like to have some tea?
- Tea...?
What...?
You dare make a fool out of me?
Shiv? Call me ''Sir'' !
Poojaji! l went about worshipping you.
And you kept making a fool out of me!
The pampered daughter of the
dear Papa...
you're a sympathiser of the poor
and recommend them, don't you?
You played around with me! You conned
me the first time we met...
and walked away with my job!
And as if that wasn't enough...
you polished off fancy delicacies with
your brother at the 5-star hotel!
Like a madman, l went around Delhi
looking for you...
and you were sitting in the theater,
watching the latest movie!
And l still got laddoos made
for a stone-hearted girl like you!
With clarified-butter!
So tell me now, Poojaji...
what am l to do with you?
Must l kill you? Or let you go?
Tell me
l agree to any punishment you
hand out to me, Mr General Manager
Will you do as l say?
- Yes, l will
Will you marry me?
''The way you look,
tells me...''
''l'm the one you love''
''The way you talk,
tells me...''
''l'm the one you could die for''
''l'd teach you the way of loving...''
''and lay down my life for you,
my love''
''You set my heart racing,
you taught me lessons in love...''
''you have accepted me,
you're my crazy lover''
''We have taken a vow...
we will never part''
''This is a new story,
this is a new friendship''
''This is my first love...
you're my first beloved''
''Under the blue skies,
two young hearts meet in love''
''The way you breathe,
it tells me...''
''l'm the one you love''
''The way you lurch forth,
it tells me...''
''l'm the one you could die for''
''l'm not in my senses;
you realise nothing''
''lt's the effect my love
has had on you''
''Let's lose ourselves
in each other...''
''so that no one in the world
can ever see us''
''Every secret of your dreams
tells me...''
''l'm the one you love''
''The way you embrace me, tells
me..''
''l'm the one you
could die for''
''l'd teach you the way to love...''
''and lay down my life
for you, my love''
''You set my heart beating,
you taught me lessons in love...''
''you have accepted me,
you're my crazy lover''
''We have sworn, we have vowed...
never to part''
lt's morning already.
But your mischief isn't over
Don't ruin the General Manager's
mood, okay?
l'm the only General Manager
in this house!
l didn't deny that. You're the
General Manager of my heart too.
lt's amazing! l sometimes wonder...
how l could to sleep alone
all these years.
What must the poor bachelors
be going through?
Are wives meant only for this?
You men are all alike!
You just won't improve.
- lf we improve, madam...
what happens of you women?
- lt's pointless arguing with you
Get up now, bathe
and leave for work
Or we won't even have this house
the company has given us
Get up...
- No
Must l go to the office today?
- l've given up the job
lf you don't go to work,
what will we live on?
Simple. We'll live on love and air.
l'll eat you up too!
This is my right!
- No rights. Just get up
See who's at the door...
go on!
Get up, please!
You're very lazy! Get up and go.
@ 02/05/11902
Who are you?
Milk!
- What?
l'm the milkmaid, sir.
My name is Kismis
Take it
How much?
Accounts are settled at
the end of the month, sir
You're a newcomer?
- Yes. We're newcomers
So tell me... is one packet enough?
Or must l give more?
One should be enough. Why?
l ask, because people in this
building use lots of milk
One is enough.
- l'll leave then, sir
l say, sir...
- What?
Lend me a hand.
With this burden.
- Sure. One moment
God! l've been had!
May l say something, sir?
- Go ahead
You're a very decent man.
A very nice gentleman
You have a handsome face...
you worthy of befriending, sir
Really?
- Oh yes. May l leave, friend?
Tomorrow morning then
Has the friend left?
Yes, she has.
lt was the milkmaid
So it's going to take so much of
time to fetch milk every morning?
You could've seen her off downstairs.
- l was only helping her...
and what are you thinking about?
A milkmaid and l...? C'mon Pooja!
l know you men very well.
Give me the milk
First give me what is mine
What?
This lungi and kurta you're
wearing, are mine
Go on. Take it off.
- Come inside. l'll give it to you
Now. Right now
Have you gone mad...?
People are watching!
Let me go!
Shiv, l'm going to take the
milk from tomorrow. Not you
This is funny. He calls us here
and doesn't turn up himself
l can't understand why he said,
we mustn't tell Pooja
They haven't had a fight, have they?
Your sister always itches for a fight
Not more than you do.
- Taking up for your sister again?
She's lucky to have found a
husband like him in such times
Here he is
Sorry, folks
Can't help this Delhi traffic.
l'd have zoomed in on a bike
Ever since l got this car,
l get stuck everywhere
What is the secret that you call us
here without even telling Pooja?
What's the day today?
- 15th of December
And tomorrow?
- The 16th of December. So what?
What, eh? You forget it, after
all the years she spent with you?
And l remember everything in
just a few months with her
Tomorrow's Pooja birthday.
- l know. So listen...
We'll first buy a huge cake.
We'll pack some food...
buy lots of balloons and gifts
and surprise her at midnight!
And l thought my husband had
brought me out to the amusement park
l'm not leaving without
sitting on the giant-wheel
As if it's your age
to sit on the giant-wheel
What...?
- No age-bar to enjoy life
We'll do just as your wife says
Come on, brother.
- lt's very high! l'm not sitting in it
Come on...
- No! l'm scared, Shiv!
Go with her instead.
- No. The couple sit together
Come on...
- Are you coming too?
lf l don't come back alive,
look after my bitch
What rubbish! Come!
- Look after my Kittu!
Not too high, mister.
l'm scared
What happened? Why's it jammed?
- Don't worry
lt'll start up again. Enjoy the sight
of Delhi from this height, my love!
Let's spend the night chatting
Will you be my friend?
My name is Shiv Kapoor.
l have a wife. A missus
Her name is Pooja
Pooja, my darling wife
l say, brother-in-law...
- Yes?
lt's already midnight, l say
Oh yes. All the way
Today's your wife's birthday?
But it's so sad.
You're stuck here... with me
Looks like they're fixing it
l wonder how many more jolts
l'm going to get tonight
Oh yes. l don't know how many jolts
this husband will take tonight!
Where were you?
First tell me where you were.
- l'll tell you. l'll explain
l know you will believe what l say.
- Now tell me the truth...
only the truth. Speak up!
- l was in the office all night
There was something only l could do.
l knew it was your birthday...
but l couldn't disobey the boss.
- Really?
But l kept calling the office
all night. Nobody took the call
All the lines were disconnected.
They were held up
lt was as if l was in the skies
and you were here, on earth
Who baked it?
- l did
Shall we cut it?
- No
Do you think l'll give in so easily?
lt's a nice story...
but what is the truth? Tell me.
You're not having a fling, are you?
What rubbish! Do l want
to have a fling and die?
Are you angry?
l flared up on you without
even thinking, didn't l?
Forgive me... l'm sorry
All right
l don't like you suspecting me
all the time
After all, how much will a man
convince you? You must trust me...
My sulking lover...
you're angry, are you?
l get all rotten ideas. l have
brains that work over-time, don't l?
All right... what's happened
is in the past
Today's your birthday, isn't it?
So this evening, is solely for you
We'll dance, make merry,
eat and drink
And make love
May l go and take some rest now?
l'm exhausted
Go on
lt's nice... and different
lt's work, day in and day out!
Who have you been talking to?
Your boss-papa
He's sending me to a conference.
- When are you leaving?
l'm not going alone.
You're going with me too
What does that mean?
- lt means...
what every lndian dreams of...
destination Switzerland
Switzerland? Really?
Of course. Your boss-papa is sending me
there to attend a conference
you and l, will celebrate
a delayed-honeymoon
Shiv, see how lucky my birthday is?
Just wait and watch
There's going to be an explosion
every second!
My God! l find you here!
l was wondering where l'd find you.
And here you are
lt's Laila! Shiv, have you
forgotten me in just a night?
Pooja? Your wife?
Celebrating your birthday, l see
We celebrated it last night
The two of us were stuck
up there, in the darkness
Shiv, in the confusion of
the darkness night...
l think my diamond-watch
slipped over to you
Did you find it?
Yes, he did. Certainly.
Your watch is with me.
This is the one, isn't it?
This diamond-watch
is terribly expensive
So l was scared.
- l was looking for you too
l wondered how l would
return to you, what is yours
Shiv, may we return her thing to her?
l've got my precious watch!
Listen to me, okay...
Hear me out, Pooja.
- What's there to say or listen to?
Maybe you're making a mistake, Pooja.
Maybe it's something else...
Shiv could explain only if you're
prepared to listen, isn't it?
What will he explain to me?
l've met the girl...
he spent the whole night with!
l'll never forgive him!
Whatever happens, l'm not
going back to him!
Enough! You break your relationship
for every little thing?
You're willing to walk out
of your house for nothing?
This isn't how you go through life.
Marriage is no child-play...
that you blow a thing like this
out of proportion, Pooja
Listen to the truth, if you must.
Shiv called us to the fair...
to prepare for a surprise
birthday party for you
l insisted on sitting on the
giant-wheel and the poor man agreed
Our misfortune! The giant-wheel
broke down...
and we had to spend
an entire night in it!
When we got down, Shiv requested us
not to tell you...
that he had spent the night
sitting with another girl
He said Pooja wouldn't be able
to take it. And he was right too!
He was right. You have done
just what he expected you to do!
lf you have any sense,
go back to your husband...
seek his forgiveness
and bring him around!
Not at all
Pooja does not need to seek
my forgiveness
She need not apologise to me.
lt's enough that she loves me so much
And yes, she has a very
unique way of loving me
And this is what l'm crazy about
l know it, Pooja. More than the
amount of anguish you cause me...
you feel tormented yourself.
More than you make me ache...
you ache too
All this, only because
you love me so much
But l have loved you too, Pooja
l have loved you too
''l'm your love,
my heart beats for you...''
''do always be with me''
''l'm your love,
my heart beats for you...''
''do always be with me''
''Should you have any
grouse against me...''
''do always tell me''
''l have loved you too, my love''
''Yes, l have loved you too''
''l'm your love,
my heart beats for you...''
''do always be with me''
''Should you have any
grouse against me...''
''do always tell me''
''l have loved you too, my love''
''Yes, l have loved you too''
''The way you drop your tresses,
and lower your gaze...''
''where did you learn this spell from?''
''You too have a way with words''
''Go on... stop pestering me''
''Passions are taking over...
my yearning is getting worse''
''don't giggle and make it worse''
''Should you have any
grouse against me...''
''do always tell me''
''You're as mischievious
as a madman...''
''but l know the truth
about your heart''
''Don't you understand what
the climes tell us...?''
''We can't do on our own anymore''
''Don't take such a deep breath,
be not so naughty...''
''don't be stubborn''
''Should you have any
grouse against me...''
''do always tell me''
''l'm your love,
my heart beats for you...''
''do always be with me''
Yes, l have loved you too
How will l spend
the entire day without you?
You know l'm here for the conference.
lt's only till this evening
l'll be back in a jiffy.
Go shopping till then
Eat and go to sleep.
And dream of me
You're the one who's giving me
a surprise. lt must be...
5 years since college and
when we last met, right?
Really? ls it so long already?
Pooja, this is Meghna.
We studied together in college
Know what, Pooja? Shiv was the
most handsome guy in college
his studies and sports.
But now that l see you, l must say...
he does have a great choice.
You're the one he finally chose
Don't believe her, Pooja.
Meghna was a brilliant student too
She always had a way with words
What are you doing in Switzerland?
- l came on business
ln fact, l must leave now
or l'll get late
You're put up at this hotel, right?
Why don't we have dinner together?
So tonight will be an amazing night
l'm glad you like some girl at least
Hurry up and go now.
And come back soon
Come on, you've got to get ready
What's up, Meghna?
- My car has broken down
Where have you to go?
- To Geneva. To attend a seminar
Life sure is a co-incidence!
l have a conference in Geneva too
Come, l'll give you a ride
How about my return?
- l've got to return to the hotel too
We'll come back together
You can talk to me in Hindi.
l'm an lndian, Madam
Do you have a bigger model
of that beautiful house?
l want a bigger one.
Not right now.
You can have it tomorrow.
All right then. l'll give you an
advance now and pick it up tomorrow
At what time tomorrow?
- 10:00 a.m. Sharp
Namaste.
- Namaste
Absent-minded professor!
You're still forgetful
ls your work over?
- Yes. And yours?
Yes. Shall we leave now?
- Let's return. Rouge Mont
lt'll take us 3 or 4 hours
l still can't believe how absent
minded you are. You haven't changed
Looks like there's a problem
Shiv! How much time will it take?
7 or 8 hours? l'll freeze
to death in the car!
Ask him if there is a place
we can spend time at
l suggest l ring up Pooja and
tell her that we're held up here
The phone had to disconnect now!
What happened?
- The line got disconnected
Let me try and make that call.
You go and change
lf something happens to you,
your wife is going to kill me
''Where have we landed...?''
Why're you laughing?
- Why? Look at you!
You look crazy! l mean...
you look like a mad gypsy!
Remember when you played mad gypsy?
- l did? When?
ln college, of course!
Have you forgotten?
How we danced during that
inter-collegiate competition
You aren't to be blamed
for what happened, Shiv
What happened between us
was just an accident
You mustn't think l will interfere
in your life, Shiv...
or that l will pose
any difficulty for you
And why must you hold
only yourself responsible?
l played an equal part in it
Shiv, l want this to remain
a secret between you and me
So l'm leaving
We will never meet again
Not a thought for me!
Do you have any defense for
the mistake you have made?
Will you ever be able to alleviate
the agony you have caused to me?
Will you ever...?
Let me ask you. Had l made
the mistake you have made...
would you ever have forgiven me?
Answer me!
Would you forgive me?
Do you have an answer...?
Speak up!
You don't, do you?
You can't!
You can't have an answer
for such a grave sin!
There can be no pardon
You and l cannot live
under the same roof anymore
We can't spend our lives
together anymore!
l will never forgive you!
The faith and trust l had in you...
You must regret your mistake
all your life
You must pay a price
for betraying my trust
l want Divorce
Divorce!
''Yes, l have loved you too''
lt's like this, Pooja. You've been
through so much, if you think of it
But you've been through nothing,
if you don't think about it
You have been courageous
in taking this step
Maybe you've done the right thing
by not staying with your brother
You haven't made your problems
the cause of their worry
Problems and sorrows
are all part of life
So why shouldn't a woman
face them...
move forward, and shape
her own destiny?
You don't have to tell anyone here
that you were married
Or that you have had a divorce
You know how people view a
woman who has been divorced
But this is the city of Mumbai
in which you have arrived
Nobody here cares for
the past lives of others
People come here to start
life afresh
There's no saying when and where
you will come across a messiah
Neha, l couldn't even dream of finding
a nice friend like you so soon
Now that you're with me,
l will surely find a way
So be courageous. Make the attempt,
and l'll do my best too...
to find you a job. Okay?
God! You're great
l wish every designer
was like you
You're a magician... a wizard
Neha, l mean it. Your boss
is the Designer Number One!
Look, l'm so beautiful.
Like Pui Bawla
Am l not right?
- Who's Pui Bawla?
Pui Bawla...? Don't you know?
She's the Heroine Number One!
l see
Bunty must also be designing
Pui Bawla's costumes, right?
Yes.
- He must be, of course!
A film star, after all. Obviously,
he must be giving her all his time
That's just what l hate about him
During the awards
function last year,...
he designed the clothes
for Heroine No 1
He's always designing clothes
for film stars
Do we society women
lack something?
What do these film stars
have at all? What?
What happened?
- The film folks are coming
They'll take offence
Who's that?
- Raj Malhotra, the film star
They're on his staff.
- Hello, Nehaji
Are our leading man's dresses ready?
- l was waiting for you, Babban Miyan
The costumes for the hero's
dance sequence are ready
God! So many costumes
for a single song...?
They must be changing behind trees!
Their tastes in eating, dressing et al!
Everything is so loud!
Why must one leading man need
so many people on his staff?
They're show-offs! Just show-offs!
- Watch your tongue...
lest my heart pops out
of my chest
Who's this lady without
any control on her tongue?
Who's this female?
l could deliver a stinging slap!
No... it's Mrs Chana Singh. Wife of
leading industrialist, Ghana Singh
Wife? ls this how wives are?
What's wrong with her husband? How
could he swallow such a big snake?
Ask him to send her around in a burqa!
Anyone who sees her, will die!
You're scaring us with your looks.
What's all that?
What's he saying?
- Shut up, you lame horse!
You wear this weird make up and pass
comments on your hero's costumes?
You're insulting our hero?
This fatso sure does blabber!
l'll feed you stale food and you can
sit bombarding on the potty!
She's already stinking
Ghana Singh's wife is insulted thus?
Go on, get lost, or people will
dump garbage on you
You old fossil in white!
Old fossil? Want to try me out?
What did you call me?
l'll have you sacked!
She sure is a funny one!
- Enough
Maria, Chinni, enough of jokes
Neha, are the costumes ready?
- Absolutely
But l've got some work
for you folks today
What is it?
You offered me secretaryship to
the film star recently, remember?
You know, l wouldn't ever
turn it down
But how will l quit
Mr Pandit's employ?
l have a friend. She's a very
nice girl. And trustworthy too
l can stand guarantee for her,
if you wish
lf you could give her the job...?
Send her over to the shoot.
She'll have the job
Really? Will she get the job?
- l can tell a man for what he's worth
Which is why we had offered
the job to you
Now that you're recommending
someone else, she must be good too
We give you our word. The three
of us will see she has the job.
Don't tell me, Neha!
How can l handle this job?
What's wrong with it, Pooja?
- Films? l...?
l know nothing about films
or the film-world
Pooja, there are good and bad
people everywhere in the world
lt's for you to conduct yourself
the way you want to
As for these folks,
l know them very well
l think you're going
to find a job there
As for your future boss...
his staff lovingly calls him hero-ji
He's a very nice man. Even in
a world of glitter and stardom...
he has his feet firmly
on the ground
No wonder he's the darling
of the masses
What's the name of the film star?
- Raj. Raj Malhotra
''How can anyone spend a lifetime
without love?''
''The beloved's eyes
hold a treasure, my friend''
''How can anyone spend a lifetime
without love?''
''The beloved's eyes
hold a treasure, my friend''
''On earth descend sometimes,
the Moon and the stars...''
''such are the treasures
the beloved's eyes hold''
''ln this lifetime,
there will be a story...''
''no longer can l spend my youth
in loneliness''
''So let me find a beloved...
on a night so lovely''
''Let me listen to her heartbeat
and tell her how l feel''
''lt's a matter of destiny to
find the support of her arms''
''The beloved's eyes
hold a treasure, my friend''
''How can anyone spend a lifetime
without love?''
''Belong to someone...
and take someone for your own''
''Let your eyes
dream lovely dreams''
''Remain in my arms...
forget the world''
''Let me lie in these tresses...
and kiss her moist lips''
''Let your eyes
dream lovely dreams''
''The beloved's eyes
hold a treasure, my friend''
''On earth descend sometimes,
the Moon and the stars...''
''such are the treasures
the beloved's eyes hold''
''How can anyone spend a lifetime
without love?''
Take it off quickly
ln a moment, hero-ji.
Will you have some patience, please?
Have some fruits, hero-ji.
- No food from home? No chicken?
No chicken. You've got to remain fit.
There's so much of competition
Look at the old-timers.
Dharmendra, Jeetendra
They've fed on fruits for
40 years and remained fit
Their staff has been fit
for 40 years too
Stop talking and tell Babban Miyan
to get the car out
The car's ready. But where will
you go and when will you return?
The secretary has left us
in a mess of schedules...
what have you thought about that?
This is the problems we have when
secretaries turn producers
Where will we find
someone honest now?
We mustn't a crooked man!
Our hero-ji's such a simple man...
they'd rip him apart.
- So where will l find the man?
lt could be a woman too, right?
- A woman?
Can a woman handle my affairs?
When l can look after your house,
your clothes, your food, everything...
why can't a girl look after your dates,
your schedules and your accounts?
lf we could find an honest
and trustworthy girl...
but where will l find one?
- We've found her already
You've found her already?
- Yes
And who is she?
Where is she?
- Just a minute
Hero-ji, this is Pooja
Neha, the designer's assistant,
has sent her over
Why talk in French?
l'd rather you did it in Tamil
She's a very good girl
You must interview her, okay?
So, you're...?
- Let me tell you at the outset, sir
l know nothing about
the film business
So how will you handle this job?
Neha and your staff asked me
to meet you. So, l...
l see. So what are you
well-versed with?
l'm familiar with computers
l know a lot about programming
and accounting. That's all
That's all? And that is enough
The knowledge you have
is enough for this job
You could say you've landed the job
- Pardon me?
Yes. lf my staff says you're good,
you really are good
So tell me how do we
sweeten your tongue now?
With these sweetmeats!
Here you are. Offer Pooja the sweets!
Wow! Here you are. Have some sweets.
- Go on
No small pieces. Take a whole laddoo
Fortunate are those who get
to eat all these goodies
No taunts, hero-ji
But you may have two laddoos
to celebrate her arrival
Not two... eat up all there is!
- Thanks. Keep this in the car
You can report to duty tomorrow
Hero-ji has appointed a new secretary.
She'll be here any moment
Pooja is here! All the mess
will now be cleared!
Come here. This is Pooja.
The new secretary
Whatever you've got to ask,
you will now ask her. Okay?
Namaste
What are you doing, Babban Miyan?
lt's a 2 'o clock shift. And you
wake me up early in the morning!
l know. Apart from film shootings...
there are many things you've
got to do on your own
This big house and all those people
downstairs... who'll handle them?
You have no one of your own either.
- So what are you folks worth?
Okay, but there are things
we can't do. Only you can
And this is something
only you can do, hero-ji. Not we
Such as...?
- Such as, signing documents
lssuing cheques. Who'll do all that?
- You do it, Miyan
No thank you. By God, don't
trust people in the world so much
lt's a terrible world!
Money's everything for them
May l say my lines now?
- Sure, go ahead
May l go for a bath?
- Sure.
But come back soon. And see...
how the world is waiting for you
You said there were a lot of people.
There's not a soul here
The producers must have fled
My mistake
Will you stop flying please?
He said there were producers here
to meet me. Where have they gone?
Bingo! The wonder girl
has worked a miracle!
She brewed such a broth
that everything fell in place!
lf you guys are going to say
everything, what lines will l say?
Now tell me what happened.
- Pooja-ji! The wonder girl!
The way she handled the producers,
l could only watch in amazement!
l swear it on God, my eyes can
never make a mistake!
This is the right girl, hero-ji.
- Really? And where is Pooja-ji?
Meaning...?
- She's working. On the computer
Are you through?
- l'm doing it... l'm still at it
Sir, l've sorted out those dates
that were messed up
Accounts of money we've
received against shooting,...
l've fed in the computer
l've fixed your appointments with
directors, during lunch-break...
so you won't be disturbed.
You've got to read some agreements...
and sign them now.
- Okay
ls all the work over?
- Yes
Nothing remaining?
- No
ln which case, why must you come here
all thirty days in a month?
Come just for a day.
- One day?
Yes. What's the date today?
The first
So we'll meet up again
on the first of the next month
lt's pack up for you.
You may go
What are you saying, hero-ji?
You've ruined all our joy!
Pooja-ji handled everything so
quickly with her intelligence...
and you just won't praise her!
- You've messed up the grease-paint!
She completed a month's work
in just one day
So what will she do for the
rest of the 29 days? What?
You've worked for a day, Pooja.
You get paid for a day's work too
Goodness isn't appreciated!
The same amount of work...
the previous secretary took
2 months to complete!
And you paid him double the salary!
- No wonder he became a producer!
And you won't appreciate Pooja for
completing everything so soon!
Where will l break my head now...?
He's laughing!
Sir, you're laughing?
- l was only joking
And you talk of breaking heads?
Where were you all these days?
Where?
l must say, you folks do
have an eye for people
Now tell me, how many years contract
do l draw up for her?
20 years? 25 years...?
- For a lifetime. Forever, sir!
No secretary works like this.
Only a wife does...
the one made for you, does!
Have l said something wrong?
- You always say the wrong line
What did l say?
- l'll tell you later
You mustn't take offense
at what they say
Because l'm so lonely, they're
always cooking things up for me
They aren't bad at heart
You have handled everything
in just a day, l'm impressed
Know what? l had this problem
for quite a few days
l couldn't decide what was right
and what was wrong
But now l think everything
will be all right
Get on with your work.
Please carry on
Poojaji, please don't feel bad
about anything
Now that you're here,
it's going to be fun
We'll do good work and
spend our days in fun
We won't even know when
the climes change
Raj, give me just two minutes. Please
Chinni, please come here
What is it, Pooja?
There was a call from
Mr Morani and Mr Soorma
l think they want to discuss
dates personally with you
So l'll meet up with them.
Just tell me when
Anytime you wish.
l'll tell you your programme
Raj, please let's have
another rehearsal
lf l mess up this time, l'm
going to get a lot of scolding
All right. Wait here, Pooja
l'll speak my lines, okay?
- No, let's begin with my lines
All right. Go ahead
l'm so happy today...
Where is she, Raja?
- Who?
She
Why need that when you
have this one?
What?
- What does that mean?
l'll tell you what it means
Rascals! Have you nothing
better to do?
Do you come here
only to bother girls?
Have you been taught nothing better?
Can you only talk nonsense?
Come here...
l'm going to smash your face
You won't be able to
face anyone again
Your tongues wag a lot!
You want to have fun!
You want girls, eh?
You want girls?
Was this enough or do you
want some more fun?
No! Enough!
So when are you leaving the hotel?
Today! Right now!
- Good
Get lost soon.
- Sure we will
Room No 420.
A room for frauds indeed.
You must apologise to all
those you have insulted
l'll wait for you
Heroji, they're escaping
Where are you guys going...?
Wait... you don't have to leave
Leave after you watch the shooting.
- No thanks
You must have fun!
How can l let you leave like this?
Go after you see the shooting
Come, l'll introduce you
to the whole unit
This is the director.
Say namaste to him
Namaste
This is our heroine.
Pay your respects to her
Our respects.
- This is my make-up man, Chinni
Hello.
- Hello
No hello. Touch his feet
Go on. Take his blessings.
You've got to play the baddies
You haven't met her. She's...
- Namaste, Pooja
Namaste, Poojaji.
- Poojaji?
Sister Pooja!
- Good. But try something new
Something spontaneous.
- Praise the Lord, Sister Pooja
Praise the Lord! You do have
respect for womenfolk
You must come to the shoot tomorrow.
Oh yes, you must!
Where are we shooting
tomorrow, Poojaji?
We're shooting at the graveyard
We're going to bury the dead.
You must attend!
You must! Please!
Don't make me lose my temper...
l might push you
They've had it
l'm sorry
Stop giggling and attend
to my hair, Chinni
What are you writing?
- Nothing
Let me see what you're writing
l knew you'd do something like this.
That you would resign
This is how you girls are.
You flare up at everything
Tell you what? Go into the
kitchen and smash things
Your temper will cool down.
- You cooled down. By beating them up
There wasn't a better way
of handling it, was there?
Was it necessary to do all that?
- lt's like this, Pooja
lt makes no difference to me
what they write or say about me
Because my life is an open book
But l know, it makes
a difference to you
You can't tolerate it, because
you're not used to it
So l did what l had to.
And you're angry with me?
You're handing in your resignation?
- Please don't misunderstand me
l don't want such a thing
to happen ever again
They... they could say
anything about you and me
So let them!
l'm not backing out, am l?
What...?
And what do you think?
That you will give me the resignation
and l will let you go?
God has brought us together
at the right time
You're lonely. So am l
Where would we meet, if not here?
Why don't we get to know
each other better?
You don't know anything about me
l don't even want to
That you've heard me out and haven't
even slapped me, is enough for me
You look so nice when you smile.
Always keep smiling
Wrong timing
Whenever l'm going to say something
nice, Mr Chopra will always call up
Mr Chopra? Yes, everything
has been arranged
Yes, l've done my packing
Aren't we going to Australia?
So...?
l have a request.
Book another ticket
The name is... Pooja.
- No
lt's confirmed, yes
How can l...?
l've been all over the world.
But there's no place like Switzerland
lt's heaven!
Why don't you want to go, Pooja?
What's wrong with that?
Besides, you're going there
on business too
How long will you keep
feeling afraid like this?
How long will you cling
to your old memories?
How long will you hide?
You must set out
on the same path again
On the same path, you must wipe out
the old foot-prints with new ones
You must show courage, Pooja.
And move forward
Don't stop yourself. Don't
Life's once again calling out to you
You must embark a new journey
once again, Pooja
You must go, Pooja.
You must
There's that lady sitting
there on Seat No. 3B
Ask her what she wants.
Or she won't ask for anything
Thanks, l want nothing
Shiv! Leave me alone!
What are you doing?
This isn't our bedroom.
lt's an aircraft. Leave me alone!
You won't stop being mischievous!
Let me go...
- Should l?
Here goes. l'll be back in a moment?
- Where to? Come back soon
You've just been married?
Yes. A few days ago. We're going
to Switzerland on a honeymoon
The dream of every lndian
Right
ls this your first visit?
- No...
Yes. This is my first visit too
l'm told it's heaven
We could have gone anywhere
else in the world
But l believe that Switzerland
is very lucky for married couples
lt's just great for those in love
l'm very lucky. My husband
is a very nice man
Are you married?
No
Maybe you won't get the
same feeling as l do
From what l'm told,
it's a place...
which gives you memories
for a lifetime,...
should you spend a few moments
there with your beloved
No matter how much you try,
you can never erase those memories
''l'm your love;
my heart beats for you...''
''do always be with me''
''Should you have a grouse
against me...''
''do tell me''
''l have loved you too...''
''Yes, l have been in love too''
''l'm your love;
my heart beats for you...''
''do always be with me''
''Should you have a grouse
against me...''
''do tell me''
''But do be with me''
''l have loved you too...''
''Yes, l'm in love with you''
''How will l forget
the moments l spent?''
''Every moment,
those memories torment me''
''How will l tell you?
lt's a secret l keep with difficulty''
''Those moments never come...''
''what's true is here,
this moment''
''Come to me, my love.
Give me a smile and talk to me...''
''do not remain silent''
''do tell me''
''But do be with me''
''everything here is
for you, my love''
''There are thorns among roses,
and a chill in the snow''
''What fire consumes
my breath all day and night?''
''This cold breeze say...''
''do not burn thus''
''Should you have a grouse
against me...''
''do tell me''
''But do be with me''
''Yes, l am in love with you''
Here you are, Babban Miyan. The
clothes for your schedule are ready
Thank you very much.
- No, l must thank you
You gave Pooja such a nice job.
- We do nothing
God gives everyone
his rightful place
Not just a family member...
a lifetime member
What did l say the other day...?
- Shut up, Chinni
''Come unto me, O beloved''
Neha, everything is all right.
Just don't worry
Your boss always advises me
to wear ordinary clothes
Ordinary clothes give one
peace of mind
The heart is no longer restless
What is more, one has control
over his tongue
You folks...? Pranaam.
- Pranaam
How are you?
How's your lovely world
of films doing?
You make such lovely films
You are such lovely folks.
Aren't you?
Are you shooting a song again?
- Well...
Go ahead.
Make a whole lot of costumes
Change as many clothes
as you wish to
Behind trees, on the mountains...
change wherever you wish to
What have l to do with it?
Right?
Well, may Chana Singh,
wife of Ghana Singh, leave now?
My two children must be impatiently
waiting for their mother's arrival
Gana Singh must be waiting for me
at the religious gathering
''When will you come?''
Good bye.
- Good bye
''Come unto me, O beloved''
Gana's going to die!
What sorrow after happiness!
Pooja told me you're going to a hill
station for shooting, Babban Miyan
A beautiful hill station in lndia
Whenever we have been there,
something has always blossomed
Let's see what blossoms
at Naini Hills this time
''Tie the dancing-bells
to my feet...''
''and watch my swagger''
Oh yes. You're shooting at
Naini Hills this time
Where is the manager?
What for, sir?
What is it regarding?
Regarding? l've got to discuss
things with him. ln detail
His cabin is over there, sir
Manager, salutations
Greetings. Well?
l'm Mr Raj Malhotra's trusted man.
His driver, his Man Friday, Babban
l came to enquire about his room.
lt's secluded, l hope?
What does that mean?
- By God...
fans nowadays harass him a lot.
He's such a simple man...
he doesn't want the hassle.
- Don't worry
l've personally made all the
arrangements for him
You will have no cause for complaint.
- That's very kind of you. Thank you
You must have seen his films?
- No, l don't see films
You live in lndia and
don't watch films?
What say, manager...?
You're different too?
That's not how it is. l used to
see films earlier. l don't anymore
And you're missing nothing. Where are
the films they used to make earlier?
Where are those heroes
and heroines anymore?
Where will you find those stories?
What films they used to make
l used to be in Mr Yusuf Khan's
employ during those days
An artist like him has never graced
the lndian screen ever again
lt's all over.
After l left him...
l joined the hero.
My hero does only hit films
l make the choice
Which is why l'm with him
Even to take a look at his room,
this servant comes first...
he'll come later
Rest assured, Babban Miyan.
You will have no complaints
When is your boss arriving?
The hero's caravan should be here
any moment
Mr Raj Malhotra has checked in, sir.
You wanted to meet him, didn't you?
l'll talk to him over the phone.
Go on
May l speak to Mr Raj Malhotra?
Who's this?
The manager of this hotel
One moment
Call for you.
- Who is it?
The manager of this hotel.
My name is Shiv Kapoor
Yes, Manager?
lf there's anything you need,
please do let me know
You have a beautiful hotel
l can see in everything that
it's being managed nicely
lf there's anything you need,
you'll find me on extension 16
Please do call me.
- Of course l'll call you...
if l have problem.
Where else will l go?
But l'm finding everything
nice today
l'm the same,
so is everything else
Yet, l see a change
in something around
These eyes of mine have always
dreamt dreams for others, Pooja
For the first time, they're
daring to dream for themselves
They aren't doing anything
wrong, are they?
You can't ignore my remark
with a smile
You must give me an answer
You want to tell me something
before telling me about your decision?
You want to tell me
about your past?
l don't want to listen
But if it's going to relieve you
of a burden...
and makes it easier for you
to decide about me...
But remember this much.
No matter what you say...
my decision won't change
Speak
Speak, Pooja
l'm a divorcee
l was in love with someone
And we were separated
l told you, it won't
make a difference to me
lt'll stop making a difference to you
if you stop living in the past
Forget what has happened
What is with you now
is the only truth
So tell me quickly...
is it ''yes'' Or is it ''yes'' ?
Because there's no question
of saying ''No''
Know what? l'll pack up with
the shooting quickly...
and we'll go and prepare
for the wedding
No, that's wrong. We'll leave
after we complete our work
Get ready quickly. The whole unit
must be waiting there for you
l'll complete my pending work
and get there too
Let's have a small party in the
lawns of the hotel this evening
To celebrate our happiness
We won't tell anyone anything
Meet the manager and
organise the party
Now what was the manager's name...?
You're with Mr Raj Malhotra.
- That's right
Mr Malhotra wants to throw a small
party on the lawns tonight
l wanted to talk to you
about it
l want everything to
be perfectly organised
lt would be better if you could
discuss it with our manager
No. lt's enough that
l have spoken to you
Who is your manager, by the way?
- Mr Kapoor
His full name?
- Mr Shiv Kapoor
Has he just arrived?
- Yes. He's been with us for a year
Where is he from?
- Delhi
Where does he stay here?
- ln the cottage behind the hotel
ls his family here too?
- No, he's all alone
l see. Please see that everything
is perfectly organised
He's the manager you were
asking me about, madam
She was asking me so many
questions about you...
and she just walks away now.
Strange!
''What's love...?''
''fall in love,
and you will know''
''Make her laugh some,
make her cry some''
''The firefly burns...
and why?''
''burn yourself,
if you must discover the secret''
Heroji, you're playing
the firefly today...
and where is your flame?
- Keep that under wraps
''Why ask him about
playing Romeo''
''Come to me,
thou shall be Juliet''
That's great, Babban Miyan!
What's happening?
Everybody disappears
in the darkness?
Where's everybody?
Who are you?
l'm the manager of this hotel
There's a power-failure.
lt'll be restored soon
So you are the manager?
l must say, you've done
a great job of our party
You remember my name?
Once l hear a name,
l don't ever forget it
And you have such a lovely name.
Shiv Kapoor
l'm thinking of using that name
for myself in my next film
You appear to be very happy, sir.
You've even thrown a party
What makes you so happy?
- That's just what l can't tell you
lt's giving me a stomach-ache!
But l think l'll tell you how l feel
l'll at least be rid
of the stomach-ache
Must l...?
- Go ahead, sir
lf it will relieve you of your
stomach-ache, give me the pain sir
You won't tell anyone, will you?
Sure?
l've fallen in love with someone
And l'm going to get married
the moment l leave this place
Congratulations. Who is it?
The lights are back!
And my beloved too
Pooja, you must've met him already.
The manager, Mr Shiv Kapoor
Look at the pains he has taken
to make this a grand party
He's amazing
Why don't we let him handle
the decorations at our wedding?
l don't know why, but l felt
a sense of belonging with him
And l told him my secret
We have decided that you will handle
the decorations at our wedding
Well?
- Yes
You will make it as beautiful
as this party. You are amazing!
You get married only
once in a lifetime
l want my wedding to be
such a grand affair...
that people are left stunned.
Let's shake hands. C'mon!
Raj, are you through
with your couplets?
There's a gathering there also.
Let's go
l'll recite a couplet
and be back. lt's just that...
''lf there is anything that
is ignorant, it's the rose''
''The whole garden
knows the secret''
Pooja, l want to discuss
something with you
But l don't wish to talk to you
l'll wait for you in my cottage
Will you remain standing there?
Come on in
Sit down
Won't you sit?
- No. l'm okay
You're still angry?
You're still sulking?
You haven't changed.
Not in the least
You're still the same person
l first met
When you and l fought
for the same job
And we're still fighting
Know something, Pooja?
l could never get over the fact...
that you gave up everything you had
in just a moment. Only for me
To settle down with me
You came to be my companion
l don't know if you
ever miss me, Pooja...
but l could never forget you
Never
To forget you, l left that job,
that city and all those memories...
and started living here
But you have come here too
Just as destiny always brought us
together...
it's the same destiny that
has brought us together again
When l found you asking about me,
it gave me a lot of confidence
l thought you had not been
able to forget me
So why all this, Pooja?
How can you leave me
and go ahead like this?
lt's my free will. Who are you
to ask me why l'm doing all this?
l will do as l please
l do not need to seek
permission from anyone
And l've seen what l got
when l asked earlier
Deceit! And betrayal!
Pooja, can't you forget all that?
Must you give me such a big punishment
for something so trivial?
So trivial? You call it trivial?
What didn't l do for you?
l changed the course of my life!
When a woman gives up everything
for her man...
she nurtures the relationship with
sincerity, devotion and desires
l honoured every vow
l took with you
But you forgot the vow of fidelity
you had taken with me
You had sworn to remain loyal,
you had sworn to be faithful
By breaking the sacred vows,
you have deceived not only me...
you have betrayed God too!
You are a sinner!
And you must be punished
for your sins!
Really? So what do you want?
What punishment do you
want to give me?
Do you want me to be hanged?
l admit, l have made
a mistake Pooja
But my home was shattered too
You gave me a divorce and
severed your relationship with me
But you didn't give me even one
opportunity to explain
l didn't say a word then, Pooja...
because l thought
you were very angry
And your anger was justified
But you're still as angry
and obstinate as ever
You have no place for me
in your heart
One mistake, even God forgives
So go and seek forgiveness from God!
l can't forgive you. Never!
l can't forgive you. l can't.
Never
All right, Pooja
lf this is what you want,
l will not come in your way
l will not come between
the two of you
l think l must leave
this place
But l have promised the man
you're going to marry...
that l will decorate his wedding
You will no problems from me
during this wedding
Believe me or not...
from my heart will come
the best wishes for you
From my heart
Come on, guys
Why the tension, Mr Khanna?
- l have a problem, Raj
The guy who was supposed
to sing at your wedding,...
his flight has been cancelled
You're the only one who can
do something now. Save my skin!
You want me to sing?
- Yes
So everybody else runs away?
- Oh no
Ask one of the guests, producer
One of them must undoubtedly
have feeling in his voice
Why don't you sing, Sardarji?
- No! The bride will run away!
No, we don't want a song in Tamil
May l suggest something, Mr Raj?
- Go ahead
The manager has an amazing voice
lf his song doesn't make your
wedding greater, nothing will
Where is he?
- Who's that?
But where is he...?
Shiv saheb!
Here he is
Yes? ls everything okay?
Yes, everything is okay, but...
your secrets are being exposed
Pardon me?
You deserve praise for doing
a great job with my wedding
You have done me a great favour.
So please do me another
What?
- l'm told you have a great voice
The guy who was to be here to sing
won't be coming
So please sing something.
Something...
that will make me, my guests
and my bride... just sway!
We must remember nothing
except you!
What? Me?
Yes, you. Know what they call someone
who stands by you in such times?
The best friend. The friend...
who gives the bride away
to the bridegroom
Forget it. Sing something that
makes your voice a blessing for us
Please sing
''May the vermillion on your forehead
forever shine''
''May the henna on your palms,
forever be fragrant''
''May you forever be together''
''May your bangles
forever tinkle''
''Bless you, bless you''
''May your wedding be blessed''
''May you always be happy.
l pray for you''
''May the world kiss the earth
you tread on...''
''may you always be happy.
l pray for you''
''For you is the Spring''
''May you never face any sorrow''
''What is it about me?
l'm crazy''
''Nobody knows how l suffer''
''May you never have to
pine for love''
''May you always be happy.
l pray for you''
''Ties of a lifetime,
you can never sever''
''Midway through a journey,
you don't desert your companion''
''You mustn't ever forget
the norms''
''The vows you take, you must honour''
''l have spent a lifetime
in loneliness...''
''may you always be happy.
l pray for you''
''l have been in love too''
''Yes, l have also been in love''
''Yes, l have been in love''
Pooja, come...
l'm here to take you along
The guests are waiting
for you downstairs
l have kept my promise
l have no complaints or regrets
l face no dilemma...
that you're leaving
Your bridegroom has sent me with
so much of love, to fetch you
As his best man.
As his best friend
Something like this must
never have happened before
Perhaps this is the
first time ever...
that a man is getting his wife
married to someone else
lt isn't a nice thing to happen
To punish you, l have punished myself
Why didn't l forgive you?
Despite the love l had for you...
why did l deny myself?
What am l to do, Shiv?
What am l to do?
The sacred fire around which
we took the vows...
now chars my heart! lt won't
let me erase your name
lt won't let your name
be erased
Pooja, Raj is waiting
for us downstairs
His guests are waiting for us.
We must go now
Come on
You knew Shiv and
didn't even tell me?
You knew each other...
and l didn't even get to know?
ls he the man you were married to?
ls he the man you have
never been able to forget?
So he's the one you loved
with all your heart
He's the one you wanted to punish,
and ended up punishing yourself
This story began between
the two of you
Will you decide its conclusion now?
Or must l do it?
l'm told it's difficult
for lovers to get together
As far as l know and feel...
l think the two of you
are made for each other
What is right and what is wrong,
what's true and what's not...
who ought to be punished,
who should be forgiven...?
mere mortals like us
can not decide
But yes, if there is anything
that can decide it...
it's the vows you take to remain
together for seven lifetimes
And every vow you take together.
Which you can't forget so easily
lt's true, Pooja. That's just why
you couldn't move any further
Your eyes could never see
the truth behind the norms
You can't love anyone but Shiv
Pooja, signatures on a piece of paper
don't make or break relationships
The name you write on your heart...
you can never erase
in a lifetime
And there's just one name
in your heart. Shiv's
When you severed your relationship...
there was no one to stop you
or reason with you
And see where it has taken
the two of you
Only the fortunate ones have
someone to lead you by hand
l'll show you the way
ou could never understand
l'll restore for good, this
relationship that had broken
l hope you had a comfortable stay
and a successful conference
What are you doing here?
You're the one who's surprising me!
lt's seven years since we last met
Seven years?
We studied together in college
He was always busy with
his studies and sports
Now that l see you, l realise that
he had a great eye for women
He reserved it for you
l'm here for a conference
You will eat, won't you?
Shall we go?