Excuse me...
Please stop.
Did you see a child on the way?
No, what's the matter?
No, it's nothing.
Where has Raju gone?
Oh God!
Lord! For what sins
am l being punished?
My wife died some years ago.
Today l've lost my son!
l'm tired looking for him.
Now l come to You as
the last refuge!
Give me my son!
Wherever he be, protect him!
Master, you have a weak heart.
How will you get better if
you keep worrying about Raju?
You need rest.
Even death won't put me at ease.
l do not fear death.
But l hope l don't die
before seeing my son... !
The search is on for him.
l'm sure he'll be found.
Master! Your son has come!
Raju!
- Father!
My child!
Where were you, my son?
Where have these
elephants come from?
l have brought them.
l fell into the jungle when we
had the accident, the other day.
A leopard attacked me.
This elephant saved me.
Good Lord!
You are indeed merciful
and abound in generosity!
Son, these are no
ordinary elephants.
Lord Ganesha himself has appeared
in this form to protect you!
Good Lord...
- What do you want?
This is my Lord, Sri Ganesha.
l want to touch their feet!
My Lord... !
- Master!
Father, what's wrong?
Take care of them
when l am no more.
Don't ever leave them.
Never...
- Why do you say this?
l may not get another
chance to speak.
l'm going... .
No, father! l don't have a mother.
Whom do l have but you?
They will be yours...
These elephants will be your mates.
Master.
- Father!
Who is this uncouth man?
Why are you standing?
Go and get the ball.
Go on. Mahesh, Ganesh... come
here. Very good.
Save me!
This elephant is after my life!
l can give you my life.
Stop right there.
Go away from here
if you value your life.
You're very bad! l said,
go away or l'll mince you!
Hey, he's really gone
hearing your voice!
He won't bother you. He knows who
l am. He understood my signals.
Seems to belong to a good family.
l just moved away from you
and he chases me again!
Shall l give you an idea?
Don't go away till he leaves.
You are joking! Ask him to go!
All right. Wild animal!
Go away or l'll shoot you!
Look at him run with
his tail between his legs!
Amazing! You're a magician!
You're just flattering me.
You haven't seen my magic.
Show you a demonstration?
- This is enough.
What are you doing here?
l was going in my car
when a ball fell on me.
When l stepped out to check,
this elephant got after me.
How sad!
Uncouth man!
- Pardon?
May l escort you to the car?
You don't look familiar. A stranger
in these parts... travelling?
Alone, or are you escorted?
- My Daddy is here too
What's so good about that?
- l mean, where do you live?
We have our own bungalow.
- What did you say your name is?
l didn't tell you my name.
- Then tell now.
My name is Tanuja but people
lovingly call me Tanu. Your's.
My name is Rajkumar but
people lovingly call me Raju.
Glad to meet you.
Are you glad?
- Somewhat.
Thanks a ton, my friend.
l have it made.
Did you like the angel?
So you're with me.
Let's go friends,
we had a good game.
Run out of petrol
in the middle of nowhere!
So this is the matter!
Loafer! Uncouth boor!
Climb down!
ls your car not working?
- My brain is not functioning!
Hence l got taken in by your words!
What have l done?
Why... ? What happened?
You've found a good way
of teasing girls!
What did l do?
- Sent your elephant after me!
And then comes by himself
to fight the elephant!
To prove what a hero he is!
Softly! What will people
say when they hear?
l've seen plenty of heroes like you!
Possibly, but you don't
have to push me for that.
l just asked if your car has
a problem and if l could help.
l don't need your help!
Get out of my car!
Go away from here!
Fine, l'll leave.
Let's go friends.
Aren't you a very nice man!
You harass me! And leave me
all alone in these forests!
Talk softly.
- The car's run out of gas.
Tow it to a gas station.
- Never.
You have rewarded me enough
for my service.
You have abused me! So go and
find some people tow it!
l'll pay you for it! 5, 10, 50...
- Even 200 Rupees?
That wouldn't feed even
one of my elephants.
So you're not going help me!
- l will.
But there's a way of seeking help.
- What way?
The way lndian women
seek help.
What's that?
- Stop acting smart.
Fold your hands and request...
Sire, l need help.
We both agree to this.
Else we're off. Good day.
l beg with joined hands...
Please help this helpless woman.
We'll surely help. Come on.
Please sit down.
Get ready to push.
- What? Will they push?
Will the elephants steer
and you want to push?
They will take you as
carefully as fragile glass.
Look at that.
''March on, my friend... ''
''O my elephant... ''
''drag this huge pile of junk... ''
''Give it a push, my friend... ''
''this motorcar has broken down''
''Give it a push, my friend''
''She's as tender as a rose... ''
''the girl who sits there
in the car''
''Walk slowly... ''
''let her not find it difficult''
''God... ''
''may she not... ''
''strain her delicate waist''
''March on, my friend... ''
''O my elephant... ''
''drag this huge pile of junk... ''
''Give it a push, my friend... ''
''this motorcar has broken down''
''Give it a push, my friend''
''Your courage might bear fruit... ''
''she might yet reward you''
''Salute the beautiful one... ''
''let your eyes do the talking''
''Come closer, my friend... ''
''don't lose an opportunity
like this one''
''March on, my friend... ''
''O my elephant... ''
''drag this huge pile of junk... ''
''Give it a push, my friend... ''
''this motorcar has broken down''
''Give it a push, my friend''
''You're the best of friends... ''
''you're so very loyal''
''The world is a falsehood... ''
''but your love is for true''
''You've never been corrupted... ''
''although the world
has changed''
''March on, my friend... ''
''O my elephant... ''
''drag this huge pile of junk... ''
''Give it a push, my friend... ''
''this motorcar has broken down''
''Give it a push, my friend''
Long live Daddy!
Come in dear. Ramprasad,
this is my only child, Tanu.
She's always singing my praise.
Good day.
- This is Ramprasad.
He's very wealthy.
He owns gardens, orchards.
His son is getting married.
- You must bring her along.
Sure, both of us will come.
l'm her shadow.
Good day.
- Good day.
Yes, dear?
- May l ask you something?
Yesterday there was a wedding
here, our gardener's son's.
He came here personally,
and requested you...
But you didn't walk
4 steps for that poor man.
But today you are willing to
go far for this stranger.
Yes, dear. The gardener is our
servant and will always remain so.
But Ramprasad is a rich man.
Today he is my friend.
Tomorrow he could be a relative.
Now you see the difference?
- Yes but l don't like it.
Be ready for the wedding
in the evening.
Yes, l know you haven't got your
full meal but what can l do?
That's all there is.
There's no more.
Why aren't they being fed today?
They are elephants not
babies of birds. Get more food.
What's wrong?
- Where do l get it from?
l cooked and fed them
whatever ration Munim gave me.
Where is he?
- lnside.
Accountant!
Yes?
May l ask why the
elephants aren't being fed well?
Because they can't speak?.
Open the locker and give me money.
Which locker? They are all empty.
Empty? Meaning... ?
Nothing is hidden from you.
Cases are filed against you
for your wealth and property.
There is no income.
And expenses are as usual.
We can't draw anything from
the bank till the court verdict.
What little we had at home
was spent on court expenses.
Or consumed by the elephants!
l'm paying for whatever
ration they are eating now.
Why are you paying for it?
The ones we bought from
have stopped giving credit.
They say we must first clear
old debt, then ask for credit.
Why didn't you go to Jamnadas?
- l did go.
He has refused to give money.
What? Another 50000 rupees?
Mister, l was going to ask you
for repayment of old accounts.
Don't worry. My ancestral
property is worth millions.
But it is under dispute.
And you have only one house.
Against which l've given you
l can't give any more.
l only need 50000.
The verdict will be known by
next month. l'll return your money.
At your rate of interest.
Any rate of interest?
- Yes.
A money lender always dies
at the knife of interest.
You too may kill me.
Please sign here.
Here you are.
Take this money and get
food for the elephants first.
The elephants are alive.
They shouldn't die of hunger.
All right
l've heard there's an
elephant race in our town.
Will your elephants participate?
- What?
lf there's a race here,
won't my elephants participate?
ls that possible?
Everybody pay attention.
The elephant race is about to begin.
Whoever wins the race will be
rewarded with a silver cup.
At the hands of the daughter of
Ratanlal, Bangalore industrialist.
l won't talk to you
if you don't stand first.
Very good!
You are well prepared sir.
Your elephant will beat all hollow.
Why not. He knows if his
master rewards him... .
And also punishes severely.
Well done son! Come on!
The elephant standing first
in this race is called Ramu.
His master, Rajkumar is requested
to come upstage and accept the prize.
l'm Sarwan Kumar, the
owner of Bombay Carnival.
My elephant too took part
but lost to yours.
That's a great animal.
- Thank you.
Dear, give him the cup.
How are you?
- Very well.
My Daddy.
- Do you know him?
l told you when l was stuck without
petrol? His elephants helped me.
You were great today.
- My elephants not me.
Come home some day.
- Sure, l will someday.
The reward for winning
was a silver cup.
At the hands of an angel.
But the reward for losing. .
What have you done?
Killed the elephant!
What about our show?
- You've always be a fool.
An ever better elephant
will come to our carnival.
The one who won the race today.
- You mean, Ramu?
Yes. That is why l shook hands
and congratulated the enemy.
But will Rajkumar sell him?
He won't but his accountant
will force him to sell.
Good day.
- Good day. Come in.
l was waiting for you.
Please be seated.
- Doesn't matter.
What's the matter?
- Something very urgent.
l want to buy the elephant
that won today's race.
And only you can help me in this.
No sir, you can't get him at
any price. He is my master's life.
You may assume that l am
asking for your master's life.
What would it be worth?
What can l say?
lt's very difficult.
l'll make it simple.
Here are 2000 rupees.
And when you get me the elephant,
l'll give you another 5000.
This isn't the cost of the
elephant but for your efforts.
The reward for just one elephant?
- Yes.
lf you think this is less,
l'll pay you 10,000.
10,000... ?
- Yes.
ln which case, l'll try and get you
all the four elephants!
Now, that's something...
very well said.
Ever since, they have become
a part of my life.
As if their favours weren't enough,
they did me another one.
What's that?
- They made me meet you...
and got you to give me a prize.
A silver cup.
Did you ever win prizes as a student
or were you always a duffer... ?
You won't believe me, if l told you.
- Tell me.
l'll believe you.
- You will? So listen.
For 3 years l stood first in
the school running race!
Cock and bull!
- No, it's true!
l would have given you a
cup of tea if not of silver.
All lies!
- How?
How old were you then?
- Then... ? About this high. .
You were a little boy
this high in half pants.
Yes, l was round and fat.
Yet l'd have beaten you.
Want to bet?
- Yes.
What's the reward?
- Reward... if you win...
lf you win, you can marry me.
And if l win, l'll marry you.
Marriage? Marriage?
Accept?
''The train moves... ''
''Like the heart beats,
dhak, dhak, dhak... ''
''Kal, kal, kal... ''
''like the rivers flow
chal, chal... ''
''There's excitement in my heart''
''Your bangles tinkle,
chhan-chhan''
''My heart and soul
sway in my love for you''
''Listen, listen... ''
''my anklets chime,
chhun-chhun... ''
''and l sing the melody of love''
''My elephants dance,
rumm, rumm... ''
''Let me go,
my ear-ring is lost''
''Find it for me.
- Me?''
''Yes, you, you you''
''Chhup chhup... ''
''Chup chup... ''
''come, let's sway quietly... ''
''let's share our
joys and sorrows''
''Our hearts skip a beat,
my love, my love... ''
''When l'm with you,
what do you grieve?''
''Do not love anyone else
in the world''
''l feel so shy''
''Let me go...
- How can l let you go?''
''Let me go... ''
Excuse me sir...
l love your daughter!
That is no sin. l want to
marry her and that's no crime!
You're probably thinking
l'm too blunt for words.
But if you tear open my heart,
you'll know l'm also heartless.
Tell me if you accept this match.
How was it?
Just start off like this
in front of the man.
And he will give his daughter's
hand to you.
And he will say, My children,
God bless both of you.
Very good.
Yes. Go on Mr. Lawyer.
Why are you troubling me?
Pardon?
- l wasn't talking to you.
l called to remind you today
is the last hearing of your case.
l hope you're coming to court.
- No way.
l have to go to another court.
- Another court?
Yes, much greater than your court.
And the decision of my
life will be taken there.
Anyway, tell your accountant
he must come as a witness.
Our case hinges on his testimony.
Sure, l'll send him.
Good day. Accountant!
l've heard everything.
Don't worry, l'm off to court.
Thanks.
- No need for thanks.
lt's my duty.
- Son...
What were you saying on the
telephone? Life, decision. . ?
Be patient. When l return you'll
be floored by the good news.
You've come!
Yes, call your Daddy. Where is he?
- Okay.
What's the matter?
- Rajkumar is here.
Ask him to sit, l'm coming.
Please take a seat.
- Do you have a mirror?
Mirror? - Mirror!
- For what? - Rehearsal.
Sir, l love your daughter. .
- Welcome.
lt's our privilege that you
came to our house. Take a seat.
Tanu said you wanted to talk to me.
Sit down.
Yes, so what is it?
Actually. .
Why are you perspiring in this cold?
No... no sweat...
That's because he drives
the car very fast.
But he's panting as if
he ran all the way.
That's his way of driving. The
car on the road and him in the car!
May l drink a glass of water?
- Yes, go ahead.
Now tell me what's the matter?
Can l have another glass?
You've come from so far,
have a cup of coffee or tea.
That can be done later.
May l ask you something personal?
Yes, ask!
- Did you speak for your own marriage?
What do you mean?
- Did you speak for yourself?.
What about me...
The day l decided...
l landed up at my in-law's home.
And told him, l love your daughter.
And that's no crime!
l want to marry her.
And that's no sin!
Then l roared like a lion.
Will you marry your
daughter to me or not?
What did he say?
- What could he say?
He sat quiet for awhile.
Then said, yes l will.
l too want to say the same.
l love your daughter and
want to marry her. Yes or no?
Terrific! l tried fooling you
and you fooled me!
My state was the same as yours
today.
l understood your story
the day of the race.
l knew all along!
l appreciate that.
Appreciate my knowledge too.
l've inquired that you too
belong to a wealthy family.
And of equal status.
l wanted such a groom for my child.
So you approve?
- Answer us Daddy.
When the couple agree. .
- What can the others do?
l said l'd give you some
good news on my return.
Have a sweet.
- First the news.
You always said this house
is huge, very beautiful.
Right?
- Yes.
So l've chosen a girl
and l'm marrying her!
But who is the girl?
How is she?
She's like a sweetmeat. Fair
and sweet. Have a bite.
Come in.
Have a bite.
We've lost the case.
l've lost everything.
That's how family feud is.
Empires are lost and rulers ousted.
l am sorry l could not
save your property.
Your accountant had been bought
and we lost a winning game.
Son, what has happened?
God! ls this a game?
You give joys with one hand and
snatch it away with the other!
Rajkumar lost the case
thanks to my false testimony!
Now he has no money.
To pay off his debts. Now the
moneylender will use pressure.
And he'll have to sell his elephants!
This is akin to lightning striking
in one place but razing another.
You've lost the case
but l have been ruined!
l stand alive before you.
l don't deny that l owe you
But l need a little time.
That's the one thing a
money lender doesn't possess.
And what will you do with time?
You've lost everything with this
case.
Nothing is lost.
You. . ?
- Yes, l've heard everything.
l want to help you.
These are 150000 rupees.
What is this money for?
- For your elephants.
Meaning?
l wondered how you
could support them in this state.
l'll buy them off.
Sell them?
- Listen to me.
Don't lose this golden opportunity.
God Himself has come to help you.
Give that money to me. l'll
give you extra time for the rest.
Go and take it.
Take your money and go away.
What are you watching?
- You're very ungrateful.
l extend a hand of friendship
and you reject it!
You are out of your mind!
You kicked away 150000 rupees!
You won't find another madman
to pay you 150000 for these animals!
l say, shut up!
They maybe animals for you but
they mean more than humans to me!
They are my childhood mates,
my friends, my brothers.
l can sell myself for them
but never will l sell them.
Be warned next time you say this,
you'll pay for the consequences.
lt is rightly said a losing gambler
and a spoilt rich brat are lethal.
You too may leave.
Yes but be warned, l'll bring
a vacation order from court.
Just as you're throwing me out some
day l'll do the same to you forever!
Listen...
There's no need for
you to go to court.
This house is now yours.
Here are the keys.
Are you crying?
Seeing the way one
human treats another?
The two legged man is the
most dangerous animal of all.
Neither is this your place nor mine.
All right, l must take leave.
l too will accompany you.
You have children, a family.
Where will you wander with me?
Do me a favour.
Find yourself a good job.
All right son.
Just as you wish.
l don't want to be a burden on you.
Did you hear about what happened
to the elephant owner Rajkumar?
What?
- He had taken a loan from Jamnadas.
Today Jamnadas took his house
away.
He and his elephants were thrown
out.
These days kings can't
maintain elephants.
What big deal was he?
Stop.
Where are you going?
To talk to Tanu.
- What's left to say?
Everything is out in the open.
l don't want to hide
anything from you.
What do you have to offer Tanu?
Not wealth, not property.
Nor home nor status.
You will spend your life
under the open sky.
ln lanes, market places.
But my daughter can't do it.
l came to say this to her.
She must forget me.
She will forget you. You
needn't meet or tell her this.
l'm her father. l can't deliberately
plunge her into trouble.
Neither for my own sake...
nor for your love.
Very well. l will go away.
But do tell Tanu...
l was here to meet her,
before l left.
Good bye.
Let's go.
Where are going?
- To meet Raju.
Listen!
Raju won't meet you.
Why? What happened?
We've been deceived.
Raju sold his house and
left the city life a thief.
He has left? But for where?
He has gone to Bombay. To marry
mill owner Chandanmal's daughter.
No, this can't be true!
He can't leave me!
He promised to marry me!
A promise to marry means nothing
compared to a storm of riches.
Raju knew l was wealthy.
But unlike Chandanmal l can't
give mills as part of dowry.
He has turned you down and gone,
it's best you too forget him.
No! l can't do this!
Don't shed tears for a man
who doesn't value these pearls.
l know you can't
live here anymore.
His memories will torment you.
We'll leave this place tomorrow.
How did these elephants come here?
Whom do they belong to?
They are mine.
But what are they doing here?
Unless l find some place for
them, where can l leave them?
This is an office,
not a circus tent!
Leave them elsewhere if
you wish to work here.
Can't maintain himself and
wants to keep animals!
Fire me if you wish
but don't malign them.
They maybe dark skinned
but clean hearted.
More decent than you and me.
Serving others yet
acting as a prince.
You're not doing me a favour.
You've employed me as l work.
You're fired!
Who are you? What do you want?
l want a place to stay.
- Sorry, no rooms available.
l'll lie out here.
- Fine.
Friends.
From where have these elephants
come? - They are my mates.
That's all fine but this inn
has been built for human beings.
Not animals. Please go away.
Where can l go in this rain?
l'll leave in the morning.
lt's a question of my job.
Please leave now.
Thank God, you made this world.
Had man made it, he would
have created no place for animals!
Friends, this is God's home.
Nobody can throw us out of here.
Listen put this stuff in that car.
Kept the stuff?.
- Yes sir. That man is taking it.
ln whose hand have you given it?
Looks like he's drunk early morning!
What has happened to you?
Daddy, this is Raju!
- Don't create a scene in the market.
Let's go, driver!
Raju is in this state!
You lied to me!
He's gone to Bombay to
marry some wealthy girl!
Why did you lie to me?
Answer me Daddy! Why?
Yes, l lied to you.
But only for your welfare.
l had found out that Raju
had lost his home and wealth.
He had no option but to
wander from pillar to post.
l did not wish my darling
daughter to wander with him.
This was very wrong.
You sacrificed my love for yours.
l could have shared his
sorrow if not given him relief.
l'm going to him!
Wait Tanu.
l won't let you go.
l won't tolerate my child
plunging into fire before my eyes.
You won't tolerate my going!
And l can't stay here!
You don't know...
cars, bungalows...
... have no value in a woman's eyes.
She only wants a good husband.
Who will give her love and
in whose feet her world lays.
l have seen poverty, you haven't.
You wouldn't speak in this
way if you had been poor.
l think you must forget him.
- No, Daddy!
l can't live without him!
You have to forget him
and live without him!
Hey, elephant! What are you doing?
Let go! Leave me!
Where are you taking me?
You brought me to a sick man!
Why don't you tell first?
Holy smoke! His body is fiery
hot! l'll have to give a shot.
These elephants brought me here.
Are they yours?
l came out after a visit
and he dragged me here.
You're running high fever.
l'll admit you to a hospital.
l can't go there.
lf l go there, who
will look after them?
l can't go.
That will be terrible.
All right...
l'll give you some pills.
Take these thrice a day.
Your fees...
- To hell with it!
Why do you worry? Just rest.
l am leaving.
Why do you cry son?
l did what l could.
Your master will soon
be well. Trust God.
What is it?
Brought it from the temple?
You went to the temple
to pray for me?
l can never repay you for your love!
Never!
Kids, watch this game of a
monkey and throw some money.
See these players
like a pair of twins.
Children clap for them.
They will salute you!
Climb up and salute all!
Your mother is unwell.
Get some water.
Listen to me, dear son.
All right, get it for your wife.
Look at him, working for the wife!
Didn't bring it for the mother.
- Hen pecked husband!
Now see how they get
possessed by ghosts!
Let go, spirits!
Let go your demons!
Abracadabra!
Go my child, and set them
on your shoulder.
Get some money for the
upkeep of the monkeys.
They danced so well for you!
Crowd thinning here.
But building there.
Let's go and see who
this enemy of ours is.
Now for another trick.
How're we going to compete
with those elephants?
Shut up! And come with me!
Go the betel-shop. l'll come there.
- Where are you going?
To hell!
Wow! We've made 250 Rupees.
We're going to have a feast
you friends will always remember.
What's going on?
Where did this elephant come from?
He's dragging me. .
- Something must be wrong.
Handle the traffic.
l'll look after the animal.
Take this and go home.
l will back afterwards.
Thief! Rascal! Where is my money?
l don't have any money.
Hey, what's going on!
l am a poor monkey trainer.
He started an elephant show
and ruined mine.
And now he set these
elephants on my tail!
Arrest him.
- He's a thief and a liar!
The elephants are chasing him
because he stole my money.
Ha! Search me.
No need for that.
Here is the money.
He gave the money to me when the
elephants chased him. Take it.
You rascal. . !
- Constable, take him away.
Here your's money.
Your elephants are very smart.
Thank you.
- That's all right.
Well done, boys.
Give me a reward for
getting a thief caught.
Here, take this.
- l didn't do this for money.
Give me some little job.
- Want job?
Earlier l made monkeys dance.
Now l'll make elephants dance.
As well as massage you.
What do you say pals?
All right.
- Good.
That's it.
Dear...
You've given your decision.
Hear mine now.
l am going. Don't look for me.
Neither must you follow me.
Know one thing, you can imprison
me.
You can bind my body in ropes
but not chain my heart.
Your daughter, Tanu.
Forgive me. l no longer have the
right to call you by your name.
Why do you say that?
- l've lost all that l had.
l show tricks on the road. Every
penny people throw at me is precious.
But your father can still
weigh you out in gold.
There's no comparison between the
two.
Don't punish me for what Daddy did.
He told me you had ditched me.
And you're married into a rich
family.
You're getting factories in dowry.
Do you see my factory?
lt's great! The best mill owner
won't have such a fantastic factory!
Don't poke fun at me.
l found out the truth only
when l saw you on the road.
That's when l realised my Daddy
had deceived me not you.
Since then l had only
one thing in mind.
That l meet and apologise to you.
But how could l come?
l was imprisoned at home.
But today l escaped from home.
l found you here after
searching all day long.
But what's the gain in searching.
What do l have to offer you?
Neither wealth nor home,
nor status nor property.
All day l'm on the roads
with my elephants.
l return when it's dark
to sleep in these ruins.
This gypsy life is not for you!
l accept this life but
not going back to that Hell!
l won't leave you and go.
- l can't keep you with me!
Why?
- You see the state l'm in?
And look at these ruins.
What will people say?
That l'm purposely ensnaring you
to grab your wealth someday.
Tell me what l must do!
My hands are broken.
l'll move heaven and earth
and try to be worthy of you.
When that happens, l'll
ask your Daddy for your hand.
Not before that or without that.
For now, you must leave.
ls this your last decision?
- My last decision and the right one.
lt's best that you return
home just as you'd come.
l've left my home far behind.
You are not aware of what
decisions are being taken for me.
Daddy wants to forcibly
marry me elsewhere.
l ran away and came to you!
lf you also reject me,
there's only one option for me.
To put an end to my life!
Forgive me, l had no idea
matters were beyond control.
lf you love me so much,
l'll fight the world for you.
But l won't let you down.
Come on in. Tanu,
he's my assistant.
Who is this lady?
- Tell you later. First let's eat.
l bought enough for two.
l didn't know about guests.
Guests stay for just a day.
But she won't go anywhere.
Got it! She's your wife!
Going to be.
- l'll get special eats for her.
No. We'll split what there is.
She has started budget
soon as she entered.
Do you know the problem with us?
- What is it?
Two people eat what three should.
And one eats what
- Two should eat!
Lecture on arrival?
But l like it, what do you say?
Right.
Hearing this, l feel
women should permanently rule us!
''Gentlemen! Friends...
watch the fun!''
''Work, if you want to live''
''Salute everyone around
in respect''
''Else, this world won't let you live''
''lt won't feed you,
you'll go thirsty''
''Give them something new
everyday''
''Work, if you want to live''
''Salute everyone around
in respect''
''Else, this world won't let you live''
''lt won't feed you,
you'll go thirsty''
''Without money, you get no bread''
''You get no clothes''
''Do not spoil your name''
''Salute everyone around
in respect''
''Work, if you want to live''
''Our dreams, we shall
realise some day''
''Say something, my boy... ''
''that leaves everyone
clutching at their hearts''
''Salute everyone in respect.
Work, if you wish to live''
''Say your prayers''
''Like a mare pulling
a horse-carriage... ''
''she darts across the tight rope''
''Let's go home.
Say good-bye to everyone''
''Work, if you wish to live.
Respect everyone''
''Else, this world won't let you live''
''lt won't feed you,
you'll go thirsty''
''Give them something
new everyday''
This is a cheetah!
lt's called a leopard!
A wild cat... it's
very intelligent.
Look at this goat...
- lt ain't a goat. lt's a male.
C'mon... let's move.
There's so much more to see.
Do you know what this is?
lt's a kind of creature.
lt's called a hedgehog.
These are its' guards, thorns.
This is what it will do
if somebody attacks it.
Why are you screaming your lungs
out?
Forget the style and
clean this place up.
That's what l do all day!
So leave that braid
and hold the broom. Go!
Going! l'm going!
These are lions.
The king of the forest.
And children, these are elephants.
A reincarnation of
Lord Ganesha. Bow to them.
And this is a crocodile.
He's powerful in water
like the lion on land.
What is it?
Why is he looking
listless? Didn't you feed him?
l did but this pigeon ate it.
Shouldn't you give him more?
- Yes.
Your job is feeding him. Get it fast!
- Yes sir.
Calls me sire, and rubs
his hand on my cheek!
Come along kids.
This is a sloth bear.
Walks on hind legs like man.
Why is he so dirty?
- God made him dark.
So he doesn't feel cold.
Like we wear sweaters.
How are you kids?
- Hello.
Finished seeing this place?
- Yes, it is great.
We'll come again.
- Not bunking school.
You've done a great deed by
bringing animals to the city.
The children are
blooming like flowers.
l wish to ask you something
in the capacity of a journalist.
Yes go on.
- Why do you love animals so much?
There's a long story behind it.
l owe my success to them.
l never considered them animals,
they were always my mates.
l belong to them as
they belong to me.
Setting a world of love
must have cost a lot of money.
l had to take loans but
l did this only so that. .
l want to prove to the world
through this world of love...
Man can stay in
harmony with animals.
So why can't men live with each
other?
Men fight over casts,
language, religion.
And wants to kill other men. Why?
Very good. l'll write
all this in my newspaper.
And print it with pictures.
Thanks.
- Good day.
What are you watching?
- You and your world of love.
You've personally done everything
here
You faced many difficulties,
obstacles rose in your path.
But you didn't hold back.
Kept marching ahead.
And reached your destination.
l couldn't have made it so far
had you not been with me.
You are equally
responsible for my success.
l want you to be a part of my life.
l'll meet your father
tomorrow and say to him...
l want to marry your daughter.
Daddy... ?
- Yes son.
l've come to see both of you.
- That's very nice. .
Tanu daddy is here!
Why are you quiet?
- Poor girl is probably thinking. .
How to greet an unwanted guest.
Sit or leave.
- No, Daddy.
We are fortunate that
you came to our house.
l wanted to come earlier
but whenever l decided...
My false pride bound
my feet in chains.
And l never made it. But today
my loneliness convinced me.
Become a great man
before a rich man.
l am the father of a daughter.
You are truly magnanimous.
Else l was to come to you to ask
if l'm worthy of your daughter.
l thought you had married her
without inviting this old father.
Tanu and l had decided if we get
married it will be with your blessing
And wish.
My wish has no meaning here.
You are asking for your right
not my daughter's hand.
l'll get you married
in pomp in splendour.
Eat, these snacks have specially
been ordered from Benaras.
He doesn't have a sweet.
- Here.
What are you thinking of?.
Your father's guests
are already dining.
My mates must be waiting.
Shall we go to them?
Get food for all our friends.
You've been invited for the
wedding!
Come fast, everyone is waiting!
Good boy.
Come on Johnny.
Sit in your places.
l'll get the elephants.
Come in Ramu, Ganesh, Mahesh.
That way.
Friends, mates...
This is my father-in-law,
Mr. Ratanlal.
Today's feast is from his side.
Don't feel shy. Eat well.
Such opportunities are rare.
Serve the food.
Eat, why are you angry?
Good boy.
When l've brought the moon home
to banish the darkness of my life. .
Then why do l need lights?
What's the matter?
- That was Ramu.
Something is wrong. l must go.
At this hour? Why must you go?
Servants can look after them.
- They are mere servants.
For them Ramu is just an animal.
He means more than my life to me.
And l mean nothing to you?
You... you are everything...
l'll be back very soon.
What's wrong with him?
- Suddenly took sick.
What's wrong son?
- Must have eaten too much.
Call the doctor.
What's the matter my friend?
Can't diagnose his problem.
Elders have rightly said,
children and animals are the same.
They can't tell what's wrong.
- You are right
What's that?
Nail. . ? There's a nail in his foot!
Dig a mountain...
- To find a mouse!
Now you'll be fine. The
doctor has removed the nail.
l apologise for troubling you.
That is my duty. Good bye.
What a day!
Struggled all night. Only in the
morning we found a nail in his foot.
He was in pain all night.
Do you know how l spent the night?
You tell me how could l leave him?
You could leave me alone.
lt is said the nuptial night is a
union of two bodies, minds and lives.
But...
Don't cry.
l've been punished. We're
stepping into a new life together.
And we should step into it
with a smile not tears.
We'll go somewhere far today.
Where there will be nobody but us.
Only silent mountains, cool winds.
Dark clouds...
Now smile... Come on.
''Listen to us, O cool breeze''
''Wait a while, O dark cloud''
''We talk of love... ''
''listen to our sweet-nothings
before you leave''
''Listen to us, O cool breeze''
''Wait a while, O dark cloud''
''We talk of love... ''
''listen to our sweet-nothings
before you leave''
''The two of us are
on our own tonight... ''
''don't you squeal about it''
''Should l drift into sleep
in my beloved's arms... ''
''do not wake me up all my life''
''Slowly and steadily... ''
''our hearts speak of love...
come, listen to it''
''Listen to us, O cool breeze''
''Wait a while, O dark cloud''
''Remember, you are not to tell
anyone else about what we say to each other''
''Our eyes refuse to sleep tonight.
Our hearts are restless''
''Slowly, on the sly... ''
''that which we say to each other,
come... listen to it''
''Listen to us, O cool breeze''
''Wait a while, O dark cloud''
''We talk of love... ''
''listen to our sweet-nothings
before you leave''
You've killed me!
lf you clean this place all day
when will you enter my heart?
This is a good opportunity.
That little kid has gone out.
Throw this broom and hold my hand.
Let's talk of love.
You've left your work and
are trying to ensnare a girl!
No, l was teaching her
how to clean the house.
Get lost! Teaching me!
What are you standing here for?
l've just cleaned the place.
My boss pays you for it!
Get on with it!
Get lost! The young and old...
they're all rascals!
What a girl...
she's so hot-tempered!
So the carnival was a hit
on the first day in Bangalore.
Sort out the notes.
Have you slept?
l was thinking.
Do you know we haven't
stepped out for a week?.
What do we have to do outside?
The beauty of the world has
shrunk into this room.
l want to spend the
rest of my life like this.
My head resting in your lap
and your tresses covering my face.
l too desire the same.
Life is actually nothing.
But a woman and a man
together, transform it.
The only thing missing is a girl.
You're very greedy. You've
got me and want another.
This is my birthright.
l want two kids not one.
Two?
- One like me and one like you.
Sweet, chubby, cute.
Telegram, sir.
Who is it from?
What's wrong?
- lt's from Chotu.
Says, come immediately or
world of love will be ruined.
What could have gone wrong?
The carnival is the villain.
Thanks to it, people
don't come here anymore.
That is why l sent you that cable.
What can we do to draw
the public back here?
lt's not so easy to get them back.
You don't know what goes on there.
Gambling, dirty dancing by girls.
l will shut down this place but
there won't be gambling or dancing.
You have high ideals.
But the truth is man wants
new excitement every day.
He finds new ways to
spend his evenings.
Your method is old. ln order
to bring the crowds back here. .
You have to think of a new game.
Sir...
Who is on the door?
- l am Raju. l want to meet you.
Who is Raju? l don't know
any Raju. Go away from here!
The journalist Sharma sent me to
you
l see. The door is open. Come in.
Good day sir.
- What's the matter?
l've come to ask you for something.
From me? What can a poor
handicapped man offer anyone?
l want you to be my teacher.
l want you to teach me to set your
clothes on fire and jump into water.
Which used to drive people crazy.
Even l would go crazy.
Their applause and appreciation
is so intoxicating...
More than any liquor.
When a man sets his clothes afire
and plunges into the water...
People applaud and ask him
to jump from higher.
He jumps higher.
Then higher and higher.
But when he falls from
the peak of renown...
Do you know what the outcome is?
See this!
That time people praised me,
appreciate me.
But today l doubt if my bier
fill find four shoulders.
This game is very dangerous.
You'll get what l got.
lnfamy, destruction!
And these crutches
to carry your corpse!
l accept this too.
Do you love fame and
wealth so much?
l neither love fame nor wealth.
But l love some lives
more than my own.
l want to do this for them.
l beg you to accept me
as your disciple.
Your resolve has weakened
my resistance.
l will impart this knowledge to you.
Yes Daddy. l don't
understand what to do.
He neither listens to me nor
others. Will you talk to him?
He might listen to you.
- Don't worry.
l'll come and meet him tomorrow.
Walk carefully dear!
You shouldn't walk so
swiftly in this condition.
l hadn't seen Raju for days.
Thought l'd meet him.
Please have a seat.
l'll get tea for you.
- Go slowly dear, don't run.
My daughter is innocent and silly.
Take care of her.
l do what is possible.
- l'm sure.
Yes?
- l want your advice.
From me?
- Yes, l got a statement from my bank.
l found l had too much extra cash.
l thought to myself what's the
point of keeping this in the bank?.
Why not invest it in business
that would help me and another.
What do you say?
- What can l tell you?
You are familiar with the real
world. l only know my world of love.
Why don't l invest in
your world of love?
Your efforts and my money.
We'll be partners.
Daddy is right.
But these days my world
of love is running losses.
You might lose your money.
Every business has profits and
losses.
What man considers gold turns to
dust.
lt's also possible that your
world of love which is in loss. .
... can start earning profits.
What amount shall l fill in?
How much money are
you getting for me?
You asked Daddy to come
here and talk to me.
Give me money. So that l
don't play that dangerous game.
lsn't it?
l consider life a war.
Where man has to fight for his
principles, his way of life.
Only your own power and strength
and courage help you in this.
Those who fire from the
shoulders of others are cowards!
lf you want to give me
something, ask Daddy to bless me.
My blessings are always with you.
l am glad today l saw
a real man within you.
May God grant you success.
- May God grant you success.
God bless you
What's wrong?
Congratulations, you
are blessed with a son.
Are the mother and baby fine?
- Yes.
But...
- But... ?
We had to operate because
the case was complicated.
She can't have another baby.
Don't worry. The country's slogan
now is, small family, happy family.
Can we meet her?
- Sure
He's so sweet!
- Just like you!
How are you, dear?
Fine.
Congratulations. Your son
is as beautiful as you.
Are you crying?
What's wrong?
Didn't the doctor tell you?
l can't give you a
pretty little doll.
Why is that making you cry?
A thousand stars can't give
the light one sun can.
Sun. The good Lord has
sent a little sun to us.
So why do we need a moon?
l've even named him,
Suraj. Like it?
Listen everyone!
Good news for all!
There's a new guest
in our world of love!
Your brother and my son, Suraj!
Everywhere you turn only
Raju is being discussed!
He has ruined our carnival!
Nobody comes here at all!
We'll have to wind up
if matters continue so.
lt makes sense to leave the
filed when you can't win.
Shut up! You don't know me!
Even if l lose all my wealth,
l'll evict Raju from here!
Understand?
Let him sleep, Come on!
l will sleep with my son,
Yes Raju!
Okay then, sleep with your son.
l am going.
''O sweetheart... ''
''a lovely breeze flows
outside''
''ln fun and frolic,
we shall spend a lifetime''
''O sweetheart... ''
''a lovely breeze flows
outside''
''ln fun and frolic,
we shall spend a lifetime''
''Days, in love, we'll spend
like we spend moments''
''When did the sunset... ?
When were the lights switched on?''
''Listen, my dear man... ''
''Me''
''Listen, my dear man,
it's all thanks to you... ''
''in fun and frolic,
we'll spend a lifetime''
''O sweetheart... ''
''a lovely breeze flows
outside''
''Everyone has gone to sleep?
Why are you awake?''
''What's the matter, friends?''
''Go to sleep, O king of the forests.
lt's night already''
''Sweet dreams beckon you''
''in fun and frolic,
we'll spend a lifetime''
''O sweetheart... ''
''a lovely breeze flows
outside''
''in fun and frolic,
we'll spend a lifetime''
World of love.
Owner...
Hello brother.
How are you children?
So you own this place!
Eat fast, l too am famished.
Who are you? Why are you here?
lt clearly says on the board,
no touching or feeding animals.
l'm illiterate. l don't
know what's written there.
Now you know? Stuff this banana
in your mouth not the elephant's!
lt's a good deed to
feed a mute animal.
You take this money for a betel
leaf and l'll feed the elephant.
l can't deceive Raju even
if you pay me 400 rupees!
Take your money and get lost!
l will feed the elephant.
l'll see how you stop me!
That fleeing man was feeding
the elephant a needle in a banana!
You haven't changed despite
the sentence in prison.
Who are you?
- Raju is chasing me!
Who is he?
- The owner of world of love.
l don't know what old enmity
prompted him to kill me.
Help me hide!
- Okay, hide there.
How did you come this way?
A man ran this way.
He tried to kill my elephant.
Nobody came here.
- l saw him myself.
The one you're looking
for is not here.
You're trying to hide him.
You can't go in without permission.
He is a criminal and it's a
crime to give refuge to a criminal.
l can call the police.
- Sure.
The criminal will wait
till they arrive.
Will you make a move or
should l call the guard?
Hey, come out.
Tell me the truth. Did you
try to kill his elephant?
Yes and l'd kill him too if l could!
He's my sworn enemy!
He put me out of business!
Shake hands.
- Pardon?
Raju's enemy is my friend.
Likes you l too have a
debt to clear with him.
l have a brain to think of ideas
and you have the hands to execute it.
We'll take revenge together.
Shake hands!
lt's a deal!
There's nothing in the X ray.
l knew the child only had cough.
You worry needlessly.
lt's natural as it's your first
child.
First and last too.
Take this medicine from the chemist
and feed the child thrice a day.
Come fast doctor.
There's an emergency case!
My child! Lord! What have you
done!
What happen?
- The elephant crushed him head!
Take him to the OT.
Be brave. How did this happen?
My destiny was against me!
His father is a mahout. He grew
amongst elephants right from birth.
He always played with them.
God knows what happened.
The elephant went mad suddenly.
He picked up the child in
his trunk and threw him down!
After all he's an animal!
God knows what happened.
The elephant went mad suddenly.
He picked up the child in his
trunk and threw him down!
After all he's an animal!
What's wrong?
- Nothing. Go on.
Calm, down! What's wrong?
Ramu crushed my son!
He killed my son!
- What's wrong with you?
You are carrying your son!
My baby! My darling!
Then what is that?
Silly girl! lt's a doll.
l'll get 10 such dolls
for my son from the market.
You can buy dolls from the market
but can you get me another son?
What are you taking?
- My heart sinks!
My son can suffer the same
fate as the doll someday.
What?
- Send Ramu out and tie him in chains.
Bind him in chains? But why?
l saw a mahout's son in the hospital.
His face is swimming
before my eyes even now!
My heart is not in control!
The child was playing
with the elephant.
When suddenly the elephant lifted
him in his trunk and threw him down!
And crushed him underfoot!
l don't want this to
happen to my son someday!
Tie Ramu up!
Do you think Ramu will ever do this?
Once you said he loves
our son more than we do.
He looks after him so well.
- Whatever said, he is an animal!
How can you trust him?
- But l fully trust him.
l don't think our son can
face any danger from him!
You are mistaken.
No! My heart says take
him out and tie him up!
l can do anything for you but tying
him up is akin to tying my little son!
l'm not asking this for myself!
l want our child's well being!
he is your life and mine too!
lf you care for me and
love your son even a little...
You will tie him up!
l bind you by oath!
Tie him up! Please!
Tougher than your iron chains...
much more cruel...
My pal, you can cry.
l can't even do that.
Come on.
lf you care for me
and love your son...
Then tie him up!
l bind you by oath!
Tie him up!
l'm tying myself up in
this chain not you.
Forgive me if you can.
l ask what have you done so far?
l've paid so much money and you. .
l've made such a plan that Raju's
name will be wiped off the earth!
What plan is that?
- Listen...
Coming madam.
- Come this way.
Take him out to play.
- All right.
Take care of him.
Ramu is tied outside.
Don't let him come near Suraj.
Okay
Good baby. l'll just be back.
Where did you get this from?
For you.
- Me? Show!
Why is the elephant roaring?
- Let him. Why are you yelling?
l left baby alone. l hope...
He is tied there.
You be comfortable.
Help!
llliterate! lgnorant woman!
Told you keep Suraj away from him!
Honestly, it's not my fault!
We were playing when he came
after breaking his chains.
He kicked me aside and wrapped
the child in his trunk!
What happened?
- l can't stay in this...
house for one minute!
- Why? What's the matter?
Paro had taken baby out when Ramu
broke his chain, tried to kill my son.
You are mistaken.
- This is true!
l myself saw it!
l reached in time and saved him.
Or he would have crushed him!
Ask Paro if you don't believe me!
l agree Ramu may
have broken the chain.
He may have gone close to baby,
but to play with him not kill him.
You know how he loves him.
Everything would have finished
today!
But l'm amazed that the
animal means all to you.
l mean nothing, your
son means nothing!
Why do you say that?
lt's your imagination.
No! l only know that l
don't want Ramu here! No!
Don't forget it was Ramu
who brought us together.
All our joys are thanks to him!
The car you drive in, the
ornaments you wear are his gifts!
We are obliged to him.
Do you want me to sacrifice my son
to repay this animal's obligations?
Do you want me to shoot Ramu?
Hear me out! As long as Ramu is
here, l won't stay here nor my son!
You are blind in love for your son!
Your love for that animal
is blind, deaf and mad!
Do you think l'm my son's enemy?
Yes, you are his enemy!
ls this how you treat my child?
Aren't you ashamed to beat her?
l could kill her today!
Stop it!
You seem to have turned into
an animal with those elephants!
Yes, l've turned an animal!
lf you so proud of being human...
get the hell out of here
and take your daughter too!
Tanu, l'm not going to let you
stay here for another minute.
l got my daughter married to him.
l didn't sell my self-respect!
Let's go, dear.
- Go away! l don't need anyone!
Worthless being!
l had shacked you, hadn't l?
Why did you break the chain?
Why did you go anywhere
near the child?
Why did you... ?
Tell me!
No Daddy, l can't leave my home.
You can take me home
but not change my destiny.
Destiny is too great,
l can't even change your mind.
l'm not asking you to leave
your husband or your home.
l'm just asking you to come
with me for a few days.
Today Raju is angry.
Tomorrow he will cool down.
And come for you.
- lf he doesn't. . ?
l will swallow my pride
and come to drop you back.
Come, my dear. Let's go.
Move aside. My daughter won't
stay here as long as you are here.
Raju will scold me.
Don't follow them.
Go back, l say!
Your wife left with
her father in the car.
And Ramu followed them.
l slapped you in a fit of temper.
But you left home.
Telegram for you sir.
- Telegram?
What's wrong Daddy?
- My friend had a stroke in Mysore.
Do you have to go there?
- That's what l'm wondering.
How do l leave you
alone in this state?
Don't worry about me.
Go and return soon.
Take care of yourself and the baby.
Get a box of milk powder
for the baby from the market.
You've followed me
here too! Go away!
l said, go away!
Go away!
No! l won't go with you!
l can't live in that house
peacefully as long as you're there!
All right. Stay here if you wish!
l'm glad you called. l was
worried where to contact you.
What's wrong?
- Ramu came here after you left.
He won't budge. l don't think
he'll leave without killing my son.
The servant has gone home.
l'm very frightened.
Come back as soon as possible.
l'll leave immediately and
l'll bring a hunter friend along.
He'll shoot the elephant.
You take care of Suraj.
This animal is a pain!
No!
l won't let you go near my son!
l won't let you in! Go away!
How did this door break?.
The elephant must be responsible.
Where is the elephant?
- Come with me.
Come.
Do you see this snake?
Snake!
Where did this snake come from?
l smell petrol.
Why are you throwing petrol here?
Let go!
- l won't!
Stop!
Don't interfere in a fight of men!
Let go of him!
Or l'll shoot you!
l say, let go of him!
Scoundrel! Rascal!
You shot my Ramu!
l'll kill you!
l won't spare you!
These are the men!
- Yes inspector!
They are the ones who shot
my poor mute Ramu!
Take them away from my sight!
''A world of hatred... ''
''you are leaving''
''May you be happy, my friend''
''You are leaving
a world of hatred... ''
''for a world of love... ''
''May you be happy, my friend''
''Sever your ties with
this world of falsehoods''
''Your love shall be immortal''
''May you be happy, my friend''
''When an animal
kills a hum0an... ''
''they are called wild beasts''
''An animal has this day
been slain by human beings... ''
''and why is the world quiet?''
''May you be happy, my friend''
''This is our last meeting''
''Our game is over''
''ln your memory,
l shall spend my life... ''
''in tears''
''You are leaving
a world of hatred... ''
''for a world of love... ''
''May you be happy, my friend''
Forgive me Raju!
Now what do you want?
My pal, Ramu is no more.
My world is ruined.
l want nothing now!
Don't say that! Please!
Maternal love had
really turned me blind!
The Ramu l considered
my son's enemy...
That very Ramu saved him
from a snake and proved...
that he was his protector not enemy.
And today he has done me a great
obligation by saving my husband!
l can never forget him all life!
There's no point repenting.
The one who had to, has gone.
You didn't pay heed to me.
And shunned your own family.
And this poor mute guy
gave his life to prove that.
Wouldn't any mother have done
what l did seeing her child in danger?
How could a heart quivering with
fear understand your arguments?
How could l hear them?
Son...
l am the culprit.
l request you to forgive
me and my daughter.
Give us an opportunity to atone.
What are you thinking of?.
- Yes, forgive me.
For your darling son whom you
love and Ramu too had loved.
Forgive us.
Get up, Tanu.
Ramu brought us together
for the first time.
Today he gave his life
to unite us again.