Mammy, we're almost through
with the picking.
Yes, sir! And we done put in
a good season's work.
- Zeke.
- Ma'am?
You got all of them things that you
got to buy in town tomorrow?
Yes, Mammy, I've got them right here.
Here it is, Mammy.
Why, here's a nice shirt for Pappy...
and a pair of pants for Spunk.
You knows you just joking.
Why, I never had no new pants in my life.
Why, as soon as you goes out 'em,
I stepped in.
- And a dress for Missy Rose...
- Oh, Zeke, what kind?
It ain't gonna be no wedding dress
and you needn't be...
asking me for none neither.
Ain't nobody asked you
for no wedding dress.
- Who'd marry you?
- Why, you would.
What does you think
Mammy adopted you for...
except so you could marry me?
- She didn't do nothing, did you Mammy?
- Course she did.
Oh, children, don't you all fuss.
Zeke, what you gonna bring the children?
I don't see nothing on here for Sears.
Not a thing?
Nor Roebuck.
Gee whiz!
Nor Coe.
Did you done forgot?
Oh, don't tease them, Zeke.
Don't I see a new bright pocket knife
hanging on that string?
And a whole lot of marbles.
That's right!
And a big pack of chewing gum.
Yes.
I believe you sure is right, Mammy.
But what you want me to bring you
from town, Mammy?
You's always leaving yourself out.
- Don't matter about me, son.
- Yes'm, it do.
Well, looky here.
Here's a straw hat with a whole lot of
feathers on it for you, Mammy.
And a pair of them shiny gold spectacles.
Don't bring me nothing, son.
Mammy, I can't buy nothing.
I got to buy you something.
Why, there ain't no "nothing" to buy.
Well, all right then. Anything you choose.
Oh, cotton
Hey, cotton
Cotton
"...have no other God before me.
"Thou shalt not make unto thee
any graven image or any likeness...
"of any thing that is in heaven above,
or that is in the earth beneath...
"or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow..."
- Hello, Henry.
- Hello, folks.
Come on, Henry. We got a great big dish
of chitlins just waiting for you.
Everybody loves chitlins.
Henry, I sure am glad to see you.
Sit right down and make yourself at home.
Every time I see you,
you got that old banjo with you.
- What's the matter with...
- Better put that old starvation box down...
you gonna have a lot of trouble,
some of these days.
What you talking about, man?
This banjo is my best friend.
- What you talking about?
- How come it is?
Why sure, you know what I did?
Just here, last week, I told this old banjo:
"Banjo, I'm tired
of telling time by the old sun."
I said, "I wants me a watch."
Well, what did it do?
- Here it is.
- Let me see it. Look at that, Pappy.
- That sure is a good watch.
- Look at that baby!
You sure is lucky to get a watch like that.
Mammy, it's alive. I hear its heart beating.
Let me hear it.
You're just lucky.
I don't believe you stole it.
- Fine watch.
- Don't you know, this thing's ticking.
- Sure, it's going to tick.
- Let me look at it, then.
What time is by your watch, Henry?
There it is.
Sure is.
It sure is.
Henry, if you ain't gonna eat
none of these chitlins...
we gonna clear away the table.
- Yes.
- We sure is.
- Come on, boys. Let's have a little dance.
- I'm gonna do good.
Hello, Adam and Eve.
What are you doing around here?
Well, we just come down to see
if you had time to marry us.
That's right.
- To marry you?
- Yes.
Ain't these eleven children yours?
That's right.
And we thought it was about time...
for us to make it more permanent.
That's right.
Seems like you made it mighty late
getting round here to be married.
- The damage is all done.
- It sure is.
But could you fix us up, anyhow?
Well, it's never too late
to do the will of the Lord.
That's right. That's right.
Well, children, I certainly is glad to see
you all done make up your minds...
to do the right thing.
Thank you. 'Cause you know,
I've always been a respectable woman...
and I don't want that to come up
against my character.
Oh, it ain't what you was.
It's what you is today.
Look here,
you ain't got on no wedding veil.
I ain't gonna marry you in no wedding veil.
- Now, Missy, go get the veil.
- Yes.
I guess we'll conduct this
marriage ceremony right around there...
under that tree.
Just follow me round here.
The Lord is with us to see this wedding.
- Look like you're gonna have your way.
- That's right.
Venus, come
and be your Pappy's best man.
Here, boy, come on round here.
You look more like your mammy...
every day.
...in the time of man's innocence...
signifying unto us the mystical union...
that is between Christ and his church.
- Which holy estate Christ adorned...
- Hello, Zeke.
Come on, kiss me, Missy Rose.
...and first miracle that he wrought
in Cana of Galilee.
What's the matter with you?
What's the matter with your eyes?
- Don't look at me like that.
- I been looking at you all day.
You sure do look good tonight,
Missy Rose.
Oh, Zeke, don't do that.
- Come on, kiss me.
- Don't do that, Zeke.
- Don't do that.
Oh, Zeke.
...or lightly, but reverently.
- Man and wife.
- Amen.
The wedding's all over. They're married.
Come on out and kiss the bride.
Excuse me, Missy Rose, but it looks like
the devil's in me here tonight.
That's all right, Zeke. I'll forgive you.
Go ahead, my son.
- Ready, Henry?
- Yeah, I'm ready.
- That's it.
- Oh, yeah!
Sweet little baby
Now I lay me down to sleep,
I pray the Lord my soul to keep.
If I should die before I wake
I pray the Lord, my soul to take.
Bless Mammy and Pappy.
Bless Missy Rose,
Brother Zeke and Spunk.
Bless Sears, Roebuck and Coe. Amen.
Hush you bye
Don't you cry
Go to sleep
Little baby
You shall have
All the horses in the pasture
They belong to Mammy's little baby
Go to sleep
Little baby
Now, get up there. Here, here, here.
Go along. Go to bed. You're old enough
to go to bed by yourself.
- Goodnight, Mammy.
- Goodnight.
- Goodnight, Spunk.
- Goodnight, Pappy.
- Goodnight, Missy.
- Goodnight, Mammy.
- Goodnight, Zeke.
- I'll see you in the morning.
- Lord, grant me.
- Goodnight, Zeke.
- Goodnight. Sleep tight.
- Goodnight, Pappy.
- Goodnight, Zeke.
- Goodnight, Spunk.
Thank God.
These mules are so stubborn.
Stop right here.
- Whoa there, mule.
- Take it down to Veteran Smith.
Let us give thanks
for our success this year.
Let us kneel right down here.
We is most grateful for this
bountiful crop, O Lord...
- Yes, sir.
...and we trust you won't be offended...
- No.
...if we just ask one favor more.
Please, Lord, let us get a good price...
- for our cotton.
- Do pray, Lord.
- Amen.
- Don't forget the flour and the pepper.
- All right.
- Buy me my chewing gum.
- Don't forget my bowie knife.
- Good bye.
My buddy and my buddy's friend
Can pick more cotton than the gin can gin
Come on there, mule, giddap!
Whoa, there.
Come on here, Spunk. Let's hurry up
and get this cotton ginned...
so we can get on downtown
there before everything's closed up.
It'll be over in two shakes of a lamb's tail.
Well, if you'd just shake
your tail a little bit...
- it'd be so much better.
- Come on and help me.
- I is. I done all the work, anyhow.
- What do you know?
- Listen.
- I'm listening.
Sure sounds pretty, don't it?
Sure is.
You know that song.
- But I ain't sung that in a long time.
- Sounds like At the End of the Road.
The way is long
The night is dark
But I don't mind 'cause a happy lark
Will be singing
At the end of the road
I can't go wrong, I must go right
I'll find my way 'cause the guiding light
Will be shining
At the end of the road
There may be thorns in my path
But I'll wear a smile
'Cause in a little while
My path will be roses
The rain may fall from up above
But I won't stop 'cause the ones I love
Will be waiting
At the end of the road
The way is long, the night is dark
But I don't mind 'cause a happy lark
Will be singing
At the end of the road
I can't go wrong, I must go right
I'll find my way 'cause a guiding light
Will be shining
At the end of the road
I seem to roam through a field
That is snowy white
And through the silent night
A banjo is strumming
It says, "Come back, I roam no more"
My mammy's heart and the cabin door
Will be open
At the end of the road
- We sure needs you around here, Zeke.
- Hello there, fellas. How is everything?
You sure can sing good, fellas.
I feel much better. I can work harder.
Can't you?
Yes, indeed. I'm going to get
this cotton on down in this gin here.
Come on here, boy. Let's get through.
Yes. Here I is, fellas.
Let her come on down here.
Take it on down here.
- Look out, down there.
- There.
Going down to New Orleans
- Going to leave my honey downriver
- Roll down from night till day
- Well, I'm sure going away forever
- Going down to New Orleans
- Going to leave my honey downriver
- Roll down from night till day
Roll the cotton, roll the cotton
Roll the cotton from early morn
Roll this baby sure as you're born
Roll the cotton, roll the cotton
Roll the cotton from early morn
Roll this baby sure as you're born
I sure is going to eat myself...
plenty of corn bread
and chitlins here tonight.
Do it, Cy. Do it for your papa.
What did he get?
- Lord save us, look at that gal.
- Did you see those eyes?
Yes, sir!
Some chicken.
What a brown-skinned
bunch of sweetness she is.
Three steps to Heaven.
Angels walking on earth.
Boy, she's chocolate to the bone.
Boy, shake that starboard hip.
Open that door and let me in here.
Boy, she knows her stuff.
That baby's got a wiggle
even worms can't realize.
- No fooling, that gal sure knows her...
- Get back here, boy.
- Oh, Lord.
- Here, here, here.
You is just what I has got on my mind.
Let's get on away from here.
Say, get out of the way, small change.
You don't look like no big money to me.
I don't, doesn't I?
Well, just let your eyes feast upon this.
Guy got a roll that would choke
an elephant.
No, no, it ain't nothing like that.
This here money is mine,
and here it is where it remains.
Say, where did you get all the money,
big boy?
Cotton, cotton
Always picking cotton
Don't matter where I gets my money,
I has it just the same.
Where is you going, honey?
Anywhere you going, big boy.
Sure enough?
- Well, let's go away from here.
- I want to look good...
Come on away from here, honey.
Hello there, gal, how you feeling?
Got any money?
Let's have it, tin can.
- That's it, girl.
- Get out there, will you, honey.
The Benevolent Orders
of the Flat-Footed Waiters
Gave their annual ball
With the price of admission
only one half-a-dollar
They just crowded the hall
Flat-footing around
They suddenly found
An original movement
that they call the Swanee Shuffle
It's for you and for all
Now learn to do the Swanee Shuffle
Nothing to the Swanee Shuffle
Against the beat, you make your feet
Swanee Shuffle along
If they're flat just make them flatter
Like a pancake on a platter
I'm telling you, it's easy to
Swanee Shuffle along
Now just imitate the way a waiter
Walks with a plate of chow
Why, you needn't wait to do it later
Why not now? I'll show you how
Come with me where Dixie marches
Marches on its fallen arches
And see them Swanee Shuffle along
Learn to do the Swanee Shuffle
Nothing to the Swanee Shuffle
Now if they're flat just make them flatter
Like a pancake on a platter
I'm telling you, it's easy to
Swanee Shuffle along
Now just imitate the way a waiter
Walks with a plate of chow
Why, you needn't wait to do it later
Why not now? I'll show you how
Come with me where Dixie marches
Marches on its fallen arches
And see them Swanee Shuffle along
Come on!
There it is now. There it is now.
Oh, shuffle it, boy. Move it, baby.
Now that boy's sweet as honey.
All right, nice.
Everybody dance!
Oh, play that thing.
How you feel, big boy?
Like my dancing?
Does I?
Honey, I likes anything you's got.
My great, big, dancing,
teasing, trancing man.
How much money is you got, big boy?
Well, I's got to close on 'round...
About $100.
You ain't got $200, is you, honey?
No, I ain't got no $200.
$100 suits me all right, right now.
But wouldn't it be nice if you had $200...
so you and me could spend $100...
and then you could take that other $100
home where it belongs?
Well, where's I gonna get any $200?
Why, it took my family six months'
hard work to get half that much.
But with financing,
there ain't nothing you can't get.
Why, honey, a boy came here last week...
with only $10 to his name...
and when he walked out...
he had close around to
$300 in his hind pocket...
and Hot Shot's favorite diamond ring.
Where did he get all that luck from?
- Just dancing with you, honey?
- Now who's been talking to you?
I's just overflowing with luck.
Dancing with me is like having
a rabbit foot in each pocket.
Then I ought to be about the luckiest man
in the world, right now.
I ought to have been here a long time ago.
Why, what do you know about that?
- Why, if that ain't the old boy himself.
- Where?
Well, there's Hot Shot now, honey.
Say listen, he's got more money
than he knows what to do with.
And is one of the most generous suckers
I ever heard tell of.
- Is that true, sure enough?
- I mean it.
Let's go on to him and ask. Right now.
Come on, let's go see what he got.
Come on, big boy.
Atta boy.
Hey, Hot Shot, look here.
Who called Hot Shot?
Come here a minute, will you?
What's on your mind, high yellow?
What's aching you now?
Here's a boy who says he feels
kind of lucky.
And he wants to know if you gonna
give him a little accommodation.
Say, come on now
and help the boy out a little.
You know anything
about shooting dice, son?
Well, I just knows the words.
I ain't so familiar with the tune.
You old sweet rascal, you.
- You sure can say some cute things.
- Sure enough?
Not tonight.
I ain't wasting no time
on no buck-and-a-half cotton picker.
Say, what's the matter with you,
goofy head.
This boy ain't one of those kind,
is you, big boy?
Say, what does he mean,
buck-and-a-half cotton picker?
I bet I got more money in my pocket
right now...
- than he ever thought of having.
- Sure you have.
Say, honey, wouldn't it be nice
if you'd spent a $100...
all on your baby? By this time tomorrow...
Yeah, what is the matter
with that tinhorn?
Come on over here,
let me show him something.
What do you mean,
"buck-and-a-half cotton picker"?
Suppose I paid you $20 right off the bat?
That makes a lot of difference.
Money talks with me brother,
money talks.
That's just what I said, money talks.
Go ahead, he wins the first throw.
Deuce...
- and a six.
- Atta, baby!
Stand close to me, honey.
Keep on feeding me luck, yeah?
Oh, boy.
Let's hit old stiff hat
for a natural right now.
That'll be good.
Oh, boy.
Eleven. How do you like that?
Just fine.
Well, I'll give you a break, big boy.
Go ahead, shoot that 40.
Go ahead and shoot the 40.
You... He can't win no more.
Come on, now, money can't
grow down there in the hand.
Put it down. Atta boy!
Don't fail me this time, dice.
- Roll right out on a natural.
- Here it is again.
Sure is.
Now you knows I can't keep this up
all night long, brother.
You sure can't.
Bound to crap out some of these times.
Shoot that $80.
Let the $80 ride. Come on.
If you win, you'll have a $160.
And we'll be sitting pretty.
She's telling you right, boy.
- Come on, put your money out there.
- Let's go. Can't wait all night.
Well, this is the time we hit him.
Honey, stick close to me now,
sure enough.
Yeah, and this is the time
that old boy craps.
Let it be snake eyes.
Let me be right, dice, let me be right.
Keep the big boy broke.
This is my last chance.
Natural, dice, natural.
Right in the dough.
In the dough is right.
That is a six and an ace.
This is the best gravy train ever rolled
up my alley.
That didn't take long.
Pretty good day.
He's took all my money.
I didn't know. I thought you'd win.
Oh, I'll help you to get some more money.
Oh, don't act like this.
Oh, my goodness.
Let me see them dice.
You ain't suspecting me, is you, big boy.
There ain't nothing wrong with them dice.
Go on, let him see the dice, Hot Shot.
Well, I ain't saying nothing,
but let me see them dice.
Come on, why don't you let him see them?
That ain't nothing.
There they is.
There ain't nothing wrong with them dice.
There ain't nothing wrong
with the dice, big boy.
I don't see nothing wrong.
Let me see that pair of dice
you just playing with.
Oh, you're starting that bellyaching, huh?
Starting that racket.
Come on, let him see the dice,
if you got any more in your pocket.
Let me see that pair of dice you got
in your pocket.
Say, you better keep quiet.
You big country hick.
Say, don't call him no country hick.
He ain't no country hick.
You'll be getting my back up in a minute.
Why don't you stop all this?
Going around here squawking about
losing your dough like a big 10-year-old.
Oh, my goodness.
Say, don't take it so hard, big boy.
There's lots more cotton in the field.
Let me alone.
I'm asking you once more.
Let me see them dice you got
in your pocket.
Now, I'm getting pretty tired of you
trying to bullyrag me.
Now you get your hide out of here
before I throws it out.
Go on out, big boy.
I'll be out in a minute. Go on.
Now, you clear out of here
before I let you have some of this.
Give 'em room, give 'em room.
Come on, get a move on.
Zeke.
There's the door.
Come back here and give me
my money back, you dirty thieves.
You dirty skunks.
Spunk.
Where did you come from?
How did you find me?
I heard your voice.
You ain't hurt, is you?
I'm hurt, right here.
You're all right, ain't you?
Speak to me, Spunk.
Oh, God!
- Where is you hurt, Spunk?
- Right here...
Zeke, did they get the money from
the cotton seed?
I'm so glad I found you, big brother.
Can't you...
Can't you do something for me?
Hold me.
These bullets...
These bullets hurt me so.
- Wait a minute...
- Oh, Lord, help me.
...and I'll see if I can get
somebody to help me.
Oh, help me, somebody.
Come here and help me.
My brother is dying.
Oh, God, won't somebody help me?
Help me, please. Help me, please.
Spunk.
I'll take you home to Mammy.
She'll help me.
Can you stand up, Spunk?
Can you try to help and get up?
Come on. Come across you.
You're holding out on me, eh?
You keep quiet.
You only get half of what I won.
Didn't I have $40 when I started?
Oh, you ain't never had $40 in your life.
Oh, Lord...
have mercy on my children.
Have mercy on my soul.
- Haven't they been here, Mammy?
- Mammy, didn't the boys...
Didn't the boys come home yet?
Mama, what's the matter?
Children ain't come home yet.
Have mercy upon my children.
Mammy, don't cry.
Have mercy on my soul.
Don't cry, Mammy, they coming home.
Oh, Lord!
Mammy, don't cry.
The Lord will bring them home safe.
The Lord will bring them home, Mammy.
Don't worry.
- Oh, our poor boys.
- Don't cry, Mammy.
We wonder this morning where they are.
Send them to us, sweet Jesus.
Yes, Lord. Lord have mercy upon them.
Let our boys come. Where can they be?
Yes, Lord.
Have mercy upon our brothers.
Where can our boys be this morning?
Lord, have mercy upon them.
Can they be on their way here?
What's that I hear?
Zeke.
Oh, my God.
Where is our boy Spunk?
Where is Spunk?
Oh, our poor boy.
Oh, Lord, have mercy upon us. Oh, Lord.
Lord, have mercy upon us this morning.
Lord, have mercy...
Oh, graveyard
You must give us his body now
Weep not
Weep not, dear Mother
The Lord giveth and the Lord taketh away
Weep not, Father
Come, son.
I am not here to judge you.
Oh, Pappy, I've sinned.
I've sinned...
and I am hanging on the edge of hell.
Yes, son.
But the Lord forgives.
My heart is aching for my poor brother.
Oh, my heart is aching.
Oh, Pappy, show me how to repent.
Show me the way.
Look, son...
the Lord has sent an angel...
to show you the way.
Can't you see him coming...
in that snow-white chariot...
and snow-white robe?
Can't you hear him, son?
It is the angel of the Lord...
that comforts...
them that mourn.
Look, son...
can't you see him?
Yes, Pappy.
I see him and I hear him.
The Lord's done showed me the light.
The Lord has done revealed
the truth of his creation.
I lay my brother...
down in the ground...
but the ground can't hold my brother.
No, Pappy.
The ground can't hold him.
'Cause the Lord is stronger
than the ground.
Yes.
Why, the Lord is the ground.
The Lord is the sky...
and the heavens
and the moon and the sun.
The Lord is the earth...
and all the living things of the earth.
Yes.
The Lord in his kingdom.
Ain't no more pain.
There ain't no more sorrow.
And there ain't no more death.
So why do we wail in grief?
Oh, my brother...
I gives you back to the sky and the wind...
and to the earth and to the seas.
Oh, my brother...
I gives you back to the Lord.
For the Lord is the beginning...
as well as the end.
Come with your sorrow...
and leave with his joy.
Come with your failure...
and leave with his victory.
Come, oh come with your emptiness...
and leave with the fullness of his joy.
Come, oh, come to the Lord.
Come to that land of green pastures.
Come to the Lord.
Amen.
Hallelujah!
Out in the night.
Swing low, sweet chariot
Coming for to carry me home
I looked over Jordan and what did I see
A band of angels coming after me
Coming for to carry me home
Amen.
Get on board, little children
There's room for many a-more
Brethren and sisters...
the servant of the Lord is here,
to give you all...
a free airplane ride direct to glory.
Let's go!
Amen.
Amen. All right, you fellas.
- Give me a dunking down.
- Get on behind him.
- All right, just lead him. I'll kick him out.
- Get down!
I'm glad to shake your hand.
Thank you, sir. Yes, sir.
Come down to the meeting tonight.
Thank you, brother!
Giddap!
I've had me a good time today, really!
Hot mama, raring to go.
Where you going, buttercup?
I is going where I's going,
that's where I's going!
You move out the way.
Everywhere I go,
you come following along behind me.
- Oh, now...
- Oh, move out the way! Get out!
Hallelujah! Brother Zekiel's coming!
Hallelujah!
Great day, the righteous marching
Great day
God's going to build up Zion's walls
Great day, the righteous marching
Great day
God's going to build up Zion's walls
This is the day of jubilee
God's going to set his...
Be still!
Look at that little mule!
What kind of mule is that?
Hey, Chick...
ain't that, that guy
we cleaned out down in Greenville?
What you know about that? It sure am.
Well, well, well!
So that's who this guy is, eh?
That's that guy. Can you beat that!
Hey, let's have some fun
with this guy here. Come on.
Hey there, Brother!
How's the dice rolling these days?
A big fella like you ought to be carrying
that little donkey instead of riding it!
- Hey, did you get that look?
- Did I?
You've kind of turned up your nose
at us sinners, nowadays, huh?
Shut up, you yellow hussy.
You ain't never going to be nothing at all.
All you want is to come here
and get after my boy!
Go on back down there
to that alley where you belong.
Oh, well, it's just another one
of the Lord's little mistakes!
The Lord don't make no mistakes,
you understand?
You can make a fool of Zekiel...
but you can't make fun of the Lord,
while Zekiel is around...
- and I'm gonna make you respect him.
- Are you gonna stand for that?
Why don't you knock him down?
I'll knock your brains out, you big lug.
What you mean, anyway?
And you can't make fun of the Lord
neither, while I'm around!
- Let me go!
- I ain't none of them things.
I'm the servant of the Lord, and I've got
the strength of the Lord in my arms.
You're hurting me!
In these two arms!
It's too bad that he's got to put
his holy hands on you. You'll spoil them!
Amen!
The Lord will surely punish them for that.
I wish I was about 10 years older.
I'd show you something!
You got some nerve, coming down here!
Great day, the righteous marching
Great day
God's going to build up...
Give me that old-time religion
And it's good enough for me
It was good for the Hebrew children
Old-time religion
Give me that old-time religion
And it's good enough for me
- Hallelujah!
Look at that boy sitting up there
with his whole family around him!
I bet you ten-to-one
you can't save me, Brother Zekiel.
Make me cry. You're making
everybody else cry around here!
- Say, boy, look...
- What's the matter with you, gal?
- You crazy?
- Dry it up, small change!
Brethren and sisters...
the text of my sermon is going to be:
"Repent, ye sinners...
"before it is too late."
- Oh yeah!
- Hallelujah!
The road to hell is downhill.
Downhill!
Easy and greased like lightning.
And the Cannonball Express...
is leaving for hell twice a day.
Yeah!
I'm talking to all you sinners out there,
who's on that train.
I'm going along with you...
and I'm gonna give all you sinners
your last chance.
But remember...
there ain't no round trip ticket to hell!
All aboard.
Brothers and sisters...
we's gonna make three stops
before we get to hell...
and we're approaching the first one now.
The first stop, is the town of Faith.
Town of Faith!
It's just a little place,
but the climate is cool...
and the people is friendly and kind.
Some of you bootleggers...
and some of you gamblers...
better get off and take hold of Faith!
Brothers, come right along!
Preach it right and long!
Children, come on and get off at Faith!
That's right, children.
Don't you make no mistake
in locating in Faith.
We're going on to the next station.
Hear that old train pulling out?
Pulling out!
Children, you see that old devil
throw that cinder in my eye?
Dirty devil!
He's just trying to make me miss
that next stop...
but I'll surely fool him.
I'll surely fool him.
Get ready.
We is coming to the next station.
- Obedience.
- Obedience!
Oh, but Obedience.
Here, sister. Don't leave your man behind.
Make him get off at Obedience.
I'll get him!
Come on, sister. Bring your man on
and make him get off at Obedience.
- That's right.
- Obedience...
- Yeah.
...is a nine o'clock town.
- Surely, it is.
And the curfew rings every night.
- Sure it does.
- Sure do!
Bring up your children in obedience,
and you'll know...
they'll grow up good Christians...
and not just little old scalawags!
Children should be seen and not heard.
Amen!
All you sinners.
Come on and jump aboard, you sinners.
This side is for
the leading citizens in Obedience.
Get out here.
We's going on to the last station.
Watch it go.
Can't get enough steam now.
The last station.
We's coming to that last station,
the last station:
Repentance...
is the last station before hell.
Anybody here want to get off
at Repentance?
Oh, yeah!
That's right, children.
Come on, kneel on down.
It gets kind of hot in Repentance
sometimes...
but never as hot as hell.
Won't you come, sister? Won't you come?
I beg with you. I plead with you.
Don't bother me. Leave me alone.
I don't want to hear nothing
you got to say.
Won't you come? Come on and repent...
repent, I say.
I'm speaking to that last sinner
and I don't want her to go to hell.
Won't you come? Won't you come?
You hear that old devil say
Come on down below
But you just let him know
You're heading for Heaven
Come on and climb the golden stairs
And all your troubles and all your cares
Will be over at the end of the road
At the end of the road
Won't you come, sister?
I'm pleading with you.
I want to go, Brother Zekiel.
Don't leave me.
I want to be saved. Oh, Lord.
I want to be good.
I'm coming, Brother Zekiel.
I'm sticking with the last sinner...
and I don't want her to go to hell!
'Cause the guiding light will be shining
At the end of the road
Hallelujah!
Carry me to the water
Oh, carry me to the water
To be baptized
Hallelujah!
Carry me to the water
Stand right around, brother.
Fold your arms.
Hallelujah!
Amen.
I have another building
Not made by hand, I know
I know I have another building
A building not made by hand
Not made by hand, I know
I know I have another building
A building not made by hand
Praise the Lord!
Praise the name! Hallelujah!
Carry me to the water
To be baptized
Hallelujah!
Oh, Lord, make me good.
Oh, Lord! Oh, Lord, make me pure.
Praise the Lord! Praise the Lord!
Hallelujah!
Oh, brother!
Praise his holy name.
Amen.
I've been a wicked woman.
- But I'm sanctified now.
- I know how it is.
- Hallelujah!
- Amen.
Hold me close to you, Brother Zekiel.
Keep me good.
Don't let me sin no more.
Pray, Brother Zekiel.
You're so good.
Zeke!
Leave her here with me.
You go on there back to your people.
Oh, God!
Have mercy on me!
Here, what's the matter with you, gal?
Ain't nothing. I know what it is.
Yes, you got more religion
than what's good for you...
you hypocrite!
Come on up here, Christmas!
You're slower than cold molasses
in the winter time.
Come on up here.
Tuck your heads there, boys. Come on.
Even so, we've been mighty lucky.
That's the first she-devil we run across
since we've started on this trip.
She sure is pretty, Mammy.
I never see such big eyes in all my life.
Oh, big eyes!
Why, Zeke ain't had no mind
for no big eyes.
Not since his brother died,
anything but them.
We got trouble here, trouble there
I really don't believe
We got trouble everywhere
We got trouble everywhere we go
He's coming now, Mammy.
I'm gonna change my apron.
... trouble there
I really does believe
We got trouble everywhere
We got trouble everywhere we go
Tired, son?
I'll let you have a nice plate
of this hot chitlins.
I sure would, Mammy.
But I likes everything you cook.
I know you certainly is crazy
about chitlins.
What's the matter, son?
I was just thinking, Mammy.
I don't know what I would do...
if I didn't have you and Missy Rose
to look after me.
It does take a good woman for to
keep a man out of mischief these days.
That's right, Mammy. It sure does.
Now, don't go fretting, son.
Your Pappy and me
is the best friends you got.
And we gonna look after you
just as long as we can.
Thank you, Mammy.
Because you're the same old Zeke to me.
- Missy Rose!
- Ma'am?
Come on here and look after
these vittles on the stove...
while I get ready to go to the jubilee.
Yes.
Missy Rose, come over here
and sit down with me, won't you?
Why, what's the matter, Brother Zeke?
That's just it,
I don't know what is the matter.
Seems like the devil's done
took ahold of me.
What you mean? What kind of talk is that?
A big strong man like you ain't
going to give in to that nasty devil...
- after we done traveled this far.
- I don't want to give in...
but he just keeps on a-clawing
and a-pulling after me all the time.
- That's just the way he do.
- Just won't let me be.
What's we going to do, big brother?
I don't know what we're going to do.
- Unless...
- Unless what, Zeke?
Missy Rose, supposing you and me...
Let's you and me get married,
at the next station.
That'll stop him quicker than anything.
Brother Zeke.
You know, I love you.
Mammy, where is my pipe?
What you hide my pipe for, anyway?
Why can't you let things be?
I suspect it's up somewhere
where you just left it.
Oh, here it is, you old stew pot.
Mammy, Pappy, Missy Rose
and me's got a surprise for you.
- Yeah?
- Yes. Ain't we, honey?
- Yes.
- What is it?
We is done decided to get married
at the next station.
Oh, Lord!
- Pappy, ain't that happy news?
- I long expected that.
- Yes, and I'm glad.
- They had to come to it.
Let me kiss both of you.
God bless you all. Well, well, well.
Children, that's just as it ought to be.
Zeke and Missy.
Looky here, children.
You know the Lord's going to set
his blessing on this wedding.
Well, well, well, this is justice for you.
Pappy and I done waited
a long time for this day.
Here, honey,
this ain't no time for no crying.
Why, don't you know that
me and you is going to make...
that old devil run so fast...
that his horns and his tail's
gonna drop off?
Don't cry no more, now.
Please don't cry, honey.
- No, this ain't no time to cry.
- Yeah, Mammy, you talk to her.
Yes, she ain't nothing at all but a child.
Well, appears it's better
for you to cry first and then laugh last.
I'm crying because I'm happy, Mammy.
Yes, well these men, they ain't no angels.
There ain't none of them no angels.
But I tell you, you wouldn't find
a better boy than my Zeke...
if you was to scratch this world
with a fine tooth comb.
Give me that old-time religion
It is good enough for me
It was good for the Hebrew children
And it's good enough for me
Hallelujah!
Give me that old-time religion
What are you doing here, Hot Shot?
What are you doing here?
So you're all hopped up about
that fake preacher, huh?
Go on, Hot Shot, leave me be.
I ain't got no time for you now.
Come on, you ain't got
no time for me now, huh?
I been wrong all these years, understand?
I found happiness.
Brother Zekiel has given me strength
and shown me the way.
Well, of all the people in this world
to fall for that kind of 'lasses.
- Come on, babe, give me a kiss.
- Get out of my way, Hot Shot.
I got religion now.
Oh, I don't care nothing about
your religion. Come on.
Take your hands off of me, Hot Shot!
How come you don't want my hands
on you no more?
I'll make you forget that psalm-singing,
crap-shooting faker.
- He ain't none of them things.
- Yes, he is.
And I is late for the services...
and you or nobody else
ain't going to keep me...
from the protecting arms
of Brother Zekiel.
- You ain't going out that door.
- Let me go!
Can't you see that my blood
is washed in the spirit of the Lamb?
I can see that your blood's
been washed in the fire of the devil.
Can't you see that I'm through sinning,
Hot Shot? Oh, please.
Oh, you ain't never gonna quit sinning, gal.
It's right there in your blood.
Oh, Lord, give me strength!
Oh, help me, Brothel Zekiel!
I'll break your neck.
Get off of me. I'll show you.
Don't use that poker, gal.
Don't come around no more.
- Oh, my head!
- You dirty skunk!
That's what I'm doing to anybody
that stands in my path to glory.
Oh, my!
Come on, old Devil.
Put up your hands
before I bust you in the jaw.
- Hit him, Brother Zekiel! Sock him!
- Don't be backing around in that corner...
like you're scared of me.
I is with you, Brother Zekiel.
This bell ain't going to ring
until you been down and out.
Preach it, Brother Zeke.
- You got me that time.
- We're proud of you, Brother.
Yes, go ahead and laugh. Laugh.
This going to be your last time...
because you're going to
finish your laugh in hell.
Hell, Brother Zekiel, hell!
I'm tired of you making sinners
out of my people.
Now, come on get up from there.
Pick up your bones...
- because the fight ain't over yet.
- No.
Now, brothers,
he's trying to give me a battle.
- That's for the gamblers you done made.
- True.
Yes, sir.
- That's for the backbiters.
- Preach it.
- And that's for the midnight ramblers.
- Tell it so they can hear it. Tell it, yes.
And that's for the corn-whiskey drinkers,
the jazz dancers...
the scandal-mongers and the bootleggers.
Look at him.
There he is, the old devil is down and out.
Somebody come here and get a stretcher
and take him away from here.
Put him on that train to hell, and let him...
ride, let him ride on down by himself.
- Oh, brothers, we done been sanctified.
- Sanctified!
We done been purified.
We done been saved...
and we don't belong to him no more.
Amen.
I belong to that band
Hallelujah
This is Missy calling you!
Oh, Lordy! Come back!
Please don't leave me, Brother Zeke!
This is Missy calling you!
Oh, Zeke, where is you?
Please don't go. Come back! Don't leave!
Oh, Lordy!
Brother Zeke! Where are you?
Oh, no!
- Zeke's gone.
- Zeke is gone?
Knocking off, now.
Come on, boys, let's go.
Come on here, Jim.
Gee, Babe!
I sure had a hard time finding you.
And another thing, I ain't going
to leave you until you goes with me.
Give me some of that good old loving
you got there. Come on.
Holy mackerel!
The man is coming from the mill.
Give me my hat, woman. I'll see you later.
I hate to see
That evening sun go down
My man's done quit me
And done left this town
Feeling tomorrow
Just like I feel today
I'm gonna pack my trunk
And make my getaway
Easy rider
He done lost his rein
With gin and gambling
They're gonna hide your face
To work for that woman
Say, what's the matter with you,
long face? Don't you like my singing?
What's that buggy doing out there?
Buggy? Why, honey, I ain't seen no buggy.
I don't know nothing about no buggy.
Well, there was one out there
when I come in.
Oh, don't be suspicious.
Come on and show your baby.
My goodness,
you just as fussy as you can be.
Now come on out there
and show me where the buggy is.
Don't be like that.
Now see that, baby?
I told you there wasn't no buggy out there.
Come on and eat your dinner.
Don't be like that.
You know I love you.
Come on now and be good.
Come on now and sit down.
What's the matter, you sick?
- No.
- Well, what's the matter then?
Has the boss
been at you again today, huh?
No. I told you no. Don't bother me.
Tell me, honey, what's on your mind?
Here I've been waiting for you all day...
to come home and put
your big strong arms around me...
and now you treat me
just like I'm a stepchild.
- Is you treating me right, Chick?
- Course I is.
Let your baby sit on your lap
and make you...
feel so good.
That's it, dreaming boy.
Rest your head on Chick.
I sure is tired, Chick.
I'm tired of thinking.
I know you is. Stop thinking.
Thinking makes you say
bad words to Chick.
Zeke, you asleep?
Zeke.
- Come on, Chick! He's following us.
- Oh, I can't run!
- Hurry up. He's got a gun!
- No, I can't run.
Please!
Hold tight, Chick.
Hold tight.
Look out the wheel's going.
Thought you was going
to get away from me, didn't you?
Don't you know
you can't quit me like that?
Before I let you get away from me,
I'll break you in two.
I is broke in two already, Zeke.
Please take me out of this mud.
Don't talk to me like that. Oh, please.
Won't you please take me out?
Oh, please.
Don't you know
you can't quit me like that?
I ain't two-timing you, Zeke.
- That's what you been doing all the time.
- I never knowed what I wanted.
Don't be sore with me.
That old devil's coming closer now...
and I is getting more scared all the time.
That old devil's
reaching out his claws for me.
Can't you help your Chick now?
No.
Your Chick's done gone to the devil.
No, honey. You can't go! You can't go!
Zekiel, don't let that old devil get me.
Old devil can't get you, honey.
Not as long as I'm around.
Hold me, Brother Zekiel.
Hold me in your strong arms.
I'm holding you, honey.
I'm holding you, baby.
Holding you in my heart, forever.
I is scared, Brother Zekiel.
I is scared to meet the Lord...
so scared.
Who done this? Who done this?
I know. I know!
She hurt? I couldn't help it. The wheel...
What's the matter with this thing?
Whoa there, boy. Whoa!
Oh, my!
Don't kill me, don't...
This old hammer kill John Henry
But it won't kill me
No it won't kill me
There ain't no hammer
On this mountaintop
That rings like mine
Going home
I'm a going home
Quiet like
Some still day
I'm just going home
It's not far
Just close by
Through an open door
Work all done
Care laid by
Time to fear no more
Mother's there
Expecting me
Father's waiting, too
Lots of folks
Gathered there
All the friends I knew
Mammy.
Zeke! Oh, my boy.
Thank God!
I'm so glad you come, my son.
Oh, thank God.
- Where do you come from, Zeke?
- Brother, you gone and left us.
Brother Zeke, where do you come from?
We're glad to see you back.
You don't look well, Brother Zeke.
Pappy, can I come into your house?
Boy, you're just in time
to help us with the picking.
Missy Rose,
you ain't forgotten me, is you?
Of course not. I love you too much.
Do you, sure enough, honey?
Son, you must be mighty hungry.
Don't you want
some chitlins and spare ribs?
- Mammy, I likes anything you cook.
- Come on, then.
Ripped by:
SkyFury