1999.
Kargil.
An unheard name that
suddenly came to the limelight...
A name where the
fights in the mountains...
...turned green camouflage red.
To win back these
mountains from the enemy...
...near the national
highway number one...
...the Indian army is
making arduous efforts.
After a difficult
battle of two months...
...only six mountains are left.
Let's meet some of these
soldiers who are trying...
...to win back these mountains.
Akash Sarin. IBN 7.
Balkar Singh, aren't
you afraid of bullets?
I am.
But not for me, for
the sake of our people.
Because when the
bullet hits the target...
...it pierces our hearts and passes
through the hearts of our dear ones.
What do you think about the war?
The real war used to take
place between Kings and Emperors.
Some of the soldiers
came forward and fought.
Balkar Singh tell me,
when will this war end?
The day when our
leaders and ministers...
...who give us orders to fight...
...when thy go along
with us and fight.
The day the war will get over.
Do you get a chance to
talk to your family?
Each one to his own destiny.
Do you write letters?
Yes, I write letters.
We do write letters.
What do you write?
Are you a reporter or a spy?
Here, you keep it.
But if something
happens to me, don't post it.
Why?
Because this letter has
my dreams written in it.
Which I will never
be able to fulfill.
Writing a letter is
tradition which we follow.
Actually even I
have written a letter.
You can keep it.
It'll be of use in your research.
I don't need it.
Because if something happens to me...
...the Army will call my brother.
And he will fly me back.
Brother?
Squadron leader, Vikram Shergill.
- Yes, Air Force.
And yes...
If you see him,
tell him I will be back
...to kick his ass.
Sir! Excuse me, Sir!
Sir...
Sir, are you going back?
- Yes.
Can you post this for me in Kargil?
- Yes. Sure.
Who is it for?
- Leave application, sir.
I'll post it.
- Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
But before I could post the letter.
I got the news that Sahil
Naqvi sacrificed his life.
Along with the
remaining three mountains...
...three people were
left just for namesake...
Balkar Singh, Dhananjay Shergill,
Sahil Naqvi.
And many more like them.
This is not a story
of three soldiers.
This story is about our country.
"Loneliness."
Will you put me to sleep?
Change the channel!
"Uncle moon has slept and
uncle sun has waked up."
Hey! Turn right from ahead.
"Hold the needles of the watch,
they are running."
"One story has ended and the...
...other has begun, uncle."
"Uncle, the sun has risen."
Hey! Stop! Take this,
enjoy yourself.
This is fine.
Hi, baby!
It's for you.
Thank you.
Nice pants.
- Oh! Just bought them today.
Come in. C'mon in.
I hope your parents
aren't there inside?
This leather pant is boiling.
Come, close baby!
Uh... Can I use your toilet please?
Stop!
- Why? - Safety baby!
I thought you would have it!
What! Why would I have it! Fool!
Ok! Two minutes!
- What?!
What a relief!
- Come fast, sweetheart!
Coming baby!
Give me the keys of the bike.
I'll be back in a jiffy!
Sam, it's risky.
What if my Dad sees you?
I've been waiting for a month.
Don't make me wait any more.
Either way I have never seen your
father and neither has he seen me.
And even if he sees me...
...just tell him that a
friend had borrowed his bike.
Sammy! These are Dad's shorts!
They are clean, right?
Give me the keys.
Baby! I'll be back!
What's up, Nawab Saab (sir)?
Where are you?
Saand, I am in deep trouble.
Tell me, what happened?
Saand, I was wearing
those leather pants...
Nawab Saab, you have worn
it but do not remove it.
Once you remove it, you
won't be able to wear it again.
It shirks with sweat and heat
Saand, I've made that mistake.
Oh Nawab Saab, you are screwed!
I had told you not to wear leather
pants in the summers of Delhi.
Nawab Saab, what have you done?
Now give me a solution.
Ok, Nawab Saab, is
there any cream around?
Cream? Yes. Some hair remove.
Don't think... apply it immediately!
Cream is a lubricant.
Oh... Oh my God! where is it?
Nawab Saab, your Shivani... safety.
Baby, I've a surprise for you.
Oh shit!
Saand, it has formed some strange...
...paste and even my
hair is falling off.
Nawab Saab, you have
applied hair removal cream...
...and on top of it
added powder to that!
You were the one who
told me to do that.
Hey, Nawab Saab, not fair.
you can't blame me
for everything, ok?
Go, I'm not talking to you. Go!
Oh, Saand, oh, Saand,
listen, listen, listen...
You idiot! You too will suffer!
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
Hey uncle, you found my bike
to jump across to kill yourself?
Oh! Your bike! Anyway, son,
I'm going up to staff quarters.
Can I hitch a ride?
Come on sit!
- Thank you.
- Yes.
Son, take a right from ahead...
which way are you going?
I am also going that way.
Go slow, son. Looks
like you are in a hurry!
Uncle, one doesn't get such a
chance often. - What chance?
The girl is alone at home.
I am going to give her company.
You never did
ding-dong during your heydays?
Ding-dong? And son, what
about the girl's father?
He's not there.
- What?
That fool has left early in the
morning to give tuition to someone...
...leaving his
daughter alone at home.
Son, just stop
after these two houses.
Enough, enough, enough, enough.
Uncle!
- I've reached!
Do you live some where around here?
Forget about me. Tell me
about you, you want to go here?
Oh yes uncle! How do you know?
Son, that is because the bike
that you are riding is mine.
And the shorts that you are
wearing also belong to me.
And the wonderful
thing is that the house...
...where you want to go is also mine.
Father has come back after
giving his tuition, son.
What took you so long, Sam?
Baby.
Saand, idiot! You are
going to get thrashed!
You've seen my condition!
What have you made me do?
Nawab Saab, it's all because of you!
Because of me! And do
you know, there is a...
...party at Shivani's house today?
I've lost that opportunity too!
Party! What are you saying?
Party! Nawab Saab, I've an idea!
How can we go? Only
girls and strippers allowed.
Hey girls, the strippers are here!
Wow.
It's interesting! Wow.
"Now we're gonna teach you
never gonna let you go."
"Heart obtained such a gem..."
"Hey, girls. Let's have some fun."
"Heart obtained such a gem...
...I feel I'm flying high."
"These..."
"These mischievous guys."
"Heart obtained such a gem
I feel I'm flying high."
"These mischievous guys!"
"In your hearts, in your lips...
...in your hair, we want
to touch you everywhere."
"Hey, handsome guy!"
"Don't lock your eyes,
it may kill you."
"You might land you into trouble."
"Tell me how do you find this slap?"
"...I feel I'm flying high."
"These mischievous guys!"
"Fall in love..."
"Make me..."
"Fall in love with me."
"Make me yours."
"Take away the knife..."
"Let's welcome this golden moment."
"Let's welcome..."
"I feel I'm flying high."
"Guys!"
"These mischievous guys!"
"Heart obtained such a gem...
...I feel I'm flying high."
"These mischievous guys!"
"Come into my life, o beloved."
"You're not less
than a roadside Romeo."
"Your beauty is really amazing."
"Just get lost,
don't try to flatter me."
"You've created uproar in my heart."
"Mind it, I'm the lioness."
"My heart says I love you."
"You're a museum piece."
"Give me one chance
to show my talent."
"This victory will be a fun."
"How will you survive today?"
How will you survive?
"These mischievous guys."
Stop it!
I know him.
He is not a stripper.
- Who cares!
I think he should leave.
Hey, Nawab Saab, where are you
going? Say sorry to the CHICK.
I am mean sorry! To the ladies!
Sorry.
Institute of film making announces...
...the graduation
of the present batch
It is said that a new
generation brings in a new vision.
You'll form the new age of Cinema.
But some students who have
scored less marks will...
...have to submit a graduate
film to get their degrees.
For others, I congratulate
you as you stand graduates.
I've passed!
Nawab Saab.
Congratulations!
Mr. Sameer Suri and Mr. Ali Shah.
I'd like to see you in my office.
Sir, have we come first?
Yes, but from the back.
Do you know in this whole batch.
Only your grades are least?
Only us?
- Yes.
You've not attended
a single lecture.
And have failed the
practical as well.
No sir we have
attended two practical.
The ones in which we cheated
And we come to college everyday.
- Really?
Meet him.
Who is he?
Uncle!
He's Piya's dad.
Hello, uncle. How are you?
Not uncle, son. Your professor.
When did this happen?
Since the last term.
Piya told me he tutors.
Sir, you can imagine the
caliber of these two...
...who don't even know
who their professor is.
Correct, uncle.
- Yes, correct.
You'll have to
submit a graduation film.
Or else I will not give
you a graduation certificate.
Without which you can not
apply for your American visa.
But, sir
- Enough.
If you want to go to America,
get me the film.
Why are you two so happy?
You have not even graduated.
But we can not tell our family that.
Think about it, the only heir to
the Royal family of Indore fails!
And your dad would
congratulate you right?
Why do you always get
into problems together?
Because since
childhood we had pledged...
...to live and die together.
Ali, have you thought of
the topic for the film,?
Don't think too much, Nawab Saab.
We're making a porn movie.
- What?
'A night in the forest.'
And do you know who
will be our forest queen?
Piya.
- Shut up!
We thought under the
pretext of post-graduation
We will enjoy a vacation
for 2 years in America.
But now we will have
to make a film. Or else.
Or else, vacation cancelled.
We joined the course thinking
that everything would be easy
But Nawab Saab, this
has become a pain.
Saand, what do you think
should be the topic of our film?
Religion, politics, socio-economics.
Easy, Nawab Saab. Easy.
We can not even spell
most of these words.
What was that? Socio. Shoo-shoo.
Why don't you make a film on
joining the Indian Defense Forces?
Indian Defense?
This is all what a cadet of
the military academy can suggest.
Shut up!
And why are you doing it?
Who joins the
defense force these days?
I will.
You'll die if you join.
Looks like You are
looking for a one-day job?
You get shot straight in the head.
It's of no use.
In news channels, they
show it in the subtitles...
...one soldier dead in cross firing.'
Absolutely, You don't
even get paid well enough.
I just want that.
Amit is absolutely right.
You're risking your life,
And, what if you die?
Right. And on top of
that a grieving family!
Nawab Saab, I've found a topic.
The topic of our film.
'Why one shouldn't
join the defense forces? '
Amazing, Saand.
'Why not to join
the defense forces.'
Good one.
Why do you guys
always think negatively?
Riya, whatever you've heard in
the last one minute is right.
We gave you 3 reasons but Karan...
...couldn't... even give one.
Maybe, I just don't have a reason.
But I have an emotion
that I cannot explain.
Oh! Quiet! You find your emotion.
Meanwhile Nawab Saab
and I will make our film.
You know, you two
could meet my cousin.
He's a war journalist.
Maybe he could be of some help.
Viola, there, our
film is made, Nawab Saab.
Good morning sir.
- Good morning.
How is the chick at the reception,
Nawab Saab? - Stop it Sam!
Are you Sameer?
- Yes, sir.
Hi. Akash Sarin. Piya's cousin.
Ali.
- Sit down, sit down.
So tell me. What can I do for you?
Akash, just like you...
...we two graduated from the
institution... Err, I mean...
I mean...
- We've completed it, sir.
We've completed it, sir.
Yes, Riya has told me about it.
For the graduation
project we've decided to make...
...a film on 'Why not to join
the Indian defense forces? '
'Why not to join the
Indian defense forces? ' Yes.
I see. Interesting.
And Sir, we want you to share
your war experiences with us.
In a small interview sir.
Our film will be made, sir
- here write
Well, you know I've a
better idea than this interview.
Do you boys like adventure?
Any time, Sir!
Good. Come with me.
Excuse me.
Here, take these 3
letters to their addresses...
...and record your experience.
You'll get your film.
Sir, what's special
about these letters?
These are the last letters.
Last letters?
There is a tradition in
the Indian defense forces...
Every solider writes a
letter before leaving for war...
...which he keeps in his pocket.
If that soldier is
martyred the defense...
...force posts that
letter to his family.
That letter contains a few
last emotions of that soldier...
You two want to know why one
shouldn't join the army, right?
Meet these families...
You'll know it.
But sir, how did you
get these letters?
It's my 3 years old
research material.
Now it would be useful for you.
All the best.
- Thank you.
Good luck.
- Thank you. Bye.
Listen you guys.
You both are doing something
by your self for the first time.
Sometimes a little step
towards something takes...
...you to a lifelong path.
I hope this is it for you guys.
Let's go.
Day one. Track of turn.
We are out to look for
an answer to our question.
Whether one should
join Indian Army or not.
"Olla Signor.
- What's up, my bro?"
"Two friends have
left on a journey."
"The distance and
paths are nothing...
...when we are together."
"Olla Signor.
- What's up, my bro?"
"Two friends have
left on a journey."
"The distance and
paths are nothing...
...when we are together."
"We'll have fun on the go."
"The muddy roads...
...are welcoming us with open arms."
"And making some gestures."
"You didn't understand...
...small thing.
- What, pal?"
"The road says, keep moving on."
"We'll reach for the
sky as we're special."
"We've the license
to rock and roll."
"Listen." Hey...
signore! What's up, my bro?"
"Two friends have
left on a journey."
"The distance and
paths are nothing...
...when we are together.
We'll have fun on the go."
Hey!
Does anyone know
Kuljeet Kaur's house?
I know where you can
find Kuljeet Kaur.
Yourself?
Saand praji (elder
brother) -Nawab saab.
Easy, easy. Watch the potholes.
Gyani ji (learned grand father)
says our country will go very far.
But with such roads a
person remains there only.
How can the country move
forwards on these kind of roads.
Stop, stop!
There. That's Kuljeet Kaur.
Hey... Kuljeet!
Saand, camera.
Fool, you call your
mother by her name.
Have you any shame?
Mom... Shut up!
Where did you find
these sun glasses?
They are his, mom.
They were looking for you.
Greetings.
- Greetings.
We're students. We've come
here from Delhi to make a film.
We've brought this letter for you.
Can we record it?
Sure.
Thank you.
But the army could've posted it too.
Our acquaintances found some
letters in the records recently.
So we brought it.
We wanted to talk about
some other things as well.
Can we meet you later?
- Yes.
Where are you staying?
We'll find a hotel nearby.
On one hand you do
such a huge favor on me.
On the other hand you don't
even want to accept my gratitude.
Jassi tell them, guests in our
Punjab don't stay at hotels.
Come home.
Come. Come.
This is the fifth one. No more.
Gyani ji says, son, while
eating you shouldn't count.
Sons, here, have a
glass of buttermilk.
Everything will get digested.
Young man, you have some too.
Sons, when I was of your age.
I used to eat 10 such parathas
(Indian bread) just like that.
Isn't it, Lajo?
Oh forget it, you.
- Oh why should I forget it.
"Our Punjab oye."
"On top of that corn
bread and mustard goulash."
"When I sit in the field
I look like a royalty."
"Our Punjab oye."
Grand Father.
Father.
You're so old still you
want to dance like that.
At least think of your age.
Lajo, I'm a martyr's father.
I won't be defeated
by age or disease.
Jassi, go to sleep, son.
So soon?
If I give you one,
you won't ask for more. Go.
Go to sleep, son.
If you don't mind, can
we take some pictures?
Yes. Why not?
Dear, I was
thinking that this year...
...if we make a shed for
the cows it will be good.
The poor child is trying.
Father, as soon as the
installment of the tractor is paid...
...l'll collect money for the shed.
Jassi will be going to
higher school next year.
I'm saving the
pension money for that.
No problem, dear.
You always do the right thing.
You're the son of this family.
This grand father will give me
a real bad stomach upset, pal.
Stomach is already upset, pal.
There will be a toilet here, right?
- Definitely not.
I'm certain we've to go to
the fields in the morning.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
You both are not asleep yet.
If you need anything...
No. We're fine.
I've a request if you don't mind.
Nobody at home is really educated.
And I don't want Jassi to read it.
If you could read
this letter for me...
Of course, Why not?
My dear Kuljeet...
I'm fine.
I hope you all are fine too.
The weather is pleasant.
Everyone is awaiting the
glistening summer sunlight.
The nights are too cold here.
But we manage to go through
the nights with a born fire
The post is peaceful at the moment.
But even rare firing and
bombing keeps us alert.
Kuljeet, when I
return home this time...
...l'll take you and Jassi on a trip.
You know, a few
days back I was posted...
...on a hill top near a river.
There along with my comrades
I've learnt a way of fishing.
Catching fish with your bare hands
has a different charm all together.
Folding your pants and getting
knee-deep into icy cold water.
In a few moments
everything goes numb.
Then we put our hands
into the freezing waters.
You can't feel a thing
except the slithering of...
...a fish passing from
in between your hands...
...and with that
your hands start to...
...shake automatically,
instantly you grab the fish.
I'll surely want to teach
this technique to Jassi.
I want to see you all real soon.
I keep hearing Jassi's laughter.
Tell father we'll get him
operated as soon as I'm back.
That was already done last year.
Didn't he write anything else?
Yes.
- Kuljeet, I love you very much.
I miss you a lot.
That's why I want to
reach you before this letter.
And I'll reach there for you.
You take care of everyone.
Take care of yourself too.
Your Balkar Singh. AC 159838.
Sand praji, get up.
Nawab Saab, get up... fast.
Get up. The Villagers
are here to meet you.
Get up fast.
Villagers?
It looks like the
whole village is here.
Get up!
He is still sleeping.
Yes, friend! Just go and check out...
They are not from the TV channel.
Listen to us too.
Hear us, brother. Let us meet them.
- I can't let you meet them.
Uncle, please let us meet them.
Let us meet them.
The TV crew is there.
Listen to us. They
didn't let us meet you.
I said they're not TV crew.
Son, are you a TV crew?
I'm just a cameraman.
He's the director.
Oh the director! Director's here!
Oh... son, so you're the
TV crew. Come with me.
Sit here. Sit.
- Come on.
Sit. You too sit here
next to the director.
Sit. Sit.
- Focus the camera here.
Come on, click a snap.
Is it live? Live? Here.
Son, there is serious
water problem in our town.
Wife, turn on the TV quickly.
I'm on TV.
Everyone is watching, Everyone.
It's live.
Greetings. Is
everything fine in Canada?
Bansi, you've not sent my CD player.
Send a bottle of Black Label too.
And video games for Chhotu.
Brother, shoot me too.
Sir, tell your
government to ban his liquor.
Heard, father?
He drinks liquor during
happiness and in sorrow.
Now you say.
Aunt, we just came to
know about Balkar Singh.
Wife, I'll call later.
Ask me about Balkar Singh, sir.
He was a friend of friends.
He single-handedly taught
a lesson to the enemies.
Balkar Singh is the
pride of our town.
No one in this town is as
brave as our Balkar Singh, son.
Ok, sir. Greetings.
Bye.
Do come home.
We'll talk a lot about Balkar.
Come, brothers.
Greetings.
- Greetings.
Bye, child.
Son Jassi, the tractor is stuck.
I'll just get it out, mom.
Jassi, can we come too?
To get the tractor out?
Yes. This
bare-dude likes dare, dude.
Ok, come.
Hey Saand!
Bring it here!
Saand praji!
- Yes.
'S' is for Superman, right?
- Oh shut up.
'S' for Saand (bull)!
Apply some more strength,
try harder! See this
Very good Saand. 'S' for Supermen?
No 'S' for Saand.
Oh! Forget it!
Now push!
Come on Jassi!
Push!
- It is out! Come on, push!
Apply more strength!
Push harder!
Jassi, couldn't
you tell us earlier...
...We have to raise the
plough of the tractor?
I was testing.
- What?
How strong is the bull!
Naughty you!
Hey Jassi, you are an expert.
Very good Saand, Saand.
Saand, pull!
- I am pulling!
Let it loose! Let it loose!
Why don't you do it?
- No!
Take it closer!
Should I? Here you are!
Come on! Saand! C'mon!
Come on.
Cut it, cut it.
Take it closer!
Got you!
Rascal, you're cheating!
First you ask me to take it
closer and then you cut my kite!
I won't play with you!
You can't defeat me!
Wait! I'll get the kite back.
Nawab saab, stop! That's Pakistan!
Can a border look like this too?
Saand, check it out,
this is Pakistan buddy!
Saand, hurry, come fast!
What are you saying? It's
unbelievable! Looks the same!
Jassi look, our fields and
theirs are exactly the same!
It's not the same,
praji (elder brother).
You see this barb
wire separating them...
...Gyani ji (learned grand father)
says... this makes us very different.
Jassi, will you take
a photograph of ours?
Pass me the camera!
Jassi, let me take one of yours.
No, I'm fine.
Hey Jassi! Ever been across?
No. Papa had gone
and never came back.
But you shouldn't feel bad
because he was doing his job.
And they were doing theirs.
That's what Gyani ji says.
Come on, once more!
Hey Jassi! Wait!
Greetings, Mr. Gurjan Singh!
Greetings, aunt.
- Greetings!
Greetings, contractor.
- Is everything fine?
God is kind. How are you?
- I'm fine.
Greetings, contractor.
Greetings, Kuljeet.
Two installments of the
tractor have not been paid.
I did whatever I could.
I have to answer to my superiors.
- Contractor sir... - Dad!
Contractor sir, you won't have
to answer to anyone. - Good.
I'll take your leave.
Dear, I think the cows can spend
another monsoon without a shed.
Don't worry about it.
Listen!
I have a silver anklet.
It is of no use to me at this age.
I think we should sell it...
- Mom!
Dad, don't you trust me?
My child!
I'll pay the
installment with the money...
...I had saved for Jassi's schooling.
Neither will the cows
get wet in monsoon nor...
...the silver bracelet be sold.
We'd rather better our today
than be hopeful for a tomorrow.
Daughter, we never missed
Balkar while you're with us.
God bless you.
God bless you with
all the happiness.
Saand praji, papa and mom had
met for the first time right here.
Papa used to come
everyday to look at her.
And one day he spoke to her.
Have a look, dad!
"I had asked for this wish."
"If I attain you,
it will be heaven."
"I had asked for this wish."
"If I attain you,
it will be heaven."
"I have fallen in love
for the first time."
"Come into my heart as my beloved."
"I had asked for this wish."
"If I attain you,
it will be heaven."
Through out the day
boys are looking at her.
With how many of them
will her brother fight?
The girl has young enough now.
Think of her wedding!
I was thinking...
- I am young too! In two ways!
Hey.
- Greetings aunt! - Father.
Long live my son! Long live!
Where's Kuljeet?
I am sorry, son.
I didn't recognize you!
Everyone knew me in the village...
...now they since I went to taran
taran no one seems to recognize me.
Never mind! I've come to
marry your daughter, Kuljeet.
Who are you? You just
barge into the house.
Hey, hey! I am not unknown.
You know me.
I don't come to the Gurudwara
(Punjabi temple) to see you!
Our story is even
older than the Gurudwara!
Hey you!
- Just shut up! Sit down.
Look into your heart dear!
You'll find me only!
Dad, the boy has gone mad! Anyway...
I have already
selected my life partner.
Hey you! Another boy!
Tell her, she'll marry me only!
Shut up and get lost!
Oh! Kuljeet dear. wait
I went to Taran Taaran and...
...the people back in
village have all forgotten me!
Balkar.
Kuljeet, do you recognize him?
See this.
Do you remember I wore the
uniform in Gurudwara. Let's talk.
Shall I take it as confirmed, uncle?
Tell me.
Am I not handsome?
"Our love is accepted by God."
"Hence God has sent
us to this world."
"Ask your father, how is the boy?"
"My father laughingly
said the boy is very good."
"My heart aches for you."
"If I attain you,
it will be heaven."
"I have fallen in love
for the first time."
"Come into my heart as my beloved."
Listen! I'll sacrifice
many lives for you...
...but this life is for my country.
Do you accept?
If you do then eat it.
Feed me too.
"If we get married soon."
"I want two boys next year."
"I am with you in your wishes."
"I will obey your orders."
"Now I am finally able
to attain my wishes."
"If I attain you,
it will be heaven."
"I have fallen in love
for the first time."
"Come into my heart as my beloved."
What happened? You've
started throwing tantrums...
...as soon as we are married!
Don't go!
I have to go.
What shall I name our child?
Jassi! If it's a girl, Jasmeet.
If it's a boy, Jaswindar.
We'll call them both Jassi lovingly.
At least now give me a smile.
C'mon, hurry!
May God take care of you!
'One day father went off like this;
and only his memories returned.'
Today is the second
day of our journey.
The answer to the question is true.
One should not join the
Indian army. That's the truth.
The truth is a soldier
gets killed in a war.
And leaves behind a wife to
face all the troubles, all alone
Everyone wants to
sacrifice something or the other.
But only for a while.
Because problems will never end.
Problems will recur.
Bigger and stronger!
Balkar Singh was not just a soldier.
He was also a son, a
husband and a father.
Cut!
It's true Nawab saab, who will want
to join the army for such a life?
Jassi!
What are you doing?
Saand praji, give me a hand.
Wait.
Saand praji, pick me up!
What are you doing?
Papa's uniform was incomplete.
I am completing it.
I'll also join the
army like my papa.
Then who will take
care of your mother?
Mom takes care of everyone and
will take care of herself too.
I'll take care of my country...
...this is what papa used
to say. And I believe that!
Jassi!
Go to sleep.
You rest too. You have to
set out early tomorrow morning.
The path you had taken, now your
son is walking on the same path.
He wants to join the army.
I miss you a lot!
But it's ok.
I am just proud to be your widow.
I would sacrifice a
million lives for you.
Some snacks for the road.
No thanks.
Elders say, never refuse food.
Very good!
Thank you, all of you.
Goodbye!
- Goodbye!
Say goodbye to Jassi.
All right. Goodbye.
Saand praji, Nawab, stop!
Stop!
Saand! Nawab! Stop.
- Jassi?
Subtitles by LeapinLar