Begin the Turban Race!
Can't l worship with my
uncovered American head?
No, a turban is an essential
part of the ceremony.
You don't know anything!
Why don't you find yourself an lndian
bride to help you tie your pants?
They are noisy like children.
They have a right to enjoy today.
There's no use in
restricting their fun.
l'm talking about discipline.
You should be disciplined too.
What do you mean?
You're going to a music concert
during the Diwali festival.
How is the turban?
Amrita, when you fix my turban
my music becomes strong.
l'd be an average singer
without you.
Come home early today.
Why?
You should be here to talk
to your ltalian student.
Don't worry he knows many
languages including Hindi.
Did Nandini vacate her room
for the guest?
l had told her to,
but she became mad and left.
What's there to be mad about?
That's between you and your daughter.
l'll call her.
Where were you Nandini?
Are you still angry?
l went out to buy
this decoration.
But where will you put it?
You must vacate your room.
l'll never vacate my room!
lt's takes time to decorate my room and
l don't like strangers staying in it.
Why are you all after my room?
Because you have the best room.
We'll help you move out.
There's not much in your room,
flowers, a chandelier, a diary and...
lf you tease me l'll destroy
your floor decoration.
Where were you Nandini?
You know l don't go to any
concerts without seeing you.
Oh are you a statue? But you
can talk with your eyes.
Did you vacate your room?
You are still angry.
The visitor is our guest. And
a guest is like God to us.
Vacate your room before
my return.
The decoration is very pretty.
Let ltalian come, l'll make
him leave within two days.
l'm going to a big house dad.
No, l've not left mom like you.
No, l don't need your help.
l'll find my way.
The sand will show me the way.
You're happy to see your son
in distress.
But listen. l will succeed
and learn my music.
l'll live in lndia and
call mom in ltaly.
Do you realize you've slapped
me for the first time.
l am still going.
Why shouldn't l?
What's there?
Oh ltalian! Get lost, suffer
hunger, never reach my room.
What a jump! From ltaly into
the pool. How do you do?
Meet all of us. My brother
Neelesh. My wife Pushpa.
She is Parul, Shilpa,
Anapoorna, Haresh.
And he is my brother,recently
returned from America, Tarun.
Look at this boy's behaviour!
Oh don't worry.
His arrival has brought us laughter.
His departure will bring us tears.
And l'm Bhairav
What have you done to the
guest?
Forgive us. Let me take you
to your room.
Very jolly fellow.
We will have good time.
After eating Pushpa's dishes
he'll learn to speak Gujarati.
What's the purpose in inviting
him in this house?
What if he starts having an
affair with our young girls?
Auntie Kamna! Can't you talk
well about anybody?
Vithal Singh, who's that lady?
She is the mistress of the house.
Everybody listens to her judgment.
She has a very good heart.
You've come on very auspicious
day. Today is Diwali.
How was your journey. Have you
been swimming?
l just fell into the pool.
Vithal, show him to his room,
and give him breakfast.
l'm going to the temple.
l know, my husband says
the same thing.
What did you say?
The ltalian is here!
How are you?
Are you okay?
My name is Sameer. You may
call me Sam, out of love.
What's your name?
Nandini.
Can l call you Nandu?
Only Nandini.
Your name is different
Does it mean Nandita Ben?
A name need not have a meaning.
And you need not light every
candle while looking at me.
You move your eyes, first.
How can l? Your eyes have
hypnotized me.
Why would they do that?
Careful, you might burn your hand.
You were affected
by evil eyes.
Must be yours, my eyes are
not like that.
What are your eyes like?
They can look into your soul.
So, what do you see?
Lemon! Sour lemon.
Move your eyes Nandu,
you might lose the rope.
Let it be.
The chandelier will fall.
Let it fall.
Glass will break.
Let it break.
And if the glass breaks
your eyes will blink.
Let's see who blinks first.
lf you continue looking at me
you will fall in love.
Listen. Did you fall in love?
His stuff is showing.
Move from here.
Come on girls. Tell me what're
you whispering about?
Won't you tell me?
Nothing. That boy from ltaly.
They were looking at him.
So tell me. How does he look?
You have come here too.
l heard you laughing.
This is a home, not a park
that you just stroll through.
Grandma, l'm Sameer, l've come
from ltaly. How do you do?
Sameer - a cold gust of wind.
He is a hailstorm. He'll
infect us all with running noses.
You have no manners. Bathing
in the open, entering girls' room.
lf you want to live here
you must follow our rules.
Why are you so angry
Mandakini?
My name is Nandini
You took my room, now you're
enticing me with your sweet talk.
Tomorrow you will become
my father's favorite.
Have you come to learn music
or mischief?
You call yourself a singer,
but you look like a rogue.
He has made a mess of my room.
So disorganized.
Oh God! When will he go back?
What are you doing in my room?
This is my room you idiot.
Now this is my room and l
can walk naked like this.
l've come to pick up my diary.
You put on your clothes.
Oh diary. Get lost in desert
so you never reach my room...
Don't read my diary, stop now.
What have you done to my room?
Don't you think this room
looks livelier than before?
Nandini Ben, Darbar Sahib
wants to meet him.
Go, go quickly.
Have you come to eat or bathe?
Go and put on your clothes.
Oh. l went there in the towel.
We were coming to stop you,
but you did not hear.
Never mind, now to please father,
go and salute him like this...
She is not misguiding me?
No l will punish her for doing
that to our guest.
What are you doing?
Just saluting you sir.
Who told you to do this?
Go and sit there.
Hold on. Let him sing first.
Let him eat first.
He's hungry.
No. l'll decide right now.
He has come from ltaly. Let me
see if he is worth teaching.
Very good. You know music
and you also have a good soul.
By teaching you l might learn
something from you.
May l teach you now sir?
My music is everything to me.
Music is great like God.
You need purity of soul.
An insincere person sings from
the throat.
A hungry person from
the stomach.
But a truthful person sings
from his heart.
l will teach you because you
sing from your heart.
What about your fees sir?
My music is not for sale.
l will ask for compensation
at a proper time.
Or maybe l won't.
My father is very happy.
No l can't eat any more.
You've not eaten enough until
you belch like me.
You're young you must
eat more than 10-12 pooris...
This secret should remain
between us, please...
Grandma was right...
Sameer -like a gust of wind...
Why are you after me?
Are you thinking about me?
- Yes.
No.
No, you're thinking about me.
No. Why should l?
Then, who's in your thoughts?
l was thinking about myself.
What difference does it make.
Don't get involved in wishful
thinking. You'll get hurt.
What are you doing on the roof
so late in the night?
l often come here to hear
father's music with the stars.
Grandma says by changing their
paths, the stars change our destiny.
For me, the stars are my friends.
What if they went against you?
l would fight till they wrote
my destiny as l aspire.
Do you believe in destiny.
Sure. l can even read destiny.
Really? Read mine.
Palm reading is lndian style.
ltalians read the feet.
Your feet are very beautiful.
And they will soon take you aboard...
Are you ticklish? So am l.
They will take you aboard
to the love of your life.
Madras
Calcutta
Bihar
A falling star!
What did you ask for?
Nothing...
My mother says never ask
anything from a broken star.
You miss your mother?
Because she is very far.
And your father?
He is very near to me.
And your girl friend?
l don't have a girl friend.
Will you be my friend?
Women can't compete with men.
- No, both are equal.
What's the matter?
Tell them how men are
superior to women.
They're superior in many ways.
Tell us what men can do but
women can't do.
There are many things but l'll
give you one example.
Can you do this?
What're you doing here?
This is a women's only function.
l was attracted by the music.
Do you see any other man here?
- Yes Vithal...
Vithal has looked after us
childhood.
lf you are spotted, women
will beat you up. So go away.
You've songs for all occasion?
- Yes... from birth to death.
For all seasons, love songs
marriage songs, folk songs..
You have not seen Bhavai? Let
me show you...
What's that clapping song.
That song is called Garbha.
What else?
- Bhangra
Now you're joking.
May l tell you something?
- Yes.
l love your voice.
Only voice?
And...
Your hair.
- And?
Your smile.
Your style of describing
falling stars.
And? Say it quickly.
Your mom, your father, this food,
flowers, furniture.
You are just a lemon.
Even till the end, l didn't say it.
Why are you laughing.
You don't know!
The marriage procession has
arrived and you are not ready!
Get ready and check on Anu.
Sour Lemon!
l look better than you do.
Just see when l get dressed.
As if she is Miss World.
Are you ready Anu?
Give me a few minutes.
You must go with me Anu.
l can't live without you.
You don't know how l spent
last the six months without you.
l left to become capable of
asking your hand in marriage.
Now leave everything
and elope with me.
The procession is at the door,
and you want me to elope with you!
My parents will commit suicide
out of shame...
it's too late now. Go away.
What happened Anu?
- Nothing, l dropped a vase.
Some day we'll meet again Anu.
Thank God you opened the door.
What were you doing.
How do l look Nandini?
lt takes time to be a
first time bride.
Are you afraid?
- Little bit.
l am so happy for you Anu.
You get ready...
l want to see grandma.
You have no shame.
Nandini please listen.
- l don't want to hear you.
Why do you punish me?
l was just joking.
Do you want to hear what l
wanted to say last night?
l don't want to hear with so
many people around.
Leave me alone.
- Please let me tell you.
Open the door. How many times
should l ask your forgiveness.
l was mad for what you did
in front of so many people.
The ceremonies are starting.
Don't spoil the fun please.
Tell me what was in your mind.
l'm ready to listen now.
l was going to say that you do
not deserve my love.
Really? With so many guests
someone will approve of me.
And when he asks for my hand,
you'll repent Sour Lemon.
l arranged a meeting with
Nandini but l couldn't find you.
l'd be tongue-tied in front
of such a beautiful girl.
You could have told her
certain things with your eyes.
You must meet her.
What if she doesn't
approve of me.
She is fair you're dark, she
has blue eyes you've black,
she is popular and you can't
even sing in your bathroom.
But you have something special.
- What?
Your beautiful heart.
There's one thing more.
- What's that?
You're changing the topic.
Do you like Nandini or not?
l like her.
Then touch a hand for Nandini.
Touch one more time.
Sanyukta, no matter which hand
l touch, Nandini will be mine.
Anu got married. Nandini has
grown up.
Have you thought about Nandini?
- What's there to think about?
Touch one of my hands.
What's this childishness.
l knew you'd touch this hand.
There's a very good marriage
proposal for Nandini.
Vikramjit the lawyer, has sought
Nandini's hand for Vanraj.
Boy and family are good.
On Holi we'll go their town,
visit their home and
give our consent.
What do you say?
A daughter has to
leave one day.
Does he sing?
You never think about
anything except music...
yes he sings, but he is not
melodious.
Look at Nandini's picture. She
spoiled the family portrait.
All are looking at the camera,
she seems to have a bad cold.
Sameer why do ltalians
eat pizza?
Because we don't have grandma's
favorite Gujarati dishes.
Sameer you always say
something very sweet.
Because he's a sweet boy.
What happened? Don't like the
food. Nandini cooked it.
lt's hot.
Hot food is for hot girls -
not for sweet stupid boys.
Well said Nandini.
What an insane thing to do.
Stop Sameer. Leave it.
Why do you torture him?
What happened?
Sameer ate lot of chilies.
His mouth must be burning.
Give him some honey.
Go and ask his forgiveness.
He has eaten chilies. He will
see its reaction in morning.
lt's the prize of love...
and my deserved punishment.
Mommy! Wouldn't it be wonderful
to fly like a kite in the sky.
A daughter is like a kite. She flies
freely above the roof before marriage,
and then gives control to someone
else after her marriage.
As happened to Anu, and now it
is Nandini's turn.
Not so soon.
No use pretending...
you're so fond of flying, why
don't you get married sooner?
What's it to you, Auntie? l'll
get married when l want to.
Will you decide about your
own marriage?
Yes it will be my decision.
You are behaving as if l don't
know anything...
l keep my eyes open on
all your flights.
You have to live with your own
destiny. Some kites fly high
in the sky, others don't leave
the ground... like you.
Nandini, don't talk to
your elders like this.
Seek her forgiveness
Forgive her Kamna.
- lt's okay. She is a child.
We are talking to a very good
family about her marriage...
lf the horoscopes match we'll
soon finalize her marriage.
Her mother's matching her horoscope
and she is romancing in sky.
Wouldn't it be fun if her kite
was lost in the sky?
Leave it Kamna.
Nandini, l defeated your father
in the kite flying race.
lt would have been fun if you
were holding my thread-wheel.
l neither like paper toys nor
holding wheels for your kites.
One day someone will steal me
from you right under your nose
and you won't do anything
except stare at the sky.
l'll do everything!
l will break him,
beat him, destroy him.
Do you have any idea how much
ridicule l've suffered.
Break him, beat him...
always joking, always immature
They are after my marriage.
People will come to see me..
ask me to demonstrate how l walk...
how l sit, sing, laugh and...
l'll have to do it,
but you won't do anything.
You'll just keep
looking from a corner.
You won't care if they approve
and take me away from you,
you won't care...
if l go to someone else...
if l am married to someone else...
...if l die.
l'll talk to your father.
How can you tell to my father
what you have not told me so far?
Don't Sameer. lt's a sin.
lt's not a sin.
What if something happened?
Like what?
A child.
A child won't come like this.
lt's not right Sameer.
Father will never agree.
Why won't he agree?
lsn't this sinful?
No, it's not sinful.
You won't leave me?
- Never.
There is someone here.
Where are you going?
- l must leave.
Where is the bloody book.
Why are you here Kamna auntie?
l wanted to read a book.
Which one?
What're you doing here?
Didn't you go kite flying?
lt was so enjoyable.
l was arranging my books.
- First arrange your dress.
Keep to your affairs, Auntie.
Don't interfere in my life.
l've given you a long rope,
you'll fall flat if l pull it.
Found it? How is this book.
lt's in English
So what.
l'm even ready to learn ltalian.
The horoscopes match completely.
Congratulations Darbar.
Did the horoscopes match?
- Yes. All 36 qualities match.
l knew it.
- Give the sweets to everyone.
Wait! Let me give one to the man
whose marriage has been arranged.
Hold on. You can't be our son-
in-law by matching horoscopes.
You are marrying a musician's
daughter. We want to make sure
you would be in tune with her.
We want to hear you sing.
You want me to sing?
He must pass this test.
Let him hear. We will test
Nandini's courtroom skills.
Enough. You lack melody and
rhythm. Nandini will fix that.
Your voice has sincerity.
You'll make my daughter happy.
Sky is full of stars, grandma.
Looks like a thousand lovers are
holding lights in their hands.
Light is within the lovers.
How do you know this grandma?
- Love told me.
You too have been in love?
Love colors everybody.
Doesn't spare anybody.
Did you have a love marriage?
First marriage, then love.
How did it happen grandma?
l married at age 1 4. l was
combing my hair on the roof.
Your grandpa was flying a kite
on the adjacent roof.
He slipped from the roof.
l ran to his rescue.
He was hanging from the balcony.
l gave him my hand.
As he touched it, currents
passed through my body.
Then?
- Our eyes met. Love sprang.
He kissed, my first kiss.
Then you became a mother.
You stupid girl. Kissing
doesn't make you a mother.
Then?
- Then life began with kids.
- Home filled with happiness.
Then?
- Our children got married...
dancing, singing, functions.
- Then?
You came, and came laughter
and lullabies for you kids
your quarrels and friendships
Then?
- Then nothing.
- Then after 60 years, two
lovers met on this same roof
and then grandma
caught them red-handed.
Your father has always desired
a musician husband for you.
You would have the same dream.
l want to discuss it with you.
l too want to tell you
something. May l tell you?
Okay, you tell me first.
First you promise you won't be
angry after hearing me.
Angry? But why?
What's the matter?
ln fact l wanted to tell you...
Anu has come from her in-laws
home. She is very distressed.
Come quickly!
Listen Anu, you must return
to your in-laws' home.
No father, l'll never go back to
that house.
Anu you must forget Bharat and
go back to your in-laws.
l'll kill myself but l'll
never go back to that house...
l'll never spend another night
as a corpse in that man's bed.
A daughter's marriage takes
place by her father's will.
Traditionally, her husband is
her God after her marriage...
Anu must return to her home
after the Holi festival..
No! Turn back this shameless
girl today. l can't stand her.
Beating a grown up daughter is
against our tradition.
By Holi things will cool down.
Fatherdy, Anu will never be happy
in that house.
See how badly she was beaten.
Don't interfere in the
decisions of your elders.
At least ask the person whose
life is at stake.
How can she live with a man
she doesn't even love?
Leave!
Sameer has arranged everything
and Bharat is waiting for you.
Why are you giving
me all this?
ls this right? Family
disgrace?
What if something happens to Bharat?
- What you're doing is right.
You must live your own life.
ls everything arranged.
- Yes Bharat is waiting.
Hi. You are not afraid? l am afraid.
l am afraid of Nandini's father.
Anu will be happy. We've done
a great job of uniting them.
lt was so romantic. May we
marry by eloping to ltaly?
Why should we elope? You
will ask for my hand from my father.
Who is responsible for this.
Where's Anu?
Tell me. l'll kill you.
Why are you beating him?
You're responsible for this.
- What are you talking about?
l asked you to return
her quickly, you didn't agree...
Anu has eloped with someone else.
See the mangalsutra and this note.
She spitted on us and stains
have fallen on your face too.
Keep your voice down.
Because you are the elder you
can't bear it when others speak.
By what right you do force your
decision on us.
Why should we suffer
for your mistakes?
lt's your fault. You did not
teach our family's traditions
to your children and now you
are insulting me.
l'm not insulting you.
You'll know my suffering when
Nandini elopes with someone.
Stop, you have said enough.
Before blaming others you must
take care of your own home.
When you find out what your
daughter has been doing,
your head will fall in shame.
- Shut up!
l'll not tolerate any nonsense
spoken about Nandini.
She is my faith, she is my teacher,
she is as pure as my music.
My music will die if she is
found to be impure...
l'll never sing thereafter.
lf you have that much faith
call her. See what's truth.
Nandini ... Nandini ...!
How can she hear you
if she is not home?
Go out and hear her tunes.
With the first step we'll vow
to share happiness and pain.
With the second you'll vow
to protect my life and honor,
and you will give me
love and respect.
During the fourth step, l will
ask to go ahead of you.
Why?
- So if death comes l can
embrace it before you do.
We'll embrace death together.
l did not expect it from you.
What have you done to us?
lt has been going on for eight
months and nobody knew it?
You did not confide in me!
l will hate you for that.
- People become mad in love
Never thought he will do this.
- Now l feel that madness...
can't remember the moment
when l started loving him...
Nobody has the choice to love
in this household.
There are certain traditions
of our dynasty...
people respect your father
you bowed his head in shame.
How do you think he will
tolerate this pain.
We lifted our heads to
look at the stars...
that brief moment turned
into such deep relationship...
Sameer says father loves him.
He'll surely agree mom
How will he agree to a
relationship with a foreigner
about whom we know nothing?
Your marriage to Vanraj has
been decided.
We have matched
your horoscopes.
While explaining Hindu marriage
rites when we took seven steps
it appeared whole universe
was celebrating our union.
Seven steps? Marriage rites?
Have you crossed boundaries?
Have you done something for
which we should be ashamed?
Tell me Nandini... has he
touched you anywhere?
Here...
and here...
and here mom...
Stop Nandini... l can't bear.
he has touched my soul, his
eyes watch me from inside..
don't break me in two parts,
l will be dead without him...
l only belong to him...
l love him too much mom...
make father agree to
our marriage.
Control your emotions and
listen Nandini... l will try
to persuade your father,
don't move until l come back.
l have abandoned my music,
l've nothing more to teach you.
Why are you punishing yourself
for our mistakes?
l've done nothing wrong. l've come
to seek Nandini's hand.
lt is time for compensation.
On the oath of the knowledge
l've given you, you will promise
to neither meet Nandini
nor keep any relation with her.
This is my compensation.
Can l see Nandini one
last time?
Sameer is going Nandini!
Your father didn't agree...
he won't listen to me.