Who am I to you?
My eyes are restless!
T'is the effect of love!
Can't be mum, all I can say is that..
..who am I to you?
Who am I to you?
I had to restrain myself, my love.
Ultimately, I had to say it.
In my dreams.. why do you come?
Who am I to you?
My eyes are restless!
T'is the effect of love.
I'm sort of lost..
please don't ask me..
..who am I to you?
Who am I to you?
How should I tell you
the feelings in my heart?
Try to read my face sometimes.
You may call it my shyness!
Who am I to you?
We welcome all
the spectators to ' Prem Nivas'.
Greetings to one and
all from Laloo Prasad.
The match is about to begin
in a short while from now.
I will be giving
the live commentary.
The sky is absolutely clear..
there are a few clouds.
The umpire has inspected the pitch
and is about to take his place.
The batsman is ready.
Fielders, be on the alert.
Presenting to you, one who bowls
at a speed faster than the wind!
I will hit him for a 6 off
the first ball itself.
Should I hit him for a 4 or a 6?
Hey Laloo, you are always out
to the first ball!
I just gave the bowler a chance.
It's your turn to bat.
No, it's my turn. I will play too.
You must be aware as to what
happened when Rita last came to bat.
She broke her legs.
Prem will coach me this time.
Won't you, Prem?
Will I coach you?
Go and field on the boundary line.
You always ask me to field.
It's similar to what you've been
doing to hook Prem for all these years.
You will field while Prem will bat.
You will go and bowl.
Kapil Dev, come to my rescue!
Protect yourself from my attack,
Prem.
Here comes Laloo with his googly.
Rita, catch the ball.
I' m dead. I'm dead.
- Don't utter inauspicious things.
My back is broken.
I'm sorry. - You fool,
what are you doing here?
Auntie, she had come here to
Iearn to play cricket.
This game of cricket is
becoming a nuisance.
Kids will always play! - Quiet.
Greetings auntie.
How many times have I told you
not to call me auntie?
Not only humans but dogs too
are pampered here in this house.
What are you staring at me?
Come with me.
I'm dead! - Uncle
why is auntie in such a 'haste?
She's come to talk to your
uncle about Rajesh's wedding.
Honestly speaking, Rajesh is worth
every good word spoken about him!
Not only me but everybody is
of the same opinion.
It's not a joke to manage this
big business at this young age!
What do you say? - Perfect.
You have to think
about his wedding now.
Tell me if you know
of some good girl.
I have seen the girl. - Is that so?
You have met my brother from Delhi,
Rita's dad, haven't you? - Yes.
I was referring to his elder daughter,
that's Rita's elder sister, Sweetie.
Sweetie has always been with him
in Delhi and Rita's been with me.
Sweetie is a very beautiful,
understanding and decent girl!
Isn't that so? - Yes.
She's failed in B.A.
She thinks in terms of
the present generation.
She's already had a couple of
broken engagements. Isn't that so?
So what? Think about the big family.
Their business is worth millions.
The wedding will be a pompous one.
She'll bring along something
worthwhile as dowry too.
But you won't understand
these norms of life!
After all, you are a professor
at the college.
If you agree, I will inform
my brother accordingly.
Rita, it's time for our
kitty party. Let's go.
We're leaving. - Thanks.
- What did you say? - Nothing.
I'll leave, brother. - So long then.
Come on. You're quite a hog.
Wealth is all that she thinks of!
We don't want her
rich brother's daughter.
What we want is a down-to-earth
and a lovely daughter-in-law!
One who will bless this house
with her love and care!
You have brought up this house
with so much love!
Rajesh and Prem were so small
when sister and her husband died.
You abandoned your studies too
to look after these children.
You started off with a small job.
For their future, you only thought
of hard work as your goal.
You didn't marry too!
You've brought up these children
with such good values!
That's the reason
for Rajesh's success.
Prem too has stood first at
the MBA exams this year.
Brother, I have seen
a girl for Rajesh.
Sometimes back, I had gone to
Poona for a conference.
I met Professor S. S. Chowdhury
over there.
Would that be Prof. Siddharth
Chowdhury? - Do you know him?
We've studied at the same college.
We were very good friends.
I met his elder daughter
over there.
Just saw her for once, and she's
made a home for herself in my heart!
I liked her so much that
I brought her photograph too.
Her name is Pooja. She's passed
B.A. Very sweet in nature!
They'll make a good pair.
- I agree.
Professor has gone on a pilgrimage
with his family to Ramtekdi.
As soon as he returns, we'll pay him
a visit. It's just a trip of 3-4 hours.
All that's required is for them to like
each other. - That's the main problem.
Whenever I talk about marriage
to Rajesh, he ignores it.
How can we make the two of them meet?
There is a way. Why don't we
go to Ramtekdi too?
It would be a combination of
a holiday and a pilgrimage.
And also the selection
of sister-in-law.
But brother shouldn't be aware of
this plan. Everyone should be alert.
Big brother is here.
Come on, uncle.
So you're back, Rajesh. You're
meeting took a long time today!
What did the foreign collaborators say?
We had a detailed discussion.
They'll study our report now.
Uncle, if everything works
out properly..
..like you said, this factory will be
the first of it's kind in this country!
Prem, your brother is setting up
such a big factory to launch you.
Big brother, the food is ready.
Hey, there's a feast out here!
Is it some special occasion?
Actually, big brother.. - Well,
we all are very happy today. - Happy?
Well, big brother, we have decided
to go to Ramtekdi for our holidays.
Ramtekdi? But uncle, you were
insisting on going to a hill station.
Ramtekdi is a very holy place.
My uncle and aunt go there every year.
They make vows too!
- The program is fixed.
This time we'll take that new
dress of yours too.
Why is it needed over there?
- Why not?..
What did he say uncle?
- I didn't hear.
We don't interfere in such matters.
Chameli, let's get some food.
That's amazing.
Nobody is telling me anything.
What should we tell you brother..
as to what we will get at Ramtekdi.
Be quick dad.
Mom will be mad if she catches you
at this experiment in the kitchen
Let her be angry.
I'm not afraid of her.
If she notices these sweets
she'll be tempted to break her f!ast.
Are you listening? - What is it?
- It's not me but mom.
Who broke the jar? - What?
- Who broke the jar?
Pooja, when Lord Ram
broke Lord Shiv's bow..
..Lord Shiv very angrily asked as
to who had broken the bow.
Lord Ram, with all simplicity
and love replied..
Have some shame. We've got two grown
up girls. What will they think?
What will they think? Did I say
something wrong, my love?
I didn't say anything wrong.
I was just..
It's difficult for both of us
to win against you.
If anyone can win against you,
it will be.. Nisha.
Good morning, manager uncle.
Devil! You always come
like an express train!
Papa has sent the books from
the library and has said thanks.
Brother, your bill? - Here's your
bill. You remove the books.
Nisha child, will you do
me a small favor?
Will you add this up by the time
we come back from the storeroom?
Don't indulge in any mischief.
Come on now. What are you staring?
Is this Ram Narayan guesthouse?
Didn't you read the board outside?..
where was I?
What is it? - Can you tell me
which room Prof. Chowdhury is in?
Why? - Well.. I had some work.
I understood. - What? - Stand up.
Stand up. You people don't study
all the year round.
Don't study at all and then
panic at the time of exams.
You've come here to
enhance your marks.
You better change
the number of your glasses.
Wonder what you think of yourself
after sitting on the manager's chair?
Well.. - Nisha. - Oh God!
I' m over here, sister.
You're sitting here! Mom is
waiting for you out there.
What were you doing? - Well,
I was.. I was..
Welcome. - Uncle, you proceed
while I keep the baggage.
You were asking for
Prof. Chowdhury, right?
These are his daughters,
Pooja and Nisha.
Pooja child, he is Mr. Kailashnath.
He's your dad's pal.
Greetings. - Greetings.
He wants to meet the professor.
- Please come.
Take this. I've calculated it.
You've calculated it. That's great.
Here's your reward.
Manager, you please recalculate.
People say that beautiful girls
are always wrong at calculating.
What did you say? - Do you
eat chocolates, Miss Nisha.
Don't mention my name.
These sweets taste great, professor.
Have it with this 'chutney' and you
will forget the famous 'Mathura sweets'.
My younger nephew, Prem.
- May you live long, child.
Your uncle has lost a bet.
- Which one?
He had said that only I would go
bald but he has lost his hair too.
Have a look at who has come over.
Greetings. Did you recognize?
- How are you?
He has to be fine. After all he's
one of the top industrialists!
Come and have a seat.
Truly, whenever I read about you in
the papers, I feel very proud!
Prem, you may not be aware about
the history of the three of us.
We were in college together and
we had a lot of fun.
Keep it here.
You've already met my daughters,
right? - Yes.
Do you come here every year?
I've come this year with
a very special mission.
I'd like my nephew Rajesh to get
married to your elder daughter.
That's if you don't
have any objections.
Objection? What are you talking?
After all, he's your nephew!
Rajesh has come with us. You meet him.
Go and call brother.
Go right ahead.
Thanks. - Professor
I should be thanking y'ou.
God has given me everything!
The love of these children..
..a big business empire..
but the house seems barren!
Rajesh has had his share
of motherly love..
..but Prem has been deprived
of that love.
Come on brother. Come in Rajesh.
The Professor.. and his wife.
Have a seat, child.
Apart from your work,
what are your other hobbies?
Brother paints very well.
Isn't that right, brother?
Is that so? - Just a little bit.
Pooja paints well too,
isn't that so?
Yes dad. - Show Rajesh that painting
of the temple that you're doing.
Brother, let's go and see the
painting. We'll just be back, uncle.
Come on brother, let's have
a look at the painting.
Where are you going?
- How does it concern you?
You let them talk.
You can talk to me.
What should I talk to you? - Why?
Are you still angry with me?
Don't mention my name.
It's a very nice painting!
You paint too. Don't you?
I do paint but..
not something so beautiful!
Give it to me.
Brother, did you like the painting?
I've been noticing since afternoon.
You've been asking me the same
question every 15 minutes.
What's the matter?
Well, I will go and get
you some nice tea.
Wait.
Tell me, what is the truth.
Promise me that you won't scold me
nor will you beat me.
It's a promise. - Did you
like the painting? - Yes.
Did you like the colors of
the painting? - Yes.
Did you like the one
who did the painting?
That's great. We had brought you
here to hear this. Congrats.
Uncle. - You wait.
Uncle, brother's life is made.
Greetings, priest.
Bhabhi, save me.
You're great Lord..
what a pair you have created!
Congratulations to my
brother and bhabhi!
More than any other
ritual in this world..
..the relation of hearts
is the most important!
Thanks to you, this event has
seen the light of the day.
Congratulations to my sister
and brother-in-law!
More than any other ritual
in this world..
..the relation of hearts is
the most important!
You're great Lord!..
You're great Lord!
My brother,
who is sitting so quietly.
Bhabhi, have a look at
his stubborn posture.
But, he is a very good guy.
He is a very good guy
but a bit naughty.
You're the only one that
he has fallen for!
My sister is acting tough now!
Congratulations to my
brother and bhabhi!
More than any other ritual
in this world..
..the relation of hearts
is the most important!
You're great, Lord!
Brother-in-law, for your sake..
..my sister has prayed a lot!
She's been to the temples..
she's been to the temples..
..prayed day and night!
She's been invoking
Almighty all the time.
I've got a bhabhi as
I had desired!
Congratulations to my sister
and brother-in-law!
More than any other
ritual in this world..
..the relation of hearts
is the most important!
You're great, Lord!
That's a nice garland
you've brought, Tuffy.
Tuffy too knows that this evening,
folks from brother's in-law's place..
..are coming with
the ritual offerings.
There shouldn't be anything amiss
in welcoming them. Right, Tuffy?
Big brother, is she coming too?
- I'll just be back, uncle.
What happened?
- You' re always the fool!
Uncle, does the girl come
over before wedding?
How do I know?
We aren't married as yet.
You are needed desperately
down here in the hall.
The doctor has come too.
Let him come.
I'll take care of him.
Greetings, doctor. - Greetings.
What's the matter?
Why are you so angry?
Are you asking me?
You ask him that question.
He confirmed Rajesh's marriage,
chose the daughter-in-law.
I get the news today.
What is it?.. I don't want it.
I'm very angry today.
I won't eat nor drink today.
I'm leaving. Congratulations.
Goodbye. Move aside.
The photo of my daughter-in-law
is on the table.
How did you like daughter-in-law?
Her simplicity reminds me of a poem.
Sit down. Doctor will recite a poem.
It goes something like this..
- Wow, wow..
Let me start the poem.
I've turned into a photo
after looking at the photo..
I've turned into a photo after
Iooking at the photo..
..I'm so jealous of
my friend's good fortune.
Have a look. He told me that
he is very angry.
Told me not to talk to anyone.
One look at daughter-in-law's
photo and your anger vanished!
Welcome, bhabhi.
I can understand that you
are a heart specialist..
..and bhabhi is a child specialist.
What I can't understand is this
combination of a doctor and a poet.
That's something he has taken
to very seriously.
Uncle, why do you indulge in poetry?
Poetry in its truest form is
always in front of you!
What did you say? What did you say?
Did you hear that? This younger
one talks a lot these days.
Shall we get you too married
along with your brother?
Auntie, why delay something good?
- Shameless.
I heard doctor auntie's talks.
It's your turn to search for a bride.
I' m just coming.
Somebody is calling me.
Whenever I want to talk to you,
somebody always calls for you.
But I know very well how to
win over your heart.
The formula to make sweets
in half an hour.
First of all, the utensil..
where's it?
Stupid, I'm hurt.
How could I know that you
were standing here?
Ouiet. Give me the utensil.
By the way, baby,
what are you doing here?
I'm making sweets.
- So you're making sweets for Prem!
Are you making it as per this book?
Just answer whatever I ask of you.
Where's the 'Suji'?
- It's over there.
'Ghee'? - Right next to it.
Sugar? - In that jar.
Baby, you are..
What happened? - She brought
salt instead of sugar.
Why don't you tell her? - Let it
be. She called me stupid.
Congratulations, brother.
The news of Rajesh's engagement
has gladdened my heart.
I've just been to the temple
to offer my prayers.
She's coming from the beauty parlor.
What happened?
I've heard that daughter-in-law's
dad is a professor at college.
In that case, there must not
have been any talks of dowry.
He must be like him
a simpleton all his lif'é.
Don't say that.
He's from a very big family.
But he is his friend. Whatever
he gives has to be accepted.
If my Sweetie were to come,
she would have brought a lot.
So much that the safe wouldn't be
able to accommodate everything.
My Rajesh is worth millions!
Something worth millions is
being made.. Sweets!
Rita baby is making it.
- Is baby making it?
Will you taste it? - Give me some.
Baby, is the sweet ready? - Yes.
I've praised your sweet
a lot outside.
Your aunt wants to die..
I mean taste it.
I'll just go and give it.
Baby, you've learnt a lot.
Auntie, eat with this big spoon.
Baby has made it.
Have it.
What happened?
- Auntie liked the sweet a lot.
Have all of this, auntie.
Is this what you call sweet?
It's full of salt.
Salt? - Yes. It's very bitter.
My dear, it's your tongue
that's bitter.
What did you say? - Nothing.
The girl's family is about to come.
You wipe your face.
Move aside with your sweet. - Rita,
you won't be able to make this sweet.
If I can't make the sweet for you,
who will?
Greetings. Please come.
May you live long, son.
How are you?
Are you studying computers? Wow.
Nisha, Laloo and Chameli have
come to meet you.
Meet him too, he happens to be the
most loved member of this family.
Brother-in-law. You show us your
paintings. - Definitely, come.
Rajesh, please come here, dear.
This father-in-law of yours
is a very interesting person.
I'll just be there. Prem, you
please show Nisha the paintings.
Brother-in-law is truly great.
I'll show you the most beautiful
painting done by my brother. Please come.
How do you find it?
Do you know to play the
instrument or are you just posing?
People tell me that
I play very well.
You may make a decision
when you hear it.
I almost forgot. Sister has sent
this gift for you. - Bhabhi sent it?
I told her that it wasn't necessary.
Open it.
Put it on your coat. It will make a
good impression on your girlfriends.
Please help me put it.
Move aside.
Did that prick?
So, just like that? - I would
have felt this way if it had pricked.
What happened?
- This time, it pricked.
When it pricks, it feels this way.
You two are wanted downstairs.
It's time for
the religious ceremony.
Shall we go in Nisha?
It's time for the relation
to be confirmed.
Kailashnath.. Rajesh is ours now.
Come and give me a hug.
Henceforth I won't be in demand.
Why? - Well, I'm from the girl's side.
I have to bow down!
We won't spare you two by
just hugging each other.
What then? - We will have some
song and dance now.
Get the musical instruments.
The party is on but who will
put life into it?
Shall I tell? It's a day of the
in-laws. One sing and the other dance.
Dear in-law, sing something for us.
- Me? - Yes.
I don't have that charm.
You're the charming one!
Shall I reveal your secret? - No.
You've done it to me so many times
when I was young? - Ouiet.
I refer to the time when we
three used to study together.
His uncle, me and my wife.
Her smile is beyond
compare even today.
There was a time when everyone
was dying for one look.
I'll just be back.
- Where are you going?
Among the ones crazy about her
smile was your loving uncle too!
Uncle, you?
Don't lie. Don't lie.
Sing something for the sake of
your shyness and her smile.
Rajesh, you please tell
your father-in-law.
Why don't you request him on my
behalf. It will make a difference.
Please sing something.
There's this strange
conflict in my heart today.
I'm singing and my in-law
is in front of me.
I'd like to say something
that is on her heart too.
I'm singing and my in-law
is in front of me.
The earrings on her ears look
like the moon and the sun!
The earrings on the ears look
This ' Banarasi' sari
Iooks great too!
I'll tell you a secret..
I'll tell you a secret.
My in-law is tickled even today
when her anklets make a noise.
It's a secret.. he is tickled even
today when her anklets make a noise.
The smile on her lips..
the shyness of her eyes!
Such innocence is a boon!
I'll tell you a secret..
I'll tell you a secret.
My in-law is truly blessed! She is
like 'Laxmi' the goddess of wealth..
..who has transformed this
house into heaven!
My in-law is truly blessed! She is
like 'Laxmi' the goddess of wealth..
..who has transformed this
house into heaven!
There's this strange conflict
in my heart today.
I'm singing and my in-law
is in front of me.
What I have to live up to is
a very delicate relationship!
I'm singing and my in-law
is in front of me.
She's my shade who's moving
into your house.
She's lived like a dream
on my eyelids!
I'll tell you a secret..
I'll tell you a secret.
This life time earnings of mine..
..is the brilliance of your
Iawn henceforth.
It's a secret, this life time
earnings of mine..
..is the brilliance of
your lawn henceforth.
It's a secret, this life time
earnings of mine..
..is the brilliance of
your lawn henceforth.
It seems that my sister will
die of hunger over here!
Why? - Have a look, my brother-in-law
isn't eating anything.
Take this, you feed him yourself.
Open your mouth.
If you feed him everything over here,
what will you do for the wedding?
You'll come to know about our
hospitality when you come over.
You'll come, won't you?
- I'll definitely come.
When I come, there'll be
fireworks all around.
Bring it here.
What is it? - Please do us a favor.
Please have a seat here.
I'm very busy Nisha, the marriage
procession is about to come.
If you do our work, I will tell your
mom to choose a nice bride for you.
All right then. Here I go.
Sorry brother.
Nisha, will you make your
brother-in-law sit here?
He'll be sitting there. This seat
is for his brother and his friends.
Let them too know
about our hospitality.
I'll do the introductions.
Uncle, can I have a group photograph.
- Why not?
He's Bhola Prasad.
The son of my wife's brother.
Bhola is doing research on
the works of Kalidas' Shakuntala.
By the way, he's on the look out
for a Shakuntala of his own too.
Let us click the photograph.
The stairs will be a nice place.
Come on.
It's perfume!
Come, brother-in-law.
- Where are you taking him?
He'll sit with us.
They all want to meet him.
He's your brother-in-law!
Take him.
You'll come too. - We too?
We have to take care of you too!
I smell a rat, brother.
- I like a challenge.
Let's check it out. Friends
we'll be back soon.
Escuse me. - What is it?
- You please don't go there.
Why? - There's danger over there.
- Danger?
Please have a seat, brother-in-law.
You'll have a seat too.
- Should we sit over here?
Come brother, come. Come fast.
Please sit down. There won't be
a noise when you sit down.
What did you say? - Nothing.
Wait. I'd like to investigate.
Is everything all right? - Yes,
everything is all right.
Please sit. - Yes, we will sit
but there is a condition.
You all will sit first.
That's not done. You are the guest.
You please sit down.
What's the matter, Prem? - Brother
one needs to be very cautious..
..wherever your loving
sister-in-laws are present..
I'll just be back, brother-in-law.
- Excuse me.
Before you leave, please show me
the place where I can sit.
Please come. I will give you
the most special seat.
Don't feel shy. Please come.
You go and sit there. On top of it.
What happened?
What news have you brought?
They've kept brother-in-law's shoes
in a red and yellow sweet box.
Sister, why are we stealing
the shoes? It's bad to steal.
This is a tradition. We'll get cash
from brother-in-law for the shoes.
The red and yellow sweet box.
The fun starts now.
Nobody will doubt that
we have hidden the shoes here.
Be quiet. We have a lot
of enemies over here.
Bhabhi is coming.
Are you Prem? - Yes.
- There's a call for you.
My call? Who can it be?
Be cautious. I'll just be back.
Do you recognize? I'm Suman.
- Who Suman?
The one who was sitting with
you is calling you.
You go ahead. I'll just come.
Tuffy, be cautious.
I'll be back soon.
Tuffy, will you be my friend?
This is Munia and this is Gudia.
Come on.
Hide it on the table, fast.
Believe me, I don't know
any Suman or her dad.
What? I loved her? When?
I see, in my last birth?
Tell me something.
How is Nisha for this birth?
Hung up? These girls
are truly selfish.
What are you doing here? - I was
waiting for you to finish your talks.
You called me, didn't you? - Yes,
I.. did I call?
Yes you called me and now you deny it.
We're finished.
That breathes life into me!
I was so afraid.
I'll check it up. It's full
of sweets. - What nonsense?
The shoes have turned to sweets.
Have a look.
Sweets look good in a sweet boK.
Prem brother, these girls
have truly fooled us.
Have you accepted defeat so soon?
- Defeat? No way.
I'll just be back with some courage.
Oh Lord, you are the worker of
miracles. You can do anything.
Lord, please do something so that
we win and they're the fools.
Please do something, Lord.
Please do something.
It'll come off in public. Are you
keen on insulting me in public?
I think he wants to
take us somewhere.
I guess he knows where the shoes are.
You have worked a miracle, Oh Lord.
Come on.
Brother, here are the shoes.
Now go and keep this
box in that place.
Hide the shoes in such a place
where she just won't find it.
Definitely not. - Children,
please listen to me.
Let's settle for 500 rupees.
- Definitely not.
We will take nothing less than 1001.
Only then shall we give the shoes.
What do you say dad? - Yes,
this is a rare opportunity.
Ask unflinchingly. Rajesh,
do be seated bare footed.
You are amazing. You're sitting
amongst these children!
Get up Nisha. It's getting late.
- Getting late? Definitely not.
Repeat along with me.
1001 rupees cash.
It's time for me to get up now.
- Why?
Is it your wedding?
- No child, I was..
In that case, you please sit down.
Doctor, these sister-in-laws
are very smart.
Where's our tiger?
- I'm over here, uncle.
You are amazing. Instead of helping
us, you are busy eating.
Say something. - You do the negotiations
first. I'll speak at the end.
What do you say? - Well children,
now.. - Definitely not.
Well Rajesh, give the cash.
Just a minute uncle.
Uncle, tell them to give the shoes
first and then take the cash.
That's perfect. Give with one
hand and take with the other.
That's fantastic Prem.
- All right. We'll get the shoes.
For a beautiful girl..
a beautiful gift.
Sister, who has taken the shoes?
You sister-in-law's of the groom
with the green drapes.
You sister-in-law's of the
groom with the green drapes.
Return the shoes and take the cash.
You brother-in-law of the bride
don't show off so much.
Give the cash and take the shoes.
Return the shoes and take the cash.
Count the cash. - Get the shoes.
Enough of your fuss.
- Get the shoes.
Am I a fraud?
- You should know better.
You are stubborn. - Whatever you say.
Things will get out of control.
- So be it.
We'll demand more. - Doesn't matter.
Don't act smart. - The shoes first.
- The cash first.
We've taken the shoes
not robbed some jewelr'ý.
You brother-in-law of the bride
don't show off so much.
Give the cash and take the shoes.
Return the shoes and take the cash.
Have a drink. - Not in the mood.
Have some snacks. - Not in the mood.
Have an ice cream. - We've had a lot.
Have a 'paan' - We've had a lot.
Some 'rasmalai'. - It's for you.
So much of sweet. - It's for you.
The shoes first. - Will you eat them?
As you wish! - Not at all.
You tuneless songs of some lousy poet.
You sister-in-law's of the groom
with the green drapes.
Return the shoes and take the cash.
Give the cash and take the shoes.
Whatever I've learnt from here..
..I'm taking it all along
with me to my house.
I'm taking it to my house.
I'm leaving for my house.
With these memories
your beloved is leaving!..
..for an unknown house.
How can I forget, dad..
..all the stories that
I've heard from you?
Mom, I'm leaving back..
..all the memories of my childhood!
My loving sister, take care of
that house too the same way.
This house of my birth has
become alien to me now.
I've found myself a new world!
I' m tied up now to
this new relation.
My father-in-law is my dad and
my husband is my God now.
My brother-in-law is
like Lord Krishna.
I'm leaving for my house..
I'm leaving for my house.
May you live long and always
be a bride!
Please come.
You come here.
Where are you going?
You're happy, right? You are
responsible for this relation.
What all has that professor given.
He's given a lot. Diamond necklace,
imported car, TV and VCR.
Did you get it all? - No. - Why?
When we weighed all that against
the weight of our Bhabhi..
..the weight of all that goods
was negligible so we left it there.
And you, were you just applauding
the act? What is this?
I'll give this to our
daughter-in-law as a blessing.
Yes, give her the books. If it
was my Sweetie who had come..
..I would have laded her with gold.
Daughter-in-law, this necklace
belongs to Rajesh's mom.
You alone are the wealth
of this house now!
May you live long! This is
for you, daughter-in-law.
I'm giving you 'The Ramayan'.
Sita is in it!
The way a ring is enhanced by
the presence of a diamond..
..it's my sincere wish that you two
always live happily in the same way.
Take this, Rajesh, my child.
- Doctor uncle, I..
What are you looking at your uncle?
Didn't you take pennies from me
when you went to school?
Now that you are big,
have you become rich?
Keep it. - At least don't scold
him this way in front of her.
I will scold him this way even
in front of his children!
This is for you. Distribute
all this among the rest.
Come here Laloo. Daughter-in-law,
this is Laloo, my son.
Take this. - No Sir
you have given me such espect.
You've also given me such a
good sister-in-law. I'm blessed.
Will you at least accept it from
the hands of your sister-in-law?
Didn't you tell me that Pooja
resembles your own sister-in-law?
Just consider that she is in front
of you and is offering it to you.
What will I get uncle?
Yes brother, give your
younger one something too.
What he'll get is some duty.
Well, the sister-in-law loves
her brother-in-law the most.
So make sure that she never ever
Iongs for her maternal home.
Have you understood? - Yes,
I have understood, uncle.
I promise that I will give my
sister-in-law all the happiness!
What's happening?
- She's teaching me to speak English.
Write, Jawaharlal Nehru.
Should I start Jawaharlal with
a J or a D? - Start with a Z.
You are fooling me. - You fool,
does anyone study on a Sunday?
Bhabhi, let's play cricket.
She'll not go anywhere. - Come here.
- What's the matter?
Chameli, try and explain to him.
I've had a tough time getting
brother to agree to play cricket.
Have you understood anything,
you fool?
Sister-in-law, let's keep the
rest of the studies for tomorrow.
Come Bhabhi. - But Prem
I don't know to play cricke!t.
In that case, you sit and watch.
- Yes, sister-in-law.
There are clouds in the sky..
Brother, it's your turn to bat.
Let's go.
What's happening? - Come on,
Iet's play cricket.
You move this side. Field properly.
Are you through with your fielding?
- Take this, big brother.
Hey Prem, at a cricket ground,
there's no permission to only watch.
One has to play too.
All right. Bhabhi,
you will have to bowl. - Me?
It's a matter of prestige. - No.
It's very easy. You just have
to do this much.
Spectators, a loud round of
applause for our new player.
Come on.
Our new player is moving towards
the bowling crease.
I guess I said something wrong.
Our new player has grabbed
the attention of one and all.
Of the very first ball, she has
clean bowled a seasoned player.
Bhabhi, it's your turn to bat now.
Our new player is moving
towards the batting crease.
Shall we?
The match has entered
a very crucial moment now.
Our seasoned player has rolled
back his sleeves.
He is all excited and is
out for revenge.
Our new player has taken her
position with absolute confidence.
The ball has been bowled.. and
the ball is racing towards the sky.
It's racing towards
the boundary and.. and..
Tuffy, you fool!
Bhabhi, you're the treasure
house of happiness!
From the time the
first rays show up..
..my bhabhi is awake
from that time.
She takes care of all and works
till late in the evening.
From the time the first
rays show up..
..my bhabhi is awake
from that time.
I've been missing all
this since childhood!
I'll be married too!
All of them seem to be telling me so.
You make a choice and
don't listen to anyone.
I'll be married too!
All of them seem to
be telling me so.
You search for a replica of
yourself and get her here.
Till when should I be the youngest?
Let someone younger
than me come too.
Give these arms of mine
a laughing and talking toy!
Till when should I be the youngest?
Let someone younger
than me come too.
We ask of you for a lovely offering!
Bhabhi, you're the treasure
house of happiness!
Come brother.
- All the work is over.
I've spoken to the confectioner and
have told him about the function..
..that we have to celebrate the
arrival of a new member in our family.
Daughter-in-law, you've transformed
Laloo into an Englishman.
How will a monkey appreciate
the taste of ginger?!
Ginger tea, auntie.
Oh, henna problem, no problem.
That's great!
This tea is really good.
But uncle
why are you laughing so much?
Well, call up the professor.
I'd like to ask them about their
time of arrival for the function.
Who?
You! Tell me.
- Your sister will speak to you.
Talk to mummy.
May you live long, child!
Well, it seems difficult for us
to come for the function.
You find it difficult to come?
Talk to uncle.
Greetings. What's the matter?
His college eKams, instead of
being postponed are due these days.
But at least somebody should come.
At least send Nisha.
- Just a second.
Will you go?
- To sister's place? Yes!
Nisha will be coming. - All right.
Prem will be there tomorrow
to pick up Nisha.
You'll go, right Prem?
Yes, I'll go.
Get up child.
Get ready fast. Get up.
What is this, mom?
What a girl you are!
Get up child.
Prem should be here any moment.
Your slave is at your service!
For what? - For waiting for me.
I didn't wait for you.
In that case, were you counting stars
in the day on the roof?
People say, when a beautiful girl lies
she looks more beautiful.
Have you come, son?
How are you, auntie?.. Where's uncle?
Good morning, son. A special snack.
Taste it. - Uncle, have you made it?
It's your auntie's favorite.
It's a secret. This snack mi Ked
with butter pleases the wife.
Actually, we aren't on talking
terms for the past few days.
Why auntie?
- It's our daughter's first child.
It's the ceremony to welcome the
child and we're not going!
I'll take you with much fanfare on
the birth of our grand child.
At least taste it now.
Catch her hand. Taste it.
Can I ask you something? Why do
I get these flowers today?
Basically, whenever we've met,
we've always fought.
Flowers were the best way to
strengthen this acquaintance.
Why did you ask me to forgive you
while leaving after the marriage?
I was just trying to impress you.
If I tell you the fact, you will
humor me. - I won't. Tell me.
It was that touching moment!
We were taking Bhabhi home.
You were bidding her good bye.
Thought to myself, why not
share some of your sorrows.
Have you seen that Tuffy?
A genuine man has no value!
I wasn't laughing at you.
Sometimes, a human errs
in judging a person.
You aren't the type I thought you
were when I first met you.
How am I then? - I'll think of
it at leisure and tell you.
There's a surprise for you
in the back seat.
Have a look.
For you.
What's the matter, Tuffy?
Flowers first, then chocolates!
Is it some special day?
For the first time today, a girl is
sitting on the front seat of my car.
People say that this day occurs
in every person's life.
Today happens to be that
special day for me.
What happened? - Nothing.
I'm sharing my secrets with you
and you' re with your comics.
It's not allowed to read or
write while travelling.
Travel should be full of song and
fun. What do you say, Tuffy?
From the time I saw you singing
on the roof, I'm your fan.
You share some secrets too.
I won't tell anyone.
- Some other time.
Why? - I've a sore throat.
Tuffy, before the third comic is
opened, I guess I have to impress her.
The drapes are flying
in the cold breeze.
The heart is beating fast,
it's because of the teen age.
No control over the heart..
what sort of magic is this?
T'is the magic of the season, dear!
No control over the heart now, dear!
My gaze has lost and gone insane..
..the sight of you
is so breathtaking.
T'is the magic of the season, pal!
This fair girl with the city boy..
..looks like the shining moon!
These beautiful flowers
and the buds..
..this naughty call of the wind!
These beautiful flowers
and the buds..
..this naughty call of the wind!
They signal to me to spend
my time over here.
Previously, never ever would
these flowers talk to me this way!
T'is the magic of the season, dear!
No control over the heart, dear!
My gaze has lost and gone insane..
..the sight of you
is so breathtaking.
T'is the magic of the season, dear!
Tell the truth and don't
keep it a secret.
From where have you'll come
and where do you want to go?
I' m taking her with me to my place.