We've been waiting for you
since this morning.
Really?
We're waiting to welcome you
with the flowers for ages...
Honest?
- Absolutely!
All the way here, I had the answer
to your question memorized in my heart.
I didn't know, I wouldn't
need to say a single word.
Both of us have been
tied together in a bond.
Where can you go?
Come on, kids.
Have some fresh guavas!
You'll find a lot of Rajasthani
color in our attire and speech.
My heart is overjoyed to see you.
What are you explaining to her?
She has lived abroad.
I'm introducing her to the village.
I've heard that people in
the cities are so busy...
They don't have time
to eat meals in peace.
That is why people from cities
come to the village for holidays.
They get peace of mind here.
Grandma, we've left
those lanes far behind.
But excuse me, what's
left in this village?
Neither planes come
here nor mobile phones.
There's a shortage of electricity!
We've left the electricity way behind.
We're going for a walk.
Coming.
Come on.
- You go ahead.
I'll help the ladies in the kitchen.
You too were supposed
to go for the walk.
Who said?
- You said so a while ago.
You've reformed...
- No...
Shall we...?
Come on!
Brother! Elder brother!
We came for a walk
but here we're running!
Shall we return?
- Just a little further.
I want to show Prem how far
the factory has progressed.
Prem, come on.
Come on.
This is the site.
Production will begin in a few months.
Can we check the progress of the
factory from close quarters later?
I'm feeling terribly cold!
Okay, we'll sit here for sometime.
Won't Papa be terribly happy
when the factory is operational.
What are you thinking of?
Nothing.
- I think he's starving.
Go for a run. I have to
talk to Prem about something.
Talk to him at home.
After breakfast.
Which way do I go? Not this way
it's all uphill.
What's the matter?
Brother...
When you see poverty and
difficulties around you...
Helplessness writ large
on the faces of people.
Don't you then feel...
What is all this for?
Sometimes I feel my education,
my Masters Degree...
Everything seems futile.
We can't run away from the truth.
Will your thinking
diminish somebody's sorrow?
If you want to share their sorrow...
Do something that will
bring joy to their lives.
Look at this plant.
When it is operational...
This place will always have power.
This is Papa's dream.
For the progress of this village.
For the future of those kids
who will be me and you tomorrow.
You have a lot to do in life.
Study hard. At this point
this is your only duty.
Yes, you do have another duty.
Towards Preeti.
A girl gives up everything for you.
She behaves the way you'd want her to.
In return, she only
asks for a little love.
I know you do lover her a lot.
But you have to express
the love in your heart.
Bring the words in
your heart to your lips.
And you'll see how she blooms.
Have you guys finished talking?
- Yes.
Anything serious?
I'll talk to you when the time comes
You've made excellent
dumplings, sister-in-law!
We made them. I had no idea
you could cook so well.
Prem, now taste this
and tell us how it is.
No! Please...
What's the matter?
When we insisted, for the first
time, she made Prem's favorite sweet.
And she's feeling shy to serve it.
She thinks it's not good enough.
Prem will certify whether
it's good or not. Serve him.
Just a second.
The video too is ready.
How is it?
- Good.
Good or very good?
Very good.
- Then take some more.
I will.
- Here you are!
Brother's face is
as red as the sweet!
I am feeling shy!
Don't be so conscious. I'm
taking your photo with them.
Speak in our tongue.
Prem, put the picnic bags in the bus.
The sweet dish was very good.
I was making it for the first time
I feared whether you'd like it.
You must make it again.
Stop riding and come here.
We're discussing the love life
of a king who lived 1000 years ago.
Look at that...
- So how many queens did he have?
100. Let's go to the umbrella.
See how lucky he was!
I swear! Had it been me...
And this is the palace of the queens.
They say, the youngest queen
was the most beautiful one!
She's sing in her melodious
voice among her friends.
And dance too.
Hearing the sound of their
music and their anklets...
Hundreds of peacocks
would dance here with them.
Do they still come here?
The sky is overcast with clouds.
Beautiful ladies stand before us.
How can the poor peacocks escape?
Continue the romance.
Look at that.
What is it? Peacock?
- No, elephants.
Elephant?
Prem is a different kettle of fish.
Sometimes he rides horses.
Otherwise he gets elephants.
Come, I'll take you
for an elephant ride.
Come on, kids.
- Come here sister-in-law.
- I'm going ahead.
Preeti, sit here.
Have fun! Give her a hand.
Everybody be seated.
Sit down.
Where do I go?
- Come here.
- Everybody hold hands.
Take me carefully.
I mustn't fall down.
I haven't even got engaged.
My friend, the elephant.
Praise be Lord Ganesha.
Look at the peacock!
- Where is it?
- There!
How beautiful!
Yes, truly beautiful!
"My heart..."
"Peacock dance in my heart."
"The black bee screeches
and my heart blooms."
"Has the season changed or the
scenario or simply my perspective?"
"Peacock dance in my heart."
"The black bee screeches
and my heart blooms."
"Has the season changed or
the scenario or my perspective?"
"You are a newly wed bride.
You reflect radiant love."
"Henna on your hands and kohl in
eyes brings a sparkle to my life."
"You came as the answer
to my questions, my love."
"Peacocks dance in my heart."
"We're tied in such a bond
I've madly fallen in love."
"Has the season changed or the
scenario or simply my perspective?"
"The season of love is here.
It has sprung love everywhere."
"The secret that was in my heart
has finally come to my lips."
"I'll install you in my heart and
take you to the kingdom of love."
"Peacocks dance in my heart."
"Take me wherever you please,
I'll follow you, my dearest."
"Has the season changed or the
scenario or simply my perspective?
"The procession of the moon and
stars brought this glorious moment."
"What a great moment!
The queen of my dreams is with me."
"You troubled me so much.
Today I won't let go your arm."
The moon light night is beautiful!
It's bright outside. Only
we don't have current.
How can that be?
I'll take a look.
The current is back?
What do you think?
I'll just be back.
Welcome!
My dear fellow, congratulations
on your daughter's engagement.
What are you doing?
We've come to ask you
for your child's hand.
Mummy and Papa are here.
- They're asking for you.
- I won't go!
Strange! You're getting
engaged today and look at you.
Tease me, go on.
You're the one who spread
the tale of the fuse off!
Everyone is laughing!
What will Mummy and Papa think?
Mummy was really mad at you. Said
nobody in the family behaved like you!
I'm dead!
- I'll say it was your ideal.
- Want to kill me?
Tell them the light
went off by chance.
Please, my Moms!
Come on.
Good Lord!
- The light went off by chance.
- Really? - It wasn't my fault.
Isn't it?
Brother and his wife are to be blamed.
They said, get engaged.
So I said, all right.
- It finishes one job.
- Oh, I see.
Come on, Mummy.
"Mother Yashodha..."
"This son of yours..."
"Mother Yashodha, this son of yours..."
"Holds my arms at the riverbank."
"He troubles me a lot,
keeps fighting with me."
"I was spared thanks to Lord Rama."
"Mother Yoshodha, this son of yours..."
"holds my arms at the river bank."
"He troubles me a lot,
he keeps fighting with me."
"I was spared thanks to Lord Rama."
"In the streets of Gokul,
on the banks of the Jamuna."
"He shyly throws pebbles at me."
"He's so mischievous but
his countenance innocent."
"He drenches my blouse
when Holi comes by."
"He won't leave my arm."
"He twists my wrists."
"I fall at his feet yet
he won't leave me in peace."
"He traps me with his sweet words."
"Each time Mohan plays the flute..."
"My anklets start to
dance on their own."
"When he teases me with his eyes..."
"The damsel foolishly in love
holds on to heart for dear life."
"She has lost her heart."
"She has lost her sleep."
"She couldn't do what
she set out to do."
"With great difficulty,
she controlled her heart."
"Thanks to Lord Rama"
"The Kanha of Gokul
lives in every heart."
"Fortunate am I that I found him."
"Agreed that he belongs to all."
"Yet he will always be yours, mother."
"He's a beloved."
"You've given him to us."
"You've taken us into your
shield of maternal love."
"Oh mother, we have
to live at your feet."
"Thanks to Lord Rama's kindness."
Come here.
Why are you sitting there
with the old guys? Come here.
Only waiting for you.
You will first hava a son
followed by a daughter.
What formula is this?
It's simple. If the ring is
straight, it will be a son.
If it spins, it will be a girl.
And if it doesn't spin, full stop.
What a scientific method!
He's fond of reading from various
sources and using it to impress.
Man should view every new
thing with curiosity.
And it was true in our case.
Preeti, now it's your turn.
Come on, show your hand.
Now everybody is interested.
You'll just have a
sweet little boy. Happy?
Yes, now it's your turn.
Son...
Daughter.
Son. Daughter.
Son. Daughter...
I've had it!
I was pulling your leg.
- Give me your hand.
- I won't.
- Why? - What's this?
Do you have to return today?
What has cropped up that
Anurag has called you today?
It must be important or
brother wouldn't have called.
Today we were planning a
picnic to the factory site.
We won't enjoy without the kids.
We'll plan another trip after
Prem and Vinod get married.
Papa, we'll all go together.
By then the seat next
to your should be full.
I've fixed my program
with sister-in-law.
When they will be three,
we will be two.
We'll take leave.
It's time.
We didn't realize how these days
flew by in games and laughter.
30 years ago, I left
this village with a dream.
I wanted to do something so that
the villagers wouldn't have to...
...leave their families
and go far for work.
Today I see that dream taking shape.
Brother and Bhaijaan are waiting
for us at the site. We'll go there.
- Let's go to work.
- Shall we stay here?
We're all waiting for the
factory to be inaugurated.
The moment the plant is inaugurated
we'll hear the wedding bells.
The date for the wedding
matches this perfectly.
Now we're just waiting
for that auspicious date.
And I hand over the business
to my sons and be carefree.
I've decided to hand charge of the
company, the directorship to Vivek.
I'd made her a promise.
Once our sons are married,
all my time will be hers.
So the daily appointments
dairy will be with her?
You will be burdening Vivek
with a huge responsibility.
He deserves it every way.
Wow! What news!
Congratulations!
You don't understand anything.!
If Vivek becomes the
company managing director...
Adarsh will be one up on us!
- That is true.
- What will our son-in-law have?
They will always have to obey Vivek.
They will have to beg
him for every little thing!
What shame in asking
your elder brother?
Power can corrupt. Family
relations are forgotten.
This concerns our daughters too.
You are very good friends.
Do something and stop
this from happening.
Take the wife into confidence.
- Why? - The minds of women
work better in this regard.
Don't worry. Follow me.
We don't understand your
making Vivek the MD.
- Why?
- Is that fair to us?
With Vinod and Prem?
Such an important announcement
and you simply said it.
No party, no celebration.
Dharmraj is most upset about this.
That is why he has decided that
tomorrow before we leave for town...
He will distribute Jaipur
sweetmeats to the village!
Why did you have to do this?
May the Lord always be kind to you.
My good fellow, everybody
is blessing you for this!
All of you are leaving.
We will be left alone.
That is why we leave Sapna with you.
Or we'd take her along.
Next time, I'll bring him along.
He'll stay here for a few
days to learn the work.
I'll come here to work
but not make small talk.
If I get the time...
When do you leave for
your studies abroad?
Tomorrow night.
Here are the sweets and savories.
Keep them in the bag.
I didn't make them.
Did you...?
Preeti made them. Don't you dare
distribute them amongest friends!
When will you return?
How can I say?
Only till the exams.
Then he'll be with you.
Write a love letter to mother
everyday instead of to Preeti.
- You spoke again!
- The flight is on time. Hurry up.
You come here, I'll show you!
Shall we leave?
You may stay.
This is very good.
Going on a world trip with your wife.
You'll have Prem's
company on the flight.
You're keeping the promise
you gave your wife.
And I'm keeping mine.
Leave this veil behind for some days.
She'll wear jeans abroad.
Come here. Sit with Papa today.
I had to make an important phone call.
Try to understand the important
phone call after engagement!
This will be a daily occurrence.
Did you decide the
color for your room?
Prem, let us know your choice too.
I have to make rooms for both
of you before your marriages.
Vinod has given me a long list.
You too must tell me.
What can I say? As Preeti wishes.
He has really changed.
I'll just say this. All three boys
should have similar rooms.
They are the same. Vivek's is up
stairs and Prem and Vinod are down.
They too should have rooms upstairs.
Why shouldn't they get a garden view?
Later these are the issues that
will create fights between them.
She's laughing.
- Uncle is here.
- Good day to you.
Welcome.
Since when do you have this ailment?
Excuse me, I think I'm
going through a bad phase.
Get them in.
I've brought some sweets
for Janmashtami, from Agra.
Pass them here!
You are our favorite
relative from all the three!
Call Papa in the office
and tell him brother is here.
Don't disturb him in work.
I've come to meet sister.
First of all do something for us.
What can I say in family matters?
You have all the rights.
- You're giving your daughter!
- Yes. That's right.
You get after every little thing!
Excuse me.
Sangita here.
I've been thinking
of you since morning.
- How are the kids?
- All fine.
Are you feeling all right?
- Yes, is Vivek home?
- He's in the office.
I'll talk to him there.
Nothing special. Bye.
Don't worry. Give the line to Anand.
Something important cropped up.
We'll discuss this later.
I don't know what exactly happened
between Anand and Anurag.
But Sangita and Anand
are quite worried.
They have called me there.
Why are you crying?
What's the matter?
You are aware that we have
been a tight knit family.
Brother Anurag, Jyoti,
Sangita, me and the three kids.
We've had no ill feelings.
Since Anurag called us from Rampur...
He seemed changed.
I thought it was tension of work.
But yesterday he called us and said...
We must look for a separate business.
A separate home.
Anurag said that? I can't believe it.
It is true.
After doing computer engineering
my work has been technical.
Brother looked after the
company accounts and finances.
When he transfered the company
property and shares to his name...
We didn't realize it.
Tell me, did your father make a will?
- No, Uncle.
- Then forgive me...
Your brother has no legal
right to grab everything!
We can go to court and
stake a claim in everything!
You will get your right!
- No, Uncle.
- No?
The work that father started
with such love and efforts...
I don't want to drag it to court.
And then how can I fight my brother?
This concerns your life.
Life can be started again.
We thought we'd shift to Banglore.
It has a growing computer industry.
I have friends there.
I'll begin a new project.
That's not so simple.
And you have the responsibility
of Sangita and Radhika.
That's the only thought
that makes me nervous.
Then I called Vivek.
When he was in agreement
with my decision...
I took Anurag's blessings and left.
Did we take the right decision?
We're all proud of you.
The only sad part is...
The family is broken.
They will be one again.
Absolutely.
Come here, baby.
Come to me, child.
I'm very worried.
How will Anand establish
his work alone in a new city?
There's no need to worry.
I just spoke to Mr. Richard.
He's our agent in London
who also deals in computers.
He wants Anand to join him and
look after the South India business.
And there's no problem
about accomodatiion there.
I have a flat there.
Sangita can be comfortable.
Vinod and I will leave
for Banglore today itself.
We'll return only after settling them.
Consider these
difficult times a test.
You'll see there's some
good hidden in this too.
- Take this, my dear.
- May I take two more?
Sure. Here.
One for Raju and
the other for Bablu.
I'll give it when we meet.
Radhika will miss
Raju and Bablu a lot.
Shall we leave?
Yes brother.
See you Mummy.
Take care dear.
"In happy times or sad..."
"They who come to the Lord's
refuge face no obstacles."
"Time and religion may fail you."
"Surrender yourself at the
Lord's feet and gain solace."
"Mother don't let your mind
get poisoned by unfortunate."
I'm very worried.
What happened to Anand
shouldn't happen to us.
I don't understand...
I've come here from Rampur
only to explain this to you!
Ram Kishen is appointing Vivek
the Managing Director. That's good.
But in the future if there's a
misunderstanding between the brother?
What he means is, getting charge of
the business like Anurag if Vivek...
...blesses Vinod and Prem and
sends them out of the house.
Vivek loves his brothers
more than his own self!
Excuse me but the most loving
man changes on getting power.
You sang praise of Anurag.
What happened?
Truthfully speaking, I couldn't
bear to see Sangita's sad face.
The thought brings tears to my eyes!
The ones whose children
played in Sangita's lap...
Played with Mumu... They did this!
With the real brother!
If a real brother could do this,
don't forget Vivek is a step brother!
You can't deny the truth.
Yes, today Anand is
facing such problems.
He called Vivek to advise him
about what to do.
And what did Vivek do?
Tell me the truth, if he really
had the heart of a brother...
Would he leave his sister mid stream?
He would fight, do anything!
He'd get her her rights!
He wouldn't wash his hands
off his sister's responsibility.
You and your husband are very generous.
You bore your daughter's
sorrows with a smile.
But if this same thing
happens to Prem or Vinod...
Pritam and I won't be
able to bear this sorrow.
We've given our daughters to you.
Now their joys and good
fortune lie in your hands.
What are you doing?
Vinod will fight and have his way.
But what about Prem?
Don't we all know him?
He's way apart from worldliness.
At least think of him.
Your husband's dream is great.
The entire family
lives together happily!
But is it possible?
Can two brides live
together without fighting?
- Show me one house.
- Don't forget...
The man who runs the office,
his wife rules the home.
In the future if Sadhna doesn't
make Preeti and Sapna...
dance to her tune...
I'll eat my words.
In your shoes I would never hand
the family to Vivek and Sadhna!
The truth is however much
you may love Vivek and Sadhna...
He is not your own!
He is not your blood!
Yes Sangita, is
everything settled there?
I see, Anandbabu has gone
to the office with Vivek?
And what is little Radhika doing?
She's having breakfast.
Here, talk to her.
Grandpa, I'm drinking milk by myself.
I too am drinking milk.
- How did you land there?
- For goodies made by my daughter.
In fact, I suggest you
come here with your wife.
I'll talk to her.
Talk to him.
Vivek and I will return by evening.
Finally, the daughter is happy.
Mummy hasn't eaten a
thing since last night.
She seems very worried.
Send her breakfast upstairs.
I'll talk to her.
I just spoke to Sangita.
She is happy.
No need to worry.
Let's go to her for some days.
She will appreciate it.
What's the matter?
Some other worry?
I don't want Prem and Vinod to
go through Anand's experience.
What do you mean?
Why are you appointing
Vivek the Managing Director?
Is that all?
Can Vivek ever treat
his brothers in this way?
Ask your own heart.
You know him better than I do.
I know that this family has 3 sons.
Instead of giving everything to one
divide everything between them.
What are you saying?
It's not too late.
It will be done with love.
And I want it done before
Prem and Vinod get married.
Do you know what you're saying?
Split them up? Separate
Vivek, Prem and Vinod?
These children are our dreams!
- You want to break them up?
- What dreams are you talking of?
Our daughter has been
thrown out of her own home!
Haven't we experienced
highs and lows in life?
Why are you becoming weak today?
This is the time we must stay close
and give strength to our daughter.
I don't want to argue with you.
For the first time
I'm asking you for something.
And I want it.
What you want, you're
asking for... is wrong!
- Breakfast.
- I'm not hungry.
Mother.
I know you are very upset at
what happened with Anand and Sangita.
Your thinking that this shouldn't
happen in our family too is right.
But if we split up like this...
If this house is broken into three...
Will we be happy?
Think about it. When
Sangita comes for rakhi...
To which brother's house
will she go first?
And we still have to
make Vinod's career.
His innocence will be stifled
in the division of business.
Don't punish everybody for me.
Don't break everyone up.
I don't want to be
the Managing Director.
Sadhna and I will go to Rampur.
The new plant has to be looked after.
We'll stay there.
I'll tell Papa to make
Prem the Managing Director.
I assure you that Prem and Vinod
will never suffer as long as I live.
Sadhna has brought you dinner.
Eat a little. For our sake.
Come on, mother.
What are you saying?
Both of you will go to Rampur!
Yes, Vinod.
What's wrong with it?
Prem will look after everything here.
And Rampur is not far
Just a few hours away.
All right then. If you
have decided to go...
And Mummy is happy about it...
Then I too will go with you!
- No Vinod.
- Nobody will go anywhere!
Nobody will go anywhere.
May I come in, sir?
Yes, come in.
Have you brought all the papers?
Give it another thought.
No, Khan.
The time for seperation is here.
Sadhna and I are leaving
for Rampur today.
You won't go anywhere!
I've given my word to mother.
Mother, we're leaving.
Vinod insists of coming along.
I'll send him back soon.
I'd also like to say this...
Why this is happening?
The reason behind it...
People will ask us. Don't
keep a load on your heart.
No mother will wish ill for her son.
Forgive me, father.
I hurt you.
Silly boy. Do the words
of a son hurt a father?
You are going. Go.
I won't stop you.
Emulate every quality of your brother.
Only the fortunate are blessed
with such a son and brother.
What can I tell you?
We brought her home
with such splendor.
Isn't it?
Excuse my saying this but
this is the law of the world...
Gradually bonds break up.
The times you spend together are yours.
I'm glad you are keeping
yourself busy with work.
I've studied all the papers. Begin
work on the electricity division.
From today Vinod will join
me at the factory site.
How do you feel now?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing, grandma.
Exhaustion, I guess.
Don't make Vinod work too hard.
That he will have to do.
He should have full knowledge of
production before the inauguration.
So he can return and take
training in finance and sales.
I won't go back.
I won't leave you and sister-in-law.
What rain!
Sister-in-law!
Sister-in-law...
They have returned.
How are you, Vinod?
- How was the first day at the site?
- Don't ask!
Today I realize how
hard brother works!
I'm starving!
Have a wash. Dinner is ready.
Go and call the little sir.
What happened?
He's dozed off.
That's because he worked hard today.
How sweet is the smile on his face.
The smile has returned to his face.
But I fear... when Prem returns...
How will I assure him?
I think we have talked about it.
Yes. Prem returns today.
Don't spoil our mood by
repeating the same thing.
Kindly leave us alone.
I want to talk to my sister.
I don't have anything
left to say to you.
The only sorrow is...
Today I have no face left
to meet Ram Kishen's eyes.
On whose instigation did you
do this? These butterflies?
Those who never settled down,
can't teach us to run our homes!
They only want to watch the scene!
They will end the play here and
go elsewhere for the curtains!
I am a lawyer.
I've seen families bickering,
relationships breaking up.
I can only say that nobody has
been happy breaking their families.
Nobody can be happy.
See for yourself! Your Prem has
gone straight to meet Vivek.
Instead of coming to see you!
This is not possible.
Why not?
Son, we will return
with you and Sadhna.
We've shared so many moments
of happiness with this family.
I won't let it be overcast
be clouds of sorrow!
Today is such a happy day.
We hear Sadhna's giving us good news.
Accompany Prem even if only
to share this good news!
Adarsh, you tell Vivek.
I understand your
feelings and Prem's too.
Nobody would be happier than me
if Vivek & Sadhna return to the fold.
But Vivek's silence says a lot.
Vivek is doing his duty.
You do yours.
Ram Kishen and the business needs you.
Aunt, it is Ram Kishen's values...
...that two brothers today
fight for each others' happiness.
All you brothers are the same.
One heart beats in all three chests.
For the first time I've
seen you brothers fighting.
The one we fight with...
we love him the most.
Listen to me, Prem.
Go back before I become weak.
The little fellow too is here.
How are you?
We're going to become Uncles.
You the elder one, me the younger.
Rosogollas from the sweetmeat shop.
The first one is for Uncle.
Bought specially for you.
- No, I won't eat today.
- Why?
Just don't feel like it.
- Not even one?
- Just half...
Have one. I'm glad though in
a way, we are together.
You don't talk to Prem.
We'll talk to him.
Sounds like him!
Did you call for me?
Yes, son. Come inside!
Come in and sit down.
Whatever your mother did,
good or bad...
It's for your good and Vinod's.
A mother gambles all that
she has for her children.
So don't be mad with your mother.
I say, what has she done?
Since she heard, Sadhana
is giving us good news...
We've been spreading joys!
We're distributing saris
to all the ladies in Club.
And this silver present for
all friends and relatives.
What else is required?
Even a real mother wouldn't do this.
May I leave?
Everything will remain the same.
Nothing here is the same.
Neither you nor me.
See what Vivek has written to me.
Today Prem has become
the Managing Director.
Stay with him all day.
Close to him.
He has never measured
relations with money.
We always considered his
simplicity his weakness.
Actually that is his strength.
Give him lots of love.
May I ask you something?
When the elder brother's love
and father's blessing are with you...
Why don't you sit on your chair?
Why here...?
This is elder brother's right.
Whenever he returns, whichever day...
He'll find everything the same.
You worry for no reasomn.
It will take Prem time to realize.
We achieved what we wanted.
He has become the Managing Director!
You just make his favorite
dishes and feed him yourself.
We'll see how long the son
will be mad with the mother.
Bye bhaijaan.
You haven't eaten a thing since
morning. Eat something now.
Yes Bhaijaan.
Wash up and come. Dinner is ready.
No, mother. I'm not hungry.
All your favorite dishes.
I made them.
I'm not hungry.
I've shifted your things
to the room upstairs.
Where are you going?
To bring my things
back from Vivek's room.
You and Preeti have to
stay here after marriage.
How did you even think of it?
The entire fault is mine!
I'm to be blamed!
I love you so much!
Fight the world for you!
Doesn't a mother have this right?
She does. Only if she doesn't
differentiate between the kids.
I didn't do anything.
Vivek left on his own.
And you let him go?
Tomorrow if I want to leave
everything and go away...
Will you let me go?
Won't you stop me?
Right from childhood, Vivek
has respected you more than us.
He has loved you the most.
And you forgot all this!
Try to recall. The Prem and Vinod
for whom you're fighting yourself...
They would have left you
and gone away long back!
If Vivek hadn't lost his
arm to save their lives!
For what happened to Sangita,
you're blaming brother Vivek.
Thinking of Sangita
brings tears to our eyes.
The name of Anurag
fills us with anger.
But are we less at
blame than Anurag?
The Sadhna whom we lovingly
brought home as a bride...
We made her a stranger in a moment!
When she waits at the
foot steps of motherhood!
Isn't this discrimination?
You've acted as a
step-mother, not Vivek!
Nobody can take the place
of brother Vivek and Sadhna.
Neither in this house nor in
this room. Nor in this heart.
And if your conditiion is that
I step into Vivek's shoes...
and Preeti into Sadhna's...
I swear by Sadhna,
I will never get married!
Uncle, forgive me.
I can't get married.
I knew this would be your decision.
The country that honors the brother
as a father and his wife as mother...
Prem will never crush their joys
to erect his own palace of dreams.
I knew it.
I had already told Preeti.
Won't you stay?
I wouldn't have been able to take
Sadhna's rights even if you asked me.
Sit down.
Whether we're tied in a bond or not...
We're tied in an
emotiional bond of hearts.
Isn't it?
Don't worry about Sadhna.
Her delivery is my responsibility.
It will be a normal delivery.
You might have to go to
the hospital any moment.
- Sit down.
- See what father sent for you.
A little Krishna.
He wants you to always keep
this idol in front of you.
- Give it to me.
- Why are you staying here?
- Sapna is here.
- I've taken official leave from sir.
I'm going to stay
here till you deliver.
Tea...
Doctor, Preeti is staying
here leaving all her work.
And Sapna isn't taking part
in her college cultural program.
I have three daughters not one.
Vinod will complete training by
the time the factory is inaugurated.
Then we'll send him back to the city.
Time just flew by
laughing with Sapna.
We didn't realize anything.
Time moves at its' own pace.
Time takes its' tests
all the time in some way.
I don't understand! Why has
productiion in the factory stopped?
We faced technical
problems earrlier too!
Sir, Anand could tackle them.
I've heard this a number of times.
Quickly appoint a good engineer.
In this manner, we won't be
able to clear the bank loans!
I'm on my way.
Now how are they?
They still have high temperature.
Jyoti mentioned that they haven't
been eating well for some days.
They've stopped playing too.
- Yes.
- Anyway continue the medicines.
Inform me tomorrow morning.
I have to talk to you.
I want to say something to
you as your family doctor.
Children are as delicate as flowers.
If they don't find a loving
enviroment, they wither away.
And that's not good.
I'm unable to give them time
because of my problems at work.
I often lose my temper with them.
Yesterday you raised your hand at them.
They were being stubborn.
They wanted to go to
Anand and Sangita.
Why don't you give in to them?
Don't lose the peace of your
family to personal grudges.
Or no doctor will be able to help.
Anand and his wife have come!
With Radhika!
Brother!
You didn't inform us that
Raju and Bablu were so ill.
We left as soon as
sister-in-law called up.
You didn't consider us family.
Forgive me.
What are you saying?
I had turned blind with selfishness.
I acheived one success
after another in business.
I assumed it was because of me.
But after Anand left, I found
out the success wasn't mine.
But of our team.
Since Anand left home,
without asking or taking anything...
I haven't had any peace.
I lost everything I had.
The happiness of the children.
The smile on Jyoti's face.
But we're together again!
We will live together.
Today is such a joyous day.
My daughter's house
is settled again.
We've come to ask you for something.
Ask brother Vivek to return home.
It was Vivek's belief that
we'll be together again.
I remember the day we were
leaving for Banglore...
He placed his hand on
my head and said...
All your sorrows be mine
May all my joys be yours.
I've committed a grave sin!
A grave sin!
Nothing is lost.
Look there.
No, Mamta.
You are the same Mamta for me.
...who gave our children
such a noble upbringing.
Made them such good humans.
Shall we go to Rampur?
We are going to be grandparents.
Yes, Sadhna needs you
the most at this hour.
Anything to worry about?
No, Sadhna is fine.
Start the final testing of the
machines. We're off to the hospital.
- Brother is here!
- Hurrah!
- You've become a Papa!
- You have a son!
Many congratulations.
- You...?
- Talk later.
Sangita, take him in.
Let's go.
Mother...
I've come to take my
daughter-in-law and grandson home.
I won't take him.
You left. Not once did
you ask your mother...
What is my fault?
Attentiion! The heir to the
family is making his entry!
- Give the baby to me!
- No!
- I'm the aunt!
It's the Papa's turn first.
No, first of all it's
the turn of Papa's mummy.
Aunt, compared to all
the joys of the world...
The joy of becoming a
grandmother is the best.
Mother, all of us are in
line to meet the baby.
- Me, first.
- Sure.
Aunt before the Uncle.
Let's love him together.
It's also the right of the elder
uncle and aunt to love the baby.
Yes, Prem.
One day for my sake...
You took a pledge in front of mother.
Today for my sake I want you,
You take another pledge.
Garland her.
Here is your Mummy!
- Okay, you may...
- I have garlanded her.
Sister-in-law, on thid joyous
occasion I've brought special sweets!
You really do too much!
Forgive me for all that I did
so far was with ulterior motives.
Blinded by love for my daughter.
I fed flour to the ants,
watered the god of the trees.
- Prayers, invocatioin...
- Yes, I did all that.
But I couldn't shake the
foundation of your family.
Mother Ram Kishen is right.
It's all a game of values.