"This is amazing, Mr Rustom"
We've never seen anyone make
so much of progress in just a year
Do you think I'm lying? The Karan
Malhotra you're talking about...
"used to do the rounds of my house
in a run-down jeep, only a year ago"
The rounds of your house?
- Yes. And I used to scold him too
"That's right. And Priya,
the girl Karan has married..."
she used to be our paying-guest.
- Really?
See that group of boys and girls
over there?
They were part of Karan's band in
which Karan and Priya used to sing
Karan and Priya
look fabulous!
Congratulations on the wedding!
- Thanks
Whom do you give credit for making it
from a small time dance troupe...
to this huge bungalow?
Is it your hardwork or destiny?
The credit of my success
goes only to Priya
I only dreamt big.
Had she not been with me...
"my dreams would never be fulfilled.
- You're very lucky, Mrs Malhotra"
Your husband gives you
all the credit for his success
"That's how much he loves me,
but I did nothing"
I only walked the path
he showed me
"We're so fortunate, Karan.
We have everything we wanted"
The best of my good-fortunes
is that you are with me
Will you always love me so much?
Will I always be so dear to you?
"Wake up, Priya"
It's eight
You've got to go to
the rehearsals
"Karan, what's wrong with your voice?"
"Karan? Priya, I'm Kajal, not Karan!
Wake up now!"
"Wake up, Priya... wake up"
You? I had such a lovely dream...
why did you wake me up?
Karan's been waiting for you
downstairs from a long time
Go on
Shut that horn... stop it!
"Why did you throw garbage
on me, Rustom Uncle?"
D'you expect me to shower rose-petals?
How often have I told you...
not to honk here early in the day
and cause noise-pollution
You could use your mouth to say it?
- I have blisters trying to tell you!
I have to honk because
you won't let me go upstairs
Haven't I told you that this
is a dormitory for girls?
"If I let boys upstairs, what if
something untoward happened?"
What good morning?
He's ruined my morning! Go away!
"Sure, I'll go away. Where's Priya?
- She'll be ready in five minutes"
So I'll leave. Come to the
rehearsal hall as soon as possible
Now look here.
Today's the 30th
Ask Priya to pack her bags.
I want my room vacated
I don't want these everyday hassles.
You play music the whole night...
and won't let me go to sleep!
And this guy arrives at 8...
to honk and ruin my sleep!
- Rustom!
What is it?
- Your breakfast is served
Why're you getting angry with
the kids so early in the day?
You're angry with me
and I'm angry with them!
Shut up and come on inside.
Your breakfast is ready
Ready indeed! Eggs and buns again.
- If you drive the girls away...
how will we get a free ticket
to go on a cruise?
Let them find a job
on the ship first!
"What are you up to, Aditi?
- What happened?"
Your movements are okay.
But your expressions!
"Is this any time to come, Priya?
You said 5 minutes, it's an hour!"
Don't be angry. I've got something
important to tell you. Come
"Sit down, I must tell you something!"
Know what? You looked smashing
in a suit today
I haven't worn a suit in years.
When did you see me in a suit?
"In my dreams! I had a lovely dream
this morning, Karan!"
"I dreamed that we had a bungalow,
a fleet of cars..."
you're the owner of a leading
music company. And we're marrying!
Our reception is being attended
by the cream of Bombay's society!
Your dream will surely come true
Only our troupe must get selected
to perform on the cruise
I'm sure our troupe will be selected
I'm not much worried
about the other troupes...
but Jojo Fernandes will be
our main rival at the audition
He has so much of experience.
- So what if he has experience?
"We have the spirit, the passion!
We'll work hard, day and night!"
No need for the rehearsals.
The audition has been called off
Why?
- They have selected Jojo Fernandes...
without an audition.
- How can that happen?
We've worked through the days and
nights to prepare for the audition...
and they select Jojo Fernandes?
I'll personally go and meet the
owner of Singhania Shipping
"It's extremely difficult
to meet Raj Singhania, Karan"
"He's such a busy man, you've got to
take an appointment weeks in advance"
Whatever happens...
I'm going to meet him
Grandma
"Good morning, grandma.
How are you?"
I'm okay. Now quickly switch on
your computer. I want to see you
It's a week since I last saw you
"Switch on your camera, will you?"
"What a sight you are!
Unkempt hair, a stubble?"
"I was at my workouts, grandma.
So I look like this"
Stop flattering me and tell me
when you are coming to Jaipur
"Grandma, our cruise sets out
next week. The day it returns..."
I'll come to you in Jaipur
How is Darshan?
I hope he's taking care of you?
"Taking care of me?
I've got to take care of him, grandma"
He keeps giving every story
a strange twist
"If I ask him why, he says
What if it happened?"
But he's very good at heart
Have Darshan and Saxena arrived?
- They're waiting for you in the hall
Some things always ought
to be kept a secret
And Raj loves this quality in me
"What are you doing, Mrs Braganza?
You've been here for so many years..."
is this any way of serving tea?
You've spilt it!
"It's okay, Mr Darshan.
I'll wipe it out"
"It's okay, you say? This incident
could have set my house on fire!"
Fire? That's strange
"How could your house be on fire,
for the tea that is spilt?"
"Simple logic. Had the tea fallen
on me, it'd have left a stain"
I'd have gone home with the stain...
and my wife would mistake it
for a lipstick mark
"She'd fight with me, because she'd
think I'm having an affair!"
And she'd try to commit suicide.
She'd set herself on fire...
"and burn down my house too.
- But you're still a bachelor, Darshan"
"Where have you been married?
- What "if" I were already married?"
Wouldn't it burn my house?
And you're telling me!
Right?
- Right...
"Whose house is burnt, Darshan?
What are you talking about?"
"Actually, I've been teaching them
some logic Raj bhaiyya"
"If they still don't understand, there
will be a flood in this house someday"
But don't ask me how!
- Am I crazy to ask you?
Try asking... I guarantee you
a flood!
"Darshan, take Saxena's car
and go to the ad agency"
Collect the publicity material
from one Mr Jacob there
"You come with me, Saxena.
- Right, sir"
Have copies of our agreements
with Star Cruise...
"despatched to Singapore, Malaysia
and Bangkok today itself"
I received email from them
this morning
You can't have an appointment
with Mr Singhania this week
And he's sailing next week.
- It's in connection with that...
that I must discuss something
important with him. If you could...
Praise the Lord...
"Where to, feller? This lift is
meant for the bosses"
The common-lift's over there.
Get going
"I say, Shiv Prasad...
- My name is Gauri Shankar"
Gauri Shankar! What difference?
They're both names for Lord Shiva!
That's true. Praise Lord Shiva!
- Gauri Shankar...
I don't want to go in your lift.
Could you tell me...
"on which floor you left Mr Singhania?
- Company rules, my friend..."
we can't tell outsiders anything
about the bosses. Sorry...
I can't tell you I've dropped
Mr Singhania on the 20th floor
"All right, don't tell me.
Could you at least tell me..."
which section he has gone to?
- You're an amazing man!
When I won't tell you that I left
my boss on the 20th floor...
how will I tell you that the boss
has gone to the accounts department?
"You do follow the rules
very strictly, I say"
I have to... I'm very
strict about such things
"I don't know how, but every visitor
gets to know everything about the boss"
Like it happened yesterday.
Mr Chopra's wife was here
"She asked me a million times,
but I wouldn't tell her..."
"that Mr Chopra wasn't in his office,
he was in the stores with his secretary"
Don't tell me!
- But she got to know
She rushed to the stores...
and caught Mr Chopra in a compromising
position with his secretary
How could she have got to know?
- There's surely a traitor around
Of course
"This accounts department?
Is it to the left, or to the right?"
I can tell you that. It has
nothing to do with the boss!
"The accounts department is neither
to the left, nor to the right"
Walk right ahead...
there you are!
"See you. Thanks, Shiv Prasad...
- Shiv Prasad?"
"What difference? Both are
names for Lord Shiva, after all"
Praise the Lord!
"Several countries have requested
extra tickets, despite their quota"
"Our cruise is a success,
even before it sets sail"
"No, Saxena. Our cruise will be
a success when people praise it"
"And they will praise it, sir"
"After all, they are travelling
on our cruise for the comfort"
"And the comfort our cruise offers
is world-class, sir"
People can find comforts
even in 5-star and 7-star hotels
There is only one thing which will give
people satisfaction on the cruise
"Know what that is?
- Entertainment, sir"
The biggest USP of your cruise
Which department are you from?
"I'm not from a department
of your company, sir"
I'm Karan Malhotra and I wish to
talk to you for only five minutes
What I want to say
has to do with entertainment
"Whatever you wish to say, can't
be said without an appointment"
"Wait a minute, Saxena...
what do you wish to say?"
"I have a dance-troupe, sir.
Like many dance troupes in the city..."
I too had applied to perform
on your cruise
We were told that an audition
would be held for all of us
"But we were told this morning that
Jojo Fernandes was chosen..."
without even an audition!
I only want to know...
why your company has indulged
in such discrimination
"Is it true, Saxena?
- Yes, sir"
There's only a week for the cruise
to sail and there's a lot to do
And the Jojo Fernandes we have chosen
is the very best in Mumbai
"I know, ours is a new troupe
compared to Jojo's"
"But yours is a new cruise too, sir.
People are skipping the old ones..."
"to travel on your cruise. And why?
Because people now want novelty, sir"
And our troupe has the novelty!
I only want you to give me
an opportunity to prove that
"Saxena, arrange for an audition.
Call the judges..."
What happened?
"Congratulations, Jojo.
You have been selected"
"You can't do this, sir!
We have been cheated!"
"I took this decision going by
the judges' approval, Mr Karan"
"But I saw him...
- I'm sorry, there's nothing I can do"
"One second, sir...
- C'mon Karan. Learn to accept defeat!"
"Our troupe has worked very hard
for this audition, Jojo"
Now go and tell Mr Saxena that you
tossed a coin on the floor!
Are you crazy?
You don't win a competition
merely by prancing around
"You need brains to win it.
What say, guys?"
You? You come all the way here?
"You were seething at the
competition, weren't you?"
What makes you so calm now?
"I get it. You will say,
Jojo, forget what has happened..."
give me employment in your troupe.
Am I right?
Why are you so quiet?
What's the problem?
I'm with you.
I'll give you a job
and that babe of yours too
Now go and bring her over
I'll take a test of hers tonight
and hire you both tomorrow
You'll take a test of hers?
You want to test her?
"Had we been selected, we'd have
been going on the cruise right now"
We wouldn't have been
depressed like this
"Yes, Karan is right here"
This is his partner speaking.
What is this regarding?
What?
What are you saying?
What happened?
- Singhania Corporation called...
to say that we've been chosen
to perform on the cruise!
"Know what, Karan? Jojo Fernandes
died in an accident last night!"
And they've chosen us to
replace him on the cruise!
"See Karan? Bad guys, bad endings"
We've got to send our passports
to their office immediately
We're leaving for Singapore tomorrow!
"Karan, this is the first step
we take in realising our dreams"
"The first step is difficult to come by.
They come thick and fast, afterwards"
It's such a big ship!
Just like a 5-star hotel!
"Not a 5-star hotel,
it's like a 7-star hotel darling!"
"Karan, my boy..."
you may take my house in exchange
for a permanent room on this ship
"Even we aren't permanent yet, Rustom.
We're still temporary"
Let's go
"You're the limit, Rustom. He gave us
two complimentary tickets on the ship"
And you now want a permanent room.
You don't have any sense!
Let's go.
- Stop talking and come on
"Rosy darling, I'm terribly scared. We
shouldn't have brought John on the ship"
So what should we have done?
Should we have left him at home?
What sort of a man are you?
John is only 2 years old
"Look, that 2-year old darling of yours
is trying to get out of the basket"
"He's not trying to get out of the
basket, he only wants some fresh air"
"Keep your stuff in your cabins
and come to the auditorium, Harry"
We'll check out the systems first
"All this is thanks to
your blessings, grandma"
Where are you right now?
- We've just left Singapore
We're midseas right now.
- Do telephone me every day
"Sure, grandma. I'll give
you a call everyday, okay?"
"Go on, Saxena"
Tell them that I'll personally
discuss it with them in Mumbai
"Raj, the captain wants a copy
of the permission for docking"
It's lying there.
- Where?
Raj...
want me to tell you
something confidential?
War is about to break out
between India and America
"Since our cruise is a success..."
"the American shipping industry
will close down..."
"America will be out on the streets
and out of frustration..."
will launch an attack!
- The shipping industry...
"is based in Greece, not America.
- If it was based in America?"
Wouldn't there be a war?
"Even after 20 helpings of this,
I'm not going to get any fatter"
I can see that
I took a walk on the deck today
Just imagine how romantic and beautiful
the deck will look at night
What with the open skies and the
twinkling stars... am I right?
What are you staring at?
- The stars you're talking about...
they're actually in your eyes
You and I will go to the deck
all by ourselves tonight
"Karan, aren't you having anything?"
I thought you'd fall short of it
"I'll have only orange-juice.
Will you have something, Karan?"
Anything will do
What is it?
- You know why...
I brought you on this luxury cruise.
- Why did you?
Because you shower all
your affection on Johny
Give Tommy a bit of your love
at least some time!
"Old men don't get love,
they get respect. Get that?"
So why did you marry me then?
- How was I to know that you're old?
I discovered it on the
night of our honeymoon...
that you're wearing a wig
and a set of dentures!
Don't make me say anymore. Okay?
Help!
My skirt!
"Actually, there was that dog
after me..."
"I was very scared,
my skirt gave way and..."
That puppy...
I'm really very sorry
to have disturbed you
I'm leaving now
Maybe you locked the door
when you walked inside
"Looks like you haven't recognised me.
I'm Karan Malhotra, sir"
I came to your office without an
appointment... for the audition?
Oh yes. It's your troupe that is
performing on the cruise
"Right, right...
Today's our first show, sir"
"Please do attend. I can assure you,
you'll get what you want in our show"
I can't tolerate it anymore
"I can't stay away from you
even for a day"
Not even for a day
Love is amazing
It raises a million questions
It makes you dream...
it awakens an aching
It adds to your woes...
it takes you around paradise too
"Where will we go away
from paradise?"
"Where?
Oh, where will we go?"
I can't tolerate it anymore
"I can't stay away from you
even for a day"
Not even for a day
"What is love worth,
if it isn't for desire?"
"What is life worth,
without the beloved?"
"Love keeps you going...
but it also torments you"
"It brings you closer,
but it also increases the distances"
"Let these distances be
done away with then"
I can't tolerate it anymore
"I can't stay away from you
even for a day"
Not even for a day
We made a great first impression.
What an amazing response for the show!
That's because our co-ordination
was perfect
And why not? I had rehearsed so much.
- Oh sure...
"she's the only one who rehearsed,
none of us did anything at all"
Fatso!
A bouquet from Raj Singhania!
And listen to this...
the show as superb
"Priya, Raj Singhania
has invited you to dinner!"
Not fair. All of us worked hard
and only you get invited
I'm not going all alone.
We'll all go together
No Priya. Don't do that
"If you don't go, Raj Singhania
will feel very hurt"
Think of the great honour
he has bestowed on you
"Yes, and it isn't an honour
just for you. It's for all of us"
"I've been on this ship, but
I didn't get to see this place"
It's meant only for my special guests.
And you're my first guest
I've watched a lot of shows
As for yours and Karan's
performance...
"It looked as if it wasn't a
performance, as if it were for real"
"What is a performance that
doesn't look real, sir?"
"Please stop flattering me so much.
Else, I'm going to be very conscious"
"All right, but you will
call me Raj. Not sir"
Sir again?
"The next time you say that, I'm going
to push my 'sar' (head) ahead!"
What are you thinking about?
You're such a great dancer...
I'm the one who ought
to feel apprehensive
I've heard that music somewhere
You must've heard it in my office
yesterday. It's my favourite
"Whenever I hear it,
I feel very relaxed"
And how are you feeling now?
"The one I was always looking for,
is now with me"
You were looking for me? What for?
- To give you the heart
What?
You forgot your heart
in my office yesterday
"I didn't even realise it!
- Matters of the heart, you see"
You never know when you lose
your heart to someone
What would anyone do with
such a little heart anyway?
One could wear it around his neck
and keep it close to his heart
I can't believe that a business
tycoon like you can be as romantic!
Why not? Does a business tycoon
not have a heart?
"How are you, son?
- I'm fine grandma. How are you?"
I'm okay
"Grandma, I want to introduce you
to a friend of mine"
A friend?
- Yes. Switch on your computer
"Come, I'll introduce you to grandma.
- Your grandma?"
Where's the friend
you want me to meet?
"Come, Priya"
"Grandma, this is Priya.
- Namaste"
May you live long.
How long have you known Raj?
We met on the ship
Who else is there in your family?
I'm all alone
Who did you come with
on the ship?
I perform in the shows
that are held on the ship
"So long, grandma.
I'll talk to you tomorrow. Okay?"
How's everyone else at home?
Convey my regards to uncle and aunt
Give my love to the young ones.
The kids too
What are you looking at?
You can see everything from here
"On the outside, it appears
to be a mirror"
You mean... you saw
everything yesterday?
"Everything. Your performance,
your dance..."
and your flying kiss
"Yash, you're ahead by a beat.
It's all out of sync"
"Your position has changed too.
- Sorry, I'll set it right"
How many times do I tell you
that you're position is over here!
"Keep a distance from him,
or it'll look awful"
Guess where Raj took me for dinner?
- Where?
In his special lounge! A place
reserved for his special guests
"Especially for me! The dancing,
the dinner, the wine..."
"He has style in everything he does,
a special way of his own..."
I was absolutely zapped!
I think our troupe is going
to get permanent status!
"I beg your pardon. I bring bad news,
but you mustn't be disheartened"
I know the benefits
a temporary worker enjoys
"The ones with temporary jobs
are their own bosses, not servants"
"They can work when they want to,
or kick their jobs"
"They spend their time anywhere...
they enjoy freedom, you know"
"If you're singing on a ship today,
you might sing in a train tomorrow..."
"or maybe the tower, the plane
or the Moon!"
"I'm sorry to say this, but our boss
couldn't bear to see your freedom"
So... he has given you
permanent status
What?
- I tried to make him see reason
"I said, please don't do this.
Let them enjoy..."
"You mean, we're now permanent?"
Give me just two days.
I'll talk him out of it
You really had us scared!
You sure do have a sense of humour!
"Strange boys and girls, I say!"
"Karan, everything is happening
the way you wanted it to"
Our troupe has been selected
and we have permanent status too
This ship is only a means
of reaching our goal
Our goal is not to merely
become stage performers...
we've got to be rich
and influential folks
"After marriage, I want
to give you everything"
And so much of love
that no man ever gave his wife
You can fulfill your promise
But the ship reaches Malaysia tomorrow.
Aren't we going sightseeing in Malaysia?
"Let us reach our goal,
and what is Malaysia..."
I'll take you around the whole world!
At six. Exactly.
- Right here?
Don't forget to bring
what I've asked you for!
And come back soon
You haven't gone around Malaysia?
- No
Why not?
- Because of you
Because of me!
- Yes
You gave our troupe
permanent status yesterday...
and that adds to our responsibility.
To do better in every show...
some of us will remain in the ship
for the rehearsals
"Rehearsals can happen later.
Come on, let's go out"
"I can't go, I have another reason.
- I'm not listening to anything, okay?"
I have yet to see
a sincere girl like you
The whole group goes sightseeing...
- And I've yet to see a boss like you
Your employee wants to work
and you take her out
"I stand to gain, even in that.
- How come?"
A beautiful girl keeps me company
for ten hours
"Come, Priya"
This is the best restaurant
in Malaysia. Let's eat first...
and go sightseeing later.
- But I can't go with you
Why not?
- They must have a dress-code here
And I'm not properly dressed.
- What are you talking about?
Come on.
- I haven't worn any sandals
Why not?
- I had taken a pledge that...
"should our troupe be made permanent,
I'd spend 24 hours barefoot"
I wanted to tell you on the ship.
But you didn't give me the opportunity
It must be a very insignificant
thing for you...
but it's a huge event for our troupe.
I have a suggestion
"Drop me at the ship, or you'll have to
face embarrassment because of me"
Right. Embarrassed I will be. If
you're the only one who's barefoot
What are you doing?
"If you can go barefoot for
your friends, can't I do it for you?"
Almost everyone prays to God
for himself...
but rare are those who
pray for others
So let's go to a place where there
is no dress code or formalities
"You must be visiting Malaysia
very often, isn't it?"
For both actually
"It's a beautiful city, isn't it?"
Will you have an ice-cream?
"Look, the lunch was on you. So let me
buy the ice-cream. I'll be back!"
My feet... they're burning!
My heart is convinced...
I've fallen in love with you
"Ever since I have met you,
my love..."
"I've known what it means
to fall in love"
Your charm has driven me crazy
Crazy
My heart is convinced...
I've fallen in love with you
"Ever since I have met you,
my love..."
"I've known what it means
to fall in love"
Your charm has driven me crazy
My heart is convinced...
I've fallen in love with you
"Ever since I have met you,
my love..."
"I've known what it means
to fall in love"
Those eyes have driven me crazy
My heart gave me no time to think
"I don't know when
I fell in love"
"My destiny, you came to shape..."
"may our love not
attract the evil eye"
"Ever since I have met you,
my love..."
"I've known what it means
to fall in love"
Your eyes have driven me crazy
My heart is convinced...
I've fallen in love with you
Take my heart away...
"You are my peace,
you are my happiness..."
"you are the desire
of my heart"
You are my dawn...
you are what I am known for
"Ever since I have met you,
my love..."
"I've known what it means
to fall in love"
Your charm has driven me crazy
I'll see how you take
that dog on board!
You call my John a dog?
Call him a dog and I'll see that you
don't board the ship again. Get that?
"All right, I'll call him John.
But if you take him on the ship..."
I'll lodge a complaint against you.
- Why are you fighting?
What is the problem?
- The problem is her John
He barks all night
and drives me up the wall
You shouldn't say such things
about Mr John
"Whatever it is, you must
sort it out amicably"
What will I settle amicably?
He was at my feet yesterday...
and he pissed on my trousers.
- He pissed on your trousers?
He's the one who pissed
on my trousers
You shouldn't be doing such things.
You can't piss on people's trousers
I'm talking about the dog!
- You call my John a dog again?
"Now, now... I admit,
what he did was wrong"
But you're calling her husband
a dog again and again. That is bad
You think my husband
is a dog?
"Not me, he's the one who said it.
Why're you angry with me?"
"My name is Tommy, not John."
Tommy? So who's John?
- This is John
A dog? On the ship?
- Yes
Don't you know? Animals are
not allowed on the ship!
That dog is not going on the vessel.
You think this is a ship for dogs?
"If dogs were allowed,
there'd be dogs everywhere"
"Dogs in the kitchen, in the disco,
in the rations... dogs everywhere!"
"If dogs fell in the water, how many
times would we stop the ship?"
Every time a dog fell in the water?
- But why would a dog jump at all?
And what if it did?
You'll have your John in Singapore.
Understand?
"Till then, help yourself
to this Tommy"
Number eight
"Don't gamble anymore, Karan"
"Luck doesn't seem to be on your side.
- You're right, sir"
"Ever since I've arrived,
I've only been losing"
Here's a tip. Start every game
with lady-luck
You'll never lose.
- Really?
"Sir, you've made a blunder
by giving me that tip!"
"I'm going to win your whole casino now!
- That won't help, Karan"
Lady-luck is very much like love
It goes to the one
who approaches it first
"Priya, have you ever tried
your hand at Black Jack?"
"Come on, I'll show it to you"
"Karan, looks like you can't notice it.
But I can see it. Priya is changing"
Oh no. I have all
the faith in Priya
I thought you had forgotten
"I sure had forgotten,
but it wasn't your birthday"
"I had forgotten that life
isn't only about a future..."
it's about the present too
For you
I got it specially for you
from Malaysia
Now wear it quickly
and come to the deck
We'll celebrate your birthday there
How did you get to know
that today is my birthday?
Your passport told me.
Come on
Karan and the others are awaiting me...
- They'll soon join us. Come on
"Darshan, go and fetch the rest
of the members from Priya's troupe"
The cake has arrived!
Here you guys are and I've looked
for you all over the ship!
The boss has sent for you. Come on!
- It's Priya's birthday today
We'll come immediately after
we have cut the cake
Priya's at the Belle Vista and
the boss has thrown a huge party...
to celebrate her birthday.
He has invited everybody on board!
You must first feed the cake
to the members of your troupe
They're the closest to you
"Right now, you're the one who's
closest to Priya, sir"
And we're only happy that you have
thrown such a grand party for her
"Karan, sing a song that will bring
every lover closer to his beloved"
And those who have still not
professed their love...
must find themselves
speaking their heart
"Sir, I'll sing a song today..."
which every lover will
always remember
Fall in love...
express love...
reciprocate love...
or deny love...
"whatever punishment you
choose to give..."
"giving you my heart
is fun in itself"
"Fall in love,
express your love..."
"reciprocate love
or deny me your love..."
"choose the punishment
you will give me"
"Giving you my heart
is fun in itself"
"When you find someone
you love dearly..."
"looking away from you,
you can't endure it"
Love drives you helpless
"For it is an exchange
of hearts"
"Strange is this game
of hearts..."
in its victory lies defeat
Win it or lose it...
this way or that...
"choose the punishment
you will give me"
"Giving you my heart
is fun in itself"
I have now come to believe...
I'm in love
"For the first ever time,
I feel a sense of belonging"
I must now have the one...
my heart has desired
"Who will gain?
And who will lose?"
Who knows what destiny holds
"Whatever destiny offers me,
my beloved is with me"
Whatever God wishes...
"giving you my heart
is fun in itself"
"Giving you my heart
I still can't believe that was
my birthday celebration
I've never ever seen such a grand
celebration in my life!
"However, there was something lacking.
I didn't give you a birthday gift"
"Priya, I wish to marry you"
"Should you wear this ring,
I'll think you have accepted me"
"Otherwise, you may keep this ring
as your birthday gift"
"Whatever you decide, I'll always
respect you as I respect you now"
What are you thinking about?
Just that some dreams do come true
"Karan, Raj proposed to me today.
He wants to take me to Jaipur..."
to meet his folks for the engagement
And what did you say to him?
I accepted his ring
What?
Yes Karan
What are you talking about?
- It's true
I can't believe our plan
has worked so soon!
"I'm so happy...
I'm so happy, Karan!"
My grandmother means everything to me.
I never hide anything from her
"Before I proposed to you,
I told her about us"
She wanted to take
a quick look at you
What are you wondering?
- Only... will your family accept me?
"Papa, when is Raj Uncle bringing
my new Aunt?"
Should be here soon
Raj is here
Welcome Priya
I'm fine
Uncle...
- Bless you
"How are you?
- Fine. Uncle, this is Priya"
Enough my child.
May you be happy
Priya this is Prithvi. My cousin.
- Namaste (Greetings)
Let's go inside. Come...
How are you grandma?
- I'm all right
"May you be happy, my child"
"Aunt, won't you introduce Priya?
- Why not?"
I'm your aunt.
- Namaste
Bless you. Nidhi is my daughter-in-law.
"These three...
- One minute, Mummy"
Let us introduce ourselves.
I'm Ashu
I'm Kiran.
- And I am Neha
No one introduced me to my Aunt!
- But you don't want to see her
Didn't you say so?
- Because Aunt Kiran told us...
that the new aunt has
big claws and big eyes
"Kiran, take Priya inside"
Raj my son...
- Yes?
"Wait, I must talk to you.
- Sure, grandma"
Yes and no won't do.
You're going to give us the details
How did you meet him?
- Was it love at first sight?
Love-at-first-sight happens only
in novels and films. Not in real life
As if you majored in love-life.
- At first sight...
Priya must've bowled him over
The children will be
your responsibility
Sure
"Namaste, grandma.
- Come Priya, sit"
You may leave.
I'll make tea
"Allow me...
- No, guests may not"
"Priya, you aren't getting engaged
to Raj"
"Not only my decision,
Raj has concurred too"
I've decided. No engagement.
The wedding is on the 5th of this month
"For the next six months,
there are no dates"
What are you thinking?
If you have any reservations...
No grandma... as you wish
"Come to me, my child"
Nidhi... cast away the evil eye
Your eyes will tell a tale...
"once, you and I are together"
Come with me...
"Come on, I'll give
you the time of your life"
"There are no villains
in our love story"
"And no tearjerkers,
no jealousies"
"Fun for all time to come,
and lots of love..."
"and lots of kissing
and lots of horseplay"
"You're going to make tongues wag,
you're going to make heads turn..."
"once, you and I are together"
Come with me...
"Come on, I'll give
you the time of your life"
I'm delighted for you
"You remind me
of your grandfather"
"Make him proud,
carry forth the family"
"When your bride is cross,
woo her with love"
"Grandma, that makes sense"
Your grandson is no less a man
"Next year, you're going to have
a great-grandson, I promise"
"Come on, I'll give
you the time of your life"
Shy? As if you're seeing me
for the first time?
"If you're so shy, how am I going to
fulfill the promise I made to grandma?"
What happened?
Why are you so apprehensive?
"Raj, I must tell you something.
- Tonight isn't for talking"
"Tonight is for love.
Whatever it is, tell me quickly"
When I saw you for the first time
I took a liking to you
Then you came close to me
and I went mad with joy
Then you proposed to me
and my every dream came true
But your status
made me conscious of mine
"I was always apprehensive,
lest I lose you"
"So I swore to myself,
I took an oath"
"If I ever married you, for a month
after the marriage, I'd stay a virgin"
"For me, it's a vow.
But if it's against your wishes..."
"I won't stop you,
because I am your wife"
How could you imagine
I wouldn't heed you?
We are man and wife.
Decisions we take about our lives...
"aren't yours or mine only,
these decisions are ours"
"I consider myself fortunate,
ours has been a union of hearts"
"For consummation, we have
a whole life ahead of us"
"If we're married, maybe
it's because of your vow"
"Karan, this is Priya.
- Is everything all right?"
Why aren't you returning my calls?
- I got married yesterday
"Your idea about the vow worked.
He agreed, he didn't even touch me"
I was sure it'd work!
Back in Malaysia...
that's just why I told you
not to wear shoes
I've taken just a big step
because I trust you
Now wait and watch
how I work out a divorce
And with all that money...
all our dreams will come true
When are you coming back to Mumbai?
- As soon as the rituals are over
Someone's coming.
I'm hanging up
You're becoming a billionaire
Wonderful plan
Looks just like yesterday... when you
joined our troupe. And in no time...
you were our leader. Then you seduced
the loveliest girl in the troupe
"And Priya, so blindly in love
so blind to all else"
Then you got her to seduce
Raj Singhania. And he married her
"Next, you're going to have her divorced.
Priya will receive millions in alimony"
You're about to become a billionaire.
Won't you make me a millionaire?
Are you blackmailing me?
- Am I blackmailing you?
"No, I'm only asking for my share.
5 million is all that I want"
2.5 for withholding information
from Raj Singhania
2.5 for saving you from the police.
- Police?
Only I know about Jojo Fernandes.
It was no accident. You killed him
"That night, you were so depressed
when you left. I followed you..."
"thinking you might commit suicide.
Instead, you killed him"
I thought you killed Jojo to ensure
that we kept the contract. I kept mum
But I know better.
You did it for your gain
"All right, you'll get the money.
But only after Priya's divorce"
"No, I want the money in 15 days.
Clever as you are, you'll find a way"
You serve grandma.
I'll serve the rest of them
"Come, sit"
"For the first time, you have cooked
in my kitchen. You must feed me"
Wonderful! I hope you fill Raj's life
with such sweetness
"Bless you, my child"
"In our family, brides and sons
are equals. It's a family tradition"
Thank you.
- May you be happy
Shares of the Singhania Group
of Companies. Worth 5 billion
"From now, you own these shares"
"Not only Raj's life partner, you're
a partner of the Singhania empire"
I'm certain that you will discharge
this responsibility with diligence
Our house
"Karan! Someday we'll own
a huge bungalow, several cars..."
we'll have everything
How do you like it?
Just like it was in my dreams
No one got wind of your wedding.
How come?
This party is meant
to inform everyone
After he has met his guests
Holding him here
would've been troublesome for you
No one from your troupe in tow?
- The troupe is gone
"Your boss has married our star.
- Something to be happy about, no?"
A small-time dancer is married
to such a big man
"So, stay away from Priya.
You might break her home"
How come?
- If she sees you...
she will take pity and she will
consider going back to the troupe
Think! She's a rich man's wife!
And how will he feel...
if she goes dancing in your troupe?
The relationship will get strained
"One-upmanship, guilt complexes?
Fights, quarrels, police, divorce..."
you'll wreck her home...
do you want to wreck her home?
Try to understand.
- I've come to congratulate her
To congratulate her?
What if it ends up in a homewreck?
You must be wondering
why I haven't brought you a gift?
You owe me two months' rent.
Consider it my gift
Many-many happy returns
Here's Karan I told you about
Were it not for him
Priya wouldn't have come into my life
"Raj, tell us how you felt when
you saw Priya for the first time"
That first meeting...
I couldn't take my eyes of her
And all I could think of was...
I'd bear a grouse if there was
anyone else like her on earth
anyone else who liked her
Now that you're married
what's the feeling like?
May I?
You walked into my life...
and my life...
oh how you changed my life
With your love...
you changed my life
No more can I bear...
anyone else...
"who'd die for you, as I'd die"
"No, not even a touch..."
I cannot even bear...
"to hear someone else
talking about you"
You came close to me...
and my life...
oh how you have changed my life
"If even the mirror
praises your beauty..."
I'd feel like smashing mirrors too
"You are my obsession,
in you I find my peace"
"I'm crazy about you,
and I don't care who says what"
You drove me crazy...
and you changed my life forever
You walked into my life...
and my life...
"oh how you have changed
my life forever"
"What a wife! Newly-wedded brides
wake up early, they make tea..."
then they wake their husbands.
And you?
I'll make tea right away.
- I was just joking
"Every morning, I want only..."
"Curfew on kisses too?
Well, never mind"
"It's a matter of only a fortnight.
Afterwards, I want a handsome son"
And a daughter... just like you.
Followed by...
maybe a cricket
or football team?
It's a matter of only a fortnight.
I want a handsome son and a daughter
Welcome Mrs Singhania!
I've been wondering how to meet you
Karan! We must speak!
- Step inside first
Look! Isn't that the kind
of house we always dreamt about?
"Huge lawn in front,
six-or-seven-roomed, sea-facing"
They guy who owns it will sell out
for just a 100 million
"After your divorce, we're going to be
rich! This house will be our first buy"
But how will it come to be?
Raj loves me dearly
After the wedding I was to start
quarreling with him
But what am I to say?
- You needn't do a thing
I've got a lawyer working
on your divorce already
"We're going to court, claiming that
after a fortnight of being married..."
you're still a virgin
"All you got to prove in court is,
your husband Raj Singhania is impotent"
No reason to quarrel. I think you
won't even have to go to court
Raj Singhania would never want his
family affairs brought out in public
He will pre-empt you from going to
court. He will give you a divorce
Be here at two tomorrow to sign
the papers. I'll handle the rest
"We claim that after a fortnight of
being married, you're still a virgin"
It's a matter of only a fortnight.
I want a handsome son and a daughter
"All you got to prove in court is,
your husband Raj Singhania is impotent"
Is everything all right?
We suspect an internal injury
in the cranial area
But we are unable to confirm it yet.
In the next 24 hours...
"unless she comes around,
she might slip into a coma"
"All you got to prove in court is,
your husband Raj Singhania is impotent"
He's impotent
Raj Singhania would never want his
family affairs brought out in public
He will pre-empt you from going to
court. He will give you a divorce
Your wife has come around
You're perfectly all right now
"Doctor, where is my husband?
- Ever since you were brought in..."
he has been here. Last night
he seemed quite anxious for you
How is my wife now?
She has also cleared all the tests.
Shock was the reason for the blackout
You may take her home.
All she needs is rest
"You look relaxed, you've slept
through the last 24 hours"
Are you all right?
I'm fine
"Then I'll tell the doctor,
I'm carrying my bride home right away"
Wonderful! You can't even cross
a street? What were you upto?
Thanks to your accident
everything is undone
By now Raj would've been delivered
the notice. It's all gone haywire now
All because of you
"Not for once, have you asked me
how I am"
Why are you talking like this?
You think I don't care for you?
"Whatever I'm doing,
is for your sake, darling"
Now forget all this and get well soon.
And come over to sign the papers
Now take rest. I'm leaving
"Yes Harry, tell me.
- 15 days are over"
Are you paying up?
Or do I go to Raj Singhania?
You don't know about Priya's accident?
- Find someone else for giving excuses
Dilly-dallying over instalment one?
What happens to full-and-final payment?
What instalment? 50 million was agreed.
- Past tense
50 million is first instalment.
I'll settle full-and-final later
"And listen, this evening I'm at
the gym. Get the cash and come over"
Bad times
That was instalment one
And here's full-and-final settlement
"Mr Raj Singhania isn't in the office,
leave your message after the beep"
"Mr Singhania, this is Harry.
Karan just tried to kill me"
Priya is in league with him and they
are about to con you out of your money
Karan killed Jojo Fernandes
right in front of my eyes
By the time you get this message
I might be dead
How are you feeling now?
- I'm fine
I'll take breakfast
at the dining table with Raj
But Mr Raj isn't having breakfast.
- Why?
I don't know. He hasn't eaten anything
these last two days
Hi Priya... come
Mrs Braganza was saying that you
haven't eaten in the last two days
"Forget about me. Tell me,
how are you feeling?"
You haven't answered my question
If you can keep such a tough vow
for my sake...
"for your sake,
can I not go hungry for a few days?"
"When I saw you in the hospital
lying senseless, I was afraid..."
I'd lose you
"I was desperate... and I thought...
why not give it a try, your way?"
And look... here you are with me
in the pink of health
"Tell me...
all about love..."
"what relationships
are all about"
You have made me realise...
and my life...
oh how you've changed my life
Put Priya on the line
She has gone to see Dr Joshi.
- Why what's wrong? Is she all right?
"She's fine, but she mentioned
a routine check-up"
"I've been waiting for you forever!
Come on, the divorce papers are ready"
Only your signature is needed.
- I haven't come to sign the papers
I won't do the mistakes
we were about to commit
What are you saying?
- I can't deceive Raj
What's come over you all of a sudden?
Do you sympathise with Raj?
He has enough money. Even if
we take away a billion or two...
"it won't make a difference to him.
- This isn't about money, Karan"
It's about trust that
husband reposes in wife
I cannot betray
my husband's trust
Husband?
A few sweet nothings...
and he becomes your husband?
- He became my husband...
"the day I married him,
even if it was for deceit"
Now I realise how significant
those marriage vows are
"What about the promises you gave me?
- Yes, promises between lovers"
"Now I stand before you,
another man's wife"
I'm so close to success!
You can't betray me now
You must divorce Raj.
- I can't...
"You got to do it, baby"
You can't ruin me like this
"Look at me.
You love me, it's me you desire"
No Karan
I'm in love with Raj.
I'd die rather than divorce him
"I'm leaving, Karan"
Wait Priya
"Forgive me, I've been selfish"
So what if I didn't realise
my dreams?
All your dreams have come true
"After this day, I shall never
come between you and Raj"
"If you are happy with Raj,
then I'm happy for your sake"
"Harry, I can't give you
the 5 million"
Try to understand...
Priya isn't getting divorced
How will Priya get hold
of so much money?
I can't ask her
for her jewellery
Harry! You aren't going to Raj!
Get it? No! You won't go to Raj
"What happened?
- Priya, I hid something from you"
Harry knows all about us. The cur!
He's blackmailing me for 5 million
Unless he is paid by tomorrow
he's going to tell Raj everything
What?
- Don't worry
"I won't let him ruin your life,
and I'll do anything for that"
No Karan! You'll do nothing wrong.
- Where will the money come from?
"Wasn't Harry asking for jewellery?
- Yes, but I won't..."
"Look, there's no other way out.
I'll be here at four tomorrow"
With the jewellery
"I've been waiting for you, for ages.
Your cellphone was switched off"
Is everything all right?
- I went to see Dr Joshi
Mr Braganza told me about the check-up.
Then I called him and he said...
you never went there.
- I bumped into Uncle Rustom on the way
He persuaded me to go home with him.
- So what's there to hide?
Did you think I'd be angry about it?
Nothing about you can make me angry
Over nothing at all?
- You speak as if...
you have the darkest secrets
hidden away?
No one can fathom a woman's heart
"You are the only one in my heart,
only you"
"Look Mr Rustomjee, this is an office.
You can't throw your weight around"
"I'm not throwing my weight around,
I only want to see Raj"
He won't have the time in 5 days
to talk to freeloaders like you
What do you mean freeloaders?
Do you take me for a beggar?
Move on
You can't throw your weight around!
There he is...
Hello Rustom Uncle...
- Raj my boy...
"He was in his office,
must've been busy"
Come Uncle
"Sit, what will you have?
- Tea give me dysentery"
Coffee gives me constipation.
And no cold drinks. Doctor's orders
So I stick to the night-time whisky.
- And what brings you here?
Having survived 30 years
of Shirin's bickerings...
now I must celebrate the marriage
anniversary. Small party. On Tuesday
I came to give you the invitation.
- Why did you take the trouble?
Priya visited you yesterday.
You could've told her
Yesterday? I've never seen her face
ever after you married her
Priya said she visited you yesterday.
- Joking is a habit with her
She must've been pulling your leg
"Excuse me, I must leave
...lots more to invite"
May I speak to Raj Singhania
- Your name?
"There's a man who wants to talk about
your wife. Says, it's urgent"
Put him on
I want to pass on some information
about your wife
Who are you?
- A well-wisher
You wife is having an affair with
Karan. It began before you married her
Don't disconnect
"She's squandering your money,
she's giving it all away to him"
"If you don't believe, go over
to Karan's house at 4pm today"
You will find Priya in his arms
"Priya, I'm so worried!
Harry called me again"
All last night...
I couldn't sleep... I was worried
...what if you never came?
I'm leaving.
- Priya...
My best wishes
for your new life
"As for me, you will always live
in my heart... as a good friend"
I went to see Dr Joshi.
- He told me you never went there
I bumped into Uncle Rustom on the way.
He persuaded me to go home with him
Yesterday? I've never seen her face
ever after you married her
So I took an oath.
If I ever married you...
"for a month after the marriage,
I'd stay a virgin"
You wife is having an affair with
Karan. It began before you married her
Sir... you?
Once you barged into my office
without permission
"Today, I'm here"
I was looking for a magazine
to while away my time...
and I found this file of yours
You researched me thoroughly
"Not someone rich, I want to marry
a girl of character"
You have come to my house for the
first time. What can I do for you?
You got me to marry Priya.
What better can you do?
So I came to do something for you
Nice
Go on
"In myplace, if your wife was deceiving
you in league with her lover..."
what would you do?
- I?
I would've thrown her out.
I would've divorced her
But I'll do nothing of the sort
Much sets us apart. You can't even
afford a decent place to live in
Were it not for the sympathies
of the owner of this house...
"who let you stay on,
you'd be out on the streets"
I also live
in your wife's heart
Nothing can be more shameful
for a husband...
than a wife who prefers
a lover to her husband
Lover...
Iover is one who will
gouge out the eyes...
that even dare to ogle
at the object of his love
"You're no lover,
you're a pimp"
And I'm here to give you your cut.
Not that you deserve even that
But this concerns Raj Singhania's wife.
So I'm giving you 500 million
To get out of Priya's life?
- No
To kill Priya
"For your sake, she has played
with my emotions"
She has ridiculed the trust
that my family reposed in her
"I loved her more than dear life.
Not anymore, now I hate her"
"Only after you have killed her,
my heart will find peace"
How could you imagine I'd do this?
No imaginations. I know
you will do this job
"If Priya deceived me,
she did it for your sake"
So you got to do the killing
"Mr Singhania, this is Harry.
Karan just tried to kill me"
"They are about to con you
out of your money"
"Karan killed Jojo Fernandes
right in front of my eyes"
"By the time you get this message
I might be dead"
You have only two options
One takes you to the gallows.
The other makes you a millionaire
"If you want to become a millionaire,
come over to my house at five sharp"
I will give you an advance.
100 million
And I'll tell you when and how
to commit the murder
"Rather late, aren't you?
- There was an urgent meeting"
"You look disturbed.
- Yes, there was this deal"
I wagered my life and it's failed.
- How?
Someone very close to me
has deceived me...
someone I'd trust
as much as I trust you
But deceit can't last forever.
Now I know who it is
"Only a matter of a few days now,
I'll set everything right"
"Oh yes, Uncle Rustom's anniversary.
The party is tomorrow"
Make sure you go.
- Won't you come?
No. I got one last meeting to attend
to square off this deal
"But you must go. Else,
Uncle Rustom will mind"
"In that dress, you look lovely!
- How are you, Kajal?"
What have you been doing?
- After the troupe broke up...
I took up a job in Calcutta.
I'm here just for this party
I wanted to meet all of you.
Are you in touch with the others?
"And what's Karan upto? Poor thing,
he must be upset about the break-up"
A hundred million is lots of money.
That's why...
What are you ogling at?
Mansions like these are built upon...
"the business of hard work,
not pimping"
Wonderful! I'm getting to learn
It was great having you here.
- And Raj never came?
"He would've come,
but he has an important meeting"
You will kill Priya tomorrow
Tomorrow is Friday. Only Priya
and Mrs Braganza will be at home
At 4:30 sharp Mrs Braganza leaves
for the church
She uses a remote control device
to open the gates
"The gate takes 30 seconds to shut.
By then, you should get in"
"And remember, the boundaries
are secured by alarms"
"Priya, what's wrong with your mood?
- Nothing, really"
"You must be hiding something from me.
Look, I'm your best friend"
"Share your woes with friends,
unburden yourself. What happened?"
A tiff with Raj?
I'll leave this window open
for you to enter
"You enter the hall,
then you hide behind that curtain"
"At 4:45 sharp, I'll place a call
on that telephone"
Priya will come to receive the phone.
As she takes the call...
the phone mustn't be disconnected.
I want to hear her every dying scream
Such devious planning? I'm glad
you broke ties with Karan
But I'm still hiding it from Raj.
I think I'm still deceiving him
"To hide one lie, I've been lying
again and again"
I don't know what to do.
- Between husband and wife...
there must be no secrets.
How long will you go on lying?
You must tell him before he comes to
know. I'm sure he will forgive you
"Raj, here's something I must tell you
even if I might lose you forever"
Because no husband who has heard this
will forgive his wife
"Raj, I have deceived you.
Before we were married..."
"I didn't love you,
I was in love with Karan"
His every word I trusted
Then Karan showed me a dream;
to make his dream come true...
"I married you, with the intention
of divorcing you..."
so that Karan and I could grab
your money
But now I have broken
all ties with Karan
"In my heart, in my every breath,
yours is the only name that lingers"
"I do not deserve your sympathies.
Yet, after you have heard it all..."
"if you think you can forgive me,
just give me a call"
"Tonight, come home to your bride,
not to Priya"
If you cannot forgive me...
I will depart from this world
in peace knowing...
"if only for a day, I have been yours,
in heart and soul"
Put it down
You know what day it's today?
- I know. The month is over
"Tonight, I'm giving you
a big surprise"
"What more pleasant a surprise for me,
than having you to myself?"
How could I not be yours?
Wasn't it for my sake
that you took such a vow?
The month is finished
But every moment till tonight
is going to haunt me
Thank God you aren't hurt.
- Breaking glass is a good omen
I imagine I'm going to be given
my heart's wish
May God give you your every wish
Why are you looking at me like that?
That innocence writ on your face
that drove me crazy... is still there
Saxena... you?
Aren't you supposed to report on the
textile mills at today's board meeting?
I came over to discuss
a few details
Singhania Cements. The 2-year old
baby in the Singhania group
Singhania Cements has achieved
a turnover exceeding 15 billion...
a 150 percent growth
over last year
Our share value has doubled
Dressed like a bride? You look exotic.
Something special today?
"Yes, it's the most important day
in my life"
"At the church, I'll pray,
may God save you from the evil eye"
The textiles unit has just bagged
a 5-year contract for army uniforms
I think the meeting has produced
desired results
"No Saxena, I've only mooted the plan.
It remains to be executed"
Raj...
"Raj, here's something I must tell you
even if I might lose you forever"
Because no husband who has heard this
will forgive his wife
Why are you killing me?
Who are you?
Then Karan showed me a dream; to make
his dream come true I married you
Don't kill me
Don't... oh what have I done?
"I do not deserve your sympathies.
Yet, after you have heard it all..."
"if you think you can forgive me,
just give me a call"
"Tonight, come home to your bride,
not to Priya"
"If you cannot forgive me, I will depart
from this world in peace knowing..."
"if only for a day, I have been yours,
in heart and soul"
Why didn't you tell me before?
Your wife has survived
a murderous assault
The assassin has been killed
Will you please come with me
The break-in shows that he knew
his way around your house
Take a look at the corpse.
You might know him
Remove the shroud
Do you know him?
- No
Come Mr Karan
He is the one
who saved your wife
Had he not arrived in the nick of time
and killed the assassin...
the unthinkable might've happened.
- It's the Lord above who sent me here
Do you remember telling me...
"that mansions like these are built
on businesses, not out of pimping?"
"So I thought,
how about some business?"
You wanted me to kill Priya
in order to frame me
I sent in a substitute.
Now I've got you framed...
for some more profit
out of business
"You seem agitated.
Relax, we'll talk later"
We've found out about the attacker.
He was a small-time thief
"A sum of 500,000 was recovered
from his residence"
We are investigating
where he got so much money from
I'll keep you informed
about developments
Yes... grandma?
- Such a grave incident...
and you don't even give us a call?
- I didn't want you to get anxious
You will return to Jaipur forthwith
and bring Priya along
Thank God Karan turned up in the
nick of time and he saved Priya
"Karan?
- Yes, he's in Jaipur on business"
He's right here. One minute
Karan...
- Yes?
Come here
Talk to Raj
"My friend, how are you?
- How is Priya?"
What are you doing there?
I'm here on business...
it's the deal I told you about
Why don't you come over to Jaipur?
I'm coming
He's coming
Priya and Raj
How is it going?
Good to have you here
"Take Priya inside...
cast away the evil eye. Go on, dear"
Has the police found out the identity
of the man who attacked Priya?
"They say, he was a thief.
- I can't accept that"
It seemed to me as if
he was bent upon killing her
"Luckily, I landed there
in the nick of time"
"Son, we are indebted to you.
- No obligations"
Once we have agreed upon the terms
and conditions of our business...
"consider the debt paid. Else,
I can always fall back upon you, no?"
Get fresh Raj. I'll see you
in my room
Welcome
How dare you come here?
If Harry's cassette
gives you this attitude...
"remember, you can't prove that
I killed Harry using that cassette"
Murder may be assumed
only after the recovery of a corpse
But the corpse... has vanished
"As for Jojo's murder, even the police
think it was an accident"
Raj Singhania... my plan for
framing you was perfect
Only Priya deceived me
You can forgive her? That's very well.
But I can't forgive her
So when you came offering me
the contract to kill Priya...
I found another way
to make my plan succeed
"You played an audio cassette,
didn't you? Let me show you a video"
You will kill Priya tomorrow
Tomorrow is Friday. Only Priya
and Mrs Braganza will be at home
I'll leave this window open
for you to enter
"At 4:45 sharp, I'll dial that number.
Priya will come to receive the phone"
The phone mustn't be disconnected.
I want to hear her every dying scream
How do you like my video episode?
I culled that idea from TV
"In fact, it's going to be
a great hit on TV"
Now what?
"Conspiracy for murder...
at least 7-8 years, guaranteed"
But that's only what happens to you.
Think! What happens to your family?
Who will ever marry
your sisters? Not I
What about those kids? Won't they
ask you why you're handcuffed?
Finding answers could be tough.
And grandma... poor grandma
The shame of it will drive her
to suicide
You gave me two options.
I'll give you three
"One, divorce Priya. Alimony, 1 billion"
"Two, jail. Three, kill yourself"
"If you like option One, a divorce deed
will be ready for you tomorrow"
Come over to Jaigarh fort
for the signing formalities
"Yes, make sure you bring
the balance 40 million you owe me"
It's only for the expenses
until the divorce goes through
Welcome... welcome
What do I look like?
Some businessman... like you?
Haven't you brought the money?
"Anyway, I can recover from you
anytime"
"The divorce papers, please"
My security
"Nowadays for a businessman,
danger is lurking everywhere"
"Telephone calls, threats,
who knows who might do what?"
"Here, sign. I must get it
registered in court today"
I have decided.
I'm going to jail
But not for 7 years. For 14 years
I'm going to kill you
Good you brought them along.
They can carry your corpse
I didn't want
any more of these killings
But a moron like you
won't let me live like a gentleman
Now you die
Priya still thinks I am a gentleman.
Today or tomorrow...
she will come to me
and she will bring your wealth along
"Wonderful to have you here, Priya!
You don't know..."
what a rogue your husband is!
The man who attacked you...
was no burglar. He's the man
who sent him
He wants to kill you!
I swear... I swear
And I have the proof
I saw the evidence for myself
when you were blackmailing Raj
I also know how many men
you killed for your motives
"And I thought you're a good friend,
a sympathiser. But now I know..."
"how greedy, how selfish you are.
No, I'm not coming to you"
I regret that I ever had anything
to do with a scoundrel like you