(MUSIC PLAYING ON GRAMOPHONE)
PERCIVAL:
All the world's a stage,
and all the men and women
merely players.
They have their exits
and their entrances,
all with
a specific role to play.
Even at a funeral.
I was searching
for my role in life.
You get one shot.
Can't go back
and change anything.
Strange, all these people
showing up to see a dead guy.
Folks from small towns
are always up for a show.
Even at a funeral.
I know because I spent
most of my life
in this very room.
Different faces, but always
the same characters.
Some full of regret,
feeling trapped,
in need of something
outside this small town.
That was the day
me and Rooster met.
It was the first time Rooster
had ever seen a real dead guy,
and the first time
I'd ever touched one.
Of course,
Rooster put me up to it.
It was
his Uncle Eddie's funeral.
He was like
a father to Rooster.
He was a classy gangster.
And so was his partner, Spats.
Son,
this was your uncle's.
Don't never lose it.
I won't.
FLASK: How you doing?
Are you ready?
We about to have a ball.
I'm your best friend.
PERCIVAL: They were
high rollers with fast cash...
Go on, take a whiff.
Don't be shy.
... and faster ladies.
Stinky.
And, man,
talk about the ladies.
(RHYTHMICALLY)
Talk about the ladies.
Man, talk about the ladies.
See? Pink satin,
just like I told you.
You owe me five cents. Pay up.
Them some sexy drawers!
PERCIVAL: My father said
Rooster was trouble,
and didn't want me
playing with him
or anybody else,
for that matter.
I pretty much lived
my life inside,
except for the days
I visited my mother.
(CHILDREN PLAYING)
My Auntie Belle made me
keep up with my lessons.
Percival.
Pay attention, Percival.
It's right in front of you.
B flat.
(GRUNTING)
(BELL RINGING)
Hey, baby.
Stop! Police! Freeze!
Come and get me, copper.
(LAUGHING)
(PLAYING PIANO)
PERCIVAL: Piano was my thing.
Rooster preferred
singing and gambling.
Praise Jesus.
Today is my lucky day,
fellows.
Y'all owe me some money.
Pay up.
Collect my money,
if you know what I mean.
PERCIVAL: But my Auntie Belle
didn't approve.
Let's get out of here!
That didn't matter
much to Rooster.
He never listened
to anybody anyway.
Eventually, my father started
preparing me to take over
the family business.
PERCY: Thing is,
make the deceased look
like they're at peace.
Go on. Go on. Go.
Peaceful.
Not happy.
PERCIVAL: I learned
my family business,
and Rooster learned his.
Seventy-five bottles
this month.
Bootlegging.
That's $48.
$46.50.
Seventy-five bottles
at 62 cents each is...
$46.50.
Boy's too smart
for his own britches.
(LAUGHING)
SPATS: Good looking out, man.
How the hell
am I going to make it
to Biloxi by sundown?
I got an idea.
ROOSTER: We can hide
the bottles in here.
(GRUNTS)
Shit. Think he heard us?
I don't know.
Let's go check it out.
Come on.
(SNORING)
He'll be awake by 8:00.
PERCIVAL: We were from
two totally different sides
of the track,
with one common ground.
You got to get it
back by 8:00.
I'll have it back. I promise.
Music.
Here.
God don't make no mistakes.
Ain't nothing slick
to a can of oil.
The records got old.
So did me and Rooster.
(COW MOOING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
PHOTOGRAPHER: All right,
now that's perfect. Okay, now.
Give me a big smile.
One, two...
(BABY CRYING)
One more time. And cheese.
That's perfect.
Man, Rooster.
You got a big family now.
Come on, Rooster,
you can smile
better than that.
Ain't y'all pretty?
Man, take the picture.
One, two...
Cheese.
PERCIVAL: Rooster had to
take care of his family,
and I had to
take care of mine.
10:00 a.m. Damn shame.
One, two, three.
Ain't y'all finished yet?
By day, I helped my father
work in the mortuary.
PERCY:
Get that carnation right, now.
Yes, sir.
But by night,
Rooster got me a part-time gig
playing at a local juke joint
where he worked,
Church.
That's what we called
the place, but it was
anything but that.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
TAFFY:
How y'all feeling tonight?
MAN 1:
Depends on what you're doing.
I don't give a damn.
MAN 2:
I'd be your bra right now!
WOMAN: She ain't nothing.
(SINGING) Mama
I've been away from home
To join the circus
MAN 3: Man, look at them
hams on that chippie!
MAN 4: Save me
one of them drinks, Taffy.
Papa
I'm going to the place
where the crowd gets down
(ALL CHEERING)
Gets down
Sister
I know that there are lions,
tigers and bears
I'll be safe and sure to
call y'all when I get there
Yo, yo, fix me another drink.
CHORUS: (SINGING)
Greatest show on earth
WOMAN 2: Ain't you had
enough to drink?
TAFFY: Shut up
while I'm singing.
Step right up, step right up.
Come one, come all.
What you want
CHORUS: What you need
TAFFY: What you need
Got some coke
Wanna drink?
Got some weed
All that shit
I've got it, yeah
I've got it
I got it
Renée, take your brother.
Well, hush.
ZORA: I'm fed up
with this, Rooster.
And it's starting to take
a toll on me and the kids.
And we ain't just gonna sit
at home while you romp around
every night in this...
Cover them ears.
Whorehouse.
Zora, for the last time,
this is a respectable
business,
and I make good money.
Now, you know
I got responsibilities.
Responsibilities?
That's bullshit.
When was the last time
you been to a real church,
Rooster?
You can't even remember, huh?
It's been so long.
I got...
You need the Spirit
in your life.
You need to start spending
some time with the kids.
Tell you what.
Why don't I take you shopping
in the morning?
You and the kids.
Would you like that?
I got $100 love over here.
I got $1,000 love.
Your name must be
Bob or David.
You got all that
fucking grease in your hair.
Why don't you
go wash your hair?
Yes, yes!
CHORUS: (SINGING)
Greatest show on earth
TAFFY: Get your damn hands
off my bottle.
Barbecue.
That is barbecue right there.
What the hell you looking at?
I wish you'd get
that song right.
Always drunk.
I should set her ass on fire.
Girl, now what you mad at?
You did good.
PERCIVAL: That's Monk.
He works backstage,
but no one knows what he does
besides borrow money.
Taffy, you sho' nuff gorgeous.
Love the hair.
Loan me a nickel note,
dime note, two cents,
whatever.
Go on, Monk.
You still owe me
from last week.
You better pay me.
And that's Ace.
Ace owns Church.
He liked to be
called Sunshine Ace,
but most folks
just called him Ace.
Goddamn Rooster!
Unless they wanted something.
Sunshine Ace!
Just the man
I'm looking for.
Listen to me,
you son of a big jackass,
you ain't gonna get nothing
from me but the what for.
The what for?
Yeah, when I put my foot
in your ass, you gonna say,
"What for? What for?"
Now move.
You're $85 in the hole!
Come on, Sawed-Off.
ALL: Rooster! Rooster!
MAN: Come on, man.
DIRECTOR: Man, I hope
they don't start
throwing bottles again.
(ALL BOOING)
Holy moly!
Rooster's late again.
Y'all jackasses,
play something quick.
Like what?
He ain't even here yet, man.
I don't care what you play.
All I know is I got
a house full of angry people,
and ain't none of
these niggers getting
their money back.
All right, Baby Blue,
you're on, man.
Jackass!
One, two, three, four.
PERCIVAL: Suddenly, I was
forced into the hot seat.
I hated the spotlight.
It always gave me the jitters.
MAN 1: Somebody
owe us something.
MAN 2: Now I done
paid my damn money!
(CROWD JEERING)
MUSIC NOTES: I told you
to bring the good songs.
You better come
harder than that, sweetie!
TAFFY: This ain't no mortuary!
MAN: Keep your hand
on the keys, man.
MUSIC NOTES: Now,
y'all gonna throw up.
Look at the keys.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Jackass gonna get my club
torn to pieces.
Hi, daddy.
Hey.
ROOSTER: Kids,
y'all be good tonight.
Mind your mother.
You want to go
shopping tomorrow?
KIDS: Yes.
Okay. Go on
and give me a kiss.
GIRL 1: Bye, Daddy.
GIRL 2: Bye, Daddy.
Love you.
How's my tie?
Perfect.
I'll see you in the morning.
ZORA: I'll be glad
when the police come and
bust this place up, Rooster.
And don't you come calling me
to bail you out.
Girl, bye.
Here comes the family man.
Shit. Family man?
More like bow tie pimp.
Late again, as usual.
(ALL CLAMORING)
MAN: Oh, hell, man.
He's going to throw up again?
WOMAN: I'm in here!
No, oh, man. No.
Watch out, ladies.
He gonna blow.
(ALARM BUZZING)
Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls,
give it up for
the amazing Rooster.
(ALL CHEERING)
Evening, ladies.
Hey.
Sho' nuff looking
right tonight.
Thanks.
Just gotta do one thing.
What's that, baby?
Don't show so much so soon.
You got to give a man
something to dream about.
That's right.
Okay, Rooster.
Okay, my ass.
Bye, daddy.
Rooster.
Ain't he fine?
FLASK: Riding so smooth, baby.
I'm as smooth as
a baby's bottom is.
No, he didn't.
That's disgusting.
Thanks for holding it
down for me, boy.
No problem.
(BAND PLAYING)
MONK: In the groove.
Too smooth.
Don't you mess with me.
Showtime.
(ALL CHEERING)
CHORUS: (SINGING)
Crocodile on my feet
Fox fur on my back
Bow tie round my neck
That's why they call me
the gangsta mack
in the Cadillac
Nasty Noompsy Nightingale
Fresh in that tuxedo
Cummerbund with no suspenders
My torpedo, your libido
Need to chat
CHORUS: Chip, chop it up,
shoot the breeze
I'm your R-O-L-A-l-D-S
Release the squeeze
or release the keys
To the shackles on her wrist
She can tackle some of this
Smack on smack
on some of this, Dick Tracy
Arrest her, book her,
fingerprint your hooker
You took her to the club
and now her body's
full of liquor
Off that butterscotch schnapps
and Baileys Irish Cream
She's a damsel in distress
Impressed with stylish things
What you mean?
CHORUS: Chip, chop it up,
shoot the breeze
In the parking lot we primp
Crooked booty
to the scene where we...
CHORUS: Crocodile on my feet
Fox fur on my back
Bow tie round my neck
That's why they call me
the gangsta mack
In the Cadillac, yeah
Oh, Lord,
how could it be so hard
To put on a pair of panties
Much less a pair of jeans
or the leotards
I got to start
by complimenting you
on your physique
CHORUS: On your physique
You unique, you best believe
I'm gonna skeet once I speak
Spoke, spit, spatter,
spat and I macked her
just like that
But it'd take
years of perseverance
and experience to get that cat
So why don't I chase
this Hennessy down
with some of that?
On your back,
like a cheerleader
missing the final stack
CHORUS: As we strut,
skip the line
through the glass
window glance
We look fine, right on time
As we step in the place
The nursery's crunk,
we've come to play
Oh, everybody's watching
'Cause them furs
just hit the dirt
While them gators creeping
(CLAMORING)
Crawling oh-so-wicked
across that floor
To the VIP where
we proceed to give you
what you need
Throw your hands up
if you feel me
WOMAN 1: Careful.
WOMAN 2: Go, daddy!
'Cause you're well-designed
Bow tie!
Like the finest wine
Feel good to be fly
Bow tie!
So don't you ask me why
I got the ladies in line
Bow tie!
Come on over here.
Welcome to the Church.
So raise your hands to the sky
Come on, pull up a chair.
Just in time to see
your boy do his thing.
Got my eye on business
Don't jive with me,
jive with me
Got my eye on business
Don't jive with me,
jive with me, sucker
Got my eye on business
Don't jive with me,
jive with me
Got my eye on business
Don't jive with me,
jive with me, sucker
Got my eye on business
Don't jive with me,
jive with me
Got my eye on business
Don't jive with me,
jive with me, sucker
(ALL CHEERING)
ALL:
Rooster! Rooster! Rooster!
Hey, boy.
Good show there, Rooster.
Glad you liked it.
Rooster,
y'all cut a fool tonight!
Damn, girl.
Hi.
Ace.
You almost got
my goddamn place torn up!
Hey, Rose. Gorgeous dress.
Thanks for noticing, sweetie.
ACE: Hey...
Why don't you go chase
a couple of drinks while me
and the boys chew the fat?
Sure, daddy.
(EXCLAIMING)
(GRUNTING)
Anything for you, Rooster.
Taste like chitlins.
Looking dapper as ever.
How you been, Spats?
Never bad, son. Never bad.
Got you a little present.
And I appreciate this already.
ACE: Hey, Trumpy!
I guess they let anybody
into the Church.
(CACKLING)
Ace.
Oh, you taught him
how to speak.
(ACE LAUGHING)
Nice. But the name
is Sunshine Ace, nigger.
Business look good.
I'm impressed.
We got the prettiest girls
for more than
100 square miles.
We're selling more
hot sauce than anybody
this side of the Mason-Dixon.
Ain't that right, sweetheart?
(LAUGHING)
It's been like that
for the past three months,
every night.
This shit here
sells like canned pussy.
(CHUCKLING)
I bet you thought
I was gonna say "hotcakes,"
didn't you?
Bravo, bravo!
Baby Blue,
you have done it again.
Monk, not right now.
You scared
all the women away from me.
Honey Bun and China!
Don't you know I've been
working on them two broads
for three weeks,
and you go and heave
right in front of them,
and blew the whole night.
"I don't know, Monk.
He kind of strange."
"No, girls,
you got him all wrong.
"He's a little incentric.
"Classy!"
You're a sad case, man.
Maybe you right.
The word is "eccentric."
I know the word.
What make you think I want
any of one of these floozies?
(SHUSHING)
Don't you want
somebody worth having?
Ain't nobody talking
about getting hitched!
I just wanna have
a good time.
I know one thing
for sure, Percy.
Better get on
one of these old girls,
'cause nothing will
just drop out the sky!
Damn fool.
Two. Three.
That's what I'm talking about.
MAN: Lord.
MONK: Good gracious.
Lord, Lord, Lord.
Fellows,
would you look at that there?
(SNIFFING)
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Have you ever...
Gentlemen.
Good Lord God almighty.
You look like the man
I'm here to see.
No, I'm sorry, ma'am,
I'm just a piano player.
Well, listen, piano player,
I just traveled 19 hours from
Saint Louis in a coach seat,
and Angel Davenport
don't ride coach.
Angel Davenport?
(WOMEN CHATTERING)
The Angel Davenport?
In the flesh, honey.
May I make your acquaintance?
Monk S. Dubois.
The "S" stands for Sherman.
What brings you
to town, Spats?
I wanted you both
to hear it from me.
I'm getting out the business.
(LAUGHING)
Come on, man.
What's the play, man?
This ain't no play, Ace.
I'm tired.
If I don't get out now,
I never will.
Business is doing so good
I can retire, give everybody
a piece of the rock.
For the right price.
(LAUGHING)
Good Lord, girl,
you finer than all outdoors!
Shit, girl, you a star!
MONK: Of course,
we weren't expecting you
till next week.
(WHISTLES)
Well, my show in Saint Louis
finally came to an end.
Three months of back-to-back
shows in that city
would wear anybody out.
Now I told my agent, Nathan,
I needed a change of scenery.
He said, "Why not head on
down to Idlewild early?"
Thought I'd come and see
what the big fuss in Idlewild,
Georgia, is all about.
I must admit,
so far I'm not impressed.
(WOMEN EXCLAIMING)
Twenty-five thousand?
Plus the $1,250 you owe me
from the last shipment.
That's a heavy load, Spats.
Twenty-five large buy you
a direct line to my supplier
and my entire clientele.
Now if I can't
find me a buyer,
then I gotta turn my operation
over to someone I can trust,
in which case,
I become a stockholder
and collect my dividends.
You always been good
with numbers, Rooster.
How about it?
Know what?
Maybe you right, Spats.
I am good with numbers.
I'm going to mull that over.
ACE: Like hell you will!
I've got your 25 large.
And I got a big plan
that's going to bring more
people in here than ever.
So, if you allow me,
I'd like to make
a toast to you.
To fast women, fast money,
and new beginnings.
The hell with that.
To 25 large.
Where is this
Mr. Sunshine Ace?
He sent me a coach ticket.
That was not part of
our agreement.
A lady has standards
to maintain, you know.
Well, I'm sure that it...
It says right here
in the telegram,
"First class."
Don't say nothing
about no coach.
What does it say?
First class.
That's right. First class.
Right there in bold writing.
So how the hell
did I get coach?
Well, look at
Miss Goody Two-Shoes.
She look better
in the pictures,
if you ask me.
(LAUGHS)
Excuse me.
Do I know you?
Hell, no. But if you
fix yourself up a little...
Taffy!
Miss Angel Davenport. Lord.
Don't try it, man.
I just traveled 19 hours
on a stinking train
from Saint Louis
in a lousy coach seat.
I deeply regret that.
Some jackass
didn't follow my orders.
I did exactly what you...
(GRUNTING EMPHATICALLY)
But now that you're here,
Sunshine Ace will take
real good care of you.
Just as soon as we take care
of the legal paperwork.
Now I just so happen
to have your contract.
Now, never mind
all this fine print.
Them just the details.
Sign by the "X."
Give me a pen.
Here. Right there.
Yup.
Now that the legal stuff
is out the way, you can
have anything you want.
Anything?
Anything. Just you name it.
White carnations.
You heard the lady.
Got you.
And my own dressing room.
ACE:
And her own dressing room.
Taffy, come here.
The rest of you niggers,
get back to work.
Come on, Sawed-Off.
MONK: Follow me,
Miss Davenport.
Ladies!
(LAUGHING)
MONK: Look at this shit.
I don't even like you, girl.
Get your ass up out of here!
Monk?
You know,
we can do this another time.
Get your stinky ass up
out of here. You too.
What... No, stop!
You didn't even want to
loan me no money?
Get your ass out, too.
What the hell is this?
I'm sorry, just...
Right after you,
Miss Davenport.
Thank you, Monk.
You welcome.
(EXHALES)
ANGEL: Bye, Monk.
Bye.
(ROSE MOANING)
Oh, Rooster.
Baby, why you make me
act so bad?
Who, me?
Yes, you.
You bad boy.
Guess I kind of inherited it
from my Uncle Eddie.
Got a weakness for fine women
such as yourself.
And that perfume
don't help, either.
One second. One second.
Bad boy.
Let's head over to the garage.
Hey, Ace. Excuse me, man.
I want to...
What?
I want to talk to you
about the piano.
Some of the notes
are still sticking and I...
Don't you touch
that damn piano.
That piano is
a bona fide antique.
Jelly Roll Morton
brought the house down
with that piano!
If it's good enough
for Jelly Roll,
it's good enough for
a mortician nigger
like yourself.
It just needs a little tuning.
I mean, I hit a couple
of bad notes, but...
Let me tell you something.
The only reason
why you even here,
because Rooster said, "Please,
"please let my mortician
friend come play the piano
at your club."
That's the only reason
why you here.
Watch your conduct, nigger!
Jackass!
(ACE LAUGHING)
ACE: I still got girls.
WOMEN: Bye, Percy.
Idiot.
Never heard of
this one before.
No one has.
So you play piano
and write songs.
Yeah, I play a little bit,
just to pass the time.
That's a creepy car.
Yeah, I wouldn't want to be
caught dead in that one.
That's funny.
You're cute, piano player.
Thank you.
You got a name?
Percival.
Percival Jenkins.
Well, see you around,
Hey, Percival.
Why don't you take that phony
broad back to the mortuary?
(ALL LAUGHING)
TAFFY:
Maybe you'll get you some!
(MOANING)
Let me ask you something.
Oh, baby.
Why are
all the good ones taken?
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Shit! Goddamn!
The big man.
Here, take this out of here.
What he doing here?
Where you going?
Get my panties.
Watch yourself, Spats.
Yeah, yeah. Come on, man.
(ROSE WHISPERING)
Get my panties.
You know, I got big plans
shaking from out them
trees out there.
That's the only way
today's Negro going to
make it in today's society.
It's like something
my mama used to tell me,
well, not my birth mama,
but the lady that raised me.
Bitch, what you doing in here?
I just wanted to
finish up the receipts,
so me and you could
spend some quality time
together tonight, daddy.
Receipts.
Right. Right.
I'll tell you what.
You go upstairs,
keep the bed warm for me.
Take this with you.
I didn't know
you was gonna bring company.
See you later, fellows.
Lord, Lord, Lord, Lord.
Pussy and money.
If God created
anything better,
he kept it to himself.
Amen.
I've been waiting
on this day, Spats.
I've been dreaming about it.
I didn't know
it was gonna come so soon,
but I ain't about to
let you talk me out of it.
A big man's got to
have big plans.
And this is my big plan.
In a year's time,
I can run for mayor
of this goddamn town.
Hell, I just might.
The way I see things,
you work for me now.
You get your
greasy-ass hands off of me.
Relax, son.
He ain't mean nothing by it.
I'm not going to
tell you again.
Say, slick,
what's your fucking problem?
You talking to Sunshine Ace.
Watch your conduct around me,
nigger.
TRUMPY: Nigger, I don't
give a damn who you are.
I would never work
for some stinking, fat,
whore-loving trick like you.
Now, get the fuck...
Spats. Spats.
You know I'm not
trying to disrespect
your business, Spats,
and I don't believe
in violence, but I will
cut this motherfucker!
Watch your conduct!
Put it away, Trumpy.
You, too, Ace.
No, don't worry, Spats.
Sunshine Ace ain't
cutting nobody today.
Trembling like a little bitch.
I told you to
put it away, Trumpy.
We're here on business.
Trumpy.
Son, you beginning
to forget your place.
ACE: Spats, come get
this half-breed.
Do you hear me, Trumpy?
Yeah, I hear you.
ACE: Nigger, you crazy.
And the problem is,
I've heard you loud
and clear for six years.
Six long years
I've been out there
busting my goddamn conk
for you to keep
your hands clean. And why?
So a piece of shit
like this can get rich?
Put the damn gun down now,
Trumpy.
What? This slimy pig
mean something to you?
You really are senile,
old man.
ACE: You're talking to Spats.
Boy, you about to
get your ass whipped.
You done lost
your natural mind.
That's right, Spats.
No, it's quite
the opposite, sir.
That's right.
You see, I've watched you
for a long time, Spats.
And you taught me
that when opportunity knocks,
you said
the smart man answers.
(GUN FIRES)
ACE: Spats! Spats!
Son!
See, that was some
really good advice.
Trumpy.
Hey, what was that
that you told me?
Trumpy.
Trumpy. No, Trumpy.
What was it? Was it, like,
never...
I'm gonna put
the knife down, Trumpy.
Will you shut
the fuck up for a second?
I'm trying to think.
Never...
I'm going to put
the knife down, Trumpy.
I got it.
Never bring a knife
to a gunfight, mother...
A fool and his money...
So this your big plan, huh?
Angel Davenport? A singer?
Hey, fat man,
where is the money?
(GROANS)
Let's see.
Fuck you, Trumpy.
(ACE LAUGHS)
(GUN FIRING)
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
(METALLIC RATTLING)
(CAT YOWLS)
Shit.
(SINGING) The fear of clocks
The fear of time
How's the cost of living?
Ain't got much time left
I've got to funk you now
I take what I've been given
Ain't got much time left
I've got to funk you now
Pastor say, "Be strong"
Ain't got much time left
I've got to funk you now
I ain't got time
Leave me alone
Ain't got much time left
I've got to funk you now
Y'all know
what I'm talking about
Chronomentrophobia
Morning.
(CLOCK TICKING)
No! Go on. Going on, now.
What you hitting me for?
You ain't got
no business being out
all hours of the night.
That's the devil's hour.
Here we go. Zora, don't start.
I had a rough night
last night.
Know what? It's Saturday.
Remember you said
you was gonna take me
and the kids downtown?
That's just what you gonna do.
Now get your lying,
cheating ass up out this bed.
Come on!
Give me the damn cover.
I ain't going nowhere.
(GROUP SINGING)
Looks like it was over money.
Probably.
That was nice, wasn't it?
Come on. Come on, now.
Look at all them
pretty ladies right there.
ZORA: You ain't
off the hook yet.
Let me help you
with that, my friend.
What you doing here, Trumpy?
Driving by.
Noticed you was out doing
the little family thing.
Thought it'd be rude
if I didn't stop by
and say hello.
What do you want with me?
Last night,
old man Spats and Ace
got into a little scuffle.
Tragic.
See, the way I figure,
you are naturally
next in line to run Church,
seeing as how you was
Ace's flunky and all.
And since you naturally
inherit the club, you also
naturally inherit its debt.
So?
Well, Ace was a month
behind in paying Spats.
So you now owe me
$1,250.
Now who told you
you was in charge?
Who's going to
tell me I'm not?
I mean, you're a smart man.
ZORA: Hands.
You got a lot to lose.
Afternoon, Zora.
Mighty nice hat.
Here's $150.
That's all I got.
$1,100 short.
And, by the way,
the price of hooch
just went up to $2 a bottle.
Two dollars a bottle?
That's double the price.
Inflation.
Ain't you heard?
I mean, times are
hard everywhere.
(LAUGHS)
Yeah, well,
I ain't coming on that tab.
You know, funny thing.
(CHILDREN GIGGLING)
Settle down.
I tripped over these
last night.
Seen Rose lately?
Don't get any bright ideas.
ZORA: What was that
all about?
ROOSTER: Spats got
gunned down last night.
Him, Ace,
both of them stretched out.
Oh, my God.
What you gonna do?
Pull over right here.
I need to
take care of something.
Rooster, wait.
Do you remember
how it used to be
in the beginning, me and you?
Before we was married.
When you took me out
to that peach orchard?
We said we was gonna get us
our own orchard one day.
Grow us some peaches.
Raise us some kids.
And look at you.
You're so smart.
You could make
a business doing anything.
We could get out
of town right now.
Take our babies
and start over
and start it right.
Zora, I just need
for you to trust me.
Just until I sort things out.
That's all.
Be careful.
Everything will be okay.
(SCATTING)
PERCY: Percival. Percival.
Percival, will you stop
banging on that piano
and get down here?
(BANGS PIANO KEY)
Percival. Percival.
We got two bodies down here.
Busy day. Come on.
Put him over there.
Yeah.
PERCIVAL: Afternoon, fellows.
Mr. Fat Man.
Finally got
stretched out, huh?
They got you good.
They weren't playing,
were they?
But it serves you well.
You shouldn't have been
trying to put me on the spot
and embarrass me.
I am that mortician nigger.
But you know what that means?
That means that
before you leave this place,
you have to come see me.
So now who's the jackass?
What?
Man, I ought to wash
your mouth out with soap.
Does your mother know
you talk like that?
I didn't think so.
Guess it don't matter
too much now.
But you can tell me
how in the hell
am I going to get
your fat ass in this casket?
You think this is play time?
No, sir.
You gotta learn to have
more respect for the dead.
Take your job more seriously.
Where's your pride?
Your pride is in your work.
I apologize.
I don't want your apologies.
Just do your job.
Now get this man cleaned up.
And stop playing.
(MUTTERING)
Business is business.
Jackass.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Hello?
Rose.
Hey, hey, Rose.
It's me, Rooster.
I see who you is.
What you doing here, man?
Put the goddamn
frying pan down.
I ain't putting shit down
till you tell me why you here.
Is you trying to kill me,
Rooster?
Hell, no.
Now put the goddamn
frying pan down.
It's me. It's Rooster, baby.
(ANGEL CLEARS THROAT)
Boo!
(LAUGHING)
Hi, piano player.
Hi.
So you really do work
with dead people.
Now that would
give me the creeps.
You get used to it
after a while.
Doesn't bother me naught.
What are you doing here?
Well, I'm doing
a little investigating.
There's a rumor that
Sunshine Ace got
stretched out last night.
Guess you heard, huh?
What you look at me
like that for?
I ain't buying
nobody's horseshit story
they shot each other.
Since I'm the only one
that can pin Trumpy
to that damn garage,
it ain't going to be too long
before he after me.
So I'm getting out of here,
and there ain't nothing
you can do to stop me.
I ain't come to stop you.
I came to say goodbye.
Damn, Rooster.
As soon as I get myself caught
in the middle of some shit,
you just gonna up
and leave me like that?
It's gotta be different now.
Oh, now
it's gotta be different.
You know
Just my luck.
So is he here?
(ANGEL SCREAMS)
Okay, okay. Cover him up.
Damn.
Just my luck.
Dead as a doorknob.
Now what am I going to do?
I'm stuck in this cow town
and it's gonna cost me $107
for a ticket out of here.
You owe me $107, fat man!
Did you check his pocket?
Oh, I know you ain't gonna
skip out without paying
my goddamn rent.
Don't talk that jive to him,
you old battle-ax.
Rose, I'm really sorry
about everything.
Don't you say that to me.
Don't you ever
say that to me.
Well, hey, maybe
you should talk to Rooster.
I think he's going to be
running the club from now on,
and he may have
something for you.
Thanks for your help.
I'll see you around,
Percival.
Well, well.
What happened?
(STUTTERING)
I followed Rooster
over to this
spot over there on...
BOBO: Come on.
Come on, Sonny. Spit it out.
...Baker Street.
Baker?
It was Rose's place.
Rose's place.
(CHUCKLING)
See, I told you
that fool was going to
lead us right to her.
He sure did, Trumpy.
TRUMPY: And?
And then she got into
a cab
with all kind of...
Come on. Spit it out.
...luggage and shit.
Where the hell did she go?
I don't know where she went.
But I followed Rooster
back here.
You must have
a peanut for a brain.
I specifically remember
telling you to follow Rose.
BOBO: Follow Rose.
I ain't need you
to follow Rooster.
Not Rooster.
What am I going
to do with you?
Let me see your gun, Sonny.
BOBO: Come on, Sonny.
Give him the gun.
Thank you.
Spats once told me.
He said in every relationship,
the person least interested in
maintaining the relationship
is going to dominate,
because they won't compromise.
See, Sonny.
No compromise.
In this relationship
right here,
I can't afford to compromise.
BOBO: Now take it like a man.
Stand still.
Take it like a man, Sonny.
Come on.
(GUN CLICKS)
Pissed him off now.
(BOBO LAUGHING)
PERCIVAL:
All the world's a stage,
and all the men and women
merely players.
They have their exits
and their entrances,
all with
a specific role to play.
Even at a funeral.
Sometimes in a show,
a lead actor's
contract expires.
When that happens,
an understudy has to
step in and perform,
whether he's ready or not.
Sorry about what happened
with Spats, man.
Sure going to miss him.
Yeah, me, too.
Now I got to run the club,
pay everybody
and sing on top of that.
You'll figure it out.
You always do.
I don't know.
If I don't get killed first,
Zora gonna leave me
for real this time.
PERCIVAL:
She always says that.
You know
she ain't going nowhere.
Trumpy raising
the price of hooch.
He's sucking up
all the profit.
I ain't making a dime.
No, it's all right.
What if you go around Trumpy?
Like you always tell me,
can't find a way, make one.
I need a favor.
Yeah.
I need to borrow the hearse.
Bring it back by 8:00.
God don't make no mistakes.
You ain't said nothing
slick to a can of oil.
Meet you at the house.
Ain't life a bitch?
How you holding up, Rooster?
Never bad, never bad.
That's what Spats used to say.
I can float you for a while,
but you're gonna
have to pay me.
And you gonna
have to keep this quiet.
ROOSTER: (SINGING) Yeah
(ALL CHEERING)
Somebody done told you wrong
Thought I was gonna lay it off
like that there, huh?
If Trumpy get wind of it...
Trumpy ain't gonna
hear about this.
Just give me a little time.
Too motherfucking hot
I'm motherfucking cool
Give me a bad word
Okay, I started out alone
'Cause my baby mama left me
Now there's nobody at home
Beginning to feel like
Ms. Jackson done got cloned
Well, it's some real shit
and I'm living it
through this song
A moving vehicle
took my family
As I slept out on the sofa
in the Boom Boom Room
I woke up very upset
I throw the covers
back and peek out
through the draperies
My daughter, my baby,
my baby mama all escaping me
Like a candle in the wind,
she was my friend
She was my passion, never lied
Therefore we tried
and tried again
But in the end you pay
attention to the pluses
But the minuses behind it
make it seem like
you can't win
Throw your neck out,
throw your back out
ROOSTER: Oh, hell, no!
All right, I told you
not to do that to...
Give me a sec.
Okay.
What you doing, Cap?
You got one more time, Cap.
One more time.
Throw your back out
Round two, a single parent,
what is Big to do?
Throw a party?
Not hardly I'm trying to
stay up out of that womb
Or that P-U-S-S uss, I say uss
Luther Vandross couldn't make
a home out of this house
that we smooshed
Smashed, pushed to the limit
Smash and turned it timid
And everyone was suffering,
the house was feeling wicked
What is this, the break room?
Get y'all ass back
out there on stage!
WOMAN 1: I'm sorry.
WOMAN 2: Oh, God.
Now let's fight for it
You build it up to
break it down and take it
from the start
Repeatedly leading a path
that only ends in the clash
Of two stubborn minds,
grown folks blind to the sign
Throw your neck out
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I will cut your ass.
Wait now, wait now.
Come on, brother.
Put that chair down, brother.
Put that down, now.
Come on, look.
Okay, work this out. Okay?
Throw your neck out,
throw your back out
Why not come here
and do your job, too?
Man, I got this.
You owe me $74...
Oh, damn.
Throw your back out,
throw your back out
KO, knocked out
by technicality
The love has kissed the canvas
Now the whole family
gets mad at me
My daughter don't want me
at her PTA meetings
And then my son,
he can't talk,
when I change him he's peeing
I think he's pissed
I can't dismiss the matter
of the fact because
he saw me and you argue
Now the energy is coming back
Set an example,
a positive pattern,
keep life on track
But I'm married to the music
and committed to the wax,
taste and tea
Baby, please,
you make me wanna scream
You're on the team
starting first string
so why are we arguing?
Wax, taste and tea
Baby, please
Motherfucker!
How you gonna leave me
without paying me
my goddamn money?
Get him! You cheap
son of a bitch! Get him!
Get him!
What?
Get back here.
Get him, Rooster!
Throw your neck out,
throw your back out
Taste and tea
Baby, please,
you make me wanna scream
You're on my team
starting first string
so why are we arguing?
DIRECTOR: Party up in here!
Stirring it up!
Ladies and gentlemen, Rooster!
(ALL CHEERING)
What's the line?
What's the line, Sonny?
You get to lose.
Put it on the line,
you stuttering son of a bitch.
Get up.
SONNY: Fuck you.
Oh, my, my.
(ALL CHEERING)
Damn.
God damn.
Give me my damn money.
You took all my money,
you stuttering idiot.
Give me my damn money.
Monkey mouth!
Hey, Roo,
you don't look so good.
Oh, you came here
to tell me that?
Well... No, I came here
to borrow some bread.
You know, I owe Ace $85,
but now that he's dead,
my debt is clear. Yeah!
Boy, I feel so good he gone.
Excuse me, but I'm free.
I'm free, baby. I know it.
Your debt ain't clear.
It says so
right in the books. $85.
It's right here in the book.
You got one week to pay up.
Let me see.
Man, get off my desk.
'Cause I want my money
and the money you owe Ace.
I won't forget it.
Me, I will not forget.
Where you going
with that hooch?
Give me a second.
I'll be right back.
MAN:
Oh, I don't see a problem.
WOMAN: Well, why don't you
buy me a drink first?
The answer's no,
so don't waste your breath.
Excuse me.
May I have a word with you?
Thank you.
As you may or may not know,
Ace and I had a contract.
And if you take a close look
at this contract,
you are obliged to provide me
one first class ticket
to my next destination
which is Saint Louis,
Missouri.
Mmm-hmm.
And seeing as
how you're now the manager
of this establishment,
the responsibility of honoring
this contract falls upon you.
You know,
it don't make no difference
if Ace is dead or not.
Says so right there
in the fine print.
Let me see that.
I'll have you know that's
a legally-binding obligation
signed by both parties.
You know what?
You're right.
It obliges you to sing.
And it's your first week.
You still want me to sing?
You ain't got no choice.
It says so right here
at the top.
"Club owner hereby
engages artist
for a period of four weeks."
In fine print.
As you pointed out,
this is a legally-binding
obligation.
Yeah. Well, of course,
it'll take me
a little while to prepare.
Don't worry about that.
You on tomorrow night, sugar.
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow night, you on.
9:00 sharp.
Why, I need at least a week
to get my band together.
Oh, sugar, you look so good.
Rooster, please, have a heart.
I'm not ready.
Come on. Don't be late.
Money in the bank.
(PIANO PLAYING)
TRUMPY:
No, no, no. I asked you,
is GW actually connected
to Capone's people
out of Chicago?
BOBO: It would appear so.
This music is killing me, man.
Hey, Percy, Jr. Percy, Jr.
What's that you playing?
Working on something new.
Sound like some bullshit.
I mean, you really think
the audience is gonna
appreciate that?
Well, Rooster said that
I could play whatever
I wanted to play, so...
No, no. Never mind anything
that Rooster say.
BOBO: Rooster said,
Rooster said.
You need to
play stuff I like, okay?
Well, what do you like?
TRUMPY:
I don't like that.
Excuse me.
BOBO: Nobody likes that.
Can the artists get
a little space around here?