Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Bra. Caution.
We go back, Tom.
The storm is coming.
It looks pretty scary,
right?
I'm sitting here behind you, Tom.
E minor.
Proper chord.
- Hello?
- Ms. Whitman? Dr. Jansson.
I have bad news.
What is it, Princess?
Why not spin?
We must receive your dad again.
Seizures
only comes closer.
This time
it seems pretty serious.
I understand.
Mr. Whitman?
Tom?
- I'll discuss it with you.
- I will as soon as possible.
Can you hear my voice,
Mr. Whitman?
Matthew realized the hopelessness.
Nothing had any meaning.
Mr. White fused
Matthews face.
Snowman did not talk anymore.
happy face that Matthew
had loved, was now just slush.
Matthew looked up in the sky
- then last winter snowflakes
descended.
Man said that its touch was magical, -
- but Matthew
no longer believed in fairy tales.
When snowflake touched
Mr. White's hand, -
- disappeared fresh hoar frost
and the pond under the snowman
- crackled when it froze.
Matthew was happy
- when he saw
Mr. White come to life.
last snowflake fairy
was real.
Troll Winter
would never end.
Bedtime, kids.
Are you the new kid, Tom?
You built the snowman
in the backyard.
My name is Ann.
What's that? She is beautiful.
- Can not you talk?
- I can talk.
Are they your parents?
It's my mother.
She was sick and ...
She's dead now.
My father is a pilot.
- Is he dead?
- He's not!
My father is Theodore Whitman,
a hero.
He saved all the passengers
away from the tornado.
But he had to make an emergency landing.
When he is rescued,
he comes and gets me.
- No one here has parents.
- Turn off the light!
Good night, Tom.
Sleep well, Princess.
This should get you melt.
Well, well, what have we here?
Nice to see an old friend.
I stood there
in the backyard for myself -
- When I felt a twinge in his arm.
How to say?
It was enough that little thing.
We take a trip
and see where we end up.
Maybe we encounter some
of your old friends.
We find such
you've only dreamed about.
I must be dreaming.
Therefore everything is so strange.
Come on, it'll be fun.
You're safe with me.
Dude,
If you are afraid to join, -
- I understand that.
Maybe you're not like your father.
Do not worry, keep dreaming.
Or are you with me
on adventures.
It feels real.
Ice and genuine oak.
Come on!
There was something
to rest your eyes on!
- What is it?
- Only rotten wood and steel.
Should we look for?
Behold, your father.
Are not you glad
to see him again?
This is just a dream.
More real than it
are not.
Ms. Whitman ...
Your father suffers
vascular dementia.
It comes from repeated infarctions.
We have often talked about the case.
It has.
But considering the state of ...
You will stop treatment.
It is not so.
He is not a machine.
His heart
stopped twice.
- We revived, but now ...
- How am I supposed to sign?
You are making the right choice.
It is best
to let him go.
He has already
lived in a fantasy world for a few years.
He is childhood again.
It had been bad ...
Can I get you home with your father
if we should talk?
You're not flying back
in this weather?
No.
Like that. I'll leave you alone.
Nothing has changed?
I'm not even a memory,
or what?
I'm just a blur, as always.
I waited so long for
you should consult.
This was a mistake.
I've done enough for you.
Oh no!
We must turn back!
It's too late, I can not!
Help!
- No!
- Hold on!
Now what? What is this?
You are just yourself.
Hey, Tom.
It was a long time ago.
- Do I know you?
- Of course.
We've known each other
since childhood.
- You are crazy.
- I was once.
Come,
I'll patch it together.
You wonder where you are.
I'm in a dream.
With a mad woman.
If I am,
it provides no good picture of you.
In many different ways.
Before I was your voice of reason.
You really needed one.
You were good at many things -
- But not on
to cope with reality.
This is not seized.
It should.
I'm just waiting for you.
Friend! Hello, how are you?
- Hey! I am here.
- Quiet! He finds you.
Let it be.
It just brings back memories.
You are crazy. Let me be!
Selfishness and plump.
The Tom I know.
A snowman
is not the best guide.
He is not the
he appears to be.
Let him take the rest of you.
I can not see you, buddy!
- I am ...
- Shout as loud as you can!
Damn young!
You're hiding.
Now he is not so nice anymore.
Hey, you there!
Beware, the tracks are unstable.
They could collapse at any time.
- Why is this here?
- No idea.
Some thought it was
a good idea to build here.
Hey, wait!
Do you know where the music comes from?
It sounds familiar.
Have you heard it?
We've all heard it.
It is played daily,
same tune. I get nauseous.
Oh no!
Damn!
Why do I care?
This can not be repaired.
What will you do, Gem?
Gem?
Let it be. It is lifeless.
Right. Thank you. Let it rot.
Be careful.
A song about me?
Worthless crap! A moment without
eye and saw all this.
The scoundrel
provides too many worries.
Damn!
- Wow, I missed a spot.
- What are you doing?
Nothing. I was looking just for you.
And now I found you.
Come here.
Let me take a look at you.
What? This?
I got a little criticism
in the storm.
Do not worry about me.
Hey! Skalvi have some fun?
No! What is it with you?
First we crashed, and now this?
- Stupid dream, I'm out.
- Hold on, buddy! Calm down.
I have something for both of us.
Two circus tickets.
It is just around the corner.
I'll show you.
No, let me be.
This is too weird.
You will not leave me!
- Come out! See what's here.
- Go away!
I'm not angry.
Come and share
- this painting with me.
What happened? What have you done?
Reveal me -
- wizard who never
has failed ...
deep sigh, -
- like a belt around my chest.
Hey, Tom. So good that you got away.
- What did you do with my arabesque?
- Before calling it your princess.
Could she actually spin,
as you said?
Or was it also
a foolish lie?
Excuse me. A different story.
A silver platter?
Did you really think it
would arrange everything between you?
You would not
arrange it in reality.
I do not want it.
It is destroyed.
What do you do? It's mine.
I'll have the same thing.
Castles of glass,
rhyming stanzas.
deeper dream, -
- of all time.
Who are you?
Slowly, my dear, slowly.
Slowly ...
Only the weak-
- are never alone.
Slowly ...
Slowly, my dear, slowly.
Before you played so beautifully,
Tom.
You had a song
for everything in your life.
What a pity
that it must end.
I understand.
Do not call me Tom.
You do not know me even.
It is you who
know people, Tom.
It's your fault.
Because you fed him.
Do not let him take all of you.
Wait!
Doors
not protect secrets.
Dad ...
I had nightmares.
What do you do?
Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
Go back to bed.
- But Dad ...
- Is it about your mom again?
The circus ...
It is not until tomorrow.
Go to bed.
Dad ...
What is it?
Are you afraid?
How can you be afraid?
Without having seen it.
Look. Only clowns.
Trapeze artists in costume.
That's all.
Do you understand, dear?
Crawl back to bed now.
Thomas ... Yes, Dad?
Nothing.
Go to bed.
ASAP.
No!
... it continues to snow,
temperature drops.
forecast says
It is a record cold night -
- so it's best to stay indoors,
especially for the elderly.
authorities warn
possible power outages.
Keep batteries and
candles and take care of the old.
Hello ...
But look at you, you.
- You are beautiful.
- Ann. Of course.
- How did you get in?
- With witchcraft.
I can not reveal more
than a brick belonged.
Nice to see you.
How are:
"You ruined my life, bitch"?
You ruined nothing.
You did what you wanted.
Everyone took care of itself.
That was unfair.
- It was not so?
- How was it? Because ...
The band, tours and money
and all the stupid shit-
- Felt important for Dad
than me or my mom.
At home, he was also always
immersed in his own thoughts.
Enough is enough. You may have-
- Unresolved stuff with Tom,
but it has not.
Yep. It makes me.
I have never been
part of his life.
You were the most important in his life.
It was better.
Understand why
He also saved on the bad.
He could not let go.
So cute ...
You were a happy child.
There I was.
But no thanks to him.
He just wanted to forget everything -
- And continue on with you.
But it's not successful.
It was a long time ago, Ann.
You could leave it alone.
At a certain age you stop fear
death and begin to wait for it.
After a while one longs,
although one can not say that.
Do you know why? To
Lose your mind before you die -
- Is worse than death itself.
You want to go away
before brain just gets mash.
You seem still quite sharp.
I'm talking about your father.
He is a gloomy place now.
Does it bother you not when you do not know
how he remembers you?
No. I think
it bothers you more.
If he at all remember,
then it is damaged and repaired.
He was not good at repairing.
He did his best.
I'm tired.
Watch it, buddy. Otherwise, do
this a nightmare.
No! You're hurting me.
You know I do not.
I just want your best.
That's the way it should be.
- Dude, what are you doing there?
- Come here, it begins.
Sorry!
I realize that you're part of the show.
This I must see.
Once upon a time
Dagmar in a race.
I will meet you, little children.
Join the show.
It's time to go to bed,
but yet rays cradle.
13 strokes turn the dead man's watch,
tick tock tick tock.
Dad!
bride seduces,
she steaks you, eat you.
Your innocence is transformed
a festive dish.
Burning farms,
screaming pig.
swimming in ormers dust,
Let the delicious poison sting.
Ladies and Gentlemen ...
I salute you
welcome to-
- Cirque De Morgue!
We have something to show
for you tonight!
Madame ...
Mr. Thomas Whitman!
Composer and poet.
A vile, vile father.
With a wretched, wretched memory.
No, stop!
No!
Restless souls,
put on your dancing shoes.
Evil Spirits
with many members.
Sorcerers, contortionists, -
- line dancers
ranging warp cord.
This is about your wife.
There is no
much left of her.
Barely-
- Worth the trouble.
Memories ... But you
have no benefit from them.
All we lose
parts of ourselves -
- Bit by bit.
What?
What the fuck? That is it's not.
No, that's wrong.
Do not change anything!
You're ruining it!
Thomas ...
Damn ...
How many numbers
these tend to have?
No idea.
Do not try to violence,
it did not succeed.
We must open
this stupid thing.
Why, Ann?
When Tom hide something is important.
He has no money,
you wasted it all.
Are you a little bitter?
For that I must
pay care, yes.
Well done.
You let him get home
- With their memories.
Not bad
for one who blows his father.
What else could I do?
Family friends
would have accused me.
Nonsense.
The family has not had
some friends for years.
What is it?
Tom cares about people.
That's what I say.
He cared.
Another trick!
He chose something
he would not forget.
What a cliche!
What's that?
"... But I am
only an illusion ... "
It's all about him.
As surprising!
"Miracles come in small packages."
"It takes little to make a child
the world's happiest creature ... "
No, stop!
- Go away, I hate you!
- Wait! Who are you?
Wait!
Are you happy now?
Yes. For this
is my childhood environment.
Loose-leaf, songs, words of wisdom.
Adventure around me.
Do you see it?
His precious arabesque.
His princess.
He said the dancer spun-
- If I played well
the piano lesson.
- Listen, Gem ...
- I grew up with wishful thinking-
- And bizarre monologues.
Everything was just a show.
He did the same with my mother.
Watched her.
He gave promises that he broke.
And always she thought. Always!
Dad was always a disappointment
because you always come first.
So she died, because of you.
Hope it was worth it.
Damn!
Good morning, General.
I was so small-
- In his magical music world.
He wrote songs
to everyone around him.
Perhaps also
this little shit.
But never to my mom or me.
One, two, three, four!
Good morning, Herr General.
Lucky you found it.
What is this?
- Where am I?
- You are on the battlefield, sir.
You have fought for years
in this room.
I am ashamed because I
hurt you. In vain.
- I do not understand.
- Do not save my feelings.
I dealt a violent blow.
I can only ask for your forgiveness.
- I stomped on you.
- I attack you.
But my motive was noble.
I tried courageously to prevent your departure
with the cursed snowman.
The ugly bastard!
It's about memories, sir.
He takes them.
He takes you deeper into the darkness.
But why?
You were old.
But you win for now.
The best memories hurt him.
You have chased the best memory.
- The girl?
- Yes, your daughter.
A girl like that!
Such a memory! Brilliant!
You probably remember her childhood with
using common toy -
- That I or the beautiful lady-
- Where the glass ball.
You love us,
that your daughter too.
- I remember her.
- Very well ...
There is nothing to do.
C'est la vie!
Longer than here, we will not.
- Do not ...
- Sir?
I need your help.
I will remember her.
I will find her.
Comrades!
Forward, march!
You still have precious memories.
We know where you hid them.
Not so far away.
- I do not have many left.
- Oh no ...
I do not even know who I am.
We are all wounded.
- I apologize for that.
- I'm a soldier, injured by war.
You'd have given us -
- But you gave us your daughter-
- And underlined the importance of
we are. Hooray!
We must hurry, sir.
Did Tom come before the
evening when your mother was perished, -
- Could all have been different.
- He was with you, Ann.
You have misunderstood.
My life was a mess then.
It was crazy, with the band ...
It was too much for me.
I did not take enough pills,
for I woke up and Tom was there.
It was not how I planned it.
- I do not want to hear this.
- He was with me -
- But did not look at me
after what I had done.
Your little tricks
must have corrupted the band.
No, no.
It was probably the band's end -
- It is true, but ...
What I did was-
- How shall I say it ...
too personal for him.
- You do not seem to.
- You know what?
Do not you know,
that Tom's father committed suicide?
Theodore Whitman
shot himself in the head-
- While Tom watched.
What I did was too heavy for him.
The evening
accident happened to your mother.
The band split.
He did not care about it -
- But did
that he would lose you too.
- Why tell you this?
- Because you do not know your father.
He worshiped his father,
even if he was bleak.
Tom said that he
could really be bad.
When Tom started to go
in the same direction, -
- He pushed you away.
I know. He pushed properly.
We're here, sir.
I remember!
I hid them jo. They are here!
May I say
It was a pleasure to serve you.
"Miracles come in small packages.
It takes so little to make a child
the world's happiest being.
It was not so much to the circus.
Uncouth, limp and tired.
Still excited about the show-
- And she pressed laughing
my hand.
I felt like a father
then she laughed. "
Why could not he
tell it to me?
He did it
the only way he could.
I always hoped-
- That it would be
something valuable in the safe, -
- Not such a waste.
Mild powers!
These are not only spread
thoughts or feelings. See!
Partially finished, but the rest ...
Words ending or derails.
Openings, empty rooms ...
"She's a picture of his mother,
my broken, lost beloved ...
So small,
but as wise and beautiful.
I am proud of love.
Now I push her away. "
"She will not share my gloom.
I hope
she understands a beautiful day. "
Hid you all good things here?
What then, this?
I got a little bank.
You should see your little friend.
- I know what you want.
- Congratulations. What did we learn?
Your father got tired of you,
took his life. Song Bird tried.
And your little girl hates you.
There is nothing left.
- Not for you either.
- I have a thing.
Magic.
The light brings darkness. Delicious irony.
Your world, your rules.
Who could have dreamed it together?
Here it comes.
Like watching
their greatest fears come to life.
A crow flew to me,
but stopped at a distance.
being so proud.
I saw its soul,
envied pride.
But I did nothing
who heard it.
Then came an owl,
so old and so wise.
needed straight
in my youth.
I learned its manners,
envied sins.
But I did nothing
who heard it.
A dove came to me,
without fear.
It rested on my arm.
I touched the quiet,
envied love.
But I did nothing
who heard it.
A swan so white,
it came to me.
Sea mirror
its quiet beauty.
Its neck I kissed,
I admired its grace.
But I did nothing
who heard it.
Ann. Ann ...
See ...
It is your father.
See, he did everything by hand.
Where there are empty
uncompleted sections.
He started writing things down, -
- When he realized
he lost his mind.
Where is the last page?
What was it?
All these pieces, the memories ...
This is his life.
- Superbly.
- I'll see if the fuse went.
Yes, the power went out.
The phone is obviously dead.
I go there.
Damn!
I can not call a taxi.
- I have a car.
- Have you? Then we go.
Sorry, old man.
Your daughter does not take the phone.
It must be because of the storm.
No! I'm not finished yet!
It is immediately over.
Are you running away?
You are on the tracks, you idiot!
I know what's down there.
You do not like it!
I will not let you do that!
You do not just luck next time!
E minor!
I was right. She twirled!
Hurry in, so I parked the car.
I'll be right there.
I got you!
I am your future mate!
You should not
take my life from me again!
I do remains
into a living hell.
You probably know why.
Your music and your dreams-
- Is just
ruins and empty canvas now.
You think only of me.
Tell us why!
- I can not help it!
- You always knew I was married.
You could have chosen her
by making me less.
- But you gave me strength each year.
- I had to!
I would not forget you.
I deleted
bad dreams and memories -
- You little shit!
- Dad, stop!
- I'm going down with me!
- You knew that. Dad!
Stop it!
I have to let you go.
Katie: Daddy?
Thanks for the ride.
Sleep well, Princess.
I am here.
I'm sorry.
Dad?
Is this what you want?
What?
Princess ...
I did see that I hear
chords again.
Without them I stray
in this emptiness.
Wandering by a distant music -
- through a desert of ashes.
Should melody have a color, -
- would the mix
pink and red.
Always afraid of the fade.
fear of silence
which may occur.
My last memories leave me
- towards the end of a black alley.
There is a door in the dark.
I struggle to
take me through.
I hear it clearly now.
The sweetest melody
created by a human.
rises into the room.
And where is it forever ... -
- transition ZOOM.
Transalate By ZOOM
www.zoom.lk
Edited for HD Zacamacafaca