Masters in Pol. Sc. Optimally dainty.
Optically challenged.
Name: Sudeshna.
Masters in German. Left wing at
football. Politically, rightist.
Name: Amithabh.
Masters in History.
Exponent of Bengali culture.
Gem of a singer. Name:
Mahamaya Bandopadhyay.
Damn! -
- What?
1st division, direct entry into M. Phil.
No... -
- Please.
Don't tell me you're
having second thoughts again.
Somewhat. -
- I think I'll go mad now.
Graduation in Bengali, M.A. In History,
now what? Mountaineering?
It's only because of you that I'm
here instead of my Dad's business.
Stop flirting, Amit. Listen Maya,
if you want to do Music...
...I think you might as... -
- Miss Firebrand,
Mr. Coward Lee...
Not again!
Let's go to the canteen.
M. Phil in Portuguese studies.
Gujarati by birth. Aspiring Bengali.
Name: Withheld for the time being.
Why don't you complain? -
- Why? What's bugging you?
Moreover I think he is quite cute.
Stop joking. Shut up. -
- Brother, three.
If someone stalks me,
wont I get irritated?
And I know these guys very well.
Mouli has told me...
...typical Gujarati guy with a rich dad.
Weird! Follows me everywhere I go.
Keeps sending messages
through people! Is this a college?
Oh I see! You mean you
would've dated him in college?
This is university, so... -
- Not at all.
Not even during
my pension years.
Yes, true. The bugger's totally crazy.
He was supposed to pass
out four years ago but...
...then he saw her and fell in love.
Then he started with some
Portuguese or Spanish studies...
Excuse me.
Yes.
I want to... err...
...I needed to speak to you.
Only you. Only you shall I tell.
Shut up.
Tell me.
Err...
Not here, if you could come out...
English would be better. I don't
prefer Hindi and you can't speak Bengali.
Sit, I'll be back.
Yellow pants.
Correct decision.
I really don't have time.
And I hate walking.
The thing is... sorry...
...what I wanted to say is...
I mean to say...
...the things is that... -
- The thing is that
you're wasting your time.
Because you're interested in
someone about whom you know nothing.
You don't know her, don't
know her likes and dislikes,
...you can't even
pronounce her name properly.
Just a second, Madam.
You're not letting me speak.
I am a complete Bengali.
I was born in Kolkata.
My father's a chartered accountant.
You're Bengali is
flawed and desperate.
This existential crisis is very
insulting for my mother tongue.
And the city is called Kolkata,
not 'Kolkata'.
Thirdly, I really don't
care if your dad's a...
...chartered
accountant or a businessman.
We don't have any similarities.
Love is a far cry.
Friendship too won't work.
You have Dhoklas for breakfast
and our plates are aquariums, so...
I like fish too.
In fact Hilsa is my... -
- Eating Hilsa fish makes
you a Bengali?
I read Bengali poetry and
stories too. I read Tagore.
Satyajit Ray? -
- Think you can land...
...a Bengali girl reading
Tagore's translated work, Mr. Lee?
I suggest you get lost.
In translation. -
- Mr. Lee? But I'm Rohit.
Good. Stay whatever you are
and let me remain the way I am.
I know Bengali songs too.
Maybe it's only for you
That I am wildly in love
I know you're unique-
- Wow! You have a very nice voice!
Okay, here's the deal.
First compose a Bengali song about me...
...and then sing it with
proper Bengali pronunciation.
And then, I'll think
about your proposition. Okay?
Reliance Entertainment presents
Prosenjit Chatterjee
Jishu Sengupta
Swastika Mukherjee
Guest Appearance: Mamata Shankar
Guest Appearance: Rahul Arunoday Banerjee
Guest Appearance: Ria Sen
Guest Appearance: Abir Chatterjee
Guest Appearence: Ananya Chatterjee
Kharaj Mukherjee Tamal Roy Choudhury
Dwijen Banerjee Sumit Samaddar
Biswajit Chakrabarty,
Neel Mukherjee, Kaushik Ghosh
Bharat Kaul Chaitali Dasgupta
Guest Appearance: Anupam Roy, Rupam Islam
Guest
Appearance: Kalikaprasad Bhattacharjee
Appearance: Sidhhartha Roy, Anindya Chatterjee
Guest Appearance: Gourab Chatterjee
Make-up: Vikram
Gaekwad(Prosenjit Chatterjee)
Make-up: Sriroop
Das(Swastika Mukherjee), Mohd. Ali
Hair-dresser: Pranay
(Prosenjit Chatterjee)
Hair-dresser: Dipa Mullick
Costume Design: Sabarni Das
Art Direction: Koushik-Barik
Sound Design: Anirban
Sengupta, Dipankar Chaki
Music: Kabir Suman
Asst. Music Direction
and Background Score:
Indraadeep Dasgupta
Lyrics: Kabir Suman,
Antony Phiringi, Bhola Moyra,
Lalan Fakir, Ram Basu, Jogyeshwari,
Thakur Singha
Additional songs: Anupam Roy,
Sidhhartha Roy, Saki
DI Colorist: Debojyoti
Ghosh (Edit FX Studios)
Special Effects: Neon FX Studios
Publicity Design: Grinning Tree
Post-production
Supervision: Ahana Chakrabarty
Production controller: Debiprasad Kar
Chief Assistant
Director: Soumyabrata Rakshit
Editing: Bodhaditya Banerjee
Cinematography: Soumik Haldar
Reliance Entertainment
team: Sanjiv Lamba, Shibasish Sarkar,
Mahesh Ramanathan, Uthpal Acharya,
Samir Chopra, Purba Naresh
DAG Creative Media
Management: Rana Sarkar
Producer: Reliance Entertainment Pvt Ltd
and DAG Creative Media Pvt Ltd
Story, Screenplay, Dialogue, Direction:
Srijit Mukherji
'Jaatishwar'(The Re-incarnate)
Good morning.
Welcome to the final semester...
...of our
international exchange program.
I'm Professor Salazar, your
chief counsellor for this session.
A session on the historical
segments of Portuguese studies.
During the semester we'll
have a total of sixteen credits.
And you shall be graded
on a final dissertation.
For your topic you'll have
a choice of the following:
Colonial Politics.
Fine Arts.
Music.
Or Architecture.
And for each of the broad subjects,
there's going to be an
expert supervisor...
...who will help you
with your chosen subject,
in terms of the bibliography,
videographic  and
audiographic material...
...and the presentation techniques.
I want to thank you all for
your attention and your time...
and I want to wish you the
very best for this semester...
...and for the rest of your career.
Thank you very much.
Med school student.
Has a petite girlfriend.
Only Bengali guy in the
campus. Name: Bodhisatya.
Hello Mr. Disco Dandia.
Again that grumpy face.
What's wrong with you?
How many times do I have to tell you?
Only speak in Bengali with me.
I need practice. -
- Mission Maya?
How long shall this madness continue?
See I understand
people fall in love.
Things don't work out.
They move on.
No one laments like
you for three years.
I'm lamenting? -
- Aren't you?
When you don't have studies,
you either sit here...
...or in the music
class, lost in your thoughts for hours.
Just being optimistic.
Somewhere, someday...
...a miracle may happen. -
- Now this is too much!
Sitting here like a
'Lathkhor' (loser)... -
- What?
What's this 'Lathkhor'?
Lathkhor. Lath? Kick?
You know, a kick?
A kick?
And 'khor' means the one who...
Will you stop this? -
- Okay.
Okay let's assume I suddenly
bump into her somewhere one day.
If I don't know Bengali...
...sorry for the pronunciation.
How am I supposed to speak
to her then? And about what?
If I don't learn music,
don't know Bengali culture, -
- Listen bro, it doesn't work like that.
And you seriously think
this is an issue nowadays?
Bengali-Gujarati, Bengali-Punjabi,
Bengali-Marwari...
...it's happening all the time now.
I have a distant cousin who
married a man from Greenland.
Eskimo blood running in his veins. Fine.
Don't look that far.
Look at me and Gabriela.
Listen,
Maya is not
interested in you as a person.
She just used that
'culture' crap to avoid you.
You don't know her, Bodhi.
She's Bengali with a vengeance.
Immersed in Bengali culture.
All the time she is with...
...Bengali songs...
...Bengali poetry...
...Bengali dance.
She feels, Bengali is intellectually...
...the most superior race.
Sorry for my flawed Bengali.
In fact, can you imagine...
...if not necessary...
...she does not use one
English word...
...in a Bengali sentence.
Hello friends, we're
back from a break. I'm Maya.
You're listening to 'World of
Music' on 98.3 Radio Mirchi.
You just heard 'Bhindeshi
Tara' by Chandrabindoo...
...and Sudhin
Dasgupta's 'Kathay Kathay'...
...in Manna Dey's voice.
Our last song today, Salil
Choudhury's composition,
...lyrics by Sukanto,
sung by Hemant Kumar... -
- Boss is calling you.
...'Abak Prithibi'.
Enjoy!
Please,
concentrate on your studies
instead of thinking of Maya.
Don't forget this is
your dissertation year.
Thought of a topic?
No.
Think I'll go to the library
after the music class tomorrow.
Let's see...
...I'll figure out something.
It has to do with music.
And knowing you,
Bengali music.
Adios Amigo.
Born in the suburbs, now
resides in upmarket Kolkata.
Bengali roots; forgotten. Speaks English
with pride. Bikram Botobyal aka Vicky.
The reports are out,
not happening man.
Just not happening.
What is not happening and from
which angle do I appear to be a man?
Cut it out, Maya.
You're articulate, you've
a nice texture,
so I offered you Coffee house
Classics at prime time, you refused.
You said you want to play
Bengali songs. I said, fine.
I said change your name,
you threw tantrums there too.
Of course! What was the
problem with the name, 'Mahamaya'?
As in?
RJ Mahamaya?
Are you kidding me?
It sounds so... so... -
- Bengali, and you have
a problem with that?
Maya, now don't start all over
again with your Language Movement.
The ratings are dropping man.
See, I am cool with remixed
Rabindrasangeet and Bangla Band.
We can have a separate slot
for that because they sell.
But these drab songs
that you play from 50s... -
- Not selling, isn't it?
You're mixing up the TG.
Ratings are dropping.
Listen Mr. Vicky aka Bikram,
my target group is...
...the population that likes
listening to all kinds of Bengali songs.
They may be few in number but
they're increasing and realizing...
...that there is Bengali music
beyond Rabindrasangeet and bands.
Yes but... -
- No, there can be no 'but', Sir.
Along with Rabindrasangeet
and band music I play...
...Sudhin Dasgupta and
Salil Choudhury too.
In order to love Bengali
music one must listen to...
...Mohiner Ghoraguli
and Ramprasad likewise.
Because both Nachiketa Chakrabarty and
Nachiekta Ghosh have written about me.
Because both
Anjan Dutta and Mukul Dutta...
...have written their
songs in my language.
Because Apupam Roy, Anupam Ghatak,
Rupam Islam, Nazrul Islam, all are mine.
Bye.
How have you been!
How have you been?
You've shaved!
And how're you?
Had to do away with the
intellectual stubble for my job.
Okay... this one's yours.
Give me.
And...
...wait a second...
...this too is yours. -
- Oh my God!
This is yours. -
- Thank you!
And check this out. -
- Saradindu? For her?
Inform your dentist
before you read that Bengali.
So tell me, how do you find
your city after so many years?
Let's see... the roads are less dug up.
The water's turned mineral,
the air's less polluted...
...and among fruits,
mangoes have become costlier.
And what else? What did
you do in the last two years?
I found a job after
the university...
What about you? -
- Well... umm...
...my story too has
been quite... you know...
Great. Writing the screenplays
of your lives together, are you?
Tell her! -
- See, the situation is a bit like...
...we're seeing each other.
'A bit' as in?
In grams or metric tonne? Though
I haven't been informed, so... -
Maya... -
- Maya.
She is not pissed off.
That's brilliant!
Congratulations! Something
worthwhile finally, both of you.
And as they say, you
may now kiss the bride.
Okay!
Stop it.
What? -
- Anyway, what about you?
What about me? Life
goes on. Radio station.
Chatting people up, playing
their requests, that's it.
Still single?
Sadly. Because you changed. -
- Cut the crap.
What about that cute guy,
is he still pursuing you?
Right, what was his name?
That guy...
Mr. Coward Lee. Did he
finally gather the courage?
No. He had managed to get my
email id and sent me a mail.
Doing something somewhere. -
- What did he write?
Is the knight with a shining guitar...
...returning with
Bengali alphabets?
Sir, I need to go back to India. -
- An unscheduled vacation?
Err... no Sir, a research assignment.
Hello. -
- Hello.
Namaskar, Sir.
Please come. Please take your seat.
He looks exactly like
Heynsman Sahib. Isn't it?
Gourhari? -
- Yes, you're right.
So what's your name, sahib? -
- Antony. Heynsman Antony.
He was born in a very wealthy
Portuguese family, Sir.
He came down to India in
the early nineteenth century.
Landed at Chandannagore, West Bengal.
Earlier it was known
as Phawrashdanga.
Though he was a businessman's son,
his main interest was music.
And he then went on to become
one of the main proponents...
...of the 'Kabigaan'
tradition of Bengal.
Kabigaan? -
- Yes... sort of...
...sort of troubadours
or minstrels, Sir.
They would get into
musical battles through songs...
...and the songs were mainly
about the Hindu gods and goddesses.
Hold on, let me get
this straight.
This is your dissertation topic?
Yes, Sir.
I feel that's a very
interesting topic but...
...couldn't you find something
else that has a little more...
...information available?
Which is exactly why
I need to go, Sir.
There is very little
information on the internet,
apart from a mention of a
fictionalized Bengali film.
Actually, Sir, I feel
very strongly about this.
I'm a Bengali, you know.
And a musician too.
I find it very inspiring that
one can actually learn a language,
overcome all odds and then
go onto write a song.
Okay, let's see.
A Portuguese musician makes
it big in colonised Bengal.
Go for it, son. I'll speak
to Maurinho on your behalf.
How about some music
today, Sahib?
Want to listen?
What do I sing?
A song, of course.
Not tax accounts obviously.
Heard you're into music?
Are you carrying an
instrument in that bag?
Want to see?
Wow!
Going only for the dissertation, right?
Took music lessons all these days,
learnt Bengali from you,
won't I accept the challenge?
Brilliant!
That was ecstatic!
Enchanting!
Sahib, care for a drag?
Mini...
Mini!
The cool widow. For
everything from a power cut to...
...terrorism, recommends a cup
of tea as a solution. Name: Ma.
What a surprise!
You two have remained the same,
not changed a bit!
Really! -
- So your diet's not working.
Come in. -
- Tofu has become her stable food!
Auntie, long time since we
had your special egg curry.
Why not today? -
- I got diagnozed with Uric Acid.
Oh no.
You're laughing? -
- And what's with you?
Your boss has driven me
crazy with his phone calls.
Why do you leave your phone behind?
I think I'm fired. -
- Huh?
What!
Anyway,
tea? -
- Yes.
Ma! I just lost my job
and your offering them tea?
Look at her!
We'll miss the tea
because you got fired?
You called? -
- Thirteen times.
What is the use of carrying a
mobile phone if you can't...
...carry it along wherever you... -
- Am I fired?
What! Why?
After that day's speech and
today's missed calls, that's natural.
Rubbish, Maya.
Listen.
I've had a phone call from
a very important person.
Someone in the ministry. They want to...
...they want us to organize a concert.
So, it's kind of huge,
can you come down?
Right now? Impossible!
Tomorrow, at the station?
Okay.
Tomorrow morning, at six. -
- What!
Hello.
This is Rohit Mehta.
And this is the first
documentation under coursework numbered...
...536, under the title...
...'The Life and
Times of Henysman Antony'.
We're at Chandannagore now...
...looking for our
first lead.
Heynsman Antony, who was
known as Antony Phiringi here.
Before we gather any
written information...
...let's see, what is the
general awareness and perception...
...about Antony
amongst the normal public.
Has anyone heard of him?
Do people know him? Etc.
Let's start with the market.
Antony, the foreigner? -
- I don't quite... -
Must be a Frenchman.
Marcus Anthony?
My name is Anthony Gonsalves.
I want to spend my whole life
Antony? -
- Yes.
What? A school?
I am the night and you're my moon-
- Uttam Kumar played
the role in Bengali...
...and Amitabh Bachhan in Hindi.
No. -
- You mean Uttam Kumar?
Shakespeare.
"Friends, Romans, countrymen;
lend me your ears, I have
come to bury Caeser.
Not to praise him."
ATV star? -
- No idea.
The Zamindar families here?
Ask there. You'll find him.
A Bengali film.
We're ordinary people. All we're
concerned about is our daily bread.
Open the gill. -
- What's the address they've given?
Chandannagore is a huge area. -
- I've acted in plays in college.
Kundu Villa is nearby, go there. -
- Antony and Cleopatra.
I played Cleopatra.
I get all that
but who is Antony?
Excuse me. -
- Yes.
Which way is the
Central Library?
Go straight,
take a right and then left.
Yes?
Needed some books on 19th
century Bengali culture.
Name of the book?
Who is the author?
I have it on my mobile.
Just a second.
Yes, Ishwarchandra Gupta's...
'A Poet's
Biography', Prafulla Chandra Pal's...
'Ancient Poet's Song',
Niranjan Chakrabarty's
'19th Century Scriptures...
...and Bengali Literature'.
And Madan Bandopadhyay's...
'Singer-song-writer,
Antony, the Foreigner'.
Kushal, see what he wants.
Assistant librarian by profession.
Voracious appetite for books.
Name: Kushal Hajra.
Hello. These books...
...Ishwarchandra Gupta's... -
- Not available.
Huh?
The four books you want,
we don't have them.
We've the fourth edition
of Asith Bandopadhyay's...
'History of Bengali Literature'.
I can give it to you.
But if you want to know about
Antony the singer-song writer,
you won't get more than two pages in it.
Umm... I mean... err...
...can you tell me where
can I find these books?
Not in Chandannagore. Try
College Street in Kolkata.
But people usually don't
keep these books anymore.
You could take a chance at the
Bengali Literature Association.
Okay.
Thank you.
But you won't find.
But...
...you just said... -
- You'll find the books.
Not Antony.
And definitely not his times.
So where can I find
Antony and his times?
Do you have the
time for that?
And the patience?
Try me.
Fine.
Wait behind the Sacred
Heart Church at 8pm tonight.
I will...
...take you to Antony.
The government is about to get
into a pact with Bangladesh.
Before that they want to
organize some sort of a...
...a Fraternity concert
and all that, you know.
As in involving student
communities of both the Bengals.
Some kind of a, you know... rock fest...
...or a rock band competition
or something like that, so...
...they want us to
be the radio partners...
...and organize this
side of the entire thing.
So we'll have to decide what... -
- Yes, but why Bangla bands only?
Is Bangla band the only
way to unite the Bengals?
Rabindrasangeet, Atul Prasad,
Nazrulgeeti... -
- Maya! Hold on.
Hold on for a second.
Hold on to your crusade.
This is not your radio show, okay?
This is a format decided by authorities.
So they must have thought that it...
...has a youth connect or
something like that. Whatever,
...that is not the point.
Point is this coming...
...21st February, on World
Mother Tongue day, will you... -
- At least call this day by
it's Bengali name?
Okay! Whatever!
Will you help me put up
the show?
Is the question mark just a
formality or do I have the option to refuse?
Christ! Maya,
Bengali songs are your strength!
So this huge process, you know...
...the screenings, the
student auditions...
...program scheduling,
deciding on the judges... Maya!
You know all the music
personalities in town!
It can't happen without you, Maya,
I mean it'll be a mess.
It'll be a pandemonium! -
- No, a bandemonium.
Huh?
I'll be there. And the concert
will be called Bandemonium, 2014.
Hello.
Now we're going for the second
documentation of the coursework.
An interview... with the very
mysterious Mr. Kushal Hajra,
...who is about to
introduce us to Mr. Antony.
Henysman Antony, a guy
who according to the history books,
...is dead for one seventy-seven years.
Needless to say I feel Mr.
Kushal is a fraud.
In fact, worse still, he
may have other intentions.
But there was something about his voice,
so I came.
And who knows, I might find
a crucial lead about Antony.
Let's see.
So...
...you had told me that...
...I'll get to meet Antony? -
- All in good time.
Sit.
And tell me what you know about Antony?
Not much.
In the late 18th century,
he was born in... -
- What a shame!
'Late 18th century'
after reading so many books?
Don't even know his birth year?
Yes, I mean...
...err...
You won't find Antony in pages of books,
Google.com or black and
white Bengali films, Rohit.
You'll find printed letters...
...some dates, bits
and pieces of lyrics.
You'll find Uttam Kumar, the film star,
and Manna Dey's voice and...
...you'll find the year
he died in, 1836.
But where's Antony?
Where is he?
Where?
Here.
At Pharashdanga.
1786, the year Lord
Cornwaliis came to Calcutta,
...Antony was born to a
salt merchant, Henysman.
But the internet says...
...he was born in Portugal.
He did come to India... -
- Are you a Marwari?
Huh?
Marwari, Punjabi, Marathi,
Gujarati or...
...a non-residential Bengali?
I am a Gujarati.
But born and brought up in Kolkata.
So was Antony.
Portuguese Christian.
Born and brought up in...
...Bengal.
If you ever make it big, if you
touch people's lives, you might find...
...erroneous information about
you on the internet, after 150 years!
But...
...what about Antony... -
No time, isn't it?
In a hurry?
Not that.
Go on.
Please speak.
I will have
to speak.
Or, gradually, I will...
A lean Antony came to
the world with a mole...
...on his right leg and
his father's huge business.
From childhood itself he did not
get along with his brother, Kelly.
Outside his bedroom
there was a...
...Banyan tree.
That was Antony's only friend.
When water dripped from it's
branches in the monsoons...
...Antony could see his mother...
...water dripping from her hair...
...Antony's mother passed away
while giving birth to him.
But how do you know
these things?
You don't find
these in a history book.
I know.
Because I have seen.
I see it everyday.
Because I was there.
Because I am Antony.
Antony 'Phiringi' (foreigner).
150 years back, had
looked for you, wanted to meet
Tired and weary, had slept off
in the darkness of the street
And now you come looking for me
150 years back, had
written songs in your praise
Had washed my eyes with my
mother tongue's watery haze
And now you come looking for me
150 years back, had
looked for you, wanted to meet
Tired and weary, had slept off
in the darkness of the street
And now you come looking for me
150 years back, had
written songs in your praise
Had washed my eyes with my
mother tongue's watery haze
And now you come looking for me
You are...
...Antony 'Phiringi'?
What! -
- Yes.
I am Antony 'Phiringi'.
Though...
...not in this birth.
In this birth I am...
...Kushal Hajra.
Assistant Librarian,
Chandannagore Central Library.
Salary; ten thousand rupees.
I have rice in the
morning and go to work.
Are you trying to... I mean...
...what the fu...
Rebirth? -
- Don't be so flabbergasted, Rohit.
The first time I saw myself I too was...
...shocked
I choked out of fear.
For a few hours had no
memory from either of the births,
complete black out.
I was at Asansol back then.
I had a good job at
a private firm.
The doctor said, I was getting
nightmares due to work pressure.
So I took leave for a few
days and went to Hazaribag.
One evening,
I had gone for a walk.
Far away at some temple, the
evening chants were going on.
Suddenly, had this vision,
I saw...
...the royal family of
Debs in Kolkata.
The courtyard...
...Kabigaan...
I am singing.
So many people!
Lights.
The hall, the applause.
And a hefty looking man
came and put a garland...
...a garland around
my neck...
...a garland... -
- Mr. Kushal...
Mr. Kushal... -
- No.
Mr. Kushal?
The same story, the same visual
year after year, like a movie.
My birth...
...my childhood...
...getting addicted to
Marijuana...
...then getting out of it.
And Saudamini...
And then Kabigaan.
Gorokhhonath.
Learning Bengali,
writing songs in it.
In the end...
...in the end... -
- What?
Nothing.
I was used to the visions
by then.
And...
...through books and investigation, I...
...came across some names and places...
...through which I figured
out who I was in my last birth.
I also understood that...
...I can't continue with the
job in Asansol for long...
...because my senior manager...
...had come to know that I had
been visiting a psychiatrist.
They created such a fuss...
...so I quit the job...
...and came and settled here.
And this new job...
...am I mad?
Yes, no... I mean...
...not quite...
...err... but... -
You don't believe me?
No.
I too could not believe.
After all, I'm a rational
middle class Bengali engineer.
I may be proud of Ritwik
Ghatak having written...
...the film on reincarnation,
'Madhumati',
or even be excited to watch Ray's
film on reincarnation, 'Sonar Kella'.
Heard of lan Stevenson?
Famous Canadian
bio-chemist and psychiatrist?
'Twenty Cases
Suggestive of Reincarnation'?
No.
The case of Shanti Devi
who was declared to be...
...a 'Jatiswar' by a scienctific
commission set up by Mahatma Gandhi?
Jatis... -
- Jatiswar.
Someone who has
memories from previous birth.
But... -
...I know.
Not just Shanti Devi...
...hundreds of such cases or...
...thousands of scientific
reports would still keep...
...would've not had any effect on my
cynicism had this not happened to me.
So you see, Rohit, what
is 'somehow', 'but'...
...'if', 'maybe'... to
me it is a real disease.
A persistent feeling of deja vu,
...a curse.
A curse?
Rather, you're lucky.
How can you say such
childish things!
What's wrong with you?
I lost my job!
I had to leave my city.
You are saying I'm lucky?
Faces, incidents,
problems of both the...
...births are jumbling up my mind and...
...you're saying I'm lucky?
I'll not be able to have this
conversation after a few months,
...and you're saying I am lucky? -
- No... err...
What I meant was actually... -
- What do you mean?
What?
Gradually,
Antony is eating up...
...the memories of this brith.
The visions are increasing.
I'm forgetting who I am,
which language I speak in,
how to lead a life in...
...in the year 2013...
When I experience these
visions...
...my blood
pressure increases.
Twice!
I have had a stroke twice!
And you will still say that I am...
I know...
...what my disease is...
...but I don't know...
...what the cure is, how long
I'll be able to survive this way.
I don't even know...
...how long I'll be able
to remember that I'm...
...Kushal Hajra.
My previous birth's memories...
...are spreading in my mind...
...like cancer.
I'm melting in to the dark
and still you'll say I am...
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to...
Can I suggest something?
Come to Kolkata with me.
You know the disease,
not the remedy.
So, let's go and see the
best psychiatrist in town.
Then let's see if we can save
Kushal Hajra from Antony 'Phiringi'.
Don't worry about the expenses.
I'll take care of it.
And in any case, in return...
...I need something from you.
So, don't worry.
No favors are
being done here.
What?
You'll have to...
...tell me the entire...
...story of Antony.
I need it for my
dissertation.
And may be...
...for my life.
Intermission.
Hello,
we're now with the fifth
documentation of the coursework.
It has been about seven
days we've come to Kolkata.
I have already had two
sessions with Mr. Kushal.
And we've covered most
of Antony's early life.
The plan is to gather as much information
as possible about Antony...
...before we can cross-check for
authenticity with historical sources.
So today, we'll look into the
musical career of Heynsman Antony.
Somehow Antony had been able to...
...come out of the infamous
company of weed-smokers.
Slowly,
he had started with his music.
Kabigaan was very popular
back in those times.
So, to listen to Kabigaan
for the first time...
...Antony went to...
...'Raja' (zamindar)
Gopi Mohan Deb's court.
Shovabajar,
courtyard.
The Kabigaan fight was between
veteran bard, Horu Thakur...
...and his ex-students Nilu
Thakur and Bhawani Bene's group.
Inspite of having many students,
...Horu Thakur's
favourite student was...
...Bhola 'Moyra' (sweetmeat maker).
Which is why Nilu
Thakur and Bhawani Bene's
...were very jealous of him.
So,
the group of students disintegrated.
They formed a new group.
It was...
...midnight.
Horu Thakur...
...started singing.
Only if I had known beforehand,
my friend
That Lord Krishna's emotion
is indeed a venomous potion
Only if I had known beforehand,
my friend
That Lord Krishna's emotion
is mixed with a venomous potion
Only if I had known beforehand,
my friend
The Honoured,
my friends, in all innocence,
Wouldn't have been
deceived in this way
The Honoured,
my friends, in all innocence,
Wouldn't have been
deceived in this way
Only if I had known beforehand,
my friend
That Lord Krishna's emotion
is indeed a venomous potion
Only if I had known beforehand,
my friend
Just after Horu Thakur's
Sakhisangbad got over... -
- Sorry. Sakhisangbad... what's that?
A part of Kabigaan.
There were mainly five
rounds in a Kabigaan duel.
Bhawani bishayak...
...where various songs were
sung about Goddess Uma or Durga.
Sakhisangbad...
...which was about Radha and
Krishna's love story in Vrindavan.
Viraha...
...written about normal people,
sad love songs.
Kheur...
...songs about gods and goddesses...
...which had frivolous,
sometimes rather...
...indecent lyrics.
And Lahar,
direct personal attack.
Insulting the opponent by
singing the most indecent of verses.
Thanks.
Please continue.
Brilliant! Salutations!
Nilu Thakur realized that Horu Thakur
had impressed the 'Raja' and the audience...
...much before he
reached Kheur round.
So, instead of singing Kheur...
...he sang Lahar and started insulting
Horuthakur with his vulgar verses.
But that did not help.
According to the Raja and the
public's verdict, Horu Thakur won.
And Antony acquired a new passion.
Kabigaan.
But...
...it must have been very difficult.
Err... I mean...
...I know that Antony...
...had been hearing Bengali
all around him since childhood,
he could even speak it. But...
...writing songs in that language... -
- Of course it was difficult.
Initially he used to
speak Sanskritized Bengali...
...because he had
learn it from the books.
Later, by interacting
with the natives...
...as in the villagers...
...he learnt the
colloquial version too.
He had written songs but
in Protuguese, not yet in Bengali.
And then...
...something struck him.
The main topic of
songs back then were...
...Vaishnav and Shakto Padabali,
as in...
...Radha, Krishna, Uma, Menoka...
and many more...
...of such gods and
goddesses from the Puranas.
He began by learning
Sanskrit from a tutor at home.
After all, the Language of the Gods.
It took time.
But he had learnt Latin
from his father as a kid, so...
...though he faced problems initially,
gradually he picked up.
After learning Sanskrit
Antony felt like he had...
...opened a door with a key.
He discovered a huge,
ancient, magical universe.
He had heard of it but never seen it.
But he could see it now.
He started reading
'Shastras' (holy scriptures).
Vedas, Upanishads,
Puranas, Upapuranans,
he read everthing.
He had music in him.
He learnt the topic and
the language of the songs.
But to understand how that language
morphed into lyrics of a song
he started listening
to Bengali folk music.
Jhumur, Panchali, Murshidi, Bhawaiya,
he'd go land up
anywhere and everywhere.
He listened carefully. And...
...he'd be on the look
out for Kabigaan duels.
He'd rush to the venue,
wherever it was, village or the city.
Bhola Moyra, Keshta 'Muchi'
(cobbler), Thakur Singha,
Ram Basu,
these guys were the masters.
Is he a Hindu God?
Or a Muslim Peer?
Oh, tell me, tell me, tell me!
So now you understand,
this Horu Thakur of yours
is not the Lord Krishna we know
He's the universe while this
one's a retard, dense and slow
This one's a retard, dense and slow!
During that time Antony had been to
Kumarkhali to listen to Fakiri music.
A student of Shiraj Shah,
had become very famous.
No one's interested in the truth
Only brouhaha, meaningless
Rancour, in the name of caste
Is indeed a strange business
One who visits the whore on the sly
Is called faithless, I wonder why
- Listening to his music Antony understood,
even after the melody,
the lyrics and the topic of the song,
a huge component remains.
The philosophy.
Lalon wonders what indeed is caste
Lalon wonders
Fakir Lalon wonders
Lalon wonders what indeed is caste
A strange deception
which never ceases
Rancour, in the name of caste
Is indeed a strange business
No one's interested in the truth
At a point he realized
a 'Dnarakabi' group was... -
- Sorry. 'Dnarakabi'?
Ameteur bards. As in...
...you could say, an amateur group.
So, Antony thought of
forming an amateur group.
Which is when he met...
...an upcoming 'Bnadhandaar'.
Gorokhhonath.
Sorry...
...'Bnadhandar' was the person who would
compose the lyrics for the bard.
It's not that all bards would
sing songs written by themselves.
The groups often had 'Bnadhandars'.
So you're coming?
Hope there will be some
depressing snacks for lunch?
For sure.
And some fat books on Bengali literature
to be used as paper weights.
Fine then.
I'll have a look at my schedule.
We need to screen a lot of bands.
We need to separate
the wheat from the chaff.
Yes. More than a thousand
bands have registered.
And the judges will be divided
into groups to screen them.
Your remuneration?
Everything depends
on my work pressure.
There will be a bit of
work pressure at that time...
...but I'll definitely
try to make it.
I'll be happy to judge.
Okay listen,
when you go to meet Rupam,
please take me with you,
I think he's very cute.
You haven't heard Rupam Islam
music enough to find him cute.
Shut up, moron!
Oh please! - -Hello brother...
...we're hungry. Come fast.
Listen, get us one Keema Matar,
one Chicken Bharta,
two boneleess Mutton tadkas,
and Nan for any of you?
None of us.
Four Tawa rotis,
we'll tell you if we need more.
And one Masala cold drink,
without lime.
Salad? Onions? -
- No!
You can find mouth freshners
in India, you know.
No, you see...
onions aren't good for health.
Don't overdo it. You'll
have to see a doctor eventually!
What you need more than a doctor,
Mr. Hajra...
...is rest.
These hallucinations, visions or
nightmares; whatever you call them,
if they keep increasing then
it's going to take a toll on your... -
- Heart.
Tell me something new, doctor.
Something I don't know.
Like...
...will this ever get cured?
Will it ever... - -See...
...I've spoken to three
internationally acclaimed...
...parapsychologists
regarding your problem.
I've had a detailed discussion
with Dr. Debasish Ghosh here as well.
Let me explain.
This part of the brain
is called Hippocampal gyrus.
This is our memory centre.
New and old,
all memories are stored here.
Now this Hippocampalgyrus...
...can be aroused
in many ways. Like...
...ringing bells in temple chants,
chanting of the word 'Om' etc.
...all of these generate
3.5 Hz brainwave.
At this 3.5 Hz...
...Hippocampal gyrusstarts resonating.
During that, the old memory,
even past life memory may come back.
Now the second possible explanation.
There's a gland called
the Pineal gland here,
which is called, the Third eye.
Now, we don't know how or why
this gets aroused but if it does...
...your lost memory
may suddenly come back.
The third explanation is,
genetic memory.
Carl Jung said,
'Collective unconscious'.
We're all connected to each
other in some way or the other...
...via our DNA.
This too is possible that
you may have a genetic connect...
...with the person,
whose memories have come back to you.
Whatever that may be...
...now the problem is, the memories
that are coming back to you...
...if they keep increasing
in frequency and intensity,
it may subvert your
present memory and...
...turn these memories
into your dominant memories.
And during this,
not only schizophrenia
and split personality,
...there's a chance of identity
crisis or memory replacement too. -
- Just a minute. Can you explain
this in an easier language.
As in, how long will
his normal memory last?
As in, before he... -
- Before I lose himself.
Well, difficult to say.
Matters of the brain, you see.
May take weeks or even a year.
Depends on the rate of replacement
by the dominant memory.
See, due to the neural
plasticity of the Hippocampus,
a consolidation of memory occurs.
May lead to a regression too.
As in, this growth may become slower.
It may even come
to a halt one fine day.
Yes!
But how?
Avery common and easy
way is reconciliation.
As in revisiting the places and the
people whom you see in the visions.
No, that's not working.
That's why I shifted to Chandannagore
from Asansol but it increased.
Next... as in is there another way?
There is another way.
Past life regression.
Do you have any trauma
from your past life...
...that had given you a big shock?
Or a very important task
that you couldn't complete?
Mr. Hajra, were you looking
for someone or something?
Or are you still searching?
Don't worry,
I think whatever had happened...
...I think you must
not worry about this.
Things will get better. You... -
- Hey wait! Stop the car!
Stop! - -What happened?
What happened Mr. Kushal...
...where are you going! Mr. Kushal...
Don't go Mr. Kushal!
Wait!
What are you doing? Leave me!
He's...
...okay fine.
Pull over.
Mr. Kushal!
Give way, will you?
Greetings, sahib.
Some cash is required
to build the wall on the North.
So Madam asked me to tell you. -
- Come and take it tomorrow.
So, where is she?
She was here a while ago. Should I... -
- That won't be necessary.
I will find Soudamini myself.
Mr. Kushal...
...what are you looking at?
Let's go! Mr. Kushal...
Mr. Kushal, come with me.
Come on, let's leave!
Amitabh and Sudeshna
have settled down too.
At least now you
must look for someone.
Love is incapable of taming me.
And I can't settle down with someone.
I'll have to unsettle up.
Why?
Sujit was a nice guy.
Waste of time.
And Amiya? -
- Casting pearls before swine.
Oh really! And you are such a pearl!
Human Elsa. Born Free.
That's enough! Arguing all the time.
Switch on the Bengali
channel on the TV.
My serial is about to begin.
What's this?
Have you really gone mad?
Why this Gujarati channel? Asked
you to switch on the Bengali channel.
705.
Mom, when did you realize
that Dad's case was real?
Huh?
Real? -
- Hmm.
It's not an infatuation
or a passing phase...
...it's the real thing.
True love...
...and all that jazz.
On my way back from the crematorium...
Mr. Kushal...
...come.
What? Come inside.
Sit.
Tell me.
Any problem?
Can't get sleep?
Sorry.
Sorry?
For what?
I mean...
...anything could've
happened on the road.
Because of...
...I lost myself.
Don't even think
about it, Mr. Kushal.
Losing yourself for something,
I know how that feels.
It's not always in your control.
Thank you.
What are you writing?
All that I've...
...read...
...learnt...
...understood...
felt... all these years...
...now they want to come out.
What is it?
A song?
Want to listen to it?
This is the first draft.
Written for someone very special.
Okay.
So...
...what's her name?
As they say...
...everything is 'Maya' (illusion).
Into my life, Out of the blue,
Did you arrive, Tell me, did you?
My broken life, It's frayed brink,
Of city-days', just at the kink,
Into my life, Out of the blue,
Did you arrive, Tell me, did you?
My broken life, It's frayed brink,
Of city-days', just at the kink,
Did you arrive, Tell me, did you?
Alas no more You will get here,
A thing you can, Consider dear,
With ease.
O where was I
Going as such,
From where was I Expecting much,
With ease.
Now simple words, Are hardly that,
Survival's prime Simple format.
My broken life, It's frayed brink,
Of city-days', just at the kink,
Into my life, Out of the blue,
Did you arrive, Tell me, did you?
This is how I...
...met her for
the first time.
I mean...
...Antony met
Soudamini for the first time.
Cinematic stuff.
You could say so.
Where's your...
...camera?
Didn't record this?
No.
Not this one.
Perfect!
I want to go home!
Hello.
I want to register
for Bandemonium.
Here's my entry.
Another weirdo!
Details please.
Hmmm. Nice body!
Details, as in? -
- As in your name,
your father's name,
your manager's name.
Antony.
Henysman Antony.
Damned Anglo-Indian for sure!
Woah! What a sexy name!
Which college?
Or university?
Humboldt university.
Sorry.
Humboldt university,
second year.
Portuguese studies.
How many members in the band?
Members? Err...
...I am alone.
Oh God! This is a band show,
not a solo.
Wasted my time...
read and come next time.
No, but I... -
- Now please go!
I've a lot of work to do.
Now go!
Please go will you?
Band of idiots!
Excuse me.
What now? -
- Take down the band's name.
What! -
- The band's name.
Pharashdanga Graduate band.
What 'danga'?
I clearly remember my... I mean...
...sorry...
...Antony's first Kabigaan fight.
The opponent was the
famous female bard,
Jogyeshwari.
Rumour was...
...she was Ram Basu's girlfriend.
Wow!
Bob Dylan-Joan Baez of that era?
Wow.
I see that Sahib has come
in the guise of a Bengali.
Yes.
Just like you've come in
the guise of a woman.
Since you have become my soul mate
Let me confide in you,
A glance at your face
and I get over my blues
Since you have become my soul mate
Let me confide in you,
Imprisoned by love,
slow and surely I get tamed
The 'virtuos' woman that I am,
what am I without a husband?
Imprisoned by love,
slow and surely I get tamed
The 'virtuos' woman that I am,
what am I without a husband?
Forsake your home, be
it spring or monsoon,
Deny the pious and satiate me soon.
Since you have become my soul mate
Let me confide in you,
A glance at your face
and I get over my blues
Since you have become my soul mate
Let me confide in you,
Brilliant!
Salutations!
Just edit that bit.
I think there's some
problem in the monitoring.
Can you hear it?
Yes.
In that case, you know
how humans growl?
I want that sort of a growl,
like a human or a beast, you get it?
And practice the scatting bit too.
Antony's group had
just started the 'Jill'.
'Jill'? Jacking
me with jargons again?
Sorry.
'Jill'... it is like
a commencement...
...with instruments like
'dhol' and 'kasha'.
As in...
...like musically
challenging your opponent.
As soon as that happened, I,
as in Antony, started getting tense.
It was the first
duel after all.
But the moment I, I mean
Antony stood up...
...the moment he started singing the
Viraha written by Gorokkho...
...that was it. The public, the
judge and the opponet went mute.
The first time when
you went on stage...
...did you have stage fright? -
- My first performance...
...there have been
many kinds of first times.
But yes, speaking of stage frights...
...let me tell you about the
first time I performed my songs,
when I got on stage to perform
my own songs the first time,
I was scared.
But then...
...the dark silhouetted
heads of the audience...
...the blinding lights...
...the microphone's metalic echo...
...set everything right.
Not anymore, my love,
don't come in my way
Can't understand your visits
Please pay heed to what I say
Not anymore, my love,
don't come in my way
Gorokhho!
Mr. Kushal...
Who is it? Gorokkho?
You're here finally?
You lowly money
minded swine!
Mr. Kushal...
- Why do you decieve like a woman?
How greedy can you get!
Listen... -
- Don't you know what I've lost?
Don't you know Kelly
cheated me off my property.
You may be my 'Bnadhandar' but...
...I too can compose songs for
duels if it comes to that, remember!
Mr. Kushal... I am...
Now go! Get lost!
You nasty maggot!
Go away!
You greedy dog!
Get lost from here!
Go away!
Mr. Kushal...
Mr. Kushal... please!
See, I have already
committed to a duel in Chinsura.
Our group has earned a
bit of a reputation.
This one last time,
after that I'll...
Mr. Kushal...
...pay you the price you want.
The salary you ask for.
Mr. Kushal! Geta hold on yourself!
It's me!
I'm Rohit.
I'm Rohit, Mr. Kushal.
Mr. Kushal...
What's wrong with you?
Mr. Kushal?
Rohit.
Camera.
Losing out on time.
I'm...
...sinking fast.
Because Gorokhhonath refused
to compose lyrics for me...
...I myself had to start
composing for the Kabigaan duels.
And after composing my first song...
...I never had to look back.
It was my...
...first duel with Ram Basu.
What are your devious ways,
O Goddess, of ignoring me?
Will you have mercy on me,
finally?
I am a foreigner by birth,
O Goddess
Hence you ignore me and go away
I am a foreigner by birth,
O Goddess
I don't know how to
chant and pray
I don't know how to pray to you,
so my prayers go unanswered
So the foreigner will
seek your blessings Matangi,
Till his voice his heard
The Goddess Matangi blessed me.
I had already beaten Jogyeshwari.
Later I beat Ram Basu, Keshta Muchi,
Jogeshwar 'Dhopa'
(washerman) and even Thakur Singha.
Tell me, O Antony, could
you please kindly explain
Having come to my country, why
aren't you dressed like clergymen?
Tell me, O Antony, could
you please kindly explain
Having come to my country, why
aren't you dressed like clergymen?
Tell me, O Antony
Tell me, O Antony, where are
your shoes and boots and socks
It seems you favour our sandals more
Could you solve this little
paradox?
Tell me, O Antony, could
you please kindly explain
Having come to my country, why
aren't you dressed like clergymen?
Tell me, O Antony
Well done! Brilliant!
I'm quite happy in my
Bengalin my fancy Bengali dress
Being Thakur Singha's son-in-law
have forsaken my foreign ways
I'm quite happy in my
Bengalin my fancy Bengali dress
Being Thakur Singha's son-in-law
have forsaken my foreign ways
Father-in-laws and
son-in-laws have common ways, you see
I belong to the soil of Bengal
and Bengal belongs to me
Bengal belongs to him!
Not only Viraha, Kheur and Lahar,
my most popular genre was the...
...the welcome songs
of Mother Goddess Durga.
Hail O Goddess Mahamaya
Your endless clemency
One who invokes you,
O Mother Durga
You take care of his destiny
Hence I cry out to you, O Mother,
in this mortal world
I cry out in distress
But you pay no heed
to your son, O Mother
Why are you so heartless?
Admitted, I have been a bad son
But why will you be
a bad mother?
Like you were born of a stone
You behave like no other
Tell me, O Merciful one,
tell me
Will I have your blessing eventually?
Tell me, O Merciful one,
tell me
Will I have your blessing eventually?
Brilliant!
Well done! Welll done!
Hello brother! -
- When? Where? How?
Slow down.
Too many questions at one go.
Holy Christ!
You've got a huge place!
So, Mr. Disco Dandia,
what's up with you?
Your Mr. Disco Dandia has
taken to Raybne she dancing now.
Oh my God! What have you done?
Which Bengali cleansed
your Bengali pronunciation?
I'm surely sending Gaby to you. -
- Not a Bengali.
A Portuguese. -
- What!
Close your mouth, a fly may get in.
Can you give me some weed?
Though after this, a couple of
reefers would've had the same effect.
Hey, listen...
I just want to meet Uncle
Reincarnate once, please!
Please! -
- He is sleeping.
And he isn't keeping well, too.
Okay.
Obviously that happens later then.
And what's going on with your
music?
Have you been able
to serenade Maya yet?
I've got a chance. -
- Okay.
As in... like a show.
You know... Radio Mirchi?
They're doing a concert.
She's the main organizer.
I've been selected also.
But there's a hitch. -
- Hitch?
I lied during the
registration that I have a band.
Or they wouldn't allow.
And I don't know
anybody in the band circuit.
At least if I could
get some musicians... -
Or leave it to the hands. Right?
Don't worry.
We'll arrange something.
I will take you to someone.
My senior from the
Medical college days here.
Like a friend.
I think he'll be able
to guide you well.
Don't worry.
The decision has to
be taken today itself.
Of course. We've to... -
- That's why I came.
We need to finish this.
Remember everybody.
Listen to me everyone.
Let's listen to what he
has to say. Then we speak.
Here he comes.
Wait.
Hello brothers. -
- Listen, you untouchable,
you've married a Hindu girl
rescuing her from the Sati pyre.
We've not said anything.
You've been breaking
all rules.
Respected people in the village
have lost their caste because of you.
We didn't say anything.
But today when we heard... -
Will you stop listing his
blasphemies and get to the point?
Fine, I'll get to it.
Today we heard you're
planning to organize a Durga Puja!
That's true. -
- Then listen...
...this Puja will not happen. -
- Why?
We're staying here, at the outskirts of
the village without bothering anyone. -
- Shut up!
We've already told
you this puja won't... -
Go inside, Mini.
Go in.
Listen Antony Sahib, I'll tell
you why this Puja cannot happen.
You're a Christian by birth.
Moreover you're poking your nose
into our traditions, our customs,
even our festivals!
Even the Viceroy would
not have dared that!
A crow doesn't turn into a peacock
putting on a peacock's feather.
And an amateur poet doesn't become a
Bengali by singing a few Kheur songs.
And Durga Puja?
That's our very own...
...Bengali festival. Therefore... -
- Listen brothers, Goddess
Mahamaya herself decides...
...who is a Bengali and who isn't.
I am just a humble devotee.
Worshipping her is my duty.
I will do that.
You may do anything you
want to, I don't mind at all.
Goodbye.
What I am thinking is...
...I am a judge at the
same competition...
Will it be correct if I guide you?
I don't have any interest in...
...in competing there.
I just want to sing this
song for someone there.
If need be declare an
out of competition... -
- Just a minute.
Sing it for 'someone' as in?
The same cardiac case everywhere.
Well well!
Good!
In that case I'll say that
your song is very nice...
...I really liked it.
A unique composition. I got
a very special feeling in it.
So it's better not to
approach it with a typical...
...drums, bass guitar,
guitar, keyboard set up.
So...
...what do you suggest?
How you should arrange this song,
how you should present it,
I think there is only
one person in Kolkata.
If he agrees to help you,
you're done.
You'll get a set of musicians and...
...then if he agrees to
play along, nothing like it.
Do one thing,
I'll give him a
call and speak to him.
Then you can go, meet him.
Sing him your songs.
And that's it.
Thank you Sidhu, I didn't
imagine you'll help us like this.
Don't be so formal. I've
been in college too, isn't it?
And in such cardiac cases my
emotion works a little more.
Rita from NRS and Bodhi
from National college...
...when they had just begun,
I've contributed a lot in that.
Fine.
Who's this person?
All arrangements
will be made on time.
Only you won't be there.
I know, you've become
very famous now.
You're very busy.
Fine,
one day when you come back...
...you'll find my dead body
lying here.
Then I'll kill myself and lie
down in the grave beside you.
No.
That won't happen.
Why will I be buried
because I married you?
I will be cremated.
Will you stop?
I have duels on all the
three evenings of Durga Puja.
And on the
last night...
...I'm competing with
Bhola Moyra, at Sovabajar.
And that's a duel I...
...had to fight.
With this the last
chapter of my life began.
My...
...last Kabigaan duel.
Even a birth later...
...when those incidents...
...emerge in my mind
just like a film...
...I...
When I reached 'Raja' Gopi
Mohan Deb's palace that evening,
I saw,
it was a huge affair.
Bhola Moyra was waiting
therewith his group to attack me.
We took our seats.
The competition began.
As the night fell, the
fight became tougher.
Both sides got equal appreciation
from the Raja and public...
...in Bhawani Bishayak,
Sakhisangbad and Viraha.
So it was obvious that the
judgement would be made in...
...the Kheur and Lahar rounds.
Here you are.
I needed to talk to you,
there's a problem.
I'll have to reach the venue directly
from the airport on that day.
No problem.
There will be a car waiting.
That's very good.
A nothing thing... the main thing...
...how's the participation
looking like?
Some very good bands have registered.
Looks like it'll be a tough fight.
Come.
Love engulfs the soul,
Love engulfs the soul
In faraway lands you roam,
I come back to an empty home
The heart explodes, I worry and fret,
And grapple with my lovesick state
Love engulfs the soul
As the mind is on a roll,
Look who's here! Mr. Coward Lee!
How are you? Still
studying or that's finally over?
Still going on.
Nice.
Still learning Bengali or have you
shifted to Hebrew to impress girls?
No.
Still trying my luck at Bengali.
Maya.
Even today.
Where to?
We've come to Sidhu's house.
There's a concert on the 21st.
I need passes.
Oh God! Now I'll have to meet you
at Bengali music concerts as well?
So be it.
Keep a Bengali to
English dictionary handy.
Fulfill by experiencing
Krishna within yourself,
and be sure to avoid his touch
Lest misfortune befalls
you before your union,
And you miss him again as much.
O Moon-faced one,
besotted with the Lord
That your pining end
with devotion, overawed
Don't worry, O Radha, your
pangs of separation have ceased
By the prancing flautist now, you
will hence have your heart seized!
Don't worry, O Radha
What's this crap you smoke!
Saw dust and wood scrap.
Smoke something nice
if you have to.
I still remember...
...smoking the hookah
with my Grandpa.
Are you down?
Tea? -
- No!
Nothing's wrong with me
and I don't want anything.
You snap at me exactly
like your father used to.
Only, you have
better teeth.
Who's the guy?
Or is it a girl?
Mom!
Why not? Better if it's
a girl, less complicated.
He used to study
in our university.
Gujarati fellow.
I shunned him because he was
a huge nag and very clingy.
Met him a few days back.
Looks like he's still the same.
Still as clingy?
Hope he does not love you. -
- What!
Mom, please!
No, I am just asking.
Anyway.
In a few days your concert
will begin. You'll get busy.
You won't have the time to
think about all this.
These incorrigible, irritating lads!
Disgusting!
Now will you care for a cup of tea?
It's about to rain.
Come downstairs.
A misfit schitzo, a hunted torso
And the 'I'-ego
Let it grow What's the harm in that?
And a fellatio
Each rumour's ratio
Rude? You could say so
But am I the only brat?
What's the harm in that?
A misfit schitzo, a hunted torso
And the 'I'-ego
Let it grow What's the harm in that?
And a fellatio
Each rumour's ratio
Rude? You could say so
But am I the only brat?
My well fed cerebellum
Astro chart's ultimatum
Funeral memorium
Anointing Bengali rock
Let gambling be abetted
Let me be domesticated
Pituitary generated
Eroding one's inner block
If the die is cast,
You're lucky to lose
Boiled macaroni-dieting blues
I'am lion at heart
And a Leo by sign
So I scream and growl
At any given time
I'am lion at heart
And a Leo by sign
So, through the amp I roar
At any given time
I'am lion at heart
And a Leo by sign
So I scream and growl
At any given time
I'am lion at heart
And a Leo by sign
So, through the amp I
roar At any given time
If the female source of energy
(Shakti), O Shiva, created you
Then why do you call her
your wife? Why do you?
Tell me, O Bhola (Lord Shiva), Any
explanation? Do you have a clue?
If the female source of energy
(Shakti), O Shiva, created you
Then why do you call her
your wife? Why do you?
Tell me, O Bhola (Lord Shiva), Any
explanation? Do you have a clue?
explanation,? Do you have a clue?
Don't you know Bhola,
I am your Parvati dear?
After carrying you in my womb
Now I'm your wife, I hear
Don't you know Bhola,
I am your Parvati dear?
After carrying you in my womb
Now I'm your wife, I hear
During the churning of the ocean
When you consumed the poison
You cried out my name Said,
'Durga, I seek your protection'.
You suckled on my breasts
Saved your own endangered life
I wonder, when was I your mother
And exactly when I became your wife
If the female source of energy
(Shakti), O Shiva, created you
Then why do you call her
your wife? Why do you?
Tell me, O Bhola (Lord Shiva), Any
explanation? Do you have a clue?
It grapples, struggles
grows and loses fizz
In my clumsy, unkempt wardrobe
Where my torn jeans gets violent
In such disdainful implausible times,
will you still remain silent?
The morning comes, I hate it
Better I sleep and forget it
Dare you awaken your defiance,
will you ponder in your silence?
What if the alarm
rings in your coffin?
It grapples, struggles
grows and loses fizz
A heathen, an outcaste, a foreigner
Incorrigible,
can't reform you anymore!
A heathen, an outcaste, a foreigner
Incorrigible,
can't reform you anymore!
Can't reform you anymore!
Incorrigible,
can't reform you anymore!
Can't reform you anymore!
Let me tell you honestly
O Rotten One, on an evil spree
Not for you are Gods Krishna, Kali
Go back to your Jesus
silently
In the church at Serampore
Well done!
Where's Rupam? -
- He went to Darjeeling for a show.
Got stuck in a landslide. -
- Now what?
He won't make it. He
badly wanted to come though.
Okay.
But Maya insisted so
he didn't take the risk.
Therefore? -
- Gabu.
Last minute replacement
on Maya's request.
Bunch of worthless fools!
Hey there...
...the next band is
Pharashdanga Graduate band?
Who on earth are they now?
Where are they? Look for them!
The musicians are setting up inside.
But the lead singer... -
- I'm here.
Hi. -
- You! You're next!
For Christ's sake, hurry up!
What happened?
Why did you go speechless, sahib?
Say something?
Lost your tongue?
Christ and 'Krishta' (Lord Krishna)
Are hardly different, my friend
Just difference in the diction
is where all differences end
Christ and 'Krishta' (Lord Krishna)
Are hardly different, my friend
My Christian God is the
same as your Hindu Lord
Getting Krishna's blessings
makes my life worthily spent
Christ and 'Krishta' (Lord Krishna)
Are hardly different, my friend
Brilliant!
Salutations!
Well done!
Brilliant!
Coming up next to perform,
Pharashdanga Graduate band!
Thank you.
Thanks to all of you.
Wherever I am today,
for that I am...
...extremely
grateful to a lot of people.
Among them I want to
specially mention three names.
One.
Sidhu. Thank you Sidhu,
thank you so much.
Two.
Kabir Suman, without whose
help I wouldn't have reached here.
He has arranged this song
of mine with a lot of love.
And three.
The one who is the
inspiration for this song,
the one whom I have loved,
who has encouraged me,
...to dare to come here,
the one, to whom
this song is dedicated...
...that name is...
...the entire family of
Radio Mirchi.
Who is this 'you' that I behold,
Who holds a mirror in her eyes,
Why is it that when I caress you,
This 'you' inexplicably cries...
Who is this 'you' that I behold,
Who holds a mirror in her eyes,
Why is it that when I caress you,
This 'you' inexplicably cries...
Birth and re-birth, the cycle goes
on, As your memory echoes in time,
Like ancient melodies of our
land, In today's tunes they chyme
Birth and re-birth, the cycle goes
on, As your memory echoes in time,
Like ancient melodies of our
land, In today's tunes they chyme
Come and fill up my silence,
With alphabets of sighs
Why is it that when I caress you,
This 'you' inexplicably cries...
Who is this 'you' that I behold,
Who holds a mirror in her eyes,
Why is it that when I caress you,
This 'you' inexplicably cries...
In some birth I was the poet
Jaidev, and you were Padmavati,
The forgotten tales of scriptures
which Cry like you incessantly...
In some birth I was the poet
Jaidev, and you were Padmavati,
The forgotten tales of scriptures
which Cry like you incessantly...
And in each teardrop,
I die and am born again
As recounting tales of many births,
is your silent pain
And in each teardrop,
I die and am born again
As recounting tales of many births,
is your silent pain
You've poured yourself on me before,
Drench me like rain from the skies,
Why is it that when I caress you,
This 'you' inexplicably cries...
Who is this 'you' that I behold,
Who holds a mirror in her eyes,
Why is it that when I caress you,
This 'you' inexplicably cries...
Who is this 'you' that I behold,
Who holds a mirror in her eyes,
Why is it that when I caress you,
This 'you' inexplicably cries...
Yes.
May I come in?
Sure.
You went off key twice and you
missed the beat once as well.
Though you can always
say it was all...
...intentional.
Not only that.
My pronunciation of
'S' isn't perfect yet.
My 'R' is still like a non
residential Bengali and maybe...
...sometimes I say
'O' instead of an 'Aw'.
I'm sorry.
Can I get another year?
Last chance.
My mother is waiting
outside to meet you.
A couple of friends are waiting too.
Should I call them? -
- Yeah... of...
...of course.
Err... obviously.
I too have somebody
I want you to meet.
Just a second.
Hello, Mr. Kushal...
Birju?
How do you have his phone?
Gave it to you and left?
As in? When?
Where did he go?
You don't know?
This is ridiculous!
The man is unwell.
He just disappeared?
Don't you have
any responsibility?
What do you mean? Go look
for him. When did he leave?
Go look for him outside!
Right now!
Idiot!
Mr. Kushal!
You got me so worried!
You just left without telling anyone?
Anyway,
Mr. Kushal...
...I want you to
meet someone special.
I told you about Maya...
...this is Mahamaya.
Hello, Mr. Kushal.
Heard a lot...
Hail O Goddess Mahamaya
Your endless clemency
Mr. Kushal?
Hail O Goddess Mahamaya
Your endless clemency
Mr. Kushal?
Mr. Kushal, don't do this!
Please, Mr. Kushal!
Mr. Kushal, listen to me.
Mr. Kushal, I'm Rohit.
Mr. Kushal! -
- Mistake!
You've come to the wrong bard.
I am not Kushal.
I am Antony.
Antony 'Phiringi'.
Shit! -
- Antony 'Phiringi'...
Mr. Kushal, look at me!
Look at me,
Mr. Kushal.
You live here.
You are a librarian in Chadannagore.
Mr. Kushal, you're a librarian,
you used to stay in Asansol.
Mr. Kushal, you have
past life memories!
Mr. Kushal?
Come on, look at me! -
- Hey!
Who are you?
Who sent you?
Who has sent you?
Come on, tell me!
Who sent you? Hey!
That worthless village
headman sent you, right?
Aren't you done yet,
even after killing my Mini?
You've finished us!
We're homeless now!
What do you want now?
Tell me or I'll kill you!
Tell me who has sent you?
'Raja' Gopi Mohan Deb!
'Raja'?
The Raja sent you?
You should've told me earlier!
I am so sorry!
I did not recognize you.
Oh no!
I am so sorry.
I've really lost it
after Mini's death.
Anyway,
what's gone
is gone.
But I can't ignore Goddess
Saraswati's blessings, can I?
There will be death,
there will be old age...
but work is work.
I am a bard after all. Isn't it?
So you've come to invite me?
Who's on the other side?
Surely Bhola?
I knew he won't let go.
Horu Thakur's disciple,
he definitely has an ego! -
- We lost him.
Can he forget how I beat
him in front of the Raja?
He must be sitting somewhere,
singing,
I'm not the Bhola you
pray to, I'm not the creator
Horu's disciple from the city
I'm the sweetmeat maker,
He's not the Bhola you
pray to, he's not the creator
Horu's disciple from the city,
he's the sweetmeat maker,
Hello.
Dr. Sengupta?
I desire not to be immortal,
Have no other wishes too,?
The only drive of my mortal stint,
Is merely wanting you.
Moments pass like previous births,
Reincarnating fast,
Alphabets just fade away,
like The memories from the past.
Torn pages of scriptures, sighing,
The wind just rustles through,
The only drive of my mortal stint,
Is merely wanting you.
Lokhkhinodor's myth dances on a,
Cobra's outstretched hood,
Our tradition never did
allow For Behula's widowhood.
The rafts float by, carrying
along The corpses, all the same,
Have been looking for you for many
days now to tell you just this...
...sorry Maya,
I should have stayed back that day.
I have been born, a myriad times,
Have died before, on your lap,
Just to see you once more, I
have Embraced this re-birth's trap.
Time and again, we have come back,
To the Earth, the calling's strong,
Sometime Gangur, or Kopai,
even, In Kopotakhkho's song.
Gangur turned into Cauvery,
and Often Mississipi too,
Rhine and Congo, as rivers wrote
Their music whole life through.
I will not, I, have never
written Down music ever before,
Let wanting you reflect, in
folk Songs' unwritten score.
When I fell in love with you,
A thousand births ago,
Buddha painted his loneliness?
In the evening glow.
His kindness had you wander in
Solitude, begging for alms,
And I yearned for an yearning you,
As I met those outstretched palms.
On my knees, those times found me,
I am still on my knees,
Come bewitch with eyes, with palms
Outstretched in dreams, come please.
Place your lips on my parched lips,
Let's build a barricade new,
I swear by the Revolt and Love,
I only desire you.
Enchanted by my dreams, you had,
Taken births endlessly,
I was your scream, your
desire and Revolution, your fury.
Whenever pain had touched you,
know That, that touch was my hand,
I am your man, I am your roots,
I am your motherland.
Whenever you had borne a child,
It's father was my desire,?
Lost count of our children
who Have lit our crimson pyre.
We come back, 'n' we come
again Each time, we go back too,
Will come again, declare again,
I only desire you.
We come back, 'n' we come
again Each time, we go back too,
Will come again, declare again,
I only desire you.