Here comes the sugar man.
This'll make the last payment on my car.
Yeah, but it's all worn out.
Where you been all this time?
Hartwell.
Donegan.
Yoo-hoo!
Man, give me that fortune.
What are you gonna do
with all that money?
I'm gonna buy a herd of chorus girls
and make 'em dance on my bed.
Ninety-five, a hundred...
five, six...
seven... a hundred and eight dollars.
Good week, Vince.
You ready?
Yeah.
Vince likes that kind of punishment.
Someday he's gonna learn.
Okay, drinks are on me.
That's the kind of athletic contest
I appreciate. He's game, that boy.
I'll get you next week.
You bet, Vince.
Buy me a drink, cowboy?
- You're buyin', aren't you?
- Jake, draw one for the lady.
- I'll take a shot, if you can afford it.
- I can afford it.
I saw you here last week
cashing your check.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Hey, you got nice hair.
I get through work around 4:00.
- Why, you two-bit little tramp!
- Hey!
She didn't mean anything.
I bought a round for the house.
- Keep outta this.
- She wasn't outta line.
- I said, keep your mouth outta this.
- Leave her alone.
Look, buster. You want some teeth
knocked out, just keep it up.
You scare me.
Woman beaters always scare me.
Why don't you run along, sonny,
before I muss up your hair?
Vince, he's had enough!
He's had enough!
Hey, kid, you can hit.
Somebody call a doctor.
This guy's hurt bad.
You've been found guilty by a jury of
your peers of the crime of manslaughter.
You're hereby remanded to
the custody of the sheriff...
and you'll be transported
to the state penitentiary...
to serve a term of not less than one,
nor more than ten years of imprisonment.
Court dismissed.
A tough woodchuck, huh?
Well, that's what we're here for,
to teach you hooligans.
It says here you killed a man
with your bare hands.
We don't use hands here.
We use guns.
I'll tell you another thing we use for
cons who don't toe the mark: The whip.
- Understand?
- Yes.
Sir!
Yes, sir.
I'm puttin' you in with
Hunk Houghton, an old-timer.
- All right, that's all.
- Thank you, sir.
When do I finish my processing?
No hurry.
You got plenty of time.
Hang it up.
- Put it up where you got it.
- Sure.
Didn't know you're
touchy about it.
I live here.
I'm touchy about everything.
You're on my bunk.
Is this okay?
- My name's Vince Everett.
- You know my name.
Glad to know you.
Yeah.
- You're not through processing.
- Not yet.
- What about your haircut?
- What about it?
You want a good one
or a fresh fish special?
- A fresh fish...
- A fresh fish special.
They hack it up. A good one will
cost you three packs of cigarettes.
I haven't got three packs.
- You got any money?
- Nope. Spent it all on my lawyer.
I'll loan you three packs,
you pay back four.
Kind of silly savin' up
cigarettes like that.
You'll learn.
Okay, tell me about
the cigarettes.
I run a business, sonny.
I'm what you might call
one of the top cons in this stir.
I got representatives in the
tailor shop, commissary, sick bay...
kitchen and shoe shop,
and they all work for me.
You want a good haircut? I fix it.
A good pair of shoes? You ask me.
Like everything else,
you gotta pay for it.
This here is
the coin of the realm.
Where do you get cigarettes?
You trade with guys who don't smoke,
you buy 'em, you steal 'em...
just like you did
for money on the outside.
I'm broke. I'll never
accumulate any cigarettes.
The state pays you 18 cents a day.
That's a start.
- Play ball with me, and I'll stake you.
- That's real nice of you.
I can't have my cell mate
lookin' like a bum.
I got a reputation
to live up to.
- You been assigned a job yet?
- Not yet.
You'll probably draw the coal yard.
It's hard and it's dirty.
Maybe I can get you out of it, get you
assigned to the print shop where I am.
How many packs?
Five cartons of cigarettes.
I'll loan 'em to you.
At what interest rate?
You're learnin' fast.
The interest rate won't be too high.
You just do what I say when I say it.
That's the basis
of my organization.
- No, thanks.
- Huh?
I'll take my chances.
Suit yourself.
- Thanks anyway, though.
- It's no skin off my behind.
Hey, guard,
how about a water call?
One water call every two hours.
You oughta know the rules by now.
- In this heat?
- Get back to work.
That new warden, the jerk!
Ever since he come here,
this can ain't fit to live in.
- Hey, Houghton!
- I hear you callin'.
What are we gonna do about conditions?
I've had a bellyful.
I got less than a deuce to go.
I'm gonna suffer my little heart out.
- Not me. I'm gonna do somethin'.
- What a lousy dump!
I'd better quiet
those steers down.
I'm up in the mornin'
with the risin' sun
I work like a slave
'til the day is done
Just workin' and sleepin'
and nothin' more
And every day is just
like the day before
One more day
One day older
and nearer to my Lord
One more day
Listen to the prayer
of a lonely man
Livin' day to day
the best he can
Give me the strength
to carry my load
Glory waits for me
at the end of the road
One more day
One day older
and nearer to my Lord
One more day
That's mighty pretty, Hunk.
Give us another.
Thanks a lot, neighbors.
Appearin' before you has given me
a big hunk of pleasure.
I hope to be around pickin' and
singin' for you again real soon.
Whereabouts did you learn
to sing like that?
That used to be my trade,
sonny buck.
I was singin' country music
before the words were invented.
I was on the stage with the best of 'em:
Eddy Arnold, Roy Acuff.
Did you make good money?
I made two bills a week.
I was swimmin' in gravy in those days.
Get on to the sad part.
A woman and a bank did it.
She got used to bonded bourbon,
I robbed a bank.
I thought you were
makin' 200 a week?
Booking's got a little thin.
- You made all that money just singin'?
- Why not?
Mind if I horse around with it?
Don't break any strings.
I can sing better than you.
Naturally.
I used to have an uncle
that had one of these things.
I fooled around with it some.
Here's one of his songs.
You're so young
And beautiful
And I love you so
Your lips so red
Your eyes that shine
Shame the stars that glow
So feel
These lonely arms of mine
And kiss me tenderly
Then you'll be
Forever young
And beautiful to me
Like my singin'?
You don't know one thing
about the guitar.
The boarders liked it.
They're what you might call
a captive audience.
Here, let me show you
a few chords.
That's a C-major chord.
That's a big one.
Now try the G.
You will never make a guitar player.
You got no rhythm in your bones.
Well, I never heard of anybody
payin' money to hear a guitar player.
Don't pay any attention to me.
I was only in the business
for ten years, that's all.
Yeah. I read you,
loud and clear.
Try it again.
Vince, take a water break.
Hey, screw,
I'm gonna get some water.
We're gonna have
a prisoners' show.
A committee from the state legislature
is comin' to investigate.
The warden wants to throw up
a smoke screen.
He's all heart, that warden.
- Who do you think's producin' the show?
- You.
Who told you?
I got a spot for you in the show.
I'll teach you a new tune.
I don't know. What's the percentage
in singin' for a bunch of cons?
Experience, you lunkhead.
That's the percentage.
- I'll consider it.
- Fine. You do that.
While you're about it, consider the fact
this show is goin' on national TV.
- You're kiddin'.
- No. It's called "Breadth of a Nation."
I guess they figure we got color.
I considered. I'm on.
What do you think's prettier?
Red or blue?
- Red or blue what?
- Color for a convertible.
Geez!
You guests of the state
are gonna be mighty sorry...
this next boy's a short-termer...
'cause he sure sings pretty.
Let's hear it for Vince Everett!
There's no joy in my heart
Only sorrow
And I'm sad as a man can be
I sit alone in the darkness
Of my lonely room
And this room
is a prison to me
I look out my window
And what do I see
I see a bird
Way up in a tree
- I wanna be free
- Oh, yes
- Free
Free
I wanna be free
Like the bird in the tree
Wanna be free
Hurry up, fellas.
I gotta count my fan mail.
Vince Everett.
Hey, you birds, come here.
How'd you like to make
five cartons apiece?
Five? Who do you
want us to murder?
It's the easiest money you'll ever make.
Just keep your mouth shut.
I mean, about the mail.
I made a mistake. I gave the kid
the best spot in the show.
If word gets out all this mail's for
Vince Everett, it makes me look bad.
Follow? I mean me,
the professional singer.
I, uh... I see.
If within a week the word's not around,
you get the cigarettes.
Yeah, but it's Everett's mail.
Who's gonna keep him quiet?
If I know the warden,
Everett will never get it.
We'd be a natural together.
Both ex-cons.
The publicity
would be sensational.
Look.
You get out in six months.
I follow you 12 months later.
- What do you say, boy?
- You mean we sing together?
Together, alone,
it makes no difference.
We hire a couple of other acts,
we got our own show.
We play the circuit
and we roll.
I don't know anything
about gettin' bookings...
Let me worry about
the business end.
Here.
I've made a contract for us.
We split everything down the middle.
Sit down here a minute.
Come on, boy, sit down here.
Sign right there.
How come you're willing to
give me 50% of your earnings?
I mean, like you said, you're the one
that's got the experience and the name.
One simple reason:
I got faith in your possibilities.
You're never gonna
command the dough I can...
but with training,
you'll do all right.
Besides, I need a young man
to appeal to the kids.
I'm levelin' with you, boy.
Alone, son...
you'd be like a lamb
in a pack of wolves.
Go ahead.
I wouldn't feed this garbage
to a razorback hog.
I thought that investigatin' committee
was gonna fix things up here.
Investigatin' committee.
What do those jerks see?
What the warden
wants 'em to see!
Slop.
Slop!
Come on!
Let's get back to the cell!
Come on. Back to your cell!
All right.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
I didn't have money enough
to buy the grease.
- The price was 300. I didn't have it.
- I wish you did.
It's a lesson to remember.
Without money, you may as well be dead.
That's all the sympathy I'll give you.
Pity's a commodity in here.
You buy it and sell it
just like anything else.
What are you, man?
Some kind of an animal?
That's right, buddy.
I'm an animal in a jungle,
and I got a motto:
"Do unto others as they would
do unto you, only do it first."
That's right.
Do it first.
And it's just as bad
on the outside.
Worse.
Remember that.
I don't aim to forget it.
Everett, you ready?
Drop in on us when you're
in this part of the country.
- Glad to put you up for the night.
- Just go away, screw!
I wanna say good-bye
to my friend.
See you in about ten months.
That's right, boy.
Together we'll knock 'em over.
The name of the joint
is the Florita.
I wrote a letter to Sam Brewster,
the owner, an old buddy of mine.
- I'm positive he'll give you a job.
- Okay. See you.
Take it easy.
Here's what the state
owes you: $54.
Do I owe income taxes?
Don't give me any sass, bub,
and get outta here.
I'll try not to break down.
Oh, wait a minute.
- Here's something belongs to you.
- What's this?
Letters you got
after that television show.
You're a real star, Everett.
- How come I didn't see these before?
- 'Cause I didn't want you to.
That's against the law,
keepin' mail from an inmate.
Have me arrested.
Now get out, and don't come back.
You've been just like
a father to me, Warden.
Sir!
I'll send a woman up
to make the bed directly.
What do you want?
It's custom to tip a man
when he brings you to your room.
Well, I'm startin'
a new custom: No tip.
No law against tryin'.
"Dear Vince, I saw you on television
today singing from the jail...
"and I thought you looked real cool.
"My name is Marijane Hamilton, and
I'm 15 with blue eyes and brown hair.
"My measurements are 33-25-36.
"Do you think I should reduce?
Ha-ha.
"If you come to Riverport, how about
giving me a blast on the phone?
"My number is Lockwood 4357."
Where's the nearest pawnshop?
Down the street to the right,
a couple of blocks.
What you gonna do?
Buy yourself a diamond ring?
No. I'm gonna buy a guitar
and sing love songs to you.
- Hi, Jerry.
- Hi, Peggy.
- Shorty.
- How's your boy doin'?
- Large. He's on top.
"Crying to the Stars"
got 84 plays.
Yeah? I'm sick of it.
Now watch your tongue, Shorty.
Tell me what you see.
About 5'4", weight 115,
pretty well stacked.
- I'm glad you find me pleasing.
- I don't find you nothin'.
- Then why are you staring?
- I'm interested in the jukebox.
Well, I'm sorry.
I don't know about mechanics.
I don't either.
I'm a singer.
Indeed.
I saw you writin' down
some figures in your little book...
and I wondered what you were doing,
so don't get fancy ideas about yourself.
Oh, I see.
- Well, I'm afraid I misunderstood.
- I'm afraid you did.
If you buy me a fresh drink,
I'll tell you about the figures.
Buy your own drink.
Is yours the approved manner
with ladies in the backwoods?
- Just tell me about the figures.
- All right.
I'm an exploitation man
in the record business.
I work for Mickey Alba.
You've heard of him?
Word sometimes gets
to the backwoods, yeah.
Well, I plug his records with
disc jockeys, jukeboxes, stores.
- Oh, hello, Sam.
- Hello, kid.
This is Sam Brewster,
the cheerful owner.
Vince Everett.
Did you get Hunk Houghton's letter?
- So you want a job, huh?
- When do I go to work?
- Whenever you want.
- Tonight's good as any.
It's up to you.
Bring me a seltzer, will you?
Can those guys play
with me when I sing?
What do you mean, "sing"?
Sing! You said
I could start tonight.
As bar boy.
- Make setups, bring ice.
- Hunk said you'd give me a job singing.
What do you think I am,
a mental case?
This place is
no hobby, you know.
All I want is a chance,
Mr. Brewster.
Look, kid,
I'll save you some grief.
So Hunk taught you
a couple of songs? Swell.
Be the life of the
next party you go to...
but we don't have
opportunity night here.
Do you want the job
or don't you?
Bar boy.
I'll see you around, honey.
Hunk Houghton.
That name sounds familiar.
He's an old country music singer.
I met him in the penitentiary.
Make setups and bring ice.
Ladies and gentlemen...
I'm not a part of this show, so don't
encourage me or pay me any mind at all.
But the man that owns this place thinks
I can't sing, so I gotta prove it.
So you just go ahead
with whatever you're doin'.
It won't take long.
Do a chorus of "Young and Beautiful."
You're so young
And beautiful
And I love you so
Your lips are red
Your eyes that shine
Shame the stars that glow
Don't let me
interrupt you, mister.
I won't.
So fill these lonely arms of mine
And kiss me tenderly
Then you'll be forever young
And beautiful to me
Hey! You forgot something!
- What?
- Me.
That was quite
a temper tantrum back there.
That creep had it comin'.
Look. Why don't you get me
off the streets, huh?
I'm bushed.
She'll do 80 on a straightaway.
Come on, huh?
Do you always bust guitars
on talking customers?
- I wasn't that bad.
- Oh?
Do you think so?
Well, I didn't think
you were very good, Vince.
After listening to
Mickey Alba all day...
All right.
You tell me.
Why didn't they listen to you?
I don't know.
I'm no worse than a lot of 'em.
And no better.
Okay, you're used to the top talent.
Why waste your time working me over?
I like the way
you swing a guitar.
I guess I did get a lot of
wrist action into it, didn't I?
Well, that's all she wrote.
My musical career started
and ended with one song.
I don't know why...
not until you've given
yourself every chance.
But if they won't listen to me,
I can't hold a gun on 'em.
Did you ever listen to yourself?
How can I listen to myself
when I'm singing?
Make a tape recording.
Maybe when you hear yourself,
you can discover what's wrong.
How much does it cost?
About $20 for the
recording studio, I think.
I haven't got a guitar.
I'll borrow one for you.
Can't hurt anything.
- I'm sorry I'm late, Vince.
- Just don't pay attention to my nerves.
- I brought you some background.
- Who's gonna pay 'em?
It's on the house.
Have you picked a tune?
Yeah. Sit down, fellas.
Let's see if you know this one.
Don't leave me now
Now that I need you
Okay, I'm ready
as I'll ever be.
Stand by, please.
Everett demonstration
number one, take one.
One, two, three.
Don't leave me now
Now that I need you
How blue and lonely I'd be
If you should say we're through
Don't break my heart
This heart that loves you
Man, it's awful.
Do I sound like that?
If you should leave me now
What good is dreamin'
I guess I owe that guy
at the Florita a couple of drinks.
It's a nice tune, though.
There's nothing wrong with the tune.
It's the way I'm doing it.
How do you mean?
I sound like
a million other singers.
- Then sing it differently.
- Like how?
Like how you feel it.
Put your own emotions into the song.
Make it fit you.
Well, the first thing
is that guitar.
It's tough tryin'
to find the chords.
- I just won't use it.
- Nobody cares.
- Okay, fellas, let's do it again.
- Good.
Burn me up this time. Let's see
if we can get a little fire in it.
- Try it again, sir.
- All right. Stand by.
Everett demonstration
number two, take one.
Don't leave me now
- Now that I need you
- Oooh
How blue and lonely I'd be
If you should say we're through
Don't say we're through
Don't break my heart
This heart that loves you
There'd just be nothin' for me
If you should leave me now
Don't leave me now
What good is dreamin'
If I must dream all alone
By myself
Without you, darlin'
- What do you think?
- I think it's wonderful.
- Good enough for a record?
- It sure is.
- Then let's go ahead.
- With a record?
Why not?
How do you go about it?
It isn't that easy, Vince.
You have to go to a record company
and sell 'em on the idea.
Let's do it. You know the business,
and I want to cash in on some loot.
Well, I don't know.
We might try Geneva Records.
What can they do?
Send me back to the pen?
- Thanks, Peg, for lettin' me hear it.
- I think he's got a distinctive style.
Everybody's got
a distinctive style these days.
I'd like to hear someone
sing a song straight for a change.
But you know they're going
for the new sounds, Jack.
I wish I could help you with it,
but you know our program this year.
No experiments.
We're sticking with
the established record sellers.
Well, I guess we'll have
to let MGM Records have it.
- I wish you luck.
- Thanks anyway, Jack.
Let's get outta here.
I'll tell you what.
Leave the tape with me. I'll play it
over the phone to D.L. in New York.
That's the best I can do.
That'd be wonderful, Jack.
Thank you.
I don't promise you anything.
- It's nice to meet you, sonny.
- Likewise.
Pretty sharp cuff links.
I'm gonna have me
some like that someday.
Mickey Alba made me a present of these
when we gave him his eighth gold record.
Maybe someday you'll make me
the same kind of present.
That'd be nice.
- Good-bye, Jack.
- Bye, Peg.
- Hello?
- Hello, Vince.
- I'm afraid I have bad news.
- You saw Lease, huh?
He said the man in New York
didn't like the tape.
What do we do now?
- Keep on trying other labels, I guess.
- Okay, you do that.
I'll meet you at that
same restaurant about 7:00.
Okay. Good-bye.
Hi.
You've kept me waiting
20 minutes.
- I've been sleepin'. You eat yet?
- Certainly not.
Don't you know the meaning
of the word "courtesy"?
We don't use it much
in the backwoods. Let's eat.
You might at least ask me
what happened this afternoon.
- What happened this afternoon?
- I sold your record, that's all.
Swell. I could tear
into a good steak.
Would it hurt you just to say
that you're happy about it?
It wouldn't be easy.
When the money starts rolling in,
then I'll say I'm happy.
Who'd you make the deal with?
- Deltona.
- Never heard of 'em.
It's fairly new.
They're crazy about it, Vince.
They say they're gonna push it hard.
Great.
Let's celebrate, huh, Vince?
We'll have a bottle of wine
and a nice meal...
and then after dinner we'll drive out
and see my father and mother.
- I didn't know you had parents.
- They didn't win me on a quiz show.
You like burgundy?
Goes great with steak.
I like anything that goes
with steak. I'm broke.
If it's all right with you,
I'll pay for the meal.
You will if we eat.
Hey, waitress.
It's a real crazy pad.
What does your old man do for a livin'?
He's a professor
at Bertrand College.
- Hello, darling.
- Hello, daddy.
- I'd like you to meet Vince Everett.
- Welcome, young man.
Mother, this is Mr. Everett,
the singer Peggy's been working with.
- How do you do?
- Can I fix you a drink?
- No, thank you.
- Scotch? Bourbon?
- You got any beer?
- Coming up.
We're very pleased to see you.
Peggy's told us about you.
She hasn't told me
anything about you.
I hear you sold
your first record today.
You seem to hear
everything about me, huh?
How long have you been
in the music business?
- About a week.
- I see.
There you are, sir.
And what did you do before that?
- Peggy didn't tell you?
- No.
- Mr. Everett was in the penitentiary.
- Is that so?
- What was the rap?
- One to ten. I did 14 months.
August, why don't you put on
that new record by Stubby Rightmire?
I'm sure Mr. Everett's
interested in jazz music.
- It's his profession.
- Righto.
Will you excuse me?
I have to fix the sandwiches.
That bomb kind of
laid an egg, didn't it?
- What bomb?
- About the penitentiary.
I'm afraid the shock value
isn't worth very much.
I think Stubby's gone overboard
with those altered chords, don't you?
I think Brubeck and Desmond have gone
as far with dissonance as I care to go.
Oh, nonsense. Have you heard
Lenny Tristano's latest recording?
He reached outer space.
Someday they'll make the cycle
and get back to pure old Dixieland.
I say atonality is just
a passing phase in jazz music.
What do you think,
Mr. Everett?
I don't know what the hell
you're talkin' about.
You finally got your sensation.
I hope you're satisfied.
Get off my back.
You insulted my father, mother and me,
and it's just unforgivable!
I have a little beer,
first thing you know...
some old broad's
askin' me a stupid question.
They were trying to bring you
into the conversation.
They can shove their conversation.
I'm not sure they were talkin' English.
- I'll drive you to your hotel.
- I'll walk.
I think I'm gonna just hate you.
You ain't gonna hate me.
I ain't gonna let you hate me.
How dare you think such
cheap tactics would work with me.
That ain't tactics, honey.
That's just the beast in me.
Before we go in,
there's something I'd better say.
About the other night...
I guess I did get
out of line a foot or two.
I got a pretty big mouth
sometimes...
so if you'll just tell
your old lady I said I'm...
Sorry?
Yeah. Come on.
May I help you?
Today's the release date for
"Don't Leave Me Now." Do you have it?
We sure do. The kids
are all crazy about it.
It's the greatest.
- I think I'll take a half a dozen.
- Yes, sir.
Did you hear that?
They're crazy about it.
- I'm gonna start off with a red one.
- A red what?
Convertible.
That'll be six dollars plus tax.
May I see those records, please?
What's the matter, Peg?
"'Don't Leave Me Now'
by Mickey Alba"?
Geneva Record Company.
- I'm afraid I don't get it.
- I do.
- Which booth can we use?
- Any of them.
Of all the low and filthy...
Peggy, tell me what's goin' on.
Don't leave me now
Now that I need you
How blue and lonely
That lousy thief.
He stole my style,
my arrangement, my everything.
Lease copied your tape
and gave it to him.
What about my record?
You can forget it.
It's gone.
- Miss...
- I'll see you later.
- Vince!
- I'll see you later, Peg.
Vince, where are you going?
Sonny, you don't own that song.
It's published. Anyone can record it.
You turned it down.
You said you didn't like it.
- We didn't want to record an unknown.
- What about my arrangement?
So see your lawyer.
You can't copyright an arrangement.
- You're a thievin' rat!
- Listen to me, sonny.
Don't "sonny" me, you louse!
Crawl back under your rock,
you snake!
Come in.
- What did you do to him?
- Nothin'.
Just slapped him
a couple of times.
Isn't that dangerous?
I mean, he might have you
arrested or something.
Why are you scared?
It's not you.
I just don't want anything
to happen to you, that's all.
I'm terribly sorry, Vince.
Old Hunk Houghton told me
once back in the pen.
He said, "Watch out for the teeth,
sonny. It's a jungle."
Yeah, he had it taped.
On the inside, they're Cub Scouts
compared to Jack Lease.
If you make something,
they might steal it from you...
but they'd be too honorable to go around
saying they made it themselves.
Yeah, it was
a pretty rotten thing.
Now that the crying's over...
I wanna make another record.
The same thing might
happen all over again.
You got no guts, Peggy.
So if they steal from you,
there's only one thing to do:
- Start your own record company.
- Your own company?
Certainly.
What's the mystery?
We can find out the details
from a lawyer or something.
You don't have to own a factory.
You contract for the pressings.
But you just don't go out and start
your own record company, just like that!
Why not?
It's done every day.
We're just as smart
as those other birds.
Look, I make the decisions now.
I can't louse things up
any worse than you did.
Distribution.
Well, I know a little bit about it.
Sure you do. And exploitation.
That's your racket.
Look, we'll be partners.
We'll split things up 60-40.
- Sixty-forty?
- I'm the artist, don't forget.
Are you with me?
Yeah. Yeah, I guess I am.
Well, I'll quit my job tomorrow.
My own record company.
I can smell the money already.
This really calls for a celebration,
doesn't it, Vince?
Do you know a lawyer?
Do you know how to dance?
We'll need a good one,
a guy with an eye to a buck.
Do you know a lawyer?
Yeah, I know a lawyer.
Mr. Shores.
But he's a cold-blooded old fish.
Good. How's he fixed financially?
They say he's got
the first dollar he ever earned.
Sounds like my man,
interested only in money.
Is that all you're
interested in, Vince?
Well, what else?
Nothing.
Hey, when can we see
this Mr. Shores?
Tonight, if you want to.
Good.
And incorporation papers
will cost you $100.
We'll raise it.
What else?
Registering your trademark, $25.
Are you interested
in show business?
Not in the slightest.
How would you like
to be my manager?
I should want to first ascertain
what your earning potential will be.
We're real kinfolk, Mr. Shores.
Peggy and I are gonna earn
some money, and when we do...
we'll make another record,
and then we'll be in business.
You know somethin'?
I'm gonna make you rich.
I'm already rich.
You'll be richer.
Good night.
- Thank you, Mr. Shores.
- You're welcome.
You got it?
- Okay, we're ready.
- Stand by, please.
- What's this new label of yours?
- Laurel Records.
Laurel number 101, take one.
When I walk through that door
Baby, be polite
You're gonna make me sore
If you don't greet me right
Don't you ever kiss me once
Kiss me twice
Treat me nice
I know that you've been told
It's not fair to tease
So if you come on cold
I'm really gonna freeze
If you don't want me to be
cold as ice
Treat me nice
Make me feel at home
If you really care
Scratch my back and run
your pretty fingers through my hair
You know I'd be your slave
If you asked me to
But if you don't behave
I'll walk right out on you
If you want my love
then take my advice
Treat me nice
Make me feel at home
If you really care
Scratch my back and run
your pretty fingers through my hair
You know I'd be your slave
If you asked me to
But if you don't behave
I'll walk right out on you
If you want my love
then take my advice
Treat me nice
If you really want my lovin'
- Hi, Ted.
- Hi, darlin'.
What's this I hear about you quitting
Alba and becoming a recording tycoon?
That's right.
Here's my first offering.
"'Treat Me Nice',
Vince Everett."
- How is it?
- Good enough to make me quit my job.
And you want me to
give it a couple of shots?
If you only would, Teddy.
It would mean so much to us.
Well, we'll try,
see how the cookie crumbles.
Thanks.
Peg, how long are
you gonna be in town?
About a day or two.
Well, suppose we get together
and split a herring?
- I'd like that.
- Good.
"Folks, does your dog turn up his nose
at the same old canned dog foods?
"Then why don't you try fresh meat?
"Cy's Pet Shop will deliver fresh,
red, juicy horse meat...
"wrapped in the size package
you demand, right to your door.
"It's a bit more, but the treat for your
dog will be worth dollars in health.
"Remember Cy's Pet Shop.
Telephone Mammoth-62480.
"That's Mammoth-62480."
Friends, I owe our listeners
an apology.
Callers have complained they couldn't
hear all of the Vince Everett record...
because of the commercial,
so we're going to play it again.
We're doing it for Betty,
Maryjo, Linda, Julie...
the gang down at Ray's Auto Upholstery
and... well, the list is too long.
Apparently, just about everybody
wants to hear this new platter.
So here he is, Vince Everett
singing "Treat Me Nice"...
on the new Laurel label.
Mr. Shores.
I now have confidence in your
earning potential, Mr. Everett.
You're in.
For 10% of the record company
and 5% of your earnings.
Nine percent of the company.
That leaves me 51%
and controlling interest.
Agreed.
- And 4% of my personal take.
- I have the papers already prepared.
With those figures?
I anticipated you, Mr. Everett.
How do you like that? He smelled
the money from 400 miles away.
I think I got it made.
Vince. Come on in.
I just checked the record shop.
We sold 425 copies.
- That's great.
- We got a hit.
You stick with me, and I'll
put diamonds in your teeth.
Oh, that's nice.
How do you like the cuff links?
A dollar a week.
Do you intend on using them
for a landing strip?
It's the mark of a man's success.
You look sexy tonight.
You start the hammers
to pounding in my skull.
You must have read my mind
when you wore this dress.
- What's on your little mind?
- A celebration.
Tonight's the night
for a real celebration.
- I like the idea.
- We'll send up rockets.
- But not with you.
- Soft music, loud champagne.
We'll charge it to
Laurel Records' ex...
- Not with me?
- No, not tonight.
- Who with?
- I have a date with Teddy Talbot.
- That record spinner? You're kiddin'.
- That record spinner made a hit for you.
But I've already got reservations
at the local nightspot and everything.
Vince, you should have made
reservations with me.
I still have a life
of my own, you know.
I thought this was one night
you wouldn't let me down.
Vince, I don't understand
why you're so upset.
You told me yourself. I asked you if
money was all you were interested in...
and your answer was,
and I quote, "What else?"
Ah, that was different then.
Was it?
Vince, I will not be subject
to your beck and call.
Excuse me.
- Hi, Ted.
- Hi.
- You do look scrumptious.
- Thank you.
- Be right with you.
- Okay.
- Hi, Vince.
- What do you say?
- Seein' much of our little metropolis?
- Oh, I've seen enough.
Did you thank the man
for all the help he's given us?
Oh, that's not necessary.
Thank the man, Vincent.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Good night, Vince.
After the success
of his initial record...
Mr. Everett was enabled to command
more advantageous contracts.
I was told the adolescents found
Mr. Everett's unique style of singing...
quite titillating.
Our expenses, however,
increased with gross income.
I found transportation costs
to be particularly high.
This, however,
was a deductible item.
Oh, his choice of color was white.
I doubted I could convince
the Internal Revenue Department...
that all of Mr. Everett's entertaining
was for business purposes only.
On the other hand,
my client felt extremely elated...
over his latest good fortune.
He'd been invited by
the National Broadcasting Company...
to participate in a nationwide
television extravaganza.
Hiya, pard.
How are you? Huh?
I guess you heard the news
about the TV show.
Yes, Mr. Shores told me.
Come on.
I wanna introduce you
to a new member of the troupe.
Laury Jackson,
this is Peggy Van Alden.
- Pleased to make your acquaintance.
- How do you do?
Laury is a real cool little singer.
I'm takin' her to New York with me.
In that case,
I don't think I'll go.
Were you planning to go?
What for?
No reason I can think of now.
Got nothin' to do with
the record business.
Of course not.
It's just like you said
that night in Joplin:
"You and me,
it's strictly business."
Let's keep it that way.
Let me know when you wanna
cut another record, pard.
Okay, I'll see you.
You gonna wish me luck?
Luck.
Where's my Vince boy?
Hi, son.
Remember me?
Hunk, you old son of a gun.
How are you?
You must be Peggy Van Alden,
the gal that started the record company.
- How do you do?
- I'm the bird got Vince started, right?
You'd better believe it. How'd you
know about the record company?
I gotta keep up with
the activities of my partner.
You've got more partners
than a square dance.
Yep. I taught the boy plenty.
You'll find out just
how well you taught him.
Good night.
That's a pretty little thing.
Well, boy, I'm rarin' to go.
How do you like it?
Thirty cartons of cigarettes.
You old stud.
How about a drink?
Sing it to me
in the key of G.
Folks, meet Hunk Houghton,
the toughest old con in cell block 21.
Howdy. Pleased to meet you.
- How 'bout that drink now?
- You can pour me a gourd full.
Uncle Matthew bonded bourbon.
Do you know how old this bourbon is?
- How old?
- Twelve years old.
Heavens above.
That's like an angel dancing
over the tip of your tongue.
It seems a shame to even
digest this bourbon.
You made it, huh? I've been readin'
about it, and I feel proud of you.
- Yeah, I've been lucky so far.
- Lucky?
Talent. I knew you had it
the minute you opened your mouth.
- Now you're goin' on TV.
- You know everythin', don't you?
I feel good.
What's your plans for me, boy?
Well, I ain't exactly
got any, Hunk.
- No plans for Hunk, your old partner?
- What do you wanna do?
I want a spot in that TV show.
You're talkin' crazy, Hunk.
You better think it over.
I've been thinkin' about it
for 18 years.
Yeah, I know, but...
times have changed
and styles have changed.
You might fall
flat on your face, boy.
I might get lucky like you too.
I tried your style, like you taught me.
Boy, I laid a bomb.
But you ain't me.
I need one good break.
You can get it for me on that show.
I owe you that much, but I
don't know how it's gonna work out.
Oh, you let me worry about that.
You're a good boy.
Ladies and gentlemen,
a little while back...
I had kind of a vacation with a bunch
of men in a big place out yonder.
While I was there, these men...
kind of guests, you might say...
we'd get together and horse around
a little bit and sing...
'cause we were havin'
such a good time...
and we always had a lot of fun
with this one, "The Jailhouse Rock."
And we always had a lot of fun
One, two
One, two, two
The warden threw a party
in the county jail
The prison band was there
and they began to wail
The band was jumpin'
and the joint began to swing
You should've heard
those knocked-out jailbirds sing
Let's rock
Everybody, let's rock
Everybody in the whole cell block
Was dancin' to the jailhouse rock
Spider Murphy played
the tenor saxophone
Little Joe was blowin'
on the slide trombone
The drummer boy from Illinois
went crash, boom, bang
The whole rhythm section
was a purple gang
Let's rock
Everybody, let's rock
Everybody in the whole cell block
Was dancin' to the jailhouse rock
Number 47 said to number 3
You're the cutest jailbird
I ever did see
I sure would be delighted
with your company
Come on and do
the jailhouse rock with me
- Let's rock
- Go, go, go
- Everybody, let's rock
- Lay it on me, daddy-o
Everybody in the whole cell block
Was dancin' to the jailhouse rock
Rock, rock
Rock to the jailhouse rock
Sad Sack was sitting
on a block of stone
Way over in the corner
weepin' all alone
The warden said, hey, buddy
don't you be no square
If you can't find a partner
use a wooden chair
- Let's rock
- Rock, rock
- Everybody, let's rock
Everybody in the whole cell block
Was dancin' to the jailhouse rock
Shifty Henry said to Bugs
For heaven's sake
No one's lookin'
Now's the chance to make a break
Bugsy turned to Shifty
and he said, Nix, nix
I wanna stick around
while I get my kicks
- Let's rock
- Rock
- Everybody, let's rock
Everybody in the whole cell block
Was dancin' to the jailhouse rock
- Dancin' to the jailhouse rock
- Rock, rock, rock
Dancin' to the jailhouse rock
Thank you, Mr. Everett.
Very good, Jack...
but a couple of your dancers
missed their marks, and we lost them.
We'll go right into
the hillbilly number.
What's his name? Houseman?
Hunk Houghton.
All right, Mr. Houghton.
Okay, cut to four.
Dolly in and hold.
I'm up in the mornin'
with the risin' sun
I work like a slave
'til the day is done
Just workin' and sleepin'
- Where'd he come from?
- Some pal of Everett's.
- Say, what is this?
- Don't blame me, Mr. Barton.
It wasn't my idea.
He came as part of the Everett deal.
I'm sorry. Deal or no deal,
he's off the show.
Okay, Mr. Barton.
Everett might bellyache.
Compared to the sponsor's pain,
his would be nothing.
- I wonder what he ever did for Everett.
- I've got no money...
Freddie, we're way over length.
We're gonna have to trim four minutes.
Tell you what.
We'll go right from
"The Jailhouse Rock" to the film clip.
Cut the hillbilly number.
I get calls and wires from all over
the world, but not little Peggy.
No, not little Peg. I'll bet she
doesn't even tune me in tonight.
Okay, baby,
you wait for me to call you?
Well, it'll be a cold day in...
Yeah, that's what it'll be.
- That ain't gonna help.
- It always has.
- I warned you, but you wouldn't listen.
- Don't rub it in.
And don't ask for pity.
You taught me that.
- Don't worry, I'll get along.
- How?
One flop ain't a man's whole life.
How'd you expect me to follow
that three-ring circus you put on?
You couldn't have
followed a juggler.
Naturally.
I haven't got your talent.
That's right, you haven't.
So what are you gonna do?
That's not your business.
Now look, Hunk...
I'm gonna be honest with you.
I'm not gonna put the brakes
on my career now.
I don't want you as part of my troupe.
You're not good enough.
It's been a long time, Hunk.
Music changes every six months.
You gotta change with it.
I was in show business
when you were in wet pants...
and I'll be in it when they
can't remember your name.
Fine, but not with me.
- Aren't you forgettin' somethin', sonny?
- I was wondering when you'd bring it up.
Right down the middle, 50-50.
It's a legal contract.
Uh-uh. I put Mr. Shores
on that contract.
It's not worth the ink
it took to write it.
You should've checked
with a lawyer, dad.
I figured it was a contract in
good faith, more than how legal it was.
Is that what you figured, Hunk?
Is that what you figured...
even after the fan mail you knew about
that I got in the can?
A contract is a contract.
Let's level, huh?
Okay, you did me a favor.
You started me out in music,
and then you tried to rob me.
But I ain't forgettin' about the
whippin' you tried to buy me out of.
So I'm gonna honor that contract,
providing I don't hear...
any more of that jazz
about good faith.
I'm gonna honor it, Hunk,
but not for no 50%.
- How much?
- Ten.
I wonder if Shorty checked those airline
reservations. Will you find out for me?
- Ten percent, huh?
- Ten.
You know...
a punk like you is liable to get lucky
enough to make a million dollars a year.
That's just what
I intend to do.
And 10% of a million
is 100,000.
There you go. You were
always good at arithmetic.
You're gonna have the most expensive
flunky in show business.
After the television show,
the floodgates opened wide.
We had engagements in the best-paying
recreation centers in America.
Receipts doubled and redoubled.
Our tax situation became acute.
The record business was neglected
during this phase, much to my regret.
However, my hands were tied.
There seemed to be emotional problems
between the two principal stockholders.
The 40% participant...
refused to telephone
the 60% partner.
It was an impasse,
and highly unbusinesslike.
Finally, there was only one phase
of the entertainment industry left...
so we went there.
We signed a nonexclusive contract
with Climax Studios.
We welcome you, Vince,
with all our hearts.
You may find Hollywood
to be a lonely town.
You're new here,
and good friends are hard to find...
just as in any other industry.
I want you to know that you may feel
free to regard my home as your own.
Come to me anytime...
- Yes?
- The photographer's here.
Please send him in.
We want to get your publicity
campaign started right away...
so we're having
a studio photographer come in.
Mr. Everett, meet Miss Sherry Wilson,
your leading lady.
How do you do?
We thought some
photographs together...
- Sure.
- If you'll just step in there.
Thank you very much.
Now smile pretty.
That's fine.
Now maybe an action shot...
like you just signed your contract
and you're shakin' hands.
Smile pretty now.
Thank you.
Now we have a little chore
for you two young people.
We want you to be seen together.
I'm not doin' a thing for
the next couple of days and nights.
And, Sherry? Remember
that old cooperation, dear.
Of course. A job's a job
You'll find I grow on you.
Who's gonna see us here?
I got my eye on you every minute.
I thought we'd have
lunch at Romanoff's.
You can only eat
so much, you know.
On your left, across the street...
you will see the mansion
of Jack Benny.
Oh, brother!
- Sensational, huh?
- It's a smash.
Don't bother
seeing me to the door.
I could make it.
I asked for nothing,
I expected nothing and I got nothing.
What'd you expect for nothin'?
Okay, everybody,
let's get this show on the road.
Mr. Drummond, do we have to do
the love scene the very first shot?
Oh, we can't change
the schedule now, Sherry.
I wanted to sort of
work myself up to it.
Making love to that rube
won't be easy.
Oh, you'll be fine, dear.
You're a trooper.
- Let's rehearse it!
- On the set, everybody!
The situation is a simple one.
Vince, you've just come home
with great news about your promotion...
but your wife is lying
on the couch with a bad headache.
You're bursting with happiness...
but when you see she isn't well,
you're concerned for her.
You kiss her tenderly,
and then tell her. Got it?
- Got it.
- Let's run through it.
Quiet on the set!
All right, Vince, come in.
Hey, honey, guess what?
I finally got that promotion.
What's the matter?
I guess it's one of those
miserable headaches again.
- Did you take any aspirin?
- It doesn't seem to do any good.
Let me rub your temples.
Good. Now kiss her.
Gently!
No, Vince!
Let's try it again!
- How's your headache?
- I'm coming all unglued.
- You know how to float?
- No.
Come on. I'll teach you.
Come on.
There you go.
Lay your head back.
Move your arms.
Kick your feet.
There you go.
Okay, you're on your own.
- I wanna throw a party.
- For what?
To celebrate.
You don't like crazy music
You don't like rockin' bands
You just wanna go
to a movie show
And sit there holdin' hands
You're so square
Baby, I don't care
You don't like hot rod racin'
Or drivin' late at night
You just wanna park
where it's nice and dark
You just wanna hold me tight
You're so square
Baby, I don't care
You don't know any dance steps
that are new
But no one else can love me
like you do
Do, do, do
I don't know why my heart flips
I only know it does
I wonder why I love you, babe
I guess it's just because
you're so square
Baby, I don't care
I don't know why my heart flips
I only know it does
I wonder why I love you, babe
I guess it's just because
you're so square
Baby, I don't care
Baby, I don't care, care, care
I don't care, care, care
Gee, Vince, when you sing,
it's really gonesville.
- All for you, honey.
- 'Bye.
I didn't see you applauding.
You didn't like me?
You've come a long way
since cell block 21.
Yeah, and it's been
a tough road to hoe.
I don't know. You hardly haven't
touched the ground at all.
What do you mean?
You walked most of the way
on other people.
You're just gettin' bitter,
old buddy.
- Doll, where've you been?
- Right in your little heart.
You didn't say a thing
about my outfit.
Flippy.
Real flippy.
I thought you'd
never come back, Peg.
Every time I see you,
you're working a neck.
I just been waitin'
and wonderin'...
if you missed me
like I missed you.
There was always the telephone.
It would've been nice if you'd called.
I been up to my ears in work, Peg.
No foolin'.
I understand.
The real reason I came
was about the record company.
Isn't it about time
you cut a few sides?
Records?
Is that why you came back?
Nobody gets so big that they
can ignore the records, Vince.
Not even you.
Sure, I'll make records.
You set up a date, huh?
Now if you'll excuse me,
I'll see that my guests are happy.
How do you like
our movie star, Peggy?
He has adapted very quickly.
There's not much oxygen up where he is,
and a man gets lightheaded.
Most actors,
when they become stars...
go through a brief period
of being modest.
Not our boy.
He became a heel overnight.
What are you doin'
here today, Peg?
I guess I like punishment.
You don't have to
take it, you know.
I'll learn.
Sure.
You're too smart a gal
to let him cut you up.
Sure I am.
- Where's Mr. Everett?
- He's over there.
Mr. Everett, may I speak to you?
I have startling news.
Did you hit uranium?
I've just received a most impressive
proposition from Geneva Records.
Ah, don't mention
that clip joint to me.
Even though it involves three-quarters
of a million dollars in capital gains?
- Mention it.
- They want to buy Laurel Records.
In addition to sale price, they want you
in an exclusive contract for recordings.
For which they'll pay?
Seven and one half percent
of all the records you sell.
No artist has ever received
an offer that big.
What about Peggy?
I haven't discussed it with her.
Good. Let me talk to her.
You're due at the studio in
a half hour to shoot that last scene.
Order up some booze so I can
pour a few drinks for the crew.
Yes, your majesty.
These dogs don't get enough exercise.
They're gettin' fat and lazy.
- Why don't you hunt 'em?
- I got a better idea.
Take 'em for a walk.
What's the matter?
My contract says nothing
about walkin' dogs.
Contract?
What contract?
Okay, I'll walk your dogs.
You know I ain't askin' you
to shine my shoes or nothin'.
A man just takes so much, sonny.
Keep that in mind.
It's been a wonderful party.
Let's do it again.
- Thank you very much.
- Good-bye.
Vince, see you.
Take it easy.
Where've you been?
Almost everybody's gone.
- I missed a streetcar.
- Let me fix you a blast, huh?
You missed a swell party.
What is it that you wanted
to talk about, Vince?
Oh, yeah.
See you fellas later.
- It's about the record company, Peg.
- Mush, you coyotes!
Who's buyin' the drinks?
What have you been doin'
to these dogs?
I almost walked
the feet off 'em.
I covered eight miles
and four saloons.
What are you tryin'
to prove, dad?
Well, you said to exercise 'em.
I was afraid the Indians
would cut us off at the pass.
I don't see nothin' funny!
Vince, what about Laurel Records?
What is it?
We got an offer for the label.
It's too good to turn down.
- What kind of an offer?
- To sell out to Geneva Records.
Wait a minute.
Wait'll you hear the deal.
Seven hundred and fifty thousand
dollars, a capital gain.
That's 225,000 in cold cash
for you, after taxes.
But, Vince,
I don't wanna sell out.
You got no choice, kid.
I own...
I know. Sixty percent.
That's the way the mop flops.
You'd think I was
tryin' to rob you.
You're getting practically
a quarter of a million dollars!
Dollars!
Is that the beginning
and the end of the world for you?
Is there no emotion left in you
but the lust for money?
Emotion?
What emotion?
It's strictly business
between you and me. You said that.
I don't care what I said.
We started this thing together.
We nursed it and
brought it up, you and I.
It may be just a ledger page
to you and Mr. Shores...
but to me
it's part of my life!
Go ahead and sell it!
I don't care what you do!
Nothin' but a record company.
It's not just the record company
that's botherin' her.
Trampin' on me
is one thing, sonny.
Hurtin' a little girl
like Peggy is another.
Just don't you go gettin'
no ideas, Hunk.
There comes a time when you gotta take
a hand in things, and that time is now.
- Don't push me, Hunk.
- I'm gonna beat hell outta you.
Don't try.
You're talkin' crazy, man.
- You know you got it comin', son.
- I said, don't try!
Man, what's the matter with you?
Now stop it, Hunk!
Just stop it!
Stop it!
Get up and fight,
you yellow punk!
I don't wanna fight you, Hunk.
I told you I don't wanna fight you!
There's your contract.
What's the matter?
Somebody get an ambulance!
Get an ambulance!
Hurry up!
Well, it was a close call.
The blow hit him in the larynx,
or Adam's apple...
causing it to swell
and cutting off his windpipe.
- We had to do a tracheotomy.
- What's that?
Cut a hole in his windpipe down here
so that he could breathe.
Now, the big thing is his voice.
A blow like that can change
the whole structure of the voice box.
- You mean, he might not be able to sing?
- That's right.
We'll have to wait a few days
until the swelling goes down.
We'll see.
You can visit him in about 24 hours,
but please don't let him talk.
How do you feel?
Can I get you anything?
Bottle of whiskey or somethin'?
I want you to know
I feel terrible, son.
I can't find the words
to tell you how bad I do feel.
It was an awful thing I did.
If I could only take it back, I'd
cut off both my arms up to the elbow.
I can't ask you to forgive me.
I want you to know
I'll never forget it.
Hi.
You look fine.
We talked to the surgeon...
and he thinks
the operation was a success.
Hunk told me what happened
in the fight...
and the fact that
you wouldn't hit him.
I think it was wonderful, Vince.
It was an act of true love.
Yes, it was.
Don't be afraid to love, Vince...
because I love you.
How's it look, Doc?
It looks just like last week,
Mr. Everett: Completely healed.
Doesn't feel too good.
Well, the injury is healed
and the surgery was successful.
Your larynx looks
as good as it ever did.
Whether or not your voice is the same
can only be determined by trying it.
Sure.
Try it. Sayin' it's easy,
but what if it's not there?
Look, Mr. Everett...
these morbid fancies of yours
are doing you no good.
Unless you get hold of yourself,
you'll be a mute, musically speaking.
Give it a try.
Gotta find out sometime.
I don't know, Peg.
Well, now is as
good a time as any.
I got nobody to play for me.
Come on in, fellas.
Yo, Vince, how you doin'?
- Let's go to work.
- Hi.
Pretty big audience.
Give a man stage fright.
Now, Vince.
Okay, but just with the piano.
- The rest of you guys...
- We'll wait in the other room.
- Doc, you better stay here, okay?
- All right.
You're so young
And beautiful
And I love you so
Your lips so red
Your eyes that shine
Shame the stars that glow
So fill these lonely
Arms of mine
And kiss me tenderly
Then you'll be
Forever young
And beautiful to me
You're so young
And beautiful
You're everything I love
Your angel smile
Your gentle touch
Are all I'm dreaming of
Oh, take this heart
I offer you
And never set me free
Then you'll be
Forever young
And beautiful to me