In our nation, one in
a lakh people owns a bungalow.
One in a thousand owns a car.
One in a hundred owns a computer.
But ever one of tow has
a gun or a sickle.
There are more opportunities
to die than live.
My friend told so
I can never forget
what he told his student..
...who had come
to learn Kung Fu at him.
Not always it requires to kill
the opponent to win the battle..
It'll be nice if he
completes this sentence.
His name is Sanjay Sahu.
Come on, let's enjoy it!
JALSA
[Enjoyment]
He consumes liquor
ever Saturday and Sunday.
He drinks it on Monday with scare that
he shouldn't drink for remaining 5 days.
He drinks on Tuesday that it has passed.
He drinks on Wednesday, in
the agony of that Saturday hasn't come..
He drinks on Thursday and Friday..
...out of shame that
he boozes daily.
- So, he drinks liquor whole week.
- Sir! The glass has broken.
Henceforth keep steel glass.
It won't break.
He has a bad habit along with drinking.
It's studying.
- He has done 3 Post Graduations
already. -Greetings sir!
Present he is doing 4th PG.
What you are thinking is right.
- They both are in love.
- Stop it.
- Are you sleeping?
- No.
How could you sleep
in this tension?
I didn't sleep.
Look! I am sending my all forces
on your father closing my eyes.
- Come out.
- Ok.
- The door is stuck.
- What? Get down.
- The door lock is locked.
- Do it, no problem.
Get down.
No problem.
Don't talk too much.
- Ok.
- He thinks you are an innocent.
- I won't open my mouth.
- He thinks that you're arrogant.
Ok.
Indhu! You had it earlier.
But now I am facing it.
- What?
- Approving the groom.
Gosh! Is it him?
Hey..
Come.
- Can I sit here? -You don't lack
in all these dignified talk.
But you don't ask me
to approve your love.
- It'll be disgusting if I ask you.
- What?
How can I ask you to permit to
love your daughter or elope with her?
- Don't tr to talk smart.
- It'll be disgusting sir.
What qualification do you have
to marr with my daughter?
Wealth or fame?
You have curly hair alone.
If you want,
I'll change my hair style.
Even if you change your life style,
I won't let my daughter marr you.
It's injustice sir.
Are you taking out the revolver?
Will you kill this innocent
because we fell in love?
You said you will elope my daughter.
How will you be an innocent?
Look at it!
Who is he, sir?
He is going to become my son-in-law.
What do I lack?
Your height.
Your colour.
And your education.
Money is important than everything.
Money is important to live.
But it's wrong that
money only is important.
- A house and a car are
also required. -You..
- How much stipend you get for a month?
- From Rs.3,500 to 4,000.
Is it a bus to go from here to there?
Tell correctly.
Rs. 3,500 or 4,000?
- 3,500 rupees.
- What?
3,500 rupees.
Do you know how much he gets?
One lakh and fifty thousand rupees.
- For an year?
- For a month!
Is he doing a job or
black mailing the owner?
He is a software engineer.
I am giving 1 crore rupee as dowry.
If you give me that 1 crore rupees..
...I'll lend it out get you
Rs.3 lakh interest for a month.
Are you taking out another photo?
He looks very handsome, sir!
- Really?
- Yes sir.
- No doubt, he is first class.
- Don't feel shy to tell.
There's no doubt.
Fix this alliance.
What did my dad say?
What did you say?
What should we do now?
You idiot!
Don't cr!
If anyone sees you, they think
that you are crying for the bride.
Greetings sir!
Why have you come here?
We heard outside that
food is good here.
That's why, my friends asked me..
...-To bring here.
- Who is he uncle?
Didn't I tell you that a guy loved Indhu?
He is that guy.
Have you told everything?
I have a doubt on you.
You may blackmail her..
...when you need money.
Is it me?
If I want I'll ask her and take it.
Why should I blackmail her?
Dear! Reddy sir told that
he brings his children..
- You know him already, isn't it?
Yes. -I too know her.
- Take us a photo. -Thulasi dear!
Bring the garland. -Coming aunty.
Thulasi madam! I'll take it.
Please be seated.
I'll come.
A little more.
After 52 weeks this love story got failed
a girl entered his life.
Girls never come alone.
Like sweat in summer..
Mud in Rainy season..
Mosquitoes in winter..
Girls and rowdies come
as undivided package.
What is this?
Hefty ladies are coming.
Why do they come to gym
if they are slim?
They'll tr into the movies.
Let us see who's comes out
in next 5 minutes.
If it's a slim girl she's mine.
Yours, if it's otherwise.
Let's go for a drive.
Let's do it in the car.
Tell me.
Stop.
it's not hot,
Road means it's not a road,
it's full of ups and downs,
They are teasing us, sir.
Ask them not to disturb our song.
Are they your friends?
Talk them and come fast.
I'll sit there and recollect my lyrics.
You may join with us after we finish.
Will we have the mood to rape them
after we kill him?
Run away.
Catch him.
Don't leave him.
I feel giddy.
All the liquor spilled out
because of you.
Hey Chotu!
For how many years
you have been learning from me?
- For how many years..
- For 5 years.
5 years, isn't it?
What did I say you?
Didn't I tell you the guy
whom you slap shouldn't get up?
- Did I tell you or not?
- You told.
Then why are you
fighting like a child's play?
Hey fatso, come!
You come and show me
how you hit him just now.
No problem, show me.
There is a good communication
among you. Hit me.
Not only the songs,
even the fights are also romantic.
Remember only one thing.
We get like this rod rarely like
getting tickets for Chiranjeevi cinema.
We shouldn't fight empty-handed
because they're empty handed.
Only one concentration.
We have a rod in our hand
and his head is there.
Our rod,
his head.
If we hit them their head
should break into pieces.
Do you know the use of the rain?
He and I only know that he pissed.
Do you know it?
Take me to the house.
In the windstorm,
He looks handsome, isn't it?
Girls look good in pharmacy.
Boys look good in physics.
Lecturers look good in maths.
You have come so far in half an hour..
...So it'll easy to you to count
till the wall in 3 hours.
Is there a wall?
It won't be a difference whether the wall
is there or not after you count to 1 lakh.
- What is your name?
- Saroja.
Did you give 'sir' to your husband?
- I am not married yet, sir.
- Will you marr me?
Are you angry or grateful?
You don't worry.
I won't give you hard works like them.
You seemed a slim girl.
It's very easy.
Come and kiss me on
my cheeks and go straight..
...there will be your classroom
at right side.
- Study well.
- Kiss?
Don't you want?
Ok, we'll do it so easily.
I'll come and kiss on your lips..
...If you go straight, there will be
your classroom at right side.
Study well.
Who is he? He looks like
slim Chiranjeevi. How can he help us?
Seems he is in a romantic mood.
Where is he?
Girls! Who is the guy from..
Look dear! You mind your
business of your department.
It's our problem.
We'll rag for fun,
and rape seriously.
Why do you bother?
- Oh gosh!
- Why should I bother?
If girls get ragged
they call me for help.
Who is he in between?
Call the guy who ragged them.
- It is him only.
- Is it him?
Call me again when he gets up,
I'll come and hit him again.
Look darling!
You don't worry.
Keep your romantic eyes up and
go straight jumping with your feet..
...and turn right side,
your classroom is there.
You'll get a degree
if you study in leisure time.
He'll get a headache
when he sees you.
Live the life happily.
Should swim against the tide
if you jump into a river.
Did Hiroshima stop its growing,
after the atom bomb explosion?
Cheer up, we'll live only a few days,
No worries, mingle joyfully,
Let's go for a variety look
moving the mirror aside
if we say in Telugu,
don't worry be happy,
Let's change into another version
mixing a new look,
Let's cheer up saying,
you and I, let's go high,
Life is like Saturday night,
Let's cheer up,
The colourful life is inviting you,
Throw your doubts away,
if you have the belief,
tears taste like ambrosia,
Pain looks like a wonder, isn't it?
In botanical language they are petals,
In material science
they are dreams in the brain,
In mechanical breathing they are thoughts,
In heart's language
they are sweet stories,
To get the victory,
fight is compulsory,
Don't bother about the risk, buddy!
If you want to climb Himalayas,
no need to worry about anything,
Engraving your name in
the history is your aim,
Let's move here and there
in the thoughts of Utopia,
Let's rise up and dance
to the tunes of Euphoria.
The world is a magic
in the eyes of Philosophy,
We won't find any of us
in the anatomy lab,
Take a deep breath!
Stop it.
Exhale it out when I tell you.
If you want to know Yoga,
you can come to me.
If you want to know it well,
you can go to him.
- If we want to meet Sanju..
- Go inside!
You idiot!
What is this?
He fell down like that.
Is he gone?
He should have told me
when he wanted to breathe.
Why did he feel shy for that?
Who is it?
It's an hangover.
It feels like a hammer hit
even if a small pin falls over.
- Night..
- Flowers.
Hangover will vanish if
the last night leftover beer is consumed.
Your house is nice.
It's not my home.
It's his uncle's.
Your taste is seen in the furniture.
The cost is visible but not the taste.
Because it's not mine,
it's his.
- Tell me the matter.
- Say thanks.
You wait here.
I'll send them out, lock the door
and come back.
We'll do it.
What do we do?
Not this and that, let's do it directly.
I didn't say you
I love you in that thought.
In which thought you said it?
Shall I tell you?
If you say me I love you,
I should say 'Me too'.
Will you keep quiet after telling it...?
We should marr in 3 or 4 years.
Will you keep quiet
after getting married...?
Movies, shopping, saris and blouses..
...otherwise crying or yelling.
If we slap you to control..
...domestic violence, torture in house,
women organizations and TV 9.
Gathering all of them you'll tie
us like a dog to the window.
To bear all these..
Don't you like me?
200 percent I don't like you.
Say only one reason.
Do you have any problem
if I say you 3 reasons?
One is your pony tail.
Second one is your high heels.
Third one is your brilliance.
I don't like it.
Is that all?
Not only that, there is another thing.
When you go out lock the door lightly,
I want to go to bed.
Why are you here?
Is she your friend?
Why've you let you hair loose
like a ghost?
Why are you holding your slippers?
Yuck!
You said that you don't like it.
It doesn't suit for her.
It'll suit for you.
Will you come once?
- Is it urgent or important?
- It's serious.
Serious! Come.
I tried a Yoga step.
I don't now how to remove it.
- How did you do it?
- It happened like that.
We should get all of
his parts into a position.
Instead of that, it's enough
if you turn his head only.
- Joining both of you will kill him.
- That is..
- Is your father rich?
- Yes.
He should be.
If you want to get a degree with
this brain, he should be a millionaire.
Koka Peta
Site settlement.
Greetings sir!
They both bought 10 acres in Koka Peta.
But the owner of the site
hasn't sold it yet.
They say that they've given
him 5 crores advance.
But some Lala from Pune
has come in the middle.
He bought that site giving
50 crores more than them.
They are digging a bore, sir!
They told more enough.
He is a wicked guy and
eats mutton biriyani.
They are good people
and eat curd rice only.
He will build a bar here.
But they will build a temple.
Saying like this...
To make me crazy like this
problems come to my settlement.
Do you feel like laughing at me?
This should come.
Getting 10,000 rupees salary for a month,
if you guard me recklessly..
...someone will come and shoot me.
Something has run
from here to there, isn't it?
- What is it?
- Fear!
You should have that.
Otherwise it'll come out like this.
If he is alive,
take him to the hospital.
I am not interested in it.
Go away.
We'll give you 25 crore rupees.
I need the money.
That's all.
But I am not fond of it.
Shall I settle the deal
if they offer 30 crore rupees?
Tell them I'll do it
if they offer 40 crore rupees.
You idiot! Drink milk.
What you are seeing is right.
This is a jail.
They will do all settlements from here.
If you think how it possible
read paper daily or watch news.
You won't get that doubt.
Why do you get tense Bagi?
He said no to Jo, didn't he?
I am also happy that he scolded her.
Then what?
She is glamorous than me.
He hated her.
Will he consider me?
I should have told it early
that he is mine.
I a always 10 seconds late.
What did you say?
In the end!
- How long?
- 10 seconds.
Exactly mine is also same timing sister!
My name is bunk Seenu.
Last year when I was
going out from my bunk..
...I threw the cigarette to my back 10 secs
earlier thinking that I crossed it.
- What happened?
- What will happen?
I lost my bunk
and I remained as Seenu.
She is 10 seconds late like money order.
I am 10 seconds fast like telegram.
If we both join together, we'll reach
in time like the courier.
- Who is he?
- Basically I am very fast..
...10 seconds early for everything..
That's why my life swings here and there.
- After seeing all your reports..
- Tumor? -No.
- Cancer? -No man.
Then what else doctor?
Has Dengue come
getting mixing Malaria and Filariasis?
Has Typhoid come
getting mixing TB and Thyroid?
Will heart attack come
growing BP and Sugar?
Has AIDS come because of
a hole in condoms?
You've a dangerous disease than all these.
Hastiness!
I'll collect my fees 25 thousand rupees
if I treat anyone? That's truth.
I'll collect my fees 50 thousand rupees,
if I treat getting so hard like this.
- Look!
- My name is Seenu.
Look Seenu! First you listen to others.
Then you talk, ok?
It is said that the guy who comes late,
has no discipline.
You idiot! It is said that the guy
who comes early, has no work.
Any doubts?
What is the meaning of idiot?
The person who listens
like this unnecessary things..
...leaving important things
has been called idiot!
Open your mouth.
What did he tell you finally?
He asked me to count to 10
before I start any work.
If count?
10 seconds gets over
if you count till 10.
Then you'll do any work in correct time.
He collected 50 thousand rupees
as fees for this.
- It is right that you went to the doctor.
- What correct?
I am speed so he asked me to count
10 numbers before I start the work.
She is late, so he'll ask her to count
10 numbers after she finishes the work.
She has to offer him 25 thousand
rupees as his fees. It's a waste.
- What shall we do then?
- It's very simple sister.
If you give me 10 thousand rupees,
I'll make a call to him.
He'll give me an idea
and I'll tell it to you.
You can save 15 thousand rupees
from the fees..
...and I'll cover 10 thousand
rupees in my loss.
Oh gosh! Here 1,000 rupees
also resemble like 10,000 rupees.
I'll take it later from you.
- Sir! It's me, Seenu!
- Tell me.
- Sir! A girl of my friend is
in love problem. -Look ahead.
Ok sir! I'll call you
after seeing the boy.
He isn't yet cured.
Where can I see him?
Don't know why girls are loving
and whom they are loving.
It's ok. What is the use
of thinking it now?
Sister! This time not like you,
go early 10 seconds like me.
You go I'll tell you.
Go and flatter him.
- He was enquiring about you.
- Why?
I was asking him why
he rejected your friend Jo.
Why?
Give me your hand.
Earth revolves around the Sun..
...The Moon revolves around the Earth..
...Poets and people like me
revolve around the Moon.
That is science.
If boys roam around the girls,
it's romance.
If girls roam around the boys,
it is nonsense.
Girls shouldn't be like hills.
Everyone will come there.
They should be like peaks.
Remember one thing.
Some guys meet on Friday..
go to pub on Saturday..
Do a party on Sunday..
and part on Monday.
That's why you should be tight.
- She tightened herself.
- Has she?
I have some thesis on this topic..
Whenever you get the leisure
time in the evening..
...come, I'll teach you.
If you want to see how
he pays the bill after losing it..
...keep watching your news channel TV9.
Hey Sanjay
Stop there!
It is the bail petition of A1 accused
Chegunta Damodhar Reddy..
...belonging to the murder
which happened in Kalwakurthi dam.
It is third time your
bail petition is getting rejected..
What is your comment on this?
Your opponents are telling you're
also the one among 4 people..
...who has a criminal
history in Rayalaseema.
Is the court going to prove it?
Zoom it.
If I would be the rude criminal,
would you dare to ask this question..
...or can you go home
safely after asking it?
- Haven't you got the bail?
- No.
That lawyer is a waste fellow.
Let's kill him.
It's enough to transfer him.
We should seek higher
officials help to transfer him.
It's enough to hold a knife to kill him.
- Think for a while.
- Ok.
Are you going to the jail...?
I have some work on the way.
I'll see it and come there.
- What is this sir?
- I'll take care of it.
You don't get tense.
I'll talk to the boss.
Sir!
He is our Reddy sir!
Stop it.
- We have come..
- I didn't stop to listen to you.
It is for you to listen to what I say.
He says that he won't listen to us
and we should listen to him.
That's why he stopped it.
I paid the right price to buy this land.
Don't tr to show your strength to me.
If you show you're a rowdy,
I'll show I am a don.
Then your plight will become miserable.
He says that it won't work out.
Is that all what he has told so far?
It'll be the meaning of his total words.
Ok, tell me what he has told in Hindi.
Don't tell me whatever Hindi you know.
We're just local rowdies
and he is a mafia don.
If we tr to show him our muscles,
he knows what to show us.
Then he showed the gun
from the window.
I've to talk to him.
He wants to talk to you.
- Tell him do the work.
- Do the work.
Why isn't sir talking?
He seems not to listen to sir.
He came and he left too.
Wait!
I didn't stop it to listen to you.
To make you listen to me.
We didn't stop it to listen to you.
To make you listen to him.
If you want to do business here, learn to
get scared along with buying and building.
No need for language for threaten.
He'll understand.
Wipe both that blood, his name
and write your name there.
- Hey man!
- Sami!
If you have a leisure time, ask him
to seek pardon from me in Telugu.
His voice is very good.
I am coming.
Where is the door?
It means we shouldn't lose our prestige
and he should become crazy to you.
Is it?
It looks like learning cycling
without getting hurt.
Why should we break our heads?
We have paid him, isn't it?
Let's ask him.
She is my daughter, sir.
Nowadays she is behaving differently.
To show you..
That sir! She is behaving
a little hot like this.
She isn't behaving
a little hot, Subba Rao?
- It's craziness.
- What should I do now?
- Guruji! It's me Seenu.
- What?
As you said I saw that boy.
He looks very handsome.
- Did I tell you?
- Don't crack jokes in this matters.
The girl likes him very much.
- Whose girl?
- I don't know her father's name.
Why do you call me?
What wrong have I done to you?
You can scold sir.
You are senior
so you can scold me..
I am junior, so I'll bear it.
- What should she do now?
- What should I do sir?
What to do now?
It'll be better if met regularly.
Should she meet him?
This hint is enough, sir.
I'll perform her marriage in 10 days.
When will you learn
how to talk on the phone?
Why do you consider
the answer to them as yours?
Damn marriage!
Is there any use performing her marriage?
Why not?
You can bring her here 2 days in a week.
Your son-in-law will bring
her in another 2 days.
You should meet
him regularly, that's all.
How can I meet him without any work?
Normal people wait for reasons.
But lovers like you
create reasons.
What did he tell you yesterday?
Meeting on Friday..
I have a thesis on this topic.
Whenever you get the leisure time
in the evening, come I'll teach you.
Isn't it enough to make
the things turn in our favour?
So you are going
to meet him today evening.
You don't worry.
I am with you. Do it well.
If you get any doubts,
call me..
Why didn't you tell me
that it's a dog van?
Before I could tell you..
Did they bite you very hard?
Seems dogs are using Colgate paste.
Their teeth are very strong.
What are you doing here?
You told me that if I meet you,
you'll tell me about girls nature
I told it generally.
Did you take it seriously?
Look Bagi! Nowadays girls
are roaming around boys.
But in the olden days it wasn't like that.
Even they don't even look at men.
Moreover, when Rama was fighting
over the bridge with demons..
...Sita just laid down under the tree.
But she didn't climb the tree and
looked at Rama how he was. No.
Devadas drank bottles
of liquor for Parvathi..
...did Parvathi drink a peg
of liquor for Devadas? -No.
So, what do you understand from this?
You flattering us and
we getting flattered, both are normal.
How is it?
A guy is coming from the way.
Let him come.
Don't look at him.
He will be going..
let him go but don't look at him.
More..
A little more..
When almost he is going away,
throw your glance at him.
Not directly,
in a side angle..
How is it?
How do I say an English girl like you?
- Like diagonally!
- Diagonally!
At that time he'll look at you,
you smile at him.
Smile with your eyes
but not with your teeth.
How can you smile with eyes?
Now.. not that..
Keep your smile from here..
...take it like that..
you close here..
There will come
a glow in your eyes..
He'll ruin with that glow..
Now the theory is completed.
We need a first class idiot
to do it practically. Found one.
Look! He is coming there.
He is coming with the stripes shirt.
He is looking at you.
Let's make him fall down.
Don't look!
Let him go.
Keep your eyes down.
Now look at him.
Throw a smile with your eyes.
How did he know that
I saw him from my behind?
If anyone wants us to look at them
our glance will pierce their back.
Girl! I am giving you all my power.
Use it as you like.
Thank you Swami!
Meanwhile I'll go shopping.
You enjoy it.
Shall I come with you?
I want to buy briefs for me.
Will you come?
- No.
- No. Then go.
Isn't it ladies hostel?
What is all this?
Boys are not allowed
inside the compound.
The warden won't keep quiet.
They don't bother if they run a family
outside the compound, isn't it?
It's good.
Come here.
The situation is very dangerous here.
As soon as possible
find a room outside and shift.
Tr to understand
why I am telling to you!
Have you called me?
My heart is beating in some
strange manner, know it,
My heart is moving aimlessly
Don't know how long to wait,
My lips are not uttering
the word which is in the heart,
it'll be found out
when searched in the eyes,
Tea spoon is visible
as a long one in front of eyes,
The fool Moon is making me agitate,
Cloud nine has come under the foot,
Land mine blasts in the heart,
Has any storm attacked you suddenly?
Has it sunk the heart into
the elation which hasn't before?
The burden of the breath
won't rise up unnecessarily.
Your appearance is in
the whole of my body.
Let the thoughts make you
to roam here and there.
Are you alone trying to extinguish
the feelings with the pillow?
When the cell gets your message
it'll be like the stun gun firing,
When ceiling fan blows,
it'll be like a touch of the cyclone,
Has he come in terms?
Tell me.
He is coming into my dreams.
Don't be satisfied that
he is coming into your dreams.
I'll make him lay on your lap.
- Sir!
What is the matter?
- My two brother-in-laws are crazy.
- What is the wonder in that?
- The elder one beats everyone.
- Like you.
The second one takes tablets
wherever he sees one.
Sir! It's me, Seenu.
Didn't we setup
a love affair last time?
- It's my fate.
- What should they do now?
What should they both do?
Wait a minute.
Ask them to stay in one place.
- It's extraordinary, sir.
- He won't come good.
You are not telling at all
how our guys can get cured.
The elder one beats the younger one..
The younger one takes tablets
for that beats..
I'll be happy.
He is asking both of you
should stay in one place.
There is a penthouse in his house.
- How can I go there suddenly?
- By the car.
What did he tell
you day before yesterday?
As soon as possible find a room
outside and shift.
That's why you are going.
What are you doing here?
Aren't you going to your place?
Is it you who is going
to shift into the first floor?
What about the hostel?
You told me not to stay there.
What is she? I told it generally,
but she took it seriously.
It's very good man.
I'll send it.
You go.
You go happily.
She would've taken it herself.
Why do you bother?
I didn't say that I'll carr these.
I said that I'll send it.
Don't stare. Carr it.
I don't know myself
how would I behave,
My respect grows every time
when I converse with you,
My feet makes me
roam around you,
The lust of tune is
growing inside the heart,
The dreams are calling
the heart softly,
The joy is making me
move forward anxiously,
The freedom is
welcoming to fly in the air,
My life moves as a
heart pierced by an arrow,
Sir! Look!
It is him.
- Be careful Sami!
Be careful sir!
- Be careful sir!
- Take the vehicle to the left.
Be careful, sir!
Sir! Our boss is going.
- Sir! -Leave me.
- Listen to me.
Now we have to go to jail.
- Before that he should go
to the graveyard. -Sir!
Search for the guy who roams on
AP-09 AP 7475 bike in this whole city.
I want to know all his
history in 24 hours.
Ask him to come back.
They have struggled for 2 days.
He is in the right position
it's enough to press trigger..
He feels that a 4m. red iron
rod piercing into his forehead.
He'll die before he gets the pain.
Like doing operation
with chloroform injection..
...are we doctors to kill him
without giving pain?
He should yell out
when he dies, should cr and..
...should beg at our feet to leave him.
Without that fun if you kill him,
what joy will be there?
- Sami asks you to come back.
- Why?
This is not like questioning me but him.
Want you ask him?
- I put red coin down.
- Hit the follow coin.
Who is it?
Why have you called now?
Have you remembered me?
Is it?
Truly? Tell it to kids.
There are no phone calls for 10 days.
You are saying that
you remembered me?
I think it's his lover.
He is talking so affectionately.
It is your girlfriend.
Is it my lover?
Give me the phone.
How many times I told you
not to call me at this time?
Put it down.
He isn't a ordinary person
who lifted the phone.
He is a smart guy.
Tr to understand
why I am saying it.
- What?
- My car got repaired.
- Then! -There is
a reception of my friend's.
Then!
- I want to go to the parlour.
- Go.
- Will you come with me?
- He'll come.
- Abi! Take her to the beauty parlour.
- Yes sir.
- Decorate her well..
Take her to the reception, make her eat
the food and take her to the house.
I've not enough time to do the labour work
Find some other guy.
What labour work?
Do you know what will happen
if you don't go with her?
What will happen?
You controlled him very well.
This is the right time.
If you give him that too,
he'll roam around you like a puppy.
You are like my sister,
I can't tell you more than this.
- Is it you? -Yes sir.
How is your health?
- I am fine sir.
- Who is it?
Didn't I tell you on the phone?
It is her.
She looks amorous.
She looks pretty.
Lights and plates are good.
But food isn't good.
- You.. -I brought her here
when her car got repaired.
- Is it that car?
- That only.
The car looks good, isn't it?
Did she prepare well going to the parlour
by telling the car got repaired?
When I told her that I am going to Sagar
she gave me her car at once.
I got a little doubt then.
That's why I cancelled my programme
and came here.
He rejected you
when you proposed to him.
He thought like that
but I didn't think like that.
Don't anyone of you bother here
to know what I am thinking?
What are you thinking?
Are you thinking that
she is a beauty? Look!
We can't see her
when she isn't in her make-up.
She can't see properly
without her spectacles.
Spectacles!
Do you need a spectacles for your face?
You didn't tell
that you wear spectacles.
You are a big liar.
Doing all the mischief..
Like she is a police and
I am the thief..
Are you trying to kill me?
Stop it.
No sorry.
It's enough what you did.
Stop it.
- She is crying, sir.
- I can't get it.
She hit him.
Then why is she crying?
Give an idea, sir.
Else he'll go on the bike
and she'll go in the car.
- Please tell me something.
- Draw air from it.
You united a couple.
He won't come good.
My car tire got flat.
Really, I didn't do anything.
I don't know how it happened
I lost my lenses and
couldn't find glasses.
It is raining.
I don't know anyone around here.
I feel very cold.
If you cr I'll pierce into your neck.
Stop it.
You did everything and crying now.
Why are you crying again?
You don't lack in these formalities.
Come here.
Come near.
I won't eat you.
Look Bagi! Beauty means
you should be your own.
But not to be like to others.
Understood?
Brother Sanjay! Send a little one here.
He is a good person.
When I ask he does it.
It's over.
You should have done it before.
Doctor advised you not
to drink too much alcohol.
But you are having it.
You'll die early.
I won't die so soon.
I'll take you along with me when I go.
- To where?
- Upstairs.
- Why? -Ice is over.
I want to go and get it.
Did I disturb you?
Is it Malleshwari?
- Have you stopped to cr?
- Yes.
- Can I get ice here?
- Sit down.
- Why are you calling me
with respect? -Sit.
- Do you know it is my favourite song?
- I know it.
Banumathi madam gives
good face expressions!
- What?
- First wear the spectacles.
Who asked you to remove it?
You don't look pretty without it either.
Sorry Bagi, I said it in a flow.
- Do you want more?
- Do you have?
Do you have the stock in the house?
Are you also drinking this brand?
- I don't drink.
- Then?
I thought you'll come..
Did you guess that
I would come here?
Say one thing.
Didn't you come here wantonly?
I made old tenants vacate
by offering 25 thousand rupees bribe.
You thief!
Bribe?
Meeting you at the shopping
complex that day..
...when I offered a full bottle
to Abi, he told it.
Did you give a full bottle to Abi?
All these crimes took
place in my kingdom.
Did he take bribe from you?
I can't get it.
What do both of us lack?
We are being like friends.
We often meet in university.
And I am staying in downstairs,
you are in upstairs.
What else do you want than this?
Is this a drink that you want more?
I want you totally.
Totally?
Am I a thing?
Are you a girl?
Indeed you are a girl.
Look at me once!
Lift your head up and see.
Have you learnt shyness?
I am not looking handsome.
Listen to me.
You'll get a husband with
trim body as brandy. Go with him.
Listen to me Bagi!
Wait once!
Why don't you listen to me?
I am not a match for you.
- You can't bear me.
- I can bear you.
What can you bear?
Damn it!
Haven't you seen how I behaved
staying half an hour in your room?
I behaved too much.
No problem. I can adjust it.
- I'll scold when I booze.
- I'll listen to it.
- I'll hit also.
- I can bear it.
Oh God! How can I make
this girl understand?
What did you say?
- I can't breathe properly.
- You said that you'll bear it.
Bear it.
Feel like flying in the air,
as a blasting heart,
And feel like hitting the
honey thread with a stone,
Feel like the body shaking,
smoking a fag,
And feel like boozing a full bottle,
Who are you to my eyes?
An angel or a demon or a lover?
Who are you to my mind?
A breath or a dream or swing?
Dreams are coming in the sleep
and call is coming through the lips,
the heart is rising up
inside beyond my control,
My youth is coming out and
my cheeks are becoming red,
and I myself rising up
at your thoughts,
Who are you to my desire?
Colours or wings or directions?
Who are you to my youth?
A bee or a naughty or hastiness?
Desire is coming into the thoughts
and affection is coming into the shyness,
and the youth is coming out into me,
Eyes gain prominence,
feet feel like running,
and joy goes out of limits
at your naughty smile,
Who are you to my sky?
An east or a dawn or a Sun?
Who are you to my night?
A Moon or Moonlight or a Star?
- Are you sleeping?
- No. -Come on.
I am opening it.
- What happened to the door?
- What happened?
- You open it from outside.
- It isn't opening.
Kick it.
No problem.
- Shall I kick it?
- Kick it.
Don't kick it in a hurry.
There is something wrong.
Seems I am watching a replay.
Bring coffee for me also.
What is the news sir?
It has been long time since I saw you.
Tell me the matter.
Last time you did as you wished.
I didn't say a word against it.
This time my word should win.
You have to perform my marriage with Bagi.
My situation is like I begot daughters
to supply you as girlfriends
I am asking it without knowingly.
Aren't you ashamed that you loved
her sister, but want to marr her?
Not ashamed sir.
There is no information.
If I had known
why would I do all these?
Without the information..
This wouldn't be happened
if she had come to her sister's marriage.
- Then she was in America.
- That is it.
You wanted to save 1 lakh rupees
by keeping her off that marriage.
Now see!
Listen to me and
allow me to marr Bagi.
I'll stay in your house before you
like a parrot and a myna..
You are not a Myna.
You belong to the vulture and owl race
God! Give me patience not to harm him.
How can God reduce your BP?
- Consult a good doctor.
- I'll beg at your feet.
You are an elder person.
Don't fall at my feet.
- If you want you can greet me.
- I'll..
What about the marriage matter?
Look sir! I don't want one crore rupee
like your elder son-in-law..
...arrange 60 or 70 lakh rupees for me..
I'll give you for 5 minutes.
If you still stay in this club
and in my daughter's life..
If stayed...?
I am telling you in
the witness of five directions..
Hey stop there!
What are those five directions?
I thought to challenge you
with that five directions..
I thought that
it'll be a routine dialogue..
Bye uncle.
- What did my dad tell you?
- Greetings!
I met Bagi's father today.
And I told him our love affair.
He also heard our total
love affair with patience
I hope, he'll take a
good decision on this..
We are waiting for his comment.
I am taking leave
and 'Victor to India'.
What did you say?
It means yes or no?
How can a child like me
answer for this big question?
Go and ask your dad!
See you.
- The sheep has got trapped.
- Play Bulli Reddy.
Come let's go to the canteen.
Brother!
Damn it!
Come let's get the vehicle.
Have you written your exams well?
Don't toil hard.
No problem however it is.
I am not going to eat it.
It's him.
- Do you only want best quality?
- Have it, it'll be good for your health.
- Put it there.
- Have it.
Is this a tea?
If the tea isn't good,
order for another one.
Why do you make fuss?
- Who are you idiot?
- How dare you call me like that?
You idiot!
Don't hit him.
I am telling you.
Hey Chotu! Bring a tea for him.
You sit boss.
You come.
If I shout loudly,
you'll urinate..
- What urinate...!
- I'll hack you
I'll take care of him.
Abi come.
- Go with him.
- How dare he...?
Don't act smart.
- Go away. -Get on the bike.
- He is giving pose coming to our campus.
Get on the bike.
I'll kill you today..
Leave him.
Stop the vehicle.
His head will break like a watermelon.
Come man.
Stop the vehicle.
Are you got tired?
Hey Dhoni! Hit it well!
He is hitting rudely.
I won't be with you.
Here is your advance.
I am leaving the place.
Don't come forward.
I'll kill him.
I'll stab him if you come forward.
- Don't come.
- Stab him.
Don't be foolish.
I'll stab him if you come forward.
- I am telling you only.
- I am telling you, stab him.
- Don't come forward.
- Stab him.
- Don't come.
I'll stab him truly.
- Whether you'll kill him or not,
I'll kill you. -Are you mad?
You'll get satisfied that you
killed a person before your die.
Come and lift him.
Careful.
Leave him.
He'll die.
- Listen to me, he'll die.
- Stop it.
If he dies their people
will remember us and kill us.
You won't care.
You don't have a permanent place.
You can live anyhow.
But we should live here.
What do you know about our problems?
- Problems?
- What do you know?
Problems? What did you say?
Are they problems?
You roam in imported bikes,
live in A/C rooms..
...wear designer dress and
spend a thousand rupee for a day.
You don't have the rights
to talk about the problems.
I'll tell you about the real problems
in life, you listen it today.
If I've to go to school daily,
I should walk up to 8 km. You know that?
I know it.
You know that they eat ragi food daily
and eat rice once for six months..
Only for the festival
we cook rice
I know it.
Do you know the children
are dying without getting..
...proper treatment at their young age?
The people when they feel
thirsty they look at the sky..
...and when they feel hungry
they look at the earth..
There are also such people
who are living in the society.
You know that?
A mother died within 6 hours
after the father died.
Have you ever experienced such a pain?
I've experienced it.
Have you ever felt some
strange force pressing you into the earth?
Have you ever felt the pain of stretching
your shoulders when you were young?
Have you ever experienced it?
To live in this society our name,
occupation and strength isn't enough.
Have you ever felt like
running way from the people?
Has ever the forest appeared
to you as a mother?
Have you ever felt only a gun
can make you feel secured?
Have you ever felt that we can't live
without killing another one?
I've experienced it.
I held the gun and went into the forest.
I have become a naxalite
I only have the right
to talk about the problem.
You don't have it.
Definitely you don't have it.
Move forward,
I'll tell him.
He is still in ICU.
The doctor is examining.
After knowing the matter..
I'll call you.
- How is he, sir?
- There is no major problem.
It'll take 7 or 10 days to get recovered.
You don't need to get tense.
Out of danger buddy!
Till then I know his height
and weight only.
At first time I saw his deep that day.
He was born in a peasant's family..
...at Booma Reddy village
in Kareem Nagar district.
His father name is Janardhan Sahu.
His mother, Sumitra Sahu.
His brother, Govind Sahu.
According to WHO accounts,
his family was living..
...4 km far for water..
...8 km far for government hospital..
...10 km far for the school..
...and very close to misfortune.
Brother!
What happened brother?
Nothing. There is a hole in the heart.
We have to take him to Hyderabad
and take some tests.
It's very expensive.
- Five is.. -No need of 5 lakh rupees.
One lakh rupee is enough.
There is no enough time.
That is the problem.
How many days are
there to make it?
Maximum, a month.
That's all.
What did he say?
He fell down because of weakness.
He said he'll be cured
if he takes this tonic.
The boy was very active.
That's why he died 10 days earlier
than the doctor said.
First time he saw the graveyard
when he was 8.
After that he didn't run for so long.
After some years,
Janardhan Sahu's crop had insects.
By pledging his farmland and house,
he bought chemicals and used it.
It didn't work out.
He got angry.
He himself drank that toxin.
It worked out.
Dad!
Careful!
You stay with your mom.
You both didn't eat anything
since yesterday.
I'll go and get the tiff in.
Why are you sitting here?
Where is aunt?
Aunt!
We have to go to the graveyard again.
Have you got your leg hurt?
What happened?
- Damn stone!
- Go!
- Stop it!
- Go away.
Sanjay, Stop it.
Do you know whose stone is this?
It is the border stone
of the sir's farmland.
1000 acres of land which is
visible belonging to him.
How dare you touched his border stone?
Will you pluck that stone out?
Will you hit me?
How many people are there
in your sir's family?
- How many people are there
in your sir's family? -2 people.
Why do just 2 of them
need 1000 acres?
As per the rule how much
they should have?
Tell me how much they should have.
- Tell me. -Do you know
he is a king to this place?
Your sir may be the king of this place
but I am not his slave.
Is it the border line?
Is it your sir's land?
Is it a border stone?
Come here.
Doing rowdyism!
You'll bur the stones on the farmland.
You'll sell the drinking water.
You'll spoil the air
by building factories.
Don't humans inhale fresh air?
You will stock the
Kerosene oil and gas cylinders..
...sell them in the black market?
Come here.
Sit down.
What would we do
if you divide the sky also?
Don't we have to live in the earth?
Don't we have the right
to live here or not?
The earth, water, fire, air and
the sky belong to everyone.
It's not your dad's property
and your sir dad's property.
Understood?
Tell him as my word.
Your sir only don't
have 1000 acres of land.
Tell him as my word
to give his extra land.
- Tell him as my word.
Do you know my name? -No!
Tell him that Sanjay Sahu told it.
They will die.
Stop it.
The anger which you got is not only
on the stone which hurt you..
...or on the sir who buried that stone..
...or on the people who came to fight you..
Yet it depends in so many things..
...and the situations which
you are bearing for 25 years.
The people like you
have the same anger..
...are staying in that forest.
Will you work with them?
Will you come?
Has anybody buried the stones there also?
Come let's pluck it out.
Move forward,
The anger of a man..
Only then he found out
a person's anger as a group..
...would tend to perseverance.
He started his life as a courier boy,
became a cadre..
...and within a short time
he became the leader.
For whom is this gift?
Next week a minister
would go through the way.
How do you say that
his car alone would get blasted?
There will be a dozen convoy cars.
Other cars will also get blasted.
He will die if his car gets blasted.
He'll get scared
if his behind car gets blasted.
Anything is better?
It is wrong to kill innocent people
for his sake.
We are fighting a battle.
It can't have norms.
Only a victor or a defeat
will be the result.
If innocent people die in our fight
for innocent people,
What is the meaning of our fight?
This order has come from our seniors..
It's only important to me.
- Not your opinion.
- It's not an opinion. It's a truth.
He wanted
to tell that but he didn't.
When he was in the confusion
whether his fight was right or wrong..
One day..
Hey police are attacking.
Don't go forward.
You'll die.
- How many people are there?
- 5 or 6 people.
- Do you feel cold?
- No, sinus.
Why don't you use medicines?
- What?
- Don't you use the medicines?
It won't go until I die.
Then do one thing. Go ahead a little.
It'll happen.
Put your gun down.
You..
- Is it a scorpion?
- No, it's an ant.
- Are scaring of an ant..
- Why are you laughing?
- Nothing. -You think that
it'll be good if I die, isn't it?
You tied my hands.
How could I?
Do you know all this happened
because of you only?
Encounters and combings..
I was very happy in Hyderabad.
I am roaming in this forest without
having proper food since 2 years.
Will you blast government offices,
buses and everything?
Are you thinking they are Diwali things?
Not too far with my department..
...you can't remove
at least my shirt button.
- Are all mistakes ours?
Don't you have? -It's all yours
I am telling it
because you are doing it.
- Nothing.
- What nothing?
- The mistake is not ours.
- Accept all the mistake is yours.
- I won't accept.
- Accept it.
- The mistake is not ours.
- Why should I accept it?
- Because I have the gun, accept it.
Ok, the mistake is ours.
Remove it. It'll get fired.
Didn't I accept that the mistake
is ours. Remove it.
I'll make all of them..
- What is this?
- It's a mire.
- Did you arrange it?
- I haven't much technology.
Save me
or else I'll kill you.
- A small correction.
- What?
Say that pull me out
or else I'll die.
Why do you use the grammar at this time?
Save me.
- Wait a minute.
- Come.
- Come!
- Give me that gun.
- I am coming.
- Hold it.
- Give me that gun.
- Pull me!
- Pull me.
- Be careful.
What dear?
What did you say just now?
Are we doing the troubles?
What you are doing?
Social service?
Why do the people like us fight
if you don't make the mistakes?
The mistake is yours.
If the mistake had ours,
I would have killed you then.
Don't argue madly.
Accept the mistake is yours.
- Why should I accept it?
- Because I have the gun.
Accept that the mistake is yours.
- Ok!
- What ok?
The mistake is ours.
It's not hearing,
tell correctly.
The mistake is ours, ok?
You put it in your neck.
Just now you made me to carr. Get up!
Get up!
Hey move forward,
You should know the journey of yours,
First, decide with whom to fight,
You can't live without killing
and kill for your livelihood,
when you learn it from the forest,
what's the use seeking a good path?
Killing is a nature and
challenging is a dream,
will the intelligence
know itself is a enemy?
Mother's lap is same for brave
and pitiable people,
The tears are same
for courageous and cowardice.
Then we was uncivilized
and now we are civilized,
but we didn't achieve
a growth than animals.
Becoming like Lord Ram
we can fight demons,
but we already forgot our own faces
by covering all the disguise.
By starting a journey
as a naxalite and police..
...became like two people after 8 hours.
NARASAPUR
Seems some vehicle is coming.
It would be a police jeep.
Give me the gun.
I won't tell them
that you are a naxalite here.
I'll go to the police station, call
the press and make to live in the society.
May be Naxalites are coming..
I'll keep the gun with me.
You go and hide in that bush.
After I go, you go to
the nearby police station here.
What if it would be a public bus..
Let's throw the gun into the bush..
Let's board the bus, get down in village
and will go in their respective ways.
What is it?
Why many cars are coming?
It's home minister's car.
- What? -Don't go there.
There is a land mine.
How do you know
that there is a land mine?
I was one of the members
in the team that buried it.
- How much is its capacity?
- Half the cars would be blasted.
How? They are coming.
- Stop it. -How should
I stop it? -Shout loudly.
They can't hear
if I shout loudly.
Remove your shirt and wave.
Stop it.
Give me your shirt.
- Give me.
- I won't give you. -Why?
Why? If they ask
whose shirt saved the car..
...If you tell it's mine,
who will get that credit, you or I?
You should get that credit.
- Oh gosh!
- Be careful.
There is a land mine.
Stop it.
Where is the minister?
Be careful, the land mine is there.
You saved my life.
It's I who waved the shirt.
You waved it for a lift.
Look at that guy!
He waved red cloth.
It's the stopping signal.
Why do you expose?
Wear the shirt.
- Who is he? -He asked you
for a Hyderabad transfer
I am coming.
I am on the way.
Keeping red cloth with you,
why did you make me remove my shirt?
Forget the department..
...you can't remove even
my shirt buttons.
- I said it generally.
- But I took it seriously.
Hey..
I'll kill you.
I tested it whether it'll
get blasted or not..
- Is it you who asked for a
Hyderabad transfer? -Yes sir!
I'll be in this posting for 3 years.
You can see not only the road but
at least a deserted area in this 3 years
I am dedicating you to this forest.
3 years in Chitha Palli forest..
What is it?
I said it in barbaric language
that I was roaming.
He got society life
and I got exile.
POLICE STATION
KOTHULA VALASA.
He was dancing in Hyderabad disco.
I was dancing in Kothula Valasa.
He was eating burgers and pizzas..
I was eating roots and vegetables.
I said it in barbaric language
that he showed me the hell.
Don't ask that.
I am used to it.
If I had been there for some days,
I would've forgotten Telugu.
He may not be a great person..
But he is a good person.
What good?
He came to marr your sister
one and half year ago.
Now he says that he is loving with you.
Are you supporting him?
What about me?
Use sister's books.
A new bike for you to go to the college.
- What about me?
- Use sister's cycle.
- You got a good husband.
- Then what about me?
Here is your sister's boyfriend.
I'll listen to you dad.
I know it Bagi.
I'll also come with you.
Why should you?
Why should you run way
for no mistake of yours?
Your exams will be
completed in 2 months. Then come.
No dad, if I stay here,
he will..
He can't harm you.
I selected a sharp guy for your security.
- You have remembered
what I told, isn't it? -Yes sir.
If he acts over smart..
Is there any problem
to you if I kill him?
Not that Sami!
They are city guys.
They tried for some plans..
He didn't know that.
He hit them black and blue.
If it would be our guys..
...they will make a plan
after killing him.
How to vanish the corpse?
Shall I call them?
If wants to switch off the light,
no need to blast the transformer.
It's enough to make switch off
I am thinking where his switch is.
You made your father to accept.
You are not an ordinary person.
If you get 10 days time,
you'll convince Pakistan..
...and make them tell
that they don't want Kashmir.
What happened Bagi?
I hate liars.
Have you gone mad? When did I
lie to you? I can't get it. Tell me.
See how he is asking..
Like Kamalhasan in Swathimuthiam movie..
Why didn't you tell me
that you were a Naxalite?
Was I a Naxalite?
It's a small matter.
If you laugh,
I'll slap you.
Why didn't you tell me
that you were a Naxalite?
Did you tell me
that your father was a SP?
- You didn't tell me.
- I hate you.
I don't care even if you were
a Naxalite or Veerappan..
Should I settle with
secondhand things all my life?
Like books, cycle
and at last love also.
Am I a secondhand taker?
You didn't tell me that
you had an affair with my sister..
...when you were coming out from my dad.
Leave me. You didn't tell me
that you had a sister.
You didn't.
GO AWAY.
What did you tell?
Did you tell anything about your family?
You didn't tell me about
your mother, father and everyone
I hid 2 things from you.
It's a simple matter..
...that I was a Naxalite
and I loved your sister.
Did I love her after knowing
she was your sister?
I didn't. But it happened.
Did we plan it before?
Did I know that I'll
fall in love with both of you?
I didn't know anything.
It happened like that.
Why do you make fuss for this?
What do I know
except your brandy and whisky?
I would have told you
if you had asked it.
I don't have to ask and find out.
I too don't have the habit
to tell it without getting asked.
Shall I give you autobiography
ever since I was born? Is it enough?
No need! It's not manners to know
about strangers details.
Am I a stranger?
Oh god!
Let's put our relationship into
the cupboard and live our own freshly.
- Bagi! You are.. -Not like this emotional,
let's behave like matured guys
I have a sister..
...and have a puppy since 1 year.
What about you?
- What you do?
- I'll keep off mad guys.
Damn fresh!
Who are you?
Are you a watchman?
Who I am.
- Moreover who are you?
- Who am I?
Telling her and you who I am..
I'll tell.
My name is Sanjay Sahu.
I am doing MA Economics
in Osmania university..
...I'll make aerobics with guys..
...and go with girls to watch
movies in Multiplexes.
Turn your head.
Never ask me who I am.
You are for yours and we are for ours,
Let's hold it.
- Those also.
- These too!
- Do you have a bowl?
- No.
- Then stretch your hands?
- Why?
Do you want the answer or milk?
- I want milk only.
- Stretch your hands.
- Stretch your hands, sir.
- Hands.
Half milk for you and
half milk for me..
When there was 2 pockets..
...you might took one pocket and
you would give me another pocket.
Oh god! I didn't get the idea.
How can you think these ideas?
Have you heard what he told?
Amn't I an unlucky guy
that's why I can think.
- What is it?
- Sleeping tablets.
- Why? -When we mix it in
Bagi's drinking milk tonight..
...she'll drink and go to a deep sleep.
She won't bother
if we celebrate a festival..
...and she won't resist even if I rape her.
You sinners! What an atrocity?
- Pranav sir!
- The glass may break.
- That is..
- Is there no glass?
I thought it would be there.
- Pranav sir!
- You dare to steal ladies chastity..
It's not so difficult
for you to remove the glass.
- No sir.
- You idiots!
It's just for fun, sir.
Just listen to me sir.
Don't tell this to Bagi.
How dare you point your finger at me?
I'll cut your hand.
What do you think of me?
- Shut up.
- Don't spoil my life.
- What do you think of me?
- Don't dare to me.
- What happened?
- What happened to your cheek?
- I scratched the wall.
How could you scratch on your left side
when the wall is on right side?
I scratched the wall when
I was getting down.
Why did your eye turn into red?
Why do you ask
all the questions now?
...like a class teacher.
- Where are you going again?
- I'll get mad if I stay here
I'll go outside, roam and come back.
No, why do I go?
I don't go.
You said that you'll go outside.
If I said that I'll go,
should I?
I don't go.
I'll stay in the house.
What is it Pranav?
How it is if you talk
disappointing words?
Do you know what will happen
if you disappoint me?
After seeing it you should
take a decision yourself.
God is there for everything.
Did you give her?
Did she drink?
Why are you lying?
Seeing milk on your moustache I can say
that you have drunken the milk.
A little got remained in the last..
My idea is you should drink the milk..
What joy will be there raping a girl
while she is in sleep?
...should do it with running girl..
Now you should go to bed and she'll run.
She'll shout and cr..
Save my chastity.
Then I..
It is the days of Sanjay Sahu
to tr to forget Bagumathi.
Similarly it is the days of Damodhar Reddy
not to tr to forget Sanjay Sahu.
It is the bus stop you're
looking for last 15 minutes.
Go and enjoy.
Can I reach Jubilee Hills
if get into 16B bus?
Look brother! It's in
our hands to get into 16B..
...will it reach Jubilee hills or reach
Apollo hospitals by an accident..
...Is in driver's hands.
Don't worry too much.
Take it lightly.
Who is it?
What is that bag?
Adhi, come here! Are you seeing
a guy walking with pyjama?
- Go and give the bag to him.
- Seems he forgot it. -Ok sir.
It's you.
It'll take a week to bur the pit.
Will need 10 days to build the bunk..
Will need a month
to this child to get cured.
Don't know how many years
will he take to laugh like past?
Stop. She is studying inside.
Is she studying?
She may study it later.
You go.
Go.
Why do you bother?
Have you got scared?
Nothing Bagi.
I want to tell you something.
- What?
- About Jo!
I am feeling shy.
She looks very sexy, isn't it?
- Will you give me her number?
- For what?
The people who are matured
don't ask like this questions.
You helped me a good one.
In your Economics, a guy always
wear a check shirt, looks tall and fair.
- He is Sekhar and I know him.
- He looks handsome.
- Do you have his number?
- I have.
- Will you give me once?
- I won't. -Why?
I am not matured like you.
What a speed!
When he called her,
she has come at once.
I want full details of
what they are talking and doing.
That day I talked in inebriation..
He may notice me if I stay here.
I am busy.
I'll call you.
I'll talk you.
- Sami have this fruit!
- Wait.
Dear!
Don't be in a hurry!
Wash it and eat.
Sami! I want money.
Ask like peace and delight
But don't ask money.
I don't want that.
I want 5 thousand rupees urgently.
- It's a waste expense.
- You..
Sami! Don't use abuse words.
There is a cupboard in the corner.
A shirt with 5,000 rupees are inside it.
Take it and go.
Is it that shirt?
Where is the money?
He pulled it.
I want a shirt.
- Full hands or half hands?
- Half hands.
It is in the cup board.
Take it and go.
I've to change the shirt.
It's fine that he didn't ask for a brief.
He pulled the door.
I gave you a ring.
Where is it?
It is in the cupboard.
Take it and go.
Has he eyed this ring too?
There is no use.
You wait.
What is there in the cupboard?
You are sending them
to the cupboard for everything.
There is a dirty shirt
and a hole for that.
They took my shirt and money.
Is this a celestial bowl
to get rings and diamonds?
- Damn it. -Who is he?
He is using abuse words.
Jo, you don't bother about it.
He is an insane.
- Is it me?
- You are only..
- Insane?
- Yes.
You are crazy for women.
- He spoiled my mood.
- You go madam.
- I'll kill you.
- That devil would have sent him here.
She is an angel but not a devil.
- She sent me to save you.
- Don't trust him.
- Come to the party in the evening.
- Jo, I'll be there in time.
You go.
Put the gear..
- He is a demon who wore a t-shirt.
- Go madam.
What Pranav?
Is anything looking differently?
- Nothing is like that. -Don't you think
that there is a small difference?
- I don't feel so.
- Don't you feel cold?
Some type of cold is..
Oh gosh!
Gosh! My dhoti got stripped.
- What did you tell just now?
- I told something.
Do you tell her about my real identity?
I'll show your nudity
to all the colony people.
Can you tell what
this naughty Sanjay will do?
- You'll switch off the fountain.
- Abi, you got 10 percent mark.
Now I can go to the party peacefully.
This beauty looks like
a Jenifer Lopez sketch!
This Cadbury looks like
a replica of Britney Spears,
Her hip is like Shakeera,
with a lucky touch,
Her walking is like Bayonet,
her laugh can make holes,
Don't kill me with your wink
wearing jeans pant like James bond.
Don't play with nonchalk
as wearing a belt like Jackie Chan,
Are you the laser of deer eyes?
Are you the Paradise flavor?
Are you the oxidized lady bomb?
Are you the bend of Saxophone?
Are you the best friend of the volcano?
Are you 1000 volts electricity?
Are you the youth
falling on a tornado?
Are you the earthquake?
Are your both eyes radium bubbles?
Are your lips platinum flowers?
Is there romance if you say hello?
Is your silence a violence?
Monalisa will get angry hearing that
you are the part 2 of Titanic heroine,
Won't all the Sumo's greet you
that you have the looks of playboy?
Are you the DTS ring tone?
Are you the heart shape Moon?
Are you the beauty of CD-Rom software?
Are you chloroform anesthesia?
Are you the clone of Romeo?
Are the twin of Rainbow?
Are you the dean of dream university?
Are you my zodiac sign?
Are you 24 carat vanilla
or Hot Mexican tequila?
With fully loaded riffle
you raid me as Rambo,
Hey French model! You increased the pulse
rate as making Madonna as a ball,
Don't give me flying kiss
like how Maradona put a goal,
I've found a good alliance for you.
I saw a guy yesterday.
He is very handsome.
I don't want dad.
I can't hear just now.
I'll switch on speaker.
- Come again. -I saw that guy yesterday.
He is very handsome.
He is in Hyderabad.
He has a good job in TCS.
Let's see it later.
First tell me this. Is he fair?
He looks very white like an egg.
He will look red like a Tomato
when he feels shy.
If you see him you'll say
that he looks like Aravind Sami.
Shall I arrange your meeting
at his house?
It'll look cheap,
if we go like that.
Girls shouldn't be like hills..
They should be like mountains.
Only then there is dignity.
Ask him to come for lunch at Taj.
Originality should be in romance..
Copying other's ideas like..
It's a big sin as distributing British
company chocolates on August 15th.
- You Raasi! -What does it mean?
- A demon.
Short form is enough for you.
My name is Raghu Ram.
I am working as project leader in TCS.
Take home up to 70 thousand rupees.
Recently I bought a car.
I have almost all bank credit cards.
My parents also..
My work will get finished
in one hour in the morning.
After that I'll sit in internet.
I'll come early in the evenings.
Do you have food allergy?
I don't like snake-guard.
Now what you are
eating is snake-guard.
- Why money? -It's difficult
to happen his marriage.
I'll hit and kill you with the paper.
Hey Pranav! Come here.
- Calling me in singular?
- Who is it? Is it that idiot?
You can't bear it when
I call you in plural. You'll die.
Where are you going
wearing the coat?
- To get eggs.
- Eggs! To whom?
- For madam.
- For madam?
- What will you do with it?
- I'll make omelets.
It's enough that.
Come here.
- What? -There is
some work with you.
- Sit.
- No thanks.
Unnecessary trouble!
- Take this thousand rupee note..
- Is it a thousand rupee note?
Buy full bottle.
Not that sir, he gave me 10 rupees
and saying it is a thousand rupee note..
Go away.
- Hey Pranav!
- Sir!
- Chicken is over. So, 2 plates of chicken.
- I want prawns.
2 plates prawns for him.
And a fish for him.
- Get it all these.
- In this thousand rupees..
Yes, don't cr.
Keep the change with you.
- Are you telling me to keep the change
if it remains? -Yes man!
Can't you get it?
Go.
Who is he?
This house isn't looking like
where respected people stay.
Strangers are coming here as their wish.
Hey snake-guard! Stop there.
Respected people are living in this house.
She won't get up if we
don't ring the bell like that.
What Raghu? You have come here.
That is..
We want to talk.
Talk.
Tell me what the news is.
We want to talk personally.
What personal talk at midnight?
Are you thinking that
this is a whore house?
- What?
- I didn't mean it sir.
- What? -I got
discharged in the evening.
She would be worrying thinking of me.
Is it she?
She loved me for an year but now she isn't
caring of me when I consume raw alcohol.
You got introduced just 2 days back
Will she care of you?
We want some privacy.
I too want Aiswariya Rai
but it won't happen.
If you make trouble here
I'll call Pranav.
Pranav?
Is he Arnold Schwarzenegger?
You expect him to save you.
I'll do her whatever I wish.
Let me see what will
that Pranav do.
Don't get emotional for me.
Have you got it?
Go down and
make the pegs ready. Go.
I don't know sir.
- You crazy Pranav! Will everything
come along the birth? -Then how?
You'll mix 2 or 3 pegs wrongly.
- I'll hit you hard.
- Is it me?
Then you'll know it automatically.
Go and make it ready.
Go away.
Seems he'll kill me.
- Damn steps also there!
- Where is the balance money?
Balance money?
When I give you thousand rupees, won't you
tell me the accounts? -Thousand rupees?
You asked me to keep the change.
I said like that?
It's my kind heart.
But you should give it.
It's your manners.
When he is scolding you
why do you listen it?
They are hitting me, madam.
- Is he hitting you?
- They are hitting me without a reason.
- Are your complaints over?
- Isn't it truth, sir?
Go down, I'll see to you.
- Go down. -I'll go.
I've to get down on steps again.
- Baggi?
- You..
What is it? You are calling her
as your own wife.
I have stopped to call
you like that, isn't it Baggi?
I'll take it.
You can go.
He is going.
Let him go.
He is doing nuisance.
Why should he bother
when I talk to Raghu?
At last he is hitting Pranav also.
Why are you staring?
Speak something.
How can he tell it than this
that he is loving you?
Some people write letters.
Some people give flowers.
You do lie.
He shouts and beats.
It's his expression.
When our dad rejected
our marriage proposal..
...He didn't convince him.
Do you know what he told
when I ask him the reason?
I'm not a sales man to convince you..
...that your life will be nice
if you marr me.
You can get freedom at Sanju.
To tell it in a simple manner..
Raghu is like a park.
After going for a week,..
...there won't be new things to know.
Sanju is like a forest..
He daily gives a surprise,
till the death.
He is loving you more than I.
Have it.
What wrong I did?
I got so many problems.
When I was enjoying my life
besides studying degree..
She came into my life, exposes..
...wearing saris and flattered me.
Will you leave me in
the middle of the road?
Lord Anjaneya! Tomorrow
I'll come to your temple..
...I'll definitely come,
make me to forget her.
Oh god!
Why did you hit me now sir?
If you tell to anyone that I am crying..
Are you waiting that..
...I didn't complete the dialogue?
- Yes! -I didn't.
- Oh gosh!
- It's my wish.
- Oh god!
Tell it wherever you want.
If we tell him respectively
he won't listen to us.
- Let's slap him and tell it.
- Till now you are slapping me, isn't it?
You lay down.
Seems Sanjay Sahu and
Bagumathi are joined.
He couldn't get a plate meals
easily in his life.
Then how can he get his fiancée.
He couldn't get anything easily.
...he should get hurt for that.
The problem which has come
now is Damodhar Reddy.
How do you know that I am here?
Tell me what the matter is.
Look there!
What a timing of yours!
Brothers! You wait here.
I'll come back sending sister-in-law.
Come.
I'll call you and tell it.
You go.
Why did you come with applying dots?
To kill me!
You'll get a hard kick.
When we are fighting seriously
why he is standing idle?
I didn't like his action.
That's why there is
a small change in the fight.
But the remaining fight
will be done as it is.
Stop you bull!
Didn't I tell you that
you'll get a hard kick?
Bright smile!
I didn't expect it.
Dear!
Who has sent you to here?
Tell me.
What to do?
I should find it out in
a hard manner like Chiranjeevi.
God! The coconut broke well.
Similarly Munna's head will break like it.
He didn't take it much care..
...when bombs are blasting
and his friend getting stabbed.
But he got hurt for making trouble
while a girl is telling him I Love You.
It is the moment, he noticed
Damodhar Reddy seriously.
It is the same moment, the death
is looking for Damodhar Reddy.
Munna! I am coming.
Let's enjoy!
Enjoy it,
- Let's enjoy,
- Enjoy it,
Do anyone know how will tsunami
look when it comes in front?
Ever!
Can we know ever?
Do anyone know how the sound will be
when a cyclone knocks at the door?
If you don't know, look at him!
He is the human tsunami,
He's a real danger,
you've got to believe me,
He will become Mount Everest,
if you want to measure his height,
if you think how can he fight,
he'll put you in a stretcher
if you think he's grass pile that
can be cut, he'll chew you,
Giving a pin if you ask him
to make a garland, he'll dig the mound
if you think he is your friend,
becoming a flight,
he'll take you on his shoulders,
if you think he is your enemy,
becoming a danger,
he'll make you a corpse in seconds,
When I ask him some flowers,
he gets baskets of flowers,
if the death rope hangs to his neck,
he'll make a swing of it,
Greetings! They were not allowed
parking outside.
So here is..
I too joined in Margadarsi.
And bought a gun.
- Who is he?
- Damodhar Reddy.
Where does he stay?
Our Munna told me about you.
Uncle! I can't get a thing..
There're people to do murder for..
...the happiness in brother-in-law's eyes
and anger in sister's eyes
I don't have any connection with you..
What is this all?
Is there no connection?
Why are you staring like that?
Are we your fans to follow you?
6 years ago you hit my men
I left you as you were in
the agony of your father's death.
5 years ago you robbed my wealth
I kept quiet that you were
in the fast in perseverance.
You arranged meetings in my place
and buried flags in my land.
You made me lose my kingdom
and coming to the city..
...do settlements for livelihood.
I thought my time wasn't good.
You hit on my influence.
I thought that I didn't have God's grace.
But, 8 years ago you hit on my chest.
Don't you remember it?
Do you know who he is?
My son.
He is younger son to me.
He should be roaming like a tiger..
...but he is lying in Vikram hospital
as a coma patient.
Since 8 years..
If it comes to us,
it'll be a problem.
If it comes to our relatives,
it'll be the hell.
To show you, all these happened.
Rowdies who kidnapped your friends.
Made to run madly after the car..
The bombs which blasted
in front of your eyes..
These all are like onion to kill the rat.
Do you know why I did all these?
You shouldn't be scared to die.
You should be scared to live.
Fear! I don't know how it is.
But I feel good watching it
on opponent's eyes.
Mostly it'll be glad to me
seeing it in your eyes.
After hearing what you said,
I thought one thing.
The money, name, position, influence
and the land. You have everything.
Except fear!
Except you watching the fear in your
opponent eyes you never did fear, isn't it?
This is not a big issue.
With in short time,
you will get scared
I'll make it happen.
Bulli Reddy! Tell uncle
that I stand on my words.
It's my responsibility
to make you piss in fear.
You idiot! What do you
think of yourself?
Leave my hand.
Go away.
You..
Lord Krishna! You are my protector,
After I stopped using abuse words,
then why do you..
Why should we've trouble between us?
Let us work as a team.
What?
Didn't I tell you?
Your work will be finished.
Definitely I'll give you.
Not in grams and kilos.
I'll give you in tonnes..
Fear!
Let's meet after the marriage.
She doesn't like it dad!
Did I conduct your
marriage with your willing?
Have you seen her face?
With crying face.
You may tell to your dad
that she doesn't like it.
- I already told. He's taking
out my love story. Oh gosh!
No need of all that.
Exchange your rings.
Has the betrothal finished?
What Bulli Reddy? Which one has
become slow, we or the time?
They did in a hurry.
No problem.
Give the ring to him and
give your daughter to his elder son.
Don't scare.
He isn't a rowdy like my second son.
He'll take care your daughter very well.
No need of dowr.
Charge sheets can have
rowdies and goons names..
...but not the invitation.
I have 1000 crores of wealth.
There are 100 cases on you.
Why do I need that?
If you can vacate the place,
I've so many work to do.
You told to tell him
the truth before the betrothal.
Have you seen what happened
before we told it?
That's why your father has come
after you got the ring.
He is our boy.
You won't give him your daughter
if you know that his father got arrested.
We made him tell a small lie
that his father is dead.
Your girl's horoscope is nice.
The muhurtham has been fixed here
and he got the bail there.
We have come straight from the jail.
We are waiting in the car outside
for half an hour..
...to come here after
finishing exchanging the rings.
I didn't do this marriage
out of anger on you.
- Your daughter's..
- Her lover!
I am doing this with anger on him
I heard a good muhurtham
is there in tomorrow morning 10.20.
He'll conduct their
marriage at that time.
You both are invited.
You go and sit inside the car.
You too.
I am a police officer.
This threats are not new to me.
I can also behave as a rowdy at present.
Don't make me behave like that.
If I start to enter,
it's beginning only.
You yourself think
how worst the ending will be.
- You go dear!
Go. -Dear!
Look sir! If you come
as daughter's father..
...you may stand in the marriage hall,
it'll be respectful to you.
Or else, Home minister
will come to the marriage..
...you will have to guard in the entrance.
But it is sure that
the marriage will happen.
Madam! You tell your husband.
I too offered a light
to this dark world..
Wow! It's very excellent.
It is very wonderful and original.
Did Damodhar Reddy come yesterday
after the engagement got over?
He came.
Why not?
The guy who is going to become your
future son-in-law is already his son..
He threatened you and took Bagi with them
The marriage is tomorrow's morning.
He kept Bagi in his house.
Goons and rowdies are guarding
the house with weapons.
Damn goons and weapons!
- 40 or 50 dogs are also there.
- Dogs?
If dogs are there,
I can't do it.
I can manage with goons..
...but there is a language
problem between the dogs and me.
If we tr to escape,
they have 4 legs and I have 2 legs!
If any situations come that
they catch my calf..
...I don't have enough calf.
And if it catches my neck,
dog death will happen.
Dog death means
we are not killing the dog..
...we'll die by the dog.
It is called dog death.
Ok, don't worry somehow
I'll stop her marriage..
Are you thinking how I've come here?
That is wonder.
You should believe it.
You'll be happy if you believe it.
Have a tea, go home and sleep well..
...wake up and go to the marriage
by wearing the suit which you like.
After what will happen..
I don't say uncle,
I feel shy. Watch on the screen.
See you uncle.
Greetings! Are you fine?
- Have meals and go.
- Sure.
Move aside.
- Greetings!
- What is this dress?
- Didn't you tell him?
- What should I tell him?
Look! How the bride looks like..
She isn't looking like to marr..
...she looks like
to enter into the movies.
Bring the dhoti!
- Give phone to sir?
- Wait a minute.
Sir! A call for you..
Sir! I am Sidhu speaking..
Your second son is missing.
We searched whole hospital
and called everyone of our guys.
Come, they have gone.
- Come, they have gone.
- What about me?
I want to learn Kung fu from you..
Do you want to learn Kung fu?
No problem, learn it.
- I'll join you today itself.
- Will you join today itself?
You are very interested in it.
Look! We should do warm ups
before learning Kung fu.
- Do you know how to warm up?
- I don't know sir.
You have to make your body loosely.
If you loose our body..
And again we do warm up
before going to fight.
Don't worry at all.
I'll call a batch like this
to teach Kung fu a guy like you.
I'll teach you practically
with this batch.
- See carefully and learn it.
- Ok sir.
It's like a small trial part.
You play! Why do you scare of them?
Why are you all coming
like for freedom fight?
So far I haven't killed anyone
and I hit very carefully.
After seeing you all I lost my patience.
Come forward.
I don't know what will happen to you.
You idiot!
Come forward whoever has
affection for your boss.
If you had come here for liquor
and biriyani packets.. go back.
I am telling you.
Run away.
Don't build up muscles
for your body only..
...learn to build up for fingers too.
I can't see your defeat.
This is the fear of sign.
Even having the food when
you don't eat it, it's fasting.
Even having the cot when you
don't go to bed, it's guarding.
Having the sword in hands
when get the anger..
...and having the person to kill,
leaving him is humanity
I have it.
Do you have it?
Shall I tell you a top secret?
You know who stopped this marriage.
It is you only.
How?
He should be roaming like a tiger..
...but he is in Vikram hospitals
bed as a patient in coma.
I went to Vikram hospital straightly.
I gave 4 thousand rupees to the nurse.
I gave a thousand rupees
to the watchman..
They allowed me
to take whole hospital.
I said I don't want it, I kidnapped
your son and brought him out.
After kidnapping where should I hide him?
Sanjay Sahu got a brilliant idea.
What the brilliant idea was..
Excuse me where is the Urvasi bar?
Urvasi bar? Go straight,
there comes a junction..
...-If you ask anyone there,
they'll tell you. -Is it there?
Come on guys.
4 guys have come
and 3 guys have left.
What happened to the another guy?
I hid him into the car dicky
which you decorated for the marriage.
Have you seen my humanity, uncle?
We arranged carefully oxygen
and glucose without missing him..
...even you did bad to me.
Do you have any sense?
You wasted 8 months to catch me.
Instead of that if you had took care
of him since he was in 8..
...now he would have become
a great person like Abdul Kalam.
Don't enter into others
personal matters.
Uncle! You don't do studying like us,
attending interviews..
...going for jobs and paying taxes.
I am asking you to live happily.
What should I do more than this?
Should I die?
That's why I tell you,
let's live as our wish.
You go in the car doing rowdyism
I'll go along without knowing anything.
If you get down wherever you want..
...the situation will be like this.
Nowadays the guys are very dangerous.
If you quarrel them,
they'll kill you as comedy.
If you don't convince
even I've told so far..
...bring a fresh batch tomorrow
but not like these people.
For fighting, scolding, killing
and at last for warm talking..
...I always wait for 24 hours
C\o Osmania canteen, Hyderabad..
...I am very hot buddy!
When I kicked slowly,
why did it cut down like that?
CM sir! What we have to
understand seeing this?
If the sword cut down into the road
when a slim guy like me kicked..
What we have to understand seeing this..
...the contractors are swindling
government money.
Anyhow with an immediate effect
you've to stop this..
...I wish that you'll do it
and I am leaving from here.
- What again? -Why did you
leave him alive without killing?
To win in the battle field,
we don't kill the opponent..
...and make him to defeat the opponent.
- What did I tell you?
- To make him defeat.
To make him defeat..
The aim of the battle is
to make to defeat
...but not to killing.
What happened to my father?
I didn't kill him. But if he dies,
I won't be the responsible.
- It's enough you gave
me that gap. -Go.
All of you close your eyes.
Why did they become like that?
Don't know the reason but Damodhar Reddy
don't speak to anyone after that.
With the shame of that he got
defeat before their men..
...or in the agony of Bulli Reddy died.
He stopped talking.
What the sad news was..
He was admitted in the hospital
the same day when his son got discharged.
Daily in the evenings
they took him to the same park.
He was watching the knife stick
which was on the middle of the road.
How the people of India
don't bother about the things..
...similarly they don't bother
about that knife stick.
2 people only could tell what it was..
One is the guy who came to learn Kung fu.
Second one is Damodhar Reddy.
No one would ask him
and this one won't speak out.
After 6 months on a fine day..
Have you stopped drinking
because of Bagi?
Do one thing.
Leave Bagi.
- You can drink daily.
- It's better.
See! Your cell phone is ringing.
May be it is your fiancée.
It's like that
if marriage happens..
- Look at these roamers!
- Yes.
What is this stick?
Why is it on the middle of the road?
- Sir! What happened?
- Hey bring the car!
The sword which was the reason to kill..
...a great faction leader
by this ordinary Sanjay Sahu..
...has remained under the road.
Another road was put on
that after a few years.
This time the contractor
was a good person..
...with that the knife
never been disclosed.
What is it? You don't
get tense. I'll take care of it.
Do something.
- It's me Seenu.
- Tell me Seenu.
A small problem has come to the girl
for whom we helped for marriage.
Wait a minute.
You contact some lawyer.
Why do you ask me?
- Ok sir, I'll contact a lawyer, bye.
- Listen Seenu!
He won't come to good.
What about the party?
Take this thousand rupees
and get a full bottle.
- Is it a thousand rupees note?
- Do you want a loan? -Yes sir.
What purpose?
- A friend of mine got married.
- So what?
He gave a wedding party.
- Did you pay the bill?
- He only paid.
- Then why do you need money?
- He is a unique guy.
He gives 10 rupees
but says it is 1000 rupees.
And he asks for the balance money also.
It is difficult to tell you in detail.
Give me 3 lakh rupees loan.
If I go to them empty-handed,
they'll hit me.