JEANNE
AND THE PERFECT GUY
Can I take a message?
Call back Monday.
Jet Tours, hello.
Sorry, he just left.
You know, Fridays... Of course.
I'll tell him. Good-bye.
- Seen the runner?
- The messenger, you mean. No.
You're cheerful.
I'm bored.
This magazine's dumb.
Try reading a novel instead.
I can't read a novel here.
I keep getting interrupted.
See what I mean?
I'll put you through.
Triton, for you.
- Are you taking it?
- Not now!
They go on for hours.
I'll pass it to Moutier,
he just left.
Don't forget, Sunday at 7.
I won't.
Sorry, he's left.
Call back Monday...
Okay, Mr Frost?
Can't complain.
But my name's not Frost.
I sell Frost heaters.
But my name's Martin.
I'm sorry.
I don't mind, it suits me.
- What's wrong?
- The usual.
Ground floor?
- Can't you help, Jean-Baptiste?
- It's not my field.
Jean-Baptiste!
Well... I could try.
I'll get to work.
I know the way.
Good luck, Mr Frost!
Call me
when the runner...
I mean the messenger comes.
Please hold, I'll put you through.
All this is for you.
My pleasure...
I'll need you again later...
Nothing for you.
No, I leave in 5 minutes.
Work overtime if you feel like it.
Of course...
Have a good weekend!
For all the workers
It's closing time
Now we come in
To clean the dirt and grime
With brooms at the ready
We clean the mess we find
We get things spick and span
We work the daily grind
And after all this work
This one long ordeal
Deportation from France
Sums up the whole raw deal
They can't give us papers
Or so they say
Even our kids
Will never be French one day
We spend our time
Cleaning for the nobs
We suffer in our prime
They never hear our sobs
We keep our mouths shut
For to toil is our fate
We stay here in our rut
We don't give in to hate!
Have a good weekend.
You're man crazy, little sister.
- A new guy every day.
- I'm happy.
I should hope so,
the way you collect them.
I don't.
I can't resist, that's all.
- Why should I resist?
- To seem less like a slut.
Screw that.
- What about Jean-Baptiste?
- He doesn't know.
- You lie to them all.
- That's my problem.
- I love them.
- But some expect fidelity.
- I don't tell them.
- Great excuse!
I don't sleep with everyone.
I'm sure I'll find him one day.
I don't know who he is
Nor what he's like
He's not in my dreams
I've never seen him
I don't know his voice
Nor the colour of his eyes
His body's a mystery
His hands have no shape
- He has ten fingers though?
- He has a prick too!
- Him!
My ideal
But I don't know it yet
He'll be here one day
- I'll know him.
- You'll know him.
I don't know why
I don't know how
My heart will tell me.
What will it say?
He's the one!
It's not Jean-Baptiste
or the messenger...
I'm not sure yet.
There's no mistaking the signs.
How do you know?
Give me a break. I just know.
If the sex is no good,
it's not love.
I can't argue with that!
Excuse me, I'm late...
- One for Springtime.
- Sold-out.
Excuse me, please...
- I forget your name.
- Jeanne.
- You're Francis.
- François.
What're you seeing?
Springtime in Paris
but it's sold-out.
Oh, I wanted to see it too.
Let's have coffee.
- Still a student?
- Come on!
I've moved up in the world.
I teach.
Lucky students.
With you, I'd have worked harder.
- Did you finish school?
- Just about.
I answer phones at Jet Tours now.
- Great for romantic weekends...
- I can't really say.
- You're married with kids?
- No, I live alone.
I haven't got
a guy to go away with.
Me neither. And I get no discounts!
You had that cute boyfriend...
Pierre, was it?
It's years since I saw you.
You couldn't know.
- Sorry, you've split up...
- No, he died.
- How? An accident?
- No, Aids.
What else these days?
Life is full of surprises
Things you never hope for
One day the sun rises
And love's gone out the door
But life can be unfair
And bring you down, you see
Your happy love affair
Can turn into tragedy
You meet a guy who loves you
And give him all the love you can
You know it'll be tough to do
That it may not last with that man
Then Aids steps in the door
And you know he's going to die
So you love him more and more
He suffers, you try and try
But love is not a cure
For a disease of this kind
And love can't reassure
The lover left behind
And when he dies, shit, you're sad
Your body yearns for his touch
But despite the times you've had
Against death, love can't do much
And then his family appears
They never really accepted you
They scorn your bitter tears
And your love for him too
So you end up all alone
Like a poor widowed wife
Whose husband's shroud is sewn
And struggles on with her life
But at thirty this isn't what you seek
You just can't keep on mourning
And taking flowers every week
To his grave on Sunday morning
And so you fall in love again
You believe in love and life
But they give you joy and then
They only ever lead to strife
Sorrow, mourning and rage
Take you to the depths of despair
You struggle at every stage
For better days to share
Yet you live with the grief
Of all these friends and lovers
Living lives so brief
And so mourned by others
Our shining dreams are rust
The ghosts around us prove it
When a faggot bites the dust
No one really gives a shit
- Sorry, I brought you down.
- No, it was my fault.
- It's horrible. What can we do?
- Nothing.
Apart from fight.
I joined Act-Up 4 years ago.
I've seen them on TV.
You should see us for real.
Come to the march next Saturday.
Sure. I'll try to.
You won't find time...
I'm sorry,
the driver's so clumsy!
It was my pleasure.
I'll call you, Olivier.
You were in a hurry.
An urgent appointment?
Am I prying?
No, I'm always in a hurry.
God knows why.
I'm free all day today.
You're not busy?
I am now.
What?
You're going to offer me a drink...
You should buy me one
to apologize.
Haven't I just done that?
I'm running late now.
You were in a hurry.
I have Sunday lunch
with my parents.
You'll get told off because of me.
- Don't keep them waiting.
- Okay, I'm going.
Well... See you around...
Bye.
Sorry, I just realized
I can't call you.
- Got a pen?
- I'll remember.
Okay, 42293099...
See you...
- What a life you lead.
- Don't start, I'm tired.
That's what worries me.
You wear yourself out
...and you don't seem happy.
- I am happy, mom.
No steady boyfriend...
It's not that easy
to find someone, you know.
I try but I can't find anyone.
Look at your sister.
And us.
Sophie and you are exceptions.
Love at first sight isn't for me.
I can live with that.
You have to want love to find it.
Are you really looking for it?
At least go to bed earlier.
- Shit, give me a break!
- Jeanne!
We never taught you to swear.
True, but I left a while ago.
Be nice to your mother.
I am being nice.
Try to be more selfish.
Treat yourselves. Go on a trip.
Visit friends in the country.
We don't want to.
We're fine here.
Okay, if I keep out of your lives,
keep out of mine.
- Are you never on time?
- I can't help it...
- I want to dance.
- I wanted to talk...
- Let's go for a drink.
- No, they're waiting.
Cool it, we've got all night.
Good evening...
- You look gorgeous.
- Thanks.
This is Nathalie...
Jeanne... Jean-Baptiste.
Sit down.
What'll you have?
Same as you.
Champagne.
Another bottle!
- How's the training course?
- Almost over.
- Any good?
- I've learnt a lot.
Management isn't easy.
Will it lead to a job?
Not with them.
But they've given me a few leads.
Finding work's tough.
Right, we're not in the 80s now.
I mean, we deserve decent pay.
We were at business school!
Do you have to?
Sorry, we're boring you.
Try to understand,
it's a big worry.
Maybe but we're here for fun.
Coming to Cabourg at Whitsun?
You bet, as usual.
And Jeanne too?
I can't, it's my birthday.
We'll throw a party for you.
It's my sister's too.
Your twin?
My older sister.
And my mother's too.
All three the same week.
We celebrate and...
Too bad.
We walk, go out riding...
Some other time.
Thanks but I don't like horses.
They scare me.
- I won't have time.
- You work a lot?
Too much.
Doing what?
- I answer...
- She works with me.
Want to dance a tango?
There's something not quite right
I wonder what it can be
Something in the air tonight
This isn't right for me
Maybe I'm in the wrong place
Dancing with the bourgeoisie
We're not of the same race
This isn't right for me
Now as we dance the tango
He holds me so tightly
And, maybe, you never know
He might want to marry me
Maybe
Now what am I to do?
I'm just an employee
His love may well be true
But this isn't right for me
Maybe I'm mistaken
Perhaps he doesn't love me
Should I wait to be forsaken?
Should I run, should I flee?
Now as we dance the tango
And he holds me so tightly
How come I don't know
If he truly loves me?
How can that be?
So I have the feeling
As he dances close to me
That for him I'm nothing
Just a girl who's free
I know it's not right
Sleeping with a guy's no key
For nothing here tonight
Will make me join the bourgeoisie
Yes, now I know why
He doesn't love me, not he
For my perfect guy
Would never bring me here,
you see
Yes, now I know why
I don't love him, not me
For my perfect guy
Would never come here, you see
Come on, we're leaving.
It'll take three days to mend.
The bosses don't care.
They never use that washroom.
Theirs is perfect.
The selfishness
of the modern world!
What can we do?
In the meantime...
Any trouble, call me
and I'll pop in.
Okay? Bye then.
- Enjoy your weekend.
- See you soon, I'm afraid.
Is Julien still crazy about his car?
Yes but it makes a weird noise.
That's bad for a new car.
- It's under guarantee.
- I always forget.
New things are like new lovers.
If they break down,
you take them back
...and replace them.
- Silly...
Duck with Chinese five spice.
It's true.
Chicken with cashews.
When old lovers break down
it's no end of trouble.
- But new ones...
- New ones too...
You're so happy. A new lover?
I'll have to tell you.
Both trays.
Any drinks?
Beer?
Two Tsing-Tao beers.
58 francs as usual?
Well? Tell me.
I've just met the perfect guy
When I saw him in front of me
I felt Cupid's arrow from the sky
And love handed me the key
Where did you meet him, please?
On the subway, I thought I'd die
I fell and landed on his knees
I felt so dumb, I don't know why
And yet I also felt at ease
His first words, I cannot lie,
Were coarse, common and gross
Then I caught the look in his eye
And my heart melted to be so close
He smiled, said some sweet things
I couldn't resist his voice
His deep brown eyes
gave me wings
I fell for him, I had no choice
What's he like?
I can't lie
He's perfect, I wanted him
His looks just made me sigh
And now my heart's out on a limb
Jeanne, again! You never say die
It's love that decides, not me
All these lovers, how d'you get by?
Right now, I only have three
But this one with this gentle look
Has a smile as sweet as any child
He's really got me on the hook
With him, I just go wild
- How about sex?
- A real high
Ardent, violent, an incredible guy
He made me scream and sigh
If this isn't love I want to die
Our longing was so great
We did it on the subway train
On the train? You couldn't wait?
It was fun, I'd do it again
Jeanne, this guy sounds sly
Not at all, when he's with me
In my arms, he seems so shy
As if he really needed me
So here's to the perfect guy
And the love I feel for him
Aids!
End the epidemic, no more tricks!
- I'm leaving.
- Already?
It's a great march.
It's important.
- I know...
- You're too much.
You turn up for once
then vanish.
You're not like a campaigner,
or a friend.
It's important...
- More important than this?
- I'm meeting a girl.
- You should have brought her.
- It's complicated...
Run, rabbit!
- We'll have dinner sometime.
- Sure...
- I'll call you.
- I'll be waiting, like Penelope.
Aids is war, Act-Up says no more!
- What's all this?
- The march I told you about.
Act-Up's out on the streets.
You're right. I'm with you,
it can't go on.
- Can I cross?
- The riot cops'll stop you.
Shit, I'm late! See you.
See you!
Your place or mine?
- Been waiting long?
- You're here now, it's okay.
- Have a good week?
- Work as usual.
- Not too tough?
- Can't complain.
As long as I get
weekends and evenings off.
You're so cheerful.
- Is that wrong?
- No, it's just rare.
I've been thinking of you.
That kept me busy.
Same here.
So what's the conclusion?
Nothing, I like it.
- I'm glad I met you.
- Thank you. So am I.
What did you do?
I didn't feel too good
so I stayed at home.
- I went to the march today though.
- That's funny.
- Not really.
- I didn't mean that.
It's a coincidence.
Never mind...
You go to those marches?
Sometimes. I feel concerned.
Why? Got HIV-positive friends?
I'm HIV-positive.
That's okay, we used a condom.
- That's a new one.
- Sorry, I didn't mean...
When the doctor told me I had
This disease, I thought: I'm dead
I didn't believe it at first
I ignored the voice that said:
"Tomorrow, you'll be dead"
I hated the world around me
People acted as if I was dead
Then I got over it and thought:
"Okay, I'm going to die
But I'm not yet dead"
You won't die. I love you.
- Love never saved anyone.
- I believe it can!
- I don't.
- Don't be so hard.
It's not me, it's my disease.
Go on, kiss me.
- Have you known long?
- Six years, I'd say
I did drugs
And used a bad needle one day
D'you know who contaminated you?
Don't ask that, no one's to blame
No one set out
With contamination as his aim
The ones to blame, I know why
Are those who turn away
And let junkies die
I blame the government
I blame the jails
When a junkie croaks
No one weeps and wails
When you use drugs
You fear the cops
You're a hunted animal
And it never stops
I stayed in my room
Locked behind my door
I lost my friends
I was a man no more
Then I started living again
I have no time before life fades
For now I know
That I'll die of Aids
- You had a worried look.
- A bad dream, I guess.
- With me here?
- You can't control your dreams.
- I've made breakfast. Hungry?
- Yes.
Don't move.
We're going to stay in bed all day
No one needs us out there
We can manage without them
They don't exist
They don't and we don't care
I want to kiss you a thousand times
And then a thousand more
I want to lose myself
In your arms
Making love for ever more
We'll share a thousand kisses
Kisses great and small
Even the bitterest man on earth
Could never count them all
Sunday
What a glorious day
For once you're not in a hurry,
I guess
Please send some bread my way
You want me to butter it? Yes?
Some jam made from plums?
Or honey, if you prefer?
I'd rather have it as it comes
Pass me the sugar, it's too bitter
Listen to the sounds of the street
The hubbub, the stress below
Forget all that today, my sweet
We're here together, you know
It's nice to listen to the sound
Of cars honking outside
When there's no one else around
And I'm here with you at my side
You've lovely skin without a doubt
I love your tender touch
- All day long to laze about
- Idling, not doing too much
We'll share a thousand kisses
Kisses great and small
Even the bitterest man on earth
Could never count them all
I don't believe it.
- You're never on time.
- My life's complicated.
- It's Sunday. What can we do?
- Let's go up to the Sacré-Coeur.
They sell fun stuff there.
- Not the Sacré-Coeur!
- Don't start. I have no choice.
This black guy sells jewellery there.
Perfect for my sister.
- Maybe for your mom too?
- It wouldn't suit her.
- Why?
- My parents are old.
They're both almost 60.
- Did they meet late?
- No, they were very young.
They got married right away.
They were too happy to have kids?
No, it's a sad story.
My brother and sister
died in a car crash.
Grandad was driving.
- Shit, I'm sorry.
- I never knew them.
My parents lived alone
for ten unhappy years.
Then mom decided
she wanted kids.
The three of us arrived later.
- Wasn't it tough?
- No, we were happy.
They were so glad,
they really pampered us.
- Spoiled me, hasn't it?
- Not that much.
That's why birthdays
are so important.
- D'you love your parents?
- Of course.
They hassle me to get married
but that's normal, huh?
Mom wants grandchildren.
My sister's not ready
and I'm too young, huh?
Of course.
Olivier, what is it?
A weak spell.
What? Does it happen often?
Only when I skip lunch.
That's my fault.
No, it's okay.
- I was scared, I thought...
- What did you think?
- Nothing, I don't know...
- That I was going to drop dead?
- Don't say that!
- I'm sorry.
I don't like talking about it,
not with you.
Let's not worry. I'm fine.
I'm just HIV-positive.
There's no need to worry.
Okay?
Let's change the subject.
Good idea...
- Shall we go?
- Let's eat first.
Good, isn't it? Really tasty.
A photo?
- Come on, you're cute.
- I hate photos...
You can't refuse her.
- You can't refuse.
- If you insist.
He can't!
There you go.
I like it.
- Don't let people see it.
- I'll keep it for myself.
Hi!
Hello, sweetheart.
Roast lamb...
You're here, dear.
- With your sister?
- No, by train.
I'll go and change.
You're here.
I didn't hear you.
Are you hiding?
I was getting ready. Alone.
- I'm disturbing you.
- No, I'm glad to see you.
Sit down.
Tell me about life in the army.
It'll bore you, believe me.
- What about you?
- I kind of like it.
I'm re-enlisting.
That's an odd idea.
I can't find a job.
Besides, I like it.
I'm not saying you're wrong...
But I don't understand.
I like sport, I like marching
I like nights out with my pals
Being in a bar, a glass in my hand
That's the life for me
Still, it's an odd life
You can't see why I belong
Never thinking all the day
Following the guys, marching along
Obeying without delay
It's a good life
No stress or strife
It shows you the way
To go from day to day
Never worry
It's all done for you
You obey
And even give orders too
You're weird, brother dear
I'm not bothered, is that clear?
That's how I am but I don't care
I never liked school, I think
I don't like work, I love fresh air
I like a laugh and a good drink
The army changes a guy
but this is crazy!
We're waiting for you.
I was just getting ready.
I've been busy all day.
- Brought your boyfriend?
- No, it's too soon.
- But I will, I promise.
- Mom was hoping...
Are we eating?
- Rémi's re-enlisting.
- That's his problem.
Yes but I mean...
Just one more.
It's delicious.
There, a lovely slice.
- Rémi first...
- Rare, please.
I'll have that thick one.
- What about Jeanne?
- I'll wait for dessert.
A kiss first...
This one's for Jeanne,
this one for Sophie
and this for mom.
Present time!
- Hurry up!
- Wait for me!
Sit down!
- What is it?
- A film.
Okay...
A Streetcar Named Desire?
It's too hard.
Some Like It Hot?
- Not that.
- Backside...
Legs...
- Thigh...
- Legs Diamond!
Legs Diamond, is that it?
Another one...
Is something wrong between you?
No, it's me. She's perfect.
She's pretty, intelligent, funny,
and she likes me.
So what more do you want?
What more? 10 years, 20...
I want a life!
I want time to love and be happy!
Why bother loving
if it leads to death?
I ought to end it before it's too late.
Someone will always suffer
whatever you do.
I know, we can't avoid it.
- But I'd rather limit the damage.
- Thanks a lot!
I just don't want others to suffer.
I wish I didn't care.
I'd have good time and split.
But I can't do that.
When I'm with her, time stands still.
I'm hooked, see.
Don't freak out about it.
Maybe she's not so mad about you.
Maybe she'll leave.
You're the one who's ill.
What do you care about others?
- Especially some girl you just met.
- Right, she's a girl...
- You goddam faggot!
- You're talking sense at last.
Let's go and get smashed.
It'll help.
A gay bar, okay?
I can't take straight ones.
I'm putting you to bed.
- May I help you?
- Yes.
- What are you looking for?
- A novel.
We have quite a few.
Can you be more specific?
- Who's it for? Your girl?
- I suppose.
- What does she like?
- Romantic stuff, I guess.
Sure, don't we all?
Not this one... It's a best-seller
but it's no good.
If she likes it,
she doesn't deserve you.
- She doesn't like that writer.
- Very well...
There's Duras
but she's probably read them all.
I don't know.
Maybe it's a bit too...
- It's for her birthday.
- Right, too intellectual.
Something less high-brow...
I live here among all these books
I sell to all and sundry
To handsome guys with good looks
To women blond and sultry
Men come in for romance
Women go for the weepy style
And kids, with just one glance
Find tales set on a magic isle
I sell fiction, I sell dreams
True-life tales, best-sellers
Even guides to get-rich schemes
Long novels and novellas
Lovers come to me to find
Books for their own lovers
Book of the romantic kind
To show there are no others
I live here among these books
I share them all around
They pass as easy as looks
Spreading love unbound
People know the books
they've found
Will spread love all around
What about this one here?
It's not her style, see
Why not this one here?
It's set across the sea
- Do you know it?
- Of course I do!
- Will she like it?
- I'm sure she will
One look at you and I knew
This'll give her such a thrill
How can you be so sure?
Because your smile's so pure
Will you take it then?
Where've you been?
I was away.
Too bad,
there was this really wild rave.
I wouldn't have come anyway.
What's up?
I didn't want to see you.
It's for you.
It's important. Sirène Express.
- Wait there.
- Where could I go?
I'm putting you through.
Want to go dancing next weekend?
With Richard and Nathalie?
No thanks!
Some other time.
We'll see a movie or a play.
We can go to the sea too.
How about the Basque Coast?
A weekend package.
- It's summer there already.
- I'm too busy.
- Something simpler...
- No, forget it.
I'm not going out with you.
You want to dump me?
Hold the line, please.
Come on, let's talk.
You'll get me fired!
I'll vouch for you.
No, this isn't Radio Nostalgie.
Sorry, I don't know their number.
You're hurting me!
- Let me answer.
- They can wait, I can't.
My contract ends soon.
- So? Good riddance.
- It can't end like this.
Cut it out! What are you doing?
Cut it out! Let me go!
We can be alone here.
Are you out of your mind?
You bastard! Stop or I'll scream!
I'm sorry.
Tidy yourself up, you're a mess.
Mr Martin?
- Not Mr Frost?
- It's not your name.
I liked it.
We were checking.
- And?
- Clogged again.
I called in on my way home.
I'll sort it out.
It needs a major overhaul.
We'll call you. Thanks.
Have a good evening.
You too, Mr Frost.
What do they do in here
To clog it every day?
What's down there?
What's in the way?
Something's in the spout
I should mend it now
Too bad
The day's over anyhow
Plumber, do your job
Plumber, ply your trade
Why should I care
If it's clogged, see?
It's a lucky break
It means more work for me
If I weren't here
lt'd go on and on
Without me,
They'd never use the john
Plumber, what a great job
Plumber
What a great trade
Are you okay?
It's just a cold.
I'll get some cough medicine.
I always take this.
Forget it,
I take enough medicine.
Herb tea and honey then.
- I hate herb tea.
- It would do you good.
I have to go.
You could stay in bed.
Have your tea and you'll feel better.
Take care, okay.
Excuse me...
- Olivier Lagrange, please.
- Room 19-20.
- Can I see him?
- Yes, he's awake.
- He'll be pleased to have a visit.
- Yes, I know.
- Okay?
- Yes.
Thanks for coming.
You call, here I am.
I'm just checking on you.
Don't let me tire you.
A good campaigner's just
what I need.
Okay?
Act-Up, you mean?
The same as usual.
How's the book going?
- What's it about?
- It's my thesis. I've finished.
I defend it next month.
- You must be pleased.
- Yes, I'm very happy.
You should be. And proud.
- What's it on? Remind me.
- Activism.
I stick with what I know, see.
I write about my own acts,
other people's acts.
That's good.
What will it get you?
Nothing...
Maybe a university job.
That's good for you.
Good work, good pay.
Cute young students...
Stupid...
It'll be a great life.
Sorry, I have black-outs.
I'm glad you came.
I don't feel too good.
- I can't stand the medication.
- It helps though.
I'm always tired.
Nothing works anymore.
Maybe a new therapy will.
- Maybe I don't want to fight.
- Olivier, come on...
I don't want to stay here.
I'm afraid.
- Fancy meeting you here.
- I come here often.
- A second home but no fun.
- I can imagine.
Sorry, a friend's in a bad way.
He's had enough,
he wants to give up.
- What about you?
- I'm fine!
No, why're you here?
I'm visiting a friend.
Nothing serious?
- Something going on?
- You're too curious!
I won't keep you. You're late.
Give him my love.
Sure!
Jealous too...
I woke you.
No, I wasn't asleep. I was thinking.
- Flowers... That's sweet.
- I've brought fruit too.
- How was your day?
- Just work, nothing much.
Nothing much has happened
since I met you.
- I mean nothing equivalent.
- Jeanne...
And you? Do you feel better?
Yes, don't worry. I'll be okay.
When you get out,
I'll look after you.
I'd rather
you didn't come tomorrow.
- Fine but why?
- Because my parents are coming.
You don't want me to meet them?
It's not that.
This isn't the best place
for an introduction.
I'd rather be alone with them.
- D'you mind? You do understand?
- It's a bit stupid but...
You can always call me.
I couldn't go a day without calling.
Surely I can say I love you,
that I'm fond of you...
I've had a lot of lovers, you know
So many guys in my life
I've fallen in love so often
But I loved with passion though
I was seeking an ideal
From heart to heart, bed to bed
I was always so delighted
I loved, it was so real
I loved them
I loved holding them too
But I never loved them like you
But I was always disappointed
I never found Mr Right
And in their arms at night
I could see no point to it
As I searched for my ideal
Between nights of love
and gloomy days
I found men set in their ways
And others so boringly real
Yet I loved
I loved their bodies next to mine
Still I loved
I hoped, waiting for a sign
One day you appeared
out of the blue
That morning on the subway car
I saw the beauty of what you are
And I offered up my heart to you
Your touch was like a fantasy
My body melted into yours
This time I knew the cause
I'm here to share your destiny
You loved me
And you held me tight
I loved you
I need you every single night
I've found you
In your arms, our love grew
I loved you
And I'll love no one but you
What are you telling me?
The story of our love...
Why are you telling me?
I needed to say it
It's going to change, you'll see
But will you forgive me?
Forgive you for what?
For not loving you enough
For not ending all that stuff
There were others too
Who held me just like you
- It doesn't matter...
- I let others kiss me
Just as you had done
Forgive me
Hold me tight now
Olivier, I can't live without you
Forgive me
It doesn't matter
It doesn't matter anymore
So what?
You saw a guy in a bad way?
- You couldn't find the right words?
- No.
There I was, helpless, incapable,
pathetic...
forced to be pathetic.
I don't know
why he wanted to see me.
He must have closer friends.
- Act-Up makes you a specialist.
- Specialist, my ass!
I don't specialize in the dying!
- Accept it.
- I went there, didn't I?
But others do "counselling"
better than me.
Why did he want to talk to me?
I was pathetic.
- Perhaps he's in love with you.
- A dying guy, thanks...
He's straight, he's got a girl.
I think so.
He told me all about her.
He wanted to split up
so she wouldn't see him ill.
- It scared him.
- Understandable...
I wonder...
Maybe he has left her.
I never thought to ask him.
I was paralysed.
I never mentioned her.
I'm pathetic!
You're a perfect guy.
And I love you.
What d'you want?
- Have dinner with me.
- Piss off.
- I want to apologize.
- It's too late, you jerk.
- Why so aggressive?
- Just get off my back!
Don't you get it?
- Is there someone else?
- People are watching!
- That bothers you?
- I'm in a hurry.
- I've a right to know.
- Okay, fine.
Yes, I love another guy.
But he's not why I left you.
You weren't the only one.
Okay, I loved you
but it's over.
I'm not sleeping with you.
Asshole!
NO ADMITTANCE
STERILE ENVIRONMENT
- Why all the precautions?
- Against infection.
- What? Olivier's fine.
- He left yesterday.
I called three times yesterday,
he never said!
That's all I know.
- Where did he go?
- Ask admissions or my colleague.
She's on duty at 9:00 p.m.
Why wasn't I told?
Sorry, I'm busy.
We have a lot of patients...
- Can I ask you something?
- Go ahead.
I had a close friend here.
He's left
and I want to know where he is.
We don't always know
where the patients go.
Couldn't the nurse tell you?
- She wasn't on duty when he left.
- I'll just check.
He was discharged.
I don't know where he went.
Excuse me...
- Where's the maternity wing?
- First on your left.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
- Can I have his parents' address?
- I'm afraid not.
Why not?
I can't give out
that kind of information.
If he didn't tell you
...he had his reasons.
- No way!
We're in love.
I must find him.
Don't insist, I can't tell you.
Excuse me...
What time's that nurse on duty?
- 9:00 p.m.
- Okay, I'll wait.
- She won't be able to help.
- I'll wait. Where else can I look?
You can wait over there.
You wanted to see me?
- Tell me where he is.
- His parents took him.
- His parents?
- Yes, he wanted home nursing.
- So you know where he is.
- At his parents'.
- Where do they live?
- I don't know.
He must have said.
If he's your friend,
you should know.
But I don't.
You can't leave me like this.
What can I do? If he didn't tell you,
he had his reasons.
He had no reason. I don't get it.
You must realize...
He's very ill.
Many patients return home
at that stage in the disease.
If he's very ill, he needs me.
We love each other.
He'll be in touch.
- Go home, he'll call you.
- You're right.
Love him well,
he deserves it. He needs it.
Give him our best wishes.
Go on home. Be brave.
Get it the right way up...
Don't you like it like that?
Come on, move it...
It's you!
I can't be content
with only the nights anymore
I don't want to be yours
only at night anymore
I spend my days outside your door
I want to be with you
Jeanne, after dawn
has replaced the night
Jeanne, I love you,
I feel your might
Jeanne, I love you still
I want to see you
For I suffer
In the day without you
I want to share
That time with you too
I want to be with you by day
Will you please let me stay?
Let me fall asleep at sunrise
My head resting on your thighs
I want your Sundays too
Not just nights alone with you
I want midday, I want dawn
And every night until morn
Jeanne, I need it all
Not only when you call
It's not the way
Jeanne, I want you night and day
Jeanne, I love you
You can give me so much joy
Jeanne, by day too
A heart beats in this boy
I never promised you anything.
What are you doing here?
- Have you come to join Act-Up?
- Why not...
I need to ask a favour.
That friend in hospital...
He has Aids and I must find him...
I don't get it.
The hospital won't give me
his parents' address.
- They can't.
- Maybe you could convince them.
- Not if you can't.
- Act-Up can help...
- What d'you mean?
- We could hold a march.
You must be kidding!
- Who is he? Do I know him?
- I doubt it.
- Maybe he's in your files.
- Hold on...
This isn't the CIA!
- You won't help?
- Maybe he just wants some peace.
Just respect his decision.
Thanks for the lecture!
You're like the hospital!
What use is Act-Up
if you can't help people?
Thanks a lot!
- Who's that maniac?
- Some girl I know...
OBITUARIES
Okay?
Yes, no bad news today.
So it's time for good news?
Yes, bring me breakfast
while I wait.
- Coming up.
- Thanks.
Health: Excellent for Gemini.
Money: Try to spend less.
Love: What's going on?
Why is your love life so uneventful?
Cheer up, spring's here.
You're sheer bliss,
pretty miss
Yes, but I'm running late
I'm afraid I can't wait
Don't run off so fast
Try to make the moment last
- Can I have more than one glance?
- Yes, you stand a chance
I come this way
Every single day
- It's you I often see
- Are you after me?
- You're angry?
- Not at all
See you tomorrow
- Why didn't you answer?
- I didn't hear you.
What's wrong?
Why didn't you answer?
I have to go.
I have to go home to change,
I'll be late.
I'm rubbing off on you.
- Sure you don't want to come?
- I'm sure.
You're right, it'll be tedious.
I don't know anyone there.
I want to be alone tonight.
- That's not nice...
- See you tomorrow.
See you...
What's wrong?
Come in.
- We could have done dinner.
- It's okay, I can't stay.
Julien...
It's Jeanne.
- I'm disturbing you.
- Not at all.
- You were watching TV.
- It's only a video.
- What was it?
- What's it called?
- A Weekend in San Sebastien.
- I read the book.
- Don't tell us the end.
- I'm not that mean.
- Want a drink?
- Please.
Julien, can you do us
a little pick-me-up?
He's crazy about cocktails.
- A super-duper-double-whammy?
- Perfect.
Take your time
so we can talk.
Throwing me out?
Go on...
Get in the kitchen.
What's wrong?
Still thinking of him?
He left ages ago...
He's forgotten me?
I didn't say that...
He's keeping his distance.
That's his decision, I know.
I've done everything to find him.
I know I shouldn't have.
But he had no right
to make me suffer like this.
I need to see him, Sophie,
to talk to him, to touch him.
We were so happy together.
I can't forget him.
No one's asking you to forget him.
Be patient.
Perhaps he'll come back.
No, he won't come back.
Can I come back?
She should've let you stay.
Look at those!
Classy, huh?
- How do you make them?
- He's got this great shaker.
You two are crazy.
More new stuff!
How do you manage?
- What's it all for?
- Cocktails.
Here I am.
In this world today
Consuming is so easy
Spend and spend away
Buy everything you see
Borrow from banks
They lend with thanks
- TV and video-recorder...
- On credit
Fridge
- Washer, camcorder...
- On credit
- Microwave oven
- Clothes drier
- Food steamer
- And the cocktail shaker
On credit!
You're really with it, on credit
The couch and bed
- The kitchen
- The jacuzzi
- Holidays in Nepal
- On credit!
You're really with it, on credit
Life's grand, on the credit plan
Yes, my love
My love!
- I'm sorry.
- Just watch out.
Don't get on
when the buzzer sounds.
She could have hurt me.
I have a hernia.
- Young people don't care.
- I'm sorry...
Apologizing won't make it better.
Think before you act.
I know you. You were on the subway
with Olivier Lagrange.
I landed on top of him.
I was often with Olivier.
Where can I find him?
I've been looking for him.
You can keep looking.
You haven't heard?
He died yesterday.
Would you please stand...
It's no use staying.
We don't know anyone.
Let's go.
I don't know if he was right.
- About what?
- Vanishing like that.
Then coming back dead.
Pride, perhaps.
To hell with it...
English subtitles: Lan Burley
Laboratoires Eclair