Sir! Get up Sir!
Drink it.
If you win, 4 doIIars.
- If you Iose, 2 doIIars.
Try to guess which of us is
Visu and Ramu correctIy.
Goat, Cow, CaIf, Visu!
- No, you got it wrong today as weII.
I am Visu and he is
Ramamoorthy. I wiII do it tomorrow.
Why?! Despite aII my
knowIedge, I can't teII between them!
You need to be one of six
senses you onIy have five.
How can you teII?
- I am their father!
Fine. To heIp others can't
they at Ieast dress differentIy?
No. If there are
differences, it wiII Iead to separation inevitabIy.
My chiIdren must never
be separated. Hence I brought them up so.
When did you come to the
US? When my sons were infants.
I rose sIowIy from being
the cook to the owner and stayed on.
So they're both your
sons? Very smart chiIdren!
Both of them study
medicine and heIp out at night.
Have some coffee Sir.
My American friend
SoIomon Iikes your food.
He has a party at his
pIace tomorrow.
CouId you cook for 20
peopIe tomorrow for that party?
Tomorrow is the weekend
and the restaurant is cIosed.
We sIog through the week
and have no time to taIk to each other.
So on the weekends, we
take off without teIIing anyone!
CoIumbus! We're on
hoIiday! Find us an isIand to ceIebrate on!
HoIiday! HoIiday! IsIand
wanted! IsIand wanted!
CoIumbus! We're on
hoIiday! Find us an isIand to ceIebrate on!
HoIiday! HoIiday! IsIand
wanted! IsIand wanted!
Weekend romance mine
is! AII machines want to be humans!
No army! No weapons!
No poverty! No poIitics!
Can you find us an isIand
with no machines? CoIumbus!
Five days, we sIog away!
At the end, we appreciate nature!
Become the wind and
steaI away the trees and Iighten our hearts!
We'II become chiIdren
again by pIaying with the waves!
If a bird's wings are
avaiIabIe to rent, fIy away with them!
Birds have not passports!
FIy over aII continents!
Now is the time to reIax!
But it is not yet! Let us be Iike free fish!
2 Iegged fIowers are
apIenty! Become a Iover today itseIf!
Adorn her with waves!
GarIand with stringed stars!
If it aII be okay, then Iove
her!
Oh boy who wants to
waste time, just Iove away!
Live Iife for two days a
week at Ieast!
CoIumbus! We're on
hoIiday! Find us an isIand to ceIebrate on!
HoIiday! HoIiday! IsIand
wanted! IsIand wanted!
I wiII deIiver the staffs'
food. You deIiver to infIight services'.
Look carefuIIy. Where
did you keep the address? In my pocket!
Is he asking us to go
home? TeII him Sivasu's name! Let me do it then!
He's Iost it!
- Are you peopIe TamiIians?
Thank God for you.
Granny, pIease be quiet.
I'm Madhumita, my
brother Maadhesh and Granny.
We're here to get an op
performed for her.
He Iost my uncIe's
address here. The immigration's not aIIowing us.
Do not worry. I wiII take
care of it.
That's pickIes. This is
Indian cake. That's tamarind.
This .. show it to me.
Another side dish.
Why throw everything?!
- What is it?
TeII him these are my
pickIes and I eat them. He'II teII you!
They don't aIIow these in.
- I cannot Iive without pickIes.
TeII me what you want
and how much! I'II get it for you!
Stay here tiII we get out
and make sure we're safe pIease.
WaIk quickIy. Enough
sight-seeing. I'm doing that?
Why is this moving Iike
this? Be carefuI Granny.
WaIk quickIy! As if
you've never seen an airport before!
Where is he? He seems to
have gone reaIIy quickIy. SIow down.
There he is!
Don't shout away! At
Ieast I speak EngIish! Get him!
Gents' toiIet!
- Oh is this why he was rushing?
Go in and hoId on!
What? HoId on to him before he Ieaves!
You had to go urgentIy?
- TamiIian? Was I speaking in TeIegu?
What's your name?
Have you forgotten? Maadhesh!
Magesh?
Catch him quickIy! Come
quickIy! We're coming aIong!
SIown down. Oh no! He's
vanished again.
Where did you go?
You ran away and you ask us?!
Did you get our Madras
Iine? No, you try now.
I'II just be back now.
Where are you going?
There. So fast. Yes.
Where are you? A tamiI
famiIy got caught here at immigration.
I've heIped them. Look
for a Sivasubramaniam out there.
If he is not there, book a
cab. We'II track his address down.
They are in the Iounge
now. Can you come there?
It's my Ieader's name!
Say it correctIy once!
Did you get confused?
We're twins. I'm Visu. He's Ramu.
Both of you Iook
identicaI.
No wonder you went to
the bathroom ''twice''.
Everyone gets confused.
Ramu, did you see Sivasubramaniam?
There's no such person
outside. So I haiIed a cab instead.
Where wiII we go?
I've got the Madras Iine. Get his address.
He's cheated us such.
Scum!
He's not in town. He gave
us the address though.
Here's my card. My
numbers are here. Give me a caII anytime.
Which hospitaI are you
bringing her to?
ULA hospitaI. That's
where we study. We'II see you then.
We came trusting Sivasu!
What came upon him?!
In Madras, he sticks to
me! He didn't think about Iooking after me!
He not onIy didn't come
but is keeping us at a rented pIace!
Granny. PIease eat.
What is it? Oh no! Bread again!
I don't even have any
pickIes as they took it away!
What kind of a country is
this? I shouId have died at home!
Madhu! The pain is
kiIIing me! Dear!
You go and pay the fees.
When is the op?
- Day after tomorrow.
Sign here. Why?
MereIy a formaIity. Sign.
Why did you make me
sign? It's common at aII hospitaIs.
What do you mean? If
something goes wrong, they're not IiabIe,..
Are they saying it wiII
happen? - Not that.
Are they saying I wiII
die?I know. I wiII die. My death is near.
I wiII onIy Iive for today.
This is my Iast day aIive.
SmeII of medication,
doctors, band aids, machines
I do not wish to die
amongst these.
Bring me eIsewhere.
Anywhere. Movie, shops, beach!
I'II Iook at everything!
CIose my eyes tight and sIeep!
Then they can do
anything they want to me.
One must not onIy Iive
happiIy but die such too!
I don't wish to remain
here. Bring me out.
They're very strict here.
How can I? Do something! Anything!
If you refuse, I wiII die of
frustration before the op.
Sit down.
TeII me. What is it? I
need a smaII favour. CouId you come?
Can I come after cIass?
-Oh. How Iong wiII it be?
It Iooks urgent. Go with
her. I'II go to cIass. We'II discuss it.
Is it serious? In India
yes! Here, it's Iike chewing gum.
Don't worry. - I don't.
She does. She's restIess.
She doesn't Iike the
atmosphere and wants to go out.
They wiII not aIIow that.
- Yes they are very strict on that.
Even if we got out, we
know not the pIace or anyone eIse.
That's why I came to you
for heIp.
Come without being
scared.
Granny, saying bye?
- Don't bother. Come quickIy.
You said you'II show us
America? Is that aII it is?
Goodness! No Granny,
this is our hoteI.
WeIcome. This is my
father. Greetings.
She's Krishnaveni, this is
Madhumita and this is Maadhesh.
Maghesh? No!
Maadhesh! Is the op for him?
Why are you being
disrespectfuI? Let it be.
Your taste buds must be
dead. Sit down and eat first.
Enjoy one of our meaIs.
That wiII cure haIf your iIIness.
The food is heavy. Can
Granny eat aII of this?
She can eat anything.
They wiII deaI with it. Don't controI her.
Everything wiII be
superb. Enjoy yourseIf.
Great food. To digest this,
one must dance away!
Who's stopping you?
Dance! At this age? You're joking.
Indian woman are such.
Wish for it but never do it.
Here, 60 year oId women
dance baIIet!
Dance. Come on.
- No. Let me go.
I can't sing. I know how
to start her off. Come!
Come on friend! Come
and have some fun!
Come on friend! My oId
friend! WhistIe away IoudIy!
You are the epitome of
Iove! CIoser than Mother herseIf!
Even when oIder, I wish
to Iie on you as I did when young!
Hey Granny! My sweetie!
A beauty! Have some fun!
Come on friend! Come
and have some fun!
Come on friend! My oId
friend! WhistIe away IoudIy!
Wear Jeans! Adorn
Iipstick! CoIour your grey to hide age!
Oh my! What a joke! My
age has changed1
I'II diaI CIinton! TeII him
'I Love you' in a romantic way!
When asked who you are,
say not Miss WorId but Miss OId!
Come on friend! Come
and have some fun!
Come on friend! My oId
friend! WhistIe away IoudIy!
Dance foIk dance to
computerised music!
Sing our morning prayers
on MTV!
Wear a two piece and sun
bathe Granny!
Come and do a rice fIour
fIoor design at DisneyIand!
Set up a street side staII
and seII Indian doughnuts!
Come on friend! Come
and have some fun!
Come on friend! My oId
friend! WhistIe away IoudIy!
You are the epitome of
Iove! CIoser than Mother herseIf!
Even when oIder, I wish
to Iie on you as I did when young!
Come on friend! Come
and have some fun!
Come on friend! My oId
friend! WhistIe away IoudIy!
Don't worry. We're
praying for you. You'II be fine.
The op wiII take Iong. It's
a waste to wait here. I'II manage fine.
No. You need someone to
heIp. I'II Ieave .. Visu here with you.
I'II send you food through
Maadhesh. Come.
It's a compIicated op.
Despite the doctor's skiIIs,
the patient needs to have
the strength to survive it.
Granny is 60 and she onIy
has that much of strength in her.
She's aIive but she can't
taIk or sit up.
If cared for weII, she'II be
fine on the bed itseIf.
Granny! It's Madhu here!
Open your eyes and Iook at me!
TaIk to me! CaII out my
name! Granny.
Can you hear me? Can
you hear what I am saying?
Why is she Iike this Visu?
You said it's a great hospitaI! Look!
Was it wrong to come
here? We couId've stayed in Madras!
At Ieast for 6 months, she
wouId've been waIking at Ieast.
Why did this happen
Visu?
Mistake! I was wrong to
come! Look at me Granny!
What happened?
Idiots! They did the op wrongIy!
What are you saying?
Her tumour was on the right!
They did the op on the Ieft
side!
What are you saying?
You're mereIy a student! What do you know?
You did the op on the
wrong side of the brain!
He Iooked at another
patient's records and did the op!
You shouId not have
asked her in the operating theatre!
Your accent wouId make
Karishma Nichaani sound Iike her name!
How fair is it that you
take a nod from a frightened patient such?
How did the case sheet
change?
WiII apoIogising make her
waIk again?
I wiII aIso initate a Iawsuit
for the trauma to victim and famiIy.
Father, Granny's op is
over! She's fine now.
She speaks weII. She'II
soon be up and waIking.
Yes, she's very shy.
So I am getting an
identicaI wig for her.
We're aII fine. You don't
worry about anything.
I'II caII you Iater. I'II hang
up now.
What is this?
- 2 MiIIion doIIars.
I don't understand.
Compensation. The hospitaI's apoIogising.
They're seeking a
settIement out of court to avoid a Iawsuit.
But you getting Granny
back fine that's happiness!
Worth over a 100 miIIion
doIIars!
They're here! Get
them to be seated. I'm coming.
SmeIIs great. WeIcome!
- Back in the kitchen aIready?
How are you? Fine.
- Visu is.. here. How are you?
I'm fine. Ramu?
- Fine too. Junno, how are you?
I'm fine Granny!
Why struggIe such?
PIanning this! Not good at aII!
Everything is fine. Heart,
mind, body. AII thanks to you.
If not for you and your
kids, I'd be dead by now. I must do this.
We're Ieaving tomorrow.
I wish to cook for you at Ieast once!
Visu, here have more.
Ramu, how is the food?
I've never had such good
food before.
ShaII we pIay
Andhakshari? What is that?
A game of songs.
Who'II sing first? I wiII.
-But not the same song as Iast time!
She's a TamiI beauty, one
who Iaughs beautifuIIy to Iook Iike the moon!
With her beautifuI Iips,
she serves nectars with a Iowered head!
She's ended with the
aIphabet 'Ah'. You must begin with that.
Live as the bird does!
Dance Iike the waves!
On this same sky, on the
same soiI, we'II sing united!
It has yet again ended at
the aIphabet 'Ah'.
Dear Rakkamma cIap
your hands! Create a new song in a new tune!
Create a new rhythm!
Touch your beIoved's heart!
Set up a dais! Tie a rose
garIand for me!
PIace it on your beIoved's
shouIders! Make music through the night!
This wiII not be
acceptabIe! But what is there to stop this Iove?
Start a song with either
'Cha' or 'Chi'.
My young dearest, the
smaII ant is biting!
Without being with you,
every night it suffers!
The fIowers you bought
are not enough!
Come Muniamma! Come!
Both of us as a coupIe, come to beach!
The protector of my Iove!
Answer me oh Iover!
UnbearabIe wait!
It's Junno's turn. Start
with 'Che' or 'Cha'.
If I sing, you wiII aII stand
up.
We'II see if we run or
stand! Sing first!
I must start with 'Cha'
right?
We've come to the
airport. I'II say the usuaI.
Write to us when you're
home. But caII us first.
SureIy. I was to go in a
coffin. I waIk due to your sons.
Can I forget this? I am
not satisfied in thanking you.
I must bring you home
and care for you aII for a few months!
If the occasion arises, we
wiII come. You must. Junno, you too!
I wiII. Just get me a girI
Iike Madhu and I'II marry and settIe there.
Did you hear what Junno
said? No, what was it?
Have you forgotten us
aIready?
No, I feeI Iike I've Ieft
something behind.
No, everything's here.
- Yes, it is here indeed.
Madhu, go and get us the
boarding passes.
I need to teII you
something. Go on.
I didn't feeI anything
when I was with you.
Now that we are Ieaving, I
shouId say what's on my mind.
You're Visuanathan
right?- No, I am Ramamurthy.
Go on. No, I forgot
what I was coming to say!
Do you want to taIk to
Visu? Wait, I'II send him to you.
Madhu wants to taIk to
you. Go and see what it is.
I'm Visu. You had
wanted to taIk to me about something.
That is ,O
Why stare at me Iike a
viIIain? I am Sivasu UncIe!
Where's sister? There.
- Come Iet us go and see her.
Let me go! Idiot! Coming
weII after when you were supposed to!
Why did you come? To
send me off is it?!
I had urgent work and
went off to AIaska.
What was so urgent? As
compared to me?
It was fixed in advance.
PunctuaIity is important to me.
Is it right to forget your
word and forget gratitude?
Thanks to Nachiappan's
famiIy, we survived! Great heIp!
ShaII we take a group
photo?
If you don't mind, can
you take a photo for us?
Turn the camera around.
Don't just stand here. Go
to the security checks.
Come, it's getting Iate.
- Why are you rushing me now?
Are you expecting
someone eIse? No. Then go in.
One minute Granny.
Come!
Where did you go?
Everyone was Iooking for you!
You're tearing!
I do not know how to say
it. It was fine whiIe she was here.
Once she was Ieaving, my
heart shattered.
You're a fooI! You wasted
time from morning and cry now!
She's perfect. Don't
worry. We'II catch her before she Ieaves!
I'm back again. What
happened? My body is the probIem.
So I returned as quickIy
as I had Ieft.
My head is hurting again!
Just Iike before!
The doctor toId us to
canceI our trip. We caIIed Nachiappan!
I toId them to come here
and stay with us.
You said you fainted in
the airport. Yes.
But here you sound so
active in story teIIing! How?
I was happy to see the
boys. Now that you mention it,
The back of my head
hurts
Put Granny to sIeep.
We'II taIk in the morning.
Did I faint for you to sit
and stare at your hand?
I feIt faint so I fainted!
I am shocked in the joy
that she is back!
Do that Iater. TeII her
about your Iove first. Now?
Yes. Granny is with
her. How do I do it?
I'II take care of that.
At my age, I can onIy
faint. Can I say the ''I Iove you' too?
I'm Ramu! Visu wants to
taIk. CouId you come to the pooI?
I .. you ..
- I understand. Me too.
For me? For me?
- Are you just for me?
Oh Taj MahaI that weighs
fifty are you just for me?
The heavens that
descended from the fIight for me?
The moon in a packet
are you just for me?
The femaIe poem in the
teIax are you for me?
Can I adorn you? Can I
sIeep on your Iips?
O FIower! SmaII isIand!
Permit me to touch your waist!
Oh Taj MahaI that weighs
fifty are you just for me?
The heavens that
descended from the fIight for me?
ShaII we expIore America
on foot?
Spread a bIanket on the
ocean and expIore Europe!
To sing our Iove, as a
poem,..
Let's disturb SheIIy's and
Byron's resting peace.
You're jumping out of the
sky! Is this fun and ceIebration?
Impassioned, you bite the
air! The chiId is insane! What wiII be?
The wind is oId! The
earth is oId!
Eons may pass but Iove
does not get oId!
The wind toId the cherry
fIowers that it Ioved it!
The singing bird in the
Cyprus trees said it Ioves me!
Once you expressed your
Iove, the wind and bird wept!
FIowers yearn to be a part
of your hair shaII I put them on?
Rain comes to earth to be
your bath water shaII I be such too?
When the heart stops, Iife
stiII goes on for a few seconds!
Leave me and survive a
second more I wiII not!
Oh Taj MahaI that weighs
fifty are you just for me?
The heavens that
descended from the fIight for me?
The moon in a packet I
am for you!
The femaIe poem in the
teIax I am for you.
Can I adorn you? Can I
sIeep on your Iips?
ShaII we shower in kisses?
ShaII we use our hair to dry off?
O FIower! SmaII isIand!
Permit me to touch your waist!
4 if you win. 2 if you Iose.
Guess who is who between us!
You're wrong. I am
Ramu and he is Visu.
God have you no
compassion for me?
You won't get it in this
Iifetime! Your money wiII aII be mine!
PIease give me the money
. Why? To see it for a Iast time.
I feIt Iike taIking to you at
five in the morning.
I came to your room and
both of you were sIeeping.
I wanted to wake you up
but I didn't know who was who.
I was scared I wouId wake
Ramu up wrongIy. So I Ieft.
Who do you think I am
now? Why? Visu right?
No, I am Ramu. You
toId Juno you are Visu.
It was just a dupe. He
Ioses most of the time.
But sometimes, he gets
Iucky. We stiII wouId cheat him then!
The beauty is that you got
confused to. It's aIright. I'II send him.
Have you been waiting
Iong? No, onIy now.
I've bought you
something too.
It's very nice. For Ramu?
It's in different coIours.
Yes. I've been fooIed
twice today. It's so embarrassing.
I want to know who my
Visu is.
It's a habit of 21 years.
Neither I nor Ramu can do this.
Father neither. Do you
see my probIem?
What if I say the wrong
things to Ramu thinking it's you?
That's where you wrong.
He'II point it out immediateIy.
Just for a whiIe. Can't
you heIp me tiII I can see the difference?
It's not fair to make us
change a habit of many years.
So what if he does not
take the outfits?
Is there no other way for
there to be a difference?
I'II fracture Ramu's hand
with one hit!
The one with the cast is
Ramu; the other, your Ramu!
What kind of idea is this?
Breaking Iimbs indeed! Lunatic!
They do not understand
young brains!
Do not Iook so upset my
dear.
Once you get cIose, you'II
know who your guy is.
I can't get cIose. I am just
too scared I'II see Ramu as Visu.
So I can't watch or speak
to him weII.
When I can't watch or
speak, how do I get cIose?
Stop caIIing me a Iunatic,
haIf baked nut and so on!
I've changed the tactic.
You just need a difference between them?
I've an idea that wiII
differentiate them for 6 months at Ieast.
OIder brother on the Ieft
and younger brother on the right.
Why were you trying to
shave my son's hair?
Madhu couId not
differentiate between them!
Why must she teII the
difference? Because ..
Don't bIabber! Madhu
and Visu Iove each other!
You came as you were
unweII. Once fine, Ieave.
Don't bring up the topics
of Iove and marriage here.
Why? They both Iove
each other! And so I came to taIk about it!
I have the right to decide
for them. I refuse to Iet this wedding be!
Why not? Does she not
Iook good, have education and aII?
Not about that. Is it
caste? - No, not that either.
Have you decided she's
immoraI as she feII in Iove?
Your girI is amazing! But
I cannot accept it!
Are you just opposing Iike
other because they've Ioved each other?
I do have a reason to
oppose!
I too am a twin. Siamese
twin.
4 idIis, 2 mutton chops, 2
fishes, 2 drinks.
Give me 8 and haIf
rupees.
That's wrong brother. It's
-9 and haIf rupees.
Is that so? Then as sister-
in-Iaw says, it's 9 and haIf!
Your eIder brother sIogs
so hard in the kitchen!
If you Iose one rupee per
head, it's the end of the shop.
You've eaten! We didn't
cheat you right? Just Ieave!
Must you be such that
customers mock you?
Can't you be carefuI with
regard to these smaII caIcuIations?
What has happened? He
just said it as a rupee Iess. Is it a crime?
My husband is a boss too!
Not your hired servant!
I didn't shout at him.
You toId him to be better!
If you teII a maIe that,
what wiII the peopIe think of him?
What have I said that you
are yeIIing such now?
If you have to say it, say it
through your husband! Not by yourseIf!
Respect your brother-
in-Iaw. It's but a smaII issue
They'II start with this and
pick on everything that you do!
Soon, she'II make you her
sIave and ride on your back!
What is this? If there's
yeIIing aII day, wouId the shop do weII?
Or wouId the famiIy do
weII?
As if they run everything
and aII we do is ruin it and be Ieeches!
You're out of Iine!
WouId you rather I
remain quiet Iike him?
Don't taIk to brother Iike
that. He's my God.
To a femaIe, her husband
is God.
Why shouId I keep quiet
if one insuIts you in front of me?!
I won't speak anymore.
Just Iet me be.
Give you an inch and
you'II take a yard.
Both of you go in. Go and
do the work.
I am useIess. I can't even
do simpIe addition.
I cause the fights at home
too. I do not know what to do.
You're my brother. I care
not how you are.
But I cannot bear your
tears. Wipe your tears and go on.
I'II take my Ieave. It
feeIs weird. My abdomen's churning.
I might give birth this
afternoon.
ShaII I stay on? You'II
need heIp. I'II Iet brother buy the things!
No, don't. He won't know
how to buy the right things.
They'II seII him oId goats
and sick chickens.
He wiII forget something
and we must go there again.
You go ahead. I'II be
back soon.
CouId you come here?
- What is it?
My throat is parched.
CouId you get me a soda drink?
I'II do it now! Stop!
Where are you running to Iike a dog?
To get a soda You
can't buy goats or chickens but this, you can?
Draw water for me, I
need to wash up. Ask her to go if she wants!
Don't say that. She says
she does not feeI weII.
AII of it is a drama! When
pregnant, everyone wouId want to sit!
Go do something eIse.
Why make such a fuss
over me heIping a pregnant woman?
Do you heIp because she's
pregnant or because she's pretty?
Don't be so mean! You're
a woman and shouId understand.
She's seduced you indeed!
One maIe is not enough!
A husband to cook and a
brother-in-Iaw on the side Iines!
That's why you can't bear
her pain!
Stop it! ScoId me Iater!
I'II go and get the drink first!
Take one more step and
I'II remove my nuptiaI string!
No one needs to remove
anything. I'II get the drink myseIf.
I can't bear anything any
more. Don't speak such again!
My beIoved daughter!
You've Ieft me and gone!
Your wife has died!
I kiIIed her! I Iistened to
my wife and kiIIed her!
She asked for a drink!
For that, my wife fought and spoke harshIy,
She did not die of
chiIdbirth! She had seIf pride!
She died due to the words
thrown at her!
She died because she did
not want to face the deviI I married!
Look! I've rendered them
motherIess!
KiII me! Hack me! Even
grass won't grow where I am buried!
KiII me for this crime!
Both are identicaI! How
couId she bear to Ieave them behind?
It's enough! Marrying my
daughter to you!
And have your brother
and his wife kiII her!
You've kiIIed my
daughter. Give me these twins, I'II bring them up!
WouId this woman who
kiIIed my daughter bring them up?
Enough! I've had enough!
Get up! Is it your wife
who has died now? Why Iook so sad?!
Strangers IabeI us
murderers and I must keep quiet?!
Who are you caIIing
names? Just keep quiet!
We can run a shop under
a tree and stiII Iive with pride.
We don't need this house.
Come out! Ask for your share!
SpIit the shop! Is this
the pIace to taIk? Brother is broken.
Why stiII cannot bear to
Ieave your brother?
Do you want to Iook after
the babies and sing IuIIabies?
You heIped her aII the
time when she Iived!
Now, you wish to wash,
feed and cIean her young ones!
If the chiIdren are hurt
accidentaIIy, we'd be bIamed for that too!
No need! Ask for your
share of the weaIth!
I can't Ieave my brother
and come! I won't oppose him!
Then Iet me go! I'd rather
be another's mistress than your wife!
If that is your decision, go
ahead!
What is this? Who taught
you this?! Doing it aII the time!
A good famiIy shouId not
be such.
What do you want? The
shop, house and weaIth? Keep it! AII!
Just because she asks you
wish to give?! She shouId not get a penny!
Let her go to heII brother!
Marriage is not to break
up! But to compromise! That's Iife!
For as Iong as I Iive, our
shop must not spIit. Nor must your famiIy!
How wiII he bring up
these two kids aII aIone?
Brother don't Ieave me!
- The famiIy is shattering now!
God! Brother don't
Ieave me!
You twins shouId have
married sisters!
They wouId have Iived
happiIy together and been fine.
You didn't Iisten to me!
You are orphaned now!
Brother do not Ieave me!
I Iive happiIy in weaIth
here! But my brother is suffering back there!
This was because we
married girIs of different famiIies!
That won't happen again!
I decided then that my sons ..
wiII marry twin sisters
onIy!
There is no change in
that!
Oh god! I did not expect
that my probIem wouId be soIved such!
What do you mean?
You've articuIated my concerns too!
My granddaughter
Madhu is a twin too!
Sounds Iike a fiIm story.
- Life is from cinema and vice-versa.
Fact can be stranger than
fiction sometimes.
When her mom was
pregnant, her stomach was very big.
Her dad is an astroIogy
fanatic. The astroIoger said its twins!
AIso that whiIe twin boys
bring Iuck, twin girIs shorten his Iife to 40!
Her father's a vioIent
man and waIked around with a machete!
As we feared both were
born girIs! In fear of one's Iife,
I gave one girI to our cook
with a Iot of money and toId him ..
.. to bring her up tiII her
father reached 40.
Her name is Vaishnavi.
Her younger sister. Studying in KodaikaanaI.
How do I beIieve this?
- One minute!
I swear upon this
camphor that it be true!
TeII me now. Do you
agree to this marriage?
The moment you swore
she's a twin, I agreed immediateIy!
What's the other girI's
name? Vaishnavi.
What? Madhu is not a
twin! You scheming oId woman!
Shut up and keep quiet
you fooI!
What do you mean? I am
not a twin?
No. EIders say you can
teII a thousand Iies to hoId a wedding.
What have you done?
What a huge Iie! Where wiII this Iead to?
Another Iie wiII end it!
Finish your wedding first.
Then say that the young
girI had died of jaundice!
Or say she ran off with
someone and finish off the story!
Isn't that wrong? I
swore on camphor!
They're coming to see
that girI in India. Keep quiet tiII the wedding!
Hi Maadhesh! How are
you?
I am perfectIy aIright!
Thanks to these peopIe.
He's Mr Nachiappan. I
am VeIIaiappan. Let me go on.
My cIothes are white
(veIIai) as is my heart and bank account!
Because I do not know
how to Iie.
You're Visuanathan and
Ramamoorthy! I'm reaIIy gIad to see them.
Had I had twin girIs, I
wouId have married them to your twins!
What to do? I onIy have
one girI.
You had feared having
femaIe twins! Why say this now?
Why had I feared?
Had not he carried a
machete when she was pregnant?
Yes. Why is he saying
he'II get them married now?
Why did you carry a
machete? Yes, when did I do that?
You were waIking around
tensed when she was pregnant? Yes.
I was teIIing them stories
of that. That's aII. But the machete.
God heIp me! Mother,
that machete business ..
You had prayed to offer
to our god! That's what he's asking.
Don't confuse! I'II kiII
you! You said the machete was to kiII!
Now you have changed
the story. How?!
Keep quiet! My son does
not know about Vaishnavi at aII!
What if my son hears this
wrongIy and kiIIs Vaishnavi?
Then the wedding wiII
end! And we've never even seen her.
He does not know where
she is. Then how can he kiII her?
Be quiet! Do not be
disrespectfuI to eIders!
She says Vaishu wiII in
danger! So just be quiet. But ..
Keep quiet and come on
in.
WiII I never get food
again? Why?
You said Iiars starve! Not
even food. I'II die without a drop of coffee
Mocking me? But
you've said countIess Iies. AstroIger, twins..
I wiII not get even a drop
of water!
Shut up! She Ioves him!
We shouId get them together!
Nothing wrong in Iying a
bit for that. So teII me now.
How many daughters do
you have? One. No, two. Come on.
One if it is one. Two if it is
two. But one onIy is aIive.
Another couId have born.
Died then. Or born dead.
Or I couId not have
known. And someone eIse took her away.
One daughter for me and
one for my wife. It comes to two!
Even if you do not Iie, just
bIabber such and I wiII manage.
How about you? I can
Iie. Except on days when I am fasting.
Monday for Sivan,
Tuesday, Lord Murugan, Thurday, ..
For Rajini? No,
Ragavendhra. Same difference.
Friday for Durgai,
Saturday, for Vishnu, Sunday, for Mangadu.
Wednesday is free. I
can Iie on Wednesday.
But if fuII moons and
other dates cIash, I can't.
Why do you fast on so
many days? For your heaIth.
She'II even fire-waIk. Just
scared that you'II scoId.
Why does your wife Iove
me so much? Bring on the herbaI Ieaves!
Perform another fast for
the sake of your daughter's wedding.
What fast is it? SiIent
fast. Auntie? I toId you to keep quiet!
Why are you throwing
stones at me? What do you think?
You keep saying
Vaishnavi's coming. Where and who?!
What a question! You!
- Me? Yes, doubIe action!
Kidding? That's betrayaI
of trust! I cannot do it!
Go! Hug the sweet
wrappers, used batteries and cry!
Your dad wiII marry you
to another!
Think of another! And
romance your husband?
Isn't that a betrayaI of
trust? That's disgusting!
Why torture me? It's
not that. They want to see the other girI.
You'II just whiz in and
out for this.
Instead of suffering for
Iife away from your Ioved one,
Nothing wrong in acting
for a few days.
Look there's Vaishnavi!
You've grown so much!
Do you know me? I'm
your grandmother Krishnaveni! BIess me!
She's your second
daughter, Vaishnavi!
A second born is second.
Third born is third!
At the end, aII the
daughters are the same to me.
You beIieved astroIogy
and set me aside for so many years.
If not for the uncIe, what
wouId have happened to me by now?
Why mother? Did you not
Iove me at Ieast?
You are on a siIent fast!
You're not mute!
He's Mr Nachiappan, a
restaurant owner in the US.
How's the girI? Like the
Goddess of WeaIth!
This is Junno, his head
cook. Hi. Something is not right.
He just hit you. No. Her
fresh fIowers suggest that ..
she got on at the Iast
station and got down here.
Don't peopIe freshen up
one station before arriving?
She did this as she was
meeting everyone here.
This is my eIder son Visu.
He's studying medicine.
It's your sister that I am
going to be marrying. ReaIIy?
Great news brother-in-
Iaw. Where's my sister?
She decided to go to the
tempIe and pray for her safe return.
Who's this? Vaishu! I
am your younger brother, Maadhesh!
Me .. introduce me.
He's my younger son
Ramu, a twin just Iike you.
BeIoved! KiII me not!
Dearest! SteaI not my eyes!
ExpIode not my heart
with your smiIe!
Suck not my Iife in your
movements!
I Iooked at your sIim
waist! The Creator is stingy indeed!
I rose a bit and was
stunned! He is a phiIanthropist indeed!
A painting Ravivarman
did with captured Iightening!
A scuIpture which
craftsman did with much difficuIty!
Of aII the women born in
this soiI, you are the greatest beauty!
AII this beauty torturing
me together is painfuI!
BeIoved! KiII me not!
Dearest! SteaI not my eyes!
BIessed fIower! Speak of
her hair's fragrance!
BIessed river! Speak of
the joy of her bathing!
BIessed ankIets! Speak of
her feet's beauty!
BIessed pendants! Speak
of her chest's beauty!
I wiII fiII the moon with
oxygen and buiId you a house!
To protect your Iife, I'd
use my Iife to serve as an exchange!
I wiII bring down cIouds
to make you a bed and put you to sIeep.
When you perspire whiIe
sIeeping, with stars I wiII brush it off!
I wiII coIIect dew drops
for the fair bird to shower!
Those drops you've
showered with I'II drink as hoIy water!
BeIoved! KiII me not!
Dearest! SteaI not my eyes!
Superb acting! She's one
piIIar and you're another!
You even asked me who I
was! Give me your hand!
Nonsense! OnIy I know
what I am suffering every minute.
The oIder brother Visu is
knocking your room door!
Get changed quickIy!
What are you doing? Do something to buy time!
One minute. I'm coming.
- You go in.
You've been gone so Iong.
Didn't even come to the station?
I'd gone to the tempIe and
it was crowded. You were home before me.
Why are you speaking
with the Brahmin accent?
My sister's accent just
rubbed off onto me as we were speaking.
Leave that. Did you ask
her about Ramu? Does she Iike him?
She just came. We're
taIking about chiIdhood now.
Long way before we
discuss marriage.
So pIease do not disturb
me for a few days. PIease.
I'II go and taIk to her.
It's me Ramu. What are
you doing here?
She's bathing inside.
- Ramu wishes to taIk. Come quickIy.
I'II take at Ieast an hour
sister!
I'II wait. ShaII I caII you
once she comes.
Why? You go on. I can do
this.
Get out! A bunch of
desperate brothers!
You are? I am Ramu.
- Oh go on.
I spent a day shopping to
bring you aII of this!
This is used by aII the
heroines in HoIIywood.
Do you Iike it? You
must have spent a Iot of time on this.
No, if I may say
something. I do not use cosmetics.
Grean peas for face, dhaI
for the body and herbs for my hair.
That's aII. PIease do not
take offence and take these away.
So you don't Iike it.
Doctors in the US too
suggest herbaI products.
This was Madhu's toy,
bottIe cap, waist chain pendant,
her schooI badge, her
ankIets when young ..
And this container was
what she drunk miIk in.
I'm so embarrassed
Why? I had bought her a Iot of cosmetics.
She onIy uses herbaI
things. You did a stupid thing.
First go out aIone with
her and get to know each other better.
Bring her out aIone? I feeI
scared.
Is this the same person
who encouraged me on? Scared for yourseIf?
That's Iove. A joyous
torture! Suffer!
ShaII I teII you what your
favourite coIour is? Green. White.
Iucky number is? Seven! One.
No, I need to go.
- One minute.
ShaII I teII you who your
favourite actor is? KamaI! Rajini.
What can you teII from
this? You're mistaken about me.
Yes, because I do not
know anything about you. So?
We're going to Park
Sheraton tonight. Get to know each other!
Granny! Who's there? I
am coming!
Is it you? What is it?
Nothing much.
I caIIed her out aIone with
me to taIk. She panicked.
Is that it? Vaishu, go on
in. Is she American bred to come immediateIy?
Brought up traditionaIIy
here and is such!
She aIso wanted to go to
tempIe in the evening. She won't come!
Where are you going in
this outfit? To the tempIe.
Go on ahead. CaII
Vaishu, Granny. Why?
You said she's going to
the tempIe. So I'II accompany her. CaII her.
She won't come. Why?
- How can I teII you this? Why?
She won't come for a few
days. Try to understand. Why?!
These are Iadies'
probIems! Try to understand!
It's aIright. I wiII bring
her with me after 3 days then.
Granny said you're
suffering from women's probIem. What?
Oh God. So what now?
- Ladies don't Iike discussing this.
I know how a woman
suffers at this time. So I got you medicines.
I know you don't Iike
EngIish medicines. So I went herbaI too!
Take a handfuI of this
with warm water and your pain wiII ease!
what is this? Coconut
rice. No, I did not mean that.
You have your daughter
after 20 years but seem unhappy.
Any probIem? Yes
and no maybe.
Laughter impossibIe
during a probIem and soIves it not either!
Can one run from a
probIem and does that soIve a probIem?
A probIem means a big
thing to begin with.
You are out of the game
for speaking too much on ''probIems'' !
I'II ask her. What is is? -
I'm on a siIent fast and must be quiet.
But you are speaking!-
She's new to this and is Iearning the ruIes
What eIse? Parents tend
to be stressed with the chiId's wedding!
That's aII. Why don't you
Iaugh out Ioud sometimes son?
We're Iaughing but
she's not. PIease Iaugh.
She Iaughs Iike a viIIain.
By the way, Vaishnavi is
missing? She's unweII and resting.
What happened? Dad.
Keep quiet. These are Iadies' concerns.
Do you want some of
her curry? Granny! I want some of it!
Why are you eating off
my pIate?
It's an Indian tradition.
The wife eating off the husband's pIate.
It symboIises that you and
I are not separated from one another.
Vaishnavi's here.
- Madhumita's gone.
Sit next to Ramu.
Your uncIe's said it. Sit down.
Eat weII. Do not be shy.
Serve yourseIf, I'II come soon.
How's the stomach pain?
- It's okay.
It's an Indian tradition.
The wife eating off the husband's pIate.
It symboIises that you and
I are not separated from one another.
Sorry I spun it around too
fast. What happened? The saIt spiIIed!
It happens! Come, Iet me
get you a new pIate instead.
Madhu, where's
Vaishnavi? She's resting in her room.
I onIy see either of you.
Never seen both of you together!
Wait, Iet me go and get
Vaishnavi now.
Why are you going to
disturb one who's resting?
He just wishes to see both
his daughter-in-Iaws together. Why not?
Nothing wrong. Tonight,
they wiII sing for you together.
Why, they wiII even dance
together!
I bought this reaI time
animation computer in the US!
I've Vaish's image here!
This wiring sends my movements to it!
Now the Vaishnavi in the
computer wiII do aII that I do.
I wiII use the projector to
create a hoIogram on stage!
Everything the eye sees
my Lord, does not beIong to the eyes!
But as you are a part of
my eye, you wiII not Ieave my gaze! Or me!
The Ianguage of TamiI
has coupIet words does it not?
It is not fair to separate
them! No meanings they carry then!
Together they are! Both
are but one!
Night and Iight we have
but the day itseIf is one entity!
Two Iegs one may have
the journey is onIy one though!
Two hearts may be
invoIved the Iove is onIy one though!
Everything the eye sees
my Lord, does not beIong to the eyes!
A bird which is a twin
that Iives together wiII not separate!
Eyes are Iike twins one
cries and the other pours!
Do you understand? Do
not pour away!
In one's sIeep we carry
each other's dreams!
In one's breathing, we
carry each other's Iives!
OnIy for sustenance, do
we exist separateIy!
Everything the eye sees
my Lord!
my Lord, does not beIong to the eyes!
But as you are a part of
my eye, you wiII not Ieave my gaze! Or me!
Come! Come! What is
this? Why have you become such?
Leave that! How are you?
- After a Iong time, I am happy again!
Didn't Sundram come
with you? She didn't come.
She hasn't changed.
MereIy gotten worse.
First caII your sons! I
want to see them!
BIess us UncIe.
- May you Iive as Kings.
Between Visu, the oIder
son of Karaikudi's Nachiappan, and
Madhumita, the oIder
daughter of VeIIaiappan,
and between Ramu, the
younger son of Nachiappan, and
and between Vaishnavi,
the younger daughter of VeIIaiappan,
it is agreed to hoId the
marriage in the month of Thai,
wherein the first wedding
be in the first auspicious day and
the second wedding be on
the second auspicious day ..
One minute. Why is it
different days? HoId it together!
No! Then it is beIieved
onIy one of the two marriages does weII!
The two such marriages I
know did not do weII.
One has no chiId and
another husband is insane.
Were those the wedding
of twins? No.
Then why must you fear?
It was separate weddings that kiIIed my wife.
So for my chiIdren, both
the weddings must be heId together.
No change in that.
Rewrite the document.
Is the engagement over?
- Yes.
My wife and I are going
to Thirupathi to wash away our sins.
What .. He means the
sin of isoIating his daughter aII these years.
It couId be that or maybe
not. WouId God punish us then? Or Ieave us?
Stop it! I shouId have
kept the siIent fast instead of you.
Whose name is
Nachiappan? EIder brother's!
Debt is it? How much?
Why not just ask me about it?!
Money won't make this
right. She stiII hates you very much!
In her angst at being
chiIdIess, she became much more worse!
It's aIways fight! When I
decided to end it aII, I saw your Ietter!
I wanted to see you and
my sons before I die! I aIso saw their wives!
In that joy, I came to die
here!
This useIess being not
onIy can't Iive but is not even capabIe of dying!
I won't Iet you die! Who
eIse do I have but you and Sundram?
My chiIdren's wedding
wiII go on onIy if you & your wife come!
I wiII go as you to
Karaikudi for a whiIe!
I wiII correct her and
bring her here.
You stay here as
Nachiappan.
You're not just my
brother. You're God.
Whatever you do has to
be right.
You gave money to that
guy! Don't come after me for that.
Bring down those things!
- Get Iost!
I wiII kiII you! These are
my mother's gifts to me! CIear the shop!
I wiII not heIp that man
who ran away due to debt probIems!
Get everything that is
inside out!
PIease wait. Why? What
do I have to gain when aII is Iost?
If you can earn and
support me, send me a note.
Otherwise, forget your
pride and come to my mother!
My father feeds 4 dogs!
You can come and be the fifth!
Get the vehicIe moving.
Your Iottery ticket has
won a price!
Stop! Look here!
The poor man is so tired!
Get him a seat! Buy him a soda!
Just a whiIe ago, he was a
dog! Now he's rich, she's back here!
It's my husband! I'II act
as I wish. Doesn't your wife scoId you?!
Look! My scoIding has
brought you a good time.
Give me the ticket. I wiII
go and get the money.
If you go, they wiII give
you a pittance and cheat you.
If the money is with me,
I'II run the famiIy weII. I'II give you a bit daiIy.
No. I've written my name
to ensure no one cheats me. So I must go.
I'm your wife won't
they even give it to me?
If there's any troubIe, just
open this book and pretend to read it.
Which edition is this
encycIopaedia?
I came to thank you.
- What is it for?
Others buy winning chits
so as to convert bIack money to good.
He's changed the hoteI so
much in two days. Very smart indeed!
I am bad at accounts. So
I've given the job to you.
Do it weII and it's my job
to ensure you're treated comfortabIy.
Do you have engagement
rings in this design?
We're out of stock but
you can pIace an order for it.
Your name?
Ramamoorthy.
I can't bear Ramu!
Why? What is he doing?
He brought an
engagement ring and insists that I put it on!
I can't act as Vaishnavi
for even another minute!
You can't act as .. Don't
then!
From now on, you don't
need to do this.
You Ieave for home
tonight cIaiming exams as a pretext.
What do we do now?
- There are onIy two ways.
One,we get another
daughter ready.
Or we must change
Nachiappan's mind!
How do we do that?
- I wiII be discussing that with my friends!
Don't Iook for me. I wiII
come at the right time and finish this off!
Look, now you're doing
weII thanks to God.
But what is the use?
You're Ieft with no heir to care for you!
Marry this girI and she'II
give you four chiIdren at Ieast!
No one in my famiIy re-
marries. Even my brother did not!
Your brother has two
sons! You have none to do your rites!
It couId be due to me.
- Not possibIe. Your famiIy is not such!
When your brother has
kids, why can't you have them?
Your wife kiIIed his wife
without giving her a drink remember?
It's that sin that she's
paying for right now!
She's earned so much
curses that her womb is dead! No chance!
Who doesn't have fIaws?
I do! I can't cook! Or do accounts!
If she can Iive with aII of
that, why can't I Iive with her fIaw?
Look! I can have no heir
at aII but I wiII not betray my wife. Leave!
Come. It is this
compartment.
Fruits. Water. Everything
is here.
Here. For your reading.
I got rid of everyone
because I wanted to taIk to you.
But you don't speak at aII.
I Iike that siIence too.
You remind me of your
sister.
She too couId not teII my
brother of her Iove at the airport.
But fate got them
together. If you too Ieave such,
I wiII just die here. Do you
Iike me?
Or do you feeI that you're
being forced into this as you're a twin?
It's not Iike that right?
You do Iike me I hope?
SiIence represents
consent. It's not enough. Just teII me!
The train's moving but
our Iove is not getting anywhere.
Just teII me that you Iove
me! Just one word! PIease!
I don't wish to Ieave you!
ShaII I just come with you too?
PIease get off! I wiII write
to you aII my thoughts in a Ietter.
I get it. You can't taIk. So
you'd rather write! Fine! I'II Ieave !
Just write one cIear Iine!
That you Iove me!
I feeI Iike dying! Who's
Ramu? My brother-in-Iaw?
That's equaI to my chiId!
He's running around Iike a mad man now!
What wiII happen to him
if he knows she's not reaI?
If he does something to
himseIf, how wiII I be abIe to face Visu?
Rather than marry with
this web of Iies and deceit over me,
I am going to faII at their
feet and teII them aII the truth!
After that if my Iove has
the strength, Iet it survive!
What are you saying?
Ruining everything at this juncture?
Your roIe is over! You
won't cheat him anymore!
When your wedding is
over, I'II faII at Ramu's feet ..
and teII him I did this for
your sake and beg his forgiveness!
I'II faII at everyone's feet!
- Does apoIogising make it aII right?
I can't! Go! TeII them
aII! I wiII just die in this train itseIf!
Go ahead! As if I am
going to Iive after teIIing them the truth!
Isn't this Maadhesh's
room? What are you doing here?
This is a great PC. When
Madhu and Vaishnavi were dancing,
Maadhesh was dancing
away with this computer!
I want to dance too but I
can't find the right switch. Try find it.
Put this aII away and
come. I'II try it one Iast time.
You're going to get into
troubIe.
Hey Vaish! Look! She's
doing everything that I'm doing.
You have nothing better
to do!
Hey Madhu! Give a pose!
- Stop it Maadhesh! At Ieast a hand gesture!
I understand your anger!
I came to teII you the truth now!
What truth?! You'II teII
yet another Iie! Do I Iook Iike an idiot?!
PIease Iisten to me!
- Stop it! What harm did I do to you?
I Ioved you so much! And
you did this in return for that!
Let me taIk! I was a
fooI! I Ioved you! What about my brother?!
You brought him here
and cheated him and made a fooI of him!
Don't be angry! She's not
at fauIt! I was the one who Iied about it!
I aIso made her act as
Vaishnavi!
ScoId me! Hit me with
your shoe and I'II take it! Stop it!
What kind of Iady are
you? You sicken me! AII Iies!
For aII the heIp we gave
you, you've made fooIs of my famiIy!
I had no intention to
harm anyone! PIease beIieve me!
You swore upon God and
Iied! How can I beIieve you?!
He's a young boy and he's
angry and so speaks such!
You'd said you'II onIy
marry them off to twins and ..
I didn't want them to
break up. So at that time, I Iied!
AII I said were Iies! I aIso
cheated! I'II faII at your feet!
PIease carry out their
wedding.
Dad, move away. She may
just trip you whiIe begging your pardon!
Don't trust her! It's aII
Iies! AII a drama! FamiIy of frauds!
Come father! Let us go!
I've known you since
young. You've never Iooked so sad. Eat.
If you starve, your granny
wiII kiII me. PIease eat. No, Joseph.
We'II take two days to
return. ShaII I turn the boat back?
It's aIright. I've been
hurt. I don't want to see anyone.
If you don't mind me
asking, is it faiIure in Iove?
Liking someone is aIways
troubIe!
One who burned my
smiIe! One who toId me hug tears!
My earth is now thorns!
My air is now poisoned!
My Iife! Eat not my body!
My dearest eyes! Leave not my face!
If truth becomes a Iie,
what does the Iie become?
WiII a Iove of Iies Iive on?
Don't go in! The waves
are strong! Two peopIe died yesterday!
Go back to the shore! I'II
take care of this.
You made me cry!
Why? Scared I'd commit suicide?
I'm past that. You are
scaring me. I want my oId Ramu back.
Come Iet's go to US. I
don't want this country at aII.
Why Iie that you want to
Ieave your Iife here and go?
There's no change in my
decision for now.
Why do you insist on it?
Brother can't marry another and be happy!
If he's not happy, I won't
be. Then you won't be happy either!
Do you want to bury our
happiness and Iive with your principIes?
TeII me! Whatever it is,
wait for brother to come. We'II discuss it.
Why must your brother
come to decide your kids' weddings?
He is the cause of aII these
probIems!
If he had been smart, this
probIem wouId not have arisen.
If his wife was a good
Iady, your famiIy wouId not have spIit.
Just because he and his
wife are such, why ruin our Iives?!
Enough!
I'II get her married to
you.
But not at the fixed date.
As quickIy as possibIe. Why?
Let this wedding be over
before I change my mind.
PIease Iisten to me!
PIease Iisten to me! Did
you Iisten me?!
I begged you the same
way! I cried so much!
Without Iistening, you
caIIed me a fraud and traitor!
Now he's here! Get Iost!
- Yes! I am in that same position now!
Won't you understand
and accept me?
Fruits within a fIower
miracIe! CoIours on a butterfIy miracIe!
Accompanying wind
becomes music miracIe!
The song of a teacher-Iess
songbird miracIe!
You my miracIe which
astounds miracIes themseIves!
Love which came before
the stones, sand and sea a miracIe!
Love that strikes when
one is but onIy of sixteen years a miracIe!
Fruits within a fIower
miracIe! CoIours on a butterfIy miracIe!
Accompanying wind
becomes music miracIe!
The song of a teacher-Iess
songbird miracIe!
You my miracIe which
astounds miracIes themseIves!
Fragrant fIowers on an
odourIess branch fragrance is a miracIe!
CIouds of rain water
carry not a drop of saIt rain is a miracIe!
Fire fIies which Iight up
without eIectricity yet another miracIe!
Where in our being is
there Iife? Where in our Iive is there Iove?
As you think about it, it
too is a miracIe!
Love which came before
the stones, sand and sea a miracIe!
Love that strikes when
one is but onIy of sixteen years a miracIe!
Fruits within a fIower
miracIe! CoIours on a butterfIy miracIe!
Accompanying wind
becomes music miracIe!
The song of a teacher-Iess
songbird miracIe!
You my miracIe which
astounds miracIes themseIves!
An isIand of feminity
works on two Iegs you are my miracIe!
There are not seven
wonders in this worId you be the eighth!
Eyes that are the sky;
cheeks which drip honey;
Like a fIower you are a
miracIe!
The young Iady's fingers
a miracIe! NaiIs which crown a miracIe!
The way she moves yet
another miracIe!
Love which came before
the stones, sand and sea a miracIe!
Love that strikes when
one is but onIy of sixteen years a miracIe!
Fruits within a fIower
miracIe! CoIours on a butterfIy miracIe!
Accompanying wind
becomes music miracIe!
The song of a teacher-Iess
songbird miracIe!
You my miracIe which
astounds miracIes themseIves!
Do you know something?
Brother is here! I even met him.
ReaIIy? Such an
important thing and you say it such!
His sons are getting
married in Madras.
He's scared to come in
person as you might fight yet again.
I am yearning for
reIations now. What nonsense is this?
AII our years of troubIe
has fIown away!
Someone from Madras
has come to visit you!
WeIcome! Who is
this? Our daughter-in-Iaws' brother!
Why is he here now?
You may have won money
but onIy a miIIionaire!
Your enemy, that
Nachiappan is a biIIionaire!
You too must go to
America, compete with him, become rich!
That's why I am here.
Listen to me and I'II do aII of this!
No, we're .. Just stop
with taking orders in the restaurant.
His brother insists on
having twins for daughter-in-Iaws!
That's the probIem! My
sister is not reaIIy a twin!
If toId this, he won't
agree. And the son won't agree to marry!
The onIy way to deaI with
it! Impersonation!
If your husband comes as
his brother, the wedding wiII happen!
Then what about
Nachiappan? One hit! He's out!
Lock him in the room and
Iet him out when the wedding's over!
ShameIess dog! Ideas to
break up my famiIy?! How dare you?!
Let him go! I'II taIk to her
and make her understand.
I wiII kiII him! If we
chase him, he wiII mess things up there.
We'II do as he says and
get him into troubIe with brother!
Everyone's Iooking for
you since it is time for the wedding!
For who? For Madhu!
At 10:30 this morning!
Who's the groom? The
oIder son of your brother!
We were so worried! GIad
to see you! Is this your wife? WeIcome!
Where had you gone?
You Iook so ugIy! Go on in! Bring her in.
Come in. Where's
brother? He was just here somewhere.
Don't waste time! Watch
the stove! Ladies pIease prepare it aII!
What's going on? Who
gave permission for this wedding?
Isn't it because of me?
Change your outfit first!
She's pretty just Iike her
mother!
Don't mock me.
Brother don't!
Visu, get down!
What is this? Why ask
him to get down?
Did we do something
wrong? Or not weIcome you weII?
I've said it since start that
I want onIy twins for their wives!
But your daughter is not
one! You cheated me into this wedding!
Why is this happening
again? You had agreed to this too!
Who agreed? Don't!
What's wrong? You'd
said that we shouId hoId this wedding!
Isn't it because of you
that we caIIed the wedding forward?
Look! Your son says
you'd agreed to this wedding!
What do we do if you
refuse now?
I'd agreed that day but I
say we must stop it now!
What are you saying?!
Are you joking?!
Didn't you Iie? Cheat us
and fooI us? How much it hurt!
You must know that pain!
You must suffer it too!
So I pretended to agree
that day! Come down!
Don't! - Go on. This
won't work. We've made a mistake!
We must pay for this.
Everything is over!
Stop! PIease stop!
Why do you insist on this
issue? Because you have two sons?
From now on, you onIy
have one son! I wiII go and die now!
Why must you die? Who
is he to stop this wedding?
Is this man reaIIy our
father? He's a fraud! CriminaI!
How dare you! Do you
know his diIemma now?
Shut up! Don't be hasty.
Be quiet.
Father never agreed to
this wedding.
You can kiII me! You're
doing this to save my famiIy!
Even if my famiIy spIits,
you and your chiIdren must not!
I'II say it now. He didn't
agree to this wedding! I did it!
He was not in town tiII
yesterday!
I was in his disguise and
agreed to this wedding!
So you came as my
husband there?! Are you human?!
How can a woman Iive
not knowing who her husband is?!
AII this whiIe I was
senseIess and threatened to remove this!
Now I'II say it! Rather
than not know who's wife I am,
I'd rather remove this
and be without a husband!
Stop it! Why do you
torture me with this Iine?
What harm did I do to
you? Despite knowing I did you good,
Why focus on my
pretending and insist on Ieaving?!
Aren't you being
stubborn in insisting on the twins?
You can act to correct me
but she can't act to get the guy she Ioves?
You Iied for your brother
but she can't do it for her grandchiId?
Are you and them to be
judged on differing vaIue systems?
If what you did was for
good, then what they did is for good too!
If what you did was right,
so were they!
If they're wrong, then so
are you!
If you were right, my
husband and I wiII stay and bIess them!
If you were wrong, I wiII
remove this and go off!
TiII our chiIdren do not
faII in Iove we can act for them.
But once there's Iove,
their Iife is in their hands!
It's not fair to transfer
our Iife onto theirs.
Isn't Iife about
compromise? Look at your sons
They compomise so weII.
Nothing wrong in giving in to them.