Jeff Wayne's Musical Version
of H.G. Wells
THE WAR OF THE WORLDS
Mars is incapable of sustaining life.
Our efforts to sustain the
biosphere are exhausted.
The water tables and tempratures
decrease annually as does our
population.
The only consequential course
of action is the conquest
and occupation of Earth,
our young, sunward neighbour.
Earth is abundant with life
and resources are bountiful.
The environment will seem
uncomfortable but not inhibitive.
The problem is of course the humans.
They have developed primitive
intelligence.
Yet, their society is structured
around perpetual conquest
and conflict.
A rapid offensive to their
social and economic heart,
should prevent any significant
opposition.
The means and methods for this
attack are already being realised.
A large scale hydrogen accelerator
will be constructed.
This will launch suspension pods
carrying the assault forces.
Part one: The Coming of the Martians
No one would have believed, in
the last years of the 19th century,
that human affairs were being watched
from the timeless worlds of space.
No one could have dreamed that
we were being scrutinized
as someone with a microscope studies
creatures that swarm
and multiply in a drop of water.
Few men even considered the
possibility of life on other planets.
And yet, across the gulf of space,
minds immeasurably superior to ours
regarded this earth with
envious eyes,
and slowly and surely, they drew
their plans against us.
At midnight, on the 12th of August,
a huge mass of luminous gas
erupted from Mars and sped towards
Earth.
Across two hundred million miles of
void, invisibly hurtling towards us,
came the first of the missiles
that were to bring so
much calamity to Earth.
As I watched, there was another
jet of gas.
It was another missile, starting
on its way.
And that's how it was for the next
ten nights.
A flare, spurting out from Mars.
Bright green, drawing a green mist
behind it;
a beautiful, but somehow disturbing
sight.
Ogilby, the astronomer, assured me
we were in no danger.
He was convinced there could be
no living thing
on that remote,forbidding planet.
The chances of anything coming
from Mars
Are a million to one, he said
The chances of anything coming
from Mars
Are a million to one, but still,
they come...
Then came the night the first missile
approached Earth.
It was thought to be an ordinary
falling star,
but next day there was a huge crater
in the middle of the common,
and Ogilby came to examine what
lay there.
A cylinder, thirty yards across,
glowing hot, with faint sounds
of movement coming from within.
Suddenly the top began moving:
rotating, unscrewing;
and Ogilby feared there was a man
inside trying to escape.
He rushed to the cylinder but
the intense heat stopped him
before he could burn himself
on the metal.
The chances of anything coming
from Mars
Are a million to one, he said
The chances of anything coming
from Mars
Are a million to one, but still,
they come...
Yes, the chances of anything coming
from Mars
Are a million to one, he said
The chances of anything coming
from Mars
Are a million to one, but still,
they come...
It seems totally incredible to me now
that everyone spent that evening
as though it were just like
any other.
From the railway station came the
sound of shunting trains,
ringing and rumbling, softened almost
into melody by the distance.
It all seemed so safe and tranquil.
Next morning a crowd gathered
on the common,
hypnotized by the unscrewing
of the cylinder.
Two feet of shining screw
projected when suddenly,
the lid fell off.
Two luminous, disk-like eyes
appeared above the rim.
A huge rounded bulk, larger
than a bear, rose up slowly,
glistening like wet leather.
Its lipless mouth quivered and
slathered, and snakelike tentacles
writhed as the clumsy body
heaved and pulsated.
A few young men crept closer
to the pit.
A tall funnel rose and an invisible
ray of heat leapt from man to man,
and there was a bright glare as
each was instantly turned to fire.
Every tree and bush became a mass
of flames at the touch of this
savage, unearthly heat ray.
People clawed their way off the
common, and I ran too.
I felt I was being toyed with,
that when I was on the very verge
of safety this mysterious death would
leap after me and strike me down.
At last I reached Maybury Hill, and
in the dim coolness of my home
I wrote an account for my
newspaper
before I sank into a
, haunted sleep.
I awoke to alien sounds of
hammering from the pit
and hurried to the railway station
to buy the paper.
Around me, the daily routine of life,
working, eating, sleeping,
was continuing serenely as it had
for countless years.
On Horsell Common,
the Martians continued
hammering and stirring, sleepless,
indefatigable, at work on the
machines they were making.
Now and again a light like the beam
of a warship's searchlight
would sweep the common, and the heat
ray was ready to follow.
In the afternoon, a company of
soldiers came through
and deployed along the common
to form a cordon.
That evening, there was a violent
crash and I realized with horror
that my home was within range
of the Martian's heat ray.
At dawn, a falling star with
a trail of green mist
landed with a flash like summer
lightning.
This was the second cylinder.
The hammering from the pit and
the pounding of guns grew louder.
My fear rose at the sound of
someone creeping into the house.
Then I saw it was a young
artilleryman,
weary, streaked with blood
and dirt.
Anyone here?
-Come in. Here, drink this.
Thank you.
-What's happened?
They wiped us out. Hundreds dead,
maybe thousands.
The heat ray?
-The Martians.
They were inside the hoods of
machines they'd made,
massive metal things on legs.
Giant machines that walked.
They attacked us.
They wiped us out.
Machines?
-Fighting machines,
picking up men and bashing
them against trees.
Just hunks of metal, but they knew
exactly what they were doing.
Hmm. There was another cylinder
came last night.
Yes. Yes, it looked bound for London.
London! Carrie! I hadn't dreamed
there could be danger
to Carrie and her father,
so many miles away.
I must go to London at once.
And me, got to report to
headquarters,
if there's anything left of it.
At Byfleet, we came upon an inn,
but it was deserted.
Is everybody dead?
-Not everybody, look...
Six cannons with gunners
standing by.
Bows and arrows against the
lightning.
They haven't seen the heat ray yet.
We hurried along the road to
Weybridge.
Suddenly, there was a heavy
explosion.
The Ground heaved,
windows shatterd
and gusts of smoke erupted
into the air.
Look! There they are!
What did I tell you!
Quickly, one after the other, four
of the fighting machines appeared.
Monstrous tripods, higher than
the tallest steeple,
striding over the pine trees
and smashing them,
walking engines of glittering metal.
Each carried a huge funnel
and I realized with horror
that I'd seen this awful thing
before.
A fifth machine
appeared on the far bank.
It raised itself to full height,
flourished the funnel high
in the air,
and the ghostly terrible
heat ray struck the town.
As it struck, all five fighting
machines exulted,
emitting deafening howls which
roared like thunder.
The six guns we had seen
now fired simultaneously,
decapitating a fighting machine.
The Martian inside the hood was
slain, splashed to the four winds,
and the body, nothing now but an
intricate device of metal,
went whirling to destruction.
As the other monsters advanced,
people ran away blindly,
the artilleryman among them,
but I jumped into the water
and hid until forced up to breathe.
Now the guns spoke again,
but this time the heat ray
sent them to oblivion.
With a white flash the heat ray
swept across the river.
Scalded, half blinded and agonized,
I staggered through leaping,
hissing water towards the shore.
I fell in full sight of the Martians,
expecting nothing but death.
The foot of a fighting machine
came down close to my head,
then lifted again as the four
Martians carried away the debris
of their fallen comrade, and I
realized that by a miracle,
I had escaped.
For three days I fought my way
along roads packed with refugees,
the homeless, burdened with boxes
and bundles containing their
valuables.
All that was of value to me was
in London.
By the time I reached their
little red brick house,
Carrie and her father were gone.
The summer sun is fading as the
year grows old,
And darker days are drawing near,
The winter winds will be much colder,
Now you're not here.
I watch the birds fly south
across the autumn sky
And one by one they disappear,
I wish that I was flying with them
Now you're not here.
Like the sun through the trees
you came to love me,
Like a leaf on a breeze
you blew away...
Through autumn's golden gown
we used to kick our way,
You always loved this time of year
Those fallen leaves lie undisturbed
now
Cause you're not here
Fire suddenly leapt from house
to house.
The population panicked and ran,
and I was swept along with them,
aimless and lost without Carrie.
Finally, I headed eastward
for the ocean
and my only hope of survival:
a boat out of England.
Like the sun through the trees
you came to love me,
Like a leaf on the breeze you
blew away...
A gentle rain falls softly on
my weary eyes
As if to hide a lonely tear
My life will be forever autumn,
Cause you're not here
As I hastened through Covent Garden,
Blackfriars and Billingsgate,
more and more people joined
the painful exodus.
Sad, weary women, their children
stumbling in the street with tears,
their men bitter and angry,
the rich rubbing shoulders
with beggars and outcasts.
Dogs snarled and whined, the horse's
bits were covered with foam,
and here and there were wounded
soldiers, as helpless as the rest.
We saw tripods wading up the Thames,
cutting through bridges
as though they were paper.
Waterloo bridge, Westminster bridge,
one appeared above Big Ben.
Never before in the history
of the world,
had such a mass of human beings
moved and suffered together.
This was no disciplined march,
it was a stampede,
without order and without a goal,
six million people unarmed
and unprovisioned driving headlong.
It was the beginning of the
rout of civilization,
of the massacre of mankind.
A vast crowd buffeted me towards
the already packed steamer.
I looked up enviously at those
safely on board...
straight into the eyes of my
beloved Carrie.
At sight of me she began to fight
her way along the packed deck
to the gangplank.
At that very moment, it was raised,
and I caught a last glimpse
of her despairing face as the crowd
swept me away from her.
Like the sun through the trees
you came to love me,
Like a leaf on a breeze
you blew away...
Through autumn's golden gown
we used to kick our way
You always loved this time of year
Those fallen leaves lie undisturbed
now
Cause you're not here
The steamer began to move slowly
away, but on the landward horizon
appeared the silhouette of a
fighting machine.
Another came, and another, striding
over hills and trees,
plunging far out to sea and blocking
the exit of the steamer.
Between them lay the silent, gray,
ironclad Thunderchild.
Slowly it moved towards shore,
then with a deafening roar
and whoosh of spray it swung about
and drove at full speed towards
the waiting Martians.
There were ships of shapes and sizes,
Scattered out along the bay
And I thought I heard her calling,
As the steamer pulled away
The invaders must have seen them
As across the coast they filed
Standing firm between them,
There lay Thunderchild
Moving swiftly through the waters,
Cannons blazing as she came,
Brought a mighty metal warlord
Crashing down in sheets of flame,
Sensing victory was nearing,
Thinking fortune must have smiled,
People started cheering,
"Come on Thunderchild!
Come on Thunderchild!"
The Martians released their black
smoke, but the ship sped on,
cutting down one of the
tripod figures.
Instantly, the others raised
their heat rays,
and melted the Thunderchild's
valiant heart.
Lashing ropes and smashing timbers,
Flashing heat rays pierced the deck,
Dashing hopes for our deliverance,
As we watched the sinking wreck,
With the smoke of battle clearing,
Over graves and waves defiled,
Slowly disappearing,
farewell Thunderchild!
Farewell Thunderchild!
Farewell Thunderchild,
child, child, child, child...
When the smoke cleared,
the little steamer had reached
the misty horizon,
and Carrie was safe.
But the Thunderchild had vanished
forever, taking with her
man's last hope of victory.
The leaden sky was lit by green
flashes, cylinder following cylinder,
and no one and nothing was
left now to fight them.
The earth belonged to the
Martians.
Part Two:
The Earth Under the Martians
Next day, the dawn was a brilliant,
fiery red and I wandered
through the weird and lurid landscape
of another planet,
for the vegetation that
gives Mars
its red appearance had
taken root on earth.
As man had succumbed to the Martians,
so our land now succumbed
to the red weed.
Wherever there was a stream
the red weed clung
and grew with frightening
voraciousness,
its claw-like fronds choking
the movement of the water.
And then it began to creep
like a slimy red animal
across the land covering field
and ditch and tree and hedgerow
with living scarlet feelers,
crawling, crawling.
I suddenly noticed the body
of a parson lying on the ground
in a ruined churchyard.
I felt unable to leave him to
the mercy of the red weed,
and decided to bury him, decently.
Nathaniel! Nathaniel!
The parson's eyes flickered open.
He was alive!
Nathaniel, I saw the church burst
into flame, are you all right?
Don't touch me!
But it's me, Beth! Your wife!
No! You're one of them- a devil!
He's delirious!
-Lies! I saw the devil's sign!
What are you saying?
-The green flash in the sky.
His demons were here all along,
in our hearts and souls,
just waiting for a sign from Him.
And now they're destroying our world!
But they're not devils,
they're Martians.
We must leave here.
-Look, a house still standing,
come Nathaniel, quickly.
We took shelter in a cottage, and
black smoke spread, hemming us in.
Then a fighting machine came across
the field spraying jets of steam
that turned the smoke into thick,
black dust.
Dear God, help us!
The voice of the Devil is heard
in our land!
Listen, do you hear them drawing near
In their search for the sinners?
Feeding on the power of our fear
And the evil within us?
In carnation of Satan's creation
of all that we dread
When the demons arrive those alive
will be better off dead
There must be something worth
living for
trying for
Even something worth dying for
And if one man can stand tall
There must be hope for us all
Somewhere, somewhere in
the spirit of man
Once, there was a time when I
believed without hesitation
That the power of love and truth
could conquer all
In the name of salvation
Tell me what kind of weapon is love
when it comes to the fight?
And just how much protection is truth
against all Satan's might?
There must be something worth
living for
trying for
Even some things worth dying for
And if one man could stand tall
There must be some hope for us all
Somewhere, somewhere in
the spirit of man
People loved you, and trusted you,
came to you for help...
Didn't I warn them this would happen?
Be on your guard, I said,
for the Evil One never rests...
I said exorcise the devil!
But no, they wouldn't listen,
the demons inside them grew
and grew,
until Satan gave his signal
and destroyed the world we knew!
No Nathaniel, oh no Nathaniel,
No Nathaniel, no, there must be
more to life,
There has to be a way that we can
Restore to life the love we used
to know
Nathaniel, no, there must be
more to life,
There has to be a way that we can
Restore to life the light that
we have lost
Now darkness has descended
on our land
And all your prayers cannot save us
Like fools we've let the devil
take command
Of the souls that God gave us
To the altar of evil like lambs
to the slaughter were led
When the demons arrive the survivors
will envy the dead!
There must be something worth
living for
No, there is nothing!
There must be something worth
trying for -I don't believe it's so!
Even something worth dying for
If just one man could stand tall
There would be some hope for us all,
Somewhere, somewhere in
the spirit of man
Forget about goodness and mercy,
they're gone!
Didn't I warn them?
Pray, I said!
Destroy the devil, I said!
They wouldn't listen!
I could have saved the world!
But now it's too late...
too late!
No Nathaniel, oh no Nathaniel,
No Nathaniel, no, there must be
more to life,
There has to be a way that we can
Restore to life the love we used
to know
Nathaniel, no, there must be
more to life,
There has to be a way that we can
Restore to life the light that
we have lost...
Dear God! A cylinder's landed
on the house,
and we are underneath it,
in the pit!
The Martians spent the night making
a new machine.
It was a squat, metallic spider
with huge, articulated claws,
but it, too, had a hood in which
a Martian sat.
I watched it pursuing some people
across a field.
It caught them nimbly and
tossed them
into a great metal basket
upon its back.
Beth? She’s dead!
Buried under the rubble.
Why?
Satan! Why did you take one of
your own?
There is a curse on mankind
We may as well be resigned
To let the devil, the devil take
the spirit of man
As time passed in our dark and
dusty prison,
the parson wrestled endlessly
with his doubts.
His outcries invited death for
us both, and yet I pitied him.
Then, on the ninth day, we saw
the Martians eating.
Inside the hood of their new machine
they were drawing the fresh,
living blood of men and women and
injecting it into their own veins.
Aaah! It's a sign!
I've been given a sign!
They must be cast out, and I
have been chosen to do it!
I must confront them now!
-No, parson, no!
Those machines are just demons
in another form.
I shall destroy them with my
prayers,
I shall burn them with my holy
cross. I shall...
The curious eye of a Martian
appeared at the window slit,
and a menacing claw explored
the room.
I dragged the parson down
to the coal cellar.
I heard the Martian fumbling
at the latch.
In the darkness I could see
the claw touching things,
walls, coal, wood.
And then, it touched my boot.
I almost shouted.
For a time it was still,
and then, with a click,
it gripped something: the parson!
With slow, deliberate movements, his
unconscious body was dragged away,
and there was nothing I could do
to prevent it.
I crept to the blocked window slit
and peered through the creeper.
The Martians, and all their
machinery, had gone!
Trembling, I dug my way out and
clambered to the top of the mound:
not a Martian in sight!
The day seemed dazzling bright
after my imprisonment
and the sky a glowing blue.
Red weed covered every scrap
of ground but a gentle breeze
kept it swaying, and oh,
the sweetness of the air.
Again, I was on my way to London
through towns and villages
that were blackened ruins,
totally silent,
desolated, deserted.
Man's empire had passed away,
taken swiftly and without error
by these creatures who were
composed entirely of brain.
Unhampered by the complex systems
which make up man,
they made and used different bodies
according to their needs.
They never tired, never slept,
and never suffered,
having long since eliminated
from their planet the bacteria
which cause all fevers and
other morbidities.
Halt! Who goes there?
-Er, a friend...
Be on your way, this is
my territory!
Your territory? What do you mean?
Wait a minute... it's you!
The man from Maybury Hill!
Good heavens, the artilleryman.
I thought you'd surely burned.
I thought you'd surely drowned.
-Have you seen any Martians?
Everywhere. We're done for all
right. -We can't just give up.
`Course we can't. It's now that
we've got to start fighting.
Not against them,
cause we can't win.
Now, we've got to fight for
survival.
I reckon we can make it.
I've got a plan.
We're gonna build a whole
new world for ourselves.
Look, they clap eyes on us
and we're dead, right?
So, we gotta make a new life
where they'll never find us.
You know where? Underground.
You should see it down there,
hundreds of miles of drains,
sweet and clean now after
the rain, dark, quiet, safe.
We can build houses and everything,
start again from scratch.
And what's so bad about living
underground, eh?
S'not been so great living up
here, if you want my opinion.
Take a look around you at
the world we've come to know
Does it seem to be much more
than a crazy circus show
Maybe from the madness,
something beautiful will grow
In a brave new world,
with just a handful of men,
We'll start... we'll start
all over again!
All over again! All over again!
All over again!
We'll build shops and hospitals
and barracks,
right under their noses,
right under their feet.
Everything we need:
banks, prisons and schools.
We'll send scouting parties
to collect books and stuff,
and men like you we'll teach
the kids.
Not poems and rubbish; science,
so we can get everything working!
We'll build villages and towns,
and...
and we'll play each other
at cricket!
Listen, maybe one day we'll capture
a fighting machine,
learn how to make `em ourselves,
and then: WALLOP!
Our turn to do some wiping out!
WHOOSH! With our heat ray!
Whoosh!
And them running and dying,
beaten at their own game,
man on top again!
Now our domination of the earth
is fading fast,
And out of the confusion
a chance has come at last,
To build a better future
from the ashes of the past,
In a brave new world,
with just a handful of men,
We'll start all over again!
Look, man is born in freedom,
but he soon becomes a slave,
In cages of convention from
the cradle to the grave,
The weak fall by the wayside
but the strong will be saved,
In a brave new world,
with just a handful of men,
We'll start all over again!
I'm not trying to tell you
what to be,
Oh no, oh no, not me...
But if mankind is to survive,
the people life alive,
They're gonna have to build
this world anew
And it's going to have to start
with me and you... YES!
I'm not trying to tell you what
to be,
Oh no, oh no, not me...
But if mankind is to survive,
the people left alive,
They're gonna have to build
this world anew
Yes and we will have to be
the chosen few...
Just think of all the poverty,
the hatred and the lies,
And imagine the destruction
of all that you despise,
Slowly from the ashes
the phoenix will arise,
In a brave new world,
with just a handful of men
We'll start all over again!
Take a look around you at the
world you've loved so well,
And bid the aging empire
of man a last farewell
It may not sound like heaven
but at least it isn't hell
It's a brave new world
with just a handful of men,
We'll start, we'll start
all over again!
All over again! All over again!
All over again!
I'VE GOT A PLAN!
Can't you just see it?
Civilization starting all over
again! A second chance!
Heh- we'll even build a railway
and tunnel to the coast,
go there for our holidays!
Nothing can stop men like us!
I've made a start already.
Come on down here and have a look.
In the cellar there was a tunnel
scarcely ten yards long.
It had taken him a week to dig.
I could have dug that much in
a day, and I suddenly had
my first inkling of the gulf
between his dreams and his power.
It's doing the working and the
thinking that wears a fellow out.
I'm ready for a bit of a rest.
How about a drink, eh?
Nothing but champagne now
I'm the boss.
We drank, and then he insisted
upon playing cards.
With our species on the edge
of extermination,
with no prospect but a horrible
death, we actually played games.
Later he talked more of his plan,
but I saw flames flashing
in the deep blue night,
red weed glowing,
tripod figures moving distantly,
and I put down my champagne glass.
I felt a traitor to my kind,
and I knew I must leave this
strange dreamer.
Take a look around you at
the world we've come to know
Does it seem to be much more
than a crazy circus show?
Maybe from the madness
something beautiful will grow...
There were a dozen dead bodies
in the Euston road,
their outlines softened by
the black dust.
All was still, houses locked
and empty, shops closed,
but looters had helped themselves
to wine and food,
and outside a jewelers some gold
chains and a watch
were scattered on the pavement.
I stopped, staring towards the sound.
It seemed as if that mighty desert
of houses had found a voice
for its fear and solitude.
The desolating cry worked
upon my mind.
The wailing took possession of me.
I was intensely weary, footsore,
hungry and thirsty.
Why was I wandering alone
in this city of the dead?
Why was I alive when London was
lying in state in its black shroud?
I felt intolerably lonely,
drifting from street to empty street,
drawn inexorably towards that cry.
I saw, over the trees on
Primrose Hill,
the fighting machine from which
the howling came.
I crossed Regent's Canal.
There stood a second machine,
upright, but as still as the first.
Abruptly, the sound ceased.
Suddenly the desolation,
the solitude, became unendurable.
While that voice sounded London
still seemed alive,
now suddenly there was a change,
the passing of something,
and all that remained was
this gaunt quiet.
I looked up, and saw a third machine.
It was erect and motionless,
like the others.
An insane resolve possessed me:
I would give my life to the Martians,
here and now.
I marched recklessly towards
the titan and saw that a multitude
of black birds were circling and
clustering about the hood.
I began running along the road.
I felt no fear, only a wild,
trembling exultation
as I ran up the hill
towards the motionless monster.
Out of the hood hung red shreds,
at which the hungry birds now
pecked and tore.
I scrambled up to the crest
of Primrose hill,
the Martian's camp was below me.
A mighty space it was,
and scattered about it,
in their overturned machines,
were the Martians, dead,
slain after all man's devices
had failed
by the humblest creatures on the
earth: bacteria.
Minute, invisible, bacteria.
Directly the invaders arrived
and drank and fed,
our microscopic allies attacked
them.
From that moment, they were doomed.
The torment was ended.
The people scattered over the
country,
desperate, leaderless, starved,
the thousands who had fled by sea
including the one most dear to me;
all could return, the pulse of life
growing stronger and stronger
would beat again.
As life returns to normal,
the question of another
attack from Mars causes universal
concern.
Is our planet safe, or is this
time of peace merely a reprieve?
It may be that across the immensity
of space,
they have learned their lessons,
and even now await their opportunity.
Perhaps the future belongs not
to us, but to the Martians.
Looking good, going good,
we're getting great pictures
here at NASA control Pasadina.
Landing craft touched down on Mars
28 kilometers from the aim point.
We're looking at a remarkable
landscape,
littered with different kinds
of rocks.
Red, purple... how about that,
Burmuda?
Fantastic. Look at that dune field!
Hey, wait, I- I'm getting a
no-go signal.
Now I'm losing one of the craft.
Hey Burmuda, you getting it?
Nah, lost contact. There's
a lot of dust blowing up there.
Now I lost the second craft.
We got problems.
Full contact lost, Pasadina.
Maybe the antenna's...
What's that flare? See it?
A green flare coming from Mars.
Kind of a green mist behind it.
It's getting closer.
You see it, Burmuda?
Come in, Burmuda!
Houston, come in! What's going on...
tracking station 43 Canberra,
come in Canberra!
tracking station 63,
can you hear me Madrid...
can anybody hear me? Come in...!
Come in...