Jer...
My mom used to be
used to be my dad.
Used to be my
Used to be my dad.
Snip. snip.
- Used to be my dad.
- Snip.
l was jilted by a lesbian
by a lesbian...
Bull dyke.
..by a lesbian dwarf.
She gave good
But she gave good head.
Slurp. Slurp.
But she gave good head. Slurp.
l used to be a lap-dancing
pre-operative transsexual.
A chick
A chick with a dick.
With a dick.
l want to be
want to be
on TV.
Please let me be
Choose me.
Please. me.
Please
let me.
Jer...
Jerry.
Excuse me. Is this the right room
for The Dave Letterman Show?
You got the wrong room. pal. Loser.
- Fuck you.
- Fuck you back.
When does it start?
How should l know?
l hope l get to see
some bare breasts.
Me. too.
Why are all men such losers?
Nice to see the lesbian's in.
Cocksuckers.
l hope there's some fighting.
Of course there'll be some fighting.
you stupid asshole.
Who are you calling asshole?
You. asshole.
Ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to The Jerry Sprínger Show.
- Please will you welcome...
- Jerry.
- Welcome...
Welcome your moderator
and warm-up artist.
Jer...
Ladies and gentlemen.
my name is Jonathan Wierus.
Oh. yeah.
Before the show starts.
we gotta lay down a few rules.
Whatever.
Things get pretty hot up here
so we gotta have a few rules.
Got the message.
Nobody's allowed on stage.
and nobody's allowed to throw things
at the guests.
Don't throw things at the guests.
- Another rule.
- What?
During the show. No heckling.
- No heckling.
No heckling? What are you saying?
Are you mad?
No way.
Apart from
''aaaah'' for the good guys.
- Aaaah.
- Yes. that's right.
- You've got it.
And for the bad guys ''boo''.
- Boo.
- Yup.
- Great.
- Boo.
- Yes. that's right.
Save it for the show.
And we like it when you say
Jerry. Jerry.
- Jerry. Jerry.
- Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
- Go. Jerry. go.
Jerry. Jerry.
Come on. Come on.
Eveybody. let's go.
- Jerry. Jerry.
- Go. Go.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
Let's go. Let's go.
- Jerry.
- Let's go.
- Go. Jerry. go.
- Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
- So just to recap. No heckling.
- No heckling.
- No fighting.
- No throwing things or throwing up.
And most of all.
Most of all.
Seriously.
Especially.
obviously.
- Have yourselves a good time.
- Good time.
A good
Have a good
Have yourselves a real good time.
- Good time.
Good time. Jerry.
A good...
We want some action.
Ready for some action.
We want Jerry.
Where the fuck is Jerry?
- What do you want?
- Lesbians fighting.
- Open-crotch sightings.
Pimps in bad suits.
mothers who are prostitutes.
mutants. psychos. saddos. winos.
cocaine abusers with no noses.
- Bring on the losers.
- Bring 'em on.
- Bring 'em on. Bring 'em on.
Bring on the losers.
La-la-la-la-la-la-la-la
losers.
Bring on the losers.
La-la-la-la-la-la-la-la
losers.
- Are you ready? Are you ready?
- Yes. we're ready. Yes. we're ready.
- Oh. for fuck's sake. we are ready.
- We are.
- Alright.
There's no need for sarcasm.
l'm only trying to
- do my frickin' job.
- Yes. we are fucking ready.
- Tough crowd.
- Ready.
- Really tough.
- Trailer trash.
- Fuck you !
Come on. Come on.
- Alright already.
- Come on. Come on.
- Where the fuck is Jerry?
The crowd is turning ugly.
Ladies and gentlemen.
people of most nations of the world.
Go. Jerry. Go. Jerry.
Jerry.
Welcome the host
of the greatest show on this earth.
Go. Jerry. Go. Jerry.
Jerry.
Bigger than Dave Letterman.
Bigger than Bob Hope.
And give or take a few million.
bigger than the fucking Pope.
- Lo! He comes.
- Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
- Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
- Jerry. Jerry.
- Go. Jerry. go.
Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
- Go. Jerry
- Jerry.
- Go. Jerry.
- Welcome. Welcome to the show.
- Jerry! Jerry! Jerry!
How you doing?
Good to see you. Thank you.
Thank you and welcome to the show.
My guests today
all have guilty secrets.
They also have partners
and wanna get those guilty secrets
ofl their chests and come clean.
Please welcome my first guest
with a guilty secret. Dwight.
Welcome to the show. Dwight.
- Hey. Jerry. Wassup?
- Wassup?
- So. Dwight. what's on your mind?
l've been seeing my fiancée
for two years.
Aw!
And we're gettin' married
in two months.
Aw!
What is it you wanna tell
your fiancée?
l've been seeing someone else.
Someone else.
- Boo!
- Someone else. Someone else.
- Whatever.
- Boo!
- Get over it.
And does your fiancée know
this person?
- It's her best friend Zandra.
- Boo!
- Whatever.
- OK.
OK. OK. So. Dwight.
you're getting married in two months.
Now. why would you cheat
on your future wife?
l don't know. Jerry.
it just happened.
But l really love her.
God. l really love her. but l gotta
get my secret ofl my chest.
- Ofl his chest.
- Ofl my chest.
Let's see how she feels about it.
Please say hello to Peaches.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
- Pig. Pig.
- Bitch. Bitch.
Hi. Peaches. Don't listen to them.
they're just kidding.
Pig.
Welcome to the show. Peaches.
Do you know why you're here?
- No idea. Jerry.
- So. how's the relationship?
- It's good.
- Uh-huh.
- Real good.
Well. Dwight's got something
to tell you. So go ahead. Dwight.
Baby. we've been going out
for two years.
Uh-huh. uh-huh.
- Things are going good.
- Uh-huh. uh-huh.
- But l got something to say.
- Something that's burning inside.
- Uh-huh.
l've been seeing someone else.
l've been seeing. seeing someone.
someone. seeing someone else.
What the fuck? What the fuck?
What the fucking. fucking fuck?
Peaches. Peaches. You seem surprised.
So. what would you like to say
to Dwight?
- Who? Who?
- Calm down. baby.
- Take it easy. Ty to chill.
- Who? Who?
- She don't mean a thing to me.
- She's just a tramp. Just a whore.
- Who? Who?
- It ain't easy for me. baby.
Who? Who? Who? Who?
l've been seeing your best friend.
Your best friend. Your best friend.
lf it's true. then fuck you.
Alright. let's bring out Peaches's
best friend. Please welcome Zandra.
Dirty whore. Dirty whore. Filthy.
dirty. manky. skanky slut whore.
Manky. skanky slut whore.
l remember when we was young.
We had some laughs.
We had some fun.
We lived on dreams.
We was full of hope.
Until l got addicted
to crack and dope.
Crack and dope.
Bitch.
- Steve.
- Bitch !
- Bitch. bitch. bitch. bitch!
- Steve.
- Steve. Steve. Steve. Steve.
- Bitch. bitch. bitch. bitch!
- Bitch!
Hi.
My name's Steve Wilcos. l'm head of
secuiity Qn The Jerry Sprínger Show.
You know. a lot of people ask me what
are the hardest fights to break up.
l gotta tell you.
it's. er. it's always the women.
- Bitch!
- Why'd you tell her. asshole?
- Gotta fess up. Gotta fess up.
Peaches. it weren't me.
It was the blow.
- Shut it. bitch!
- Peaches.
- Crackhead.
- Slut junkie.
Zandra.
Peaches has been your best friend
from childhood.
Now. why would you cheat
on your best friend?
He'd come round. Know what
l'm saying? Know what l'm saying?
When he was stressed.
Know what l'm saying?
l would sympathise.
Sympathise. Know what l'm saying?
Know what l'm saying?
Crack whore.
Your partner has cheated on you.
Your best friend has betrayed you.
You don't have to put up with this.
You're the innocent one here.
A weird thing happened last night
when l went to take a leak.
l ended up pissing on a man
with a glorious physique.
l said ''What on earth are you doing
on the restroom floor?''
He said. ''Don't ask stupid questions.
just piss on me some more.''
''Piss on me. you whore.''
l pissed some more.
l guess we all got our flaws. Jerry.
Well. l'm confused here. Peaches.
So. are you going to take him back?
- Uh-huh. uh-huh. uh-huh. uh-huh.
- Baby. l love you.
Well. l guess you got away with it
this time. Dwight.
Jerry.
lt's OK. it's my inner Valkyrie.
How can l help you today?
Jerry makes the morons fight.
but how does Jerry sleep at night?
How do l sleep? l sleep on my back.
Thank you.
You know. it's easy to occupy
the moral high ground.
What's more diflicult
is to confidently occupy
the moral low ground. Go away.
So. Dwight. you told our producers
before the show
that you've got another secret.
- Baby. there's one more thing.
- Uh-huh.
One more. baby.
There's one more. baby. There's...
l've been seeing someone else.
What the fuck? What the fuck?
What the fucking. fucking fuck?
- Bring 'em on.
- Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry.
- Chick with a dick.
- l am a man.
l am a man.
l'm a man.
Tacky. tack-tack. tack-tacky queen.
Hush all your shouting.
You can hush all your bitching.
You can talk to the hand
cos the face ain't listening.
Loser.
- Talk to the hand.
- Loser.
- Cos the face ain't listening.
- Loser. Faggot.
Look at little piggy.
See how she squeals.
My advice to you. bitch.
get a face peel.
- Loser. loser. butt boy.
- To the hand.
Loser. loser. butt boy.
Hush your dirty mouth.
my tubby lady chimp.
Lose the facial hair
and you might find a pimp.
- Loser. loser. loser.
- To the hand.
Loser. loser. loser.
Talk to the hand.
You so tragic. you so sad.
cos your brother is your dad.
Talk to the hand.
You so slow. you so dumb.
cos you live off gay men's cum.
Do you want some? Do you want some?
Come and get it. Come and get it.
When you're dead
and buried in the grass.
l'll dig you up
and fuck you up the ass.
Talk to the hand.
- Cos the face ain't listening.
- Talk to the hand.
Talk to the hand.
Talk to the hand
cos the face ain't listening.
- Talk to the hand.
- To the hand. To the hand.
- To the hand. To the...
Vomit. vomit. vomit.
Puke up my guts. Throw up. re-vomit.
Kill all gays. Kill all gays.
Welcome to the show. Tremont.
So. Tremont.
let me get this straight.
She says she's his.
She says he's hers.
They say he's theirs.
So l guess you're saying he's yours.
Now. what's going on?
He said that she said that I said
that I said
that he said that she said
that they said that she said
we both said that he said
that l said that you said
something or other. l forget.
She said that he said that l said
that l said that she said
that they said.
- He's mine.
- l don't think so.
- He said that she said...
- l don't think so. l don't think so.
- He's mine. He's mine.
He said that she said.
he said that you said.
- Does it really matter?
- What?
Does it really matter?
What?
Cos
at the end of the day
l...
l love you.
Chick with a dick with a heart.
Ladyboy.
L-L-L-L-Ladyboy. F-F-F-F-Faggot.
Butt boy.
What the fuck? What the fuck?
What the fucking. fucking fuck?
OK. OK. Dwight. So.
who's it gonna be?
l want my baby back.
Peaches. baby. please come back.
They don't mean shit to me.
They're just whores and douchebags.
Steve.
Well. Peaches. it's your call.
Where do we go from here?
You don't see me cry.
l just say goodbye.
Bisexual. bye-bye.
- Bisexual. bye-bye.
You're just a tramp.
Come back. baby.
You're just a crack whore.
lt wasn't me. it was the smack.
You're just a butt-plugging.
cornholing. man-loving.
- sodomising. boy-fucking...
- Talk to the hand.
- ..crazy dirtbag.
You're all scum.
Talk to the hand.
Loser.
More secrets after these commercials.
Don't go away.
You may look beautiful now.
but in ten years.
you're gonna look like a dog.
The future is ugly.
What's to become of me?
Surgery.
Doctor Knife. Doctor Knife. Keeping
you young for the rest of your life.
Are you insured? Are you insured?
No insurance means no cure.
You'll die alone in your home.
- Screaming in agony.
- Retching and puking.
- From evey orifice.
Think you'd better get insured.
Don't let weight problems
spoil your night.
Throw away your diets
and use a parasite.
Some people do
as they think they should.
Others get Viagra and get wood.
- Jerry. Jerry.
- Go. Jerry. go.
Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
Thank you. Welcome...
lf you all like Jerry.
clap your hands.
Then slap your glands
and fuck your best friend's wife.
Oh. slap your glands
Thank you and welcome back.
My next guest with a guilty secret
is Montel.
So. Montel. what's on your mind?
l've been seeing Andrea here
- and we're in love.
- Ah !
- We're in love.
We're in love.
Ah!
- What is it you want to tell Andrea?
- Well. Jerry.
Don't talk to me. talk to Andrea.
Baby. l love you with all of my heart
but there is one thing
you could do for me
which could change
my life.
Change my life.
Tell me. baby. Tell me. baby.
- Well. baby.
- Tell me. baby. Tell me. baby.
Well. baby.
Tell me. baby. Tell me. baby.
Tell me.
l wanna be your baby.
baby.
You are my baby.
What l mean is.
l wanna be your baby.
What?
Be your baby.
- You've gotta be kidding.
- Be your baby. Be your baby.
- Tell me this is bullshit.
l want to be your baby. baby.
B-A-B with a Y.
- What the fuck?
- B-A-B-Y.
lf baby gets bad.
if baby gets slack.
Momma give B-A-B-Y big. big smack.
- Montel. what are you saying?
- Baby.
Stop it.
What the fuck is happening here?
- Baby. Baby.
- Stop it. Watch it.
Montel. Montel.
what the fuck is going on here?
Momma get all ang-wy.
Stop it. Montel.
- Stop it.
- Andrea...
You seem upset.
So. what is it
you want to say to Montel?
- Montel.
- Momma.
- Stop this.
- We can...
- Momma.
..work it out.
lt would mean a lot to me. baby.
Get some therapy.
lt would help in the bed department.
- Bed department?
- Yes.
Are you saying l'm bad in bed?
No. baby.
- What. then?
- Well...
Spit it out. Spit it out.
Are you trying to say you're gay?
- No. baby. It's so very hard.
- Put your pants on.
- Be a man and tell me.
- So hard.
- Tell me.
- Well...
- What?
- It's...
- Er...
- What?
Please don't tell us. we can guess.
Will you get out of my head?
l'm working here.
Now get.
Some people like to relax in casinos.
others get their kicks
shoving powder up their nose.
That's how it is.
Some people chill with a pill
or a reefer.
others like to eat their lunch
off a whore's beaver.
That's how it is.
For some. morning mass.
for others. hairy ass.
l got a need. a special desire.
a little thing. a harmless thing
which sets my soul on fire.
which sends me spinning into space
and puts me in a trance.
A little thing. a harmless thing.
l just wanna shit my pants.
Oh. l just wanna shit my pants.
Oh. pooping in my Calvin Kleins.
lt might seem pathetic.
might show a lack of class.
l only feel the real me
when the shit's
pouring outta my ass.
So. spit it out. Montel.
what's the big secret?
l had to get my diaper action.
Had to get my diaper action.
l've been seeing Baby Jane.
Please welcome Baby Jane.
This is my Jerry Springer moment.
l don't want this moment to die.
So dip me in chocolate
and throw me to the lesbians.
l don't want this moment to die.
This is her Jerry Springer moment.
She don't want this moment to die.
So dip her in chocolate
and throw her to the lesbians.
To the lesbians.
She don't want this moment to die.
- Thank you. Baby Jane.
- Jerry!
Oh. er... No. not right now.
Nice dress.
So. Baby Jane.
what is it you want to say to Andrea?
- Momma gimme smack on the asshole.
- Disgusting.
- Momma gimme smack evey night.
- Do you want some?
Momma gimme smack on the asshole.
- Eveything will be alright.
- You fucking sicko.
You frickin' pervert.
l'm gonna whup your ass.
Dirty. stealing.
stupid. fucking bitch. Bitch. Bitch.
- Momma.
- Bitch.
Bitch. Bitch.
Eveything will be al...
Go. go. girl. Take her eyes out.
Go. go. girl. Rip her hair out.
Nothing more exciting
than bitches fighting.
Go. go. girl. Slash her K-Mart pants.
Go. go. girl. Burst her implants.
Alright. Alright. Alright.
So. Montel.
Andrea is your partner of two years.
Surely you must have something
to say to her.
lf you feel blue.
my advice to you
is.. .
- Poop your fucking pants.
- Why don't you poop your pants?
- Poop your pants. Poop your pants.
Poop your pants.
Poop your fu-u-u-u-u-ucking pants.
- Stop this fucking shit.
- Loser. Loser.
- Show me some respect.
Do you want some?
Who-o-o-oa. bitch.
You know.
l never wanted to be
a talk-show host.
Well. here we go.
- Bitch.
- Do you want some?
Come and get it.
Come and get it, motherfuckers.
Come and get it. Come and get it.
l wish you could like her.
Like her then wipe her
- diaper.
- Fuck you.
Diaper pooping. Diaper pooping.
- Diaper.
- That's enough.
Diaper pooping. Diaper pooping.
- Diaper.
- Baby. please.
Who-o-o-oa . diaper.
- Baby.
- Pooping.
- Diaper.
Pooping.
Diaper.
Dia-Dia-Dia-Diaper.
More guilt after the break.
Don't go away.
l want to sing something beautiful.
OK. honey. that's enough.
l want to sing something positive.
Why don't we carry this on
in the greenroom?
l want to learn how to dream again.
To feel again.
Look, we really
gotta wind this up now.
- l wanna stand on top...
- Thank you.
- ..of a hill...
- Steve.
..in the arms of my lover.
bathed in the light
of rainbows.
With spring in my heart
and love by my side.
Oh. stay with me. Stay with me.
Stay with me. baby.
Stay with me. Stay with me.
No motivation.
No idea. No aim.
No problem.
No worries.
Novocaine.
Buy a gun. Buy a big gun.
Have some fun with a big gun.
Ooh. look at my gun.
Look at my big gun.
Ooh. look at my gun. Look at my
big gun. You could have a gun. too.
Yes. you could have a gun. too.
but you gotta buy it first.
Bounce back.
Bounce back with Prozac.
Give in to Jesus.
Give in to Jesus
or alternatively die.
Die a ho-o-o-o-o-o-orrible.
die a horrible death. Jesus.
The first time l saw Jerry on TV.
l knew that there was hope for me.
When l saw how he worked the crowd.
l knew that he could help me out.
Before that. l was empty inside.
l had considered suicide.
But now l'm a vital member
of Jerry's team.
But sometimes l wonder
how much he values me.
What the fuck is that
idiot warm-up man doing out there?
He's turning my people
into a mob.
You're right. Steve. he's got to go.
Hey. Jerry. what can l say. man?
Tough crowd.
Nice to see you. Jonathan.
Sorry if l let those assholes
get a little too loud.
Those assholes are my audience.
Jerry. don't bullshit me.
You and me both.
we know they are scum.
Filthy cocksucking scum.
Your job is to control those scum
and keep them from
upstaging my guests.
Pimps and perverts. teenage whores.
people so fat they get
stuck in revolving doors.
And we get them through those doors
and onto a plane to Chicago.
Sluts and faggots.
gimps eating maggots.
We never had a maggot-eating gimp
on this show.
- Jerry. you could do anything.
- What are you talking about?
You could run for Senate
or even president.
lf l want my dick sucked.
l'll call my agent.
Looks like you're cruising.
playing it safe.
You're way out of line. pal.
You need a challenge
and l got just the thing.
Gonna make you sweat
when you're in the ring.
Jonathan. let's cut this short.
You need help. Help and a new job.
No! You...
So thanks for this little chat.
Oh. and good luck
in the warm-up industry.
Sorry. faggots. if l'm outta line.
Sorry if l'm taking
too much of your time.
Mister Fucking Big Shot.
sun shines out his ass.
take your job and shove it.
It's been such a blast.
That's the last we'll see of him.
Fuck you. Fuck you.
l'm so lonely.
That went well.
You know. when l was a younger man.
l was passionate about civil rights.
education. the antiwar movement.
l was even elected
to the city council.
And then one day.
l. er. l went to a prostitute.
and l paid her with a cheque.
Next day it was all over.
But l faced up to it.
And later l was elected mayor
of Cincinnati.
That's the third largest city...
in Ohio.
There are only two things you need
to know about politics. One.
you'll never get anywhere unless
you have the courage to speak up
about what you know to be the truth.
And two.
some things
should always be paid for in cash.
My cards? Where are my cards?
- Jerry. Jerry.
- Go. Jerry. go.
Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
- Hello.
- Oh. Jerry.
- How are you?
- Jerry.
- Thank you and welcome back.
Thank you. And now our final guest.
Please say hello to Shawntel.
Fat bitch. Fat bitch.
- Shut up. Shut up. Sit down.
- Dumb ho.
Shawntel. it says here
that you want to be a pole dancer.
All my life
All my life.
l've been running after other people.
looking after them.
cleaning up their shit.
now l wanna find my dreams again.
- What? In a strip club?
- Good one.
Bug-eyed loser. strip slut.
- Talk to the ass.
- Strip slut.
- You fucking bitch.
- What did...?
Shawntel. l can see you have
a lot of natural talent.
l also see here that you're married.
So. what does your husband think?
l don't know. We don't talk.
Well. let's bring him on
and find out. Please welcome Chucky.
Hillbilly. Hillbilly.
Squeal like a piggy.
Squeal like a piggy. Eeeeee!
Put your fucking clothes on.
you stupid bitch.
- Don't you touch me...
- You stupid bitch!
- ..or l'll kill you in your sleep.
- You stupid bitch.
- Cocksucker. Talk to the ass.
- You look ridiculous.
- Talk to the ass.
So, Chucky. l take it you're not too thrilled
with Shawntel's pole-dancing dreams?
She looks like a clown.
She looks like a slut.
He don't know shit.
He never saw me dance.
But he watches other women dance
every night
- with his buddies.
- Yeah. right.
Well. let's see her dance.
We have a pole.
We have some music. Let's go.
Dance. dance. dance. dance. dance.
dance. dance. dance. strip slut.
Shake that booty. strip slut.
- Shake that booty. strip slut.
- Bullshit!
l don't give a fuck no more
if people think l am a whore.
l just wanna dance.
Oh. l just wanna dance.
Things are going bad for me.
l am feeling sad for me.
So. l just wanna dance.
Oh. l just wanna dance.
l'm tired of laughing.
l'm tired of crying.
l'm tired of failing.
and l'm tired of all this trying.
l wanna do some living
cos l've done enough dying.
l just wanna dance.
l just wanna fucking dance.
Oh. dance.
Dance.
She's tired of laughing.
she's tired of crying.
She's tired of failing
and she's tired of all this trying.
She wants to do some living
cos she's done enough dying.
She just wants to dance.
She just wants to fucking dance.
Dance.
- She just wants to fucking dance.
- Dance.
Dance.
- l just wanna fucking...
- Thank you. Shawntel.
But we've got another guest
who's none too happy
with your choice of career.
Your mother Irene.
lt has no name.
lt is a whore.
- It has no name.
- Momma.
- It is a whore.
- It will burn.
- Momma.
- It will fry.
You're just a sack of misery.
Everything you touch turns to cancer.
Hope you die
slow with pain swimming
round your ugly ass.
your skanky sorry ass.
Welcome to the show. Irene.
l. erm. sense some hostility
towards your daughter.
Some are descended from angels.
Others are descended from apes.
Some are the result of romantic love.
Others the result of rapes.
Well. l wish she'd died at birth.
And l wish you'd died at birth. too.
Well. at least you agree
on one thing.
So. Chucky.
how do you fit into all of this?
lf she don't stop.
l'll find me another woman.
What you gonna do?
Buy her or drug her?
Gonna find me something to replace
her tainted. sagging old skin.
Good. Good.
l'm tired of your little dick flesh.
lt's so small l get more pleasure
from fucking myself
with my own clitoris.
All women are whores.
Whores or sluts or prostitutes.
You don't know shit.
He's just an inbred
three-nippled cousin-fucker.
lnbreed three-nippled cousin-fucker.
Three-nippled cousin-fuck...
Three-nippled cousin-fucker.
You're the innocent one here. Chucky.
l ain't easy. but l'm honest.
So. no secrets. then?
l like flowers more than people.
No. Jerry.
Well. that's strange. Chucky.
because we followed you around
with our secret camera. the Jerrycam.
And to be honest. we were
a little surprised by what we saw.
He came. he saw. he Jerrycam.
Vení, vídí, Jerrycam.
Adoremus Jerrycam.
Benedictus Jerry fucking...
Bring on the Klan.
No. not the fucking Klan.
Well. l guess it would be rude not
to. Please welcome the Ku Klux Klan.
Come on. boys.
Come on.
Get your fuckin' hands off of me.
You fucked-up...
This is our Jerry Springer moment.
We don't want this moment to die.
So dip us in chocolate
and throw us to the lesbians.
We don't want this moment to die.
Jews and blacks will go to hell.
New York Democrats as well.
We don't want this moment to
die.
Die.
We're running out of time.
My final thought.
Die.
l've been shot.
l'm confused. Why would l get shot?
Wow! That's some medication
they got me on.
Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
- Jerry.
- Oh. Jerry.
Jerry.
Are you sure that's mine?
l never eat sweet corn.
Steve!
lt's good to see you.
Oh. you never let me down.
But you didn't take that bullet.
Just kidding.
Jerry. Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
- Jerry.
- Oh. Jerry.
Jerry.
Steve. how cool is this?
Singing nurses.
a giant cigar
and. look. my own moving chair.
ls there a problem here?
Visitors.
l hope they brought me some grapes.
We eat. excrete and watch TV.
And you are there for us. Jerry.
Jerry. can you understand?
We sit out in nowhereland.
wanting and yearning.
our bloated stomachs churning.
Eat. excrete and watch TV.
You are there for us. Jerry.
Steve. let me get this straight.
- You eat. excrete...
- And watch TV.
- But l am there for you?
- Jerry.
Steve. what exactly
are they saying here?
Jerry. you're so diflicult.
They're exactly saying
that they eat. excrete and watch TV
but you are there for them. Jerry.
Oh. well. it's so nice of you guys to
take time out of your day to drop by.
l never knew l had so many friends.
So. how's it going with you guys?
To be frank. pretty fucked.
Well. l can sympathise.
Ratings are low.
l've got a class-action suit pending.
Not to mention
this bullet-wound-in-the-chest thing.
Come and see.
Come and see what you have done
to me.
Steve. this sounds like lawyer talk.
Don't say anything.
One day you're 17.
17, 17.
Then just before you're 18. 18.
suddenly. suddenly.
you realise you're 56.
56? Well. you've got your whole life
ahead of you.
You're one good-looking woman.
He was handsome.
He was smart.
He betrayed every friend.
He broke every heart.
But one day he awoke
to a scene that made him heave.
He'd been drugged up and fucked
by some sailors on leave.
Sailors on leave.
Hired and paid for by me.
You hired him a sailor. Shawntel?
Jeez. Chucky. you're a lucky guy.
All my wife ever got me
was a reflexologist.
l came home from a titty bar.
where l'd spent all night.
She covers me in kerosene
and sets me fucking alight.
Fry!
You set him on fire.
your husband of 15 years?
What was it. your anniversay?
Light of my life.
fire of my loins.
lover and laugher
and drinker and friend.
You stole my dreams.
You broke my jaw.
But you said you were Sorry
so l came back for more.
Stupid whore.
Came back for more.
More. more.
More.
You know. if there's one thing that
really sickens me. it's violence.
Unless it's on TV. in
a carefully controlled environment.
When you fall in love.
it could last forever.
But usually it lasts about a month.
So l shot myself in the head
but l missed and ended up half dead.
Now there's a hole
where my brain used to be.
l'm hooked to a monitor.
l find it hard to pee.
l slur and l dribble
and l live off my drip feed
but l still can get a hard-on
if l jerk till l bleed.
Jerk
till l bleed.
Jerk till l bleed.
At least something good
came out of it.
l made love
to a dying man.
l knew he was dying
cos l was holding the pillow
over his face.
Steve. l think we'd better
get out of here.
There is only one cure
for unrequited love.
Chocolate and howling at the moon.
Eat. excrete and watch TV.
You know what? It's been great
catching up with you guys.
And you've taken some knocks.
but you've gotta pick yourselves up.
Dust yourselves off
and have a magical day.
Behind you. Behind you.
Behind you.
Díes Irae.
What now?
Dead woman walking.
Baby Jane. you look like shit.
What happened to you?
Momma gave me smack on the asshole.
Momma gave me smack on the head.
But Momma gave me smack
with a monkey wrench
and now l am dead.
You know. Steve.
a person with less broadcasting
experience might feel responsible.
Your dreams take place in Manhattan.
Ours take place in Minnesota.
Your dreams are driven in a Bentley.
Ours in a rusty Skoda.
Big dreams
and small dreams.
like all dreams
just stay dreams.
l guess this must be
what guilt feels like.
That was my Jerry Springer moment.
l didn't want that moment
to die.
Seen all over the planet
on worldwide TV.
except developing countries
and Germany.
You know, l'll never understand why they
didn't pick the show up in Germany.
But don't get me started.
Oh. how my heart
aches for love.
Aches for love.
Oh. how my heart
aches for love.
Aches for love.
- Oh. how my heart
Aches.
Alright. let's clear up
a basic misunderstanding right now.
You all wanted to come on the show.
You all had your 15 seconds of fame.
You all got to stay
in a three-star hotel.
You all got an expenses-paid trip.
Minus minibar bills, Chucky,
to Chicago.
And. remember. that's Chicago.
the Windy City.
The city of. of...
wind.
You all knew the risks.
You signed the disclaimer.
So stop breaking my balls
and get out of my...
Steve. where the fuck are we?
Jerry. Jerry.
You have been chosen.
Chosen?
ls that a good thing?
Could you be a little more specific?
Chosen.
- Chosen.
- Chosen for what?
Will you people stop fucking with me?
Lo! He comes.
Oh. great! It's that loser
warm-up guy. Jonathan Wierus.
Wrong. Him am the devil.
- Ooh. yes. l'm evil.
- Him am not good.
The opposite. in fact.
ln fact. him a total cunt.
One way of putting it.
Him act as total cunt should.
What a cunt.
What a cunting. cunting.
cunting. cunting cunt.
- You're telling me you're the devil?
- Yes.
lt takes more than a little red suit
to be the devil.
Steve. throw this psycho out of here.
l don't think so.
N-N-N-N-N...
- Steve !
- Naughty.
- N-N-N-N-N-N-N-N-Naughty.
- Steve. Steve!
OK. OK. hang on. hang on.
So maybe l was a little hasty
with that firing thing.
That is of no concern.
Though it was not what l deserved.
l simply come to take you down
to hell where you will...
Serve.
Whoa. whoa. whoa! Time out!
Let's rewind this a little.
Now. l don't want to serve in hell.
At this stage in my career.
that would be a sideways move.
Come. Jerry. gird your loins.
for we must journey south of heaven.
Step into this elevator and set
a course for the basement level.
Fall with me.
- Fall with him.
- l've got a table booked at The Ivy.
lf you're proud and you walk tall.
you only got further to fall.
Like the apple on the tree.
you'll soon succumb to gravity.
Fall with me.
Fall with him.
Fall. fall. fall. fall. fall. fall.
Doesn't matter what you are.
prince or pauper. king or clown.
there is no greater act of love
than going down.
- Going down with me.
- Steve!
- Going down with him.
- l can't go to hell. l'm Jewish.
Surrender your mortal soul.
Let life swallow you up whole.
Wipe off that suspicious frown.
cos. baby. we all gotta go down.
- The white man.
- Gotta go down.
- The black man.
The red man. green man.
pink man. beige man.
Gotta go. gotta go d-d-down.
d-d-down.
- The tax man.
- Down.
- The gas man.
- The VAT man.
- Down.
- The weatherman.
- The snowman.
- Down.
- The doorman.
- The woman man.
- Down.
Down. down.
Wait.
Prince of Darkness.
punish him not.
Jerry is not to blame.
With or without Jerry's show.
we'd all end up the same.
Men and women. black and white.
transsexual girls and boys.
the burned and crippled.
blind. the maimed.
distorted.
destroyed.
For society
has an ugly face.
Contorted.
smeared with shit.
Jerry did not make it so.
He merely holds a mirror to it.
That's right. what she said there.
l do the mirror thing.
Tell him again. Tell him again.
- The Wicker Man.
- Gotta go down.
- Elephant Man.
- The Piltdown Man.
- Gotta go down.
- The blah-blah man.
Blah. blah. blah. blah.
- Blah.
- Blah. blah-blah. blah-blah. blah.
- Blah. blah.
The man with hair
and the man with none.
the man with the knife
and the man with the gun.
the man on the moon
and the man on the farm.
the man with a needle
stuck in his arm.
the man on the crapper
with voices in his head.
the man who wishes
evey other man was dead.
the man with ten kids
and a loving wife.
the man who has nothing
to show for his life.
Every last motherfucker
should go down.
- Down.
- Wait a minute.
l'm confused here.
Why are you dragging me down to hell?
l don't deserve this.
l'm not a bad guy.
l just got lucky. that's all.
l mean. Jesus. is that a sin?
- No.
- You see? They agree.
l take you to hell
to solve a problem
that's been chapping my ass
since the dawn of time.
Since the dawn of time.
You've got the wrong guy.
l don't solve problems.
l just televise them.
Now. what do you want from me?
l want you to do a show for me.
Wait, let me get this straight.
You want me to do a show for you.
the devil. in hell?
Look. l'm under exclusive contract
to USA Studios.
They've got a whole
building full of lawyers.
You'd have to talk to the head of
the company and he's not here right now.
Yes. he is. Yes. he is.
Show business.
Razzle-dazzle. Razzle-dazzle.
Do your greatest show for me.
Turn chaos into harmony.
- And if l refuse?
- For all eternity.
you will be. you will be...
Fried and flambéed.
Baked and sautéed.
- Steamed and stewed.
- Then.
- Barbecued
- Grilled and roasted.
- Then.
Lightly toasted.
- Then. then. then. then.
- Then. what?
Fucked up the ass
with barbed wire.
OK. so that's the downside.
So. what's the upside if l succeed
in this? What's in it for me?
Not getting ass-fucked
with barbed wire.
So. what are the hours?
Jerry is going to hell.
- No. no. no. no. no.
- Hot enough for ya?
Hot enough for ya?
- Jerry's going...
- No!
..to hell.
Hell.
Hot enough for ya?
Demons and devils.
incubi and succubi
and princes and princesses of hell.
welcome for one night only
or perhaps for all eternity.
He's bigger than the planet earth.
Bigger than the biggest big.
Biggie. biggie. biggie. big.
Biggie. biggie. biggie. biggie. big.
- Lo! He comes.
- Jerry. Jerry. Jerry. Jerry.
Laudamus Jerry.
- Te adoremus.
- Biggie. biggie. big.
Laudamus Jerry.
- Te adoremus.
- Biggie. biggie. big.
Big.
Steve. this all seems
strangely familiar.
Baby Jane.
- So. what am l supposed to do?
- Just say the cards.
Hello and welcome to a very special
edition of The Jerry Sprínger Show.
That's me. That's my show.
You know. from time immemorial.
heaven and hell have been at war.
But is there a way of reconciling
the irreconcilable
and giving both parties some sense
of closure and a chance to move on?
Hey. wait a minute.
Look. l don't do. never have done
and never will do
conflict resolution.
- Then you will fy.
- Please welcome my first guest.
the Prince of Darkness. Satan.
- Satan. Satan.
- Go. Satan. go.
Satan. Satan.
Satan. Satan. Satan. Satan.
Satan. Satan. Sa...
Once in happy realms of light.
l was transcendental.
golden
and bright.
Bright.
But l rebelled and was cast down.
forced to surrender
my celestial crown.
Oh.
My Crown.
Then God hurled me from the skies.
not merciful enough
to let
me die.
Let me die.
Confounded.
immortal l.
Paradise
lost
and pain eternal.
Pain eternal.
You seem upset.
So. what exactly do you want?
l want it to be just like old times.
with Baby Jesus by my side.
l want my old wings back. as well.
Wanna get out of this dump
called hell.
But first and most importantly.
l want a fucking apology.
- Apology.
- An apology?
You instigated a coup d'état
against God in heaven.
You went down to earth and you led
mankind into a whole world of shit.
And you want me to get
the good guys to apologise to you?
Are you out of your mind?
How in hell am l supposed to do that?
Just read the cards.
This is your handwriting. l suppose.
Let's see if we can get an apology
from my next guest.
the hypocrite son
of the fascist tyrant on high.
Jesus of Nazareth.
Jesus. Jesus. what the fuck?
Coming here. pushing his luck.
Make him wear a thorny crown.
Grab his pants and pull them down.
Old friend.
old foe.
l missed you.
Jesus. what a beautiful moment.
Jesus.
Satan has something
he wants to say to you.
Go ahead. Satan.
Fu...
Fu... Fu-Fu...
Fu... Fu...
Ta...
Fu...
- Fu...
- Ta...
- Fu...uu-uu...
- Ta...aa-aa...
- Fu...
- Ta...
Ta...
Fu...
- Ta...
- Fu...
- Fu-Fu-Fu-Fu... Fu-Fu-Fu-Fu...
- Ta...
- Fu-Fu-Fu-Fu-Fu-Fu-Fu-Fu...
- Fu...
- Ta...
- Fu-Fu-Fu...
- Fu-Fu-Fu-Fu...
- T!
- Ta...
- Fu-Fu... Fu-Fu...
- T!
Fu-Fu...ck
you.
Talk to the
stigmata.
Always has to have the last word.
That's right.
- Apologise.
- Son of Man.
lt ain't gonna happen.
Sit down on your ass.
Jesus. Jesus. Jesus!
Give me a second.
Satan. what are you doing here?
You're making the situation worse.
Jesus has flown a long way
to be here today.
This is not his neighbourhood.
Show him a little courtesy.
So he turned some water into wine.
Ooh!
So he walked across
the frickin' seas.
Ooh!
So you got yourself crucified.
Here's a little biscuit from me.
l am Jesus.
Son of Man.
son of Mary.
son of God.
So do not.
do not.
do not fuck with me!
Ooh. scared.
l do not want your biscuit.
l want your love
and your respect.
For l am love
and l love all mankind.
- Jesus is gay.
- Pathetic!
- Gimme a break!
G-A-Y. gay! G-A-Y. gay!
Actually.
l am a bit gay.
G-A-Y. gay! G-A-Y. gay!
- G-A-Y. gay! G-A-Y. gay!
- Satan.
Satan.
between you and me.
if you want to achieve anything here.
you and your people are going
to have to work with me on this.
Just read the cards.
Oh. Jesus!
You call yourself Jesus
but you are not worthy of the name.
- Who wrote this shit?
- The cards.
Let's meet two other guests who are
also after an apology from Jesus.
He was fashioned
from a lump of clay.
And she showed kindness to a snake.
The mother and father of humanity.
Adam and Eve.
Put your fucking clothes on.
you stupid bitch.
- Don't you touch me...
- You stupid bitch!
- ..or l'll kill you in your sleep.
- You stupid bitch.
- Cocksucker. Talk to the ass.
- You look ridiculous.
- Talk to the ass.
- She looks ridiculous.
Welcome to the show.
How's the relationship going?
All women are whores.
Whores or sluts or prostitutes.
He don't know shit.
He's just a piece of...
- Shut it. Slut!
- Shut it. Gimp!
Whatever.
Putting aside your domestic
grievances for just a moment.
Eve. what is it
you want to say to Jesus?
- For one little apple...
- Don't talk to me. Talk to Jesus.
For one little apple
on a little tree.
we get a life of grief and misey.
She made me do it.
made me do it.
You had your chance and you blew it.
Forbidden fruit.
But vegetables allowed.
- God's plan.
- One little apple.
- Just a little apple.
- She made me do it. made me do it.
- God's plan. God's plan.
Just a little apple.
One little apple.
- Just a little apple.
- Blame it on the snake. man.
One little apple.
- Just a little apple.
- God's plan.
What the fuck? What the fuck?
What the fucking. fucking fuck?
That's just great. Jesus.
You hit a woman.
l think you should
apologise to her.
You followed the way
of ambition and vanity.
But it was me
who had to redeem humanity.
You're weeping now
but you didn't give a toss
when l was crying out.
crying out.
crying out on the cross.
On the cross.
- On the cross.
- Always with the crucifixion.
Whatever!
That was 2,000 years ago.
lnstead of banging on about it.
why don't you get over it
and give us all a fucking break?
Enough of this shit. Get on with it.
l'm trying to get on with it.
l'm trying to get you your apology.
but this is an impossible situation.
Fucked up the ass
with barbed wire.
l'm not going to read this.
There's no point.
Barbed wire.
Well. Satan.
we've got a surprise guest
who wants to give
her version of events.
Please welcome the teenage mother
of Jesus. Mary.
Raped by an angel.
Raped by God.
What exactly are you saying here?
Where were you when l was on my own?
Where were you
when they rolled the stone?
when l was getting old?
Where were you
when l was sick and bald?
Where? Where?
Where were you?
- Where were you?
- Jesus wasn't there. He didn't care.
Where were you
when the children cried?
when the children died?
Where were you when l was crucified?
Where were you
when they pierced my side?
Where?
- Where were you?
- Wasn't there. Didn't care.
Where? Where?
Where were you?
Doesn't know. Didn't show.
Never there. Doesn't care!
Where were you when he got fleas?
Where were you when he lost his keys?
Where were you
when her pants don't fit?
Where were you when the condom split?
- Is it me?
- When the condom split.
- Somebody help me out here.
You really gotta help me out.
l don't know what to do.
We're tired of laughing
and we're tired of crying.
We're tired of failing.
- We're tired of all this trying.
- l don't know what to do.
We wanna do some living
cos we've done enough dying.
So come on. Jerry Springer.
- and just read the fucking cards.
- l don't have any cards.
Cards.
Just read the fucking cards.
- l don't have any more cards!
- Well. neither do l.
l can't get you your apologies.
This isn't fair. It's a set-up!
There's no way of solving this.
short of a miracle.
Behold God!
We are beholding him.
- Then. behold him more!
- What?
- Behold him more!
- God?
Oh. thank God.
Thank God. you're here.
lt ain't easy being me.
lt so ain't easy being me.
Billions of voices
making all the wrong choices.
then turning round and blaming me.
l tell ya.
it ain't easy being me.
- It ain't easy being him.
- It ain't.
- It so ain't easy being him.
Billions of voices
making all the wrong choices.
lt...
lt ain't easy being me.
God.
You weren't on Satan's list
of guests. What are you doing here?
What do you want?
Sit in heaven beside me.
Hold my hand and guide me.
Cos it ain't easy being me.
ln fact. it's diflicult.
Sit in heaven beside you.
hold your hand and guide you?
Well. that's a no-brainer!
l'm your man. And. Satan.
You can take that barbed wire
and stick it up your own ass.
Back into your sky.
- Jerry stays here to fry.
- No. no. no. no.
- Fry!
- He's mine.
- l don't think so. l don't think so.
He's mine. l don't think so.
- He's mine. He's mine.
- l don't think so. l don't think so.
l don't think so.
What the fuck?
- Fry!
- Save us. Jerry. Save us. Jerry.
- Steve. do something.
Seize the day and act. Jerry.
Burn. Jerry. Burn. Jerry.
Jerry. burn.
Anybody. help!
Burn. Jerry. Burn. Jerry.
Jerry's gonna fry. Jerry's gonna fry.
Wait! Wait!
At least give me one chance
to sort this out.
l have a dream.
l have a dream where eveyone here
turns to their neighbour
and shakes them by the hand and says.
''You know.
you're not such a bad guy.''
''Why don't you come on over?
My wife's making meat loaf.''
- Seize the day.
- Burn. Jerry. Burn. Jerry.
Wait. wait! At least give me
a second chance to sort this out.
Four score and seven years ago.
our forefathers brought forth
on this continent
a new nation conceived in liberty.
conceived in freedom
and in...
other abstract concepts.
like smell. l-l...
- Burn. Jerry.
- Wait. wait. wait. wait. wait.
At least give me a third chance
to sort this out.
There's just one thing l want to say
to eveyone here today.
Please.
Please don't kill me. Please.
- Seize the day.
- Burn. Jerry. Burn. Jerry.
What the heck! Go ahead and burn me
if it makes you happy. See if l care.
You're never gonna agree
on eveything.
And what's so bad about that?
Satan. you're never gonna get
your apologies.
And. God. you just don't get
a shoulder to cry on.
And. Jesus.
Grow up. for Christ's sake.
and put some fucking clothes on.
Haven't you people
heard of yin and yang.
love and hate.
attraction and repulsion?
lt's the human condition
we're talking about here.
Energy is pure delight.
Nothing is wrong
and nothing is right.
And everything that lives is holy.
And. in conclusion.
fuck you.
Fuck you all!
Eveything that lives
is holy.
Energy
is delight.
We stand together.
joined.
joined in might.
Energy is pure delight.
Nothing is wrong
and nothing is right.
Energy is pure delight.
Nothing is wrong
and nothing is right.
Let poets through the ages tell
how Springer united
heaven and hell.
What did l say?
This is his Jerry Springer moment.
Him don't want him moment to die.
Die. die. die. die.
So dip him in chocolate
and throw him to the lesbians.
Him don't want him moment to die.
This is his Jerry Springer moment.
So dip him in chocolate
and throw him to the lesbians.
Him don't want him moment
Him don't want him
Him don't. him don't.
him don't. him don't...
Jerry.
it is finished.
Excuse me?
You're free.
Say what?
Free.
You know what. Baby Jane?
l like it here in hell.
l think l'm gonna stay.
l'm not confused here.
For the first time. l'm not confused
about anything any more.
Goodbye.
Jerry.
Jerry eleíson.
Eleíson.
l've been shot.
l'm confused.
Why would l get shot?
Please don't die.
Jerry.
You shot me in the chest.
Why would you shoot me in the chest
after eveything l've achieved?
Please don't die.
Jerry.
Accidentally shot
by a man in a diaper
trying to kill a member of
the Ku Klux Klan.
Not exactly the epitaph
l was hoping for.
Still. it might look good in Latin.
Who will speak for us?
- What do you mean?
- When you are gone.
You've got lots of people out there.
You got Oprah Winfrey.
She's too tame.
Sally Jesse Raphael.
She's too old.
Dr. Phil.
He's too shit.
Ricki Lake.
l guess she's OK.
Now. if you don't mind.
l think l'll ty to get
to a hospital.
Wait. Jerry.
Final thoughts.
Well. firstly.
l'd like to add my name
to the list of celebrities
calling for tighter gun control.
Secondly. it's been a helluva day.
l've learned that there
are no absolutes of good and evil
and that we all live
in a glorious state of flux.
What can l say?
You're not looking
at a dying man here.
You're looking at yourselves
in a matter of months or years
or whatever.
And. for better or for worse.
history defines us by what we do
and what we choose not to do.
Hopefully.
what will survive of us is love.
So. until the next time.
take care of yourselves
and each other.
Ta...
Take care of yourselves
and each other.
Take care
Take care of yourselves
and each other.
Take care of yourselves.
yourselves.
and each other.
Take. take care of yourselves
Take care of each other.
Take care of yourselves.
Take care of
Ta...
Each other.
Take care of yourselves
and each other.
Take...
lt ain't easy being me.
lt so ain't easy being me.
Billions of voices
making all the wrong choices.
then turning round and blaming me.
l tell ya.
it ain't easy being...
Jer...
Jerry.
l've been seeing
someone else.
someone
else.
lt ain't easy
being me.
lt so ain't easy
Billions of voices
making all the wrong choices.
then turning round
and blaming me.
- Me.
l tell ya.
it ain't easy being
Me.
Momma gimme smack on the asshole.
Momma gimme smack every night.
Everything will be alright.
Have yourselves a good time.
We just wanna dance.
We just wanna. we just wanna.
we just wanna...
Talk to the hand.
- Cos the face ain't listening.
- Talk to the hand.
Cos the face ain't listening.
l'm a man. l'm a man.
- Talk to the hand.
- Cos the face ain't listening.
Talk
to the
Talk to the
ha-a-and!
Talk
to the
Talk to the
hand.
What the fuck? What the fuck?
What the fucking. fucking fuck?
Three-nippled cousin-fucker.
What the fuck? What the fuck?
- Three-nippled cousin-fucker.
- What the fuck?
Three-nippled cousin-fucker.
What the fuck? What the fuck?
- What the fuck? What the fuck?
- Three-nippled cousin-fucker.
- What the fuck?
- Three-nippled.
- Cousin-fucker.
What the fuck? What the fuck?
- We just wanna dance.
- What?
- We just. we just...
- We just wanna fucking dance.
This is our Jerry Springer moment.
We don't want this moment
to die. die. die.
Die. D-D-Die.
Dip us.
why don't you dip us in chocolate?
Ch-Ch-Ch-Chocolate.
- Throw us to the lesbians.
- Lesbians.
Whoo!
We don't want this moment.
moment. moment.
moment.
moment
to
die.