As around 20,000 people
took part in a protest against...
Meanwhile,
hundreds of anti-capitalist protestors...
REPORTER 1 : Society continues to generate
waste and squander resources.
REPORTER 2: This is a global issue.
REPORTER 3: John, what's your view
on the oil market's reaction?
l mean, earlier today, we were...
Hundreds of anti-war activists...
REPORTER 4:
...Spain and Greece and right across Europe...
...resorted to using gas, stun grenades
and rubber bullets
to disperse the angry crowd.
MALE PROTESTOR: Hey, stop filming!
The police can use it!
Stay back! Stay back!
REPORTER 5: But the tough economy
is pushing people to the brink.
The question remains, are there...
# My mind is clearer now
# At last, all too well
# l can see
# Where we all soon will be
# lf you strip away
# The myth from the man
# You will see
# Where we all soon will be
# Jesus!
# You've started to believe
the things they say of you
# You really do believe
this talk of God is true
# And all the good you've done
will soon get swept away
# You've begun to matter more
# Than the things you say
# Listen, Jesus
l don't like what l see
# All l ask is that you listen to me
# And remember
# l've been your right-hand man all along
# You have set them all on fire
# They think they've found the new Messiah
# And they'll hurt you
when they find they're wrong
# l remember when this whole thing began
# No talk of God then
We called you a man
# And believe me
# My admiration for you hasn't died
# But every word you say today
# Just gets twisted 'round some other way
# And they'll hurt you if they think you've lied
# Nazareth, your famous son
should have stayed a great unknown
# Like his father carving wood
he'd have made good
# Tables, chairs and oaken chests
would have suited Jesus best
# He'd have caused nobody harm
No one alarm
# Listen, Jesus
Do you care for your race?
# Can't you see
we must keep in our place?
# We are occupied
# Have you forgotten how far down we are?
# l am frightened by the crowd
# For we are getting much too loud
# They will crush us if we go too far
# lf we go too far
# Listen, Jesus, to the warning l give
# Please remember that l want us to live
# But it's sad to see our chances
# Weakening with every hour
# All of your followers are blind
# They've too much heaven on their minds
# It was beautiful, but now it's sour
# Yes, it's all gone sour
# Listen, Jesus, to the warning l give
# Please remember that l want us to live
# Come on, come on
# He won't listen to me, oh
# So, it's all
# Gone
# Sour#
# What's the buzz?
Tell me what's a-happening
# Why should you want to know?
# Don't you mind about the future
# Don't you try to think ahead
# Save tomorrow for tomorrow
# Think about today instead
# What's the buzz?
Tell me what's a-happening
# l could give you facts and figures
# What's the buzz?
Tell me what's a-happening
# l could give you plans and forecasts
# When do we ride to Jerusalem?
# Even tell you where l'm goin'
# Why should you want to know?
# Why are you obsessed with fighting
# Times and fates you can't defy?
# lf you knew the path we're riding
# You'd understand it less than l
# What's the buzz?
Tell me what's a-happening
# Let me try to cool down your face a bit
Let me try to cool down your face a bit
# Let me try, let me try
Try to cool down your face a bit
# Let me try to cool down your face a bit
Let me try to cool down your face a bit
# Let me try, let me try
# Mary, ooh, that is good
# While you prattle through your supper
# Where and when and who and how
# She alone has tried to give me
# What l need right here and now
# What's the buzz?
Tell me what's a-happening
Tell me what's a-happening #
# lt seems to me a strange thing
# Mystifying
# That a man like you should waste his time
# On women of her kind
# Yes, I can understand that
# She amuses
# But to let her stroke you and kiss your hair
# lt's hardly in your line
# lt's not that l object to her profession
# But she doesn't fit in well
with what we teach and say
# lt doesn't help us if you're inconsistent
# They only need a small excuse
# To put us all away
# Who are you to criticise her?
# Who are you to despise her?
# Leave her, leave her
Let her be now
She's with me now
# lf your slate is clean
then you can throw stones
# lf your slate is not, then leave her alone!
# l'm amazed that men like you
# Can be so shallow, thick and slow
# There is not a man among you
who knows or cares if l come or go
# No, you're wrong
You're very wrong
# How can you say that?
# How can you say that? #
Not one of you!
# Try not to get worried
# Try not to turn onto
# Problems that upset you
# Don't you know everything's all right?
# Yes, everything's fine
# And we want you to sleep well tonight
# Let the world turn without you tonight
# lf we try, we'll get by
so forget all about us tonight
# Everything's all right, yes
# Sleep and l shall soothe you
# Calm you and anoint you
# Myrrh for your hot forehead
# Then you'll feel everything's all right
# Yes, everything's fine
# And it's cool and the ointment's sweet
# For the fire in your head and feet
# Close your eyes, close your eyes
# And relax, think of nothing tonight
# Everything's all right, yes
# Woman, your fine ointment
Brand-new and expensive
# Could have been saved for the poor
# Why has it been wasted?
# We could have raised maybe
# 300 silver pieces or more
# People who are hungry
# People who are starving
# Matter more than your
# Feet and hair
# Try not to get worried
# Try not to turn onto
# Problems that upset you
# Don't you know everything's all right?
# Yes, everything's fine
# And we want you to sleep well tonight
# Let the world turn without you tonight
# lf we try, we'll get by
so forget all about us tonight
# Everything's all right, yes
# Surely you're not saying
# We have the resources
# To save the poor from their lot?
# There will be poor
always pathetically struggling
# Look at the good things you've got!
# Think while you still have me
# Move while you still see me
# You'll be lost and you'll be so, so sorry
# When l'm gone
# Sleep and l shall soothe you
# Calm you and anoint you
# Myrrh for your hot forehead
# Then you'll feel everything's all right, yes
# Everything's fine
# And it's cool and the ointment's sweet
# For the fire in your head and feet
# Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax
# Think of nothing
# Tonight
# Close your eyes, close your eyes and relax
# Think of nothing
# Everything's all right, yes
# Close your eyes, close your eyes and relax
# Everything's all right, yes #
ANNAS: # Good Caiaphas
# The Council waits for you
# The Pharisees
# And priests are here for you
# Ah, gentlemen
# You know why we are here
# We've not much time
# And quite a problem here
# Hosanna! Superstar!
# Listen to that howling mob
# Of blockheads in the street
# A trick or two with lepers
# And the whole town's on its feet
# He is dangerous!
# Jesus Christ, Superstar
# Tell us that
you're who they say you are
# That man is in town right now
# To whip up some support
# A rabble-rousing mission
# That l think we must abort
# He is dangerous!
# Jesus Christ
# Superstar
# He is dangerous!
# Look, Caiaphas
They're right outside our yard
# Quick, Caiaphas
Go call the Roman guard
No, wait!
# We need a more permanent solution
to our problem
# What then to do about Jesus of Nazareth?
# Miracle wonderman, hero of fools
# No riots, no army
# No fighting, no slogans
# Infantile sermons, the multitude drools
# We dare not leave him to his own devices
# His half-witted fans will get out of control
# But how do we stop him?
His glamour increases
# By leaps every minute
# He's top of the pole
# l see bad things arising
# The crowd crown him king
which the Romans would ban
# l see blood and destruction
# Our elimination because of one man
# Blood and destruction because of one man
# Because, because
because of one man
# Our elimination because of one man
# Because, because, because of one
# 'Cause of one, 'cause of one man
# What then to do about this Jesus mania?
# How do we deal with the carpenter king?
# Where do we start with a man who is bigger
# Than John was
when John did his baptism thing?
# Fools, you have no perception
# The stakes we are gambling
are frighteningly high
# We must crush him completely
# So like John before him
this Jesus must die
# For the sake of the nation
# Must die, must die
this Jesus must die
# So like John before him
# Must die, must die
This Jesus must, Jesus must
# Jesus must
# Die #
# Hosanna, heysanna, sanna, sanna, ho
# Sanna, heysanna, hosanna
# Hey, J.C., J.C.
# Won't you fight for me?
# Sanna, hosanna, hey, superstar
# Tell the rabble to be quiet
# We anticipate a riot
# This common crowd
# ls much too loud
# Tell the mob who sing your song
# That they are fools and they are wrong
# They are a curse
# They should disperse
# Hosanna, heysanna, sanna, sanna, ho
# Sanna, heysanna, hosanna
# Hey, J.C., J.C.
# You're all right by me
# Sanna, hosanna, hey, superstar
# Why waste your breath moaning
at the crowd?
# Nothing can be done to stop the shouting
# lf every tongue were still
# The noise would still continue
# The rocks and stones themselves
# Would start to sing
# Hosanna, heysanna, sanna, sanna, ho
# Sanna, heysanna, hosanna
# Hey, J.C., J.C.
# Won't you fight for me?
# Sanna, hosanna, hey, superstar
# Sing me a song, but not for me alone
CROWD: Yes, yes.
# Sing out for yourselves
# For you are blessed
# There is not one of you
# Who cannot win the Kingdom
# The slow, the suffering
# The quick, the dead
# Hosanna, heysanna, sanna, sanna, ho
# Sanna, heysanna, hosanna
# Hey, J.C., J.C.
# Won't you die for me?
# Sanna, hosanna, hey, superstar
# Superstar#
# Christ, you know l love you
Did you see l waved?
# l believe in you and God
so tell me that l'm saved
# Christ, you know l love you
Did you see l waved?
# l believe in you and God
so tell me that l'm saved
# Jesus, l am with you
Touch me, touch me, Jesus
# Jesus, l am on your side
Kiss me, kiss me, Jesus
# Christ, what more do you need
to convince you
# That you've made it
and you're easily as strong
# As the filth from Rome
who rape our country
# And who've terrorised our people
for so long?
# Christ, you know l love you
Did you see l waved?
# They love you
# l believe in you and God
so tell me that l'm saved
# Christ, you know l love you
Did you see l waved?
# l believe in you and God
so tell me that l'm saved
# Jesus, l am with you
Touch me, touch me, Jesus
# Jesus, l am on your side
Kiss me, kiss me, Jesus
# There must be over 50,000
# Screaming love and more for you
# And every one of 50,000
# Would do whatever you asked them to
# But keep them yelling their devotion
# Add a touch of hate at Rome
# You will rise to a greater power
# We will win ourselves a home
# You'll get the power and the glory
# You'll get the glory
# Forever and ever and ever
# You'll get the power
# You'll get the power and the glory
# You'll get the glory
# Forever and ever and ever
# And the power
# Neither you, Simon
# Nor the 50,000
# Nor the Romans
# Nor the Jews
# Nor Judas
# Nor the 12
# Nor the priests nor the scribes
# Nor doomed Jerusalem itself
# Understand what power is
# Understand what glory is
# Understand at all
# lf you knew
# All that l knew
# My poor Jerusalem
# You'd see the truth
# But you'd close your eyes
# While you live
# Your troubles are many
# Poor Jerusalem
# To conquer death
# You only have to die
# You only have to die #
# l dreamed l met a Galilean
# A most amazing man
# He had that look
# You very rarely find
# The haunting, hunted kind
# l asked him
# To say what had happened
# How it all began
# l asked again
# He never said a word
# As if he hadn't heard
# And next
# The room was full
# Of wild and angry men
# They seemed to hate this man
# They fell on him and then
# They disappeared again
# Then l saw
# Thousands of millions
# Crying for this man
# And then l heard them
# Mentioning my name
# And leaving me the blame #
# Roll on up for my price is down
Come on in for the best in town
# Take your pick of the finest wine
Lay your bets on this bird of mine
# Roll on up for my price is down
Come on in for the best in town
# Take your pick of the finest wine
Lay your bets on this bird of mine
# Name your price, l got everything
# Come and buy, it's all going fast
# Borrow cash on the finest terms
# Hurry now while stocks still last
# Roll on up, Jerusalem
# Here it isn't us and them
# While our temples still survive
# We at least are still alive
# Come all classes, come all creeds
# l can fix your wildest needs
# Name your pleasure l will sell
# l got heaven, l got hell
# What you see is what you get
# No one's been disappointed yet
# Don't be scared, give me a try
# There is nothing you can't buy
# Roll on up for my price is down
Come on in for the best in town
# Take your pick of the finest wine
Lay your bets on this bird of mine
# Roll on up for my price is down
Come on in for the best in town
# My temple should be
# A house of prayer
# But you have made it
# A den of thieves
Get out!
# My time
# ls almost through
# Little left to do
# l've tried for three years
# Seems like 30
# See my eyes, l can hardly see
# See me stand, l can hardly walk
# l believe you can make me whole
# See his tongue, he can hardly talk
# See my skin, l'm a mass of blood
# Change my life, oh, l know you can
# l believe you can make me well
# See my purse, l'm a poor, poor man
# Will you touch, will you mend me, Christ?
# Won't you touch, will you heal me, Christ?
# Will you kiss, you can cure me, Christ
# Won't you kiss, won't you pay me, Christ?
# See our eyes, we can hardly see
# See us stand, we can hardly walk
# We believe you can make us whole
# See the tongues that can hardly talk
# See our skin, we're a mass of blood
# Change our lives, oh, we know you can
# We believe you can make us well
# You're the hope of the poor, poor man
# Will you touch, will you mend me, Christ?
# Won't you touch, will you heal me, Christ?
# Will you kiss, you can cure me, Christ
# Won't you kiss, won't you pay me, Christ?
# See our eyes, we can hardly see
# See us stand, we can hardly walk
# We believe you can make us whole
# See the tongues that can hardly talk
# See our skin, we're a mass of blood
# Change our lives, oh, we know you can
# We believe you can make us well
# You're the hope of the poor, poor man
# Will you touch, will you mend me, Christ?
# Won't you touch, will you heal me, Christ?
# Will you kiss, you can cure me, Christ
# Won't you kiss, won't you pay me, Christ?
# See my eyes, we can hardly see
-Ah, there's too...
# See me stand, we can hardly walk
-..too many of you.
# l believe you can make us whole
-Don't...
# See my tongue that can hardly talk
-Ah, don't crowd me.
# See my skin, l'm a mass of blood
-Don't crowd me.
# See my legs, l can hardly stand
-Don't crowd me!
# We believe you can make us well
-Ah, don't crowd me.
# Won't you kiss, won't you pay me, Christ? #
-Heal yourselves!
# Try not to get worried
# Try not to turn onto
# Problems that upset you
# Oh, don't you know everything's all right?
# Yes, everything's fine
# And l think l shall sleep well tonight
# Let the world turn without me tonight
# lf we try, we'll get by
so forget all about us tonight #
# l don't know how to love him
# What to do
# How to move him
# l've been changed
# Yes, really changed
# ln these past few days
# When l've seen myself
# l seem like someone else
# l don't know how to take this
# l don't see why he moves me
# He's a man
# He's just a man
# And l've had so many men before
# ln very many ways
# He's just one more
# Should l bring him down
# Should l scream and shout
# Should l speak of love
# Let my feelings out?
# l never thought l'd come to this
# What's it all about?
# Don't you think it's rather funny
# l should be in this position?
# l'm the one
# Who's always been
# So calm, so cool
# No lover's fool
# Running every show
# He scares me so
# l never thought
# l'd come to this
# What's it all about?
# Yet if he said he loved me
# l'd be lost
# l'd be frightened
# l couldn't cope
# Just couldn't cope
# l'd turn my head
# l'd back away
# l wouldn't want to know
# He scares me so
# l want him so
# l love him
# So #
# Now if l help you, it matters that you see
# These sordid kind of things
are coming hard to me
# lt's taken me some time
to work out what to do
# l weighed the whole thing up
before l came to you
# l have no thought at all
about my own reward
# l really didn't come here of my own accord
# Just don't say l'm
# l came because l had to
l'm the one who saw
# Jesus can't control it like he did before
# And furthermore
l know that Jesus thinks so too
# Jesus wouldn't mind
that l'm here with you
# l have no thought at all
about my own reward
# l really didn't come here of my own accord
# Damned for all time!
# Annas, you're a friend
a worldly man and wise
# Caiaphas, my friend
l know you sympathise
# Why are we the prophets?
Why are we the ones?
# We see the sad solution
Know what must be done
# l have no thought at all
about my own reward
# l really didn't come here of my own accord
# Damned
# For all time!
# Cut the protesting
# Forget the excuses
# We want information
# Get up off the floor
# We have the papers
# We need to arrest him
# You know his movements
# We know the law
# Your help in this matter
won't go unrewarded
# We'll pay you in silver
Cash on the nail
# We just need to know
where our soldiers can find him
# With no crowd 'round him
# Then we can't fail
# l don't need your blood money
# Oh, that doesn't matter,
our expenses are good
# l don't want your blood money
# But you might as well take it
We think that you should
# Think of the things
you could do with that money
# Choose any charity, give to the poor
# We've noted your motives
We've noted your feelings
# This isn't blood money, it's a fee
# Just a fee
# On Thursday night
# You'll find him where you want him
# Far from the crowds
# ln the Garden
# Of Gethsemane
# Well done, Judas
# Good old Judas
# Good old Judas #
# Look at all my trials and tribulations
# Sinking in a gentle pool of wine
# Don't disturb me now
# l can see the answers
# Till this evening is this morning
# Life is fine
# Always hoped that l'd be an apostle
# Knew that l would make it if l tried
# Then when we retire
# We can write the Gospels
# So they'll still talk about us when we've died
# The end
# ls just a little harder
# When brought about
# For all you care
# This wine could be my blood
# Could be my body
# The end
# This is my blood you drink
# This is my body you eat
# lf you would, remember me
# When you eat and drink
# l must be mad, thinking l'll be remembered
# Yes, l must be out of my head!
# Look at your blank faces
# My name will mean nothing
# Ten minutes after l'm dead!
# One of you denies me
# One of you betrays me
# Peter will deny me in just a few hours
# Three times will deny me
# And that's not all l see
# One of you here dining
One of my 12 chosen
# Will leave to betray me
# Cut out the dramatics!
You know very well who
# Why don't you go do it?
# You want me to do it!
# Hurry, they are waiting
# lf you knew why l do it
# l don't care why you do it!
# To think l admired you
Well, now l despise you
# You liar, you Judas
# You wanted me to do it!
# What if l just stayed here
and ruined your ambition?
# Christ, you deserve it!
# Hurry, you fool
Hurry and go
# Save me your speeches
l don't want to know
# Go!
# Look at all my trials and tribulations
# Sinking in a gentle pool of wine
# What's that in the bread
# lt's gone to my head
# Till this morning is this evening
# Life is fine
# Always hoped that l'd be an apostle
# Knew that l would make it if l tried
# Then when we retire
# We can write the Gospels
# So they'll all talk about us when we've died
# You sad, pathetic man
# Look what you've brought us to
# Our ideals die around us
# And all because of you
# And now the saddest cut of all
# ls someone had to turn you in
# Like a common criminal
# Like a wounded animal
# A jaded mandarin
# Like a jaded mandarin
# Get out! They're waiting!
# Get out!
# They're waiting!
# Oh, they're waiting for you!
# Every time l look at you
# l don't understand
# Why you let the things you did
get so out of hand
# You'd have managed better
# lf you'd had it planned
# Why?
# Look at all my trials and tribulations
# Sinking in a gentle pool of wine
# Don't disturb me now
# l can see the answers
# Till this evening is this morning
# Life is fine
# Always hoped that l'd be an apostle
# Knew that l would make it if l tried
# Then when we retire
# We can write the Gospels
# So they'll still talk about us when we've died
# Will no one stay awake with me?
# Peter?
# John?
# James?
# Will none of you wait with me?
# Peter?
# John?
# James? #
# l only want to say
# lf there is a way
# Take this cup away from me
# For l don't want to taste its poison
# Feel it burn me
# l have changed
# l'm not as sure
# As when we started
# Then, l was inspired
# Now
# l'm sad and tired
# Listen
# Surely l've exceeded expectations
# l tried for three years
# Seems like 30
# Could you ask as much
# From any other man?
# But if l die
# See the saga through
# And do the things you ask of me
# Let them hate me, hit me, hurt me
# Nail me to their tree
# l'd want to know
l'd want to know, my God
# l'd want to see
l'd want to see, my God
# Why l should die
# Would l be more noticed
# Than l ever was before?
# Would the things l've said and done
# Matter any more?
# l'd have to know
l'd have to know, my Lord
# l'd have to see
l'd have to see, my Lord
# lf l die, what would be my reward?
# Have to know
Have to know, my Lord
# Why
# Should l die?
# Can you show me now
# That l would not be killed in vain?
# Show me just a little
# Of your omnipresent brain
# Show me there's a reason
# For your wanting me to die
# You're far too keen on where and how
# And not so hot on why
# All right
# l'll die!
# Just watch me die!
# See how l die!
# Then
# l was inspired
# Now
# l'm sad and tired
# l've tried for three years
# Seems like 90
# Why then am l scared to finish
# What l started
# What you started?
# l didn't start it
# God, Thy will be done
# Take your only son
# l will drink your cup of poison
# Nail me to your cross
# And break me
# Bleed me
# Beat me, kill me
# Take me now
# Before l change my mind
# Now
# Before l change my mind #
# There he is
# They're all asleep, the fools
# Judas, must you betray me
# With a kiss?
# What's the buzz?
Tell me what's happening
# Tell me what's happening
# What's the buzz?
Tell me what's happening
# Hang on, Lord
We're gonna fight for you
# You hang on, Lord
# Put away your sword
# Don't you know that it's all over?
# lt was nice, but now it's gone
# Why are you obsessed with fighting?
# Stick to fishing from now on
# Tell me, Christ, how you feel tonight
# Do you plan to put up a fight?
# Do you feel that you've had the breaks?
# What would you say
were your big mistakes?
# How do you view your coming trial?
# Have your men proved at all worthwhile?
# Did you pick an efficient team?
# ls that it for the Jewish dream?
# Come with us to see Caiaphas
# You'll just love the high priest's house
# You'll just love seeing Caiaphas
# You'll just die in the high priest's house
# Come on, God, this is not like you
# Let us know what you're gonna do
# You know what your supporters feel
# You'll escape in the final reel
# Tell me, Christ, how you feel tonight
# Do you plan to put up a fight?
# Do you feel that you had the breaks?
# What would you say
were your big mistakes?
# Come with us to see Caiaphas
# You'll just love the high priest's house
# You'll just love seeing Caiaphas
# You'll just die in the high priest's house
# Now we have him, now we've got him
# Now we have him now
We have got him now
# Jesus, you must realise
# The serious charges facing you
# You say you're the son of God
in all your handouts
# Well, is it true?
# That's what you say
You say that l am
# There you have it, gentlemen
# What more evidence do you need?
# Judas, thank you for the victim
# Stay a while and you'll see him bleed!
# Now we have him, now we've got him
# Take him to Pilate, take him to Pilate!
# l think l've seen you somewhere
# l remember
# You were with that man they took away
# l recognise your face
# You've got the wrong man, lady
# l don't know him
# And l wasn't where he was tonight
# Never near the place
# That's strange
for l am sure l saw you with him
# You were right by his side
and yet you denied
# l tell you, l was never, ever with him
# But l saw you, too
lt looked just like you
# l don't know him!
# Peter
# Don't you know what you have said?
# You've gone and cut him dead
# l had to do it
# Don't you see?
# Or else they'd go for me
# lt's what he told us you would do
# l wonder how he knew #
# Who is
# This broken man
# Cluttering up
# My hallway?
# Who is this unfortunate
# Someone, Christ, King of the Jews
# Oh, so this is Jesus Christ
# l am really quite surprised
# You look so small
# Not a king at all
We all know that you are news
# But are you King?
# King of the Jews?
# That's what you say
# What do
# You mean by that?
# That is not an answer
# You're deep
# In trouble, friend
# Someone, Christ, King of the Jews
# How can someone in your state
# Be so cool about his fate?
# An amazing thing
# This silent king
# Since you come from Galilee
# Then you need not come to me
# You're Herod's race
# He's Herod's case
# Hosanna, heysanna
# Sanna, sanna, ho
# Sanna, heysanna, hosanna
# Hey, J.C., J.C.
# Please explain to me
# You had everything
# Where is it now? #
# Jesus
# l am overjoyed
# To meet you face-to-face
# You've been getting quite a name
# All around the place
# Healing cripples
# Raising from the dead
That's pretty good.
# And now l understand you're God
# At least that's what he said
# So
# You are the Christ
# You're the great Jesus Christ
# Prove to me that you're divine
# Change my water into wine
# That's all you need do
# And l'll know it's all true
# Come on, King of the Jews
# Jesus, you just won't believe
the hit you've made around here
# You are all we talk about,
the wonder of the year
# But, oh, what a pity if it's all a lie
# Still l'm sure
that you can rock the cynics if you try
# So if you are the Christ
# Yes, the great Jesus Christ
# Prove to me that you're no fool
# Walk across my swimming pool
# lf you do that for me
# Then l'll let you go free
# Come on, King of the Jews
# So you decide
# ls he the Lord
or is he a fraud?
# Text our number now
We'll see you after the break
# l only ask things
l'd ask any superstar
# What is it that you have got
that puts you where you are?
# Oh, l am waiting
# Yes, l'm a captive fan
# l'm dying to be shown
that you are not just any man
# So if you are the Christ
# Yes, the great Jesus Christ
# Feed my household with this bread
# You can do it on your head
# Or has something gone wrong?
Why do you take so long?
# Come on, King of the Jews!
# Hey, aren't you
# Scared of me, Christ?
# Mr Wonderful Christ
# You're a joke! You're not the Lord
You are nothing but a fraud
# Take him away
# He's got nothing to say!
# Get out, you King of the
# Get out, you King of the Jews! #
Thank you for watching
the show tonight.
Join me tomorrow
when l'll be interviewing One Direction.
Thank you, Birmingham,
and good night.
# l've been living to see you
# Dying to see you
but it shouldn't be like this
# This was unexpected
# What do l do now?
# Could we start again, please?
# l've been very hopeful so far
# Now for the first time
# l think we're going wrong
# Hurry up and tell me
# This is all a dream
# Or could we start again, please?
# Could we start again, please?
# l think you've made your point now
# You've even gone a bit too far
# To get your message home
# Before it gets too frightening
# We ought to call a halt
# So could we start again, please?
# Could we start again, please?
# l've been living to see you
# Dying to see you
but it shouldn't be like this
# This was unexpected
# What do l do now?
# Could we start again, please?
# l think you've made your point now
# You've even gone a bit too far
to get your message home
# Before it gets too frightening
# We ought to call a halt
# So could we start again, please?
# Could we start again, please?
# Could we start again?
MAN: Guards!
# My God, l saw him
# He looked three-quarters dead
and he was so bad, l had to turn my head
# They beat him so hard
that he was bent and lame
# And l know who everybody's gonna blame
# l don't believe he knows l acted for our good
# l'd save him all this suffering if l could
# Don't believe our good
# l'd save him if l could
# Cut the confession, forget the excuses
# l don't understand
why you're filled with remorse
# All that you've said
has come true with a vengeance
# The mob turned against him
You backed the right horse
# What you have done
will be the saving of lsrael
# You'll be remembered forever for this
# And not only that
You've been paid for your efforts
# Pretty good wages for one little kiss
# Christ, l know you can't hear me
# But l only did what you wanted me to
# Christ, l'd sell out the nation
# For l have been saddled
with the murder of you
# l have been spattered with innocent blood
# l shall be dragged
through the slime and the mud
# l have been spattered with innocent blood
# l shall be dragged
through the slime and the slime and the
# Slime and the mud
# l
# Don't know how to love him
# l don't know why he moves me
# He's a man
# He's just a man
# He is not a king
# He's just the same
# As anyone l know
# He scares me so
# When he's cold and dead
# Will he let me be?
Does he love
# Does he love me, too?
# Does he care for me?
# My mind is in darkness now
# Oh, God, l am sick!
# l've been used!
# And you knew all the time!
# God!
I will never, ever know
# Why you chose me
# For your crime!
# For your bloody crime!
# You have murdered me!
# Jesus!
# Poor old Judas
# So long, Judas
# And so the King
# ls once again my guest
# And why is this?
# Was Herod unimpressed?
# We turn to Rome
# To sentence Nazareth
# We have no law
# To put a man to death
# We need him crucified
# lt's all you have to do
# Talk to me, Jesus Christ
You have been brought here
# Manacled, beaten by your own people
# Do you have the first idea
why you deserve it?
# Listen, King of the Jews
Where is your kingdom?
# Look at me
Am l a Jew?
# l have got no kingdom
# ln this world, l'm through
# Through, through
# Talk to me, Jesus Christ
# There may be a kingdom for me somewhere
# lf l only knew
# Then you are a king
# lt's what you say l am
# l look for truth and find that l get damned
# But what is truth?
Not easy to define
# We both have truths
Are yours the same as mine?
# Crucify him! Crucify him!
# What do you mean?
You'd crucify your king?
# We have no king but Caesar
# He's done no wrong
No, not the slightest thing
# We have no king but Caesar
Crucify him!
# Well, this is new
Respect for Caesar!
# Till now, this has been noticeably lacking
# Who is this Jesus? Why is he different?
# You Jews produce Messiahs by the sackful
# We need him crucified
lt's all you have to do
# Talk to me, Jesus Christ
# Look at your Jesus Christ
# l'll agree he's mad
# Ought to be locked up
# But that is not a reason to destroy him
# He's a sad little man, not a king or God
# Not a thief, I need a crime
# Kill him, he says he's God
He's a blasphemer
# He'll conquer you and us
and even Caesar
# Kill him!
# Crucify him! Crucify him!
# Behold the man, behold your shattered king
# We have no king but Caesar
# You hypocrites, you hate us more than him
Crucify him!
# I find no reason, I see no evil
# This man is harmless
so why does he upset you?
# He's just misguided, thinks he's important
# But to keep you vultures happy
l shall flog him!
# Crucify! Crucify!
-One!
-(SCREAMlNG)
Two!
Three!
Four!
Five!
Six!
Seven!
Eight!
Nine!
Ten!
Eleven!
Twelve!
Thirteen!
Fourteen!
Fifteen!
Sixteen!
Seventeen!
Eighteen!
Nineteen!
Twenty!
Twenty-one!
Twenty-two!
Twenty-three!
Twenty-four!
Twenty-five!
Twenty-six!
Twenty-seven!
Twenty-eight!
Twenty-nine!
Thirty!
Thirty-one!
Thirty-two!
Thirty-three!
Thirty-four!
Thirty-five!
Thirty-six!
Thirty-seven!
Thirty-eight!
Thirty-nine!
# Where are you from, Jesus?
# What do you want, Jesus?
# Tell me
# You've got to be careful
# You could be dead soon
# Could well be
# Why do you not speak
# When l have your life in my hands?
# How can you stay quiet?
# l don't believe you understand
# You have nothing in your hands
# Any power you have
comes to you from far beyond
# Everything is fixed, and you can't change it
# You're a fool, Jesus Christ!
# How can l help you?
# Pilate, crucify him! Crucify!
# Remember Caesar
# You have a duty to keep the peace
# So crucify him!
# Remember Caesar
# You'll be demoted, you'll be deported
# Crucify him!
# Remember Caesar
# You have a duty to keep the peace
So crucify him!
# Remember Caesar
# You'll be demoted, you'll be deported
# Crucify him!
# Remember Caesar
# You have a duty to keep the peace
So crucify him!
# Remember Caesar
# You'll be demoted, you'll be deported
# Crucify him!
# Don't let me stop
# Your great self-destruction
# Die if you want to
# You misguided martyr!
# l wash my hands
# Of your demolition
# Die if you want to
# You innocent puppet!
# Every time l look at you, l don't understand
# Why you let the things you did
get so out of hand
# You'd have managed better
if you'd had it planned
# Why'd you choose such
a backwards time and such a strange land?
# lf you'd come today
you would have reached a whole nation
# lsrael in 4 B.C. had no mass communication
# Don't you get me wrong
# Only wanna know
# Jesus Christ
# Who are you? What have you sacrificed?
# Superstar
# Do you think you're what they say you are?
# Jesus Christ
# Superstar
# Do you think you're what they say you are?
# What you think about your friends at the top
# Who do you think besides yourself's
the pick of the crop?
# Buddha, was he where it's at?
ls he where you are?
# Could Muhammad move a mountain,
baby, or did he just have good P.R.?
# Did you mean to die like that?
Was that a mistake
# Or did you know that your messy death
would be a record breaker?
# Don't you get me wrong
# Only wanna know
# Jesus Christ
# Who are you? What have you sacrificed?
# Jesus Christ Superstar
# Superstar
# Do you think you're what they say you are?
# Jesus Christ Superstar
# Do you think you're
# Do you think you're what they say you are?
# l only wanna know
# Tell me, tell me
# Won't you tell me, Jesus?
# Don't you get me wrong
# Only wanna, only wanna, only wanna know
# Only wanna know
God, forgive them.
They don't know what they're doing.
Where is my mother?
My God.
My God, why have you forsaken me?
l'm thirsty, l'm thirsty.
lt is finished.
Father,
into your hands
l commend
my spirit.
-Thank you.
-Thanks again.
Oh, my gosh.
l just don't know really what to say...
Thank you to everybody.
l mean, what an extraordinary thing for me
to see this brought back,
to where l'd hoped it would always be,
in a rock and roll arena.
And with this fabulous, fabulous cast.
One of the problems about being
in a rock venue is, um,
Tim will tell you, and Mel will tell you,
is that...
What happens is that about this time of night
the set gets moved, so we could be here...
And if l talked for hours
and l said thank you to everybody,
bits and pieces of the scenery would start
to be removed from underneath me,
so, um... And all of us.
So l'm gonna keep it very, very simple
and l'd like to say
thank you to our fantastic cast.
And Laurence Connor,
who directed the show so brilliantly.
And our wonderful live rock band.
We are live, remember that.
And just before they clear the set away...
This may sound very, very strange.
l would like to dedicate this performance
to one person
who was with me when Superstar was written.
Her name was Sarah, and l'd like to say,
if you're in the audience, Sarah,
thank you for coming.
Thank you, all of you.