Welcome sir
Come, we were just waiting for you
Karthik has sent you a gift
It's over, he's dead
'A few months before...'
Hello, I'm out...
I'm coming in
Hi viewers, welcome back to
'Start Camera, Action'
Now we are in the semi-final round,
and things have gotten tougher
because every contestant
have created...
...an unique short film of its kind
on a specific genre
Just before the Ad-break
We all enjoyed watching the short film
directed by our contestant Karthik
Hey, where the hell you've been?
Quick, walk fast
Don't stop, keep walking
Keep moving man!
Before the Ad-break we
watched your short film
We have got 4 contestants in
this exciting semifinals
And only three of them
can reach the finals
One of the contestants
has to be eliminated
So Karthik, how are you
feeling at this moment?
Alright! I believe you are bit tensed
Let's listen to the comments about
your film from our 2 esteemed judges
National award winning director
- Mr Mukhil
Blueberry Productions producer
- Mr Sundar
Mukhil sir, your comments
on Karthik's film
Rubbish movie
'Cold Heart'
Sundar sir, your comments please
Out of all the films I watched here,
This is the best!
It may look rubbish for
the experienced director,
But for my eyes it looks great
This film is the best
Because of producers like you,
Our cinema industry is on it's downfall
Because of directors like you...
commenting every movie as rubbish
is the reason for it's downfall
But I'm not a fool like you
I'm a fool to produce your movie
Didn't you beg me
to make a movie?
You keep quiet
- Did I knock at your door for a chance?
- If talks anymore, you'll get my swears
Sir, please let's talk and sort it out
Sir, I didn't mean that way
Wait for a while, sir
He's getting sacred of me
How dare him call me a fool
Why the hell did you invite me?
- Sir...
- Shut up
Shut the camera!
Sir, let's adjust and finish it off
This argument is more than enough for
them to show case for 10 episodes
Why should I do this?
You know very well
that he is an idiot
Then why did you invite such an idiot?
That lunatic is calling me a fool...
You know very well
that he is an idiot
Then why did you invite such an idiot?
If you can give your judgment,
we can wrap up the show
Don't irritate me
I came here because your boss invited me
But you insulted very well
Ask him to tell the judgment
If you can give your judgment,
we can wrap up the show
I'll give my judgment, but make sure you
don't telecast the argument we had earlier
No sir! We won't
Please come in
I wont speak one more word
Sir, just come on to the stage,
we'll take care of the rest
Let's finish it off and leave
We have reached the end
of this semi-final round...
...3 of the contestants here
would move on to the finals
And the winner would be given a
chance to direct a feature film
Our judges will now announce the results
Let him announce
Mukhil sir, who is gonna
be eliminated today?
Given an option I would
eliminate all 4 of them
But as the situation demands
just one elimination...
...Karthik
...I reject you
Winning is just not about being
acclaimed by critic or reaching the finals
It's about making a profit
That is why we, producers, only can
determine the winning formula
I am telling right away,
I am gonna produce his film
Karthik, come by my office
tomorrow and collect your advance
I will produce your film
Idiotic semi-finals
Nonsense judgement
From today you are
a feature film director
It has been a big day
Today on our stage we got
a producer for Karthik's debut film
They've killed somebody
Look, what an atrocity!
No one came to help
even in middle of the day
I'm already very tensed
Just keep quiet
Yesterday I just uttered a few
words out of frustration
Believing that he has come
all the way to office
There has been reports of your act
in almost all newspapers
The boy's uncle is a reporter,
hence there is a half page coverage
What to do then?
Karthik?
Sir is calling you
Be confident and narrate your story
All the best
A train traveling at high speed
Let's have shots cut
at every station track
Then we 'll super impose
the title melody sound track here
Train sound...
Now he gets down
at the main train station
Goes straight to her
house but its locked
He breaks in with full force-
He finds her hanging to death, Right?
- Yes, sir
- I know
Finally it boils down to
killing the Actor to bag an award
Sir, it's not such an ordinary script
I have a strong message
in this movie that reflects...
...and questions the societal
problems of the world
After that, who will run
behind the law suits?
Look, you have substance
I don't want to make movies
on Social revolutions
I want...uh...uh...
I want to make a Gangster movie
On hardcore violence and bloodshed
A movie like Godfather, Scarface
and the likes
See like this movies
A similar script! Am even okay
if you rip off from these scripts
Come up with a good Gangster script
I'll produce your movie
I Guarantee
Correct...no more excuses!
I've decided to make
a Gangster movie
- Superb pal...
- But not an imaginary story
I am going to meet them...understand them
And then make a soulful story
A Realistic movie
Based on a True story!
Welding Kumar who got
life sentence got murdered
Did you find anything?
These are all that I could find
These are the same old stories
Already made in to movies
And they are all dead
I want to know about
a gangster who is in on the rise...
...need to meet him, personally,
watch him closely, and then write a script
You expect them to write an autobiography
and place it in the library
Why are you wasting my time?
You are an experienced reporter
You should be knowing someone
I just cover politics and Lankan issue
Both are one and the same
During your days...
...the 'Cat eyed Actress'
was Madhuri, right?
All the gangsters life
has the same template
They will kill someone and take his place
In turn someone else
will kill him and takes his
How long are you gonna
make the same sort of movies?
There is a guy, like
never seen in any movie
- An outlaw in Madurai
- Rowdy in Madurai?
Great! Who is that?
His name is...
3 years ago, 4 murders were happen
in the fruit market at Madurai
- I heard of him, sir!
- He is the first accused in that
young, should be in his late thirties
Unable to retrieve his name
Don't worry
I will get you the case file
Don't ever use his name
He will find and kill you
He is a psychopath
His name is Sethu
'Assault' Sethu
What's your name?
'Hidden Tiger'
Hey, there is an article about him
Shocking revelation!
That was written by uncle's friend
Right! He is writing it in his
pen name as 'Hidden Tiger'
Even he writes it spying on him
I can get you his contact details,
but you gotta be careful
You are the one, right?
You could have published
my photo, right?
Instead you drew a cartoon
How many of them
would have laughed at it?
Do I look funny?
Till now it was working
Anyone else got a light?
That's why snatched this
Do you?
Even if he has, it would
be wet by now
Hey, get the tools
Brother, I'll kill him
Why are you in such a hurry to kill?
You have not been around that long,
first watch and learn
- One step at a time
- Okay, brother
Thank God!
All that petrol would be wasted
'Sleeping Truth' by 'Hidden Tiger'
Truth hurts, do you know that?
Especially the truth of peeping
into my house will hurt like hell
Hey he may be a psycho
Not may be, he is actually a psycho
I am going to Madurai and
making a movie on Sethu's life
All the Madurai talk strikes a bell
on someone in our college
'Oorni'
Stop
That lady is my customer
That white shirt man
is my customer
That blue T-Shirt guy,
he's my customer
Look! He is staring at me
Move aside
He is mine, move along
I said I don't need an auto
Give back my bag
Just shut up and come with me
Brother is waiting for you
Hello, I think you have mistaken me
Shut up and come
Just give me my bag
I'll leave
He is my guy
You got scared?
Were you gonna pee in your pants?
Ganesh you shouldn't have
threatened him a lot
How long it's been since college
Should make a grand appearance, right?
Then why all of a sudden to Madurai?
Hey why are you settling down?
Dude, I am your guest
What plan you have come?
Take bath, let's visit
the temple and then my shop
Let's have lunch at Amma mess and then
you can board the train back home tonight
Oorni, just for a month! Will write
a story about Sethu and I'll leave
They are all cold blooded murderers
We can't go close to them
Let them be
You need to
take risk in life to succeed
Risk?
I am gonna have a kid in 5 months, that
itself makes my mark in the risk factor
Shame on you
So, that's your achievement in life?
That is what most men
achieve in their life
And that is enough for me
Are you even listening?
Leave my bag
I got this only for you!
All right, forget the night train
Leave early tomorrow
Don't you understand
It's for your sake
Sethu and his gang are
extremely dangerous...
...violent people
There are plenty of subjects
untapped in movies
I have a couple of stories
Hear me out
Is it true?
Will I actually look good on-screen?
I'm actually a stage performer
at school! Not sure of big screens
Will I look good?
Second hero?
- Don't mock me dude
- Am serious
Am I a hero material?
You will make me act, right?
Is Sethu that big a deal?
Is he impossible to reach?
Is he such a big-wig?
Superb!
We start our movie work first
thing tomorrow morning
Start it...and kill it
Get on board
- Who is he?
- Friend bro!
Even you're not telling anything bro
Dude, he is Sethu
Don't look at him
In this city,
Sethu is a brand
Happy birthday
To Sethurayan
Brother, greetings
An underworld don,
A political weapon, A Kingmaker
An Establishment by himself
You expect us to not to react?
Sir we didn't start anything
I have just closed down
what he started
Sir we didn't start anything
They murdered my brother last month
It's tit for tat, now its tallied
- Chopped his hand?
- That too in a dreadful way
- Friend bro
- Welcome
- He should have been killed 5 years ago
- How did it happen?
Rasu
Surround him
Kill him
What happened?
Sethu, are you alright?
Sethu's best ally is Rasu
Sethu's school friend,
Now his Right-hand
Been with him since Sethu started
Sethu's prime weapon in field
He will stare at everyone, will
hit anyone who stands up to him
A hardcore alcoholic,
his only weakness
After Rasu, its Senthil
Half of Madurai is deaf
because of his slaps
Dumb but yet a strong weapon
A foodie
Strange for a gangster
A teetotaler who doesn't stare at a girl
A family attached gangster
A great devotee
His only weakness...
Soft porn!
A movie a day keeps him awake
A hardcore film buff
After them the next
alarming person is Palani
Petty-shop Palani
The public is scared to
go even near his shop
Bores the entire crowd to death
with his most annoying stories
Mastered the art of killing
through story-telling
Been in this area since Sethu's birth
A one-stop-shop for Sethu's history
Some confidence and a whole lot
of patience can crack this weapon
Sethu is very dangerous
I can't get close to him directly
He is like a lion
Nearing him will kill us
We have got 3 monkeys to near him
Rasu
- What do you want to eat?
- Get me some eggs
Senthil
Boys, do check
if they'll play all the scenes
Don't waste money
Palani
He shouldn't know we are
here to make a film on him
If he gets to know...
We are dead
You took all these days to find that?
I told you that on Day-1
It's takes a lot of work and
effort to write Sethu's script
My only support in this
dangerous mission is...
The future superstar of Tamil movies,
our movie's second hero 'Oorni'
Use this trump card always
Let's see how you keep up
- They are calling you, bro
- Wait, I'll be back
There are 3 weapons that
I can use for my mission
Rasu...Senthil...Palani
So how did Sethu became the Sethu?
That's the question
Sethu...I'm waiting!
See in that top rack
I'll take this
Hello, come on...why
do you snatch all sarees that I choose?
Mind your words
I'll cut your tongue
I've come to take sarees of my choice
Not to snatch the ones
chosen by some fool
Dullard
Mind your tongue
I'll show you who I am
How dare you call me like that
Please be quiet
Why do you quarrel unnecessarily?
- Please don't quarrel
- Mind your business
- Excuse me, your bag is open
- Thanks
I remember seeing you somewhere
Me...I am a film director
You should've seen me in TV shows
Oh...Ok
We came first...you've to
give that saree to us
I saw it first
There are 2 sarees missing
Are you ladies creating a scene
and ransacking our store?
What, do we look like
petty thieves to you?
Didn't I tell you then
let us go for another shop?
But you didn't listen
Let's go
For a month's interest,
he'll scold for 3 months
Dude, someone has stolen 2 sarees
Very well, this is what happens
to those who cheat me
This happens frequently?
They steal from here and sell it
at installments at a lower rate
All those ladies are partners-in-crime
Perfect planning and execution
That's their profession
We should show this as
a scene in our movie
Hello Ramesh bro,
Seems to be very busy nowadays
Came for shopping with my friend
Do you want it?
We'll not go to the court
But we want all our
proposition to be sealed
Else, I'll have to take a tougher route
Don't make a fuss about it
Brother, I think it's a good proposition
Probably we can get away
with the rice mill
Keep quiet
Let's get this done right away
Let's not blew it up
- Okay
- Let's finish it
Take everything except the rice mill
And ask your party to pay
Rs 4 million instead
My party will give only 3 Million...not 4
Let's finish it
We'll finish the registration
process on Wednesday
Sethu, some of your men are
crossing their limits
Warn them not to invite trouble
How dare you warn us?
Brother have some beer please
Don't, bro
- You won't drink, brother
- He doesn't drink beer
- Shut up
- Don't get angry
Here's your cut
Between us, you don't have to be formal
Take it
Business is Business
These fools argument get us money
So your father is not
active in business now?
Are you taking care
of the business now?
Dad is not keeping well
The stab on his intestines has
got him down completely
I've quit my job! And taking
care of the business completely
Take care of him
He was a legend at his time
Dad asked me
to inform you something
Mariappan had come to meet dad
Bhupathi's right-hand
Sekar and Ganesh gang have reconciled
They cannot do business
when you are alive
Am not sure if that’s the truth
But I could sense someone outside
or within us spying you
Be careful!
Why do they keep talking?
Won't they get into action?
What he said is correct
Hey go and speak
Yes, I've mediated for that
What is your problem now?
Don't buy the trouble yourself
What rubbish are you talking, dullard!
Get lost
Kuruvamma!
She is a beauty
- During childhood Sethu...
- First listen to this
I went to her house to
convey my wish to marry her
Their parents didn't bother
to respect me, I was ashamed
But I said I won't leave home
Until Kuruvamma comes and
says she doesn't like me
I am telling you such
an important information
Today we don't have porn bits
Just leave the place now
What crap is this?
Nothing beats that german movie
That's classic
Worth an infinite watch
Especially the kitchen scene
Do you have that CD?
That's the best I've ever seen!
But they speak in English
But do you have
a translated copy of this?
- I'll try
- Let's not exchange in open
Keep your CD in my bike
I'll watch and keep it back in yours bike
That's the worst deal in history
It was during the sunset
Siva strolls along the street
A beautiful girl walks towards him
The moment she comes closer,
I realised she is Kuruvamma
That day I scolded her a lot
She poured kerosene on her and
was about to burn herself alive
She did that because you scolded her?
- Yes, you're right
- Nonsense
So, they say Sethu was imprisoned
for 3 years...Do you know?
That's the day she had
cooked my brinjal fry
Brinjal fry!
So...is this movie
a sequel of yesterday's?
No dude, it's completely
a different story
Hey, just turn the bike
That's my uncle
If he looks at me,
I am done
Isn't this where the Aadukalam
movie is screening?
Guys that Japanese movie is excellent
Kept in your bike
You do keep if you've got anything new
So your interest is World cinema?
I could see
an old lady sitting there
No one is there, but what
you see is Kuruvamma
Could you see Sivanesan on this side?
You can't see
That's why it's called Hallucination
If we still keep hearing
stories from that old man...
...these characters would
be part of our life
Enough!
Let's find a solution to all of this
Will you just stop
your Kuruvamma story?
I've been asking about
Sethu all these days
- Why do you ask about Sethu?
- Why?
Did we ever ask why you
tell Kuruvamma stories?
Why do you ask us then?
I can't tell anything about Sethu
Take this 100 bucks
Close our account
We are never coming back here
Whoever comes here
will enquire about Sethu
Even last week, there was someone
He tweaked lot of questions about Sethu
Didn't know why?
Then?
Someone said a reporter
wanted to write about Sethu
Then...
He went alone to the fields
tied his hands and burnt himself alive
What?
I said he was burnt
alive by Sethu's gang
Ruthless killers
How did they know
about the reporter?
I told them
They gave me 350 bucks
Did you guys ask about Sethu?
No...why do we talk about him?
Ruthless killers
Dude, get me a drink
Please, give him one
You are such a waste
We drink here everyday
Is that of any use?
That needs some smartness
Tandoori chicken
Goes good with your drink
We sit in the next table everyday
We are neighbours-in-drinks
Matter over
If he eats that chicken,
we have befriended him
Is he eating that?
Yes, he is...
That's it
While leaving, he'll thank us
He's coming
Don't mention it
No thanks between us
Do you think
I can't afford a chicken?
What are you showing off for?
- What's my account balance here?
- 5000 bucks or more
He'll settle it
He has to
Pith chicken for me?!?!
Smart move!
Senthil is our last hope
Feels like we live to
supply porn films to him
Just observe
How are you brother?
You guys are worse than me
Just get married soon
Definitely bro!
So how was the Korean movie?
Korean movie? The last one
was an African movie, right?
The other day
I kept it in your bike
Written 'Vettayadu Vilayadu'
movie name in its cover
That day when I waved to you
I thought you are telling 'bye'
Why didn't you tell me
about it that day?
That's ok
It's in your back, tell me
how it is after watching the movie
Want some Samosa?
Even the last hope flopped
- What film is that?
- Some action movie
Her dad forgot and
left it on the bike
(Tamil hero Kamal Hassan's movie song)
Stop it
Don't tease him
Served hot, have it brother
For all the trauma he went through
at least stop teasing him
So, what happens
in the climax of the movie?
What have you cooked?
Add more spice in it
Okay, bro
- So, couldn't see you last week?
- Yeah, had been to a family function
Greetings, bro
Brother...
Have this
Use the first toilet
I just cleaned it
Use the first one,
You should be paying me
for using this toilet
Brother, Sethu chapter is closed
Wanna hear the bullet shots?
Sethu looks very different
He has put down a lot of
weight, since I last saw him
Come, drag whats left of Sethu
So, all doors are shut
What do we do now?
There's a guy called
Pandi in Sethu's gang
He visits the brothel everyday
Shall we follow him too?
Go back home
Roaming with you
lost almost a months business
Can't you guys
even clean the shop
You guys celebrate my absence
Utter loudly
and bring the customers
Hello...what's happening?
The girl in the Orange clothes
is eyeing me for quite some days
- Our area saree bandit
- That's okay
I have a brilliant idea
The girl eyeing you,
date her
Who...that saree thief?
Just pretend to love her
Why?
Her mom cooks food for Sethu's gang
And her mom want her
to be married to Sethu
You mean she is Sethu's would-be
May be!
That's the stupidest idea ever
Sethu doesn't even turn towards her
But she could be the trump card
we want to know about Sethu
Mom and Daughter will tell
you stories about Sethu
This is the risk that
you always boast about
Taking risk is not an issue
She looks okay
Love and work doesn't go along well
That's my concern
Too much!
Do you want some bangles?
That sister gave you this
What's that?
It's a letter from that girl...
Things are falling
into place, enjoy
Speaking the love lingo
Communicating through eyes
Coward! He's not attending the call
It's surely Ganesh! Sekar
would've picked up the call
Is this a telugu song?
For sure it's Sekar
Who sent you?
Tell me
I won't disclose
Look at this terrorist attitude
It's either Sekar or Ganesh...
...want to kill me
You eat only once, eat another idly
I don't have time to investigate
Have this Idly
Don't you see me talking
All you do is
feed me with the left overs
Just leave
I make fresh food everyday
and you complain
- Have you all eaten?
- We all had
Serve him some idly
He will eat
Please leave now
Why waste the food on a dead man?
Where were we?
So...someone wants me dead
And you won't disclose them
So...the only option is
to kill all my enemies
You'll realise only when you die
So you die
Just kill him...and get rid of the body
Sethu, I'll tell the truth
What's in it for me?
Just close his mouth...immediately
Push it inside
I am asking you since morning,
You didn't utter a word
Now you offer a pity clue and
You expect me to listen
And he needs some gift
You just die
I know how to find him
Just kill him...and give him
a horrifying death
I'll do it
What the hell is this shirt
look at the color
And you want to kill someone
For 2 years I've not done anything big
Trust me and give this to me! I'll do it
You have just joined
You'll have to mature to do it
First, change your shirt
You look like a comedian
Just because you waited
long, doesn't mean I've to
I'll do it please
Kasi bro, just leave him
I'll do it
Rasu bro, do tell him
to give me a chance
Leave him, Rasu bro
Early in the morning, in the middle of
the house, that too during breakfast
Does it look like
a child's play to you both?
Just clean this up
Are you happy now?
Clean that blood
Both of us didn't execute at the end
Police...Police is coming
Let's take it back inside!
Sub-Inspector is here
What do we do now?
- Sir, how about our case?
- I'll take care
- Get a chair for sir
- Poured something down?
Sethu, did you find the guy
who tried to kill you
That's not a plot to kill me
It's some other problem
I was incidentally there!
That's all
So you didn't catch him?
I told you
he didn't come to kill me
You're the Police
Find the killer
Coffee?
No thanks, got to leave
as I am in duty
Take this money
and help me double it
I plan to enroll my son in
an Engineering college next year
No one lends money nowadays
Bank lends it if you just sign documents
Try your best
One more information
20 days back we were asked to send your
file to the Commissioner's office
I am not sure
if it's an encounter plan
So, be careful
If it's an encounter,
someone will be spying you
I'll inform you if I get
any information from my officials
You be careful
I'll leave now
- Why did you drop the body, Idiot?
- Am I an idiot? You're the one...
Fighting over a dead body
in the middle of the house
What's the prayer for?
Prayers won't be effective if shared
But if it happens, we'll come here
again and light 2000 lamps
What?
We light 2000 lamps
Off late you are more
into romance I guess
Just now our plan is getting executed
I am slowly fetching details
about Sethu from her
Be careful
Don't play with her too much
Else, I'll have to find you
a business here for a living
I am just pretending
to be in love with her
Will tell her the truth,
once our work is done
What are you doing?
Am gonna go through Sethu's street
Just turn the bike
Don't invite problems
What's an issue to go through his streets?
He doesn't own the road
Dude, I could see a problem
Which house?
Not sure! I am not
familiar with this area
At sight we can definitely find it
That's the one
Red benz car is outside
Just take a picture as we pass by
Take my phone
Last week itself I've paid the bills
How could they say we haven't?
He looked at us...
Go fast
- Did you take the photograph?
- Stupid go
Tomorrow I'll look into this payment
It's a dead end
You didn't tell me
I told you I am not familiar
with these streets
For sure, we are dead today
Just be cool
We'll casually return! I'll take care
Don't worry
I'll call you back
- Hey, what's up?
- Who are you both?
- My name is Karthik
- Why are you roaming here?
- We came to visit our friend
- Which house?
- Ramakrishnan
- Chandrabose
- Ramakrishna Chandrabose
- Tell the address clearly
- Near the temple
- Near tea shop
You have a bangle shop, right?
Don't roam around here
Get lost
- What's the problem?
- Kids...lost their ways
I had an issue
with them at the bar
I was embarrassed
at my house cause of them
Are they spying on us?
Doesn't seem like that
They were scared
One of the guys
owns a bangle shop
Even the inspector warned us
We can't trust anyone
Let's keep an eye on them
I'll take care
It's a small task anyways
Watch them closely
If you suspect anything,
inform us! We'll close it
Okay, bro
Oorni, why did you switch on the TV?
Your parents have gone to Mumbai
Your wife has gone for her pregnancy
So, you and sir have a party everyday
He has come all the way to catch porn
movies in the day and drink all night?
I am a Visual Communication student
I've come to take photos of Madurai
Oh photos!
Can we see those photos?
We are just going to start it today
So, shall we start then?
Everything is over, I am going
to die without seeing my kid
They will watch us now and
kill us in the evening
I warned you a million times
My family will miss me
Did you shoot my picture?
What's your plot?
Take the film reel out
You had a photogenic posture, that's why
Don't be sarcastic
Take the film reel out
I swear you were looking good
I am going to break your camera
Take the reel out first
No film reel!
It's digital
Just look at the pictures once
How can you show immediatel?
Don't you have to process the reel?
Don't try to fool me
No processing is required!
Look!
If you've told me,
I would have posed with the glasses
Can we take one more photo?
Brilliant pictures
I've never seen me nicer
You have a gangster like personality
That's exactly what we do all this work
I need a rapid growth in life
I can't wait for years
I've a 4 year old daughter
I want to earn well...
Keep the family happy
Then settle down with a small business
Good drinks...and enjoy
my life to the fullest
So, how did Sethu
become such a big shot?
Do you know any
history behind this?
About Sethu brother...
What do you want to know about Sethu?
Ask me, I'll tell you everything
Yes
"When the beauty of
the land falls in love"
"The rage of bull is instigated"
"And when the seasonal flowers blossom"
"The legendary bull fights begin"
"The lone lady is enthralled"
"And caught up in the web of love..."
- Is that Sethu?
- Yes
I took a big risk
and stole it for you
Why do you want this?
When I make a family subject movie,
I can use this as reference
- It's a nice dress
- New dress
- You bought it or stole it?
- Our company only steals Sarees
Policies, huh?
"The seed of love is sown"
"These are too expensive"
"Now we leave it to time"
"For the side it grows"
"When the beauty of
the land falls in love"
"The rage of bull is instigated"
"And when the seasonal flowers blossom"
"The legendary bull fights begin"
He too was once a big shot
What are they doing together?
Wastrel keeps company
with the wastrels
"While the king is still getting ready"
"The queen could hardly wait"
"As the drama carries
on in its own pace"
"The wait has become
too unbearable"
"She is caught in her own trap"
"In too deep, happily stuck"
Rain! You!
Me! Ilayaraja!
Haiku!
Awesome
In a caste dispute-
How dare you talk about her?
No photos, you stupid
"The lone lady is enthralled"
"And caught up in the web of love..."
Is Taj Mahal back drop ok?
Change to some foreign places
Bombay, London, Paris and likes
She wants to visit those places
Is it so?
- What's her name?
- Ganga! Daughter's name is Sri Priya
- Love marriage?
- Yes
Why do you feel shy for that?
Sethu brother is calling me
Hello...!
Tell me, brother
Ya, I'm nearby
I'll be there immediately
Sethu himself is calling me
Why?
We are going to kill
someone tonight
Who is that?
What for?
I am not sure who
But am sure some
big person is the target
They usually don't call me
for such big assignment
Other day, I stood up for myself
this is my returns for that
Is it?
Just wait for 10 minutes
I'll be back
Make it fast, I need to hurry
Hey, where have you kept
the black box that was in my bag?
It's in the other room, why?
We've got a great opportunity today
They are going to kill someone
And this dumbo is also
involved in that
And we can listen
to that incident live
Be clear! I've lot of
clothes to wash still
My Reporter uncle
gave me this spy mic
This audio transmitter is
to spy on people
I can stick this device to anything
Then we can listen to what they speak
Clearly through this
receiver from a distance
Clear reception for at least 1KM wide
You sound exactly like
a tele shopping sales girl
What are you going to do with this?
We can see photos too?
Photos, songs, movies...
Everything
This is amazing
You wanted to show pictures
to your wife, right?
Yes
Take it tonight
and return it tomorrow
So I'll take it
Thanks bro!
- You'll return it, right?
- Hey, you can trust me
Bye
Come fast
Let's check
- Hi brother
- Come
Sethu brother himself called
What's the matter?
You cried for not calling you
for big projects, right?
So come and watch a big project
To watch, I dreamt big for tonight
Who is the target?
- Sekar
- Sekar!
- Who is Sekar?
- Sekar is Sethu's rival for decades
We suspected him all these days
We have closed all other suspects
So we are killing Sekar tonight
He is always guarded
He is in politics too
He has got an affair with someone
living in SS Colony 7th street
Every Friday he settles there
- Do you know this place?
- Yeah!
No security
Today is Friday
His gang is also cornered
All his guys number
would be switched off
So what's the plot?
Three of our men has
surrounded the streets
They alerted us when
Sekar entered the house
Oh, he is already in the house?
Kasi has studied the house for a while
Then punctured his vehicles
And waiting on the backyard to watch him
SS colony is a large area
But I have a friend's house there
Let's go and sit in the terrace
Let's start now
We won't get signal if we start now
We won't know their next steps
We will leave after them
What's the time now?
12:30!
We've half hour to go
Go fill the fuel
- He's going to the main road
- Let's go
Sekar brother, important information
They have plotted
to kill you tonight
We'll be there in 30 minutes
He's speaking to Sekar
- What are you saying?
- You are in SS colony, right?
Yes
There are 3 people watching
you from your street corner
What's happening?
You're right
They have flattened
your car tires
The back gate is locked too
He has leaked the entire plan
Its a perfect plan! Sorry
I got the news late
Just escape somehow
Let the lights and TV be on
be careful while you escape
They're watching you from outside
Don't try to bring your guys
They're all trapped too
He played a perfect double game
Thought him to be an idiot
He's been spying on Sethu
You've just got 30 minutes to escape
This is a mega twist
See, he is leaving
Follow him fast
Follow him quick
Brother
No police vehicle
It's just an ambulance, you can come
- Can you hear him?
- Wait...
Can hear now
Looks like no one is in the house
Break it
Sethu has reached
He fled the house
Sekar has escaped
What were you all doing?
We were alert, no one
went out of the house
What about the ambulance?
We thought some emergency
case in the neighborhood
He fled by the ambulance
Sekar is a brilliant
fellow I guess
He made a fool of Sethu himself,
better you take Sekar's as movie
So he fled the place
despite all of you
That too in an ambulance
Why is he laughing?
Sekar is brilliant
Isn't it Sounder?
We can still catch
that ambulance, brother
For what? We've already
caught the prey
The plot is not for Sekar
It's for you
Rushing into everything
You want to fly even
before you got wings
When we recited the plot to you for
the first time, you should have sensed it
You've a lot to learn Sounder
Who is brilliant now?
Sethu is a master mind
This is a brilliant scene for my movie
He is just caught red-handed
A dumb fellow
What are they gonna do to him?
So you have played double-game on us?
Getting hit
I just agreed to let him know
if there is a plot for him
Please believe me, bro
You are like my hero
He took care of my monthly family expenses
That's why I agreed
I just need to inform the plot that's it
Nothing else brother
Listen to me
Pardon me once
Please speak out Rasu brother
I beg you, bro
He just shot him
He killed Sounder
Sethu, we trapped him like a mouse
Sekar, watching Titanic?
Seem like you are doing
a research with films these days
Looking handsome
- Looking good?
- Believe me, Sethu
I didn't send him to kill you
Just a safety net for me
Why do you build over and over?
He shot Sekar too
Let's leave now
I am scared
Die...!
Why do you think I called you all
to catch these two silly dastards?
Think well before
you plot against me
Take that
Let's go now
Come on
Some MP3 player
To listen songs
Let's go now
Take these dogs to our farm and
Burn them to ashes
Brother, there is a mic stuck on this
There is someone spying you
It should be this dog, Sekar
- I don't think it's him
- Then?
This will work only in close proximity
Its no use to him
Also, why did he wait
until Sounder called?
He could have fled while
you planned this plot
It's someone else
close to the house
Only police or reporters use this mic
They are going to kill us now
I told you not to get in to this
I think he might be still listening
Let's go somewhere...please
Wait, let me think
There is no escape
Even the SI warned us
Let's go
Hey!
The idiot at the other end listening
Whoever you is...
Listen carefully
You will be dead in an hour...
...with my own hands
Let's just run from here
Definitely they'll kill us
Ruthless killers
My whole life...
Hurry up, there is
no time to cry
They might not have suspected us
They will be behind
Ganesh and gang
Let's run before it's late
We'll leave tonight
Where...where will I go?
I am going to die without
even seeing my kid
Don't get scared, we can talk later
Let's pack and leave
Come on Oorni
Let's go!
They are not breaking the silence
Every one we catch
are like terrorists
Why keep bothering them,
just kill them
They are here
to keep an eye on us
Don't know whether they are
police or some other gang
They are police Bro
Look they have got the case file,
as well tracked us with a mic
Definitely Police
What are you contemplating bro?
Let's kill them quick and go home
Have to take my dad
to the hospital in the morning
Ok then you start now,
We'll take care
Ok bro, I'll leave now
Please tell them the truth
They will burn us alive
if we tell the truth
If you don't
are they gonna treat us?
They think we are a policemen
Do tell the truth
Look at these spy faces
Okay
Finish them
Get the tools
They will kills us
Please tell the truth
What are you guys murmuring?
Speak out loud
- We are not police
- Then...?
I came here to write a story
What story?
- A movie script
- He is a director
Ohh you are
a cinema director?
Sethu brother please believe me
A producer found me
I came to do research...
...to watch you in person
Make your life a movie
What did you say?
Gonna take a movie based
on your life story
About my life?
Hence came to write
a story here
That's why I spied you
Movie?
Like the one
which comes in TV
Reality shows, following criminals
No, It's like Godfather,
Scarface, something like that
How can I believe you?
Mahesh is also a good boy
How many times
should I tell you?
Good
But the movie duration is less
They are short films
But your story
would be a feature film
Big film, right?
If you need some information
you should have come directly
Why all these unnecessary spy
stuffs, get yourself hurt
You burnt a reporter alive
for writing about you
That's why?
He is a reporter
who writes the truth
That is very dangerous
You are gonna make a movie
Like Godfather, Scarface
It will be good to see
my story in theatres
What you say guys?
Yes brother
Hereafter any information
you need, just ask me
Because it's our film
A film about me
Guys...they belong to our gang
Let's Start
Just a minute
No...
Just be casual
- Don't want this?
- Nope
Rolling!
You tell, I am feeling uneasy
I can't do that
- At least you narrate
- I can't do that
What is this?
You feel different to narrate
in front of the camera
I'll get the other phone,
we can do a voice recording
That's alright
First time before camera...
What should I say?
Today you're big shot
When and where did it all started?
Say that
Right from my childhood,
my dreams, ambition...
...vision everything
is being a Gangster
During my 3rd standard we had
a stage drama in our school
Panchali Sabatham
I am Droupathi
Durchathanan removes my saree
and Krishna failed to hold my saree
I stood as a shameless goose
in front of everyone
All those guys around
me laughed at me
I can never accept
anyone mocking me
That's when I got
powered up and beat them
- No...no
- Sethu, let him go
Out of fear,  when everyone
paves way for us-
You'll feel a high
Once you've felt it,
you can never get over it
That's where it all started
From then you beat
for every reason...
...and beat every person
School issues, college issues,
and area issues...
Ego issues, Issues between
two gangs, in this race...
We din't even have time to
sleep, we were more into issues...
...problems and fights
till a point of time
Most of them turned to rogue
because of a love story
Even our life had a twist,
because of his love story
During our college days
To see your lover in their locality...
...is like a war mission
One day when he went to see his lover,
her brother caught us red handed
Who are they?
Finish it quick,
they're coming here
Let's leave now
You want us to run and hide
- Who is her brother?
- The one with the black scarf
Who are you?
You're from Jaihindpuram
locality, right?
Yes
What the damn
are you doing here?
He came to drool
with his sister
I came to beat black and blue
if anybody talk rude with us
You think you're a big...
At that time that locality had
a big rogue named Murugan
I've never seen him before
What's the problem guys?
These guys have come
to meet my sister
I just asked him
but he is trying to hit me
Which locality you guys are from?
Is it Jaihindpuram?
Yes
Won't your locality
have any girls?
We've got lot of women there
But we heard there isn't any men here
You...?
He struck Murugan
Let's run away
That incident took my name
and reputation to next level
Then had a peace talk
with murugan group
I apologised
and we closed that chapter
But I made
a mark on his face
When he sees that mark on mirror
he will always remember me
People like us, we never settle
Are you Sethu?
You scarred Murugan's face
Do you think yourself
to be a big shot?
Don't mess with me
Hereafter if I get to
hear any news about you,
I myself will kill you
Look at his face
We can't live here
opposing Shanmugham
So...
- Let's move away now
- Did they beat you?
Yes
Sir...come and see this
Both of them
are lying dead here, sir
Stay there
Don't come close
Is it Murugan?
Murugan as well
My death is not in his hands
I stabbed that
rogue to death
There they are, catch them
Move...move away
That's my first execution
But a big and best execution
You become a gangster,
only by killing someone
Way of execution
and the number of murders
Determines his respect,
worth and everything
Every murder is
like a medal of honour
So far how many?
You alone did 18
We all together did
- I am 13
- Me 5
I am 4
All together 48
Totally 48 murders
If we would have killed you both,
we could have celebrated the half century
What do you say?
Great escape
Then what happened?
What happened?
We both were taking each
other group members lives
In the name of revenge
Then spending a lot of money to get
ourselves out of police cases
Again to earn money getting
us involved in,
High interest rates lending,
politics, fruit market lease etc...
To safeguard us we kill 4 enemies
In turn they're
waiting to kill us
Our job runs like this
We enter the business taking a life,
and you have to pay with your life to get out
That's our profession
Should live like a King
With pride and honour
For that to happen,
do anything, kill anyone
That's not wrong
This is our policy
Any more questions?
About your Mom and Dad?
My dad died
in a mill accident
My sibling died
at a young age
One who is sitting there,
that's my Mom
She hates my business completely
She said she won't speak,
if I don't quit
She told that 12 years ago
Till now haven't spoken a word
My Mom right?
How do you expect then?
Anything else?
Out of all your criminal records,
Interesting fights,
kidnaps and murders
If you could elaborate, it will be easy
to be shoot as a scene in the movie
Which one we can say,
the bus stand incident
Which one?
The political issue for
which I was imprisoned
That one he had 4 cuts,
but still was alive
So we stomped him
by his neck
We had a lorry run over his body
The tall one we killed
in the market fight
You mean the love story?
- I gave a sharp blow
- Just one stroke he ran away
We get a big cut of our revenue
from settling issues
Sekar, tell yourself
where will we go?
Why did you arrange for this meeting,
what's the matter?
You are a big torture
Fear of the people
is the only investment in this
I'll slit you
just sit down
Everyone sit down please
Now tell me
what's the issue?
He is a drunkard and he has
an extra marital affair too
So I won't let my daughter
to live with him
Hey...stop
Every case we attend
has got a package
A package just to
make some noise
A package to hurt others
and a separate one to kill
If I go then it's 10 lakhs rupees
If it's Rasu 5 lakhs rupees
If it's Senthil 3 lakhs rupees
How can a woman
live with a drunkard?
Only a very few in this
world doesn't drink
But that doesn't mean
we have to divorce them
- Stop it
- Start a fight
- What did you say?
- Just shut up
Just stop it
Won't you listen you drunkard?
29, 30, 31, 32nd cut
can't be shown
This one is to hurt
and this one is to kill
Different weapon to kill
What is this?
- Development fund
- For which party?
For the winning party
- Chicken gravy...
- Eat well
How dare you pour
gravy on his hand?
Don't you know what to
speak and how to speak
Sethu bro, battery drained
Give me 5 minutes
He gave me a Korean
movie, amazing one
Don't you know what to
speak and how to speak
- Who is this?
- Has come from Madras
Here to shoot a movie about Sethu
So he is moving with us
About our Sethu!
All those fights and murders
- Yes
- Very good
Put your signature
- I won't even if I die
- Here...!
How long you will
threaten in the same way?
You have got pistol right?
As per company rules
shouldn't use pistols
Just to threaten him,
I have watched it in an English film
What they did in the movie?
Let fate decide
your chance... er
Let your fate decide how many
chances do you need to sign the papers
chances you get to sign the papers
You and your nonsense idea
He may die, if Sethu bro
knows this, it will be a mess
Get him quick
One day had a guy
caught by his neck,
Started cutting his
throat with a blade
The blood was shedding
like a fountain for 2 feet
Is it?
This guy will cut with a blade
and the bloodshed like a fountain
Who will believe this?
- You don't believe it
- No
You don't believe it!
Wanna watch it?
Just catch the neck
like this and-
With this blade-
- What happened?
- Horrible murder in my dreams
To show you
a demo they cut my neck
This is how you clapped
in my dream too
I could smell blood even
when I brush the teeth
Is it really important
to write a gangster story
Don't we have any other stories,
maybe on our freedom fighters
Brilliant script is ready
Just need to go
and meet the producer
Then we will fix
Vijay Sethupathi in the lead role
Then it's the shoot
Thank God
Leave the place
Who's knocking there
the back door at midnight?
- Go!
- You go and have a look
Kayal, why at this odd time?
You still remember my name
Why do you keep weeping?
You didn't bother to meet me
How many calls and SMS
Sorry I was busy at work
Leaving home tomorrow?
Is your work done?
This love was just an act
to know about Sethu, is it?
Tell me Karthik,
Did you use me?
Kayal...Kayal
You're right
Yes, I did use you as
a bait to get information
But I like you a lot Kayal
I don't want this
love, marriage...
No such ideas
Let's be friends
I loved you
I already have other friends
Just concentrate on your work
If you start falling for this love,
You will never make a movie
You'll only make it to
the theatre with your family
Guys, Sethu brother is calling you
What is the matter?
There is a small party
for your farewell
Party!
- Where?
- Come
Inside a well?
See this setup
How's the setup?
"I am the lion that creates an
impression of respect in its every form"
"Dare not to touch me"
"I am a raging bull"
"The city speaks of my name"
"My name, when spelt
Spreads an aura of strength"
You've just finished the first draft
Lets celebrate
No need
Drown the feelings and enjoy
Have it
Come on
"I’ll hunt you down"
"I’ll beat you straight"
"Every blow will echo through your life
That you shatter in every direction"
"Understand the strength
of my city united"
"Understand the strength of
punishment and violence"
Mom...?
"Spreads an aura of strength"
"The nook and corner
of the city respects me"
"Success finds me time and again"
"The respect and fear
for strength brings it to me"
"Even the mountains won't
reach farther than my fists"
"When I clench them even
the volcano calms down"
"Spreads an aura of strength"
"I am the lion that creates an
impression of respect in its every form"
"Spreads an aura of strength"
Karthi, you are gonna
direct my life as a movie
I am very happy
and excited today
How has it come?
Make sure the lead role
is played by big stars
Cast Super Star,
it'll be unbeatable
They won't even
let us near his street
Kamal Hasan will suit
this character
I am Okay!
But he should say okay right
Sister you tell who can
be in the lead role?
She knows a lot about
the movies, you suggest
Tell whom do you want to
act in the lead role?
Who will be apt for this story
Rajini, Kamal, Ajit or Vijay?
You choose, we'll bring them
If the story is about Sethu,
then why someone else should act?
He himself can act
He looks like a hero only
Don't be sarcastic Kayal
What's wrong in her comment?
Sethu has got all the features
He looks like our
old hero Jaychandran
Why are they laughing?
I am not sarcastic
Some Dick and Harry are acting,
Why can't you?
By doing this you
can become famous
Then this stardom will be
easy to get on to politics
Then all your criminal
cases can be dropped
We have to grow up quickly
to the next level
No one thought about it
Even I didn’t think about it
What you say Karthik?
I will act as a hero in our film
Brother!
Don't make fun of it
I am not cracking jokes Karthik
I am the Hero in our film
She's crazy, don't
take her seriously
- Acting is not-
- Stop it
I didn’t ask your permission,
I'm telling you
I film
I hero
Okay?
Beat the drum
Good morning!
Have blabbered a lot in the night
Don't keep those in your mind
Thank God!
I was afraid thinking
that to be serious
It's okay
Come inside
I have got a guest at my home
He wants to meet you
Please come
Shall we go?
- Have they come?
- Yes
Sethu bro, is he the director?
He is the director
Sir is our guest
Sir...?
Have discussed everything with Sir
The hero in the movie that
you gonna direct in his production
...will be me
- What sir?
- For sure!
I am so proud to introduce
you to the film industry
What's wrong in him
playing the lead role?
He looks good like Jayachandran
This is my life
My passion and Dream
Who the damn is he?
What the hell
he knows about acting?
Acting is an art
Who the damn
is he to perform art?
Cinema is not a whore house where
anyone with money can come in
With the time spent on an emotional speech,
better do think about the solution
I don't have an option
Have to escape tonight
How?
Do go by the cross streets
Be careful and take care
- Don't get caught
- Sorry, dude
I have troubled you a lot
I can manage these troubles
But I can't tolerate
seeing Sethu as a Hero
- See you dude
- Bye
I bought it just for you
Super!
Did you get caught?
I was emotionally driven, thinking
that we will meet after many years
You left during
the movie title card
And you are back before
the movie hero's introduction
Hey look at our
hero's introduction now
Sethu, please leave me
Leave me Sethu please
Sethu bro, please let him go
Let me go, please
Do I look like a Joker?
How long would it take for me
to nail you in the coffin?
All the fear you had looking
at me from a distance,
Fear goes away once I made
you part of the gang
Either direct a film
with me as a hero
Otherwise just sit there
and think about your career
You have got only 2 options
Understood?
Don't cry
Don't cry dude
Leave me
Karthi
Is it the director?
You got hurt
Are you crying?
Don't get upset
This is just the beginning
Irony in cinema is...
To make the audience laugh,
the director has to cry
It's been 35 years
since I started crying
What are you looking at?
40 years before, I came to chennai
with a passion for cinema
5 years, I still hadn't got a start
Then 10 years I worked as an
assistant and experienced cinema
Everyone gets an opportunity
It's like an Angel
If you respect it,
It comes again and again
But if you disrespect it,
It will never come back
The new directors want to be
Sathyajitray on their debut film
They wont compromise
for a single thing
They create problems
on every small issue
Me too of same category
My producer wanted his cousins
to be casted in the movie
I said no and stood by
I said go and walked out stating
I will get 1000 more producers
But till now I haven't met...
...one among the thousands
I will just get hold of
people coming to my shop
And start telling them stories in
the name of Sivanesan and Kuruvamma
But they don't exist
That's my story Kuruvamma
If it would have got released in that period,
It would have been a massive hit
Should have been like
Balachander and Bharathiraja
Now I am 64 years old
Never Uttered the word
'Action and Cut'
Are you scared that
you'll end up like me
According to you
I might have lost,
But for me I am successful
Your success and failures,
shouldn't be determined by others
You should know from within
The clever pave their own way
Go on, do your work
I have to open the shop
Can't change a thing
by crying about it
What?
Hey I am telling you
Hey stop
Leave him
What do you want?
Thought about it
I have decided
to keep you as a hero
Nothing helps like pounding
Congratulations!
I've become a hero
We'll be unstoppable
after 5 films
They'll never leave us alone
They might come
back at us any day
What else can be done?
He has agreed
to direct the movie
Ask him to finish the shoot
smoothly and come back
Then we can look at it,
Once he is back
Yes, please ask him
to do that, just a movie
Ashok...
Just a minute
(A film monologue)
Super...Super
Was it okay?
I don't have a choice
You have to undergo
an acting training session
There is an acting
guru named 'Muthu'
You can go for
10 days acting classes
Then we will look into it
If Guru is coming,
let me also join the class
In Sethu's story definitely
I will have a role to play
Bro, I am the second hero as well
Whoever wishes to act, Can go
for the classes conducted by Muthu sir
Once he says okay,
let me start the shoot
- Only if he says okay
- He will,
If not we will ensure
When you act like a King
Every part of your body including
the hair and nails should feel like a King
Only when you act like a King
If it's a leper then...
Sir...please help me
You...?
He is our Guru,
don't hurt him
Only if he says okay
we go for the shoot
Sethu I've told you already
Don't hurt the guru
Come...come
Sir, are you okay?
Apologise sir!
It's by mistake
You may be a don in your place
You can be
whomever you are
Still you are my student
You will realise it
as we move ahead
Didn't understand?
Your classes starts from
tomorrow morning 5 a.m
Can't come at 5 AM
When I speak, I don't
want anyone to interrupt
Your classes starts from
tomorrow morning 4 a.m
For an actor the most important
language is body language
We will enact if we have to speak to someone
who doesn't understand our language
As an actor the language
we need to learn is gibberish
What's that, gibberish?
Can't understand
What is special in Madurai?
Most of the shops in Madurai is famous
for Parotta and Mutton Chukka food
Okay, convey the same in gibberish
In Madhurai Parotta...
Now everyone speaks in gibberish
This is very funny
Are you talking in Tamil?
Punishment, Ten times kill and laugh
What is it?
If you bathe in Kuttralum falls,
it will be very cool
Sethy, have you guys gone mad?
How long will this go?
From tomorrow we will
start the main course
It's just a warm up session
What did you say?
Warm up!
Are we looking like clowns?
Karuna - Compassion
Shringara - Love
Raudra - Anger
Veera-Courage
Bhayanaka-Fear
Arputham - Surprise
Bheebhatsya-Disgust
Hasya-Laughter
Shantha-Peace
Mercy...
How do you react
when someone gets injured?
Look at me and act
Why are you staring at me?
Why do you howl?
I'll hit you on your mouth
You are looking with lust,
Do I look like a woman?
Pull, pull out your tongue
You'll die
Do Shringharam
Why do you bite your lips?
Why do you cry?
Cry...feel and cry
Others should shed tears
looking at your cry
How would I make you understand?
Come on cry
Don't cry, master
Cry Sethu...cry
Love, is this how you
look at a girl with love?
Aren't you old enough?
Haven't you loved
a single girl in your life?
Didn't your heart
skip a beat ever?
Haven't you heard the melodies
of Ilayaraja in the air?
- I'm a Shankar Ganesh fan
- Very important
You won't, you will never
feel love in your life
Karthi...
I'm really sorry
You left me crying,
But you were drunk and dancing
I was so furious
So I just wanted
to get back at you
Tease...?
You ruined my career
Look at this
Have you ever
touched someone?
Not me
Will this movie be successful
with such a heroic face?
I swear it won't
Have you ever
touched any girl?
If something happens, I will...
Didn't you fool me with your love
That's why I set you up
Set up...?
An useless life
without a girl
I am talking to you,
Don't stand like a statue
Muthu sir,
don't scold him much
She can't bear it
Putting me in trouble...?
Don't Karthik, please
Sethu sir
She has been waiting so long
...and if everything
had happened in time
You wouldn't have to take this crap
from others is what Kayal feels
Could have got married
Even so, romance
would flood-
Karthik, please shut up
Karthik, I still love you
Try to understand
I just came to say it
I am not able to forget you
Hey Karthi,
She desired to
see me as an actor
Ask her to wait for sometime
Once the movie release,
immediately will marry her
Tell her
- Play that song now
- Shall I?
In my journey of 20 years
I have never come across
such a bunch of morons
But I have trained
them to my strength
So from this...
Oorni, Rasu, Senthil, Kasi,
Vettu Kumar you all stand aside
Sethu, come over here
We all passed the class
Sethu don't worry, we'll beg
and get you passed somehow
This whole lot here, even if they train
for eons to come, they can never act
Even the others could
stand in the atmosphere
But this one...?
Don't even think of placing
him in a corner of a frame
Total waste of time
Okay, sir
You sinner...!
This bugger over here
...is the worst actor
I have ever come across
But, he can act
Is there any scenes where
he has to cry or romance
Both are there
That's tough
If we could train and beat the shit out of
him, may be we can get some performance
But other than that
you can start the shooting
Producer sir, let's rock
Sir, first shot
Could you please clap,
so we can start?
I would be the only producer to invest,
knowing that it's a flop movie,
You want me to clap too?
Don't piss me off
Move away and stand
Pazhani sir, please come front
Please do the honor of
clapping for the first shot
- Should I?
- Com on, do it
'A.Kumar'
"No human in the world
is devoid of Desires"
"The same desire
that has split states"
"Only that is present,
Can be shown to the world"
"Doesn’t matter what
period you belong to"
"The craziness of love
will never wither off"
"The wonders that
the world has not seen Love"
"Will make you go in
search of, everyday!"
"Smiling like a weird slacker"
"Disrupting the harmony
of the system"
"Shouting like
the darkest animals"
"And roaming like a loafer"
28 times we have burnt him
You only did that
in your real life right?
Master teach him
crying exercise
"The wonders that
the world has not seen Love"
Haven't seen your
daughter for a while
Ask her to come over
to the shooting spot
Enough...enough
Master, teach him
crying exercise
It may rain
Let's go for a take
I told you to shoot
like the God Father movie
It's getting late
Let's go for the take
Lights off
What's the problem over there?
That Bluetooth head guy
creating problem
I can't do that
What do you want?
Lights on
After this dialogue
it's Sethu's entry
Where is Sethu?
Master, where is he?
Hey senseless goose, shot is ready
and everyone is looking for you
- I'll come right now
- Come quick, stupid
Guys take care of him
He is treating you
like a school student
Difficult to watch this
It is difficult to act as a gangster
than to really live like a gangster
"So what if you are the King,"
"You’ve to flex your muscles
to get things done"
"Taking a clown’s job will entail
making a fool of yourself"
Who kept the baby here?
You moron take it away
- Dude he is calling me a moron
- So what take it away now
What's all this second hero?
"Will make you go in
search of, everyday!"
He's hitting me for real
I'm supposed to
hit you in this scene
Till now no one has beat me
Pack up!
Master, what happened?
Slipped and fell down
How...how?
While taking bath
Did you all bath together?
In 3 months me
and Sethu will get married
Are you happy now?
If this movie flops,
you can make another
What about my life?
I loved you truly
You could have told me
when I proposed, right?
I'm not the filmy heroine type
Fighting everyone to marry my love
I will cry for few days...
...then will marry Sethu
and get on with my life
Like a breeze, you touched
my life and now you pass by
Go
Even I'm not the typical hero
...to fight Sethu
and take you away from him
I can't do all that
But I badly want to
We'll see, 3 more
months are there right
(Trailer on TV)
Whole Tamilnadu
should know my name
In the history of Madurai, Not just
Madurai in the history of whole India
For the first time a movie is getting
released in all the theatres in a city
Anywhere you turn,
you can only find his face
Entire city looks like
geared up for festival
Everywhere Sethu, Sethu
Why is the movie
named "A.Kumar"?
"Assault Kumar"
People call me
"Assault" Sethu right?
Since Assault is an English word
More tax has to be paid
That's why just the initial
We'll only release
Sharukh Khan movie
What can you do about it?
Leave the place
The movie is going to be
released tomorrow
For the next one year
only our film should run
My film should not lose,
If so it's a shame
We have given token to
every house in the city
Friday 3 p.m
and Sunday 6 p.m show okay?
2 shows? Friday have to
go to work
That's alright put
sick leave and come
We have arranged vehicles
to pick and drop everyone
Do come and enjoy the film
You've to come everyday
We are also gonna give biriyani
and alcohol for the film goers
You've got 150 tickets
Even one not turning up,
I'll kill you
Kollywood is in shock by looking
at the opening for a debut actor
We'll get to know the results
by tomorrow after the release
Is this the violent
action film that I asked for?
This is all I could manage with him
How is the movie?
Why are you crying, sir?
Dad, I'm not coming in
you go ahead
Why?
You go,
I'll watch from here
Okay
Come one by one
Get in...get in
Move...move
"In a land of blood and death,
called the grand Madurai...
among the ruthless killers was
born a man called 'A.Kumar'
In A.Kumar,
A stands for...
Azukuni Kumar
(Crybaby Kumar)
What he does is?
He cries for everything
...and tries to become a gangster
Who is that Azukuni Kumar?
Here comes our sir
If you make a gangster film with
him, it would be a laughing stock
You are acting serious
but everyone is laughing
In the next scene
I'll shoot a guy,
You see everyone
would be shocked
Cry man, cry out loud
He made me a fool
Roll camera
Do it
Hey, do it man
Listen to me carefully
Did you speak this dialogue?
What I spoke in that
scene was different
It's not even my voice
They have added it separately
Oh, you can add things
later to the movie is it?
Why are you crying, sir?
Awesome, how did you?
Awesome, man
Everyone in the audience is
gonna enjoy every minute of it
First he cut the call,
Now it's switched off
The song was different when we
shot, now it is something else
I have never seen people
laughing so much for a song
It seems like a magic
It is our fault, not knowing
what could be made in cinema
Light it and cry
Light it...and cry
Now light it and cry
Hit your head and cry
Jump crying from there
Come, let's go
He ditched us
Eating my food, under my roof,
with my story, look what he did
That's why they never
to trust the educated
- Great job
- Superb
- Mom
- Movie is very good
Tell me, sir
Acted like a buffoon
feeling ashamed
- Tell me, boss
- Sethu...
Awesome, buddy
You made Sethu a joker,
the comedy king of the decade
- Thank you, sir
- I hope your next movie with me
Hey I'm flying to Singapore tonight
You guys too be safe, don't get caught
If we get caught,
that's it
This movie is breaking genre
and trends set here
A comedy gangster flick
"Azhuguni Kumar" (Crybaby Kumar)
How did you get the idea?
People are scared of these
murderers and killers
With a story of such
a violent murderer...
I wanted to make
everyone laugh
In fact most of these rowdies
will look like a joker up close
Just thought of showing that
How did you find the lead,
looked really funny on screen?
We were looking for
a guy who looks comical
An apt face
for Azukuni Kumar,
Of the 1000 faces I saw,
he fitted perfectly for the title
The gang in chennai is in the lookout,
but they all went hiding
Our biggest assets is
the fear people have seeing us
Have lost that all in one day
Find Karthik and kill him
Kill him with my hands
There is no one in this house
Looks like locked for while
Where is Oorni?
It's been 2 weeks
since sir went abroad
You guys are staging
a drama here
He is not there
10 lakh if Sethu should come
It is fine but you finish
the deal, don't need Sethu
If he comes, everyone would burst into
laughter and no one would take it serious
- He is coming
- Is he the one?
- Where is Karthi
- I don't know brother
They have thrashed him
at the Temple
He's is safe for now, has requested
and extended his stay in the hospital
Your parents have
reached Bombay safely
Speak to them
Why are we running and hiding?
What did I do wrong?
What didn't you?
He started beating people cause someone
laughed at him in a school drama
Now everyone is laughing at him
Because of you
I didn't pull him into this
He forced me to do it
It's me who should chase
and him for this state
We've got to do something
What can we do?
We caught a reporter
once and took him to...
- Where was that?
- Sugarcane field
Took him there and
planned to burn him alive
If you had shown this
2 months back...
...there would have been
no need to even make that movie
Just had a thought
about the evidences
What is the plan?
I spoke to ACP Raman
This proof is enough
We need to get this
to Dindigul police tomorrow
Dindigul? Why don't we go
to Madurai only? It's risky
Sethu is not a gang lord for
the police to come and collect the proof
We have to go for our needs
Don't worry they are
looking for you in Chennai
That's why you are
hiding here near Madurai
It is better to hide beneath
the enemy than across him
But we can't stay hidden forever
Its been a week since my kid
was born, haven't seen him yet
Don't worry just another 10 days
Will Sethu forget everything
in 10 days?
No he'll be forever gone
They have burned the reporter alive,
will the police leave him?
ACP said if the proof is good,
he can move and get the order
- What order?
- What else?
For encountering Sethu
They will kill him?
Let him die
Every show they are
talking about Sethu
Yeah
This A.Kumar has become
the undeniable king of comedy
Have you gone mad?
Why are acting crazy?
Yes, they have made me crazy
The whole world is making fun of me
and you both are having your laughs
Its not like that Sethu,
all big stars are praising you
Have you ever had the courage
to talk in front of me?
Where did you
get the guts to talk?
You have lost the fear
for me, right?
That's why all this,
do I look funny to you?
Stop this, hitting women
If you are stuck here in this house,
they will make you a joker for real
We have got close to Karthik,
We'll find him 2 days
What happened now?
We'll murder some
and get our name back
Ponram's dad expired it seems,
just got the news
The funeral is in Dindigul house
The duet song in the A.Kumar film
is the talk of the town
More than 5 million viewers
have seen this song on YouTube
The trend setting song and the comedy
performance of the hero becomes-
Sethu...?
Let's enjoy the song
Sethu...hey Sethu
Fetch some water for me
Would they kill everyone?
I don't know about all
but Sethu for sure
Is that really needed?
Isn't it wrong?
You prefer to die
in their hands?
Its a game of cat and mouse
We have to play cat,
like they taught us
Everything is right for survival
What is that for?
Just for safety, uncle gave it
We don't need that
Once he ruled
the whole Dindigul
What did he rule?
Does this look
like a king's funeral?
Not even a single soul that lurked
in his shadows turned to his funeral
We mistake all
the fear for respect
There are a lot who are
happy that he's gone
A coffee with less sugar
He is the hero
of the movie A.Kumar
You were the actor
in AKumar movie right?
Yes, Sethu was the hero in that
Heard the movie is doing well
Have to watch it
after all this is over
Watched the movie, it was so awesome
You have done a great job
The whole movie
was a laugh riot
Your dance
and fight was excellent
I told you right, he's that hero
Stop the car
Reverse it
I think this police
business is not needed
Everything that happened
was in our favor, isn't it?
Don't keep repeating the same
If you feel like helping me,
just keep quiet
We won't get caught
don't worry
They'll never leave us in peace
Just a minute
- Who's that?
- Sounder's wife
We saw your movie
it was good
We haven't gone out
anywhere since his death
But last week your people
forced us to go watch it in theaters
I laughed after a long time
She has become your fan
watching the movie
She wanted to watch it again,
took her again the next day
You wanted to say
something right, say it
Tell him, he has to leave
Uncle you had danced well
and fights were nice
Crybaby Kumar was superb
Are you done,
shall we go?
- Doesn't she know?
- No one knows
Sekar shot Sounder
and we shot him back
That is all
She wants to
shake hands with you
You asked right, go on
(Gibberish)
Go away
Get lost
Get lost I say
Come, Oorni
Do you have Director
Maniratnam's number?
'Today'
Sir, the target is in position
shall we move?
Let's move
What?
Karthik has sent you a gift
Sir, its over
he's dead
Jigarthanda means cold-heart
It's not a usual script
It's against the social violence
and about world peace
Just think about it again,
In this subject-
Hello, I understand,
your story is good
Maybe after 2 years
we'll see about it
We'll start the shoot in 2 months
You are the hero
Are you commanding me?
Who do you think you are?
I'll make sure you don't
make films anymore
Getup, Idiot
Hey guards
Get up
What's all this? Ro...?
Rowdyism?
Cut
Okay?
Is the shot ok?
How was my performance?
Is it okay, sir?
Is the shot okay?
Sir, I've performed well, isn't it?
Sir, tell me
- Muthu
- Coming
What's this?
Is this what I asked?
- I'll correct it
- Make it fast
He can't act
even if it was real
This is not fair
Look, I am not seeking your
permission to act in my film
I'm telling you
to act in the film
Okay?
Okay, I'll do it but the next
will be Mani Ratnam's
Uncle...Uncle?
- Uncle?
- What?
Don't disturb him
No thanks, but call me Dad
Feeling romantic...?
Tell me dear,
Yeah I'm with him
He will agree
He has
I'll call you back
My wife is your fan
She wants you to act
without all these tash and beard
You'll look good
Of course, this script right?
Jigarthanda
About the social injustice
brought by violence
...and a hero who fights
back the system
A good social message
A good script
Nothing helps like pounding
Ok, let's go for one more
Double up
Looks good on you
Camera
Action