On the pages of American folklore,
a legion of mighty men have left
the symbols of their greatness.
There was Paul Bunyan's axe.
John Henry's hammer.
Davy Crockett's rifle.
And then, quite unexpectedly,
one comes upon a tin-pot hat,
a bag of apple seed and a holy book.
And strangely enough,
these are the symbols
of one of the mightiest men of all.
John Chapman, a real-life pioneer.
With the passing years, however,
reality has given way to legend.
Until today, we know this remarkable man
simply as Johnny Appleseed.
This is his story, told by an old settler
who knew Johnny well.
Listen.
Well, sir,
every time I see an apple-blossom sky,
I think of Johnny Appleseed.
Because of course
them clouds up there,
they ain't really clouds at all.
No, sir.
Why, there wouldn't be
no apple-blossom sky
if it weren't for the fact that Johnny...
But, now, hold on here.
Guess I better start back
to the beginning.
And that's when Johnny lived on a farm
near Pittsburgh town.
The year was 1806
or maybe there around.
Now, just to look at him,
you'd say Johnny Appleseed
never would make a pioneer.
He was such a sawed-off
scrawny little fella.
Of course, that didn't faze Johnny none.
He had his apple trees
and the morning sun
and the evening breeze.
The Lord is good to me
And so I thank the Lord
For giving me the things I need
The sun and rain and an apple seed
Yes, he's been good to me
I owe the Lord so much
For everything I see
I'm certain if it weren't for him
There'd be no apples on this limb
He's been good to me
Oh, here am I
Neath the blue, blue sky
A- doing as I please
Singin' with my feathered friend
Hummin' with the bees
I wake up every day
As happy as can be
Because I know that with his care
My apple trees, they will still be there
Oh, the Lord is good to me
Working, singing, carefree and gay,
that's how Johnny spent each day
attending to his apple trees.
But lately, little Johnny here
would feel a stirring in the air.
A rumbling, rolling under bead
of restless men and restless feet.
There's plenty of room for you
Get on the wagon rolling west
Out to the great unknown
Or you'll be left alone
We'd little hope before
We're starting out again
We ain't afeard of man or beast
We're strong-hearted men
So get on the wagon rolling west
Seeking a land that's new
Get on the wagon rolling west
There's plenty of room for you
Out to the great unknown
Get on the wagon rolling west
Or you'll be left alone
The rivers may be wide
The mountains may be tall
But nothing stops the pioneer
We're trailblazers all
Oh, get on the wagon rolling west
Out to the great unknown
Get on the wagon rolling west or...
You'll be left alone
Poor Johnny.
He weren't no pioneer
and he knowed it.
It was all just pretend.
And them folks going west
to build this nation
sure made picking apples
look like a plum useless occupation.
Well, sir,
that's when a miracle happened.
Well, what's holding you, Johnny?
Says a voice.
Go on. Go on out west
if that's your choice.
Well, sir, it was a angel.
Johnny's own private guardian angel.
Might look mighty queersome
to you and me,
but you know, that's just the way
John figured he'd be.
Well, speak up, boy.
Don't stand there gawking.
Unlock your jaw and get to talking.
Yes, sir.
Why don't I go west?
Because I ain't got the muscle
or the breadth of chest.
Out there it's the strong men
who's surviving.
I'm about the puniest fella alive.
Shame to you, Johnny.
You got faith and courage
and a level head.
But you see, sir,
all I know is apple trees.
And what's wrong with apples,
if you please?
Ain't they about the finest fruit
in all the land?
Why... Why, shoot, man,
they take the cake.
Just think, Johnny,
of all the things that apples make.
There's apple pickles.
Oh-so-tasty apple tarts
And apple pastry, apple dumplings
Not to mention...
- Apple sauce?
- Yes.
And there's apple fritters, light as thistle
And for folks to wet their whistle
- Tangy apple cider in a glass
Stew 'em, fry 'em, boil 'em, pick 'em
- Apple-pie and apple-cake them.
- Yep.
You can cook 'em many ways
There's apple this and apple that
The recipes'd fill your hat
Why, I could carry on like this all day
So pack your stuff and get a-going
Get them apple trees a-growing
There's a lot of work out there to do
- There's a lot of work to do
Yes, sir.
I mean, no, sir.
You see, sir, I ain't got the traps,
ain't got the gear.
Or none of the things I'll need out there.
You ain't got the...
Dad gummit, boy. I'm ashamed of you.
You got the stuff to see you through.
Why, you got all the seeds
you're needing.
And for pretty darn good reading...
There ain't nothing finer than your book
Here's a mighty handy bonnet.
Even got a handle on it.
Turn it upside down and you can cook
So come on, son, and get a-going
Get them apple trees a-growing
- There's a lot of work out there to do
- Oh, there's a lot of work to do
Well, sir, that's how it all began.
That's how Johnny, all alone,
set out to meet the great unknown.
It was a mighty big and fearsome place
for a man to face.
A little man and all alone,
without no knife, without no gun.
And though the forest is dark and wide
with fearsome critters on every side,
Johnny just kept walking on.
Walked until at last he found
a little spot of open ground
with fertile soil and warmsome breeze.
A likely place for apple trees.
Now, the varmints here,
they couldn't know
if John was friend or John was foe.
So some took off in sudden flight.
And some got set to claw and bite.
But if Johnny seen him,
he paid no heed.
Just got busy planting apple seed.
Now, them varmints
come from everywhere,
watched that man a-digging there.
Didn't like what they were seeing.
Didn't trust no human being.
Yep, that ornery human had to go.
But who was a-gonna tell him so?
Well, not a soul could answer that
till here come along
a black and white cat.
Now, he weren't too bright,
but he didn't much care.
He knowed he had a certain air
about.
Well, sir, that done it.
The critters ne'er see the be to that:
The likes of a human a-liking that cat.
Why, this little man
had went and busted every precedent.
He was the very first to come
without no knife, without no gun.
And so it was from that time on,
every last living varmint
was a friend to John.
They surely was.
The Lord is good to me
And so I thank the Lord
For giving me the things I need
The sun and rain and an apple seed
And he's been good to me
Well, as time went by,
Johnny kept right on
a- planting his apple trees
and making friends everywhere.
And his best friend was the pioneers.
For, of course, John was planting
more than an apple tree.
He was planting his own boundless faith
and courage too.
And that give folks new heart,
new hope in the job they had to do.
And as more and more pioneers
come to push back the forest,
the kindly deeds
of little Johnny Appleseed
spread throughout the land.
And more than once
with a good old-fashioned jubilee
folks would honour Johnny Appleseed
and the fruit of the apple tree.
Now, sometimes
if John was a-passing by,
he'd mosey over
and kind of look in on the doings.
Because it sure tickled him
to see how the fruit of his labours
brought all kinds of folks together
and made them good neighbours.
Come and get it.
The food is on the table set.
It's all a-waiting to be eat.
Come and get it.
- Apple pickles.
- Mighty tasty.
- Apple butter.
- Apple pastry.
- Apple dumpling.
- How'd you like some applesauce?
Yes, ma'am.
Yep, Johnny did bring folks
a heap of happiness.
But he weren't looking for thanks.
Didn't have time for it.
He knowed a man can take no rest
if he aims to plant
the whole darn wilderness
in apple trees.
And so it was for more than 40 year
John walked and planted
that old frontier.
Yes, sir,
40 years of walking and planting.
And in that space of two-score year
this little man,
he throwed his shadow
clear across the land
across a hundred thousand
miles square.
And in that shadow everywhere,
you'll find he left his blessings three:
Love and faith
And the apple tree
Boy, for sleeping you take the cake.
Come on, get up.
We got a longsome trip to make.
Oh, why, Mr. Angel. How do you do?
I'm fine. And how be you?
I'm fine. Just feeling...
Who is that
sleeping in the evening dusk?
Why, that's just your husk, John.
Your mortal husk.
My husk?
You mean to say I'm...?
I'm passed away?
Dagnabbit, angel. I just can't go.
Got crops to harvest, seeds to sow.
Now, now, now. Hold on, boy.
Down here on Earth,
your work is through.
But yonder?
Well, we need you, Johnny.
Yep, we sure do.
You think we had most all we please,
but we ain't.
We're kind of short on apple trees.
Well, I swan. I didn't know.
What are we waiting for?
Come on, let's go.
We're wasting time, let's get it going
Get them apple trees a-growing
- There's a lot of work up there to do
- Oh, there's a lot of work to do
Well, sir, now you know the reason why
whenever I see that certain sky,
I think of little John.
Because it's like I said, if you'll recall.
Them clouds ain't really clouds at all.
They're apple blossoms, if you please,
from John's heavenly orchard
of apple trees.
And someday they're will be apples there
For everyone in the world to share
The Lord is good to me