Goa 1958.
India attained freedom in 1947.
But Goa was under
Portuguese rule till 1961.
This is a city of Goa, Vasco.
And this is Alberto Vasco.
He owns the maximum land here.
In a way, he is the king.
That is why this city
is named after him.
And his statue is put up
in the central square.
Before him, nobody had
been honored thus.
That day, the scene was festive.
All the town sfolk had gathered.
Everyone was cheerful.
They were congratulating him
with heart felt wishes.
Except for one woman.
You pig!!
What do you think of yourself?
May worms feed on your body!
Nobody will give you a sip
of water when you die!
Forget it. We are not
to go into that area!
I'll see you!
This is the statue of Alberto
Vasco, the biggest land owner.
He owned more than half the city.
That is how this city
was named Vasco.
When the Portuguese
left Goa 20 years ago...
These big landlords left
their property behind.
They grabbed everything,
but it's good for us.
You'll get the kind
of place you want.
Because there's no real owner.
Driver, stop the car.
I want that house.
- For the company guesthouse.
- Sure. You'll get it.
Bihari, stop these hoodlums!
Why are they breaking my house?
Does the house become yours
if you encroach on it?
You are the tenant. Sign here and
you'll get 5000 or you get nothing.
All right.
I'll meet you at the shop.
Your stool, uncle.
He went there to steal and
the Eagles beat him up!
Idiot! Come on.
Jojo! Run!
The Bichhus(Scorpions)
Have come to thrash us!
Come on, Michael.
Hey you dog!
Didn't I say, you guys
must not step into our area?
A dozen of you have ensconced
yourselves here for 2 years.
Since then Vasco has
had problems.
Before that, you Christians
did the ball dance here!
Hey pig, have you forgotten
last time's thrashing?
You escaped because
Father Jacob intervened.
Remember what I said then?
This side of the ground is ours
and that side is yours.
Now you must live there, and die there.
Get the buildings and
homes on that side vacated.
Or I'll break your legs
and place them on your hands!
Do you think I'm easy meat?
Does your father own Vasco?
Why? Didn't your mother tell you?
We are in our spirits
Sobe in your senses
Don't you glare at us
Let'shear that again
We're in the spirits too
You had better be
in your senses
Don't you give us
those dirty looks...
What did you say?
...come again
I've come across
several guys like you
Just tell us what
you're getting at
Go away; don't come here.
And don't mess with us
Go on, get lost...
Stop fibbing... we're not scared
You're ignorant.
If you have the guts...
Come and face me...
- You have a fight!
What do you take me for?
What did you say...?
Come again
Beware... careful!
You had better be careful of us
Lay off! Keep away...
they're all scared of us
Stop making a noise. Come out
in the open, if you want a fight
- I'm alert...
- And ready
What are you worth...?
Who the hell are you?
We are in the spirits...
Talk sense
- So talk sense
Don't you glare at us
What did you say...?
Come again
Arrest all these boys!
Sir, what have I done?
I was just arm wrestling with brother.
Sir, I said I'd drop him to
Calan gute on my mobike, isn't it?
Yes Sir, and I said I'd drop him
in my Mercedes tempo.
So... coming pal?
That is why we thought
we'd wrestle arms to decide.
See that, D'costa? Sometimes
they fight, sometimes they love...
They should have been married!
The mention of marriage
makes you laugh, huh?
Bichhu married to an Eagle. Where?
In prison!
Did these children fight again?
Children...?
These children?
Last week they broke 4 street
lights, the entire vegetable market...
And Rodriques' new car.
I would handcuff
them even in jail!
Why do you fight? Want to
show your strength to each other?
I know you are young,
full of spirit.
Instead of breaking each others'
bones, make something of yourselves.
Live together like brothers.
Remember my words,
life is very precious.
Once this time is lost,
it will never return.
Remember my words.
Spare them this time.
They are immature.
- They won't repeat this.
- You're making a mistake.
They are dangerous, not immature!
Yet I spare them for your sake.
Even if you pluck a leaf
from a tree, watch it!
Come on. Move!
Now all of you go away.
Get on with your jobs.
- You got into a fight again?
- No father, they started it!
The dogs...!
But if they start a fight,
we can't keep quiet...
This blood shed will not help.
But they started it.
We were just...
I want to see you in church.
- This Sunday?
- Every Sunday.
You come in last, yet
want to leave first.
It's Max' fault. It takes so long
to wake him up! He's still sleeping!
- There's a jam session in
college on Saturday. - So...?
- Why? - The Purple Riot
Band has come from Bombay.
What happened?
Look at her hand!
May I read your palm?
You have a terrific lifeline!
And take a look at this love line...
Never seen one like this!
Solid...!
What's his name?
Okay, I'll answer that.
Does his name begin with T?
- Dog! Want one?
- No!
No? Of course you'll want one!
- Yes!
- Then why did you say no?
Next time you flirt with my
sister, you'll get thrashed!
It's going to be twelve.
Let's meet the strike.
We must reach home
before the twelve gongs.
But you must only count the
gong. Don't tell me to turn.
- Careful!
- What are you doing?
- Look ahead!
- Aunt, give way!
No problems now!
Leave her and turn right!
But why did you scream?
Who screamed? I...
- You tell him...
- No, you!
The brakes had failed.
But you didn't make it.
I'll go get my bike serviced.
The bike is fine.
It was your mistake.
Why did you get involved
with Rose Anne?
- Today is not a good day.
- Rubbish! It's very special.
What's special about today?
I'm sorry, I forgot.
What little sister? We were born
on the same day at the same time...
But I was born 15 seconds early.
Do you like it?
You made it yourself?
- It's not for this!
- But this fits best in it.
For me?
Whether Max remembers your
birthday or not, I will.
You remember it only because I too
was born on the same day, same time.
...5,6,7,8,9, 10.
One thousand and one.
Your fees for getting
the house evacuated.
You may keep the one buck.
Bihari, you are great!
It looks absolutely real!
Here's your share of
...10, 10 and 5.25000.
We do the threatening and breaking.
And this scoundrel,
Bihari reaps the rewards
I say to hell with Bihari.
Why don't we do direct
dealing with Chaudhary?
The idea is good but Bihari
forges the property papers.
Who will do the writing for us?
Little guy!
My brother!
You rogue! You've turned
stylish! Like a Bombayite!
But you are just the same.
Come on, Vasco is that way.
Mother! Come downstairs!
Rahul has come back!
Chottu, get the bagsout.
He looks terrific!
Then what? Whose brother is he?
I've thought of a great plan for us.
- Me too.
- You say first.
We all will live in Bombay.
Life is great there.
Man's luck changes in a minute.
What is left in Vasco? Will
mother agree to come to Bombay?
The guys selling the caftan
made a fool out of you.
There's a hole in this.
Give it back to Rahul. He'll
return it. He's going back.
- You're going back?
- Not alone. All of us will go.
I'll open a big fast food restaurant.
Indian, foreign every style.
Mr. Shetty will put up the
capital and my training.
In a year, I'll take you
to the skies, mother!
I don't want to reach anywhere.
I will stay here.
- But mother, over there...
- You may go.
- Leave tomorrow itself.
- No, mother.
- I'm here for a month.
- Why are you wasting time?
You've seen the place.
You've fixed everything.
Why did you come here?
You could have written.
Pack this in his bag. Invest what
you get on returning it in your hotel.
Mother! Did you have
to tell her right now?
I'd have explained to her.
Now she is angry with me.
So? She saw you after two years.
You've been home for barely 5 hours
and you're talking of returning!
Pinhead, see Vasco.
I am confident you won't leave it.
Rest tonight. I'll show you
the sights of Vasco tomorrow.
Come here. Sorry, I'm late.
Some important work cropped up.
This is my brother, Rahul.
He's very educated, a chef.
That means an English cook.
And these are my pals.
That is Lafdu. Chandu.
That is Chottu and Dasan.
And he's special, Bheja Fry.
Those two are the
newcomers, Devand Pepsi.
Why are you smiling? Show
Rahul the sights of Vasco.
So Prakash is the boss
of the Bichhu gang?
Do you know from dogs and cats
to important men, salute him?
We saw Maria's house on the way?
He pays expenses to the guys who
forcibly live there, to evacuate it.
He'll thrash them...
so this is the businessof Bicchu gang
In a while, everyone
will salute you too.
Don't call me a hood!
And there's no need to be my guide.
I'll see the place myself.
- Rahul!
- Sir!
- Don't go ahead.
- Why?
We're standing on the borderline!
- What border? - That side of
the ground belongs to the eagles!
Eagle gang is the sworn
enemy of the Bichhu gang!
Nobody from that gang
can come to our area.
And our boys can't go there!
Not even by mistake!
Not by mistake.
But he can go on purpose.
You must not go ahead!
You are the princess
of my dreams...
You put everything around
to shade
So come and take my hand
You put everything
around to shade...
Here she comes...
bathed in roses
She brings the
fragrance with her
It's your eyes...
they're intoxicating
Your beauty, I behold
You are the Princess
of my dreams...
You have put everything
around to shade
Come and take my hand
It'smagic...
you have cast a spell
I can't control
my heart anymore
Tell me at least so much,
Oh celestial beauty...
Where do you live?
And what is your name?
O Princess of my dreams...
You have put everything around
to shade
So take my hand
I don't know you but
I felt like talking to you.
- Are you new to this place?
- Yes. I came on Friday.
My family is here for 2 years
but I was studying in Bombay.
This is the first time
I've come to Goa.
It's a beautiful place.
Just a minute.
I thought it would be great
if somebody could show me around.
- My name is...
- What have you seen in Vasco?
The ground, the beach and the old fort
Have you seen Max?
What is that?
You must meet him.
He'll show you everything.
Lights at night, stars in the day...
You too will like him a lot.
He's a first rate scoundrel!
Why should we talk of that hood, Max?
Do you know why I've called you here?
For lunch.
- Then...? - For many days
I've been wanting to say something.
Each time I see you,
my heart says something.
- What did you say?
- Not to you. There...
- There's nobody there.
- There isn't?
Do you know I met your Daddy?
- When?
- Two days ago.
He was buying brandy.
He was fighting for 3 bucks.
I looked at him and said...
You scoundrel! You've come here too!
- I didn't mean you.
- You meant my Daddy!
Not even your Daddy!
These hoods have come here!
- May I sit here?
- No, we're having a private lunch.
What have you ordered?
- Why are you abusing me?
- It's the name of the dish.
Then say so. What is added to it?
- What? - It's a Chinese dish.
It will have cockroaches.
No, I'll tell you its' ingredients.
It's got noodles and chicken.
Prawns and a few carrots.
Capsicum and mushrooms...
But no cockroaches.
How does one eat it?
Chew it with your teeth.
- And how is the taste?
- Spicy.
A little sweet; a little spicy.
Must be a delicious, sweet feeling.
- Take it away and eat it!
- That's what I think.
- This...
- I thought you meant Rose.
I can't eat your lunch.
These days we're dieting.
- Yes. - You eat it.
- I don't want it.
- Eat it.
- I don't want it!
We're leaving.
Were you not here, I'd have beaten,
cut him and made Manchurian of him!
Eat quietly now.
How can I eat? I wanted to
tell you something special.
You are the largest part of my life...
Cockroach!
Hooligan! Max! Why are you after me?
Don't you know?
Rose Anne humiliated you
in front of Savio once again.
She loves me a lot but her
style of flirting is different.
I was in church and this boy
came and sat right next to me.
Right under Father's nose.
And said, this is the
first time I've come to Goa.
I wish somebody would take me
around Vasco town, etc, etc...
- Who was he?
- I don't know.
He was openly flirting.
Next time you see him, tell me.
Wow! So many potato chips?
I'll give you two box fulls.
Take them to Bombay.
And think of your mother there!
How about if I eat all
these chips right here?
What do you mean?
I mean, I have made a decision.
I won't go to Bombay.
- Really?
- Yes, I'll stay here. With you.
- I'll open a small shop here.
- That's great!
Are you happy, mother?
Don't worry about the shop.
I'll fix everything
tomorrow. Little guy!
You've won the jackpot, uncle!
My brother adores your
shop that's lying vacant.
I'll take it on rent.
I'll pay 500 a month.
Okay, I'll pay 600 but paint it.
I want 25000 as deposit.
And 5000 rent per month.
Talk if it's acceptable.
Are you giving the Taj?
Why are you interrupting?
- Give it happily or...
- Let me talk.
What do you want to say?
I'm just beginning.
I need your co-operation.
- If you...
- I see, I see everything!
He's threatening me from
there! Hooligan! Ruffian!
Old man! You think we're crazy?
Even pigeons don't lay eggs
in that ruin of yours!
If I don't go what will you do,
you land grabbing swindler?
He took the land when
his landlord died.
He's asking for 5000 when he
doesn't pay the rent himself!
You bald...!
Call a midi or a bell-bottom!
- Call anybody...
- Brother, let go!
I'll see who comes to your help!
Let go of uncle.
Should I hold you?
Let go or I'll chop you right here!
I say, leave him! Let go!
Why did you interfere?
I'd have dealt with Max!
Mother is right, you are out of hand!
The shop is our of our hands.
Would your fisticuffs
have got it for us?
- Of course! - That is how
we have to set tenants right.
You being a gentleman won't
work in this business.
Then what will work?
Bichhu's gang hooliganism?
That's not true. We deal
with business like business.
We never create fights for no reason.
- They came to talk of marriage...
- Your brother is like that...
- I'm scared of him.
- You dog! Cad!
- Flirting in my area!
- Help!
Teasing girls in our area!
You rotten Eagle!
Prakash! Let go!
Leave him!
That bastard Eagle was flirting
with one of our girls!
Stop it! I don't
want to hear anything!
Prakash has sent us.
He apologizes.
Why are you quiet?
You should apologize.
You cut the noses of Bichhu
gang in front of the Eagles!
Look, you are new here.
You don't know the problems here.
It's good he thrashed that Eagle.
Had I been there, I'd
have castrated him!
If anyone even looks at Max's
sister, Shirley, he blinds him!
Is Shirley, Max' sister?
Twin! She's his twin sister!
How can we spare anyone who
takes a girl from our area out?
We've come here because Prakash
is the leader of Bichhu gang.
He's standing there.
Go and meet him.
He may be your boss.
He's my brother. Don't
teach me what I must do!
- She's coming!
- Butterfly, where are you going?
My rain cloud. Shower on me!
Spare me a glance...
Rent of 1000 bucks
and zero deposit.
A job can be done
without spending money.
I give up, man! You're really
smart! Lafdu, take this.
Do you forgive me?
On one condition.
Only if you give up fighting
and help me in setting my shop.
Is that all? Then listen...
You're with Rahul from today.
- And you?
- I am with you.
What guys?
Will you do it or not?
You've said it.
Assume it done.
Having a fancy name won't
make the cakes sweeter?
Look at that Bichhu entering
our area unflinchingly!
Yes, Prakash's brother. Come on!
You Bichhu's don't get
visa to come to our area.
- Don't you know?
- Answer him!
He forgot the answer and the road.
I have to deliver this cake
there. Make way for me.
Else what will you do? Beat us?
Show us some punch, fair villager!
This Captain Cook can only show
examples of cake and pastries.
The baboon! Just watch
how the coward will flee!
Those who run away are cowards.
But those fighting for no
reason are not valiant.
They are fools.
What man...?
Do you have to deliver
the cake with your own hands?
But if you don't have hands...?
Now get out fast or your hands and
legs will be here and the body there.
What border? I don't see any border.
You'll see it. You will
see it before you go blind!
What is this?
Sold just one biscuit all day?
Keep this on your nose and draw a
borderline pushing it to the ground.
There...
Come on! You cookboy!
I'd kept it for a beggar.
You may each take 5 paise.
You dog#$@!
What a collar!
Not a sign of dirt.
Do you get an imported
washer man to wash it?
What is going on?
We were discussing laundering.
Laundering shirts or him?
What were they telling you?
- Showing me the way.
- Then?
The wrong path. I was going right.
Get on with your work.
Come with me.
We were doing our work.
You came and spoilt matters.
Come on guys.
What was the score?
Do you like my new car?
It's nice but look ahead and drive.
Quiet...
My bike is  new. Pinch me.
- Get lost!
- Give you a shove?
My car is new.
Much faster than your bullock cart!
Savio is throwing you a challenge.
No, it's not fair.
My bike, his jalopy.
I'm a man and Savio...
We'll have a race.
Forget it. If you race
I'll get off here.
It's a matter of my honor!
...which I'm going to plunder.
Don't you just love
to fool simple people?
You too fool him.
You love me but go out with him.
Someday God will punish you!
What happened?
God turned into an ant and bit me!
Come with me. Why are
you playing hard to get?
To how many girls have you said this?
Only you, Sandra.
Only to you, Rose Anne, My love.
I said, you are my Juliet
And she said...
you're fibbing!
Why does she think I'm lying
whenever I speak the truth?!
That must be her style...
she must be consenting at heart
She'll soon say she loves you...
why are you worried?
I suggest, you invite her...
and treat her to lunch in a hotel
Take her to the sea-shore
and just pop the question
I did invite her...
and treated her to the sour-soup
I found an opportunity and went
for it... I told her everything
What did you tell her?
I said, you're my Juliet. And she...
- She said you're lying
Why does she think I'm lying
whenever I speak the truth?
That must be her style...
She must be willing at heart
She'll come around one of these
days... why are you worried?
I've dealt with so many problems...
yours is different
You're through with everything...
yet, where's the hitch?
Elope with her...
if she knows what you want
I went to elope with her
in the middle of the night
Was that really set up?
So that was your Eagle brother, Max.
Quite a specimen.
Did you like him?
Why don't you join him for tea?
Do you cycle to college daily?
No, I go with Max on his bike.
Why don't you come
with us, triple seat?
Do you think I fear Max?
Why should I fear him?
Because he wears a leather jacket?
And rings in his ears?
Rides a bike and considers
himself the local thug?
That's stupidity not bravery.
Maybe he scares kids not me.
What do you study?
I've done a course
in Hotel Management.
Why don't you come to my shop?
I make wonderful cakes.
Why would I fear Maxi?
I am this and that...
If you're so brave,
meet me in front of Maxi.
All right. Want to bet?
But if I win, you have to kiss me.
If you have a face left.
So I win!
When will I get my prize?
Will you help me shop?
Give me two melons.
I must admit, you were great that day.
- You're very brave!
- I told you so.
- I'm not scared of Max.
- But I was scared.
When Max looked at you,
for a second, I...
I was really scared!
- For me?
- Are you okay?
Scared for me?
I don't know why...
I never felt like this before.
What did you feel?
I have to make fruit salad today.
You said you never
felt like this before.
- What did you feel?
- Yes, that's it.
Possibly... I felt...
As if...
As if...?
We're home.
And my prize?
Won't you come in?
Maxi is not home.
What a beautiful house!
Now I'll give you your prize.
Now it's not just the prize.
Much more than that.
This is proof that you love me.
That's the prize for cheaters!
Anyone can wear a mask and win a bet.
Sorry, you lose.
Thanks for carrying
so many fruits for me.
Where are you going?
Maxi will soon be home.
Looks like you want to get beaten!
- No, I want to feed him.
- What?
He'll make a fruit salad
out of you, Romeo!
- And you'll enjoy it.
- Sure.
So enjoy it. Do you have lime?
No but we have a
first aid box. Want it?
You'll know when he breaks your bones.
- Then don't tell me.
- I won't.
I say... Maxi is here...
- What?
- What...?
What, what? My bike...
I just got it painted.
Looks like such a beauty!
I'll take you for a ride. Let's go.
- Not now...
- Why not? Come on.
- I have lots of work.
- Forget it, come on!
- I don't want to come!
- Don't want to come?
Don't take it to heart.
I'll come with you tomorrow.
I made it, specially for you.
Like it?
What was that sound?
Sound...? No.
There was. Where...?
Outside...
No, in here.
Who locked you in? Shirley?
You don't want to come?
I'll take Maggie.
It will be great fun
when Max returns!
The pastry is no good today.
Then go to the shop in front!
Why do you come here?
Where is aunt?
Go to Treat House.
Hurry up! We have a big contract.
Henceforth this contract
will always come to us.
He takes away my contract
and then gloats over it!
- What's the matter?
- I know everything!
This is that rascal
Prakash' trick!
He grabbed the Goa Liberation
Day contract under threats.
But one mustn't use force.
You just tell me, I'll break the
cad's legs and hang them in your shop!
What will I do with his leg?
I want the contract!
I'm a God fearing man.
Shall I get my tempo tomorrow?
No, Mr. Mascarenhas will
collect his order personally.
Need anything else?
Nothing. Carry on.
I want to place a special order.
It should have 7 colors.
Red, blue, pink.
Green, black and white.
There should be no yellow.
...should be there.
Should be there.
Write on that...
And keep in mind...
Have we stopped
accepting advance?
One has to adjust
depending on the customer.
Come on, we have enough work.
8 o'clock tomorrow.
I hope the chloroform wasn't too much.
Or they'll sleep till morning.
This is the job of an expert.
But why did you change the name?
Come in, sir.
Please listen tome.
What a tiny shop!
Full of rats!
- You cheated me!
- Sir, listen to me.
- What to listen?
- I'll do something. -What?
What's wrong?
I'll lose my job thanks to this idiot!
What was the order?
I'll give it to you.
Take them from my shop.
You saved my job.
I'll pay you 20/. Extra.
Rats running all over the place!
I don't understand how
so many rats got in.
- Maybe a window was open.
- Which window?
I don't know.
Did anyone come to the shop?
- No.
- You are very innocent.
I know it's those Catholics at fault!
You blame the Eagle
gang for everything!
Can't a rat get in by chance?
And by chance Pascal had a thousand
sandwiches and pastries ready that day
Should I ready Francis' order?
I'd asked you to get 4 dozen breads.
I'll get it. Come on.
Another order?
- How much for the first order?
- Only 200 rupees.
The cake was very good.
You're forgetting something.
Do something. It makes such a racket.
When I go to pick her up,
the old man comes down before her.
The old man is her father.
The silencer is worn out.
Put in a new one. It's urgent.
We don't have it. You'll
only get it there, in Hell.
Hell... what do you mean?
In their area. Who will go there?
I'll go. Tonight.
- Come on.
- I won't come in.
Sit near the bikes.
Michael, come on.
Look at this. Will it fit?
Put it on the bike.
I'll find another.
Setting rats out?
Let's beat this louse into a rat!
Catch him!
Fight by yourself
if you have the guts
Brought his complete rural gang!
And asks me to fight alone.
Know what? He ruined my bike.
But who will save his shop?
I'll save his shop!
Come on! Prakash and
Maxi are having a brawl!
Kill him!
Prakash! Stop!
Stop them! This is madness!
- They'll kill each other!
- This is a man's game.
You get the hell out of here.
Hit him, Prakash!
Let go of my brother!
Let go of him, Maxi!
He will die!
Are you all right?
What happened to you? Why did you
have to intervene in the fight?
- I was frightened.
- Why? You've seen fights earlier.
What if you'd been hurt?
What would happen to me? Yes?
And if he'd died?
Who? That cook?
There'd be one Bichhu less.
Nothing will happen to me.
But the funeral of
two guys is definite.
That rascal Prakash
and his brother, Rahul.
I'll always be with you.
To look after you.
Nothing will happen.
Nothing will happen, Maxi?