[Chorus]:
¶ JUST AROUND THE CORNER
MAY BE SUNSHINE FOR YOU ¶
SKIES ABOVE MAY BE BLUE ¶
¶ KEEP A LITTLE SMILE ON
THAT'S THE RIGHT THING TO DO ¶
¶ IN LITTLE WHILE
YOUR TROUBLES ¶
¶ THEY WILL DISAPPEAR
LIKE BUBBLES ¶
¶ JUST AROUND THE CORNER
THERE'S A BLUEBIRD ON HIGH ¶
¶ WAITING ON A RAINBOW
IN THE SKY ¶
¶ SUN MAY PEEK TO ANSWER HOWDY ¶
¶ JUST AROUND THE CORNER
FROM YOU ¶
¶ [Ends]
Miss Penny, Miss Vincent
wishes to see you.
- [Woman] Miss Penny is here now.
- Hello, Gus.
- Hello, Miss Penny.
- Is my daddy here?
Penny, come here, please.
Penny, I have some
sad news for you.
But you'll be a brave
little girl, won't you?
- Is it about my daddy?
- Yes, Penny.
- Has anything happened to him?
- No. No, dear, no.
But he's sent for you.
You're going to leave us.
- Are you gonna take me right now, Gus?
Right this minute?
- Yes, Miss Penny.
- I'm gonna live with my daddy at the Riverview?
On and on, for keeps?
- Yes, Miss Penny.
- Oh, Gus!
Maybe I'd better
wait outside.
It's very sad news, Miss Vincent,
but I wanna be brave...
even though I am
gonna miss everybody so much.
- And now I'd better pack. Don't you think?
- Oh, yes.
- It's not polite to keep people waiting.
- No, dear.
Please, may I be excused?
I feel awful sad about
leaving you, Miss Vincent.
- Good-bye! [Laughs]
- Good-bye.
- Good-bye, Miss Burns.
- [Door Closes]
I wonder why Mr. Hale is taking her
out of school so suddenly.
They're going abroad,
no doubt.
It wouldn't be finances.
His last check is overdue.
Finances? Hardly--
with the Riverview
as an address?
- Why, Miss Penny.
- Hello, Corporal.
- Please don't stop me now.
I've gotta find my daddy.
- Wait a minute.
Hey, Penny,
come back here!
Fine doorman you are-- Lettin' her go
right through the door.
What kind of a doorman
you call that?
Hello, Mr. Waters.
I'm back.
Uh, Miss H-- Uh--
[Chuckles]
[Man]
No, no, no. [Groans]
[Shouting French]
Attention.
[Continues In French]
- La porte.
- No, no "la porte."
Attention. Attention.
[French Continues]
- La table.
- No! No!
- [Shouting In French]
- All right. Have it your way then.
- Who are you?
[French]
Je m'appelle Penny.
- What'd she say?
- What did she say?
Did you not listen?
A lesson we have
one week behind.
J'habite ici.
"I live here."
That proves
how stupid you are.
- You don't live here and neither does she.
- Don't mind him.
He's all mixed up. I'm the one
who lives here-- My daddy and me.
I beg your pardon.
This is my uncle's apartment.
I live here with my mother and my sister and
my Uncle Sam. Now, kindly vacate our premises.
Do you think I don't know where I live?
We've lived here three years.
Unless you want trouble with my daddy,
you'd better get out and--
I'm more sorry than I can say. I'm deeply
embarrassed. Come along, Miss Hale, quickly.
- But why?
- Run along, little girl. Scat! Shoo!
- Daddy!
- I'm taking you to your daddy right now.
- Where are you?
- This is very unfortunate. I apologize.
It will never happen again.
I assure you. I'm very sorry.
- I'm distraught, distrait.
- Daddy!
- Miss Hale, will you please-- Listen--
Children are impossible
these days.
They don't ask if they live
in your house, they just tell you.
They walk right in and tell you.
You haven't a moment of privacy...
without some child coming in
to tell you she lives with you.
Mother, I pointed out her
mistake to her emphatically--
- not only in English, but in French.
- In French? Bah!
But why did Daddy move?
He liked our penthouse, and I loved it.
Oh, questions, questions.
Curiosity killed a cat once.
- Your cat?
- Yes-- Uh, no.
And stop saying "our penthouse."
It isn't yours. Not anymore.
- [Dog Barking]
- [Clicking Tongue]
- Kitty.
- Penny, darling!
- Oh, I'm so glad to see you.
- Oh!
Show Miss Hale to her
father's apartment at once. Oh!
- That's it, boy. That's it, boy.
- Whoa!
- Come on.
- [Barking]
[Laughing]
[Barking Continues]
Okay.
This is my new job
since I've seen you last.
I think it's a wonderful way to earn money--
just playing with dogs.
Yeah, that's what I thought
when I took the job.
But everybody's got
their troubles, I guess.
Gee, even little
half-pints like you.
Now, you got a good,
strong chin.
Keep it up, darling,
no matter what happens.
- What for?
- Hello, Penny.
Hello, Mrs. O'Toole.
Mr. Hale? Mr. Hale?
Daddy?
- Penny. Oh.
- [Laughs]
- Oh!
- Oh, Daddy! Daddy!
I went up
to the penthouse.
A lot of funny people
live there now.
No wonder you moved
down here.
- Did Gus take you up there?
- Oh, no.
I just supposed--
I mean, I thought--
Gus didn't take me.
Well, he's working for those people now
because we haven't any job for him.
- I... sold our car.
- Oh.
Well, then, you and I are gonna have
a lot of nice walks together, aren't we?
Oh, sure.
Do you remember--
Do you remember how hard I used to
work before you went away to school?
How I was always planning buildings
and putting them up?
We had hardly any time at all
to be together.
And you were tired
all the time.
Well, that wasn't so good,
was it?  But it made money.
We had money to live in a penthouse
and have a car and Gus and all the others.
But now it's awfully hard
to get jobs.
There seem to be enough buildings,
so I'm not working...
and we haven't so much
in our pocketbook.
But you see what that means? It means
we have all that extra time to be together.
- That's a lot better, isn't it?
- Sure it is.
But there's one thing
I want to do.
There's one thing
I want to finish.
That's the one building
your daddy wants to finish.
- Why?
- I put all my money into it.
A lot of other men did too,
because it took a great deal.
Then we had bad times, and a banker
came along and took it away from us.
- What's a banker?
- [Chuckles]
Well, a banker--
A banker is a sort of person that, uh--
that keeps things that belong to other people.
- You mean a burglar?
- [Chuckling] Oh, no.
No, darling, not that.
But we're not licked. And your daddy
is gonna make that banker understand...
that he must let me
go through with the deal.
And then we can move upstairs,
and you can go back to school.
Who wants to go upstairs
and go back to school?
Not me.
I like it here.
There aren't so many stairs to climb,
and the rooms are small.
- I don't have to walk around so much.
- [Laughing]
- Oh!
- My legs are so short...
it used to wear me out walking across
that big apartment.
And it was so high, I used to get dizzy
looking down at all the people.
- Remember?
- Uh-huh.
Now it's different.
I can look up.
It'll be fun guessing what kind
of people go with all those feet.
And besides, it's about time
somebody looked after you.
A man without a woman around the house
is quite a problem.
[Grunting]
¶ [Humming]
- [Bangs Dish]
- ¶ [Stops, Resumes Whistling]
- [Electric Clippers Whirring]
- Oh, stand still, Corset.
- Why do they call him Corset?
- [Dog Barking]
Well, he's tied in all day,
and they let him loose at night.
- Hello, Penny, darling!
- [Dogs Barking]
- Hello, Miss Lola.
- Welcome home. My goodness,
but it's nice to see you.
Thank you, Miss Lola.
I'm glad I went away.
- It's so much fun to come home again.
- Oh!
Just a minute, please.
What'll we do first?
Go to a movie or take
a drive in the park or--
Well, I may not have much time.
I have a man to take care of.
- And you know how much trouble they can be.
- I certainly do.
We'll talk about it later.
Bye, darling.
- Good-bye, Miss Lola.
- [Dog Barking]
Isn't she nice, Kitty?
When she came up to see me at school
with Daddy, even Miss incent liked her.
She's okay, but believe me,
the rest of her tribe are wacky.
Hey, baby, look. Look what I won
on the punchboard.
Whoo, you didn't do bad
for a punch drunk.
Yeah. I'm goin' back
every day.
Maybe I'll punch out
a swing band.
Keep punchin'.
That's what I always say. [Laughs]
- It's beautiful.
- Yeah.
- What is that thing?
- That ain't a thing.
It's a sax.
A lease breaker.
What do you think of it?
- ¶ [Saxophone]
- [Dogs Barking]
[Howling, Barking Continues]
Hey, take it easy.
Old pickle-puss upstairs...
is liable to come down here
all spraddled out.
[Laughing] Pickle-puss?
Is that what you call Mr. Waters?
Yeah. Oh, but I wouldn't
repeat it if I were you.
Why shouldn't she repeat it?
What's the harm in calling
a pickle-puss a pickle-puss?
You might give
the kid ideas.
You know, you're not exactly up
on child psychology.
I ain't down on it.
¶ THIS IS A HAPPY LITTLE DITTY ¶
¶ I KNOW
THE MUSIC ISN'T PRETTY ¶
¶ YOU KNOW
THE WORDS ARE NOT SO WITTY ¶
¶ ANYONE CAN SING THIS SONG ¶
¶ CHANGE KEYS
IT REALLY DOESN'T MATTER ¶
¶ IT'S STILL
A LOT OF SILLY CHATTER ¶
¶ HO-HUM
WE'RE COMING TO THE PATTER ¶
¶ JACK AND JILL
WENT UP THE HILL ¶
¶ AND FOR ALL I KNOW
THEY'RE UP THERE STILL ¶
¶ I MUST SAY
THE MUSIC ISN'T PRETTY ¶
¶ MUST SAY
THE WORDS ARE NOT SO WITTY ¶
¶ THIS IS A HAPPY LITTLE DITTY ¶
¶ YOU CAN SING IT ALL DAY LONG ¶
[ Together ]
¶ THIS IS A HAPPY LITTLE DITTY ¶
¶ I KNOW
THE MUSIC ISN'T PRETTY ¶
¶ YOU KNOW
THE WORDS ARE NOT SO WITTY ¶
¶ ANYONE CAN SING THIS SONG ¶
[ In Affected Vibrato ]
¶ CHANGE KEYS
IT REALLY DOESN'T MATTER ¶
¶ IT'S JUST
A LOT OF SILLY CHATTER ¶
¶ HOLD ON, KIDS
WE'RE COMIN' TO THE PATTER ¶
¶ THERE WAS AN OLD WOMAN
WHO LIVED IN A SHOE ¶
IT MUST'VE BEEN
AWFUL STUFFY IN THERE.
¶ STILL SAY
THE MUSIC ISN'T PRETTY ¶
THE WORDS ARE NOT SO WITTY ¶
[ Together ]
¶ THIS IS A HAPPY LITTLE DITTY ¶
¶ YOU CAN SING IT ALL DAY LONG ¶
¶ [ Big Band ]
[ Together ]
¶ THIS IS A HAPPY LITTLE DITTY ¶
¶ I KNOW
THE MUSIC ISN'T PRETTY ¶
¶ YOU KNOW
THE WORDS ARE NOT SO WITTY ¶
¶ ANYONE CAN SING THIS SONG ¶
¶ CHANGE KEYS
IT REALLY DOESN'T MATTER ¶
¶ IT'S JUST
A LOT OF SILLY CHATTER ¶
¶ HOLD ON
WE'RE COMING
TO THE PATTER ¶
¶ EARLY TO BED
EARLY TO RISE ¶
¶ AND YOUR GAL GOES OUT
WITH OTHER GUYS ¶
¶ I STILL SAY
THE MUSIC ISN'T PRETTY ¶
¶ STILL SAY
THE WORDS ARE NOT
SO WITTY ¶
[ All ]
¶ THIS IS A HAPPY LITTLE DITTY ¶
¶ FOR YOU CAN SING IT
ALL DAY LONG ¶
¶ [Ends]
[Dogs Barking]
Retreat now
and explain later.
[ Barking Continues]
[Dogs Barking]
[No Audible Dialogue]
- Uh, Mr. Hale? Mr. Hale? [Clears Throat]
- Yes?
Mr. Hale, I may owe you a debt
of gratitude for past favors, but--
- Now what's happened?
- But I am jeopardizing my position...
by allowing you
to reside here any longer.
- What are you leading up to?
- Your daughter.
She has a capacity for making
otherwise sane individuals go berserk.
Now, unless you teach her to respect
the dignity of the Riverview Arms...
you must go, or I shall have
to get a new enginee—engineer.
No, that is final.
Final.
[Door Opens, Closes]
Oh, there you are, Daddy.
I was working so hard,
I didn't even hear you.
Wasn't that funny?
[Laughing]
Penny, what have you
been up to?
Oh, I'm just making
some fudge. Taste?
The girls at school taught me.
It's the best fudge. Now, you just
sit down and wait quietly, and--
And--
Well, you might as well
let me have it.
No, sweetheart, not that.
But what have you
been doing to Mr. Waters?
Oh, don't let's talk
about me all the time.
How about you? I've had my fingers
crossed and my feet crossed.
Did that big banker
listen to our plan?
He did not.
He wouldn't even see me.
Never mind. If he comes here,
we'll throw him out.
We won't be here to throw him out
if you don't behave.
Waters will throw us out.
Why can't people be nice
to other people?
[ Buzzer Buzzing]
- What's that?
- Wait a minute.
- [Buzzing Continues]
- That's it.
- What's it? What's wrong?
- Nothing's wrong.
Everything is gonna be all right now.
I'm gonna see a man...
and when I come back,
everything's gonna be all fixed:
Money, job and everything.
[ Knocking]
- Jeff!
- Lola!
Listen, he's all alone.
There isn't a soul in the house.
Well, you're an angel.
- [Man] Come in. Come in. What do you want?
- Good luck, darling.
[Door Closes]
Well, I've never
seen you before.
I think it's time you did.
I worked for you for two years.
Oh, yeah?
Did I fire ya?
- What's your name?
- Jeff Hale.
- I think you remember the name.
- Oh, Mr. Hale.
Yeah, the expensive Mr. Hale.
[Chuckles]
Yeah, Mr. Hale,
the architect.
Yeah, the man who dreamed of the majestic
East Gate project.
- I worked through Mr. Warner, my attorney.
- Yeah, well, you may have...
worked through him,
but you got to me...
for $10 million!
Yeah, you were the genius that handed me
that $10 million lemon!
It isn't a lemon.
If you had vision?
Vision? Don't you
talk to me about vision.
Come here.
Here, look at that.
Yeah, I don't need
any vision to see that...
but I'll need a lot to see
any of that $ 10 million again.
Who let you in here,
young man?
If you want the truth, Lola did.
She believes in this project.
- She believes in me.
- And I believe that you are the nerviest rascal...
that I ever met
in a life knee-deep in rascals.
Using my niece to get in here, feeding her
your crack-brained schemes.
- Careful. Remember your stomach.
- You leave my stomach out of it.
You leave her out of it too.
She's crack-brained enough without your help.
She's the sanest one
in the family at that.
But they're all Einsteins
compared to you.
Come here.
Now, you git.
- Mr. Henshaw--
- Git!
- Jeff, what happened? How'd it come out?
- Awful.
Oh, darling, sit down,
tell me all about it.
There isn't much to tell.
I told him, and then he told me.
- But he had an edge.
- And he wouldn't even listen
to what you had to say?
Honestly, darling,
even if he is my own uncle--
Don't bother. You can't
call him anything that I haven't.
Jeff, I know how
we can get around him.
- Oh, let's forget about it.
- Oh, so, you're quitting?
I'm not quitting,
but what can I do?
Listen, Jeff, I've been
handling him since I was a little girl...
and I've always
gotten what I wanted.
You won't get anywhere trying to
fight with him. You've got to go around him.
- Come on. Let's try it my way.
- Just to make conversation, what's your way?
- By way of Connecticut. Come on.
- Connecticut?
- What'll we do in Connecticut?
- Get married.
- Married?
- Don't you see? Once you're in the family...
my uncle would have to
do something.
- His pride would be at stake.
- What about my pride?
You can be proud when
the building's built and people live in it.
- It's a failure now. You can't be proud of that.
- You don't understand.
What good would it do me
to get it that way?
Supposing it flopped?
Then look. Married.
Starting out married life
in the basement.
But, darling, I don't care
where I live if it's with you.
That's what you think now. But you wouldn't
think so as month after month passed on.
First, you'd make up with the old weasel,
then you'd start calling on the penthouse.
Before long, you'd see no reason why
I shouldn't move up there with you.
So that's what you think of me. That's how
much faith you have in my love for you.
I'm trying to be realistic.
Don't tell yourself stories.
Just because you're a quitter,
you think I'm a quitter too.
So I'm a quitter?
That's a lovely sentiment.
Nice to know. All right.
I'll prove it to you.
- I'm quitting right now.
- Good. That suits me fine.
You couldn't stand
any more good news today.
Mother's little lamb!
Now you go to the playroom,
darling.
Be sure and play only with the good
little boys and girls.
Be careful of your nice,
new suit.
Oh-ooh! Darling!
[Blows]
Haven't you
forgotten something?
Oh.
[French]
[Laughs]
Au revoir, mon petit.
Now, don't forget to come back
for cocktails—tea, darling.
Mother wants to show you off
to her friends.
[Sighs]
- Mow 'em down! Give 'em some more!
- [Gun Clicking]
That's what you squealers
always get.
- [Chattering In Agreement]
- I guess that'll teach ya a lesson.
- You can't fool a G-woman.
- "G-man"!
- How many times do I gotta--
- You can't fool a G-man.
Now we'll get
the other rat what squealed.
- Who is he, Mugsy?
- [Kids] Not me!
Aw, cut it out, Mugsy.
I had enough the last time.
Pipe the squealer.
- Hey, mug, you wanna play?
- I wouldn't be adverse to it.
- Does that mean he does or don't?
- I don't know.
- Okay, you're the squealer.
- You mean I'm the informer?
You'll find out
what we mean. Come on.
We're taking you for a ride. That's what
happened to guys what rat on their gang.
Just a minute.
I'll be something else.
- I don't choose to be a squealer.
- Well, we choose you.
[Kids Shouting]
- [Shouting Continues]
- Hey! Hey, stick 'em up!
Hold 'em up!
Stick 'em up! Stick 'em up!
Hey, Mugsy, come up here.
Hold 'em off.
Milton, come up here.
And don't you dare move till you see
the whites of his eyes!
Come on, Milton!
Come on!
Aw, hiding behind
a girl's petticoats!
[Kids Shouting]
I don't know how
I shall ever thank you.
- Well, let's see--
- You have marvelous courage for a girl.
When I play in that neighborhood,
I have to have.
I trust this is the inception
of a beautiful friendship.
- Oh, do you wanna play some more?
- Oh, no.
- Come on.
- That's more like work.
But I can take you up to the playroom.
That's far superior to anything in town.
I know.
I used to play there.
We can have a ripping time.
Tag! You're it!
[Laughing]
- [Squealing]
- I'll get ya!
[Chattering, Laughing]
¶ [Classical Waltz]
Three hearts.
- Three spades.
- Double.
- ¶ [Continues]
- Tag! [Laughing]
- Kids, here's Penny.
- [Continues Laughing]
[Girl] I say,
what are you doing here?
Why, I just came up
to play with Milton.
Our mothers would never stand
for our playing with you.
Miss Hale,
you will leave here at once.
- Why, Mr. Waters?
- Miss Hale doesn't belong here.
She's the daughter of our house engineer,
and she's not allowed in the playroom.
He can't put you out
if I want you here.
Your mother would certainly
uphold me, Master Ramsby.
Never mind, Milton.
It's a good thing Mr. Waters came...
because I almost forgot.
- I have to help my daddy get dinner.
- [Clears Throat]
[Girl]
She even has to cook.
- Well, at least I'm a good cook.
- [ Kids Murmuring]
And stay out.
- I’m very sorry. It will never happen again. Never.
- [Chattering Resumes]
- Mr. Waters?
- Yes?
I wish to register
a slight protest.
Well, you protest to your mother.
[Yelps]
Why--
Your mother--
I will?
I certainly will never--
[Sobbing]
[Sobbing Continues]
What's the matter, sweet?
I--I  got something
in my eye.
- It's leaking.
- Hmm.
Let me try
and get it out for you.
It'll be all right.
When I was a little boy,
I always found the quickest way...
to remove extraneous matter
from the eyes...
was to put something
in the mouth.
Thank you.
Daddy?
Daddy, I think I lost
your job for you.
- Huh?
- I was up in the playroom.
I didn't mind
what Gwendolyn said.
But Mr. Waters
came in, and--
and he said
I shouldn't be there...
because I was only
the engineer's daughter.
Well, and so you are.
But there's nothing wrong
with that. It's--
- It's honorable, isn't it?
- Absolutely.
Daddy,
I just don't understand.
Why is everything
so mixed up?
Well, maybe this picture will make
you understand. You see all these people:
The farmer, the housewife,
the laborer--
Look what they're doing.
They're all pulling...
on this one poor fellow,
Uncle Sam.
- What has he done?
- He's done everything he can,
and still it's not enough.
He gives and he gives,
and he tries to make everything right...
but there just doesn't seem
to be any end to it.
- Is he the president?
- He's greater than the president, darling.
He's the most important thing
in the whole country, maybe in the world.
I don't think it's fair for everybody
worrying Uncle Sam...
especially when he gives
all the money he can all the time.
It's not only money, darling.
He has to find places for people to live...
and clothes for them to wear,
find jobs.
That's the most important thing.
- How you gonna like that?
- Hmm.
Daddy, it's a wonder somebody
doesn't try to help Uncle Sam for a change.
Well, lots of us try.
Well, I hope Uncle Sam
doesn't get discouraged.
Don't you worry about that.
He's a tough old bird.
And pretty soon,
he'll be back on his feet...
stronger than ever,
and then watch things boom.
And I'll build the tallest buildings
in the whole world, and lots of them.
- Then we'll be happy, won't we?
- Mm-hmm.
¶ [Gus Humming]
- Gus?
- Hello, toots.
Gee, but you're beautiful,
just like a repaint job.
Never mind that.
Did you read the morning paper?
No. I only look
at the funny pictures. Why?
Well, get a load of this.
[Gus Whistles]
[ Kitty]
You may be lookin' for a job.
And me with the ring
almost paid for.
Only 36 more installments.
[Scoffs]
Never mind, baby.
You can always eat as long as I got a job.
- Can I?
- Yeah. Dog biscuits.
Gee, you're a swell kid.
Ooh! Aren't those pretty?
White orchids,
the most delicate of flowers.
- How do you do, Mr. Henshaw?
- I'm all right.
- How about a statement?
- No!
- Are you closing any factories?
- None of your business!
- [Reporters Shouting]
- Who's that?
That's my Uncle Sam.
Everybody knows him.
- [Shouting Continues]
- [Penny] Uncle Sam?
Oh.
Call the manager!
Call the police! [Shouting]
- Aren't you gonna help him?
- And implicate myself? Hardly.
Shame on you, fraidy-cat!
It's the only way
to save the country.
- [Penny Shouting]
- [Groaning]
- Won't you stay?
- Get outta here, will you? Dash!
Uncle Sam.
Come on, Uncle Sam.
- A lot of reporters. All but a second, l--
- Come on.
- Come on in here. Come on.
- Oh, yeah. Here.
- [Grumbling]
- They didn't get us that time.
- You're safe for a little while, Uncle Sam.
- Uncle Sam?
- There. You'll be all right.
- I'm not all right!
- Oh, Mr. Hen…
I'm only here to help Uncle Sam.
Such impertinence,
Miss Hale.
Uh—Really, Mr. Henshaw,
I can't tell you how sorry I am.
- What have you to be sorry for?
- Uh--
Why, this young lady.
Isn't she annoying you? Well--
- Well!
- Well.
Here, you!
Milton, come back here.
Get—Oh, my nephew!
Huh!
A walking encyclopedia with curly hair,
dressed up in fancy pants...
and he's supposed to fill
my shoes someday.
I guess you get pretty tired of it all.
Don't you, Uncle Sam?
Tired? I am sick of
the whole kit and caboodle.
[Scoffs]
It--
- Hey, who are you anyway?
- I'm Penny.
You're Pen--
Oh, here.
- I suppose that's what you're waiting for.
- No, thank you.
- Why not?
- There are too many people
taking money from you now.
- I wouldn't think of it.
- Eh?
I'm usually around
about this time every day.
If you need any more help,
just call, and I'll come.
Good-bye, Uncle Sam.
Keep your chin up.
[Clearing Throat]
- [Electric Clippers Whirring]
- [Dog Barking]
The less hair you have,
the better Uncle Sam will like it.
Then he won't call you
a curly-haired encyclopedia again.
I can't imagine anything any sillier
than trying to please Uncle Sam.
- It can't be done.
- Hold still now.
- Hey!
- My, that works beautifully.
- Do you have to cut 'em all off?
- Certainly.
How can you fill
Uncle Sam's shoes someday...
if you wear fancy pants
and have curls?
- Let me see how it looks.
- No.
You better wait till I'm finished.
Now you'll only get a general idea.
I've—I've changed my mind.
You must stop
this instantly.
- I'm suddenly aware of
the grave significance of this.
- [Switches Off]
- Are you a man, or are you a mice?
- No, absolutely, no!
You shall not take off
another strand.
Oh, very well. If you wanna
look like a little girl...
- it's nothing to me.
- [Dog Barking]
[Sighs]
I hate curls on boys.
But, of course,
that doesn't matter to you.
But it does.
In fact...
that's the only reason why—
why I agreed to in the first place.
If you want to stop there,
it's all right with me.
- Penny--
- I'm very busy.
- [Dog Barking]
- You can cut off the rest of 'em.
Well, I'm not sure
that I want to.
- But, of course, if you insist--
- [Whirring]
[Dog Barking]
There we are.
Sit back.
- Here, I'll get it.
- This is the first time
this has ever happened to me.
- Getting your hair cut?
- No.
Giving in to somebody
because I wanted to.
Giving in to a girl.
Giving in to such
an attractive girl.
[Chuckles]
It's quite a change,
but I think we're gonna like it.
You look, uh,
more grown-up.
- There. Look.
- I do look more vigorous, don't I?
Mm-hmm. Just wait
till your mother sees you.
Oh, I say,
she did adore those curls.
- [Mugsy] Hiya, Penny.
- Hi, Mugsy.
- Who's that?
- That's Mugsy.
[Dogs Barking]
Hiya, bright eyes.
Say, where's the fancy layout
you wanna swap me for?
Mugsy's gonna help us.
Just getting your hair cut isn't enough.
You've got to wear he-man
clothes too. Right there on Milton.
- They're very expensive, Mugsy.
- Come on.
- I beg your pardon.
- Come on! One buck!
Hey! Hey, wait!
Hey, come back here!
You can't do that!
Come back.
Scram, bright eyes. I wouldn't wear
that fancy layout if you give me a grand.
- Then give him back his money!
- You gotta make me.
Take your hands off that woman.
Do you hear me?
- So what?
- So this.
- [Dogs Barking]
- Lead with your left! Go on!
Go on! Get him!
Keep it up! That's right!
I wonder what's keeping Milton?
- I do want to show him off to you.
- I can hardly wait.
- You must be very proud of him.
- I am very proud of him.
It must be
the mother in me.
Stop! You mustn't go in there.
- Why, Master Milton, what has happened?
- Shh!
[Mrs. Ramsby]
Is that you, lamby?
- [Waters] Mmm?
- [Giggles]
I'll bring him
right up to you.
Well, you horrid little boy.
What are you doing here?
Mater, I'm Milton.
[Wails]
- [Wailing, Moaning]
- [Women Clamoring]
- What has happened, Mrs. Ramsby?
Um, uh, water! Water!
- [Wailing Continues]
Water— Quickly! Sir— Oh.
- [Women, Waters Clamoring]
- [Clamoring Continues]
- Quiet!
- What's going on here?
- [Waters] It's Milton.
- The shock was too much for Mrs. Ramsby.
- [Mrs. Ramsby Wailing]
- Is this your work?
- Yes, sir, part of it. But I didn't do his eye.
His curls!
His beautiful curls!
- Take that awful child away.
- Yes. Come along.
- Oh, thank you so much.
- Come into my study, young man.
You too, young woman. Come on.
[Mrs. Ramsby Whimpering]
[Henshaw]
Black eye with your hair cut. Huh!
Now, then, young lady,
did you cut Milton's curls off?
- Yes, sir.
- Yeah. Where's his fancy pants?
Mugsy has them on now.
Milton traded him.
That's how he got the black eye.
But you oughta see Mugsy.
We didn't count on
the black eye, did we?
- He really looked very good before he got that.
- Hmm.
I— I guess
it's an awful shock to you.
You go ahead and get mad if you want to.
I don't mind if you're sour and cross.
Anyone would be with all these
people hanging on their neck.
- What do you know about this family?
- As though you haven't...
enough troubles with business
and the slump and all.
But they can't lick you. You're a tough old bird.
You'll come out all right.
Yeah.
Well, upon my soul.
Here. There's a silver dollar for you...
and there's a silver dollar
for every black eye you get.
- Thank you, Uncle Sam.
- [Clears Throat] Now git.
[Clears Throat]
Now git!
- [Sighs]
- First she gives a sigh
and then starts walking again.
- That's love for ya.
Do you think I ought to tell my daddy
that she's in love with him so much?
Oh, he'll undoubtedly
find out for himself...
although we could probably save considerable time
if we wanted to cooperate.
Certainly embarrassing havin' a sister
goin' around sighing all the time.
I think if she knew how much my daddy thinks
about her, she'd feel better.
- Let's tell her.
- [Sighs]
It might be interesting psychologically.
[Clears Throat]
- You tell her, and I'll attend to some other details.
- Mm-hmm.
- Hello, Miss Lola.
- Oh, hello, Penny.
If you're waiting for anybody,
I won't stay.
Oh, no.
I'm not waiting for anybody.
In the moonlight and in that pretty dress,
I thought maybe--
No. I'm supposed to be helping
mother entertain Mr. Waters.
- But he's in there, and—and you're out here.
- Not for long, I'm afraid.
All right. Tell me what you've
been doing with yourself.
I've been very busy
taking care of my daddy.
By the way, how is he?
When he's with me, he's—he's fine,
but I don't think he's so cheerful inside.
Well, maybe you just imagine that.
Or do you think he has something on his mind?
- I think he's worried.
- Probably because he hasn't any buildings to build.
- I think he's worried about you.
- Oh, Penny, you're just guessing.
- What makes you think so?
- Because he's always asking me
questions about you.
- Just like you're asking me questions about him.
- Oh, Penny!
Goodness, you must
feel better.
Excuse me.
I've got to find Milton.
- [ Knocks]
- Come in.
- What's wrong up here?
- You're wanted on the terrace.
There's a short circuit.
- What's a short circuit?
- I haven't the faintest idea.
[Laughing]
- Good evening.
- Jeff.
Now, what are you doing here?
- You oughta know. You sent for me.
- I sent for you?
- Well, that's pretty thin.
- Sure, it is. It'd be better if I'd made it up myself.
- I wouldn't have come near
if someone hadn't called me.
- Well, before I'd call you, I'd--
I didn't call you, Jeff,
but I'm awfully glad you're here.
- Then there's nothing wrong?
- Nothing that a little common sense won't heal.
- [Laughing]
- Excruciating, Mr. Waters. Excruciating!
Milton, where's Lola?
- Why, she's--
- Lola. Lola.
Lola. Lola.
Yes, Mother?
Oh, she's out in the night air again,
and it isn't good for her.
But then what kind of air can you get at night
but night air? [Laughs]
[Both Laughing]
- [Mrs. Ramsby] Oh, Lola.
- Oh, yes, Mother.
- Mother, you know Mr. Hale.
- Whatever is he dressed like that for?
He— he just came from
a masquerade.
Oh. Oh, I love masquerades. I went once
as a New England boiled dinner.
- Mother, Penny's Mr. Hale's little daughter.
- Oh. Oh.
Oh, ho-ho. Oh, it's too amazing.
She's such a busy little thing, isn't she?
When she cut off Milton's curls, I was
so upset that the doctor had to give me--
Uh, um, uh,
what was it, Lola?
- Shots, Mother.
- Oh, yes. Of course. Shots.
And don't they shoot you
in the oddest places. [Laughs]
- Well, out of sight, out of mind,
don't you say, Mr. Gale?
- "Hale," Mother.
Oh. Heh. Oh, yes, of course. Mr. Hale.
Just like "Hail Columbia." [Laughs]
- Shall we all have something to drink?
Oh, yes, of course.
- Oh, yes.
Lola, you ring for it.
Oh, no, my dear. No.
No. You stay here and talk to Mr. Waters
and Mr. "Pale." I'll do it myself.
- Shall we?
- Yes, indeed. [Chuckles]
- You know, I, uh--
- Don't go, Mr. Waters. Stay and play with us.
- [Penny] Yes, Mr. Waters.
We have a new game for you.
- [Protesting]
- Now listen. I-- Now please.
- Come on.
- This is absolutely absurd.
- Oh, now, just come on.
- Sit.
Have you ever played blindman's bluff?
You'll love it. It's a wonderful game.
- Oh, blindman's bluff.
- Now come on.
- Can you see?
- Can I see? Well, of course I can't see.
- No peeking now.
- Now the object of the game is to find Lola.
We'll start you off.
Oh. To find Lola.
Well, it isn't so silly after all, if l--
Now when we say "hot,"
it means you're close.
And when we say "cold," you're far away.
Come on. Put your hands behind your back.
- Round you go. Come on. Whoo!
- Oh! [Chuckling] Oh, stop! [Laughing]
- There you are.
- Oh, am I dizzy.
- [Penny] All right. Come on, Mr. Waters.
- Am l--
Oh. [Chuckles]
All right.
- Aw, you're cold. You're cold. You're freezing.
- You're cold.
- Am I really?
- Cold. You're gettin' warmer.
[Kids] Warmer. Warmer.
You're hot! You're hot! You're hot!
- You're getting colder, colder.
- Oh, you're freezing. You're freezing.
Cold. Cold.
- Aw, you're colder. You're colder.
- Warmer? Oh, you're cold.
- Cold.
- You're freezing.
- Warm! Hot! Hot!
- You're getting hot.
- You're hot!
- You're burning. You're burning.
- Aw, you're cold.
- Oh, you're cold.
[ Kids Laughing]
[Waters Sputtering]
[Coughing, Sputtering]
- Here, old man. Give me your arm. Here. Let me--
- Oh. Oh, thank you.
- [Waters Shivers, Coughs]
- Oh! Well, how did you get in that--Oh!
[Henshaw] Hey, now,
what's going on here? What's all this racket?
- I'll catch pneumonia.
- I never saw--
I know it. I know I'll catch--
Well, you see--
I'll catch pneumonia. I know I will.
I'll catch pneumo…You see, the…
the children, they wanted me to play, but--
but of course, l--I couldn't do tha--
- It was your--your daughter!
- I'm sorry, old man. I apologize. I--
And it was your--your son.
You see, th-th-they--
- Oh, just look at my clothes.
- Come on. We'll get some nice dry clothes.
- You must have some dry clothes!
- Ah, yes.
- [Chattering]
- You here again? Get out!
- Jeff!
- Daughter, you stay here.
I forbid you to have anything more to do
with that rat. Those are orders!
- [Stamps Foot]
- The idea of--
Now see here. You've outshouted this family
for years, but you're not going to outshout me.
- I love that man, and I'm going to marry him.
- Over my dead body you'll marry.
- I'm going to marry him
if it's over everybody's dead body.
- You won't marry him!
If you'd only listen to him about that
East Gate project, instead of being
a stupid old--
- old--old--
- Old, uh, what, my dear?
Oh, I'm sorry, Uncle Sam.
Really I am. But I'm not giving in.
- I'm going to marry Jeff Hale.
- Well, you win.
Uh, you wouldn't be my niece
if you didn't have a will of your own.
Uncle Sam,
you don't mean it?
You're going to, uh,
live in the basement, I suppose?
We won't have to live in the basement
if you'll listen to Jeff. He has so much to offer.
All he needs is to have someone
cooperate instead of fighting him.
If you'll just
do something for him.
- Well, maybe I can do something for him.
- Uncle Sam, you're a peach!
[Sputters]
Some change in tone,
my dear.
Yeah. Hello.
Henshaw speaking.
A little matter you can
attend to for me, Black.
Yeah.
The pipeline we propose to lay in Dutch Borneo
will run from here to here.
What is the terrain like,
Mr. Black?
Well, there's a range of mountains here,
and then swamp and jungle.
- Tough going?
- Very tough.
That's why we need a good man
to superintend the job.
- How did you happen to pick me?
- You were highly recommended
by a friend of mine.
- Uh, cigarette?
- Thank you, no.
After all, the man who carried on
with the East Gate project against the
odds that you did--
- It's too bad you couldn't go through with it.
- I will someday.
Mmm. I'm sure of it.
In the meantime, here's a job that needs
doing right now and will pay well.
- I could surely use it.
- Eh, you're not married, are you?
- No, not yet.
- That's good.
We don't send family men out in that country.
You'll have to leave right away.
How long should the job take?
You'd have to sign up
for two years.
Borneo.
Jeff, you can't go. You simply can't go to the end
of the world and leave us here.
Do you think for a moment
I want to go?
Oh, it's a grand job,
a wonderful chance...
but if I had anything half as good here,
l-- I wouldn't even consider it.
But you'll have something here if you wait.
Uncle promised to do something.
I don't want that sort of job.
I told you before.
- Jeff, I'm going with you.
- Now, that's the spirit.
You can't go, but--
but just the same, that's the spirit.
You see, they--they won't
take a married man on the job.
Oh, but, Jeff, think how long it is,
how desperately long.
Two whole years to wait.
I know.
I wanted to tell you.
I'm not asking you
to wait for me, Lola. It's not fair.
Now, look here,
Jeff Hale.
- I can't stop you from going, but you just
try to stop me from waiting for you.
- Mmm.
Good morning,
Miss Penny.
Corporal,
where's Borneo?
Uh, Borneo?
[Clears Throat] Borneo?
Oh. Uh, he's moved up
into Harlem.
Borneo isn't a man.
It's a place. Where is it?
Borneo-- Oh, sure.
That's where that big light
come from in the sky... nights.
- What light?
- The aurora, uh, "borenalis."
- Everybody's heard of that.
- I haven't.
Well, it's sorta north--
way up north near the North Pole.
- That's where Borneo is.
- Full of icebergs and polar bears?
Yes, ma'am.
Just stick your little nose outside of the door,
and you'll freeze to death.
And if the "polo" bears
don't eat you, the Eskimos do.
Oh.
- Gus.
- Yeah?
Gus, this is important.
I want a man's angle on it.
- On what?
- Borneo.
Bo-- Now, listen, beautiful.
I'm in a hurry.
So am I.
I've only got a few days.
- Where's Borneo?
- B-- Uh--
It's, um--
It's near Gibraltar.
- Where's Gibraltar?
- Well, I just told ya. It's, uh—It's near Borneo.
Didn't you ever hear
of  ‘The Wild Man of Borneo?’
That's it.
Wild men, lions, tigers,
swamps, fevers, uh--
Well, I gotta get to work.
- The Corporal said it was
full of icebergs and polar bears.
- Aw, that's in winter.
If anyone had lived there for two years,
could they ever come back alive?
Not a chance.
Now, you stay right here in little old
New York and let Borneo take care of itself.
But please, you'll do everything
you can think of, won't you?
I--I mean, if one thing doesn't work,
you won't stop.
- You'll go right on.
- Count on me, darling.
I want him to stay here
just as much as you do.
Not quite as much,
because, after all...
you've got Milton and--
and all, and I'll be alone.
But, Miss Lola...
even if he says no a hundred
thousand times, you just insist.
If you insist long enough
with my daddy, he always gives in...
sometimes.
Hey, what are you doing
with those shirts?
I have to look them over. You can't go
to Borneo without buttons on your shirts.
My socks.
But you've looked them over.
Oh, sure, once,
but I have to double-check.
I wouldn't think of letting you go
without double-checking.
That's the second time
you've rated those socks.
Aren't they
double-checked enough?
Well, after all these are socks.
You can't check them too much.
You might find a hole
in a sock anytime...
and then what would
those "Borneonians" say?
They'd say, "Now, what kind of a woman
is taking care of this poor man?"
There! Just look at that.
And this is a triple-check.
[Chuckles Quietly]
What you would do a way off in Borneo
without me to look after you...
I hardly can imagine.
I don't think I'll pack
any more today.
After all, there's no hurry.
We still have two more full days.
- And you might not go.
- What's that?
Anything can happen
in two days.
What if somebody did something for Uncle Sam,
and Uncle Sam did something for business?
Then you wouldn't have to go
to Borneo, would you?
No, I wouldn't
have to go, Penny.
But don't you count on it, partner,
because it won't happen.
There's no use of
our fooling ourselves, is there?
[Sighs]
[Banging]
- [ Banging In Distance]
- Mr. Waters...
I've heard nothing but tap,
tap, tap for the last hour.
- I wonder what it is?
- [ Banging Continues]
- Could it be woodpeckers?
- Oh, no, not at the Riverview.
No, no, no, no. Of course not. Well, I, for one,
intend to find out just what it is.
If I'm not back in 15 minutes--
[Clears Throat] call the police.
- [ Banging Continues]
- [Mouth Full] ¶ THIS IS A HAPPY LITTLE DITTY ¶
[ Banging Continues ]
¶ [ Continues, Mouth Full ]
- [ Knocking]
- Let me in.
It's Mr. Waters.
- It's Mr. Waters.
- Yeah.
- [ Knocks]
- What?
- [Waters] Let me in this moment.
- I knew it.
I knew it wasn't rheumatism
I felt in my bones.
Well? Open up!
Who's in there?
Don't let him in. If he catches me,
I'll be flat on my social security.
- Be calm, everybody. Be calm. Take it easy. Shh.
- [ Knocks]
- Be calm.
- [Whispers] Sure.
- Shh.
- [ Knocks Loudly]
[Whimpering]
- Don't let him in now. He'll spoil everything.
- [ Knocks]
Well, I guess it's up to me.
It's up to me, all right.
Old Gus is gonna
save the day.
- [ Knocks]
- I demand entrance!
- [ Knocking]
- Let me in this moment.
Oh!
- Who's in there?
- Uh, th-the Rotary Club.
The Rot--That's ridiculous.
There's something wrong going on in there.
- Well, sure. Sure. They're rotating.
- Uh--Oh, that's insane.
- Now, you tell me this instant what's wrong.
- All right. All right.
- Do you really have to know?
- I certainly do.
It's termites--
giant termites.
Why, the building is lo--
full of 'em.
- Ya hear 'em?
- [Tapping]
- Yes.
Why hasn't somebody
told me about this before?
- I'll have the exterminators here in five minutes.
- Uh-huh. W--
- Well, of course, you know, l-- I may be mistaken.
- Yes.
I-- I very seldom am, but there's always
that off chance, you know. [Chuckles]
Uh, probably, ya better listen in here
for yourself. Hmm.
- Do you hear anything?
- No.
- Hmm. You will in a minute.
- [Yelps]
Oh!
[Grunts]
[Yelping,
Whimpering]
Pardon me,
my little lamb's lettuce.
- Help. Help. Help.
- [Chuckles]
¶ THIS IS A CHEERFUL LITTLE DITTY ¶
- I-- [Sputtering] ¶ I KNOW THE--
- [Chuckles]
i>¶ THIS IS A CHEERFUL LITTLE
DITTY, I KNOW THE-- ¶
- You'll hear something from me!
- Help.
- [Stops Singing]
[In Affected Accent]: Thank you very much.
- Drop your nickels. Now, come on.
- [Dinging Bicycle Bell]
Don't crowd. Come on.
Drop your nickels.
- That's it.
- [Dog Barks]
- [All Chattering]
- [Kids Chattering Loudly]
- [Dogs Barking]
- Drop your nickels. Drop your nickels.
- [Continues Dinging]
I'm getting tired of hanging around
this neighborhood waiting for
a statement from Henshaw.
Whenever I ask him a question,
he always gives me "Is it?" and "Git!"
- Hey. Get a load of that.
- Drop your nickels. Drop your nickels.
- What's going on here, sister?
- It's a benefit for Uncle Sam.
- Uncle Sam?
- Yes, Mr. Samuel G. Henshaw.
He's in a very bad way, you know.
- He needs help.
- Samuel G. Henshaw's in a bad way?
Yes, the slump and everybody hanging on
his neck. So we're giving him a benefit.
Angel child,
the fourth estate salutes you.
Aw, let go
of my hair.
- Then let go of your nickel.
- [Dings]
[No Audible Sound Effects]
There's somebody back of this.
It's no child's prank by a long shot.
- It's a plot, I tell you.
- Okay.
A plot! But who did it?
Who did this thing?
That's what I want to know.
Who did it?
- Okay.
- Eh? [Mutters]
Yeah. They couldn't
bluff me out of it...
so now they're gonna try
to laugh me out of it. Huh!
Ha! Laugh me out.
Oh, it's an insidious--
- Okay. Okay.
- Diabolical, underhanded scheme to discredit me.
Now--  And why are you standing
there like a lot of dummies?
Do something. Get down to the Riverview.
Find out who's responsible for this...
- and bring him in here.
- Okay.
- [Henshaw Growls]
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
Look at that:
"Samuel G. Henshaw."
- Okay.
- Yeah. A cartoonist--
- But where are you taking me?
- Mr. Henshaw wants to see you, young lady.
Uncle Sam?
Oh, that's different.
[Penny]
Daddy!
- We have the guilty party, sir.
- Well, where is he? Let me at him.
[Sputtering]
What's the meaning of this?
- She's the one that got up the benefit.
- Yeah—y—y—
Come in here and sit down!
You git.
- Huh.
- [Door Closes]
[Sighs]
- So you were the one
that gave that benefit for me.
- Yes, sir.
- Why?
- So my daddy wouldn't have
to go away for two years.
What in gosh-all fishhooks
has a benefit for me...
got to do with your father
going away for two years?
Everything. If somebody helps you,
then you help business...
then business will help him,
then he won't have to go.
- Will he?
- Ye--  No. Uh, y-yes.
Uh, how do I know?
Whew.
[Sighs]
Come here.
- [Hale] You can't take her away.
- [Men Clamoring]
Penny.
- You shouldn't have come so soon.
- I didn't come here soon enough.
Ah, nobody but you
would have the nerve...
to show his face to me,
but now that you're here--
Now, wait a minute, Mr. Henshaw.
I'm sure that everything can be explained.
Yeah. Explained. Heh! Can you explain
about headlines-- running a benefit for me?
Can you explain about making me
a laughingstock all over America?
- I probably can if you'll let me.
- Yes or no:
- Did you tell this child that
I was responsible for the slump?
- Certainly not.
That I was responsible
for business going to the dogs...
for my troubles, your troubles,
everybody's troubles--
including the blessed fact
that you had to go away somewhere for...
…two years?
- Two years.
Certainly not.
Why, Daddy, didn't you say that when Uncle Sam
got in trouble, that the people got scared?
- Yes, but--
- And when the people got scared,
there was a slump...
and when there was a slump,
business got bad...
and when that happened,
nobody built any buildings?
- Yes, but--
- Let her alone.
Didn't you say that everybody ought to
get together and help Uncle Sam...
- instead of pulling on him?
- Yes, yes, but let's get back to Mr. Henshaw.
- But I am back to him. He's Uncle Sam, isn't he?
- Yeah--
- Him? Uncle Sam?
- Me? Uncle Sam?
- Aha.
- Oh.
All right then.
Here's the money.
- [Henshaw] Huh?
- [Coins Clatter]
You'll do something about
business now, won't you, Uncle Sam?
Mr. Henshaw, I think
I can explain everything now.
What do you suppose
I've got brains for?
And there's lots of it.
And this is only the beginning.
I'll give a benefit every week.
The benefit.
[Gasps] The benefit!
Oh, my goodness!
- Penny, wait a minute!
- Here! You two come back here!
- [ Kids Clamoring]
- ¶ [Sour Notes]
- [Clamoring Continues]
- Hey, you mugs, button your lips.
- [Clamoring Fades]
- This here show is gonna start...
and I don't want no trouble
from ya either, get it?
The first song'll be sung
by Lottie and Letty...
who left their work downstairs in
the beauty parlor to come up and help us out.
The costumes was lent by a couple
of the bellboys upstairs.
And anybody that don't want a sock in the puss
better clap when it's over!
- ¶ [Drumroll]
- [Cheering, Chattering]
¶ [Fanfare]
¶ [Speaking Rhythmically]:
VERY SHOW SHOULD HAVE
A BEGINNING, YOU MUST ADMIT ¶
¶ THIS SHOW HAS A BEGINNING
AND WE ARE IT ¶
¶ AND WE'VE BEEN TOLD
THAT YOU CAN'T GO WRONG ¶
¶ IF YOU OPEN A SHOW
WITH AN OPENING SONG ¶
¶ NOW, WE WOULDN'T CALL THIS
A GREAT SONG ¶
¶ WE WOULDN'T DREAM OF IT ¶
¶ THE BASIC THEME OF IT
IS MUCH TOO SILLY TO MENTION ¶
¶ BUT WE FONDLY BELIEVE
THAT YOU'LL ENJOY SINGING IT ¶
¶ THAT'S WHY WE'RE BRINGING IT
TO YOUR ATTENTION ¶
¶ [ Up-tempo ]
¶ [ Continues ]
¶ WE'RE THE BOYS WHO MEET YOU
THE BOYS WHO GREET YOU ¶
¶ CREAM OF CURBSTONE CADETS ¶
¶ WITH OUR BRASS BUTTONS
AND EPAULETTES ¶
¶ OH, LET US SAY GOOD MORNING
BENEATH YOUR AWNING ¶
¶ WATCH THE PLAY THAT IT GETS ¶
¶ IT'S THE BRASS BUTTONS
AND EPAULETTES ¶
- [ Cheering ]
- ¶ EVEN THIS HERE JOB
DON'T PAY MUCH DOUGH ¶
¶ BUT WE SURE GET THE ELEGANT
CLOTHES TO WEAR ¶
¶ SO WHEN YOU'RE UNIFORMIN'
A NEW YORK DOORMAN ¶
¶ BE SURE TO SEE THAT HE GETS ¶
¶ LOTS OF CLASS
LOTS OF BRASS BUTTONS
AND EPAULETTES ¶
¶ [ Continues ]
¶ HEH ¶
¶ [ Ends ]
[ Kids Cheering ]
[Cheering In Distance]
¶ [Whistling]
- Oh!
- Say, what's goin' on here?
Oh, that's just what I'm trying to find out.
I'm so sorry. Pardon. I'm--
Oh.
[Panting]
I want the police, uh, department--
the riot, uh, squad.
¶ [Fanfare]
[ Speaking Rhythmically ]:
¶ OH, MR. WEATHERMAN ¶
¶ WHERE'S THAT RAIN
YOU PROMISED ME ¶
¶ OH, MR. WEATHERMAN
I'VE BEEN WAITING PATIENTLY ¶
¶ MISTER, CAN YOU
SPARE A DROP ¶
¶ HERE A DROP
THERE A DROP ¶
¶ TWO DROPS
FOUR DROPS ¶
¶ CAN'T WE HAVE
MORE DROPS ¶
[ Bell Rings ]
¶ NOW IT'S ALL AROUND ME ¶
¶ GEE, I'M GLAD
YOU FOUND ME ¶
[ Singing ]
¶ I LOVE TO WALK
IN THE RAIN ¶
¶ LOOK FOR ME WHEN IT'S STORMY
DOWN SOME LEAFY LANE ¶
¶ AND I'LL BE THERE ¶
¶ I LOVE TO WALK IN THE RAIN
THE LIGHTNING
MAY BE FRIGHTENING ¶
¶ I LOVE THE RAIN
SO I DON'T CARE ¶
¶ I FEEL WONDERFUL ¶
¶ WHEN THE SKIES ABOVE
ARE THUNDERFUL ¶
¶ I DON'T COMPLAIN ¶
¶ I KNOW IT'S FUN
IN THE SUN ¶
¶ BUT TAKE ALL KINDS
OF WEATHER ¶
¶ WHEN ALL'S SAID AND DONE
I LOVE TO WALK ¶
¶ IN THE RAIN ¶
[ Chorus ]
¶ I LOVE TO WALK IN THE RAIN ¶
¶ LOOK FOR ME WHEN IT'S STORMY
DOWN SOME LEAFY LANE ¶
¶ AND I'LL BE THERE ¶
¶ I LOVE TO WALK IN THE RAIN ¶
¶ THE LIGHTNING
MAY BE FRIGHT'NING
BUT I LOVE THE RAIN ¶
¶ SO I DON'T CARE ¶
¶ [ Quacking ]
¶ SHOO, SHOO ¶
[ Both Imitating Buzzing ]
[ Together ]
¶ I LOVE TO WALK
IN THE RAIN ¶
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
¶ SO LIGHTNING MAY
BE FRIGHTENING ¶
¶ I LOVE THE RAIN
SO I DON'T CARE ¶
¶ SUNDAY, MONDAY
TUESDAY, WEDNESDAY
THURSDAY, FRIDAY, SATURDAY ¶
¶ HOW ABOUT A WEEK
WITH EVERY DAY
A PITTER-PATTER DAY ¶
¶ I WOULDN'T COMPLAIN ¶
[ Chorus ]
¶ I KNOW IT'S FUN IN THE SUN ¶
¶ BUT TAKE ALL KINDS OF WEATHER
WHEN ALL'S SAID AND DONE ¶
¶ I LOVE TO WALK IN THE ¶
¶ RAIN, THE RAIN
DON'T GO AWAY ¶
¶ STICK AROUND ANOTHER DAY ¶
¶ BECAUSE I LOVE
TO WALK IN THE RAIN ¶
¶ [ Ends ]
[ Cheering, Applause ]
- [Siren Wailing]
- [Tires Screech]
- [Siren Stops]
- [ Kids Cheering In Distance]
- What's goin' on here?
- Where's the riot?
[Sputtering, Panting]
[Whistle Tweets]
- [Officer] Open this door.
- [Officer #2] Let us in.
- Did you hear?
- The joint's pinched!
- Open. Open.
- [ Banging On Door]
There's the one responsible for this.
I demand her arrest in the name of the law.
- Here, what do you mean by breaking up my show?
- Your show?
Certainly my show. You can read, can't ya--
"Benefit for Uncle Sam"? Huh.
- I'll sue the Riverview for this.
- Oh, Mr. Henshaw, I didn't know!
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I—well, you'd better go.
This is all a hideous mistake.
What do you mean, a mistake?
We oughta take you in for this.
All right, take me. Lock me up.
Throw the key away.
Solitary confinement.
I come.
- I come happily.
- [Officer] Take him away, boys.
Come on. Come on.
- Henshaw, are you or are you not
closing down your industries?
- Are you liquidating your assets?
- Will you give us a definite
statement, Mr. Henshaw?
- Yes. A definite statement.
- [Henshaw] Quiet.
- Okay.
Close down my industries?
Did I ever say so?
No. Somebody's always
trying to outguess me.
And you can tell the public
that I'm going to triple my present payroll.
- May we quote you, Mr. Henshaw?
- Verbatim.
- [Photographer] Okay.
- And you can tell them, too...
that that's the trouble
with conditions today.
Somebody starts a rumor, and what happens?
Yeah. We're afraid.
We start running
like a lot of sheep.
What we need is
that good old American spirit.
And to show you
how cockeyed this rumor is...
I'm starting work on
the East Gate project tomorrow.
And this is the man that I'm putting
in full charge of that worthy project.
He has vision and, uh, courage. Yeah, now clear out.
I've got business to attend to.
- All right. All right. Shoo. Come on.
- Thank you, sir.
Hey. Yeah, Hale?
What is the meaning of this?
It's the good old
American spirit, Uncle Sam.