PANAlYUR LAKE,
40 KMS AWAY FROM PONDlCHERRY
*My life... my life...
*l'm waiting for you on the
*bank of the river.
*Though fresh water is being,
*splashed on my face,
*Yet l'm sweating profusely.
*l was a raging fire.
*l'm still radiating heat even
*after the fire is put out..
*You spread over me like
*the sheet of dew.
*Time will turn into an enemy and
*moments will become eons.
*You came closer and
*then just vanished.
*l'm breathless,
*l'm swimming in your breath.
*Maiden, come & kiss me.
*lt is taking me into a new world.
*Dreams are teasing me.
*Show me girl, which is real
*and which is a dream.
*Who else will my hands search
*other than you?
*Don't leave mel
*l'll lose myself.
*Night has surrounded me.
*lt's slowly engulfing me.
*Oh my maiden, come to me,
*l'm searching my dawn in you.
*lt's death that stalks
*me at my feet.
*Moments of love are turning
*into bad dreams.
*Come maiden, l want to sleep
*on your lap once.
*Every moment that is delayed is
*killing me in instalment.
*Won't you come to me?
*Won't you give your hand to me?
I liked being a cop.
But, there is a life in danger out there,
owing to me.
I must get up...
I can't.
My body is torn by a couple of bullets.
I've been hit by two bullets seems
like one has torn my intestine.
Aknee cap is shattered.The pain
is excruciating.
But I mustn't die.
They would've kidnapped Maya.
I must definitely save her.
She needs me.
Get up!
I must get up.
Get up.
My name is Anbuselvan.
Anbuselvan I.P.S.
The initials that follow my name
have been my life.
My penance!
A 23 year penance!
That's when I was selected to
the Indian Police Service.
Life was kind of rudderless until then;
It's never been the same ever since.
I've had my share of memorable
moments, some happy... some not so...
Some hurt.
Some disappointments*..
At 27, I was inducted into the
Narcotics division, Coimbatore, as ACP.
Two years later, it was
Crime Branch, Madras City.
Anbuselvan I.P.S.
Asst. commissioner of Police.
This's Anbuselvan, Srikanth, Arul,
llamaran, Sathyendran, lntelligence.
Guys, JCP Kumaravel.
- Hello!
You would've heard about him.
He has now been transferred
to Crime Branch.
He'll be with you throughout
the entire operation.
And of course Mr.Vasudevan Nair.
Crime Branch, Mumbai Police, retired.
Encounter specialist!
He has been involved in 27 encounters.
He has single handedly put down
24 gangsters in one year.
He's one of the best.
Vasudevan is a good friend too.
l've requested him to be
an advisor to you.
Gladly!
- This's my Criminal lntelligence Unit.
This team was assembled by me.
These guys are hand picked by me.
And will report directly to me.
Vasu, Anbuselvan & Srikanth worked
together in Coimbatore Narcotics Div.
Arul & llamaran worked together
in Tuticorin in Law & Order.
They were together in
Commando Training.
These dossiers,
contain the reports of 4 main gangsters
in Tamil Nadu.
Agaram Sethu!
Manali Gaja!
Petrol bunk Sekar!
Aasai!
We are getting information
about them everyday.
We've information that Aasai will be
in city for a pick up in 3 days.
We are waiting for your instructions.
We are ready for the hunt.
28 encounters.
ln Bombay city alone!
27 were successful and 1 was a failure.
But every body only talked
about the operation that failed.
So the whole department will
be watching you.
To see what you're able to pull off.
You can do it.
lt's all in the mind.These operations
require a totally different mind set.
Everything is here!
From the moment you drop a gangster
dead, life is never going to be same.
Their familes and gangs
won't take it silently.
They'll think you came there with the
premeditated idea of killing the gangster.
They'll seek revenge!
And most of the time they
don't target your life,
but your courage and the
lives of your dear ones.
There were 3 of us. We knew no fear.
They called us "The untouchables".
l am near Kasi Theatre.
Keep the money ready.
lf you inform the Police...
Petrol Bunk Sekar...
There may be 4 or 5 people inside.
- We should have called for more backup.
Why do we always
have to play supermen?
Freeze!
Are you okay?
- l'm okay... l'm okay.
Sir... sir...
Brother Gaja & Sethu, Police...
Perumal!
God!
Police!
What's your name?
They've told me about you.
You'll not leave this place alive.
Manali Gaja!
ls he the guy?
- Yes, it's him Dharma.
Anbu, Arul is waiting
for our phone call.
What shall we do now?
Shall we arrest him?
Why should we arrest him?
Anbu, there are no cases registered
against him with the police.
But the information collected about him,
by the department is true.
He's a rogue... Rapist!
all young girls.
2 months ago, a 16 year
old girl called Devi,
was raped by him mercilessly in a
moving train at 10 p.m.
There were 3 eye witnesses.
But no one came to give evidence.
But he was the rapist.
He's backed by a minister,
so he always escapes.
Devi is in the hospital now.
lf we arrest him,
we can get him punished
with Devi's evidence.
lf Devi can come out of the hospital,
if Devi is able to speak,
lf Devi can write.
ls it possible for her?
They're...
ls he dead?
lf he's arrested, Government has to
spend money unnecessarily.
We must use a vehicle,
and fill it up with diesel...
4 of our department people
in uniform must secure them,
Court... Judge...
Now, we've just spent the price
of one bullet!
From my pocket!
Just Rs. 50!
Devi will be very happy
to hear this, won't she?
We've done with him, haven't we?
This is atrocious!
Some one had to do something
about this somewhere.
Human rights & life aren't
respected in this country.
Just a minute, madam.
3 days earlier,
2 people were standing suspiciously
near llamaran's house.
When we questioned them,
We discovered that one of them
was Gaja's brother.
The lntelligence report sent on the
18th is on your table.
Last month on the 14th,
Petrol Bunk Sekar's gang,
met and discussed in Chintadaripet,
They've planned to kill all 4 of us
before next 'Pongal' festival.
They've taken a vow
before Sekar's wife.
Asai, Gaja, Petrol Bunk Sekar..
Do we've any personal enemity with them?
But for doing our duty,
this is our reward.
So, what's the point?
My point Madam is,
from ensuring that society can avail of small
liberties to the protection of their lives.
lt needs a policeman's sacrifice.
l don't need to hear
any of this, Mr. Anbuselvan.
We're talking about Human Rights.
Not just that!
l'm very clear as far as
l'm concerned.
My recommendations are ready.
Madam, you're talking
about Human Rights,
And Human Rights violations.
Human Rights are for humans only.
For us, all those three were not
humans at all.
lf you want to punish us,
punish us under the
act of Killing animals.
We'll accept.
6 months in the crime branch
was like walking on land mines.
Enough of this fear of
dying every moment.
lnfact we must be
celebrating this event.
You've fulfilled the task given
to you, haven't you?
No Swathi, not yet over.
Sethu!
Sethu has escaped.
lf any other man had escaped
he wouldn't be a threat.
We should have got him.
He's the kingpin.
l wouldn't have bothered if l was
transferred after that.
This transfer is temporary Anbu.
Why do you call it transfer?
Watch, we'll be shifted
back to crime branch.
They can't do without us.
Let's go.
lla come let's go.
Srikanth was right but
I was'nt able to forget Sethu.
I had a hunch that I
would get him one day.
All 3 of us were transferred
to different departments.
I was transferred from the Crime branch
to the Control room.
Control Room! Nothing much to sweat over.
Small fry.
But that's how the department functions.
No posting is permanent.
I was happy to do whatever job
that was assigned to me.
Madras City...
Keep your eyes open, and you'd find all
kinds of creeps all over the place, all the time.
Stop!
Boss, you do it!
- Yes.
Hey, what are you doing there?
Just sitting here sir.
- Don't you've homes?
We have sir, we were
just talking.
We shouldn't sit here, Sir?
We shouldn't talk here, Sir?
You can sit anywhere you like.
lf you aren't a nuisance to anyone.
Hey, turn back.
Hacksaw blade... wire...
Come on move.
- Key sir.
- Come to station tomorrow morning & take it.
Sir, l want the key.
- Hey, come on get going.
Go... didn't he tell you to go..
come on scram.
What's this sir?
You're behaving high handedly.
- Go... go... go..
They don't have guts to catch 'Veerappan'.
- They're bullying us.
Hey! Stop... what did you say?
- Kathamuthu, what was it?
They're saying that we don't have
guts to catch 'Veerappan'.
Hey! stop!
- Kathamuthu! Hey, go reach home safely.
They were right, weren't they?
We've failed to catch Veerappan.
"No guts" is all humbug.
I'm a loner!
I had very few emotional attachments.
That was my strength.
I had a certain freedom and courage that
married officers couldn't afford.
I didn't know what fear was.
I could stand upto anyone, anywhere.
I didn't have to worry, or be
responsible for anyone. I liked that.
And then one day, Maya walked into my life.
Maya... my beautiful Maya.
My most beautiful Maya.
*She's fantasy
*She's harmony.
*She's mystery.
*She's ecstasy.
*ln a place there lived a girl.
*She was beauty personified.
*She was born to define beauty.
*When l see the places,
*she moves around.
*You feel as if you know her for years.
*There'll be desires in everything
*seen at the first sight.
*She'll charm you at first sight.
*She'll stretch her
*limbs beautifully.
*She'll thrill like the flower.
*When she talks making
*gestures with the finger,
*We feel, there's lute in the wind.
*ln the dimple of her cheek.
* We can plant little sapling,
*ln the dimple on her cheek
*- Beautifully...
*We can plant little saplings.
*- Wide variety...
*We find something different
*and attractive in her.
*Like flowers holding pollen.
*There's a special fragrance in her.
*The beautiful folds of her
*sari are fans.
*The tresses on her shoulders
*are dark forests.
*When she passes by you,
*Head turns involuntarily.
*- Definitely...
*Your head will turn involuntarily.
*- To see her...
*What am l to say?...
*l want to tell more about her but...
I had met a few girls in my life,
but no one affected me like her.
And at first sight too...
Shanthi, come this side.
ldiot!
Hey! take a U-turn.
- Sir?
-Take a U-turn fast.
Yesterday you said you'd spit on me...
Today l'm grabbing your scarf, now what?
What're you doing?
You rogue...
Are you all students?
Which college?
l've broken your tooth...
will you go home like this?
What will you tell your mother?
And you... think you're some great hero?
Oh God!
That was the first time I saw her.
Get lost.
I'll never forget the anger and
fear in her eyes.
It was her again...
For the first time since college,
I wanted to keep looking at a girl.
I didn't believe in fate,
but I kept running into her.
Would you like to come in?
Excuse me.
Your anklet.
l think you dropped it.
l found it in the lift.
lsn't it yours?
- No... and you know it.
Excuse me! That's mine.
You found it in the lift?
Take it..
- Thanks.
Kathamuthu, tell him
l've come to the spot.
No one must stand there.
Give me one kilogram of sugar,
one packet of flour & a Bru coffee.
Okay, madam.
Hello.
Make it quick please.
Excuse me.
Do you live around here?
Where's your house?
Give me a coconut also.
Hello! l'm talking to you.
Where's your house?
Do l know you?
l don't need to answer you.
She didn't like me. But I liked her attitude.
Take the money.
l'll take the change later.
- Okay, madam.
I wasn't an expert on girls. But I felt that
a woman should be like her.
Sir, l'll drop my friend home
and come back to you.
Give me just half-an-hour.
- Do l have to sit here till you come back?
l can't wait. Pay the fine and go.
l don't have any money.
Whatever l had l spent on the movie...
and the vehicle belongs to my friend.
l have my license, insurance and
registration... but they are all at home.
lf you come with me, l'll show you, sir.
Give me 30 minutes, l'll drop her
and show you all the documents.
I saw her again 2 weeks later.
Sir!
- What's the problem?
He doesn't have his papers
or his license,
and he's being insolent.
Get down from the vehicle.
What's your name?
-Raja! ..you know me, sir.
Asst. Commissioner Anbuselvan.
We solved a land problem together,
in Trustpuram. Do you remember?
What's your name?
Maya
Where's your house?
-No.3, Kasturibai Nagar, Adayar.
You refused to tell me earlier.
Where are you coming from?
- We're coming from watching a movie.
Do you have the tickets?
The tickets had coupons for free juice,
from the Juice Shop on Greams Road.
We used the tickets there.
Who's she? Your sister?
- No sir! We are friends.
Friends means?
- Friends means friends.
Why are you using this road? That's why
we've put barricades here.
Why did you cross them?
You're using it because it is shorter route.
But it's not safe till we set it right again.
And at this time of night,
with a girl by your side...
shouldn't you be carrying all your papers?
Sorry sir.
- Okay, carry on.
Give him the keys.
- Okay sir.
Give him his keys.
l've taken the commissioner's signature.
Don't wait for him.
He's a little busy. You go and present
this file in the Court.
l'll talk to you in the evening.
- Okay sir.
Hello sir.
I met her again
a month later.
Hello!
My name is Maya.
- l know. l remember.
l want to say sorry.
l was a little harsh.
l didn't know then that you
were a police officer.
l understood that from your dirty look.
Did you think l was using the anklet
as a pretext to talk to you?
So, you've realized that police officers
don't roam around with anklets.
Right?
People have a special respect
for the police, don't they?
Good! Go ahead... tell me.
What?
- You said you wanted to apologize.
l'm sorry sir.
l'm really sorry sir.
Your apology is accepted.
lt's good not to talk to strangers...
but don't misjudge people, either.
What are you doing here?
- Sports day!
Student?
- Teacher!
You're a teacher in St. Stephens school...
Maya.
What subjects do you teach?
- Maths, computer science...
10th & 12th grade.
Maths for 12th grade - very tough!
What's your qualification?
- MSc. Maths... llT Madras.
llT students can get
good jobs in America.
How come you're a teacher here?
- l like teaching.
l read an article about you,
in last week's Express.
Very impressive sir.
- Thanks.
And l'm sorry...
l'm really sorry.
Don't worry about it, okay?
Bye...
- Bye...
Hello.
- Anbuselvan sir?
- Speaking, who's this?
Sir, l'm Maya speaking.
Do you remember me?
St. Stephens school.
- Maya... 12th grade maths.
l do remember you...
Tell me, what's the matter?
l wanted to talk to you...
l got this number.
Can we speak on this line?
- Yeah, no problem!
Sir, l'm calling from school...
we have a problem here.
l need your help.
Can you meet me at the school?
Hello.
- Sorry sir, for calling you here.
Don't worry. What's the problem? Tell me.
- Thanks for coming.
This is my student Roshini.
- Hello... Roshini.
- Hello sir.
Her house is in Aminjikarai.
lt's not a very good area.
A boy there is harassing her.
lt has been happening every day,
for a while now.
She can't tell her family.
There are 4 or 5 men in the gang. They
have threatened to pour acid on her face.
They followed her to the school
this morning.
She saw them on the bus
and they were here after school also.
What do you think we should do?
Can the police take any action?
Do l have to lodge a formal complaint?
l don't want her to face any problems.
Okay, both of you come with me.
Get into the jeep.
Are they here, Roshini?
They're standing near that auto.
Get down and walk over there.
Sir?
Don't be afraid. l'm here.
Don't let them know l'm here.
Get down & walk.
Hey chickee, think you can slip by silently
if you come home late from school?
Come here. Come over here!
lf you don't come now,
l'll barge into your house and
throw acid on your mother's face.
Get over here!
Come... why are you turning away
when l'm calling you?
Don't you like me?
lsn't my face handsome?
What have you got to lose
by going out with me?
l'm a cool guy.
Why are you making me angry?
Boys, tell her.
- Why are you making him angry?
Didn't he tell you he's a cool guy?
Can't you cut classes & go out with me?
Why are you so reluctant?
Hey.
- Hey, no need to talk to her.
Pour acid on her face.
Only then she'll understand.
- Come on, give him the acid.
Throw it man.
- No... no... please. No.
Do you know what will happen if l
throw this? Should l do it?
Who's he?
Police!
Sir... sir... we were just joking, sir.
Just like that.
lt isn't acid...
it's just plain water.
Sir..
Just like that.
Just joking.
No bullet. Just an empty pistol.
Got scared?
Come here man!
- l'm a devotee.
Devotee? Go away.
Rogue.
Roshini, go home.
You won't face any more
problems in the future.
Walk bravely down the street.
Remember to walk with
your head held high, okay?
Thank you sir.
l'll get down here.
Are you sure?
- Yes.
lf it had really been acid?
- My face would have been disfigured.
l can't even think about it.
Thank God!
Thank you.
After that, her face and her eyes used
to haunt me.
Like they were etched in my mind.
I didn't understand
what was happening to me.
I'm couldn't tell if
I liked it or not.
What's this, Anbu? Your punches have
gone soft.
What's happened to you?
-Oh yeah?
Yes.
- Okay.
Okay, eat this.
- Come on...
Let's go.
Hello sir...
- Hello.
l was sitting with a friend in the
coffee shop over there... l saw you.
Would you like to join us?
Sorry, l'm on duty now.
The Chief Minister is coming this way,
l need to be here.
Thanks. You carry on.
So join us after the CM is gone.
We'll wait for you.
Will you join us then?
l'm not sure. l don't know how
much time it'll take.
Don't wait for me.
You carry on, okay?
Okay... bye.
- Bye...
Sir, is that your future wife?
- Mind your own business, Kathamuthu.
Tears which had long forgotten
to drop from my eyes...
fell on her forehead that day.
I had seen many terrible accidents.
Grizzly murders, disgusting scenes...
nothing ever really disturbed me.
But when I saw her badly hurt,
it killed me.
Kathamuthu - her name is Maya.
She's a teacher in St.Stephens.
lnform the school, and tell them
to inform her house also.
Give them my mobile number.
- Okay, sir.
No... no... today is Sunday.
School will be closed.
Call the principal at his
house & inform him.
There's a coffee shop next to the
place we were standing.
She said she had come
there with a friend.
Let's wait for 24 hours,
l think she should come around
- Ok doctor.
Hello!
Hello sir. How are you?
How are you?
lt's very painful.
You'll be alright.
l'll get the doctor.
ACP sir...
[Assistant Commissioner of Police]
You missed the CM after all.
lnstead, you were taking me to the
hospital in your car.
Couldn't you have joined me for
a coffee when l invited you?
Why are you so serious?
l was just kidding.
l kept looking at you...
l forgot to look in front of me.
For the first time in our city,
the water tanker won't be accused.
Hello!
- Hello.
- She's Arthi, Maya's sister.
What happened? How is she now?
- She's okay now.
She was hit by a water tanker
on Mount Road.
She sustained head & limb injuries...
but she'll recover.
You can go in & see her.
*You're spending half your time
*at the hospital.
*l went to see her twice.
*That's all.
But l'm always thinking about her,
even when l'm working.
So you've finally come around.
So this is it.
Finally, you've fallen in love.
Nothing like that
and l don't need it also.
She met with an accident because of me.
A little guilty feeling, that's all.
You told me once,
nice guys get nice girls.
She's definitely a nice girl. But l don't
want to be that nice guy.
She made me cry that day.
l didn't like it.
l've decided not to see her again.
But I had to meet her again.
You knew you were coming to see me.
Couldn't you bring me a flower bouquet?
You're taking out a gun?
You may be a big time police official,
and everyone might be scared of you.
But, you have no clue how to
talk to a woman, or how to act.
Accept it.
- Agreed.
You're very uncomfortable, am l correct?
Why?
No, it's this chair.
- The chair?
Your sister seems uncomfortable
around me.
l noticed in the hospital.
Did you ask her why?
l know. You're a police officer who is
talking to me, that's why.
Offenders and criminals
should be uncomfortable around me.
Why should others feel uncomfortable?
Are you saying my sister is a criminal?
- No! l'm just saying, we are normal people.
We are normal people
and l'm a normal person.
That's what l wanted to say.
Please tell this to your sister also.
Oh yeah?
Well, time will tell how normal
you really are.
Thanks for accepting
my invitation.
Why are you acting so formal?
You might have been busy,
but l decided l had to meet you today.
lt's a long time since l've
been out of the house.
l thought you could give me an update on
what's happening in the country.
ls the city peaceful, ACP sir?
With you around,
l guess it must be peaceful.
Actually, l'm not that busy.
Just in the control room...
l'm depressed. l've wasted
3 months of my life...
staring at four walls.
So, l'm planning to go to Pondicherry
tomorrow, to my sister's house.
My sister also left then itself.
l feel like seeing her.
ACP sir...
Would you like to come with me?
You said you weren't busy.
You must come.
l'm taking you to a beautiful place.
You'll love it.
Come... please.
*New experience.
*lt'll grow manifolds in a second.
*lt'll bring 2 lives together.
*Changing me, becoming a
*part of my heart,
*you don't kill me slowly.
*ls today any different from yesterday?
*Am l the same man today also?
*Don't charm me with your talk.
*l want to say one thing...
*l must look into your
*face & say that.
*Shouldn't we two be alone here?
*l've also changed.
*l've become more soft.
*lf you know it,
*why don't you tell me?
*Whom should l ask?
*Won't you tell me?
*On the way there are
*flower gardens.
*Never once l had stopped
*and admired their beauty.
*l never thought l'll stop and
*pluck a flower to admire it.
*The flower you pluck,
*l'll adorn in my hair.
*l've this intention now.
*But, like always, it's silence
*that speaks for me.
*l'm developing wings like birds.
*and flying beyond stars.
l don't know if there's any place more
beautiful than this in the world.
l don't want to know also.
This wood house is ours.
When my parents were alive, we used
spend all our week ends here.
This house has seen my
days of joy & grief.
l felt you must come here.
*You've made me come here and
*made me talk.
*You made me smile.
*What's the meaning of
*the mischief in your eyes?
*My outlook is new, my thoughts are new.
*l've changed because of you.
*Your eyes must search
*me in a crowd.
*l've gone mad with
*such crazy ideas.
Shall we go?
lt's getting late.
l had a good time
after a long time.
Thanks to you.
l want to talk to you.
Don't look at your watch,
l have to talk.
There is something l know about you.
What's it?
lt happened on the day of the accident
That day when the water tanker hit me
l fell as if somebody threw me.
There was terrible pain.
l couldn't bear it.
Suddenly l felt l was being
carried by someone.
ACP Anbuselvan!
l saw.
You made me sleep on
your lap in the car.
l saw.
Your shirt was drenched
with my blood.
You tied a kerchief
to stop the bleeding.
You ordered the driver
Kathamuthu to go fast.
l knew all of it then itself.
l was watching it all.
You cried then.
Why?
Later you got me
admitted in a hospital.
l plunged in to darkness
But, l knew l wouldn't die.
At that moment, l prayed.
That when l regain consciousness
you should be there.
l must see you first.
lt happened.
Those tears might have dropped
even for someone else in your lap.
May be...
But, there was no one else
in my place...
Only l was there.
When l opened my eyes in the
hospital, you were there.
l didn't feel any pain.
l felt happy.
l'm telling you unabashedly
Actually l don't feel shy.
l love you.
Truly... madly... deeply...
- No, Maya.
Don't say you love me.
Please don't.
Until now, before you called it love
We had something special between us.
That was very nice.
Let it be like that.
l should've expected this.
lt was my mistake.
l don't want to give any excuses.
l'm used to being alone.
l like it that way.
There's no place for another
person in my home.
Literally and even otherwise
Did l ask your opinion about me?
Did l ask you to accept my love?
l just wanted to tell
what l had in my mind
l knew that this is what you'll say.
Let's go Anbuselvan...let's go.
She was changing me,
infront of my own eyes.
She was changing my world,
I didn't like that.
I wanted to go faraway from her.
But, I couldn't.
Hello Maya, how are you?
l'm fine.
Have you started going
to school again?
Mm, it's been 2 weeks now.
Have you come to see me?
l don't know anyone else here.
Okay, come.
l'm not able to concentrate.
l'm not able to take classes.
l've forgotten my mathematics.
l'm not able to talk to any one
freely in school.
l've lost appetite,
l'm sleepless.
l've come to tell you,
it's because of you only.
First l thought l'll never come,
and will never see you.
Because l hate pleading.
But now, l'm not bothered.
l like you.
l've come here to ask
you to accept my love.
One more thing.
You said earlier that you were
a normal person.
l'm sorry.
You're not a normal person.
lf you were normal,
You wouldn't have discarded my love.
What she says is right.
You're not a normal person.
l love you... truly... madly.
l'm sorry. You're not a normal person.
lf you were normal, you wouldn't have
discarded my love.
Okay, see you tomorrow.
- Bye Maya.
ACP sir, it's surprising.
How come you're here...
l don't know anyone else here.
l need to talk a lot to you.
Shall we?
l love to.
Come.
Maya, what do you want?
l don't get you.
With regard to both of us
what do you want?
l should get married to you.
l should spend my life with you.
l should be with you.
l want to talk to you happily.
l want to fight with you.
l want to cry in your arms.
l should be mad about you
always as l'm now.
l want to make love to you.
You should have 3 children.
They must be like you in
appearance & character.
l must see these eyes, always.
Then, one day l should die.
That's all.
Why?
l'm not a jolly, youthful person...
l'm a police officer.
There is danger around me.
lt'll affect people
closer to me also.
l'm elder to you by 6 years.
Why me?
lt's a girl thing.
You wouldn't understand.
You should see it as a girl.
Okay... okay.
Let's marry.
l like you, Maya.
Ever since the day
l saw you for the first time,
l didn't show it.
l can't hide it anymore.
A month from now, let's marry.
Okay?
A drop of tear in her eyes.
A flash of happiness on her face.
She gave a contented look.
I can never forget it.
I decided right then to live a life with her.
After a week...
Srikanth, Arul, Ilamaran and me,
we all four were again transferred
to the crime branch.
We re-opened gangster Sethu's file.
Operation Sethu took place.
10 days prior to this.
Pandia entered my life.
Pandia...
born and brought up in Salem.
At 19, he killed his father and
ran away to Bombay.
8 years later...
Maharashtra Police is after him with
32 criminal cases against him.
15 extortions, 9 murders, 5 kidnappings,
1 dacoity... one bank robbery.
Finally, murder of a
local MLAAshwin Naik.
Hey, hands up.
Mumbai police arrested Pandia.
He was in jail for 6 months.
6 months 8 days.
On the 9th day. He escaped.
It created a sensation in Mumbai.
Pandia reached Chennai after
escaping from Mumbai.
When we re-opened Sethu's file,
we went through his history.
OLD JETTY KATTUCHERY
There was only one information
we didn't know then.
That Pandia, who had
escaped from Mumbai,
is the brother of Sethu
whom the crime branch is tracking.
This is our place.
These are all our boys.
They'll give their lives for me.
For you too.
Pandia, when l heard you were
in jail, l was stunned.
l was at a lose
didn't no what to do
l just sat like that.
Police, have become a
big problem here also.
Police...
Brother, there is a police officer
called Shinde, in Mumbai,
he only beat me up badly in jail also.
He'll die in another 30 minutes.
But do you know how?
There won't be a scratch on his body.
Our boys would've got down
to business by now.
He has a 17 year old son.
They'll kidnap him and
confine him for 2 days.
Giving a torrid time to Shinde.
Two days later they'll send his
son's corpse in a parcel.
All policemen will get the right message,
They'll think twice before
getting in to the field boldly.
They'll fear us.
- That's what we need.
There're few people here also.
Only if we do something
like this, they'll learn a lesson.
We'll do it.
- Sethu, our Pandia has come.
Like they put up cut-outs
on a Minister's arrival,
shall we put up a cut-out
for our Pandia?
That too opposite
Commissioner's office.
Hey, l've a cut-out for him here.
- Sethu, super.
Sethu, we'll give Pandia something
like school children give flowers.
No one must give us flowers.
He's Producer's son.
Are you Arun?
- Yes.
We'll give it to someone.
Your father told us to bring you
to the studio. Shall we go?
Hello!... Yes.
l've kidnapped your son.
lf you want him, bring
25 lakhs & take him.
Your film shoot is going on. So
money won't be a problem to you.
What do you say? l'll tell you
only once. Don't go to the police.
Then, it'll not just be a kidnap case.
Does Seetharaman have the money?
Definitely he has. He's rolling in money.
He's a powerful person.
Despite so many warnings if he has
gone to police, it means...
Arun, l think your father
doesn't care for you
What's your age?
- 11.
Brother, Seetharaman hasn't
understood the gravity.
Let's make him aware of it.
Hey, what're you dropping?
Hey... stop...
Hello!
- ls that Seetharaman?
Hey Bastard! l told you once,
but l told you clearly
not go to police.Told you
we'll settle it between us.
But, you didn't listen.
Your son Arun who should be
playing in your house is lying dead there.
ls this necessary?
Hey! Bastard... your mother...