My name is Vinod.
I'm very happy here.
This is our world.
A peaceful world.
Children!
Tamil Nadu people have collected these &
sent them for you.
Don't fret about these
being second hand.
This is their love
and mercy on you.
Let's pray for 2 minutes for the welfare
of all those benevolent souls.
No need of 2 minutes.
...at least 50 seconds.
No...at least 20 seconds...
Dear children!
They're just uncontrollable.
Father, letter for you.
My son...my son.
After a long time I got
myself a pant.
Give it...give it.
Give it...
Will you give me or not?
Hey...
Hey, you've got a letter.
University of Madras.
You've got a seat
to study B.E.,
Special quota!
I never applied.
- I did.
Vinod B.E., Engineer.
How thrilling it is to hear!
I can't go, father.
- Why?
I can't live without you, father.
This time you can't escape.
What did I tell you when you
were studying in 8th class?
This school isn't good enough
for your intellect.
When I said I'll get you
admitted in a good school,
you said, you'll go after
finishing S.S.L.C.,
after finishing S.S.L.C.,
Father, will it not be good if I
go after finishing plus 2,
you told me.
You've finished plus 2 now.
You can't study further here.
You must go out from here.
You've a train tonight.
Get ready by evening.
Father, have you decided to
chase me out from here?
I'm asking you to go out
for a better life.
Do you want to spend your life sewing
food to children & me.
You've been living here
for years.
Did you ever step out of
this forest even once?
Mad boy!
World is very large.
Go out boy!
I reached the place I despised.
TAMILINI
What ever you see at 18,
cross the limits to enjoy it.
A boatman's life is restricted to the sea.
Learn to live beyond the waves.
The other name of happiness is woman.
Won't all desires lead to her?
Isn't Manhood's duty to make
womanhood go ecstatic?
TAMILINI
On the beach road when intoxication
is slowly enveloping you,
there's no difference
between men & women.
Touching at sensuous places,
getting all fired up,
there's no end to fun.
Who's she? Biting me
with her teeth.
Don't know where I had her?
Is it culture?
Fast modernizing country?
Burn down the people
who criticize this.
TAMILINI
Seeing me & expressing love to me.
Oh God! you'll say, I'm your brother.
Pinching my head,
pushing me aside when I cry,
You'll fly away to live
in America.
Love is nothing but
taking few lives.
Tears will not help you in love.
Your head is with me here,
your body is with him there.
If it happens,
whafll you be called as?
Sir, can I get any job here?
Go & stand in the queue.
- Okay sir.
Hey, what's this, man?
Buddy, we must do something
silly like this.
Only then girls
will notice us.
Hi, Babe!
Great chic!
They've admitted you in this collage,
every Tom, Dick & Harry
is joining college now.
A rogue like you...
A useless person like me.
Every one is joining college.
Don't know what the hell
you're going to do here.
Hey, go man.
That's it...that's it.
That's a great butt.
How's that?
Oh my God!
You were here just a moment back.
Changed the costume so quickly.
We must be very
careful now a days.
Or else some one else will
fly away with your girl friend.
That's why, I've a ready to
exchange set-up in hand.
If I go in this dress I'll not be
allowed in the class room.
So, this is for inside
the class room,
this is for outside
the class room.
Inside - Outside.
Adi, leave it.
Listen to me.
This is not our area to create
trouble & go soot free.
Don't get beaten up
unnecessarily.
What?" Get beaten up"!
You mean slapped on the cheek,
beaten up with slippers, etc.,
That was done in our
grandparent's time.
Now, if you observe a girl keenly
for 5 minutes,
they'll come and
propose marriage.
Watch now.
WOW!
Sorry.- It's okay.
Hello! What happened?
Hello!
Is it a dream?
Hey, what are you doing?
This is not a dream.
Is it paining?- No.
Do you want to say anything else?
We can meet in the canteen
this afternoon.
Afternoon?
How can I live without
seeing you till then?
naughty-
Didn't I tell you trapping
girls is very easy?
Don't know why girls fall on me...
Rascal!
Why are girls "falling" on you?
Oh my God! What a great chic!
What a structure!
God! If she has a lover already,
he must die today in an accident.
If there's anyone to marry her,
he must die tomorrow.
Oh my God!
Useless...idiot...bloody pig.
Where are you looking
while walking on road?
Are you ogling girls
Buffalo!
Oh, he has dented my auto.
You've made a dent.
How much money do you've?
Come on take out.
Don't you've any thing?
Where are you working?
Come.
Dear students,
You know very well how
your parents would feel...
What? Do you've a play boy?
Adi, hereafter they're our friends.
Arun, Abbas...this is Ramesh.
- Hi buddy!
Yes, sir.
Hey!
Sir...doubt...- Yes.
It's okay, sir.
Is he a good student?- He?
Yes. He'll study well about girls.
Ask him now.
He'll tell the color of her nail polish
and her waist measurement correctly.
Did you ever see anyone
ogling girls like him?
Look at the responsibility
writ large on his face.
What an intelligent face!
Hey, why're you talking and
disturbing the class?
Are you coming to college
to study or to talk?
Just think,
how our parents are struggling
to educate us.
If not for yourself at least
study well for the sake of your parents.
First pay attention to the lecture.
You too boys.
Move. Class is full of criminals.
So that you can have a
wide knowledge,
concerning the subject.
So...
Who are you?
What do you want?
Are you a student?
What's your name?
Vinod - What? - Vinod.
Shouldn't you take permission
before entering the class?
Go.
God! Don't know from where
such creatures come here?
They're entering college
under some quota.
I'm fated to teach
such students.
Hey, look there! Divya!
Our classmate.
Look, she's coming
wherever I'm standing.
We are meeting quite often today.
What do you understand from this?
Don't you see we've a connection
from our previous birth?
Both are studying in
the same college,
same class.
Where else she can go?
It seems she's coming
where ever he is.
Hey!
Sky!
Sky's color is blue.
- Has he gone mad?
Moon!...is round...your face.
Flower!
Please don't get scared.
Boy is trying his hand at poetry.
I'm not able to
understand one thing.
If you see a beautiful girl,
you'll start blabbering sky, moon, earth.
Haven't you seen all these earlier?
Are you seeing them for
the first time now?
Why're you staring
at her only, Adi?
If I stare at her
it means, she's mine.
Adi...no.
I feel she's a different
type of girl.
She's going to insult you.
Hey, what different type of girl!
High class.
That is...
Two cars will be parked
in front of her house,
our house will be of car size only.
They'll spend 5 to 6 thousand
rupees everyday,
your father's monthly salary is
that much.
She'll be having credit cards
in her bag,
we don't have even
a visiting card.
They'll go to shop
in Alsa Mall & Spencers,
We'll not be allowed to even enter there.
She'll be having a cell phone,
we don't have even a landline phone
in our house.
If we go near her, her perfume smell
will hit us,
we'll stink with sweat smell.
They'll never speak Tamil
and you can't speak English.
That's 1+1=2+3=5, high class.
They will feel disgusted
even to see us.
Hey, enough buddy.
How many girls I've met in
my illustrious career.
Watch. I'll trap her today.
No...no Professor says,
Malhotra is the best.
Hi Divya! Isn't your name Divya?
My name is Adi.
Hi...hi.- Hi...- Hi.
I'm your classmate.
Divya, sweet name.
This dress looks very good on you.
Then, you all...
- What do you want?
No...just like that.
You were discussing something,
I thought I'll also join you.
What's this?
I don't think, this is right.
You're interrupting
our discussion.
Don't you've some manners?
First as a B.E. student,
first try to behave in a decent way.
Do you understand that?
Now quit.
Then, where shall
we've our lunch?
In canteen or shall we
go out somewhere?
I spoke to her. She said,
"we'll meet later & discuss".
Okay...okay.
Just now I had a close
look at her.
She doesn't have a structure.
Look at her face. Flat nose.
Small eyes. Decayed tooth.
Buddy, do you call her a chic?
Will anyone try for her?
Cool down, buddy.
You had said you'll trap her
today itself.
You are not able to
even speak to her.
What do you want now?
She must talk to me,
that's all, isn't it?
Talking to you is very
simple, buddy.
You don't know how to approach her.
Shall I try?
What do you want him
to do now?
You don't know about him.
He'll do anything you tell him.
What's the bet?
Okay. We know her character now.
Adi must kiss her.
If he does it now,
I'll buy drinks for
next 10 days,
with side dish, okay?
What? Drinks for 10 days!
Adi, please do it. Buddy...please go.
- What's it?
Kiss?- Yes.
That girl!- Yes.
This is cheating.
- What's cheating in this?
I can also kiss like this.
Come on do it, let me see.
Give...give man...- Give.
Wow! Rs.400.
Buddy, drinks for 10 days.
Thanks buddy, thanks.
Tell me, do you want me to
kiss any where else?
Shall I give a lip to lip kiss now?
What's the bet?
Bet?...- Your bike?
Buddy, you're very brave.
Buddy, you need to master the
technique for that.
She'll definitely know someone
has kissed her.
But, can she find the man
who kissed her?
How coolly I escaped.
I must admit, I don't know
what perfume she uses...
Rose smell...
Bloody fool! Didn't I tell you
to serve after one hour?
Go away.
Yuck! Bloody idiot.
- Okay, leave him.
Listen to me...Leave me.
Enough..it's raining.
Go...nothing to be afraid of...go.
Go, nothing will happen...go.
It'll get over in few minutes...
go, listen to me...go.
Go...inside...
Nothing will happen. Go.
Father, didn't I tell you, that
I'll not go out from there?
Did you listen to me?
Now look what has happened?
What happened son?
This is disgusting, father.
I can't live in this
disgusting world.
I'll come back, father.
Please father.
I beg you, father.
Father...father... father,
I've a bus to that place now.
If I don't get it, I'll come there
at least in a lorry, father.
I'll be there with you by
tomorrow morning 7 a.m.
Vinod, you must
have determination.
You must have determination
to come out successful.
If you jump in the fire and
complain of burning,
you'll be reduced to ashes.
Come whatever may in your path,
kick it aside and go
surging ahead. Go ahead.
Hey, come here and see man,
you'll understand.
He stops respecting at
the drop of the hat.
Okay, I'm coming boy.
I'll come after 6 months.
If you still find it as disgusting
as you're saying now,
we've this orphanage, church.,
I'll bring you back here.
Father...father...- Till then, stay
there only. I'm hanging the phone. the call.
Father...father...
I'll come back, father.
Students, this problem
is very difficult.
But, very important
for examination.
Don't get scared seeing this.
Try to understand.
Now, we'll solve it step by step.
If you don't understand
this problem,
I'll solve this problem again
in the next class, okay.
You can clarify your doubts...Okay?
Divya, divergence theorem.
Good, sit down.
Step 2. Adikesavan!
What?
Do you know or not?
Get out.- Sir...
Why're you sitting here without
even knowing this?
Get out.
Please don't come to my class
to while away time.
I tell you, I don't want such
students in my class.
Out!
Laughing at me.
I'll take you to task for it.
Step 2. Senthil Kumar.
Wait...
Wake him up.
Hello! What are you doing?
I'm asking you.
What are you doing?
Do you know what's all that?
Do you know
what non sense is all that?
Some one will offer you
a free seat.
They'll feed you
with free meals.
Will you sleep here after
having free meals?
Yuck! Aren't you ashamed?
How dare you sleep in my class?
Look there! What's that?
That's a problem.
Have you ever seen it before?
Do you at least know to read it?
Take it...go & solve it.
Go...go boy.
I know you're a good
for nothing boy.
Go and stand there at least
like a broom stick.
Students! I'm highly disappointed
with this class.
Do you know how brilliant engineering
students are in other colleges?
I took 2 days to prepare
for this problem.
I had referred 6 books...
Hey, he's solving the problem.
- He has done it.
How painful it is for me!
What?
He's correct.
Please take it down.
What's this?
- Are you able to understand? No.
How did he do it?
I'm not able to get it.
I too didn't get it.
How could he do it?
He might have copied it from
some guide book.
Come, let's go & ask him.
Ask him? No way,
I'll ask Seenu.
What's wrong in asking from anyone
if we don't know?
I feel he's innocent.
Come, I'll ask him.
Come.
Excuse me.
We are not able to
understand this problem.
Can you please teach us?
Didn't I tell you he is proud?
Can't stand there even for a minute!
He smells so bad...
Yeah...yeah.
God!
I think food is rotten.
Oh my God! He's eating
rotten food also.
I can't eat anymore.
I'm going.
It's stinking like the drain.
- Hey Seenu, wait. I'm also coming.
You want to share.
I feel little delicate
to eat alone.
If you want, eat it
or else leave it.
Adi, this is my
friend's bike.
I begged, kneeled at his feet
and brought it.
Don't fall down while trying to
show heroics before Divya.
If anything happens to the bike,
I'm finished.
Hey, where are you going?
She slapped me in public for
kissing her, didn't she?
That's why.
Watch, I'll kiss her
from head to toe.
There shouldn't be a place left in her body
where I haven't kissed.
After that I don't mind if she slaps
me or beats me with a slipper.
Bloody rogue!
Did you call me for this?
She's already slapping
for everything,
and it seems her father is
a D.l.G. of Police.
No need, let's go away.
- Hey Eunuch! Get lost.
You go & tell our boys.
Tomorrow she'll come to the
college dripping in shyness.
Go.
Go & eat curd rice at home. Go.
God, I think he'll take me to Central
jail for going with him.
Today, I'll show you,
who's a real man.
I'm coming.
She was here only, wasn't she?
TAMILINI
My head is jumping with joy
on seeing a golden statue.
It's skipping a beat
on seeing her.
My heart has caught fire like
cotton with her one glance.
My head is flying in dreams.
I'm on cloud nine.
Bloody thief!
I knew the moment you
entered the room.
You've come to steal
the chocolate.
Leave it...leave it.
- I'll tell father.
TAMILINI
Hey, what's that noise?
My sweet brother. Please eat.
Enough sister.
Aren't you my sweet
little brother. Please eat.
Enough sister. How much can I
eat alone? You too have little.
If not for you, for whom
I've bought all this.
If you eat, I'll be very happy.
Okay, dear...eat.
Monkey! lf i buy anything, you'll
come, steal & eat it. - Hey, get lost.
Hey, I hit you unwittingly.
- Shut your mouth.
Then, allow me to see cartoons on T.V.
- I've to study, boy.
Father, Divya has hit me.
Rogue! do as you wish.
Is he kissing her for so long?
Isn't Jerry comical
in this dress?
Now watch, his head will swell.
Oh God!
What man?
Good morning sir.
Hello.
My name is Vinod.
What's your name?
Oh Divya! Nice name.
My parents?
They're in my native place.
I'm staying here
in the hostel.
My father is working in
Central Government.
Mother is a housewife.
It's difficult
to stay away from them.
But, what can I do?
I've to pursue the studies.
What's your father?
Oh! Is he working in Railways?
For a coffee? To canteen?
I'll come later.
Where's your house?
In T.Nagar?
Where's that...
Hello!
My name is Divya.
What's your name?
Oh Vinod! Nice name.
My parents are here only.
My father is D.l.G. of Police.
My mother is housewife.
I'm my mother's favourite.
My father is very strict.
Then...then.
My house isn't in T.Nagar,
but in Boat Club.
Coffee!
I'm asking you for the first time
to join me for a coffee.
You're refusing the offer.
Come, let's go.
Not now, let's go in
the interval. Okay?
She escaped from me yesterday.
Today, I'll kill her.
Hey, come here...come.
What happened?
He said she'll come to
college dripping in shyness.
Look, he's struggling here.
Hey, please don't do it.
Please listen to me.- Leave me.
Come Vinod.
Yuck! If you love anyone, inform us.
Love and lover's head is
playing the hide & seek game.
Butterflies are fluttering in
the eyes that are searching.
He's searching himself somewhere.
He's talking to himself
forgetting his mother tongue.
Love is an enigma.
Don't know if it's wind or fire.
Though eyes are wide awake,
I'm unconscious in love.
TAMILINI
Till yesterday I was here only.
Today, I'm missing myself.
There's no rain or sunshine.
I've seen the rainbow.
I've admired the beauty which has killed
me without really killing me.
I drew her in my head.
TAMILINI
I was walking alone
in a desert
You came and held an
umbrella for me.
I had forgotten my name,
you gave me a new identity.
I saw my face in the
mirror of your head.
My head will bloom with
your arrival only.
Once rivers join the sea,
they'll lose their identity.
In friendship you'll
forget worries.
When 2 heads are united,
there's no day or night for them.
Hey Divya, come on 'yaar'.
- Hey Seenu.
What's this?- Sorry...sorry.
If you don't like it, it's okay.
- Vinod, you come.
Please no, Divya.
Everyone is watching us.
I'm not able to differentiate
between man & woman.
Good evening, sir.
You've come with a
boy at this hour.
What should I think?
Father, please.
He's Vinod.
Sir.
He's a genius in our college.
I've begged & cajoled him to come here
to teach me for exams.
Is he a mad man to
come to our house?
What did I ask her,
she's so angry?
We haven't eaten.
Prepare tea for us.
We are studying together tonight.
Don't lock the gate.
Vinod must go home.
This is my room.
Please come in.
What happened?
You're looking stunned.
I've to buy many books. I'll take them.
- Hey, what're you doing?
Vinod, I think you're yearning
for your parents.
Go home and meet your parents.
Hi! I saw his statute
on the way.
Divya! Where should I pass urine?
Hey, we must study. Get up.
Oh God! I'm hungry.
I'm feeling cold.
What happened?
Hey, leave her.
Leave her I say.
Divya...Devi
Vinod, do you've any problem?
I don't have any problem.
I'm happy.
You're with me, aren't you?
Studying to impress a girl
will be like this only.
Will she love you even if
you study well?
Where's the answer
to this question?
Why're you still holding
a text book?
Just only one answer.
One minute sir.
No...no...- I must score
high marks in exam.
Only then, Divya will love me.
Sir, this is a question
of life & death for me.
Give. Come on, give. Now you go.
- Get lost bald man.
God! I must write exams well and
Divya must love me, please.
It's enough if Divya loves me.
I was writing well.
Suddenly, I forgot the answer
to a question.
I tried my best to recollect,
but failed miserably.
When I tried to answer
the next question,
I forgot the answer of
the next question also.
I got tensed up.
Till now, I've never failed
in any examination.
If my father comes to know about this.
He'll abuse me.
I feel like dying, Vinod.
No sir. This will definitely not be
the handiwork of any student.
I think it must be
electrical shod circuit.
What are you planning to do?
- I don't know sir.
Most probably they'll postpone
it to next year.
Poor students, they worked so hard.
Why're you crying?
Is it for the answer sheets
that got burnt.
Don't cry...please.
Don't cry, Vinod.
No, Divya. I would've definitely
won the gold medal.
I've to write the exams again.
No problem. Whenever
you write the examination,
only you'll win the gold medal.
Is there anyone who can
beat you in studies?
Will you cry for such a silly reason?
You're crying for missing
a gold medal.
I'm happy for escaping from
failing in the examination.
Then, what?
I wouldn't have got even
10 marks in this examination.
Definitely, I would've failed.
Now, God has given me
another chance.
Yes, isn't it?
- Cheer up Vinod.
To celebrate completion of examinations
my friends are going to see a film.
Come, let's also go with them.
I don't have money, Divya.
- Hey, come.
Oh God! - Hey you, bastard.
How dare...
How dare you try to...
What happened?
I must curse you.
How many times I've told you
that he gives me dirty looks.
Did you listen to me?
Do you know where he
put his hands?
What happened, Vinod?
You bloody rascal! Will you put
your hands on my friend?
Leave him. - I know from where
you would've come.
Don't beat him.
- Hey, leave him...leave him.
Go...go man.
They come as friends and put
hands as soon as the hall becomes dark.
College students are
real nasty persons.
Hey, beat him.
Look at the nasty things he does
in the garb of student.
They come here for
such things only.
Go man...go.
You'll enter if we give
you a leeway.
This is our problem, we'll settle
it between ourselves.
You keep away from it.
Please Swetha, don't cry.
Whatever it is, let's settle it
in the college.
Seenu, take her home.
She's my friend for the
past 10 years.
I would've beaten
this rogue to death.
I'm sparing him for you.
Try to understand.
Okay Divya. I'll take leave now.
Vinod, go to a doctor.
Raju...come.
Adi, I know wasn't it you
who put the hands?
Hey, don't blabber something and
put me into a fix.
I never did it. I was sitting
2 rows behind her.
Divya, are you coming
with us or not?
Has he become more
important than us?
I thought you'll get caught.
How did you manage to escape?
That's the Psychology of girls.
You say you're a friends and
touch any where.
You'll never be suspected
of debauchery.
Hey Vinod!
Would he have known
that you were the culprit?
Let him, what the hell can he do?
Would he have spared Divya without
pawing & probing?
Vinod, will you join us for a game?
Hey, why did you give
him the ball?
Let him learn. Leave it.
Pass it...Pass it.
Ramesh, this side...left side.
Come to the left...right.
Play carefully.
Come on...come on.
Buddy, he's wantonly hitting us.
Whom are you hitting?
Look Divya.
When I asked him why did he put
hands on Swetha,
mental . . .psycho.
Look, he has beaten me up.
Beast!
Don't be friendly with him.
He can do anything.
Didn't I tell you we'll complain
to the principal?
You stopped me saying
it'll spoil his studies.
Look, how he has beaten Seenu.
In friendship, there's nothing
such as separation.
No need of words for our heads
to exchange views.
Myriads of thoughts are running
shelter-skeeter in my head.
All are vying to attract
your attention.
How many more days will
I live like this?
If you withdraw yourself from me,
under whose shade will I get solace?
TAMILINI
Good morning everybody.
You know about the yearly National
Seminar conducted in our college.
This time the prize money
is Rs.50,000.
Plus admissions to foreign Universities,
job offers...and everything.
Now, 15 students from this class are
going to present papers.
To start with Mr.Vinod
on Therm o-resins.
My paper is about Thermos-resins...
It is...it is...it consists...
...by...by heating.
Vinod, I love you.
Vinod, it's okay.
Stan from the beginning.
No sir, I'll leave this college.
Give me T.C.
No sir.
You can make it.
Please listen to me.
Vinod, come back...
Come back.
Silence.
I don't know anything, father.
He never told me he's an orphan
and doesn't have anyone.
How could he?
You're torturing him so much
when he hasn't told you.
Wouldn't you've torn him apart
if he had told you?
How can he tell you?
You never told me you lived
in such conditions to study.
Is this your hostel?
Where are your parents?
Are you a waiter in a Hotel?
Day time at college,
nights you work.
When will you sleep?
I don't want anyone's sympathies.
I'm going back to my place.
You shouldn't go.
Get lost.
Go back to your friends.
Leave me.
I don't want them,
I want only you.
Leave me...I'll go back
to my place.
Leave me.
Do you know the hell I had been through
for 2 days without talking to you?
Will you go away?
I'll kill you.
Get lost.
Why did you come here?
You kept quiet when they
insulted me in the theater.
Did you say one word
in my support?
Why the hell did you
come here now?
If you say anything,
I'll break your teeth.
I'll...hey!
Didn't you sleep in my bed room?
How can I suspect you?
Why didn't you speak to me then?
Should you beat him mercilessly?
Even if he had really done it.
Will you beat him like that?
Greeting sir.
I'm Father Rosario.
- Father!
Do you remember me?
Father!
Why're you buying
all this for me?
All are priced in 1000's.
I don't have money now.
Which color shirt do you like?
No Divya, I don't want.
We've come to a shop.
I thought we'll go
back home together.
If you want us to go separately,
it's your wish.
Divya, please listen.
Take it. Wear this and come to the seminar.
What?
I'm not for this game.
Leave me.
- Where're you running away?
You know about me, don't you?
I'll not fall for this.
Divya, please.
- No chance.
You're saying it
for fun, aren't you?
You're really participating.
- I can't do it.
Hey, listen to me.
Why do you want to insult
me in public?
What's there to feel
insulted in it?
They had insulted you
in the class room.
No one sat next to you in the class.
No one talks to you.
They make derisive comments
on seeing you.
Didn't my friend Swetha thought
bad about you in the theatre?
They all must get shocked and
astonished for a second.
Show them what you can be if you
had the same opportunities: Show them.
You needn't win in the Seminar.
- No need.
Any way, you'll not win.
- Definitely not.
Make a try.
- Make a try.
You just come on the dais,
students will applause, that's enough
for me.- That's enough for me.
Never give up without a try.
- Don't give up.- Keep trying.
You'll win one day.
- One day.
Hey, go & stand near
the entrance.
I too wanted to tell
him something.
No need of your advises.
I'll tell him.
What I'm trying to say is...
- Hey, get lost man.
Hi Vincent!
Didn't I tell you,
it'll not work out well?
Am I looking good?
Oh God!
Why're you walking like a
duck spreading your legs?
Keep your legs together.
Now walk.
Like that only.
Very good.
Look at the audience.
Don't get scared.
Now, give a stylish smile.
Audience must get charmed
by your smile.
If you laugh like this,
audience will get
scared and leave.
Look at me.
Beautifully...
Slowly...
Opening your mouth.
Why're you showing all your teeth?
Without opening your mouth,
that's enough.
All this is very important
in a Seminar.
Okay...okay...
Look at me.
I welcome everybody.
Today, I'm going to submit my paper...
What's this?
Don't touch it. Wait.
I'll show.
What's there in the cover?
- Don't be in a hurry.
What's this?
Happy birthday.
What am I to call you,
a friend or my better half?
What am I to call it,
my love or my search?
My head is floating
like a cloud.
Don't say another word.
Wear it for tomorrow's seminar.
Did you see this?
Birthday candle.
Make any wish. It'll definitely
get fulfilled.
God! I must win at
tomorrow's Seminar.
Get a good job, must go to U.S.
Pray for all this.
I'll go now...bye.
TAMILINI
The gentle breeze which is
going away touching me,
won't it engulf my entire body?
The intermittent drizzle
that is falling on me,
won't it become a heavy
torrential rain?
A shyness, touched me today.
I'm able to understand the
meaning in her eyes.
I can see the path I'm treading.
As my head & soul
gets charmed,
is it a word or silence?
Is Rainbow just a colour?
Will it shine bright, when I search
for her in distress.
TAMILINI
Will this dream come true?
Can I see her everyday?
With your arrival, will I get
the new world?
My friend, with the touch of your fingers.
I've become God.
A head surrounded by fence...
I've seen a white flag on it.
When I faltered & fell down &
saw the foot marks,
there's only one sky and one earth.
I've decided to take them on.
I started loving Divya.
TAMILINI
The sky is moving,
Earth is moving.
My eyes have turned red and
I'm feeling giddy.
My head is in pain.
The night has become hot.
I can understand, this is
also happiness.
My head is asking me if it's the same
moon I had seen yesterday?
My pent up emotions are getting
a new lease of life.
I don't know which world is this.
I'm not able to understand
it's rules & regulations.
When I land up in the country of love.
There's nothing like delight or sadness.
TAMILINI
I'm very proud to
introduce Mr. Vinod.
Couldn't you've gone with him inside?
- You don't know about him, father.
If I go inside,
he'll look at me for approval
for everything that he says.
Welcome...welcome
to my paper...
My theory is about...
Vinod, where's Divya?
My paper is about...
What happened?
Power cut.
Come, let's go.
If he sees us in this condition,
he'll feel guilty.
Yes.
MY God!
Welcome to the distinguished judges
of National Seminar 2002.
So, these are my points to
prove my contention,
and I thank everybody, students,
my professor Mr. Subramaniam,
particularly the judges,
for listening to me with all
the patience in this world.
Feel free to ask your doubts
after the Seminar.
Thank you.
Divya, I was terribly scared.
That's all...that's, it's all over.
You've done it.
Didn't you ask me where's god?
She's an angel sent by god.
Hold on to her.
Hold on to her tightly.
She'll take you up with her.
You'll come back.
A glimmer of hope,
not for me, but other inmates.
No...you don't come back.
Forget about orphanage.
You follow her. Marry her.
First go and express it to her.
No...yes.
You go ahead.
God bless you.
Bye Vinod.
Thanks for your Rs.50,000.
Don't forget if you
go to foreign.
Divya, you're ravishing
in this dress.
Bastard.
Vinod come, let's go & sit there.
- Why? - Come.
Great chic!
She has fallen for him.
If I had got her I would've
sucked her life out by now.
Did you come here to sleep?
- What's it? Tell me.
Okay, you be here
don't go away.
I've been holding it
for a long time.
I'll go to the ladies room & come.
OKEY -
Seenu, what's this?
Take your hands off me.
Seenu, please no.
Listen to me.
Save me.
Don't run.
What's wrong with me?
Why isn't Divya even
looking at me?
She's always after that Vinod.
He has started lamenting again.
- Who's that?
More intoxicated than us.
May be a drug case.
What happened Divya?
Look at me...
Open your eyes.
Where do you want me to go?
Go to your house.
We can't take Divya to Hospital.
If they mistake us,
we'll be in trouble.
No one must talk bad about Divya.
Give your sister's dress
as soon as we reach home.
Later, we'll take her
to a hospital.
Divya, who did this to you?
If you don't want to reveal,
forget it.
I can drop you at home...
But at this late hour...
Please Divya.
For god's sake, don't say thanks.
Take care!
Take medicines properly.
Then, take rest.
I don't know how to console you...
Myriads of thoughts are coming
into my mind,
But are unable to come out bravely.
I shouldn't be saying all this
to you in this situation,
I never got a chance to
spend time alone with you.
Trust me Divya,
I sincerely love you...
If you're in trouble...
I can't bear it...
Don't get angry, DiVVa-
I'll take leave.
Hey, didn't you go home last night?
Did you come here
straight away?
Why are you silent?
Divya, I want to
talk to you alone.
We're alone now.
Are we in a crowd?
Tell me!
You'll not get angry,
if I tell you, will you?
You'll not say, I'm not your
friend, will you?
I'll never get angry on you
for anything. Come out!
Come tomorrow evening 6 p.m.
to the college road.
Take this in the after noon and
this one in the morning.
I'll go.
Don't forget!
I'll be waiting for you.
Mad boy!
Hey, bloody idiot! Are you blind?
- Sorry... sorry...
Rogue.- Thanks!
Where're you going?
- To the computer class.
Then, about the thing,
I said yesterday... -What?
Coffee?- Yes.
Okay! Hey, keep your cool!
She may slap you.
Hello, 2 coffees. Please...2
What's this, Divya?
Okay, sit here.
Hey, wait!
Are you the old Vinod now?
Please sit down, sir.
Coffee?
One more coffee!
Hey, give me one coffee.
Hey, you said you wanted
to say something.
I don't know how to tell you.
Divya, I'm little confused
for the past few days.
That is...
What's problem with your health?
No Divya! I feel like
seeing you... always.
Okay, see me!
Who's stopping you?
I'm getting strange thoughts.
I'm not able to sleep at night.
You studied for the examinations
keeping awake all night.
It would've become a problem.
For safe side, consult a Doctor.
Adi, sit down!
Adi, if you don't mind,
one more coffee please.
Sure!
Vinod look, what he's
doing for me?
He's not as bad as we had thought
about him earlier.
He's a good boy.
Little rough!..That's all.
He has changed a lot now a days.
Do you know he threw the
cigarette on seeing me?
Will you do me a favour, Vinod?
He still thinks, I'm having
misgivings about him.
Will you tell him, I don't
have such feelings now?
I can tell that myself, he may think
I'm making fun of him.
He has come.
Vinod, please don't say loudly so
that I can overhear it.
I'll be embarrassed.
Tell him secretly.
Hey! Tell him...tell him...
When?
Just now.
Buddy...buddy...
Ask her if it's love?
Ask her...come on ask her...
It'll definitely be love.
What if she says yes in
a different mood.
Ask her...ask her...come on.
I don't know!
She says "don't know".
I've got it...I've got it...
It's love...it's definitely love...
Look at her blushing...
Love...love...love...
love...love...
Ask her if she'll come to a movie
with me this evening.
Sathyam Theater!
Okay! Ask her if I can put my hands
on her while watching the film.
I'll beat him with slippers.
Okay, I'll not do it.
Let's be friends.
I'll put when she likes.
I'll not touch her now.
Okay buddy, I'll go and
arrange money for the film.
One humble request.
You don't come with her!
Okay! Just today only, please.
Okay'?
Okay, I'll also go now.
Hey, don't look at me like that.
You said, you weren't feeling well.
Consult a Doctor.
Okay! Bye!
6 months later...
I understood what life is all about.
I went through tremendous agony in
these 6 months.
I saw Divya & him together
in the morning,
and in the evening,
I heard & saw disgusting
scenes & sounds.
Peter & his sweet head.
Like everyone else, natural desires
awoke in me too,
But they surfaced belatedly.
They were triggered after I had
lost Divya.
I couldn't sleep at nights.
I started having wet dreams.
Hey Vinod, come in.
- It's alright.
Divya asked me to give this to you.
7'0 clock.
Okay. Give this to Divya
and tell her that I gave it.
Okey -
Hey, thanks buddy.
TAMILINI
I saw an angel & fell in love.
She merged into my soul.
She pierced into my head.
She became my breath.
She changed my identity.
A butterfly came in my path,
and left it's colours
on my finger.
I put my finger in fire.
I opened a shop in a deserted island.
I built a house of sand.
TAMILINI
An angel...an angel.
She's an angel...
Oh my sweet head! A drop of tear
is dropping from my eye.
It's enough if you understand it and
fathom it's depth.
Why are your memories
still fresh in my mind?
My breath becomes hot
when you breathe near me.
Flowers which blossom on the
graves aren't adorned by anyone.
My love & affection for
you is so enormous,
that I totter and
my dream gets shattered.
TAMILINI
Oh my friend! When you
lie on my shoulders,
My head turns into a
devil's play ground.
As a friend, you brought a change
in me & my life style.
You made me go blind in
the mirage of your love.
Even when wind tears the leaves,
they never get angry on wind.
If I'm angry with you,
where will I go and
whafll happen to me?
My success or defeat in
life is in your hands.
How many times in the day will you tell
me that "I love you."
Okay, I love you.
I love you Adi.
Marriage? Why're you in a hurry?
Wait for a year.
I promise...
Registered marriage? I'll hit you.
If my father comes to know about this,
you're finished.
What the hell! Give me some time.
Is this the house?- Yes sir.
You stay here.- Yes sir.
Where's your son?
Is he sleeping?
I've come to see the stupid face
which loves my daughter.
I don't like it. I'm in agony.
I took lot of pains for 21 years to
bring up my daughter,
and all of a sudden it seems
some rogue is trying to take her away.
I would've beaten that
rascal to death.
Sir.- It seems you're an
employee of the central government.
That's why, I came here to warn you.
Hereafter my daughter will
not attend that college.
I phoned Coimbatore last night
and got her a college seat there.
I guarantee that you won't have
any problems because of my daughter.
Similarly, I expect the same
from your son too.
Did you get it?
I'm telling this as a
father of a daughter.
Don't force to me to tell
the same thing as a policeman.
Boys must be brought up
with an iron hand.
Even my daughter was shouting.
I slapped her, she locked
herself in the room.
She won't talk to me for a couple
of days. She won't eat.
She'll threaten
to commit suicide also.
It's better for her to die instead of
living with a rogue of another caste.
We all are going to die some day.
Do you agree with me?
Let's make love, Mary.
Peter is not here.- I know.
I came to see you.
Don't get scared.
Do as I say.
There's no one to help me
other than you.
It's been 5 days since I saw Divya.
When I inquired in the college,
they said that her father has taken
the transfer certificate.
He came to our house
and threatened me.
My parents are very soft Nature.
They're begging me to leave all this.
I can't live without Divya.
I'll die.
But I'm clueless & scared.
Please. You must only help me.
If you're afraid of your own father,
what can I do?
I don't know.
But do something.
Can you live without Divya?
Please, I see her face all over.
I'm going mad.
Please do something, buddy.
Okay, I'll give you an idea,
will you listen to me?
Do you've any relatives
in other places?
My uncle lives in Bangalore.
It's better you & Divya go to Bangalore
without anyone's knowledge.
Do you want us to elope?
- There's no other choice.
I know her father,
he's a caste fanatic.
He would rather die than
accept your love.
But Divya...
- Divya won't come, I know that.
I'll some how bring her out.
You manage and take her with you.
Tell her that you'll commit suicide
if she doesn't come with you.
When?- Wait at the central station
tonight at 7.00.
I'll somehow bring her there.
What's it?
- I want to meet Divya.- Why?
Sir, I heard that Divya won't
come to college hereafter.
That's why, I want to see her
for the last time...
She said that she'll give me
your old pants & shins.
Okay go, but you must leave
immediately. Got it?
Yes sir.- Go.
Hey Adi, here's the ticket.
Take care, I'll get something to eat.
The train is about to depart
They haven't come.
May be they're waiting for the
family members to go to sleep.
Who told you to be here at 7.00 p.m.?
Which family goes to bed at 7.00 p.m.?
It's not easy to come out
of that house.
Won't they suspect
if she packs her luggage?
Look, they'll come around 12'0 clock
after everyone goes to bed.
Poor Vinod. He's going to stand
in the street all night.
Sir...see you.
Haven't they come yet?
There must be some problem.
Let's go to her house & see.
Search every where.
Look for him inside the trains
Go...go fast.
Search at the bus stand.
Sir...
Where's my daughter?
Sir!
Hey, come.
Please sir. I swear I don't know.
Vinod went to bring her.
I waited all night but
they never turned up.
Who's Vinod?
Our friend...our classmate.
He's very innocent...
Someone migh have hit him and
taken away Divya.
Sir, please check it out...
please sir.
Switch on the light.
- Yes sir.
He's a good chap.
I saw him last night also.
May be he has gone
to his native place?
But he never goes without informing us.
He's very innocent.
Ask him to open this box.
- Sir.
Yuck!
Divya!- Go back.
Oh God! She's our hotel dancer.
Close it.
Ifell in love.
I fell in love.
Hello, who's speaking?
- Whom do you want?
Adi, I'm Vinod speaking.- Vinod?
Divya is fine.
I've brought Divya here
as per your instructions.
No...no. That's not a problem.
Everything is okay.
Do you want to talk to Divya?
What? Talk to Divya?
Hello, whom do you want?
This is STD Kiosk.
You're talking without a break.
Did Divya's father inquire you?
He didn't suspect you, did he?
That's why, we left you there
and came here.
Was he worried very much?
Let him be.
He slapped Divya, didn't he?
You're talking to an
unknown person, mind it.
Will he change his head?
Good.
If he doesn't,
come here immediately.
Give it to me.
- Divya wants to speak to you.
Why?
It seems he misses you a lot.
He'll come here immediately,
if he hears your voice.
Then, all our plans will go awry.
Hey, what's this? Are you a fool?
Idiot, stupid...
Hey, why're you crying?
Okay, you can't live without her.
You'll commit suicide.
I've told her everything.
Will Divya come out of her
house just like that?
Adi, I'm allright, I love you.
What? I love you? Who's that
playing the fool with me?
Come fast. Bye.
Why is it so cold?- Don't worry,
wait for some more time.
Will it not be so cold?
- It'll get much colder.
If Adi was here with me now...
- What if Adi was here?
We would've rubbed
against each other.
What's it?- Rub.
There's a difference between
you & Adi.
Oh God! You've grown up physically.
But your mind is still immature.
You & me are different.
There's a difference in your touch
& Adi's touch.
Come near me.
Did you feel anything now?
Nothing, isn't it?
But if I had kissed Adi,
that's all...
What will happen?
- What will happen!
He won't keep quiet.
He'll kiss me back.
Not only that,
he'll hug me tight.
Then...
Yuck! Get lost.
Shall I do all that?
You don't have any sense.
You don't know what you're talking.
You shouldn't do such things.
- Why?
Why means?...
You shouldn't do such things.
Tell me, why?
- Because we both are friends.
Friends shouldn't do such things.
Neither he's a grown up
nor a kid!
Where's Divya?- She's standing
outside the gate.
I told her that I'll check whether
you're in the station or not.
Is power restored?
Father, where are you going?
- I'll send back Divya.
Father...- Yuck. What you've done
in not at all good.
Father, I can't live without you.
Hey, she loves someone else.
Leave her.
Father, you told me that
she's an angel, don't leave her.
Now you're asking me to leave her.
How do I know that
she has no love lust for you?
You've made me hang
my head in shame.
Leave me.- Father.
Few more days, father.
- Leave me.
Divya will love me.
Father.- Leave me.
I'll go mad without Divya.
- Leave me.
No...Father...Father
- Leave me, I'm having chest pain.
Oh my God! Father...
Why're you so dull?
Did you meet Father?
What did he say?
I'm asking you, am I not?
Father is not in station, he has gone
to his native place. Just come with me.
Then, where are we going to stay?
You're simply walking
in the forest.
Just come with me. I'll take you
to a peaceful place.
Hey, where have you brought me?
Don't get scared, come.
What place is this...
...in the middle of the forest.
Who's living here?
Switch on the light.
I've petitioned to the
Governor for it.
I'll switch it on when
the power comes.
Then, what about eating,
sleeping...
In the dark only.
I want to go to toilet.
Where's the toilet?
In the open field.
I never believed when
others told me about you.
But now I believe them,
you...you're mad,
a lunatic, a psycho.
Or else you wouldn't have brought me
to such a God forsaken place?
What do you expect me
to do here?
Do you want me to sit
in the corner quietly?
Yuck! Did you make me
walk all along for this?
Mosquitoes too...
Who knows whether it was a
mosquito or a snake?
There's no light to verify.
No. I won't talk to you
about anything.
You'll start to lament that you're
an orphan & so on.
I can't listen to you.
I'll sleep. Wake me up in the
morning if I'm still alive.
I'm dying of hunger.
If I had known this,
I would've purchased chips.
Yuck!
Rice, gravy, beet root, Brinjal,
there's also 'rasam'.
I don't want anyone to remain
hungry because of me.
Today, I've prepared only
vegetarian food.
Tell me if you want non-vegetarian.
I'll prepare it, though I hate it.
What to do?
I must do everything.
You've come with full faith in me.
Wait . ma.
Here's the milk, drink this too.
Everything looks like magic!
Wait.
You're always in a hurry.
Hey, you're doing wonders!
TAMILINI
A fire is raging inside me
without touching her.
I'm getting intoxicated even
before I touch her.
Your memories are burning me.
I'll throb & pine for her
till it hurts me
The more I see you
the more I feel the pain.
When will you look at me?
When will my penance
come to an end?
Staying near this beauty,
how am I to bear this torture?
Why're you digging holes
early in the morning?
Go.
What?
You wanted to go to the toilet.
Go.
Here?
Attend to the nature's call, cover the
night soil with this stone.
What's it?
- How to wash?
There're so many leaves here,
use them.
Where did you go to the toilet?
Look, I've kept 3 stones there.
Sit down.
We searched all over the orphanage.
There's no evidence that they went there.
When I thought of inquiring from Father,
it seems he died of a
head attack yesterday.
Everything seems to be a mystery.
I think he has kept
Divya somewhere here.
What are you doing?
You said you'll take bath here.
That's why I'm checking the depth.
Wait for sometime. I'll tell you
where it's not too deep.
Do you know to swim?
- No.
If you get drowned...
Vinod, tell me 2 bad words
in Tamil language.
Why are you asking?
Tell me. I want to see
whether you know them or not.
In college, people say something...
Rogue, scoundrel...
Why are you asking?
How was that?
Come.- No. I don't know to swim.
I'll teach you.
Do you've the thread
around your waist?- Yes.
Then what? Come.
I'll teach you to swim.
Won't you come if I tell you to?
Shall we go?- Let's stay here
for some more time.
No...it's time.
We must talk to Adi on phone.
What for?
What for! You never allowed me
to talk to him yesterday.
I want to hear Adi's voice.
First I must tell Adi
to come here soon.
Please turn back.
I want to change my dress.
Vinod, I'm ready.
Change your dress quickly,
we'll go.
TAMILINI
With our heads looking
at each other,
With our eyes caressing
each other,
With our lips rubbing
against each other,
The flood of love has broken barriers.
A river is flowing in my nerves.
What kind of a desire is this?
My body is getting burnt
in the fire of love.
What kind of a life is this?
With a single glance,
With a single word,
With a single touch, I'll be reborn!
TAMILINI
When love gets dried up.
It's a curse to be engulfed by lust.
It's a torture to sleep with
a thorn inside the eye.
I'll drink the water falling
from your body as medicine.
It'll reduce my bewilderment.
I'll die in your foot marks.
My soul is soaring high,
Changing it's color.
The pain is increasing.
What kind of a violence is this?
TAMILINI
Will waves get burnt
by the moon light?
Will the moon know
the sorrows of the waves?
Sorrows are engulfing
my body in a pleasant way.
Oh My body! get frozen.
Oh My head! die.
Let me be a stone
in your path.
Oh maiden! kill me with your looks.
Oh maiden! Bury me in your tresses.
But, don't forget to kiss
before you kill me.
Sir, no thanks.
Divya, it's very crowded.
You said you wanted to buy
some face cream. You go & buy.
I'll tell you when the
kiosk is free.
He's dangerous.
What's it?- Don't look back.
How did they come to know?
- Don't know.
I told you not to phone them, didn't I?
You never listened to me.
Now your father has informed
all police stations.
Is he human?
Will he never allow you
to live in peace?
You said he kidnapped her.
Why is she running with him?
I told you not to look back,
didn't I?
Sir, I can't see anything.
It's very dense.
We'll get lights from the station.
Don't get separated, stay together.
Adi...- Sir...
You stay here. I'll go & check whether
they're following us or not?
Oh my dear! Just a few days more,
Adi will be here.
Then everything will be alright.
Okey -
Stay inside.
Adi.- Hey rascal.
Thank god you've come.
I was praying to god
to send Adi.
He has sent you.
Come, I'll take you to Divya.
Hey.- What's wrong with you?
Come. If Divya sees you,
she'll hug tightly & kiss you.
She'll keep saying something
like this. Come...Come.
Adi, as you said I brought her
to the railway station.
We were caught by the
police on the way.
They questioned me where was I
taking her so late in the night?
We got scared.
We took a bus & came here.
We were going to the town
to call you up.
Police found us.
How did you come here?
Any way, you've made it up to here.
Come, I'll hand over Divya to you.
Then, I'll make a move.
Take good care of her.
Hereafter you're everything to her.
She also loves you very much.
Even I asked her, "what's so special
in that stupid's face."
Adi, what I mean to say is...
I should've also been like you.
I should've kissed & hugged her
when I got the chance.
I should've had her fully.
If I keep on calling her an angel,
this will be the result.
That's why I'm going
to have Divya first.
What do you say Adi?
Have you left me?
Why were you so late?
Look, how you got wet in the rain?
Come.
Has the police gone away?
If they find out & come here
in the morning.
My father will get me married
forcibly to someone else.
I can't live without you & Adi.
I'll go & sleep.
I don't want food.
What happened?
Why have you come to sleep here?
Are you scared to sleep alone?
Come.
I know you're in great turmoil.
I thought of asking you on the day
I saw the scars on your body.
I didn't know whether you'll
take it in a right sense or not?
If I hurt you more
by asking something...
Even now I'm not asking you anything.
If you're interested,
if you think you can
share it with me,
if you really trust me,
tell me, I'll listen.
Tell me.
I would've kept him with me,
if he was a girl.
He's of no use.
Clients doubt that I'm overaged
because of him.
How much do you want?
- Rs 10,000.
Take it & go.
I wanted to ask you...
Take Rs 15,000. Leave him here & go.
From one hell to another.
I was there for a year.
Why do you fall at my feet?
One day, I saw her in this hell.
Another family hit by poverty.
Come, you don't worry.
I'll take care of everything.
Let your children stay here & study.
Let them work for few hours
after studies.
You both go to the base of the hill
to crush stones.
Hey get up.
Get up.
I'll go.
I don't like to stay here.
I'll go to my parents.
- Sleep.
We can sleep only for 3 more hours.
If you don't sleep now, you'll feel
sleepy during work.
Come here.
Eat this & sleep.
This is your food.
You didn't eat in the evening
since you were crying.
That's why I kept it for you. Eat.
Or else you won't get sleep.
You can talk!
I thought you're dumb.
What's it?- Just sleep.
Who's he?- Don't shout.
Hey, Get up.
You said you wanted to eat
"Jilebi"(sweet).
I've brought it. Come.
I've plenty of "Jilebis". You can eat
for the next 10 days, come.
I'll take them tomorrow morning.
I'll give you now only,
come on get up.
No, I don't want.
- If you don't come now,
I'll complain to Krishnaveni madam
and get you beaten up.
Come...get up.- No please.
Don't tell about this to anyone.
Okay?- Yes.
How many "Jilebis"
will you give me?
After that, Devi never left me
alone even for a minute.
Even under such testing conditions,
we were very happy.
Devi used to talk a lot,
about leaving this hell
in the near future.
It seems, she'll marry me only
after going out from here.
It seems, we'll have a child,
...and we'll be taking care
of it very affectionately.
In this place, only dreams
weren't restricted.
Give me a fond kiss.
Sir, this is our school.
Look, how nicely they are studying.
They work for little time
after studies.
Rarely they used come to
inspect the factory.
Till now they used to take money
at the gate & go away.
But this Officer was different.
When I saw them getting
afraid of him...
I was very happy-
Open it! I want to see.
- Sir, that side...
Open it, I want to see.
- Okay, open it.
Bloody cheats!
It raised my hopes and
I told him everything.
Officer was in for a
windfall that day.
Generally one who used
to take Rs.25,000...
...went away silently
taking Rs.50,000.
Oh! Please open it.
It is burning.
Keep an eye, I'll come back
in few minutes.
Hey, Poor boy...he's very young.
- You do your work.
He complained against us
to the Officer, didn't he?
Madam is not in town,
we'll not get another chance.
Oh God!
Hey leave me... Leave...
- Don't shout.
Hey! What? Go away.
Hey, give me!
Get up!
Let's watch T.V.
Will you join me?
Why are you afraid?
Rajini, Kamal all actors will
appear on T.V.
It'll be very good to watch.
Come.
No! I don't want.
You mustn't say like that!
I've bought "Biryani" for you.
You come & eat.
Devi, don't go!
Isn't it very cold out side?
Come, let's go & sleep inside.
No, I'll not come.
Hey, don't be stubborn. - No.
- What do you want? Tell me.
Will you release Vinod?
- Vinod?
He's inside this box.
That's all!
Why did you ask me to do it?
Couldn't you've opened it yourself?
Vinod, what happened to you?
Vinod, get up.
Nothing has happened to him.
- What happened to you, Vinod?
He'll get well...
Come on get up...come...come.
Come, don't cry.
Listen to me.
Don't go...don't...
Oh God! it's paining.
Why did you bring it here?
She's dead. What else do you
want me to do?
I've informed madam.
She'll be here any moment.
Bloody street dog!
How many times I've told you
not to touch girls here?
If you feel like having a women,
why don't you go out?
Am I not enough for your
dirty face?
Bloody rascal!
You don't worry madam,
we'll bury her in a corner.
Not necessary.
Throw it into the crusher machine.
Let it come out tomorrow
as mosaic paste.
If her parents inquire about her...
...tell them, we don't know about her,
she has ran away from here.
This is the fourth girl
to die this year.
Hey, open the door.
If we come out, you're finished.
What's it, boy? Go!
What?
What's it, boy?
What? What?
TAMILINI
Unite with my head
in a relationship.
Forget about the dreadful past,
my dear.
When gentle cool breeze
blows in moon light,
it'll make you forget your wounds,
my dear.
If I look at you,
you'll bloom like a flower.
If I say a word of comfort,
your pain will vanish, my dear.
TAMILINI
Though mirror is broken
into pieces,
I've seen it showing our images.
After a cyclone,
new flower will bloom.
I'm there in it as life till the end.
This is a mask wearing World,
I've your mask less face with me.
Even if the moon's image
falls into the river,
...it'll never get wet.
Come, my friend.
TAMILINI
Time will move.
My life will become history.
My tears will linger on
for longer time
Even if you come to shower
motherly affection on me,
I want to be born in
your lap again.
My life is your mercy.
I want to become a
pan of your life.
This is not love.
This is not lust.
There's no name for
this relationship.
TAMILINI
If you look at me,
I'll bloom as a new flower.
If you say a word of comfort,
my pain will vanish, my love.
Here!
Look back!
Why are you laughing?
What else do you want me to do?
When I hear all that you say,
it makes me laugh.
What do you know about Vinod?
Suddenly, you've brought me here
and say I've been kidnapped,
he has killed a girl,
and pushed Adi from a hill.
Have you all gone mad?
We're not mad, Divya.
You've blind faith in him.
His finger prints are
on the knife & the box.
Not only that, we found a dead body
3 days ago in your college.
Name is Seenu.
Your college mate.
He was pushed into a
construction pit & the pit was closed.
I'm suspecting Vinod
in this case also.
There's a report that Seenu has been
missing since the Cultural festival.
Do you know anything
about it? Tell me.
Do you know?
I think you'll accuse Vinod for
all murders in this State.
I'll go and ask Vinod directly.
Divya! What I'm saying is true.
Believe me!
He's a dangerous criminal.
I've full faith in him.
Didn't I tell you,
I'll ask him,
Don't talk unnecessarily
about him before that.
Damn it! He's a psychopath.
Didn't I tell you not
to abuse him.
Will he kill me, if I go to him?
If you want, come behind me and watch.
Divya, what he says is true.
Do you know what Vinod
has done to me?
If you accuse him,
do I've to believe you?
Divya, please stop it!
Listen to me.
You can't go there.
Sorry Divya.
I wanted you to understand him...so.
You don't know anything about him.
I've lived 3 days alone with him.
He could've done anything with me.
He took care of me
exceptionally well, why?
He made special arrangements
for my food, bed & bath.
Even now, I can hear his
voice in my ears.
Poor boy!
Do you know the hell he had
been through as a boy?
I'll never believe!
My Vinod will never
do such things.
I'll never believe it.
Tell me it was done by Adi.
I may even believe that.
My Vinod...
that too killing me...
Divya, okay...okay!
What's it Divya?
Vinod!
I knew he'll definitely come.
Where's he?
He was here only.
Divya, relax! It's okay!
Calm down!
No Adi, I saw him.
It was Vinod.
Please, don't think about the past.
Come.
Everything will be alright.
Divya, you don't worry.
Nothing will happen to you.
Didn't I tell you, it was Vinod?
Constables. . .C0nstables!
My life will become a pan
of history in time.
My tears will linger
on for a longer time.
Though you shower motherly
affection on me,
I want to be born again
on your lap.
My life is your mercy.
Come on Adi.
Jeep...jeep.
Run fast to the jeep.
Hurry up...hurry up...
come on.
Divya, run faster.
Come on...come...hurry up...hurry
fast...fast...
Adi, where's the Inspector?
Come!
Divya, come quickly...
come quickly.
Adi, I can't run any further.
We're late!
Shall we go to our house?
This is enough! enough...
If a man sneaks into a girl's bed
without his shirt at midnight...
Any girl will suspect.
But you took me onto your lap,
and asked me about my difficulties.
Angel!
The tears I shed then washed away
all my bad intentions.
I must be with you.
That's all.
If you understand that,
it's enough..
I'm feeling sleepy.
Please, let's go to sleep.
Oh my God!
Sorry dear! Please.
I'm really; sorry'.
Please no Divya...don't...
Divya, please.
Don't get scared of me.
I'm your friend Vinod.
Would you like to beat me
as I had slapped you?
Slap me!
Do you know how I felt when I didn't
see you when I woke up?
I got scared that you may've
also left me.
I know you Divya.
You would've come to know
the truth about me.
They would've told you.
I've committed murders.
I've cheated you by telling lies.
What's wrong in it?
To stay with my Divya,
I'll do anything.
What's lacking here?
What else do you want?
Tell me, I'll bring it.
But never leave me & go away.
I don't have anyone.
I'll die, if you also leave me.
Look...how beautiful this place is.
A home of our own.
Full of light!
A family...Children...
This is my dream.
The dream I saw looking out of
the window in my young age.
Do you know how much
I had yearned for this?
Ask this wall.
It'll tell how many days
I spent crying before it.
This is my problem.
When my turn comes,
nothing will materialize.
What great things did I hope for?
An ordinary life which you're living.
Why am I being denied that life?
Why everything is going the
wrong way for me?
What sins have I committed?
But I know one thing clearly,
you...you...you're different.
I'm with you.
I'm here to fulfill
all your wishes.
Why do you need others?
Your father, mother, Adi,
you don't need anyone.
Do you think you love that Adi?
Yuck! ...no...ugh!
That's not love!
He got you admitted in a
hospital that day.
It entitles him only for thanks.
Thank him, that's all!
Will you love him for that? Idiot!
The thing which is between us,
that's love.
True Love!
How you get distressed,
if I'm in trouble.
That's love!
Okay! That's it. Poor girl!
How can you understand this?
Someone must explain this to you.
You've understood it.
Yes! you've got it.
Tell me, you love only me, don't you?
Leave it...if you don't like.
...leave it.
Just tell me, you'll always
be with me. That's enough.
Tell me!
Okay...okay.
I've got it.
You don't want to be with me
after knowing the truth.
No problem!
I'll stay in a corner like a dog.
I'll never come near you.
If you call me, I'll come.
If you ask me to go,
I'll go away.
Isn't the happiness of seeing you
enough for me?
I don't want anything else.
Tell me at least now.
You'll stay here.
Tell me...tell me.
Will you stay or not? Tell me.
No...- Why?
Why?
Because you're my friend.
- So what?
I can't be with you always.- Why?
You can't understand that!
No, you're not able
to understand me.
I was on the streets.
You turned me into a human,
and leaving me again on the streets.
You're not able to understand me.
Bloody fool, I had hit you on your head.
Didn't you die?
Isn't he the reason for all this?
If he hadn't crossed our path,
you would've always been with me,
wouldn't you?
You don't worry, Divya.
Right now, here, I'll kill him.
After that you can't go anywhere.
You must be with me only.
Look Divya! He's holding
my neck in front of you.
No, Vinod!
- You stay inside.
My Divya has refused to stay with me.
I fell in love.
Why did you come here?
Divya, leave him.
Divya, he's the one responsible
for everything.
Leave him.
He must die.
Have you gone mad, Divya?
Can't you hear my shouts?
We both are going to die for him.
Leave him...