Today the documents and proofs
that Ravi Verma has..
..presented for the property
case of Ravi Verma..
..and Surjuda, it clearly states
that Ooty command's..
..entire property's real
proprietor was Ravi Verma's..
..late father Mr. Shanta
Prasad Verma.
He had given partnership
to Surjuda because of..
..his friendship and trust.
But after his death..
..now Surjuda wants to capture
his entire property..
..from his helpless
family and son.
So the judge's decision is that
this entire tea estate of..
..Ooty command, tea factories
and palace that were of..
..Mr. Shanta Prasad, it
must be handed over to..
..Ravi Verma and not to Surjuda.
We've won the case, Kamini.
l'm so happy.
5th January, 1959. Today Surjuda
has lost the case.
And only you're responsible
for this. Mr. P. P. Roy.
The famous advocate of lndia.
But, sir. l don't know how
that boy presented..
..the real documents in the court.
And he reversed the entire case.
And now Surjuda is thinking
of reversing you.
But sir, we'll go to
the supreme court.
God didn't give the
speech to Surjuda..
..but He has surely
given him a brain.
There'll be some other advocate..
..in the supreme court, Mr.
P. P. Roy, not you.
Come, Kamini. Come, Charanjeet.
Surjuda says that we've come
to know that Ravi Verma..
..loves your sister? ls it true?
My sister has an affair
with many people.
But this boy is very rich, sir.
Then you and your sister
both can become rich.
How?
lf you get marry with Ravi
Verma before 8th January..
..and become Mrs. Ravi Verma.
And by the 1 1th of January
if you become a widow.
l mean Ravi Verma..
And by the12th of January
if you hand over..
..all his wills papers to us
then by the 15th of January..
..we'll make you the
queen of that estate.
But who will the real possessor
of the property?
lt'll be Surjuda.
You'll get 25000 rupees per month.
And Ooty's palace will be
transferred to your name.
But if you change your mind
after being the queen..
..then you also will be
lying dead like him.
My advance?
Congratulation! Congratulation,
brother-in-law!
What are you waiting for?
Click the photos.
C'mon, hurry up. Yes, click.
C'mon, once more.
C'mon.
Ramsingh. Get that luggage
down. Hurry up!
Congratulation, queen. l
also came to know that..
..your son has won the case.
- But you didn't give me..
..the real congratulations. You
didn't see this decoration?
These arrangements?
l didn't get you.
- l'll tell you, uncle.
Brother has got married in..
..Mumbai and is coming here
with sister in law.
That's why mummy is so happy.
He got married? - Mr. Satnam,
the time is changing.
Now the parent's life's aim is
their children's happiness.
Mr. Sharma, did you send
the special car..
..for Ravi at the station?
- Yes, queen.
But sir has decided to
come alone by the jeep.
But why he did this?
- You'll never understand him..
..mummy. Brother is very clever.
He might be showing the estate
to my sister in law..
..and making his impression.
Very nice. Kamini, you know
l love this tune very much.
lt seems the radio station also
have come to know that l'm..
..taking away my bride at my home.
Thank you radios broadcasting
station.
Thank you very much.
Kamini, this is our tea factory.
Verma tea estate.
Hi Robert! How are you?
- Bye!
What happened?
- Your jeep is not ready to move.
No, madam. Actually, my
jeep has given me..
..a chance to do some romance.
Do you want to reach home or not?
- Home?
Oh yes! Yes!
Today mummy will get angry on me.
lf her son will go out
somewhere alone.
She'll make all the telephones..
..and wirelesses of
the city occupied.
There's no water in the regulator.
Ok. l'll arrange it
from somewhere.
l'll just be back, darling.
No matter what you say, darling.
A wife's love is always special.
lt gives lots of tickling.
Mother's love is also very nice.
But too much love creates
a problem sometime.
Too much love, you see.
Now when we'll reach home
you just see. How she'll..
..welcome you. She'll be
ready in your service..
..all the time. And will
look after all your need.
But she doesn't know nowadays..
..daughters in law doesn't
like all this.
Kamini! My mother is very sweet.
You just touch her..
..feet when you reach home.
Just impress her. But..
Do you know how to touch the feet?
This is the problem with
the modern girl like you.
Look, how l'm touching.
You just do this way.
Look!
Bend at her and tell her,
mother, bless me.
Mummy will say. Be happy,
my daughter in law.
Live long life!
What are you doing, Kamini?
Why are you driving
the jeep on me?
No, Kamini! No. No..
Ravi! Ravi! No.. No..
this is not possible.
Such a big injustice is not
possible. You can't leave.
You had promised me
that you'd come back.
But not this way.. brother!
Brother!
My only one young son.
My pearl. No..
l won't let you go.
l'll come with you.
Your mother will come with you.
- Brother!
Leave me.. leave me.. leave me.
l want to go with him.
l want to ask her.
To this mother..
..who has snatched away
my young son from me.
You didn't felt anything
watching him dying?
lf you're a mother then
l'm also a mother.
l'll see how you don't
return me my son.
You must return me my son.
Ravi will have to come here.
At this place. ln this house.
To me. He will have to
fulfil his promise.
He will have to pay off
his mother's debt.
He must pay off his mother's debt.
Brahma! Vishnu! Mahesh! They
came to this world so..
..many times. They
took many births.
They came in so many forms. lt
says that if a man's wish..
..remains incomplete before
his death or if he misses..
..somebody. His wish surely gets
fulfilled in the next birth.
Our friend Mr. Ravi
Verma's story..
..is also somewhat
similar to this.
Who took rebirth for his mother.
At some other place.
ln some other form.
With the name.. Monty.
1 .. 2.. 3..
7.. 8.. 7, 8, 9, 10.
Money.. this money..
Money.. how's this money?
Nothing can be compared
to this money.
lf it's with you it's a problem..
And if not, is also a problem..
Yes, a problem.. Yes,
a problem..
7.. 8.. 9.. 10..
Money.. this money..
Money.. how's this money?
Nothing can be compared
to this money.
lf it's with you it's a problem..
And if not, is also a problem..
Yes, a problem.. Yes,
a problem..
7.. 8.. 9.. 10..
1 ..
- Money.. this money..
2..
- Money.. how's this money?
3.. - Nothing can be compared
to this money. - 4..
5.. - lf it's with
you it's a problem..
6.. - And if not, is
also a problem..
7.. - Yes, a problem..
- 8.. Yes, a problem..
7.. 8.. 9.. 10..
Saw a love. Saw the affection.
Saw a friendship. Saw a friend.
Saw across the heart.
Saw the entire world.
Above and below. ln and
out. Far and near..
Climate is same everywhere.
Money.. money.. money..
- Money!
1 ..
- Money.. this money..
2..
- Money.. how's this money?
3.. - Nothing can be compared
to this money. - 4..
5.. - lf it's with
you it's a problem..
6.. - And if not, is
also a problem..
7.. - Yes, a problem..
- 8.. Yes, a problem..
7.. 8.. 9.. 10..
1 .. 2.. 3..
4.. 5.. 6..
7.. 8.. 7, 8, 9, 10.
1 ..
- Money.. this money..
2..
- Money.. how's this money?
3.. - Nothing can be compared
to this money. - 4..
5.. - lf it's with
you it's a problem..
6.. - And if not, is
also a problem..
7.. - Yes, a problem..
- 8.. Yes, a problem..
7.. 8.. 9.. 10..
1 ..
- Money.. this money..
2..
- Money.. how's this money?
3.. - Nothing can be compared
to this money. - 4..
5.. - lf it's with
you it's a problem..
6.. - And if not, is
also a problem..
7.. - Yes, a problem..
- 8.. Yes, a problem..
7.. 8.. 9.. 10..
There he comes.
Just a minute, please.
Stop pushing!
Please.
- On this too. - Just a minute.
This is a railway ticket,
sir. Have a look at it.
Oh! Dayal!
- Thank God that you recognised..
..your old friend.
- Hi!
lt was a great day today. Bigger
than the biggest thing.
After all who made him?
l'm the maker.
Who made Monty a star?
- You.
Mr. G. G. Oberoi.
- Thank you.
Sir, Mr. Ratanwala has
offered 50000 rupees..
..if Monty will sing in
his daughter's marriage.
What's this? Monty never sings
in the private parties.
This is my strict
contract with him.
l can't loose the millions
for thousands.
Sir, but..
- No ifs and buts.
l'm the maker. lf Monty
will sing there..
..he'll have to pay fine in lacs.
And will have to see off
his career permanently.
l completed the doctor's
course in Delhi..
..and came to Mumbai's
hospitals for job.
Here l came to know
about your show.
So l came here. But l
was afraid whether..
..you'll recognise me or not,
after so many years?
Now you stop your prating
and come home with me.
Joseph, is mummy at home?
Tell her one of my very close
friends is coming home.
We'll have dinner together. The
food should be A-1 quality.
Ok?
- Mummy?
You were telling me you
don't have parents.
How come this parents
aroused with money?
You know l used to sing in the
trains like an orphan beggar.
God had gifted me the voice.
And also sent an angle to..
..make that voice reach
to millions of people.
Angle?
- Yes. He's a rich businessman
Mr. G. G. Oberoi.
l live with them..
..and consider them my parents.
You just come home.
You'll come to know
how fortunate l'm.
l'm the maker. Star maker Oberoi.
But Mr. Oberoi. You've also
made business from this.
So what? But who's the maker?
l'm the maker.
Here comes Monty. Ask him.
Daddy! He's my friend. Dr. Dayal.
Daddy! - lf an orphan child is
calling me daddy with love..
..what's wrong in that?
Monty, they are my friends.
They have come from London.
Will you keep on talking
here or leave now?
Look at the time. Monty, we're
going out for a dinner..
..with Mr. Pereira.
- Yes, let's go.
Actually, my daddy is always
occupied in his business.
l'm for the millions of people..
but nobody is mine.
Wealth and prosperity. God
has given me everything.
But l just hear about motherly
love, l feel it and get upset.
l don't know why but l
always miss a mother.
lf l had a mother, l would have
loved her so much that..
Monty! You're such a big
star and you're crying?
Look, l can't fill your lacking.
But you can do one job of mine.
- What?
You know my boss, Dr. Daniel?
There's a party at his place.
You must come there.
For what? - You're such a big
star. lf you'll come it'll make..
..my impression. lt's
a question of my job.
Ok, l'll come.
- Sure? - But where?
10, Mad island road. At 6:30.
lt seems you're new in Bombay.
But my friend had given
me 6:30's time.
Right? But can any rich
people's party..
..begin before 9 or 9:30?
Dr. Daniel is staying here only?
Yes. But he's sleeping upstairs.
He won't come down
before 8:30 or 9.
Shall l bring something?
- No, thank you.
Can l go there near the piano?
Yes, sure. Please come..
Joseph! - Yes. - Did you clean
up the glasses or not?
Tina is doing it. - She's very
much involved in the work.
What are you looking at, my dear?
l'm seeing how this instrument
is playing..
..and how he's playing it?
C'mon, let's do our job. C'mon.
Listen!
Please bring a glass
of water for me.
l'm telling you.
- Aye! My name is not this.
Joseph, give him a glass of water.
Throw?
- No. Go to hell.
These flowers are very
nice, isn't it?
lt seems these are rose
flowers, right?
Or it might be a marigold.
You also don't know.
- l know. lt's artificial.
There are flowers here
and a bloody fool too.
We want song! We want Monty.
We wont Monty.
- Silence. Silence.
We wont Monty. You have to sing..
you have to sing.
You have to sing. C'mon.
You please listen to me. Why
don't you listen to me?
According to Mr. Oberoi's
agreement..
..Monty never sings in
any private parties.
lf he'll sing. He'll have
to pay fine in millions.
And will also ruin his
career. Am l right?
Absolutely. Please try and
understand me. Please.
Look, l've called all my friends
for you. Now you must sing.
Papa, please tell him.
Look, Mr. Oberoi is my friend.
l've also invited him in..
..this party. lf you
say l'll call him up.
No, uncle, please. Don't make
me emotional. Please.
l'm helpless.
- No.. only one line please.
Look, l've called so many
musicians for you.
Why don't you understand?
Monty is a star.
He's a star. And he's also
my friend, sir. - Dayal!
Dr. Dayal!
For the same of Dr. Daniel
and for Dr. Dayal..
..if you say l can play
some musical instrument.
Yes.. let's do that.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
l was just a poet before..
you've made me your fan.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
Shall l sing?
- Yes.
Your fascinating eyes
are creating rhymes..
This stanza is not mine..
it's yours.
l just wrote that
you've dictated.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
When and where everybody
has disappeared?
Where all the shadows have lost?
Friends party has gone over..
The privacy is left for us.
When and where everybody
has disappeared?
Where all the shadows have lost?
Friends party has gone over..
The privacy is left for us.
What did you do?
Perhaps you've made
some curtain fall.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
Please sing..
Within a short time..
We'll get separated.
How will l search for you..
all the paths will be lost.
You've not even tell
me your name..
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
l was just a poet before..
you've made me your fan.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
l must say.. all the
big personalities..
..accepted defeat
to make you sing.
But just one girls eyes made..
..your voice and stanzas come out.
What a radioactivity.
But this radioactivity has really
worsened my situation.
l had fixed radar
and keeping watch.
A moon came. lt spread
the moonlight.
And she disappeared.
Who's she? From where
she has come.
Try and find out something
about her.
She came from the kitchen
and went back to it.
That means her menu card will
be found in the kitchen.
l'll get the information soon.
Listen! - What's the matter?
- Be careful. You're drunk.
Hi Monty! Can we sit here?
- Yes sure. - Thank you.
Meet them. They are my friends.
Hello, everybody. Thank you.
You've really sung
a nice song today.
l'm a big fan of yours.
Now what are you doing?
- l'm waiting for my friend.
We attend all your programs.
Not at all.
What? - Excuse me, please.
Private talking. Just a minute.
Excuse me!
- You please forget that girl.
She's not a servant
and not even a queen.
She had come to see
Mumbai from Ooty..
..in her school tour.
- Had come? - Had come.
The cook Francis here
is from her village.
He went to meet her. And got
her here for few hours..
..to show her a grand
party of Mumbai.
Now she's going back tonight
by 1 1 :30's train.
By now she might have left.
So you please forget
her considering it..
..a beautiful dream sequence
and eat this chicken.
You can't insult me like this.
- l didn't insult you, daddy.
Don't call me daddy.
Remember, you're not my son.
You're an employee under
contract. A stage contract.
My money.. my name..
- Money.. and money..
You need money not me.
lt might not happen that because
of your too much..
..restrictions and hatred Monty
will leave your money and..
..stage contract and go
to some other world.
What happened?
lt's a question of money.
l didn't do anything.
You convince him. Little lovingly.
Hello!
- Hello, Julie! - l see.
So Mr. Monty is hiding
here from his fans.
l'm trying to write a song from
last four days for my fans..
..but l'm not getting
the proper words.
But that day you made
our party remarkable.
What a song you've sung!
Look at the photographs
of that party.
Look at it. All my friends
were praising you so much.
They were telling me Julie, if
you weren't inspired Monty..
..he might not have sung
such a beautiful song.
After all to sing a song
and to write it..
..one needs some sort
of inspiration.
You were right, Ms. Julie.
You can say l've got
my inspiration.
Have you ever loved anybody?
- Yes.
Have you ever gone crazy
after anybody? - Yes.
l had also gone crazy.
The youths of my age..
Do not fall in love
with anybody.
The youths of my age..
Do not fall in love
with anybody.
l have lost my ease and sleep
by falling in love.
People never lie..
..that no disease is
dangerous than love.
We loose all the control on our
heart after falling in love.
There's no treatment to this
diseases in the world.
Then sing.. Ohm! Shanti Ohm.
Shanti, Shanti ohm!
Ohm! Shanti ohm. Shanti,
Shanti ohm!
Look at me.. l've spoiled
my nights..
..by offering my
heart to somebody.
Look at me.. l've spoiled
my nights..
..by offering my
heart to somebody.
l've still not received..
l've still not received any
answer from that side.
lf she'll refuse l won't
hesitate to commit suicide.
lf she'll accept then too
l'll die with a bliss.
Then sing.. Ohm! Shanti Ohm.
Shanti, Shanti ohm!
Ohm! Shanti ohm. Shanti,
Shanti ohm!
One who has hidden just by
giving a glance of her.
Now l take each of my
breath with her name..
With her name..
l have millions of fans
but now l'm her fan.
lf you come across
such situation..
..in love then sing
this song. Sing..
Then sing.. Ohm! Shanti Ohm.
Shanti, Shanti ohm!
Ohm! Shanti ohm. Shanti,
Shanti ohm!
Ohm! Shanti..
- Shanti, ohm!
Ohm! Shanti.
Ohm! Shanti. - Shanti, ohm!
Ohm! Shanti.. Ohm!
We want.. Monty!
Yes! Yes, Monty.
Try to remember.. Try to remember
do you know that..
..woman who was driving the jeep?
- No.
That boy whom she was murdering?
- Not at all.
You might have seen such
incidence in a film? - Never.
Somebody might have told
you such story? - No.
Any book, any novel?
- Not even in my dream.
Then how these images emerged..
..in your mind and when?
Yesterday night when l was..
..playing the high
nodes of guitar.
Sister, give him the guitar.
Close your eyes and
play that tune again.
No.. no, doctor, this time l've
also seen something else.
A small valley.
Goddess Kali's temple.
There's one palace.
And also a pond. But she was
the same girl and same boy.
Dr. Daniel, when this
is not concern with..
..his past life or with any shock.
lsn't it possible that this
must be his last births..
Last birth? - Yes. - What
nonsense, Dr. Shashtri?
You're talking about
reincarnation..
..and rebirth in this
modern times?
Dr. Shashtri, finally
you've proved yourself.
You may not believe this.
A 5 years old child in south
lndia could speak the entire..
..Geeta and Ramayana in Sanskrit.
And he had described
his last birth's..
..parents and village in detail.
ln the beginning people
laughed at him..
..but when this was proved true.
People considered it..
..a miracle of God and kept quiet.
Dr. Shashtri, let go off this. l
think it's a case of psychosis.
Let's go and discuss the rest
in the consulting room.
C'mon.
According to me. Monty
needs to take..
..complete one months rest.
And he shouldn't play that..
..special tune till we don't
reach to any conclusion.
Doctor, if Monty will
take on months break..
..we'll suffer loss in millions.
Then do you wish him to
finish off permanently?
Monty, according to me you must
go to some hill-station.
For example, Kashmir,
Darjeeling, Ooty.
No, doctor. No hill station
can relax me without music.
There's one hill station
that can soothe him.
And that is Ooty.
- Ooty? - Yes, sir.
That song of him.. stinging
heart.. throbbing heart.
lt's super hit over there.
lt's played there daily.
Ooty! The beauty!
Yes, doctor! l would like to
go Ooty. l'll go to Ooty.
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
Wow! Wow!
l was just a poet before..
you've made me your fan.
Then what happened?
- Then?
Then he became my fan.
- Really?
Do you think l'm lying?
You all are his fan.
But he became my fan.
l made him crazy. He was staring
at me and singing.
What he was singing?
What he said.. it was very nice.
We'll get separated..
what was it?
Within a short time..
We'll get separated.
How will l search for you..
all the paths will be lost.
You've not even tell
me your name..
Stinging in a heart..
Throbbing in a heart..
You've generated in my heart.
Tina, what's the matter?
You're sitting in the
library till 6:30?
He had called me in the college
restaurant at 6 o'clock.
You didn't go there?
- No.
Rita, l'll swear by God! my heart
is beating very heavily.
l just can't think of anything.
l can't decide.
l'm totally blank you know.
- This is the sound of his love.
But l didn't go to meet him.
- This is the sound of your love.
What nonsense?
My dear, this is such storm
that nobody can stop.
More you try to stop, more
it'll blow with force.
lf it's blowing ahead. Let it go.
lf it's coming to you.
Let it come.
Look at him. He's staring at me.
He's just staring at you.
He's not touching you.
Shall l ask you something?
- What?
You know my friend Rita?
She was telling me that..
..city boys are like the wasp.
They roam around the
flowers and escape.
Meaning? - lt means first they
sing songs then falls in love.
And slowly they take away
the girls in the hotel.
Then..
- Then?
l hope you won't do that with me?
- What are you saying?
No. Actually, Rita was telling
me that you should..
..be careful from the
boys before marriage.
What do you mean by careful?
You're very innocent, Tina.
l'll marry you first and then..
- No.
Not even after that. Let
Kabir uncle arrive first.
Kabir uncle? - Yes. He's the only
one for me in this world.
He's at abroad from
last so many years.
He has left me here under
the care taking of queen.
He had sent a note that he'll
come anytime in these days.
And he'll surprise me.
Not bad. After 10 years Kabira
is released from the jail.
But l can't see any change here.
There's one change, Sir. You've
made impact after..
..going to the jail. You're
the talk of the town.
There's a benefit after
going to the jail.
Where is the queen nowadays?
She has gone for the foreign tour.
And my sweet daughter Tina?
She's studying very sincerely.
And we're taking her monthly
expense from queen.
l also have spent 10 years
in jail because of queen.
But there's one problem, sir.
- What?
Raxi has betrayed us.
You had given him..
..your house in his bad times.
He has captured it legally.
And he has made it a beer bar.
l offered everything
for the friendship.
Are you betraying your friend?
Now see this Kabira has come.
l don't know you.
ln this generation
people forgets..
..others obligation in few days.
Whereas this is a matter of 10
years before. lt's too old.
Such a long duration can
weaken a debtor's memory.
However let me remind
you about me.
This orphan took birth
in streets..
One kind Musalman found
me in a basket.
And l don't know why
he named me Kabir.
Kabira! brought up
at Muslim family.
Had friendship with Hindus..
..and speech was like Britishers.
But l'm not that Kabir. Who
is the real man and saint.
l'm Kabir 'Badshah'.
l'm grateful to God.
And devil for a wildly
person like you.
When l had given you my house.
You considered me your friend.
And today when l've come to
ask for my house back.
You've started taking
me as your enemy?
Kabir, you better go and ask
this question to the law.
Now Roxi owns this place.
Those who do not listen to the
saints repent for years..
Have the kicks from all the
paths he passes through..
Wow! Kabira! Wow!
- Kabira!
Are you trying to give me threats?
Do not talk.
Scared people give the
threat and challenges.
l'll come tomorrow morning at
6:30 to get back my house.
You better arrange for
yourself before that.
C'mon, right. C'mon, left.
He has clearly given us a threat.
Bikhu, you gather your men
and reach here before 6:30.
l'll ruin this Kabir otherwise
l won't call myself Roxi.
Police?
- That means Roxi..
..has taken help from the police.
Then why did he call us
in the early morning?
He might have got
scared of Kabira.
Police is coming towards
us. C'mon, Jaggu.
Did you see? This is this
uniform's miracle.
And Kabira is creating
a commotion there.
l'm very much punctual of time.
Do not develop enmity with me.
Now that Kabira has come,
you better save yourself.
Kabira!
Enough, Kabira! Stop it!
l'll send this bottles
to Roxi's house.
Don't beat him so much, Kabira.
He'll become a barren.
He's also from a swine's society.
Enough, sir!
- Sir, don't say so much stanza..
..that the sermon gets complete.
This bastard has a family.
- He has a family?
Who knows about this?
- We know.
l never knew. lf he has a family..
..then take him to the hospital.
Left and right, l hope
you didn't say..
..anything to Tina about me.
We only told that God
has made your uncle..
..Vasco-de-Gamma of lndia.
Whom government has sent around
the world for ten years.
l've forgot her face too.
Uncle! Uncle! Uncle!
- My daughter!
Uncle!
Uncle, you might have
forgotten my face..
..but l didn't forget you. l got
all your gifts time to time.
Everything. Also the money.
But l won't talk with you.
l didn't get a single
letter of yours.
My child, l was taking a trip
from one country to another.
lt was government's
responsibility.
Now l've come. And l've
told the principal..
..that now my daughter
will live with me.
With you?
- Yes. Till you get marry.
Uncle, now l've grown
up, haven't l?
Grown up? My daughter has
grown up more than you.
Gentleman, if you can
find a nice boy..
Because l'm very much tensed
about her marriage.
Thank you.
Uncle, what do you
have in your hand?
Nothing.. nothing, my child.
l know. You've got gifts
for me. Right?
No.. no..
- l know. Please show me. Please.
C'mon, let's complete the
formalities at office.
Yes, c'mon. - All girls of
my school have passed..
..all have grown up. But my
daughter is still unmarried.
ls he your uncle?
- Yes.
Show me what he has brought
for you from foreign?
Today uncle reminded
me of my father.
Tina, it seems your uncle
still considers you a baby.
Here's your gift.
Why are you laughing? Uncle
thought l'm still a small kid.
He considered you right.
Your brain department
is still very small.
No, now l've grown up.
You've grown up?
- Yes.
Let me see how much
you've grown up?
Girl is really beautiful.
Mister, send the girl here.
Help! Help! ls anybody over here?
Rascals!
l see.. so one more is still left?
Don't worry, sister. Kabira says..
Monty, what's this?
You stupid! ldiot!
What are you doing? He's
my uncle! Kabir uncle!
Kabir uncle!
- Not bad. - l'm very sorry, sir.
l didn't know.
- Shake hands, my friend. - Yes.
My child, you're still a student.
- Uncle!
Do not talk. You didn't
even understand that..
..you were not beating me.
l was getting beaten.
Fighter's association.
Your drama is over.
Now get lost.
Anyway, l liked your hero.
Only strength is not
enough for fight.
What's your name?
- Monty.
Occupation?
- l sing. - l also sing.
What's your occupation?
Uncle, he's a big
singer at Mumbai.
Do not talk. Everybody
is a singer.
What's the arrangement
for bread and butter?
Everything can be meet
with this singing.
God has given me everything.
- Not bad.
You also believe in God.
- Yes.
Do you love Tina?
Do you intend to marry her or
it's company of singing only?
No, l'm intending to make
her my life partner.
Left and right.
- Yes, sir.
The boy who protects the girl.
He has a permit for marriage.
Uncle! - Thank you very much,
sir. - No, sir. Call me Kabira.
What's your age?
- l'm around 21 to 22.
But this innocent boy
seems to be of just 1 7.
Even an old man becomes
young if fallen in love.
A girl seems to be Shirin and
boy seems to be Farhad.
You've passed in Kabira's test.
Now you can go and sing some
song. l mean duet song.
A couple song.
- C'mon, Monty. Let's go fast.
Left and right.
- Yes, sir.
You'll keep following them.
l mean.. - Censure.
What's your age?
- What's your age?
l'm 16 years.
- Then l'm 1 7 years.
16.
- 1 7. - 1 7? - 16?
We might not fall in love.
Keep away for a year or two.
Don't blame me if
anything happens.
l'm 16 years and you're of 1 7.
We might not fall in love.
lt's very difficult to keep away.
Don't blame me if
anything happens.
You're of 16 and l'm 1 7.
We might not fall in love.
-Keep away for a year or two.
Don't blame me if
anything happens.
What happens if the heavy clouds
collides with the mountains?
There'll be a rain.
What will happen..
..if your heart will
meet with mine?
There'll be a procession.
God knows when there'll
be rain..
..and when there'll
be a procession.
My heart wishes tonight to
be the night of our union.
Why? Why?
- Because..
You're of 16 and l'm 1 7.
We might not fall in love.
-Keep away for a year or two.
Don't blame me if
anything happens.
True lovers never
meet each other.
Now l'll see when we'd meet.
What's the hurdle in
our meeting now?
We have the same destination.
lt's at distance
and not so close.
Now it's not good for
us to meet frequently.
Why? Why?
- Because..
l'm 16 years and you're of 1 7.
We might not fall in love.
lt's very difficult
to keep away.
Don't blame me if
anything happens.
Keep away for a year or two.
Don't blame me if
anything happens.
l'm 16 years..
- l'm 1 7 years.
This love is not so easy.
Understand this.
lt's an ocean of fire..
..and you must drown
and pass through it.
l had told you to sing.
But l didn't tell you..
..to involve so much
that you get faint.
Now go to sleep. Everything
will be fine by the morning.
C'mon, Kabira.
Finished! Everything finished!
l'm old Robert. l'm
still as it is.
Everything has changed
in these 25 years.
Everything is finished.
Verma factory finished.
Now Surjuda factory.
He's Mumbai's businessman. He's
an owner of this factory.
Verma family was a great family.
But they are finished.
Their son Ravi Verma..
..was coming from Mumbai
after marriage.
He met a car accident on the
way and he's finished.
Mummy! Mummy! lt's me. Ravi!
Yes, Ravi from Mumbai.
Mummy, l'm Ravi.
- Ravi, how are you, my child?
l'm fine, mummy. We've
won the case.
Yes.. yes.. Surjuda tried to
bribe but nothing turned out.
Now that property and land
has transferred to my name.
God is always there
with the truth.
Give it to me, mummy.
l want to talk. - Here.
Hello! Congratulations,
brother. l'm Pinky.
Now you must bring many
imported dresses for me.
Yes, l remember the entire
list of your demands..
..Miss Jyoti Verma.
- Jyoti Verma?
Have you taken a peg?
- l'll slap you now.
Beer and l? - l'm getting it's
smell on the telephone.
Ok, take my swear that
you didn't take it?
lt's ok, if you're telling me to
swear then l've taken a bottle.
Go ahead.
- Look, mummy says liquor..
..can spoil the entire family.
Talk with her.
Mummy, it's a lie.. ok,
mummy. l'm sorry.
Now l'll never take it.
- You come home soon, my child.
l'm feeling very unusual.
Mummy!
- What?
Shall l tell you one secret?
l hope you won't get angry.
- Have you seen mother's..
..anger lasting for
more than a moment?
Mummy, l've got married.
With whom? That Kamini?
- Yes, mummy.
l had to take this decision
today itself.
Otherwise her brother and..
..uncle were sending
her to London.
Now when you're married,
what l can say in this?
Bring her home soon.
l'll arrange..
..your marriage with full pomp.
Mummy, l hope it didn't hurt you.
Parents happiness lies
in their children.
Oh mummy, you're great.
Mummy, you're great!
l love you.
- You come home soon, my child.
We're waiting for you.
l promise you, mummy.
l'll definitely come.
l'll come, mummy. l'll come.
l'll come. l'll definitely
come, mummy.
l'll come back soon.
Monty! You're so stupid! ldiot!
How come you left from
home without informing?
l've good news. Queen
has come back.
Tonight there's a party
in the palace.
And you're invited there
with me. For me.
No.. for us.
- Leave it to me, Tina.
No excuse. C'mon, we have
to go home early.
What's this, Tina?
- We have to go for a party.
And you must wear
a first class suit.
And Kabir uncle was saying that
l'll go with him first..
..and then you'll come.
C'mon, now sit inside. What are
you doing? You please drive it.
Do you know how big the party is?
Big personalities will
be coming there.
This strange incidence is
shaking me from inside, Dayal.
You please keep this with you only.
Otherwise people will just
laugh instead of believing it.
l've seen it personally. That same
city, same palace, same factory..
..where l used to live
in my last birth.
My last birth's name was Ravi Verma.
But the face was totally different.
l don't know anything
about my last birth's..
..mother, sister and
wife's whereabouts.
So l think l might have to
live here for few more days.
Tonight, l'm going to
meet Tina's queen..
..who has educated and provided
all her needs from her childhood.
l'll write you the rest of the
things later, yours Monty.
You stupid, you idiot,
can't you see?
l can see.. l can see..
But you can't see that l can.
Rebirth.. different face.
Rebirth.. Ravi Verma.
Monty! Monty!
l'm waiting for you from
last half an hour.
The party is at its peak inside.
So many big personalities have come.
Queen is also there.
l've told her everything about you.
Why are you standing here? C'mon..
Look, behave very innocently
with queen.
l know. Why are you instructing me?
Don't forget your limits. Shut up!
You must listen to me.
And listen,..
..if she'll request for
a song, do not refuse.
lf queen will be impressed,
everything will be fine.
Queen is not seen anywhere?
You just wait here. l'll just come.
Excuse me! Good evening, Queen.
He has come. l had told
you about him, didn't l?
Will you please meet him?
Please.. please..
Queen, he's that person.
Monty!
Hello!
Who lives in this palace, guard?
There is a queen who
has everything from..
..servants to wealth, but
there are lack of humans.
She leaves in the mornings and..
..comes back in the evenings.
l don't know sir where
she comes from..
..or where she goes.
But they say that you
should never try..
..to know too much about the rich.
What shall l do? l am
just an employee.
l do my work, take my
salary and go away.
No discussion. Just
coming and going.
Ravi Verma died in a car accident.
This news was given
by Kamani Devi.
But within 1 year she
threw both the..
..helpless women from the house.
That time Kamani Devi
had become the owner..
..of the palace and the factory.
What could l have said?
l was just a servant.
One day her plan succeeded.
Why don't you just ask
me to commit suicide?
By mixing poison in my food,
you want to kill me.
Why are you after my life?
What a shameful thing
to say, bhabhi?
You are putting such blame on me.
Will l try to kill my brother's
wife? - Shut up!
lt was good that l
fed the cat first.
Otherwise my sister would
have been lying dead.
Today a decision will be reached.
l will call the police and
if l don't put these..
..two women behind bars, then..
..my name is not Charanjeet.
They are jealous of my sister's
fame and fortune.
Today, police will come
into this house.
No police has ever come
to the household of..
..Shanta Prasad Verma, and
nor will they ever come.
Daughter-in-law, our tears
from my son's death..
..hasn't dried yet.
And before the Verma family
is disgraced in society..
..we will go to some place
else and shed our tears.
Come on, daughter.
Such times have come when we
have to leave the house..
..built by my husband and son.
Daughter-in-law, the house
is yours. Take care of it.
We are going far-far away.
Where the mother and daughter
went, no one knows.
Sir, that day even l quit the job.
lf someone says that
they are dead..
..then l won't be surprised.
What is it?
- The big car has come.
Okay, l know. You go away
from here. - Yes.
What happened, Trilokchand?
What happened? Speak up?
Old horse, red reins.
- Oh, God!
Beautiful shot!
Let's move ahead.
l am saying the truth, S.P sir.
5 years ago our neighbor Mr.
Mathur crossed the..
..railway line and went into
the forest of Champapur.
And hasn't returned till today.
People thought that maybe
some tiger ate him up.
But the villagers say that Mr.
Mathur is seen walking about..
..along the railway line.
And when anyone goes near
him, he disappears.
Despite being the magistrate
of this town..
..you believe in these
ghost stories.
l am sorry! l don't believe
in ghost stories.
How can a person come back after
dying? lt's not possible.
My daughter says the same thing,
but for God's sake..
..don't talk such stuff,
otherwise l will get nightmares.
Very nice party.
- l am glad you could come.
May l help you, madam?
- Oh yes! Thank you.
Yes, Mr. Monty lives in
this very guest house.
But these days, he leaves
very early in the morning.
And comes back late at night.
Who are you?
- l am Chanda. The maid-servant.
Saw uncle, how he has become?
Since he saw that queen, he
does not care about me.
l have heard that everyday he
makes a trip to the palace.
Palace?
What do you want?
What do you want? l said
what do you want?
Who allowed you to come in?
Jorjee! Jorjee! Mangara!
Go away from here. l said
go away from here.
Get out of here.
You! - Shut up! Do you know
whom you are speaking to?
Kabira, take him away!
Take him away!
Come on, let's go!
- No.
Come one, let's go home.
- No, l want her.
l want her, Kabira!
- Monty, lets go home.
l want her, Kabira! l want
her her. Monty let's go!
Leave me! l want to talk to her.
l want to ask her questions.
Let us go!
You looking at the
queen like that..
..is showing disloyalty
towards Tina..
l am not disloyal to Tina!
l am worried by the disloyalty
shown to me.
lf you don't want to tell
your story, then don't say.
But if you want to
know the truth..
..about the Queen, then
ask me, who has spent..
..10 years in the lock
up because of her.
What do you know?
10 years ago, my childhood
friend and..
..Tina's father, Ramcharan,
was an old..
..servant at the palace.
But because of his drinking
habits he could not give..
..love to the motherless Tina.
Tina always used to search
for her Kabira uncle.
lt was a Friday night.
When l reached Ramcharan's
quarter, l saw Tina crying.
Ramcharan was drunk.
That day there was a quarrel
between Ramcharan..
..and me regarding Tina.
Neither did he allow me
to take Tina home..
..nor did he look after properly.
ln his drunken state
he abused me and..
..his destiny and left the house.
l started consoling the poor girl.
When he went out, Ramcharan
heard the queen..
..and his brother Charanjeet..
..who was being scolded
by a few strangers.
God knows what secrets he heard..
..that he came back to his senses.
The queen's brother saw
him and followed him.
The person who knows the
secrets of the queen..
..cannot live in this
world, Ramcharan.
Kabira!
Ramcharan, what secret
was he talking about?
Ravi Verma, Kali Temple
and the Queen!
Saying these few words,
my friend passed away.
But big people have big nets.
God knows how the police
came there suddenly.
l accepted my crime in
front of the police.
That's when Tina came
crying in front of me.
l picked her up in my lap
and took her to the Queen.
Your highness, this
is orphaned child..
..of your faithful servant.
Now, her burden is on you, like
one burden is on my heart.
Before dying Ramcharan spoke
about the secret of..
..Kali temple.. l will leave, now.
The very next day the Queen
came to meet me in prison.
She was very worried.
What secret do you know?
Such secrets are not
spoken behind bars.
Only in the courts
are such secrets..
l asked you what secret
do you know?
What is the relationship
between the..
..Kali Temple and Ravi
Verma? This secret.
What is the price to
forget this secret?
My daughter Tina should have the..
..upbringing of the highest class.
l will perform my responsibility
loyally. l promise.
Kabira is the second name
for loyalty, madam.
This deal was finalized
between the two of us.
But for 10 years l kept thinking..
..of the relationship
between Ravi Verma..
..and the Kali temple.
l will tell you, Kabira.
l will tell you what is the
relationship between..
..Ravi Verma and the Kali temple.
You?
- Yes me!
This story is beyond the
beliefs of the world.
But it has passed over me
as a reality. - Over you?
Yes, Kabira! Just think.
A boy loves a girl. He breaks
all norms and marries her.
And days after their wedding,
the girl kills the boy..
..just for the sake of his wealth.
And thanks to nature's miracle,
that heart takes birth again.
And 21 years later sees that the..
..same girl has become a queen.
The life of Verma High
School is my life.
On the occasion of my husband's..
..birth anniversary, here
is a cheque of 50,000.
Verma Convent School belongs
to the Verma family.
lt belongs to Shanta Prasad
Verma. To Ravi Verma.
l want to know where
is the Verma family?
Where is this Ravi Verma's
sister? Where is his mother?
No one knows anything, Kabira.
No one knows anything.
Oh God! You are that Ravi Verma?
- lt is the truth, Kabira!
This has happened with me.
The mountain is on my shoulders.
l am no mad person to
tell you these stories.
l have gone mad, Monty.
l can't even think where
that woman must have..
..kept your mother and sister.
l have gone mad searching
for the day and night.
No one knows anything
and can't say anything.
Don't worry! l know a few
elders of this village.
God willing, l will
find both of them.
After Shanta Prasad,
people will have..
..only one name on their
lips, Ravi Verma.
He will clear the debts
of the Verma family.
He will bring back the fame
and fortune of the family.
My son, then you shall see the
glow on this widow's face.
l shall start 2 more schools
in his name. - Mother!
Pinky? - Don't call me Pinky,
my name is Jyoti Verma!
And l have won this award for
excellence in sitar playing.
And not for tuning some guitar.
First in sitar and
zero in studies.
Here, first in studies and as
far as guitar is concerned..
..one day l will learn
that as well.
You have broken 12 guitars
in the span of one year.
And still you don't even know
how to play seven notes.
Pinky!
- What Pinky?
You have to take rebirth to
know how to play the guitar.
l searched the whole world.
l found the whole world.
But l did not find the ones
l was searching for.
No one knows where the mother
and her daughter..
..disappeared years ago.
l know. The snake which
can bite Ravi Verma.
lt is not difficult for her to
kill two helpless women, Kabira.
Monty, even snakes are afraid
of the wrath of the Lord.
Not this snake, Kabira!
Not this snake!
lf this fact is true then l swear
on my mother and sister..
..l will not let her live
for more than a day.
lf l will be hanged then
l will accept that.
l am ready to die a thousand
deaths to take revenge.
To kill that Kamini.
Oh God, what have you
done to this young man?
Give him peace or l will
fight against you.
Kabira sits at your doorsteps
asking you to fulfill all wishes.
Let them meet. Let them meet.
Chanda!
- Chanda has not come today, sir.
l have come to replace her.
Bring one jug of water.
Tea is ready, sir. - Now, l will
not drink tea but only alcohol.
lt is not good to drink
alcohol in the morning.
Stop talking nonsense
and get the water.
Wise men have said
that a household..
..gets spoiled with alcohol, sir.
You?
- My name is Laxmi.
l work as a servant in
a bungalow at Talegaon.
Chanda is not well.
So she sent me here.
Laxmi? No.
lf l have made a mistake
then forgive me, sir.
But it is not good to drink
alcohol at such young age.
Your name cannot be Laxmi.
Yes, my name is Laxmi.
l live at Talegaon.
You are lying. l know you.
Your name is Jyoti.
No! No, l am not Jyoti!
l am Laxmi.
You are lying. You are
Jyoti, Jyoti Verma.
Please don't say this, sir.
Don't mock my poverty.
Why don't you say that you are..
..the daughter of Shanta
Prasad Verma?
Shanta Prasad is dead.
Verma family is dead.
l have no relation with them.
l am a beggar woman. l clean
up other people's houses.
l am a widow who goes from
door to door for work.
To feed the stomachs
of my old mother..
..and my 2 children.
What do you want from me?
Why are you mocking me?
Why do you make fun of me? Why?
Pinky!
- Did you call me Pinky, sir?
Yes, Pinky!
You did not recognize me but
l recognized you, my sister.
Sister! Did you call me, sister?
- Yes, Pinky!
Aren't you the sister
of Ravi Verma..
..who used to call you
Pinky out of love?
Ravi Verma? How do you
know Ravi Verma?
Did you see?
Such a violent storm came
and now it is silent.
Today, atheists like me will
start believing in God.
l did not understand?
- l am Ravi Verma..
l am Ravi Verma's..
No, my father was a
friend of Ravi Verma.
l have come from Bombay.
Brother used to keep
going to Bombay.
Your family portrait
is at my house.
My daddy had told me to find
out about the Verma..
..family whenever l come here.
He too searched a lot but
he did not get any news.
We have died for the world, sir.
After brother's death life
only gave us darkness.
l and my mother are alive
like two corpses.
Your mother? How is mother?
Where is she?
l want to meet her immediately,
please.
What is the use of meeting
mother, sir?
She is a blown out candle..
..who thinks that one day
there shall be light.
She's gone crazy.
lt's been 21 years since
brother's death.
Since that day she hasn't
been able to speak or hear.
During this poverty,
l got married.
But within 3 years, my
husband passed away..
..leaving on us the
burden of 2 children.
And the burden of troubles
kept on increasing.
Give it to me! l will
wash my clothes myself.
Shut up, you are small now!
Grandma, if Aseem washes
my clothes without soap..
..so won't they tear off?
Who will bring soap? Your uncle?
Grandma, Aseem is teasing me.
Why are you troubling grandma?
Can she hear?
Let mother come! l will
tell her everything.
Just wash the clothes.
Don't trouble grandma.
We have no status to
go to the doctor.
We have tried all types
of herbal medicines.
Mother probably does not
even know what sleep is?
She keeps looking at Ravi's
picture for hours.
Ravi has come! Ravi has come!
You have come, son!
- Grandma! Mother!
Mother, grandma has started
speaking. - The sage.
Ravi you have come. Come!
You must be very tired.
Pinky, Ravi has come!
Ravi has come.
l knew you would come late,
but would definitely come.
Why aren't you saying anything?
Ravi! The apple of my eye!
Aren't you my Ravi?
Why don't you say anything?
My son, Ravi.
Mother! - Madam, sit down.
This is not your son.
He is a big shot from Bombay.
Shut up! Don't speak nonsense.
This is my son Ravi.
- Mother, sit down.
You are not well.
Come and sit down.
This is my son Ravi!
Ask a mother's heart?
He can cheat everyone, but
not a mother's heart.
Mother, this is not your son.
Don't separate me from my son.
God, if you exist come down,
look into my eyes..
..and say whether this
is my son Ravi or not?
Mother, please sit down.
Please leave her alone.
Sorry sir, but she has received
a mental shock.
Didn't l tell you to leave
her alone? - Let's go.
Sir, will handle everything.
Mother! - Aren't you my brother,
Ravi? - Yes, mother.
Yes! l am Ravi!
Nobody recognized me,
but you did instantly.
Saw, my son recognized me.
He recognized his mother.
Mother, now l have come. You
will listen to me? - Yes!
Take rest for some time, mother.
Yes, l will take rest. Now that
you have come, l will sleep.
Mother, who is this uncle?
l am your uncle. From now on you
will live with your uncle.
My messiah heals the wounds.
He Himself inflicted.
Pinky, go to your brother's house.
Days of sadness are gone,
happy days are here again.
Wait and see the games
Kabira plays.
Monty!
- Move away, Kabira!
What are you doing?
- l will finish her off.
Law may not punish her, but l
will. - And law will finish you.
Because law and police have
no evidence or witness..
..to prove that Ravi Verma
was killed by Kamini devi.
Yes, there is one witness.
The Lord.
Maybe that's why he
has sent you here..
..so that you force her into
accepting her crime..
..in front of the
world and the law.
Yes, Monty. We have
to make her suffer.
On every step we have
to place a trap.
What happened, Charan Singh?
What is in your hand?
Somebody just came and said
this was your birthday gift.
Birthday?
But no one here knows that
today is my birthday.
Let me see!
Stupid!
What happened?
Your car has given up, madam.
You? What are you doing here?
Get the hell out of my car.
Come on, get out! Out!
Why are you after me?
l want to know.
Who gave you this car? Who
let you become a driver?
Driver? Your highness,
l am not poor.
But yes l am weak at heart.
You must have got my gift.
Be thankful l did not
inform the police.
Police, law, l will
accept everything.
Even if you send me to heaven,
l will comeback.
Shut up!
- l want to remain quiet.
But what can l say l have
to clear my heart.
That l fell in love with
you, at first sight.
Nonsense! Get lost will you?
- Okay!
lt is not good for a
lady to stay alone..
..out in the wilderness,
Miss Kamini.
Think about it?
Excuse me!
- My name is Monty.
See, your car has broken down.
There is a garage in the
village down there.
And cars are repaired
only in garages.
lt's amazing, it's amazing,
it's amazing.
We fakirs know the condition
of everyone's heart.
lt's amazing, it's amazing.
lt's amazing, it's amazing,
it's amazing.
We fakirs know the condition
of everyone's heart.
lt's amazing, it's amazing.
Oh Fakir check me up..
..give me medicines
for the sweet pains.
Oh Fakir check me up..
..give me medicines
for the sweet pains.
l will chase the ghosts away
and kill the illness.
But what do l do with this,
this is love sickness.
lt's amazing, it's amazing.
lt's amazing, it's amazing,
it's amazing.
Oh good man of God,
come answer me.
How many stars are there in
the sky, give me an answer?
Count all the flowers
in the world.
The number of flowers are equal
to the number of stars.
That is my answer.
lt's amazing, it's amazing.
lt's amazing, it's amazing,
it's amazing.
Young girl, you also
ask some question.
Clear your heart's doubts.
l will tell you, fakir.
On her lips many love
stories are there.
Again youth his coming back
to her love stories.
JAWANlYA ! JAWANlYA !
You are too immature,
use your brains.
He who is in your heart,
hold his hand.
You have knitted this net
with your own hands.
lt's amazing, it's amazing,
it's amazing.
We fakirs know the condition
of everyone's heart.
lt's amazing, it's amazing.
lt's amazing, it's amazing,
it's amazing.
Mithu, now nobody can say that
the queen is getting old.
Mithu, l am so happy tonight.
Good night, sweet dreams.
No!
No, Monty!
Oh, no!
Please no.
Monty, he is dead!
Anyone who is trying to harm you..
..will get the same fate
from Monty. - But why?
lt is not what you think.
l don't want your riches.
l want you and your love.
Someone to tell me she is mine.
Well done, Jagawar! Amazing role.
Here is your 400 rupees
and your role is done.
Ravi! Ravi! Still he
hasn't come back.
lt is so late at night and
still hasn't comeback.
Yes, he is coming in a jeep,
with his wife.
But, why hasn't he come yet?
l will go and check myself.
Ravi! Ravi!
Stop, don't go ahead. Stop!
Brother, see what has
happened to mother.
There is nothing to worry about.
Thank God she is safe.
She is lucky.
Where all will you search for me?
How many more times will
you be hit? l have come.
l will take away all your sorrows.
Keep all the promises.
Just look at me once.
Open your eyes.
- Ravi, you have come.
See mother, l am in front of you.
Let's go home. Take me home.
Yes, mother lie down now.
l will take you home.
l will take you to the same
house, where l had left you.
Stop it!
Where did you learn this tune?
This tune? lt's very old!
- There is a story behind it.
Whose?
- My husband's! Ravi Verma's!
Ravi Verma? - Yes! He liked
this tune very much.
Monty, please. With this tune..
- You feel something? - Yes!
Okay, l will not play
in the future.
What are you seeing?
- Your destiny in your hands.
What is written on it?
- Amazing!
Someone's murder is written on it.
Murder! Don't be silly, Monty!
You have murdered me.
- You?
By making me fall for your..
Now l know why Monty did
not get my telegrams.
lf you have understood,
Mr. Oberoi..
..then there is no use in arguing.
So have you decided to leave me?
- Yes!
Oberoi for you it will mean,
fame and fortune.
Those only last for 2 seconds,
Mr. Oberoi.
l will sue you.
- With pleasure. - l am leaving.
l won't stop you. Goodbye.
Who was he?
He was the guardian of my destiny.
What will happen now?
He doesn't know that my destiny
is in this palace.
But Monty, l feel claustrophobic
in here.
Let's go out somewhere.
What happened?
- Your car has given up.
1 minute.
My mother in Bombay does not
allow me to drive at night.
lf l am ever late, she wakes
up the whole town.
She calls up everyone from
the police, hospital..
There is no water in the radiator.
But you don't worry. There
is a container here.
l will get the water. l love you.
ln the name of the Goddess Kali..
..may your attack never
miss it's target.
Let justice be done for all lives.
lt's getting colder. So l
was talking about mother.
Why are you sweating
in this cold weather?
Monty!
- What's wrong you seem worried?
Ghost!
- Ghost? What ghost?
l saw ghosts.
Looks like you are listening
to too many ghost stories.
That is why you are hallucinating.
Don't worry darling,
l am with you.
Monty, look over there. Ghosts
are going in that car.
Ghosts? Where?
What happened to you?
l didn't see any car or any ghost.
There! - What's wrong with you?
Have gone nuts? There is
nothing over there.
You didn't see anything.
- There is nothing there.
Monty, what has happened to me?
You need rest.
Your Highness, it isn't
safe for you..
..to have so many medicines.
The doctor has already
cautioned you.
Monty, cannot come for the
opening of your hotel.
l am not responsible for this.
lf you want to see the truth,
you can see it for yourself.
How my golden bird is trapped
in your palace's cage?
These are your Kamani
Devi's doings.
Yes, sir?
See Rita, l had told you.
He is having an affair
with that woman.
See how much fun they are having.
l can't even see.
You tell me what is happening?
He has opened the door
of the car. - Then?
She has got down.
- Then?
She is going inside.
She has stopped.
- Then.
They are laughing and talking.
Monty is going nearer to her.
- Then.
Now they are behind the pillar.
- What?
l can't see anything, Tina.
l think some thing is wrong.
You haven't told me anything
about your life and husband.
Although you had promised me.
l will tell you. But not now.
- Why?
First, let me trust
you completely.
Lovers don't ask for trust
certificate, Kamini.
Monty, l know we have come
close to each other..
You betrayer! You fool!
You make promises to
me, and love her.
You sing songs with me.
l hate you. l hate you!
Stop it, Tina! Stop it, Tina!
What is this childishness, Tina!
l'll run away! l'll die!
Let her go, Monty! This
was bound to happen.
You saw what she did?
lf l had married her, then my..
..life would have been destroyed.
l know, l know!
This is the difference between
a girl and a woman.
Monty, Monty!
- What happened?
Tina is leaving this town.
- What are you saying?
She has left this letter.
She has left home.
Kabira is searching
for her every where.
'l can't stand this shock,
Kabira uncle.'
'Don't try and look for me.
Think that Tina is dead.'
Shameless girl! Juliet's niece!
Tried to kill herself for love.
You don't know, he was talking
shameless talk..
..with the queen.
Shut up! l am no fool!
As if he is worried, and you
are increasing his worries.
What is he worried about?
For you, who else.
Thousands of rupees of mine
are stuck with her.
Don't we need money for yours
and Monty's wedding?
My wedding?
Marriage? lt's taking place?
Good! Very good!
Even l have a daughter.
Exactly like Tina.
We have called you to perform
for the charity function..
..organized on the
occasion of the..
..silver jubilee of
Verma High School.
l believe that if you participate
in this then..
..we can collect thousands
of rupees for the school.
lt is my fortune that l can do
something for Tina's school.
lt is so nice of you!
- Very good!
You are a very good boy.
lf you know any boy exactly
like you, then do say.
l have a young daughter.
We have come here for the school..
..board meeting, Mr. Baptista.
You please come, sing and dance.
Teach our girls also. Our
girls are very talented.
Even l have a girl.
Mrs. Kamini Devi will be the
chief guest on the occasion.
And that is when she
will inaugurate..
..the Ravi Verma Memorial
hall as well.
Ravi Verma Memorial Hall.
l will be there.
l will definitely come.
Hello! Hello! Yes this is Mrs.
Kamini Verma. Hello!
This is Ravi Verma!
- Ravi Verma? Who Ravi Verma?
Your husband, Ravi Verma.
What nonsense? Who is speaking?
lf not through the looks,
recognize the voice, darling.
l am Monty. - Monty? - Yes! What
kind of a joke is this?
What if we have different faces?
Actually l am Ravi Verma,
darling, not Monty.
What nonsense?
l have no proof, Kamini, with
which l can tell the law..
..and society that
you murdered me.
Murder?
Yes you murdered me when
l was Ravi Verma.
ln front of the Kali Temple
with a jeep.. - Shut up!
What has happened to you? Oh no?
Who is this?
- This is Monty, darling.
Who is this? Hello!
- Your father is speaking.
Hello!
Monty, did you just call me?
Me? How could l have? l am here.
Don't kill yourself like this.
Monty, one day l will
go mad. l will go mad.
You have already become mad,
Kamini devi. - You?
Yes, me. Servants of Sir Tudor.
What do the servants want to say?
Sir Tudor has called you.
- For what?
He has come to know
of your actions.
This is private life,
do you understand?
Sir Tudor's servants
have no private life.
Get out of here! Get out!
- Okay, let's go.
Monty, l don't want this wealth.
l'm fed up of my life.
Please, take me some place else.
l don't want to live
in this palace.
l will take you, day
after tomorrow.
To Bombay, to my home.
Why not today? Why not now?
l have promised to sing
at the function..
..of Verma High School.
Let Verma High School
go down the drain.
For so many years you have lived..
..like a queen in this palace.
Everything should be done
in it's proper time..
..and with proper respect.
l have called my mother and
sister to the same function.
Mother will be so happy to
see your status in society.
When you meet my wife
in Verma High School..
..as a respectable
daughter-in-law. - Really?
The reality is this that
my mother is fine now.
She only has to drink the
milk with her medicines.
There, again you have
dropped milk.
Pinky, when he was small, he
used to drop milk like this.
l never scolded him, but
he is scolding me today.
Where am l scolding?
l just want my mother to get
well soon so that l can..
..take my lovable mother to the
Verma High School function.
Verma High School?
- Yes mother, Verma High School.
Our school.
After sometime, we will
go to that hall and..
..you shall inaugurate the hall.
People will applaud and envy
the pride and status..
..of Mrs. Shanta Prasad Verma.
God bless you, son! After that
we will go to our palace.
Yes, mother! We will
go to our house.
Saw how much my son loves me?
And for such a long time you
kept that love away from me.
Now he has come back, so why..
..are these eyes shedding tears?
Yes, probably they want
to wash your feet.
His name is Monty, sir!
Sir, this is not what
we were thinking?
lt is to do with Ravi
Verma's property.
Okay, sir!
Romeo-Juliet, Laila-Majnu,
Shiri-Farhad.
Their true love is still
remembered by the world.
l have thought of a name,
which disrespected..
..love by cheating her own love.
This is the story of love.
Some one took life, and
some one gave life.
There was a beauty,
there was a lover.
That was the age and
those were the times.
There was a beauty,
there was a lover.
That was the age and
those were the times.
One day they met, they
kept on meeting daily.
Then their love blossomed, and..
..everything was destroyed.
Where are you lost, on
listening this story?
People are confused, because
they are strangers.
To the alley of love, we
were just talking about.
l kept visiting that alley,
There was a beauty,
there was a lover.
That was the age, those
were the times.
There was a beauty,
there was a lover.
The beauty said, listen
to me beloved.
This sky and this earth
are nothing without you.
l will die for you, that
is how much l love you.
The matter was something
else, she was a thief,
ln her heart lay the
love for wealth.
Love at that time was
just an excuse.
There was a beauty,
there was a lover.
That was the age, those
were the times.
There was a beauty,
there was a lover.
Disloyal lover cheated
on her love.
She cheated her love and
gave poison to him.
The youth died.
And now listen to the story.
He took birth far away.
Again he reached there.
With the face of a stranger
and mind being confused.
When they confronted.
The same things happened again.
This was his debt.
He had to repay his debt.
Who are you?
Who are you? l asked who you are.
You are not Monty.
lt is not true. lt is a lie.
You cannot be Ravi Verma.
You recognized me perfectly,
Your Highness.
Look at me properly.
l am Ravi Verma.
Daughter-in-law of Shanta Prasad..
The Queen of this town and..
..servant of Sir Tudor, see.
Look at this miracle of nature.
l might not have the
face of Ravi Verma..
..but the soul remains the same.
The same Ravi Verma
who was squashed..
..under the tyres of a jeep
in front of the Kali Temple.
The same Ravi Verma who
gave you love for love.
The same Ravi Verma who gave you..
..fame, fortune and everything,
but you?
What did you do?
You only disrespected
the female gender.
But today your reign ends.
This palace is not yours,
Kamini Devi.
lt belongs to Shanta Prasad.
lt belongs to his son Ravi Verma.
lt belongs to his old mother,
who is coming into..
..this house after ages,
to take rest.
Ravi we have come to our house.
This house belongs to
Ravi Verma's sister..
..who spent her youth trying
to keep her old mother..
..and her two children
from starving.
She is coming to her brother's
house to ask for her rights.
Kamini devi, this house belongs
to the Verma family.
Those members of the
Verma family..
..who didn't get anything
except darkness.
Today they are coming into
their house, their palace..
..to step into new light.
Do you have any proof
which denies..
..that you did not
kill Ravi Verma?
Do you have any proof
which denies..
..that you did not throw out
his sister and old mother..
..from this palace and
forced them to..
..clean the houses
of other people.
Say that you had killed
Ravi Verma. Say it.
Remember, Kali Temple, Ravi
Verma! You killed him.
Say that you killed him!
Yes, yes, yes! l killed Ravi
Verma! l murdered him!
What do you want to say?
l killed him! l killed him!
Ravi Verma, he cannot be alive.
He cannot be alive.
Kabira!
Saw it S.P sir, she has
accepted her crime.
Your Highness, there is
no sound in God's stick.
But when it hits you,
it hurts badly.
Kabir uncle!
Kabir uncle, this pistol
is real. lt has bullets.
So now l get it that how
foreigners came into our lands.
Roxy, l had told you earlier
that it has been my..
..hobby to be friends
with all the people..
..be it Muslims, Hindus
or foreigners.
But as an lndian l won't let
foreigners rule over here.
Understand?
Sir Tudor says that you have
to hand over Kamini to us.
Tell you mute boss, that a
person whose tongue is..
..cut, he shouldn't stick it out.
l will sacrifice my daughter
but.. - No, Kabira!
lt would be foolishness to
sacrifice Tina for this vamp.
Judah, we will hand over Kamini
if you hand over Tina.
We agree.
Kamini, will walk one
step from there..
..and Tina will walk
one step from here.
But if there is any movement,
the bullets will be fired.
Roxy, leave Tina!
You vamp!
Sir Tudor, your game is over.
Shoes from Kanpur are having fun.
You will have more fun
in getting beaten up.
You witch, you vamp!
Brother! Brother!
Mother!
Open the door! Open the door!
Light the fire.
Open the door!
Kabira!
- Don't worry about me.
Mother and Pinky have gone
out. Go and save them!
But l can't leave you in such
a condition.. - Go, go!
Ravi!
Uncle! Mother and grandma
are locked in that house.
Look after the kids.
Mother! Pinky!
Mother! Mother! Mother!
No!
Kabira!
- Sit down! Sit down!
Brother, see she is running away!
You look after mother.
Hello!
Sir, looks like the
woman has gone mad.
God bless you! Come back soon!
- Yes, mother!
This time do not disappoint me.
No, mother! l will come!
Hurry up, Monty! We have
to go to Kashmir.
We have to see honeymoon.
l have heard that honeymoon
over there is a lot of fun.
What are you saying?
Let's go, dear. l will drop
you off at the station.
Stay away for a year or two.
lf something happens,
then don't complain.
l am sixteen years old, l
am seventeen years old.