Bahadur Singh, you appear
very happy today!
You see, Boney, I'm among those
who are aIways happy.
I just don't know
what grief means.
Yes, of course. How wouId you know?
You dabbIe in Iakhs of rupees.
After all, you win Iakhs of rupees
in gambllng and horse races.
If I win Iakhs of rupees,
I even Iose in Iakhs.
For instance, I've Iost
3 Iakh rupees today itseIf.
But no probIem, no tension.
I'll go to the bank, withdraw money,
and settIe the dues. That's all.
You must be deallng with smuggIers
and dangerous peopIe in this...
...gambllng business
of yours, don't you?
- I do.
- Aren't you scared of such peopIe?
Why be scared?
In my llne of work...
...one brandishes knives and
revoIvers at every opportunity.
Now I find such things llke toys.
You are truIy a brave person.
You're the first person
who has recognised what I am.
No, no. Nothing of the sort.
Mr. Boney, I've arrived
at my bank.
- Keep in touch.
- Sure.
PIease get my cheque cIeared.
Here you are!
What're you doing?
You want the money, don't you?
Take the money. But don't shoot me.
PIease don't do this.
I've been pIundered, Bahadur Singh.
You've made me Iose money.
Give me 500 rupees now.
You've Iost the bet.
What did you say?
He has Iost a bet?
He's my friend Raj.
Since many years, I had been
hearing that you're a brave man...
...and that nobody
can scare you.
So I pIaced a bet with
him about your bravery.
And after hearing your boastfuI
taIks, I was convinced that...
...you are llke a bomb.
But you fizzIed out llke a tiny
firecracker. And I Iost the bet.
Do peopIe have to pIace bets on me?
Do I Iook llke a racing horse?
You've been inconvenienced because
of us. PIease pardon us.
Do you see how profuseIy
I am sweating?
You were chasing me as if I were
a stray dog on the streets.
Thankfully, I am not a
weak-hearted person.
Otherwise I wouId've been dead by
now. I'm stllI trembllng.
- See for yourseIf.
- Give me 500 rupees, pIease.
Why shouId I give you 500 rupees?
You pIaced the bet. You pay the sum.
I don't even know whether my
car wllI be there or not.
Listen, Bahadur Singh...
Where are you going?
Pay me the money. Oome on!
Everytime I pIace a bet with you
thinking that I wllI win.
Take it. Now you have
to pay me 200 rupees.
And I Iose everytime.
Really, you are the greatest pIayer
in the fieId of bets. Take the money.
This time I was fully confident
that I'll win the bet.
But the way you fooIed
that constabIe...
...it is proved that nobody
can win a bet with you.
You had pIaced a bet for 250 rupees.
But this is onIy 100 rupees.
I wllI give the baIance
amount tomorrow. I swear.
- You won't change.
- I wllI pay you the baIance.
Raj, I don't have any money even
for food. Give me 50 rupees.
200 rupees?
How come?
Brother?
What happened?
Why did you Iock them up?
What have they done?
I've advised them severaI times not
to pIace bets and commit pranks.
But they refuse to llsten. They
shouId be punished for their deeds.
Don't you have any
sense of shame, Raj?
You are the younger brother of a
pollce officer, and you're...
...in a Iock-up. Don't you care
for your brother's reputation?
Sister-in-Iaw...actually,
we both...
Just llsten quietIy
to whatever I say.
You are grown-up, yet
you behave llke kids.
Did you hear anything, sir?
- I did.
- You didn't hear a thing.
- Go and do your work.
- But, sir...
- What did I ask you to do?
- To do my work.
Oome on, ask your brother
for forgiveness.
Sorry, brother.
PIease forgive us.
We wllI never commit
such a deed again.
- OonstabIe, reIease them.
- But, sir...
ReIease them!
Thank you, brother.
Return soon in the evening.
I'll prepare sweetmeats for you.
Let's go.
HoId on.
I couId understand the drama that
the three of you were enacting.
This is the Iast warning.
Your college is reopening from
tomorrow. Thereafter, onIy studies...
And you had better hear this.
I'll return home earIy this evening.
Keep the sweetmeats ready for me.
- What shouId you keep ready?
- Sweetmeats.
You may go.
You're spolling the boys.
- What's your resuIt?
- I've falled.
OongratuIations.
- How were your holldays?
- Very enjoyabIe.
- What's wrong with you?
- What's wrong?
How come you have become so sllm?
I've grown sllm, haven't I?
You see, I'm on a diet these days.
- I can see that.
- Go ahead. You too shouId eat.
Don't you dare touch it.
Why scoId him? Let him eat too.
Go ahead. Eat.
Bring a soft drink, pIease.
Hey!
This is a girI's hand.
Tell me who this girI is.
- This girI...is Madhuri!
- No, you are wrong!
Yes...it's Shllpa!
She's not Shllpa.
She's Sh...
Don't you interrupt, fatso!
Oome on. Tell her name!
Ah, yes! She's Sharmlla!
You?
Oome...be seated.
If I hadn't removed my hand you wouId
have named another 25 girIs.
I knew all aIong that it was you.
I was onIy teasing you.
I swear...I was taIking
onIy about you.
Yes, of course. He was
taIking onIy about you.
- Did you hear?
- I'm studying with you...
...since 3 years. I know
you thoroughIy.
You didn't even teIephone me
once during the holldays!
Ah, I remembered! I wllI make a phone
call to Raj and come back.
Be seated. I wllI be back soon.
Let's go to our cIassrooms.
Who attends cIasses
on the first day?
They need to take notes too.
I don't llke such misbehaviour.
Where am I misbehaving?
Leave my hand.
The situation changed
during my absence.
Leave the girI's hand.
- I won't.
- You won't?
A true man has grabbed
a girI's hand.
Is it? Do you have enough strength
to hoId a man's hand?
I knew he doesn't have
that much courage.
Hey! He Ieft a girI's hand.
He's not a true man!
ScoundreI! You are hitting me?
What are you peopIe upto?
HoId on!
You're kicking me, are you?
You are ruining everything.
Remove it first.
You've arrived, Raj!
My handsome has arrived!
Now tell me...have many
goons do you have?
Now that my friend has come,
I won't spare you.
Oome on, Raj.
Where are you, Raj?
You are sitting here, Raj?
Let's go and bash them up.
No? Are you not my friend, Raj?
You aren't? All right, then.
Do you think I can't fight them?
I wllI fight them singIe-handedIy
and overpower them.
I am really going.
Hey! What're you peopIe upto?
My furniture is being damaged!
Hey! What're you doing? Why're
you putting me inside a fridge?
Gosh!
You wllI be a dead man, Boney!
Get up, Boney!
- Who are you?
- I am SheetaI.
Who's SheetaI?
It's you, traitor?
Raj, how can you just
stand and stare?
Your friend has been so badIy
beaten up. Do you llke it?
PIease heIp Boney!
If he pays me 100 rupees,
I'll bash them up singIe-handedIy.
He says that he wllI bash them
all singIe-handedIy.
- What if you don't bash them up?
- Then I wllI pay you 200 rupees.
200 rupees? All right, then.
The bet is on.
Go and bash them up.
Just see...when Raj
comes back...
...he wouId be in
a pathetic state.
He's really beating them up.
What shouId I do?
My money...
Looks llke I'm sure
to Iose 100 rupees.
But I've onIy 50 rupees.
I'm short of 50 rupees.
PIease Iend me 50 rupees.
Stupid, if you don't have money,
why do you pIace bets?
Oome, PrincipaI, and see for yourseIf
how bad the situation is.
The PrincipaI is on his way!
The oId man has come. Run!
See for yourseIf, sir.
My canteen is in shambIes.
What is wrong here?
There was a scuffIe going on
just a whlle ago.
All of them are eating cordially.
There was a big fight going on
here just a whlle ago.
But there's peace all around.
You aIways compIain wrongIy
about the students.
I wllI get your canteen shut. You
wasted my time. I'm Ieaving now.
I wllI remember you peopIe.
I wllI trap you some day
in such a manner...
...that you won't forget it
all your llfe.
Go away, wllI you?
You are being very...
Enough of your dispIay of strength.
Give me 100 rupees now.
My friend, I am short
of 50 rupees.
- Let me have that!
- He's taken that money too.
On the first day at college, we
induIge in ragging of students.
But this year, the programme
is sllghtIy changed.
Instead of the students...
...we'll be ragging the staff
members and the professors.
- How wllI we do that?
- This is how.
We wllI mix this medicine into the
bottIe and feed it...
...to the professors
and staff members.
As soon as they consume it, they'll
start winking. Like this.
It has been a Iong time since I drank
a cup of tea prepared by you.
Make time some day,
and come over to my pIace.
PIease have it.
What's the matter?
I can't find our P.T. professor.
He is a romantic. He must be
coming at a IeisureIy pace.
- PIease have it, sir.
- What is this?
On this first day to college,
llI the students...00 24 28 05,00 24 31 15,...have given a small tre
to weIcome all of you.
Hurry up, Raj.
Raj, all the professors have
started winking at each other.
But what're you doing?
Whichever professor comes
here furiousIy...
...we wllI pacify his anger
with a shower of fIowers.
What an idea!
Let's take our seats.
Hey! Where has sir disappeared?
Wow! You have Iaid out
fIowers on my path?
This is the first day
at the college.
And I can even see some new
faces among the students.
I think you are a new student.
What's there to Iaugh about?
What's your name?
Such a beautifuI name!
What misbehaviour is this?
I wllI go and compIain
to the principaI rightaway.
But why?
But llsten...
I want to meet the PrincipaI.
Yes?
- What kind of a college is this?
- It's a good college.
The Professor and the peon
misbehaved with me.
What kind of misbehaviour?
How shouId I tell you?
They winked at me.
What? They winked at you?
Such misbehaviour wllI never
be toIerated in this college.
I wllI summon the staff members
this evening and take action.
You may Ieave now.
- Who's Raj?
- The one...
- ...who showered fIowers on you.
- I see. He's Raj?
Yes. He mixed some medicine
in the soft drink...
...after drinking which the entire
staff started winking at each other.
Students who pIay such pranks
on their teachers...
...shouId be thrown out
of the college.
No, no...Raj is not such a boy.
Hello, NeeIam dear!
How has been your first
day at college, NeeIam?
It has been fine.
Let me introduce you to SheetaI,
my cIassmate. And he's my UncIe.
I've made arrangements for your
stay at the Ladies HosteI.
Oome and see the pIace yourseIf.
Moreover, I've to return
to Pune this evening itseIf.
Why don't you stay back
for a few more days?
It has been a week since
I've come here.
Moreover, there's nobody to
Iook after the business in Pune.
And how far is Mumbai from Pune?
I wllI come whenever I llke.
Wow! It means NeeIam wllI llve here
in a hosteI? All aIone in Bombay?
- It means your llne is cIear.
- Yes.
Don't try to taIk to her
thinking her to be aIone.
Otherwise she wllI beat you up
with her sandaI.
She's furious at you.
She was abusing you severeIy.
- She's really furious at you.
- Forget it. Love begins with abuses.
Didn't you see how she was Iooking at
me when the fIowers fell on her?
She overwheImed me
at first sight.
It's true. Even I am an
eye-witness to this fact.
If I tell NeeIam that
I Iove her...
...I'm confident that she wllI
aIso say that she Ioves me too.
If she says this, I wllI
give you whatever you want.
Don't say that. Just ask me
how much I've Iost.
- You wllI Iose too.
- It is just not possibIe.
There's the Rose Day
in the next few days.
Whichever boy Ioves a girI,
offers a red rose to the girI.
And if the girI too Ioves him,
she smlles and accepts the rose.
I wllI sureIy make NeeIam
accept a red rose.
What an idea!
NeeIam wllI throw the rose
back on his face.
Is it? And what if
she accepts the fIower?
- How about a bet of 50 rupees?
- Yes, of course. Just a minute.
- Shall I pIace the bet?
- Yes, go ahead.
- I hope I won't Iose.
- Rest assured.
What if NeeIam doesn't
accept the fIower?
You have confidence on me,
don't you?
- Yes, I have.
- Then just reIax.
Raj, Iet's hide. Otherwise
she wllI take the fIower.
I got a yellow fIower of
friendship with great difficuIty.
But there's not a singIe
handsome youngster...
...who wouId offer me a red
rose saying 'I Iove you'.
How dare you!
Run away from here!
- Why're you hiding here?
- We are hiding from that girI.
If she sees us, we wllI have to
give her a red rose forcibIy.
NeeIam is coming this way.
Meet me after the Iecture.
Wait here. I wllI give her
the fIower and come back.
Hurry up.
He wllI sureIy give the
red rose to NeeIam.
Ms NeeIam...whatever happened
that day in the cIassroom...
...because of me, I am very
embarrassed because of it.
Listen...accept this white fIower
and Iet's end our fight.
- She accepted the fIower, didn't she?
- She accepted onIy a white fIower.
Listen...our fight has ended.
Now accept the yellow fIower
for our friendship.
See...she's accepted
the yellow fIower too.
That's no good. Let him offer the
red rose. Then you wllI know.
- Just a minute, NeeIam.
- What now?
Now that we've become friends,
Iove shouIdn't be far behind.
Just a minute!
Here!
How did you dare to
give me this fIower?
- Give me 50 rupees. Rightaway!
- I've had it!
I onIy have 26 rupees.
WllI it do?
- You never pay up the full amount.
- I wllI pay you the next time.
Raj is an idiot!
You Iost the bet, didn't you?
What does she think of herseIf?
So you had mixed the winking
medicine in everybody's drink.
You are being suspended
from college for a week.
- But, sir...
- No ifs and buts.
- But llsten to me, sir.
- You shouId llsten to me.
Hey!
I've had it. HeIp me!
There's so much heat in their Iove.
Ohickens came out of the eggs.
Daughter, is this the
time to return?
Your college ends at 12 o'cIock.
It's 5 in the evening now.
Where were you all the whlle?
It was great fun at the college.
Is it?
Raj and Boney had a tough time
eating rotten tomatoes and eggs.
- What? Rotten eggs and tomatoes?
- Yes.
Such dirty things are given
to be eaten at your college.
Now I know why your heaIth has
been deteriorating gradually.
But llsten to me first...
I don't want to hear a thing.
Henceforth, you won't even drink
water in your college canteen.
- You don't understand anything.
- But daughter...
Sir...
The guests have arrived.
They're expecting you.
- Greetings.
- PIease be seated.
How are the preparations
for the eIections progressing?
The opposition party has
firmIy entangIed the publlc...
...in their web of
speeches and promises.
Then we wllI provide the
publlc with rations.
To pIay the game of polltics,
one needs the power of weaIth.
And I have weaIth.
Mr. Kallash, we had spent
quite a sum Iast time too.
Actually, we want the
sympathy of the publlc.
You are right.
Let me take care of
what needs to be done...
...to win publlc's sympathy.
Gosh!
You?
- I suppose you aren't hurt.
- No.
You must've been hurt here.
No, I am not hurt anywhere.
- You must be hurt over there.
- I'm not hurt anywhere.
He's taking chances.
I think that...
Hey! She's hurt!
When she says that she isn't hurt,
why don't you belleve it?
You peopIe onIy need excuses.
What a strange girI she is!
- Hey! I wanted this book.
- All right. You read it first.
No, you read it. I have read
this topic in your eyes.
- Your name?
- Miss NeeIam.
- Raj MaIhotra.
- Miss NeeIam Raj MaIhotra.
- No, Mrs. NeeIam Raj MaIhotra.
- What're you doing?
Let him go.
It's Iunch time for him.
But he has written the name
as NeeIam Raj MaIhotra.
Is it?
Yes. Know what that means?
What does it mean?
It means that...
Some day or the other,
we have to be united.
Why not from today itseIf?
- Boney, what's this going on?
- SeIection is going on.
GirIs from our college are
going to Nasik for 7 days...
...for the basketball tournament.
But NeeIam and SheetaI don't
know how to pIay basketball.
So what? They are
beautifuI, at Ieast.
The college wllI appear
very IoneIy without NeeIam.
So what?
Let's do something.
Let us go too.
Are you mad? They wllI be staying
at the girI's hosteI there.
And if we go there
even by mistake...
...we wllI sureIy be bashed up.
Listen.
- No, friend.
- Let's do it.
- No, it's not possibIe.
- But there's no harm in it.
Oan we get a llft tllI Nasik?
We have missed the Iast bus of the
day. It'll be dark soon.
How wllI we beautifuI girIs llve
in this jungIe all by ourseIves?
PIease come.
Where are you going?
We're going to Nasik to participate
in a basketball tournament.
I see...
Your name is NeeIam, isn't it?
How do you know?
I know everything about you.
The name of the person about whom
you're thinking begins with an 'R'.
- I even know that.
- How did you know?
By Iooking at your hand!
Driver, it's so hot
near the engine.
I wllI sit somewhere behind.
What's your name?
- Where wllI you llve at Nasik?
- At VithaIdas HosteI.
We too wllI be llving there.
- What?
- Yes.
- You too wllI be there?
I'm trapped. That professor
has fallen in Iove with me.
He has even written a Ietter to me.
He has asked me to meet him in
the garden to romance.
So what? He'll wait and go away. He
won't come inside this Iadies hosteI.
- I am going to meet NeeIam.
- Go ahead.
- Where are you going?
You know...NeeIam, my friend...
...neither can she sIeep,
nor does she Iet me sIeep.
So I thought of going to
some other room to sIeep.
- That's very nice.
- Very nice?
I'm aIso not feellng sIeepy.
So I thought of chatting
with somebody.
You know what? Go to NeeIam's
room to chat with her.
I wllI go to your room
and sIeep with Honey.
Boney has had it.
- Are you asIeep, Honey?
- Yes.
- So you are awake?
Why're you shivering so much?
I'm feellng so chllIy. Looks
llke I'm suffering from fever.
- I wllI go and call somebody.
- No, no. That won't be necessary.
Once I go to sIeep,
everything wllI be fine.
Let me rub baIm
on your chest.
No, no. Not on my chest.
Rub it on my back, if you wish.
You aren't wearing any cIothes.
I am used to sIeeping
without any cIothes.
That wllI be enough.
Let's go to sIeep now.
Such big hair on your feet?
Don't you use a hair-remover?
I do. I use a hair-remover.
But hair grows back again.
I am very tired now.
Let's go to sIeep now.
Now I understand why you
are unabIe to sIeep.
Supposing if Raj comes here.
What then?
- But how wllI Raj come here?
- Lovers can come anywhere.
Supposing if Raj comes here,
you'll embrace him joyfully.
Yes. I wouId definiteIy llke to.
But I won't give in so easlly.
I wllI first act pricey
and hard-to-get.
Then I wllI tell him
to go away from here.
- What if somebody sees us?
- And then?
What then? When he's about to Ieave,
I wllI stop him, and appease him.
Then I wllI Iook into his
eyes and say...
Didn't I say that Iovers
can come anywhere?
I've had it today.
Where shouId I hide?
I wllI hide under this.
Wow! She sent away her friend?
Looks llke she too
is equally excited.
Honey!
Yes?
Why have you come here?
I was freezing even as I stood
outside in the garden.
If anybody sees you coming here,
I wllI get a bad name.
Nobody has seen me.
Go away from here.
Go away? Without doing anything?
Did you pIan to do something?
Yes.
I wanted to taIk to you about Iove,
which I couIdn't in the bus.
I forgot to give you this.
Look what I've brought for you.
PIease Iook.
I've been fooIed!
Dear NeeIam, your UncIe
hasn't come as yet.
I have teIephoned.
He must be coming.
No, Mr. Kallashnath.
You don't need to come.
I've arranged for thier ball.
Rest assured.
PIease sign here.
OonstabIe, reIease those peopIe.
How wonderfuI! I called you here
to know how yourjall-trip was.
I suppose you mustn't have bothered
about your famlly's good name.
But, Daddy, we aren't
to be bIamed for this.
Actually, it is my fauIt that
I allowed you such llberties.
Why did you two have to
side with these two ruffians?
We didn't know when these two
came there dressed as girIs.
We onIy got to know in
the hosteI room that...
...the girIs are none other than
Raj and Boney. Isn't it, SheetaI?
UncIe, she's Iying.
UncIe, they are Iying!
Why wouId I lle?
What wrong have I done?
My UncIe has sent me here to study,
not to fooI around llke you.
We aren't used to foollng around
llke you two peopIe.
Whenever I study, Boney asks me
to discontinue with my studies...
...and that I wouIdn't achieve much
by passing in first grade.
She's Iying.
- Let's go and study in your room.
- That's good, dear.
- Oarry on girIs.
- Daddy, we won't eat food today.
Food causes one to sIeep earIy.
And we are unabIe to study.
All right. But do drink
fruitjuices. Go ahead.
- Yes.
- Oarry on.
See? Both of them are
so fond of studying.
And you said that they won't achieve
much by passing in first grade.
You shouId be ashamed.
You shouId make good use
of your schoIarship...
...and make a good llfe
for yourseIf.
And you are the younger brother
of Inspector Suresh, aren't you?
I wllI teIephone him rightaway and
ask him to stop your studies...
...and get you admitted to some
theatre group and that you are...
...very fond of dressing up as a
girI. I'll teIephone him rightaway.
PIease don't...UncIe.
I beg of you.
PIease don't teIephone my brother.
He's a very strict person.
You may punish us
however you llke.
I promise you. You won't have
any reason to compIain again.
I'll teIephone your brother
rightaway and ask him...
...to get you admitted to some
theatre group and that you are...
...very fond of dressing
up as a girI.
I beg of you. Don't teIephone my
brother. He's a strict person.
Enough.
Both of you cornered me in
your UncIe's presence.
And now you are making
fun of me?
You were under such a pathetic
state in Daddy's presence.
I respect your Daddy very much.
If I want, I can make your Daddy
to pIead and beg before me.
My Daddy wouId beg before you?
- Do you want to pIace a bet?
- Let it be.
Don't pIace a bet if
you don't want to.
I can say with a challenge
that I wouId emerge victorious.
- What do you say?
- I bet an amount of 500 rupees.
- I am aIso betting.
- All right then.
We three're together.
And you're on the other side.
But you'll have to force UncIe
to pIead and beg before you.
All right, then. Let's meet tomorrow
at our reguIar meeting point.
- Let's go.
- Yes.
Why don't you Iook where
you're driving?
And can't you cross the road
with your eyes open?
Let's go.
- Where are we going?
- Manori IsIand.
But the bet is about
scaring my Daddy.
That's what I'll be doing.
We wllI remain at Manori
IsIand tllI evening.
Your Daddy wllI be worried
when you don't return home.
Then I wllI teIephone him...
...saying that his daughter
has been kidnapped.
When he hears this, he wllI
pIead and beg to me...
...saying that I shouId
return him his daughter.
But I wllI tell him...
But I wllI tell him that
I need 5 Iakh rupees.
Otherwise his daughter...!
Looks llke I've Iost
this bet too.
Keep the 250 out of the
500 rupees towards the bet.
I wllI pay the rest tomorrow.
NeeIam...SheetaI. Pay him rightaway.
Why now? Let him make
the phone call first.
I'm in no hurry. Give me the
money after I make the call.
What nonsense? Why did you kidnap
my daughter? Who're you?
I am a big kidnapper.