It'll be fine as long as there is happiness
Oh God!
Everybody dreams.
But only a handful of people
see their dreams realized.
Want to be a star?
You're perfect!
The rest of us...
accept our fate...
fall into ruin...
kill ourselves...
Let's break up.
Laugh it off...
Don't come near!
Committed crime
and running after by the goddness.
Life with you...
is a terrible bore.
I feel like dying.
You have no way out.
At any rate...
the future's hopeless.
You quit your band.
So now what?
Sex!
It's not too late!
Shut up!
You can start over!
Fuck it.
And then a familiar voice called to me.
Reach out. Stretch up high
And grab a star
Matsuko!
Hi, Son.
Dad!
I need a favor of you.
I hadn't seen my Dad in 2 years.
Ever since I left home at 18 for Tokyo...
to become a musician.
What's that?
Ashes.
Mom?
I never told you
I had an older sister Matsuko.
She vanished about 30 years ago.
She was found dead in a park
3 days ago.
My dad came to Tokyo to cremate her.
She was 53...
living alone in an apartment.
My dad had to return home that day.
So he asked me to go clean up
her apartment.
She was hopeless.
And now she's been murdered.
Murderer!?
The killer's still at large.
Her life was meaningless.
Meaningless.
4 pm, July 10, 2001.
The body of a middle-aged woman
was found on a riverbank.
According to the police...
she was identified as Matsuko Kawajiri.
A tenant of a run-down apartment building.
She had been severely beaten...
"Murder, Say Police"
What a mess!
A teen idol band?
Concrete jungle!
Disgusting.
This is her?
Aunt Matsuko?
That was scribbled by the lady who
died 4 days ago.
She was...
a nuisance.
A neighborhood pest.
Fuckin' crazy!
Well, I'm her relative.
Her neighbor, Shuji.
Despite his anti-social demeanor...
My body is my canvas.
He was oddly friendly.
People called the lady here
Matsuko the Outcast.
Never threw out her trash.
Never said a word.
She smelled weird.
Sometimes, she'd scream her head off.
Teen idols?
I often saw her on the riverbank
just staring at the water.
River?
Mystifying.
Not for the hero detective.
Hi, Officer!
Fuckin' scary!
Seen him? He lived with the victim
18 years ago.
He was released from prison last month.
You think he did it?
Don't know.
But he's been spotted around here.
Hey, you!
What do you know of her?
Nothing.
She liked teen idols?
Her life...
was meaningless.
"Forgive me..."
"Forgive me for being born."
Who was she?
Schoolteacher.
A junior high teacher.
Popular, too. Beautiful voice.
The moon is crying, a star sparkles
That's where hope lies
Knowledge is endless
Matsuko, age 23, 1971
And stars reach into endlessness
Then came an incident at a school outing.
Get back to your rooms.
A student stole money...
from the inn's shop.
About $100.
Ryu was missing from dinner last night.
So what?
He was the only one missing.
Don't accuse him!
We're not accusing him.
We just want you to talk to him.
He's your student!
Do it!
Yes, Sir!
I'll join you.
For moral support.
That's okay. I'm his teacher.
I trust my students.
I selected my words carefully
so as not to hurt his feelings.
Did you take the money?
I believe you but the other teachers...
I'd like to hear it from you.
You think I did it.
If it's returned
the owner won't call the police.
We'll apologize together.
Forget it!
Oh no.
Is it me?
My fault?
No, Ryu's to blame.
He stole!
Damn you!
Wait, I know!
I'll return the money myself...
and say I got it from
the remorseful student.
Not enough!
I'll pay it right back!
I promise!
He feels terrible about it!
Then bring him here.
He needs to apologize!
Let's go see him, then.
- No! - Yes!
You making fun of me?
Um... no.
Just then...
It wasn't him.
I just wanted this over.
I took it!
I took the money!
You were letting your students
take the blame...
for a crime you committed?
I'm sorry!
I wasn't going to the police anyway.
Ms. Kawajiri?
But why?
Let's not tell the other teachers.
We'll let the inn believe you did it.
And the school will pretend
nothing happened.
We've no other choice.
As for you, Ms. Kawajiri...
I'm sorry.
How sorry?
Well...
Show me with actions, not words!
Yes, sir!
If you're really sorry
then show me your breasts.
Show me!
Now!
Ms. Kawajiri?
It was all a mistake by the inn.
Yes.
People can be so silly.
Ms. Kawajiri?
He looked me in the eye and said...
How would you like...
to go bowling on Sunday?
Then I said...
"Are you asking me out on a date?"
Then he blushed.
Yes.
Is he handsome?
Yes, and his teeth!
Sparkling white.
Good for you, Sis.
Thanks.
I promise to be happy.
Why'd you tell your sister
you have a date?
You know she's ill.
She can't go out.
She can't date.
Have you considered her feelings?
Have you no sympathy?
Hi, Sis.
I don't feel...
the least bit sorry for you!
Matsuko!
Dad had always been like this.
Matsuko, age 7, 1955
Reach out, stretch up high:
And grab a star
Stretch up high as you can
He adored my sick sister, Kumi.
I was always alone.
But one time...
after visiting Kumi in the hospital
he took me to a department store.
I ate pancakes for the first time.
It was just the two of us.
I walk the road where candy trees grow
I dance in the woods in magical shoes
Nobody hates the smile on my face
And every word I say turns into music
Because of Kumi's illness
dad was always sad.
But I made him smile.
After that I tried to win his favor
by making that face.
I wanted his attention...
his love.
In my schooling and in my job...
I worked hard to make him proud.
And yet...
I wish I could see Kumi like this.
Be serious.
But my efforts were in vain.
I started making that
face in tense situations...
without realizing it.
You making fun of me?
That's my 24 years.
Interesting.
I called you out at this hour just to...
talk your ear off. I'm sorry.
No, I'm glad you did.
That's such a relief.
Now that we're seeing each other...
I think you should know about me.
Well, I'm...
really glad.
The inn asked us to go easy on you
for stealing their money.
Yet I heard from the head teacher...
that you came crying to him
to keep this a secret.
That's a lie!
Then we heard from
the teacher you roomed with...
money was missing from her wallet.
I'll return everything
Was it you?
No! I mean it was a student
who stole from the inn.
But he wouldn't admit it.
Yes or no?
Yes, but only...
Thief!
No, I can explain! Please wait.
Please come forward, I beg you!
If not, I'll be blamed for everything!
Why?
Because I was trying to protect you!
Why'd you do that? You hate me.
I hate you!
No... I don't.
All right.
I confess. I stole the money.
We've asked Mr. Saeki to join us.
Tell the truth.
It was you who stole from the inn, right?
I didn't steal any money.
A few minutes ago...
Ms. Kawajiri threatened me...
telling me to take the blame.
Ms. Kawajiri, you're despicable!
This isn't a joke!
At that moment, I felt my life was over.
I was summarily forced to resign.
Sis?
I'm leaving.
No, don't!
Don't go!
It's all your fault!
Because of you!
It's all because of you!
Matsuko!
No!
I know I've seen this face
before somewhere.
She was crying.
She sat staring at the river
tears streaming from her face.
She was nuts, I tell you.
Don't "tsk-tsk" me.
Fuck!
Look! There!
It's him!
Murderer!
Of course, my dad called only to see
if I'd finished the job.
She was a teacher, wasn't she?
Yeah. So?
And a good singer, too?
Who cares?
We cut all ties with her.
Why?
Because...
after she left
she became a "massage parlor girl."
And a murderer!
Hope to see you at the carnival
Outrageous swimming suits
The summer sun is too too hot
No way!
How you been, my little brother?
What do you want?
Nothing.
Living with a man?
An aspiring writer... very kind.
Liar, liar, liar!
It's because of you I can't write!
Go sell your body!
Earn some money!
Tetsuya!
What do you want?
Money.
I knew it.
You're a woman.
Get work as a hostess or something.
I won't do that kind of work.
Liar, liar, liar!
Okay, strip.
Right now?
Right now. Everything.
Sorry. You're not right.
How's Kumi?
She hasn't been the same. She mumbles.
Sometimes, she won't talk or eat for days.
You destroyed our family.
Don't ever come back.
You're dead to us.
And dad?
Is he angry with me?
Dad's dead.
Suffered a stroke on the toilet.
3 months after you left.
What?
What do I need to do
To earn your love
Please tell me
Okano-san?
I was just in the neighborhood.
How's Tetsuya's writing going?
He's my arch rival, you know.
He still drinks and gets violent?
He's spirited... fancies himself
as Osamu Dazai reborn.
To be frank, he's not...
Not what?
Welcome back.
I'll be going.
Get hired?
No, they didn't want me.
Is that so?
Did he see my work?
He's no writer. He works by day.
I've devoted my life!
I borrowed money from my brother.
With that face...
you asked for money?
He told me never to return.
So what?
Don't look so pathetic!
Strip! Remove your bra, now!
Goddammit!
That night...
Tetsuya vanished from my life
leaving me with one phrase.
"Forgive me for being born."
At that moment...
I felt my life was over.
But 6 months later...
I was singing again.
Isn't life just wonderful
Oh, my life's so beautiful
Today's the much anticipated
Happy Wednesday
Ah, the joy of love
I wait for you everyday!
When you arrive on my doorstep
On Happy Wednesday
Sugar, pepper, Salt and all my love
Happy Wednesday
Please eat soup and please at me!
Without you I cannot live
But once a week I get my fix
Welcome back!
Happy Wednesday
I became Okano-san's lover.
I suppose I was jealous of Tetsuya.
He had talent and dedication.
And an attractive girl like you.
That hurts.
Tetsuya, huh?
Sorry... for reminding you.
See ya.
Happy Wednesday
Are you the Missus?
I'm looking for the Kawajiri residence.
No one by that name around here.
You are?
Sorry to bother you, ma'am.
I could beat her.
Happy Wednesday
I just knew it.
Matsuko.
Welcome back.
Don't give me that!
Quiet!
I am!
You came to my house.
Okano's wife grew suspicious and
confronted him.
So he confessed our love affair.
That's okay. She doesn't suit you.
You don't love her, right? So break up...
How dare you?!
It's you I don't love.
I've no wish to marry you.
Who can eat food this rich?
I just wanted what Tetsuya had.
I felt inferior to him.
When he died
I wanted to purge those feelings.
So I took his lover.
I don't understand. Please explain.
We're through. It's over between us.
What I did was wrong.
I let things get too far. But I couldn't resist.
You've a great body.
Please take this.
Why?
Why?!
WHY?!
"White Nights"
Why?
Because my ex-lover told me...
I have a great body.
So?
I think I'm suited for this job.
Are you?
Well?
Hire her.
She's interesting.
Hands out.
Very nice. Good luck.
Love's a bubble. Nothing but trouble
Let's play pretend love
Love's a bubble. Full of trouble
So let me lather you up
Your new name is "Yukino."
Real love is taboo but
I'll make you think it's true
Focus every bodily nerve
on pleasing the customer.
"Shy as a virgin"
Stamina is key.
Train those legs and hips.
Ah, golden shower!
Our top girl this month is... Yukino.
Great work!
"Love Technicians!"
"Novices are in! Pros are out!"
Soak up a bubble bath
"Amateur Girls!"
Times have changed.
Thanks for the memories.
We may be out of style but
we still gotta live.
Maybe I'll open a diner.
Love's a bubble Nothing but trouble
Money is the only thing to love
Fired?
I give you some love
I'm home.
"Kozo Kawajiri, 1971"
"No word from Matsuko."
Ever since I left home...
my father had ended each diary entry
the same way.
"No word from Matsuko."
Matsuko.
Daddy.
I knew it.
Kumi?
You came back!
My sister's back!
Matsuko!
Who are you?
Matsuko-san?
Money.
For my brother!
No, don't leave!
Matsuko, age 26, 1974
You were crying in your sleep.
I'm fine.
I drifted around near my hometown...
and wound up with this man, Onodera.
He was a slimy pimp looking to get rich.
I no longer cared.
I just hated being alone.
And I wanted to get away.
I hate the rain. It brings bad memories.
Let's make some good ones, then.
Are we through?
Yes.
I want my share of the money.
6 month's worth of back pay.
It's gone.
I gave it all to her.
What?
Look at yourself!
You're washed up!
No man will have you!
I'm moving in with her.
Lost!
The rain here never seemed to stop.
Stop that.
Matsuko!
Who do you think you are? I'll kill you!
I saw a face.
But I couldn't remember whose it was.
Shit!
You clumsy bitch!
God, that hurts! Call an ambulance!
Son of a bitch! I'll sue you!
It hurts like hell!
God damn you!
At that moment...
I was sure my life was over.
And yet...
my body wanted to stay alive.
Every child believes in a sparkling future.
Then you grow up...
and nothing goes as planned.
There's only pain, grief and anger.
It's all your fault.
My fault?
I'm sorry.
It's not really your fault.
It's my fault.
I realized something.
Why I felt so bored.
It's because I expected you
to do everything for me.
And did nothing myself.
Hey, Sho?
A person's life...
isn't valued by what one receives.
But... by what one gives, right?
I've thought real hard.
And it's made me ask myself...
what can I do for you? Or for the world?
So I've decided...
to join the Peace Corps and
go to Uzbekistan.
Uzbekistan?
See ya.
Hello?
What was that?
Your life isn't over.
"The Widow is a Nympho!"
No, we mustn't!
"Starring Aoi Mizusawa"
As the widow was being ravished...
I fell asleep.
And had another bizarre dream.
I was being kidnapped by a porn star.
Junior?
Come with me.
It wasn't a dream.
Who are you? Watch it!
You guys!
You knew Matsuko?
No.
I'm her nephew! She's my dad's sister.
You're cute. What's your name?
Sho.
Sorry to alarm you.
I'm Megumi Sawamura.
"Sawamura Productions
Adult Video Software"
A fan of yours, boss?
Oh my God, my debut film!
She and my aunt were old friends.
When the body was found...
Matsuko was clutching
this woman's business card.
So the police called her.
They wouldn't tell me anything.
So I had my men stake out her apartment.
They saw you.
Have they found the killer?
Not yet.
But there was a man she lived with
18 years ago.
The police are looking for him.
It's him.
Pardon me but...
how do you know my aunt?
I met her...
in prison.
After stabbing him, I ran to the station.
To go where?
I don't know.
I just went.
I took the Bullet Train to Tokyo.
Bullet Train?
I'd always wanted to ride it.
It was like a dream.
Skip it.
Before I knew it
I was in Tokyo... in Mitaka.
Mitaka?
I wanted to die there.
Tetsuya, the only man who ever loved me...
believed he was the famous writer
Osamu Dazai, reborn.
If so, I wanted to die where he took his life...
and join Tetsuya.
I don't quite follow.
But you didn't die.
I couldn't.
No water.
There's a dam up river.
All you get is a trickle here.
He was a passerby.
And?
We went for a drink.
Attractive?
No. He was the sad, introverted type.
You were committing suicide.
He looked sad...
but had gentle eyes.
Nowhere to go?
I'm Kenji Shimazu, a barber.
Single?
No wife?
Killed in an auto accident 3 years ago.
He gave me a new look.
I felt new again.
We spent the night together.
I became his assistant.
Kenji, where'd you find
such a beautiful wife?
Then one night...
I don't care what kind of past you've had.
All I know is I want to spend
the rest of my life with you.
Next thing I knew...
I was singing.
I couldn't find the words to even
say good-bye
My heart knows only Fairytale endings
Look at that. A murderer singing happily.
Yeah but...
she sings nice.
Let's go.
Matsuko Kawajiri?
Give me a moment to get ready.
"Matsuko Kawajiri - sentenced to
8 years in prison for murder"
What is a life, what is a life?
People wake up. They work
They eat, they sleep
If that's life
What is a life, what is a life?
Locked behind walls. Nothing to do
How do they find. The will to live
She did it for her family
What is a life?
She did it for pride
She did it for a precious memory
What is a life?
She lives for pleasure
I didn't know of her life before.
But she didn't look the least bit
lost or scared.
She just did as she was told.
She was different.
She wakes up to the same routine
Same faces, same places
Is there someone waiting for
you on the outside?
No, there isn't.
Not for any reason, nor anyone.
What is a life?
I live for love, where there is love
I can live on, for love is life
"Hairstylist vocational training"
Bit by bit love's changing me
If God can let me live again
I know I can change
will
Right now
Forever
March on
I live!
For love!
"Hairstylist License"
What will you do?
Live with Kenji.
He knows this?
We made a pledge.
Has he visited?
No, not once.
You sure?
He may not be waiting.
For you and only you
I want to live again
Love is life
I give myself all to you
I want to live
Love is life
To hear your voice again
I've kept my heart alive
So say to me, dear Welcome home
Love is life
I'm back.
Matsuko, age 34, 1982
Every little girl...
dreams of being Snow White, Cinderella...
of living in a fairytale.
Then we wake up one day...
and see our white swan...
has become a black crow.
One life...
is all we get.
If it's a fairytale... it's a cruel one.
You listening?
Anyway...
we met again
at a beauty salon in the Ginza.
Wow, what are the odds of that?
It was the salon's name.
The beauty salon in the Ginza...
had the same name
as the salon in prison.
Still don't know?
It's me!
Megumi?
I'm married now... Megumi Sawamura.
No way!
To a man. Don't worry.
Really!
We hung out a lot.
Talked a lot.