Do you swear to tell the truth,
nothing but the truth, so help you God?
- I do.
- Sit down, please.
You're a professional songwriter,
I believe, Mrs. Crane.
- I am.
- Your husband also?
- Yes.
- You composed love songs together, eh?
- Mostly.
- Who wrote the words?
- I did.
- I see.
And your husband furnished the music?
Oh, no, his music came first,
I furnished the words.
How long did you know the defendant
before you married him?
About four and a half years.
And you met him professionally
at that time?
Well, um, not exactly, Your Honor.
You see...
Well, he used to come into a little
restaurant on 47th Street where I worked.
I used to serve him breakfast
every day at 12.
He'd eat 50 cents' worth
and I'd only punch 20 on the check.
That's how we became acquainted.
Why did you do that?
I liked him.
Well, don't you think that was
dishonest to your employer?
No. I always put the difference
on somebody else's check.
I take it Mr. Crane wasn't so successful.
- Well, nobody appreciated him then.
- Except you.
- Well, I didn't count.
- But you encouraged him.
- Yes.
- So you feel you discovered him?
No. Eddie discovered me.
- How?
- I went out with him one night...
Proceed, Mrs. Crane.
Well, we became a habit.
I know, but how did you happen
to become a writer of lyrics?
Oh.
Well, I started rewriting
Mother Goose when I was only 6.
Then I wound up writing verses
on greeting cards...
...and the firm went bankrupt.
That's when I went into dealing them
off the arm.
- Off the arm?
- Yes. You know, like:
Oh, I'm sorry.
I mean, that's when I became a waitress.
- Your Honor, may I interrupt?
Yes.
I would like Mrs. Crane to tell us how she
formed this partnership with her husband.
It's relevant at this point.
Just tell us in your own words,
Mrs. Crane.
Well, it all happened
very suddenly one night.
We were sitting in a little gloomy piano
room at Max Milton's publishing house.
Max thought Eddie had talent,
so he let him use the room as a favor.
Well, Eddie was working with a lyric writer
on one of the best tunes he ever wrote.
But it was no dice.
I was just sitting there
listening to that piano.
They'd been going on for hours.
Something's wrong.
Maybe it's me or the tune.
I don't know, but I'm not clicking.
Well, you will. You will.
Take your time, Billy.
Look, Eddie, I'll be frank with you.
It's silly for us to waste our time.
I just don't like the tune.
Oh.
That doesn't mean we can't get together.
That's not the only tune you'll write.
I don't know whether it is or not.
You're taking it too serious, kid.
Pull yourself together. Let's get coffee.
- What do you say?
- Whatever Eddie says.
No, you go ahead.
I'll stick around for a while.
Okay. No hard feelings?
No, certainly not.
And thanks for getting together with me.
Forget it. If you think you got something,
give me a jingle.
- I want a hit as much as you. Good night.
Good night.
- Night, Dixie.
- Night.
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to take it out on you.
Eddie...
...I know you're disappointed,
and I don't blame you.
Just because Billy
says the tune's no good...
...that doesn't make it so.
Why, it's beautiful.
You don't understand.
It isn't only the song.
It isn't necessarily Billy. It's just that...
Well, in this business
you've gotta have a hookup, a team.
There's no sense in writing a tune
then peddling it like a hot fur coat...
...from one guy to another
hoping to get a fluke hit.
You've gotta work with somebody
until you've built a style...
...and a quality that's recognizable.
Look at George Gershwin. He had Ira.
There's Rodgers and Hart,
Kern and Hammerstein.
Oh, what's the use?
There are a dozen more.
They work together.
One helps the other and they go places.
Yeah. I know what you mean.
- Eddie?
- Mm?
Would you mind
if a girl wrote the words to your tune?
Of course not. There's Dorothy Fields.
She's one of the best in the business.
Well, could you get her?
No. She's tied up.
Would you listen to some I wrote?
- You?
- Oh...
I know it's ridiculous for me to think
that you could think...
...that I could write some words...
...but the melody kept saying the words
over and over while you were playing...
...and before I knew it, I had a song.
- You have?
- Uh-huh. You wanna hear it?
- Let me see the words. I can tell by looking.
You couldn't read them.
I jotted them down on my handkerchief.
I always do.
It's, well, kind of unobtrusive.
Well, go ahead and play, Eddie.
But don't laugh, will you?
- The way I feel?
- Well, not in my face, anyhow.
You'll never know
If an apple is ripe
Till you bite it
You'll never know
If a fire is gonna burn
Till you light it
You'll never know
What it means to be blue
Till you've lost an old friend
You'll never know
Just how long is your road
Till you've reached the end
You'll never know
How good a book may be
Till you've read it
You'll never know
What one kind word can do
Till you've said it
You and I could find romance
But, darling, till you take that chance
You'll never, never
Never ever
Know
Dixie, you've done it.
- I don't know how, but you've done it.
- Have I?
Why, it makes me sick, it's so wonderful.
You let me die on the vine for lyrics,
and you've got them up your sleeve.
I think it'll swing too.
- I'll bet it will. Let's try it.
- Yeah.
You'll never know if an apple is ripe
Till you bite it
You'll never know if a fire is gonna burn
Till you light it
You'll never know
What it means to be blue
Till you've lost an old friend
You'll never know how long is your road
Till you've reached the end
You'll never know
How good a book may be
Till you've read it
You'll never know what a kind word can do
Till you've said it
You and I could find romance
But, darling
Till you take
That chance
Gosh, Dixie.
Gosh, Eddie.
By golly, that deserves a kiss.
Well, I wouldn't be surprised if Crane and
Donegan had a hit on their handkerchief.
And it was a hit too.
We went to work on another one,
which didn't come so easy, incidentally.
But we fought and wrestled it through,
and it was successful.
So then I thought it was safe for me
to quit my job in the restaurant.
Besides...
...Eddie felt that he could afford
to eat in a better place.
I see.
And this successful collaboration
led to your marriage.
Yes, Your Honor.
That, plus a little item called love.
On whose part?
Well, mine, I guess.
Ah. It didn't last?
I didn't say that.
Oh, one of those.
You love him, but...
Your Honor, may I interrupt once more?
Yes.
I would like to call a witness
if the court pleases.
Someone altogether impartial
who could clarify this portion of the case.
Yes. I think it's going to need
a little clarity. Go ahead.
That will be all for the time being,
Mrs. Crane.
Miss Marilyn Marsh, please.
Name, please?
- Marilyn Marsh.
Raise your right hand.
Do you swear to tell the truth,
nothing but the truth, so help you God?
- I do.
- Sit down, please.
Will you tell the court your occupation
or profession?
I'm a dancer.
You've appeared
in Broadway productions?
I have.
How long have you known
Mr. And Mrs. Crane?
Over three years. Ever since they started
writing songs together.
- Before they were married?
- Yes, sir.
They wrote the score for a show I was in,
and we became very close friends.
In fact, I think Dixie
is my very best friend.
What was the relationship between
Miss Donegan and Mr. Crane at that time?
Well, I'm not sure.
But in your opinion they seemed suited
to one another?
I thought the match
was made in heaven.
- But it didn't work out that way?
- No, sir.
I'm afraid they still make most
of the matches in Sweden.
Miss Marsh, please confine yourself
to less philosophical statements.
I'm sorry.
What I mean is, it was a flop.
In what way?
- Well...
- To sum it up definitely, Miss Marsh...
...what would say was the basic trouble
between Mr. And Mrs. Crane?
Why...
Why, I'd say Eddie went Park Avenue.
Park Avenue?
Can you explain in a little more detail
just what you mean by that?
Well, for example,
there was the night the show closed.
It had run for a year...
...and Dixie and Eddie were giving a big
party for the cast and all their friends.
Only it turned out to be mostly
for his friends, his new ones.
Park Avenue was clustered around Eddie
like flies around honey.
Every phony in the phony 400.
On the other side of the room,
Dixie and I were sitting...
...and I couldn't help noticing
she was depressed.
I think everybody felt the room
was split up into two camps.
The friends who knew him when,
and those that knew him if.
Among his real friends
were Max Milton, his publisher.
He'd handled every song
the kids had written...
...and was kind of a godfather
to both of them.
And Red Willet, the song plugger.
He'd gone up with Eddie and so he put in
a special plug for all his tunes.
And with us was one of the most popular
radio singers in the country...
...Buddy Crawford.
We'd all known Buddy
when he was just starting out...
...and we'd watched his struggles
along with our own.
But he was on top now, and was always
singing every Crane and Donegan tune...
...he could get hold of.
Maybe we're wrong, Red.
Maybe he belongs
with these hammerheads, after all.
It isn't that bad, Marilyn.
He's just a big kid.
He's found a new sand pile to play in.
Yeah, and a golden bucket.
Can they spare it?
I guess it's perfectly natural.
Eddie come up the hard way.
When I plugged his first number 10 years
ago, he didn't have a cot to sleep in.
You can't blame him
if he wants to eat caviar...
...and go to Lady Triple Chin's
house parties.
I'm thinking of Dixie.
It's tough on her.
It's like the gag: You don't run
after a streetcar once you've caught it.
- Marilyn, you look wonderful.
- Oh, thanks, Buddy.
Red, stand up a minute, will you?
Turn around.
Thank you.
Oh, I get it,
you two want me to be alone.
That's the general idea.
Where's your girl?
There she is, over there.
Cute kid, isn't she?
Yeah. What's her name?
- Lull.
- Lull?
Lull doesn't seem to be
having a very good time.
Aw, she's happy. She's eating.
Oh, a pickle for Lull. Thank you.
Hi, Lull.
Having a lot of fun?
You know, you're gonna ruin your appetite
if you don't stop eating between bites.
- Simply fabulous.
- Out of the world.
- Wonderful.
- I'm glad you like it because I love to play.
Oh, Eddie, it's been simply divine.
The whole evening.
- I'm absolutely shattered I have to go.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
But you will join us this weekend?
At the Lattisons'.
You want me to come
and bring my piano?
- Don't be silly.
- Eddie, how fantastic.
- We want you for yourself.
- That's kind of you.
I still have never been able to get
one of these things in a taxi.
- Maybe I can stay for just one more.
- Oh, good.
- Oh, please.
- Yes, come on. Just one more, huh?
Say, Dixie, wasn't it a swell party?
Everybody said they couldn't have had
a better time.
Did you meet that real live countess?
You mean the lady
with the slight mustache?
Yeah.
And that society columnist?
Oh, yes.
You should have heard him rave
about your tune.
Yeah?
He asked me
what we're gonna do next...
...and I told him an idea of
that number we talked about last.
Oh, I don't think that's so hot.
Oh, everybody loves a love song
in spring.
I'm sure we can get it.
Look, Eddie, I dare you.
- Lets go in and run it over right now?
- Now?
We've always worked any hour
of the day or night.
Oh, no, honey. I don't feel like it.
I'm not in the mood.
Tomorrow then?
Well, maybe. We'll see.
No, I just remembered.
I'm going down to the Sound
to see the Marions' new boat.
They certainly liked our party.
I got a thrill out of looking around
that room tonight.
You know something? I'll bet we had
150 million bucks right in that living room.
Uh-huh.
Did you see all the invitations we got?
Twenty, I'll bet you.
- Did my blue suit go to the cleaners?
- Yes.
- When do I get my laundry?
- Tomorrow at 10:00.
Do you know if those brown shoes
were picked up?
The bootmaker
will have them here Friday.
We've ordered your favorite lobster and
the butler's reordered the wine you like.
Anything else, Eddie?
What's the matter?
I didn't know
you were that tired tonight.
There are a lot of things I'm tired of.
What did you mean by that?
Eddie...
...let's shake hands and call it quits.
Quits?
You see, this whole business
is your idea of fun, it isn't mine.
I think you could have
a better time alone.
I wanna work. I'm a worker.
I can't stand this routine
of bouncing red balloons in the air.
But it's your idea
of a merry-go-round, darling.
So you ride on it.
Oh, I get it.
My balloons, my merry-go-round.
As if you weren't having
a good time yourself.
If that isn't a typical feminine attitude,
always making the man the heavy.
Oh, let's not fight about it, Eddie.
It really only dawned on me tonight.
Maybe I ought to have my freedom.
Legally.
Well...
...you know I'd never stand in the way
of what you wanna do.
That's white of you, Eddie.
As long as we don't see things
the same way, what's the use of going on?
No use.
No use at all.
And we won't.
That's the whole story, as I pieced it
together from my own impressions...
...and the things Dixie told me.
As Red said, I'm afraid Eddie figured
he'd caught the streetcar...
...and didn't have to run anymore.
Hm.
Well, thank you, Miss Marsh.
That will be all.
Are there any other witnesses?
No, sir. My case rests.
Is the defendant represented in court?
No. Since there's no question
of support or property settlement...
...the case is not contested.
All right.
Well, from the evidence
we've heard today...
...we seem to have a regrettable instance
of a young man...
...who wasn't able to handle
his own success.
Even made it intolerable
for this young woman to live with him.
Funny what a little success
will do to people.
Well, much as I dislike
this divorce business...
...there doesn't seem to be
anything to do here.
There are no children.
No question of money
and certainly sufficient legal grounds.
Therefore, I grant this divorce.
Court's adjourned.
It's all over now, honey,
you're as free as a bird.
Thanks to you, Marilyn.
If anybody got my divorce for me,
you did.
We're going to my place
and celebrating.
You're swell to take me in, honey.
Oh, gosh, it's staring to rain.
Wouldn't it, though?
Today of all days.
I don't mind. It's Eddie's blue suit.
- He always wants it when it rains.
- Eddie's blue suit?
We'll stop at the cleaners
and make sure they send it to him.
Eddie may not have me, but he's gonna
have his darned old blue serge suit.
Gosh, I loved Eddie in that suit.
Divine.
Too divine.
Too, too divine.
Shove, dove, wove, glove...
- Hi, Dixie.
- Hello, honey.
- Working?
- Trying to, and getting nowhere but fast.
Any calls for me, darling?
The phone rang, but when I answered
there wasn't anyone on the wire.
- How are the lyrics going?
- Oh, I guess I'm upset.
This is the third fellow
I've tried to write with, and it's no use.
But I'll find one
if I have to put an ad in Variety.
I'll get it.
Hello? Oh, uh...
Just a minute. I'll see.
- It's Eddie.
- Eddie?
Now, don't be overanxious.
Play hard to get.
I'm afraid she's gone out.
I'll see if I can catch her.
Do something
so you'll sound out of breath.
Run around the room.
Run to the door. Go on.
Hold the wire, Eddie,
I managed to catch her.
Hello, Eddie.
I'm sorry I'm a little out of breath.
I just came in.
Marilyn caught me way down the hall.
I'm sorry to bother you
if you're going out.
Well, it is fairly important.
I was wondering if you could
run over here for few minutes.
You will? Oh, that's swell.
You're a darling.
I'll be right over.
Oh, it's something important, he said.
Marilyn, do you suppose?
Oh, gee.
- Hello, Eddie.
- Hello, Dixie.
Come on in.
Thanks.
- May I take your cape?
- Oh, yes.
I can't stay long,
people are waiting, you know?
Oh, sure, sure. As a matter of fact,
I expect some people by here pretty soon.
- Won't you sit down?
- Oh, thanks.
Oh, uh, cigarette?
- It's empty.
- Oh.
Well, never mind,
I just finished one in the cab.
Well...
...how are things, Eddie?
Oh, fine, fine.
I've been pretty busy lately.
Oh, you've been writing?
No. Been moving around a lot, though.
- You know, parties and stuff.
- Oh.
I was down at the Lessmores' yesterday
on Long Island. I had a swell time.
I bet you did.
Well, what about you?
- Have you been working?
- Me? Oh, sure.
You know me. The sewing machine kid.
- Well, is it good?
- Oh, swell, I think.
I found a new writer just the other day.
He seems to work out fine.
Oh, I'm glad.
You wanted to see me, Eddie?
Yeah.
You see...
...it's like this, Dixie.
I guess I'm not as smart
as I thought I was.
Oh?
No. I found out that living alone
isn't quite what it's cracked up to be.
I used to be able to find everything.
Socks and shirts and neckties.
At least they were put where I could
kind of dive into them like a fireman.
Yes, Eddie?
Well, the truth is, Dixie, that...
Well, it takes a woman to run things.
Yes, Eddie?
And now those crumbs
have walked out on me.
What crumbs?
The servants. They took a powder.
I don't know where anything is.
Even how to hire new ones.
That's why I phoned you.
I thought you'd give me a hand.
You thought that...?
If it wasn't too much trouble,
you could...
Well, you know, tell me what to do.
You mean you brought me over here to tell
you how to call up an employment agency?
- I didn't. You volunteered.
- Are you implying...?
I'm not implying anything except
I don't know how to run an apartment.
I gave them a vacation.
They walked in, walked out on me.
- They didn't even give me notice.
- Probably couldn't find you.
Look at this apartment.
And that dust and those ashes.
And look at that piano.
I'm admitting it.
All I need's a little advice.
- All you need is advice.
- Oh, I'm getting along swell.
You sound as though
you're feeling sorry for yourself.
You always were a sentimentalist,
my boy.
- That's why you were a great songwriter.
- What do you mean "were"?
Just that. You haven't written a thing
since you had an empty stomach.
"Were," indeed.
- What's this? One of your shirts?
- I don't know.
Go on, open it up.
A dust cloth.
Come on, open it again.
Oh.
Hey, don't throw that away.
It's a new tune.
New? It's been hanging around here
for over a year.
I know, but I was
gonna work on it tomorrow.
Oh, yeah, manana.
Don't throw away anything
with notes on it.
- It might go down in history.
- Mm-hm.
You and Beethoven.
Say, that's not bad.
What's that?
I never heard that part before.
- What?
- The middle.
When did you write it?
Quiet. I'm trying to get it now.
- Start it again.
- Huh?
From the beginning. I got an idea.
Okay.
Play the first four bars again.
Play it again, Eddie.
Just the last two bars.
That did it, brother.
- You finished?
- Yeah. Wanna hear it?
Of course. I hope the last part's
as good as the first.
My music couldn't compare
With Liszt's or Schumann's
Or gifted humans
Like Irving Berlin and Jerry Kern
My lyrics aren't in a class
With Ira Gershwin
From Ira Gershwin
I've lots to learn
If our talents we combined
I think they might agree
You mean, I'd bring out the Kern in you
And you'd bring out the Gershwin in me
Could be
Your words
And my music
Could make such a beautiful song
A simple chorus as warm as the spring
We'll get our big thrill
When we hear
Everyone singing
Your words
And my music
And although its theme may be worn
With your words
And my music
A wonderful love song
Is born
It's perfect, darling.
- You sure it doesn't sound forced?
- No. It's right on the nose.
Plenty of sentiment.
It's exactly what the tune means to me.
- Oh, I think it's swell, honey.
- I'm glad.
There's just this one little part
in the bass here.
- Eddie.
- Huh?
I'm dead. I'm gonna call it a night.
All right, honey.
When we get up we'll listen to it again.
Okay, that's a good idea.
Night, darling.
Night.
You know, honey, I think this is...
You know, Dixie, I think that's the most
commercial tune we've ever written.
Mm-hm.
Say, you don't look very comfortable.
Hey, wake up and go to sleep.
Oh, yeah.
Tired.
- Eddie.
- Hm?
- Zip, will you?
- Oh.
Thanks.
What's the matter?
Oh, dear.
- Hey, where are you going?
- I don't live here anymore.
Gee, my beads.
Well, if...
Sorry, my mistake.
It gets worse every year.
What happened to you?
Oh, I got out of one those new cabs.
I forgot there was no running board.
- No what?
- Running board.
I got out in a hurry and it wasn't there...
- If I find a lawyer, I'm gonna sue the guy.
- Take it easy, Red.
Hi, Buddy... Oh, I'm sorry.
You look just like Buddy Crawford.
Better watch that.
- Hi, Buddy.
- Hello, Red.
- Have you heard it yet?
- Heard what?
Eddie and Dixie wrote a new tune.
And is it terrific.
What do you know?
When can I hear it?
Well, I'll sing it for you right now.
Calling Mr. Crawford.
Did that come out of me?
- Here you are, fellow.
You got me off-key there.
- Is she on the phone?
- Yes. Booth 3.
- I'll handle it. I'll tell her you're out of town.
- I'll handle it.
Well, how about the new song?
- Hello, Dixie.
- Hello, Buddy, how are you?
Yes, the former Mrs. Crane speaking.
I got your flowers this morning,
they're beautiful.
You wouldn't be kidding me,
would you?
Kidding on the square. Now that you're back
in circulation, how about giving me a break?
- What are you doing the next two months?
- Oh, take it easy. Take it easy.
Buddy, I'm in Max Milton's office
and we want you to come over...
...to hear a new song
Eddie and I have written.
Yes, congratulations.
Joe was just telling me.
I'd love you to sing it for me.
In fact, I'd love you. Period.
Hi, Red.
Oh, hello, Eddie.
Say, I've been plugging your new song.
- How's it going? Do people like it?
- Nuts about it. I sang it for Buddy.
He raved. He wants to
use it on the air right away.
That's nice of him.
He'll do a great job on it.
- Sell a lot of copies.
- Yeah.
I was just thinking,
too bad you and Dixie split out.
We'll have to send the royalties
in two checks, huh?
- Yeah.
- I guess you don't feel too hot about it.
- Oh, forget it. I don't like to talk about it.
- Yeah, that's the way it goes.
When love flies out the window,
it always leaves a scar.
I guess you don't feel too good,
do you, kid?
I mean, Dixie's so marvelous.
Well, of course, it's none of my business,
but you look terrible.
- I guess she gave you the air, huh?
- Why, we're still the best of friends.
- Uh-oh. That's a sure sign it's off for keeps.
- Oh, shut up, will you?
Well, you don't have to get sore.
- What's the matter, Eddie?
- Where's Buddy?
He's over there making a phone call.
Guy brought a note in for...
Hey, Crawford.
- Hello, Eddie.
- I wanna see you, you...
- Why, you sound mad.
- I am.
- At me?
- Yes, you, you...
- You heel.
- Why, Eddie, what's eating you?
- I figured you might be the guy.
- What guy?
The snake in the grass.
- Aren't you being just a little silly?
- I am, am I?
- How would you like a punch?
- For what?
- For trying to chisel in on my wife.
- Oh, use your head.
Yeah. You haven't got a wife.
- You were talking to her on the phone.
- About business.
Don't kid me. What business
would she have with you?
Well, now, you'd be surprised.
Oh, I would? Why, I'll...
- You dope. Think of his public.
- Get out of here.
- I know what I'm doing.
- Look.
- Dixie wrote a new song.
- We wrote a new song.
Did you hear that? We.
I don't care how many
of you wrote the song.
Dixie wants me to sing it.
"Your Words And My Music"
is one song you'll never sing.
- Yes, I will.
- You won't.
Say, this is a new angle
in song plugging.
If Dixie wants me to sing it,
I'm gonna sing it.
You do, and I'll knock it
back in your teeth.
Hey, Buddy.
Now, ladies and gentlemen...
...I would like to sing for the first time,
a song written by Miss Dixie Donegan...
...and Mr. Eddie Crane.
It's always a pleasure
to introduce any song of theirs...
...especially since my very lovely
little friend Miss Dixie Donegan...
...is our guest here tonight.
Well, how do you like that?
You ought to take a poke
at that guy.
You can't tell me she's not stuck on him.
I'm not trying to.
Your words
And my music
Could make such a beautiful song
A simple chorus
As warm as the spring
We'll get our big thrill
When we hear everyone singing
Your words
And my music
And although its theme may be worn
With your words
And my music
A wonderful love song
Is born
Boy, when he sings like that
I gotta forgive him.
Yeah.
You can't blame Dixie for falling for him.
With your words
And my music
A wonderful love song
Is born
That's fine, Mr. Crawford.
You can now go over and sit
with the very lovely Miss Donegan.
Eddie, why don't you go to bed
and get a good night's sleep?
Sleep? Are you kidding?
Well, then let's go out someplace
where we can get a drink.
No.
Oh, don't take it so tough, kid.
Suppose they do get married.
There's always a chance
they won't get along.
Look at your own case.
Your words
My music
Could make a beautiful song
A simple chorus
Warm as the spring
We'll get our big thrill
When we hear everybody singing
Your words
My music
And though its theme may be worn
Your words
Your words and my music
I wonder where I parked my car.
Your words
My tune
Such a lovely love song is born
Is born
Hello, Lull.
Gee, I didn't know you couldn't sing.
Hello, chums.
- Hello.
- I just caught you on the air, Buddy.
- No kidding, you were terrific.
- Gee, thanks.
- Even Eddie had to admit it.
- Well.
- Eddie?
- We were listening up at his place.
- Why didn't you bring him along?
- I tried to, but he was too tired.
He'd rather stay home all night
over a hot torch.
I never saw such a guy.
The minute he heard you were
with Buddy, he starts to burn.
Oh, but this is strictly business,
Buddy's our salesman.
Don't give me that old
"business" business.
Say, Red.
- Yes?
Why don't you open that little door
and fly back into the clock?
Open what door?
What clock?
Oh. Yeah.
Well, what are you in hysterics about?
Good evening, Mr. Crane.
- Where's Miss Donegan's table?
- Oh, she's right over there.
Thanks.
Hello.
Well, as I live and breathe, it's Torchy.
Hello, Eddie.
Why, Eddie, Red said you'd gone to bed.
Oh, yeah. Well, I just went
down to the corner to get a paper...
...and on the way back,
I saw the lights burning...
...so I thought I'd drop in.
- Well, sit down.
- Thanks.
Eddie, I'm sorry
about the misunderstanding at the club.
It wasn't any misunderstanding.
I just have to be careful about my hands
on account of playing the piano.
- Well, what happened?
- Oh, it wasn't anything.
Just a little argument.
Eddie went out
and left Buddy standing there.
Dixie, I wanna talk to you.
Well, all right.
No, I mean, alone.
Well, I'll just send everybody home,
huh?
No, Dixie, I'm in earnest.
Well, I'm in a party,
so you'll just have to wait.
This steak big enough, sir?
Well, just a moment.
Would you try that for size?
- Bring two of those.
- Two?
Yeah, one for me
and another one for her.
Now I'd like to present,
for the first time at the Club Sirocco...
...three solid citizens
who are definitely out of this world.
And at all times,
they are really cooking with gas.
Ladies and gentlemen, the Berry Brothers.
Ah
You'll never know
If an apple is ripe
Till you bite it
You bite it
Whoa
You'll never know
If fire's going to burn
Till you light it
You light it
You strike a match and light it
Say, you'll never know
What it means to be blue
Till you've lost an old friend
You'll never know
Just how long is the road
Till you've reached
The
Until
You've
Reached the end
You'll never, never know
That you've got a friend
You'll never know
How good a book is
Till you read it
You really, really do, yeah
You'll never know
What a kind word can do
Till you said it
You need to say it
But if you say it
You and I could find romance
But, honey
Till you take that chance
You'll never, never, never ever
No, you'll never ever, never
Never ever, ever
Never know
If you can spare me for a moment,
I'll dance with Marilyn.
Why, certainly, Buddy.
Dixie, let's get out of here.
Well, I can't leave now.
- Why not?
- Because I came with Buddy.
I can't be rude to him.
Well, I can and it would be a pleasure.
Oh, Eddie, you're a big boy now.
I'm big enough to know
that Buddy's not to blame.
You're not being very pleasant.
I'm beginning to realize
what's really cooking.
- What do you mean?
- You're chasing after him.
Never a dull moment, I often say.
And what's more, if that's
what you want, you got it.
But count me out.
Hello, darling.
Oh, hello, Marilyn.
Hello, Eddie. Come in.
What, more flowers?
- Well, I...
- Say, I could choke you.
I've done nothing all day
but unwrap these flowers, and all for Dixie.
You know, I live here too.
You could have at least sent me
a piece of lettuce or something.
Oh, I'm sorry, Marilyn.
Gee, they look kind of lost in here,
at that.
If you'd been on your toes...
...you would have ordered a nice big
weeping willow for the middle of the room.
- I thought Dixie was gonna be here.
- She should be here any moment now.
A breakfast date at 11,
luncheon date at 12.
Oh, breakfast and luncheon, huh?
You think she could sandwich me in
around tea time? Just between crumpets?
Oh, I think so, Eddie.
She hasn't planned anything till dinner.
I hope she wasn't sore about last night.
I didn't mean to crash your party at the club
but I wanted to tell her something and...
Well, I guess I kind of lost my temper.
Is she very mad at me?
I don't think she gave it another thought.
I'm terribly relieved.
Hello, baby.
Gee, are the flowers still coming?
- Hello.
- Hello, Dixie.
I'm sorry to be late, Eddie.
Darling, any calls for me?
Yeah, phone's been jangling
like an ambulance.
- The messages are on your table.
- Oh, I'll have to phone back later.
You wanted to work, didn't you?
- I certainly do.
- Well, I'll hold everybody off.
We have to be ready early tonight.
We're going to Westchester.
I'll jump right in the tub with the lilacs.
Eddie, the flowers are beautiful.
I feel kind of silly getting so many.
Didn't you feel kind of silly
sending them?
No, I felt all right.
Here's a little garnish on the side.
More?
Oh, and another one.
Oh. It's from Buddy.
Now, isn't that sweet?
- Say, Dixie, about last night...
- Let's not talk about last night, Eddie.
No personalities between us.
I didn't mean that.
I meant that melody I was talking about.
I got a hunch if we get steamed up now
we can knock this town dead.
- Really?
- Sure. Only we gotta work more.
We gotta work harder.
We gotta work mornings,
afternoons, evenings.
Work, work, work till we get it.
Oh, you can do it, Dixie.
You write wonderful lyrics.
Why, as a team, we could be tops.
If we get to winging we could write
the words and music to that Hopkins show.
Now, how would you like that?
- Oh, it's a pretty tough assignment.
- Oh, that's no way to talk.
A couple of more hits and we'll be a cinch.
Nothing's too tough.
- I'm busy. I've got a dinner date tonight.
- Cancel it.
Doesn't a career mean anything to a gal
with talent like you got? Come on, Dixie.
Get out that old hanky.
Here. Here's the way it starts.
Oh, Eddie, I don't feel like it.
I'm not in the mood.
Oh, you can do it, kid.
Get in there and slug.
Come on, Dixie. Make with
those good old Donegan words.
Well, I'll try. Play it over again.
Attagirl, baby, turn on the heat.
My one and only
I am so lonely
I can't believe that it's really you
Somehow it's just too good to be true
You are the sweetest
You are so lovely
So sweet and lovely
Oh, sweet and lovely
Hey. "Oh, sweet and lovely. "
Can it be true
You are the one
Baby, be mine
Baby, be mine.
Oh, sweet and lovely
Baby, be mine
Baby, be good
Lady, be good
That's it. "Lady, be good. "
Oh, sweet and lovely
Lady, be good
Yeah.
Oh, sweet and lovely
Lady, be good
Oh, lady, be good to me
How's that?
I am so awfully misunderstood
So, lady, be good to me
Oh, I don't know what to say now
Oh, please have some pity
Pity, pity, pity. What rhymes with pity?
Kitty, ditty, witty, city.
City.
Oh, please have some pity
I'm all alone in this big city
Wait a minute.
I got myself all alone now.
I'm just a lonesome babe in the wood
So lady, be good to me
- Oh, honey, that's swell.
- You think so?
Lt'll be a smash.
Wait till Max hears this.
Yeah. When he hears it, he'll take out
his cigar, flip off the ashes and say:
"Well, kids, if I'm any judge,
I think we got a hit in our hands. "
I hope so.
Oh, sweet and lovely
Lady, be good
Oh, lady, be good to me
- I am so awfully...
- Misunderstood.
Misunderstood
So, lady, be good to me
Oh, please have some pity
I'm all alone in this big city
I tell you, I'm just a lonesome
Babe in the wood
So, lady, be good to me
- Well?
Well, kids, if I'm any judge,
I think we've got a hit on our hands.
Get me an arranger.
Oh, sweet and lovely
Lady, be very good
To me
Oh, please have some pity
I'm all alone in this big city
Oh, sweet and lovely
Lady, be good
Oh, lady, be good to me
I am so awfully misunderstood
So, lady, be good to me
Oh, please have some pity
I'm all alone in this big city
I'm just a lonesome
Babe in the wood
So, lady, be good to me
Oh, sweet and lovely
Lady, be good
Oh, lady, be good to me
Oh, sweet and lovely
Lady, be good, be good
Oh, be good to me
Oh, me bambina, please-a be good
Oh, hot potato, you gotta be good
Oh, dark and handsome
Won't you be good?
Now, ladies and gentlemen...
...number one on your hit parade...
...for the 10th consecutive week,
"Lady Be Good. "
Fellow members and guests.
Obviously, this is not an official meeting
of our organization.
The food was too good.
Every once in a while
we can meet unofficially...
...without discussing songwriting
or the problems of song publishing.
I might say we are forced
to meet socially at times.
Now, don't get me wrong.
I mean that one of our members,
or perhaps two, as is the case tonight...
...have distinguished themselves so it
is impossible for us to ignore the fact...
...that a proper tribute is due to them
and should be paid.
On these occasions in the past,
we've honored such beloved members...
...as Victor Herbert, George Gershwin,
Oscar Hammerstein, and Jerome Kern.
This is our opportunity to show
our appreciation to these members...
...who've helped make the
Songwriters and Publishers Association...
...the truly great organization it is.
A few months ago, an established
songwriting team decided to split up.
In the vernacular of Tin Pan Alley...
...the perfect wedding of words
and music were divorced.
But I'm sure that all of you
share my happiness...
...in knowing that Dixie Donegan and
Eddie Crane are working together again.
And once more they've written themselves
to the very pinnacle of our profession.
Whatever else has happened
is none of my business or yours.
What matters to us is that they've given
the world another great song.
And when you hear Dixie sing it,
I think you'll feel as I do:
That this isn't just another work
by two songwriters.
It's as if they had
a hundred million collaborators.
The Americans who feel in their hearts...
...what Eddie and Dixie have written
so beautifully in their song.
I refer to the tender and affectionate
salute to a lost city...
..."The Last Time I Saw Paris. "
A lady known as Paris
Romantic and charming
Has left her old companions
And faded from view
Lonely men with lonely eyes
Are seeking her in vain
Her streets are where they were
But there's no sign of her
She has left
The Seine
The last time I saw Paris
Her heart was warm and gay
I heard the laughter of her heart
In every street caf
The last time saw Paris
Her trees were dressed for spring
And lovers walked beneath those trees
And birds found songs to sing
I dodged the same old taxicabs
That I had dodged for years
The chorus of their squeaky horns
Was music to my ears
The last time I saw Paris
Her heart was warm and gay
No matter how they change her
I'll remember her
That way
I'll think of happy hours
And people who shared them
Old women selling flowers
In markets at dawn
Children who applauded Punch and Judy
In the park
And those who danced at night
And kept our Paris bright
Till the town
Went dark
The last time I saw Paris
Her heart was warm and gay
I heard the laughter of her heart
In every street caf
The last time I saw Paris
Her trees were dressed for spring
And lovers walked beneath those trees
And birds found songs to sing
I dodged the same old taxicabs
That I had dodged for years
The chorus of their squeaky horns
Was music to my ears
The last time I saw Paris
Her heart was warm and gay
No matter how
They change her
I'll remember her
That way
- Oh, gee. That was terrific, wasn't it?
- Mm-hm.
We've come a long way
from Tin Pan Alley, honey.
Funny.
I was remembering too.
That was a swell speech
that Max made about us, wasn't it?
Wonderful.
"The perfect wedding of words
and music," he said.
- Remember?
- Mm-hm.
Oh, Dixie, why can't we make it
a real wedding again?
Can't we?
I think our present arrangement
is very good for us.
- What's good about it?
- Well, you're...
I mean, we're writing again.
Oh, I can write
under any circumstances.
- Except when we're married.
- That's ridiculous.
No, it isn't.
You're ambitious now, Eddie.
You want things.
That's an awful good sign,
wanting things.
Oh, it is, is it?
If all you want is the writing I can do,
we'd better call the whole thing off.
Oh, but, darling,
I've enjoyed your company too.
- Thanks. Thanks too much.
- Oh, Eddie, don't you understand?
All I understand is everything was swell...
...until you twisted me around your finger
and talked me into a divorce.
- I talked you...?
- Yes, you did, don't argue, it's true.
And then a very funny thing.
All of a sudden that palooka
of a sob singer appears on the scene.
Don't be so darn silly.
You have no reason to be jealous.
I'm not jealous.
But will you kindly explain
Buddy Crawford?
But he's jealous of you.
He's jealous of...?
Why, the conceit of the guy.
I never heard of such a thing.
- That's what I tell him.
- Oh, you do, do you?
Well, I'm tired of the whole setup.
This is the end.
You can't make a chump out of me.
I know what's going on.
I'm not gonna stand for it.
Come back here and behave yourself.
Now, you think I'm blind?
I wasn't born yesterday.
- Say, who writes your corny material?
- Never mind.
You won't have to put up with it
any longer.
From now on, I'll go my way
and you can go yours.
Hello, Marilyn.
- Hello, Buddy.
- Hi.
- Forgive me for phoning you.
- I like to hear from the girl I'm gonna marry.
Mr. Crawford, isn't this rather sudden?
Have you asked your mother's consent?
She told me
when I found a girl crazy about me...
...just go right ahead and marry her,
so we're all set.
Well, wasn't that sweet of her?
No, seriously, I wanna talk to you
about the divorce.
Well, what about our children?
No, all joking aside, Buddy.
I'm really worried about Dixie's divorce.
We've got to do something about it.
I thought the judge
did a fair job on it.
- What's there left for us to do?
- We've got to get them back together.
She's really madly in love with Eddie,
and I think he is with her.
What do you want me to do? Put him
on my knee and be a mother to him?
- I have a good idea.
- I have a better one.
- You and I get married. Set an example.
- Now, now, now. I've got it all planned.
We've gotta do something
to make Eddie jealous.
That guy's so jealous,
you can hear him sizzle on a clear day.
That's the point. It only needs
one gesture on your part.
My part? Listen, I almost got punched
in the nose for no good reason at all.
You know that guy's temper.
What are you trying to cook up, a homicide?
Now, don't be frightened, junior.
Mother won't let you get hurt. I only
want you to send Dixie a diamond ring.
A diamond what? Hey, what is this?
When Eddie hears that,
he'll have Dixie in front of a preacher...
...before you can get the ring back.
This has gone far enough.
I refuse to be made a...
You're a dear, Buddy. When you
pick out the ring, be sure it's big.
- But suppose she accepts it?
- Accept a ring from you?
Oh, don't be ridiculous, darling.
Well, how do I like that?
Hello, Buttons.
Oh, have I got a surprise for you.
Come on, look what I have.
Come here. Buttons.
Come here. Stand up.
Stand up. Speak.
Oh! Marilyn, you scared me to death.
Come here, darling.
There. Don't you say thank you?
Oh, he never says a word.
What are you doing on the floor?
Working on some steps
for my new number.
Oh, it looks great.
Yeah, now if I can just do what I draw.
Marilyn, you just worry
about drawing what you do.
How come you and Eddie
didn't work today?
Oh, we were going to, but we had kind
of an argument last night after the banquet.
After Max's swell speech about you?
I thought you two would be back
together again for keeps.
What a spot to be in.
A woman who doesn't dare marry
her own husband.
Now, let's see.
What's the matter, Buttons?
Oh.
Well, come on.
Oh, so you wanna get in
on this thing too, huh?
Thought you did.
Come on, faster.
Come on, once more. Come on.
Come on.
Now, sit down. I got work to do.
Then:
Now for a little music.
Oh, so you don't like the hula, huh?
Bet you can't do it.
Sounded good. How did it go?
Oh, pretty good, Dixie.
They just phoned from downstairs to tell us
to get the horse out of the apartment.
Oh, look at this room.
Well, wait a minute. I'll help.
Oh, wait a minute. I'll get it.
It might be somebody...
- Mrs. Edward Crane?
- Yes.
Sign here, lady.
- Surprise?
- I think so.
Oh, it's simply beautiful, Dixie.
- Why, I might have chosen it myself.
- Marilyn.
Who's it from?
Oh, no card, but I know.
- Buddy?
- Uh-huh.
- Buddy? Oh, heavens, no. Eddie.
- Oh.
After last night's scene,
this is his way of apologizing.
He always does something like this
to take my mind off the real issue.
- Oh. That's Eddie.
- Oh, I'll get it.
It's probably for me.
I'm expecting a call.
Hello? Hello, Eddie. This is Marilyn.
Oh.
- Hello, Dixie.
- Hello, Buddy.
- Can I come in?
- Oh, of course.
Oh, well, come in.
Thank you.
Oh, can I take your hat?
- That's a lovely new ring you're wearing.
- Yes.
How did you guess it was new?
I didn't have to guess it was new.
I knew it was new.
- How do you like it?
- Oh, Buddy, I think it's beautiful.
Thank you.
Darling, it looks exactly like you.
Buddy.
Well, we are engaged, aren't we?
Oh, Buddy, you didn't send...
Well, I thought Eddie...
- Oh, you did send it, didn't you?
- Well, what's so awful about that?
- Nothing. I couldn't possibly...
- You keep that thing on.
I want Marilyn to know about this.
I want the whole world to know about it.
- No... You mustn't...
- Let me do the talking from now on.
- From now on I'll do the talking.
- I couldn't take this.
Well, anyway, I thought you'd
like to know she got the ring.
And is she thrilled. It's beautiful.
What ring? I never sent her a ring.
Well, somebody did.
And it's a diamond too.
And it's as big as an ink well.
What?
I don't know what's going on,
but I'm coming over to find out.
Tell her I think I'll bring a gun
and cause some trouble.
I'm not gonna stand for this.
Gun? Oh, Eddie, I was only kidding.
Honestly.
I didn't mean for you to go that far.
Hello, Eddie? Eddie? Gun?
- You've made me the happiest man.
- Dixie, come quick.
I've gotta see you alone for a moment.
Please, hurry. Hurry.
Hello, Buddy.
Something awful has happened.
That was Eddie on the phone.
- He's got a gun. He's on his way here.
- A gun? What for?
- He's gonna shoot somebody. Probably you.
- Me?
- Yes. Come on.
- You didn't tell him about the ring?
Well, I might have mentioned it.
But I didn't know he was a killer.
Help me get into my things.
- All right.
- I don't wanna get shot looking like this.
Hey, driver, quit dragging your feet.
I'm in a hurry.
Never mind your hat.
What's the matter?
- Is that my picture?
Not yet. Come on, we better hurry.
We've gotta hit the road.
Come on, Buddy.
- Come on, Buddy.
- Hey, what's happened?
Too late.
- What'll we do?
- Who is it?
- It's Eddie.
- So what?
- He's got a gun.
- He's gonna shoot us.
- Hide.
- Let's hide. Get behind the curtain.
- You get behind the curtain.
- No, you.
Why should I hide? You hide.
He's after you, not me. I hope.
Come on, Buddy.
Sit down and act natural.
Well, it's my apartment.
I guess I'll have to face him.
- Hey, Dixie.
- What?
Will you hide? He can see you.
Eddie, don't shoot. Don't shoot.
I can explain everything. It's all my fault.
- Where is Dixie?
- She's not exactly here.
- She sort of went out.
- Well, I'll find out if she did or not.
- Hello.
- Now I know she's here.
- Where's my wife?
- Married again? Congratulations.
- Trot her out.
- How? She's not here. Look for yourself.
- I suppose you two were alone, huh?
- Why not?
- Yeah, why not?
- We like it.
I know which way the wind's blowing.
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
Buddy and I've been good friends
for a long time.
We've been more than just good friends.
We've been...
Haven't we?
- Absolutely.
- There you are, the man admits it.
Pretty smart, Marilyn,
but I don't believe it.
Aha.
Come out, Dixie.
I know where you are.
Well, satisfied?
- Well, I don't understand it.
- Neither do I.
Maybe she isn't here.
Doesn't explain what you're doing here.
Oh, Eddie, don't be embarrassing.
What difference does that make?
All right, all right, I'm going.
But I'm not convinced.
Sorry.
Well...
I guess you both must think
I'm kind of daffy.
- You want the truth?
- What?
- You are.
- Who's daffy?
- You are. About Dixie.
- Eh.
Oh, darling.
Well, what happened to you?
Well, you won't think
I'm silly, will you?
- Why should I think you're silly?
- Well, it's about Dixie.
Eddie's so jealous that
I'm beginning to wonder too.
There's nothing between you, is there?
Oh, it'd break my heart if there was.
Tell me there isn't.
Well, opportunity, knock once more.
Quit it. You have no right.
You're taking advantage.
- This time we don't get away.
- Quit it.
- You have no right.
- I've waited for this.
- You're taking advantage.
- But, darling, I love you.
- Help! Dixie!
- I love you, I love you, I...
...love you.
Help, Dixie, help. Help!
Dixie, help.
- Let me up.
- Buddy. Stop it, you wolf, you.
I thought so.
I knew there was some...
What an act. What an act.
Oh, you opportunist, you.
A frame-up, huh?
Why didn't you come out in the open?
I didn't wanna get shot
by a mad musician.
- How about that diamond ring?
- I haven't accepted it yet.
- Who gave it to you?
- I gave it to her.
How do you like that? Give one gal a ring
then take advantage of her friend.
- How could you fall for such a jerk?
- Remember your temper.
- You've got a gun in that pocket.
- No, I haven't. I couldn't find one.
They're pearls, see? They were for you.
I'm gonna give them back to the oysters.
You pulled the wool over my eyes
once too often.
Do something,
or I'll never speak to you again.
Ow! Look here, it may interest you
to know...
Nothing you could say could interest me.
- That's what I thought.
- Eddie.
Wait a minute.
Marilyn, will you and Buddy go out
and have dinner someplace?
I wanna settle a few things with Eddie.
We're on our way, Dixie.
We'll be over at Twenty-One.
Eddie, come here.
Now, sit down.
- Eddie, I...
- I suppose...
...you wanna talk
about our working together again.
Dixie, darling,
I don't think I could take it.
You see, I...
I'd keep watching you.
The funny little way you turn your head...
...and the way you pull on your ear
when you haven't got an idea.
Oh, I couldn't take it, kid. I'm sorry.
Oh, Eddie,
what's the matter with you, anyway?
Do you have to be hit in the head
with a hammer?
Huh?
Oh, darling, how could you ever think
I could love anybody else?
The ring was a mistake, that's all.
A misunderstanding.
- Yeah?
- Oh, Eddie...
...I couldn't think of marrying him.
Well, then you're not sore at me?
I'm furious with you.
Oh, Dixie.
I guess you still love me, huh?
Oh, who else?
Marry me tonight.
- Oh, I shouldn't.
- I dare you.
- I shouldn't.
Do you, Dixie Donegan, take this man
for your lawful wedded husband?
Answer, "I do. "
I do.
And do you, Edward Crane, take this
woman for your lawful wedded wife?
Yeah, I do.
Well, I certainly am Joe the Jerk.
I risk my life to carry out your plans,
the two characters get married...
...and what do I get?
You're too impulsive, Buddy.
And anyway, I'm a little worried
about your intentions.
- What do you mean? I did all right.
- That's just it.
You were either loving that scene with Dixie
or you're the greatest faker.
Oh, darling, that's what I love about you.
You're so doggone consistent.
Why consistent?
You get me to make a play for your
best friend against my best friend...
...and then you rule me out for holding.
But I love you, you're wonderful.
Well, you know,
I have some emotions of my own.
Even I could have been a bit jealous.
You are?
I guess I kind of fell for my own formula.
Why didn't you tell me when we were
with the guy with the Book?
- You didn't ask me.
- I didn't ask you.
And besides, you didn't have sense
to bring a license.
I didn't have sense enough...
Did you say license?
You big chump.
What are you thinking, Dixie?
I was just thinking
about the Hopkins show.
- Think what a chance that is for us.
- Yeah. Swell, isn't it?
Oh, it's more than swell, darling.
It's our wish fulfillment.
The one big chance we've waited for.
It's as if everything else of ours
was just building toward that.
Yeah, I know.
When do we start work on it, darling?
Oh, I don't know.
Soon as we get back, I guess.
I'm afraid I'll be too tired.
Couldn't you wait till tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
No, I mean, when we get back
from our honeymoon.
Honeymoon?
- Are you clowning?
- Certainly not.
I worked hard to win you back,
now can't we just play a while?
Oh, but Eddie, the show is so important.
I thought you felt that too.
Oh, it'll wait. We can knock that off
in a couple of weeks when we get back.
I was gonna surprise you. The Martins
are loaning us their place in Bermuda.
It's across the bay from Kiki Wendover.
She's asking the mob down for a month.
Think of the fun when I tell them
we're married.
They'll love you, Dixie.
What's the matter?
- Eddie.
- Yeah?
- I've just decided something.
- What?
We've got to go on working
just the way we were.
- What do you mean?
- This show has got to be our best effort.
- When it's a hit, we can go away and play.
- I don't see it that way.
- It's got to be that way. What's...
- What are you driving at?
- We're married, aren't we?
- Yes, finally.
But until we finish the Hopkins show,
I'm gonna keep right on living with Marilyn.
- What happened?
- Do you mean that?
- I do.
- You mean I gotta go on living alone?
- Until we...
- Well, I'm not.
And if you think I am,
you can get out of this car right here.
All right, Mr. Crane.
All out, kids. This is as far as we go.
- What's this all about?
- Don't ask me.
Go ahead, drive away if you dare.
And did he?
Yes.
- Well, how'd you get back to New York?
- Well, we:
I've always wanted to do that.
Well, proceed, Mrs. Crane.
The next day, when I got back,
Mr. Hopkins, the producer of the show...
...Eddie and I were supposed to write,
told me Eddie had quit.
Well, during this time, did the defendant
make any effort to see you?
None whatsoever.
- But...
- But what, Mrs. Crane?
I did see him once,
two weeks after we were married.
What was he doing?
Composing a symphony.
How did you find out all about this?
While the show was in rehearsal,
we needed a verse...
...for the big finale number in a hurry,
and I was stuck.
I didn't seem to get ideas the way
I used to.
I remembered a half-finished lyric
I'd left in our apartment...
...when Eddie and I were working together,
so I went up to get it.
- Dixie.
- Hello, Eddie.
- Hello.
- I hate to disturb you...
...but I'll have to look
for something I left here.
May I?
Why, sure. Sure, come on in.
Oh, uh...
Dixie, you remember Mrs. Wardley.
This is my... Uh...
- Miss Donegan.
- Yes, we've met.
Of course. How do you do?
Hello.
I didn't mean to make
a dramatic entrance.
I've just come to get a piece of paper
I left here a couple of hundred years ago...
...when I was working here.
That's quite all right.
Eddie's told me all about you.
Oh?
He has?
Well, Mrs. Wardley
is terribly interested in music.
Good music, that is.
So when I told her about the symphony
I'd always wanted to write...
...why, naturally...
- The what?
Well, I guess I never mentioned it to you.
- But I always felt that...
You see, Mrs. Crane...
...Eddie's never had a fair chance
to express himself.
Of course, he wrote some simply
divine little tunes, but...
With lyrics.
Yeah, with lyrics.
My wife wrote the lyrics.
Forgive me.
Of course, he did mention that.
The point is,
he wants to write something better.
That was just a step in his career.
- How was it you explained it to me?
- What?
About what you wanted to do,
you remember?
Oh.
Well, I just told Mrs. Wardley
that I was fed up writing popular songs.
Little jingles set to tunes.
Real music speaks a language
more eloquent than words.
Give me flutes, oboes, a string section.
- Carnegie Hall.
- And Carnegie Hall. I'll show them.
- Why, you're serious.
- Miss Donegan, you...
You keep out of this.
So you're gonna walk out on the show.
You're gonna let me down.
I thought we kissed that nonsense goodbye
two weeks ago in Connecticut.
You might have had
the common decency to let me know.
- Did I hear you say "common decency"?
- Symphony, eh?
I thought I'd heard everything.
- But, Miss Donegan...
- You keep quiet and sit down.
I came to get a lyric
and I'm not leaving without it.
- Get up.
- Leave her alone.
I wouldn't think of touching
a hair of that divine coiffure.
But my lyric is in this piano seat.
Words, get it? Words.
Yeah, well, the words I've got
I can't use in front of a lady.
Oh, and you will let me hear
your symphony, won't you?
When you hear it, it'll be at Carnegie Hall,
and it'll cost you $3.30.
When you hear this it'll be
at the Melody Box Theatre...
...and it'll cost you $5.50.
You can get it
From the blare of a trumpet
You can get it from the wail
Of a slide trombone
You can get it from the slap
Of a big string bass
Or the moan of a saxophone
And every time I hear a band
Start playing
Whether it be fast or sweet and low
From the very moment it starts beating
Everything about me starts repeating
Drums roll
Saxes moan
Trumpets blare
Fascinatin' rhythm
You got me on the go
I'm all a quiver
What a mess you're makin'
The neighbors wanna know
Why I'm always shakin'just like a flivver
Each morning I get up with the sun
Start a-hoppin', never stoppin'
To find at night no work has been done
I know that once it didn't matter
But now you're doin' wrong
When you start to patter
I'm so unhappy
Won't you take a day off?
Decide to go away
Somewhere far away off
And make it snappy
Oh, how I long to be the girl
I used to be
Fascinatin' rhythm
Oh, won't you stop pickin' on me?
Da-da-di-ah
Dah
Oh, how I wish they'd take it away
Take it away from me
That rhythm hangs around me all
Da-da-da-da
Da-da-di-ah-dah
Da-da-da-di-ah-dah
I know that rhythm is cruel to me
Rhythm is ruinin' me
Makin' a fool of me
Stop it
Fascinatin' rhythm
Won't you stop pickin' on me
You got me on the go
Fascinatin' rhythm
I'm all a quiver
What a mess you're makin'
The neighbors should go
I'm always shakin' like a flivver
Each morn as I'm wakin' up
Very happy
Just to find that no work has been done
Once it didn't matter
But now you do wrong
- When you start to patter
- I'm so unhappy
Won't you take a day off?
A couple of weeks
Somewhere far away off
And make it snappy
Oh, how I long to be the man
That I used to be
Fascinatin' rhythm
Won't you stop pickin' on me?
Yes, I liked that number very much.
Oh, thank you.
- I didn't know you'd seen the show.
- Oh, yes. I was there the opening night.
And that was an amazing dance,
young lady.
Take a bow.
Thank you, sir.
Proceed with the case, Mr. Blanton.
Your Honor...
...it seems fairly obvious in the absence
of counsel for the defendant...
...and no evidence in any form to refute
the charge of intolerable cruelty...
...that my client's case is defined.
We rest, Your Honor.
- Is Mr. Edward Crane in court?
- No, Your Honor.
Do you know Mr. Crane's whereabouts?
Well, the last thing I heard,
he was taking a boat to South America.
A vacation, judge.
Mrs. Crane, it is within my jurisdiction
to grant this divorce.
The last divorce awarded you by me...
...was granted on the grounds
of incompatibility, is that right?
- Yes, Your Honor.
- Yes.
Well, now, this time,
you say it's intolerable cruelty.
Let's see.
"Defendant failed to fulfill
his marital obligations.
Lived apart from the plaintiff
for a period of more than six months. "
I take it, then, that you've
ceased to love one another.
- I didn't say that.
- But you still want a divorce.
- Yes.
Well, you're not going to get it.
- But, Your Honor, I object.
- Objection overruled.
Young lady...
...when I was a boy there was a strange
custom in this country...
...that when a fellow and a girl fell in love,
they got married and stayed that way.
And fought to make a go of it.
Now, I gave you that first divorce...
...because I knew one of two things
was going to happen:
If you didn't love each other sincerely...
...why, the divorce would stand,
and if you did, you'd get married again.
Now, once married you're not going
to get another divorce out of this court.
Not while I've the strength to lift a gavel.
So go home and behave yourself.
Case dismissed.
I beg your pardon, sir. Judge.
I thought you'd turn up.
You can't do this to me.
I have a right to be represented.
I love my wife.
- Oh, this must be Mr. Crane.
- Yes, sir.
What are all these things
I can't do to you?
You can't divorce us.
I have something to say.
I demand as a citizen
the right to trial and free speech.
I love Mrs. Crane
and no man can put us asunder.
"Until death do us part. "
Well, now, suppose you're too late?
You mean she's been here?
But you can't do that, judge.
I'm sure that isn't legal.
Look, young fellow,
contrary to your conception...
...this is a court of law,
and not a matrimonial pinball game.
I'm not here to establish a record
for marital hits and home runs.
But I'm here to mete out justice
to the best of my ability...
...from the evidence presented.
Your wife and her attorney were here...
...and they gave their testimony
as to your negligence.
- But, Your Honor...
- Your negligence and indifference...
...as a husband.
Why, they even indicated
that you were writing a symphony.
Oh, that. That was months ago.
I didn't even finish it.
- Good.
- I beg your pardon?
Oh, nothing, nothing.
At the conclusion of their testimony,
I was obliged to render a decision.
The only decision I could that would
be right under the circumstances.
But there's only one circumstance,
I love her.
Well, I'm very sorry,
but the case is entirely out of my hands.
Step on it. Drive like a maniac.
I've gotta catch her.
Catch her? You just left her.
- No, I was too late.
- Oh.
Say, won't this thing go any faster?
What do you mean? We're going 92 now.
Oh, that's 29.
Hey, there's Buddy's car. Stop.
Back up. Hurry up.
What do you want me to do,
go in sideways?
I don't care.
- Marilyn?
- Why, Eddie Cranes.
- Where have you been?
- Where did you come from?
- South America.
- Leave your boat outside?
- Where's Dixie?
- On the terrace.
- She wanted to be alone for a minute.
- Well, she isn't gonna be.
Dixie.
- Eddie.
- Oh, darling.
Edward Crane.
What do you mean rushing in
and scaring me half to death?
Do you realize I haven't seen you
for six months?
Oh, I've been wrong, darling,
I know it.
But I'm cured now.
You gotta take me back.
Well, isn't this kind of sudden?
Don't you think you might do
a little explaining?
Well, I went away alone.
This time I had to be sure.
I am now, honest.
People, songs, even pianos don't mean
a thing anymore, honey.
From now on, it's only you.
- Oh, Eddie, are you sure? It's been so...
- I'm positive.
I want you to marry me again.
Well, haven't you heard?
Hasn't anyone told you?
Yes, but that's a lot of nonsense, darling.
You still love me, don't you?
Oh, Eddie, I love you very much.
But I won't ever marry you again.
Darling, I can't stand it any longer.
I'm going crazy living alone.
You won't have to anymore.
Hey, wait a minute. We're not married.
- Eddie?
- Hm?
- Will you do me a favor?
- Mm-hm.
Will you keep right on thinking
we're not?
Oh, boy, that's a cue for a song
if I ever saw one.
Oh, sweet and lovely
Lady, be good
Oh, baby, be good to me
I am so awfully misunderstood
Oh, please have some pity
I'm all alone in this big city
I'm just a lonesome babe in the wood
So, lady, be good to me