''These moments, these memories,
l'll cherish for years to come''
''Should these seasons go away,
l'll complain''
''l'll remember these moments
for years to come''
''lf these seasons go away,
l'll complain''
Don't they suffer the heat, Daija?
Stop the car.
-Why Daija?
What are you doing?
Come. You also get down.
Get down.
But it's a desert!
- Bow to this land.
Bow? What for?
Because you're here
for the first time.
This is the threshhold
of your house.
Won't just folding my hands do?
The ground must be very hot.
Okay, okay, don't look like that.
l said, bow to it.
Sit down, sit down. There is no escape
from this.
You used to pine for this desert
out there?
This is not just a desert.
Just look around, it's full
of your family's legends
Legends don't have to bear the heat.
Else, they'd get a sun-stroke too!
Keep quiet.
Just see, they are sitting as though
this desert is air-conditioned!
What stuff are these
people made of?
They are made out of
the local soil.
They're as seasoned as
the tree above them.
Papa migrated before
l was born, else...
When this sun seasons you too
in a couple of days,...
and when it narrates to you the
unlimited legends of your ancestors...
you too will be happy.
After signing the papers,...
l'll catch the first flight
to London.
As you command.
Don't use that tone with me, please.
l feel as though you're scolding me!
l am scolding you!
Okay, l'll do my work,
bow to the land...
seek your permission,
then go away. Happy?
Forget all that for now.
Your talk has moved the
mansion itself to hug you!
Greetings - Greetings - Greetings
- Greetings - Come, Let's go.
His Lordship has
certainly grown up!
This is the caretaker
of this place. Mr. Tiwari.
What's all this farce?
- Tradition, son.
Your father went abroad, but your
parents' portraits hang here.
Parents don't have feet,
you see...
Can l remove this garland now?
Our neighbour, Mr. Thakur is here. -Okay.
Who is he?
He's not just a neighbour, but
a very good friend of your father.
When the world had deserted him,
this man stood firmly by him.
Don't just greet him casually,
but bow to him,...
and address him respectfully, come.
When kids grow, their place is not
at one's feet. lt's in one's heart.
l've come here after 18 years today.
Just to embrace you, son.
l don't commit a faux pas, did l?
No. You just reminded him
of your father.
And the proud local men and women
don't let their tears be seen.
Come, l'll show you your room.
Y
''O dear clouds...''
''O dear clouds''
''Your heart is definitely yearning,
the way you're showering...''
''whom have you fallen
in love with?''
''O dear cloud...''
''My state is
somewhat like yours''
''Your state is
somewhat like theirs''
''Drench me in rains, O clouds''
''for someone has
uttered my name''
''O dear clouds...''
''O dear clouds''
''Tell us his name...
- No''
''Where does he live?''
''ls he a prince...?
Tell us''
''Spring has set in;
flowers blossom''
''My friends say things that
make me blush; lower my gaze...''
''O dear clouds''
''Why am l longing?
Why is it raining?''
''Whom am l missing?''
''Why am l yearning...?''
What are you thinking of, son?
Of you.
Of me? l'm a thing of the past now.
Think of the days to come.
Don't avoid the issue.
You brought me to my home.
But surely you have a home too.
You haven't talked about it
till today.
Yes. And that's strange, isn't it?
l had totally forgotten.
You have reminded me that l too
had a home once.
but so much time has gone by...
that l didn't even think of it.
lt's only your voice
that echoes in my ears.
May you live long, son.
''These moments, these memories,
l'll cherish for years to come''
''And if these seasons change,
l'll beg for them''
''These moments, these memories,
l'll cherish for years to come''
''And if these seasons change,
l'll beg for them''
Y
''From these glimpses
of my dreams...''
''from the bondage l share
with my memories...''
''how will l ever
set my heart free?''
''And if these seasons change,
l'll plead for them''
''These moments...''
What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
Do you remember that small boy
who used to tell me everything?
There's nothing to tell.
Then why are you sitting
in the dark like this?
l just thought somebody
would put the light on...
And suppose l hadn't, would you
have gone on sitting? Anyway...
you have to go to a dinner
at Mr. Thakur, remember?
l'm not in the mood.
lt's you who is invited,
not your mood.
You'll have to go. Come on.
Come my son, may you live long.
l can't tell you how happy l am
to see you here.
What happened?
Son is it burning too much?
lt's nothing serious.
You're great! lf l was in your shoes,
l'd have screamed this place down.
What's the fun in burning
without making a noise?
You know my name?
See what he's asking?
Whether you know us or not,
everybody out here knows you.
You're his Lordship from London.
And who am l?
l'm Pallavi.
- What are you...
And this uncle of yours,
l'm his only daughter.
Now don't say you're happy to meet me,
for it's all said and done.
You really made me wait.
Now he'll say,
he had a telephone call.
Sorry, but l got a call.
Just as l was through with that,
l got another call.
Just as l finished,
l got a call from the S.P.
l'm fed up with this telephone.
l think l'll have my line cut.
l'm really fed up with all this.
l'm thinking of having it disconnected.
He's a first class liar!
He's always like this.
And the funniest part is, everyone
knows he has no telephone!
''These moments,
l will remember for years''
''And when the seasons change,
l will complain''
''These moments,
l will cherish for years''
''lf the seasons change,
l will beg for them''
''Do not tease me, Lord Krishna''
''l'm only a milkmaid...
l'm not Radha''
''Do not tease me, Lord Krishna''
''l'm a milkmaid...
l'm not your beloved, Radha''
''Why have you held my hand?''
''l implore you, O Krishna''
''You are naughty, O Krishna''
''l'm only a milkmaid...
l'm not your beloved Radha''
''Do not tease me, O Krishna''
''lt's Radha you always tease''
''She's the one you love''
''Why have you doused
those colours on me?''
''For l am only a milkmaid...
l'm not your Radha''
''Do not tease me, O Krishna''
''l'm only a milkmaid...
l'm not your Radha''
''Do not tease me, O Krishna''
Greetings.
- Bless you, son.
Please have this.
ls this the way to
accept a blessing?
Come on, bow to me first.
l know my name, Papa.
Come on, bow to me.
- How can he do that?
Why? Has he hurt his spine?
And l'm elder to him too.
And what are you gawking at?
Come on, bow to me.
Enough, my child.
Okay, cup your hand please.
The right one.
Better you open your mouth!
What are you looking at him for?
Forgot your mouth at home? Open it.
You couldn't have had your breakfast?
- No.
So have it with me.
- Daija won't forgive me, if l do.
She won't mind if it's with me.
He must have had all his
favorite dishes made.
''Spicy Bread''
My mouth's watering, dad...
l'm having my breakfast at his place.
You go ahead and get it all ready.
l'll join you there a little later.
l feel like having breakfast
on the terrace.
Terrace? But it's cloudy today.
That's wonderful! You keep it ready.
l'll just join you.
lf it starts raining,
how will you eat?
You'll just get wet
for nothing.
A superb breakfast. All these tasty
things and the rain falling...
Daija can really cook well.
- Here, have this...
l can eat by myself now.
l've grown up.
Everybody grows up.
But no one outgrows one's elders.
No dear, he has
really grown up now.
You have grown big, Sir.
lt's my hands that are small.
Your hand is bigger than the sky.
You haven't seen Rajasthan,
have you?
Daija, never showed it to me.
- How could l?
lt's his first visit here.
Then l'll make it
unforgettable for him.
l'll show him around and
get him stuck on to it,...
like glue on an envelope!
Anyway, it's a wet day today.
We'll make it tomorrow. Okay?
There's a man from
your house, Madam.
l'll take your leave then.
Be ready tomorrow, Viren.
Let the rain stop, my dear.
- lt's okay.
Be ready, Viren.
ls she the reason why you're so lost
in your thoughts these days?
Yes.
But she's older than you.
So what? l'm also younger to her.
lt's quits.
But such things are not
accepted in this country.
Does she love you just as much?
l don't know.
But you must know.
l'll ask her then.
What's this?
- Pallavi has sent it for you.
For me?
A letter too?
With due regards, to
His Lordship of London.
You must have seen such a dress
in the old portraits.
But this is the real attire
of our ancestors.
Play the Rajput just for today,
else you'll look like a tourist.
And Rajasthan will not be
one with you.
l'll look a fool in this!
- Your ancestors didn't!
But l'm not an ancestor.
But why tell me all this?
Return it. You can explain it to her.
No. l'll wear it.
l will come downstairs only if
you shut your eyes, Daija.
All right.
You must promise not to laugh at me.
- l promise. l will not laugh.
Even if l feel like it.
You promised you wouldn't laugh!
Didn't l say l'd look mad?
l'm not going!
No... you don't look mad at all.
You look handsome.
Hurry up and leave.
They must be awaiting you.
Go on.
Do l look good?
- Very good.
Greetings, sir.
- Greetings. May we leave?
Have you brought the car?
- No, sir.
ln that case, l'll take my car.
No? How will go?
l've brought a camel, sir.
- A camel!
Go on.
Are you okay, sir?
Make it stand.
Steady...
Nothing's going to happen.
When l'm sad, l go to this place
l'm taking you to.
What do you do when you're sad?
- But l'm never sad.
You will be sad
when you're lonely.
The song means, ''When the peacock
calls during the night...''
''it pierces my heart
like a dagger''
''When the pea-hen
calls at midnight,...''
''My bangles...''
''My bangles tinkle, O Sir...
they tinkle in my hands''
''When the pea-hen calls in
the jungle at midnight''
''l literally die of shame,
when people listen to my love story''
''l literally die of shame when
people listen to my love story''
''lt was a slip of the tongue,
when l was chatting...''
''and then my bangles tinkled, O Sir,
they tinkled in my hands''
''As the pea-hen in the jungle
called out in the night''
''Whenever l see the moon in the sky,
my eyes overflow with tears''
''l don't know when my beloved left.
But l wilted within, over the years''
''My thirst was never quenched
even by the rains''
''And my bangles tinkled, O Sir,
they tinkled in my hands...''
''as the pea-hen called
in the night''
''Nights l have spent
lonely and sleepless''
''l have been robbed
of my sleep''
''Nights l have spent
lonely and sleepless''
''l have been robbed
of my sleep''
''My peace of mind
has left with my beloved''
''And my bangles tinkled, O Sir.
The bangles tinkled in my hands...''
''as the pea-hen
called in the night''
This is Salamat Ali, Sir.
- Yes, go on.
l'm sorry, but we have
lost the case, Sir.
What? We lost the case?
But how? You said...
l tried my best, Sir, but...
But your best wasn't enough.
You just lost a case,
but l've lost everything.
My wealth, this mansion,
everything....
What's happened?
- Nothing, my dear.
l'll call the doctor.
You wait here, Viren, l'll just come.
Please sit.
l want to talk to you.
Nobody knows, except me.
l had a case against my step-brother,
concerning our property.
Today the court has
ruled against me.
l'm not bothered about myself
- You'll be fine, Sir.
Pallavi will just die,
if she gets to hear of it.
Look after her.
Explain it to her.
l can't keep her to
anybody else's care.
Nothing will happen...
l've sent for the doctor.
Come dear;
l want to tell you something.
Whatever l'm telling you...
- Don't talk, Papa...
l've explained it to Viren here.
l've entrusted your responsibility
in his hands.
What do you mean?
Trust him, child.
Please rest now.
Don't talk.
l'm very worried about her.
She hasn't eaten for the past 2 days.
She's like a stone, she won't talk
neither will she listen.
Please do something.
Where had you been?
l was awaiting you for ages!
Cry, dear...
Go ahead and cry.
What's this?
l didn't know my eyes
held so many tears.
Your father mustn't be
liking you cry like this.
l'm not used to living without him.
What shall l do?
Face the facts, and learn
to live without him.
But how did this happen?
l don't know. lt was all so sudden.
But whatever he had to tell,
he told Viren.
Who's he?
The son of our neighbour.
The one who was here yesterday?
Will you listen to something
l have to say, Viren?
Why ask? Have l ever refused
to obey you?
ln that case, you must return
to London today itself.
You're being unfair, Daija.
You wouldn't let me return,
when l wanted to.
And now that l don't want to leave,
you're asking me to go away.
l have promised her father.
Mr. Siddharth is here
to see his Lordship.
Tell him that l'll be there.
Everything is well
over there, l hope?
Can't really say, your Lordship.
Call me Vir, Mr. Bhatnagar.
That also sounds very formal.
Call me Siddharth.
l don't know whether Pallavi
has mentioned me to you before.
No. Nothing.
We love each other...
But my family background
is not as colourful as yours.
Does that make any difference?
Not to me, and maybe even you.
But her father was very orthodox.
lt was very important to him.
Let alone a background,
l don't even have a family!
But then, your name...
l'm told l was found on a street
and brought up in an orphanage.
When it was time for me
to go to school...
a father's name was essential.
The manager liked me a lot,
so he put his own name for me.
l was a good student, so l won
scholarships and continued to study.
This way, an orphan became an
officer in the Air-Force...
and at an Air-Force function,
l met Pallavi.
l was very scared
of my feelings for her.
But she's a special girl -
said it made no difference to her.
And that she'd managed her father.
He's no more, so l thought
why get married here?
May l take her with me?
We'll get married there.
lf you don't mind, we'd prefer
that she weds here.
And the bridal-couple leave
her ancestral home together.
Have you spoken to her
about the wedding?
l thought l'd talk to Viren
and then he'd convince her..
Don't worry about that
l'll talk to her myself.
This is Salamat Ali speaking.
Yes?
l've spoken to them, like you asked.
But they are very adamant.
Bring them to me.
l know how to deal with such lot.
Whose phone was it?
Give me a list of your invitees.
l'll invite them all.
There'll be just two from my side.
Daija and yourself.
l'll go now.
l didn't show him my feelings,
did l?
No, son.
This is the mother of the deceased
and they are his...
Step-brothers. My sons.
You know what l want.
How will we know what
exactly you want?
l don't want the result of this case
disclosed to the family here.
Pallavi will have to be told.
She has to vacate the house.
We're sorry that he died
just after hearing the news.
We didn't have the pleasure
of throwing him out physically..
But this bitch...
lf you say anything vile against them,
l'll pull your tongue out.
Now listen to me.
Till she leaves the house
with her husband,...
you are to stay away from here.
What will you give us for that?
- What's your price?
When will she leave?
- Next week.
That means 6 days from now.
That makes it 600,000.
And one more extra for the slap
you gave me.
Give them a cheque of one million.
Today all my efforts
have been worth it.
Today you've really matured.
Today l feel like addressing you
with your Title.
l have arrived.
How are you?
- Losing some hair...
How come you're here?
Then would there be a wedding
without me?
There's something l wanted
to discuss with you.
One moment...
Greetings!
My name is Prem.
l'm Viren's childhood friend.
When l was 7 year's old...
Greetings- Greetings.
The girl's superb. When are you getting
married my dear...
You've just come. Have a wash,
then we'll chat...
What a girl, What a choice...
l admit she's so lovely.
lt won't be easy to forget her.
But you should have told her
of your feelings, at least once.
What difference would that have made?
She'd have loved her guy anyway.
Well, it's not the end
of the world!
Who knows?
But you....
There are no ''ifs''
and ''buts'' in love.
And before loving her, l hadn't put
a condition that she loves me too.
She loved Siddharth, she'll be
happy with him. That's all l want.
May God save you
from the evil-eye.
You always were beautiful. But never
as beautiful as you look today.
l miss my father very much.
That you will, all your life.
He always said he'd go
as ''dowry'' with you.
Now his memories are your dowry.
No, don't cry.
May God give you
a long happy life.
What's wrong with Viren?
He hasn't met me for days.
He's very busy with the preparations.
He's your care-taker now.
Tell him that l won't leave
without meeting him.
lf l see him,
l'll give him your message.
''This kurta that's
made of muslin...''
''come dressed in it''
''l await you at the door.
Come dressed in a muslin kurta...''
l was told you were
asking for me...
l don't know whether my father
was happy with my choice.
But since l'm in your charge...
tell me, do you approve?
Why not?
Questions are not answered
by counter questioning.
Are you happy?
Yes.
Then l am too.
l've been very bad to you.
l've really harassed you.
What nonsense!
You're very nice,
very decent.
lf l can ever be of help,
write to me.
Can l?
Go on.
Can l call you by
your first name?
Come, my dear. Everybody is waiting.
You too Viren.
''These moments, these memories,
l shall cherish for years to come''
''Should the seasons change,
l will beg for them''
''These moments, these memories,
l shall cherish for years to come''
''Should the seasons change,
l will appeal for them''
''l will cherish for years...''
May you live long.
Whenever you come, stay here a while.
Nobody should say the house is empty.
No, don't worry about that.
We'll look after the house
for you now.
What are these people doing here?
Tell her, Sir. She's asking
what are we doing here?
This is ours now. We were quiet,
because of Viren
Else we'd have thrown you out
six days ago.
Can't you people be polite?
Who is this guy? ls he trying
to teach us to be polite?
Don't ever think it's only the Rajputs
who are self-respecting
Every decent man can kill
and die for his self-respect
lf you say another word,
there'll be a death here.
Whose death?
- Either yours, or mine.
No. This is not the
time to keep quiet.
You people had said,
you'd come tomorrow.
You've got it wrong. We were paid
a million to keep away till today.
What's all this about?
What time limit? Which million?
Throw these people
out of our property.
This house, this land,
is all ours now.
Your father had lost the case...
Yes, Viren wanted you to leave happily
before they claimed it all.
That's why he had to buy
some time from them.
Papa died, the mansion is not mine.
l've become all alone now.
God forbid! Why should you feel alone?
You have your husband with you.
l cried so much against these walls.
Such insult to those tears.
l'll never forgive Viren for this.
That's your personal opinion,
but he did his duty.
We both are indebted to him.
And it's a debt we can never repay.
Just take me away from here.
Bless you, dear.
But don't misunderstand Viren.
There's no question about that.
Now l know why he didn't wait for you.
He didn't want to face this moment.
ln his place, l'd have done the same.
No work is done without contacts
these days, especially plane-bookings.
Your seats are confirmed.
Who are those other tickets for?
- For you.
And the former one?
- For me.
l know you much better than you think.
You can't cry alone.
When your dad died, l was present.
You used a shoulder to cry on.
What will l cry for this time?
- For your love.
Till you forget Pallavi,
l'm not leaving your side.
l don't think l'll ever forget her.
''These birds and the clouds
are crazy about lovers...''
''Who are we, O companion?''
''l can't remember,
l've forgotten''
''These birds and the clouds
are crazy about lovers''
''Who are we?''
''l can't remember...
l have forgotten''
''l can't remember,
''We need nothing''
''Nothing is more
beautiful than love''
''Where will these
waves take us?''
''l have no regret,
you are my shore''
''Life is but flowing water...
it can't be trusted''
''The birds and the clouds...
they're crazy about lovers''
''Who are we?''
''l can't remember,
l've forgotten''
''l can't remember...
l have forgotten''
''Lost, we are''
''Asleep, we remain''
''The world looks for us...
and we are lost''
''Asleep in a bed of desire''
''Come, let's get closer''
''Let's lose each other
in an embrace''
''We share dreams together...
there's nobody else''
''These clouds and the birds
are crazy about lovers''
''Who are we?''
''l can't say...
l have forgotten''
''l can't remember,
''Birds and the clouds
are crazy about lovers''
''Who are we?''
''l can't remember.
l have forgotten''
''l can't remember,
How lengthy a letter will you write?
Do you aim to tire him?
l've almost finished.
May l ask you something? How long
will you go on writing to him?
Why? Don't you like it?
But he hasn't replied you at all.
What difference does that make?
But he must know, he's very special.
Come here... closer.
May l say something?
Has Viren ever told how
much he loves you?
What! Did you say he...
l thought as much that you
would have no inkling.
What nonsense you talk.
You're mad..
l realized it the day
when you ran to me.
But he thought you sought his arms.
But when you fell in my arms,...
he realized he had
no place in your heart.
But why didn't l realize it all?
Because you had
your eyes on me then.
Then why didn't you tell me?
l don't have a copyright on love.
Any man would fall in love with you.
l won't write to him!
- Why not?
Give him some time to forget you.
lt's not easy to forget a first love.
Are you my husband
or Viren's lawyer?
No advocating, l'm only speaking the
truth. Promise me you'll write to him.
l'll pen you so many letters that
you'll get fed up and reply me.
l'll never forgive you for going
away without meeting me.
Listen, l didn't know that
motherhood meant so much to me.
Haven't you caught on?
l'm pregnant.
Speak loudly please.
Very bad news, son.
- You're well, aren't you?
Yes, but Siddharth was killed
in a car accident.
She wasn't with him, was she?
- Yes, she was.
Then nothing to fret about,
is there?
Yes there is, you better rush over.
l understand, but we'll have to operate.
She has lost a lot of blood.
And between the mother and child,
l can save only one.
Then save the mother.
Please do me a favour.
Save my baby.
Don't talk so much.
l beg you...
Trust in God.
lf He wills, both will be safe.
l could save the baby,
but she's very serious.
There's no time.
She wants to see you.
Viren was also a baby when you
took over him, isn't it?
Yes.
Viren is here too.
You better go and meet her.
Please don't say anything.
You had asked me not to
hesitate if l wanted something.
Well, l want you to live
and be happy.
l want you...
''These moments, these memories,
l will cherish for years to come''
''Should the seasons change,
l will beg they be returned''
''l will cherish for years''
''When the pea-hen
calls out in the night''
''The bangles tinkle in my hands.
See this, O Sir''
''The bangles tinkle in my hands''
''When the pea-hen
calls out in the nights''
Where did you find this beauty?
Beauty is found everywhere.
Beauty is beauty after all.
Then is it...
- Yes, Pallavi's daughter.
What's her name?
She has to be brought up
with reverence.
So l've named her
''Puja'' (Puja=prayer).
Leaving today only, son?
- Yes.
Just one more day...
When l wanted to stay,
you insisted l go.
And now that l wish to go,
you stop me.
See Puja, just once at least.
She's one year old today.
l can never forget her birthday.
Can you blame her for that?
- No. But l wish her birthday,...
and Pallavi's death anniversary
didn't clash.
When will you come again?
Next year, on the
death anniversary.
You've grown up now.
Adults must learn to forget the past.
That's just it.
l just can't forget.
l'll go now.
- Bless you.
''My little doll;
My little child...''
''From fairyland one day...''
''a prince will come to take
you away to the castles''
''My little doll...''
''you will one day
cast a magic spell''
''You will grow up...''
''and l'll be an old woman''
''Don't you forget these ties
we share''
''My little doll;
my little child...''
''From fairyland one day...''
''a prince will arrive to take you
away into the castles''
''My little child;
my little doll...''
''From fairyland one day...''
''a prince will arrive to take
you away to the castles''
ls he here?
- Yes.
Don't shout.
ls he upstairs? ln that case, l won't
let him go without seeing me this time.
He's tired, so let him sleep now.
Can l just peep?
- No! How many times must l tell you?
You never let me meet him.
Go! l won't talk to you!
What are you doing here?
Keeping a watch,
so he doesn't slip out.
Mad! He's going tomorrow.
- Then l'll sit here, till tomorrow!
Okay. When you feel sleepy,
come upstairs to me.
Enough now!
Don't be silly.
l ran behind the car
but he didn't even look back.
You were behind the car,
so how could he see you?
l even called out to him.
There must've been heavy breeze,
he must not have heard.
Meet him next year.
Just let me grow up!
- And what will you do?
You won't tell him, will you?
l'll just marry him.
Then where will he go?
Every time he comes, he has
just given me a gift.
Where's my gift, by the way?
Here it is.
Prem, l found those people
a bit too smart.
Not smart, but like
their name, ''crooks''
Shows off his helicopter
to us, my foot.
We know our importance too.
So the deal will be as per our terms.
One thing, don't compromise.
There was a call for you from Anita.
Who can forget that girl?
Hadn't l called you actually?
- How could l leave him behind?
Actually we are tolerating each other.
ln fact, all are enduring each other.
God shouldn't bless anyone with beauty.
See, she's calling out to me.
Keep laughing like this forever.
You've a special place
in my life.
You have held me together,
else l'd have just died.
Why don't you come out
of those shadows?
l know. And whenever l shut my eyes,
she stands before me, alive.
Memories aren't something
man can simply expend with.
l must have failed somewhere along,
for you to not forget her as yet.
lt's my fault.
Maybe l'm not trying hard enough.
l'm speaking from here only.
Our flight is due soon.
l'm thinking of getting married.
What do you think?
Don't talk to me like that.
l'm not one of those.
Please be serious.
Of course. Do you think
it'll be proper?
How long can a man chase shadows?
What do you think of Anita?
Do you love her?
l have already loved once.
Now l want to marry.
l will marry Anita,
after l come back.
l'll call Daija too.
And that's that.