#Be optimistic#
#Don't you be a grumpy#
#When the road gets bumpy
just smile#
#Smile and be happy#
#Your trouble can't be
as bad as all that#
#When you're sad as all that#
#No one loves you#
#Be optimistic#
#Don't you be a mourner#
#Brighten up that corner#
- #And smile#
- #Smile#
#Don't wear a long face
it's never in style#
#Be optimistic and smile#
#Be optimistic#
#Don't you be a grumpy#
#When the road gets bumpy
just smile#
#Your trouble can't be
as bad as all that#
#When you're sad as all that#
#No one loves you#
#Be optimistic#
#Don't you be a mourner#
#Brighten up that corner
and smile#
#Don't wear a long face #
# It's never in style#
#Be optimistic and smile#
More, Betsy! More!
Now this concludes our little
entertainment...
and I'm sure
we've all enjoyed it immensely.
I'm sorry to say... or perhaps,
I really shouldn't say sorry...
but we won't have the pleasure
of hearing Betsy sing for us again here.
Betsy's leaving us today.
Mr. Shea, who was
a dear friend of her parents...
has come to take her to live
with him in New York.
I'm sure she has everybody's
good wishes for happiness...
in her new home.
- Is that me?
- I guess it is.
Gee. I'm certainly a big surprise
to myself!
I'll get your coat and hat.
Oh, you look
beautiful, Betsy!
- It's just splendid, isn't it?
- Mm-hmm.
I... I hope someday
you'll all have pretty dresses too.
Betsy. We'll have
to hurry now, dear.
I've still got to wrap all those toys
Mr. Shea's been bringing you.
Couldn't I leave them here,
Miss Hutchins?
Mmm, Mr. Shea might not like it.
He won't care. Please, Miss Hutchins,
I'd much rather leave them here.
Just give them to...
oh, everybody.
Oh, that's sweet of you, dear.
Say thanks to Betsy, girls.
Thank you, Betsy.
Now say good-bye to everybody,
and we'll hurry along.
- Good-bye Carol.
- Bye, Betsy.
- Good-bye, Jean.
- Good-bye, Betsy.
- Bye, Sheila.
- Good-bye, Marilyn.
- Good-bye, Betsy.
- Good-bye, Mary.
Good-bye, Rosalie.
What's the matter?
Don't you want to say good-bye to me?
- No!
- Why, Rosalie. I'm surprised.
Now be a nice girl.
Say good-bye to Betsy.
No! I don't want to
say good-bye.
- Why not?
- 'Cause...
Because I don't want
Betsy to go.
Betsy.! Betsy!
Betsy!
Where's that button?
#Should auld acquaintance#
#Be forgot#
#And never#
#Brought to mind#
#Should auld acquaintance#
#Be forgot#
#And days#
# f auld lang syne#
#For auld lang syne#
#My dear#
- #We'll take a cup#
- To the subway.
#Of kindness yet#
#For auld lang syne#
Hotel Variety.
The Three Dancing Baby Dolls?
They don't live here anymore.
I don't know. I reckon
they retired on their social security.
- You're welcome.
- Hi, Pop!
Hello, Sam.
Flossie, see if you can locate Betsy.
It's time she was in bed.
- Hello? Is Betsy up there?
- Any mail for me, Pop?
- You see...
- No, no mail for you, Sam.
Any mail for his fiddle?
Yeah, from its beau.
Those are the kind of gags
that killed vaudeville.
- Hello, Betsy.
- Hello. Hello.
Upstage. Rehearse in the theater.
- Hello, angel.
- Hello.
- Where have you been?
- Oh, just visiting.
Visiting, when you should have been
in bed? Have you done your homework?
Oh, yes.
Here's my arithmetic.
- Who helped you with these problems?
- Mr. Burdini, the magician.
Hmm. Six goes into 18 five times?
Seven goes into 21 four times?
He's a magician, all right.
Oh, he's awful clever.
He's been teaching me new tricks.
May I have my key, please?
- Is that some of your ventriloquism?
- That wasn't me.
Is there any mail for us?
Oh, hello.
It's Mr. and Mrs. Brasno.
- There you are.
- Thank you.
- It's from our son.
- He's in college.
- Look, Ma. Butch made the football team.
- Oh. Look.
"Dearest Mom and Pop...
"just a line or two.
"Hope you and Mom are well and
have found something to do.
"I am getting along fine with my studies.
My goodness!
As you can see,
I'm on the squad.''
- Hello, George, Ollie!
Hiya, folks! Hello, Bets!
- Hello, Mike.
- Is there anything for us, Mike?
- Buffalo, next week.
One act for a smoker in a hurry.
How about you?
Sorry, Mr. Brody.
I'm all booked up tonight.
On the slumber time, huh? I get it.
- Who do ya suggest, Pop?
- Why, let me see...
- Better see who owes the most rent.
- Right.
Well, there's Martin and Martin,
nine weeks.
Sullivan and Haley,
six weeks.
Jimmy Clayton and his jazz band,
it's 12 weeks.
- How about them?
- They're a knockout.
- All right, if you say so.
- Get Jimmy Clayton on the telephone.
I raise a thousand bucks.
- I think the phone's ringing.
- Don't change the subject.
I call you.
What you got?
- What do you got?
- Well, I...
I just got a little pair
of threes.
And I thought you was bluffing.
Nuts to me,
you get it?
Did you hang up
your dress?
I hung up my dress, put away my shoes,
brushed my teeth...
- washed my neck, face, hands and ears.
- Nice work.
I used to have curls
all over my head once.
- Oh, that must've been lovely.
- Yes, but they were lots of trouble.
Now, don't you sit up
and listen to that music.
You just shut your eyes
and go right to sleep.
I'll shut my eyes, but it'll
probably come in through my ears.
Hiya, Butch!
Willoughby!
- Willoughby.
- Yes, Sister?
Close that window.
Hand me the telephone book.
Yes, Sister.
You seem to be enjoying
that horrible racket.
Hmm?
Well, I... I was carried away
for the moment.
Hmm.
Yes, Miss Wendling, this is
Mr. Shea's daughter. My father...
I'm awfully sorry. The boys
are rehearsing, but I'd be glad to...
I'm tired of warning
you people.
I won't have my nights disturbed
by a lot of noisy riffraff.
I won't put up with it
any longer.
I'm sorry, Miss Wendling.
I'll go right up and...
- What's the matter?
- She called us a lot of riffraff.
- Who?
- Our landlady.
- I didn't know we had one.
- Well, if you ever see a pumpkin...
in one of the windows next door and it
isn't Halloween, that's our landlady.
Ugh!
I can't look out my window without
seeing a lot of acrobats, jugglers...
midgets and actors.
How much rent does
the Hotel Variety owe?
$2,500 past due
since the 12th.
Write a letter...
to what's-his-name... Shea.
- Sarah!
- Ah!
Tell him unless his rent is paid
within five days, in full, out he goes.
- Come on. In you go.
- Oh, boy. Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
I've got to go up there and
see about stopping that music.
- Oh, no. I like it.
- You do?
- Yes, especially that song.
- Well, it is a pretty song.
- Know why I like it?
- No. Why?
The words are just the way
I feel about you and Pop.
No fooling?
Lots of times I wanted to thank you,
oh, ever so much.
Well, you don't have to,
darling.
I'm afraid I can't
'cause...
# ow can I thank you#
#How do I start#
#The words are somewhere#
#Around my heart#
#If I could say#
#In a word or two#
#How much it means#
#To be loved by you#
#Then I could thank you#
# For all you've done #
#But I don't know what#
#To do#
#What can you say#
#When a dream comes true#
# How can I ever#
#Thank you#
Mmm. Don't you try to, dear.
Now you just close your eyes
and go right to sleep.
- Happy dreams.
- Thanks.
- Good night, darling.
- Good night.
You old pumpkin!
We've got to stick together.
It's one for all, and divided we fall.
The wolf is at the door,
and the handwriting is on the wall.
- Pop's always been regular with us.
- He sure has.
So what does
it get him?
A shady nook behind
the eight ball.
We got to go out and hock
everything we own.
Jewelry, trunks, instruments,
props, everything.
We've got our sorority pins.
Get all the dough you can
and give it to Pop.
If it wasn't for Pop, we'd all
have barnacles on our hips...
from sleeping on park benches.
And that's what'll happen if
that old battle-ax next door...
puts him out of the hotel.
It's up to us
to raise some dough.
Jimmy,
here's my watch.
What about that
stickpin?
Oh-Oh, wait, wait!
You're choking me!
My goodness,
don't pull it so hard.
I'll give it to you.
- Yes?
- May I see Miss Sarah Wendling, please?
- She's not at home.
- When will she be back?
I don't know.
If you're looking for Miss Wendling,
she isn't home.
- Is that so?
- I'm waiting for her too.
- You are?
- Oh, yes, on important business.
Well, uh, maybe if it's very important,
I might put in a good word for you.
- Do you know Miss Wendling?
- Oh, yes, very well.
- She's my aunt.
- She is? Well, say...
would you please give her this...
and tell her it's on account
for the rent of the hotel?
- The hotel? What hotel?
- Next door.
And will you please ask her
to wait until Pop can pay her the rest?
Well, uh... uh, whom shall I say
this is from?
Betsy. No, from Pop...
Mr. Shea.
Well, maybe it'd be
a better idea...
if you came inside
and told her yourself.
But she's not in.
He said so.
Oh, he did?
I have an idea he's been
imagining things.
- Miss Wendling is in, isn't she, Simmons?
- She's in the library, sir.
Oh!
Oh.
Stand in the corner.
Go on. Hide your face.
You big fibber!
That'll be all,
Simmons.
Why, if anyone did a thing
like that at the orphanage...
they'd have to stand
in the corner for an hour.
At the orphanage?
Mm-hmm. I used to be an orphan
before Pop adopted me.
Well, now that's a coincidence.
You know, I used to be an orphan myself.
Too bad we weren't orphans
at the same time.
- We could've had lots of fun together.
- I'll bet we could.
- Will you excuse me a minute?
- Mm-hmm.
Say, that's cute.
Where'd you learn that?
- Jimmy and the Bandits.
- The what?
- The jazz band.
- Oh. Look at this.
That's good too.
Where'd you learn that?
At Harvard. You've heard
of the Hasty Pudding club?
Mm-mmm. But I'll bet
it tastes good.
- We dancers have got to stick together.
- Absolutely.
#We should be together#
#Like the walls
and ceiling#
#Like a door
and doorknob#
#Like the hat
on your knob#
#Like butler goes
with doorbell#
#Keyhole with key#
#I think we'll get by#
#If you'll stick with me#
#We should be together #
#Like the frame
and picture#
#Like shoes
and stockings#
#Like the clock's
tick-tockings#
- #Like tap and toe like high and low#
- #Stop and go, honey#
- #You're a perfect lady#
- #You're a regular guy#
Oh, thanks.
#We should be together
you and I#
- #You're a cup of coffee#
- Ho, ho!
#You're a peachy pie#
#We should be together
you and I#
- Roger, what's going on?
- Oh, g... good morning, Aunt Sarah.
Betsy, this is Miss Wendling,
and this is Uncle Willoughby.
How do you do,
Miss Wendling?
- How do you do, Mr. Uncle Willoughby?
- Charmed, I'm sure.
What nonsense are you up to?
This isn't nonsense.
This is high finance.
Hear the pretty music?
This young lady wants
to give you money to pay the rent.
- Oh, nonsense!
- Come on, Betsy.
- So you've gone in for social service?
- Oh, not exactly, Aunt Sarah.
I just met an acquaintance here.
There's almost five dollars in there.
I'm sure Pop'll have the rest of it
for you very soon.
- Bless my soul!
- Keep your soul out of this.
- You'll please get rid of this child.
- But, Aunt Sarah...
If those people think they can
play on my sympathy like this...
they're greatly mistaken.
I'll have my rent... all of it...
or out they go.
Please, Miss Wendling.
Please don't put Pop out of the hotel.
He and Barbara and Jimmy and everybody,
they'll have no place to live.
That's their affair,
not mine.
But, Aunt Sarah,
aren't you being a little bit hard?
- Yes, Sarah, I think...
- Think to yourself.
The place is an infernal nuisance,
full of worthless, disreputable actors.
They are not disputable!
They're very good actors.
- Thank you.
- Roger.
Just charge it to my share of the estate.
Simmons.
You will get rid of this child.
You don't need to get rid of me.
I can go.
Just a moment, Betsy.
Aunt Sarah, I don't wish
to seem impertinent...
but after all, I do have
a third interest in the hotel.
As long as I have charge of
the Wendling estate...
I'll handle it in my own way.
Simmons, see this child
to the door. Stand aside.
Uh, that'll be all, Simmons.
I'll see the young lady home.
- Come on, Betsy.
- Wait. Shh. Just a minute.
- Here, take these.
- Thanks, Uncle Willoughby.
- Simmons, get my hat and coat, please.
- Very good, sir.
Say, I may want to see you
about this a little later.
No, no, no. I don't want
to be involved, but I'll be at the club.
Come, come, young lady.
Cheer up, darling. Cheer up.
I guess I'm not
a very good businesswoman.
Oh, that's great. Then you won't
grow up to be like my Aunt Sarah.
- Shh.
- Come on, honey.
Thank you, Simmons.
See you later, Uncle Willoughby.
- Good-bye, Mr. Uncle Willoughby.
- Bye-bye, Betsy.
And if you say one word to my sister
about those cookies...
I'll smack you
right in the kisser.
Very good, sir.
You know you shouldn't have
gone over there without permission.
- I was only trying to help, Pop.
- I'm glad she did.
I'd never have known that this place
existed. It's all very interesting.
Next door, we hardly realize we're so
close to anything so, uh... so different.
I suppose you feel like a feudal lord
visiting the tenants on his estate.
I bet you'd look grand all dressed up
like a knight on a big white horse.
Riding back to his castle
for safety?
No. Rescuing
the fairy princess.
I mean,
two fairy princesses.
Mr. Wendling, I couldn't
possibly raise the money in five days.
Well, as a matter of fact,
I was going to make a suggestion...
before your daughter
so graciously knighted me.
I was going to suggest that I could lend you
the 2,500. My aunt needn't know.
You'd lend... Why...
Thanks a million.
Thanks two million...
one from me.
I'm afraid we can't accept
your generous offer.
- Why not, Barbara?
- Because I don't know how
we could pay it back.
And we're not going to be at the mercy
of any spiteful old moneybag...
who calls us
a lot of riffraff.
I'm sorry, Mr. Shea. I, uh...
So am I. You see, I just couldn't
accept your kind offer now.
- I understand.
- Come, Betsy. It's time for your lunch.
Pop? Couldn't Mr. Wendling
stay and have lunch with me?
Well, I'm afraid...
As a matter of fact, I was
going to invite you to lunch...
but I guess the Wendlings are sort
of social outcasts around here now.
- Please let me go with him.
- I wish you would.
Please, Pop. I'm old enough to go out
with a nice young man.
- All right.
- It's a date.
Barbara's awful smart.
She reads great big books
when she's not helping Pop at the hotel.
- Oh, she does?
- Yes.
She told me she's studying
how not to be an actress.
Oh. I see.
Well, uh, does she have
many boyfriends?
Oh, yes, lots of them.
There's Ole, the Four Martins,
Jimmy and his Jazz Bandits...
No, no. I mean, is there anybody
that takes her out to dinner, lunch...
- You know, a sweetheart?
- Oh.
No. I guess she's just an old maid,
like I was till you came along.
Say, are you trying to tell me
that you like me?
Mm-hmm.
#I can't show
how much I love you#
#In this little space
I've got#
#I don't know how much
I love you#
#But it's an enormous lot#
#If all the world were paper#
#And all the seas were ink#
#I'd write a great
big note to you#
#And tell you what I think#
#I'd say
I love you dearly#
#In letters
three miles high#
#And sign it yours sincerely#
#Cross my heart
and hope to die#
#If all the stars
were diamonds#
#In golden skies above#
#They wouldn't be worth that
without your love#
#I'd like to write
I love you#
#So big that you would blink#
#If all the world were paper#
#Yes, and all the seas
were ink#
What are all those mummies
sitting in there for?
Mummies?
Those aren't mummies, Betsy...
Those are millionaires.
They spent all their lives
trying to make a million dollars...
and now they sit there
wondering why.
- Hello, old-timer!
- Shh!
- Is, uh, Mr. Wendling in?
- He's in the Grill, sir.
Oh, he's in the Grill.
#I love you as I never#
#Loved before #
#Since first I met you
on the village green#
#The village green#
#Come to me ere my dream#
#Of love#
#Is o'er#
- #I love you...
- mJim, wait a minute. That's terrible!
Oh, just a minute, gentlemen.
Whoa, just a moment now.
- I was standing right here.
Someone was a little bit sour.
- It was you.
What? Well, what do you know about music?
Well, of all
the impertinence.
You were off-key.
That part goes like this.
#I love you as I loved you#
#When you were sweet#
- That's just the way I did it.
- Oh, no!
- I did!
- No. No.
- Let's try it again.
- All right, you take it.
# I love you as I loved you #
- #When you were sweet#
- # Sweet#
#When you were sweet #
#Sixteen#
That's the best you've ever done!
Now we got it.
Let's hold it.
- The youngster knows
her stuff, don't she?
- She sure does.
Begging your pardon, gentlemen.
So sorry, but, uh, this noise...
- Noise?
- What are you talking about?
We've been having complaints.
The other club members...
Just when we're getting hot!
What's this country coming to
if a man can't sing in his club?
Isn't there someplace we can rehearse
without being disturbed?
- I know a place!
- Yeah? Where?
- A hotel!
- Say, that's a swell idea.
No, it won't work. We've been thrown out
of the finest hotels in New York...
- The Waldorf-Astoria and St. Regis.
- That's right.
Well, you'll never
be thrown out of this one.
This one is just
made-to-order for you.
Just say you're a quartet,
and you can sing all you want.
Really? Where is this place?
You mean...
She's right! Come on, boys!
A haven at last!
Last one out's an old maid!
- Well, I'm not gonna be any old maid!
- Come on, Betsy. Hurry up!
Eight bucks from
the Tristate Trio...
five from Daugherty,
and five from Conklin and Scully.
- How much are we short?
- About 2,100.
The national debt.
I thought I was bringing home the bacon.
And you laid an egg.
That's right. Bite the hand
that feeds the kitty.
Thanks just the same.
You're a great guy, Jimmy.
That goes for me too,
bubble brain.
Is that straight
from the balcony, Juliet?
It's my streamlined
personality.
- I guess I'm not as bad as I look, huh?
- You couldn't be!
That's done it! From now on
when you talk to me...
start the conversation
with good-bye.
- This way, gentlemen.
- Oh, Pop!
Hurry, Pop.
We brought you some new guests.
These gentlemen were looking
for a hotel...
so Betsy suggested
that they come over here.
- Um, professionals?
- Ooh, yes. They're a quartet.
Yes. This is the well-known
Hot and Happy Four.
Yes! The Hop and Hat...
the Hot and Happy Four.
- Where have you boys been playing?
- Ooh, hotels, clubs...
churches and places.
Now, would you prefer
single rooms or a suite?
- They want the best in
the house, don't you?
- Yes! Certainly!
There's a nice, big suite on the fourth
floor with four beds and a green carpet.
Green? My favorite color.
We'll take that.
Well, that's pretty high:
$40 a week.
That's not too steep for
these gentlemen, is it?
No! Not at all!
That's fine.
Uh... Uh...
- Where is your baggage?
- Huh?
Baggage? Oh, baggage!
Oh, well... well...
Well, we could get some if you...
if it's necessary.
Oh, it's very necessary. 'Cause guests
without baggage have to pay in advance.
- Isn't that right, Pop?
- It's a rule of the house.
Oh, that's quite all right.
How much will you want in advance?
- Well...
- Uh, suppose we let Betsy decide that.
Well, let's see.
I think about,
well, 10 years.
- No. Suppose we make it one year?
- Oh, no, no. That's too much.
No. I'm sure these gentlemen
would rather pay one year in advance.
- Wouldn't you?
- Yes, sir. Certainly.
Then they wouldn't have to worry
about the rent, and neither would you.
There you are, sir.
Fifty-two times 40 is 2,008.
Gee! You're awful good in arithmetic.
That's fine.
Uh, 426.
I'll take them up.
Follow me, gentlemen.
#Mi, mi, mi, mi, mi, mi, mi, mi...#
Say, how are
the acoustics here?
Oh, we don't have any.
We use Flit.
She uses Flit!
Come on.
I hope it don't bounce.
Pop, here's
25 bucks more.
I got it, Jimmy.
I got the 2,500.
What? And we just made
the supreme sacrifice! Look!
- What happened?
- We done a striptease in a pawnshop.
Georgie. Georgie, where are you?
Your watch!
Marco, your dummy!
Take your drums away, Jerry!
Take them away!
Here's the cello
for Heinie!
Here's your piccolo.
Here you are, Syd. Take it away.
The twins.
- Your paternity pins.
- Thanks, Jimmy.
- Ole. Your waker-upper.
- Oh, thank you, Jimmy.
Oh, no, no, no!
P-Please don't do that.
Jimmy, how you get them
out the hock?
Ask me no questions.
- Mr. Wendling?
- Oh, hello. You still mad?
How could I be after all you've done
for us? May I say thank you?
Well, sure, if you'll omit the ''mister''
and make it plain ''Roger.''
- Thank you, Roger.
- That's okay.
Barbara, Betsy wants you upstairs
to help her with her reading lesson.
Tell her I'll be right up.
Could I go along?
I used to be very good at reading.
- Well, Betsy's in the third grade.
- Third grade? That high?
- Well, maybe I could learn something.
- Come on!
'''Run for your life,' said the little
princess. 'I am the cap... “Cap...”
- Now slowly. What's this?
- “Tive.” “Captive.” Oh, yeah.
“I am the captive of a wicked, old sor...”
“Sor...” “Sorce...”
Sorceress.
You mustn't tell her.
Let her figure the words out herself.
“I'm not afraid”'
said the brave young prince.
'I have come to rescue you
and take you to my castle.”
I like him.
''But you are in
great pearl...”
Peril.
That means danger.
Then why doesn't
it say “danger”?
All right.
Skip it.
“Suddenly there was
a great roar behind him.
“It was the wicked old 'sore-sorce-ess'
riding on her broom.
“On her shoulder
was a dodo bird...
and the dodo bird was
whispering in her ear...”
- This is Winchell's daily chatter.
- Mmm.
''That expensive speed buggy parked daily
in front of Pop Shea's Hotel Variety...
“belongs to
the Roger Wending...
and the reason is Pop's
lovely daughter, Barbara.”
I thought it my duty to
inform you, Miss Wendling.
So that's why he hasn't
been dining at home.
Cancel my reservations.
I'll take a later train to Newport.
I'll put a stop
to all this right now.
Look, I want to show you here.
Now look. Up here's the little boy.
The little boy comes down here.
And he's got a dog,
but the dog won't come downstairs.
The little boy goes upstairs,
and he chucks the dog downstairs.
Isn’t that good?
So you don't like that.
Look, come here. I show you another.
Come, come. Isn't there anyone
looking after this place?
No! You all can't call South Brooklyn.
It's 10 cents in advance.
Come, come.
With or without bath?
I don't want a bath...
I mean a room.
I want to talk to that man
Shea's daughter.
She's upstairs right now.
Is there anything I can do?
There is... Have her
come downstairs at once.
Park yourself over there,
and I'll see if I can get her.
You got a cigarette,
grandma?
- No, and I'm not your grandmother.
- It's okay by me, toots.
Too...
What a face! What a face!
- What?
- Gordon's play.
You'd be great for the old witch.
Oh, I would.
Well, don't blow that smoke in my face.
Come on, Oscar.
We're going up.
Hello, Aunt Sarah.
It's the old pumpkin.
So this is where you've been
wasting your time.
Aunt Sarah, please. Please.
Uh, Barbara, Betsy.
I'd like you to meet my aunt.
- This is Miss Shea and Miss Betsy Shea.
Miss Wendling.
- How do you do?
Young lady, I've come here
to tell you...
that I want you to
let this nephew of mine alone.
You let him pay your rent,
didn't you?
- Aunt Sarah!
- I don't have to listen to this.
Aunt Sarah, that was uncalled for,
unkind and untrue.
Uncle Roger didn't give us any money.
We got it from...
from someone else.
Oh, so it's Uncle Roger now.
- Is thi...- this woman your mother?
- Practically.
- Betsy is Mr. Shea's adopted child.
- Adopted her?
So they brought her to this wholesome
atmosphere. Nice place for a child.
Why, she's using her as a decoy, and
you haven't sense enough to realize it.
Aunt Sarah, you don't know
what you're saying!
Roger, I want you to get out of here
and stay out.
- You forget that I am over 21.
- You forget I control your finances.
I won't allow any Broadway gold digger
to get your money if I can help it.
Stand aside.
Did she mean me?
No, I don't think so, Betsy.
I don't know what
she's talking about...
but I'll bet she's going to
make trouble for us.
- Yes, I'm ringing him, mister.
- Flossie?
Just a minute.
Flossie, there's something
I've been wanting to ask you.
- Yes?
- A man gets lonesome knocking...
around with no one to talk to
but a five-piece orchestra...
- and living in a...
- Hotel Variety.
That's right.
I was wondering, if I asked
a certain girl to marry me...
- what would she say?
- You're on a busy line, stupid.
- Go ahead.
- I withdraw the question.
- I want to see Mr. Shea. Is he around?
- Somebody calling me?
The law.
Yes, sir.
What can I do for you?
- What's this?
- What's the matter, Pop?
It's for Betsy.
Now, if you could come around
tomorrow morning...
Sorry. I don't like this
any more than you.
But I got to take her
back tonight.
Look here, Officer, you can't take Betsy
back to the orphan asylum.
You know why? 'Cause Betsy isn’t here.
She's down south in dear old Dixie.
Sure. Visiting with my folks.
#I wish I was in Dixie#
#Away, away#
- Hey, are you crazy?
- Yeah. No!
You see, we don't want to lose Betsy.
That's why I lied to you.
She's up in her room.
- What's the number?
- 220.
I'll go and get her.
- But where are we going to take her?
- Over to my house.
Your house? Impossible.
I don't think Miss Wendling
likes me very well.
She'll never know. She's gone to Newport
and won't be back for a month.
I guess they'd never think
of looking for her there.
No. Come on, Betsy.
Upsy-daisy.
Hang on tight now.
Hold her, Barbara.
Yeah. I got her.
- There you are.
- Thanks an awful lot.
Will you and Pop and everybody
come over to see me?
- You bet we will. Good night, darling.
- Good night.
Come on, Betsy.
- Good night, darling.
Good night.
Good night, darling.
Don't cry, Betsy.
They can't do this to us.
We'll take it up to the Supreme Court,
to Washington, to Lincoln.
Officer,
take your prisoner.
- I'm sorry, old boy.
- I know. Just doing your duty.
Now run along
before I give vent to my emotions.
Say, where are you going
with my wife?
- What do you mean, your wife?
- You keep away from my wife...
or I'll smack you
down to my size.
- But I only did it to help Betsy.
- Ah!
Ah, Georgie, listen to me.
Now don't be sore.
We had to help little Betsy.
What's the matter, darling?
Something wrong?
No, nothing,
Uncle Willoughby.
- Only...
- Only what?
Couldn't I go over to the hotel
for just a few minutes?
Oh, no, dear, no. There's been a detective
over there every day this week.
Now you just be patient
a little longer.
But I was sure someone would come over...
especially today.
Why?
What's today?
Come on. Tell me.
It's my birthday.
Your birthday.
My, my.
At the orphanage, they always had
a birthday cake for me.
Well, Pop and Barbara have been very busy,
but we'll make up for it.
Come on. Let's go
downstairs, huh?
You won't miss just
one birthday party.
You'll have so many more birthdays
and so many more parties.
How about some cookies?
But it just doesn't seem
like a birthday at all.
Well, when the detectives stop
hanging around in another week or so...
maybe we can sneak over to the hotel
and have a fine big party.
What do you say?
Oh, dear. I haven't even wished you
a happy birthday myself.
Happy birthday!
#Happy birthday to you#
# Happy birthday, dear Betsy #
- #Happy birthday to you#
- Speech! Speech!
Congratulations!
Speech! Speech!
How can I thank you?
How do I start?
#The words are somewhere#
#Around my heart#
#If I could say#
# n a word or two#
#How much it means#
#To be loved by you#
#Then I could thank you#
#For all you've done#
#But I don't know
what to do#
#What can you say#
#When a dream comes true#
#How can I ever...#
Betsy, darling.
This is no time for tears.
This is your birthday.
On behalf of the hoi polloi
gathered here...
I just want to say
many happy returns...
- and when do we eat?
- Yeah!
Now!
It's the big parade.
What a joint!
What a joint.
Oh, thank you.
That... that's very nice of you.
- Good blow!
- Happy birthday!
- Cut the cake, Betsy! Cut the cake.
- Yes, come on.
Oh, my goodness.
Get out. Get out,
all of you!
You call this
hospitality?
I'll take it up
with Emily Post.
Where are you taking that child?
Where do you suppose?
I'm taking her home!
- Officer!
- See here, Sarah!
You keep out of this,
you Judas.
There's the child
you're after.
- You let her alone! Come, Betsy.
- Just a minute.
Don't you hurt Pop!
Don't you dare hurt Pop!
We're not going
to hurt anyone.
No need in getting excited.
We've got orders.
No, no!
I want to stay with Pop!
Well, I don't blame you.
You just come along now...
and your pop can straighten
things out later.
I'm afraid you'll have
to go with him, Betsy.
But I don't want to go to the orphanage.
I want to stay with you.
Don't cry, darling.
I'll come and see you,
and I'll...
I'll get you out again.
You mean old pumpkin!
Good-bye, Pop.
Good-bye, Betsy.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
I wish you were a man
for about five minutes.
Now, Sarah!
You listen to me.
I suppose if Simmons
hadn't warned me in time...
you probably would have
had all these freaks living here.
Well, it was the child's birthday,
and people just happened to drop in.
A likely story.
Where's Roger?
- Out with that scheming
Shea girl, I suppose.
- No!
- On the contrary, he's...
- #Happy birthday...#
Well, uh, what kind
of a birthday party is this?
You're a little late,
aren't you?
Where is everyone?
Where's Betsy?
On her way to the orphan asylum,
where she'll be among decent people...
- Come on, Barbara.
- Wait! Young lady!
You can give your father a message:
He's being dispossessed.
- You can't!
- I'm tearing the hotel down.
He's paid his rent.
He's violated his lease by
having all sorts of animals.
He'll save himself a lot of
trouble by getting right out.
- I'll have something to say about that.
- I'm afraid not...
as our attorney
will inform you.
Furthermore, I warn you, if you continue
your association with this woman...
Continue it? I've been trying to get her
to make it permanent.
- Come on, Barbara.
- Roger, wait!
Roger!
Snitcher!
It really isn't
so very nice out there.
There's practically no one to play with...
just grown-ups.
- And you know how tiresome they can be.
- Yeah.
Didn't you have
any fun at all?
Well, it was fun singing
with Uncle Willoughby's quartet.
And Jimmy was
awfully good to me.
And Pop and...
and Barbara.
Aw, come on.
It's not so bad here.
No! It's not!
It's no use crying about it.
Remember what you used to tell us?
- To be optimistic?
- Don't be a grumpy.
And when the road gets bumpy,
just smile.
Your troubles can't be
as bad as all that.
- And when you're sad as all that...
- Nobody loves you.
#Be optimistic#
#Don't you be a grumpy#
#When the road gets bumpy
just smile#
#Smile and be happy#
#Your troubles can't be
as bad as all that#
#When you're sad as all that#
#No one loves you#
#Be optimistic#
#Don't you be a mourner#
#Brighten up that corner#
- #And smile#
- #Smile#
#Don't wear a long face
it's never in style#
#Be optimistic and smile#
It's my property and my money
just as much as it's hers...
and trustee or no trustee,
she's got to give it to me.
- What did you ask her?
- I asked her for the hotel and $50,000...
just enough to rent
a theater and back a show...
to give those poor devils
a chance to earn a living.
- You'll never get it.
- But I've got to get it!
Mr. Fiske, you're a lawyer.
Tell me. What can I do?
Don't get me in this. I don't want
to get tangled with Sarah Wendling.
- Me either.
- I'm just asking for advice.
- I'd rather not ha
anything to do with it.
- You can't fight Sarah Wendling.
Very well, gentlemen. Then we'll
just allow these people to starve.
People that you all
know and admire.
And don't forget, you're just a bunch
of ham actors yourselves.
Gentlemen, I'm surprised
that you'd sit here...
and make beggars and panhandlers
out of the same artists...
that you used to applaud...
to think you'd allow Sarah, just
to satisfy some simple whim of hers...
to tear the roof from over their heads,
to turn them out in the streets
- You can stop her!
- How?
By getting out a temporary injunction
restraining her.
You're a part owner.
I'm not advising you!
No, no advice.
But what do I do then?
- Let me alone, Roger!
- There's no harm in telling him.
- Come on, Mr. Fiske.
- Well, you could bring a court action...
compelling Sarah to turn over your portion
of the estate, including the hotel.
But understand now,
it's just a chance...
and I don't want to have
anything to do with it, no.
Because you're afraid of that
bullying sister of mine. Well, I'm not.
- Roger, I'm with you.
- Good for you, Uncle Willoughby.
- And you're going to take the case.
- No!
- Yes!
Yes! Now hurry up
and get out that injunction...
or I'll throw you
out of the quartet...
you, you
off-key baritone.
Here's the mail and
newspaper, Miss Hutchins.
Oh, thank you, darling.
- Read me the funnies.
- No, after dinner, when you
and the other children...
Please, Miss Hutchins.
Please read me the funnies.
All right. Come on.
Oh, look! It's Roger,
and that's Miss Wendling.
What does it say?
Please read it to me.
''Trial of Roger Wendling's
action against his Aunt Sarah...
''for the petition
of the Wendling Estate...
''was begun to day before Judge Hart
in surrogate court.
''The young millionaire's action
against his eccentric aunt...
“was occasioned by her threat
to tear down the Hotel Variety.
This was temporarily
prevented by an injunction.”
She wants to tear down
the hotel?
- So it seems.
- What'll happen to Pop and Barbara?
Oh, now, now, don't you worry.
Everything's going to be all right.
- That old pumpkin! I'd like to...
- Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh!
Come on. Get some more.
Come on. Hurry.
- Aren't you afraid, Betsy?
- You might fall and hurt yourself.
Oh, please
don't do it, Betsy.
I've got to get to Pop. He's in trouble,
and I've gotta be with him.
- Is it tight enough?
- Uh-huh.
- All right. Bye.
- Bye.
But what'll we tell
the matron?
Uh, tell her I've gone
out west to fight Indians.
Be awfully careful, Betsy.
- [ All ] Bye. Bye.
- Shh.
- What's your name?
- Betsy. What's yours?
Harry.
Where are you going?
- Home.
- Where's home?
New York,
on 49th Street.
That's a million miles from here.
- I am not going that far.
- Take me as far as you go?
All right. How come
you got way out here?
You see, last night I was riding
home with my dad in his car.
He was driving awfully fast...
and all of a sudden
he hit a bump in the road...
and I bounced
right out of the car.
- And he didn't know it?
- No.
What a dope.
You got to get off at the next corner.
If I could get to a subway,
it would almost get me home.
If... if I had a nickel.
Thanks a lot for the ride.
I appreciate it very much.
- Bye.
- So long.
Come on! Get off!
Well, here's a nickel.
- Oh, thanks.
- Come on, will ya? Scram! Get off!.
How far is it
to the subway station?
Six blocks, and
I am not going that way!
Please take me
to the subway station.
Oh, all right.
You dames are all alike.
Your witness, Mr. Barron.
Mr. Wendling, isn't it true
that you intend to use this money...
to put on a vaudeville show?
A small portion of it,
yes, sir.
And you intend to put this show on
with actors living at the Hotel Variety?
- That's right.
- Isn't it quite probable...
that this vaudeville venture
of yours may prove a failure?
Or, in the Broadway
vernacular, a flop?
What? With me and
the band? I object!
Order! Order in the court!
Do my eyes believe me?
That's Betsy. Oh, I'm so glad to see you.
I'm glad to see you,
but where is everybody?
They're over in the courthouse.
- Why aren't you there?
- You see, the crowds make Oscar nervous.
I've got to get to the trial, Ole.
You've got to take me.
Please, I want to be with Pop.
You must take me there, Ole.
Well, all right.
Come on, Oscar. Got to go.
Miss Wendling, do you
know William J. Shea?
I do.
Have you ever seen your nephew
in the company of Barbara Shea?
I object!
They told me they would be in here.
There's Pop, and there's Barbara!
Order.! Order in the court!
Well, I rode on bicycles...
Order! Order in the...
Go on to the case, please.
Has your nephew ever asked you for money
for any business ventures of any kind?
- Only once, about two weeks ago.
- Did you give it to him?
- I did not.
- Why?
Because he wanted to throw it away
on worthless, good-for-nothing actors.
They are not good-for-nothing!
They're the nicest people
in the whole world!
You said it, Bets. Your Honor, I object
to the lady's incinerations.
It's irrelephant, immemorial
and a bare-faced lie.
If there's any more of this,
I'll clear the courtroom.
Your Honor, that child
belongs in an orphanage.
I put her there myself.
Those scoundrels have kidnapped her.
I came here all by myself!.
That's another fib
you told, Miss Wendling.
Bring that youngster up here.
Young lady, do you realize you're guilty
of contempt of court?
I'm awfully sorry,
but it just made me mad...
to hear Miss Wendling say those
mean things about my friends...
'cause they aren't true.
Honest, Mr. Judge,
they're wonderful actors.
Just wonderful!
This young lady doesn't seem to agree
with you, Miss Wendling.
But she never saw them act.
Did you, Miss Wendling?
And if you saw them act, Mr. Judge...
if you saw Jimmy
and his band and everybody...
oh, I know you'd think
they were wonderful too.
- If it please the court, I'd like to...
- Just a minute.
I believe this court can be saved
a lot of time and argument...
by following the splendid suggestion
that has just been made.
It appears the immediate
issue in this case...
is whether or not the plaintiff s proposal
to invest his money is a sound one.
Your Honor
doesn't mean that...
I mean that I want to see
this show right here
in this courtroom tomorrow.
Court adjourned!
You were swell!
Yeah, yeah, start your show.
I mean, uh, present
your evidence, please.
#Your Honor
I lay my case before you#
#With a show you're invited
now to see with me#
#It's a wow one, I hope
that you'll agree with me#
#Their business
show business#
#Just comes to no business
without backing#
#That's all they're lacking#
#All they need is a chance#
#A chance to smile
to laugh, to sing, to dance#
#And that is that#
#And that is all#
#So thank you
for the use of the hall#
O-Order! Order!
You may proceed.
I-Is your evidence ready?
My first evidence,
Your Honor, exhibit “A.”
#Oh, ye'll take the high road
and I'll take the low road#
#And I'll be in Scotland
afore ye#
#But me and my true love#
#Will never meet again#
#On the bonny, bonny#
Don't stop singing, gentlemen.
Won't you sing a song for me?
#I'm afraid you wouldn't like
the old-time numbers that we sing#
- Why?
- #People don't like them nowadays#
#All they want to do
is swing#
Well, why don't you take an old song
and swing it? How would that be?
#But how do we do it#
There's nothing to it.
#Just follow me#
#First of all
you start to sway#
#Back and forth
That's the way#
#And now that you've
got yourself swinging#
#Do the same thing
with your singing#
#Swing me
an old-fashioned song#
#Down by the old mill stream#
#Da-da-dee-da-da, swing me
an old-fashioned song#
#Old-fashioned song#
#Croon me an old-fashioned tune
Da-da-da-da-da#
#In the evening
by the moonlight#
#You can hear
those darkies singing#
- #Oh, croon me an old-fashioned tune#
- #Won't you croon a tune#
#Just keep it soft and sweet
with rhythm from the start#
#But keep that
old-time beat#
#The beat that's
straight from the heart#
#Swing me
an old-fashioned song#
#I wandered today
through the hills, Maggie#
#That's it, it's just
an old-fashioned song#
#Dear old girl, the robins
sing about you#
- #Rah#
- #Dee-rah-dee-rah, rah, rah#
Won't you try it?
#Oh, my darling
Oh, my darling, darling#
#Croon me
an old-fashioned tune#
#Just keep it
soft and sweet#
#With rhythm
from the start#
#But keep that
old-time beat#
#The beat that's
straight from the heart#
#Won't you swing us
an old-fashioned song#
#Ye'll take the high road
and I'll take the low road#
#And I'll be in Scotland
afore ye#
#That's how to swing#
#An old-fashioned song#
#Now sing and you'll
be happy all day long #
# Sing an old-fashioned song#
Yeah!
Order! Order! Order!
Proceed, please.
Your Honor,
mark it exhibit “B.”
#Little Miss Broadway
is going to town#
#The toast of old Broadway
uptown and down#
#Queen of them all
with a smile for a crown#
#Her two little feet
on that fabulous street#
#Are the talk of the crowd
Every one of them proud#
#Of Little Miss Broadway
up on her toes#
#With music and laughter
wherever she goes#
#Everyone loves her
and everyone knows#
#She's captured Manhattan
from Harlem to Staten#
#And thousands applaud#
#Little Miss Broadway#
#I'm here and you're here#
#And thousands more here#
#But where is Broadway#
#You're here and I'm here#
#We're marching down here #
# But where is Broadway #
#Broadway is not
what it used to be#
#We need a new street
a just-for-you street#
#And just for fun#
#I'll show you
how it's done#
#I'll build
a Broadway for you#
#We'll trade the old
for the new#
#I'll make you famous
in old Times Square#
#I'll have your name
in neon shining there#
#You'll be their
favorite child#
#You'll have the crowds
going wild#
#I'll build a dream street
where wishes come true#
#I'll build a Broadway
for you#
#Little Miss Broadway up on her toes#
#With music and laughter
wherever she goes#
#Everyone loves her
and everyone knows#
#She's captured Manhattan#
#From Harlem to Staten#
#And thousands applaud#
#Little Miss Broadway#
#Ahh#
Bravo! Bravo!
That's good. That's good.
Your Honor, I'm George Gordon.
I offer this show a 10-week
engagement.
in my international
follies at $2,500 a week.
Your Honor, I object.
This show
is worth $5,000 a week...
and I refuse to accept
a cent less.
Attagirl.
- A marriage license? For you?
- No, for my father and mother.
Oh, for your fath... Huh?
Oh, my goodness!