Come here.
We can talk better there.
I don't mind giving interviews and things
like that. That doesn't bother me at all.
Erm... there's quite a few people
that I know that wouldn't, but I said,
"if you don't get
your point of view across,
"they label us something that we're not."
Yes, erm, yes.
Well, I don't know
if I can help you at all, but...
Can I get you a drink?
Erm, I've got orange juice or...
A cup of tea I'd like.
Or... What have we got?
Orange juice or...
- Cranberry juice?
- Cranberry juice. Yes?
It's light.
Please sit down.
Gotta go cos me pie's going.
- Yeah, OK. Yeah.
- Yeah, because I'm, I'm cooking.
- Come talk to me.
We're expecting people.
OK. Ask away.
'Hello. Welcome to Suffolk Today.
'The nightmare gets worse.
'Two more bodies discovered by police
'investigating
the killings of prostitutes in Suffolk,
'bringing the total to five.
'Well, let's go back now
to Simon Newton live in Ipswich.'
'This is an investigation
that's changing by the hour.
'We have five women found dead
in the space of ten days
'and two more bodies
found here this morning.
'So we have
more than one method of killing.
'So the question today, really, does
this mean there's more than one killer?'
'The manhunt for the
multiple murderer enters a new phase.
'The feelings of vulnerability
are not helped
'by the knowledge of whoever
carried this murdering spree
'is still free to attack again.
'This huge investigation
has had a profound impact.
'Experts say it could haunt this place
'with traditionally low levels of crime
for a long time.'
'Simon, what's
the atmosphere like there right now?
'Well, I think there's generally
A sense of disbelief across this town
'And also a great sense of sadness
'I've lived in this town
For several years
'And there is an eerie air
Hanging over it
'Though this town itself
Will bounce back
'It can only do that
When this killer is caught
'And today the answer to that
May lie in Ipswich itself
"Mam"
'Police stop and question drivers
'In the red-light district
'Officers still trying
To trace the last movements
'Of the five murdered prostitutes
'There are now more
Than 350 police officers from 31 forces
'As far afield as Northern Ireland
Working on this case...
'Experts say it could haunt this place
With traditionally low levels of crime...
'Northern Ireland
There are now more than 350...
'...the method of killing...
- 'Ipswich Ripper'
- 'The Ipswich Ripper'
- 'Ripper'
Everyone is very, very nervous
and very unsure of everything
It was sort of six years ago
when Portman Road
started expanding its football team.
And a new stadium went up that...
That prostitutes seemed
to come up this way.
We had reported the prostitutes.
I confronted one. "Get out of my road!
I'll call the police!"
- Well, I...
- She said, "Call the police." And I did.
Their whole attitude with us...
...makes it really hard for me
to have much sympathy
for, you know, what happened.
We had a girl at the bottom of me drive.
She's in the car.
She said, "Do you mind
sort of moving off?" I said, "Just..."
I swore at her, I admit.
Anyway, saying, like,
"if you keep on at me,
"I'm gonna sort of get my pimp
to burn your house down."
I know what you're up to. If I see you
here again, I'm gonna call the police.
It was... it was absolutely awful.
They wrecked...
wrecked our, my evenings.
You know, they're on my streets.
You know, my children are out at night.
I've got, I've got a teenage girl.
I've got, I've got a 14-year old.
I don't want girls...
erm... doing what they did in the streets.
And they weren't just...
getting in people's cars.
They were doing it in the alleyways
and everything else.
They certainly weren't angels.
Lots of them talking about them
being lovely girls and everything,
but in all our experience
they were... foul-mouthed slags
who'd stab you as quick as...
- That's an exaggeration.
- It's a slight exaggeration.
They did pester you.
They'd rob you
as much as anything else.
Yeah.
No, because people,
kerb crawlers,
sort of upset people's children, you know.
Daughters and things.
And then there's the girls.
I mean, you coming back from football
and things like that.
He was always being sort
of propositioned, you know. Sort of.
Poor old sod!
It's been like this for years,
but I don't want my children to see that.
We all wanted to move.
We didn't want to be here.
Then these girls...
just going missing
and... and being found
the way they... they were found.
It was a complete nightmare.
It's the most wonderful time
Oh, the most wonderful time
Oh,
the most wonderful time
Of the year
Everyone is very, very nervous... erm
And very unsure of everything
Basically
The most wonderful time...
Everyone is very, very nervous... erm
And very unsure of everything
Basically
There was a LOT of fear
from a LOT of people.
I think it's the biggest thing
that's ever... ever happened in Ipswich.
It's... erm...
Definitely changed the mood
It's quite, erm...
It's quite an unpleasant feeling because
You find that I'm walking through thinking
"Well, is it him? Is it him?"
Yeah, I think it's put Ipswich
On the map
For the wrong reasons, unfortunately
It's the most wonderful time...
Everyone's very, very nervous... erm
Erm, we're not actually selling
It's actually free
Just free personal safety alarms
On behalf of Town 102
Local radio station in Ipswich
Just handing away free personal alarms
Because of what's...
In the wake of what's been happening
In Ipswich recently
Everyone is very, very nervous... erm
And very unsure of everything
Basically
So, yeah, yeah, definitely
Obviously a lot of people
Are going out for the weekend
We're gonna be a bit worried
So we're handing out
Personal alarms to... erm
Out to all the ladies out shopping today
So that's... so that's why we're here
Everyone's very brave
Everybody's very brave
Everyone is very, very nervous
...wonderful time
- Can I have one for my daughter, please?
- Yes, certainly. Of course you can.
Obviously a lot of people
Going out for the weekend
We're gonna be a bit worried
So, erm, they're handing out
Personal alarms to, erm...
Out to all the ladies out shopping today
So that's... so that's why they're here
Obviously a lot of people
Going out for the weekend
They're gonna be a bit worried
So, erm, they're handing out
Personal alarms to, erm...
Out to all the ladies out shopping today
So that... so that's why they're here
- Everybody's very, very
- Very, very
- Nervous
But they do say it's somebody.
Either a policeman or a lawyer.
We hoped it was an immigrant,
from nish-noff land.
- If it is, there'll be an uproar.
- And we'll send the fuckers all back.
No, l-l-I'm not like that. I'm sure
you're not really like that deep clown.
I fucking am.
I reckon it's one Polish bastard.
We'll fucking have him.
- You automatically think it could be him.
- Yeah.
That's the scary thing.
That he could be amongst us.
Walking around us every day
and we don't know.
Yeah!
- It could be anyone in here.
- Yeah.
Which has now really scared me
now I'm thinking about it!
I'm just gonna, like, cry!
But they do say it's somebody.
Either a policeman or a lawyer.
Or a priest!
This was on the radio.
Always utter rubbish on Suffolk Radio.
Well, we've never had
anything like that before. No.
We're all a bit... frightened
to go out at night. Yeah.
But then we are anyway.
Some people say that
they're terrified of going anywhere.
Well, goodness me, there's a...
There's a mass murderer on the loose.
A psychopath. On the loose.
H. II.
It's as though somebody's
chucked acid over you
and you can feel it all over you.
It's... Standing here, you can feel it.
We're all guilty.
No, we're not.
No, we're not. No, we're not!
Just one person is or whatever ends up
being the final tally, but...
No, we're not.
The rest of us are s... are sane.
You automatically think it could be him
Yeah
That's the scary thing
That he could be amongst us
And look walking around with us
Every day and we don't know
Yeah
We don't know
Like, anyone
It could be anyone in here
Like, anyone, it could be anyone in here
For all we know
Which has scared me
Now I'm thinking about it
- I'm just gonna, like, cry
- Ha-ha!
You automatically think it could be him
It could be him
Erm... well, some serial killer
Seems to be on the loose
prostitutes in this area
Prostitutes from in the Ipswich area
And they've been found dead, naked
In various different areas
Surrounding Ipswich
One ten minutes away from my house
Which is scary
And it was found on the body on the land
Of a girl that goes to my school
- So that's a bit scary
- Yeah
I used to go out every Friday and
Saturday night and I don't go out any more
It's not safe for young girls and women
Out in Ipswich any more
- It's not safe
- Yeah
It's not safe for young girls and women
Out in Ipswich any more
- It's not safe
- Yeah
As it used to be
It's quite scary to think
How the world's come to this
You automatically think it could be him
Yeah
Like, anyone
It could be anyone in here
It could be anyone in here for all we know
Which has now really scared me
I'm just gonna, like, cry...
Ha-ha!
You automatically think it could be him
It could be him
Something like this happens
And you realise that there's so much
So many things that are bad in the world
That's the fire alarm
We're all going to die...
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
- But it's exciting
- Cos nothing ever happens in Ipswich
This is the first bit
Of local scandal we've ever had
Being girls, gossip mongers
We're like, "it's quite exciting"
- It's quite exciting
- Yeah, yeah
You automatically think it could be him
Yeah
Like, anyone
It could be anyone in here
It could be anyone in here for all we know
Which has now really scared me
I'm just gonna, like, cry
Hah, hah. yeah
It could be anyone here
Which has now really soared me
Now I'm thinking about it
I'm just gonna, like, cry
Ha-ha
You automatically think it could be him
It could be him
Yeah
You automatically think it could be him
That's the scary thing
That he could be amongst us
Walking around with us every day
And we're... we don't know
Yeah
We don't know
You've got this feeling of suspicious
by everybody.
Upon everybody else.
Is it him? Is it him?
Is it him? Is it him? I dunno.
Yeah.
London Road, please.
'And of course there are reports
the Met is closing on potential suspects.
'Although police
won't be drawn on the exact figure,
'it's thought there are around 5O people
they're very interested in talking to.'
It's, it's hard to find to fathom out.
Anybody doing it, really, isn't it?
Wha, wha, what was their motive behind
it?
Were there signs of this type
of behaviour? It just...
He's a white male aged between 23 and 47
He'll live in the local area
He would have been fascinated
Absolutely fascinated
With murders in his younger youth...
'Silent night
He would have tortured animals
Up till his mid-teens as well
Then he'd have had a number
Of numerous relationships
Up until he was about 25, 26
They'll have been failed
He's probably been married
Lives on his own but with a partner
And he'll definitely
Definitely, definitely
Know all the victims
Apart from one... realistically
And that'll have been his one
That he mucked up on
Cos the other ones
Would have been fine with going with him
And it's probably why he strangled her?
Because she panicked...
'Virgin mother and child...
It's, it's hard to fathom out
anybody doing it, really, isn't it?
Wha, wha, what was
their motive behind it? it just...
It just...
l-I-I've studied serial killers
Since in my mid-teens
And it doesn't mean I'm... I am one
But, er...
Oh, right.
Just find it interesting
But, but, as I say, you know
Just to emphasise
It doesn't make me a serial killer so...
Gives me a bit of the shudders
Quite honestly
'... in heavenly peace...'
His failed relationships will be
Because he became violent when drunk
Actually, he'll be an alcoholic
Or he'll have trouble
With substance abuse as well
And also in the last... last six weeks
Actually, about the last
Two... two months approximately
He'd have probably quit his job
Or he'd be off sick
Or to that effect... he, er...
He, he'll be a local in the local pubs
He'll be a bit of a loner
But, erm, that's it, spot on who he is
I guarantee it...
'Holy infant
so tender and mild...
- It's horrifying, isn't it?
- Yeah
l-I-I've studied serial killers
Since in my mid-teens
And it doesn't mean I'm... I am one
- But, er...
- Oh, right
Just, er, find it interesting
But, but as I say, you know
Just to emphasise
It doesn't make me a serial killer so...
It gives me a bit of the shudders
Quite honestly
Er, for each girl there was a team,
a different team,
and they all questioned us.
And it... it was getting awful.
We were so getting fed up
with just being asked, you know.
They were asking if you had nose hair.
Ear hair.
Wha... wha... Goodness knows
why they wanted to know that.
Police kept issuing these strange things
about what you should and shouldn't do,
but they never said, "Don't be a
prostitute and get into a stranger's car,"
which was the obvious thing, really,
wasn't it?
Cos everyone else was quite safe
walking the streets.
We assumed particularly when, I mean,
it was just prostitutes he seemed to be...
Murdering.
When they did the house
questions, you know, that was really...
I thought
he was gonna be arrested.
There was a knock on the door. Terry said,
"You're wanted. In the lounge. Police."
He was doing every house.
Every single house in London Road.
Er, your mind goes blank. "Where was
you on Monday night?" sort of thing.
Can't remember exactly the date. And you
think, "Well, where was I'? What did I do?"
Then he said, "What colour...? Have you
got blue eyes?" I said yes I think.
Yeah, you said yes.
Then he said,
"Have you got a hairy chest?"
And I looked at him and thought,
you know, "Where is this leading to?"
I got up and all I could see
were police cars going up the road
And of course, you know
I, we knew
Obviously it was in charge of, you know
Something to do with these poor girls
That's it...
And that's when it all started
it all kicked off
Well, I got woken up by the telephone
Me son rung me on his mo...
On, on my home phone
I said, "Where are you?"
He said, "I'm down the road but you need
To tell the police that I'm your son"
I said, "Why? What have you done?"
And that's when it all started
it all kicked off
He said, "No, no, no
We're not allowed down the road"
And lo and behold there was police
There was cameras, there was my son
It all started
It all kicked off
You looked up the road
And it's all you saw
Was like a tented, a tented area
You looked up the road
And it's all you saw
Was like a tented, a tented area
And outside number 79
You looked up the road
And it's all you saw
Was like a tented, a tented area
You looked up the road
And it's all you saw
Was like a tented, a tented area
And outside number 79
And I thought, "Oh, no
There's another prostitute been found"
I got up
And all I could see were police cars
going up the road
And of course, you know
I, we knew
Obviously it was in charge of, you know
Something to do with these poor girls
But, erm...
But, erm, that's when it all started
It all kicked off
I got up
And all I could see were police cars
going up the road
And of course, you know
I, we knew
Obviously it was in charge of, you know
Something to do with these poor girls
But, erm...
And that's when it started
It all kicked off
And didn't we...?
Then we started hearing on the news
That someone had been arrested there
Or someone had been arrested
And so we just put
Two and two together and said
"I think they've just arrested
Our next-door neighbour
I got up
And all I could see were police cars
going up the road
And of course, you know
I, we knew
Obviously it was in charge of, you know
Something to do with these poor girls
But, erm...
This is London Road. This is
where the second suspect was arrested.
So I think Steve Wright.
Oi...
Oi!
Right, you want me
to talk into that at the beginning?
They're not very happy
about the... intrusion.
Sorry'?
Sam?
- No!
- Stand back!
'I'm here in London Road.
The white tent...'
Oh, we're inside there.
All a little bit weird.
'Next door there's
the concerned residents looking on.'
- Please, further back.
- Keep rolling, Seb. Keep rolling.
'A very heavy police presence.
'They're very unhappy at our being here.
We are trying to get you some shots.'
'Assert the barrier with our bodies
'in respect of where the line is.
'Sorry.
'Excuse me. Back behind the tape.'
- Yeah, we're trying to get a link.
- Ten minutes.
'Get back! Come on! Move!
'I'm being apprehended
by the police.
'Get back! Get back!'
'...79 London Road
where a tented area has been erected.
'The suspect has been arrested,
Mr Steven Wright.'
Can we go down that way?
I'm afraid you have to go round.
- Back round 'ere?
- Yes. Sorry about that.
It's all right.
- When's this gonna be over?
- I don't know. Wouldn't be able to say.
- Friday?
- I wouldn't know. I would be guessing.
- Saturday?
- I'd be guessing at Saturday as well!
- Sunday?
- No. I dunno.
Monday's Christmas!
It can't be Monday!
- Can we just come here?
- Yeah. No worries about that bit.
It's against the law. I don't know whether
I'm coming or going round this area!
You're not allowed
through that bit basically.
Have you got the man that done it then?
- They won't even tell us.
- Won't they? I know the girls.
Mind you, flippin' half the town,
if you were to pull 'em in,
probably went with them girls.
Except for yours truly.
- Hopefully not yourself?
- No!
Cos I won't give 5O quid
to a little scaggy little whore.
No. Anyway, looks like my relief's
turned up, so I'm gonna get a coffee.
- Can't be a bad thing. Take care anyway.
- OK. And you.
I think it was policing
as we'd like to see it every time.
Bobbies standing at your house,
making sure no nasty people got near you.
You'd feel like
the Prime Minister, wouldn't you?
Yeah. The road was ever so quiet and
nobody stole our festive wreath this year.
Yeah.
If somebody knows
you live opposite, they wanna know...
Think you've got inside information,
which I... you haven't.
You've just got what's in the...
journalists are saying.
The police
don't tell you anything, do they?
They're not allowed to, are they?
We had no post. No bin men.
Erm... if we had post,
the postman had to be escorted by police.
Inside the cordon.
'It's half-past ten.
'This is BBC News 24.
'Live coverage of the arrival in court
of the 48-year-old man
'who's been charged
with murdering five prostitutes.
'Steven Wright will appear
inside Ipswich Magistrates Court
'within the next half hour.
'Our colleague, Chris Eakin,
is at the court
'and Chris, talk us
what we're expecting to happen.
'The building over here is just
the main police station in Ipswich,
'but it is this very dull and drab,
ominous building,
'which is the Magistrates Court
and which will be the focal point,
The center of attention
for at least the next hour
'T-T-This is now the moment
that Steven Wright faces the charges,
'if formally charged with
these five murders of the five women.'
All of this happened quite suddenly.
A very dramatic announcement
last night, late last night,
that Steven Wright was charged
with these five murders.
I've been here since about half-nine
I just saw him come along
Like, with the police sirens and that
And they were, you know
None of the photographers caught him
Caught any photos of him
Or anything but...
Just waiting to get a glimpse, really
His name is Steven Wright.
He's 48. He's a fork-lift truck driver.
He's from London Road in Ipswich.
That's pretty well it.
I tell you, if I get hold of him...
huh,huh,huh!
I really...
I've never seen anything like it.
I said to my brother
I said, "What's going on?"
I said, "What's happened?"
He says, he says, "Cos the bloke"
He said
"He's in court this morning, isn't he?"
And then when I came up here I thought
"Oh, my word! Am I gonna get parked?"
Cos they've taken
All the spaces along here
Oh, dear?
- Yeah, look at this, look at this
- It's horrible, innit, eh?
It's a wicked bloody world
Yeah, look at this, look at this
It's horrible, innit, eh?
It's a wicked bloody world...
I'm just hearing some sirens, actually,
and as he's gonna come
from this direction,
we'll just turn our camera round that way.
So that we do actually see this convoy
when it happens. Turn round this way.
They're obviously on the verge
Of bringing him out
Cos the position the cars are in
The position, the cars, the police
They're all in position, look
They're obviously on the verge
Of bringing him out
Cos the position the cars are in
The position, the cars, the police
They're all in position, look
You look around and you think
"Well, you know"
"Have they got the right...?"
He said
"He's in court this morning, isn't he?"
And then when I came up here
I thought, "Oh, my word!"
- The position of the cars, the police
- ...spaces along here
Hello...
Police motorbikes coming up the road,
not from the direction we were expecting,
so I imagine it's not the convoy.
They're closing in...
It might be, actually.
They're closing in
He's obviously coming out...
I think it is.
They're closing in
That's why the police
I could see them stopping traffic
Up there an' all
Oh, dear
Yeah, look at this, look at this
It's horrible, innit, eh?
It's a wicked bloody world
It looks like we've got Steven Wright now.
And here we have full convoy near!
Steven Wright!
'48-year-old fork-lift truck driver.'
Fucking bastard!
You piece of shit!
You're fucking dead!
Yeah, look at this, look at this
It's horrible, innit, eh? It's horrible
It's a wicked bloody world
Yeah, look at this, look at this
It's horrible, innit, eh?
It's a wicked bloody
It's a wicked bloody, it's a wicked bloody
It's a wicked bloody world!
Bloody hell!
Couldn't see. Couldn't see.
- I don't think he was in that van.
- He was.
He's definitely in the back of the van.
- Waste of time, wasn't it?
- It's a disgrace.
Oi. Hey! Get away then!
We're really upset
I just wanted him...
It to be all over
And to know
Were tho... were those prostitutes
Killed in that house?
He was only there for ten weeks
Ten weeks
It's just a chance
The one place in the... in the whole world
Where... he went to live for ten weeks
Could have been anywhere
Could have been next door to you
Everybody would rather it all went away
They must have sleepless nights
I know I do
It was awful. I was very upset.
In the evening, you know,
I'd just close the curtains and erm...
It really made me very depressed and low.
I just feel it's...
- I think there's a...
- It's like a dream still.
I, I don't know.
I don't think I've really...
- I think...
- Really come to accept it.
I... try to... keep going.
Nobody walks...
nobody walks down that road with, with...
And I'm the same.
Without staring at that house.
During the day I had
quite a bit of trouble with children.
hm, coming and really looking...
One of them threatened me talking about,
"He's a murderer and everything.
You should move" and...
He was only there for ten weeks
Ten weeks
It's just a chance
The one place
In the... in the whole world where he...
Went to live for ten weeks
Could have been anywhere
Could have been next door to you
Everybody would rather it all went away
They must have sleepless nights
I know I do
When they boarded the house up,
that's when I really didn't like it.
- We were thinking of moving.
- Well, you were, particularly.
It just sort of de-de-depressed me.
It depressed me living next door,
you know,
and I just sort of thought,
"Oh, I wanna be in a nice area."
I was thinking about moving once,
I was, yeah.
I'm moving. 14th March.
We're really upset
I just wanted him...
It to be all over... and to know
Were tho...
Were those prostitutes
Killed in that house?
They must have sleepless nights
I know I do
- Hello.
Oh, right.
- I've seen you.
- I'm Ron. I live at number 86.
Oh. I'm Julie.
Do you wanna... do you wanna come in?
In October and December of last year
In October
- In October
- And December of last year
Well, this is the third time
That Steve Wright
He arrived here at Ipswich Crown Court
But it's the first time
That he's formally entered a plea
- But it wasn't until two o'clock
- That he stood up
That he stood up
- Dressed in a black suit, white shirt
And blue tie
- White shirt and spoke
- And spoke clearly
- And confidently
And confidently when he was asked
How he would plead
To each of the five counts of murder?
They were read out in this order
Well, this is
The third time that Steve Wright
Has appeared in court
But it's the first time
That he's formally entered a plea
He arrived here at Ipswich Crown Court
But it wasn't
Until two o'clock this afternoon
That he stood up dressed in
A blue tie, black suit, white shirt
And spoke clearly and confidently
When he was asked
How he would plead
To each of the five counts of murder?
That were read out in this order
Clara Martin
Her body was the second to be found
Although she was the first woman
To go missing
Anna Reynolds
Her body was, was the first to be found
On 3rd December.
Annie Collingwood
Whose body was found in Acton
Was found in... in Acton
Sonia Farrell, Michelle Symonds
Their bodies were of course
Found in Levington
Found of course
A few hundred yards apart
Just a few hundred yards from each other
In Levington.
We know that all women
Were working in the town as prostitutes
And all their bodies were found naked
To each one of those counts of murder
Steve Wright, er, pleaded
Not guilty
We thought with everything happening
over the Christmas period,
with the prostitutes going missing
and being murdered,
we needed to get together as a community.
We got a lot of bad press
when it was all going on,
saying sort... Lon, London Road was
a prostitute area and so forth like that,
and we just got absolutely cheesed off
with it as a... as a community.
It is, it's, it's not nice being labelled.
So we got together and... and managed
to get a real good committee going.
Good evening, welcome
Welcome, welcome
Good evening
This really is our first AGM
Hoping hopefully the problem
With the girls has disappeared
We don't see them now
I believe there are still
A few round in Hanford Road
But, erm, we really can't
Concern ourselves with it
The street has got much better
I think that the police
Have done exceptionally well
Under exceptional circumstances
To clear the streets as they have done
This really is our first AGM
I wanna say thank you to the police
Thank 'em cos representatives here
And the ward councillors
The county councillors
Who have done a lot to help us
And so thank you very much all of you
Yeah, forthcoming events
Julie...
Yeah, the quiz night
Fish-and-chip supper
It's, erm, you know
More, the more the merrier?
Friends, family so...
So hopefully see you all there
With your friends and family
And also, er, London Road
In Bloom Contest
Big event on 11th July
To make the area look pretty and that
And getting people involved
And getting interested in their road
And their homes again
If you make your house look nice
And feel good about where you're living
You'll enjoy
You'll enjoy life a hell of a lot better
So get thinking about
Your gardens, your designs
Hanging baskets and so forth
So I'd like to see as many as possible
So it should be a good, good day
So get thinking about
Your gardens, your designs
Hanging baskets and so forth
So I'd like to see as many as possible
So it should be a good, good day
That's about it.
That's it. Thank you.
(Sighs)
Wm)
All right?
Impossible to report cos I can't...
I can't use the word "semen".
Can you not?
Can't use the word "semen"
At lunchtime
And I can't use it at six o'clock
I can use it at ten o'clock
But I can't use it before teatime
So what do you use instead?
I don't know, really. What can I say?
Mum
mum
Well, that's just taste reasons
Cos we... we can't basically have a...
Wha... what our editors call
a "Mummy, what's semen?" moment
Erm... in the trade
male bodily fluid...
Male body fluid
Sounds as if he's going around
Spreading it all over Ipswich
Boy juice
Ready'? Three. two. one.
Using his hands to demonstrate
Peter Wright explained
How forensic scientists
Had extracted Steve Wright's DNA
From other se...
Ready';?
Using his hands to demonstrate
Peter Wright explained
How forensic scientists
Had extracted Steve Wright's DNA
From other se...
Cellular material found in the...
Told you, didn't I?
I think he probably did do it
He must have done it really;
I think he did it
Definitely did it now
- I think they'll find him guilty
- I think he'll be found guilty but...
- It's circumstantial
- But he's gonna get away with it
It's only circumstantial evidence
They've got?
I still reckon
He's gonna get away with it, you know...
Still running.
Using his hands to demonstrate
Peter Wright explained
How forensic scientists
had extracted Peter's se...
Steve Wright...
Steve Wright, Peter Wright.
Whenever you're ready
- OK.
- Just running up.
Using his hands to demonstrate
Peter Wright explained
How forensic scientists
Had extracted Peter Wright's
Peter Wright, Steve Wright
This is the problem
With this bloody trial
Too many Wrights
- I think he probably did do it
- He must have done it really
I think he did it
Definitely did it now
- I think they'll find him guilty
- I think he'll be found guilty but...
- It's circumstantial
- But he's gonna get away with it
It's only circumstantial evidence
They've got?
I still reckon
He's gonna get away with it, you know
Ready? Three, two, one
Using his hands to demonstrate
Peter Wright explained
How forensic scientists
Had extracted Steve Wright's DNA
From other DNA material
Found on both gloves...
- Cellular material! This is complicated.
- We're running.
How many takes are we gonna do?
- Dunno
- OK
- Well, that's running up
- Shall we just say "sperm"?
- Ha!
- Sorry.
Question L, what was the first and
might possibly be the only, I'm not sure,
some people might know better than me,
the first Oscar-winning film...
'Steve Wright denies killing five women
'In late-2006...
Hang on. Ron, sorry, it's...
'Here's Simon Newton...
'For a second day, DNA expert Dr Peter
Hau from the Forensic Science Service
'arrived at Ipswich Crown Court in a van.
'Today, the jury heard more
about this pair of gardening gloves.
'They were found inside a high-vis jacket
recovered from Steve Wright's house
'at 79 London Road.'
Ooh, the house. It's here.
'Using his hands to demonstrate
'Peter Wright explained
How forensic scientists
'Had extracted Steve Wright's DNA
'From other cellular material
'Inside the thumbs of both gloves
'Dr Hau said
That within that cellular material
'He found the incomplete profile
Matching the fifth victim
'The chance of it not being hers
"'One in a billion," he said
'Simon, thank you'
Using his hands to demonstrate
Peter Wright explained
How forensic scientists
Had extracted Steve Wright's DNA
From other cellular material
Inside the thumbs of both gloves
Dr Hau said
That within that cellular material
He found the incomplete profile
Matching the fifth victim
The chance of it not being hers
"One in a billion," he said
Shoosh!
That's gotta be him then.
- That's the one.
- Seriously?
That's fine. It made sense.
Did it make sense to you?
Yeah, that's all right.
That all works. We got it.
It's up there if you need it.
Yourself, I mean...
You being as far as I can, like
as far as I'm aware, about the only person
that has actually come down here
and asked the residents how they feel.
You know, we just wanna...
wanna see an end.
End to it, and London Road
getting back to being London Road,
instead of being known for somewhere...
where the murderer lived.
You see, the police
have ignored the problem, really.
Mm, they have. They would deny it.
They will deny it, but they have ignored.
They ignored the problem
of the prostitutes.
- We've all stopped
- We've all stopped working now
We've all stopped now
An' it, and it has been
Because of the murders
And it has, yeah
That's why, like, we all stopped
I've got...
Well, saying that, I've got regulars
you got regulars...
That phone and we see
You know, won't work the street
But we've got a few regulars
That keep us going
You know, won't work the street
But we've got a few regulars
That keep us going
Ever since the murders
Took place, like
There's no point
Going down there for one
Because all the cars get stopped
And you just get arrested all the time
They weren't, like, nicking us
- They were, like, nicking the men
- They were just stopping all of the men
I wanna get myself clean
If I could do anything
You know, like get myself clean
For them almost
- Do you know what I mean?
- That's what, that's what I've done
Getting myself clean
- Since the murders...
- There's been help given us, yeah?
- There's girls that ain't took it
- We've took it
And the girls who took it
A lot of them are doing really well
And, you know
This has been a year later now
And yeah
We're coming about three times
And what with other organisations
And stuff, you know
There has been the help there, you know
With other organisations
And stuff, you know
- There has been the help there
- We've all stopped
We've all stopped now
An' it, an' it has been
Because of the murders
That's why, like, we've all stopped
I've got...
Well, saying that, I've got regulars
- We've got regulars
- That phone and we see
You know, won't work the street
But we've got a few regulars
That keep us going
You know, won't work the street
But we've got a few regulars
That keep us going
And just do, like, instead of
Hundreds of pounds' worth of drugs a day
Now all I do is, like
15 worth of drugs a day now
- If that
- I don't use it every day any more
Maybe occasionally now I still use
I'm still trying
To get over that hurdle but...
It's just that last little bit
You gotta get off, yeah
To what I was a year ago
Like, there is such a change
I never thought I'd get back
To what, where I am now
I really didn't
Like, I've never been this big before
Either I was, like, a size fucking six
I know, I've put on weight
I was like a size six
We've all put on weight, yeah
We wasn't...
It took all that for anyone
To start helping us
- Yeah, that's what's upsetting
Yeah, yeah, that's what's upsetting
Yeah
Took those five girls
That's what makes me feel
I wanna get clean for 'em
Because he's took their lives
Has took their lives
For them to help us
Come on
Let's get these girls off the street
'All parties in the case
of Ronnie Tretton, Court Four.'
Hm...
They're doing this now
just to tease us, aren't they?
'All parties in the case
of David Hughes, Court Two.'
There's that momentary pause
every time that goes off. It's awful.
As soon as that verdict's in,
it's gonna be absolute mayhem.
- What's happening?
- Don't know. Everyone's going
This could be the verdict
Could be the verdict
Hello, Victoria
They think it might be a verdict
And the digilink's gone down
I've told the desk
OK. Good luck. Bye
Broke
They think it might be a verdict
Could you give level again
Please, Colette?
And the digilink's gone down
I've told the desk
- The jury of nine men
- Could you give level again, please?
The jury of nine men
and three women started
The digilink's gone down
Deliberating
I've told the desk
And the digilink's gone down
The jury of nine men
Could you give level again?
Could you give level again, please?
He'!
We're not on the satellite
W "W
Hey,hey.heY
Hello, Victoria
What day is it? Thursday?
They went out...
They went out Tuesday, didn't they?
They think it might be a verdict
And the digilink's gone down
We think there might be a verdict
And the digilink's gone down...
- 'Suffolk Today...'
- Ron! Ron! It's the verdict!
Verdict! It's the verdict!
It was... it stretched over
That, er, remarkable
Six
Six-and-a-half weeks back in 2006
And over ten days
Four
Now it seems...
He did say that he had sex
With four of those women
- One
- Can you come to me?
- Guilty
Now we hear it's guilty on count one
- That's Clara Martin
- Can you come to me?
Clara was the first to go missing
That was October 30th
Or maybe even the early hours
Of the 31st
- Two
- Can you come to me?
- Guilty
-  We are getting the verdict
He was caught on an automatic
Number plate recognition camera
- Two
- He's guilty of killing Anna Reynolds
- So that's two guilty verdicts so far
- He is accused of five counts of murder
- We know he's guilty of the murder...
- Three, guilty
Again, he's been found guilty
Of the murder of Emily Collingwood
The jury of nine men and three women
Spent six-and-a-half hours
Deliberating this verdict
- They went out just after midday
- Two more counts to go
- Er, to consider the verdict
- Should all agree on a verdict
- Four, guilty
Four guilty, I'm told now
That Michelle Symonds has also been...
He's also guilty
Of killing Michelle Symonds
We only have to hear the fifth count now
- We only have to hear the fifth count
- We only have to hear...
Members of the jury
Will be telling the court now
- She was found very, very close
- Perhaps only...
Members of the jury will be telling...
- A hundred or so yards apart
- The fifth count now we have to hear
The jury will be...
Members of the jury
Will be telling the court now
Guilty, now he's been found guilty
Now he's been found guilty
On all five counts of murder?
Guilty, Steve Wright guilty
Of all five counts of murder?
Of all five charges of murder?
Steve Wright has been found guilty
On all charges
He's been found guilty
Guilty of killing Emily Collingwood
Guilty of killing Michelle Symonds
For one of the most
Disgusting serial killings
Emma Rummy
- Of all five charges
- Guilty, Steve Wright guilty
Of all five counts of murder?
Guilty on all five counts of murder
Steve Wright, a man
A very unremarkable man
On the surface of things
A man who has been responsible now
We know
For one of the most disgusting
Serial killings
Hm Emma Rummy
We're still awaiting news
On Steve Wright's sentencing
It's thought Mr Justice Gross will
Pass that first thing tomorrow morning
This is Kelly McCormack
Outside Ipswich Crown Court
For Classic FM
OK. OK. OK. Bye.
I'm staying connected. I'll keep
my headphones on too. Ooo-oo-oo!
Oo-oo-ooh!
Ooh.
I've got nearly 17 hanging baskets
In this back garden
Believe it or not
Begonias and petunias
And, erm, impatiens and things
Marigolds, petunias and we got up there
We got busy Lizzies
Hanging geraniums, all right, see
There's all sorts in that basket anyway
Hang it, nobilius
Petunias in a basket
Hanging basket
That's a fuchsia
Erm, there is a special name
I just call 'em lilies
They're a lily type
There is a special name
And for the first time this year
I've got a couple of, erm... baskets
Begonias and petunias
And, erm, impatiens and things
Marigolds, petunias
- Petunias
- We got busy Lizzies
- And, erm, impatiens and things
- Hanging lobelias
Hanging baskets
Variegated ivy in there
Which makes a nice show
And then you've got
These sky-blue... whatever they are
Vm-veer-bel...la-la
that's little purple ones
Rhubarb
The old-fashioned marguerites
The daisies
The roses have done
Really well this year
Yeah
Gave us an extra point for having basil
On the windowsill, didn't she?
Yeah
- Hanging baskets
- Rhubarb
- Variegated ivy in there
- The old-fashioned marguerites
- Which makes a nice show
- The roses
- And then you've got...
- Have done really well this year, yeah
- Whatever they are
- I've got nearly 17 hanging baskets
...basil on the windowsill, didn't she?
I just call 'em lilies
They're a lily type
- Impatiens and things
- Hanging baskets
Begonias and petunias
And, erm, impatiens and things
I've got nearly 17 hanging baskets
In this back garden
Believe it or not
Begonias and petunias
And, erm, impatiens and things
It's a terrible shame. It's...
I mean, we're reaping the benefits of
what's happened, really, which is, er...
There's always a silver lining.
Look, we turned this around, like,
and this is, this is what is possible.
I would like in maybe two or three years,
it's gonna take time, I know,
cos of all red tape and what have you
and town hall, you know, Munchkins...
...is for the world's press
to come back in three years' time and say,
"This was then. This is now."
I don't think anybody
really thought that they were bad girls.
You know, I mean, they were in a way,
but they weren't hurting anybody else,
were they?
That was only their selves
they were to hurting, weren't it?
I think we've been scarred.
Forever.
Women will never trust men again
and men will always... wonder
what women are thinking.
You know, people
have been... yeah, affected by this
and... I guess they always will.
I've almost got this mental picture
of when those girls got up to heaven.
That Saint Peter said, "Come in,"
and they, and they said something like...
..."Do you mean it's over?
Do you mean it's finished?
"Do you mean, erm,
they can't hurt me anymore?"
I can imagine for, erm,
people that lived outside the area
where the prostitutes
hadn't affected anyone,
you would get a different opinion.
You'd get people feeling sorry for them
and so forth... you know.
I feel sorry for the families,
but not them.
You know'?
It was just a pain in the arse.
They were a complete pain in the neck.
You know, they're...
they're better off... sitting under.
That's a horrible thing to say, isn't it?
But what's happened has happened.
But I'm not... I'm not sad.
You know'?
I'd still shake his hand.
I'd love to just shake his hand and say,
"Thank you for getting rid of them."
I mean, I would, you know,
if you had the, at the end of the day,
if you had the courage to do it,
then... erm...
I'd shake their hand if I had the courage,
but I would... I wouldn't do it, but...
I can have that thought in my... my head
to say, "Yeah, thank you very much."?
Oh, God!
Wow
Oh, wow! It's just...
Oh, wow! I think they peaked today.
Well, probably about, like, Wednesday.
Don't you think, Julie?
People have put
hanging baskets out this year
that have never done hanging baskets
or pots before in their lives.
But they made a real effort
for London Road In Bloom.
Oh, God! Wow!
I don't know a weed from a plant, I don't!
But I did do a... a pot.
Yes, we got June's pot.
These are double petunias.
- I love these. Look!
- Yeah.
Fantastic! Oh, the gardener's wife!
- Animals on the windowsill.
- Where?
Oh, this is great!
It's so...
It's nautical, religious, floral.
- All of human life is here!
-  Yeah.
Oh, look! Fabulous! It's just...
Look! Gnomes!
I gotta say,
it's Jesus that does it for me here.
It's a bit of Lourdes in London Road.
Yeah, there's gardens galore.
Very pleased with it.
Come on and give me a one
And a two
I've been waiting all night
To dance with you...
Come on! Woo!
Just help yourself to everything.
Hi again. I know you. You all right?
- Nice to see you, Julie. You all right?
- Yes, thank you. I recognise you.
You're the one!
Come on and give me a one
And a two
I've been waiting all night
To dance with you
I would like to introduce you to Julie
who has worked non-stop
to organise this event.
- Here's Julie to give out some prizes.
- Carole's doing the announcing.
And Carole's going to do some...
Carole!
I'd like to introduce you to Carole
as well then in that case.
Carole is one
of our local neighbourhood councillors
and she was one of the judges today
in the competition and...
Well, I've lost the plot
of who's gonna speak now,
so I'll get out the way
and leave you to these two.
Erm... hi, everybody.
This is the really wonderful
inaugural party in London Road.
After, er, judging the best gardens
and it really, really was difficult
choosing winners.
And Julie must just be
The hanging basket queen of London Road
Anyway, it was a real pleasure today
Really good fun
And so many people
Have made such a great effort
To make London Road look beauteous
We're going to do the best front garden
And we pick as the runner-up
As the winner, this garden
Where it was very difficult
it was a real challenge
To make this front garden beautiful
Because basically it's all parking
Er, it looks absolutely lovely
And once you look round the cars
Fantastic
Terry and June
Come to the front, come to the front
- Well done, Tel
- Well done
Really, really wonderful effort
Well done
Look at me, please
Everyone, smile
Yeah, we have...
We have official photographers
We have Jessica
We're gonna have an exhibition
An' everything
- No, we're not
- We are, we are
- Thank you
- OK
Now there is the absolute winner
The absolute winner
And it is
With the very best garden I do believe
Dodge, yes, it's Dodge
Oh, well done
Look at me, please
Everyone, smile
I think this is absolutely fantastic
So many people here tonight
I haven't counted you all
Seeing everybody have a great time
That's what it's all about
I would like to congratulate
Everyone that's really worked hard
On the gardens
Even the people that haven't won
It doesn't matter, it's...
It doesn't matter
It's sharing their gardens
With everyone else
And really working hard
And making London Road
What London Road is
A fantastic road
Look at me, please
- A fantastic road
- Look at me, please
Everyone, smile...
- You all right?
- Yes.
I'd just like to point out as well
It does seem that God
ls smiling on London Road
Cos if you'd you seen
The weather forecast for today
Well, look at it now
And if I ask something
that you don't wanna ans...
then that's fine, just tell me to...
Christina said you'll tell me
to shut up anyway.
So, erm, I know, erm, what you're all,
you know, involved in work-wise.
Used to be.
We've all stopped.
- We've all stopped working now.
-  OK.
Because of the murders
we've all stopped.
That's why we all stopped.
I stopped like a month before the murders.
We've got regulars
that phone and we see, you know.
Won't work the street,
but we've got a few regulars.
Ever since the murders took place, like,
there's no point going down there for one
because all the cars get stopped
and you just get arrested all the time.
They weren't nicking us.
They were nicking the men.
I wanna get myself clean.
If I could do anything, you know, like,
I'd get myself clean for them almost.
I got up and all I could see
were police cars going up the road.
And, of course, you know, like,
we knew, obviously, it was in charge.
- Something to do with these poor girls.
- Yeah.
But erm... And that's
when it all started. it all kicked off.
You think it could be him.
Yeah.
That he could be amongst us
and walking around with us every day
and we don't know.
Like, anyone. It could anyone in here,
which has now really soared me.
Now I'm thinking about it,
I'm just gonna, like, cry!
This was the third time
Steve Wright has appeared in court,
but it's the first time
that he's formally entered a plea.
He arrived here at Ipswich Crown Court
shortly after nine o'clock this morning,
but it wasn't until two o'clock
this afternoon that he stood up,
dressed in a black suit,
white shirt and blue tie,
and spoke clearly and confidently
when he was asked how he would plea
to each of the five counts of murder.
They were read out in this order...
I've been here since about half-nine.
I just saw him come along, like,
with the police, sirens and that.
They were... you know...
None of the photographers caught him.
Caught any photos of him
or anything but...
Just waiting to get a glimpse, really.
Yeah, look at this. Look at this.
It's horrible, innit, eh?
It's a wicked bloody world.
Yourself, I mean, you'd be,
as far as I'm, well, as far as I'm aware,
about the only person
that has actually come down here
and asked the residents how they feel.
I think this is absolutely fantastic.
So many people here tonight.
I haven't counted you all.
Seeing everybody have a great time,
that's what it's all about.
I would like to congratulate everyone
that's really worked hard
on their gardens.
Even the people that haven't won.
it doesn't matter.
It's sharing their gardens
with everyone else and really working hard
and making London Road
what London Road is -
a fantastic road.
I've got nearly 17 hanging baskets
In this back garden
Believe it or not
Begonias and petunias
And, erm, impatiens and things
Marigolds, petunias
And we got up there
We got busy Lizzies
Hanging geraniums, all right, see
There's all sorts in that basket anyway
Hanging nobilius
Petunias in a basket, hanging basket
That's a fuchsia
Erm, there is a special name
I just call 'em lilies
They're a lily type
There is a special name
And for the first time this year
I've got a couple of erm... baskets
Begonias and petunias
And, erm, impatiens and things
- Begonias and petunias
-  Marigolds, petunias
- We got busy Lizzies, hanging lobelias
-  And, erm, impatiens and things
Hanging baskets
Variegated ivy in there
Which makes a nice show
And then you've got
These sky-blue... whatever they are
Vm-veer-veer-la-la
That's, er, little purple ones
Rhubarb.
The old-fashioned marguerites
The daisies
The roses
Have done really well this year
Yeah
Gave us an extra point for having basil
On the windowsill, didn't she?
-   Hanging baskets
-   Rhubarb
- Variegated ivy in there
- The old-fashioned marguerites
- Which makes a nice show
- The daisies
The roses
Have done really well this year.
I've got nearly 17 hanging baskets
In this back garden
Gave us an extra point
For having basil
On the windowsill, didn't she?
And, erm, impatiens and things
Begonias and petunias
Impatiens and things
Impatiens
And things