THE 2 SIDES OF THE BED
Dancing,
I spend the whole day dancing
and meanwhile the neighbors
keep bothering me.
Drinking,
I spend the whole day drinking,
with the cocktail shaker ...
full of soda and vermouth.
My bones are dislocated,
my femur is way out of line.
My body is in a mess ...
but my social life ...
but my social life!
is going just fine,
I dance all day long.
with or without a partneré,
I move my leg, I move my foot.
I move my tibia and fibula,
I move my head, I move my sternum.
I move my hip when I get the chance
Drinking,
I spend the whole day drinking,
with the cocktail shaker ...
full of soda and vermouth.
Bravo!
Waiter!
To your wedding.
May you be very happy.
And to you two.
May you get married soon too.
I think we'll see
how it goes, right?
Yes. The way to see it,|is to see how it goes, right?
Of course.|It's best to do things slowly.
What?
Maybe we should wait a bit,|don't you think?
Wait a bit?
Eu quase tive um ataque do coração!
What I like most about Marta|is her sense of humor.
"Wait a bit", she says!
It's a pity we can't all get married|at the same time.
But maybe we can|christen the children ...
at the same time.|- No.
- No children, Javier.|- Why not?
It's important to have children.|What do you think?
I think the food|is disagreeing with me.
- Really?|- What's wrong?
You want some chamomile?
It's as if...
I feel short of breath.
I don't mean have one tomorrow,|but maybe in a few years...
Chamomile is good for everything.
I don't want anything, Pedro.
We'll see about children.|Shall we go to the washroom?
- Yes, we'd better.|- Don't get sick now..
I'll order chamomile.
Look, she doesn't want chamomile.|Come on.
Sorry.
They're both nervous|about the wedding.
Raquel too.
I can't take it anymore.
Neither can I. You've been|turning me on all night.
Stop, stop, I don't mean that.|We can't go on like this.
It's true.
Marta!
I'm finished with messing around.
I want to settle down with Marta.
I'd rather watch TV with her|than be out on the town...
trying to pick up some girl...
Hey, I'm sorry about ...
}about...
There it is!
Thank you.
Do you guys know|where the washroom is?
It's that way.
Where?
- I'm sorry!|- Don't worry, it's all right.
It was nothing.
I'm going to the washroom.
What were you saying about?
I don't know.
Like that?
Yes, like that!|Yes, yes, yes, yes
Hey, quit all that yessing,|I'm wetting myself!
The meal disagreed with her..
Yes, the duck.|It really disagreed with me.
The duck!!
Yeah, yeah, the duck!
Never again like that, never.
I know,|you like me to be gentle.
- Come on.|- I'm wetting myself.
Not now. Come on.
You two with the duck,
you left "sumsin".
She was really sick.|Come on.
Shit, they were mine!
These couples!
What took you so long?
We came along Mediterraneo,|Mariano de Cavia, Menendez Pelayo,
and instead of taking Goya|went down Juan Bravo.
And the traffic!
I don't know what you girls|are doing tonight, but we...
Cheer up,|this is your hen party.
Fun and games, we're in Spain!|Right, Carlitos?
- Fun and games.|- Rafa,
ease up a bit.
Sorry.
- Hello.|- Pedro...
- I was going to say...|- Yes, Rafa.
There was a blond|in the restaurant and...
Here we go ...
Haven't we got|anything better to talk about?
We're a bit old to be|talking tits and asses all day.
- Come on, pet.|- Yes, lover.
Grow up a bit, Pedro.
But...
My darling, my darling,|don't leave me for a male stripper.
I'm telling you,|they're all muscle and no brain.
Not like you.
I'm going.
The meal really disagreed with you.|You've got a huge rash there.
- Pedro, I had an allergy.|- All right.
If we don't go now|we'll miss the Happy Hour.
All right.|See you back home.
- Come on!|- So long, gorgeous.
Hey!
My love!
Have fun!
I'm getting married tomorrow, guys!
You're getting married?
- Hello.|- Hello. Who to?
To...
See that brunette?
The brunette?
Yes.
And the other one?
No, the other one,|the blonde, is mine.
And what are they?|Real good friends?
Yeah, they are, like us.
Maybe this is silly,
but I think they're closer friends|than you are.
No, he and I are inseparable.
You too?
Yes.
Fucking great!
Why?
Let's go on a stag night.
We're just having one drink.
I don't want the usual crap|with naked girls and all that.
Maybe it's not such crap.
Pedro, you don't change,|you don't evolve.
My boyfriend left me.
He did?|Why was that?
I thought it was just going|to be us tonight.
I think she likes me.
She looked at me.
We're having a great time,|aren't we?
Yes, it's really fun.
- Don't dare touch me with that.|- All right, be like that!
Have you seen those legs,
those arms, those backs,
those asses?
It's a wild, crazy party.
Why the fuck are we here?
Do you love me?
Of course I do,
but it's impossible.
- You don't understand.|- No, I don't.
Tomorrow I'm getting married,|don't you realize?
How could I not realize?
Today, the sun is shining|through my window
and my heart
is growing sad
as I look out at the city.
Why are you leaving?
Just like every night, I woke up
thinking of you,
and on my clock|I watched the hours go by.
Why are you leaving?
All of my love's promises|will leave with you.
You'll forget me.
Today at the station|I'll be crying like a child.
Why are you leaving?
In the semi-darkness|of a street light,
all the things
that were left unsaid|will lie in slumber.
They'll lie in slumber.
Beside the hands of a clock,
all the hours
.
They'll wait for you.
All of my love's promises|will leave with you.
You'll forget me.
Today at the station|I'll be crying like a child.
Why are you leaving?
You pay this, Carlos.
Rafa, all this is over for me.
It's time for other things.|I'm even talking about children.
In what sense?
In the sense of having them.
Oh, that's fine.
I think that Spanish reasoning|is intemal...
and life is a vicious circle.
- So do I.|- I've always said
that to be happy|you have to get married.
I'll tell you,|people aren't stupid
and if people have always|got married...
If they've always got married|there was a reason.
- What about Cuba?|- What do you mean?
ÉIt's the same in Cuba.|People get married.
- Everyone gets married here.|- Exactly.
You too, right?
Well, I'm thinking about it,|but, yes.
Why don't|you all do it together?
- Do what?|- Get married.
Because I still haven't|made up my mind. I'm...
She's made up her mind.
Yes, she wants to.
We haven't discussed it|but I can tell.
You're very intuitive.
Yes, yes.
But I know women too.
It's been a long time.
I'm telling you, hurry up
or someone will come along|and carry her off.
You're very intuitive.
I'm the intuitive one.|I'll tell you something, Pedro.
Maybe Pilar and I will be|getting married along with you.
That's great, Rafa.
You're the sad one.
You're all on your own.
But you're fine like that.
Here I am, without a partner.
So you guys|don't want anything to do
with any other women?
No, basically...
When you're 20, it's different,|but we won't see 30 again.
Look, real people,decent, ordinary people,
are faithful. Like me.
That's a pity
because I wanted to have|a good time tonight.
But if you're all so faithful...
We're fine, we've got it all|very clear, right?
If they'd told us a year ago
we wouldn't have believed it.
You're telling me!
Are you happy with me?
Why do you ask that?
Recently, you seem...
- What?|- A bit colder.
Me?
As if you were envious that they're|getting married and we're not.
Getting married is fine.
But maybe we could wait a little,|and not because I've got doubts.
But if you want to get married,
tell me and we'll think about it.
There he is!
- Hello.|- You look absolutely gorgeous!
Come off it.
Have you had a good look at her?|If I didn't have Marta...
Is she coming down?
Yes, but we'll leave first.|The bride has to arrive late.
Let's go!
We'll talk later.
Stop talking.|Just get married.
Coward.
We can't do this to them.
If you want me to get married, I will.
- I didn't say that.|- I don't care.
I love Javier,|like you love Pedro.
You'll get married too,
and have children|and a house in the suburbs.
And Pedro's parents are wealthy
so maybe some day|you can stop singing
and spend more time with him.
Your whole lives together!
What's wrong?
There they are!
But...
Why aren't they getting out?
She's having doubts about it!
I've got no doubts about it.
These six months with you|have been wonderful
and I'll never forget you.
She's having doubts about it.
She's thinking,|"What am I doing with that creep?"
"What am I doing with that creep?
What are they doing?
- What are you doing?|- Get out of here.
What?
You're going to get married,|but to me.
I love you!
Maybe she's confused,|or she's got doubts,
or she's changed her mind,|or she wasn't happy,
or she's tired,|or she's joined a sect,
or she's rethinking her future|or she's met someone else...
That's it.|I'm sure of it.
No, Javier.
She told me|she needs time to think.
But don't worry.
Wait a few days, she'll call you.
Anyway, who could she be with?
Some ex-boyfriend, right?
- Could I have a beer, please?|- Rafael...
Non-alcoholic.
It's much better for 1,000 reasons
but I'm not going to list them now|because it isn't the ...
Come on, don't be sad.
I bet you'll be married|by next week.
Or maybe not.|You can't force things.
Don't look at me like that.|But anyway,
come to our place
and I'll look after you|while Pedro goes to Almeria.
Why are you going there?
To check some fossils,|to see if they're Neolithic.
- Why do you have to go?|- It's my specialty.
You think I want to go to Almeria|and not be here to help you?
You're the most important thing|for me.
But it doesn't matter if he goes.|Come to our place,
we'll have a great time together.
But he doesn't really have|to come to our place, does he?
You have to start getting back|to your normal life.
Just one thing, Pedro.
Why Almeria?
There's no Neolithic there.|I mean, there are other things...
- Deserts, cacti, beaches|- Almeria is!
What if I go with you?
I'm going to work.
- I'll help you.|- Don't be so childish.
Go to a hotel, and that's it.
Don't be silly,|he's coming to our place.
Pedro, do what you want|but there's no Neolithic in Almeria.
Where are you going?
- To the area where the washrooms are.|- Me too.
There's no need|for you to come to our place.
He can't fool me.
He set this up|to steal her from me.
He didn't marry Raquel|because he wants Marta.
She's waiting for him in Almeria.
Does he think I'm stupid?
It's just getting worse!
- That's it?|- That's it
He can't fool me.
He's waiting for his chance|to jump on Raquel.
I know him, the bastard.
Well, guys.
A Spanish dick never pisses alone.
I always said that|that couple wasn't...
And when I was joking...|Look, a squashed cat!
When I was joking,|I knew deep down..
Slow down. Better to lose a minute in|your life than your life in a minute.
And to arrive five minutes late|than not at all.
But what I'm trying to say is
it's not just that.|It's the mind, my mind.
- Well, the mind...|- That's it.
Normally we only use 10%
and I feel that I'm using more|and I see more things.
Look.|There's a gas station.
- Pull in, we're low on gas.|- You see?
I was just thinking that|and I hadn't seen the warning light.
- But look, the tank is full.|- Even so...
- A stitch in time saves nine.|- Exactly.
Slow down a bit as you go in,
and let's see if we can shave|a bit closer here.
Yes, sorry.
What was that?
That was a bit of..
That was sputum.
Yes, it was,
but I was just clearing my throat,|it'll never happen again.
I hope not.
Are you crazy?
What are you doing?
I'm getting some tablets,|I've got heartburn.
What the fuck are you doing?
No Neolithic remains|have ever been found in Almeria.
What are you talking about?
- What are you talking about?|- Watch your hands.
Watch your hands.
- What's up?|- What's up?
He's crazy.|He's gone bananas.
Don't be silly.|He's upset.
He's depressed.
But I'll look after him|while you're in Almeria.
- Good night.|- Good night.
What is it?
- I can't sleep.|- And?
I want to sleep here,|move over.
There's no room|and you'll have insomnia here too.
- Thanks a lot!|- Forget it.
- Come on, move over.|- There's no room here.
In that case,|go and sleep in the guest room.
What did you say?
Look at the state he's in.|He needs company.
All right.|The three of us can sleep here.
The bed's enormous.
What are you doing?
I'll make a sacrifice.
I'll get in the middle,|it's the most uncomfortable.
- I hurt myself, Pedro.|- I'm sorry.
Good night, Javier.
Will you hold my hand?
What?
Hold my hand, I feel bad.
Why don't we leave the light on?
Look, can we get to sleep?
I just want someone to hold my hand!|It that so much to ask?
I'm not asking that much either.|I just want the light on.
Pedro, just keep quiet|and hold his hand.
What is it?|What's wrong now?
That's enough!|Swap places with me.
But it was him!
You lie here|or you go to the guest room.
- Come on.|- Unbelievable!
That's it.
We're going to sleep.
He's in my bed, in my house,|and I have to go to the spare room.
- Who'd believe it?|- That's it.
- Can I hold your hand, Raquel?|- Here, you can hold mine.
I'll hold your hand too, Pedro.
Javier, I think you're right.
I don't think I'll find anything|in Almeria. So I'll stay here,
at home.
God!!
Fuck, that must have hurt!
Rafa?
Rafael?
I was just...|Weren't you meeting someone?
Me? No.
- What's that smell?|- My father..
I mean, my father comes here|and he starts smoking..
You know what he's like.
He leaves the TV on and ...
That's easy.
We turn it off.
And what?
- Rafael!|- What do you care? Please.
- Rafael!|- What do you care?
Two don't argue|if one doesn't want to,
but, please, tell your father|he's not to smoke in here.
It won't happen again.|A word to the wise is enough.
Yes, but there's none so deaf|as he who won't hear.
That's true too.
"Dear Diary:
My love is so strong it scares me.
Yesterday when Rafa went to work
I went for a walk with my new love.
We talked about literature,
about cinema, about animals,
about cell phones...
Waken up.
Javier, it's 2:15.
Where's Pedro?
He's in the museum.
Here, have your shower.
Come on, it's late.
Are you all right?
I feel awful.
Don't be like that
You're going to find loads of girls
who'll be crazy to be with you.
Take it easy!
- What's that?|- What?
What are you doing?
- Come to bed with me.|- Why? Are you crazy?
Because I feel bad.
How can you have such a nerve?
If you were feeling bad,|I'd do it for you.
Don't be so selfish.
Selfish?
I bring you into my home, my bed...
- And?|- What more do you want?
I'm telling you.
You're a!
You needn't be like that.
If you don't want to,|just say so.
- Hello.|- Hello.
I wanted a word with you.
Yes, but not now,
- I'm in a hurry.|- Just one second.
This isn't the most romantic place|in the world
but I'll never find one|that's worthy of you.
Will you marry me?
Don't be silly!
It's no big deal.
Pedro!
Here, my love.
You're so mysterious.
I'm getting a sore throat.
Let me pass through the wind|without documents.
I'll do it for the time we had
because there's no way out,|because you seem to be asleep,
because I'd spend my whole life|looking for your smile.
I want to be the only one|who bites your lips.
I want to know that life with you|isn't going to end.
Let me close your eyes tonight
and tomorrow I'll go to bed|with a cigarette
because I've got no other intention
but to keep|drinking from this glass
that isn't so broken.
I want to be the only one who bites
your lips.
I want to know that life with you|isn't going to end.
Just because! Just because!
Because in this life
I don't want to spend|a whole day without you.
Just because!|Just because! Just because!
Because while I'm waiting
I die for you|and I don't want to live like this.
Pilar! Pili!
Look what some idiot|left in the taxi.
- What are you doing here?|- And you?
I brought you this thing.
I'm glad you're here, Carlos.
- We can have supper together.|- It's lovely, I'll put it away.
Never look a gift horse|in the mouth.
It's a lie.
- I bought it.|- What?
The umbrella. I came to see|if I'd catch her with someone else.
She's with someone, someone else,|someone who's not me.
I need you to be my right hand.|Understand?
You're the only person|I can trust. Why?
Well, today you're going to stay|and sleep in the fold-up bed.
- It's very comfortable.|- You needn't bother...
There's one vital thing.
Pay attention to the...|to all the...
things that might seem like sparks|to you, that you mightn't...
You say there's nothing.|There is, Carlos, there is!
With my mind, I'm going to find|the most hidden clues.
I'm asking you, please.|Understand?
Hey, listen, sweetheart,
Carlos says he's got builders|in his house, or something,
and he wants to stay here.|- To sleep? Yes, of course.
Stay as long as you want.
I told you,|a week, two, four...
So, when I'm out|he can keep you company, right?
Exactly.|Take down the garbage.
Yes. Right away, love.
Hey, miss!
Sorry! Keep the change.
Tell me,|what symptoms do you have?
I feel terrible.
- I've got a pain here.|- That looks very bad.
- I'll have to examine you.|- Shall I take off my blouse?
No. That isn't necessary.
Get on the couch.
Well, open your mouth.
No, my throat doesn't hurt.
The pain seems to be here.
Who's the doctor, you or I?
I'm sorry,
I'm very nervous because
I left my boyfriend today.
Am I very ill?
You're very bad.
- Take off your blouse, please.|- I told you so.
Are you sure about what you did?
Totally, I think.
I feel sorry for my boyfriend
because he's really cute|and he loves me
but I think I'm in love|with someone else.
Who?
A wicked doctor.
Well, really she's just an intem
and she never gets|a diagnosis right.
Can I be cured?
Well,
it's too early to say
but I'll give you|a thorough examination.
You kill yourself|to make them happy
and what thanks do you get?
I've been thinking about it|all afternoon
and it's just as well.
What's just as well?
It's just as well, because|we weren't going anywhere.
Marriage, mortgage, job, children,|you get old and you die.
- What's that?|- Nothing.
That's not life.
Life is something else
and we're starting to enjoy it now.
We're both here now, relaxed,
with no pressure,|talking about life.
That's true.|We're in fucking heaven here!
Just you and I.
You and I,|like it's always been.
Do you know
there was
a second when I thought|you were keen on Marta?
You know what?
I was sure you were going|to try it on with Raquel.
What do you mean?
I don't think|that's the least bit funny.
- Don't you know me?|- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Forget it.
They're idiots.
Don't they realize|what they're losing?
I'm telling you now.
They're going to come
crying and begging.
I want to see that.|Then we'll see what's what.
They're going to come back|but I'm through with them.
Do you know the life|that's ahead of us?
- Screwing all the time.|- Right.
Who with?
Hello, this is Raquel.|Leave a message.
Drinking,
I spend the whole day drinking,
with the cocktail shaker
full of soda
and vermouth.
It's the groom!
Carlota!
How are you?
Very well.|Want a drink?
Sure.
- I'll have the same as you.|- Same again, please..
Well, Pedro,|how was the wedding?
Javier.
Sorry!
How was it?
In the end I didn't get married.|I'm more of a lone wolf.
She left you.
Yes.
She left you?
And it was hard.
After years of struggling|for that relationship...
I'm really sorry.
But you look great.
- I'm delighted to see you here.|- No, wait.
The truth is,
I came to see you.
What?
How did you know I was here?
Well, I didn't,|but as I had to see Raquel too...
Anyway, the fact is|I'm glad you're here.
Why?
Because the other day you said
some very intelligent things.
I did?
What things?
Do you like my perfume?
Yes, I love it.
What intelligent things did I say?
I don't remember!
- You're very intelligent too.|- Yeah, well,
you have to pull yourself together.|Life goes on.
- Yes.|- I stopped believing in love.
Really?
And it's a pity|to lose that innocence.
It's doing me good to talk to you.
Thank you.
But I don't really like talking..
I've got a better remedy.
Dancing.
You mean right now?
No, I go to dance classes.
You don't say!
I adore dancing.
- No!|- Yes.
What kind of dancing?
Classical dancing,
modern dancing,|ballroom dancing...
- Which do you prefer?|- Modern.
Really? Just like me!
What school do you go to?
Right now, to none,|but I could go to yours.
Why not?
Heavens! Of course.
I'm the melon boy.
To be happy I want a truck.
Spitting on the urban dwellers,
feeling up my girl.
To be happy I want a truck.
To be happy I want a melon.
I'm the melon boy!
The melon boy!
Wait, wait, it's all right.
It's a trial, an experiment.
No, really, as a good person.
Listen to me, as a good person.
Carlota?
What are you doing here?
Hello, Pedro, how are you?|Has your girlfriend left you too?
Yes, and it's not funny.
No.
It's not.
I'm sorry.
But that makes three of us.
But we've discovered|a fantastic remedy.
Come with us to dance classes.
No, Pedro doesn't like dancing.
What's this about dancing?
Nothing.
Javier and I were talking|and discovered we both love dancing.
- Isn't that a coincidence?|- Yes,
it certainly is.|Javier has never liked dancing.
- No?|- What do you mean?
Don't tell lies.|I dance all day long.
I'm going to sign up too|because I do like dancing..
Oh, yeah?|Let's see, dance a bit.
You dance a bit|if you like it so much.
- I'll sign up tomorrow.|- There are no places left.
Yes, there are places
Would you like a drink?
Yes, I'll have a drink.|I'll be right back.
You don't know him.
Since his girlfriend left him|he's a wreck.
Why did she leave him?
Basically because he's so envious.
You saw what happened|about the dancing..
He copied me.
He envies you?
It's oozing out of him.
Why?
It's to do with structure,|because of women.
But your girlfriend left you too.
Yes, but I'm coping much better.
I don't want to turn you against him|or criticize him, but he's...
- I'd love a drink.|- So would I.
Will you get them, Javier?
- Gin and tonic.|- Same here.
- Could I have a slice of lemon?|- Sure.
Could I have|three ice cubes, please?
Pedro, don't be angry with us.
I'm not, it isn't that.
I had a dream,|well, more of a nightmare.
- Yeah?|- Yeah.
Javier's girlfriend.
She jilted him.
I dreamed she was a lesbian.
Fuck!
And yours?
No, no, mine isn't.
Mine isn't.
Why don't we go out somewhere|for the last drink?
- Sure, or the second last.|- All right.
- What's up?|- We're going out for a drink.
Now? But it's fine here.
Well, you stay here.
No, come on.
Where are we going?
I don't know. Wherever.
We'll race through the streets,
kick up a fuss|when no one's around.
I don't want to sleep.
Some don't get it|and punch everybody.
Someone's leaping|over the rooftops.
He won't sleep anymore.
And at night,|we'll do the usual stuff
because we like it|and because it's fun.
She's passed out,|she works too hard.
She's in a hurry|and wants to go far.
She can't sleep.
He said he was leaving|but he's still here.
One whole night|with the same story.
He doesn't know how to sleep.
And at night|we'll do the usual stuff
because we like it|and because it's fun.
You bite the pillow,|cling to the bed.
The bed is empty,|the light is out.
You want to sleep.
We're waiting|for our friend to come.
He sleeps a lot|and knows what he's doing.
He likes to sleep.
And at night|we'll do the usual stuff
because we like it|and because it's fun.
And at night|we'll do the usual stuff.
Come on.
You'll waken her.
You're a nervous spirit!
Come here, come here.
You have to control your nerves|even in the most extreme situations!
The mind.
"Dear Diary: I don't know where|this unbridled passion will lead me
but I have to live it,|feel it, enjoy it... "
That's how things are.
Do you still not know|who it could be?
Maybe some ex-boyfriend...
She's smart, she's so smart.
She never mentions|his name anywhere, just O.
Who can it be?
My mind is talking to me.
I'm going to leave her.
No, no, Carlos.
Don't insist.|You won't convince me.
I'm going to leave her.
Look, Carlos,|one thing, one "item".
No one messes me around,|I mean, like, no one!
I'll leave her, she'll come crawling|and then we'll see.
I'd ask you one thing, my friend.
Don't let me weaken, please,|because I'm very sentimental.
You know that.
You're dressing very well recently.
Hello?
Marta?
Well!
- How nice.|- What do you want?
I'm taking dancing classes.
The dance school is near here,
in Tudescos,
and I just wanted to see you.
Wait in the sitting room,|I'll be out now.
- Maybe we rushed things a bit.|- What's that?
- What?|- That.
This?
No, not that!
Nothing.
What I mean is
things are never perfect
- and people have to hang on.|- Yes, hang on.
Just hang on!
- And talk things through.|- Yes.
Well, we've talked it all through.
Fix some drinks|and we'll celebrate.
I feel something very special|for you.
I've never loved anyone|like I love you.
I think you were right|in what you said about hanging on.
You have to hang on.
But it's not only that.
Leave me alone for a moment,|I want to think about it.
What if I get in...
Pick up the phone!
It isn't ringing.
Love, if you don't want|to marry me, it's all right.
Of course it's all right.|Fix me a drink, please.
I want to know if you're willing|to start over again.
No, not start over again.|Hang on. Hang on!
Hello, Javier!
Don't look like that,|nothing's happened.
I told her not to come out because|I knew you'd get the wrong idea.
And you did, didn't you?
Bitches...
You're crazy!
Murderer!
Do you want to kill me?|Do you?
They were just bathing together.|It means nothing.
She was taking a hair|out of her mouth.
I do that too sometimes.
She had her head there,|right there.
Of all the women in the world,|those two had to have an affair.
I don't want to go in!
It was the worst thing|I've ever seen.
She pretended to be looking after me|and she was screwing my girlfriend!
I bet it was|innocent little Marta who...
And what were you doing?
You should have had|your eyes open!
And your fixation|for getting married?
How could you do this to me?
I'd have loved you to the end.
I know you'll be sorry.
Whose business is it|what I do?
Whose business is it|what I say?
This is how I am|and I'll stay like this.
I'll never change.
What dirty, treacherous grief.
It's poisoning my heart.
I know that she never went crazy
and never lost control.
Leave me.
It's senseless now.
It's best
if you go your way
and I go mine.
No.
So leave me now.
She never swore her love for me.
I believed it was eternal.
And she smiled at me
and looked out at the sea.
What a bore, what a bore!
Always thinking of the past.
Don't think too much about it,
life is waiting for you.
Get out of here.
You didn't understand me.
I only think about your skin.
You don't have to lie.
It's so easy|to torture yourself afterwards.
But I'll survive.|I know I can. I'll survive.
Where's our mistake|that can't be fixed?
You were the guilty one, not I.
Neither you nor anyone|can change me.
A thousand bells|are ringing in my heart.
It's so hard|to say you're sorry.
Neither you nor anyone|can change me.
Where's our mistake|that can't be fixed?
You were the guilty one, not I.
Neither you nor anyone|can change me.
A thousand bells|are ringing in my heart.
It's so hard|to say you're sorry.
Neither you nor anyone|can change me,
can change me,
Wait!
I don't know what to say.
Well...
My girlfriend is sleeping|with his girlfriend.
This isn't life.
Life is something else.
Now what do I do?
If you want,|we'll have dinner tomorrow.
What?
Stay out of this.
- You can't do it on your own.|- Says who?
- What time?|- I don't know..
- At 9:00?|- What do you mean, at 9:00?
At 9:00.
Help me if I start to weaken.|I know her
and when I tell her my decision|she'll be shattered
and she'll start crying|and then I'II...
But I have to... right.
There she is.
Now you'll see if an ox shits|more than a thousand pigeons.
- Hello.|- Hello
I'm Carlos
He's Rafael.
This is Gema,
my cousin.
I've mentioned her loads of times.
- How many?|- Lots.
Once watching TV, and then|on the stairs, and in the car.
- More than ten times?|- Exactly ten times.
Pilar, I have to talk to you.
What about?
Personal things.
What a coincidence.|So do I.
- You know I loved you a lot.|- Right.
Well, I still do,
because true affection|can't be bought or sold
or paid for with money.|- Right.
What?
But the flame of love is..
We're going to split up.
What?
We're... we're... What?
But don't worry, a new love|drives out the old love
and as good a love comes|as goes,,
and I know you're going to be|very happy with Gema.
Say something.
- And Rafa?|- What about Rafa?
- Where does Rafa come from?|- From Rafael.
Like Paco from Francisco,|Pepe from Jose, Pitu from Anibal.
No, listen, I think|you're getting confused.
I'm the one leaving you
I want nothing to do with you|or your cousin.
- Why not?|- Because he's hurt, but just wait.
There are lots of vibrations|between you.
You don't get it, Pilar.|I'm leaving you.
Who loses a wife, gains a lot.|You're on your own.
Where does Carlos come from?
From my father.
Pilar, look...
The longest day has an end,|time cures all,
what can't be can't be|and, anyway, it's impossible.
Leave my stuff alone!
My friend,
if you only knew|what love is like
It goes back|to whoever takes it,
hawk
or dove.
Poor fool,
naive charlatan.
I was a dove
because I wanted to be a hawk.
What's up?
I've left Pilar, so...
Why?
Because... because...
At times it isn't a question|of why, Javier.
I've left her. Understand?
Sure.
What I'd like right now|is to have a drink..
I always like to have a drink|before I go to bed,
but if you can't|or don't feel like it,
it's not...
- Shall we have one in my place?|- Is this your place?
- Come off it.|- No, I didn't know...
I don't want to go to bed late|but if you want we'll have one.
One, or all we want.
I like a drink too|before I go to bed.
Wait, wait, wait.
Not like that.
What's wrong?
I'm fed up.
You could show more interest.
What's wrong?
- Don't you like me anymore?|- Don't start that, I'm not a guy.
All right.
You know that I'm more...
more into cuddles, Marta,
and when I was with Pedro...
Pedro again!|What's up with Pedro now?
It was different.
He was more
loving, more considerate,|and now it's...
Hang on a minute.
Are you saying|I'm not considerate?
No, Marta, you're a bit rough.
Now it tums out that|Pedro has got a velvet touch..
It's not that.
Don't get annoyed,|it's just that you're
more boom-boom bang-bang...
Boom-boom bang-bang?
Yes, and it's always the same
and I'm tired of it.
Obviously, if you prefer Pedro!
I didn't say that!
It's just that Pedro|is a genius at preliminaries.
No, it's that I'm very passionate|and Pedro is a wimp!
Good night.
- Don't be so silly!|- Stop it!
- Marta, please,|- Leave me alone!
I'm just saying|it's better like this.
Stop that.
Stop!
All right, it is nice like that.
But put a bit of life|into it, please!
Well, another drink?
All right, one, or all we want.
Why the hell are you here?
- Why the hell are you here?|- I'd a date with Carlota too.
- Forget it, we're very busy.|- Hello, Javier!
Come in!
Thank you.
- Pedro!|- Really!
Come in, really!
How are you?
- Fine, and you?|- Fine.
- You look lovely.|- Yes?
Want a drink?
No, you don't.
Thank you.
I was first.
What are you, 10 years old?|Grow up a bit.
You grow up, Pedro.
- Me?|- You've been here three hours
and you're still like this.|- Because we want to be.
- These are just preliminaries.|- At this stage?
Yes, the second preliminaries.|Everything has happened.
What's happened?
Everything. Even...
Even what?
Even that.
I doubt that you've done it.
Well, stop doubting,|we've done it twice!
I don't care, because|you can't do it well and I can.
I don't know if you do it well|but you certainly do it fast.
We have problems hanging on.
I haven't got any problem.
You must have, if your girl|is doing it with another girl.
Who happens to be your girl.
Exactly.
I work like a Swiss watch.
Javier...
But the thing is|Marta is more boom-boom
bang-bang all the time.
Right.
And I prefer other things.
That's normal.
Poor thing.
Calm down, calm down.
Got a cough?
What's wrong?
My earring!
He swallowed my earring!
Better?
You nearly broke my plexus.
You've done irreversible damage.
- You first.|- No, you.
You first.
- Ready?|- Yes.
- Ready?|- Yes?
We're practicing the shot put.
How about dinner tonight?
What?
What did that idiot say?
Tell me, what's up?
You have to choose now.
- What do I have to choose?|- Which one you prefer.
- We'll end up killing each other.|- You're the one threatening me.
All right.
I hadn't thought about it,|but if you want, I'll choose.
Will you stand up for a minute?
Pedro,|can you throw your hair back?
That's fine.
You can sit down.
Both of you.
Both of us for what?
Both of us for...
Shit! A trio?
No fucking way.
A trio.
A triumvirate.
She wants us to do a trio.
Shit, maybe with another girl,|but with Javier!
What's wrong with women?
Have they all gone mad?
How do you do a trio?
I'll have to watch a porn movie|to get some ideas.
They're unbalanced,
they become lesbians,|they want to do trios.
What's going on here?
If it's an hour earlier|in the Canaries,
when the clocks go back
for an hour it's the same time
in the Canaries as in Spain.
Javier and I|mustn't touch each other
Shit,|or even look at each other.
We'll have to get drunk first
or do something to break the ice.
Wait till I tell them|in the museum!
And when the clocks go forward
for a while there are two hours more|in Spain than in the Canaries.
How is it that I'm the only one|to have realized that?
It's here.
Shit, you're lovely!
- What the fuck is that?|- Isn't it beautiful?
I saw it in the store window|and said, "Mine".
It was like an encounter.
I thought of finding|a place for it in the house.
Maybe beside the TV?
Rafa, it's disgusting.
Why?
Because it's fucking dead.
Yes,|but it looks like it's alive.
Just look at it!
Its eyes are alive!|It's in attack position...
No! Put it out on the street|I don't want dead animals in the house.
We'll go to my room.
It can go on my bedside table.
But I don't say anything|about the furniture here.
There isn't one fucking drawer.
Don't you worry,|we'll be fine in my room.
I've got a portable TV
and more things.
How long have we been|friends with Rafa?
All our lives
Why is he our friend?
I don't know.
I really don't know.
Am I...
Am I your best friend?
Yes.
You're my best friend.
You're like...
You're like a brother.
Same here.
You know that brothers|sometimes do things
that aren't very normal.
They may not be normal
but that doesn't mean|that those things are bad.
Society changes and evolves.
Evolves?|It evolves at the speed of light.
Tomorrow.
Rafa's working.
- But we don't look at each other.|- For God's sake.
For God's sake.
Wait!
Look at that offer.|Paris, 4 days, 300 euros.
Let's go.
- Shall we?|- But...
Paris?
No, not Paris
Paris? Why not?
Because
the first trip I made with Pedro
was to Paris, and...
And what?|I don't see why we can't go now.
Marta, everything is going|to remind me of Pedro,
I'll be thinking about him.
I mean... I think so.
Why don't you go back to Pedro?
Don't be silly. I love you.
Yeah, but you love Pedro more.
You talk about him all day
and everything we do reminds you|of when you were together...
Yes, I miss him
but I want to be with you too.
I'd rather you were with him|and missing me.
I need to be with someone|who's in love with me.
I want someone|who's dying about me,
and you're an angel
but you're not in love with me.
You know, the nicest thing|that's ever happened to me
was being with you,
but it's best if we finish it|before everything is ruined.
But...
Marta!
Look! Look!
Two lesbians.
What was I saying?
Spanish reasoning is internal,|I never tire of saying that,
and nothing is...|You know? Obviously.
Understand?
I listen to the radio,|know what I mean?
I know at what level|things are moving, you know,
and it's all going to hell.
Spain is finished.
This isn't the way, and you're|going down a one-way street
Éthe wrong way.|- It's a shortcut.| Don't tell me how to do my job.
I'm killing myself|twelve hours a day.
Why are we going so slowly?
ÉIt's better.
Why are we stopping?
Charlie...
Jose Carlos!
I need help.
She won't come.
She won't,
will she?
I mean,
an hour and a half.
Just as well.
Why?
Because it's just as well.
- These things never work out.|- No, they don't.
I withdraw.
I've got better things to do.
You withdraw unilaterally,|without...
"I withdraw. "
Well, now I withdraw.
No, because...
Because I said...|I said "I withdraw"
and I said it first.|- All right, you withdraw.
She came.
- Who'll open the door?|- I'll do it.
- No, I'll do it.|- We'll both do it.
}No, it's stupid if we both do it.
- Then you do it.|- No, you do it, you do it.
What's it to be?
You. Go on.
What I said before doesn't count.
You can't do that!
- Hello.|- Hello, come in.
- How are you?|- Fine, and you?
Fine.
- I'm sorry I'm late, I didn't...|- Don't worry.
You're not that late.
Where's Pedro?
- Hello.|- Hello, Pedro.
So you're here.
- Yes.|- Great.
- Sorry I'm late.|- Don't worry, we didn't even notice.
It's hot, isn't it?
- You look lovely.|- Yes, you look lovely.
Thank you.
You two look very handsome.
Shall I take your coat?
A glass of wine or...
- Or two?|- The bottle!
One question,|dinner before or after?
- Before.|- After.
- After.|- Before.
- Whatever.|- It doesn't matter.
If we're this well coordinated...
Three.
Like us.
Sit down.
Be generous, Javier.
Shall we begin?
- What, here?|- The meal.
Yes, yes!
Let's start.
These crabs...
Give me the plate.
I don't think|I can swallow anything.
Any food?
Why don't we stop messing around?
- Let's relax a bit.|- Yes! Yes!
We're kind of...
- How about a toast?|- We're going to loosen up.
This is more relaxed.
Well, here's to seduction.
- And to all our exes.|- To us.
- To us, much better.|- No, to the three of us.
Right.
Don't say a word.
I see it all
in your eyes.
You are
trying to leave.
And I
want to get you.
I want, I want,|I want to kiss you.
Hey,
sit down by my side.
I like you too much.
I am
Y:i}nervous and excited.
Baby,
don't leave me in the lurch.
Wait, don't go,|hang on for a minute.
Let me explain|why you're confused.
I just want to get to know you|and have a good time.
Give me your hand,|no one will disturb us.
There's no one home today|and I'm feeling in great form.
Let me take your clothes off
and don't switch off the light.
I want, I want,|I want to kiss you.
I want,|I want to kiss you, baby.
I want
to kiss you.
Shut up, bastard!
He's really kicking up.
If you need anything else, Rafa...
What do I do with you?
Kill you?
I'm going to tell you|a story, Carlos.
Look at him.
Look at the fox.
A wolf and a fox are different.
A wolf attacks sheep
and howls at the moon. Why?
No one knows, but it does it.
You're a wolf in sheep's clothing,
but a fox is much smarter.
I want an explanation.
He and I want an explanation.
Women...
That hurt, Carlos,
but you're right.
- Well...|- You see?
You understand me.
I've got lots of feelings,
lots of feelings,|but I do this
and I swallow them.
Do you love her?
If that's really true,|I can't stand in the way of love.
I just wanted you to say,
"Shit, Rafa, I've fallen in love|with your girl,""
and like a good feline|I'd have stood aside.
Run after her, Carlos.
- Well...|- Don't say anything.
If you don't go with her,|you'll regret it, maybe not today,
maybe not tomorrow, but soon,|and for the rest of your life.
Go with Pilar
and give her|what I couldn't give her.
So long.
Goodbye, my friend.
I did what I had to do.
I did what my heart told me.
Rafa,
this country would be beautiful|with more people like you and me.
I know, Tomas.
I know.
Shall we go up?| Got a key?
Yes, but I'm sure|they won't be in.
I'm sure they're asleep.
Come on.
He's got up. Come on.
Good morning.
- Has she gone?|- Yes.
How did you sleep?
Great.
And you?
- Want some juice?|- Sure.
- Shall I cook some eggs?|- Sure.
- What's up?|- You're an idiot.
- Why?|- Why are you copying me?
No, you're copying me.
You're an idiot.| You're a dickhead.
Hey,fried or scrambled?
Scrambled.
Please!
- Leave it, I'll do it.|- Get off.
- Let me do it.|- Get off!
- Give it to me!|- Let go. You're so silly.
So who's the queen|of the kitchen?
What's up?
Hello, Pedro.
I was...
I was thinking...
The thing is...
I'm sorry.
I've missed you so much,|because...
Javier,
Raquel is
moving in again
That's great.
But not completely,
maybe every other day
We'll see how it goes, right?
Every other day.
Great.
I'll get it.
Hello. Is Rafa here?
I don't think so.
My cousin Gema, Marta.
- Hello.|- Raquel, Pedro, my cousin Gema.
- Hello.|- How are you?
Are you five all friends?
Pedro, where's Rafa?
- He's working. Why?|- Love and hate are blood relations.
He may have done something crazy,|an atrocity, an aberration.
- Let's go.|- Well, goodbye.
See you tomorrow.
Every other day, right?
Shall we go?|Come on. So long.
- So long.|- So long.
Well, I think
we should go in, we might find|a clue, a note, because the fact is
we're worried, uncertain,
Will you just shut up?
I'm tired.
We're leaving.|Come on.
Yes, darling.|Gema, let's go.
She's old enough|to do what she wants.
Come on.
So long.
Marta...|Where does that come from?
It's a very long story.
Want to hear it?
sure
Hey!
What's up?
Nothing.
I'm back again.
I'll pack my bags now|and move out tomorrow.
Well...
I'm delighted for you|that you're back with Raquel.
Back with her...
We'll see. Right now,|it's every other day.
You will be.
She'd be crazy to let you go.
And you and Marta,|you're bound to...
With Marta or whoever.
You're great.
Yeah, I'm with someone.
You are?
Yeah, she's...
She's very strange.
- And a hot number too.|- Yes, sir.
Yes, sir.
Of course.
You needn't pack your bags,|you know.
The house is enormous.|There's room for both of us.
- No, I don't want to bother you.|- What do you mean, bother me?
That's it, it's settled.
No more arguing,|you're staying here.
All right.
Shit, of course.
Do you realize
the things that happen to us|and we're still together?
Things have happened all right.
Things have happened.
I'm sure that whatever happens,
you and I will carry on, so...
No matter what.
All our lives.
You and I.
What...
We're such good friends that...
Shit!
What are you saying?
I feel cheated.
Stop kidding yourself, Rafa
We're all bisexual.
So...
Possibly.
Possibly..