? Have you ever
dreamed of a place ?
? far away from it all? ?
? Where the air you breathe
is soft and clean ?
? and children play
in fields of green ?
? and the sound of guns ?
? doesn’t pound in your ears. ?
? Have you ever
dreamed of a place ?
? far away from it all? ?
? Where the winter winds
will never blow ?
? and living things
have room to grow ?
? and the sound of guns ?
? doesn’t pound in your ears ?
? anymore? ?
? Many miles from yesterday ?
? before you reach tomorrow ?
? where the time is
always just today. ?
? There’s a lost horizon ?
? waiting to be found. ?
? where the sound of guns ?
? doesn’t pound in your ears ?
? anymore. ?
Wise, gimme that.
George, lets get out
as many as we can.
Bring them out now.
Don't overload me Conway!
Mr. Lovett?
Calme vu.
It's all right.
Plenty of planes are coming.
Patients, patients.
Please be patient.
Plenty of planes are coming.
Please.
Don't worry. Everyone
will get away.
Please don't worry the
planes are coming.
Get me Hong Kong will you.
Talking to them sir.
Hello it's Conway here. Where are
those planes you promised me?
I still got a whole lot
of people to get out.
The whole towns on fire
and the guerrillas
are nearly here.
That runway won't
take heavy jets.
We've sent you every
other plain we
could commandeer,
even freighters.
Now, Fenner's in charge.
They should be there any time. Now,
take your people and clear out.
My people! What about
the rest of them here?
Richard, Bill Ferguson here.
Yes Bill?
We've had a lot of flak from
your local military authority.
They have forbidden us to let you
evacuate any of their nationals.
The ST says you are to take only your
own group, only those you have listed.
Do you hear me?
- Yes, I hear you Bill, but it's not...
- Hey, it's the planes.
They're here.
Just a minute, we think
the planes are here.
Thank you.
Oh my god, whats happen.
They must have blown
up the generator.
Come on.
Those planes can't
land without light.
Hello, Hong Kong.
Come in Hong Kong.
Let's go.
[Chele', Chele'!]
[Chele'!]
[Ah' roo cha']
[Chele' Chele' Chele'
Chele' Chele']
Let's get back to
the main building.
Here they are, now let
have the next group.
Only the women.
All right quiet please,
just calm down.
Hay Miss. Come on,
you get left behind.
Let the heroes go first.
You an American?
No, Mongolian.
You have to teach me
the language sometime.
He's away.
We go on the next plane. Bring
out everybody that's left.
Right.
Hello Fenner.
Hello Conway.
Having a little trouble?
Enough.
Does this thing really fly?
From time to time she does.
Over there. Keep them back.
Tell Fenner to take off.
Fenner, let's go!
Fenner!
Get down! Get down on the floor!
Get down!
Fenner, come on!
Fenner, takeoff!
Come on Fenner!
Fenner!
Everybody all right?
Yeah, sure.
Now we all have a long
journey ahead of us.
Now I suggest you make yourselves
as comfortable as possible.
Right?
- Fine.
- OK.
G-George, see if you
can find some food.
Uh, where we heading?
Hong Kong.
Who are you? I don't
remember listing you.
Yeah, well I sort of
arrived the last minute.
Names Harry Lovett the comedian.
Just finished three solid weeks,
top of the bill, Saigon USO.
Terrific audience those guys.
I love um'.
Saigon?
What were you doing in Baskul.
Yeah, well, we had a few drinks and
someone said "Let's go see the Temples."
And there was this plane and
we had a few more drinks
and uh, all of a sudden we were
in the middle of the jungle.
Temple of Baskulla
was pretty funny.
Then the shells start falling
and nobody's laughing.
All right, I'll get some
particulars from you later.
Hi, name's Harry Lovett.
The Comedian.
Sam Cornelius. The Engineer.
Milk and sandwiches.
Milk? Somebody at headquarters
has a sense of humor.
Dish it out.
I'm going to make out my report,
while I can still
remember the details.
No thank you.
Of course...
You're Sally Hughes,
of Newsweek.
Yes.
I’m George Conway,
London Express.
Hello.
Richards my brother.
I was covering him
on the peace talks
when the whole thing blew up.
Well did you get some good stuff
on the airfield just now?
Look, I'm through with all this!
And I'm tired.
I'm sorry.
The way Fenner is flying this
thing we're in for a rough night.
I uh, just found some jungle juice.
Can I freshen your milk?
Sure.
It's pretty rough eh?
Yeah.
Were you on a
project back there?
Yeah.
Really?
Really.
Well, take it easy.
Ah, well gentlemen, I ah,...
not been too
successful up front.
Could I interest you
in a little bourbon?
Oh, you're our man.
Yes.
Great.
Great?
Well, God Save the Queen.
Cheers.
Mr. Conway? Mr. Conway, wake up.
Look outside.
We're traveling in
the wrong direction.
Look, I know I
flunked boy scout,
but from what I remember
the sun rises in the east.
Hong Kong is east,
we're going west.
He's right. The suns behind us.
It's desert down there.
Must be a reason.
Fenner too good a
pilot to get lost.
What goes on?
Fenner?
What's happening?
[Meet say nay grean?]
- Whats happening?
- It's a hijack!
Hijacking DC-3. Come on.
That's what it looks like.
Well, what are we going to do?
What do you suggest?
He could be a maniac,
we gotta do something.
Such as?
Be quite!
Now listen everybody,
there's nothing we can do
about this for the moment.
So I suggest you all sit
down and as far as possible,
relax.
That guy has a gun!
There's nothing we can do about it
until he lands, now please, sit down.
George.
We're heading down!
We're going to land.
I don't see a landing
strip, do you?
[Ming mashe ta lue]
[Ah sha tee]
[Ling pi oh]
[Ay Sing ling bi oh]
[Sing ling bi oh]
Let's find out what's going on.
I think their refueling.
[Say poo da la ca poo]
The other facts to
consider are these.
That the fuel was waiting,
the armed men were waiting,
And they wouldn't let us off.
If this was an ordinary
hijacking they would
have kept us back
there in the desert.
- Exactly.
- It could be political.
That means you Richard.
I doubt it. The whole
point is on ***
Oh c'mon Conway, you'd be a
price in anybody's book.
And for good measure
they got two journalist.
And by his own account,
a famous comedian.
Very funny but, what about you Cornelius.
Maybe they want you.
Who are you!
I'm somebody flying
a strange plane,
to a strange place,
with a lunatic pilot
and I'm trying to find out why,
that's who I am.
All right all right all right.
God he's really going high.
What's the ceiling
on these planes?
I don't know.
Let's see if that
oxygen equipment works.
Thank you.
If the altitude gets
you, swallow hard.
Or hold your nose… And blow.
That's it.
Here.
Hold it.
Breathe deeply.
- OK?
- OK.
This one's empty.
Now take deep breaths.
Slowly, slowly.
Is that any better?
I feel like were heading
for outer space.
Easy now.
Mmm.... You know a guy
to get to like this.
What's happening?!
He's losing his left engine.
Seat belts, strap in!
Brace yourselves! Lean forward.
Right, forward.
Lock your hands
behind your head!
Don't let them snap back!
Ahhh!
Get down!
Oh!
Are you all right?
Look after the others.
How are the others?
Shaken, but OK.
He's had it.
Here's a map.
You see that spot where he's marked
I'll bet that's where we refueled.
There's the end of civilization.
We must be 1000
miles beyond that.
Just a blank here on the map.
Hay, whats happening Conway?
Conway?
Don't tell them
about this George.
- Conway.
- Just a minute.
- How are you?
- I'm all right.
Where the hell are we?
Down on solid ground
and it feels great.
What are you doing?
Listen buddy, I don't
know about you,
but I'm scared and this helps.
What's the situation?
- The pilots dead.
- Well where are we?
As far as I can make out, in an
unexplored part of the world.
How do we get out?
At the moment we don't.
We stay here.
Only a fully equipped
expedition could last outside.
So here we stay,
all calm and cool.
We're sure gonna' be cool.
It's not so bad we've got ah…
blankets, a stove,
emergency rations.
We can get through the days. The nights
maybe a little bit more difficult.
But will manage, until
somebody finds us.
Till somebody finds us.
They will.
- I've got another one to work.
- Good.
Hear, hear.
Drink this. It hasn't got
much taste, but it's hot.
As a matter of fact it
hasn't got any taste at all.
I'll try one then.
All right, … there.
Mr. Conway.
There lights out there.
Mr. Conway there are
lights out there!
Hey, there are people out
there, moving in the snow.
Coming towards us,
down that mountain!
There is something, they found us!
I knew they would, I knew it!
Come on.
Conway, what is this?
[I non cee, holla?]
I am from a nearby Lamasery.
My name is Chang.
Mine is Richard Conway.
How do you do?
How you do.
Forgive me, I hadn't expected anybody in
this part of the world to talk English.
I was an undergraduate at
Oxford in my young days.
It was there that I
had the opportunity
of improving my knowledge
of your language.
You speak it very well.
You have no idea how
welcome you are.
Yesterday our plane left
Baskulla for Hong Kong
but we suddenly found
ourselves hijacked
and traveling in the
opposite direction.
- The pilot…
- Where is your pilot?
He was killed in the crash.
May I see him?
Please.
[Marie ta' ma green ta luu']
Mr. Chang, you're obviously
on a journey of your own,
but could you possibly
take us to your Lamasery?
I would consider it an honor.
You will need suitable
clothes for the journey.
It is not particularly far
but it is quite difficult.
I suggest we start at daybreak.
Aah!
Welcome to Shangri
La, Mr. Conway.
You see we are sheltered by
mountains on every side.
A strange phenomenon for
which we are very grateful.
Come, let me show you.
This is Brother To Len.
He will show you to your rooms.
Shangri-La welcomes you.
If you should wish to assume our habits
of dress you will find suitable garments.
You would need to rest now.
And later I shall be most pleased
to see you all at dinner.
Mr. Chang.
Please.
I am happy to report that
the plane has arrived.
With Richard Conway?
With Conway and four others.
Excellent.
What are we going to do now?
What we always do?
- Miss. Hughes!
- Gasp!
That is the coward's way out.
You are in the midst of life.
Do not seek death,
it will find you.
But choose the road that
makes death a fulfillment.
Good evening ladies and
gentlemen, a funny thing
happened to me on the
way to the Airport.
Get a load of the outfit
have Kimona will travel.
Both look pretty silly.
When in Rome, do
as the romans do.
C'mon, let's get something
to eat, take a quick look
around the place, and catch
the first train out here.
We've just crash a plane
in the middle of nowhere,
spent all day dragging
ourselves up a mountain
and you're looking for the
nearest ticket office?
Man, where do you
think we're gonna go?
Um, suits you.
I thought I might
find Chang here.
No, sorry.
I'm not doing very well so
far I failed to find him or…
- Telephone or telex.
- Telex?
Even a socket for my razor.
Hard luck.
- You better use mine.
- Thanks.
Seriously, I must get
in touch with my paper.
Well an hour or two won't
make any difference will it?
It does to me. I want to get
this story off before we eat.
And I want a few more
peaceful moments
before the world gets its
claws into me again.
Oh well, in that case,
I'll make a big sacrifice.
I'll shave and shut up.
Thank you George,
I'm very grateful.
Until dinner.
? Friendly doors open wide ?
? Come and share the peace and
life you will find inside ?
? Share the joy ?
? Let the sun comfort you ?
? It will keep you safe and
warm, always shining through ?
? Share the joy ?
? All the lovely songs
you will hear, ?
? means we all hold dear ?
? At the same time ?
? All the grandest
things we possess, ?
? means we value less ?
? So many small things
can bring happiness ?
? Love is in all things ?
? Flowers bloom, people grow ?
? You may never want to leave
when it's time to go ?
? Share the joy ?
? Mountains rise,
mountains fall ?
? You have nothing more to prove,
you have climbed them all ?
? Now you're here ?
? May you ?
? stay and share the joy ?
Now that's the best thing to
cheer me up since we got here.
? Now you're here ?
? May you ?
? stay and share the joy ?
Bravo.
Good evening my friends.
Did you think I had
forgotten you?
- Have you everything you need?
- Everything thank you.
We're sorry, Miss Hughes?
She asked me to say
she's not feeling well,
it is nothing serious.
I hope she's well enough
to travel when we leave.
Mr. Chang, I have
some questions?
Please, ask them.
We all wish to return to
civilization as soon as possible.
Are you so certain you
are away from it?
Mr. Chang, I think I speak
for all of us, when I say
your hospitality is quite
remarkable and we're very grateful.
But were also anxious to
go home as soon as we can.
That is always the
case Mr. Conway.
And even more urgent, for some
of us, is to send cables.
Unfortunately,
we lack radio communication
of any sort.
It has always been a
source of deep regret,
that the same mountains that
allow us our splendid weather,
also prevent adequate
wireless reception.
Then perhaps you could send porter's
or messengers or some sort.
But I'd really like to
tell my agent I'm safe.
He's bound to have
some bookings for me.
We have no porter's
or messengers.
No porter's, but…
You were rescued
by our own people.
Who have never gone beyond the
point of which you were found.
Two venture further
would be too hazardous.
How'd you get all this
stuff brought here?
Ahh, yes.
Well, depending upon
favorable weather of course.
There are porters,
500 miles away who sometimes
make the journey.
They are our only contact
with what you would call,
the outside world.
How soon can we get
in touch with them?
In that respect you are
exceedingly fortunate.
We are expecting a shipment
from them at almost any moment.
And when is "almost any
moment" Mr. Chang.
Tomorrow, next week?
I cannot forecast the
exact date, precisely.
Let me see, I believe…
Aww, yes we have been expecting
this particular shipment,
for about two years.
But I assure you gentlemen, I
shall endeavor to make your stay
here as pleasant as possible.
And now, if you'll excuse
me, it is getting late.
I hope you will all sleep well.
- Good night.
Goodnight Mr. Conway.
Goodnight sir.
About two years.
Did you believe all that
stuff about the porters?
I don't know.
- Don't you care?
- Not really.
It's nice to be in a place
where time doesn't matter.
Yes, but you wanna get
out of here, don't you?
I don't know what I want.
George, something
happen when I arrived.
Did you ever go to a
totally strange place
and feel from the very first moment
that you'd been there before?
Because that's what
happened to me.
It's absurd I know.
The feeling so strong that…
I can't think of anything else.
I've always in the past, wanted
to see what it was all about.
To see what was on the other
side of the mountain.
Perhaps this is it.
It's like…
coming home.
Well with me, it's the complete reverse.
I can't wait to get back.
But I'll tell you want.
If I, mind my manners and
don't rock the boat,
will you seriously think about
getting out of here, soon.
All right, we'll have a truce.
Till we find out
about this place.
And then if we get out here...
If?
Did I say if?
Yes, you did.
Can I ask you a question?
Were we brought here on purpose?
Over 2000 people
live in the valley.
And if so, what is the purpose.
In addition to those
here in Shangri-La…
What is Shangri-La?
Who is he? You.
Good heavens, no.
Not I.
Well who, for instance.
In time, you will know.
You know for a man who
talks a great deal,
it's amazing how
unenlightening you can be.
There are some things
my dear Conway,
that I deeply regret
I cannot discuss.
Shall we continue?
You know, in the outside
world, you'd be a knockout.
I bet people would fight
to see you dance.
I fear I shall never see
you're outside world.
Never see it? Why ever not?
It is not possible.
Am I then, in some way
on trial dear Mr. Chang.
Oh no, like everyone else
you are on a pilgrimage
through life.
By chance, out of your voyage
of discovery, is here.
By chance?
Here of course, we have
more time for reflection.
Sickness is unknown.
Perfect health is the rule.
And it is quite common for us
to live to a very ripe old age.
Indeed.
And does that also apply to those who
come here from the outside world.
If it did not, Shangri-La
would never have been built.
How old it is your
oldest inhabitants?
Um? Let me see?
Considerably over 100 years old.
Considerably.
Yes, still at work,
when last I spoke to him.
Climate and diet, these are important
of course to keep you young.
But we believe it is the lack
of struggle in our way of life.
How often in your countries
do you hear the expression,
"He worried himself to death."
or " this thing or that
thing killed him."
Your lives are, as
a rule shorter.
Not so much by natural death
as by indirect suicide.
Unfortunately true.
"Climate, diet, and
harmony." you said.
And somewhere the guiding mind.
Is that it?
Is it not enough?
What worries me is that
it's a little like a dream,
from which I shall shorty,
but unpleasantly, awake.
You surprised me.
I surprised you?
Yes, as you who have written
so much of better worlds
should think it a dream
when you find one.
Or is it that you fail to recognize one
of your own dreams when you see it.
And this is our school.
This is where we start to prepare
our young for the future.
Why. Why. Why. Why. Why. Why.
? The world is a circle
without a beginning ?
? And nobody knows where
it really ends. ?
? Everything depends
on where you ?
? Are in the circle
that never begins, ?
? Nobody knows where
the circle ends. ?
? La la la, la la-la la, la la. ?
? And just because you
think you're small, ?
? That doesn't mean that
you're small at all. ?
? And just the way
a tiny branch ?
? is like a tree to a twig, ?
? To someone else you are big. ?
? The world is a circle
without a beginning, ?
? And nobody knows where
it really ends. ?
? Woooa! ?
? Everything depends
on where you ?
? Are in the circle
that's spinning around. ?
? Half of the time we
are upside down. ?
? La-la-la
La la la, la la-la la, la la. ?
? And just because they
say you're weak, ?
? That doesn't mean
you've a weak physique. ?
? And even if they're
partly right, ?
? At least they're
partially wrong. ?
? To someone else
you are strong. ?
? And just because they
say you're slow, ?
? That doesn't mean that
you're slow, you know. ?
? And even if you're
never first, ?
? Compared to someone
who's last, ?
? They're sure to
think you are fast. ?
? The world is a circle
without a beginning, ?
? And nobody knows where
it really ends. ?
? Woooa! ?
? Everything depends
on where you ?
? Are in the circle
that never begins. ?
? Nobody knows where
the circle ends. ?
? La-la-la
La la la, la la-la la. ?
? The world is a circle
that never begins. ?
? Nobody knows where
the circle ends. ?
- Oh.
- Children.
Thank you.
Sometime in the future, you shall
have the pleasure of meeting her.
Sam, Sam I had the strangest
dream last night.
I dreamt I swallowed a
50 pound marshmallow.
And when I woke up
my pillow was gone.
- You're getting better.
- I thought so.
- You go on. I'll be with you in a minute.
- OK, hurry it up.
Oh, I'm sorry, I thought
you were alone.
What is it?
Lovett had a deck of cards.
I thought you'd...
might like to play a game.
Some other time, huh?
Sure.
I didn't think I
could hold a card.
Why am I like this?
It helps talking to you.
My little cold knot in my
stomach starts easing up.
My memory
keeps coming back, that I…
really considered dropping
off this balcony.
Would you have done so?
I don't know.
If Chang hadn't called,
then maybe I would.
That's what frightens me.
What's happened to me?
Perhaps you can
answer that yourself.
Sally, "Golden Girl."
I was always taught,
dreams could come true.
That's terrific to believe
when you're a kid.
A little more difficult later on when
you're a "little more difficult."
All that passionate involvement.
Men, causes.
Going around agonizing about
man's inhumanity to man.
I made a good living out of taking pictures
of people with their heads blown off.
So other people with
their heads still on
and usually under hair dryers
could get a kick out of them before
turning to the nearest recipe.
One day it all made me sick.
The dreams were over.
That is very painful but,
also necessary so that you
may take the next step.
The next step was to start taking
pills to get the dreams back.
The excitement, the loving,
the feeling good ones.
The kicks I got, lasted about
two and a half minutes.
So you find out, that's
not the answer either.
And now?
Nothing.
- The end of the line.
- No!
You had the courage,
not to jump.
Which means?
You must tell me.
Answers!
Where the hell are any answers!
I don't know!
Try Miss. Hughes.
Inside me I guess. Is that it?
It would not be wrong
to start there.
- May I help you with some tea Mr. Conway?
- Thank you.
Let me see. 19 plus 187
gives me a grand total of…
two hundred and six.
You know if you hadn't told
me you were honest Harry,
I'd swear you were cheating.
Of course I'm cheating Sampson,
and getting away with it.
I mean there's no fun
playing cards if you don't.
And the rest of us, are we all
as content as we seem here or…
is there some delicious
drug in our food?
Or is all this, a mirage?
No, no no no my dear Mr. Conway, we
employ no such methods in Shangri-La.
To put it simply, we
believe in moderation.
We teach that virtue
lies in avoiding excess.
We rule with moderates
strictness.
In return we are satisfied
with moderate obedience.
As a result our people
are moderately sober.
Moderately chase and err...
moderately honest.
Then you're more than
moderately fortunate.
Good evening.
Well, I brought you this.
Oh, thank you.
- May I look at it?
- Yes.
Do you ever have
arguments over women?
Oh, only very rarely.
You see, it would not be
considered good manners
to take a woman that
another man wanted.
And supposing somebody wanted
some particular woman so badly,
he didn't care whether it
was good manners or not.
Well in that event.
It would be good manners on
the part of the other man...
To eh…
Yes?
To let him have her.
That's very convenient.
I think I like that.
And ah, does this arrangement
applied for women also?
Of course. You'd be surprised Mr. Conway
how a little courtesy all around
can help to smooth out the
most complicated problems.
Thank you.
- Hope it has a happy ending.
- Good night.
Excuse me.
Just a minute.
Yes Mr. Conway.
I'm… in a quandary and ah…
I thought that…
you might be able to help me.
I noticed you are having your
course in elementary Chang.
What is your problem?
Well, Chang tells me that as
soon as I meet a woman I like
I must be prepared to give her up
if somebody else likes her as well
and I don't think I'm
capable of doing that.
- When that happens…
- I think it has.
When that happens
the important thing
is to try and make the… other fellow,
the one who must be courteous.
I see, I hadn't thought
of it like that.
Perhaps you could help me
with some other questions.
I have so many I hardly
know where to begin.
You want to know who I am
and what I'm doing here.
- My name is Catherine and I was born here.
- Were you?
Well, almost born here. It
was just beyond the pass.
My parents were explorers who couldn't
rest until they had seen everything.
Unfortunately, they died
just on the other side.
And Chang rescued you.
Fateful Chang, he and his
men found me barely alive.
Here I've grown up and
here I've been happy.
With no desire to leave.
Absolutely none.
So I should know a good
thing when I see it.
Is that it?
That's it.
Goodnight Mr. Conway.
Well my friends you have seen our
mountains our valley and our people.
You've heard about our past,
now you are seeing our future.
This is our Festival
Of The Family.
A chosen couple perform a ritual,
honoring the newly born children.
? Start with a man
and you have one ?
? Add on a woman and
then you have two. ?
? Add on a child and
what have you got? ?
? You've got more than three. ?
? You have what they
call a family. ?
? Living Together, Growing
Together, just being together, ?
? that's how it starts. ?
? Three loving hearts all ?
? pulling together, working
together, just building together, ?
? that makes you strong. ?
? If things go wrong we'll
still get along somehow, ?
? living and growing together. ?
? It just takes wood
to build a house. ?
? Fill it with people
and you have a home. ?
? Fill it with love and
people take root. ?
? It's just like a tree ?
? where each branch
becomes a family that's ?
? Living Together, Growing
Together, just being together, ?
? that's how it starts. ?
? Three loving hearts all ?
? pulling together, working
together, just building together, ?
? that makes you strong. ?
? If things go wrong we'll ?
? still get along somehow, ?
? living and growing together. ?
? Living Together, Growing
Together, just being together, ?
? that's how it starts. ?
? Three loving hearts all ?
? pulling together, working
together, just building together, ?
? that makes you strong. ?
? If things go wrong we'll
still get along somehow, ?
? living and growing ?
? just like we're doing
now, together. ?
Yeaahhh!!
? Seems like I've had
so little time. ?
? All through my life ?
? Maybe that's why
I've always been ?
? so impatient. ?
? I must learn to be patient ?
? or I might frighten her away. ?
? Seems like I've had
just too much time ?
? All through my life ?
? Maybe that’s why
I’ve seemed to be ?
? So unhurried, somethings
just should be hurried ?
? Or they might
frighten him away ?
? Seemed like were part
of two different world ?
? In the way we live ?
? More than in just
a few things ?
? that mean we both
a lot to give ?
? Learning how we do things ?
? Sharing new things ?
? Looking back I see that
I’ve always been alone ?
? All through my life ?
? Maybe I knew
when it was time ?
? Love would find me ?
? I must just let it find me ?
? Or it might
frighten her away ?
? Yes it might
frighten him away ?
? If we rush we may loose ?
? What we may have found ?
? today. ?
? Mmmmh,
Mmmmm, ?
Hi.
Ah, improving your
mind again eh?
You should try it.
Yes.
Yes, maybe you're right.
Then perhaps I can
understand what it is
about this place that the rest
of you seem to enjoy so much.
Tell me, don't you ever give
a thought to leaving here?
No. I don’t know
what you left behind
but what I left behind, I'm not
in such a hurry to see again.
Aw.
Don't listen to her Maria.
She was born to be a recluse.
Hello Maria. I saw you dance at the
ceremony, and you were lovely.
Thank you.
I've read these and I've
come back for more.
I wonder what will happen
when we've read them all.
We'll be about 250 and
need new glasses.
You sound like you hate
the outside world.
- Do you?
- Well I don't love it.
But what about London and Paris?
And the Greek islands and
the Leningrad Ballet.
You mean compared to hear? Oh,
Maria you must be kidding.
Look what you got, plus all the
time the world to enjoy it.
Time, … Yes there is time.
Before George came, it didn't seem
strange to spend my days in reading.
Talk to myself, dance.
Drift through the days full of
nothing but peace and quiet.
It didn't seem too long,
but it's different now.
Oh boy, good old George.
Take it from me Maria, Shangri-La has
a definite edge over New York City,
not to mention
Calcutta and the rest.
But the way George describes it.
Listen Marie, George is a nice guy
and I don't mean to knock him,
but don't let him kid you there's
some sort of wonderland outside.
So all you have is
peace and quiet uh-uh.
You have a place here
where you can breathe.
Where no violence, no cruelty.
A place where people will
take the time to care.
George can have his rat race.
I can do without it.
? On the list of the things
that I will not miss ?
? First of all is noise ?
? On the list of the things
that I will not miss ?
? Is peace and quiet ?
? I would like to try it ?
? Different people look at life
from different points of view ?
? If you really want the things
I have just help yourself ?
? I give it all to you ?
? On the list of the things
that I will not miss ?
? I would mention crowds ?
? On the list of the things
that I will not miss ?
? Is open spaces ?
? Why can't we change places? ?
? Different people look at life
from different points of view ?
? If you really want the things
I have just help yourself ?
? I give it all to you ?
? On the list of the things
that I will not miss ?
? I would mention work ?
? On the list of the things
that I will not miss ?
? Is contemplation ?
? Sounds like a great vacation ?
? Different people look at life
from different points of view ?
? If you really want the things
I have just help yourself ?
? I give it all to you ?
? Different people look at life
from different points of view ?
? If you really want the things
I have just help yourself ?
? I give it all to you ?
? On the list of the things
that I will not miss ?
? Most of all is rain ?
? On the list of the things
that I will not miss ?
? Is too much sunshine ?
? Can there be too
much sunshine? ?
? Different people look at life
from different points of view ?
? If you really want the things
I have just help yourself ?
? They're yours ?
? I give it all to you ?
You know, those girls would
be great in my new act.
They should be so lucky.
You look beautiful.
Thanks. I guess.
Oh I mean, you looked beautiful
before but now, you look beautiful.
Tomorrow I got
something to tell you.
What's wrong with today?
I can't now, it's a secret.
Alright.
I'm afraid that truces over.
Why?
If we don't get it straight
now we never will.
Get what straight?
Who wants to leave,
and when and how.
For start, I want you to
tell them what you told me.
That we were brought
here deliberately.
And what's the point.
They're perfectly happy.
They won't be when
they find out.
Will you tell them?
No, and certainly not tonight.
Then I will.
Listen everybody.
My brother wants to
explode a small bomb but
I think I better do it.
Sit down George.
Do you realize that we
are all prisoners here?
No we're not, we're guest.
We were deliberately kidnapped.
- What is this?
- You have no proof of that.
The pilot of a plane was
a man from Shangri-La.
- May have been.
- Stop glossing over the facts.
I want to get out of here.
I can't do it alone
I need to know if anyone
else feels as I do?
Well, does anyone
else want to leave.
Mr. Conway? Mr. Conway.
Ask him if you don't believe me.
Why were we kidnapped and
brought here Mr. Chang?
Mr. Conway I'd bring you
extraordinary news.
Answer the question.
- Let him go. - Richard! - Let him go!
Mr. Chang,
Forgive my brother's determination
to force the issue.
You've been very kind
and we appreciate it.
But I think the time has come for
you to be more open with us.
Were we brought here
deliberately and if so why?
There is no time to answer
questions now Mr. Conway.
You must come at once. The
High Lama wishes to see you.
Who is the High Lama?
I thought you ran
this place Chang.
Oh no, I'm only a humbled
member of the community.
- Please Mr. Conway, you must…
- Just a minute.
Will your High Lama
answer our questions?
That is possible.
Then he's the man
that I want to see.
Richard?
Tell him that, I at least
intend to leave here.
I was here for five years
before I was called.
You cannot appreciate
the overwhelming
honor that has been
bestowed upon you.
It is unprecedented.
Good evening Mr. Conway.
Please come in.
Sit down near me.
I trust, you have been comfortable
at Shangri-La since you arrival.
I've liked it very much.
But some of my friends and in particularly
my brother are puzzled by the mystery.
I can understand
that Mr. Conway.
Perhaps if I told you
of Shangri-La's origins
things would become clearer.
Thank you.
A Belgian priest named
Father Perrault
was was the first European to enter
the valley of the Blue Moon.
When was that?
Was the year 1747.
When Father Perrault tumbled into
the valley half frozen to death,
one of his legs was
so badly frostbitten,
there being no doctor he was
forced to amputate it himself.
- He amputated his own leg?
- Yes.
Oddly enough, later, when the
natives came to trust him.
He learned from them that
his leg would have healed
without amputation.
- With frostbite that's impossible.
- Oh no.
This valley celebrates
the natural life.
And he recovered well.
Soon he was making his
way around the valley
taking a great interest
in everything.
He taught his own religion
and the best of others.
Instructing the children
knowing how important education
would be for future generations.
He began building the
Lamasery of Shangri-La
with one or two helpers.
But after some years
hundreds of the natives
who by now had come to respect
him helped with the task.
When it was finished
he was 108 years old.
He's life works is over.
He became weak and lay in his room for
many weeks between life and death.
And then a strange
thing happened.
He had a vision
of the purpose
of Shangri-La, of
its entire meaning.
And of his part in it.
From that moment on
he began to recover.
And how old was he when he died?
But that's incredible!
Yes my son.
You're still alive
Father Perrault.
Sit down my son.
You may not know it, but I've been an
admirer of yours for a great many years.
Of mine, Father?
Oh, not the Richard Conway, the
public hero, the government servant
but the Richard Conway
who once wrote,
"There are moments
in every man's life
when he glimpses the eternal."
That man seemed to belong here.
In fact, it was suggested
that someone be sent
to bring him here.
So I was right, we
were brought here.
But, what possible use could I be
to an already thriving community?
If this community is
to continue to thrive,
then we need men like you here.
You can work today.
Is there anything more pitiful.
Will surely this is
a time of crisis.
But when has the world
known any other time.
What madness there is
what blindness, what
unintelligent leadership.
A furiously harassing marshall,
bewildered, humanities, strengthening,
not in wisdom but
in vulgar passions.
The time must come when
evil will destroy itself.
I will not live to see that day.
But you might, my son.
And that is why you have
been brought to Shangri-La.
For when the day comes, that the
world begins to look for a new life,
it is our belief
that they will find a
reservoir of hope here.
So here we shall stay with
our books and our music.
And our medications.
Here we shall be, to guide the
footsteps of a weary people.
Here we shall be with
our way of life.
There's only one simple rule, …
be kind.
And it is our hope
that our brotherly love will then
spread throughout the world.
And when the strong have
devoured each other,
then, at last…
the meek shall
inherit the earth.
I am tired now my son.
Will you come again?
Yes I will.
? How do I know this is
part of my real life? ?
? If there's no pain can
I be sure I feel life? ?
? And would I go back if
I knew how to go back? ?
? What good is time when
you're sure of tomorrow? ?
? Can there be joy where
there has been no sorrow? ?
? And would I go back if
I knew how to go back? ?
? Will I find there is really
such a thing as peace of mind, ?
? and what I thought was living
was truly just confusion, ?
? the chance to live forever
is really no illusion, ?
? and this all can be mine? ?
? Why can't I make
myself believe it? ?
? Can I accept what
I see around me? ?
? Have I found Shangri-La,
or has it found me? ?
? And would I go back if
I knew how to go back? ?
? Will I find there is really
such a thing as peace of mind, ?
? and what I thought was living
was truly just confusion, ?
? the chance to live forever
is really no illusion, ?
? and this all can be mine? ?
? Why can't I make
myself believe it? ?
? There are things that you see. ?
? Other things you feel. ?
? Feelings can't be seen yet we
never doubt they are real. ?
? When you search for the truth
don't just use your eyes. ?
? Look inside yourself that is
where the truth always lies. ?
? Where knowledge
ends faith begins, ?
? and it shines like a star, ?
? till your heart fills
with hope and with love. ?
? I have looked in your heart. ?
? I have faith in you. ?
No not there.
I apologize for
being away so long.
Well, did you ask about…- What was
he like? - Richard, did you see him?
Yes.
I saw the High Lama.
And I haven't the answers to all of our
questions yet, but I will in time.
And when I do I'll tell you
exactly what the situation is.
Particularly about going home.
Until then you all
have to trust me.
Come on, come on,
Oh my lord.
- There, gold, the stream is full of it.
- So?
We can smuggle it out. Get
those porters to help us.
Correction, you bribe the porters,
I got something better to do.
Such as?
Such as not sitting around
worrying about how to
spend money in a place where
money isn't any good.
But what about when we get out?
Get out, how? Sam you
gotta' be more practical.
Trouble with you is you haven't
got any inner resources.
Who hasn't? What are
you trying to tell me?
Your life is made up of
infinite possibilities
and you're not
realizing one of them.
- Not one.
- For instance?
? When you look at yourself
do you like what you see? ?
? If you like what you see, you're
the person you should be. ?
? 'Cause your reflection
reflects in everything you do, ?
? and everything you
do reflects on you. ?
? When you wake up each day
do you like how you feel? ?
? If you like how you feel,
you've got nothing to conceal. ?
? 'Cause your reflection
reflects in everything you do, ?
? and everything you
do reflects on you. ?
? Doing something for someone else
isn't really for someone else. ?
? It does twice as much for you as
something you do just for yourself. ?
? When you lay down to sleep
do you like all your dreams? ?
? If you like all your dreams,
life's as happy as it seems. ?
? 'Cause your reflection
reflects in everything you do, ?
? and everything you
do reflects on you. ?
Now you said the other night that these
farms around here need better irrigation.
Well you were an engineer,
go irrigate them.
Yea!
Excuse me, I was looking
for your brother.
He's not here.
She seems to be quite
taken with him.
Let's hope that beautiful young women can
talk more sense into him than I can.
You spoke of her as young.
My dear friend I hate
to dissolution you.
But you must not be
deceived by her appearance.
Our way of life has preserved
her youth and her beauty.
She came here when she was 20.
She was on her wedding journey but her
carriers lost their way in the mountains
and the whole party would have
perished but for meeting our people.
They brought her here.
That was many, many years ago.
How many?
You are more beautiful than
the women of Thailand.
More feminine than
the women of France.
More pliable than
the women of Japan.
- More…
- Stop. Stop.
I don't want to hear about
all these other women.
All I want to hear is
that, you won't leave me.
Oh, I adore you.
But, I can't stay here.
There's so much I want to do with
my life that, I can't do here.
Maria, if I could find a way,
would you come back with me?
- There is no way.
- Well there has to be!
Tomorrow I'm going out to the pass that
leads out of here, to see if its guarded.
And to look for those porters.
If they exist.
They exist.
They do?
Then why didn't you
tell me before?
I hoped you would become
contented, like the others.
Con-Contented?
Oh...
Look, I have to get out of here.
Please, will you come with me?
Would you stay with
me here if I said no?
Then I will come with you.
The water starts up in
the hills all right
but about halfway down it's
starts going the wrong way.
Now if we put a dam here and these
interconnecting bamboo pipes
you'd have the whole valley. You'd
have the entire mountainside.
And just watch that stuff grow. And no
more women carrying buckets of water.
- Sam you're excited.
- Yeah, yeah.
I guess it's been a long time.
- A longtime what?
- Oh, since I was so excited.
And involved.
A long time ago I used
to work the land.
I guess I got waylaid
somewhere along the line.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
- Come on.
- Forget it. I don't wanna talk about it.
Sam, I'm interested.
Okay, does the name Simon
Causefield mean anything to you?
Causefield...
- Yeah, didn't he…
- That's me.
I remember American
Consolidated Products.
And the thing fell apart. You
were gone and the money was too.
I wasn't there because there wasn't
any money! And it wasn't my fault!
I'd worked hard and
made a little bit.
That little bit became a lot.
So I built a corporation. It
became a lot of corporations.
I was a hero.
It was the American dream.
Everybody wanted in.
I did ask them to, nobody told
them to buy, they just did.
Overnight the balloon burst.
The next day I'm the biggest crook
that the country has ever seen.
I don't know what to do.
So I started running.
Anywhere I think that
they won't find me.
That's how I ended up in Baskul.
Maybe here the running can stop.
Maybe.
Sam…
I stopped running
here, you can too.
Il pleut, il pleut, bergère.
Look, uh-uh-uh, I-I don't
know a thing about teaching.
- C'mon you're going to have to…
- Mouton.
- Il pleut, il pleut, …
- All you have to do is to follow me.
Come along with me.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Miss Catherine has to
leave you, so I want to
introduce you to your
new teacher of the day.
Your new expert Mr. Lovett.
Yea.
Well now, there you are, here
I am, and ah, where are we?
Ah, success. You think
that was funny folks,
'You ain't heard nothing yet.'
- Now what are you learning?
- French.
French. Well that lets me out.
'I know nothing about French.'.
A teacher should only teach what he knows
at all I know is ah, Show Business
I don't think they'd approve.
You know when I was a kid,
the thing that got me
was that every teacher I ever had, only
ask me questions and expected answers.
You too? Well I'll
tell you what I think.
Any dummy can know the answers. It's the
smart ones that know the questions.
? Question me an answer
bright and clear. ?
? I will answer with a
question clear and bright. ?
? Even though your
answer may be ?
? wrong my question
will be right. ?
? Question me an answer. ?
? Answer with a question. ?
? Fourteen hundred ninety two. ?
? What's the year that Babe Ruth
hit his sixtieth home run? ?
? Wellington at Waterloo. ?
? Who became the hero at
the battle of Bull Run? ?
? Learning can be lots of fun. ?
? Question me an answer
bright and clear. ?
? I will answer with a
question clear and bright. ?
? Even though your
answer may be ?
? wrong my question
will be right. ?
? Question me an answer. ?
? Answer with a question. ?
? Midnight ride of Paul Revere. ?
? What's the way that Yankee
Doodle really went to town? ?
? Cleaning up the atmosphere. ?
? What's the reason London
Bridge is always falling down. ?
? You can learn things
from a clown. ?
? Question me an answer
bright and clear. ?
? I will answer with a
question clear and bright. ?
? Even though your
answer may be ?
? wrong my question
will be right. ?
? Question me an answer. ?
? Answer with a question. ?
? On the good ship Lollypop. ?
? How did Christopher
Columbus sail upon the sea? ?
? Underneath the circus top. ?
? Where did Cleopatra get
to meet Mark Antony? ?
? They say knowledge
makes you free. ?
? Question me an answer
if you please. ?
? I will answer with a
question if I can. ?
? Let me show you just how I
became an educated man. ?
? Question me an answer. ?
? Answer with a question. ?
? If you wanna' know, if you
wanna' hear, if you wanna' see, ?
? question me an answer. ?
Harry, what are you doing?
You hear that? They love me!
They love me.
It's beautiful.
It's also inconceivable.
Father Perrault, his story and…
This place hidden away from
the rest of the world.
Then you come along and
confuse me even more.
- Am I so strange?
- No you're not.
Nothing here is strange.
And that's what's so confusing.
I'm desperately
trying to keep my…
emotional feedings…
and my spiritual needs
from clobbering each
other to death.
You're very beautiful.
And very desirable.
But like everything else beautiful
that's happened to me here.
I find it remarkable that…
it has happened to me here
and not out there.
You know, I can't
explain it but, …
everything seems familiar.
This air, …
Those beautiful gardens, you,
This lamasery with its
feet rooted in a good earth
of this fertile valley.
While its head
explores the eternal.
And I've been kidnapped…
Brought here against my will
which is a crime, a great crime.
And yet I accepted it
as, one would accept
an act performed by
a very dear friend.
Can you tell me why?
Perhaps because you've always been a
part of Shangri-La without knowing it.
I'm certain there's a, wish for
Shangri-La in everyone's heart.
I've never seen
you're outside world
but I imagine it's full
of millions of people
who secretly wish to be in a
beautiful place like this.
Well if they were, it wouldn't
be beautiful for long.
For years I hoped
that someone like you
would come and share
these moments with me.
But now you're here you're
not as I pictured you.
What did you expect?
From your books some
uh, Saintly Hero.
Almost astatic.
And much less attractive.
Well, people who worship heroes must
be prepared for disillusionment.
But, I shall become
saintly immediately.
Just, to please you.
Did you ever think…
What did you expect? Or hope?
I imagined she'd
be just like you.
I come to you…
with all my hopes and
I bring you love.
I come to you…
All my life I searched
for something rare.
A love that I could share.
? I come to you with all my
dreams and I bring you love. ?
? I come to you. ?
? There were times my
faith in life was gone, ?
? still I continued on. ?
? Those endless days
turned into years. ?
? They were lonely
years in many ways. ?
? And deep inside I'm sure I always
knew I had to wait for you. ?
? And here you are,
my own true love. ?
? I come to you. ?
? Happy birthday to you ?
? Happy birthday dear Harry ?
Thank you. Thank you my friends.
Old friends.
And new friends.
And a special thank you to Sally
for arranging the candles.
Twenty one how'd you guess?
Well, here we go.
Yea.
Well, this is a pretty
happy day for me.
Not just because it's
my birthday but ah,
because I've come
to a big decision.
I've decided to
stay in Shangri-La.
If they'll have me.
Good that's fine.
Now wait a minute. Hold it.
I hope Mr. Chang
that you'll go along with
a great idea I've got.
I shall be most interested
to hear it Mr. Lovett.
Well Mr. Chang I know
I speak for all of us
I say that ah…
this place is terrific.
I don't worry here,
and I sleep well.
Confidentially I've had some
pretty rough times lately.
Few bookings and audiences well…
They weren't throwing bread,
they sat on their hands.
But ah, these kids here…
They ah...
They love me.
You know I took a little personal
inventory about 10:30 last night,
just before going to sleep.
And I said to myself.
"Harry Lovette things are going
pretty well for a change."
And they are, so why not go for a
run of the play contract. Right?
Well down in school those kids,
Terrific kids you
got here Mr. Chang.
They're very imaginative.
They keep imitating me.
Wanting to be like me.
I thought it might be a good idea
to give them a course in dramatics.
Teach them to sing
and dance, you know
sort of that, 'Big Time Stuff.'
But ah, would that be all
right with you Mr. Chang?
Can I stay?
Watch it Mr. Chang he's liable
to cause chaos in that school.
I don't think so.
We have a saying,
"The trees that bend a little
to the harmless breeze,
will later grow to
withstand the wild wind."
Uh?
We shall be most honored
to have you Mr. Lovett.
Oh, great great great.
Now, I'll cut the cake.
Chang!
I wanna' talk with
you Mr. Chang.
That famous tribe of porter's
expected for two years
that will take us all out of
here whenever they arrive.
Well, I've just discovered they
have arrived, three days ago.
And there was never any intention
that they should take us out of here.
Isn't that right Mr. Chang?
I'm going with them Richard.
As for the rest of you
well, think about it.
Mr. Conway.
My friend you must
not let him go.
The porters could only take
him a certain distance.
Beyond that is a wilderness for
which he would never get out alive.
You should have told me
the porters where here.
I could have prepared
him for this.
Talk to him.
I'll try, I don't think
he'll listen to me.
Richard.
Be careful. He will want
you to go with him.
Well.
What shall I do Catherine?
Go and talk to Father Perrault.
Yes, I will.
And I need your help Father,
to stop him from leaving.
I am no longer able to help you.
The responsibility is yours.
My son…
I'm going to die.
I wish to place in your hands,
the future and destiny
of Shangri-La.
I knew my work was done when
I first set eyes upon you.
I'd been waiting for
you for a long time.
I've sat in this room
and seen the faces
of many newcomers.
I've looked into their eyes
and heard their voices.
Always in the hope
that I might find you.
It's not an honest task
that I bequeathed.
For our order knows
no rigid bonds.
To be gentle and patient,
to care for the
riches of the mind,
to reside here in wisdom,
while the storm rages without.
It will be such a one my son as
the world has not seen before.
There will be no safety by arms.
No help from authority.
No answer in science.
It will rage till every flower
of culture is trampled
and all human beings are leveled
in a loss chaos.
Ask yourself, has it
not already begun?
Do you, really believe that I'll
live to see the end of the storm?
I do. That is why it is you
who must preserve
the fragrance of our history
and add to it, a touch
of your own mind.
You net…
I…
My vision weakens.
I can see,
the great distance.
A new world
stirring in the ruins.
Stirring clumsily
but in hopefulness.
Seeking its lost and
legendary treasures.
They will all be here my son.
Hidden behind the mountains
in the Valley Of The Blue Moon.
Preserve in Shangri-La.
I see...
my...
miracle.
And that's the story.
He said, " I place in your hands the
future and destiny of Shangri-La."
I now know that
I found the answers to
all the confusion of the
world that has plagued
me for a long time.
I found what I'm searching for…
I don't know what to say to you.
Do you really believe
everything he told you?
Yes, I do.
Without any proof?
The proof is in the man himself.
In everything I've felt.
Here, from the beginning.
Doesn't the story
mean anything to you?
What could it mean to me?
You're right George. This
is no place for you.
And you should realize it's
no place for you either.
You're needed in
the outside world
where the problems are far
more urgent and pressing
than they are here
in Shangri-La.
Here, here you
just marking time.
Besides think of your
obligations to the U.N.
I know the obligations.
I know.
But I've found peace here.
And I've found love.
And I must hold on to it.
I'm going to pack and
see to the others.
Richard, I beg you
to think again.
And change your mind.
George, I'm staying.
Sorry.
I'm very sorry.
I shall miss you. So will
a lot of other people.
So you won't be lonely, I've
talked to the rest of them.
They're staying too.
So it'll be just Maria and me.
Maria, what she got
to do with it?
She's coming with me.
- You can't take her away.
- Why not?
Don't you know what will happen
to her if she leaves Shangri-La?
She'll begin to live the happiest part
of her life. That's what will happen.
She'll begin to live the
last moments of her life.
Her beauty is…
She must stay here
where she's safe.
She's young and strong, she'll
manage the trip all right.
George listen, she
can't make that trip.
She's not young and strong. Chang
told me that she came here, …
80 years ago.
Eighty?
What are you talking about?
Oh come on Richard, you
can't believe that.
You've seen her, she's
not a day over 20.
Shangri-La will keep her
youthful indefinitely.
I see. And what if she
leaves Shangri-La?
Chang said she would quickly
revert to her actual age.
And you must believe it.
Look, will you believe me
if I prove you're wrong?
And will you then see that,
if I'm right about Maria,
I'm probably right
about the rest too.
I'll die if I have to
stay here alone now.
George promised he
wouldn't leave me.
If it weren't for me
you'd never get out.
It was I who bribed the porters.
They were forbidden by the High
Lama to take any one out of here.
- Is it true?
- I was with her.
They only took the bribe
because he's dead now.
But aren't you afraid to leave? You
know what will happen if you go.
Happen?
Ah, I suppose Chang
told you that I am old.
That is part of the
myth of Shangri-La.
Chang did tell you didn't he.
Yes.
Look at me Mr. Conway,
Do I look like an old woman?
Is this the skin
of an old woman?
Are these the eyes
And in my heart, are these the
feedings of an old woman?
Do you believe I have
been here for 80 years?
Like us, she was kidnapped.
They brought her here
just two years ago.
Well I don't believe it. I
can't believe it. She's lying.
You're lying every word you said is a lie.
Now come on admit it.
What reason would
I have for lying?
Look Mr. Conway,
the chances are, we will never live
through this terrible journey.
But, I would rather go
out there with George,
and die in a snowstorm than
stay here one minute more.
But why have they
told me this story!
Because they need you here.
Sally and the others have already
found ways to be useful,
But you're the one they were
after, you had to be convinced.
But your job isn't here and
you must realize that now.
Are you telling me the truth?
I am 20 years old and I was
brought here two years ago.
I'm going to need your
help on this journey.
We both are.
Please come with us Richard.
I believe her.
Humph.
I once said to Chang that I
was afraid this was a dream
from which I might suddenly
and unhappily awake.
All right, I'll come with you.
Catherine!
Catherine?
To Len.
- Yes Mr. Conway.
- Where's Catherine?
Chang has given orders that
she cannot be disturbed.
But where is she,
I must see her.
I regret that is not
possible Mr. Conway.
Richard! Richard come on.
I can't find Catherine.
I'm sorry, but the
porters won't wait.
Richard, the porters won't wait.
I hope they make it.
Doesn't tempt you,
does it Harry?
Not me Sam.
We can still go with
them if you want to.
What's happened?
Where's Richard?
He's leaving my child.
- Leaving?!
- But, he will return.
Richard!
Richard.
Richard, hurry!
Richard!
Richard.
[Hundunn!]
Can't you get them to wait.
They're leaving us
father behind everyday.
They're only trying to save themselves.
We're too slow.
I am sorry. I cannot go faster.
I cannot move faster.
- Hey! Hey!
[Hoodelee]
Aahh!
Richard.
Help me.
I must rest. I cannot
go on any longer.
I must rest!
I'll carry her.
Richard? Richard!
Richard, her-her face!
Look at her face!
There's a cave over there.
Help me.
There.
Ugh.
No!
- Oh no!
- George!
No no!
- No!
Aaaahh!
Aah!
Doctor.
How are you Mr. Conway?
I dreamt for a moment
that I was back again.
Back again? Where?
Where?
How are you feeling?
I don't know whether I've
been mad, and now sane or,
I was sane for a time
and now mad again.
Mr. Conway.
How do you know my name?
The whole world knows your name
and wonders what happened to you?
You were flying back from a U.N. peace
mission when your plane disappeared.
Peace mission.
- Did we succeeded?
- Sadly no.
But there's always hope.
Yes hope.
It must be that.
Mr. Ferguson, I'm Dr. Verden.
I told Conway you're coming.
- Oh good. This is my associate Theo Murphy.
- How do you do.
- Dr..
- Please come with me.
Follow me.
When the tribesmen found him
wandering in the lower valley,
he was totally lost.
Suffering from snow blindness
and near starvation.
Despite this, they had a hard
time getting him to the village.
So keen was he to get
back into the mountains.
To get to this place
called Shangri-La.
Shangri-La. Yes, that
was in your report.
- But do you think...?
- You'll hear about it from him.
Come.
Where he is he?
I'm afraid you arrived too late.
He's gone.
Gone?
Shangri-La.
On and on he talked about
this fantastic place.
He must return. He must return!
Obviously right now that's
what he's trying to do.
But I've got to find him.
It's my job to take him home.
Your job won't be easy Mr. Ferguson,
even if you do find him.
This, obsession if you will,
kept him alive in the wilderness,
beyond all human endurance.
Even here his convalescence
is do less to medicine,
than to that, all consuming
passion to return.
In Richard Conway's mind,
Shangri-La represents the
ultimate way of life.
It's ah, Shangri-La.
Do you believe it?
Yes, I believe it.
I believe it, because
I want to believe it.
? There's a Lost Horizon, ?
? waiting to be found. ?
? There's a Lost Horizon ?
? where the sound of guns ?
? doesn't pound in your ears, ?
? anymore. ?