Showbox / Mediaplex, Inc. presents
A Popcorn Film Production
Kwon Sang-woo
Yoo Ji-tae
Son Byung-ho
Executive Producer Kim Woo-taek
Jeong Tae-sung
Producer Han Sung-goo
Running Wild
Move!
Come on! Son of a bitch!
Fucking asshole!
Director Kim Sung-su
The direct cause of death is
a fractured forehead.
It's not a suicide.
You sent us the dental record of
a missing person 3 years ago.
It's a match.
It's PARK, the boss of
the Dokang Family.
After he went missing, CHO
his right arm, took over the Family.
The motive must be a power game.
You're already on a case?
You haven't changed.
I gotta hand it to you.
You know what I nicknamed him?
Mr. Urologist'
He lays his hand on a case
it gets bigger and bigger.
This case has been closed
due to lack of evidence.
You sure?
We have a case.
Why didn't you make a baby
while staying down there?
Prosecutor OH Jin-woo
Boxes of documents!
Is he after all the thugs
in Korea, or what?
Is it lopsided?
Everybody says he's a tight ass.
Is he?
Gangsters used to shiver
at the mention of his name.
3 years ago, he busted YOO
the Kingpin...
...when he was green.
But during the interrogation...
...names of those up there
were mentioned.
So he ended up getting transferred
to the boondocks.
How are PARK's wife and kids?
I've been looking after them.
Don't worry.
Thanks.
Welcome back, Boss!
It's not a good sight.
Move them.
I'm sorry, sir.
I meant to make this quiet.
Come on, move!
So many thugs here!
On a field trip to the joint?
Who the fuck are you?
A homicide detective, asshole.
What are you, the Mob?
Shooting the Godfather?
Going to jail is no freaking medal.
- Watch it, asshole!
- CHO!
So you're a detective?
We don't want any trouble.
You have my apology.
Come on, let's go.
They were out of tofu.
That's made from beans, too.
Let's get you a suit first.
You'd been working in Japan.
Tell Mom that.
Mom?
What's going on?
What's this?
What's wrong with Mom?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Mom.
It's okay.
- It's okay.
- I'm sorry.
Hang out with those punks again
and I'll kill you.
Putting me back in jail?
I'm not a fool.
I know you ratted on me then.
But I never held a grudge.
I knew you didn't do it
to screw your half brother.
You did it for my sake.
Okay then.
My old man and yours...
They gave Mom hell
while they were alive.
And you're gonna let her die
like that?
I can't.
Damn, you've grown up.
Yeah, I'm incapable.
I wanted to be happy, too
like everybody else.
Eating out on the weekends...
Three of us playing cards
on holidays...
You know I tried.
- It didn't work.
- We gotta save her.
You watch me.
I won't let her die.
You think I'm complaining?
Maybe I should.
You never think of anything
but your job.
I'm working on a big case.
I can't afford to mess it up.
When it's over
we'll go on a trip or something.
You know what?
I'm asking for a divorce!
You're married to your job
anyway, not me.
- It won't do anything for us!
- For me, it will.
Let's get it over with ASAP.
- You show him the contract?
- He won't sign it.
Is that so?
Look, YOO.
You don't scare me.
This is no negotiation.
What are you doing?
Well, Min?
I don't want it!
You're asking for it, man.
Bro! No, Detective!
I'm freaking sorry.
Bro.
You even get drunk from coke
for God's sake.
I could've pulled it off, but...
- Sober the hell up!
- For mom's surgery!
I could've gotten the money.
I thought I got it.
She needs surgery to live
but we're broke!
I never do anything right!
Asshole!
Look, shut your hole.
Stay put here.
- How much?
- Hold on.
Lotto... Damn lotto.
8...
Sir!
Dong-jik?
Wake up.
Wake up, asshole!
Ambulance...
We need an ambulance.
Call 911!
We're from the Prosecutor's Office.
Please be cooperative in the scene.
Where's Dong-jik?
He left on business.
What business?
Gone abroad again?
Don't worry about him.
Worry about yourself.
He's still a kid.
Look after him.
Mom.
Have you ever been happy
in your life?
I don't know.
Never?
What about before you got hitched?
You're so pitiful.
To me, you are.
We both are.
Aren't we?
You and I are both pathetic.
Let's go.
Black Grandeur with Seoul plates
ending in 84.
This is it.
Forget it.
I can print it out for you.
Can you pull out a list
of lefty criminals using knives?
Someone stole your money?
This so isn't you, man.
- Can you, or not?
- No need to yell, man.
Wait.
Black Grandeur LEE Dong-hyuk
Right.
I called her yesterday.
One who bought the car from you...
It's him, isn't it?
Maybe, or maybe not.
Asshole!
Yes, that's him!
That's the guy.
- Don't waste my time.
- Okay, I won't.
He's a lefty, isn't he?
If he jerks off with a left hand!
How should I know?
- Sir.
- You...
- Call him.
- Uncuff me then.
Come on, this is unnecessary.
Uncuff me.
You find it fun cuffing me?
You're a cop, so what?
Be a cop then. Asshole!
If you change your words later...
You're dead.
Detective JANG?
Detective?
Uncuff me, pig!
Where are you going?
Son of a bitch!
I'll fucking sue you, asshole.
Have fun taking a bus home.
A rat is approaching the target.
An informer, maybe?
BAE Kwang-chun!
You know why I'm here, don't you?
All I want is BAE.
So stay the fuck out.
Now I recognize you.
What are you doing here, Detective?
What should we do?
Should we move in?
- Let's.
- Come on!
Why'd you kill Dong-jik?
Watch it.
- The badge won't protect you.
- Get the fuck out of the way!
Cops are here!
Run!
Stop right there, fuckers!
Let's go!
Get back here!
Get back here, fuckers!
Fuck!
Get up!
Don't move!
- Hold still!
- Let go, fuckers!
Fuck!
Come on, I'll kill you all!
Pin him down!
Sons of bitches!
I'll kill you all!
- What's this?
- He's a cop!
What'd you want BAE for?
Do cops need a reason
to bust thugs?
I bust thugs when I see one.
We staked out here for 4 days.
We needed evidence to indict them.
And you ruined it for us.
Not everything works out
in your favor.
Forget about it.
Got a light?
Listen.
This isn't about arresting
one petty thug.
You want to score?
Look somewhere else.
If I was sane and reasonable...
...I would suck up to you
Mr. Prosecutor.
But I have a reputation
around here.
As a crazy bastard!
You listen.
That motherfucker is mine.
You got that?
Look somewhere else
Mr. Prosecutor.
You're no different from a thug.
Fax an official request to...
Two things that I hate the most.
One is:cockroaches.
The other:thugs.
And you just called me a thug?
Who do you think you are
taking to him like...
- BANG.
- Yes?
You smoke, don't you?
I do, but I'll quit.
What the...
Mr. YOO Kang-jin was once known
as the President of the underworld.
Paroled recently, he says he
converted to Christianity.
Having established a facility
under his firm, Guryong Industries...
...he's committed
to helping the less fortunate.
Did you contact Senator HONG?
Yes, we know what he wants, sir.
Don't sir me when we're alone.
I'm okay, sir.
I don't feel comfortable.
We're friends from childhood.
How much does he want?
A lot of developers are
after that project.
To eliminate the competition
and bribe officials...
He's asking for Big Five.
He'll pocket half of it, though.
We need him, after all, on this.
Sir! Sir...
Sir!
- CHO.
- Sir?
Something's bothering me.
Prosecutor OH Jin-woo...
I think he's after you.
- He's a bad ass.
- I didn't mess up.
I've been loyal to you, sir.
You know that.
That's why I'm in a dilemma.
Should I kill you?
Or him?
Let me tell you an old saying.
It's a golden rule.
No matter how good you are
never fight against the government. '
Yes. That's true.
Isn't it?
Sir!
Sir?
Let me live!
No!
Let's go.
Sir?
I know what you wanna say.
Unless they betray me,
don't desert them.
That's my principle.
When he comes to
tell him to go under till I call him.
Yes, sir.
What do you mean
it's out of the question?
Didn't I tell you?
CHO has gone under.
I just want the list of those
connected to his Family.
What'd you just say?
Forget it, asshole!
The youth hold
our profound future.
I'll focus on helping the needy.
That's a meaningful life.
From now on, I will hold charities
like this as often as possible.
But you understand that there are
people doubting your intentions.
There's nothing I can do about it.
I'm just doing what I can
to contribute to society.
- Please, comment on...
- Excuse me.
- One more question, sir.
- Excuse us.
Excuse me.
We have suspects
who might've killed your husband.
We're working on it.
We just need more time.
I'm glad to have found his body
thanks to you.
What brings you down here?
A month ago...
A young man came to see me
right before the funeral.
He asked for money.
He said he had evidence
of my husband's murder.
- Go screw yourselves.
- Detective JANG!
Look!
- Lose the attitude.
- 'Lose the attitude. '
I'll quit, okay?
Fuck Internal Affairs!
Stop it! Cool it, will you?
They're suspending me!
He's completely out of control.
You fucking suits have no idea
what it's like out there.
Watch your language!
It'll be included in the report.
Include this, too!
Detective JANG!
That moron...
Damn it.
What are you doing here?
Isn't this place too humble
for you?
Cops can't beat up suspects.
If you're here to screw me,
take a number.
Just keep in mind
that the line is quite long.
One shot is $100 Gs.
Don't you want it?
You need money for your mom.
What the fuck!
What the fuck is this?
You think I take bribes?
Sit.
I need a man.
One that can't be bought.
So what?
You want me to be your minion?
You're after BAE.
It's for LEE Dong-jik, isn't it?
You know he's a hit man
for the Dokang Family.
I'd be better off having you on my side
than letting you get in the way.
What I want is the Dokang Family.
We can nail both CHO and BAE
as a package.
I need a light.
Come on.
What about the suspension?
I'll have it lifted
if you join my team.
One more thing.
We go strictly by the book.
Then by my orders.
So you'd like to keep me
on a short leash?
- If you don't like it, forget it.
- You called me a thug.
What changed your mind?
You refused this.
It was too little.
This might do.
100 Gs? No way.
He did 25 months for assault
and blackmailing.
I know he didn't do it.
- He was a watcher.
- Was he your informant?
I just knew him.
I put him in jail.
He asked PARK's wife
for money.
He must've known something.
That's what got him killed.
LEE Dong-jik?
LEE Dong-jik...
We didn't share the cell.
I only saw him
during exercise hours.
But I hardly knew him.
You were in together
for a year.
And you two were friends
from outside.
I said I knew nothing.
- Don't fuck with us, asshole!
- Let go of him.
Words won't do.
Fists will!
Let go of him!
Listen to him.
Stop shaking your legs!
He got killed
right after he was released.
Tell us whatever you know.
Little things help.
Dong-jik...
Now thinking about it,
he had a lot of visitors.
- Visitors?
- On behalf of the cell leader.
There were so many eyes.
He was an errand boy.
Was the cell leader
from the Dokang Family?
No.
It was YOO Kang-jin,
the boss of the Guryong Family.
They got released on the same day.
You didn't know?
LEE Dong-jik was a petty hand
in the Dokang Family.
He did 25 months in prison.
And he got killed by BAE
soon after the release.
The motive?
I believe he got hold of evidence
to the PARK's murder.
He blackmailed them for money
and got killed.
You have evidence?
We're working on it.
Are you sure?
He was a petty hand.
Don't be mistaken.
He was an errand boy for someone
while in jail.
YOO, the boss of the Guryong Family.
PARK was the boss of
the Dokang Family.
As you all know
they go way back.
They were friends
when they were local punks.
However, YOO was smarter
and more decisive.
As the Guryong Family expanded...
...they clashed a lot.
3 years after PARK disappeared,
he was found dead.
YOO is getting himself acquainted
in the political circle.
It's either to acquire concessions,
or he has another agenda.
YOO Kang-jin is behind the murders
of PARK and LEE Dong-jik.
And the killer, CHO
has gone under.
- YOO gave the order.
- Look, Jin-woo.
If YOO is a major leaguer,
PARK was a minor leaguer.
What would he kill PARK for?
Whatever it was, we'll know soon.
He isn't what he was.
He's a respected businessman now.
He's in the press's spotlight
for all his charity work.
Any evidence? Any witnesses?
You don't wanna rock the boat
for nothing.
Jin-woo.
I know there's bad blood
between you two, but let it go.
What do you mean?
You touched him 3 years ago
and got screwed.
- Trying to get back at him?
- What?
Locate CHO first.
And check out the members
of the Dokang Family.
We'll see about YOO.
- Sir!
- Jin-woo, one step at a time.
Let's make this quiet.
Okay, what's next?
Who could've imaged you were here?
We've been looking for you.
You made a promise.
What do I know?
They give orders.
And I follow them.
Leave my family alone.
As long as you're gone,
they'll be fine.
- That bastard!
- BAE Kwang-chun.
I knew you'd show up here, asshole.
Whack him!
Let's go!
Let go!
You can't die on me.
You can't.
I have to work hard to make up for
the 3-year-long break you gave me.
Time does fly.
My daughter goes to middle school.
You don't have kids, do you?
Let's cut the chitchat.
Get to the point.
You got something for me?
What is it?
They say power lies
in the truth.
This will help you.
I know you gave an order
to kill PARK.
Do yourself a favor
and rest well at home.
You don't have much time
left out here.
You haven't changed a bit.
You still don't know
how the world works.
No.
It's you who hasn't changed.
You do a lot of social work.
But you're still a gangster.
Aren't you?
Jin-woo, if you keep pushing,
you'll get hurt.
You know I have the power.
You should be...
...pretty damn powerful...
...to stop me.
You don't give up, do you?
Sure, let's do it.
Buddhist Scriptures
When my wife was pregnant
with her...
...CHO told me to whack our boss
with BAE.
I had to choose
between her and our boss.
Surprisingly,
I didn't hesitate much.
So I took him to a deer farm.
He wasn't suspicious.
He liked drinking blood
from live deer.
I betrayed our boss...
...and gave up on one ankle
for my daughter.
Will you protect her?
So before PARK got killed,
he and CHO clashed...
...over Segi Shopping Mall.
Is that right?
Our boss wanted the proceeds
to strengthen the Family.
But CHO was against it.
- He thought it was too risky.
- Risky?
We weren't the only Family
after that shopping mall project.
It says here...
llyang Development
won the project.
It was run by the Guryong Family.
The company's president is
related to YOO.
I know that for a fact.
What is politics?
It's making an effort to make people
happy and satisfied.
If I give it my heart and try hard,
they'll see how determined I am.
Have you decided on the party
and constituency?
That's still pending.
It's premature to tell you yet.
I might go independent
if I have to.
What?
You're taking my constituency?
Is this how you repay me?
I got you into the circle.
How dare you!
I've returned your favors enough.
I even let you get away with pocketing
half of the political funds I donated.
Watch it, pal.
I've tasted all the bitter
sweets in politics.
A thug can't bring me down.
What'd you just say?
Go back to the damn alley
where you belong!
Politics isn't for everybody.
Let alone thugs like you.
Know your damn place.
- Look, asshole.
- How dare you...
What's the different between
turf and constituency?
If I'm a thug, you're a worm.
Worms like you are the ones
who have fucked up the nation.
Your constituency is mine.
Don't show up again.
Unless you'd like to lie
down in a coffin!
The company wasn't doing well
when it took the project.
What's its bank?
It's Prime Bank, Yeoksam branch.
Two loans, 6 and 9 million each.
Someone must've pulled strings
to grant those loans.
- Get a search warrant issued.
- Yes, sir.
They're pros.
They must've tampered
with the books.
- The list of shop buyers?
- Yes.
Here.
Get the dossiers on buyers
whether individuals or corporations.
Ask IRS on ownership changes
if there's been any.
What's this?
Aren't we gonna nail CHO?
Those pieces of paper won't
bring him to us.
We're wasting time!
We should get out there
and track down that asshole!
Come on.
This is how things are done
around here.
We don't just go out there
and start sniffing like detectives do.
- Okay?
- God damn it!
What'd you say?
That asshole always puts me down.
He isn't cut out to be here.
Don't.
Not sleeping?
Mom likes that song.
Leave it on.
You've lost weight.
You shouldn't skip meals.
The last thing I want is
you getting sick.
You should get married soon.
It's your mom's wish.
Marriage my ass.
That's beyond my fate.
Be nice to her while she's alive.
Once she's gone
you'll regret it.
Like I do.
What?
This is good.
And...
Thanks.
We have a search warrant.
Do you admit taking
illegal political funds?
How about pulling strings
for a syndicate?
How close are you to Mr. YOO?
You'll learn the truth soon.
You bought a shop at Segi Mall
in your son's name 3 years ago.
And you sold it later
for a large capital gain.
Korea is a capitalistic nation.
You invest to make money.
Don't you?
Who gave you the investment tip?
- Wasn't it Mr. YOO?
- Well...
That's your job to find out.