Dear Priya, it's me
And this is the bucket that
I'd started filling with my tears...
two months ago, while leaving
my friends in Delhi
It's filled now
Why did Papa have to take up a job
with the Indian Embassy?
Every year they have him transferred,
from one embassy to another
This time it is Russia
Know what? The mornings here
are so cold that...
my teeth wrestle with each other
The things we used to eat on our way
to school, back in India!
Nandulal's "kachoris"...
Karim Lala's "falooda"...
In Russia, we find milkshakes,
no faloodas...
rosous, no kachoris...
Priya, this city seems to have
no houses at all
And the buildings here
look more like palaces
But looking at the brighter side
of the life...
Now that I'm here...
it seems like a Disney Magical
Adventure city to me
There's a forest on the way...
and a small pond
inside the forest
Every morning, my sister Lucky throws
bread-crumbs at the ducks in the pond
Remember, in India, my sister Lucky
always used to be immersed in...
well, well... her thoughts,
her poems and her books
Here, her plight seems
to have worsened...
now she sings religious hymns too!
My sister Lucky!
Meera in Russia
found it!
Found what?
Lucky
Your name is Lucky.
How come that's Lucky?
Oh no, it's a four-leaf clover.
They say, it brings good luck
You mean, it'll help me clear
my examinations?
Sure. But it is effective only once
If I find one like that, I'll pass
the examinations this time...
and give Papa a surprise.
- Then take this one
Really?
I need it more than you do,
because you pass every year
Thank you, sis
Okay... okay
Now shall we...?
Why do we've to go
to school every day?
"Priya, there are three Indian girls
in Lucky's class"
"But in my class,
all of them are foreigners"
"I haven't made a single friend yet"
"I miss my India everyday"
Really, I miss India so much
The volkswagen vW PD for motion
as a potent PDI PD130 engine
The ferrari Enzo is a successor
to the f40...
To the f50. Does 0.60...
in 2.6 seconds, which makes it
the fastest car in the world
sunaina, you are best.
- Thank you, darling
sunaina, how do I look?
- Like shit!
Sunaina, we have a test tomorrow
in school
And what is this that
the two of you are reading?
You study for the school test,
while I study for the "cool" test
When he comes, he'll find that
our thoughts match
Who is coming?
Girls, just guess
No way
Don't tell me he's coming!
Is it a dream?
- Should I pinch you?
I'll be meeting him
after three years
The last time he came...
he didn't even cast a glance at me
Those dirty braces spoilt my smile
But now...
- smashing seventeen!
I was also a bit plump then
But...
now...
This time he'll turn around for sure,
and also admire his new girlfriend
But who is he?
- Hush
When everyone is asleep at night, I'll
quietly dress up and go to meet him
He will be waiting for me!
He'll come for me...
and lost in his eyes,
I'll be a little nervous
He'll grab my hand and say,
"come closer"
I'll comply. At some noise,
I'll hug him, out of fright
Ah, someone might see us!
Then he'll bring his lips
closer to mine and say...
"Give me a kiss, honey".
And then...
And then?
You tell me. What would you do?
What do I say? I don't even know
who you are talking about
I know what this bore will tell.
What say, Padma?
Right. She will say,
"The moon appears so near, no?"
"Know what? The moon is 384404
kilometres away from the earth"
"I learnt that in school"
Really?
I'd say something else
"Good Lord"
"Oh my God"
"Why is my heart..."
"hysteric?"
"Someone will come,
take me in his arms..."
"and kiss my lucky lips"
"I feel ticklish..."
"I'm lost..."
"I'm half-awake, half-asleep"
"It's an entirely all-new feeling"
"A thirst lingers on my lips"
"It's a special sense of pain"
"someone will leave..."
"with a restless feeling..."
"after seeing my lucky lips"
"I'm soaring with the breeze..."
"in my obsession"
"My eyes, downcast and coy..."
"my breaths reveal my story"
"My heart thumps wildly..."
"and my lucky lips yearn"
"Good Lord"
"Oh my God"
"Why is my heart..."
"hysteric?"
"Someone will come,
take me in his arms..."
"and kiss my lucky lips"
But who's coming?
Adi.
- Adi?
Adi, who?
Ambassador sekhri's son
Oh Lucky! He's so dashing...
so charming...
- so manly
If he's so dashing and manly, why'd
he be interested in a school girl?
Please! You are just jealous.
Okay?
When he comes, just watch
how I floor him
Girls...
sunaina, sorry
sunaina, you won't believe
what blunder I've committed
Now what?
- Tomorrow is the Geography test
And I misread the timetable
and studied history
How could you be so foolish?
- I got to study the entire syllabus
The entire syllabus?
Lucky darling, you're going to fail,
I can guarantee that
I'll hang up now, bye
Lucky, they will be singing hymns
all night tomorrow at sunaina's
I don't want you to be looking
like a ghost there
Know what? All the Indians
will be there
Listen... I've packed your bag
Lingerie, toothbrush
...I've put everything
Ma, please let me study
Where's Dhara?
- In the bathroom
I don't know what to do
with this girl!
If she flunks this time,
your papa will be really angry
Besides, he's so hassled these days
Why? What happened to Papa?
Nothing
said, there's some official problem
People are on the streets,
rioting
Anyway, we've nothing to do with it
Here... your bag is packed
Dhara, make it fast!
- Two minutes, Ma
Lucky, sleep for a while, dear.
Get up early in the morning and study
Mom
Go to sleep, dear,
or you will fall sick
It's seven!
Why didn't the alarm buzz?
Get up, Dhara!
Let me sleep, sis.
It's only 2
It's 7! Get up, quick
No good waking up,
I'm going to flunk anyway
Get up!
Hush, sis! Someone is sleeping here
c'mon get up, you dumbo!
Stop it, sis
Bye, Dhara.
- Papa's on the line, Lucky
I love you
Good morning, dear.
Prepared to come first, aren't you?
Papa...
- What happened?
Mr Negi...
- Hang on, dear. Yes, sir
My son Aditya is arriving
from Paris today
His car's number is 0267 xP78. Please
see he has no problems with security
sure.
- I'll be busy in a meeting
That's why I can't receive him
He's not coming by flight, sir?
He can dump his father,
but not his car
Wherever he goes, he goes in his car.
He's driving down
Okay, sir
Yes, dear.
- Yes, papa
Best of luck, dear. I'm sure
you'll come first this time too
Bye, dear
Please help me. Please, God!
Perform a miracle, Lord!
Let the exams be postponed
I'm sure you will come first, dear
first... first... first
Papa is too much.
I'm only human
so what if I fail once?
I'm forgetting all that I studied
Oh, God!
A flat tyre! Now!
I won't have time to study now
Hey
Hi
No Russian
English?
Flat tyre?
Help?
- No. It's okay
No... no. Wait
Wait
No school today?
I'll fix it.
- No
My cycle?
Rest?
Vice caption
Just leave me.
No!
No! No leave me
Help!
Thief
Good morning
I'm giving you. You aren't
missing your flight, are you?
Thank you
Yeah! Nothing.
- Sure
Nothing
check
What the hell you are doing
in my car? No English?
What are you doing in my car?
Hang on, brother
Miss? School bus miss?
No Russian, no spanish,
no Hindi
I'm screwed
I know Hindi
Indian?
Indian passport please?
No passport?
Watch out
stay inside, I'll be back
c'mon wake up.
C'mon get up
c'mon
Drive. You drive
What are you doing? Drive
What the...? Drive
Drive!
Stop!
Stop! Hey, stop!
Bullets flying
through such huge guns...
an elephant-like tank speeds
towards my car...
and I blast my tonsils screaming, but
it hardly makes any difference to you
Drive!
Drive! I say, drive!
What were you thinking of?
What?
I can't drive
Oh God! Take care of Adi
sir
All the phone lines are dead.
Only one choice left
I'll go with the security squadron
to search for Adi
No
Unless...
I get an assessment on the situation
in the city...
I won't allow anyone to step out
of the embassy
Before the communication lines
jammed, we taped the BBc broadcast
There's no news
on the situation otherwise
Play it quickly.
- Mr Negi...
This is terrible
The terrorists have started attacking
in the open. Now what, sir?
Where's the President? Any news?
- No, sir
We hear, ministers have
been kidnapped
The army is working out a strategy to
tackle the terrorists. War is brewing
Oh my God!
I hope my Adi is safe and all right
It's a graveyard.
- Hey school girl, come in front
I might look like one,
but I'm not your chauffeur
I know it's a graveyard. But,
you know what's special about it?
We are three feet
above the ground now
If we drive further,
we'll come back right here
But then...
we'll be six feet under the ground
Then you won't be asking questions
and I won't be answering any
Now let me find out what problems
those people fighting out there have
It's got old. Would you please
open that door?
Hang on
Before you break it, let me try
Well, what's the name of the girl
who's sitting in my car?
My name is Lucky
I'm sorry.
Are you hurt?
What were you saying?
- I said, my name is Lucky
Pardon...? Lucky?
Listen... seriously, are you Lucky?
Lucky Negi
Hear that? The girl with whom I've
spent the luckiest day of my life...
happens to be Lucky Negi
How will I reach home?
I will reach you home... wouldn't you
like to know my name?
I'm Aditya sekhri
shake hands
Don't worry, I'm not going to accept
that hand forever
Good
Now how about getting down to work?
- Work?
Yes.
- What work?
You want to go home, don't you?
And your mummy isn't coming here
to fix the radio
so we got to do something.
Let's start?
Come
There are about 3000 Indians in this
area. And it is our prime duty...
to protect all of them
- Mr sinha
sir, we've begun the task
of bringing them to the embassy
Good. Any problems on the way?
- No, sir
No harm yet to the vehicles
carrying the Indian tricolour
That's very good.
Let's hope that it stays like that
Excuse me, sir
Your wife wants to see you.
It's urgent
I'm busy. Tell her, I'll see her
in ten minutes
Okay, sir
Lucky...
- What happened to Lucky?
Lucky hasn't returned
from school yet
Anjali!
Right... right
No! Left
Left... left
Right
I mean, the left was right
stay put
What news?
Stay there, I'll tell you
Look Ms Lucky...
see this... we are in Russia
There's a clash between the government
and the terrorists
What all areas are under attack?
- We are here
They are fighting here, here,
here... everywhere
Adi...
- Yes?
A bee.
- Kill it, or it'll sting you.
It'll hurt.
- Kill it!
Are you a fool?
What is with you?
Damn these school girls!
I know, I was harsh.
Okay, I'm going
c'mon, I'm going!
How sweet!
I'm hurt, but it is you
who is crying
Did you meet your boyfriend
when you were crying?
I don't have a boyfriend
Really? You're lying
All right, if you don't have
a boyfriend, would you tell me...
who gave you these "hicci"?
Hiccups?
- Not hiccups, "hicci"
Know what a love-bite is?
Strange. When I was in school
we used to call love-bites "hicci"
I don't know what they're called
these days. Whatever, but I'm sure...
your boyfriend gave you that.
- I don't have a boyfriend
And may God never give me one!
I just asked God for a miracle,
because I didn't want to fail the exam
But then, my bicycle's tyre went flat,
and then I met that filthy man...
who told me he'd fix my tyre.
But he tugged at my hair...
Tugged at your hair?
Why didn't you hit him?
I did?
- How?
With my lunch box
very good, Lucky
Tell me... how did you
get into my car?
The door was locked.
- Right. How did you unlock it?
I tried using the cutter
cutter? You keep a cutter
with you, eh?
Paper cutter
And it unlocked?
- No
Then?
- I used the compass
And it gave in?
- No
I got it. Then you shoved the compass
as well as the divider...
into the lock and broke it. Right?
- Right
But it took all my strength
Had you waited two more minutes,
I'd have come and rescued you
I don't have...
Pardon...? If you could talk
a little louder...
a normal man like me
would hear you
I don't have a boyfriend.
I'm not those types
Please believe me
I've heard that several times before
But I believe you
Let's go
shall we...?
Adi, are we going home?
- We'll have to take the same way back
And you know the situation.
Dead phones, dead radio...
Do you have grandparents?
- No, they are dead
Would you like to meet them?
You wouldn't, right?
So we'll have to stay here
Thank you.
- What for?
I saw you thrash him
Tell me...
was that lunch box empty? Or full?
Actually, I couldn't
reach school, so...
What's this?
A hotel inside a school bag!
Come here... I'm famished
This way, please
Official sources say that,
as of now...
the fight between the government and
the rebels has come to a stop
Indefinite curfew has been imposed
in the central city and the suburbs
citizens are requested
not to step out of their houses
Wonderful!
Thank God I don't eat such food
everyday. Because if I did...
I'd not be like this,
I'd be a fatso
Your mother cooked it, right?
Ask me how I know
How?
- Because every mummy cooks yummy food
Won't you eat?
- I hope they won't mind
They? Who?
They
- They
Who? Who's here?
I mean, we're sitting on a grave
with food...
it feels bad
I see. One second
Peter. 1903
The poor guy has been sleeping here
since 1903
He himself doesn't know when he died.
I don't think he'll get up...
and say, "Hello. I'm Peter.
When I was alive..."
"my favourite dish used to be
Indian. Potato pancakes"
still, if you insist,
I'll invite him for dinner. Okay?
Peter, I'm Aditya sekhri.
And she is Lucky Negi
Nice to meet you.
We want you to dine with us
The food will be great, guaranteed
If you still have those fingers,
you will chew them up too
Because the food comes
from Lucky Inn
chicken, or potatoes,
pizza or bread...
you're welcome to Lucky Inn,
even if you are dead
I'm to funny
Well? Wasn't I funny...?
I think I wasn't
Well, I'm thirsty. I'll get water
from the jeep
No, I have water here.
No need to go anywhere
so hurry up
One minute...
Not water, it's only a sip of water
Give it back if you don't want.
- I'm drinking
Looks like you'll have to spend
the night with me. Know what?
Girls would do anything
for such an opportunity
I know. The girls in my school...
are willing to do anything
for this opportunity
The girls in your school
are still talking about me?
Not bad!
I'm not history yet!
Look, I belong to a well to do
family, so the front seat is mine
You take the backseat.
And here's your blanket
What happened, Lucky? Why are you
making noises under the blanket?
I've never spent a night
away from home
I'm scared
If it's because you are spending
the night with me...
don't be afraid at all
Because I'm not those types
Trust me
Adi...
I trust you
Thank you, Ms Lucky Negi
Go to sleep
"come and hold me in your arms..."
"I implore you"
"I'm dying, my love"
"come and take me in your arms..."
"for my sake"
"I'm dying, my love"
"come and take me in your arms..."
"for my sake"
"I'm dying, my love"
"Love is amazing"
"Wonderful things, my eyes behold"
"Until yesterday
my heart was mine..."
"now it belongs to you"
"An unusual desire..."
"appeals"
"I've spent every moment..."
"suffering in pain"
"Look..."
"look, don't..."
"torment me anymore"
"I'm dying, my love"
"Alluring naivete"
"Amazing intoxication"
"To you..."
"I now give my life"
"Amazing reality"
"What a story"
"Beside me..."
"stands the princess of my dreams"
"No more..."
"no more can I bear..."
"this grief of separation"
"I'm dying, my love"
Betrayal! D'you intend to
elope with Peter?
Look Lucky, please don't do this
I can't live without you.
I'll die without you!
I beg of you, please don't dump me
Now stop dreaming about Peter,
it's too late in the night
come and sleep, Ms Lucky Negi
But sir, who's this man?
Should be coming any moment.
See for yourself
Only this person can find
Adi and Lucky
Greetings.
- Greetings
Any news of Lucky?
Anjali...
Hello, hi... no need
for such formalities
If I am not mistaken,
you are the girl's father
Right... but how do you know?
That dejected look...
and those dried up tears...
under your eyes
reveal your identity
Handkerchief... wipe off those
tears and distress
A great man said, "Tears are nothing
but salty water. Wipe them off"
No Mr Negi, I'm not mad
And you can confirm that
with the Ambassador
My hand... four fingers and a thumb
Kidnapping, robbery, bribery,
rape and murder
I've spent 17 years with
the Intelligence service
I've come across all kinds
of criminals
clench the fist...
and there's no criminal activity
Pindi Das Kapoor's fist
has never opened...
nor can anyone open it
sir.
- I trust you completely
These are the pictures
of Aditya and Lucky
They are missing.
And we fear they might have...
fear?
What for? As long as a person
is missing, he is alive
If this can relieve you a bit,
then let me tell you that...
your daughter's bicycle has been
found, in the forest near the school
And Lucky? Any news of her?
Belongs to her
A great man once said...
"No boundary, no power on earth
can stop me..."
"from uniting a mother
and her daughter"
Ms Lucky, tell me something
Did you have a premonition
of the war? You are fully prepared
I hope you aren't a KGB agent?
- I was going to stay at sunaina's
That's why I had packed my bags
sunaina? Who?
Oh yes. Sunaina. How's she?
It's been long since we met
As kids, we used to play together
I'm hungry
Last night I told you to eat,
but you were worried about ghosts
Wonderful
Hi! I'm Aditya sekhri.
And you?
- I'm Lucky Negi
strange. Last night too
I met one Lucky Negi
But she wasn't like you one bit
Do you know her?
- I used to
History, eh?
You forgot her so fast.
Would you forget me too?
Hello, no need to get ideas.
I was only joking
Let me go and arrange
some food for you
I know
What's that for?
- To pluck apples
I'm going with you.
- No. Stay here...
and take care of my Queen Tullu
Who will come here?
- Anyone
Who?
Look that way.
- Why?
Turn around!
I feel shy, I need to
take my underwear
c'mon
Today's school girls!
Done. And, also clean my car