It's time. I prepare dinner.
But in the meantime can play rhymes?
With what?
With a word "cat".
Starved cat is eating again...
Opening the fridge and finding... an egg?
Egg belongs to cat, a cat is hatching it
An insane kitty, who's
giving him heat.
They're prowling, flying so far.
The egg breaks and appears a...
...seagull!
Little soul of equilibrist.
Nothing in the world makes him so glad
as that unexpected drips
what brings the wind, what
brings the sun.
That is beautiful!
Yes, it is. It should be saved.
What brings the wind, what
brings the sun...
And now, attention!
A final frightening!
As black as oil, with a thousand red eyes.
From their black lairs look eyes of rats.
In a town, what sleeps and dreams,
they bug out, bug out...
rats from ditchs.
What are you doing, little ones!
They bug out, bug out from dumpsters
strong and powerful, ferocious rats.
What eat cats!
Dinner is ready!
LUCKY AND ZORBA
------------------------------
English translation
(based on the Romanian version and the original one)
~~~        Astroni Toderas        ~~~
(ewa.astroni@wp.pl)
------------------------------
~ It's hard, but someone have to do it ~
~ It's hard to not always be what you want ~
~ It's hard, but this someone is us ~
~ They are asking us, why we do that ~
~ They're all standing aside, here's why ~
~ I take a look to understand that ~
~ what you've throw out, may be useful to me ~
~ It's hard, but someone have to do it ~
~ It's hard to not always be what you want ~
Move on, quickly, unload!
~ We continue to work ~
~ Each of us multiplies it more ~
~ While hideous cats consume crunchy food ~
~ The effort what we make ~
~ Soon will give us an reward ~
~ The moment is coming ~
~ Soon all that city will belong to us ~
It's hard to accept, but that
disgusting rat is right...
Even if so... That stinkers
become every day more fat
and more numerous.
For all rats! It smells so disgusting!
Quiet, youngster.
We can not stay indifferent!
We must do something!
Right, Diderot?
Thus masa multiplied by 3.14...
Considering hydraulic
lever arm...
It is brilliant!
Have you heard me, clever one?
We must do something!
- Evidently, Zorba.
- So?
This, what do we do, namely what will you do,
is to climb up to the command cabin
and... do you see?
Press the red button
to turn round the lever arm.
Green one, to lift the weight.
Yellow one, to move it into a truck.
Violet one, to release weight,
making it fall into...
Yes, and then the supercat
is gonna make a carnage,
breaks them tails and smash
theirs stinky mugs!
What are you doing here, Small Ball?
I came to help Zorba
deal with him, grandpa.
So, "supercat", are you ready?
Move forward, and I,
the supercat, will cover you.
- Go ahead, Secretary.
- Me?
Why just me?
Becouse you are a robust and courageous cat.
Yes, sure, but I am extremely
allergic to trash...
Go, young one!
Let's go!
Courage!
For all rats!
Which one press? Red, green...
- It wasn't so powerful, just small sneeze...
- Shut up!
Click the buttons!
- How's it going?
- I do not know!
What are orders, great rat?
Enough, get out of here!
Leave it!
Retreat!
Now comes the supertomcat
and makes meatballs!
Run for your life!
For nothing sighs as much
as for that rain...
A rain that falls from the sky
and dews the sea.
Good evening!
Miss, let me introduce myself
My name is Colonel of cats from port...
Please excuse us we bother you,
but by accident we were followed
hier by those uncivilized rats.
We even have one wounded.
Who?
Me?
No, Colonel, overact!...
I am very delighted.
Bubulina Siamese.
The pleasure is mine.
Zorba the Cat.
It hurts heavily?
Does it hurt?
No, I swear, it's nothing.
Just a scratch.
I am sure he was great!
And really enormous!
And Zorba crushed them all!
But if am I...
"If it was me", Small Ball.
If it was me I would have grabbed that
inflated rat and blasted from bottom
and then I would...
Bubulina, what are you doing?
Hide yourself, quick!
Move on, youngster!
Come on, Small Ball!
Who are you?
Who is it, Bubulina? Your fiancé?
Aren't you impolite for her, crumb?
Oh, hi!
Nina, come inside before
the rain begins!
Be right back, dad!
Come on, run to your friends
before the rain begins!
Do you want to hear how I have
changed the poem about seagulls?
Their little acrobat heart
for nothing sighs as much
as for that silly drips... which
almost always brings wind and sun.
But it doesn't rhyme!
It became a poem for the great.
It grew up and lost the rhyme!
But is a shame!
Seagulls! Frizzoni island on the right!
Prepare yourself for a settle!
Hi! Where are you from?
From the Baltic Sea. And you?
From here, nearly. From North Sea.
Paro island.
I return home from my first migration.
And now I am going to lay egg.
You know, my first egg!
Big congratulations!
Being a mother is a wonderful experience.
I'm a happy father.
I am not uneducated.
My name is Igor!
Hello, Igor! My name is Kenga.
Hi, Colonel!
I heard that last night you've
given them a hefty spanking!
Can you say it out loud?
It was not so!...
Silence, youngster!
Nose up with dignity!
You have given them a good lesson!
Since the time of the second
war for independence from canines
I haven't had so much fun!
Yes, sir, those were hard times.
Dogs was made masters, and
for us, cats, was no rescue.
In that time we couldn't
move freely on the street.
One day, when I could not stand it any more,
we mobilize us in mass and force
them to return to their places.
Get out of here!
The problem is, that young ones
today have quite different concerns.
Grandpa, why is that guy doing this?
I think his stomach a little hurts.
He fall in love.
And it hurts so bad?
No, but it happens that a male
cat finds a female cat and...
Enough, Secretary!
Do something useful and obtain
much fat from friendly sellers above.
Yes, sir, to order!
Becouse of it they both hug
and meow all night?
No... Becouse of...
Then they don't make kittens?
You have the nerve to show up here?
Do you know, what rats did last night?
Ate two boxes of hake!
You are worth nothing, vamoose!
How strange! What are those
colored sheets over ships?
Flags. People call them so.
Each flag corresponds to one country
and each country corresponds
to a different language.
Oh, yes! And how do people understand
with each other when they talk?
Sardine on the right!
Come on, Kenga!
It's really good, isn't it?
I have never eaten so good fish!
Let's catch one more!
Go ahead!
Danger, danger!
What is happening?
I see everything in black!
And the sea is black!
That's oil, the people curse.
I am unable to fly!
Go on, Kenga, the flock cannot
wait, you have to fly!
Do not manage!
Come on, before the flock departs!
Do not leave me here!
You can't save yourself from people curse.
Inhale air as much as you can,
then dive into the water, wash yourself
and with all strength try to
get out of the black lacquer!
You must succeed, for your egg!
Bravo, we present just for food!
But where have you been all night?
How squeamish you are!
What happened to you?
You have a fight with someone?
Mommy's pretty boy!
Stay there as I bring you some tucker.
Please do not eat me!
Do not eat me!
To eat you? It even didn't
go through my head!
How strong stink!
But how you get like this?
I got into a black wave, what
people let out into the sea.
- Oil?
- Yes.
And I feel I am going to die.
How: to die? You're just tired and dirty!
Do not manage!
That was my last flight.
It's so disgusting!
Anyway thank you, my friend!
Friend? What are you saying?
Cats and seagulls were never friends.
Not a chance. I'm gonna
never clean her like that.
I really have to go for help.
Wait!
With my last strength
I will try to lay my egg.
But I have to ask you for
promise me three things.
Promises? Forget it!
I am dying!
I can't wait any longer, please!
All right, I promise, I promise!
What's that?
Firstly: promise me not to eat an egg.
Agree. What else?
Secondly: promise you'll take care
of it, until the baby hatch.
And the last thing:
promise me you teach him to fly.
To fly?
But I'm a cat!
But you have a great spirit like a seagull!
Will you do what I've asked you?
Okay, okay, I promise.
Now I go to seek help.
Grandpa, look, it's Zorba!
Welcome, youngster! How may I serve you?
I have no time, Colonel!
I need a help and an advice.
These people are a bit quirky!
Build new museums and then abandon them.
One so beautiful in center of the city!
You know, the last rational people
were during time of ancient Egyptians,
who worshiping god-cat
by built the pyramids.
A sphinx, Colonel!
And what have I said? A sphinx!
And with what kind of people
we have to live instead?
They treat us as if we were
some stupid dog-like vermins!
An horrible horribleness!
Rats, that ignorants, ate a page of an atlas!
I have lost Portugal!
We can repay it to them too, son,
but be careful now!
We have another problem!
S... S as "seagull"...
What invention irresistible
that encyclopedia!
Every time you flick it, you learn something new.
Grandpa, what's that... enciploredia?
It is said "encyclopedia".
Sure, Small Ball, it is said the encyclopedia.
It's a big store that sells cycles with pedals
of all types, cycles, bicycle...
Actually it's a great book of science, where
is information about all things of the world.
Of the world, that is.
That I wanted to say too.
Sea... Seafront... Seagull!
What does it say?
Oh, yes, perfect!
His flesh is hard a bit,
but absolutely edible!
It's terrible, but they do not
explained clear enough.
Seagull of filth, gull anointed
served with oil, seagull full of stains...
Brilliant!
I found!
Stain removal!
I found. Remove the stains... a damp
cloth... gasoline...
We need a gasoline!
The problem is resolved, son -
we must get a gasoline.
I wish to know how! We are cats!
We can not go to the gas station to ask:
"20 liters of petrol Super, please!"
20 liters of petrol Super, please!
Immediately, sir!
Who are you?
Poor little one!
Where's your mom?
- No, please, no.
- Stop lamenting and go ahead!
- Why me?
- Because of the longer tail.
I was brave as you, Zorba!
That gas station bumpkin has thought as a fool
There cannot be anyone...
Hurry up!
For all rats!
Too late!
We have to close the wings.
What's doing, sleep?
No, she flew in the sky.
How?
She flew up there without using wings?
- Becouse...
- An egg! An egg!
For all rats! What do
I do with an egg?
- A good omelet!
- Omelet?
An optimal idea!
In an encyclopedia we can find, how
to prepare an omelet with flakes.
No, paws down, we can't touch that egg.
I'd feel a... a murderer.
A murderer?
Zorba, do not tell me it's your first egg!
I want an explanation, young one.
Why do you keep so much the seagull egg?
Because... I have promised.
Secretary, what is he saying?
What promise is talking about?
I promised not to eat that egg...
to care for a chick, what will be born...
and that'll teach him to fly.
She was feeling so bad...
A sad story, but you get
in big trouble, young man!
And you think you are able to
respect these promises?
Zorba always respects
promises, what he makes!
Of course I respect, but...
I do not know, how to care for an egg.
If that can be done by some stupid birds,
we, cats, can do that three
thousands times better for sure!
It's extremely simple!
Volume "E", keyword "egg".
No need an encyclopedia.
We are talking about hatching.
What hatching?
It can not be! There was
never a hatching by a cat!
It's beneath us!
It means heat transmission
to the egg from the mother.
Mother?
What mother?
You have to wrap around the egg.
Slowly, do not crush it!
Maybe, but I think it's
very uncomfortable.
How long should I sit
motionless in the nest?
An hour, a month... how long?
We'll get that info in Diderot's
encyclopedia and tell you.
~ A short, but beautiful
flight is life of mine ~
~ But it does not lead any regrets ~
~ With my wings on the blue sky ~
~ Nothing was more beautiful
than to fly up there ~
~ But I am sad, because... ~
~ Because I will not be with you ~
~ You are looking for me ~
~ But I will not be near to you ~
~ And I pray ~
~ That true friends would help you ~
~ Until you grow a little ~
~ And if I will be no longer
able to do it, you will fly... ~
~ You will fly... ~
My dear fellow cats,
We are gathered here
in this moonlit night
to give last salute
an young unlucky seagull.
It is saddened, that she
left us, but especially
our hearts are crying
for the way she left,
killed by human folly,
which one day will destroy
the wild and wonderful world,
what mother nature has given us.
And now, all miaow together
the moon farewell song
of us, of cats from port.
Shut up, imbecile, you
want to be discovered?
They certainly went mad!
It is terribly cold!
I wouldn't say. In fact the temperature
is above the average in season.
Look!
For me this is a polar cold!
Even doesn't seem so!
Excuse me.
Is icily!
Cat's egg! I'm gonna scoff it!
What do you say?
You are stupid? It's unsafe!
- Unsafe?
- How do you imagine a cat lays an egg?
So if cats begin to make eggs,
wont take long as they become...
I have told you, sir, that dry food was
predicting to have strong side effects...
Crisps it's corruption of cats.
It's the way that's going to lead us
to power and to light!
What are you doing here yet?
We are waiting for orders, Your Holiness!
Our orders were given!
Give me the report!
Zorba, what are you playing?
What do you have there?
Come on, show me.
What's happening?
What do you try to tell me?
Wait, let me think.
Egg...
You want to eat it!
Egg... in throat!
I didn't know you were so funny!
I have good news! I discovered how
long an seagull egg should be hatched.
How long?
Only 20 days!
For all heavens cats! An eternity!
Hi!
What are you doing on the ground?
I thought I saw... Ciao, how are you?
Good, and you? I have not seen you yet.
Well, you know, I'm a busy cat,
I have a lot of things to do.
Excuse me, but now
I have to go, I'm sorry.
See you in a few days.
Zorba, it is true what they meows around?
Is that true, that you are
an hatching seagull egg?
An egg? What egg?
You hear, what that cats came up with!
I simply stayed in home,
because I had fever.
Hideously cold.
- Not!
- What happened?
What have I done?
- What you said?
- Nothing.
Excuse me, Bubulina, but I'm busy,
you don't know how busy!
I am very busy!
You are sure that you okay?
You need something?
- No! I feel very good!
- Bye!
Mom, mom, I'm hungry!
So was born a cat-chick.
We have to go to the Great Rat.
- HUNGRY!
- Yes, yes, alright.
Now I will bring you...
What bring to you?
- What do you eat?
- Papa, papa, papa!
Here is your "papa".
It's good, isn't it?
I want papa!
I go to see what I can find.
Now!
But what if it will grow?
Puss-puss... Puss-puss...
It comes...
Just a bit more, closer...
Mom, I'm hungry!
I want papa!
Good papa!
Mom, I'm hungry!
Look at him, bulging one is adapting!
I'm so sleepy, mommy!
Listen, baby, I am sorry,
but I am not your mom.
But yeah, sure you are!
You're the mom, who is
the best on the world.
Zorba, where are you?
Mom, where am I?
Here you are? You keep me company.
I want to change ground in pots.
I need a small vessel for those violets.
Where I left it then?
Well well!
Zorba, you're naughty!
What's wrong today?
What are you doing, do you want
to break also the another?
What's wrong, Zorba, you feel bad?
I understood, buster,
it's time of your crunching.
Ok then, I bring you now.
Stay here quietly, I will back soon.
Here you are!
Help!
Help, mom!
They wanted to eat me, mommy.
We eating a baby? What an idea!
No, know that we
are vegetarians, lady!
Lady?
No, I was wrong.
Anyway have a lovely baby!
I'm sure it becomes
a big and beautiful cat.
There's no a cat, it's a seagull chick.
Exactly, it's what I always say.
Seagull chicks are the most beautiful.
All would like to have one.
Yes. Be seagulls.
Have a good day, madam.
And you too, mommy chick, bye.
You are the strongest mom at the world!
Let's go home. Go.
I have to find a safer place for you.
A cat that hatches...
Pure madness, Your Majesty!
Uncontrolled madness.
Insanity.
If the cats lost their wits,
it is great news for us.
We give them a memorable lesson.
What are you still doing here?
- We...
- Go back and watch every his move!
Fast, faster! Forward! March!
Look what nice pack Zorba
brought for us!
Congratulations, kid!
It's a really very nice chicken.
Is horrible!
Don't you think, he looks
a bit like Zorba?
You have even the same eyes.
How much weighs little one?
How do I know?
I'm not his mom!
Who are they, mom?
Mama! You heard, he called you "mama".
How tender chick!
They are my friends
and I say you, that you will
stay here until'll be bigger.
As you wish, mom!
"As you wish, mom!"
What is his name?
Already... do not know.
- I didn't think...
- You have to give him a name.
But first we need to find
out if it's boy or girl.
An letter "S".
Spice... Spirala...
Susan... Sex...
Unfortunately encyclopedia doesn't say,
how to determine the sex of seagulls.
Look at "seabirds".
Nation of birds, birds of sea.
Is needed to check a sea wolf
or better, a sea cat.
Maybe someone specializes in
chickens, like Wind Rose.
That's what I said, Wind Rose.
When will you stop draw out
meowing from my mouth?
- Wind Rose!
- Welcome to the port, sailor!
For thousand marinated anchovies!
My friends!
We must talk with you!
Let me anchor. I go to you right away.
Mom, I'm hungry!
What to do in such cases?
Flies! Catch as many flies as you can!
For a soul of all insane scomber!
The thing certain is serious!
Grow a seagull chick?
You've kinda messed up!
But there is a solution:
take it back to Zorbas house,
leave it to letting his owner to find it
and let she think about how to grow it.
It seems very reasonable.
It's true.
- However...
- I don't know, it doesn't convince me.
- And what do you say, Zorba?
- Me?
I believe that...
How good it is to be a cat!
Okay, I understand. Let me see.
- So?
- So, for the wings of flying fish!
It is a seagull femele. It is a girl.
Congratulations, youngster.
Is ugly. That chicken has a brain.
It's a horribly horrible girl.
Yes, kid, it's true.
but one day this lady here
will lay so many eggs
as many hairs on your
tail you have, slicker.
What a yucky!
Okey, now we can give her a name.
- "Horriblea".
- Small Ball!
What you say about "Snowball"?
What a name! It's better with "Mizi".
Minu.
- Princess!
- Paniodina!
Gosh, we even some fun!
We make a big mistake,
all these are names for cats.
- Instead...
- I'm a cat!
I found! I found!
I thought, as the seagulls was
lucky to get under our protection,
we might call her Lucky.
I am ready to meow!
For the liver of hake, it's
a very beautiful name!
Lucky, yes, it's a very
beautiful cat name!
~ We are cats ~
~ We are we ~
~ How good to us! ~
~ On the streets, we
happy, meeting our friends ~
~ How are you? ~
~ The problems, what we have on our heads ~
~ Are disappearing here ~
~ On the street, all
together we feel so good ~
~ I am a tomcat among tomcats ~
~ I am proud and satisfied,
what more do you want? ~
~ We are cats... ~
~ With friends and with the mom ~
~ Everyone is calling me ~
~ I am here! ~
~ Everything is beautiful,
there's nothing bad ~
~ I want to do everything and always say "yes" ~
~ We are cats, we are we ~
Good, Bubulina, I open for you.
You will get out of here with
your meowing when I hit your head!
Dad, come, we must give
food that cats!
Cats? What cats?
Come on, let's go!
- How is cat-chicken?
- Learns, Your Rattness.
And grow?
Yes, Your Rattness, it becames rounder.
Excellent!
Do not you think it's time
to move your plan to action, sir?
Yeah, sure.
I want rats guarding
every corner of the city.
Today we eat a good sausage of a chicken!
Good, isn't it?
I think they was very hungry.
I would call the girl.
- Fishes...
- Come on, Lucky.
Come to eat.
Look, dad.
What bird is it? A pigeon?
When they are so small, I do not know.
Surely however it sounds strange.
Look here, little one. You like?
Isn't that nice, dad?
- Yes. Now we go home.
- Bye, kitties!
Supercat arrives, strikes the right side,
crushes all opponents...
Fifi hits of the center,
from left, from center...
Let me play too from time to time.
It is mine!
- It's not yours, it's mine!
- Yes, I have it!
It's mine, I got it from Zorba!
What is happening here?
- She started!
- He did!
I do not care who started!
With a bundle Lucky is playing. You
surprise me much with your behavior, son.
You're older than her.
You argue with her for a bundle
when you're big enough to hunt rats?
Small Ball, if you want to play more, I...
I do not care about your stupid game!
It's easy to be good, sister,
when the adults are crazy about you!
- Small Ball, but I...
- You what, Horriblea?
Do you know why Zorba and others spoil you?
- Because they love me?
- No!
Because they want you to
be fat when they eat you!
It's not a true! They would never do that!
Of course yes, cats eat birds!
But I am a cat!
Yes, and where are your whiskers?
And claws?
And tail? You're not a cat!
You are a bird just like them!
I got him!
...to do not forget all...
- 6 times 7 equals 44.
- 42!
...forget all when rain
falls in love with twilight.
- 8 times 3... 24.
- Bravo!
You know what, all cat of our
friends seem so stupid.
They are thinking always about food,
how to split it between them.
And I'm like that for you?
Sometimes yes.
And sometimes not.
You are... different.
In fact, you are different too.
- You...
- Yes, I am different.
because I was lucky to meet two people
who understand that every being
has his soul, thoughts,
feelings...
Exactly what I wanted to talk with you about.
I have... many feelings.
Very many.
But the most important... is that one,
what I feel when I am close
to someone, who I...
Who you...?
...who I... wish... wish so much...
- Come quickly to the museum!
- Why?
Something terrible happened!
Lucky ran away!
Who have seen her as last?
I have.
She was arguing for a bundle with Small Ball.
I finished it.
Then the last one who seen her is Small Ball.
Small Ball, what happened?
I... don't know...
She was so... I didn't want...
I really didn't want!
But I fell into anger.
- And then...
- Then?
I've said you want to eat her.
Go, we have to find her! Hurry!
~ I'm not a cat ~
~ Who am I? ~
~ Me, my mother and my friends
was the happiest cats ~
~ From the street ~
~ But the celebration was ended ~
~ And I was left with just a lie ~
~ A lie ~
~ I'm not a cat ~
~ Who am I? ~
~ I wished to that life ~
~ Would never ended, just was my life! ~
~ Was beautiful, was perfect ~
~ But why did you tell me a lie? ~
~ A lie ~
~ I'm not a cat ~
~ Who am I? ~
Bravo, beautiful show!
- Now come with us!
- No!
I do not know, really do not know!
Curiosity killed the cat...
An terrible thing!
An awfuly terrible thing!
What is it, Small Ball?
Let attack them directly in
the canal and destroy them!
In due time. I respect your courage, but...
In this case we must act craftily.
Craftily military, strategy, tactics,
ocular, diversion...
Right, but how?
Please, Secretary. I am just
trying to understand...
- I found!
- What, Diderot?
The solution!
The encyclopedia is suggesting
it, in the 13th volume,
a letter "H" from "Homer".
- What is that?
- A great poet of antiquity.
In his work, "Iliad", is the
solution to our problem.
In other words?
Look!
Not bad!
Really not bad!
I do not want to be pessimistic,
but there is few of us.
This is a war, all cats in the
city will bring their contribution.
Quickly, we have no time to lose!
Come back here, cat thief!
Why always me?
Thank you, Bubulina, you're great!
It's nothing, Diderot.
I just did my duty.
If you will see him,
pass greetings to Zorba
Next!
Is not fair, grandpa!
I want to come too!
Negative, my boy.
That's the most dangerous action
that we, cats, ever tried!
Females and kittens should stay home.
I'm not kitten! I am big, even
you've said that I am big!
Enough! Orders are orders!
You are bad! You are
bad and not fair!
Calm down.
Do you think he is big enough?
Winds Rose does!
- When action takes place?
- Tonight!
We will give a hard time those canal rats!
~ We are rats ~
~ No one, nobody ~
~ We circulate alone in the dark night ~
His Majesty, the Great Rat
~ The moment, what we are
waiting for, will arrive ~
~ Soon that entire city will be ours ~
Subject rats of all canals
For a long time our nation has grown in numbers
in importance as well as in weight.
Rats, see this chick?
It was raised by cats.
~ We hate cats, just a little longer
and they go away from here ~
And this demonstrates that
now the cats have lost their reason.
~ We come out from canals ~
~ On the top ~
~ We will win and nothing's gonna stop us ~
~ The world is ours at last ~
~ For us nothing is frightening ~
But before we go outside,
Let's celebrate with scoffing juicy... chicken!
No!
Leave her alone!
Leave her right now!
Keep away from her!
Bring me here that grub!
Leave me!
Small Ball!
Shut up, chicken sausages!
Be respectful with her, understand?
She is a cat!
And I'm Snow White!
Kill him!
Great Rat!
Your Highness, historical news!
Cats surrendered!
As a sign of peace sent a gift!
Pull on!
Bring him here to taste it.
Stuff your belly!
Come out, rats!
Today should be a great day,
but it's so big triumph
that today it's a glorious day!
A glorious day for us!
What are you waiting for, herds of rabbits?
Attack!
Tomcat, I advise you to be
careful with these claws
Better you watch out for your neck.
Release my friends!
- You can't.
- No?
You can... Release the grub!
Good. And the chick.
Quickly, let's all get out of here!
With strength ahead!
Throw them out.
How dare you spit on me?
Still thinking about what
Small Ball said to you, huh?
Yes.
And you're sad.
You should know, that he said something true
and something false.
It's true that cats eat birds,
it's part of their nature.
But we could never eat you,
because we love you and
we love you ever so much more
just because you're different than us.
I don't want to be different from you.
I want to be a cat!
We are pleased and proud
that you want to be like us.
But we are more proud since
you're a beautiful seagull.
And someday you'll be able to fly
free in the sky just like your mom.
Brawo, youngster copes with words.
- It's eminent cat.
- Talk like from a book.
So you're not my real mom?
Are you, Zorba?
No, Lucky. Your mother was
a young and brave seagull.
She was gracile, elegant, noble
like all creatures who can fly.
But I'm afraid to fly!
You don't need to fear
of your natural instincts.
I promise that when you will
be ready, I'll be close.
I love you, Zorba.
I love you all.
Movement of pressure points
A and B must be accelerated.
Expand C node.
Expand D node.
Raising point E.
Leveling point F.
30 beats per minute.
Points A and B raised to chest.
And departure...
I fell.
Never mind, Lucky, calm down.
Nobody flies at first attempt.
Let's try again.
I'm not good at anything!
We reached 21 trial.
I fail to understand!
I studied Leonardo Da Vinci's machine
until the smallest details.
I strictly kept instructions, but...
Anyway done for now.
If we continue to failures,
Lucky never gonna fly.
Why do not we try with a volunteer?
Volunteer?
How great is our Secretary!
This is what I like, awake
heart and brave brain.
Help! But why all me?
Obvious, cause you're the lightest,
most agile and more aerodynamic.
Start
I rise up!
- Hang on, young one!
- Fly!
I rise up!
Compass went crazy.
The waves were as tall as buildings.
The storm had already lasted five long days
and I didn't know if we was going
towards the ground or on the deep sea.
So what did you do?
All crew began to cry and pray.
But right then the steersman saw three seagulls.
For barracuda teeth!
Those seagulls were flying towards ground.
Let's follow them and we are saved!
You mean seagulls flies
in the midst of the storm?
For the scared crampfish! Birds are
the most robust in the universe!
Cool... You are cool!
- It seems she wants to fly.
- I know, we've tried in all ways.
I exhausted all flying items, plane and wings.
It is absolutely the first time,
when encyclopedia disappoints me.
Perhaps she lived with us too long
and now she can't anymore...
For the swordfish, not to say foolishness!
It's a seagull and seagulls fly!
I promised her mother that she's
gonna fly. And she is gonna fly.
Let try make her fly from
a very, very high place.
I found, from belfry!
We need to get up there,
where are the bells.
No, youngster, it's not possible.
It's closed, it's not possible
for us, cats, to reach up there.
We must consult someone who
is not part of the animal world.
- Who could that be?
- It would be... human beings.
Excluded!
Speaking people language
is absolutely forbidden!
You have no idea, what would
people make with speaking cats.
Would close immediately in a cage.
Yes, and then do their stupid medical exams.
Would put it in a zoo
and use in circuses,
for all to see and laugh at him.
You're right. I am convinced that most people
are not yet able to accept the idea
that different being can be intelligent
and, eventually, could be smarter than them.
And even if, assuming we want to miaow with man,
- who do you think would...
- My captain is a good person.
He's a sailor, he has nothing
to do with flight, with air.
What about humans from fishing?
Yeah, right, like that which gaves
the Secretary shoot in ass.
No, he is absolutely unworthy of this mission.
Could it be your human, Zorba?
No, my heart suffers.
But I can not talk to him.
I would lose my domestic human.
In fact it would require
a truly superior human.
Actually we need even more special one.
Someone who understands that
all beings in the world
have a soul, thoughts and feelings.
I know someone like that.
I knew I do wrong if I let you go in.
What do you want to do?
Do not move, be quiet and watch.
But Zorba, it's forbidden!
- Ciao, Nina.
- Where did you put my friends?
- How can you speak?
- Everything is possible in a dream.
- Are you in a dream?
- Yes, but I want to talk about something real.
There is a seagull who
needs to fly, but fails.
- I will help him.
- Yes.
When you wake up, you have to take
us to the highest building in town,
Belfry of St. Michael.
Doors are locked up and
we do not know how to enter.
Do not worry, sir cat.
Dad occasionally go up there at night
to think, through a gate what is always open.
Thank you, Nina. See you later.
Wait!
What's your name?
Zorba, is that you?
Cat from a dream! Bubulina, you
understand what I say too?
Just as I've always suspected.
Come quickly, but carefully.
Do not wake up my dad.
How big you have grown!
She is Nina.
She wants to help you, Lucky.
Come here, little one!
I am your friend.
I am scared, mom.
Lucky, I am not your mom.
I am scared... dad.
But you want to fly, don't you?
Yes.
Look, you can see a yard where you're born.
And there is the Diderot's museum.
I am so scared!
Courage, seagull!
I know you're scared, I haven't
a courage to look down.
Don't forget that you have wings,
and who has wings, isn't afraid of heights,
and any obstacle what he can meet.
If you have wings, nothing can stop you.
You can fly to up there, to the moon!
Fly, little seagull, fly!
Do it for us, cats. I have never flown!
Be the first flying cat!
I love you, Zorba!
Me too, Lucky.
- Courage!
- Fly!
Fly, little seagull!
Majesty! Cat's daughter flies!
What's the big deal?
We, rats, fly thousands of centuries!
Crazy idiot!
~ My feet do not touch anymore ~
~ I am flying in blue ~
~ It's strange and beautiful to look from here ~
~ And see houses so much small ~
~ The world is different from up here ~
~ It has no barriers anymore ~
~ And, all my friends ~
~ I owe it to you ~
I am FLYING!
~ I am flying, I would never have believed ~
- Goodbye, Zorba.
- Goodbye, Lucky.
~ Look at me! ~
Bye, sister!
~ Look at me, it seems a play to fly so ~
~ Look at me, it seems a play ~
~ Now I know where is my place,
and the sky is my place ~
~ And these wings, I feel
it now, are my freedom ~
~ Distant sky, blue ocean ~
~ Are already calling me ~
~ That's my life and now
I am getting to know my destiny ~
~ I am flying, I would never have believed ~
~ I am flying, I would never have hoped ~
~ I am flying ~
~ Look at me! ~
~ Look at me, it seems a play to fly so ~