I am in luck
This does not mean that I'm superstitious,
but I try not to pass
under a ladder
I'm not afraid of damage or the evil eye
not believe in luck, and April 1
But I try to follow all the rules
When I lie down in bed,
put on the window sill
rabbit's foot
When I find quatrefoil
clover, a lucky day
There are 13 reasons why
I do
I never was afraid of witches
and, therefore, declare
I feel great
and do not complain about health
Why should I
tempt fate?
I never knew the evil eye,
He does not scare me
Still do not have anything
against a horseshoe over the door
I do not believe in mystical forces
it's all nonsense
Still keeping my fingers
criss-cross
make a wish when
I see a shooting star
never eat oysters
if the month has no letter "P"
ever caught a ladybug,
just let her
There are 13 reasons why
I do
can not dance
a barrel-organ
Podberesh rusty pin -
wife will be with a double chin
not get a light threesome.
Make a circle, knock on wood
On the walk be careful -
Never comes on crack
Children with a skipping rope - good luck
But if they drop the rope ...
I can go on the list
All Day
Rope, horoscope, rusty
pins, double chins
whole lot more
such as wedding rings
wedding rings.
I see myself
sad and dreamy
in a wedding dress
This does not mean that I'm superstitious,
But I see no harm if
look in mart
cut off the petals of daisies
and wonder just how very
Believe it or not, but I'm ready
everything
Even if I fall in love
PARIS BEAUTY
Miss Williams.
-Sign.
-Five minutes before leaving.
-Oh, well, thank you.
-Good.
Hap, here is your shirt.
Thank you, Candy.
-Duc, come in for a minute.
Yes.
Do you think this makeup will suit?
-Come on already.
-Wait, wait. Come here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the invisible man!
-Hap, you stop?
-Oh, you poor thing.
I want a little paint
your life is gray.
"You and drove me into this life.
-Who feeds us.
I read that wrote about us
Miami Post?
"Hap Snyder
world-famous clown
represents the Paris beauties
extravagant room full of
vivid scenes and uncontrollable laughter. "
-This is our advertising.
-What is the difference?
It's a newspaper?
Live, stupid, live.
-I wish I was like you ...
So, come for a visit.
Why should I have been
off Broadway
and come to this Klembeyk?
Great!
I have to tell everyone.
He wants to know why he
arrived in Klembeyk ...
-Wait a minute.
-Have you heard?
-Duc wants to know -
-Go performance.
"You do not know?
-I do not say.
He does not know why.
And we now know.
No work, he did not believe it.
But you believed in him.
You thought he had talent?
Glad to see you.
What Klembeyk already forgotten?
I found you in the gutter
and took in his show.
Out of the ditch in such a show -
small progress.
Duc, warn
do not irritate me.
It's a theater, or flop?
Again, no water.
Hey, Broadway, let's.
And one more thing.
Your number begins to stall.
Add tempo, dynamics.
Well, you know.
-Hap, stop.
-What is it?
Whistle in the dressing room -
a bad omen.
Two months into show business,
and knows all the rules.
-You yourself told me this.
-Listen to what else to say.
You're too talented,
to be so superstitious.
Beautiful face, smile,
figure ...
I wrote your name
on the bill, see?
Yes ...
"Yes," said she, too, is beautiful.
Why do you not an island on the stage?
Soon, your exit.
"We are already going.
-Lightning is not buttoned ...
-I will help you.
No, do not.
Herself.
Come on, baby.
Go!
That's it. Without using their hands.
Come on, baby.
This is an old trick.
How's the audience?
An almost empty hall, Hap.
-Do not pay attention.
"But they're asleep.
Wait, now I'll go.
I am their wake.
Women!
Men, horrible man
used to be said and am saying now
What do I think about men -
You can write a book
happy girl,
which does not promise in marriage
girls, you head in the clouds
Who likes this?
Who needs it?
They throw you
with song and dance
they throw you for the sake
another pair of pants
Men such a nose
like a chicken that
rummaging through garbage
And believe me, sir,
so all men,
up to the President
Love, horrible word
Show me this darling,
and I ask him
main thing is not looks,
a checkbook
Do not believe promises -
Do as Mom says
doubt everything
Men
Ah, women.
Do not forget - a woman
supports man
in troubles, hardships
and trials.
That is, in fact, from what
Man freed,
if he is a bachelor.
What do you think about this?
You a little, but you guys are strong.
Correctly.
-Stunning success.
-The audience simply lies.
Men bloodthirsty men
History says this
such as Bluebeard
with axes and knives
Look what they did
with their wives
Ladies, think about the ladies
poisoned her lovers poison
Lucrezia Borgia
You are beautiful
She prepared a drink
man drank
and became a board
Men - devils from hell
example Henry VIII
married at six or seven
And when killed them
beheaded him
Hey, hey, sing and dance
There is always a skirt for
anyone who wears pants
And when they pass by
In them there is something
and I can not live without them
I need a beautiful lady
I lost my head
I want all the men at once
For God's sake, give me a man
I think that's terrific.
You're the only one who thinks so
because they do not pay for the ticket.
We came to say
that we should get out
bye, bye
Thank you straight from the heart
until the curtain falls.
for your loud ovation.
And the curtain falls
Excuse us, we must
leaving
O-la-la,
You were great
But think about other cities,
where waiting for our jokes and songs
Here's a kiss
beauties of Paris
I said goodbye and kiss you
and you and you and you ...
Six, seven, eight,
nine, ten, eleven ...
"What's wrong with you?
-In Hall 13 spectators.
No time for superstitions.
Back, back.
Professor!
I am filled with emotion when
I look and see how -
Lower the screen.
- leave me.
I will not leave you, friends
On - because I -
Sorry. Lu. Louis,
What are you doing?
Getting a movie.
Louis, what do you do
too early, Lou!
You turn on the projector?
Oh, no.
We both can not lay an egg.
Well jokes.
I thought they set their sights on me.
Get him off the stage!
I will not leave you, because -
What's happening?
Where the director? Where is he?
Have you seen?
Where stagehands,
What do they do?
I submit to the court. This is the worst show.
Get out of my theater.
What are you talking about?
We are the stars. Love us.
-The audience I have here.
-Here's your money.
I found a room for the night.
Need to buy tickets.
Bus in 15 minutes.
We can handle wave at him.
"What's with our money?
-A funny thing has turned out.
"What?"
-I caught the lenders.
"And you've got left?
Empty-pockets.
So we are now on the rocks?
It's not so bad.
I have something come up.
Above his head.
The clouds blue sky.
Look cheerful.
We are hungry, and you
feed us with songs.
Someday we will laugh
on it. Is that right?
Honey, do you hold your own.
There are many places to go.
You know, wherever I want?
Right here.
"Anton's Restaurant."
Not bad.
We have nothing but talent
but there is some sort of crook
comes over his name
neon signs.
"Good evening, Mr. Mahoney.
"Good morning, Bonnie.
How-ever?
Yes, please.
Oh, look who it is.
Parisian beauty.
Mr. Snyder is
very funny show,
that I have ever seen.
-Thank you, Mr. Mahoney.
-Glad you enjoyed it.
Like it? Yes, I'm shocked!
You are all lovely.
Where will you serve
next week?
-If it is near -
-This is your neighborhood?
-12 Years here I serve.
-Come on.
Mahoney, show me a favor.
Great service.
-You're welcome, Mr. Snyder.
-Good.
Now I'll take their
artists in the hotel across the road.
And we will show a little trick.
When I shout to you,
We will arrest you.
Arrest you?
I can not.
But I really need.
I beg of you.
Arrest us.
Just arrest.
It's not too
big favor for a friend?
But when I arrest you
and will lead to the site,
what I'm messing around with you?
Plot? Charge?
You just do not overdo it
Mahoney.
This is a trick. Joke. Do you understand?
When we come out of the hotel
You release us.
-You do it?
"Of course.
Thank you, Mahoney,
You are a true friend.
-Are you okay?
"Do not worry.
I invite you all to dinner.
-Dining.
-Come on, guys, get ready.
Restaurant, Anton!
-Are you crazy?
No time for questions.
You're hungry?
And what about money?
We will arrange Mahoney
small performance.
You took a troupe of police?
In some ways, yes. Come on.
Well, well. Keep your distance.
Elegant dinner.
And like all tasty, yes?
Hey, France, your guys will be able to
play "Reg-Half 1912 street"?
Take the card.
Thank you.
One on hand.
Will order dessert?
Naturally.
-What are we going?
-We will see.
I'll be cookies "Alaska."
-How does it taste?
-Sensational.
Two dollars.
But all the same?
Can order a pair.
-Cookie "Alaska."
-Two servings.
-Choose?
-Crepes Suzette.
"And me too.
Jacques.
Two cookies "Alaska"
and twice with pancakes.
Crepes Suzette with us
tasty and holodnenkie.
That is life.
I said all I will build?
This is the first time
you not mistaken.
I have a minute.
Excuse me. Sorry.
Excuse me, please.
-There is no thoroughfare.
-Nothing, baby.
Cute, right? How you?
Why did you not tell him anything?
I'm not familiar with it.
Oh, I was greeted with illumination.
-Here I am.
-Are you okay?
Fear not, Mahoney series.
Ok, Mahoney.
Get in the car, I change you.
Nothing, Elmer, I am for you otdezhuryu.
It's kind of an evening stroll.
Stop fooling around
and sit in the car.
Sergeant, I really do not want to -
-Fast in the car!
Yes, sir.
How much should chefs
to cook it all.
France, the remains can be wrapped?
I'll take them to the dog.
You will take away a dog
cookies "Alaska"?
Yes. I have a husky.
Funny. Funny!
The table, he is a genius.
-I told you, sensationally.
-Fascinating.
-When you're done, here's your check.
-One moment.
$ 98 40 cents.
Absolutely.
Anton.
How do you say in French:
"I have no money.
I can not pay the check?
I have no money.
That is, you can not pay.
-It can happen to anyone.
"I do not understand.
Then I say easier.
I'm broke. Penniless.
I have no money.
-I need to call.
-This is a fraud. Theft.
-I'll call the police.
"What do you say?
-I said I'll call the police.
"Do not bother. I myself will call.
Hap, you're crazy?
Wait. I understood everything.
Mahoney!
Sorry to bother again.
Do not spoil our reputation.
Let's settle in another way.
None. You want the police,
and I'll call the police.
-Police!
-Do not make unnecessary problems.
Take him away.
-Come with me.
-Police!
Do not listen to him!
Wait a minute.
Give me a glass of water.
Police.
Take him away!
-Please.
-Here it is. Hurry, please.
This is not Mahoney.
-What is the problem?
-Arrest him.
The officer, make your case.
Mahoney -
Remove from my hands.
I have my own police.
Mahoney - I agreed.
You know Mahoney?
-In the other door.
"What's with the door -?
-Come in, you interfere.
-Keep your hands off.
All right, all right.
This did not work for the artist.
I, Doug McGee, play
front compartment with broccoli.
That's all you and your ideas.
I also do not like it here,
but this is the most honest
way to pay.
-Would you prefer jail?
Yes.
George, come on.
The menu does not match -
Do not stand idle!
Will not rest until
run for every penny.
Thieves! SCAM!
Husky!
-So give him a mop.
"And his head in a bucket.
Dishes, utensils!
For what we are given arm?
Why not stop
complain?
Another day of work, and the bill is paid.
Finally, let us themselves.
"And where?
Yes, where?
Snyder, a telegram.
-Thank you. I was waiting for her.
-From whom?
I sent a letter to the owner
Hotel Max Briskin.
We have received an invitation.
Hap Snyder and Company
straight from the world famous
Hotel Tropical Palms
-Where do we clean up?
-Perhaps you need money?
I have asked to send a hundred.
I even offered to share in the show.
Listen. "I'm sorry, but this letter
I never got it. Max Briskin. "
"I'm sorry, but this letter
I never got it. "
What to do.
I give up.
-We would have lunch.
-Who is able to eat?
I never thought that
received from him like that.
Get some fresh air.
Cheer up, Hap.
I do not understand how Max
could act
after I had
many times he took a loan.
Hap may not be worth
offer him a share of the show?
-What is the show?
Yes, all is well.
Well, sorry, did not work.
But you learned to haggle.
At this time we lost.
How can you say that?
Hap Snyder
when I came to the show
You said that these
artists never give up.
Now is exactly the same case.
But we are not defeated.
You know what I say?
This girl was a great artist,
than any of you ..
You're right, baby.
For what?
"You kissed me on the left ear.
-So what?
And I have to kiss
you to answer
and it will be disaster
for many years.
Those who have much to say
of happiness
it is always very small.
no money in their pockets -
assume nothing
played all the time,
And without bread
With each passing day
our sufferings grow
But the actor does not know the word "death"
right
Great Expectations,
great expectations
never played in the palaces
Never played at festivals
Great Expectations,
great expectations
There were no photos
in Sunday newspapers
We are tired of dragging suitcases
When George Cohen
began to show business
That's what the Yankees said this:
"Smile while you can,
until the curtain falls,
even if you die "
and whether the show
failed if,
We agree with the point of view
Cohen.
And all our hopes
come true
Great Expectations,
great expectations
There were large orchestras
It was just a piano
Great Expectations,
great expectations
Never heard about yourself
"Sister, you're famous"
wonder how it -
feel like a star?
Listen
to start reserve
ticket to Hoboken
Five times a day of the show
Then break
and all again in a circle
Back to the old Broadway
And so the days
Waiting for an agent, while coming.
and all your great hope
come true
and bad and good times
wait patiently on themselves
and your great, great expectations
come true
My statue! Peel off the statue!
Bumbling fools!
"We did not get destroyed the statue.
-Sorry.
Vandals!
Killer!
-All right.
Just a little glue ...
"You pay for the statue!
-Go away.
You will stay here
and work out every penny!
Every penny!
Remember this moonlit night,
As the moon shines
doing something this evening
Best for Love
Tell the birds in the trees
to sing louder
Let flowers spread
scent of love
This is a ballad for the first act.
Yes, lovely room.
But the main theme,
I have not finished it yet.
Will something like this.
me luck
Destiny works for me
Nothing will knock me down
No
Because I am lucky
This is a quick, bright room.
For the final.
Well, Dick, good.
You wrote a great script.
May be the best.
But who knows about it,
if not a producer?
What do you mean?
I'll be a producer.
Fine.
I'll no longer needed.
You're my agent or what?
I've had more hits
on Broadway than anyone else.
I wrote two successful shows,
and you know it.
Dick, I agree, you know
as the author of hits,
but for the money bags,
Dick Carson name means nothing.
Dick Carson!
Living Mr. Carson.
You need anything?
No, no. I just - yes.
If you put on a show,
may find a role for me?
I'm sorry, but
Casting has not yet started.
"You could not wait in the lobby -?
-You think I'm just a maid.
I would first and thought.
I made a mistake?
I am artist.
Just from the tour
I Paris beauty.
Flo Neely.
Heard of it?
Play, sing, dance.
-I'll show you.
-Wait a minute, young lady.
See.
This is probably a new service at the hotel.
Instead of TV
sing and play in the rooms.
If you remove the carpet,
will hear the dance.
I'm still juggling.
Poor girl.
It should not be dangerous,
otherwise she would not be allowed to work.
Come down from heaven to earth.
Let's give up the script
Lenu and Bartlitu.
They have twice made
hits for us.
hits for himself.
This is my script
and my score.
And this is my success
or my failure.
Nothing can stop me.
-There is a problem.
-What?
-Money.
"Only what I hear.
Y Lena and Bartlita they are,
and you do not.
Who do you give money?
Where is this angel?
Hi, angel.
Hello, dear.
I interrupted your conversation?
Yes, yes, of course.
In the middle of it. Come on.
Get to know this is my agent,
Mr. Tommy Arthur.
This is Miss Lorraine Teyr.
-Hello, Mr. Arthur.
-Hello.
Her father, Otis Teyr.
The one who has 42
oil wells?
Forty-four.
Morning has two more.
Perhaps he had expected this, but
hardly hoped for twins.
Dick so much about you said that
I think we already know.
He said that without you nowhere.
I'm afraid it will be so this time,
Miss Teyr if -
If my father did not finance
show that Dick wrote?
-Well ...
-This is a good chance, Mr. Arthur.
A very good chance.
I feel that I was alone.
Glad to meet you, Miss Teyr.
You know, Dick - a talented guy.
-Really talented.
-I think so too.
Goodbye, Mr. Arthur.
Yes, good-bye, Tommy.
See ya.
Expensive?
-There is great news.
-Yes? What?
I told my father about the show
and he is interested.
Excellent. If he likes it,
it will work.
On Friday evening, my father
would be welcome.
on the day of birth.
The ideal case to
You play their numbers.
Elegant idea.
All together, all happy
all the fun.
-I do not know how to thank you.
-Do you know?
I mean, what do you
a true friend.
Thank you and on this one.
What is it?
From my side it was
not entirely disinterested.
It is my understanding that the show Carson -
good investment.
Yes, for my father.
But I'm not a player like him.
Come on, I clarified the picture.
Your father was a wealthy man,
and he has a big business.
As you said, he is a player.
But not only that.
He has a reputation for winning.
He chose my show,
because it is luck.
Because it is a victory.
And not because you
chose me.
Understand?
Most have nothing to add.
-That is just business?
-Oh, no, just -
Not a very good feeling,
when you realize that you
want to use.
As long as you have not used,
There is no reason
upset.
"You do not worry, Dick?
No, Lorraine.
Just like when all
cards thrown on the table.
Of course, dear. But this does not mean
you have to play patience.
Sure, I'm sure.
I tell you who it is.
Dick Carson.
The famous composer?
Yes.
-The guy that wrote hits?
-In room 610.
He composes a new show
and is going to produce myself.
-Casting is not it?
-No.
Understand what that means?
Show. Broadway show.
"And we could participate in it.
-Our first real success.
-I bet it is our good fortune.
-What are you all talking about?
-If you would just talk to him.
"He is not so easy to talk to.
I tried to arrange it
audition
and it seemed to me that he
to me than anything cast.
Machine Mr. Carson.
I just got lucky.
Good kitty.
Well, all -
Fine.
-Are you okay, sir?
Yes. All is well.
-Are you okay, ma'am?
Yes, okay.
I'm afraid I'll have to send
you home in a taxi.
-I now call.
-Thank you.
-This is very bad.
-Yeah.
How funny
She did not even notice.
Did not happen anything
can not be corrected for the money.
It always happens.
-Behind the wheel was a woman?
No, a woman passenger.
Believe me, it's much worse.
How long will the repair?
-A couple of days.
-A couple of days?
I better call a taxi.
I've got back to the hotel.
Take my car.
I then take away.
Thank you.
Not this one.
All safe.
Listen, I just remembered -
Does not look very,
but runs like a dream.
Come here, folks.
Read his past, present
and the future of the gypsy-fortune-teller.
"She sees everything - how are you?
-Fine.
Two coins?
Right on you.
People, this is the place.
Come here, here
happiness for everyone.
Be attentive, my child.
You have a time of great
opportunities.
you on the edge of adventure.
Soon to you will be
a mysterious stranger.
stranger to hold you
on your fate to luck.
Mysterious Stranger.
I?
Why?
Why what?
-What have I?
"You always walk on the streets
just such a manner?
I just hopped between the cracks.
Between the cracks?
Well, you know, jump through the crack,
to escape hell. "
-Oh, yeah.
-This is just silly superstition.
-I do not take it seriously.
And black cats do not believe me?
You saw how I went
from your hotel?
-I was, so to speak, within reach.
-Oh my God.
You know, you are dangerous to
traffic.
Well, it certainly was not my fault.
If you look back,
where you go,
but not where I go -
By the way, where did you go?
I'm going back to the hotel.
Let us then'll drop.
No, thank you very much.
You're very kind.
Oh, nothing. Just when you
in the car, I was safe.
Do not worry, you too
will be safe.
I'm a little late.
Do you live in the hotel?
Yes.
On vacation here?
No, I work.
And where is work?
In the hotel.
Live in a hotel
and work there?
Yes.
What do you do?
Well, now I'm
I work in the kitchen.
There is nothing wrong
work in the kitchen.
No, I do not think so.
Just a little bit surprised -
You do not look like a girl
which works in the kitchen.
And what do you say about yourself?
You're also not found
for auto mechanics.
But you're an auto mechanic.
Yes.
And one of the best.
By the way what's your name?
Williams. Candy Williams.
Candy Williams?
I like it.
It is beautiful here, right?
I never imagined
how beautiful Miami.
And even more beautiful at night.
I can imagine.
Tell me, how much you
depart from kitchenware -?
When do the job?
At nine in the evening.
We finish about the same.
This is what I thought -
If we encounter such
in an unusual way -
this is destiny.
It would be good for us
meet tonight.
Dinner, dancing,
have fun.
No, I do not think that happens.
I hardly know you.
You are practically a stranger.
You are the stranger.
-The Mysterious Stranger.
-I?
This is amazing.
I think, still beginning,
and then get to know better.
Can think about the evenings?
Normally I refuse to, but
because you are a stranger,
then with pleasure.
Yes, yes, so of course better.
-At nine o'clock?
-Well, at nine.
Prior to the meeting.
-Thank you for a lift.
-You're welcome.
-Goodbye.
-Bye. Tell me ...
You do not even know my name.
-I know.
-Do you know?
It is written on the door.
I do not know how it is pronounced.
EDDIE SCHEPANSKI
Shizpanski?
-Schepanski. Yes.
This is my last name -
A name is not as complicated.
Eddie.
-In the nine?
B-nine.
Do not forget?
Well, that is to say,
extremely unlikely.
B-nine.
The same Dick Carson!
-Come on.
-I tell you.
-Are you sure?
-Definitely.
How do you like?
We think, as we would
to meet with Carson,
and Candy have already done it.
If Carson is that he
makes a car mechanic?
Do not know what he was doing there,
but I know it was him.
-I wonder at it -
-Why?
Why surprised?
Why?
-I do not think Candy knows who he is.
"Of course knew.
If you would not know who he is,
would not have gone.
Or do you think that Candy
will go with anyone?
Or with anyone?
Or go?
Magnolias are fragrant.
You yourself as a magnolia.
-This is a perfume that you sent me.
-Yes?
Like it?
By the way thank you very much
for candy and flowers.
-It was so nice.
-With pleasure.
"But should not have done.
-Why?
I think it is too
wasteful.
You have such a hard-
earn money.
Oh, yeah.
To work
twelve hours a day.
Sometimes in the evenings I -
get out of the pit garage
and I feel so tired,
the head is barely holding on.
You need more sleep at night.
-Too many meetings?
-Date? I?
You can count on
fingers of one hand.
Most romantic
the case for me
is to find a hairpin
in a strange gig.
And so tonight
means so much to me.
Can not imagine how
romantic lie like this,
but not underneath the car.
And I like it cares.
Much water and no utensils.
Funny.
But I do you
do not quite understand.
-Really?
No, nothing bad
Any work is good, but -
This is a temporary job.
I did something actress.
You artist?
-I am a singer.
Singer?
Our troupe stranded,
and while we are working at the hotel.
Oh, then that explains everything
about the girl.
-What girl?
A maid at the hotel, said,
that she was a dancer.
-Oh, this is Flo.
Flow?
She is a dancer.
A very good way.
-I am sure of it.
-And how do you know about Flo?
By Dick Carson.
He lives in a hotel, this is my client.
I heard him say
about this case
when I changed his oil.
He laughed at her?
No, Candy, you are wrong
think of Mr. Carson.
It's a great guy.
What's in it such a fine?
He was polite, courteous,
talented but not conceited.
And why should he be
conceited?
I do not know, all those handsome.
Handsome?
I'm sure he is working on this.
Baths, hairdressing, solarium.
If he was plowing in the garage
12 hours a day,
it would look no better than you.
Thank you, Candy.
Shooting star!
Again, your superstition.
You must close your eyes, think of
desire, and it will come true.
I can prove that it is not true.
How?
I wish and
but it did not come true.
And you close your eyes?
If you close your eyes,
my wish will come true.
Hey, a mechanic.
"What?"
-This is your truck on the road?
Truck?
Yes, but what?
Then I was lucky.
I am an Englishman. The car broke down.
I happened to see you -
Man, I had finished the job.
-I have a date with a young lady -
"But I have an accident.
My wife at the airport.
I think it's carburetor.
-Sorry, we are a young lady -
"Do not worry about me.
-A man problem. Need help.
-Thank you, ladies.
-Also I want to see
as you work.
No, no. Not that.
I get nervous when someone
worth of the soul.
I'll be back soon.
-I'll pay you for the work.
-Watch for falling stars.
I say the stars
In a sky full of wonder
In a world full of wonders
Can they hear
what thinks my heart
We can hear your heart
We know what you think
I say the stars
and ask them
I'm not mistaken?
illusion of it
-or true love?
-This is true love
Should I believe
promises
in the eyes of a stranger?
What happens,
When the magic end?
Can I die?
I say the stars
And I'm waiting for an answer
little star, tell me.
But they seemed not to hear
and only twinkle above
Then I turn to my
and ask your heart
And my heart will answer me
I'm in love
Heart can believe
heart does not lie
you love
I'm in love
Mr. ...
It seems to me that you
a decent man.
I need you to say something.
What is it?
I'm not a mechanic.
-You are not a mechanic?
-No. It's just a joke.
I played the girl.
She thinks I'm a mechanic.
Joke?
But here you all sorted out.
-How now collect -
"Do not worry.
I just wanted to help you.
But in foreign cars
I do not understand.
I'm afraid to scratch it.
But what I do
with my Jaguar?
Oh, yeah. That would suggest that.
Here is a coin.
Call the British embassy.
Hey.
Hey!
All finished?
Well, as I put it,
he no longer needs
in my services.
You know what?
You just like the doctor.
Helping people in emergencies
situations like this.
Believe me, nothing special.
Wait a minute.
Before us so
rudely interrupted,
my wish almost came true.
Remember?
Close your eyes.
-You are one of the guests?
-No.
-I am looking for Dick Carson.
Dick Carson? He did not make an order.
Oh, here they are.
Eddy Schepanski. That's what I want -
-Oh, look who's here.
What a coincidence.
Excuse me, brother.
I was looking for you around the city,
while you're here.
-Are you okay?
-Candy, and Come.
Introduce me to Mr. Carson.
Continuing with our show.
, Mr. Carson?
-Okay, I did.
I Hap Snyder.
Oh, do not get up. I do not like.
-You are lucky, Mr. Carson.
-Hap, you're crazy?
-This is not Mr. Carson. That -
-Do not Dick Carson?
Of course not.
Eddie Carson, a car mechanic.
-Candy, if you -
-This is Eddie Schepanski.
-Sche-who-ski?
-Schepanski.
-Schepanski?
-Candy, listen to me.
Play well, yes?
Portray sort of
Schepanskogo-gentry?
A good way to meet
with a young girl, huh?
-Depicts an honest mechanic.
-Wait.
-What are you talking -?
"I know this whole process.
Invite to dinner.
Poite champagne.
Lonely moonlight.
Or is it already?
Too big man
to call your name?
And I have for you a name.
Only his utter shame
in front of ladies.
As for the new show,
we will not fall.
-Come here.
-Wait a minute.
Take your hands. Sorry, Eddie.
Eddie? Good, smart, go ahead.
Tell her your real name.
Out there in the corner.
Candy got a misunderstanding.
All the time I tried to explain.
Ladies and gentlemen,
We are pleased to see among the guests
wonderful composer
whose melodies delight us all.
Mr. Dick Carson.
Candy, Candy, listen.
I know how you feel.
I will explain.
I have not started it.
You yourself agreed that I
Eddie Schepanski.
Naturally, I decided
you Eddie Schepanski.
-I agree that it is you start?
Yes, I am. And you have not reassured.
This is a misunderstanding.
And you're wrong about my
respect thereto.
Of course. All confirmed
Your reputation.
-Reputation.
-Look, Candy.
It started as a joke
but went on by itself.
You're in show business,
should understand the humor.
I have a great sense of humor,
Mr. Carson.
-Candy, listen.
-True, I sometimes sentimental.
Candy -
I was terribly uncomfortable.
You feel uncomfortable?
And I like?
It is all in me.
-Good morning, Mr. Carson.
-Good morning.
Here please.
I'll take it.
See? Always at work.
-Good morning, sir.
-Good morning.
Very stylish look.
No need to applause.
I can not stand the noise in the morning.
-How do our business?
-Worked with it all morning.
He told me about you.
Your entire history.
-About your glory of your talent.
-Good.
How did you start working
still in college.
How hard it was.
Spoke about the military records.
How much do you give to
charity.
-I told her everything.
-So what?
She hates you.
Do not go.
Pass her a note.
-Good morning, sir.
-Good morning.
Postman.
Specially for Miss Candy
Dick Williams of Carson.
-Here is my answer.
-Wait. What are you doing?
"You deny it?
Listen, I'm sorry.
Yes, but -
-Wait a minute.
Candy is absolutely right.
This is his first show. Location
we know that it happens?
We need to do your own show.
We know what can.
Of course, when all work it out.
Babes, I have a number
for the second act.
When the restaurant closes
porepetiruem under the piano.
Believe me, once you start
working again
feel himself a millionaire.
-I am sure.
-And I'll take Mr. Carson answered.
-Thanks, Hap.
No one. Come.
Prepare props.
Candy, see your text.
Come here. Naduy balls.
Excuse me, miss Teyr,
Mr. Carson did not respond.
Want to leave a message?
No, I've tried.
Thank you very much.
The children, all ready?
Let's begin.
So. One, two, three, four.
Pipers silenced in the Valley
Sandy McTavish
not return home
He is far from the flowers,
that once bloomed bright
But the bells of Broadway
ring through the night
He sits on the stage
with bare knees
Around him a crowd of girls,
and he plays the bagpipes
Sandy in a Scottish skirt,
he looks bravo
And the bells of Broadway
ring through the night
Stop.
Boogie-Woogie on the bagpipes,
this is so cool
and fans scream:
"Oh, what a guy in a skirt!"
Coast deserted Loch Lomond
Because Sandy McTavish
three thousand miles
He is far from the heather,
that once bloomed
But the bells of Broadway
ring through the night
Oh, tell me, where the left
my boy?
He went to a jazz band
52 street
And there you can listen to
his bagpipes
It tam
and socks with tassels
When he plays, rhythm increases
until it becomes like a rock
It compresses goat skin
and it turns jazz
Sandy - Star
DIPS-Doodle-five.
While he plays with them -
rhythm that should
And the bells of Broadway
jingle
bells are ringing
a bagpipe on Broadway
On Broadway
all night
Candy, you're just gorgeous.
Hap-how could you?
-Candy.
I told you that she
gorgeous?
Candy.
Candy, wait!
Hear me out.
Candy. Candy.
What kind of obsession?
Princeton, Number 1948.
Still play, an athlete?
Candy, well, listen.
-Let go.
"You should listen to me.
Yesterday evening, a wonderful
superstitious girl
named Candy Williams
Walked with a guy who
impersonate another,
and now she hates him.
-Absolutely.
So, forget those two.
Talk about a producer who
going to put on a show.
He saw the girl and would like to
use it in his show.
We can talk
about these two people?
I do not know what you have for the show,
Mr. Carson,
but you're the producer, playboy
and trying to ohmurit naive girl
taking it in her show,
I'm already too old for this.
But Candy -
You'd better get up,
Mr. Carson.
You can catch a cold
without the car over you.
Hear.
How would you have to do with me,
do not be so stubborn.
It's not often offer
soloist in the Broadway show.
Thank you very much.
Solo?
If you can.
And I know - you can.
-How about Hepa and the rest?
-Everyone can find a role.
But this is just business,
Mr. Carson.
Yes, Miss Williams,
just business.
Oh, Mr. Carson.
That's why I want to sing like an angel
And dance like the devil
So gather the orchestra, Mr.
conductor, and let's begin
"Well, Tommy, what do you think?
-Sensational.
With our search methods
Talents
You could stay
undisclosed.
Undisclosed? Wait a minute.
She was in my show,
"Parisian Beauty."
-So what it saw.
However, very little.
It was opened by Hap Snyder.
He made it great.
If you would like it Teyru,
we get the money.
Oh, I hope.
-Come on.
"Do not worry, you ocharuesh it.
How, you say, he
oil wells?
Forty-four.
-Oil. Black gold.
Guys, guys.
'll Work on the ballad.
-It must be sung at a good pace.
-Good.
And I think that should be slower.
Slightly corny.
Something like this:
I love you dearly,
more than just -
Flow is not exactly
that I had in mind.
No, no.
Need a nice easy rhythm:
I love you dearly -
Okay, okay.
Stop, right?
Let the one who wrote the song,
explain to a girl
who will sing a song
as the one who wrote the song,
wants a girl
who will sing a song
sang this song.
Understand?
-Forward.
-Thank you.
Too slow.
The song needs a drive.
See what I mean?
I love you dearly -
more than just -
Listen, if you do not mind -
I'm better alone.
Please.
I will work in another room,
away from you.
Understood.
They are you nervous about?
I will bring them.
Flow, we're going.
Up! Gone, gone.
Well done. Duc, an!
Go on, guy.
Fish. Fish for the boy.
Gone, gone.
When they came to me,
nothing could.
Well, let's try it.
I love you dearly
More than just a really
More than I can say,
-Love
-I love you dearly
My love is bigger than the moon
Darling, you took my breath
May - it's time for love
promenade
arms to embrace
-A lip
A lip
To whisper
I love you dearly
More than just a really
My love is like a rose
a spring bouquet
Should I repeat that I love you
Again and again, every day
May - it's time for love
promenade
arms to embrace
And lips
to whisper
I love you dearly
More than just a really
My love is like a rose
a spring bouquet
Should I repeat that I love you
Again and again,
every day
Candy, it's wonderful.
That -
It's just wonderful.
But not good enough.
It should be more dynamic.
In the end, on stage
I can not help you.
You'll be singing themselves,
unaided.
Yes, I know, Dick, but I do not -
-Mr Carson.
Let's keep your distance.
Do not be too ambitious.
Lorraine!
Come on.
Lorraine, I want to present to you
Miss Williams.
Miss Candy Williams.
This is Miss Teyr.
Miss Lorraine Teyr.
-Hello, Miss Teyr.
-Hello.
Today we did a good job.
Continue to work the same way.
Rehearse in front of a mirror,
In the morning I go in with you.
You now have learned a lot.
I did too much today
learned.
Well, Lorraine, how?
-I have two days I can not find you.
-Really? Very sorry.
"I do not know you were busy casting.
CAST -? Oh, yes, casting.
That's what I was doing.
Very, very hard work.
Lorraine, listen, I
great idea.
-As for this girl, this ...
-Williams?
-Candy Williams?
Yes. Yes.
Tommy so many leads,
I do not remember.
Yeah.
Lorraine, listen.
This girl - dynamite.
Straight dynamite.
Of course, I do not want it to
know what I think about it.
So what is the mind.
At the reception, your father,
instead of me sitting at the piano,
singing songs and trying to
show voice
how they will look
on stage
will this girl sing,
and your father will be able to see
how it will look
in reality.
This will be a hundred times more
effectively, is not it?
-Do you agree?
Dick, you're a genius.
It is not only more efficient
way to listen to songs,
but we still see love
Is it this girl ..
That's right.
-And if all is well,
The father agreed to her
major role in the show.
I myself have thought of before.
At first, my only interest
was to help put on a show,
and now - to take part
the fate of a young,
budding actress.
Help her achieve fame.
This is a fantastic idea.
Just fabulous.
Now, when I heard the words,
Give me some music.
If this dishwasher close
to my father, I will destroy her.
Lorraine, you are unfair.
The show should be a girl.
-Not this one.
"Why not?
You have a lot of it just promise?
Well, I'll be frank.
Or I or this blond.
And if not me,
there will be no pope.
And would not the pope, will not show.
"But Lorraine -
-Think, Dick.
-Call me at home.
-Lorraine -
Oh, my God -
Excuse me.
Candy.
Candy, I came as soon as he could.
I do not want you to
incorrectly thought ...
Hey, Candy, it was a joke.
I would like to introduce you
Lorraine as an artist.
I did not want her to think,
that between us something personal.
Between us, nothing personal
Mr. Carson.
Why are you so? From Lorraine
depends on funding. You know.
-I do not know that depends on it.
-She is jealous proprietress.
-It is not so bad.
-Not in this case ...
She does not want you to sing
in her home.
She does not want to -?
This I refuse to sing
in her home.
Why are you so?
You're all wrong understanding -
Jealous-proprietress?
Yes.
Tuck did not file her cause.
-I did not let on. Hear me out.
I'm sure you said:
"It's just business, nothing more."
You'll never believe this,
I said.
I'm sure you said so.
I did not know men
but good to know women.
-Candy, fires -
They do not get jealous
proprietress without -
without that there was no
for good reason.
Candy, listen, wait -
Lorraine, please -
Candy. Candy!
Wait.
-This is not the Princeton College.
-Okay, but listen to me.
Something that was between me and Lorraine,
was before I met you.
Candy, it's true.
Candy.
Candy, I love you.
Anyone but you.
And it is also true.
If you say you love me
why not say it's Lorraine
instead of having to humiliate me?
-I tried. Did not happen.
"She sees even what is not.
"She knows you too well.
Candy -
Candy just like a child, yes?
The very immediacy.
More so you will not find anywhere else -
Candy, my dear -
What I'm saying. Immediacy.
See what I mean?
Nervous. You understand
when you're nervous, you -
This does not mean it's -
Well, you know? That -
Well at least not a cake.
Sorry.
Honey, what -? Wait. That's me.
What happened to you?
What happened between you?
I do not understand. First
cake, then a slap.
Why not just kill him
and does not end this show?
-There will be no show.
"Do not be a show? Why?
Oil does not want to miss me
Here's why.
"Rehearsing before a mirror."
Cheater!
Hey, what's wrong with you?
The same misfortune for seven years.
Let there be fourteen.
Maybe try a 21?
All right, dear.
I never knew you had it
love so much.
Please, show
small service Anton.
Do not touch anything.
Go away quietly.
And please, do not come back.
Well it's here.
Alcatraz.
Do not worry, we've worked well.
Can be proud.
Wait a minute.
Why do not we go back
Back to Broadway
and there they show in the kitchen?
Hey, look.
-Hopefully see you soon, Dick.
-Thank you. See you soon.
He is probably going to receive
sing for her excellent Lorraine.
Tommy. Tommy!
And you do not go along with it?
No, I need to overtake him
machine in New York.
After what he did with Candy
I wish him a failure.
There will be no failure, no success.
He refused to show.
He refused to show?
So, he leaves -?
"He went to the airport.
"He flies to New York.
-What happened?
How do I know?
He suddenly said,
did not want to put on a show
in Florida.
Spends his last 150 bucks
ticket and flies away.
So he lied.
About what?
He loves me.
So this is it because of you fly away?
Because I hurt his feelings
and did not believe him.
Do not blame yourself. Could it be
Lorraine gave him a ticket -
No, he flies away
from Lorraine.
He threw everything, because
loves me.
-Fine. And what do I do?
-What to do?
I know what I do.
Whatever happens, we are with you.
We still troupe.
-Where are you going?
"I want to see Mr. Teyra.
-Teyra?
"She was crazy. If Lorraine
see it, then run.
-Candy. Candy.
Candy, not so fast.
Listen to me.
If we Frenchman catches,
We psycho in solitary confinement.
The last time I tell you.
If there was a possibility
receive money to stage,
then it's gone.
This lady knows you.
"She never -
"She knows me.
But does not know it.
Lorraine, my first dance.
I can remember. Mrs. Herbert
glad to see you again.
-Thank you, dear.
-Good evening.
Marjorie.
-Hi.
Arthur.
Yes, Miss Teyr?
-Is everything ready?
Yes.
Pro-lighting is not forgotten?
-No.
Well.
-Ask them to stop the music
Yes, ma'am.
-Pope.
Yes, dear?
-Excuse us, please.
"Of course.
Please post here.
-Happy birthday, Dad.
-Thank you, dear.
Happy birthday, Otis.
-Congratulations, Otis.
-Thank you.
-Happy birthday.
-All the best.
-Thank you very much.
Otis, which I have not seen.
It's really something.
A bit pretentious
I would say.
This idea of Lorraine.
Maybe someday it will cease
brag about my money
but I can brag about
his daughter.
What is the liveliest,
True, my lady?
Yes, my lord.
Excuse me, my lord and my lady
I wish you personally
welcome.
It's so rare to find fellow countryman.
-Thank you.
How do you find London
these days?
Oh, easy, easy.
The fog clears, and there he is here.
Contrary to what everyone says,
we have a sense of humor.
Yes.
-Your hat, my lord.
"Of course, this is my hat.
Whose hat is it then?
He thinks it's not my hat.
-Duc, I'm afraid.
-Oh, nonsense.
Draws in his lips and all.
Take me by the arm.
An excellent evening, right?
Enormously.
Just tremendous.
-I beg your pardon.
-Oh, hello, sir?
My name is Lord Belford.
-Can I offer you a drink?
Yes, of course.
I'll be whiskey and soda.
But no ice.
And ma'am?
Whiskey and soda.
But without the whiskey.
Her Serene Highness the wheel.
Would you like to eat?
Wish.
-Who are they?
"Who?"
Do you know them?
This is probably friends of his father.
Turn away. It goes.
-Good evening. I Miss Teyr.
-Lord Belford.
-I would like to submit a lady Belford.
-Hello.
I'm glad you came.
I hope you enjoy the evening.
Oh, it's divine.
Almost like when Their Lordships
and I got married.
Probably very interesting
to be the wife of Lord.
Just try.
That is going beyond the Lord.
Excuse me.
-What does it far, so good.
My name is Rogers.
My business - oil.
How are you?
That I was dead, it's
Lord and Lady Belford!
Hi, guys. Hi all.
Hi all.
"Do not expect to meet you here.
-The world is small, does not it?
Yes, very small. Not like Texas.
Hey, Betty Lou, come here,
old mare.
I'm here, my sweet.
You all know this little girl.
Texas Flower.
My little cactus.
"How then is it going?
-I give my best performance -
We fooled everyone.
Even Lorraine. She is over there.
-One fly in the ointment?
-This is just a fly.
So would prishlepnula.
You know what to do.
I take Teyra.
-Your hand, my lady.
Yes, my lord.
-And here did not dance?
-What are the dance?
Here, elegant public.
Watch your language.
What are you talking about?
I say like everyone else.
Even better.
How are you? All right?
-I see, okay. The cool kids.
Yes, sir.
I'll give everyone a herd of cows.
How about this?
Good?
Arthur ...
-Mr Carson has not come yet?
-Not yet, Miss Teyr.
If you do not mind, I am too.
This is the dry martini
of those that I drank.
Do not worry. All right.
Friends, for the oil business.
I, too, all in oil, you know.
Terms of an oil.
It makes me rich.
But I want to start a hobby.
I want to do something else.
Well, playing golf, for example.
Decided is how to build something
golf course.
And guess what happened?
18 oil fountains. How do you?
You are a fine fellow, Teyr.
I like you.
People such as you have done
Texas what it is.
And like you.
It's good you say, pal.
You are right. All heard
what he said?
Like me. The same steep.
I clearly say?
You are from the North?
A great honor to meet you,
Your Grace.
-Thank you. HSH -
"Why throw the child -?
Oh, let me introduce
our good friend,
Mrs. Rogers from Texas.
-Hello. How are you?
-I am fascinated.
"We met at the coronation.
-At the coronation?
Oh, it certainly was
stunner.
Of course. Even the queen was.
Glad to meet you, Mrs. Winston.
Oh, all right.
I always carry a spare.
-What brought you to Florida?
-Just thought of something to buy.
I want to buy Miami, you know?
Otis, what you said,
old devil?
We need to find Lorraine.
And I told how I
was Penhendle?
It was - yes -
And how about a little dance?
All right, sir?
This is because of the shoes.
I used to bear boots.
-Once again, repeat.
"Yes, miss.
You have to stay, dear.
I know that I do, Dad.
Carson this yet?
"He will be soon.
-Lorraine, listen.
I intend to invest big money
to this guy for you.
But please do not lose
him as the others.
Do not worry, I'll take care of your
precious investment.
-Honey, I have no doubt -
-Lorraine.
-You promised me a dance.
-Oh, of course.
Excuse me, sir.
Well, I think now is the
time to start.
Completely, my lady.
You know what to do?
-Shall we dance, my lord?
-Excuse me, miss Teyr.
-No, my lady.
-I am away for a minute?
Yes, of course.
Miss Teyr,
You just passed.
How are things going?
On the right track.
What are you doing? ..
-How are things going?
-How does the current.
You can drum roll?
Ladies and gentlemen,
minute attention.
As you know, Mr. Teyr
asked Dick Carson,
renowned composer, to
He sang songs from his shows.
However, Mr. Carson
unexpectedly delayed.
And I would like to replace it,
As far as I can.
With your permission,
Mr. Teyr.
Of course, young lady.
Start.
Thank you very much.
Arthur, place the public
Sit back.
Sorry.
you ever wondered
What happened to Tom Sawyer
They grew up and became a lawyer
A boy, whose name was Hugo
runs off with lessons on fishing
become a doctor
As for me, I always knew
for which I was born
-Oh, Mr. Carson.
-Hi.
I want to sing
Like an angel
And dance like the devil
and play so well,
John Barrymore
in the play Camille
When I was a child with dolls
I dreamed one day I'll
famous star of the show
and audiences will applaud me
I want to be where the lights
and give their lives to the theater
Where people forget about the cares
Hooked representation
So I want to sing like an angel
and dance like the devil
Mr. Conductor,
Collect Orchestra
and starts, begin, begin.
I want to be where the lights
and gave his life to the theater
where people forget about the cares
Hooked representation
So I want to sing
Like an angel
And dance like the devil
Mr. Conductor,
Collect Orchestra
start to
Started!
-Delightfully, young lady!.
-Thank you, Mr. Teyr.
-Want to hear the rest of the troupe?
-I heard all I needed to hear.
Son, will work.
-Thank you, Mr. Teyr.
"You put on a show?
I guarantee you.
I just have
blank form and a pen.
Will you sign a check?
Of course.
Wait a minute, Dad.
What is it -?
-Where were you?
-In the pool.
All with their drinking.
-I told you to stay?
"But she -
If we begin to show business,
that is no reason for you to
show your character.
It is a pity that you have not heard
how this girl sings.
She's just adorable.
Everything is ready to deal with your
friend Dick Carson.
You can forget about Carson
and about the show.
You were misled.
"But I -
-It was my fault, Mr. Teyr -
Do not, Candy -
Someone explain to me
what is happening here?
Mr. Teyr, I certify
that you were misled.
But not as it seems.
I would like to hear from you only
investments in the entertainment business.
And nothing more.
I talked about this with your daughter,
but did not discuss with you.
It was my mistake.
Carson, we're probably better
discuss this situation
at other times.
This would not be necessary.
Good night.
Candy -
Candy.
Dick, leave me alone.
Do not cry, dear. Please.
Nothing happened.
Yes it is.
I spoiled you all -
You do not spoil.
When I left, I thought
I lost
everything in this world.
I do not care about this show.
True.
If you need to become a mechanic,
as Schepanski, I agree.
All I need is you.
I love you, Candy.
I will always love you.
I apologize.
We ought to talk about show business.
I like what I see
but here in Texas,
if we want something,
do not waste time and do not delay.
Teyr, I'm the same player
Like you, sir.
Carson, I am willing to invest
hundred thousand in your show.
Stough -?
-Calm down.
You are not allowed to
This bouncer took the show?
Of course not.
Carson.
I give 125 000.
-It can not be -
-This is wonderful.
Raise rates.
I give 150 thousand.
Carson, as necessary, to
put on a show?
From 150 to 175 thousand.
Young lady, where the checkbook?
-Here, Mr Teyr.
Vaught, 175 thousand dollars.
-Procedure.
Dick.
Two hundred thousand dollars.
Well ...
You won. I pass.
Wait a minute, Mr. Teyr.
We sang for you in your home.
And we accept your 175,000.
In addition, we believe in ethics.
Rogers?
Yield to the young lady. I pass.
Well, if the transaction was executed.
-What day is today?
-Friday.
A number?
-Your birthday, Otis.
Friday, the 13th.
On, Friday, the 13th.
Does anyone have any superstitious?
Yes, I -
Was.
But no more.
No, I'm lucky.
[RUSSIAN]