More! More!
Mr. Farnham, can l have your autograph?
Sure, honey.
l never refuse the few requests l get.
My mom and dad took me to see
your show on Broadway last year.
l think you're the greatest dancer
in the world.
lt's you and me against Fred Astaire.
-May l cut in?
-Certainly.
-Aren't we supposed to dance?
-l'd love to.
But, unfortunately, l don't know how.
-You don't know how?
-No.
-Then why did you cut in?
-Well, l thought we might sit this one out.
That l know how.
-l'll teach you to dance.
-l'm a very poor pupil.
Follow me. Right foot back.
One, two, three, four.
-One, two...
Four.
Shall we try it again?
Only this year they're doing it
without the ''ouch.''
Oh, my poor feet.
l'm afraid you'll never learn.
lt's just as well. l wanted
to get better-acquainted anyway.
-lt's such a short boat ride.
-What, five days?
l wasted four and a half
before l met you.
How do you do?
My name is Tom Farnham.
How do you do? l'm Melinda Howard.
Well, that's over.
Now, what do you say
we throw caution to the winds.
Please. Let's not make up
four and a half days in four seconds.
Okay. l'll wait.
What's another minute or two?
The ship's paper says you're visiting
New York after several years' absence.
Oh, really? Did it also give my age and say
that l don't like men who operate so fast?
All right, all right. You win.
After that number l saw you do,
l'd say you were in show business.
l am. ln a way.
l've been touring the provinces
with a small theatrical company.
Saved a little money and decided to come
to America and surprise my mother.
-They always have a mother.
-Gosh, l haven't seen her in years.
You've probably heard of her. Jessica
Howard. She's very famous on Broadway.
-On Broadway? Now?
-She's starring in a musical.
Excuse me.
l don't know much about show business.
What do you do, Mr. Farnham?
Oh, l spend most of my time
trying to get girls to call me Tom.
lf you'll excuse me, l just remembered
that l have some packing to do.
-l'll help you.
-Oh, no, thank you, l'll manage.
What's the matter, don't you trust me?
What's this for?
There's a message on it for you
from the women of the world.
Good night, Mr. Farnham.
''ln God we trust.''
Well, it wasn't a total loss.
Sorry to disturb you, Diamond Jim,
but that's the front door.
Front door, living room,
master bedroom, library.
This is like living
in a pinball machine.
Can't even eat around here.
-Why did l ever leave show business?
-l'll bite. Why did you?
-Yes, miss?
-Oh, how do you do? l'm Miss Howard.
Would you bring in my luggage?
l'll take this one.
l beg your pardon.
Have Mother come down,
but don't say who's here.
This is the residence of Adolph Hubbell.
He has no children.
-That anyone's been able to trace.
-What's he doing in my mother's house?
-Are you sure you have the right address?
-This is 485 Beekman Place, isn't it?
Hasn't been changed.
That's the address on every letter
that Mother sends me.
-Oh, no. You're not Melinda Howard?
-Yes.
You're in England.
You're gonna stay there, aren't you?
l'm here.
Follow me.
-Where are we going?
-You should've written you were coming.
-l just wanted to surprise her.
-You'll surprise her.
She's rented the house to Adolph Hubbell.
You know, Hubbell Breweries.
Just while she's on tour.
On tour?
Don't tell me she's out of town.
She's due in a day or so
for a conference with her producers.
-l'll see if l can find her.
-lf she isn't here...
...where am l going to stay?
l haven't any money.
No money?
Welcome to the club.
Am l intruding?
Oh, Gloria. This is Miss Howard.
You know, Jessica's daughter.
Miss Davis, the lucky girl
marrying me.
-How do you do?
-Hello.
Be with you in a minute, Gloria.
This way, please.
A charming room if you don't mind
staying in the servants' wing.
Oh, l don't mind at all.
lt's nice of you to go to all this trouble.
This ought to fix you up temporarily.
And don't worry about your mother.
l'll see that she gets here.
-Why shouldn't she?
-Oh, that's right. Why shouldn't she?
l've been one of your mother's
admirers for years.
You see, l- l used to be
in show business myself.
Oh, really?
But then why are you doing this?
Oh, l don't know, it was just a mad,
impulsive desire to keep from starving.
-Good night, Bob.
-Thank you.
Joe, hit me.
Jessie, you have another show.
You won't be able to see the customers.
That's all l've got to look forward
to at the end of a hard day.
Not seeing the customers.
-Jessica.
-Hello, Lefty.
-Baby, you're singing better than ever.
-You don't have to lie to me.
We're not on the same bill anymore.
-This isn't exactly the Palace either.
-What will you have?
-Give me a Bromo. With a chaser.
-One olive or two?
-Did you mail that check to the kid?
-Yeah, but l could've saved you a stamp.
She's here.
Here? ln New York?
-You didn't bring her down?
-No, she's at the house.
The house she thinks you own.
You've got to send her back.
How do we do it, with mirrors?
She's come to see you.
lt's been a long time.
l draw a blank.
l don't know where to go from here.
There's only one way.
l told her you're on the road.
Tomorrow you come into town for one day,
have a big reunion and go back on the road.
And where do we hold this big reunion?
ln a telephone booth?
l've arranged that too.
Tomorrow the Hubbells throw a party.
Half of Broadway is the entertainment.
-You come back and steal the show.
-lf l can get in.
Here's your invitation.
l made out the guest list.
No, Lefty.
l couldn't face her. l-
She'd know. She'd-
How? Who's gonna tell her?
Look at me.
Greenwich Village Gertie.
lt'll be like the old days.
Everybody in town will be there.
Lights, music...
...and Jessica Howard. You'll be a smash.
Do you really think
l could get away with it?
lf Jessica Howard
can't play Jessica Howard, who can?
All right, Lefty, l'll try.
-Nine o'clock?
-Sure, sure.
-But promise me one thing.
-Not a drop.
Everything's gonna be all right.
lncidentally, the kid's a knockout.
Like her mother.
Hit me again, Joe.
lt's homecoming day.
Hi.
Hello.
ls it all right if l go upstairs
and look around?
-l don't know.
-My mother wrote...
...and told me so much about this place.
l'd like to see it.
Oh, l guess it'll be all right.
Mr. and Mrs. Hubbell are asleep by now.
-Right up those stairs.
-Thanks.
Oh, listen, while you're staying here...
...keep away from Mrs. Hubbell
if you can.
Thanks for the tip.
Oh, this house is so wonderful.
-Mother must be doing all right, huh?
-Oh, yes, she's really flying.
Oh, l'm so sorry.
-l thought you were asleep.
-Who are you? What are you doing here...
-...twisting around in my living room?
-l'm Miss Howard.
-This means something?
-l hope l didn't disturb you...
...but l just wanted to sort of
have a look around the house.
-lsn't that a beautiful painting?
-Painting? Madam, this is not a museum.
People don't come in off the streets.
Don't do that. lt's liable to leave a ring.
Do you realize how much
a table like this costs?
You are in the furniture business now?
You shouldn't take advantage
that my mother's out of town...
-...and abuse her furnishings.
-l abuse what l want!
Please don't spill any more beer. How
would you like it if this were your house?
Right now l wouldn't like it.
What is this?
-Better l get the police.
-Something wrong, sir?
Yes. This girl, she comes in my house,
she dances around in circles.
She won't let me drip beer
on my own rug.
l sneak down to get away
from Mrs. Hubbell, and what do l get?
-Another Mrs. Hubbell.
-Leave everything to me.
Come, l have good news about your mother.
Wait for me downstairs.
-l'll explain everything.
-What's going on in my own house?
Who is she?
Do you remember many years ago you
backed a Broadway show, Pretty Lady?
-Of course.
-Remember the star?
Yeah, Jessica Howard.
How could l forget?
A wonderful woman.
Too bad what happened to her.
This girl is Jessica Howard's daughter.
What?
She doesn't know about her mother.
We want to keep it from her.
-Will you help us?
-Anything. Anything l can do.
Thank you, sir.
Sorry, l keep thinking it's my house.
The dancing will be interrupted
for a few minutes while two great artists...
...who are taking a vacation
from the theater entertain you.
l'm really enjoying myself,
Mr. Hubbell.
Pretty soon your mother gets here,
and even better you will enjoy it.
Lefty. Lefty, you were wonderful.
So why am l passing this tray?
Oh, it's nice that you asked
so many show people.
You invite actors,
free entertainment you get.
Confidentially, Ferndel, the producer,
brings them so l put money in his show.
This way l throw two stones
at one bird.
There's Ferndel now.
Ladies and gentlemen,
your attention, please.
Here he is, my boy, Tom Farnham.
With the number that will be
the hit of my new show.
-Come on out here, Tom.
-George.
Thank you.
Unaccustomed as l am
to public auditions...
...l'm always glad to raise a buck
for my producer. Let's go, Page.
-What's he gonna do?
-Like a dream he dances.
Come up here.
You wouldn't believe this,
but l gave him his first lesson.
Lefty, why her mother don't get here?
l don't know. Keep her occupied
till l find out what's happened.
-All right, l introduce her to Mrs. Hubbell.
-No, no, you stay away from her.
What will your wife think? You, taking a
blond and giving her a room in your home?
You mean, you-?
You think she would think that l...?
Thank you. That's the nicest thing
anyone has said to me in 15 years.
Thank you.
Oh, Miss Howard.
l have some money for you.
Here's a nickel.
You owe me four insults.
You picked up dancing pretty quickly
for a beginner.
Oh, l'm ready for more lessons anytime.
What are you doing here anyway?
l never thought l'd see you again.
lt's a small, uncomfortable world,
isn't it?
l see l've got a lot of explaining to do.
That was my shipboard treatment
you got that day.
On land, l'm really not a bad guy.
Tell me, how are you underwater?
Would you give me a little time
to redeem myself?
Oh, Tom.
l've got to butter up Mrs. Hubbell.
Back in two seconds.
Oh, you can take longer than that.
-Here, Tom, l think you earned this.
-Thank you, Mrs. Hubbell.
-Did you like my little number?
-l think it'll be wonderful.
ln a show my husband
doesn't have to back.
-He hasn't done too badly in show business.
-He's lost everything but his accent.
-Well, now, if you'll excuse me, l-
-Better wait.
l may call on you
to rescue my husband from Ferndel.
No, no, not even a nickel does my wife
let me put in another Broadway show.
But, Adolph, l counted on you for 50,000.
l'm already in rehearsal.
Rehearsal already.
And who picked the chorus girls? You.
Who stages the numbers? You.
Who picks the music? You.
And who pays the bills? Me.
But this is a modern Broadway show.
l'd like to have you help, but your taste
in music and girls is a little old-fashioned.
So my money's old-fashioned too.
lt won't go out of the house.
Remember us, Mr. Ferndel?
Davis and Mack?
-Oh, sure, sure.
-We're just working here for laughs.
Not to mention food,
lodging and clothing.
Oh, but the theater's our first love.
Give us a spot in your show,
l'll turn in my dickey.
There isn't gonna be any new show.
My angel just flew the coop.
Freeloader.
-Fine, Tom. Very, very good.
-Thank you.
How much did you go for this time?
Not a cent.
l kept my promise to you. Sure.
Anna, l wonder, do you mind
if l ask something?
-What?
-The music, the excitement...
...l'm getting too old for it.
Every bone in my head aches.
Always too old. Always something aches.
l just thought if l could go upstairs,
slip away without anyone noticing.
-That's just to get out of dancing with me.
-Anna-
All right, go upstairs
to your hot-water bottle, but l stay.
How can you sneak away? There's people
here who want something from you.
l manage it, don't worry.
Sure you won't mind staying a little longer
and carrying on for me?
Not a bit. l'll dance with Tom.
Won't l, Tom?
-Well, l... l'd be glad to, Mrs. Hubbell, but-
-Thanks, it helps me out. l won't forget it.
Good night, Anna. lf anybody asks for me,
tell them l'm enjoying poor health.
Well, shall we give it a tussle?
Mr. Hubbell. Excuse me,
has my mother arrived yet?
Don't worry, she will come.
Everything l have taken care of.
-What are you doing here all alone?
-Oh, l'm trying to avoid a dancing lesson.
What's the matter,
you don't like the teacher?
Well, l haven't made up my mind yet.
A pity l am too old,
or l would dance with you.
You would?
Oh, well, you know the old saying:
-''The young in heart never grow old.''
-So?
-l think you're one of the young in heart.
-Thank you.
May l have this dance, please?
-Me?
-Oh, this is a nice waltz.
All right, but too much
you shouldn't expect.
My heart is young,
but my feet are ready to retire.
Shall we then?
-Right now?
-Would you rather wait for the next one?
Oh, no, no, by that time,
even older l will be.
Come on, you can do it. lt's easy.
-See? You dance beautifully.
-Thank you.
l'm afraid l'm not as lightheaded
as l used to be.
Look, there's Adolph.
And he told me that he had a headache.
-Getting a little tired?
-No, it's a little crowded.
Let's get closer
to where the crowd ain't.
Who is that girl?
Look, l'm gonna stop dancing.
One Hubbell creating a spectacle is enough.
l should cut in.
Before he knocks himself out.
-Yes, go on.
-Excuse me.
Why, Tom, what a surprise.
For years l haven't seen you.
-You know Miss...?
-Howard, Melinda Howard.
-How do you do?
Excuse me, l see somebody makes motions
to me. Pardon me.
-May l?
-l'm charmed.
Who is that girl, and why did you
come back here to dance with her?
You know, when- As l was going out,
l bumped into George- George Gubbins.
-You often hear me speak of him.
-Never.
And what has that got to do with it?
She's his daughter, you know.
Poor child.
Men don't seem to like her.
He asked me to talk to her about it.
-Men seem to like her now.
-Yes, l talked to her.
Three O'Clock Club.
Oh, hello, Lefty.
Who? Jessie?
No. No, they poured her out of here
around 2:00 this morning.
-What's happened to her?
-The usual. Screaming meanies.
-She was breaking up the joint.
-l'll come down right away.
But she's not here.
They took her away.
Same place.
lt's tough.
-Lefty, any news from her mother?
-She's not going to make it.
Why? What happened?
She's drinking again.
They've taken her to a hospital.
-l better go and see if she's all right.
-Go, l pay all the bills. Go.
-Thank you, boss.
-Go.
-Mr. Hubbell, what time is it, please?
-Time, who cares for time?
Mother was supposed
to be here at 9:00-
Why doesn't everybody have fun?
Tom, sing another song.
Give the party a shot in the head.
Please, no more solos.
l'm tied up for the evening.
Well, do something together.
-What?
-Even better it will be.
-Well, what do you say?
-l'll just be in your way.
We'll have a wonderful time
falling all over each other.
Come on, you start it.
Will you play ''You're Getting
to Be a Habit With Me''?
Gather around.
Have a little surprise for you.
Now you're gonna get some
real entertainment.
Melinda, still up?
What are you doing here?
Everybody goes home an hour ago.
-Oh, Mr. Hubbell, l'm worried.
-Your mother?
Think something happened
to the train?
l promise you, to the train
nothing happened.
Now, please, go to bed.
Lefty, where have you been?
Have you heard anything?
-l just talked to your mother on the phone.
-You did? Where is she?
l don't know how to tell you.
She's not coming home right away.
-She's not coming home? Why not?
-You know how it is. The show's a hit.
lf they took her out of it, it'd kill
the business. She's the star, you know.
-Did you tell her l was here?
-Of course not.
-You wanted to surprise her.
-That's right.
Easy it is to understand.
Maybe you go back to England.
When her show finishes,
she will come to see you, no?
-l'll pack your bags in the morning.
-Lefty, l'm not going.
l'm gonna stay right here and wait
for her, even if it takes months.
Months? You know how long is months?
Oh, l know l was foolish
coming so unexpectedly.
But now that l'm here,
l can't go until l see her.
Months. Maybe better you
should go to a hotel and wait.
Oh, Mr. Hubbell, if you don't mind,
l'd much rather stay here.
You have so many empty rooms
in the house and everything.
Wouldn't it be kind of foolish
if l went to a hotel?
So foolish l don't know
why you even brought it up.
-Thank you, Mr. Hubbell.
-Yeah.
-Good night.
Adolph, who's downstairs?
No, no, no, nobody is downstairs.
Nobody.
Months.
Just look at these grocery bills. And most
of them are for food for the servants.
They have to eat.
That butler and maid eat enough
for three people.
No, it's only two. Two actors
is the same as three people.
They're out of the house
most of the time.
-They are trying to go back to the theater.
-Well, l hope they get back soon.
Anyway, the bills have got to come down,
or they go out. Tell them.
-You rang?
-You heard?
We can't cut down. You wouldn't want us
to deprive Melinda of anything.
Oh, no, no, no, but what can we do?
Well, we could cut down
on your dinners.
All right. lf l get hungry,
l'll come down and eat with you.
Maybe l have been spending
too much money on food.
But it's just to keep
Melinda's spirits up.
She's in pretty bad shape.
Came all the way to this country.
Her mother won't see her. She's broke.
Had to pawn her coat today.
We have to take care of that.
And she cries all the time.
-When nobody's looking.
-lt's terrible, terrible.
Mr. Hubbell, you've got a chance
to do something wonderful.
Cheer her up. Take her to dinner,
to a show.
lt'll bring the sunshine to her lips...
...and the rosebuds to her cheeks.
Gee, l should be on the dramatic stage
instead of vaudeville.
But how can l take her out?
l am married.
-Can you think of a better reason?
-No, l couldn't. My wife. No.
Ferndel was right.
-What you know about Ferndel?
-l heard what he told you.
You're old-fashioned.
You have no eye for beautiful women.
He shouldn't judge me by my wife.
But what would he think if he saw you
with Melinda tonight, alone...
...having dinner?
Wouldn't you feel young again?
l wouldn't be old-fashioned then, huh?
Why, you may have found the leading lady
for his new show right under his nose.
Already l feel younger.
But, Melinda, you think she
would come to dinner with me?
Yes. She knows
you're trying to help her.
She's worried and alone.
Why, you'd be doing her a good turn.
Tonight l'll do my good deed.
Wasn't it nice of Mr. Hubbell
to ask me to dinner?
You remember one thing, dearie.
Don't let him get any ideas.
What? Why, he's like a father to me.
Take it from a girl who's been out with a lot
of fathers in her time, lead with your left.
Here you are, sir.
Every night he has to go
to his club for pinochle.
Mama, tonight l got a feeling
l'm going to hold the best hand in years.
-Good night, darling.
-Good night.
Don't wait up for me.
The game may go on for hours.
-Good night, Mr. Hubbell.
-Good night.
-Oh, good evening, Mr. Hubbell.
-Good evening, Mr. Mack.
ls she ready?
-All ready, Mr. Hubbell?
-Come on, then. We go stepping.
Oh, forgot my hat.
-Already l feel 20 years younger.
-Adolph?
l feel 20 years older.
What are you doing here? l thought
you were going to play pinochle.
-l...
-Mr. Hubbell just dropped in...
...to give us a lecture
on our extravagance.
And he had a perfect right
to mention it to us.
-Our food bill has been much too high.
-Much high.
We'll cut down someplace.
l didn't think he'd speak
to you about it.
That's the reason l came downstairs.
Thank you. Have a good game.
l will, l will. Don't wait up for me.
Good night.
-What's the matter with that door?
-lt was stuck.
-Didn't l hear Mrs. Hubbell down here?
-Big as life.
-Oh, is she coming with us?
-No, a headache she has. Too bad.
Come.
-Well, have fun.
-Don't worry.
Sidney, the theater's dying.
The angels aren't happy just to lose their
money, they want to produce the flops too.
All of which means Hubbell
didn't stand still, huh?
He wanted to help with the casting.
And the old boy doesn't know
a pretty girl from a guernsey cow.
Hey, don't look now, but he just walked
in with the pride of the dairy.
-Two, Mr. Hubbell?
-You said it, kiddo.
Yes, sir.
That girl was at his party.
She's a pretty good performer.
Or she runs a little hat shop.
You don't think that-?
Offer her a part in your show and see how
quickly he pulls out his checkbook.
-A drink before dinner?
-Oh, not for me, thank you.
How about you, Mr. Hubbell?
Your usual beer?
Beer? Where you been living, pop?
ln a cave?
-A double zombie.
-For you?
What's the matter, you want
to see my driver's license?
l tell your fortune.
Good evening, Adolph.
Hello, kid. How is tricks?
Haven't l seen your charming
companion somewhere?
At the party the other night,
Mr. Ferndel.
She is my discovery.
l pick pretty good
for an old-fashioned Joe, huh?
My compliments.
She also has a good voice.
-Thank you.
-Naturally.
So l am putting her into a show.
-Mr. Hubbell, you didn't tell me.
-He's full of surprises tonight.
To Adolph Hubbell, the star-maker.
Are you trying to run me off the street?
Why can't we get together
on my new show?
l'm sure we can find something
very interesting in it for this young lady.
Well, everyone seems to have my future
pretty well settled.
l don't know. We'll see
about backing your show. Maybe.
How much l write in my checkbook
depends on how much l got to say.
Mr. Hubbell,
you're producing the show.
l'll give you the check tomorrow.
All made out and ready for you
to sign, Adolph. There.
Tom Farnham will be at my office at 2:30
tomorrow to run through some numbers.
lt'll be a good time for us
all to get together.
Don't blow on it! After that zombie,
you might scorch it.
-l can pick them, huh?
-So can l.
-Well, see you tomorrow, Miss Howard.
-Fine.
-Good evening.
l remember your mother once sung
a great song, ''Lullaby of Broadway.''
-That was her favorite.
-l'll revive it and let you sing it.
-l got another idea.
-What?
Tonight l am full of them.
We call the show Lullaby of Broadway.
May l have your order, madam?
l'm so excited, l think
l'll just have crackers and milk.
And for dessert she has shrimp cocktail,
steak, potatoes and coffee.
-And you?
-Another double zombie.
Yes, sir.
-They're very nice, but $ 1500?
-lt is our established price.
Then how come the model l see
in the window-? This one, you see.
Please, please, come down.
No, you are the one should come down.
The price here is only 1400. Yes.
Mr. Hubbell, are you all right?
Would you like some water?
-Water? A double zombie.
-That's a nice jacket you're modeling.
You got nothing better to do
than peek in store windows?
l'm sure it'll look much nicer
on your wife.
-l'll take it. This one in the window.
-Yes, sir, l'll have it giftwrapped.
l'll come and put the card on it
and take it with me.
lt isn't for my wife.
Don't mind me,
l still read The Bobbsey Twins.
lt's for a girl who is lonely in New York.
l want her to know she has a friend.
No better way to win friends
and influence girls.
You keep it under your hat.
l wouldn't want it to drip out.
My lips are sealed.
And now, if you have to be
at Ferndel's office by 2:30...
...please don't let me detour you.
Hello, doll. Who's inside?
Somebody trying out?
-Mr. Hubbell has a little surprise for you.
-For me?
Take a look.
-Surprise!
-Yes, surprise.
-But the sock is on the other shoe.
-What's this about?
l'm giving her a part
in Lullaby of Broadway.
-That's great.
-That's wonderful!
Only a half-hour rehearsal she has...
...and she sings ''Somebody Loves Me''
like nobody in the world.
l'd like to hear it.
Come on, let's do it together.
-You think you can handle this, Buddy?
-Oh, l think l can.
That's enough.
-We work pretty good together, huh?
-Yes, she makes you look good.
Come on, Ferndel,
l think l run along.
-Goodbye.
-So long.
-Bye.
-Goodbye.
Keep working,
maybe she teaches you something.
Well, thanks again for everything.
-l told you l could pick them, huh?
-You certainly can.
Only one mistake l made in my life,
and l married it.
What a small, wonderful world.
Here we are in a show together.
Oh, l can hardly believe it.
-Here.
-Thank you.
Did you really like
the way l did the number?
Honey, in the first part
you were great.
-Oh, good.
-But...
...l think we can improve
on that kiss.
-Care to run through it for a half an hour?
-Thank you...
...but l wouldn't think
of imposing on you.
Oh, that's all right.
l don't mind a bit.
Now, relax.
Approach it like a loser.
lf you're going to fight it,
you'll have a long downhill struggle.
Mr. Farnham, l may have been
in Europe...
...but l'm sure that kissing
is the same the world over.
You'll have to sell me.
And stop calling me Mr. Farnham.
The name's Tom.
Now, here we go.
Close your eyes.
Pucker up.
A little more.
What'd you say your name was?
Hi. What are you two doing up?
-Something wrong?
-lt's Gloria.
She's about to tear down something
that's big and fine and noble.
lt's Mr. Hubbell. Bright eyes here started
something that's gotten a little out of hand.
But how? Mr. Hubbell's been wonderful
to me.
Why, he gave me a part in the show,
and he's been devoting so much time to me.
-Why?
-Well, l guess he thinks l have talent.
lf he doesn't,
then it's just out of friendship.
Come here.
You don't spend money like this
on a friend.
lt was left here this afternoon.
l opened it thinking it was the groceries.
l've never seen anything so beautiful.
Oh, Melinda, you're such a babe
in the woods.
''To keep your little shoulders warm
when l take you to the benefit...
...at the Broadway Theatre. Adolph.''
Oh, isn't that sweet of him?
Yes. lmagine him worrying
about your little shoulders.
Oh, now, wait a minute.
Gloria, you don't really think
that Mr. Hubbell and l-?
At his age? Why, that's
the most ridiculous thing l've ever heard.
l don't know about that.
Lots of times there's snow on the roof
and fire in the cellar.
So what? lf it gets too hot,
you can always turn the damper down.
Oh, you couldn't believe
that of Mr. Hubbell.
l've been around, honey.
As long as they've got a pulse beat,
they're in there pitching.
l'm ashamed of you.
l'm ashamed of both of you.
He shouldn't have sent this expensive coat,
and l'm returning it.
But as far as thinking what you did-
Don't link me with Gloria in this.
Mentally, we're perfect strangers.
Well, l'm gonna show you
how wonderful Mr. Hubbell is.
He's going to get Mr. Ferndel
to give you both a spot in the show.
As for that coat, l'll call the furrier's myself
and have them take it back.
You got a mink coat to return
to Thayler's?
Not so loud. Just a minute.
Come here, Mr. Mack,
and see what l've got.
And l thought Mr. Hubbell
forgot my birthday.
Just look how small he got it.
He thinks l'm still as thin as l used to be.
He's so sweet.
When he sees you, he thinks
of a young, beautiful girl.
Oh, thank you, Mr. Mack.
-You think it's becoming?
-You look charming.
Thank you, Mr. Mack.
Oh, a note.
-Thank you.
-All in the day's work.
Oh, just listen to this. Tonight Mr. Hubbell's
taking me to the Beaux Arts Benefit.
My best evening gown is at the cleaners.
Go get it.
-l got something to tell Mr. Hubbell.
-Tell him later. Go to the cleaners.
l need that dress.
Wait. l'm in a hurry.
Where's that mink?
l couldn't get it back in the box
with what was in it.
-What are you got up for?
-Thank you.
lt's a little small, but your heart
was in the right place.
The jacket! Where you got it? How?
l'm sorry to spoil your surprise,
but l found it on the table downstairs.
Downstairs? How far downstairs?
Downstairs. You did buy it for me,
didn't you?
No. l mean yes, yes.
Oh, and l loved the note
you pinned on it.
What note?
lnviting me to the Broadway Theatre
tonight.
-You did invite me, didn't you?
-No. Yes, yes.
What's the matter?
Don't you want to take me?
No, l- Sure, l-
Why shouldn't l want-?
My darling, l just forget to buy you
the corsage.
Thank you. You've been thoughtful enough
as it is. l'll wait for you downstairs.
Tonight everything happens so quick.
Your wife was like a retriever
the way she went after that fur.
l left it for one second in the hall...
...and the next second
she's rooting it out of the box.
Worse yet. Melinda waits for me
at the Broadway Theatre...
...to take her to the benefit.
You have to go down and
tell her l don't show up.
Say l am sick. And it is no lie.
lt's our night off.
Gloria and me are going bowling.
lt won't take you a minute to stop.
Just so everything in the end
straighten itself out.
But the coat. How do l get
the mink coat back from my wife?
No. lt would ruin the coat.
Mink coat, mink coat.
-Oh, there she is.
-Hi, Melinda.
What are you doing?
l thought you were going bowling.
-We are, but we got a message for you.
-Mr. Hubbell can't meet you. He's sick.
Sick? Oh, that's too bad.
We'll make it up to you
and take you with us.
-Well, hello, everybody.
-Hi, Tom.
ls this private,
or can anybody get in?
Barge right in. We're going bowling.
A foursome?
Thanks very much, Lefty,
but l'm on the bill tonight.
Aren't you overdressed for bowling?
l was going to the theater
with Mr. Hubbell...
...and Gloria told me he's sick
and can't come.
-Hubbell?
-l guess he wanted me to see your act.
You can see it.
l'll take you backstage.
-Oh, good. Do you mind?
-Not a bit.
You can come too, Gloria.
-No, you don't.
-All right, Lefty, l understand.
But why didn't you let me go?
What, are you crazy or something?
Who's gonna set up my pins? Come on.
Ladies and gentlemen,
recently on my trip abroad...
...l visited a famous toy maker
in the beautiful city of Florence.
l discovered he had perfected
life-size mechanical dancing figures...
...of which his toys are replicas.
l induced him to bring
his dancing dolls to America.
So tonight for the first time
in this country...
...the De Mattiazzis present
their dancing mechanical dolls.
Music, maestro, please.
-What are you looking at?
-There's Mr. Hubbell.
Well, he certainly made
a quick recovery, didn't he?
-Tom. Tom, look. lsn't that sweet?
-lsn't what sweet?
Mr. Hubbell gave the mink jacket
to his wife.
lsn't it customary for a husband
to give his wife furs?
Certainly, but in this case
he didn't originally buy it for her.
l'll say he didn't.
Looks a little small, doesn't it?
l guess he forgot we don't wear
the same size.
We? What is this, a sister act?
-You're on next, Tom.
-Right, Eddie.
Go on with me. We're doing
''l Love the Way You Say Goodnight.''
We've rehearsed it enough.
Now we can show it to the boss.
-Are you serious?
-Of course.
l can't dance in this.
-With or without the kiss?
-l don't know.
-Your big romance is out front.
-Oh, silly.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
a surprise.
From the forthcoming show,
Lullaby of Broadway...
...a preview of one of the new numbers.
l hope you like it. Music, professor.
Put her there, partner. l think we're in.
-Melinda.
-Yeah?
l want to get something straight.
Did he buy that mink coat for you?
He wanted to, but, naturally,
l gave it back to him.
-He's been nice enough already.
-Have you been seeing him?
Of course, we're very good friends.
-And you've been going out with him?
-Naturally.
-Why do you ask?
-How much comes naturally with you?
l better take you home.
-You live here?
-Yes.
-But this is Hubbell's house.
-Well, naturally.
-Will you stop using that word?
-He was nice enough to let me stay here.
That's awfully white of him.
Well, it's better than paying
for a hotel room.
What?
lt's a shame we had to leave so early.
We could've gone out together.
That would have been cozy.
He was with his wife.
Oh, what difference does that make?
-lt wouldn't have bothered you?
-Well, of course not.
lt would've given me a chance to tell her
how wonderful Mr. Hubbell's been to me.
You mean, you'd have told her?
Well, why not?
Look, Melinda, l've got to go home
while l still know where l live.
-Hey, aren't you gonna kiss me good night?
-Does everybody?
-Did you have a good time?
-l should've slapped his face.
You had a good time.
-She'll be right along.
-Confidentially, how is she?
She'll be all right
as long as she stays this way.
So long. Don't think
it hasn't been charming.
Don't play another
return engagement, dearie.
-l'm gonna take you right to the house.
-What for?
We've held the curtain long enough.
Time to make an appearance.
ln this condition?
Not a chance, big boy.
l want her to remember me the way
l looked the last time she saw me.
l was young and pretty.
-l was Broadway's darling.
-Jessica, listen.
l was a headliner, a star.
Next to closing, my name in lights.
Nothing was too good
for Jessica Howard.
Now nothing's too bad.
Old, ugly, has-been, once-was.
A voice that even the drunks
won't listen to.
Jessica Howard, the beer singer
of Washington Square.
Why go back to the club?
Just take it easy.
Take it easy? l've got to earn a living.
l've got a kid to support.
l'm dying to see her, Lefty...
...but she's just got to wait
until l straighten myself out.
Come on.
Hello? We should be very happy
to exchange the jacket for a larger size.
But l here can find no record of any coat
for Mrs. Adolph Hubbell...
...of 485 Beekman Place.
Oh, wait a minute, madam.
Yes, there was a call to pick up a jacket.
Yesterday.
From a Miss Melinda Howard
of the same address.
A Miss Melinda Howard, eh?
-Are you sure it wasn't a Miss Gubbins?
-Yes, l'm quite sure.
Thank you, you don't know
what a help you've been.
Adolph.
-Yes, my darling.
-Where are you going?
-To play some pinochle.
-At this hour?
We are having a matine.
-How can you play so much pinochle?
-l force myself.
Lefty.
Gloria.
Oh, l forget, they are at rehearsal.
Melinda. Melinda, l take you to rehearsal.
Melinda, it's me. Adolph.
Would you care to play pinochle with me?
Mama!
Here's your paper, Mr. Farnham.
Thanks, Elmer.
-Melinda.
-Come in.
-Hi.
-Hello.
What does a fella have to do
to make you smile?
As soon as we finish rehearsing,
l'd like to have a talk with you.
ls something wrong?
Just remember, whatever happens,
l'll stick with you.
-How about a statement?
-You deny the allegations?
-How did you meet?
-Did he give you a bracelet?
-ls Mr. Hubbell still in town?
-What?
-Haven't you seen this?
-His wife's gonna sue for divorce.
-Here, read the story.
-Let me read one of these papers.
-Didn't he give you a charge account?
-ls it true you call him Cuddles?
Mr. Hubbell is a gentleman,
and l respect him as l would my father.
-That's all there is to it.
-All right, boys. All right. All right.
Miss Howard has no statement to make.
lf you'll be good sports and wait a minute,
we both may give you one. Deal?
-Okay, Tom.
-lt's a deal.
-Come on out, have a smoke.
-l need a cigarette.
Don't worry, sweetheart.
Everything's gonna be all right.
By tomorrow, they'll forget it.
And as for your mother,
l'm sure she'll understand.
-l hope so.
-l know so.
She'll be just as forgiving as l am.
Forgiving?
What you've done is over.
We're never gonna mention it again.
-What do you mean by that remark?
-The past is over.
We've got the future to look forward to.
What past are you talking about?
l love you, darling.
l want you to marry me.
You left out four words, didn't you?
-What words?
-''ln spite of everything.''
You didn't say them,
but you meant them.
-Oh, now, look, Melinda-
-Look, nothing.
l suppose l should be grateful to you
for offering to make an honest girl of me...
...but l'm not grateful.
l'm just disgusted.
Get out of here.
l never wanna see you again.
-Melinda, please.
-Get out of here.
Miss Howard.
-Please, won't you let me alone?
-l'm not gonna bother you.
Just give me an exclusive
on the story.
l have nothing more to say.
Okay, Miss Howard,
l was only trying to...
Hey, wait a minute.
Are you and Jessica Howard related?
She happens to be my mother.
Jessica Howard of the Three O'Clock Club?
-The Three O'Clock Club? What's that?
-lt's a clip joint down in Greenwich Village.
You mind if l take this?
We don't have a picture of your mother
without a glass in her hand.
Listen, lady, either come in or get out.
You can't stand here.
And now for the local news.
Melinda Howard, pretty actress
named as co-respondent...
...in the divorce suit against millionaire
Adolph Hubbell, has disappeared.
A citywide search has failed
to reveal her whereabouts.
Mr. Hubbell.
Listen, Adolph, what are we going to do
about the show?
lf your wife's divorce suit
chased our star out of town...
...l'm coming up there
and break her arm in three places.
Upstairs, downstairs and in the basement.
Don't forget, we got an attic.
She's probably hiding somewhere,
alone and hungry.
lt's tough starving to death, isn't it?
lt all depends on how much
you like food.
-Hello.
-Hello, Lefty.
Melinda!
Lefty, will you do something for me?
We've hunted high and low for you.
Your mother's in town.
She's been in town all along.
At the Three O'Clock Club.
l don't have to have a brick house
fall on me.
l know she doesn't care anything
about seeing me.
Wait, you've got the wrong angle.
Your mother's had a lot of hard luck.
She didn't want you to know
she was singing in a joint.
Do you think that would've made
any difference?
ls that the best excuse she can offer
for not seeing me?
Well, there were other fluid reasons.
Lefty, l wanna go home on the
Queen Victoria, and it sails this afternoon.
Now, l've reserved my ticket.
Would you come down and pay for it?
l'll send the money back to you
when l get home.
What about the show? lt opens tonight.
They haven't got anybody to replace you.
Do you think l could face people
after all that's happened?
Will you come and help me
with my ticket, or won't you?
Okay, if that's the way you want it.
Who am l to fight you.
ln the hands of a woman,
l'm so much putty.
Everything's all set. You got a nice cabin
several feet from the rail.
-Here's a bottle of seasick pills.
-Thanks, l'll probably need them.
Lefty takes them when he goes
to a newsreel theater.
-Why?
-He gets seasick...
...when he sees the fleet come in.
Come on. Here we are.
Go in and see how you like it.
-Mother.
-That's what it says on the birth certificate.
l guess that's the only way
you could tell.
Melinda...
...don't make it tougher than it is.
But l thought you didn't wanna see me.
You've got it all wrong.
l didn't want you to see me.
Why? Just because you had tough luck?
That's when l should've been
with you.
l know it now, dear.
lf we'd been together,
all this wouldn't have happened.
You've seen the newspapers?
-Do you believe it?
-Of course not.
But you mustn't run away.
Or other people will think it's true.
But l can't stay after all those
terrible things they've said about me.
Look, darling, don't make
the same mistake l did.
All my life l was running away,
trying to hide from unpleasant things.
And look at all the unhappiness
it's caused.
-But what about the Hubbells?
-Mrs. Hubbell knows the truth now.
Thanks to Lefty.
The little man's had a busy day.
l still can't go back.
There's another reason.
Tom?
l never wanna see him again.
He's evil-minded.
He's conceited, condescen-
-How do you know about him?
-Lefty told me.
-You love Tom, don't you?
-Oh, yes.
Look, it's tough for me
to talk like a mother.
l need a couple of more rehearsals.
But if you love that boy...
...don't lose him.
He'll never look at me now.
Not after what l've said to him.
He'll look at you.
And remember this, sweetheart:
From here in, it's you and me together.
Mother.
Can't you wait a few minutes?
The passengers who have this room
are onboard.
How long do you expect to use this room
for $5?
Let's get down to the theater.
l hate peace and comfort. You still got the
2 bucks you were saving for a rainy day?
-Yeah. Why?
-Well, break it out, it's pouring.
-Come on, Melinda.
-Oh, Mother, my bag.