- I almost burst!
- I made you!
I hope you burst, so I won't
ever have to see you again!
- Picking a fight again?
- You are! You block-head!
- Get lost, you insect!
- You sorry excuse of a man!
- Madalena, no more words I said!
- Lambis, no more fighting!
Congratulations for your son.
And for your daughter
the blabber-mouth!
My Madalena was sweet,
she spoke only kind words.
Our dispute is to blame!
Let's make peace.
- Then stop being a boatman.
- I was born a boatman.
I don't know how to do
anything else. I'll starve.
You were a farmer. You became
a seaman just five years ago.
And I'll remain a seaman,
until I make you a farmer.
You and you mulishness! That's
why they call you captain Windy!
And you, captain Calm.
You're such a sorry man!
Who's coming with our boat?
Come with the Flying Bird!
In half an hour,
you'll be in Hora.
Come with the Island Dolphin!
In half an hour it can
bring you back to White Island.
Whoever comes with me
goes fast!
Get out of my way!
- I had a bad dream!
- I had a great dream!
- I saw you got no passengers!
- Get out of my way!
I almost choked!
The damn thing won't work!
You're deafening me!
What are you laughing at?
She's sly.
- She's a girl!
- She's a hazard!
Don't take her
as a daughter-in-law.
- I rather drown.
- Since you can't swim.
- Watch your mouth, Cosmas!
- Don't threaten me!
I'll stick your head in the sea
and you'll make bubbles...
...like the mayor's hookah!
- Get it?
- Are you telling me?
Mr. Mayor...
Mr. Baroutis,
may I ask you something?
- Do I have the permission...
- You have it.
What shall we do with the boatmen?
They're fighting like dogs.
- Let them fight.
- But, we fight, too.
- The village is cut in two.
- Just like we were with politics.
Half of you
are with captain Cosmas...
and the other half
with captain Giorgaros.
You get it out of your system...
and, in the end,
you all vote for me.
We also vote for you
to keep unity in the island.
But does this island
want unity?
- Of course it does, father.
- No, it doesn't.
Don't you remember
when we were divided again...
half with father Anestis,
may he rest in peace...
and the other half, with me?
Two churches, two parishes,
two priests!
And you were with father Anestis,
may he rest in peace.
When one priest was missing...
they wouldn't baptize, marry
or commune with the other one.
You delayed your wedding
for three months...
when father Anestis was sick
in Athens!
The bride almost burst,
waiting for your priest!
Listen to them!
Come with me, I'm a woman!
- She's my passenger.
- Now she's mine!
- Aren't you coming with us?
- I'm going with the sheep.
When the Lord took
father Anestis in his arms...
and I was left the only priest
and there was unity...
after three months you were
separated in two parties again.
In two windmills.
When you were ill in Athens
for four months...
your clients preferred
to starve!
And the others showed them
the loafs...
and they went insane
from hunger.
But the Lord, who is wise,
blew away the one mill.
- And there was peace.
- For six months.
On the seven month, we
were divided in two boats.
He is my uncle!
Come with me uncle,
for aunt's sake!
- He's my uncle, too.
- How come?
What did you tell him?
That you have a cat on board!
He has a dog...
Liar!
Two boats, two parties!
For some reason, we need
to be divided in two.
As if we're asking
for dispute in this island!
Not only us,
but the whole world.
I read the Old Testament
and I only find quarrels!
Even the angels
were divided in two.
That's where the demons
came from.
You sinner!
Does your sainthood allow you
to read the coffee-cup?
It does, when you have to do
with demons and ghosts!
- She's past you!
- She has a short chain.
Father! Untie the rope!
We're sailing!
- Open our sail!
- Hurray, my captain!
- What did you say?
- Didn't you hear me?
- I wanted to hear it again!
You're not good enough
to be a deck-boy!
Don't go against me...
cause I'll make you repent
40 times evening and night...
for 40 days!
You'll loose weight and people
will stop saying...
that you have your teeth
in community funds!
Captain Madalena!
See you later!
- We have to get past him!
- Hold the tiller!
- The boat will turn over!
- Let it!
- You want as to drown?
- We have our pride to think of!
Captain Lambis, I'll dock
and help you with the rope.
Madalena, my child, I don't
want you to fight with them.
- Giorgaros is a harsh man!
- His son is.
You mustn't call them names.
You're a woman, a girl!
- What does that mean?
- You're a fragile creature.
- If you were a son, a male...
- You always say that!
Because I think about it.
If something happens to me...
what will become of you,
six girls and Pantelis?
I have a thorn in my heart.
The doctor said...
dictators and bad hearts never
know when their time will come.
But there is nothing wrong with
you! What do doctors know?
If they knew anything...
Dr. Valintas wouldn't have died
yesterday from a grain in his...
Relax, there's
nothing wrong with me.
You have a great heart,
nothing can happen to it.
I want to see you smile!
See? I'm smiling!
OnIy if you never say again:
"I wish you were a male".
If just need Mr.Lambis' pants
to be a male, too.
- Nothing else?
- What else?
Crew, get on deck!
Time for the mess!
Get in line!
- Violeto!
- Present!
Pothito!... Marouso!...
Hrouso!... Paraskevo!...
And last, Pantelis!
Didn't I sew your
button this morning?
This one!
Now I lost the other one!
- Did you bring me some candy?
- Grandma! You got a sweet-tooth!
Go prepare the donkey,
I'm going to the vineyard.
Let's go, Pantelis.
We'll all go together.
She's better than a son.
But, she's not a son!
- You love him that much?
- Don't be jealous!
You know we grew up together.
Born on the same day
and at the same time.
But he was born a male.
- How do we call our donkey?
- Giorgaros!
To mock captain Windy!
Now, we'll call him "Lambis".
Will he listen to us
now that we'll change his name?
We'll call him so the whole
village will listen...
and laugh at mister Lambis!
The donkey!
Father, come down!
Mr. Lambis is ready!
You always take care of me.
You spoil me.
Bless you, my son!
- I don't want to scare the kids.
- What's wrong, father?
It's nothing.
Father, I'm scared.
It'll pass.
- Shall I take you upstairs?
- Yes, I want to relax.
- Are you well now?
- I'm better.
Come closer.
If anything happens to me...
take care of the children.
Swear to me, that you'll
That's why
I wanted you to be a son.
Now, you'll be a father.
I can't take it...
The captain is crying!
Aren't you ashamed?
I want you to see you
in the storm!
Nothing is wrong with father.
Isn't that right?
Don't look at me with sad eyes.
What can I do to make you laugh?
Do you want me to make
Paraskevo say a difficult word?
Do you want us to sing?
Do you want us to dance?
Let's dance together like
we did the other day.
See the son you have!
Laugh! SmiIe!
What are you doing?
I brought you some spirit
and cotton, son-in-law.
We're dancing
to make father laugh!
That's not a funny dance!
Dance
"How do they grate pepper".
You're right, grandma!
Let's go, guys.
How do they grate pepper...
the devil's monks?
They grate it with their arm!
Well done, children.
They also grate it
with their ass!
They grate it with their rear!
You have my blessing!
Cosmas Haridimos
58 years old
After nine days, will give him
a proper memorial.
He didn't leave you a fortune,
but he left you a name.
A good name
is the best dowry, Madalena.
If anything happens to you,
you come to me.
God embraces the orphans.
And if He sometimes forgets,
He'll never fail you.
Well done, daughter.
You are brave.
The whole village
spoke of your courage.
What are you going to live on,
until you get married?
- We'll live of my boat.
- You'll hire a boatman.
Am I not capable?
I'll sail it.
- You're a girl, a female!
- I might be a female...
but I'm better boatman
than any captain!
- That's how my father called me.
- He was joking!
You don't know me well,
but you will see me.
- I know the village.
- The village will see me, too.
Are you going against
our traditions?
I know nothing about traditions.
I only know what I swore.
My father told me...
"Swear that you'll
take care of the children".
"Be a father to them".
And you're telling me to break
my oath? And you're a priest!
How will I confess to you
so I can commune?
We'll both go to hell! And you
will go much deeper in it!
Do you think that Giorgaros
will let you?
They'll declare war on you!
"In the storm..."
"I want to see you there".
That's what my father told me.
If they want war,
they'll get it.
I heard Madalena will
continue sailing the boat.
Alone?
Don't laugh.
She's not like the others.
- It's her spite!
- It'll harm her.
- Are we going to fight a woman?
- I'll show her!
Not like that!
Don't be harsh.
I say we let her get a passenger
once in a while...
now that her father is dead.
We have to finish with her.
If she gets married...
her husband
will be our rival forever.
We have to fight her,
whether we like it or not!
If they want a war,
they'll get it!
You, eat! And you, Paraskevo!
This is not a game.
We are having a family
meeting here.
Let's have a meeting,
but not a war.
I want a war!
Paraskevo, get the slingshots.
He's going
to kill a chicken again!
I'll kill Lambis' rooster!
You keep your mouth shut!
I'm in a meeting!
Tomorrow morning, the whole
crew is going to the boat!
You'll walk behind me
and then, we'll see.
Who's coming with our boat?
The good boatman is here!
Here's the Island Dolphin!
Whoever comes with me,
goes fast and safe!
Blow your whelk! You can blow
as much as you want now!
- Blow it!
- It broke!
Who's coming with the boat?
We're leaving!
Who's coming with our boat?
Have some eggs, but I can't
come with your boat.
Take your eggs back,
we thank you.
My siblings are not beggars!
Who's coming with our boat?
That's it.
Release the cable!
Who's coming with our boat?
Not even one.
I told you so.
Man can become a monster
for his ego.
Not even a couple
from compassion?
I would have thrown them out!
I need no charity!
I know you well, they don't.
They don't trust you!
They're scared that they'll
drown with a girl like you.
A girl like me?
They'll see me now!
Kids, get in!
- We're taking the priest?
- We're going to the demons!
We'll get them! Hold up, my boat!
Hold up, Madalena.
Our Father who art in heaven,
Hallowed be thy name.
The kingdom come.
- What are you saying?
- I'm praying so will catch them.
Hold tight
and we'll catch them!
I wish I had a flag!
Pantelis,
take your pants off.
Captain Lambis,
this is the fIag that suits you!
Silence! Shut up!
Peace be with you!
I'm taIking!
What happened this morning
was inhumane!
Are we going to leave
seven orphans to starve?
What do you think, Lambis?
The priest is right!
This morning
you called her names!
That's business. Human
kindness is something different!
So is nobility!
Well done, son.
I was happy to see our boat full,
but when I saw hers empty...
and the children
dressed in black...
Six children, Harisis.
Didn't your heart bleed?
Don't take any passengers
and let them in the other boat.
Business is business.
But you should say so,
when you see something wrong.
I have to say it.
If I don't, I'll choke.
I can't even think
of such things!
Because your head is filled
with debts and interests.
While the sea blows in our
heads and clears them.
How can you trust your life
in boatman wearing a dress?
I'm in a dress and you
trust me with your soul!
She doesn't have a sweet tongue!
She was booing people!
- She is wild.
- She's been wronged!
Whoever is wronged, turns wild.
That's why the notables
must make things right...
so she'll be calm again.
That is what we'll do today.
Do we have an agreement?
- The bell!
- Who is ringing it?
It's ringing from the strange
things it heard!
Can it be a fire?
Maybe something
happened to Lambis!
- I'll faint!
- Leave it for later!
You know everything, that's
why they call you "newspaper".
You're the sergeant's wife!
Move aside!
- Who killed? Where's the body?
- What happened?
We'll find out! I'm going
to the scene of the crime.
Move aside!
The authority is here!
The authorities!
- Where is the body?
- There is no body.
- The murderer?
- This is the offender!
- The donkey?
- He rang the bell!
The rope is cut and they
have put a vine here.
The donkey smelled the vine,
chewed on it...
and the bell rang.
They were saying
that I was ringing it.
- Whose is the donkey?
- Madalena's.
She always creates trouble.
There she is.
- What did you do?
- He embarrassed us.
- Is it his fauIt?
- Is it mine?
It's the one's who tied
the vine on the rope.
You did that, mayor.
And you are a churchwarden!
Didn't I tell you to buy
some rope for the bell?
We had to call a meeting
to decide on the sum.
You did it because
of your nearness!
It's your fault!
You let your donkey run free!
It's your fault, you Scrooge!
- You're calling me Scrooge?
- The whole village does.
They call you a miser
and a thief!
You are presumptuous!
Hear her, fellow-citizens?
And you wanted me to travel
with her boat out of charity!
I don't want to hear
that word again!
I don't need your charity!
Leave me alone!
You torturers!
Let me bless you!
Not the holy water, again!
So we won't get a bad eye
now that our boat is doing well!
Madalena's grandmother
does the same.
I don't know why God listens
to our prayers...
and not to seven orphans.
You feel bad for them, too.
The poor things.
- What about Madalena...
- I don't feel sorry for her.
I admire her.
She fights like a man.
And that pride of hers!
Sometimes, she makes me proud!
Take the wheat to the mill.
They're grinding today.
You'll load me
like a donkey again!
Come on, Lambis!
You're walking like
you're wearing heels today.
Maybe you're sad, too.
We're grinding our last wheat.
The Lord might forget,
but He never fails you.
Quit with the melancholy!
Why the long face?
You look like Mr. Lambis
when he saw our boat full.
Check out that load!
Let's go see him up close.
- Did I talk to you?
- Did I?
- You laughed.
- I laughed at my donkey.
He complaints about the load.
Doesn't he see you?
- What can I tell you?
- Nothing.
Your tongue is sticking out!
- Throw it over.
- Leave me alone.
Throw it over!
You're a sorry sight.
- You hate me that much?
- It's not because of that.
- Why then?
- You call me names all the time.
You're calling
your donkey Lambis.
My donkey is not just any
donkey like... I better not say...
He's a donkey with pride,
not like... I better not say...
- And you are a...
- Come on!
You're lucky I'm dying
to have a cigarette!
Isn't it nice?
- I told you so.
- You have a kind heart.
In spite of what they say...
- "Nice but tough".
- As for tough...
You scare me!
There's a strange sight!
I'll help you.
- Leave it, that's mine.
- I'll carry it upstairs.
He's not like we say he is...
I think it's time I stopped
calling you Lambis.
- Who's first?
- Lambis came first.
- You would have gone past me.
- Because of the donkey.
- You grind yours first.
- You go.
We can go back together and
you'll get to smoke on the way.
I'll grind for both of you.
You mustn't fight.
Such a beautiful girl
and such a handsome man...
should do other things together
and not fight.
- What are you talking about?
- What is this?
Stop with the fighting...
join your boats
and make a partnership.
That can't happen,
we won't compromise.
Think I would compromise?
Compromise with what?
You've got no one left.
You took everyone
with lies and dirty tricks.
- Calling names again?
- I'll do as I pIease!
Get out of here!
You're not called "Lambis"
anymore, but "Mayor".
You'll be just like him.
You can yammer and kick,
so you'll be just like the Mayor.
Mayor!
They gave me nickname!
I won't dare
to look at a donkey again!
That's what she did to me.
Get it?
She calls me a donkey!
I don't get one think.
How can she call you donkey,
when you are not one.
- She's calling you a donkey?
- She's calling the donkey "mayor".
Then the donkey
should file a complaint!
You confused me!
Who's the donkey
and who's the mayor?
Go arrest Madalena
and use handcuffs.
- We have no handcuffs.
- Use a rope.
Since we have no handcuffs,
keep your hands together.
- On your back!
- I get it.
- What will they do to you?
- They won't hang me.
They might fry my a bit.
But, I'll fry them, too!
- You've strapped her too tight!
- Release yourself.
Come here.
Your name and your residence.
Why won't you answer?
Are you kidding me?
You know all that!
I have to write a report.
Are you going to disgrace me
in the papers?
It's not for the press,
it's for my records.
I don't have to explain myself
to you! I'm a sergeant.
What are you now?
A war hero?
You'll have to defend yourself!
Why name your donkey "mayor"?
- That's criminal vituperation!
- The mayor is the criminal.
He's letting my siblings
starve to death.
If you were just, you should
have brought him here.
But you're no better
than him!
- Better than who?
- I won't fight about that!
- Put her behind bars.
- We have no bars.
- Take her to jail.
- We have no jail.
Let's built one now
that we have the chance.
That's how I want you to march!
How's the prisoner?
She's hungry!
I'm starving!
- Of course, it's two o' clock.
- We haven't eaten either.
- Let's go, Hercules.
- Duty first!
You'll starve all day
for correction!
- Hercules, the girl is eating!
- Thank you, Mrs. Sergeant
Mrs. Deputy Governor!
She won't eat!
- But I'm hungry!
- I spoke!
You say what your wife
tells you!
He's sleeping.
- How did you get here?
- We've been hiding.
The guard is sleeping.
- When will they hang you?
- Why hang me?
They put you in jail!
- Did you feed the donkey?
- I took a sack of straw to him.
Shame on you,
torturing a girl like that!
You are right!
I told the sergeant, but...
- But why do you care?
- I don't!
She calls me
names all the time!
I'm just saying, that
you can't treat a girl like that.
You are forbidden
to care for the girl.
What you're doing is harsh.
Tell your sergeant
that Lambis said so!
You're forbidden to speak
like that about my sergeant.
- You spoke like that.
- I'm an authority.
Authorities have the right
to insult each other.
It's a common thing. But I
forbid you to care for the girl.
- He's right!
- What did you say?
Why are you
interfering in our business?
- They locked you up!
- It's their right!
Is it their right to lock up
a girl in a basement?
They don't have a proper prison?
- A girl? A fragile creature?
- You are fragile!
I came here
to get you out and you...
Who told you that I want out?
I like it in here!
She's right.
Why would you care?
What do you care
what we do between us?
- Split!
- Hit the road!
You're a lunatic!
I'm leaving!
Have a safe trip!
Well done!
- You told him right!
- Thank you!
He came here to act
like a savior! A man!
Now he got a taste of Madalena.
Men are ridiculous!
Your cooking is remarkable!
That's why I'm going
to pardon the prisoner...
so she'll eat and I won't
have to worry about her...
and spoil my feast!
That's all I needed! Roses!
Two months now, the same thing!
- Good morning, my child.
- Good morning, father.
You came to the dock again?
It doesn't matter,
what you tell them!
- They fear the mayor.
- And won't fear the Lord.
I hear you are selling
your vineyard.
I owe the grocer
and his pressuring me.
The mayor put him up to it.
- Patience, child. The Lord...
- The Lord...
Any objection is forbidden.
The Lord my forget,
but He'll never fail you!
- Will you take me across?
- You must be in a hurry.
I decided to go with your boat.
I'll tell my siblings and my cousins!
To as many as I can!
He won't fail you!
Get in, Mr. Yakoumis.
Get in with your right foot!
Maybe we'll get our luck back!
Bless the Lord!
Forgive me Lord, but I'll get
Yakoumis for what he did.
- You have a sweet voice.
- I'm happy.
Thank you
for not fearing the mayor.
I wonder myself,
but love can defy anything!
- Love?
- I have you in my heart.
That's why you came
with my boat.
I fear the sea. I wouldn't get
in a boat sailed by a woman.
"When the captain is a woman,
the passenger is a fool!"
- What are you doing?
- Taking you back.
I want people to come with my
boat because I'm a captain...
not because I'm a girl!
- I want to marry you.
- I want passengers, not grooms!
If I marry you, you'll trap me
in the fields and the animals...
and I'll have to leave the sea!
The world will come to an end!
- You're in love with the sea.
- In love? What is that?
The sea is something else!
I love its space, its wind,
its saltiness!
- And its storms!
- They're sweet, too.
It's the sea, not milk
to turn it into yogurt!
You are persistent!
I wasn't lucky today.
All our prayers went to vain!
That's it. 3.215, 60.
- My father told me 2.500.
- You don't remember correctly.
Those were his last words.
You don't forget such things.
Maybe the diseased
didn't remember correctly.
I thought that from the 3.000
I got from my vineyard...
I would have something left.
Take it all
and I'll owe you the rest.
Are you doubting me?
I have everything written here.
- You know well how do add.
- And you how to multiply...
I sold you.
I sold you to pay our debts.
What are you looking at me for?
We've been together for 17 years.
Wouldn't you have sold me?
What? The boat?
The boat is sacred,
don't be disrespectful.
Don't look at me, because...
I have to turn you over.
You seem in a hurry. I always
knew you were ungrateful.
I shouldn't have fed you
all that straw!
Come...
I want to get rid of you!
Don't stare at me!
You won't make me feel sorry!
The last thing I need
is to burst in tears.
My poor donkey!
The mayor got you!
My poor Mayor,
the donkey got you!
Are you hungry?
- You are. Want cheese?
- No, I don't.
In Madalena's home they are
suffering. They have no food.
You mind your own business!
They went to the grocery, but
Harisis didn't give them anything.
- Hear me, Lambis?
- Why are you telling me?
Tell it to her.
She's arrogant and hot-tempered!
- You used to call her proud.
- She's quarrels like a man!
She can't be a woman!
Get off my case with her!
You are teaming.
So I won't forget that once,
I was a teamster.
You're a priest.
But I can also be a teamster
if needed.
Here, I sow
and I get a crop.
At church, I sow my words
and very few listen.
That's why once in a while,
I fetch my animals.
Why didn't you come
to confession?
I'm not worthy to commune.
I've sinned.
- Did you fall in love?
- That's the last thing I need!
- Then, why did you sin?
- Because of hatred.
Let's go to church.
I hate everyone.
Can you believe that?
Even you.
And I had you like a father.
I want everyone's harm.
When I here that something
happened to someone...
a bad turn, a sickness, a death...
I feel happy.
When I see people laughing,
I'm heart-broken.
I think of dark thoughts.
I want to break, to destroy,
to do harm.
Not just to some people,
but to the whole village.
I stopped praying at night.
You want to know why?
In my prayers,
I prayed for harm.
I pleaded God
to burn this island!
- Did you say everything?
- As much as I could.
I need to hear no more.
I can't stand any more.
You have my blessing.
You can commune.
- I'll be shaking.
- No, I will.
O Lord Jesus Christ my God
I commit my spirit.
Do Thou bless me, do
Thou have mercy on me...
The priest will silence now
and the teamster will take action.
The good teamster...
My Lord, show mercy...
but sometimes you forget
about your White Island.
You forgot about Your child,
the orphan.
Maybe you left this to me.
You don't have time
for everything. Right?
It must be that way.
I understand.
So I'll act according
to Your will.
Madalena, your torments
will be soon over.
I have a plan.
It was hard to decide it,
but the Lord helped me.
- He spoke to me.
- What did he tell you?
He told me...
I don't have to explain to you
what the Lord told me!
Those are secrets of the business.
The day after tomorrow,
on Epiphany Day...
when we'll throw the cross
in the sea, you...
I want you to catch the cross
this year, too.
- That's what you say every year!
- For the good of our business.
- Wear this charm.
- Another? I told you, I'll catch it.
Five years now, our Lambis wins.
Beware of Sotiris and Grigoris.
They practiced new dives.
Leave me alone!
I'm going to find a good spot.
Do as I told you.
Be ready.
I'm scared.
Don't be scared,
I'm here for you.
Be ready.
My Lord, please forgive me,
the sinner.
- I'm shaking!
- I make the rules here!
The cross fell up front!
I caught it!
You caught the cross?
This hasn't happened since 100
years ago when my grandmother...
Maybe it's a sign from heaven.
What do you say, Christians?
Is this Your will?
Have we wronged the orphan?
Since we've wronged her, we
must make good as Christians.
Don't say too much.
We'll get caught.
- Since we wronged the girl...
- The captain!
we must make good now.
From tomorrow, whoever doesn't
travel with the girl's boat...
- With captain Madalena's boat...
- Just "captain"!
I'm no God or doctor
to change your sex!
From tomorrow, all of you
travel with her boat...
- Not all, half of them.
- I'll throw it back in!
Whoever doesn't go with her boat,
I'll put him in my books.
And what is written,
can't be erased!
Forgive them, my Lord,
and me, too...
and bless Your White Island
which has repented.
Blow, you deadbeat!
You weren't even worthy
of catching the cross!
Look! We're doomed!
I don't want anymore
with my boat, they are enough!
- Uncle! You come.
- I'll go with the blessed.
- Aren't you coming with us?
- I'm going with the blessed.
- Won't you come with the sheep?
- I'm going with God.
Release the cables!
We broke the spell!
We're sailing!
- I see you're singing!
- See our food!
Potatoes, beans
I hadn't seen for months...
spaghetti my grandmother makes...
- Oil, rice, soap...
- Halva!
That's why we sing.
Food and songs go together.
And captain Giorgaros
is broke and he's cursing!
Those two go together, too.
Since the Lord blessed you,
no one stepped in his boat again!
- He's eating himself up!
- I didn't eat anything!
Crew, let's go!
My Lord, I know you're mad
at your servant.
You heard the poor
children in the morning.
Their laughter brought
my eyes tears of joy!
I know, I have sinned.
When You take me in your
arms, I'll pay the price.
But they are seven orphans.
You made them orphans,
let's not forget about that.
There were
extenuating circumstances.
You can forgive
your unworthy priest.
- We must get her out of the way!
- She made me look like a fooI!
They're calling me captain Whelk!
I'm always with a whelk in hand.
- Your throat must be sore.
- Silence, women!
It's the only way
we'll get rid of her.
Our plan must remain secret.
- It's a sin. She's an orphan.
- Shut up!
- Don't defend her!
- We're striving for you.
- For your dowry.
- I don't want that dowry.
We'll destroy seven orphans
for my dowry!
- Have you lost your mind?
- You lost your compassion.
You were proud to be a fine man.
I was proud of you
and now I feel shame.
Thank you, brother.
I'll never forget this.
You praised Madalena
and spoke of her pride!
He spoke such words.
He made me love
and feel for Madalena.
Who the hell leaves these?
Is he some ghost?
Think somel ghost
fell in Iove with me?
- Are you talking to yourself?
- I wanted to see you.
I heard you fought with your
parents and took my side.
- I like you.
- It's not a small thing.
When everyone is after you,
it's good to know...
I heard they slapped you.
Did it hurt?
- I've never been slapped.
- It was my first time, too.
And all that for me.
Rozina, I'll give you this rose.
- It's not worth anything for me.
- Who gave it to you?
A ghost! I find one
on my boat every morning.
- Some fool must put them there.
- Fool or in love?
Same thing.
This is a rose
with one hundred leafs.
We are the only ones in
the island with roses like this.
Come with me to our garden.
It's the only rose-bush
of this kind in the island.
Whoever cuts it,
cuts it from here.
- But who?
- Who else?
Who can get in our garden?
Think about it.
I don't know. Who?
Lambis.
Your brother?
He swears at me all day long.
He swears at you in public,
because he secretly loves you.
How can that be?
Men are very shy.
When they're in love
they're too shy to admit it.
He brings you the roses!
He secretly loves you!
That's why he tries to kill me?
If he loved me in public,
he'd chop my head off.
Who's coming with my boat?
Here's the Island Dolphin!
Whoever goes with me goes...
- No shouting today?
- No.
- How come?
- No reason.
This is a safe boat!
The captain is male!
When the captain is female,
the passenger is a fool!
No swearing either.
- How come?
- No reason.
- You're getting shy, finally.
- You're the shy one.
Men are very shy.
I'm not too shy to swear at you
after the names you've called me!
Arrogant! Skinny! Basket-case!
- Go on.
- You like it?
I like it!
The girls are getting
the magic water...
to see if they are going
to marry quickly.
Weddings, children,
christenings...
Children grow, get married,
bear other chiIdren...
Grow and conquer
the White Island with my blessings!
Does the church accept
these traditions?
No, that's alchemy.
All the free men gather branches.
The crier is calling them to
prepare for Saint John's fires.
There will be a big feast tonight.
Is it true that those who jump
more times over the flames...
are going to marry sooner?
Don't cause me to sin!
That's alchemy.
- Once more, Lambis!
- Once more, Rozina!
Come jump, too.
- She's not for such things.
- She wears a dress.
So what?
She says so herself...
She's a boatman, not a woman.
The good boatman is here!
The male boatman is here!
When the captain is female...
the passenger is a fool!
A captain with a dress...
You're laughing?
I'm laughing.
I'm in a good mood.
- What is that?
- You're asking me?
This is strange.
She's going crazy!
I'll drown her!
The good boatmen are here!
Whoever goes with me goes fast!
Whoever goes with him goes safe!
The good boats are here!
I got you!
So you're bringing me
the roses!
All of them?
What can I tell you?
Are you an officer or a ghost?
And you're a thief, too. You
must have stolen over 50 roses.
Sixty-seven.
Will you take me to the other side?
On one condition: No more roses!
I was mocked!
Why are you mad?
Because I thought
you were someone else.
So you didn't place the roses?
That's what we thought.
She showed me the roses and
I thought she was mocking me.
She was mocking herself.
And now, she's in love with you.
- Are you serious?
- With all I told her...
Words! Us women, like words!
What happens now?
Explain to her so she'll
stop imagining things.
Why should she stop?
Cut me a rose!
You liar! You fraud!
You cheater!
You dare speak to me?
Liar! Cheater!
Stop shouting!
The whole village will hear us!
I don't need your words,
your doings will do!
- It's Rozina's fault!
- You're the same blood!
- You'll be sorry for what you said!
- I'm not scared of you anymore!
Madalena's boat is over.
The poor orphan will starve.
Giorgaros bought a petrol boat.
It's not a small thing.
A boat with an engine!
The new technology is coming!
- We'll crush that damn female...
- Now she'll stop bragging!
This is the end of poor Madalena.
My boat... My Madalena...
What do we do now?
Give the coin back!
Aren't you ashamed to cry now
that they are laughing?
Be a man!
I won't cry... I'm a man...
But what about the coin?
The coin will show them
that we have no hatred.
The Lord is Great for those
who have a great heart.
That's what father Fotis says.
Of course the Lord is Great...
In His greatness
He made a mistake.
He gave us more brain
than we need...
and we build all these machines
that will give us a better life...
while they only bring disaster.
No one comes
with your boat anymore.
They go with the engine boat. They
even forgot about the blessed.
They rather go the fast way.
Fast!
That will eat us up!
Didn't I once buy a fast mule...
which threw me off its back
and I broke three ribs.
I brought a candle
to light in honor of the saint.
The saint needs no candles.
Candles are for people.
Saint Nicolas
takes care of the seamen...
What can the saint do?
This is an engine...
It's technology...
The devil's craft...
The engine won this battle.
Can't the Lord
fight the engine?
Of course He can,
but He doesn't want to.
Don't ask me why.
No one knows His will.
No, thank you, Mr.Yakoumis.
Madalena doesn't want charity.
It's not charity, it's a gift.
Two heads of cheese.
What if we take one head
so Madalena won't be that angry.
- There she is.
- What brings you here?
I was passing by
and stopped to say hello.
Did you bring food?
You're not holding anything.
I brought it
while you were playing.
We're having rice-soup.
Don't you believe me?
I'll got put the pot on fire.
- Where is this going?
- If she hears you, she'll be furious!
- Did you tell her about me?
- I didn't dare to.
- You didn't put the rice in.
- Let the water boil first.
- Grandma puts the rice first.
- I put it later.
I must be going.
Have a nice evening.
You are bad!
I will fight! I still have courage.
You have been defeated.
Admit it.
You tried things
that were difficult.
You were a woman
working like a man.
That's what makes me furious!
They hurt my pride.
Forget about the boat.
Marry Yakoumis who keeps
coming to me to convince you.
How will I marry him?
I don't love him.
What will become of you?
You're starving.
Consider your siblings.
You swore to your father!
And I'll keep my promise.
I decided to sell my house.
I'll buy an engine-boat, too.
I won't let that fraud Lambis
laugh at my expense!
I will take my revenge.
And you will sell your house
for revenge?
How will you marry
when your time comes?
Here they say that a bride with
no home, is a groom with no pants!
I know, but I'll sell it!
That spite of yours!
Women confess in me
all these years...
and they are still
a mystery to me.
Yes, father...
I'll sell the house.
You were a captain, too.
You understand.
And you will forgive me.
Fire...
The children...
Help!
The orphan is alive!
Bring me a blanket!
Keep away!
My tormented child...
A bride with no home...
- Where is she going?
- What is she doing?
She'll burn!
She's lost her mind.
Get up...
Be strong...
For the children.
For the oath you gave.
Yes, father Fotis.
I know. I understand.
- Let's go.
- Where?
To Yakoumis.
Sacrifice and mercy.
May God bless you!
Tomorrow...
Tomorrow we'll have
your engagements.
Right, Madalena?
Right... Tomorrow...
- You are very happy.
- Yes, but something concerns me.
Madalena has no love inside her.
That might separate us
sooner or later.
The people I wed,
love can't separate them.
Stop drinking...
You'll get drunk.
I will get drunk.
We're celebrating!
Have something to drink.
It'll give you a good mood.
I'll find my mood.
When I say "yes", I mean it.
Don't drink anymore,
you'll get dizzy.
I'm already dizzy.
- So you really love her.
- Shut up!
I just asked.
You don't ask a fooI
of his foolishness.
- Yakoumis, won't you dance?
- If Madalena wants to.
The circumstance calls for it.
PIay a "baIos" dance!
I wish I could kiss
your eyes, Madalena.
Your sweet mouth.
- May I?
- Of course.
- I don't want to.
- It's tradition.
And if I deny him?
Then I'll have to fight him.
I'll dance.
- So you're getting married?
- It doesn't concern you.
- Marrying the one you loath?
- He's not the only one.
- You loath me, too?
- Dance and don't talk.
I love you.
You can't imagine how much.
- You are crazy...
- Not yet.
- But if I loose you...
- You're drunk.
When I heard you were getting
married, that's when I realized.
It seems I'm in love with you
for a long time.
- And you swore at me!
- I was selfish.
I didn't want to admit
I loved you.
- And you crushed me.
- Now you crushed me, too.
Play a fast "balos"!
Let the organs play!
I want to dance!
- I'm lost without you.
- Stop it, I'll scream.
- You'll be lost, too.
- Let me.
Is that all you have to say?
Nothing more?
Now, I have nothing...
Slowly...
I loath you...
Stop the music!
I can't take it anymore!
Our life is in your hands.
Both mine and Madalena's.
She wants me, too. And
not the one you're giving her.
If I don't marry her, I'm lost.
I'll do crazy things.
- I'll have her by force.
- Never! I'll curse you.
Then I have nothing left,
but the sea.
You love her that much?
If we weren't in a church
I could open my heart to you.
I would shout it out
and you'd believe me.
I love her.
Like you love the Virgin Mary.
- Are you leaving?
- I shouldn't have come.
I came to ask for your help
and today you'll engage them.
I can see it...
It's too late.
Since I fixed this wedding...
I will have to...
My Lord,
what do your Christians ask for!
They'll be saved
and I'll end up in hell!
- Shall we start, Madalena?
- And get over with it.
Do you Yakoumis take Madalena
to be your wife?
If Madalena agrees, I do.
Do you take Yakoumis to
be your husband and master?
I do.
I have to remind you...
- This is your life.
- Seven lives.
If you have changed your minds
there is still time.
Father, bless us.
The child of the Lord,
Iakovos...
is engaged
to the child of the Lord...
The child of the Lord,
Madalena...
is engaged
to the child of the Lord...
Lambis!
I know what I'm saying, son.
What love brings together,
no man can separate.
- So you're getting married.
- To tall handsome man!
I wish you
a life to be a bed of roses!
But not with a hundred leafs!
- It stopped.
- The engine broke down.
I'll fix it now.
Crew, get in!
Captain, throw a rope
and I'll pull you!
Subtitling
www.videopress.gr