Film by
featuring
production manager
dramaturge
sound
music
choreographer
music producer
editor
written by
composer
photography
directed by
Rock and roll!
Go on.
Hi!
Come with me.
How long did you spend
in the United States?
Four years.
And then six months in Manchester.
Manchester!
- Did you see any football?
- Of course.
We lived next to the stadium.
Manchester are no big deal,
are they?!
Honved would thrash them!
- Go Honved!
How long do you plan to stay?
- A pretty long time.
- More specifically?
Twenty or thirty years, minimum.
Could you tell me
why you came back to Hungary?
Because of Honved.
The footie's better here.
- It's all been organised
with the Ministry. - Really?!
We'll soon see about that.
Yes?
Yes!
Sixty-two forint.
Sixty...
...two.
Who are you?
Balogh. I'm the joint tenant.
The bathroom is mine
until 5:30
and the kitchen until 7:00.
Everything is yours after 8:00.
Stay with me tonight!
Baby-doll, Stay with me tonight!
I'm on my knees and begging please,
Stay with me tonight!
Stay tonight now please!
One more night is all I need!
Baby, baby, give this night to me!
Stay with me tonight!
Stay tonight now please!
Solo...
Stay, babe...
Stay, babe!
Stay with me,
You're my baby!
Stay with me tonight!
Thanks a lot!
That was the Angela Band!
Angel Land, Angel Land.
Sure, that's right.
You boys go and load your stuff.
I'm delighted to welcome everyone
on such a beautiful day.
You can come a bit closer!
Don't be scared, I don't bite!
- You were great!
- Thanks.
- Did it sound okay?
- Brilliant! You were great!
Can we carry your guitar, Rone?
No one want to take this?
Hi, baby! You look wonderful!
And now for one of the musical
highlights of the afternoon,
from the Number-Two Automobile
Repair Workshop
the one and only Figaro!
You show them, son! Go on!
There are places in the world
abroad today,
Where they only think of work
and never play.
Over there they've got it all wrong,
They should all sing this song.
The work you do means more
than just pay.
The Angela Band was really good!
Angel Land.
- I'm counting on you for state
holidays! - Will you pay us then?
You got drinks, didn't you?
- Didn't you get your "Bambi"?
- Sure!
Thanks for the refreshments,
Comrade Bigali!
Enjoy!
Bigali can stuff
his "Bambi" up his...!
Csipu, go get some shots
and a tray of beer.
You are loaded!
So lift your hands up high
and all sing after me.
So lift your hands up high,
up up up high, up high
and all sing after me.
Over there they never have
a happy day.
- Cheers!
Who's that?
I don't know.
I've never seen him before.
A mango and vanilla shake.
- Have you run out?
- We've just got this!
He looks bloody familiar...
Hi, Csipu!
Hi there...
- Miki!!
- Kids, it's Miki!
- Hi, guys!
- Hi, Miki!
- You look great!
- Thanks.
- Shit hot!
- Hey! Watch the hair!
- Okay. Hi! Welcome to Hungary!
- Drink this instead!
What is it?
- Whiskey!
- No! Really?
An Elvis lighter!
- Let's have a look!
- Kid!
- Have you crawled back home?
- Shame you missed us!
We played
"Stay Here Tomorrow"!
- What?
- It's cool!
- We got it off Radio Luxembourg!
- Hang on!
- You know Frank Sinatra?
- We did him too.
No one listens to Sinatra
anymore.
Really?
- Will you tell us
what they listen to? - Sure!
Stuff like Johnny Cash
and Jerry Lee Lewis!
- I love Jerry Lee!
- You should see him live.
You've seen Jerry Lee live?
Don't swallow everything!
I saw him in Kansas City with
Johnny Cash and Carl Perkins.
- You saw Carl Perkins?
- Come on!
Perkins!
- Perkins...
- No!
- Perkins.
- Perkins!
What about Kansas City?
The best thing
that ever happened to me!
Was it wild?
Wild? The support band went off
and all the lights went out.
Then a thousand spots
came on all at once
and Jerry Lee was standing
at the piano.
He wore sequined white
trousers,
a French wig on his head,
and silver moccasins.
He said...
Don't drink all the whiskey!
"I stick my finger in hot pussy
and wipe it along the keys
so the stride slides better."
That's wild!
Jerry started with his left hand
and then the right joined in.
A gentle tinkle
and the feet started.
Then the knees.
Let's see your knees!
Comrades! Emergency!
Urgent police intervention
is required!
Fucking move!
Welcome to
employees of the interior Ministry.
You are the swift response unit!
What are you playing at?!
Let's show them a really
happy day!
Left hand's boogie,
right hand's rock,
Show us girls, what you all got!
Let's rock,
everybody rock.
The people's will can't be stopped
When we go wild
with the people's rock!
Way down south,
back of the woods,
I grew up there,
the best I could.
Through the good times and the bad
the boogie was the only hope I had.
So I took my chance
like Memphis would.
Where the southern sun
never fails to shine,
The boogie-woogie rhythm
was always mine.
Playing the piano night and day,
All those southern girls
came out to play.
The dance floor is the place for me,
Two hands where they should
always be,
Between the waistband and the knee!
Music from the USA,
Playing in the park for you today.
We ain't listening
to what you say.
Let's rock,
everybody rock.
In the shadow of the Eastern Bloc,
Let's go wild with the people's rock.
Just one thing:
don't never give up.
Life's a Coca-Cola,
so drink it up!
Closer, closer! A bit closer!
You can be what you want to be
from ABC to XYZ.
Good tunes are our only goal,
They simply call it rock and roll!
Water cannons now!
Fuck you too, mate!
Someone went and called the cops,
It'll take much more to make us stop.
Music from the USA
Playing in the park for you today.
We're listening to what they play,
Though we all might get locked away.
This is one lively May Day!
Let's go!
Let's go wild to the people's rock!
We've all gone wild
to the people's rock!
Where have you been?
What do you look like?
- I got wet.
- It hasn't been raining.
A passing shower.
On Tisza Street?
How do you know?
Who grassed?
You are in Hungary now, son!
Everyone sees and hears everything.
Have you been out like that?
I'll fetch a towel.
Just look at yourself!
Pure provocation!
It's just a Hawaiian shirt.
You have to blend
into the background...
Be a sparrow among sparrows
and not parade around
like a cockatoo!
You never had a problem
with this shirt before!
- It was fine on 5th Avenue but
not here. - Really?
So why aren't we still
on 5th Avenue?!
Did I ask you to
drag me back here?!
This is our home, my boy!
It's your home!
I'm really sorry, Comrade Miltenyi.
It's not my fault.
They changed the programme
and the youth reacted badly.
They went completely mad.
They're not interested in "Pol-Beat".
They just want the tom-tom.
This is where freedom has taken us.
Have you ever been grape-picking...
Comrade Bigali?
Grape-picking?
When the grapes...
Precisely.
What mustn't you do to the barrels
of grape juice?
Close them. But why?
Why?
Because they start to ferment
and then... boom!
Is the picture clear, Comrade Bigali?
Clear. Completely clear.
The youth have started to ferment and
that's not necessarily a bad thing.
They need to be given space.
Of course, all within strict limits.
There is a new directive,
Comrade Bigali.
We are going to organise
a talent competition.
The youth
can explore their identity
within a cultured environment.
I am depending on you to organise
the district qualifiers.
Thank you.
It will be an honour.
It wasn't easy.
I stood up for you.
Don't let me down... Arpad!
Thank you... Sandor.
Cultural centres across
the country
are filled with the sound
of feverish preparation
as the auditions are announced
for "Show What You Know".
It is important that we increase
our pupils' artistic activity
and for them to take part
in such events.
Entrants are invited for poetry
reading, music groups...
Can you read it, sweetheart?
- "Show What You Know".
- Clever you. That's right!
Do you want it?
Sure.
Any more where that came from?
Are you interested in
American records?
Sure.
Okay.
Cool wheels.
- Can I give it a go some time?
- Sure, why not?
But be careful because
it's brand-new.
- "Brook 'en hairy ha."
- No!
It's "broken heart", man.
You looking for something?
Listen!
Tripolisz on drums, Csipu...
Csipu and Nyiro guitar.
And then you and me.
What do you say?
I know a stack of Jerry Lee Lewis
numbers and we can sing in English.
Like in real English!
It'd be cool.
What do you reckon?
And...
we could think up the hair and
the image and the whole thing.
What?
We could be a pro band.
Balloons, smoke, coloured lights,
backing singers. The whole lot.
The gig could be ready in time
for "Show What You Know".
- Gig?
- Gig!
That's what they call it over there.
Hands off my band, you little monkey!
Summer by the pool,
Sun's hot, water's cool!
The girl's are pretty hot,
Come on down
and you can see the lot!
Let's go a ride on your moped,
I ain't gonna listen
to what my ma said.
Step on the gas
and not on the brake,
Pretty checks are waiting
down at the lake.
We've tried
all the dances on the list,
The time has come to try the twist!
Tune in on my radio,
Rock and roll's the only way to go!
Come on, come on, Julie,
you know I'll love you truly
all the summer long.
The party starts at six
I won't look at other chicks,
Dance the twist with me
and you can't go wrong!
This is a dance not like the rest,
You've danced with the others
but I am the best.
Come on, baby, it will be fine,
Dance with me in the summer sunshine!
I brought it in for a full service.
Let's go and eat.
Hey, what's that?
A tap.
- Tap?
- Press it!
- Thanks fellas.
- Hi, Miki!
Hi there!
- Do you recognise me?
- Of course.
You came back then?
It sort of looks like it.
Who was that?
No one.
Just a girl.
Let's show them all
how to do the grind!
- What's the grind?
- This is the grind!
Now let's show them
how to do the wind!
- What's the wind?
- This is the wind!
- Stamp that cigarette out!
- Go, go!
- If you like, it give a shout!
- Oh, oh!
- Come on now and let it all out!
- Go, go!
Let's go!
I guess this means we're not going
to the cinema tonight.
Sure we are! Eight o'clock.
We agreed to meet at eight.
What's going on?
Grab him!
What's that?
Buddy Holly?
What kind of name is Buddy?
Buddy Holly.
- He's American.
- America? Typical.
And they've got the atomic bomb?
Has the world gone mad?
Buddy and the boys have got the bomb.
Where did you get this from?
Are you distributing contraband goods?
It's not contraband.
- No?
- No!
If I see you here again, I'll kick
your arses! ls the picture clear?
- Clear.
- Sorry!
- It's clear!
- Make yourselves scarce!
No more pool for you this summer.
The Yankee stays where he is.
You're not a bad kid, I know that.
But they don't want to believe me.
Who?
They say that you are
ruining the minds
of the Hungarian youth.
What am I doing?
You have imported this infection,
this virus.
- It's just a record.
- This?
No, son.
This is six years in prison.
Anti-state agitation.
- That's rubbish.
- What did you say?
- I said it's rubbish.
- I thought I heard wrong.
Did your dad bring things like
this back too?
- Insightful literature?
- Leave my dad out of this.
Okay. We can do that.
- Do you know about
"Show What You Know"? - Yes.
I have got a couple of protégés
in the Young Socialists
and a couple of the girls can sing...
Gretchen and Hella might come
with two others from East Germany.
I want you to do something colossal
with them and my son.
What do you say?
Good.
And leave your father to me.
We'll offer him a helping hand.
Tuesday it is then.
Buddy Hooligan.
No more ham?
Bacon, son! Bacon!
Bacon...
Okay, bacon.
Your father has been
to the Ministry today.
They won't take him back.
Kollar doesn't work there anymore,
he's been transferred...
or something.
All new faces.
They promised to let him know
if anything comes up.
We'll just have to make do with
what I earn at the hairdresser's.
And that is very tough
for a man to live with.
Am I interrupting?
Preparations are going
precisely to plan.
The activity of the pupils
is exceeding all expectations.
Very good.
Prosit!
It goes something like this.
Getting ready for my first ball,
And I'll never forget it all.
Jacket and tie, shoes all shined,
I was looking all so fine.
Combed my hair in the barber's chair,
Heard a tune or two
and just dreaming of you.
Join in now!
Ciao Marina!
It was always so great with you!
My love for you was always so true.
I love you.
Your taxi, sir!
Welcome to the winning team!
Ciao Marina!
You're my darling angel from above.
I still don't know
how we fell in love.
I love you.
Stop!
You're speeding up!
Don't be stupid!
- You're all over the place!
- What's your problem?
- I've got the right tempo!
- Entschuldigung!
- Ist Miki zufallig hier?
- Csipu, you're good at Russian.
- Just because I didn't fail!
- Wir suchen einen gewissen Miki.
Hello!
- Tripolisz.
- Gretchen.
- Kak tyibja zavut?
- You idiot, she's called Gretchen.
- Csipu.
- Gretchen.
- Lotti.
- Tripolisz.
- Csipu.
- Lotti.
- Sura.
- Gretchen.
Ich bin malenkij Nyiro.
Oh... they're already here.
Madchen!
Wiedersehen... Ja.
Tschuss...
You can start packing!
Come on, one two!
What are you doing here?
You know...
East German cultural gift hamper.
What's the whispering?
Make yourself scarce!
Well, girls...
Los, los, ja?
- Comrade Bigali.
- Yes?
- Could the boys join in?
- Reach into your mouth,
remove what's in it,
and continue.
Yes?
So, could Csipu and the boys
join us?
It would be good for the girls.
We could rehearse with a band.
Why not? it's a colossal idea!
Okay, you can unpack.
- But we...
- Sorry, kid, no time to waste!
- I'll get you for this.
- It'll be fine, you'll see!
- What?
- Your hair looks great.
Thanks.
- Where are you going, son?
- It's six o'clock.
Get back on stage!
I'll bring a doctor's note, okay...
Bigali?
Right.
You can walk out if you like.
- If I embarrass you or the girls.
- Or me.
We're waiting.
Right.
- What are we going to hear?
- An American...
What?
- Latin... Latin-American
- Sorry?
Cuban...
...a Cuban song.
Great. What's it about?
The workers on the plantation
conspire behind the foreman's back
and discuss where they are to hold
their illegal communist gathering.
Great!
Let's see it!
And the East German girls?
I trust they are in good hands!
Hang on!
I don't understand!
But of course!
Comrade Bigali is looking after them.
Stop a minute!
Where's the plantation?
Is this the illegal plot?
You get out of here!
I don't believe this!
Stop this reactionary music, Miki!
Stop now!
Comrade Bigali?
Comrade Miltenyi.
This is... it's a little...
A little... Cuban Mediterranean...
music that got a little...
How shall I say?
A little song
from the Cuban plantations and...
Kubanische revolutionen...
And that is the point we are at.
More or less.
Ja, stimmt!
Chewing gum?
- What chewing gum?
- No chewing gum.
- Try to be normal.
- Okay.
Don't be your usual self...
Sanyi Miltenyi is
my only influential friend.
He's promised to find me
some acceptable work.
- Do you understand what I am asking?
- He's understood.
The wanderer returns.
Come on in. This way please.
- Hello! And you?
- The young one.
- Hello, my dear.
- Hello!
- Oh, thank you, sweetheart.
Just a bit of lipstick.
Vera! Surprise!
Looks who's here!
Well, you've grown into a big girl!
A young lady.
- Hello!
- Hello, my dear!
- Hi!
What's wrong?
You two used to be so close.
So how was the land of milk
and honey?
Not for us.
They don't make such good stew
do they?
They call it goulash over there.
Goulash?
Goulash is goulash.
And stew is stew.
Am I right?
- Vera made the dumplings!
- Mother!
You cook beautifully!
She's a treasure!
- She'll make some man very happy.
- Did you hear that, Miki?
Miki hasn't got time for that.
He's become very active recently.
I saw it with my own eyes.
- I didn't know that.
- You can be proud of him!
He is preparing four East German
comrades for "Show What You Know".
I'm pleased to hear it.
Vera's entering
the competition too.
- That's not been decided.
- Oh yes it has!
But let's talk about
more serious matters.
What are we going to drink?
Vera!
Why didn't you answer my letters,
Miki?
Why, did you write any?
Did you really write to me?
Don't do that, it's pathetic!
You know I wrote.
Like we agreed.
A letter a week.
I spent all my pocket money
on stamps.
I'm sorry. Really I am.
And I can pay for the stamps...
Who cares about the stupid stamps?
You dropped me, that's all.
No big deal.
I thought we'd never see
each other again.
There was no point
in digging up the past.
- And I'm the past you had to dig up?
- Not at all!
Listen, Miki!
I'm not angry with you.
We were just kids.
We thought it was more, it was
different, it was the real thing...
But we were wrong. That's all.
You'll find someone else.
You've turned into a good-looking guy.
Just my luck.
What do you want?
Do you want me to beg?
Sorry...
But I won't make this easier for you.
You don't deserve it.
A toast! Do you want some too?
No. I'm making ice tea.
- What to?
- I've got a job.
See?
- I told you so!
- Sanyi is going to help.
- Cheers!
- To Sanyi!
No ice tray?
No.
Show me that!
Is that still here?!
You're too soft!
- Oh no, they're old mates.
- They're dubious.
In your position, it's no game!
Where's your necklace?
- What?
- Your necklace.
Oh, I didn't put it on.
It doesn't go with these earrings.
Cheers.
Savings Book
How much is it worth now?
Well...
There's plenty to last us...
for a week.
Come here!
From now on, you do what I say.
Tasteful dance music. Positive
message in a cultured environment.
Put this on.
Right.
I hope you know this one.
Is the picture clear?
Mihaly Vaczi:
"Still Not Enough".
It's not enough to fear,
fight the fight instead.
Hello there!
I want a word with you.
Have you got any original
Jerry Lee Lewis records?
- Aha.
- Supraphon?
- Sun Records.
- Sun Records?
"You ain't gonna make her...
a bong, a bong, bong..."
You got that?
- Frankie Lane, "Jezebel"?
- Sure!
- "Green Fields"?
- I've got them all!
Listen...
I've got to have them!
Come here! How much do you want, kid?
- They're not for sale.
- Name your price!
Get lost!
It's not enough to guess
what road lies ahead.
Live in hope and not in dread!
Thank you, congratulations.
And now for the fabulous...
Figaro Band!
What are you going to sing?
A song.
Great!
And what is the song about?
- The unveiling of the Berlin Wall.
- Bravo!
Marika, give me one of those!
Is business good?
So-so.
That's the spirit! Cheers!
Thanks. I'll be back in a minute.
Sweetheart, give me another
one of those.
Bravo, kid!
Your father must be proud of you.
Here we go!
They call him the Kissin' King
behind his back,
He strolled into town
down an old dirt track.
When he turns his radio on,
The girls in town rush out the salon,
And dance around the king
from dusk till dawn.
I saw him at the movies
the other night,
Kissin' a girl and holding her
oh so tight.
Some folks will say that he's a fake,
But the Kissin' King
is a loving mistake.
He kisses girls
and leaves them to shake.
- He's the Kissin' King!
- The king! The king!
- The Kissin' King!
He's the Kissin' King!
That's him!
The guitar!
Grab him!
Come on!
Stop this at once!
Let him go!
He hasn't done anything wrong!
What's going on?
We have reports of theft from
seventeen women
who had valuables stolen
during intimate relations.
Intimate?
What do you mean, "intimate"?
He kissed the dames
and swiped their stones.
They're just joking, babe.
Can't you see?
What?
Why don't you laugh with us a bit?
Hit him again!
Calm down, girls!
He's the Kissin' King!
King! King!
The Kissin' King!
If he strolls into a corner bar,
The girls come running
from near and far.
But he's so cool,
you know what I mean,
He drops a coin
in the music machine.
The Kissin' King dances
with his latest queen.
He runs his fingers
through her silky curls,
Around her neck
a gleaming string of pearls.
They stop outside for one more kiss,
But the Kissin' King,
don't miss a thing.
He sure can kiss!
A ring-a-ding-ding!
He's a woman's man,
Doing all he can.
I'm his greatest fan.
I just wanna be the Kissin' King!
Hey! Miki! Miki! Miki!
Come on! Jump in!
We're celebrating, hey, girls?
What? You monkey!
We're through to
the next round, that's all!
Smoke?
Do you know what I want?
You've got no idea!
I just want to make music
and fall in love!
Rone is right.
The communists should be squashed!
Be careful or they'll squash you!
Do you know what
rock and roll really is?
Rock and roll is music, that's all!
You should grow up!
Never!
We'll write a song to your memory.
About what a great musician
you could have been!
If anything happens,
my dad will kill...
- Kill who?
- Us!
- If we get caught, what should
we say? - That we found it.
I'm gonna piss my pants!
Stop!
Vodka?
- I'm going back!
- No! it's here in my jacket.
That's right! Is it far?
Is it far? it's on the corner!
Every night, I see your face,
And I watch you every morn.
And when I pass you in the park,
My heart starts bleeding
because it is torn.
I walk the streets lost and alone,
'cus I don't have you to call my own.
I try so hard to hide my emotions,
But my darling
I'm not made of stone.
I know now, baby, I need you so,
Why did I ever let you go?
I want you to be mine forever,
Please don't say no!
I sit and watch you from time to time,
As you comb your long brown hair.
Do something!
Do you care for me my darling?
The piano's on fire!
Or just say the word...
and I'll be gone...
Put it out!
I wanted to be a fireman
when I was a kid.
I can't pee because of my hernia!
We did our best.
Thanks.
Do you think your dad will notice?
How much did you get for it?
I didn't sell it.
But?
I lost it.
You lost a piano?
I see.
- Did it fall out of your pocket?
- Darling!
Where have you been?
What's the money for?
A woman? Alcohol?
Do you want me to
breathe on you, Dad?
- He never drinks!
- What else will you sell?
- I guess it'll be
the family clock next... - Clock?
My son is a criminal!
He'll rot in prison!
He was serenading!
Doing what?
He was serenading the girl he loves.
You should be proud.
Proud? Are you mad?
What is there to be proud of?
That he stole the family piano,
dragged it down the street
and threw it in the Danube
like an old bike?!
- You serenaded me!
- Me? Out of the question!
Zalakaros in the summer of '47.
You stood with the hotel band
under my window.
You lit candles around the pool,
and you balanced
on a blue lilo
in the middle of the pool
- and sang "'Ô Sole Mio".
- Me?
Yes, you!
You had to sell your watch and
a pair of shoes to pay for it all.
That wasn't such a sane thing
to do either!
But it was wonderful...
Wonderful!
I'll strangle this woman.
If I had,
I'd have served my sentence
and I'd be coming out of prison
just as the kid goes in!
Don't be so grumpy!
When was the last time you saw
Karoly Csibi?
Who?
I play with this hand...
Are you saying you don't know Rone?
Oh, Rone? I know him.
Where is he hiding? Tell me!
Are you deaf?!
Who's hiding him?
Has he tried to sell you jewellery?
No.
Sadly not.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Your equipment.
Make way.
Twist, twist, twist!
Come on boys and girls,
let's do the twist!
I've been working hard
all night and day
Time to throw all my cares away,
Now the weekends here
and it's time to play,
Come and join me twisting away!
- Twist, twist!
- Twist, twist, casino twist!
- Casino twist!
- Twist, twist, casino twist.
- Twist, twist!
- Twist, twist, casino twist!
I'll show you how it goes.
It's all you need to know!
Slot machines are flashing
in a coffee bar,
I've tried my luck
but never got too far.
But what the hell,
I think I'll have another go
I put the money in,
pull the handle slow.
- Twist, twist...
- Twist, casino twist.
- Casino twist.
- Twist, twist...
- Twist, casino twist...
Come on over baby,
let's do it again!
Miki! isn't that your dad?
- Twist, twist!
- Twist, casino twist.
- Casino twist.
- Twist, twist, casino twist.
- Twist, twist.
Twist the alphabet,
count one to ten!
Come on, Miki!
Come on, it'll be fine!
What's this dance, kids?
- Is it the rumba?
- Nooo!
- Perhaps the samba?
- Maybe the mambo?
- Nooo!
Well, what then?
Twist, twist!
Twist, twist, twist, twist!
See you at the hottest place in town,
We'll all be there,
just getting down.
The pretty girls
will all stand in a queue
There's plenty of me for all of you!
- Twist, twist.
- Twist, twist, casino twist.
- Casino twist!
- Twist, twist! Casino twist.
- Twist, twist!
- Twist, twist, casino twist.
There are dances I can list
but none like the twist!
- To the right!
- Twist, twist, a casino twist
- To the left!
- Twist, twist, casino twist!
- To the back!
Twist, twist!
- Puke at home! Get out!
- Run home, kid!
Shit!
We should divide the women up now
so there's no fighting later.
- Sure! I'm having Zsofi Winkler!
- Magda Szukits!
Which girl do you want, Miki?
- Leave him, he's out of it.
- Vera Miltenyi!
They'd never allow her out.
That's my mum's!
- Let's go for it, fellas!
- That's the spirit!
Who are you after, Nyiro?
- I can't hear!
- Come on out.
Who are you after?
Mari Winkler.
- Wow!
- Man! Are you sure?
Yes, why?
- You know she likes
to be tortured during sex! - No!
- I know.
- He knows.
What does that mean?
Should I pull her hair?
- No!
- My dad's toolbox is in the pantry.
There's Mari!
Hear that, Nyiro?!
Go for it, hard man!
Nyiro fancies you!
Hi, Mary!
Want to dance?
We could do something better first.
Right then...
Just cha-cha-cha,
That's the task for today.
Yes, cha-cha-cha,
Let the rhythm sway.
And cha-cha-cha,
Now go this way and that way.
...three, four, one, two.
Cha-cha-cha!
Cha-cha-cha,
Do it with passion, hey!
I don't care if he's rich or poor,
Bringing diamonds to my door...
I don't need no luxury,
Just a man who gives me more.
And cha-cha-cha,
I just can't stop!
I'll cha-cha-cha,
Until I drop!
Oh, cha-cha-cha!
In the street,
or in the bar,
If you're a star or just who you are.
Dance with me and we'll go far.
Come on baby! Ooh and ah!
Just cha-cha-cha,
It's the dance we all want to do.
Hey, cha-cha-cha,
It's for me and you.
I don't need nothing from my school,
Only the cha-cha is cool!
Don't be a square,
don't be a fool,
it makes me so hot
'cus it's so cool!
Oh, cha-cha-cha,
I just can't stop!
I'll cha-cha-cha
until I drop.
If this turns you on...
Get out, you bastard!
You animal!
That animal climbed on me
and sawed my ponytail off!
You told me to! You bastards!
It suits you.
Rone! Rone's here!
- Hi!
- Where the hell were you?
We thought you'd defected!
American kid!
Have you got a fan club now?
- You really are a big man now!
- Hi.
Hi.
What's this?
Rick Nelson!
- Rone!
- Catch it, kid!
It's all in the wrist action!
Give it back!
Tripolisz!
Don't let a girl tell you what to do!
If you break it, you pay for it!
Thanks.
What's this, babe?
Are you dating the slime-ball?
What's it to do with you?
- Arsehole!
- What?
Has the American kid got you now too?
What does he give you
so you'll kiss his arse?
Sura! Chewing gum?
You bend over for this spy
for a packet of gum?
Miki isn't a grass!
Not a grass?
Why do you think the Yanks
sent them home?
Why not?
Tripo!
You can't be that stupid!
They sent them home because
they were spying for the commies.
Has the penny dropped?
- You're an idiot!
- Get off!
Why does he kiss Bigali's arse?
He sings with East German sluts
rather than us!
How do you think they came
back home with no trouble?
That's true.
You got your flat back and your jobs.
That's not true.
Back into the interior Ministry!
The Ministry of industry.
So it was industrial espionage!
- We really don't know about his dad.
- Fuck off, Nyiro!
I know you grassed me up,
you monkey!
Hi, Vera!
Both him and his dad are grasses.
Hi, guys.
ls the party still going?
Vera!
Vera! Vera!
Vera! I'm sorry...
I didn't mean to.
Rings of fire...
before my eyes,
My heart is burning for the prize.
This love we have can't be denied,
I fell for you on a Saturday night!
You're the only one I want,
You're the only one I need.
Do I really have to plead?
My heart stops
still when you look at me!
I saw you at the local hop,
And you brought me a soda-pop,
I know now that I've reached the top,
One taste of you
and I just can't stop!
You're the only one I want,
You're the only one I need.
Do I really have to plead?
My heart stops
still when you look at me!
Vera!
Is everything okay?
Kid!
What are you doing?
Watch out because it's brand-new!
Do you want some gum?
What's up, kid?
Need any help?
No thanks, I can manage!
Don't need words
when our love is true,
Somehow I guess I always knew,
It's you for me and me for you,
Stay with me the whole night through!
You're the only one I want,
You're the only one I need,
Do I really have to plead?
My heart stops
still when you look at me!
My heart stops...
My heart stops!
Stop!
You're under arrest!
Thank you!
Listen to me!
If I see you near my daughter again,
I'll cut your balls off!
Where did you screw the dames?
Hands behind your back!
Is the record stuck?
Where are the necklaces?
I'm in no hurry...
Won't you give me one, boss?
Give him one!
Stop that!
What good will all this do?
Relax, kid,
you can go home soon!
you'll go home soon!
Fucking bastard!
Your dad will be shocked when
he sees what his comrades did.
When the Cuban missile crisis erupted,
the CIA reviewed
all recent immigrants.
They found out my father
had been a Party member.
We were given 48 hours
to leave the country.
We hung around in Manchester
for 6 months.
It took that long to arrange
to come home and not get locked up.
Do you know
what he did before we left?
He was an engineer.
And now...
he's a bus conductor!
A bus conductor...
Bus conductor! Great!
I only wanted to live a normal life
and to break out of this leper colony.
I wanted to have a flat and a car.
Look at Marina.
She's a first-class girl, hey?
So sweet...
Should I take her home to my dad?
To my alcoholic dad in a basement?
In a land where these thugs
dictate the morals,
I want to be the biggest gangster.
Take the band.
But with your own songs!
You're good at this game.
You really are.
Driving a Chevrolet down the streets
of Budapest lined with palm trees.
You're right.
That's what's needed here.
Pretend it's America.
Pretend we live normal lives.
It wasn't easy to get you out
but I organised it.
Thanks.
It was nothing!
The finals are just
around the corner, hey, Miki?
Seven o'clock tonight
in your Sunday best.
We can go.
Sorry...
You didn't steal from me!
Why didn't you steal from me?
I only steal from the wives
of wealthy communists.
Look at me!
Look into my eyes, Karcsi.
What did you come here for?
What for?
What do you think?
Let's finish it, baby.
Find yourself another guy.
- You'll be a granny when I get out!
- They've got no proof.
They'll find the gear sooner or later.
Where is it?
- It's better if you
don't get involved. - Where is it?
Search the place!
What's the problem?
ls there a problem?
I'll be back for
the car tomorrow, Karcsi.
My name's Gyula.
Ah, bambina!
- You came then!
- Hi, Brenner!
Impress me.
Cool!
Hi, babe.
You look great.
There is something left, hey?
Aha.
But... no more rock and roll.
Hi!
Come on, hurry up, son!
I've got some good news
but don't get too excited.
- It looks like I'm on the jury!
- Dad!
Calm down. You still have
to work hard. Especially you!
Because I'll knock your block off.
Okay then. Kiss!
Und ja, und schon, und alles...
Gehen!
Miki!
- Hi! They let you out?
- Yes!
- And Rone too?
- No, not him.
Come on, Miki!
Bye!
Sorry!
Good evening!
This way!
We are now going to
a live broadcast...
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the final of Hungarian
Television's talent contest.
This exciting series
has now reached its climax,
when the youth of Hungary can
eventually respond to the challenge of:
"Show What You Know"!
Let the show commence.
First in the folk music category
we have the
Pecel Endeavour Zither Ensemble.
- How was your day?
- Fabulous!
The first on stage to recite a poem
is Vera Miltenyi from Budapest.
Mihaly Vaczi:
"Still Not Enough"
it's not enough to fear,
fight the fight instead.
It's not enough to flicker,
but burn with flames of red.
It's not enough to talk,
but say what's not been said.
It is not enough to sense,
you have to know instead.
It's not enough to journey,
but walk where others dare not tread.
You have to set out first,
along the road ahead.
One man is not enough,
others must be led.
And only those should lead,
who are for leading bred.
Goodwill is not enough,
it takes a stronger head.
But is a head enough?
No, it needs a heart to spread
the message of this verse,
of pain and passion true.
To strive for a better life,
a life for me and you.
It's not enough to guess...
it's not enough to guess
what road lies ahead.
Thank you for
that wonderful rendition.
- Have we got the bathroom yet?
- Five more minutes, sweetheart.
Now, in the dance music category,
a true international delight
combining the best of Hungarian
and East German talent.
All the way from 13th District:
Figaro!
I know them.
Miki! Where is that...?
Miki!
Stupid kid!
Fantastic, thank you!
It's going to be tough for the jury.
Points please!
Seven.
Six.
Eight.
Five.
A can't see Arpad Bigali's points.
Ten! Thank you!
We only have one more winner to pick.
And that's in
the dance music category.
And now for our last performers...
Roll on up the rug tonight
'cus we're dancing!
Come on roll it up right now!
It's gonna be a night for romancing,
don't worry I'll show you how!
Turn the lights down low,
open the piano,
Forget all about that
"quick, quick, slow"!
Tonight we're gonna rumble,
sing loud and don't mumble,
Come on roll the rug up now!
Can we join you?
Everybody's sleeping,
no need for creeping
around in the street outside.
It's quiet in the town square.
No need to play fair.
There's nothing we've got to hide.
The neighbours can all just hang.
Play the drum with a bang, bang, bang!
What the hell do we care?
They can all come and stare!
Come on roll the rug up now!
I've waited all my life
for this night to come,
Smoking, drinking beer
and chewing gum!
The place is ours to do as we want,
So say you will and
don't say that you won't.
Come on, darling,
you're the only one!
Roll on up the rug tonight
'cus we're dancing!
Come on roll it up right now!
It's gonna be a night for romancing,
don't you worry I'll show you how!
Turn the lights down low,
open the piano,
Forget all about that
"quick, quick, slow"!
Tonight we're gonna rumble,
sing loud and don't mumble,
Come on roll the rug up now!
Thank you.
And that was?
Isn't that your son?
Yes, he is!
The Hungaria Band!
Jury, points please!
10 points.
10 points, 10 points...
And another 10...
10 points.
Fantastic.
Let's see the last score.
If it's more than five...
Zero?
What?
Ten points!
And so Hungaria are the winners!
That's cold!
- Sandor, what are you doing?
- What's going on?
I told you, I'd cut your balls off!
"May I enter with
new songs for a new age?"
Yes, of course...
in a cultured environment.
That's our kind of rock and roll!
Congratulations, son!
Thank you!
Your poem was wonderful!
Let's have a drink!
Good evening.
Evening.
Mum!
The light!
Made in Hungaria,
My only mania.
Where music played and dance
floors swayed to a new melodia.
With a shiny new guitar
I brought rhythms from afar,
The flame caught light
and still burns bright.
Why did I wander?
Then my heart caught fire,
And took us all much higher.
Now or never!
We were all filled with hope,
but life's a slippery slope,
So along with the rest,
I soon learned to cope.
Hungary my home,
The one place that's my own.
But now I'm back there’s noway
I'll roam.
Made in Hungaria,
My only mania.
It's been so good to me
my lovely Hungary.
I've been to the USA,
And heard how they play,
I brought it home to my home town
to sing my own way.
Because the only way I know,
Was to stay and not to go,
My homeland may be small
but I love it so.
It's only when your
roots are strong
that you can ever grow.
We are all filled with hope,
but life's a slippery slope,
So along with the rest,
we soon learn to cope.
Hungaria my home,
The one place that's my own.
But now I'm back there's no way
I'll roam.
Made in Hungaria,
Not all agree,
But it's been good to me
my lovely Hungary.
I've had my finger on the beat
of the pulse of the street.
'Cus rock and roll is the school
of knocks that keeps you on your feet.
But the rewards are always sweet.
Made in Hungaria.
You are all filled with hope,
but life's a slippery slope,
But along with the rest,
you'll soon learn to cope.
Hungary my home,
The one place that's my own,
I'm back to stay,
there's no way I'll roam.
Made in Hungaria,
It's a magic mania.
And it's been so good to me
my lovely Hungary.
Made in Hungaria,
It's a magic mania.
And it's been so good to me
my lovely Hungary.