What is the time?
- It is ten past eight.
Ten past eight?
We are very late.
Please drive faster.
- Are you crazy?
This stormy night and
these bad roads.
There are still twenty
two miles left.
Why don't you drive
a bit faster?
Why are you acting so hasty?
Whether sister-in-law
is worried or not..
But my dear friend..
Sir..
Shall we take this?
- Yes.
What happened?
Sir. These are very big rocks.
You please go and
sit in the car.
Go. You go. Run and go.
There is a landlord's
bungalow up there.
You please go and rest there.
We will surely be trapped
in this rain.
Come on. We will go
to the bungalow.
will sit here.
Come on. Come on.
There is
- There is nobody inside.
Now that we have come,
let us see.
Who opened the door?
I did. The door opener
is there. And you?
Yes. Why not? Please come.
It seems to be a very
old bungalow.
Yes. There was. But
it fell down..
This is the limit.
He will take some
time to arrange..
See if the rain has
settled down or not.
Doctor..
No.
No. I don't want brandy
or anything.
Who?
- What happened?
Did you hear some girl
shouting? - No.
Maybe I had some misconception.
I had prepared it.
I don't know anything
about that.
What happened? What
noise was it?
He was the last landlord
of this area.
Sir..
I remember it now. I
remember it clearly.
Maybe it is of the
previous birth.
As if it was inviting me.
''I am afraid, I don't
get lost somewhere.''
''Who smiles hiding
in the flowers?''
''For what is the
spring yearning?''
''There is a bulbul somewhere.''
''These seas dance and
trip like this.''
''That sky is coming
down on the earth.''
''We haven't seen
scene anywhere.''
Sir, don't go ahead.
''Come..''
''O foreigner..''
Brother.. is this the
way to Shamghad?
This side or that side?
I understood.
Not down. Up here.
Oh god!
Who are you then?
Here.
Hey..
I will tell you if you
give me four annas.
Here you are. We are
right now, isn't it?
What is your name?
You tell me first.
My name is Anand.
Greetings.
Listen..
Shamgadh? Timber estate?
Mr. Anand?
Your name is Anand?
Yes. I have told that
my name is Anand.
You please come with me.
It is quite a beautiful place.
It seems beautiful to you now?
You are really very tired?
Why don't you drink
a cup of tea?
And the biggest one here is..
The best person here is
the accountant here.
Greetings, sir.
Did you have any troubles
on the way?
No. I didn't have any troubles.
I'd sent Charan. He is
a bit of a drunkard.
There is a liquor
shop in the way.
..then how would sir reach here?
No..
- Okay. Everything is all right.
I will come to work
from tomorrow.
Look around the area
a bit. You will..
..get to see excellent
scenes here.
But we are unfortunate.
You are new here, isn't
it? Please take care.
Everyone here is a thief.
I am a child.
- You fool!
Sir. You please have some rest.
And please tell me if
you need anything.
What are you doing
standing there?
''Come..
'' O foreigner..''
''My eyes are waiting for you.''
It was very good at that time.
And where is his son nowadays?
Because he become the chief now.
Sir. Greetings.
- Greetings.
This is our new manager, Anand.
Greetings.
- Greetings.
We cut seven hundred
trees today.
Leave something
for tomorrow too.
Come on. Come to the office.
- Yes, come on.
Sir..
- Yes?
What is this?
Let it be, sir.
Sir.. this letter.
Oh my god!
- What happened?
The younger king is coming here.
So what is to be
so scared in it?
No sir. There is nothing
to be scared in it.
Veer Singh.. Veer Singh..
oh Veer Singh..
Where have everyone died?
Sir..
Yes. I have heard it.
And the public there
is dead in fear.
And it doesn't have
any effect on you?
Why will it affect me?
Sir.. sir..
Sir..
I forgot to tell you something.
Why?
There are big and strange
animal here.
There are beasts here too.
I cannot think that
you are a animal.
Forget about animals,
please come here.
The company people have
put up a notice.
Nobody can go there.
- You go.
I was going down here.
''Please come..
o foreigner..''
''My eyes are waiting for you.''
''I am such a wick of light..''
''We were to stay throughout
births.''
''Why did you forget
it, o beloved?''
''I yearn all through
the day and night.''
''I am a lake and yet
I am thirsty.''
''This is a deep secret
but a small matter.''
''Without every thing
is so incomplete.''
Who are you? What is your name?
Madhumati.
Why did you steal my picture?
Please don't cut my
money this month.
My house and door all
has fallen down.
Please cut my money
the next month.
What are you saying?
I will die. -
If you don't die, I will die
Kill me..
- Give me the money.
Please give me justice, sir.
Shut up.
Veer Singh.. give
him back the money.
Okay.
Charan..
- Yes?
Where are these girls going?
Girls?
Oh! What can be said
about them, sir?
The girls are an excellent race.
They come and go in a breeze.
They go to the fair
every year, sir.
But you please don't go there.
Why shouldn't I go there?
Will you go there?
- Yes. I will go there.
Yes? Then I will go there too.
''I saw a heartless man..''
''I saw a heartless man.''
''What kind of night was this?''
''He plays the flute secretly.''
''He makes me hear
an exciting song.''
''He calls me in the
shadow of the stars.''
''He steal my sleep,
I keep awake.''
''He is behind me.''
''The illness increases
as we talk.''
''See my craziness someone.''
''I call the moon with
my beloved's name.''
''A magical wand worked
on my mind.''
Hey.. run run..
Run.. run..
My child.. my child..
You beast.
Who said it?
Sorry.
Bless you, brother.
You saved my son.
You are so good.
Sir, I am hurt.
Just like that.
- I will make you bleed.
Please wait.. I will
come right away.
Please let me see it.
I was scared.
- And now?
I am not scared now.
Why are you not scared now?
You are a good man,
sir. You risked..
..your life and saved
Manglu's brother.
Hey.. he was saved by his fate.
How am I connected with that?
Is it still paining you?
- Yes.
Then why don't you
come to my house?
Father will apply
some nice medicine.
Will he get angry?
If he will be happy, come on.
- Come on.
Listen.. Walk a bit slowly.
Please run and come.
How far is your house now?
Come.
Come on.
See that. Down there.
That is my house.
Is it down there?
Yes.
But how will we go down?
From here? Oh no! I
won't be able to go.
Come. Please come.
Father..
Where has he gone?
Father.. father..
Please sit. I will see, okay?
Father..
Who are you?
I.. me.. I am the manager..
Why did you come here?
I came with her..
Who?
I brought him, father. Yes.
Sit down.
Let me see where
you are wounded.
It is not a wound, I just
have a gash here.
Yes. Sir. It is a
small gash first.
And then, it is
a very big wound.
The medicine is a bit strong.
Sir.. are you new here?
I have come here a few days ago.
Just to wander around?
No, I work here.
- Where?
In work in his majesty's
timber estate.
Go away from here.
But what did I do?
Madhu..
Father..
He doesn't even know the way.
He will search for it.
Come on inside.
Charan..
Who is it? Who is it?
It is me.
You are in, then outside..
Sir, where were you
lost in the fair?
Listen, Charan..
He is Pand the king..
King?
- Yes.
His ancestors were kings.
Okay. The king of this time..
Enmity?
What are you talking
about enmity?
The company people
aren't permitted..
..to neither go there
and nor to talk there.
Why?
- Sir. Many years ago..
And he killed him, sir.
Not only this..
..they even did a
lot of injustice.
Ruined.
What I didn't want
to say, I said it.
Sir.. the betel nuts
here are excellent.
Why don't you eat
the betel nuts?
Jeevan.. how is the
work going around?
It is going on nicely.
Sir.. you are a educated
and learned man.
Why do you come
into the forest..
..everyday to look at
the work going on?
You should just sit
in the office.
The laborers are a
bit afraid of you.
Why? Am I the devil incarnate?
Sir.. the king has called you.
Yes. Tell him that
I am busy now.
I will come there in some time.
Please listen..
His majesty is a very
different man.
And please listen..
His majesty likes being praised.
If you just praise
him a little bit..
I will try to remember
your suggestion.
Did you like the photograph?
You..
Greetings.
Are you the new manager?
- Yes.
You are a brave man.
It was proved in the
fair that day.
You had called me?
- Yes.
Helplessly.
After I have come here,
everyone..
See.
When the employer comes, it is..
..customary here to
come and greet him.
Know this.
- I know it now.
I was stuck up in
the old accounts.
It is cured.
If you'd see it, you'd
understand..
If I had to see it,
why would I pay you?
Please don't believe
any of your servant..
I will tell, not even me.
I praise the way you speak.
I live in the city normally.
I sometimes have to
come to this jungle.
There are servants
all around me here.
Ramsingh..
- Yes, sir?
You can go.
- Farewell. - Open it quickly!
He is a very good man at heart.
I have heard it. Where
are you going?
I am going to the
nearby village.
We will meet tomorrow.
- Where?
Here. At this time.
Madhu..
- I am coming, father.
Where had you stopped?
Sir..
Sir.. I have come.
Do you know what I had thought?
That I won't come, isn't it?
- Yes.
Didn't I promise you?
See sir, the tree is moving.
Like this and like that.
It is so happy.
Even I am happy.
I am just happy.
Madhmati..
I will make your picture, Madhu.
You will make a picture?
Make it.
I cannot sit down anymore, sir.
I am getting late.
Wait for a while more, Madhu.
The picture will be
done right away.
Sir.. see.
- What is the matter?
Come here. Come here.
What is the matter?
See. The ants are going home.
So what if the ants
are going home?
The water is coming, isn't it?
Where is the water coming?
Where have you gone?
Please make the nose
a bit longer. A bit.
The sun?
- Yes.
Come on. Come on.
I will show you.
The sun hides there
in the night.
..from the cave behind
that mountain.
When we are sleeping,
it travels through..
..hell and goes back
there once again.
From down below?
I will make you understand.
You will make me understand?
Now go and sit on that
rock. Go. Go. Go.
Am I some tree or
some rock, that..
..I will be rooted at
one place?
I had come..
We will chat a bit. But you..
What are you staring at?
You.
Madhu..
God has made you so beautiful..
..that I cannot make
your portrait at all.
Look here.
Show me your face.
Someone is coming.
No. I just draw some
stupid lines.
I have made it with
my own thoughts.
Wow. You have a nice creativity.
You are right.
Let me go.
- No, I can't hear to anything.
Let me go!
No. nobody can go from here.
Please let me go. Please
have mercy on me.
I don't know any mercy
or anything.
Please let me go.
My son will die.
What can I do if your
son will die?
I beg you, please let me go.
No. nobody can go from here.
What is the matter, Veer Singh?
Sir.. he isn't letting
me go that side.
A snake has bitten my son.
Nobody except Pand can cure him.
Please tell him to let
us go that side.
Let these people go that side.
This is his majesty's orders.
Wait..
- Veer Singh!
You go.
Sit down.
And Mr. Anand and she are..
Okay. So this is the matter?
But even then he paints
her picture.
And he meets her too.
Near the lake.
Oh..
Are you in a haste
to go somewhere?
Yes. My work is done
for today and..
I have some work left.
Thank you.
''My heart beats
again and again.''
''Why does it beat
again and again?''
''Today, we are to meet.''
''I have got so much love.''
''Please brace yourself and see.''
So you are Mr. Anand's thoughts?
Let me go. Let me go!
''My heart yearns and says,
please come.''
''The roses have not bloomed
in your wait.''
''My heart yearns and says,
please come.''
''My life is so beautiful
because of you.''
''I am living because
I Iove you.''
''There is the result
of laughing love.''
''Where are we, where
is my heart?''
''I don't know anything.''
''I don't know anything
where it is.''
Come closer.
Yes, come closer.
Don't talk to me.
Why didn't you come yesterday?
You don't know, Madhu.
If you were a man,
you'd have known..
..they don't give us
time for love at all.
Then why do you do such a job?
What else should I do?
I will bring food for you.
And a apartment?
That's enough. Your
needs are increasing.
Okay.. when you didn't
come yesterday..
What would have happened to you?
What if someone snatches
me from you?
I will kill him. Who is he?
Nobody. I was just
asking like that.
Where?
- Why don't you just come?
It is such a strange place.
I wanted to bring you here.
- Here? - Yes.
This is where I wanted
to bring you.
Do you see those rocks there?
There is so much of
peace and calm here.
All alone.
At that time, I am not alone.
I feel as if..
What are you saying?
Really, sir. Nothing
dies in this world.
And we have come somewhere..
..up from these
stars in the sky.
What kind of brightness is this?
''Oh!''
''Filling the pot.. oh!''
''The sinful scorpion
climbed up!''
''I will say some hymns.''
''The soft body..''
''Leave it and go.''
''Go!''
'' Beloved, please come home.''
''Come home. Come home.''
''See, see.. the scorpion
has gone up.''
''The poison is gone,
the scorpion is left.''
You don't know.
I don't even care for
him even this much.
As much as you listen
to these sirs..
..they become as much pompous.
He wasn't giving me
a holiday at all.
When I became angry,
he became a goat.
And he started telling me.
He folded his hands.
And he told me..
And he even held my feet.
He was crying, he was crying.
Then what?
And then?
Then?
Sir.. sir..
Then I was scared and
took out this tie.
I thought that if sir
asks me, I will..
..say that I am sorry.
- Then?
Please start and hit me.
This is your shoe.
Let it be, sir. Please
come. Forget it.
Sir, Madhu is saying something.
You won't do such a
stupid antic again.
What about me? I will
write and go.
All this is because of alcohol.
You please don't drink
it. It is very bad.
You dance very well.
It is too late now.
Father will be angry.
I will reach quickly
on the forest road.
I am a wild girl, sir.
Okay.
Where are you going?
Come on inside.
Sir.. sir..
Madhu..
You?
I was dreaming about you.
Sir.. how did you come here?
I came to meet you.
Did father come
to know about it?
Sir..
You are all wet. Sit
down. Sit down.
Here, take this fire.
How can I tell you?
What happened, sir?
When you didn't come,
god knows..
The rain surrounded
me from all sides.
All of them made a storm
set in my heart.
I couldn't tolerate
it. I came here.
I fell down and
got up many times..
I wasn't in my senses.
When I raised and looked around.
You were there everywhere.
Oh! You are crying!
You took such pain,
sir. And me..
..the fool just smiled
and slept here.
If only this is the
case everything.
How many ever storms
and lightning.
All of them should
come in my share.
No sir, I swear.
I tell you.
If I live, I will live
in your presence.
No, Madhu.
- Really, sir.
Even if I die, I will
stay with you.
If I smile, I will
smile with you,
If I stay, I will stay with you.
Who had come here?
Tell me. Tell me.
Okay. I will see it for myself.
Father..
Father.. father..
You wretch. You rogue.
Take this.
Slash my neck away, but don't..
There is sin even in your blood.
Get aside, Madhu.
- No, father no.
You are very proud of
your love, isn't it?
And I will be proud
of it till I die.
You are lying.
No, father. He is
telling the truth.
You fool. You don't
know these conmen.
Ask him and see. Will
he marry you?
Sir.. will you marry me?
Yes, Madhu, if you
father allows us.
I want that girl, that's it.
Sir.. this matter is not easy.
Silence! Get the girl
in anyway you can.
Sir, there is one way for it.
The fair in Chandanpur
is about to start.
..this work will be
done in a jiffy.
It will be arranged for.
Give it to me, daughter
give me the bag.
Come quickly, father.
And the, even I am in haste.
And listen..
Whatever you feel like, dad.
If only your brother
was alive today.
Okay. Okay, I will bring them.
All the arrangements
are done too.
I won't be here for
a couple of days.
And it is necessay to
go to Neelpur too.
Tell me, how can I help you?
But your majesty..
Please go as soon as possible.
Very good. Farewell.
- Farewell.
No.. I won't let you go.
Why won't you let me go?
I feel so scared without you.
No. Not kind of fear, sir.
Listen. You don't worry
about the king.
He has gone with his
friends for a hunt.
And I will return
before he does.
See.. I am going now.
Please smile a little.. please..
The flower has fallen down.
So what if the flower
has fallen down?
It is very inauspicious.
If someone's flower
falls down, he dies.
No, this is the truth.
I don't want to die.
I wasn't scared of death
before seeing you.
God.. I amn't even
married till now.
Here, you are married now.
God is a witness.
Today you have Charan
drink so much..
Don't worry, sir.
I will have him drink so much..
..he won't come to his
senses till two days.
Very good.
Oh!
Too bad!
Should I get more?
No. I have drunk a lot.
Not a drop more.
''Someone likes green
green notes.''
''Someone likes boot,
suit and coat.''
''Friends.. I like drinks..''
Charan.. it is a problem.
A problem? I didn't sing fully.
If I sang fully, it
would be better.
Charan, there is
a major problem.
Sir has met with an accident.
Yes. He is very injured.
- Where is he?
He is taking Madhu's name.
Okay.
What happened, Charan?
He is badly injured.
- Injured?
Where is he?
He is in his majesty's bungalow.
Why is he there?
He had gone to his office.
The police chief has
brought him there.
He is taking your name
again and again.
Come on, quickly.
Sir..
How is sir? Is it him? Sir..
Madhu..
Please give me some
drinking water..
Madhu..
Sir.. where is Madhu?
Why? Where did she go?
And she isn't there.
No. I myself am returning
from Neelpur.
I had gone there for two days.
Then she surely is
in some problem.
Shall we search for her?
Come on.
Madhu..
What happened?
Looking for her is useless.
Madhu..
Come.. o foreigner..
Where is Madhu?
Where is Madhu now?
I heard her voice.
Didn't you hear it?
No.
Come.. I am waiting for you..
''Come..''
Did you hear that?
Where, sir?
Didn't you hear anything?
No. this is just your
misconception.
Sir..
Sir.. have you come sir?
It is all my fault.
You can punish me.
Why? What did you do?
Veer Singh told me
that you have..
But the king wasn't
there at all.
No, sir.
I have found out that
all that was false.
He didn't go anywhere at all.
''Your heart cannot be
equal to my heart.''
''I will tell the state
of the heart.''
''Whether you listen
to it or not.'
''A hundred times, I will tell.''
''Whether you will
listen or not.''
Where is Madhu?
Madhu..
Yes, where is she?
What do I know? Get lost..
You wretch.
I know which hunt you went for.
You have molested
an innocent woman.
I will show you.
Tell me..
Tell me where she is,
come on. Tell me.
Veer Singh.
Yes, sir?
Throw this dead body
out of my area.
Very well.
Wait, you wretch.
Come on!
Where are you taking the sir?
I say, let me go.
And I say, get down.
I have to settle old
accounts with you.
Not one, but many. Get down!
Where are you taking
the vehicle?
Here you are.. and this
too.. and this too.
And this too.
What happened?
She didn't come.
Who didn't come?
The one who was to.
The one who was to didn't come?
What is the problem?
And now I am almost ill.
Okay, come on.
Careful.. careful..
Take it carefully.
But not with your heart.
I will find you under
any circumstances.
What is it?
Ruined.
How is that?
When I took the tea
and went inside..
I don't know what has
happened to him.
I know what has happened to him.
Should I tell you?
Yes.
- Should I?
Will you tell me or
should I hit you?
A ghost..
Not on you, but on your sir.
On sir.. what should we do now?
Give me a bidi.
Will you come with me?
Come on. Come on right now.
Will you be scared?
I will be scared!
I don't know what the
meaning of fear is.
Come in.
Don't sit here.
Someone else is sitting here.
There is nobody here.
Will you ever do anything
like this?
Hold your ears.
Sit down. Get up.
Get up.
Sit down. Go.
You will not go?
I tell you, go away silently.
You won't go?
Okay, wait.
Oh! He has started burning!
Is he behind me?
Sit down.
What is the matter?
So what should I do?
I mean, a witch.
She is very bad.
If she very bad, I
am the son of bad.
Son or father?
- Father!
But your skull?
- Take it and come.
Go.. go and call your employer.
Employer of ghost?
- The employer..
Sir.. sir.. nothing.
Is it? Then close the door.
Louder.. Baba..
Did you see?
- No.
Or else, he won't go.
Give it to me.
Twenty five paise..
That is not my responsibility.
Where did sir go?
You dangerous! Tell
me where is sir..
..or else I will smash
your head down.
See. He has become a cat.
But why are you running
like a dog?
Where were you, Madhu?
I had gone crazy searching
for you.
Why are you staring
at me like this?
Come closer to me. Come to me.
Brother.. brother..
This was Madhavi's voice,
isn't it?
Yes. It was her voice.
Is she in some trouble?
Trouble? You mean a tiger?
My gun.. my gun..
You search here, I
will search there.
Madhavi, where are you?
Sir.. sir..
Brother.. brother..
Madhavi, where are you?
Why are you running
from me, Madhu?
Who is Madhu? I am not Madhu.
No, don't say like this.
Say that you have forgotten
your father.
That you don't love
me any longer.
You have some misconception.
Please let me go. Please
let me go. Brother..
I wasn't insulting
anyone. I was..
Hey.. what is this?
My name is Anand.
Should I splatter
your brains out?
He seems to be crazy. Run away!
He is the police chief
of this area.
And I am his brother-in-law.
Where do you reside?
I live in the Dak Bungalow.
In the Bungalow..
He has ruined the
whole picnic today.
Come on, Ms. Madhavi.
Come on. Madhavi.
Come on, forget it.
Brother.. look at this.
Yes, Madhavi. This is strange.
This picture is similar to you.
But he never saw me before this.
Yes. It is possible.
It is seen sometimes..
..that even when there
is no relation..
..the faces of two people
are so similar..
..that even the police
are stunned.
Then the poor man wasn't lying.
He should get this picture..
The poor man?
''The broken dreams
have taught us..''
''Who had been achieved
by the heart.''
''The eyes have lost her.''
''I keep searching for her.''
''The guest of my heart.''
''What my ambition was.''
''What has come to be done.''
'' But even this yearning
is useless.''
Does anyone named
Anand live here?
What can I tell you, madam?
This poor man is a thief
of just cooking.
Even that, I have to eat.
Neither is sir here, and
nor is his bearer.
Excuse me.
Charan..
You don't speak with me.
What are you saying?
Thief, fool, rogue, wretch..
You are a thief, your
father is a thief.
You ruined my money yesterday.
You wretch. Where is the ghost?
Me.. no.. me.. no..
What happened?
No..
Move.
Madhavi..
Is it?
I will touch you, okay..
The same nose, the
same features.
That same mouth and
those same eyes.
So sir had thought
you to be Madhu.
Okay, tell me. Who
is this Madhu?
What has happened to her?
This is the poor
girl's sad story.
Looking at you, now
I have understood..
Has sir come?
Mr. Anand..
I know.
I have heard everything.
I feel that..
That Madhu's sorrow is mine now.
Don't spend any tears on me.
Those eyes, that face.
That look.
''Come..''
''O foreigner..''
Are you hearing it?
- What?
She is calling me.
Where are you going?
Madhu.. Madhu..
I am living with you.
I had promised you.
I have won, he has lost.
Who is it?
Ugranarayan.
He wanted to bite me that day.
Anand.. Anand..
Madhu.. Madhu..
I am going.
Where?
His hands have my Madhu's blood.
And that snake is alive yet.
Whom are you speaking about?
Ugranarayan. Ugranarayan.
Ugranarayan. I know that wretch.
There have been a
couple of murders..
..earlier, and he has
had an hand in them.
Why don't you arrest
him, inspector?
Didn't I tell you
my helplessness?
I cannot do anything
without proof.
Hello?
Hello, Kamal.. yes..
There are still a full
fifteen minutes left.
I will come there
directly from here.
Ciao..
Wait. Give me the pistol.
Give it to me.
Please give the pistol
to me for two days.
I will kill the
sinner with this.
Hang me after that if you wish.
Just my revenge should
be completed.
Listen..
Then find some solid
proof for it.
I will help you.
Where are you going?
I don't know.
Come with me.
- Where? - Come on.
Hello.
- Hello, inspector.
You are very late.
Yes, we were late due
to the office work.
''Oh.. the scorpion..''
'' Beloved, please come home.''
The proof is in your presence.
What are you saying?
I didn't understand.
..then even he will
be stunned like me.
What will happen then?
Madhavidevi.. this
is my last request.
Please help me..
Brother..
When will we have to go?
I will tell you
when I come back.
Sir, you are with me?
It is the law's duty
to be with you.
You are sitting here?
What have you come to do here?
I had come to apologize to you.
What did you want
to apologize for?
I wanted to apologize
to you for them.
And you see what the
result of that is.
I don't have anything
to eat or wear.
I am tired of life.
Make he do some work.
Your pride isn't broken as yet.
I will make these pictures.
Come some time else.
Your majesty..
But I don't have
time in the day.
When you will have some time.
Okay. I will leave
now. Thank you.
Here you are.
You will come, won't you?
I asked Charan and
had these made..
..exactly as Madhu had
worn that night.
But..
The road to Shampur is very bad.
You will come with her,
isn't it? - Yes.
Okay, I will leave now.
Madhavi.. please arrange
for some tea.
No. please don't
take the trouble.
I cannot wait here
for even a minute.
But..
Yes, I will.
Poor man.
Very well.
It is such a dangerous night.
Do your work silently.
Behind me.. where? Who is it?
Anand.. you wanted to scare me?
No. I myself was scared,
your majesty.
I don't have time
to waste. Quickly.
There isn't more time for eight.
Do your work quietly.
Your majesty, blood.
- Blood? - Yes, blood.
Come here, look at this.
There is someone else's
hand in this blood.
But who else is there
other than us here?
There is someone here.
I can feel it.
Did you hear that noise?
You are listening
to it, isn't it?
I can't listen to anything else.
Make the picture.
Were you scared?
No. not at all.
How are you staring at me?
Just like a painter looks.
..self out of his subject.
Your majesty, do you
believe in spirits?
Why are you asking
me such questions?
The night is something
like that.
It seems that a spirit,
whose dream..
Do you see those
dancing shadows?
What kind of noise is this?
Who is that?
Anand.. light.. light.. Anand..
Don't move ahead. Go away.
I tell you, go away from here.
Anand.. tell her to go away.
Why are you scared today?
Do you remember that
stormy night..
..when you called
me here giving..
..me the false message
that he is wounded?
What happened after that?
Tell me, what happened
after that?
Why are you silent?
I tried to force myself on you.
You saved yourself
from my clutches..
Don't you dare.
Killing a innocent woman..
You will never have any peace.
So that nobody knows.
Is there anyone? Light.. light..
You are under arrest.
All this is lies, this
is a conspiracy.
You can say everything
else in the court.
Guards.. take the gun.
But how do you know all this?
Where are you going,
Madhavidevi?
Brother.. it is eight.
I will go.
Mr. Anand.. Mr. Anand..
I am sorry.
Madhu..
What happened?
She had come.
Who?
Madhu..
Where?
Sir..
Did you hear that?
She is calling me.
Sir.
Anand..
Madhavi..
Sir..
Anand..
Madhu..
Sir..
Anand..
Madhu..
''Come.. I have been waiting
at this bank..''
''Oh.. Please come..''
''Come.. o foreigner..''
And this was the end
of my last birth.
I didn't get Madhu
in that birth.
And in this birth,
I have got her.
Who. Sister-in-law?
- Yes.
Our love has taken
birth once again..
..breaking the darkness
of death.
And we have taken
birth once again.
Oh! It is morning.
And we don't know..
..anything about that
driver. Radha..
..must be so worried
thinking about us.
Sir.. sir..
What? Has the road
been cleared out?
How do you know that?
The driver is telling
it downstairs.
No, this is not possible.
Come on, doctor.
Radha..
You are all right.
I had died listening
about the accident.
It is as if that I have
got you once again.
Do you know?
Oh! I had forgotten!