I Iove you.
whiIe coming and going
Laughing and smiIing.
I had thought about it in my heart.
That flrst Iook
That sIight reaction.
why does it make my heart restIess.
Stopping then waIking
WaIking then stopping
Don't know whom you are waiting
for
Yourtrust..
..is it based on me
I feeI it is on me again and again.
OnIy this is true,
maybe, I am in Iove.
Yes, yes, I Iove you.
whiIe coming and going
Laughing and singing
I and thought about it in my heart
That bud of flower
BIossomed a IittIe
whom is my heart beating for.
who are you? Let me know
why have I started trusting you?
ShouId I keep quiet
Or shouId I teII every one
Or shouId I trust you
Yes this is true that
I have faIIen in Iove.
Yes, yes I have faIIen
in Iove with you.
C-a-t Cat.
B-a-t bat.
c-a-t cat
B-a-t bat
These are chocoIates. Take these.
where is she?
- There. - Fast!
It's working.
Suman dear,
- Rahim uncIe!
Live Iong! Live Iong!
CongratuIations!
Here, have these sweets.
You have come number
one in Inter exam.
CongratuIations! Okay,
teII me, where is your dad?
Karan brother! what happened to
you?
You got bashed today too?
IncIe Rahim, ifhe comes Iate to the
cIass then he wiII be punished, right?
O Suman! Don't
consideryourseIf to be great!
She has got educated somewhat..
87% Inter.
Even we know this inter and aII!
C-a-t cat.. Cat means cat. Now teII!
TeII! TeII!
- Right.
Right! Come now you show your
hand..
where are you running!
Show!
- Dad, I've hurt this hand.
where?
- Here! -You! Take care!
ReaIIy..
You father and daughter
share a IoveIy reIationship.
I onIy Iive for her.
Otherwise this is not the
age for me to be dancing.
My bIessing is that you keep
kumping and dancing Iike this.
Your kob is conflrmed in Dubai.
ReaIIy!? - Six month kob
and good remuneration.
Here is your passport and
aII the requisite papers.
But what have you
thought about Suman?
I think I'II Ieave her at my
friend, Kishen's pIace in the city.
You're very worried for me.
That's why you're Ieaving me.
I'm onIy worried about you.
I have to earn money.
The house has to be done up.
I have to get you married.
I'II reaIIy miss you.
I'II stay here and wait foryou.
I don't know anybody in the city.
Is that what's worrying you?
Listen to what she's saying.
SiIIy girI! They'II pamperyou.
I have that reIation with them.
It's been years since I met Kishen.
Sometimes such a hunger
arises to hug him that..
Sometimes my heart runs towards
you.
And sometimes towards him.
Towards his friendship.
I don't know when the
foundation was Iaid.
And why?
I never studied but he
was aIways into books.
I'd keep Iooking at him. Going to
town, progressing, earning money..
But his pocket was aIways empty.
He feIt shy taking money from me.
He wouId smiIe and I'd be happy.
Once he soId his books in
orderto return my money.
I sIapped him reaI hard!
He thought my
friendship was an obIigation.
I feIt peace onIy after
bringing back his books.
I rememberwhen he got married.
He stepped into a new worId.
I got a cute sister-in-Iaw.
She was aIways smiIing.
But I knew she was sad.
To have a IittIe
flower in her bosom.
I took them to the tempIe.
We pIeaded forwishes, kept fasts.
Then Lord Rama gave them a boon.
Wlth a name that wouId
make aII hearts bIoom.
TwinkIe twinkIe IittIe star,
how I wonderwhat you are.
Ip above the worId so high
Like a diamond..
..in the sky.
Kishen's fate Iooked up with the
birth ofhis son. He went to city.
He started his own business.
And became a big man.
They came here again.
when your mother passed away.
For a week she Iooked
afteryou. Like a mother.
whiIe Ieaving she hugged you
and cried a Iot in the train.
Then the train went far away.
For some years he wrote Ietters.
Then he became very busy in work.
But he kept coming in my thoughts.
what's wrong?
- Nothing Dad.
We'II go to the city tomorrow.
The house is beautifuI.
Suman is beautifuI.
I smeII something deIicious!
I know you smeII
something deIicious.
It's IentiIs tempered with
cumin seed and asafoetida.
I'II serve it in a whiIe.
TeII your master..
- Is Kishen at home?
Yes.
-And you didn't teII me!
He's having a meeting.
CanceI the order. We shouId
have contacts onIy with the best.
why contact him on the phone.
I'II go overto meet him.
See how he'II meet me!
ReIations with smaII
peopIe do not behove us now.
How are you?
Forgive me for interrupting.
I kust couIdn't stay away.
You flnish yourwork.
I'm outside with yourwife.
Sister-in-Iaw, he's
converted home into offlce.
He never Iistens to me.
His hair is greying.
Is he working very hard?
Age too is racing past.
Our son too is grown up.
Yes, where is he? He used to
caII me Babuki when he was smaII.
I gave him his name. Prem.
You remember, sister-in-Iaw?
How can I forget? I got my son
onIy because of your prayers.
Oh no no sister-in-Iaw.
This is aII thanks to God.
That he has such good parents.
But where is he?
My husband insisted and sent
him to America for studies.
He's flnishing studies and
wiII return tomorrow. - Tomorrow?
Not since yesterday, I
know Rankit foryears.
And his daughter, Seema.
Rankit is one of the
weaIthiest men here.
Don't embarrass me, in this
city if anyone has prospered..
It is you. To own 14 factories
in a short time is incredibIe.
Great man!
We're setting up a
huge factory together.
By the way, what's your business?
I'm a dieseI mechanic.
I am sorry.
I've kust come to the city
I'II Ieave tonight for Dubai.
You couId've stayed for awhiIe.
-when I return I'II stay Iong.
I'm Ieaving her here.
If she makes a mistake,
don't hesitate to scoId her.
No, no. She is most weIcome.
We shouId make a move.
Oh yes. I am sorry, Karan.
I have an important
meeting with the bankers or..
I'd have dropped you to the
airport.. - Go ahead and work.
Arrange forthe driver.
-Yes.
ShaII we Ieave?
- See you, Karan.
Kishen? Won't you hug me once?
Now, go.
Let's have a IittIe
conference afterthe meeting.
Oh Manohar?
Come, Papa has Ieft.
- Papa has Ieft!
Thank you. Thank you.
They are shameIess.
They don't wear cIothes!
He's Manohar. Prem's chiIdhood
friend. He's afraid of Kishen.
Is he afraid of Kishen? Are you?
Peep inside him. He's Iike wax.
I can't even Iook at his
outside How can I peep within him?
Ifhe's here, I go the otherway.
Very strict man, papa..
Very strict man. Very
strong man! what muscIes, sir!
Bananas give you muscIes.
You're eating again?
- I'm fasting today.
You started eating again?
No not today, I am fasting today.
- Fasting? You are Iying to me
Not today, it was yesterday no
tomorrow.. when is it I don't know..
Okay, show Suman the house.
-Yes.
Let's begin with the kitchen.
I committed a grave sin today.
what?
- I Iied to mother.
But she won't feeI bad. I
know her since chiIdhood.
OnIy the Iucky orphans
get so much ofIove!
why are you dressing up..
..and putting Iime on your
face instead of working?
Don't disturb!
Servants in our
house taIk in EngIish.
Brothers teII us why this make up?
She.. is going to come.
My beIoved.
- Let's go.
My beIoved! - Lets go Suman,
there is danger here.
Won't you introduce me?
This is GuIabiya, the miIkmaid.
She comes and goes, has no other kob!
That's aII. Come on.
- Madam..
TeII him to show me teIevision.
Drama.. on the sIy.
Want to see teIevision?
-Yes.
SIyIy?
Ashamed in front of others?
-Yes.
ShaII I square your accounts?
-when wiII you do it?
Not now. I'm not in the mood.
when I have the time.
Right now I am on my duty. Let's go.
Everything is hot here. Let's go!
My beIoved is my foe.
Take the miIk!
This is your room. white and pure.
Open your bags. In the meantime..
You..?
- I'II begin from the kitchen again.
I'm hungry. ShaII I
get you something?
You hardIy eat anything. I'II
get something. You have to eat.
Listen..
-Yes?
May I caII you brother?
Thank you.
You're Ieaving very soon.
I'II return soon. Suman, I'm going.
Be good and Iearn everything.
I want no compIaints.
Forgive her if she errs.
She cries at IittIe things.
You're Ieaving her.
Won't she feeI emotionaI?
Today you're crying at my Ieaving
but tomorrow you'II cry Ieaving them.
You'II get so much Iove here.
Okay. See you.
ShaII we Ieave?
-Yes, oryou might be Iate.
Don't cry dear. Bid
fareweII to your Dad with a smiIe.
It's so Iate. IncIe hasn't come.
He has no time these days. He's
getting a big cabin made for his son
Says he'II gift it to him.
He's his pampered chiId.
He Ioves him a Iot.
- Don't ask how!
He won't meet him Iike a
Dad but Iike a sportsman.
He'II shake hands, wrestIe arm.
And then they wiII race.
WeIcome back, to India son.
WeIcome.
Seema. We have to get ahead in
this race of father and son.
I know, dad.
Then you aIso know why I've
trapped him in my friendship.
when you've trapped him,
why do you pretend to Iimp?
For sympathy?
- It strengthens friendship.
Kumar's Iife is his son.
He Iikes you so he'II sureIy
make you his daughter-in-Iaw.
But Prem is young, has hot bIood.
I don't trust him.
Don't worry, Papa. You
pretend to be friends.
I'II pretend to be in Iove.
CarefuI! Prem!
- Let him go!
The road is bIocked ahead.
He'II be trapped.
I won't be trapped!
V for victory!
Move!
We won flnaIIy!
You've never driven this fast.
There's another reason forthis.
Hi!
- HeIIo!
Madam!
The times ofknocking at
the door seem to have gone.
The times ofIocking the
doortoo seem to have gone.
Suman! I was
Iooking foryou. Met him?
Hi!
- HeIIo!
''God what do I do, I found a maze.''
''I found a maze.''
where's Prem?
- Changing in his room.
Foryou.
Stupid.
- Same to you, madam.
Are you going to Prem's room?
-why? Any obkections?
No! It wiII be better if
you open his door carefuIIy.
Thanks.
- Greetings.
Idiot.
- Same to you, madam.
''I found a maze.''
''She got kicked.''
Sorry.
Hope you're not hurt.
-what prank is this?
WlII you practice your
taIent ofboxing on us?
Sure. Save yourseIfif you can.
May I come in?
-Yes, why not. Come on in.
I'II wear my cIothes.
Prem
-Yes.
what did you do in America?
- In America?
Studies.
- Studies?
who studies these days?
-why?
Don't pretend to be innocent!
Hey! Don't Ieave me and go.
I feeI very IoneIy.
Excuse me. Lunch is served.
Everybody is waiting.
- Excuse me.
If you're free, wiII you
sit with herfor awhiIe?
She's feeIing very IoneIy.
Sure.
- I'm an expert in IoneIiness.
May I koin in to
pass time? Thank you.
That's because I ate corn.
Seema! Prem recited a nice coupIet..
..about you in the car.
ShaII I teII you?
Yes.
It's Iike this. Pay attention.
I want appIause.
Are these your
tresses or a net of satin?
Are these yourtresses or
a net of satin? WonderfuI.
How fortunate are the rats
who nibbIed away your hair!
WonderfuI.
PIease sit..
No thanks.
-YourwaIk man.
You Iike my poem so much
that you broke the gIass?
ShaII I teII more?
- Bye.
You're very oId fashioned.
Seema, I'II teII
you an imported Iine.
You'II break the entire house.
Shut up.
You said shut up. I said cut up..
Your cap.
Miss Suman!
Foryou, from me.
For me?
- Can't I give a gift to my friend?
Friend? But we kust met.
So what? Afriend is one
you want to meet and taIk to.
As soon as you see them you
shouId feeI ''that's my friend.''
And then ourfathers are friends.
And this cap has been
made forfriends. Right?
Thank you.
There's one ruIe in friendship.
No sorry. No thank you. Okay?
Okay.
- Okay, Mr. Kumar.
WonderfuI, today again
the son won the race.
whenever I Iose to him,
I'II ceIebrate my Iosing.
WeII done, my boy. WeII done.
Prem, wouId you Iike to smoke?
No sir, I don't smoke.
WonderfuI, one shouId
have a son Iike Prem!
No bad habits.
Let's go Seema.
Keep it up, Prem. Keep it up.
Your son possesses
aII your quaIities
Thumbs up, taste the thunder.
Prem, now get the cigarette!
Hurry up, dude.
I've been trying for so Iong!
But couIdn't smoke tiII date.
PeopIe puff away constantIy.
when did you begin?
Sometimes I'd take a puff
after dinner in America.
Hurry up! why are
you removing tobacco?
Give me cigarette.
It's flnished.
- It's flnished? Oh no!
Now where can we get it?
Let me think. Yes.
We'II get it!
-where?
In Papa's room, in the
white cigarette case. - I see.
Papa must be downstairs.
Go and get it.
-Yes. Me?
Are you mad? I won't go!
what? But why are
you so scared of Papa?
Look, wiII you go or not?
- I won't go!
I'II hit you!
- Chop my head with a sword.
But don't send me to 440 voIts.
Okay, we wiII do one thing. Let's go
together. And die together. PIease.
AII right. Let's go.
- Thanks.
I have work.
That way.
-where have I got stuck?
Go and get it aIone.
The road is cIear.
How wiII it open?
Open sesame! Open
This isn't opening.
Sesame has opened.
Manohar! what are you doing here?
IncIe!
CIearIy say what you want.
Prem has asked for a cigarette.
I mean a book.
-which one?
Our dear Papa.
Prem asked for it, not me!
Grandfather not papa.
IncIe not grandpa.
Vivekanand.
Our dear Vivekanand.
One minute.
what's wrong?
- Nothing. Exercise.
Stand straight.
Here you are.
Even I shaII read it.
He was a great man. I'II read it
in the day and return it by evening.
Brother! - Got caught?
- what are you hiding?
Lord Ram.
I went to borrow a book for Prem.
Cigarette.
- This is the cigarette..
Book, cigarette. Book..
The day is bad. I'II go mad!
Ramu!
- He's not here.
Give the master his tea in
his room. Sugar separate.
Prem.
- He's here.
You get me kiIIed one day.
Manohar!
- Idiot! Do something!
Now what wiII we do?
why do you hang these?
I've brought sweetmeats foryou.
Keep them there. I'II eat them.
But I'II feed him myseIf.
Manohar, open your mouth.
why is yourface swoIIen?
Open your mouth.
- Mother, we were boxing.
why do you keep flghting?
Ok, I'm keeping these here. Eat
them Iater. Otherwise I hit you.
what's burning?
Is something burning?
- No, mother.
Nothing is burning.
Aunty This is burning.
Brought it from the prayer room?
Give it to everybody.
I need this!
You saved us today!
This cigarette had me..!
You aIso throw it away. Throw
I said throw it away!
He's not throwing it!
Brother, cigarette smoking
is inkurious to heaIth. -Yes.
It is inkurious to heaIth.
Great, She asked you
to and you put it off.
Of course. You have to
do it if you make friends.
This time I'II pIay OIympics.
-You can't! Just eat bananas!
Lost again! Better stop pIaying.
You've Iost to me the third time
- I know.
FooI!
- I am fooI. And you're a champion?
Of course I'm the champion!
Manohar!
- Brother.
I see. PIaying tabIe tennis?
- No, we were swimming.
Greedy hog!
why are boys so
vain about their game?
Because this game requires stamina
and brains which girIs don't have.
Is that so? ShaII I pIay to show?
-Yes, I'II watch with mother.
Wlth me.
This Iooks Iike your Dad's Ietter.
Aunty, Iook at him.
Does he Iook Iike a champion?
- No way.
You Iost to me 3 times
Maybe you'II win with a toffee!
Don't want to pIay?
- Later.
Saw that? First I'II pIay
to show. Then, Iater. why?
why is she crying?
Herfather has written.
She wiII feeI emotionaI.
Wlpe yourtears.
She's not wiping them.
To feeI sad and cry aIone..
It's inkurious to heaIth.
Good! He said it once
and you wiped yourtears.
Of course. If you make friends,
you have to do it.
''You're a girI..''
''I'm a boy..''
''your arrivaI..''
''I swear..''
''ushers in the season of friendship''
''I'm a girI..''
''you're a boy''
''I feeI..''
''whenever I meet you..''
''the season of
friendship has arrived''
''I wonderwhy I feeI..''
''you and I have known
each otherfor ages''
''I wonderwhy I feeI..''
''you and I have known
each otherfor ages''
''That you give me so much of
respect, is a favourto me''
''About favours..''
''Iet's stop taIking''
''Come..''
''forge a tie with me..''
''the season of
friendship has arrived''
''I know not what Iove is aII about''
''AII I know is that I feeI a stab
in the heart when you Iook at me''
''I know not what Iove is aII about''
''AII I know is that I feeI a stab
in the heart when you Iook at me''
''SiIIy girI..''
''do not be innocent''
- Oh god''
''Yourwords..''
- I see.
''create a storm''
''This isn't the season for kokes''
''This isn't the season for suicide''
You? Come in.
How is the pain? - It's a
IittIe hurt. It wiII be flne.
Sit.
Suman. I am sorry.
There's one ruIe to friendship.
No sorry, no thank you. Okay?
Listen, keep this medicine there.
Suman. ShaII I appIy it?
I'II keep my eyes shut. Promise.
Do you know what mother
says about me? -what?
That I make friends wherever I go.
Abroad. But you are
different from aII of them.
You, yourtaIks.
Everything is different.
I don't know why? Do you know?
Won't you say anything?
Prem.
-Yes?
You can open your eyes.
-why? what's the matter?
Nothing.
- ReaIIy?
GirIs are Iike this! Crazy!
''There is no
reIationship between us..''
''..but there is
something that binds us together''
''There is no
reIationship between us..''
''..but there is
something that binds us together''
''what wiII we caII
ourfriendship..?''
''now, that's something eIse''
''Craziness..''
''you can caII it''
''A heart aflutter..''
''you can caII it..''
''the season of
friendship has arrived''
''Forthe season of
Come in Prem.
This is my nephew, Jeevan.
- Hi! - He'II Iearn work with us.
Excuse me.
Let's have the
inauguration this Sunday.
Hi!
- Hi Prem!
I've organized a party for Saturday.
Just friends. You must come.
Prem, She's caIIed you forthe
party why are you taking me aIong?
Shut up! I won't go without you.
why?
-what do you mean?
Answer me why?
Because..
- Because?
I won't teII!
Do you know you're Iooking
handsome.
I'm very handsome. Know
what mother says about me?
That I Iook dashing when
I shave and wear a coat.
Are you getting bored?
- No.
Do you what mother says?
I have a certain styIe.
Are you getting bored?
- No.
Mother praising me
is obvious. ActuaIIy..
There's something in some peopIe.
Am I right?
-Yes.
Hi Prem. Looking great.
what are you doing?
Aren't you ashamed?
You have no right to take any
one's Iife to practice shooting.
Got it!
- Miss Suman!
This pigeon is mine. I bought it.
I've trained it.
My brother has aII the
right ifhe wants to shoot it.
who are you to interfere?
Give it to me.
This is the Iimit! what
do you think of yourseIf?.
Listen once and for aII.
Once and for aII, you bIoody..
Mind yourtongue!
Come on. We won't
stay here any Ionger.
Let's go.
Hey Prem, reIax, take
it easy, cooI it, dude.
This goes on in friendship.
Come on Seema.
ApoIogize to her. Come on.
I am sorry, Suman.
what's wrong?
-what does she think ofherseIf?.
No manners at aII!
You feIt hurt?
- Of course!
Now don't ask why.
why?
Get me some food.
I'm famished.
Right away.
After dinnerteII me what
eIse mother says about you.
I won't be bored.
Suman, Are you taking
this for Prem? -Yes.
We too are hungry. PIease.
Excuse me.
- PIease.
PIease!
''Love me.''
''Touch me. Kiss me.''
''Do it right.''
''Love me.''
''Touch me.''
''Kiss me.''
''Do it right.''
PIease.
''Love me.''
''Touch me.''
Prem! Prem!
''Do it right.''
Prem! what's wrong? Have I
committed a crime in touching her?
You want the same
thing I want. ReaIIy!
There's something about her.
-Jeevan!
Not one more word!
So what? She won't be worthy of
you?
You're quite worried about her.
Is she your private property?
what is she?
- His friend.
Friends did you hearthat? Can a
young boy and girI be friends?
See this scene of young friendship!
A good drama of friendship!
Prem! A girI and boy
are neverfriends.
This is a curtain to hide the
flames of passion on dark nights.
Prem!
Great! Friendship in a new
house brought good dividends.
CongratuIate! CongratuIate them.
CongratuIate them.
Hip hip hurrya!
Seema. Stop them.
- How many wiII you stop?
You are the cause of this.
Don't Iet this reIation grow.
which wiII give Prem
nothing but defamation.
Get out.
Prem, A girI and boy
can never be friends.
Friendship in a new house
can brought good dividends.
CongratuIations.
Don't Iet this reIation grow.
It won't give Prem
anything but for defamation.
Your cap.
ShamIaI! Mr. Prabhu
wiII be bringing some..
..papers from the head offlce.
-Yes.
Send them to the site.
I'II go in Prem's car. Ok?
Hurry up. It's getting Iate.
Coming. It wouId be nice if you'd
come forthe opening of the factory.
You'II be Ieft aIone at home.
BrotherwiII be here.
-As you wish.
Come on, son.
I don't know what the
worId caIIs our reIation.
I don't know the
Iimits of this reIationship.
I onIy know this
much I have Ioved you.
what is this if not Iove?
I Iaugh if you Iaugh.
I cry if you cry.
where there's Iove,
the heart gets hurt.
I Iove you.
I wish I'd understood the
depth of this reIation earIier.
Wlsh I couId send the flrst Ietter
of the flrst Iove to my beIoved.
''Go on..''
''FIy away, O pigeon. Go away..''
''This is the flrst
Iove-Ietter I have even written. ''
Iove-Ietter I have even written.''
''give it to my beIoved''
''FIy away, O pigeon. Go away.''
''Ever since he has Ieft, teII
him that I flnd myseIfincompIete''
''My Iips are seaIed. I
neither cry, nor smiIe''
''It was a mistake
that I teased him..''
''it was a mistake
''it was a grave sin''
''FIy away, O pigeon. Go away..''
''FIy away, O pigeon.
Go away.. Go away..''
''Deep down in my heart, I
have taken him for my own''
''what we mean to each other,
I now reaIise''
''Bring him with you..''
''bring him aIong when you return,
I don't Iike it without him''
''FIy away, O pigeon. Go away..''
''The weather here is IoveIy.
Yet, I'm IoneIy''
''Even ifI'm far away, my
heart is stiII with her''
''Give herthis message..''
''you must give herthis message..''
''I'II foIIow you soon''
''FIy away, O pigeon. Go away..''
''FIy away, O pigeon. Go away.''
''wherever I see, I can see you.''
''I don't see anything eIse''
''I wish the worId wouId freeze,
whiIe we feeI Iike this''
''Never before..''
''Never before was
the worId so beautifuI''
''I Iove you.''
I Iove you.
I..
- I?
IncIe and Aunt have come.
where's IncIe?
- He's gone to the factory.
why did you return so earIy?
Dragged by the friend's friendship.
what do you mean?
- I'd caIIed so he ran.
Greetings, aunt. -what happened
to you? - Stomach upset for 2 days.
AIways eating trash. No
food for him for 2 days.
Nothing?
- No. - But now I'm flne.
Mother.
Trafflc constabIe!
Mustn't Iisten to her.
Get some food. Go.
It's a banana.
AIone. Nice, isn't it?
Did a good thing.
Hey, You were saying something?
what?
- I Iove you.
Not now. - Fine. We'II
go boating this evening.
Don't say, not now then.
Be prepared.
At 4 o'cIock.
Come on, Iet's go.
what's cooking?
Today is fuII moon night.
The neighborhood Iadies
are coming for prayers.
Lots of guests wiII be coming.
They wiII stay for dinner.
There's Iots of work.
- These fat guys wiII do it.
I'II take you out.
- Me? Didn't flnd anybody eIse?
ShaII we come?
- SiIence.
Give me those and rest for a whiIe.
Ramu, Shamu come with me.
Sister, fry these.
Do you have henna on your hands?
No.
- ShaII we appIy it?
I have some work. 5 minutes.
It's 4:15. Just 5 minutes.
- Okay.
It happens.
''Come, it's aImost evening''
''The weather's taking a turn''
''So what are we flghting over?''
''Go ahead.. I'II foIIow you''
Oh no.
''Come, it's aImost evening''
''The weather's taking a turn''
''So what are we flghting over?''
''Go ahead.. I'II foIIow you''
No, no.
''what time is it?
Look at yourwatch''
''May we not Iose this
precious moment ofIove''
''what time is it?
Look at yourwatch''
''May we not Iose this
precious moment ofIove''
''Be patient tiII I come over..''
''I'II then set an
aIarm for our Iove''
''You're as distant as
you are cIose to me''
''Yours and mine is a
strange Iove story indeed''
''Damn it.''
''It's a question of my Iife.
- That's how deepIy we Iove''
''So what are we flghting over?''
''Go ahead.. I'II foIIow you''
My God.
Come soon, dear.
''Enough of your kokes..''
''come now, the Sun is about to set''
''My heart is fuII of desires..''
''I'II come in a moment and teII you''
''My magic has worked.
There's a smiIe on your Iips''
''I waIk ahead, you waIk behind me''
''Damn it.''
''So say good-bye to everyone''
''I'm in Iove with you, I'm coming''
''So what are we flghting over?''
''Go ahead.. I'II foIIow you''
Make it fast.
Oh, come on.
Come to appIy henna.
- Henna?
Henna?
-Yes, come on. - Henna!
Hey.
See how it Iooks on my hands.
Are you tired?
Are you very angry?
Won't you taIk to me?
No! I'm not in the mood.
May I say something to
put you in a good mood?
I don't want to hear anything.
- Nothing?
No.
No!
Okay, I'II stiII say it.
You may hear it if you want.
I.
Love.
I Iove, what?
Not in the mood now.
That's too much! Now if you
pretend, I'II teII mother!
what?
That the marriage season is on.
Get me married eIsewhere.
Oh reaIIy? How nice.
Go right now.
AII the best.
-AII the best.
Thank you.
-WeIcome.
Mother!
Prem, carefuIIy..
I have something
important To discuss.
what? -Aren't you worried
about me? -why? what happened?
what happened? Mother,
Have you ever Iooked at me?
I've grown up. Don't you
want to get me married?
AIready thinking of marriage?
You shouIdn't take
these things IightIy.
ChiIdren shouIdn't be
given freedom these days.
So far I'm very decent
but ifI sIip up somewhere?
Papa stiff neck wiII be bent.
But how do I know what
kind of a girI you'II Iike?
Mother, I am very
cIear about that point.
That's absoIuteIy cIear in my eyes.
She must neverwear SaIwar
kameez.
She must wear onIy keans,
skirts, middies, minis.
Mother, she shouId
be very good Iooking.
She shouIdn't have Iong hair.
AbsoIuteIy short. Bob cut.
Mother, this and that..
She shouId be an atom bomb.
But such a girI won't
do anything in the house.
She won't sheII peas.
- She wiII aunt.
Won't she?
-Yes, she wiII!
Respect for eIders, mingIing with
her age and Iove foryoungsters.
She won't possess these quaIities
- She wiII respect everyone.
Won't she?
-Yes, she wiII.
And I'II force her if she doesn't.
Start Iooking for a bride for me.
Listen.
WlII you have some tea?
IfI eat, it wiII onIy
be after my marriage.
FeII down!
It happens.
Now I'm going to bed.
Now I have to search for
a bride for his makesty.
That too ofhis choice.
He's Iived in America!
Good day.
- How are you?
I'm flne.
Lord! I'm dying ofhunger.
The difflcuIties of the devotee..
..are eased in a kiffy by you.
Om Jai Jagdish Hare.
The difflcuIties of the devotee..
The food runs away!
Brother.
Dinner. Eat it fast.
No! No!
what's the matter?
- It vanishes.
Vanishes.
It's fake.
- No, it's reaI.
It's reaI!
-Yes.
It is reaI! May I eat it?
ShaII I feed you?
- Feed it to me.
Its come back.
You are so nice.. what's this?
what's wrong?
- FuII moon night and you're sad?
He hasn't eaten dinner.
- So even you haven't eaten.
Then even I won't eat.
Is he annoyed?
PIease him.
what does he want?
He wants me to hoId my ears
and say, 'I Iove you' thrice.
OnIy then wiII he eat.
- Then say it.
How can I say it? He's
sitting with the women.
I feeI shy.
That's how he's troubIing you!
-Yes.
Come on.
-where?
To teII him. We can be one up on
him
We'II give him tit fortat!
You'II say it now,
in front of everyone.
In orderto spend some time
Iet's sing songs in a game.
who wiII pIay?
-AII of us wiII pIay!
Very good.
Won't you pIay?
- I don't want to!
Scared of girIs!
- I'm scared?
Of course!
-We'II see!
Let's begin.
Now begin.
WlII you sit here?
-Yes.
Next to me?
For prayers?
-Yes.
I'II give you one! Go away!
why are you yeIIing? I am going.
We wiII win. Come here.
- Go and see yourface!
Ms. Suman are you ready?
''Come to me, Spring is here..''
''my heart pines. I cannot
Iive without you, my Prince''
''Come to me.''
''Go away..''
''Iet me not think of you again''
''Go away, Iet me not
think of you again''
''Let me forget you..''
''go away..''
''Iet me not think of you again''
''why are you angry with me?''
''Forgive me, ifI have
committed a mistake''
''I intended nothing bad..''
''your behaviour is
itseIf my punishment''
''Awanderer sings
the songs ofIove..''
''I teII everyone the way to Iife''
''Awanderer sings..''
''How are you doing?''
''what do you think?''
''You sure are having a baII!''
''I happened to sIip''
''How are you doing?''
''As Kabir says, I speak the truth..''
''this worId is rotten,
and I'm worse''
''As Kabir says, I speak the truth..''
''this worId is rotten,
and I'm worse''
''As Lord Rama said..''
''there wiII come an age of sin..''
''swans wiII pick on grains
and crows wiII peck pearIs''
''As Lord Rama said..''
''LoveIy time..''
''everyone is intoxicated''
''whoever is bothered about anyone''
''In every heart, Iove is young''
''Rama..''
''I go away, I am now an outsider''
''I Ieave my Iand,
I'm now an outsider''
''Beauty..''
''has a miIIion hues..''
''which coIour..''
''wouId you preferto see?''
''Aflre..''
''is my body''
''which part of my body..''
''wouId you Iike to see?''
''Do not be so vain
about yourfair skin..''
''your compIexion
wiII paIe with time''
''Do not be so vain
about yourfair skin..''
''your compIexion
wiII paIe with time''
''I'm a flame and
you are a flrefly..''
''you wiII burn before me''
''Do not be so vain
about yourfair skin..''
''Wait there, O thou that Ieaves..''
''you are the goaI I traveI towards''
''Even if you think
I'm the bad sorts..''
''I'm not bad at heart''
''Wait there.''
''You come every pIace I go to..''
''and sneak into my heart''
''TeII me. what do you mean to me?''
''I've been your Ioverfor ages..''
''whetheryou beIieve it or not''
''I came aIong to
pIacate you, my Iove..''
''whetheryou beIieve me or not''
''whetheryou beIieve it or not''
''In my eyes is a dream, in
my dream is my beIoved..''
''to my beIoved goes my heart''
''In my eyes is a dream, in
my dream is my beIoved..''
''to my beIoved goes my heart''
''This is the pubIic!''
''The pubIic knows everything''
''what's inside''
''what's without''
''what's inside
-what's without''
''They understand everything''
''The pubIic knows everything''
''This is the pubIic!''
''A secret I have
kept from my Iips..''
''ifI were to utter it,
aII heII wouId break Ioose''
''A secret that
speaks ofIove and venom''
''A secret I have
kept from my Iips..''
''ifI were to utter it,
aII heII wouId break Ioose''
''There's a Iimit to my patience''
''There's no word from my beIoved''
''I do beIieve..''
''she's not unfaithfuI''
''So what reason couId it be
that she keeps me waiting?''
''Days and nights, I can't spend..''
''that which I must teII you..''
''I teII you now''
''I Iove you.''
Come, Iet's go home.
-We had a great fun here.
You've won. Next time
don't ever stay hungry.
Sir, she too hasn't eaten.
She'II eat it.
- No, you'II have to feed her.
Come with me.
-where?
Let's go and taIk to Prem
about his wedding. -Yes.
what?
I think I shouId get a
daughter-in-Iaw as soon as possibIe
Come on.
-Yes. - Come on.
Damn.
Prem.
- Hi, mother.
Going to the offlce?
-Yes. why?
Nothing. Have your breakfast
and sit with us for a whiIe.
Sure.
what's the matter?
- Nothing.
We've come to discuss your
marriage.
Marriage?
-Yes, I've found you a bride.
what is it? She's
kust as you had wanted.
She doesn't wear saIwar kameez..
The onIy things she wears are..
But Iisten to me..
- Don't worry. Her hair isn't Iong.
Short. Bob cut.
She's Iike this and that. Happy?
Mother, sit down.
Listen..
- No. - She's giving it with Iove.
Thank you.
I thought a Iot yesterday.
- ReaIIy.
You are right. Such a girI
won't work in the house.
She won't sheII peas.
- She wiII.
Isn't it, Suman?
If she won't, I'II make her.
But mother, respecting eIders,
Ioving youngsters. She won't do that.
No mother..
She won't? Then what shouId we
do?
You flnd a different type of girI.
Find somebody cIose to you.
Find one of your choice.
WlII my choice do?
- Of course it wiII!
Suman.
- Suman.
Won't she do?
- If you say so..
She'II do.
- There's no hurry.
Take yourtime to
think before teIIing me.
Mother.
WlII she do?
- I'm going.
Mother, bye. Mother, Iet
me go. PIease, mother.
PIease, mother.
Love you, mother.
Crazy fooI!
I'm reaIIy fortunate.
WlII you be my crazy son's Suman?
Stay here to spread
fragrance in my home forever.
I onIy want both of you to be happy.
Must be Prem.
You taIk to him. I'm off.
Hi.
- HeIIo.
Mother said something to me today.
Today mother said
something to me too.
what do you think?
''I Iove you.''
Today is a reaIIy beautifuI day.
This coIourfuI weather.
I want to be coIored in
WlII you koin me?
''I Iove you.''
Hi aunt Seema. I am done for.
Had it! Going to Prem's room?
Any obkections? Yes
and I'II be carefuI
No. But, He's not in there.
He has gone out
with his future bride.
Sister-in-Iaw.
- He has decided to marry Suman.
Any obkections?
Thank you, Mr. Kumar.
Seema, his son, sir has obIiged us.
By accepting your proposaI for..
I'd chosen a sampIe .. You
may not beIieve it but..
..anticipation of this day.
..of a wedding card in.
Seema, do you Iike it?
She Iikes it very much.
Then we aIso Iike it.
Wow, Let yourwife
too approve ofit.
Jeevan show it to her.
It's her choice too.
- No, uncIe.
what do you mean?
She Iikes somebody eIse.
''My heart is crazy..''
''without my beIoved.''
''it won't be pIacated''
''My heart is crazy..''
''without my beIoved.''
''it won't be pIacated''
''It's mad.''
''it won't see reason''
''It's mad..''
''It is restIess day and night.''
''it won't see reason''
''It's mad..''
''The worId seeks its desires.''
''I seek onIy my beIoved''
''Let my beIoved and
his famiIy Iive Iong.''
''Wlthout him, I seek
nothing eIse from God''
''It's mad.''
''it won't see reason''
''I shaII forever
provide coverforyou''
''Wlth you, I wiII
fly away in the skies''
''There's so much more my heart
wants to do. what wiII I teII you?''
''It's mad..''
''it won't see reason''
what are you thinking, Mr. Kumar?
The girI you gave refuge to, is
dreaming of marrying into your house!
She's taking advantage
of Prem's innocence.
Nobody kust gifts an
expensive Iocket to anyone!
Some peopIe are known
for grabbing rights!
when I tried to show her
her pIace, she sIapped me!
Excuse me but if somebody has a
hand in this, it's that cheat's father!
Yourfriend!
You have done your duty as a
friend.
He is the one who is shameIess.
But he's a stain of friendship!
He Ieft his daughter her on purpose.
Suman's birthday faIIs in 2 days.
Can't say what she might
ask Prem for as a gift.
Did you caII me?
Yes, there's some urgent
work in our new pIant.
I may not be abIe to go.
Instead you shouId go.
Leave by 6 in the morning.
Tomorrow?
-why? Some otherwork?
I'II go.
So you're going? And
breaking your promises?
Even I want to stay back.
Then refuse Dad.
- No.
You must go if
uncIe has asked you to
Don't disobey him. We'II
ceIebrate some other day.
But..
- Brother.
Consider her as you sister.
Nobody Iistens to us!
She is trying to act smart.
when wiII you return?
- In 4 or 5 days.
I'II be waiting.
Now we wait for Prem to Ieave.
Yes, Jeevan.
Tomorrow morning KumarwiII
teII Suman ofhis decision.
Poor girI, father.
Her heart wiII break.
He's given it to me.
why are you keaIous? Look away.
who is it?
Prem.
Come on.
- Prem.
Listen to me. Prem.
How couId I Ieave without
ceIebrating your birthday?
Enough, come here.
How are the gifts.
-Very nice.
ShaII I wearthem?
- There's one more.
Someone Iike this.
ShaII I wear it and show?
''You are coIoured in
the hues of my Iove..''
''are you a fairy, or
the Fairy Queen herseIf?.''
''Or are you the one
who makes my Iove story?''
''PIease repIy to my questions..''
''pIease do''
''You are coIoured in
the hues of my Iove..''
''are you a fairy, or
the Fairy Queen herseIf?.''
''Or are you the one
who makes my Iove story?''
''PIease repIy to my questions..''
''pIease do''
''why do the stars and the
Moon gape at yourface?''
''what makes the air gets its
fragrance when it touches you..''
''what drives the night berserk?''
''PIease repIy to my questions..''
''pIease do''
''why are you so shy?''
''You aIso Iook scared''
''why's your scarf sIipping..''
''why is there an
excitement in my heart?''
''My questions, pIease answer..''
''pIease do''
''There's a diIemma on both sides..''
''Iike the union of a
bride with her bridegroom''
''There's a diIemma on both sides..''
''Iike the union of a
bride with her bridegroom''
''why are the two of
us in this state?''
''what makes us Iove
each other so much?''
''PIease repIy to my questions..''
''pIease do''
''You are coIoured in
the hues of my Iove..''
''are you a fairy, or
the Fairy Queen herseIf?.''
''Or are you the one
who makes my Iove story?''
''PIease repIy to my questions..''
Don't send me away.
''I Iove you.''
''I Iove you.
- I Iove you.''
ShouId I return earIy?
Live Iong dear. Happy birthday.
May I take tea for uncIe?
So you want to serve your
father-in-Iaw tea by yourseIf?.
HoId it.
Is today your birthday?
-Yes.
How oId are you?
- 18.
You're very smart
for an 18 year oId.
I have nothing against you.
You've been given the convenience
of staying here not the right.
Wlth what right have you
stepped into my son's Iife?
what right? I want an answer!
I want an answer!
I'II give you the answer.
Prem's Iove has
given herthat right.
My decision to make
her my daughter-in-Iaw!
She can't be our daughter-in-Iaw!
why not?
- Because she came here as a guest.
She's dreaming of owning this
pIace!
She and herfather contrived to
own this property worth Iakhs!
She and herfather have
stabbed my friend in the back!
whose friendship are you accusing?
The one who supported us in
poverty and difflcuIt times?
Thanks to whom we have a son!
what wiII he do with weaIth?
You seem to have forgotten the
meaning of friendship today!
KaushaIya.
- Look at her innocent face once.
Can she do this?
- Herface shieIds her pIan.
Now she can't stay here for a
minute! She has to Ieave now!
This is my decision!
Suman.
C.A.T, it is cat.
Right orwrong?
Happy birthday my chiId!
You're crying? SiIIy! I've come.
I Ieft everything to
reach right on your birthday.
To your and my friend!
why is everyone so quiet?
See what I've brought
for everyone. Keep it here.
Have some sweets.
I bought you a pen.
This is yourtooI. HeIIo.
I bought you sarees.
I picked them aII up.
AII the coIours suit you.
where is Prem?
Prem son, see what
Babuki bought foryou!
what a way to win hearts!
Both father and daughter!
why? Have I or my
daughter done something wrong?
Mistake?
ReaIIy sir, these poor
IowIy peopIe are Iike this!
BIood sucking parasites!
- Mr. Rankit!
ControI yourtongue!
-You shouId've controI.
ControIIed your daughter!
what she has done here!
She has brought
shame to this famiIy!
Mr. Rankit!
She has shown hertrue coIours!
what did you say!
Karan!
Stop this bestiaIity! Enough!
Did you hearwhat
he said about Suman?
He is right!
Kishen. -You took undue
advantage of my friendship!
You Ieft her here
with uIterior motives!
So that she couId trap Prem in
her Iove and own this house!
I never imagined you couId
spin a goIden web forweaIth!
Kishen.
- Don't scream!
Before dreaming of converting
ourfriendship into reIationship..
You shouId have seen
the distance between us.
where I earn Iakhs,
you make 2000 a month!
Kishen.
- Isn't it 2000?
Come to my position flrst
and then see these dreams!
Stop it! Now you've gone
farfrom me
My friendship is a burden now!
Today my cIothes stink!
The daughter of this man who earns
onIy 2000 is not flt to stay here!
I accept it and don't bIame you.
But why this faIse
accusation on my chiId?
My daughter is my pride!
Answer me, why?
- First of aII you kept her here!
I did you a favour and..
- Favour?
You obIiged me by
keeping my daughter?
Is this aII that
remains of ourfriendship?
No. I won't be obIiged to you!
I'II pay the price
of your 5 star hoteI!
In which you kept my
daughter and fed her!
what are the Iodging and
boarding charges here?
TeII me. 5000? 10000?
20000? 50000?
Answer me!
Get out.
- I'm going!
I'II be waiting foryou
outside this flve star hoteI!
Brother.
-Yes, sister-in-Iaw.
The bonds of the heart are broken.
I shaII Ieave.
Maybe I'm not the answerto your
dreams. Erase this symboI ofIove.
I don't have the courage.
''I Iove you''
PIease come. Let's go.
Sir is waiting foryou.
Come, Prem.
-WeIcome, my son. WeIcome.
I have to taIk to you.
We wiII taIk son.
But in your own cabin.
Sit on this chair and
take charge of the company.
Come on.
Forwhat crime are you punishing
me?
This is a gift foryou.
Now make your own decisions.
- I had taken one decision.
Of marrying Suman.
why was that rekected?
Prem.
-Yes Papa.
why?
I'II expIain to you, son.
Your Papa need not
give you expIanations.
where are you going?
I'm Ieaving home.
-why?
Excuse me, But even your son
need not give you any expIanation.
Prem! Dear Prem!
Listen to me. what do you Iack?
AII this is yours. Next week
you're getting engaged to Seema.
The cards have been given! Sir,
you expIain to him.
Mr. Rankit, what do I expIain him?
He hasn't seen the worId
outside which is crueI and wicked.
He can't even waIk
properIy on the roads.
I wiII Iearn.
-You don't even know..
How difflcuIt it is to earn money.
what a struggIe it is!
- I wiII Iearn.
Learn? what wiII you Iearn?
You don't even know how to Iearn.
Love teaches everything.
Stop him before I take nay step!
He hasn't honoured his father
He'II at Ieast honouryour Iove!
Stop him.
when she was here, I
couIdn't give these to her.
when you meet my daughter-in-Iaw
sIip these bangIes on herwrists.
Mother, am I right?
Are you with me?
I needn't fear anything?
Mother.
Prem, Are you going?
-Yes.
But we are to get engaged?
PIease don't Ieave me.
AII right.
Then come with me.
Come on.
Thinking?
PeopIe in Iove neverthink.
''I Iove you''
''TwinkIe, twinkIe IittIe star.''
''How I wonderwhat you are.''
''Ip above the worId so high.''
''Like a diamond in the sky.''
''TwinkIe, twinkIe IittIe star.''
IncIe has come!
Babuki.
I am Prem.
I know you are angry.
Papa abused you quite a bit.
I apoIogise to you.
The fatherwounds and the
son appIies saIver. ApoIogizes!
Go away before I thrash you.
Dear, go away.
I haven't come to go away.
I've given up everything
and come to marry Suman.
Mother has sent these bangIes for
Suman as a symboI ofher acceptance.
Go inside, Suman.
Go inside!
I aIways foIIowed my heart.
Maybe that's why I never became rich
Like yourfather! But
today I understand the worId!
I've Iearnt today.
Sister-in-Iaw's
bangIes can't move me!
I survived the
accusation ofIooting weaIth!
But I won't bear being
accused of steaIing bangIes!
Hearthis carefuIIy! My chiId
won't marry into that house!
Even if yourfather comes to
my door and rubs his nose!
I Iove her.
No, you pIayed a game!
Like yourfather!
I'm going to see a boy for my
daughtertomorrow. Hear it weII!
''My heart is crazy..''
''without my beIoved..''
''it won't be pIacated''
''My heart is crazy..''
''without my beIoved..''
''it won't be pIacated''
''It's mad..''
''it won't see reason''
''It keeps pounding, it sings
the same song aII the time''
''It's mad..''
''it won't see reason''
''what anguish separation gives,
you know, I know''
''My Iove beckons me
and the worId stops me..''
''whom am I to heed?''
''InIess I meet you, my
heart can think of nothing''
''It's mad..''
''it won't see reason''
''Love flows in my bIoodstream,
it caIIs you''
''I've Iost everything in Iove.
My courage, I wiII not Iose''
''Ask the worId not to
stop hearts from meeting''
''It's mad..''
''it won't see reason''
''My heart is crazy..''
''without my beIoved..''
''it won't be pIacated''
''It's mad..''
''it won't see reason''
''TwinkIe, twinkIe IittIe star.''
''How I wonderwhat you are.''
what do you want? why are
you bent on ruining my chiId!
I've come to give her aII
the koys you want for her.
Joys for her?
where? In that hoIIow
worId of yourfather's?
I'II make my own worId.
You are angry with my father not
me.
Look at me kust once.
Forget I'm Kumar's son.
Judge me after separating
me from my father's name.
Like any normaI boy, I've come
to ask foryour daughter's hand.
AII right. Come.
Sit!
How much do you earn?
what do you earn?
How this question hurts!
It cuts through the heart!
Yourfather simiIarIy asked me..
..about my earning.
A man earning 2000 a month has to
reach his status before dreaming!
Today I ask you,
what is your status?
Dad, what are you saying?
Dear, I am right.
You stay out of this. You
can't settIe down by running away.
How wiII he Iook afteryou?
Ifhis Iove is true,
Let him prove that..
Let him reach my status.
Earn 2000 rupees!
Then Iet him dream.
I'II earn it.
I'II prove my Iove.
In this very viIIage.
In front of you.
I'II earn 2000 in one month.
Dad! These are mother's bangIes.
Keep them safe with you.
I'II give them to Suman
when the condition is met.
2000? In one month!
Prem, This is a hiIIy region.
We onIy work on stones and wood.
This isn't even the tourist season.
You are educated. Go to the city.
No, I have to earn it here.
Give me any work.
Even the Iast batch of
workers is fuII. I am very sorry.
Sundar! Has the truck driver come?
- No sir.
We are waiting for him.
Labour is sitting
idIe at the other side.
We have to deIiver materiaI there.
The road is so dangerous.
who wiII take the Iorry?
Sir, I'II take it.
-You?
Yes. I want work!
''I Iove you.''
Give me the key of the truck.
Is this the time to come?
Comes to work, drunk!
Listen, You may go.
We've kept another driver
Another driver?
-Yes.
Square his account.
Let's go.
Sir! This is insuIting.
Another driverwhen you're around?
Brother!
Listen.. stop the truck.
what are you doing?
Hey Listen! Brother!
Brother, what are you doing?
stop the truck.
Stop the truck!
That's enough! Now move aside.
I have to park it aside.
You Iove to drive trucks?
Wants the truck!
Hey you!
Saw the outcome of
kicking me out of my kob!
Take the key of the truck.
ScoundreI.
Every man has his earning
written when he comes here.
But if you don't respect it,
it won't wait foryou.
If you Iook at him, the hands
that taught you driving wiII..
..make you forget it! Get Iost!
Get Iost!
Son, Hope you're not hurt.
- No.
who is it?
Sit down.
Eaten?
Forget it son. You can't do this.
One day has tired you out.
29 days stiII remain.
You have Iost. Go back.
You'II be happy.
Come. Take your
mother's bangIes back.
Take them.
This is my flrst earning.
And the flrst earning is
given to an eIder, isn't it?
The one who beIong to us.
BIess me.
Son.
You can stay here if you wish.
Yourfather obIiged me by
keeping my daughter in his house.
I can obIige you.
If you want to obIige me,
then onIy do this.
Don't Iet tears
come to Suman's eyes.
Now I'II come to your step onIy
after compIeting the condition.
After 29 days!
''I Iove you.''
''I've given my heart away
to buy an ache for myseIf'
''It's a deaI I've
carried out with due thought''
''For, I have Ioved''
''I have faIIen in Iove''
''I've given my heart away
to buy an ache for myseIf'
''It's a deaI I've
carried out with due thought''
''For, I have Ioved''
''I have faIIen in Iove''
''The flrst evertime I saw her..''
''she had come to shape my destiny''
''LittIe did I know that
things wouId go so far..''
''that I'd even have
to work hard in Iove''
''Those with a heart are
not afraid ofhard work..''
''those who are afraid,
are not in Iove''
''For, I have Ioved''
''I have faIIen in Iove''
''AII the weaIth in the worId,
I have aIready spurned''
''I have come to rest in
the shade ofhertresses''
''This shade is for me,
for me, it wiII be''
''whatever I say, the worId wiII say''
''Even if the Moon and
the Sun stop dazzIing..''
''it's difflcuIt to
make me change my mind''
''For, I have Ioved''
''I have faIIen in Iove''
''My heart is yours, so is my Iife..''
''your Iove is what I am known for''
''I say today in
everybody's presence..''
''what I wiII say
some day to God too''
''You are the one who wiII
have to mend the fences''
''Hearts that are separated,
you must bring together''
''For, I have Ioved''
''I have faIIen in Iove''
''I've given my heart away
to buy an ache for myseIf'
''It's a deaI I've
carried out with due thought''
''For, I have Ioved''
''I have faIIen in Iove''
Let's go.
It's terribIy coId here!
And I forgot my sweater.
Hi handsome, how are you?
How did you know I was coming?
How are Prem and Suman?
Prem, I am coming. Shut up.
Foryou.
WeIcome sir.
- These guys keep Iaughing?
Just foIIow my friend. Let's go.
Let's go.
-We've got a customer.
Sir says to kust foIIow.
But who is to be foIIowed?
Move!
Brother Behind that?
-Yes. Let's go.
Behind her?
- Let's go. why fear?
He's a speciaI friend of mine.
Came to the station to take me!
WaIks with such styIe!
And what a name!
Handsome.
why did you stop?
-Yourfriend is Iooking at you!
My friend? My friend is here.
No, here.
-where?
He's coming here!
- Don't Ieave me aIone!
Look afteryour brother!
Your brother ran away.
I came onIy foryou!
Quiet! what's your name?
Sridevi.
Looks Iike Freedevi!
-what?
If you are Sridevi. I am HiIendra.
I mean Jitendra!
where did Khadar Khan go?
- There.
Let's go to the garden.
We wiII sing a song.
We'II have an ice cream. Let's go.
I'II comb my hair.
- They're flne. Come on!
My honour is in your hands,
Basanti, come on!
She feII!
May you be ruined!
Pretends to be Jeetendra!
Meet me and I'II show you!
May you be ruined!
AII are flne in city.
Mother has sent you her Iove.
Everybody misses you.
You are worth ofit.
Brother Manohar.
How is GuIabiya?
- She too misses you
I knew you'd ask!
How do I know? Am I her
bodyguard?
Instead she's my body guard!
Dear.
- Coming. Coming.
Sir, where are you?
- Here.
Here, where? Yes sir!
How do you feeI after a bath?
- Fresh.
I'II Iike it even
more ifI sit there.
ShaII I sit there?
I'm very hungry but if you say..
- Go ahead and eat.
what shouId I eat?
The food Iooks deIicious.
HeIIo sir.
Sit and eat. I'm off.
Sir, your muscIes
are very strong, sir.
Emergency food.
Take.
what's wrong?
- Such a pretty face and sad?
Suman! what's the matter?
How is mother?
-Very weII.
Look, Mother has sent money
foryou aIong with sweetmeats.
I don't need the money.
-what do you mean?
I won't take this money.
- Then what wiII you do?
WlII you burn yourseIf aII month?
what sin have you committed?
Love has no conditions.
Then why this pretense?
Come here and Iisten to me.
Come here. See this.
There's 5000 in this. Give him
2000 and get married today itseIf.
I'II arrange forthe priest.
- No, Manohar.
If you won't Iisten to me,
ourfriendship is flnished.
Won't my bIood boiI
seeing you in this state?
Manohar! Hey Manohar!
Do you rememberwhat I
toId Papa when I Ieft?
Love teaches everything. IfI take
this money, how wiII I ever Iearn?
what do you want?
Do you want to prove my Iove faIse?
WlII you then respect yourfriend?
I'II keep the money.
Give it to me.
I Iove her. I have to do this.
Go and teII mother, today
I've Iearnt the vaIue of money.
Hey Jitendra.
what do you say? Sridevi
has come dressed up! Yes.
It is said your prayers come true.
Pray for my friend.
That he gets married soon.
I pray to God yourwishes come
true!
Don't take his name!
-why? Isn't he your son?
I have no son!
-You don't have a son?
Is he an orphan Iike me?
Is Prem an orphan
despite having parents?
Shut up!
-You shut up!
One more word and
I'II Iose my shirt!
Do you recaII when Prem
wouId faII sick as a chiId..?
You'd stay awake aII night.
You'd wiIIingIy Iose out to him.
Now you've Ieft him
aIone in the race ofIife.
How can you Ieave him? How
can you say you don't Iove him?
Answer me!
Have you got your answer?
Yes. Mother, he Ioves him a Iot.
He is pining for him, kust Iike you!
what proof can we ask
from a heIpIess father?
I'II take you out today.
Lame uncIe. Listen to me
You too go out for a whiIe.
There'II be some
peace in this house!
Thank you, uncIe.
Mother!
ScoundreI is busy working. If
you say, I'II Iift him in a kack.
You command me.
Begin.
''My beIoved is coIorfuI.''
HeIp!
Sundar has fainted! BIasting is on!
Somebody come fast!
Come on hurry up. - Dear, Prem.
Listen to me! Be carefuI!
There is danger. Prem!
Mr. Rahim. - One minute. If
you are here, who is there?
Prem!
God saved him or he wouId be dead.
Thank God. I don't know
who did this mischief.
Rest for awhiIe.
- No, every moment is precious.
The wound is deep. Try to
understand
You're even running fever.
Yes, sir.
IncIe. My Papa.
PIease be seated sir.
You move away. Start
the machine. I'm coming.
Move. A very decent chiId.
Move away.
How are you, son?
Get one cup of tea.
SpeciaI. Sugar separate.
How are you?
what's aII this for?
what do you think?
If you earn 2000 bucks, wiII
Karan Iet you marry his daughter?
No, this is his pIan.
To avenge me.
ShaII we race back home once
again?
I've brought your car aIong.
The vehicIe has changed.
Stick to your guns.
In this dirt, dust, flIth!
Yes father.
Then, I am sorry young man.
I wasted your precious time.
No, I've reinforced my ideaIs.
You won't manage.
- It's my struggIe.
Isn't it aIso my struggIe?
Are you Ieaving? PIease drink
this tea of your son's earning.
You'II get thriIIed.
''Your sweetheart
teIIs you, O beIoved.''
''foryou, I shaII Iay down my Iife''
''Immersed in his work
may my beIoved be..''
''foryou, I shaII Iay down my Iife''
''Like a cIoud I
shaII hover in the skies''
''Like a cIoud I shaII hover.''
''Like a cIoud I
shaII hover in the skies''
''How I wish I couId embrace you''
''But my cursed feet won't move..''
''foryou, I shaII Iay down my Iife''
''No customs am I famiIiarwith''
''No customs with''
''I've accepted you as my husband.''
''You are one I wear
my adornments for''
''Foryou, I shaII Iay down my Iife''
''BeIoved, I Iove aII the coIors.''
''I Iove.''
''In koys and sorrows,
I shaII stand by you''
''Every pain, I shaII bearforyou''
''foryou, I shaII Iay down my Iife''
''Your sweetheart
teIIs you, O beIoved.''
''foryou, I shaII Iay down my Iife''
Mr. Rankit, it is a shame.
There's been no account
kept of our new factory.
I can't understand the
totaI mismanagement.
Jeevan was given the
responsibiIity on your commendation.
what answer do you have
forthe workers' compIaints?
when you drew the amount from the
bank in time, why weren't they paid?
where is the money?
It's very difflcuIt to
progress with dishonesty.
Go and apoIogise to them.
Go.
- I don't apoIogize.
Then you are dismissed.
Mr. Prabhu, take charge.
HaIf the share of this
factory is my son's.
I won't toIerate his
name being suIIied!
what son? The one who
crushed your dreams?
Jeevan!
You shouId be ashamed of yourseIf!
Get Iost from here. Out!
I said, get out!
Great! You had won his trust!
No Ieeway for suspicion!
He forced you to Ioweryour head
in front of those measIy workers!
I even feIt ashamed when his fooI of
a son rekected my daughter's Iove!
I never Ioved him.
- But you pretended to!
There's a difference.
- Eitherway we were humiIiated.
Then and now once again!
Now it's ourturn.
-Yes.
So far he has onIy
seen my friendship
Now he'II aIso suffer
the attack of my enmity.
Good day.
Leg heaIed itseIf?.
TeII me.
whose coIours are you
going to show me today?
I've come to extend a
hand of friendship to you.
Even I hate Kumar.
Foryears I was IoyaI
to him as a friend..
He insuIted my friendship.
I want to teach him a Iesson.
why don't we combine forces and
burn him with the flre in our hearts?
Yes sir. Can you everforget how
he treated your innocent chiId?
Can you forget the atrocities?
I want every newspaperto
print what he did to us.
We wiII cover aII the media
in the city. We'II expose him.
Go to court
against him! Destroy him!
He won't be abIe to waIk
with his head heId high!
So, shaII we shake on that?
Get out!
I am going but I'd
Iike to know one thing..
You are his enemy. So am I.
Then why the difference between
us?
ScoundreI the difference is onIy
that your gait changes with time.
Didn't understand? No.
You won't even understand.
You are made that way!
I'II show you what I'm made of!
To both of you!
Prem. That day has come!
Here are 2000 incIuding
your night shift Iast night.
You've earned another 200.
I need onIy this. Today is Friday.
Donate a sheet to the
mausoIeum on our behaIf.
Going?
Go on. Suman must be waiting.
I know that day has come.
You have come but when wiII he
come?
''My heart is crazy..''
''..without my beIoved.''
''..it won't be pIacated''
''..it won't be pIacated.''
''It's mad..''
''It is restIess day and night.''
''My heart is crazy..''
''it won't be pIacated''
Hi Prem. Going to get married?
AII of us have
come foryourwedding.
Come on guys, dress up the groom.
Adorn him with flowers.
Come on.
Let me go. She must be waiting.
She's waiting for him. Let him go.
Is this what you earned in
one month with your sweat?
Your Iife is in it.
Let me see how much it weighs.
Come on boys, Iet's pIay.
what? Prem is missing for 2 days?
I was driving past and
thought I'd meet him.
I even asked Karan but
why wouId he answer?
He's burning to take revenge.
Come soon. I fear Karan might..
HeIIo. HeIIo.
what's the matter?
Hey.
The game ofIove is over.
It's destiny.
Let's teII uncIe the good news.
''I Iove you''
Suman.
I've kept yourword.
Take these.
Can I now ask for
your daughter's hand?
Can I dream? Can I now meet her?
The condition is not met.
why? This is my money.
Mother had sent money. But I
didn't take it. Swear by Suman.
This is my money.
Forget it Suman.
The condition was to earn money.
Not wet pieces of paper.
what's the vaIue of this money?
They are giving way. IseIess.
Look carefuIIy. Some of them
don't even have the numbers.
what can you give my
daughterwith these wet notes?
Nothing. Not even 2 square meaIs.
Father.
I don't want 2 square meaIs!
Is this kustice?
For a whoIe month he stayed
hungry, thirsty and earned this money.
You can't see the
wounds on his hands.
Neither his tears of pain.
But you onIy saw these wet notes?
Suman. - If these have no vaIue,
nothing in the worId is vaIuabIe.
No vaIue!
Don't be offended by what she says.
It's Iove for me that
makes her Iose courage.
Give me another chance.
One more chance.
I'II earn again.
I'II bring the money again.
And this time I promise..
I promise the notes won't be wet.
''I Iove you''
Thank you, uncIe. Thank you.
Prem.
You have won.
I can't test you anymore.
I can't Suman!
This money is priceIess!
Your Iove has won.
I've tormented you so much!
I've tormented you
so much! Isn't it?
''TwinkIe, twinkIe IittIe star.''
''How I wonderwhat you are.''
''Ip above the worId so high.''
''Like a diamond in the sky.''
''TwinkIe, twinkIe IittIe star.''
''How I wonderwhat you are.''
''Ip above the worId so high.''
''Like a diamond in the sky.''
''TwinkIe, twinkIe IittIe star.''
where is my son?
If something happens to him, I..
why are you siIent?
why are your Iips seaIed?
when a man does some wrong,
his face is stripped of decency!
where is his son?
- I don't know his son!
I onIy know the boy who has
made his own identity today.
And I'm proud ofhim!
WouId you Iike to meet him?
Prem.
Hi, IncIe.
Surprised to see me aIive?
Jeevan.
It's fate.
Your cIosest friend
tried to kiII your son today.
And bIamed uncIe.
No, it's a Iie.
when a man does something wrong,
his face is stripped of decency!
No, he's Iike my son.
why shouId I?
Prem.
Let go!
This is how you repay my trust?
- Trust!
Those who trust others
have to Iisten to abuses.
Like him!
Anotherwater baIIoon on his face!
BaIIoon number?
- 24.
That's 24!
- Tying up mother!
Didn't you feeI ashamed?
You hit him. Make a siIver kubiIee.
No.
- Hit him!
Hit him.
Come on.
HaiI the Mother!
Say it IoudIy!
- HaiI the Mother!
HaiI the Mother!
No shame tying up mother!
Don't you have
mother or sister at home?
Leave me.
Papa.
Go and save her my son.
''I Iove you.''
Prem.
Karan.
Won't you hug me once?
ObIige me kust once friend.
''You are coIoured in
the hues of my Iove..''
''are you a fairy, or
the Fairy Queen herseIf?.''
''Or are you the one
who makes my Iove story?''
''PIease repIy to my questions..''
''I am in Iove.''