She is calling you. There's very
little time, please hurry.
As per Ms. Bhavna's will...
...her son, Rahul's inheritance
has been entrusted to you.
Are you her relative?
No.
Did you know her since long?
Since the time she was in school.
The inheritance she's left for
her son has been put in a Trust.
Once all the documents are ready,
they will be sent to you.
Where will you
take the child now?
Does yourfamily live there...
No. l live alone.
Will you look after a small child
in this old age?
l mean...
...doesn't he have a father?
Anyway, once the documents are
ready, we will send them to you.
Take him away!
...Mummy! Take him away!
-What's the matter?
- Sister, take the dog away!
-Who brought it?
- Papa did.
-You're scared of a tiny dog?!
- No way! l'm not scared.
You aren't, right? Now watch!
No! l'll tell mummy!
You aren't scared, right? Look!
This point here...
Please let there be light.
You had to provide ramps
from here to this point.
And what are
these proportions! Are you...
Speak softly, my dear.
What's the matter?
What did the dog do?
l'll be home soon.
ls your mummy there?
No? ...Thank God!
And listen! lf she
returns soon, don't tell her.
l'll be there before she does.
...Yes, my dear!
My wife loves dogs, sir.
My wife hates them.
You get dead tired, going out
in this city in the traffic!
l left at 4 O'clock!
Here are your colour pencils.
Don't lose them again.
Where has the flower vase gone
from here? Who has removed it?
Abdul, get me some water.
-Where has the flower vase gone?
- l don't know.
Nobody in this house
ever knows anything!
Here are your pencils.
Hey! Who's kept a cactus
in place of the photo frame?
She's always missing!
She's never at home!
Why are all of you
sitting so quietly?
Hear, hear!
Can't we sit quietly at home?
lndeed! l know what it means
when all of you sit quietly!
Papa, mummy is going to
the bathroom to wash herface.
Oh! We'll be damned!
lndu... uh... are you
going to the bathroom?
What!
Are you going to wash yourface?
-Why?
- For no reason.
l've heard that washing the face
too much spoils the skin.
Where did you hearthat?
Well... Mini was saying so.
No, papa! Sister said so.
No! Even l didn't say so! ...
Mummy, l'd heard it on the radio.
-Yes! We'd heard it on the radio.
-What's wrong with all of you?!
We are doomed now!
Yes.
Take this dog away!
Who brought it here?!
l said, take the dog away!
l asked, who brought it here?!
Let's go.
l knew it!
- Please let the dog stay here.
- Quiet!
The dog broke a photo frame,
a flower vase and tore a curtain!
These were the disasters
struck on the very first day!
lt'll destroy the whole house in
no time! Who'll take care of it?
We'll put a leash around it.
There's no need!
Who asked you to get it?!
Bela is not yet here!
She is always missing!
l'm warning you,
l will not keep the dog!
How often have l said,
throw away those glasses!
Hey! How will l read then!
-You look just like a peon!
- So what?
How's your backache?
lt's okay now but l had to
stand in the site for 2-3 hours.
l'll massage it.
Why do you have to work so much?
Come off it! l work for
you and your children.
Stop it! ...
You are fond of working!
We have everything.
Everything is what we don't have.
What do we lack?
A diamond necklace.
Well, who wants one!
Oh really! Then, why were you
lustily eyeing Kanta's necklace?
Nonsense! l was looking at it
because it was so ugly!
l see.
Forget the necklace but you'd
surely want a husband like hers?
Get me the most precious gem, yet
l wouldn't want a man like Suri.
What kind of
a husband do you want?
l have one.
Yes, you do. But do sing praises
about him sometimes!
Shall l say something?
Let's keep the puppy at home?
You sly monkey!
Yuck! l'm not going to
drink this! There's cream in it!
Nothing doing! Drink the milk!
Keep your hand down!
How will l drink my coffee then?!
Use the other hand.
Keep papa's name as puppy.
Stupid! Keep the puppy's
name as papa!
Stop fighting
early in the morning!
-Allow me to take the coffee.
- No!
The puppy drinks milk,
not coffee.
l'm not talking about
the puppy... but about papa.
Shall we name him also Mini?
ls that a name!
Naming him Mini
will create a problem.
lf we call the puppy,
you'll come running...
...and if we call you,
it will come running!
When there will be no dog,
what's the use of finding a name?
Have you had your vitamins?
- Have you?
-Yes, papa.
- l'm asking you also.
-Yes, even l've had it.
Papa, you lie?
Don't forget we have to go to
Mr. Suri's party in the evening.
There's a tank
filled with hot water.
ln it, your host, his wife
and you are almost naked!
The pressure of the hot water
massages your body!
And you get tickled all over.
-Adjust yourtie properly!
-What's wrong with it?
-You've come for a party.
- lt's okay.
Hey, you Late Kate!
- Suri, how are you?
-Absolutely fine.
Mr. Suri, DK will not
drink too much today.
- The question does not arise!
- lndeed! He gets high with 2 pegs!
And listen... please don't
recite couplets either!
l can't promise that.
All right! But do everything
within your limits, DK!
Let's have a very large peg.
l had no idea that
there'd be so many people.
Bring a glass of
champagne for him.
We'll have a large peg later.
Listen to what l say!
Son, he makes films. Deliver
the dialogues from Sholay'.
''How many men were there?''
''Two, sir.''
''And you were three.
Yet, you returned empty-handed!''
He's good, isn't he?
You were to phone me
day before yesterday!
l was busy, l had to go out.
You are always busy
with your work!
You were going to
quit smoking, weren't you?
- From tomorrow.
- Tomorrow indeed!
Hadn't you worn the
same one for Sheetal's party?
They are very beautiful.
- Hasn't Ratna come?
- l did call her.
But you know her condition.
ldiot! She keeps crying, and that
too away from her husband's eyes.
She doesn't protest by
eitherfighting or crying!
Meaning?
Remember, DK, in those days,
your athleticism...
And my naughtiness...
How many girls went crazy!
Any letters from the Major?
lt's a thing of the past.
Forget it!
Have you forgotten?
Why do you worry?
Don't l look fine?
''Raise not your hands
and arch backwards''
''Take a look at your bosom''
''As slowly
slides down your veil''
Wow! What a couplet!
Remember, there was a song...
''O' lovely maiden, walk not
with your nose in the air''
Should we sing?
Will you sing?
l have a bad throat.
Why don't you begin?
- Putting up your price, huh?
- No way!
You start, l'll join you.
What are you doing!
- How is Ratna now?
- l don't know.
Lie straight.
No, Ratna, don't cry.
Was your problem solved by
swallowing sleeping pills? ...No!
You should have given them
to your husband instead!
Orto his mistress!
What will you gain by dying?!
Quiet, Chanda! ls this
the time to scold her?!
You're here?
What have you come to take now?!
You've put Ratna in this state!
What more do you want to do?!
- Please be quiet, Chanda.
-Why should l?!
Somebody has to speak!
Should everyone be quiet like her
and let this man do as he please?
Let's go... We'll leave now.
Think and talk!
lf you were in her shoes,
would you think and talk?!
Sleeping pills
do not solve problems.
But her husband is also crazy.
How can he change,
even after having children?
lf you can't bearthe
responsibility, why get married?
Mummy, if l were not born,
what would have happened?
Then there would have been
a baby boy in your place!
My brother.
- Not yours but mine!
- He'd have been my brothertoo.
How would he, stupid!
You wouldn't be born!
Don't! Does one talk this way
with an elder sister?
Does one speak this way
with a younger sister?
l'll beat you!
You call me stupid!
Hey, you'll fall!
That's enough now!
Go to your room.
lndu, suppose you
had a baby boy, then?
l have one.
Where is he?
Have you hidden him?
Here he is!
lsn't he enough for me?
Why?
You have one, l don't.
You don't even tell me whether
l've received a reply or not.
lf there was, then l'd have
come to you immediately.
Why do you worry when l'm around?
Worried, l certainly am.
About this boy.
After all, l'm getting older.
Here, send him
a telegram this time.
Get yourself treated properly.
- ls there a cure for old age?
-Why do you talk like this...
Go and send
a telegram immediately.
- There's a telegram.
- From whom?
From Nainital?
He's asked you to come at once,
as there's some important work.
-Who is he?
- The headmaster of my old school.
-Anything important?
- l don't know.
He has never before...
- l haven't met him since years.
- Then?
l'll phone him from office.
Gupta, check this.
Bring it in.
Mr. Dhawan is waiting foryou.
- ls the new client here?
-Yes.
-What's his name?
- Mr. Bansal.
Listen... get me a trunk call
to Nainital. This is the number.
And this is the embassy.
And yes! This is Neelkamal
Building, of which you mentioned.
These are its schematic designs.
Come, DK. We were waiting
foryou... This is Mr. Bansal.
Please sit, DK.
He wants to build a complex -
Bansal Bhavan... is that the name?
He wants us
to give him a proposal.
You will be giving
the first presentation.
l was showing him the schematic
designs of Neelkamal Building.
-You explain to him.
- Sure.
No. Mr. Gurudayal has retired.
- Please give me his phone number.
- He doesn't have a phone.
Who's speaking?
DK from Delhi. l've received
a telegram from Mr. Gurudayal.
-Are you DK Malhotra?
-Yes. Who are you?
My name is Tiwari.
l had sent you the telegram.
The master had sent a lettertoo.
- l haven't received the letter.
-You haven't?
But l did get his telegram.
Mr. Tiwari, what work did he have?
lt's something very personal...
-What work did he have?
-Are you really DK Malhotra?
Yes, l am DK speaking!
What work did he have?
He's asked you to come
to Nainital. Your son...
What did the master say?
He says he has
very little time, and...
All right! But what
work does he have with me?
He wants you to take away
your son from here.
Son!
Whose son?
l have no son.
What are you talking about?!
Hello, Mr. Tiwari?!
What is the matter? Do you know
what else the master has said?
Yes. A small boy
lives in his house.
Since the time his mother
left him with the master...
Hello! Who's left him?
His mother - Bhavna.
l see.
Yes, Mr. Tiwari? ...
-Worked up about something?
- No.
Did you phone Nainital?
Yes. The master was not there but
l spoke to a man named Mr. Tiwari.
lndu, he said...
What did he say?
He said that
the master was unwell...
The line was bad,
l couldn't hear properly.
But he did say that
the master was unwell.
Send him some money
for his treatment.
- lndu, that's not all.
- Then what is it?
l have some problem.
What is that problem
of yours which isn't mine?
What is it?
Nothing.
lt's an office problem.
- lt's me.
-Yes, lndu?
There's a letterfrom Nainital.
Shall l read it?
- Have you read it?
- No. l've not even opened it.
- Shall l open it?
- No, don't.
l'll come home in the evening
and read it. Okay?
Or l'll send the office peon.
Give it to him.
Anita, cancel all appointments.
''DK, she never wanted you
to know about this child.''
''When l learnt about it
afterthe child was born...
...Bhavna had said
just one thing.''
''Do not tell DK, since he has
his own life... his own family.'''
''That child
neither laughs nor cries.''
''He keeps staring out
of the window all day long.''
''Waiting for, l wonder, whom.''
''lt appears as if his childhood
is vanishing at such a young age.''
''l cannot give him anything
in my old age.''
''He needs a mother,
a father... a family, DK.''
''He asks me questions whose
answers l can't give, you can.''
''Son, l won't live
very long now.''
''Before l die, l want
to send your son to you.''
Mummy, shout at her!
Stupid, shut it!
You stupid! They are
showing Chintu's songs!
- Mummy, ask herto shut it!
- Concentrate here!
What to do about this?
- Make blocks of these sums.
- How do you do that?
That's what l don't know,
so l'm asking you.
O God! Your New Math is tough!
Mini, stop your chorus!
They are showing Chintu's songs.
ls Chintu your uncle?!
Shut it!
Mummy, please! They're showing
Uncle Chintu's songs!
lt's disturbing.
Forget that.
Mummy, first tell me...
Stop it, Mini!
Mummy, l stand first in all the
other subjects except Maths...
Papa, you're here!
Papa, they were showing Uncle
Chintu's songs but mummy shut it!
Who's Uncle Chintu?
Damn! How many times have l
told you about Uncle Chintu!
Quiet! ...Papa, ljust
cannot solve this sum.
Ask mummy.
She doesn't know.
You explain, papa.
No way! Thank God, you've come.
You handle them!
-Will you have tea?
-Yes. - Papa, please explain!
-Add little sugar.
- Papa, solve the sum first.
Fine.
Doing Winky's homework
is beyond me.
ln any case, l was weak in Math.
And l don't know about these new
blocks to be made in New Math.
From now on, you manage her.
lf that fatso stands first in
class, Winky will not forgive me!
Get up!
Won't you change your clothes?
l want to tell you something.
Go ahead.
You won't like it.
What's it?
Let it be.
l'll tell you some othertime.
lt's nothing.
Please, DK! Don't say this.
What is it?
There was another girl in my life.
- Don't joke about such matters.
- l am not joking, lndu.
l am not joking.
When l... had gone... there...
-Where?
- To Nainital.
Forthe school's
Old Boys' function...
At that time...
...Winky was going to be born.
Yes.
l'd met herthere.
Who?
Bhavna... that girl.
l...
l don't know...
how l couldn't control myself.
Perhaps because l was alone,
and... so was she.
l went to her house once and...
...at her insistence,
l stayed back at night.
l shouldn't have stayed back...
l shouldn't have stayed but...
l never ever saw her
afterthat... l swear!
And even then, l shared
nothing special with her.
You shared nothing special?!
What can be more special
than this, DK?
So, what does she want now?
Nothing. She's dead.
Then?
She has a son from me.
No! Don't say that!
What's happening!
Please don't say that!
l'm very scared.
Winky dear, go and sleep.
You said you've been busy.
So what brings you here today?
l want to talk to you...
There's a big problem.
With Bansal? lf you want, l'll
phone him now and fix matters.
- No. Listen to me.
- Tell me something.
lf your company acquires that
contract, what'll be your share?
- That's not the problem.
- Then?
- lt's something else.
- Then, let's solve the problem!
Mr. Suri, how was the game?
Please don't joke. Doing business
and drinking whisky is my forte.
Else, even l would be preparing
for Wimbledon like my son!
DK, the joy of
watching your son grow!
lt wasn't the same
even in my youth!
A son is important.
Your son must be handling
your business now, right?
l'll leave now.
Hey, you wanted to discuss
a problem. What is it?
-What's it?
-We'll talk later.
Yes, l will inform him.
Mr. Bansal, this is
a foundation problem.
As per Mr. Malhotra's
original estimates...
...you'll find mica content
at a depth of 40 feet.
But as perthe...
Sorry, sir.
l have to go home.
- lndu, where are you going?
-Anywhere! ...l don't know!
Please listen to me!
l don't want to listen!
Please listen to me for a minute!
l didn't know that the boy
was going to come here.
- Stop lying!
- l swear, l didn't know!
Come what may, that boy is
not going to come to this house!
- Do you need the taxi or not?
-We don't want it!
Take this.
lndu, listen!
Just for a few days!
Please, lndu! What can l
do now if he's coming here?
Do what you want, but he
is not going to come here!
l promise he won't stay here
for more than 2-3 days.
l promise.
l do not trust you anymore!
You'd said, my problem is yours
too. Won't you help me this time?
Mummy, ask sisterto return
my scented rubber!
Quiet! lt was my rubber!
So what if l took it?!
What do you want?! That you
do any wrong and l endure it?!
l'm also human, l have feelings.
Have you everthought about that?
And these children...
what will you tell them?!
l'll beat you! ...
Mummy, just look at her!
Mummy, two of my sums were
wrong!
Come on, l'll show you.
Come on, mummy!
Papa, please carry me.
Now take me inside.
Mini and Winky, please come here.
What's it?
A boy will be coming
to stay in our house.
-Who is he?
- His name is...
His mummy is dead,
so he's coming to stay with us.
But who was his mummy?
She was our distant relative.
Mummy, how old is he?
He...
He is 8-9 years old.
Such a small boy! My exams are
nearing, he won't let me study!
No. He'll play with me.
Where is his father?
Why doesn't he go to him?
His father has gone away.
Leaving him behind?
My papa would have
never done that!
Children, go to
your room and sleep.
- Come on, hurry.
- lt will be great fun now!
lt will be no fun!
You took care.
l was taking care of my children!
Shall l roll the window down?
Look, that's the Old Fort.
lt's a... very old... fort!
lt was built by Sher Shah Suri
...or perhaps Humayun...
There's a big zoo inside now.
There are many animals and a...
Did you know my mummy?
Y... y... yes. Yes, l did know her.
And papa?
Not papa.
Mummy used to say that
l'll surely find my papa.
Even mummy is no more. lf papa
does come, how will he find me?
He will, son... he will find you.
Mini, he is Rahul.
Winky dear, come here.
Rahul, she is Winky.
She is my mummy...
Mummy, he is Rahul.
Will Rahul sleep in my room?
No. His bed has been
put in the study.
But l study there.
My dear, it's a matter
of only a few days.
Abdul, keep his baggage
in the study.
Both of you come upstairs.
Get up, this is my place.
l sit with papa.
Go and sit there.
Abdul... has not brought the rice.
l had a puppy
whose name was also Mini.
Eat quietly, Mini.
When papa used to call
the puppy, l'd come running.
And when he'd call me,
the puppy would come running.
Mummy is upset today.
lndu, aren't you going to eat?
Son.
What are you
doing all alone here?
Gazing at the stars.
Mummy used to say that
if you see a shooting star...
...your wish gets fulfilled.
Look, uncle, a shooting star!
-Where is it?
- lt's disappeared.
- Did you wish for something?
-Yes.
-What?
- l can't tell you.
Why?
l see... Should we go inside?
Yes?
Shall l tell you
what l wished for?
l prayed that l'd find my papa.
Come on, papa, it's getting late.
Papa, come on.
lt's getting very late.
He's taking so long.
The children are getting late.
Did you know my mummy?
No!
But uncle knew her.
l know!
What is it? Why are you
looking at me that way?
Even my mummy used to wear
a similarfloral print sari.
Fine... Let me work now.
And how have you let
that boy stay in your house?!
l haven't. He just came home.
What could l do?
Whenever l see him,
l think of DK and that girl.
Chanda, it seems as if
all relationships are a farce.
lt seems as if...
...such incidents occur
only in other people's lives.
l don't know what to do now.
lndu, the weakeryou become,
the more you will have to endure.
Yes, l'll be there.
l'll be back in a jiffy.
When the Major left me,
even l'd felt defeated like you.
But look at me now.
What do l lack?
l work, l live for myself,
...the way l want to!
Like a free woman.
And don't you miss your son?
5+...
- Shall l recite a poetry foryou?
- No need! l'm studying!
l said, l'm studying!
''Who created
the sparrows that fly?''
-All right, l'll go.
- l'll beat you!
Brother Rahul.
Shall l recite a poetry foryou?
Yes, please.
''Who created
the sparrows that fly?''
''Who created you and me?''
''The Lord is present in everything''
Whose picture is this?
My papa's.
ls this how your papa looks?
l don't know.
Perhaps this is how he looks.
Where's he?
He must be dead.
No! Mummy used to say that
he has gone very far away.
And that he'd
surely return someday.
l'd seen another child's father
go somewhere far away, on TV.
His mummy too had said that
his father would return.
But he was dead.
And the boy didn't even know!
Films are not reality.
Yes, indeed. They are films.
l'll tell papa.
He'll find yourfather.
How will he find him?
My papa is very clever.
Watch, he will find yourfather!
Mini! ...What are you doing here?
Playing with Brother Rahul.
Go and sleep.
Since when did Rahul
become your brother?!
What's that you're swallowing?
Sleeping pills.
Will taking sleeping pills
solve anything?
How often have
l apologised to you!
How often have l admitted
that l've indeed made a mistake!
Can't you forget it?
How can l?
l was leading a farcical
relationship for 1 0 years!
You cheated me for 1 0 years!
You call
this relationship a farce?!
Are you calling those
two children a farce?
- lf our children are...
- Even she had a child.
Will you call that a farce?
Believe me, l was totally
ignorant about this child.
- lf l had known...
-What would you have done then?!
Left us?!
Don't touch me!
Hello. ls that
Mr. DK Malhotra speaking?
My name is...
Hey, l'm Suri here.
You've become very lazy!
Do you know it's Sunday today?
Do you have to visit sites today?
Aren't you coming to the farm?
No, Suri. l can't come.
l am not in the mood.
Not in the mood?
l'll take care of your mood!
Suri, listen! l think
even lndu isn't in the mood.
Are you lndu's uncle?!
Give the line to her.
Well, Mr. Moody? Moods become
all right when with friends.
Come, Brother Rahul.
...Come on.
Hello, Uncle Suri!
How are you?
Hello, child!
How were your exams?
They haven't begun as yet.
Hey! Whose cute child is this?
My word! He is so sweet!
Whose son is he?
Well, who is he?
He's Brother Rahul. His mother is
dead and his papa has gone away.
Why didn't you come
for Chulbul's party?
- Don't hit the plants!
-Why not?
They belong to my father!
l will break them!
They also have life,
they too will get hurt.
Rubbish! Who says so?!
- My mother used to say that.
-Your mother is dead! - Don't!
Papa, Babbu hit Brother Rahul.
Babbu hit Rahul? lmpossible!
l saw Babbu hit him.
Come here.
- Did you hit Rahul?
- No, l didn't hit him.
l told you so.
My Babbu never hits anybody.
- He's lying. He hit him.
-All right. Let's go.
Come, son.
-What will you drink?
- Thums up.
Did Babbu hit you?
No, he didn't.
Who will play cricket?
Come on, everyone!
- My turn first!
- Let's toss.
- Give it to him.
- My turn first.
- Kids afterthe elders.
- No. Elders afterthe kids.
The kids have finished their
turn. Now it's the elders' turn.
DK, bowl a googly!
Watchman! What are you doing?!
Leave me! ...This is cheating!
l made it!
Mr. Umpire, your place is here!
-Aunt Kanta! Run!
-Where do l throw it?
Here!
-Wow! Good throw, my lioness!
- Naturally!
You're cheating!
He's not out. l am the umpire.
Mummy! Move a little there.
...That's right.
Watchman! Move behind... Further!
- Here?
- That's fine!
A little more.
Yes... That's fine.
Come, son!
lt's only cricket!
lt's my turn to bat!
Hadn't l told you he'd
grow up to be like Kapil Dev!
-Aunt, take the catch!
- Go take your run!
Ourfielding isn't tight.
lt's a tough game!
Mr. Umpire, keep this here.
Come on!
Didn't l tell you he'd
become a Gavaskar someday!
With bowlers like me, he will
surely become a Gavaskar!
- Come, Rahul. You bowl too.
- No.
No problem. Play underarm.
Give it a try, Rahul.
- He's going to bowl fast!
-You're sacred!
Come on, my lion!
Come on!
Well, Mr. Lion Suri!!
Saw how amazing my...
These crockery and cutlery...
...have been bought from
Harrod's store in London.
And these idiots levy
a duty of 1 50% on it.
l could nevertolerate
cheap spoons in college...
...so l can't possibly
tolerate them now!
You have a mania
for imported items.
You should have got
an imported wife, too!
Take some.
Wife? ...Well, you don't get
wives at the Harrod's store.
Or else, l would
have surely got one.
But once in New York...
Tell your wife.
Don't hide things from Kanta.
No. There's nothing to hide.
Trixie came into my life
before Kanta did.
Trixie? Who's she?
Trixie means full of tricks.
Kanta, don't take him seriously.
He loves to tease you.
There is nothing to tease about.
lf l have ever met anyone else
after marrying you, then...
...have l evertold you about it?
lf there is another woman,
then remarry!
He is joking, Kanta. Would he
ever leave you to remarry?!
One can form relationships,
even without getting married.
- lndu, what are you saying?
- The truth.
lndu, you may say
whateveryou like about me.
But there is no need to
speak about DK this way.
There was a need,
so l spoke.
Meaning?
You can ask him that!
Hey! What's wrong
with her? ...lndu!
What's the matter?
l've been observing this tension
between you since morning.
And the way lndu was
talking to that boy Rahul...
Who is Rahul?
- He is my son.
-What!
When l went
to Nainital in 1 973...
- No, l won't have.
-You're grown up now!
-You're going to be a father!
- Get lost!
Well... but you aren't
even married as yet!
ln the midst of the din, she too
was there... lonely and quiet.
Her name was Bhavna.
l knew herfrom my school days.
She used to be so lively.
But now...
This girl has been
through a big tragedy.
She lost herfamily in a car
accident while still in school.
The master said that Bhavna had
completely withdrawn since then.
The master knew Bhavna and
herfamily since a long time...
...so, in a way,
her responsibility fell on him.
He wanted Bhavna to
somehow overcome her grief.
Orthat someone explain to her.
DK, show me your hand.
This is your marriage line.
How deep and strong it is!
lndu and you are
very happy, aren't you?
Yes, very much so.
Look, how strong
it is all throughout. But...
- But at one point...
-At one point? What?
Never mind. Since you don't
believe in it, forget it.
But what did you see?
Nothing. Never mind.
Tell me one more thing.
Will we get a
baby boy or a baby girl?
You do have a boy. But l'm
not sure if it will be this time.
l want a son!
Then you'll surely get a son.
Show me your hand.
-What will you do looking at it?
-At least show it.
Now l'll tell you yourfuture.
...Show me your hand.
Where is your marriage line?
- Oh yes! ...The left hand.
- lt's this one.
lt's incomplete.
But there is
a faint line all along.
Yes. l can't understand.
There is a marriage line,
and yet there isn't.
Let me see.
Where is your life line?
Here it is.
This one? ...it's rather short.
l know.
You do?
l see! That means,
you have decided to die soon!
l haven't decided that.
...l know it.
She knows!
And she is dead.
l can't believe it!
She had a strange blind belief.
On meeting Bhavna,
l was surprised to see...
...that a person could bottle up
one's grief for so long.
As though sorrows had become
the sole purpose of her life.
l was sympathetic towards Bhavna.
And Bhavna needed that.
lt was plain sympathy, which one
can feel towards anybody.
Nothing more.
Forget all this, Bhavna.
These things are useless.
Fate and destiny are all rubbish!
Lead the life of a normal girl.
Please don't scold me, DK.
Please come and sit next to me.
She asked me to sit next to her,
and l did not refuse.
What happened afterthat...
l can't explain to anyone.
lndu and my children...
...mean the world to me.
My... My home is
breaking apart, Suri.
What do l do?
How do l explain to lndu?
My home is breaking apart.
You will have to do one thing.
You will have to
send that boy away.
l know that.
But where will l send him?
To a boarding school.
He too has a right.
Where will he go?
How is he at fault?
What has that
innocent child done?
Mummy, l can't solve
these sums. Please help me.
Winky, don't disturb me.
l can't solve your sums.
What's the matter with
you these days, mummy?
Suppose that fatso stands first
in class again, then?
- May l help you?
- Do you know to solve them?
Yes, l do.
Show me.
Mini, what are you doing!
...How do you know this, Rahul?
l always stood first in Math.
But l was a bit weak in Hindi.
Won't you study further?
Stay back in Delhi.
Study here.
- Shall l stay here?
-Yes! Stay here.
l'll have to ask aunty.
Why ask mummy?
She loves all children.
Yes! Mummy loves children!
Me, too?
Yes! She is a little shy
of you. You're still new.
Gupta was saying that a lot
remains to be done on the design.
Yes, sir. That's right.
We have a presentation at
Mr. Bansal's office within a week.
He has already called twice.
What's the matter with you?
lt's a personal problem.
l'll take this home.
l'll try to finish it there.
For how long will you
continue to have sleeping pills?
Till l don't get sleep!
''Respected Master,
l am absolutely fine here.''
''ls there been
any letterfrom my father?''
lt should be Has there been
any letter' and not ls there'.
Okay?
''Any news about him?
Uncle loves me a lot.''
''There is an aunty too. Even she
loves me but is a little shy.''
''Are you all right?''
- Brother Rahul, who's drawn this?
- l have.
- But who are they?
- This is your papa...
...your mother,
your sister and you.
Where is mummy's bun?
lt's behind. You can't see it.
That's right. You can't see it.
But where are you?
l'm sitting right here.
-Where are you in this picture?
- l'm not here.
- Shall l draw myself here?
- Please do.
lt's mummy's birthday
the day aftertomorrow.
l forgot to get bangles for her.
Brother Rahul, what
will you get for mummy?
l...
Shall l make a
bangle box for aunty?
l've composed a poem.
Shall l recite it?
Forget it!
''Awooden log,
On it is a wooden horse''
''A hammerfell- Crash, boom, bang
on the horse's tail!''
-You'll come in, won't you?
- No. l'll come later.
Come on, Brother Rahul.
Let's go in.
- Let's go.
- No. - Come on.
l'll come later.
Move aside.
- Let me also do something.
- Quiet! Don't harass us!
Let her do it.
She won't do a thing. She will
only spoil my handwriting.
l'll also write.
Don't write anything.
You don't know anything!
What are you doing, children?
Please go away!
Mummy is coming!
- Please come, mummy.
-What's the matter?
Nothing. Please be seated
and have your breakfast.
-What's this?
-Your birthday present.
-What is it?
- Open it and have a look.
lt's lovely!
- Did you get it, Winky?
- No.
l don't think Mini must
have got it. Who bought it?
Brother Rahul has personally
made it foryour birthday.
Papa, look what
Brother Rahul made for mummy.
Papa, look what Rahul
made for mummy... Look, papa.
Have you made this?
...lt's lovely!
Didn't aunty like it?
- Of course, she did.
- She liked it very much.
Yes! She liked it very much.
-What happened?
- Take your son away!
l am not your mother! Don't you
dare call me mummy again!
Yuck! l don't like brinjal!
Stupid! You don't like anything!
You stupid! ...
You brinjal! You pumpkin!
- Mummy, tell her.
-Winky, have your dinner quietly.
Brother Rahul, please
pass me the cauliflower.
Blood! Papa, Brother Rahul's
hand is bleeding!
Mummy, look!
Brother Rahul's hand is bleeding!
What happened?
What's happened?
lndu, how did he hurt himself?
lndu! How did he hurt himself?
How should l know?!
He didn't tell me!
A child gets hurt at home,
and you aren't even aware!
Don't scream at me
in front of the children!
Just because
he is not your child?!
Let the one who has sinned
take care of him! Why bother me?!
Aren't you ashamed
of speaking so?!
l have not been as shameless
as you! Are you ashamed?!
So what should l do?!
Tell me, what should l do?!
Should l kill myself?!
You want to go on leave?!
What's wrong with you, DK?
The other architects have
already sent their proposals!
Sir, if l don't get leave,
l will have to resign.
Resign! Will you will have to
resign! What nonsense you speak!
This is too much!
A height of negligence!
You should have informed me
earlierthat you can't work!
Sir, l'd told you earlier
that l have a personal problem!
Even l have a problem!
Look, l have to run the company.
l can't possibly do it alone.
Tell me what the matter is.
All right... You may go!
You know your responsibility.
...You may go.
- Uncle, will you take me boating?
- Sure.
-What about riding?
- l'll take you riding too.
-What about China Peak?
-You want to go there?
-Yes.
-Walking?
Yes. That's the master's house.
Mr. Tiwari?
-When did you come?
- This morning. Good you found us.
We were going to come to school
at 2 p.m. for Rahul's admission.
- The Principal told me.
- Son, greet him.
- How are you, son?
- l'm fine. How are you?
Absolutely fine.
Where is the master?
He passed away.
What! ...When?
He suffered a heart attack
a few days ago.
Uncle, do you think my mother
may have lied to me?
Why?
Maybe, my father isn't alive?
He'll be here soon.
Please understand,
even l have some problems.
Mr. Tiwari, will l
get admission here?
Yes, son. We are trying.
Will l have to stay here then?
Yes. You can stay
in the hostel here.
Where do l get his books?
You'll get the list from office.
- Do l get his uniforms or...
- They will be made here.
Rahul, come here.
...Meet your Principal.
How will you send him?
l will be going to Delhi,
so l'll fetch him.
Mr. Tiwari will bring him here.
So now you're going
to join our school.
Thank him, son. He has
agreed to give you admission.
Say thank you.
Can l send you
a cheque forthe fee?
You can sign the papers after
2 days when the office opens.
All right.
Send him after 1 0 days.
And do not be late.
l don't like boys who come late.
...Do you understand?
Let's leave, Rahul.
...Thank you, Brother.
Uncle, the string has gone in.
The string has gone in?
Tie it around from outside.
Come here.
- Sleep the way it is.
- No. lt will fall.
lt won't fall.
Take a blanket to sleep.
Go to sleep.
What's the time?
lt's 8:30. Why?
Mini must be in the bathroom
brushing herteeth...
...and Winky must be
banging loudly at the door.
Hurry up, Mini!
Hurry! ...Hurry up, stupid!
Yuck!
Why is there so much of noise?
Mummy, tell Mini. She occupies
the bathroom for so long.
Dirty girl!
Go wash yourface.
One more thing... Both of you
can sleep with me tonight.
Are you afraid
of being alone, mummy?
Uncle, l like you very much.
- Really?
-Yes.
Son, even l like you very much.
When my papa comes,
l won't stay with him.
-Why not?
- l will stay with you.
Will l be able to
call you papa then?
l don't want to
stay in this school!
Why not?
l don't like it!
Stay here for a few days
and you will begin to like it.
There are many other children
also who stay here.
- Can't l stay in Delhi?
- No!
You have to stay here for a while
in the hostel. Understand?
Why can't l stay in your house?!
And who is this?
That's me and my papa.
- Does your papa wear spectacles?
-Yes.
Papa and Brother Rahul are back!
Rahul is back?
Mummy! Papa is back!
Papa is back!
Papa, what have you got for me?
- Did you get my badminton racket?
-Yes!
Just a minute. l'll be back.
She was screaming a while ago,
''Brother Rahul is back!''
And now you're not
even talking to him.
No, l wasn't screaming.
She's so shy of you now,
but soon she will be afteryou!
No!
Here it comes on you, Mini!
- Did you get your admission?
-Yes.
- So you'll go away?
What happened?
Major and l have once again...
You've understood what
l am trying to say, right?
Yes.
But you would always say
that you don't need any support.
That you don't need a family.
And that you are
an independent woman.
lt would be fine
if l were just a woman.
But l'm a mothertoo.
When my child
held my hand and said...
''Please come home, mummy''
...l couldn't hold myself back.
ljust couldn't
hold myself back, lndu.
Shall l say something, lndu?
Awoman has no say when the
motherly feelings in her arise.
-You tell her!
-You tell!
-What happened?
- Sister has stood first in class.
She defeated that fatso!
Very good! Well-done!
lf Brother Rahul had not taught
her, it would've been impossible.
-Who's Rahul?
- Brother Rahul!
The boy whom l
spoke to you about.
lt's good that the kids have
mingled with each other so well.
lt's not in this either.
They are my personal papers!
They are Rahul's Nainital papers.
Where are they?
l had told you to keep them
in a personal file!
l have to send them
with Rahul to Nainital.
Look in that drawer.
...the lower one.
Sir, are these the papers?
Yes. Where were they? Can't you
even file them properly?!
- Rahul, take care of these.
-All right, uncle.
They are your papers.
Take them home.
-Are you being naughty?
- No.
Sit in my cabin.
l'll go meet Mr. Dhawan.
Son.
This letter must have fallen
from those papers. Keep it there.
-Whose letter is it?
- To Mr. Malhotra...
Give it to me.
l see.
You wanted a proposal from the
best architect. lt had to be good.
l think we'll clinch the deal.
Yes... All right,
l'll call you tomorrow.
Fine... after 2-3 days.
Bye, Mr. Bansal. Thank you.
DK, l think Mr. Bansal has
liked your proposal very much.
Come on.
Come on!
Don't forget the papers.
Wish him, Rahul.
Wish him.
-Whose son is he?
- My friend's.
He's a very cute child.
Where does he study?
He'll be going to a
boarding school in Nainital.
Rahul is not at home!
-What!
- l searched everywhere.
And the front door was open.
Stay with the children.
l'll take a look outside.
What happened, mummy?
Where is Rahul?
lt's nothing.
Why was papa shouting his name?
-Watchman, did any child pass by?
- No.
- Light skinned with blue eyes?
- No, sir.
He's nowhere to be seen. Call
the police, l'll take the car.
Wait, lndu...
Don't call the police.
Give the phone here.
l'll call Suri.
- Please call Mr. Suri.
- He's sleeping.
l know that, but wake him up.
-Who's calling?
- l'm DK Malhotra.
- Call Mr. Suri. lt's urgent.
- But he is sleeping.
l know he's sleeping!
l say, wake him up!
Ask Suri to stay ready.
l'll pick him up.
There he is!
Rahul, where are you running?
Wait, Rahul!
Suri, it's not him.
Where the hell is he?!
Where could he have disappeared?!
-Where do l look for him?!
- Come on, now!
What's the use of looking for
him here? lt wasn't that boy.
-What do l do?
- Let's go to the police station.
So how are you?
How is everything else?
l'd called you the other day
but you didn't come.
Well, l don't get the time... Bye.
Could you please hurry?
Father's name?
Father's name!
What will you do
with the father's name?
You have the child's name
and his entire description.
On finding him, will you
ask him his father's name?!
Father's name?
Louder.
DK Malhotra! Can't you hear?!
Calm down.
DK, any news? Did you find him?
Where are you calling from?
l'm calling from a petrol pump
nearthe police station.
We have filed a report at the
police station. But of no avail.
There's no news of him.
l wonder what's happened to him.
Come home.
lt's no use sitting there.
What is she saying?
Excuse me!
Any news of the boy?
None, yet.
Of what use is such a big unit?!
Can't you find even a child?!
What are you here for?!
Come on!
We found this boy.
ls he yours?
We found this letter
in his pocket.
He refused to say where he lives.
This letter had your address.
Please sign here.
Where did you go?
l asked, where did you go?!
l am asking you something!
Where did you go?!
Aren't you ashamed?! You are
a guest at somebody's house!
We're doing so much foryou!
lnstead of being grateful,
this is what you do!
Now, what's the use of standing
in front of me like a statue?!
You don't even have
the courtesy to apologise!
l am glad you're leaving!
We'll be rid of you!
There has been no peace in the
house ever since you've come!
Do you know how worried
Mini and Winky have been foryou?
Mini hasn't stopped crying!
And l've been in and around
the house looking foryou!
What would we have done
if you were harmed in any way?!
Does one walk out
at midnight in this city!
They kidnap small children!
The entire police force of the city
is in search of you!
lf something were to happen
to you, yourfather and l...
l mean, your uncle and l...
- l know.
-What do you know?
That he's my papa.
lt is written in the letter.
DK, wait.
Just a minute.
- He knows.
-What?
About your relationship with him.
How?
He had this with him.
Go to him.
Listen.
Son, you shouldn't do this.
Where did you go?
Uncle Suri and l
looked foryou everywhere.
Are you angry with me?
What happened?
Nothing.
What does he say?
He isn't saying a word.
l can understand.
lmagine a child who is trying to
trace his father since years...
...and when he finally
does find him...
...his father
does not accept him.
He keeps him apart
and sends him far away.
You can imagine what that
child must be going through.
Sorry about saying all this.
Let's go to sleep.
Carry on. l'll come later.
Drop the children to school
by taxi in the morning.
l'll take Rahul to the station.
Come on, Mini.
Come, Mini.
We are getting late.
Mummy, why had Rahul run away?
l don't know.
Won't he ever return now?
-Whom will he stay with?
-With his papa.
But he doesn't have a papa.
He does. He had drawn his papa's
picture and showed it to me.
Hey, this is Rahul's sketch book.
Yes. He gave it to me.
This is mummy, me, you,
papa and Brother Rahul.
This is Brother Rahul
and his papa.
Did you strike off
Rahul's picture?
No.
-Where is sir?
- He's taken Rahul to the station.
Mr. Tiwari! Here.
- How are you?
- Let's go, Rahul.
The train is about to leave.
- l'll carry it.
- No, allow me.
- How are you, Rahul?
- This way, Mr. Tiwari.
The seat numbers are 55 and 56.
Come on, Rahul.
The train is about to leave.
Will you come to meet me?
Yes, son. l will surely come.
Wheneveryou say so.
You won't
forget me again, will you?
No, son. l will neverforget you.
...Not this time.
You won't forget me, will you?
How can l forget you?
After all, you are my papa.
Yes... Yes, son. l'm your papa.
l am your papa.
Come on, Rahul, hurry up.
The train is about to leave.
Write to me once you get there.
- Mr. Tiwari...
- l've made all the arrangements.
l've taken care of everything.
-What about the food?
- l'll arrange it in the train.
Don't let him
have waterfrom outside.
- Have you kept his water bottle?
- lt must be with him.
- Son, where is your bottle?
- lt's in the car.
- l'll go get it.
- But the train is about to leave!
Mr. DK, please! The train
is about to leave. Mr. DK!
Excuse me! ...Ticket!
l'll be back in a moment.
l have to get something.
- Fine, but where's yourticket?
- l have it.
But where?
My child is in the train. l have
to get his bottle. l'll be back.
- Come this side.
- l repeat, l do have the ticket!
l say, stand aside!
Whose car is this?
-Whose car is this?!
- That's the person, sir.
Move your car! ls this how
you park?! l can't open my car!
- Hurry up!
- l'm moving it away.
The train is about to leave!
- Papa, Rahul will stay with us.
- Mummy said so.
Now, will you
keep sitting here...
...or come home?