"This heart lays in search..."
"...once again for those
days and nights of leisure..."
"This heart lays in search..."
"...once again for those
days and nights of leisure..."
"We remain sitting,
waiting when to know..."
"This heart lays in search..."
"...once again for those
days and nights of leisure..."
"This delicate heat
of autumn we bear..."
"...lying in the courtyard."
"We pull off of the shade of
the veil from your eyes..."
"We lay on our stomachs,
tossing and turning."
"This heart lays in search..."
"...once again for those
days and nights of leisure..."
"When the winds blow in
the nights of summer..."
"...we keep awake..."
"...in cold white
sheets until late."
"We kept staring at the
stars lying on terraces..."
"This heart lays in search..."
"...once again for those
days and nights of leisure..."
Hello Sir.
- Hello.
This is Mr. Chawla, our biggest
distributor in eastern India.
How do you do sir?
Dr. Kamal Bose.
How do you do?
I know you well
by your medicines.
That is why I am infamous.
In fact all my doctor
friends prescribe your medicines.
Nowadays your name
dominates the market. - Okay.
Mr. Chawla, isn't your
head office in Calcutta?
Yes. I had come here only to
arrange this cottage for you.
Mr. Bali had called.
Didn't Mr. Bali
mention over the phone that...
...during these holidays
I do not wish to hear...
...even the names of medicines?
I want a
complete rest from work.
Physical as well as mental.
Neither do I want to tell
anything about them, nor hear.
Whose cottage is this?
Dinshaw Irani's. A Parsi
medicine man of Calcutta...
...who is now settled in Bombay.
He has maintained
his house beautifully.
Yes, that is the
uniqueness of the Parsis.
Even if hundreds of years pass
by, their wallpapers don't spoil.
Greetings, sir... Greetings.
I have heard you are very
fond of eating and drinking.
So I have arranged this cook
for you. He cooks very well.
The twin pills of
Gill's medicines.
You can have them with
either water or milk.
They provide relief from
cold and cough immediately.
These medicines do
not leave me here also.
They are medicines
discovered by you, Dr. Gill.
Yes, where am I refusing that?
My deeds are chasing me.
They don't leave me at all.
Beautiful!
Is this the first time you
have come to Darjeeling?
No, I have come once
before also. Many years ago.
About 25 years ago. Before I
gave my doctor's examination.
Then I had an accident.
Accident? - Yes! I had
fallen in love with a girl.
Oh! That happens in youth, doctor
I also had them. - With her?
Yes. I mean, no. It was on
the hill station and now...
...I am the father
of her three kids.
No, man, I did not do
anything like that with her.
That is why you were saved
and I had to get married.
Listen.
- Yes sir.
What is your name?
- Mangal Singh sir.
Mangal Singh sir?
- No sir, only Mangal Singh.
Tell someone to put the chairs
out. We shall sit there only.
Excuse me, Dr. Gill.
I'll take your leave now.
I have work in the hospital.
I'll meet in the evening.
Okay.
- Mr. Chawla?
Mr. Chawla, you too may leave.
No need for formalities.
I'll take some rest now.
We'll meet in the evening.
Bye for now. We'll
meet in the evening.
If you need me for anything,
here's my card. Come on.
Dhyan Singh...
- Yes sir?
Why are you throwing
cold water on the car...
...early in the morning? I am
feeling cold just by its sight.
Don't you feel anything?
It's better if I wash it now
only. If the master asks for it...
...as soon as he wakes up,
then what shall I do?
This is not
Calcutta; this is Darjeeling.
Dr. Gill has come
here on vacation.
He'll not wake up so soon.
Yes, this is the
condition since yesterday.
I myself was
waiting till 11 o'clock.
When will the
master have breakfast?
Today the master will
have a very heavy breakfast.
He has not eaten
anything since yesterday.
When will he have it?
- As soon as he wakes up.
Who will wake up?
- The master.
Early morning, the master...
Now this hill
station has changed a lot.
When I had come
here many years ago...
...there weren't
so many cars here.
There were only mostly
rickshaws plying here.
Now it is not even the season.
When the season comes...
...you shall see, there's
so much rush here that...
...people do not even get
adequate place to stay.
Then we could manage to get
lodging at someone's house...
...as a paying guest even.
I myself had stayed...
...at a contractor's place.
Mr... Mr. Jodhpal.
Do you know what the
rent of the room was?
Seven rupees.
But sir, now that
can be only dreamt of.
Right said! The whole
place looked different then.
See that wood shed there?
- Yes.
There used to be a
doctor's shop there.
When had you come here before?
It is many years now.
But we are seeing this shed
here like this since many years.
I am talking of a
time before that.
You must be mistaken.
No. I cannot be
mistaken about this place.
A little ahead from here,
there are those stairs, isn't it?
Those which descend
from the Upper Bazaar?
Yes.
- Then this is the same place.
But sir, there was
never a doctor's shop here.
We have always
seen this shed here.
You must be talking
of the doctor Thapa.
Yes, yes, he's the
one. Harihar Thapa.
It's ages since he died, sir.
But he was not that old.
Does it take time
to grow old, sir?
If there is sorrow,
man can age very quickly.
Which sorrow did he have?
The sorrow of a
daughter is very bad, sir.
He had a young girl. She
had a very pretty name...
Chanda? - Yes, Chanda. You
have a sharp memory, sir.
Then?
- She wouldn't marry. - Why?
She would tell some
doctor would come to take her.
Then?
Does anyone come back, sir?
She was humiliated in society.
We don't know who the man
who gave her sorrow was.
The doctor also stuck to
the bed in such a way...
...that he died on the bed
itself. Only before dying...
...he entrusted his daughter
to a lame stammering man.
Lame? Stammering?
Yes. He was staying
down in the Blue Valley.
A factory had opened
up there that time.
We had heard Chanda
also worked there.
When she returned home
upon her father's death...
...she had a child in her arms.
Her husband did not come.
Some tell he died;
some tell he left her.
Show that to me...
- Here.
Show me that one. - That
one's mine. - Show it please.
What happened? Did
you have a fall?
Yes. This...
Is it a sprain or an injury?
I do not know.
Perhaps it is a sprain.
There's a doctor here. Get
him to put an ointment on it.
It will be well in an instant.
- Is that so?
He is a very good doctor. Yes.
Did you bring the herbs?
Which all did you get?
I found some of them. And I
also found a patient, father.
He has a sprain in his
foot. He'll come now...
...to get an ointment put on it.
Those stairs in the bazaar.
He fell on them.
Did he fall by himself
or did you push him?
Why will I push him?
Who knows? You may be
helping your father's business.
Very good! If someone falls,
that means I have pushed him.
Don't know what he thinks of me!
Come, come, come. Did
you sprain your leg?
Yes. It seems like that.
It is the fault of the eyes,
and the legs have to suffer.
A foolish leader commits a
folly; the whole village pays.
Give me your foot.
So you slipped on
the bazaar steps?
It doesn't matter.
You are saved.
If you had been hit on the
head, that would be grave.
Chanda, bring the
herbal oil kept inside.
I'm warming and
bringing it, father.
Shall I bring the turmeric also.
Yes, bring that also.
Did you see? Before
the patient comes...
...the preparation of
the medicine has begun.
Do you know astrology also?
Yes, I know.
Okay! So that's how you
came to know about it.
Seen her? She's my astrologer.
She keeps herself updated
with the goings-on of the city.
From where have you come?
- From Calcutta.
What is your name?
- Amar Nath Gill.
What are you doing?
- Learning to be a doctor.
It is the last year so I
have come here for preparation.
"Whether you take
a prescription.".
"...or rely on drugs..."
"A man has to face the
consequences of his deeds."
"Whatever he does, the
doctor ends up getting richer."
If you do not have the
sole intent of earning money...
...then there is no occupation
better than this, Amar Nath.
Amar Nath what?
- Gill.
There is so much
pleasure in this job that...
...it cannot be expressed in
words. It is like worship.
That is why I am
learning to be a doctor.
So you'll open your
clinic in the city?
It won't work in the village.
- Why?
Who will buy such expensive
medicines here, Amar Nath?
Gill!
Yes, Gill. Here only
our herbs will work.
The virtues are
earned by the tree...
...while the peepal
tree has to sacrifice.
Where's a doctor like me
who can take care of all?
Once I have the knowledge, sir...
...I shall learn
the wisdom from you.
Where do you stay here?
That bungalow of the contractor
Jodhpal... I stay there only.
That is very near.
Father, the bandage.
Okay, so you stay in
Jodhpal's bungalow. - Yes.
Anyway that remains
vacant ten months in a year.
Where do you eat?
In a wayside restaurant.
How bad! Being a student, you
eat in a wayside restaurant?
How will you top
your class then?
No, no, no. From today
you'll eat with us. Okay Chanda?
Thank you. How much?
Let it be. First you become
all right, Amar Nath... - Gill.
I'll take the money later.
When you come to dine at night...
...l'll change the bandage.
Thank you. Good bye.
Take care, take care. Take my
stick. Chanda, give my stick.
Bring in the evening
without fail. - Okay.
Father, the
sprained one hasn't come.
May I give his
share to the goat?
Why? Did you eat the
hay meant for the goat?
Am I an animal to eat
the fodder of animals?
Then why will you give
his share to the goat?
Does the goat
also have a sprain?
What is there
about a sprain in this?
Always doing charity.
You don't take money from...
...the villagers because they
are from the same village.
You found one foreigner, but
he too turned to be a student.
More than a student, he
has become something else.
How will it do if you
treat everyone for free?
You have to get me married
in the future. What then?
Don't get married.
Do you mean that? Can
you promise me that?
I can promise you but who
will bear this headache for...
...a lifetime?
Now you call me a headache.
But when I shall go...
...you shall not be able
to find anyone like me...
...who would find
your herbs for free.
Go yourself in the jungles then.
Listen Chanda, I'll do one
thing. I'll see Amar Nath myself.
He stays near here
in Jodhpal's bungalow.
No need. I am
going to Hansa's place.
I'll see him on the way.
Doesn't give any money; on top
of that, he's taken the stick.
You? Come. Come inside.
You did not come to eat.
Father was waiting.
I could not come. I have fever.
This foot is also swollen.
You did not eat anything?
I am not hungry. I
have warmed the milk.
I'll drink that only.
You sit. I'll bring
it. Where's the milk?
There in the kitchen.
Drink the milk and sleep
now. I'll tell father.
He'll come here and
change the bandage tomorrow.
Do you have a
thermometer at your place?
What?
A thermo...
- What is that?
It is a glass tube.
What is that?
Tube. A tube of glass.
It has mercury below it.
What below?
Mercury. Mercury. When
you put it in your mouth...
...you know the temperature.
I mean, fever.
What is there to laugh in that?
Do you need a tube
to tell about fever?
We can simply touch and
tell how much fever one has.
Touch me and tell
how much fever I have.
You have. But not much. Shall
I bring the medicine tomorrow?
What tablets, I mean
medicine do you have?
No tablets. I have some
flowers, which I shall...
...boil and make a brew.
You yourself are a good doctor.
Living with herbs
day and night, even...
...my goat has become
somewhat of a doctor.
Can't I become then?
You can be.
Shall I go?
- Yes, go.
Can I take this stick?
Let it be. I'll need it.
Father, have your breakfast.
- Keep it.
Take this pill
and this medicine.
What to do of that
man with the stick?
You only go. Give
him these medicines...
...and apply this ointment also.
Take your stick back
and get rid of him.
You'll have to only
give instead of taking.
He hasn't paid for
his first ailment...
...and has attracted
another on the contrary.
He'll give. Take
something to eat also.
Here.
- He's a student. A student.
They are the
future of the country.
Don't know when he'll be
the future of the country...
...but right now he is
affecting our future.
He has caught the
stick in such a way...
...he doesn't leave it at all.
Oh my God! Do you have
to study so many books...
...to become a doctor?
What else? This is
not village medicine...
...that a person can learn
sitting next to his goat.
Did you call my father a goat?
No, I called the goat
your father. I mean...
...you only had told yesterday
that if your father sat...
...next to the goat... sorry, the
goat sat next to your father...
...then it could learn also.
It is not that simple. 300.
No, I don't know how many...
...there are species of roots,
flowers and herbs.
You should be able to
recognise each leaf.
Only then can a
man give medicine.
It is not like this. Just
read a book and give medicine.
Why don't you treat yourself?
You too are a doctor.
I would have done it.
But the medicines I need...
...I do not get them here.
Then where do you get them?
There in Calcutta.
Then you should have
fallen there also.
Why did you fall here?
Do you not get any other stick?
No. I'll take this one only.
Father had bought
it for three rupees.
He had not got it from a tree.
Hello, Chanda.
- Come, come. - Greetings.
Greetings. I had
forgotten your gait.
I didn't see you so many days.
Actually I had
forgotten my gait.
Lay out the plates for him also.
Tell me, how is your health now.
I am all right now.
Also the temperature...
...the fever, that
is, has gone down.
Chanda! O Chanda! Come here.
Come here I say.
What is this? You did not
greet him? He is your guest.
Greetings!
- Greetings!
Eat.
How are studies going on?
- Okay.
Will you top?
I hope to.
How many patients
will you kill in a year?
Some... what?
What to worry of
those who have to go?
Creatures come and go. If
they are saved, it is due to...
...the Almighty's blessings.
If they die, it's
the doctor's doing.
Sir, along with wisdom,
you also teach me...
...how to make couplets. I'll
recite them when I operate.
Operation means the
cutting up of the body.
That's it. I do not like this
cutting up in your medicine.
Do you also do it?
It has to be done in surgery.
When has it to be done?
In surgery. Surgery.
There's no meaning of that.
Sir, nowadays technology in
surgery is fast developing.
Is that so? - Now we can
even transplant hearts.
Oh! We change hearts also, but
by instilling good thoughts.
What else?
Eat, eat. Did you not like it?
No, it is very nice.
Whatever little it is,
it is at least home-made.
Listen, as long as you are
here, you are our guest.
Give.
Why are you taking this stick?
I'll give you one. Silent!
She is after this
stick since ten days, sir.
She is not at all
concerned about my foot.
"This stick... this stick..."
"...has stuck around my neck."
"Like shackles around the feet,
or sometimes like handcuffs."
"This stick... this stick..."
"...has stuck around my neck."
"Give a turn to
the straight paths..."
"...give some solace to
disinterested souls..."
"...this chain of
breath may not cease..."
breath may not cease."
"This stick... this stick..."
"...has stuck around my neck."
"Like shackles around the feet,
or sometimes like handcuffs."
"This stick... this stick..."
"...has stuck around my neck."
"It seems that some glass
is broken in my breath."
"Some strange pain
pierces the chest."
"I have tied this
fiery pain to my veil."
"This stick... this stick..."
"...has stuck around my neck."
"Like shackles around the feet,
or sometimes like handcuffs."
"This stick... this stick..."
"...has stuck around my neck."
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Sorry, Dr. Gill, we
have entered your house...
...without your permission.
Mr. Mehta, dean of the...
...government hospital.
- How do you do?
Mr. E. Suratwalla, chief
surgeon. - How do you do?
And you already
know Dr. Kamal Bose.
Please sit down.
We have come here to invite
you for the opening of a clinic.
Well gentlemen,
thank you for the honour.
But I am here on a holiday. I
wish to spend these holidays...
...in absolute solitude.
We won't take
much time, Dr. Gill.
It is a very small function.
We are opening a clinic in
the Blue Valley. We wish that...
...you encourage the young
doctors who are leaving...
...the city and beginning their
careers in this faraway village.
Where are you
opening this clinic?
In the Blue Valley.
When?
- Next week, Friday.
Okay.
- Thank you.
You are welcome.
Bye doctor. Okay.
By the way, dean. Is
there a mill there...
...where clothes are made?
Yes there is one, a small one.
It is not very famous too.
The womenfolk of the
village work there.
There's a better mill at Siliguri
It makes better cloth too.
Okay. Anyway, I
shall reach at 11.
We shall come to pick you up.
- Okay, bye.
The Blue Valley! (Nili Ghati)
Come, come.
I am looking for a
woman named Chanda.
She works with you perhaps.
Chanda! Yes there is one.
She is an old lady.
Perhaps yes, she is the one.
You wait. I'll call her.
Come, come inside,
mother. No need to worry.
Is she the one?
No. Sorry,
mother, I troubled you.
Go mother. Do your work.
She must not have become so old.
You know her?
Yes. I know her.
Then come yourself and see.
No.
Do you know very well
she works here only?
Yes, I have heard. Since
when are you working here?
Since about 10 to 12 years.
I am speaking of a time
before that. About 20 years ago.
Munim, listen. Was a
woman named Chanda...
...working here 20 years ago?
What name?
- Chanda. Isn't that right?
I do not remember anything.
Did she live here?
No, she had come here
after marriage in Darjeeling.
Her husband was lame.
Are you speaking
about Langu Harkara?
Yes, he's the one.
He had married the
daughter of some doctor.
Yes. Her name is Chanda.
She used to work here. In
the coloring department.
She would colour threads.
Her husband had died...
...just one year
after her marriage.
She had a daughter with Langu.
I am searching for
them only, Munim sir.
Do you know where they are?
Where can I meet them?
I cannot tell that, sir. It
seems to be another life now.
But I know that even
after the death of Langu...
...she was here for
three or four years.
She knew the herbs very well.
It was in those days only...
...that she went somewhere.
Perhaps she went to Dhaulpur.
A woman named
Chanda in Dhaulpur?
Yes. She's a widow.
She has a daughter.
She had come from the Blue
Valley about 15 years ago.
She knows herbs well.
She knows Ayurveda also.
We do not know any
woman by this name.
Thank you.
Darjeeling to the Blue Valley
and from there to Dhaulpur.
I only know that much.
It is difficult to
find her like this, sir.
How many places
have you been to?
You do not know the
name of her husband...
...you do not know the
name of her daughter...
...and the one you know, who
knows if she is alive or...
No! She is not dead.
This cannot be.
But will you recognise her
if you meet her daughter?
I will recognise. If not by
the face, then by the voice.
The voice will be
the same... Of Chanda.
"This heart lays in search..."
"...once again for those
days and nights of leisure..."
"This heart lays in search..."
"...once again for those
days and nights of leisure..."
"We remain sitting,
waiting when to know..."
"This heart lays in search..."
"...once again for those
days and nights of leisure..."
"This heart lays in
search once again..."
"On seeing the delicate
sunshine of the winter..."
"...and lying in the courtyard..."
"On seeing the delicate
sunshine of the winter..."
"...and lying in the courtyard..."
"Pulling the shade of
your coat over my eyes..."
"We lay on our stomachs,
tossing and turning."
"This heart searches..."
"This heart lays in search..."
"...once again for those
days and nights of leisure..."
"This heart lays in
search once again..."
"When the winds blow in
the nights of summer..."
"...we keep awake in cold
white sheets until late."
"We kept staring at the
stars lying on terraces..."
"This heart searches..."
"This heart lays in search..."
"...once again for those
days and nights of leisure..."
"This heart
searches once again..."
"...for those days and
nights of leisure..."
"We keep sitting, not
knowing where to go..."
"This heart
searches once again..."
"...for those days
and nights of leisure."
Excuse me. I need to know
the whereabouts of a girl.
If you now, then...
Whose girl?
She's named Chanda. A woman now.
She knows herbs well.
She had come to stay here...
...from the Blue Valley. She
has a child also. She's a widow.
Thapa the doctor's daughter?
Yes, she's the one.
Where is she?
She was. She was
a very nice girl.
Was? Does that
mean she isn't now?
No. She went from here.
It is many years now...
...she used to collect herbs
and bring and then sell them...
...in the bazaar. She used
to prescribe medicines also.
She had suffered
many torturous days.
Don't know how she got
an idea in her mind!
She would tell of
going to the city...
...and educate her
daughter to become a doctor.
But the wretched woman
was ruined by her own self.
What had happened to her?
Where is she gone?
Who knows who he was?
Dhanu or somebody.
Don't know what his
name was. Perhaps he was...
...her husband's brother.
Less of a brother...
...more of a slaughterer.
He would take whatever...
...she would earn. He tried to
keep her forcibly in his house.
He would threaten to kidnap
the girl and take her away.
She was getting
insulted due to him.
She had just one folly.
She would mutter to herself.
She would speak to herself only.
But she was fond
of making medicines.
If I would tell her the medicine
for her asthmatic problem...
...she would tell me
her own prescriptions.
She would tell to put all
the seven salts in some leaf...
Where has she gone now?
I'll tell. Let me
finish what I am saying.
Here. Jodha... Jodh...
- Jodhpal.
Yes. Here, you see this.
She had written this here.
It is her handwriting.
Contractor Jodhpal,
Pili Kothi, Siliguri.
This is the Pili Kothi. But it
has been sold since 2 years.
Where does the
contractor Jodhpal stay nowadays?
He has retired now. He
stays in Calcutta only.
There was a woman named Chanda.
I have come from very
far to search for her.
Please tell me
where I can find her.
There's a gardener
living behind the cottage.
Meet him and ask. He was
taking care of that mad one.
Mad?
Yes. The elder one had lost
her senses and the younger...
You meet him only and
ask. He'll tell you.
Can I get a glass of water?
Yes, definitely.
You do not seem to
be well, sir. Here.
A mad woman stayed here.
Chanda. - Yes.
Can you tell me
anything about her?
She's not here anymore,
sir. She died.
When?
It is eight months.
How did she die?
What had happened?
It is a very sad tale, sir.
I would just hear and weep.
In her last days, she
had lost all her senses.
She would run here and
there in her madness.
If she would see a
book in anyone's hands...
...she would hold
their hand and ask them...
...if their exams were over.
Are the exams over?
Have you become a doctor?
When you become a doctor...
...you marry my daughter.
Teach her also. Her also...
Sir... Sir...
She has lived
her life in misery.
There was an old overcoat.
She would wear that.
She also had a stick in
her hand. She used to tell...
...to burn the stick along
with her on her funeral pyre.
And Kajli? What happened to her?
No news from her since
she went to the city.
She would send some
money for her mother...
...every month or two. She
had sent the message that...
...she had got a good job
and she was still studying.
When she becomes a doctor,
she will come...
...and treat her mother herself.
- Do you know her whereabouts?
She never sent any.
Does she know
that Chanda is dead?
Yes. I had sent a
message with the person...
...who used to bring the money.
When the money stopped...
...I understood that she
must have got the news.
She would make Kajli
wear this and look at her.
And this... she had told Kajli
that she would give it to her...
...when she became a doctor.
Don't know where she got it from.
Can I keep this too?
Yes, keep it too.
Listen, give me that box.
It is that same thing, perhaps.
- What, sir?
I had given her
a white necklace.
Of ivory? I have seen it.
She told Kajli that...
...she would give
it to her as dowry.
It wasn't of ivory. I had lied
to her and she began arguing.
That time, I was
preparing to return to the city.
It is very beautiful.
Is it ivory? - Yes.
How much is it of?
- Of 715 rupees.
What happened?
How do you have so much money?
- That...
There were 128 rupees in
it. Only 60 are left now.
Where are the rest?
I have kept those sixty
for returning to the city.
Don't touch them.
Why did you touch them?
There were 128 rupees here.
How many days have
passed since I kept them?
Don't I have any expense?
What expense do you have?
You eat for free.
I wash your clothes. You get
milk twice in a day. That's all.
And this necklace of 45
rupees? Does the pundit...
...in the temple distribute them?
Is it of 45 rupees?
Doesn't it seem to be so?
That it does.
Give me the remaining money.
What money is left? I
spent 50 paise on tea...
...and 50 paise for the rickshaw.
Tea? Had you drunk in a bucket?
Not drunk, but bathed in it.
What is this? Show.
Hey...
58 rupees.
- Isn't it a good photo?
How did these come? Tell
me how much this is of.
You'll have to swear on me.
No, no. This box, it
is of three rupees.
And this necklace?
- Of 75 paise.
I do not want a necklace
of 75 paise. Am I a beggar?
Great! So long as it was
of 45 rupees, it was nice.
Now that it is of
75 paise, it is bad?
Princess Chanda, it
is the same necklace.
Is a 75 paise
necklace a necklace?
What if the
necklace is of 75 paise?
The heart is not of 75 paise.
Take your hand away.
- What happened?
Do not rub your ears.
It becomes septic.
What does it become?
- Septic.
Look, you forget this medicine.
You'll simply kill some patient.
You become a doctor.
I'll leave then.
What will be the delay
in my becoming a doctor?
Just about ten days.
I'll go next Tuesday...
...there will be the
exams on Wednesday.
What will be there?
- Exams! Examination.
Didn't you say that
you will get something?
Yes, a first class degree.
After that I can kill anyone.
When will you speak to father?
You are going on Tuesday.
Now five days is remain.
I'll speak tomorrow itself.
What will you tell him?
I'll tell I want to marry
Chanda and take her with me.
Will you not give me time
to make the preparations?
If I just send her like that,
she will think I only...
...washed my hands off my
responsibility. No, my son.
Not like this. I'm fortunate
that Chanda is born in my house.
You are also fortunate that
she is going to your house.
When such a goddess of
wealth enters someone's home...
Go, son, go. I
am obliged to you.
Whenever you shall come, I
shall return your wealth to you.
Go.
That was the last
time I saw Chanda.
I thought that this journey
will take me back to Chanda...
...in a few weeks, but it
extended to many years.
I committed a very big mistake.
It's result would be this,
I never imagined.
I should have returned.
Yes please.
- Do you have aspirin?
Can I give you Gill's tablets?
They are very effective.
You'll get relief soon.
No, brother. They have
more chlorine, less medicine.
Give me aspirin only.
As you wish.
Scoundrel, rascal, will you
sit here the whole night...
...for ten rupees?
Is this your house?
If you come here again,
I shall cut you up and...
...feed you to the
crows. I shall...
Give me my slippers.
Take these. And beat
your wife with them.
Where do they come from?
What are you seeing, sir?
If you want to have fun...
...come upstairs.
Or else, go away.
Come on, Kajli. Why are
you spoiling business?
Only God can
understand your anger.
Sir, aspirin. Take your aspirin.
What are you
embroiling yourself into, sir?
This happens here every night.
This girl... who is this girl?
She is a prostitute, sir.
Didn't you hear her language?
Such foul words!
You can hear such
dirty language here that...
...a gentleman would go
home and wash his ears.
Three rupees.
Your balance, sir.
Does some girl
named Kajli live here?
I want to meet her.
She is resting now; a customer
has just left. She is tired.
Will someone else do?
- I have some work with her.
Everyone has the
same work. Come.
Get up. - Who is it? -
Go inside and sleep. Sit.
Kajli, get up. Someone
has come for you. Get up.
Let me sleep, auntie. How
much will you make me toil?
Get up, child. He seems
to be a very rich man.
If he was a pauper, I myself
would have shooed him off.
I do not think he will sit.
He'll have fun you and go away.
Meet him. And do not agree to
anything less than 30 or 40.
Hey sir, you were
so late in coming.
I am yawning. Sit.
Will you have
something to drink?
No whisky. But I have country
beer, like myself. Will it do?
No, daughter. I
just came to meet you.
Why do you call me daughter?
Just come down to business.
I have come here with
some other work, daughter.
Don't tell daughter. I
have heard lot of this.
Tell me if you want to sit.
What is your name?
What will you do with
my name? Do you want...
...to take me home? Why
know about my ancestors?
My mother was mad,
my father was lame.
Want to ask something more?
Why are you
getting angry, daughter?
Auntie... auntie...
Listen to me.
You only take care
of this old man.
He has come to adopt me.
What happened?
Come on inside.
Is Kajli there?
Kajli... See your old
man has come. Go. Go.
So you came back?
Listen to what I
have to say, daughter.
Daughter again?
Go. Get out. Go away.
Where do these people come from?
These people...
What is it? What
do you want now?
I want Kajli. I have whisky.
I need soda. Can I get it?
So you have come on
the right path. Come.
Sit. I'll bring the soda.
What is it? What is your name?
- Paro.
Will you take some whisky, sir?
- No.
So you too are bonkers for
Kajli! She is quite an item.
Once you are addicted to her,
you can have no one else.
Husain, did you like anyone?
None from this lot.
- Then go inside. Go.
Come on, let's play poker.
Do you have money?
- Certainly.
Can I come also? - Be seated
there. It is strictly cash here.
Here, this is mine.
Distribute for me. I'll
come just now. - Come soon.
Is there any place
to sit separately?
Yes. It will take Rs. 5 more.
Doesn't matter.
- Come on. Bring the soda.
Go, sir. Go.
Sit down.
Since when do you drink?
Since I am in this job. The
one who would come earlier...
...used to give me forcibly.
Now it has become a habit.
If I don't drink,
I cannot sleep.
You didn't touch the glasses.
Cheers!
What did you say?
Nothing.
Kajli!
What is it, auntie?
- Listen.
Will he sit the
whole night or go?
I don't know.
- Ask him.
Why? - Chawdhary has come.
He doesn't go to anyone...
...but you.
What do I do, auntie?
He's sitting. Tell him...
...someone took me outside.
Come on, why are you fretting.
Chawdhary, she is
sitting with a client.
Let me show.
Chawdhary! What are you doing?
It's a very rich
client you have trapped.
You sit with him Kajli.
I shall deal with him.
Come on with me.
- What will you take?
Many people come here.
Some days many people come
here. But on some other days...
...it is so empty here, do
not even ask about them.
People do not come
here even to just drink.
But that Gangu Rani, she
takes good care of the girls.
Just like a mother
she treats them. Drink.
You are very slow.
What's the hurry?
Will you stay the whole night?
Yes. Do you go out also?
Yes. If he is atrustworthy
man, Gangu Rani sends me.
What does trustworthy mean?
Gangu Rani looks at
the man and understands.
She has seen in a lot in life.
Will she send you with me?
It appears so.
Not for just one night.
For many days.
Out of the city?
No, in this city only.
As long as I am in this city.
I understand. I have also seen
life. But it will cost a lot.
Do not worry about money. I
will give as much as you ask.
But you will have to stay
with me where I tell you.
Agreed. Okay.
Tell me, from when.
From today.
How much will you take? Tell me.
Shall I call Gangu Rani?
You'll give an advance. No drugs.
Call her.
You sleep.
Dinner, sir?
I have eaten. You sleep.
Turn off the lights.
Where are we?
Good morning, sir.
- Good morning.
Keep the tea
outside in the lawn.
Good morning, sir.
- Good morning.
I waited for you
till late at night.
Yes, I was delayed.
Those papers which have
come from the office...
...I have signed them and kept.
You can take them and return.
Take Dhyan Singh also with
you. I shall not need him.
Tell in the office not todisturb
me at all these vacations.
I do not know
when I shall return.
Tell Kiran to mind the business.
Do you want to ask anything?
- No.
You woke up? - Yes. I
got much drunk last night.
You go. Make
preparations for your return.
This whisky is a
very miserable thing.
Look, do not swear.
I have sworn at whisky, not you.
It may be for the whisky; but
girls don't look good cussing.
Whether it is a boy or a girl,
a swear word is a swear word.
What is good in that?
Let us get some new
clothes for you today.
I have some.
They are in the box.
Even then, let me buy
some more. - Buy them.
What loss it is to me? But
do not cut it from my fees.
You are good at business.
What else? If you have to
sell your body to live...
...then you'll know.
What are you doing?
- What?
Why are you smoking a beedi?
I smoke beedi.
That may be. But is
it a problem if you...
...do not smoke here
in front of everybody?
Look friend, this will be
very difficult. You've paid me...
...but do not boss on
me as if I am your wife.
Do not smoke; do not swear;
don't do this; don't do that.
For what you have paid me,
that I know and you know too.
Look, if you feel so much
like smoking, then go inside.
Outside there are servants.
People look.
If you keep my respect among
them, it will be a favour.
Otherwise, let's bathe and go
out. Where do I refuse there?
I get humiliated very
much with a respectable man.
Sir, you have a
trunk call from Calcutta.
Hello. Speak Kiran.
I am all right.
I have money. I'll ask
if I need. And listen...
I am sending Mathur and Kiran
back. Oh, don't you bother...
...and don't bother me also.
What? Okay, you sign it. Okay.
Sorry sir. I had to
disturb you in the morning.
I'm going back today. I
thought of meeting you.
If you need anything from
Calcutta, you can tell me.
Sir...
- What is it?
Where is the box of my clothes?
In my drunkenness, I
lost my wits only.
It is outside in the car. Tell
the driver. He'll remove it.
So, when are you going?
I thought of meeting you. - Will
you have tea? - No, I'll go now.
I wouldn't want to disturb you
much. Have a good time, sir.
I got it. It was in the car.
Did you have to ask now only?
- What happened?
Don't you have anything
else to wear? Like some saris?
You go, get ready.
We'll go to the bazaar.
Look, how beautiful
you look like this.
Unnecessarily you
put all the makeup.
You speak like a lover. No
one has told me this before.
Can't you speak
without calling names?
If you feel bad, I
shan't say so, my friend.
Wear one of these saris.
Which one will you wear?
The one that you like.
You wear it. I'll go outside.
Why do you go out? I shall
wear it in front of you, friend.
Won't you feel ashamed
to change in front of me?
Your daughter may get
ashamed. Why should I?
People spend so much
money for the body.
Will it always remain like this?
I was going to call you a name.
You wear. I'll go outside.
I understood you. - What? -
You are another type of man.
Another type?
Yes, the romantic. They
keep girls only for roaming...
...drinking and dancing.
Isn't that true?
Yes. I am that
other type of man.
But you have
committed a mistake. - What?
It would have been better
if you'd have chosen Champa.
She dances quite well. She
taught me, but I didn't learn.
But I'll show you.
- Okay. Wear the sari.
"I sway a lot in my love... My
lover, get aside... get aside..."
"If I wink..."
What is this? What is happening?
"If I wink, you
shall fall, my lover..."
Oh no!
"My lover, get aside,
get aside, get aside..."
"I sway a lot in my love... My
lover, get aside... get aside..."
"My waist is so thin..."
"...and on that thin
waist I have tied a pot..."
"My lover, get aside,
get aside, get aside..."
"I sway a lot in my love... My
lover, get aside... get aside..."
What happened?
Do you feel dizzy?
Yes, a little.
Enough! You've done too much.
Didn't you like it?
- It's nice. It's very nice.
"The intoxication of
alcohol on the peach colour..."
"My lover has
spoiled my habits..."
"My lover, get aside,
get aside, get aside..."
"I sway a lot in my love... My
lover, get aside... get aside..."
"If I wink..."
Enough, Kajli.
I am doing this for you. You
are spending so much on me.
Do not worry about my money.
I have a lot of it.
Ask how much you want.
What do I want to do?
If I get for my food and
booze, enough. What else?
Will you drink some?
No. Not today.
Are you sick?
No. Is it necessary
man should drink daily.
I'll not be able
to drink, friend.
Try abstaining for one day.
You will make me
go out of business.
When I was not doing all this,
someone used to come...
...and make me do all
this forcibly. But now...
...somehow you have come.
Why did you not come then?
When?
When I was young.
I could not come then. I
am repenting for that now.
But if you'd have come then,
we would not have gelled.
Why? - But you would
have gelled with my mother...
...because she was
also very beautiful.
What was your mother doing?
She was just dying. She
kept dying for twenty years.
For some scoundrel of a doctor.
But don't remind me of all that.
Do not ever talk of my family.
I'll warn you
against that now only.
I do not feel naked
sitting among naked people now...
...but I do feel ashamed
among respectable folk.
I can then see my nakedness.
You only had gone
and sat in nakedness.
Come back to where
you had gone from.
Do you not know of the cobbler...
...who spent a
lifetime working in leather?
The day he passed by a
perfumery, he fainted.
He had gone there after
many days; that's why.
If he goes there daily,
then he will not faint.
It isn't needed at
all. If one feels...
...naked going somewhere,
why should they go there?
I will have to travel to the
market of perfumes so many...
...times, you will forget
the stench of leather.
You must have gone to
some other paths too.
Not all the time... - Sir...
this was left in the both room.
This... is this yours?
Yes.
Why do you wear this coral.
Someone had given it to me.
Who had?
Some one.
- Is he not there any longer?
He is there. I don't
know how and where he is.
What is his name?
Kundan.
Do you want to
search for him? Do you?
Why are you
worried about my life?
Do you want some alcohol?
Shall I bring the glass?
I look dignified
with you now, isn't it?
There is something.
You are a good man.
But you are useless for me.
- What do you mean?
Have you kept a
woman for the first time?
Yes.
Never married?
No.
Why?
It was a long time ago.
I loved a woman.
I wanted to come
back and marry her.
But... in those days...
A man was killed at my
hands during an operation.
Are you a doctor?
No. A surgeon.
There was a police case, and
I was jailed for three years.
Because of that shame, I
didn't tell her anything.
I didn't come back,
and neither did I marry.
Don't scratch your ears.
They get poisoned.
Who told you that if you itch
your ears, they get poisoned?
Mother. Mother told it
to me. In my childhood.
Where are we going?
The blue valley.
Have you ever gone there?
Yes, in my childhood.
How is the place?
I just remember two places.
One is the company,
mother used to work there.
And the hospital, where
mother used to take me to.
Why?
She used to tell the
doctors to make me a doctor.
Then?
Then what. Does anyone want
a doctor without studying?
If you wish, you can
continue your studies.
You can become doctor.
Should I tell you something?
I hate the word doctor.
I don't hate that man
as much who made me...
...a prostitute, as much
as I hate that doctor...
...because of whom my
mother went crazy.
If I would meet him
once in this life...
Then? What would you do?
Even I don't know what I'd do.
I just know that whatever
I'd do would be very bad.
Rascal! Wretch!
- Oh god...
Get lost from here. Get lost.
- No, I won't... I won't...
What is going on? Why
are you two fighting?
Dare he hit me! I will
wreck his entire family.
I will...
- Silent, Kajli.
What is the matter?
Sir, I told her not to
come in the kitchen.
But she didn't listen to me.
Who are you to refuse me?
Is this your father's house?
See, sir... when I told her
to go out of the kitchen...
...she abused me on my mother.
Why did you send her separate?
See, sir... I have been
silent till today because of you.
Otherwise, you
know it very well.
I cannot eat
anything that she touches.
If you can eat it,
please have her cook it.
I will have her cook it.
Go away from here.
This is not correct, sir. A
respectable man like you...
You don't have to
worry about my respect.
I will take care
of my own respect.
Please leave.
Come with me.
I threw the cook away.
To hell with the wretch.
And which wretch
will cook the good?
I will cook the food,
don't I know how to?
Eat it and see. You
will forget this wretch.
Is it? Okay. Bring it. Come on.
Are you going to Dholpur?
Yes. I think that is
the name of that place.
What work do you have there?
I want to search
for a man there.
What is the name of that person?
Kundan.
- Why? - I have some work.
What is the work?
Not me, but you can
have some work with him.
No, I don't have any work,
I don't want to meet him.
You loved Kundan, isn't it?
Yes, so?
What if Kundan is
still waiting for you?
Nobody waits for
anybody for so long.
Didn't your mother
wait for a doctor?
Twenty years.
It isn't wrong to meet him once.
I am not worthy of
him anymore now.
And I will not hide
anything from him too.
It is possible that the
doctor thought like this...
...and he didn't return too.
If that doctor returned...
wouldn't your mother forgive him?
Yes?
Kundan... Kundan
stayed here, isn't it?
Yes, he stays here...
I... I...
I wanted to meet him.
He has gone out for some work.
Tell me. I am his wife.
So... he has married...
Can I tell you something, Kajli?
Why don't you marry someone too?
Someone nice...
- Who lets anyone remain nice?
No woman is a born prostitute.
You get people to make them.
I have got also.
- Who?
Dinu, my father's brother.
He used to regard me
as his daughter and...
Where was your
mother at that time?
Mother was crazy by
that time. Already crazy.
"The baton... how did
it stick to the neck?"
You have become crazy, Chanda.
Mother, go inside.
Dinu... Why did you
come once again?
I am your father's brother.
Regard me as your uncle.
How can you speak
to me like this?
I have seen your brotherhood.
I have told you so many times.
You don't need to
come here anymore.
Even if I do come, I
come to see your well being.
See, I have spoken to
the doctor upstairs.
Take Chanda and
have her admitted.
I don't want to send
mother to a mental asylum.
I will have her cured.
Uncle Moti...
- Yes?
Uncle, I am going to
get medicine for mother.
Please take care of her.
- What is all this?
When Kajli becomes a bride,
I will have her wear this.
I can make her a bride tomorrow.
But she should agree, isn't it?
How will you have her
married now? Are you crazy?
Let her become a doctor.
When she becomes a doctor...
I will give her this...
You have ruined your
life for some doctor.
He must have died
a long time ago.
Kajli... hey, did Kajli
go to get the medicines?
She has gone to the school,
to become a doctor.
What is the work?
The landlord has called her.
Send her when she returns.
That landlord! Till when
will he save her? I'll see!
If I cannot do it right away...
You? What are you doing here?
What do you want?
While I was unconscious,
he took me to the city.
The dark room... and... and...
I was sold the day
I saw brightness.
At Gangurani's courtesan hall.
What did you do?
If I was with my
Kajli at that time...
Good morning.
Good morning. Yes... thank you.
You woke up
early in the morning?
My days and nights
have changed due to you.
I sleep early in the night,
and wake up quickly in the day.
I felt like praying
today in the morning.
You should have done it.
Do you know how to?
I didn't learn it at all.
Here...
- You have it. - Take this.
No. I had it lighted for you.
You will not have it?
No. You don't
like it. Therefore...
I thought that I'd not
have it in your presence.
That means, you will
have it if I am not around.
What?
Nothing, I forgot.
You will not be with me forever.
And if I tell you that I
will be with you forever.
I want to keep you
with me forever, then?
It is good for the number of
days that you are with me.
Don't promise me forever. I
am scared of such promises.
Someone had promised my
mother this once upon a time.
And I had promised
someone the second time.
Now...
There was so much
money here. Where is it?
The wallet too...
yes... I found them.
There was so much money... now,
there are just this much.
If you spend them like this,
you won't have any to return.
Shall I keep some
of them, carefully?
Kajli... many years ago, a
woman saved my money like this.
Even at that time, she kept
sixty rupees for my return.
If she wouldn't keep it, if
I wouldn't go... then... then...
I am feeling very strange.
When Kundan was here many
years ago, I felt like this.
Did you say something?
- No.
Where had you gone?
Are you still angry with me?
I committed a mistake,
forgive me.
I have come to take my clothes.
You will not get them.
You will not get your clothes,
salary or holiday. Nothing!
See, this house is yours, and
the owner of this house too.
I don't have anything here.
Nor the employer nor the house.
He has kept you to
look after the house.
You look after it.
You don't know why
and how we are kept?
Nobody gives us houses.
Then why have you come here?
To trouble a dignified man?
I had come here for my business.
And I forgot it.
I started looking
at him like a woman.
I don't know... how
this took birth within me.
Uncle... uncle...
please come back...
I will go tomorrow.
Your employer
won't lose anything.
I won't be worth anywhere.
Neither the house... nor...
Who has come at this time?
Get up, see.
You? Come... come inside...
Have a seat.
Tell me. Why did you
come here at this time?
Your previous money
hasn't finished as yet.
I wanted to speak about
something. Therefore...
I don't know how
to tell this to you.
Do you want to change the girl?
Are you tired of Kajli?
You will not understand.
It is like this...
Kajli is from a good house.
I want to take
her out from here.
Sir... nobody is good in this.
All of them are whores.
Yes, they do nice business.
Do your work, and
return the seeds to us.
Don't try to sow them.
How much do you earn from Kajli?
How much will you earn from her?
And till when will
you earn from her?
Five years? Ten years?
Fifteen years?
Take all the money that you
can earn from here. From me.
Has Kajli sent you?
- She doesn't know about this.
I didn't even tell her this.
And I don't know how I
will tell her about this.
Don't be crazy, sir.
This is not the market of sheep.
My daughters live here.
You can sell your daughters.
I don't sell them.
They are not saleable.
Such a amount, which you
must have just heard...
...but never seen in your life,
fill it. I will give it to you.
But give Kajli to me. I
will wait for your answer.
"These halted steps..."
"They stop and
then move ahead..."
"These halted steps..."
"They stop and
then move ahead..."
"At peace..."
"...they become restless again."
"These halted steps..."
"They stop and
then move ahead..."
"These halted steps..."
"The morning didn't come... I
woke many times from my sleep."
"I spent this whole life
in a night once again."
"These halted steps..."
"I had the gratitude of
the heart on my bosom..."
"I repaid this debt to you too."
"At peace, they
become restless again."
"These halted steps..."
"They stop and
then move ahead..."
"These halted steps..."
What is this that
you are wearing?
Clothes. I wear
them all the time.
What is so surprising in this?
Get up. Get up and
change your clothes.
See, don't order me
around like a husband.
I am not your wife. What
is wrong with these clothes?
You look vulgar
in these clothes.
It seems... these
clothes look so cheap.
Don't you know where
you have brought me from?
See, I don't want
to argue with you.
Just change your clothes.
Haven't you heard that phrase?
The crow tries to
walk like a duck.
I had forgotten my business.
I had gone to
business today therefore...
Where had you gone?
To my client. That Chaudhary.
Do you remember?
That day... He had come...
Why did you go?
Why did you go out?
What do you lack here?
You want money, isn't it?
Don't I give you money? Don't
you get money for your time?
I know. This is the
time that you have bought.
I will not betray you.
I got these. Keep them.
Get lost. Get lost from here.
Nothing can be done to you.
I cannot do anything.
You have come from the dirt.
You will remain in the dirt.
Mangal, give her
all her belongings.
What is the matter?
Tell me.
Nothing. Nothing at all.
I forgot my way.
Inside me... inside me...
a woman is still alive.
I thought, she had
died a long time ago.
But she is alive.
I wish to be a mother, Champa.
I wish to be a mother.
Has our Banno returned?
Where is Kajjo?
Come... come... have you
returned from your in-laws?
Come on, get up and sit there.
You look so nice in this saree.
That old man made you a bride.
Anyone would take you home.
Come on. Sit on the chair.
The new one for nine days, and
the old one for a hundred days.
I am your lover
since so many years now.
He is here today,
he will go tomorrow.
And I... I will be
here with you forever.
I have heard it,
come on... get up.
That pimp has made
you so arrogant.
You must be the pimp. Your
father doesn't feed him.
Don't you dare abuse him.
A woman worth two
bits. She slaps me?
What did you say?
Get lost from here...
Will you hit me?
Will you?
Come on!
What happened?
He was abusing.
Whom?
Him.
With whom I stay nowadays.
Is he your husband?
No. I am not related to him.
But who is
Chaudhary to abuse him?
But why did you feel so bad?
I never saw you so
angry ever before.
I never met anyone
before this too.
Nobody gave me such dignity too.
For the first time,
someone saw me like a woman.
Not like a courtesan. He
didn't even touch me till now.
Aunty, he really loves me.
I can't tolerate his love.
Kajli, does he love you...
...or do you love him?
Even you have changed a lot.
See, child...
The steps of these halls
don't lead to any house.
I have never seen
any woman settle...
...down after leaving
these courtesan halls.
I haven't seen
such guts in any man.
Whoever comes,
comes all excited.
When the excitement is over...
But for the first time... I
saw a man to be so truthful.
Such truth in his words...
That old man...
with whom you reside.
He came to me too.
To pay for you.
He came here?
Yes. And he gave me
this blank cheque.
Told me to write
off anything in it.
This hasn't happened
ever in life, child.
But even if one person
does it once out of millions...
...I will think that you
and I have done our duty.
If he takes you as
his own, go. Go away.
I don't want anything, I
don't want anything at all.
Champa, should I go?
Should I go away?
Once... just once...
I want to be a complete woman...
I don't want to be incomplete...
Who? Who is it?
Your Kajli...
You? Why have you come here?
What have you come here for now?
To love you. To
give myself to you.
Have you seen
anything ahead of this body?
Thought about it? Recognized it?
Did your mother give
birth to you for this day?
Did she give birth to
you for this market?
It is good that Chanda
went away before all this.
Chanda?
If she wasn't mad
for that doctor...
...she would have
been mad for you.
You would have made her mad.
Chanda wanted to make you this?
She wanted to see you like this?
You know this, isn't it?
Don't you recognize it?
This... all this... these
veils, this vermillion...
Don't you know all this?
She accumulated dowry even in...
...her madness to
see you as a bride.
And you...
You want to ask
who I am, isn't it?
I am that same doctor.
Dr. Amar Nath.
You want to avenge
your mother from him.
Tell me. What do you
want in revenge? Tell me!
No...
Mangal...
- Yes, sir?
Here...
Why did you come back?
Do you want something from me?
What do you have in your hand?
What are you hiding? Show me...
Him... you are the one, isn't it?
You made my mother
wait for twenty years?
You are the one, for
whom my mother went crazy?
For whom her whole
life was ruined.
Neither did she survive,
and nor me.
Even I was sold in
the market for you.
It is your fault.
Mother will never forgive you.
She will never forgive you.
Yes, child. Chanda
will never forgive me.
But my Kajli can
forgive me? I know.
I have erred. I am a sinner.
Therefore, I came
to you repeatedly.
To ask for my
repentance from you, child.
Please forgive me, child...
Will you come with me?
We don't have anything to
turn and look back, child.
Come with me... come on...