MEGHE DHAKA TARA
(Cloud-Capped Star)
Supriya Choudhury, Anil Chatterjee,
Bijon Bhattacharya
Gita De, Gita Ghatak
Dwiju Bhawal, Niranjan Roy, Gyanesh
Mukherjee, Ranen Roy Choudhury
Story by Shaktipada Rajguru
Photographed by Dinen Gupta
Film editing by Ramesh Joshi.
Music by Jyotirindra Moitra
Production, scenario and direction
by Ritwik Ghatak
Tell your father you owe us for
two months. lt's getting difficult
Yes, l will
l can't do without a shave,
so please shave me
Any idea what you owe?
A dark girl
A dark complexion
Get off to school now
Her tuitions should be over;
she'll be hurt if she overhears
Such a responsible girl
Studying and giving two tuitions,
bringing home forty rupees a month
l heard at the meeting that
there are more and more evictions
They might even stop school grants
Would you like a mat,
to sit and gossip on?
Your sandal is torn, Khuki
l'll have it mended
Teacher, about your tax...
What a good thing l bumped into you.
Now, about your dramatic society...
The bumblebee flew humming
into the room
Bathe, you're late for college
A love letter!
''l didn't appreciate your worth,
l thought you were like the others
''But now l see you in the clouds...
''...perhaps a cloud-capped star,
veiled by circumstances...
''...your aura dimmed''
Sanat. That idiot! l haven't
seen him for ages
Poking your nose into personal affairs
lf you're a ''person'', then
l'll be a genius one day
You know that's true, hence your pride
lf only the barber would understand
what a genius l am
Can you spare some money?
The beard's itching
Two annas, or maybe four...
...or maybe eight - l'd like
some tobacco
Or why not a whole rupee. You've got
your tuition money, haven't you?
Why not get a job, Brother?
lt's beneath an artist's dignity
ln a couple of years, cash will
rain down on me
Do you know how much Amir Khan Sahib
gets for a concert?
Remember what l said about the rupee
Ma, Manashi in our college has
a sari with a beautiful motif...
...a cow-girl
Ma, don't listen to her
lt's the college's football final
tomorrow
l can't wear these awful saris
any more
The ''heiress'' has spent three years
in the same class
l must have studded boots by tomorrow
He can't afford food, but he makes
demands like a prince
Half the month we can't afford
a second course
lt's the first of the month -
sister will have been paid
You didn't buy sandals, did you?
l'll buy them later. l bought
material for brother's shirt
After all these years... isn't that
Father's pupil Sanat?
Don't you recognize me?
lt's Montu, isn't it?
What are you gawping at?
You've changed so much. You were
only a girl, and now...
-Who?
-Neeta
You write letters, but you don't
come to see us
l know that handwriting; l give
those letters to Neeta
She's hardly at home, what with
college and tuitions
Let's go home. Ma will be cross
Geeta has grown into quite a beauty
A beauty... but she can't afford
decent clothes
Neeta, l need some cash to have
the diagrams printed
lt's all gone this month, Sanat
l can't even buy my brother and
sister what they ask
l know, but l still bring my woes
to you. One feels powerless
lt's your struggle. Can't we share it?
l'll find a way next month
Please visit us. Father often
speaks of you
Yes, but only when l've some money
Your spoilt darling will spend it
by the fistful
After all, it's her money
The hussy must have spent it all,
my entire month's budget
l ought to give, but l don't.
How can l say no?
No sympathy in the whole world,
and no one who'll understand
Khuki, won't you eat?
l'm not feeling well
Don't be angry with Ma
Deprivation... it's destroyed her mind
l'm not angry
Remember that poem by Yeats, Khuki?
A bad headache
Here's another precious prodigy
A god in a devil's clan.
Shear it off
You've bought nice material
Going to bed already? Won't you eat?
Mother must have said something
lgnore what people say. Your motto
should be: Do what you think best
Eyes full of tears? They'll fall
at the slightest provocation
l'll utter a spell. All right?
-l'm not feeling well
-So l'm uttering it
Mother, your girl's such a Khuki.
She wants to catch the moon
She can't make out anything
She's such a Khuki, mother
-A rupee tomorrow, please
-There's nothing left
All right, next month, then
Next month it all goes straight to Ma
Whoever gives up money
is a full-scale idiot
Where are you going, all dressed up?
l couldn't wait till morning
to wear it
Slightly bovine
There's pleasure in practice
New month, very busy right now
Please send last month's bill
You'll settle it? What did you want?
Just the bill
Not going to college?
Flunking exams for novels and films
Everything's scarce in this house,
you don't have anything you need
So create a paradise
Dress like fairies, all of you
l'll rest, wriggling my big toe,
in perfumed splendour
This year you and Shankar
just have to sing for us
l've given up singing, and Shankar's
maestro won't give him permission
But we'll invite lots of guests.
We must talk this over
All right, l'll call in at the
library and see you
Well, how are the rehearsals?
Not making much progress
Progress indeed!
The tuition money
All of it?
l asked Banshi to send his bill.
He's so rude every day
Keep five rupees for pocket-money
Have you no shame, living off
your old father?
The girl works to foot your bills
l'll be earning, too
Since the radio audition l get lots
of calls, my maestro's furious
He won't let me perform until
l've studied for another two years
Hasn't your maestro a hennaed beard?
Why not just grab it and hang on
like a midget? Why come here?
Does any young man sit at home?
My bread doesn't come cheap
How can l look people in the eye?
No food for you, unless you pay up
-Going off without eating?
-You told Ma l'm a glutton
He can't make out anything.
He's such a Khuka, mother
Why destroy the future because of
such simple bickering?
Grit your teeth and hang on
for two years
Khuki, only you know my worth
Going off like that... don't you know
what's on tomorrow?
lt's Jagatdhatri Puja
lt's your birthday
Father's taking me out,
like he used to
Where to?
Anywhere, it's not decided
All right. l'll come, too.
Don't tell him
Brother, you're such a child
Father would refuse if l told him
Sunrise
Didn't Keats have a poem?
This flourishing field... it costs
nothing to perceive its beauty
There is no money, but this is here
Appreciating life is an art
Don't overdo it, you'll get
indigestion
Will you always be this greedy?
You shouldn't say such things
Anything for us?
Sir, your tax is three months overdue
Come tomorrow morning,
l'll see what l can do
Aren't you in that group of...
l left. l wasn't getting any parts
An actor, is it?
Who are you?
l'm Sanat, sir
You got a good second in pure physics
Someone told me... Khuki told me
Yes, we meet sometimes
What's happened? You're so pale
and drawn
What are your plans?
l'm looking for a scholarship
to do doctoral research
Monkey!
-For a D.Sc?
-D.Phils are all too common
Swine!
What's the subject of your thesis?
The Reynolds number of the Supersonic
Vibration of the Lower Gangetic Plain
Ape!
Not you, l mean Shankar.
l was comparing you two
He's done nothing
Son, have a bite to eat
So you're immersed in studies?
No other way out in life
What a lovely place
l haven't time
Give Sanat some tea
ls Sanat here?
What are you staring at?
Take this, l'm late
How do you manage to sit indoors
all evening?
Drink the tea. l'll go late for
tuition, as you're here
Let's go for a walk
A walk, l said. Miles away,
weren't you?
Where is everyone?
What's this? Get out at once!
Dear me, what's going on?
Come inside
You know the guru l told you about
When was that?
Bring home all the vagabonds!
Can't feed yourself...
Beginning's a bit troublesome
Such a lovely voice.
You'd be spellbound
lf you bring such a nuisance again...
Quick, bring some money
Don't tell your mother. We're busy.
Lessons to be taught
We're going out. l'll do the tuition
on the way back
lt won't work. l can't manage
without a job
No, you mustn't
But l can't get a scholarship
After so much work
Just a few more months
And then?
Then l'll get a job
And with your earnings...
lt makes no difference
You're so gifted
-That picture in my room...
-The two kids?
Me and Brother
Once we went up to the hills
We got up before dawn to see the
sunrise from a peak. How hard it was
But when the sun came...
l can't explain the thrill
Brother used to tease me:
''She wants to catch the moon''
He still teases me
Neeta, you're just not cut out
to endure all this
Then keep me in a glass case,
like a wax doll
l'll be late for tuition
That's why l come to you,
you make my worries vanish
No cause for alarm, just a broken bone
Neeta, a word with you
Such an injury in old age...
it'll take long to mend
You'll have to run the household
from now on
l'll give a sedative,
it'll last until morning
What brings you here? Weren't you
finishing your studies this year?
l couldn't. l've had to take a job
You'd better spin a new yarn
about your rent
-l said yesterday...
-''You'll get it as soon as l do''
Do you take us for your benefactor,
to rest on our shoulder?
Why not get a job? Settle down in life
You'll never understand suffering
for an ideal
l asked your friend Saroj
what could be done about it
What did he say?
National Chemical, Joy Engineering,
Jagat Hosiery
Three jobs just waiting for you...
...and you're researching hot air
in the atmosphere
Sir, the lady's here
Your ideal is here
What a time l've had.
Luckily, l got a job
The way things are after
Father's accident...
l can't say l like it.
Why abandon your studies?
What can l do?
So many at home, all counting on me
Walk me to the station
Praise to the Goddess of Learning,
bestower of perseverance
And four annas for me, for a shave
Goddess of Learning,
Mother of the Universe
lt will be unbearable if l do research
while you work
l'll work and you study.
l can easily get a job
Then our wedding...
Can't happen now
How can it? lf l leave the household...
My father, brothers and sister...
Shankar's a rascal, why support him?
You don't understand him at all
One day he will be big,
and you will, too
l pin my hopes on both of you
Then my time will come
That means, until then...
We must wait
Why should we wait?
Don't be silly
l'll drop by in a day or two
l have a question
Come along
A singer can certainly afford a shave
Have you shorn off your sense
of shame, too?
What shame?
The lot of you living off one sister,
destroying her future
Everyone's talking about it.
Aren't you the elder brother?
Banshi, just because you give credit
it doesn't mean you can criticize
l call Neeta ''Sinbad the Sailor''
They're all on her shoulders,
like the old man of the sea
That'll be her fate until
she drops dead
Wasting all my days
l've come to the river at a bad time.
l don't know your name, boatman
Who shall l call out to?
Who will row me across?
The boat is here, but no boatman
Not a soul to be seen
Sir, l've finished the lesson
lt's late. You'd better go home, son
Montu has skipped college for a month.
l heard today that he's failed
He's been struck off the roll because
he couldn't pay the fees
What good would college do him,
anyway?
lt's just as well that girl has a job
Father, do you know about Montu?
No need to tell me. Bad news
travels fast
Everyone knows you're the happiest
to see us harmed
You and your young man
Wife!
Because he's known as a sportsman,
Montu's been given a factory job
He was frightened to tell you.
He's brought home his first pay
Everything's kept secret from me,
as if l were an enemy
Like father, like children
l won't touch this money. You can
run the household and face the music
A job in a factory? Labour!
So what? These jobs have better
prospects nowadays
See what the middle classes
have sunk to?
Help me into the next room
You all think l just pick fault
Time has taken a heavy toll
of my mind and spirit
Something's come over me
You needn't explain, Ma
l can't take the burden of this
household any more. Set me free
lf Shankar had been a man, you
wouldn't have to shoulder the burden
Brother is very nice
Don't count on your father any more.
Maybe he will stand and walk again
But l think his mind is
becoming confused
He won't be able to earn again.
l've known him since l was seven
Don't worry, Ma... l'm here
You, too, have your hopes...
lots of things, l expect
Anyway, you're all l have
Yes, but l can't help thinking
You're my sole support...
that's the truth
But even you scare me
My own daughter, yet l don't know you
What if you go away, too?
l still don't know you
-Oh, it's you
-Just listening
-What is it?
-Come and eat, it's late
-Why haven't you eaten?
-Because you haven't eaten
l bother you all the time, don't l?
-How sentimental
-Not really
Your whole future... your marriage...
People are turning nasty
lt hurts your manhood?
-Haven't you an ego?
-Something much bigger: my music
Right now l'm exploiting you
But deep down it really disturbs me
Are you serious?
l love you all to distraction
We all love each other,
but we shy from saying so
lf anyone else loves me,
he'll surely wait for me
lt doesn't worry me
l won't marry right now
l'll marry when you become
really famous
Won't l survive until then?
All my suffering will vanish then
Don't you vanish, too
Will you take me to the hills then?
''She's such a Khuki, mother''
l will. You're such a child
Banish sadness and poverty,
bring happiness to all
Sadarang makes a plea
O Being! l shall worship You,
Supreme Being
What have you done to yourself?
Don't fall. l spoke like Father
Why haven't you come for so long?
l can't seem to make it
-The question you were going to ask?
-l don't feel the need
l'll be back after tuition