How many famous families are here
in this state?
We can count them on our fingers
As far as our Thirunelveli district
is concerned
My grandfather Chellappanadar was
the 1st man who bought a car
Look at that
When grandfather used to come in a car
all villagers were wonder struck
My wife expired at an early age
It is very difficult to
bring up a child without mother
That is why, I left her
in a hostel
Fortunately the incharge of the hostel
was my manager's sister
I felt miserable after leaving
my little girl in a hostel
What could I do without
her mother?
That Lady took special care
of Priya
Priya too adjusted herself
very well
You look at her, She is playing
Piano at that little age
She is very intelligent
After that, my life almost
became like a factory
The factory started by
my father
But I developed it by laying
a 2nd plan
At that time G.H. Patel was
the Governor
I invited him for the inauguration
He accepted it happily
Who is that man
like a Joker?
He is like a joker
He is a Joker
He was my manager
Completely deaf
Neither he could hear
nor he had brains
I got fed up & dismissed him
Look at his Luck! He started a
factory opposite & got settled
It's said that he started that factory
with the money swindled from me
But I really didn't bother
That's his son Thomas, some what
intelligent, unlike his father
To show off he sent Thomas
to America for higher studies
He is still in States
See his mentality
He is very selfish
He is giving sweets only to
his son, lt's intolerable
This was when we had laid
a new plan in our factory
We organised a big feast
for all the workers
Priya is distributing
sweets to every body
Puppy give me chocolate-No
Do you want chocolate?
Baby give him chocolate-No
Come on share the chocolate
In future, I'll never eat
chocolates
She told this in her
childhood out of anger
And she's still keeping
up her word
She was extremely good at
her studies, had Gift of the Gab
She sang as per her
will & pleasure
Her mother was quiet by nature
But they had one thing in common
Both of them had a liking
for flowers
My desire is to hear the noise of
blooming flowers
My desire is to hear the
noise of flower buds
The voice of birds
The noise of worms
Will teach us music my dear
Wearing trinkets in the feet
Playing lute on the shore
You hear the song sung
by river my dear
The earth is a lute
the wind plays it
We are hearing the sound of Rhythms
When eyes are about to sleep
when the atmosphere is silent
The sound of time piece is music
The place which can't see the sound
mingling with Rhythms
The train making sound is music
At the time of hunger the sound
of cooking food
Is happy music
Mothers who are feeding milk to
babies through their breasts
That sound is also music
Little sparrows after taking bath
Fluttering their wings to dry
that sound is also music
The sound of sea waves hitting
on black rocks
Is also music
The sound of Breeze
rubbing the wind
Is the music of love
The sound of frogs Jumping
step by step over water
Is also a music
Taking a Doctorate from
Harvard University of America
The young Lion Thomas Thangadurai is
coming today to his native place
Our hearty welcome to him
Young Lion Thomas Thangadurai live long
What's this father
so much of Crowd?
You will come to know
about it son
Those who had gone to London in
the ship for their studies
They are still boasting
about it
You went in a plane to America
for your studies-ls it a joke?
That man must see all this
Where is the Garland?
Didn't you take money?
When wealth comes suddenly
They'll behave like this
Correct Sir, They'll use
umberlla in moonlight
Young Lion Thomas Thangadurai
live long
You wait for sometimes, Why are
you blowing the horn?
Young Lion Thomas Thangadurai
live long
Hey call that Thangadurai
Hey! Clear the way
Hey! Call your master
Thangadurai what's this?
Is this an Industrial Estate or
a Drama company, for staging a show?
My son has come from America
That's why labourers...
What is the use?
These crackers, loud speakers...
It's nothing great going to States
one must've taste, taste
What is he saying?
He is saying, this is corporation
road, don't act smart
He is attacking him nicely
He is tearing him into pieces
I am hearing well,
hearing well give it to him
Come on
Thomas Thangadurai-live long
Young Lion Thomas Thangadurai
- live long
You have torn him into pieces
my son I am very happy
Yes, you know why I had sent you
to america?
To study business management
- Not for that
Just now you spoke English
so fluently for that only
Now you had over taken my Boss that's
enough for me & I am very happy
He is an elderly person but he
doesn't know to behave like one-That's it
Old man lacks brains
He is arrogant say that I'll be
very happy, very happy
Any how everything has gone well
Okay shall we go?
No father this's the 1st time
I've come to the office-Today
I can start the work
- How is it possible?
You forgot everything in 10 years?
In our house while starting
a new business
We have to take blessings from
your Aunt you forgot Isn't it?
Hey! Why are you pouring water?
Can't she pray instead
of troubling us?
I think she wants to
maintain cleanliness?
Hey go! I'll teach you
a lesson
Their happiness is to make
us suffer
If others enjoy, they'll
get tensed up
Okay! Is there no retirement
for them?
You didn't understand
Mother Superior?
Is it wrong to
be ordered to clean?
Welcome Angel
You stay here permanently
& clean everything
We need Sunday
Boy friend for her...
And movie for her
What's there in Movies?
Only that much Isn't it?
Hugging the hero &...
The only male in the campus
Who?
Old watchman
Go & kiss him
It fell from Mother Superior's Office
I had doubt for a long time
Did you see her lips?
- I knew at that time itself
Hey! Don't whistle
I didn't whistle
The noise is coming from
Mother Superior's Offce
No Priya... Go
It's wrong to smoke in
Mother Superior's Cabin
It's wrong to peep also
I'll report to Mother Superior
Even I'll report
What will you report?
You're trying to attract me
You climbed up to Mother Superior's
Office to see a man
She won't believe this I am her
favourite student
She's my favourite Aunty
Aunty?
It's me
Who's that?
Aunty
Hey! Leave me
What's this
- What?
Cigeratte Smell
Have you learnt only this
from America?
No, definitely no
In America only studies
studies... studies...
I know everything
Are you going to prove your American
ideas in your father's Business?
Yes, That's why, I came to you
Before joining the Business
To get your blessings
And then to roam around here
My blessings will be there
always for you
But you can't roam here
Oh God! I'll simply roam here...
like this...
This is a girls convent
You shouldn't go beyond
the visitors room
Okay, I'll roam in this
room itself
What?
I want to meet girls
Visting hours are over
No, lt's impossible
No, this's a very urgent matter
If it's urgent, go & meet
Mother Superior
Oh God, no need of
I want to meet only girls
Meet them tomorrow
Time is up Please go
No, I came here for that only
Hey! How did he look like?
He was very handsome and
had moustache
First you say! Lncarnation of Lord
At a glance we can understand that
he belongs to Mother Superior's family
Both of them are mad
Very fair like marble
Have you seen him?
A little-I saw him clearly
How is he? -Very strong body
Don't lie, How could you see him?
Hey! Which hand did he catch?
This hand?
You all are crazy about men
Why are you screaming?
She slipped & fell down
- yes because of soap...
Were you quarrelling?
- Not at all
This is a bathroom not a play ground
Go soon after taking bath
Have they gone?
May I go to mother superior
& report now? -No
Look at his eyes, a suspicious look
His cheeks are turning reddish
He is feeling shy
He is innocent, Leave him
Mother superior is his favourite Aunt
That's why he is very proud
If we give him width
he will ride on us
That's his character since childhood
- How do you know about him?
I know it-No not like that
Earlier you caught my hand, Now you've
come to the ladies bathroom
What do you want?
I need a help from you
- What's it?
Mother Superior's Office is very
beautiful where should I put this?
You put there-No you put it here
You put it here, here
Don't tell lie, That day you
changed the place isn't it?
Catching hand, getting into
ladies bath room
According to that I thought
you are a scoundrel
What you did today was
heart warming
What's your name?
Don't you know?
No, What is your name?
Name?
When the rain of sympathy drenched
the world-the divine figure appeared
His body glittered like diamond
even lying on the straw
This is not good
This is a prayer to God
Something is missing Isn't it?
We've to practice more
Every thing must be perfect
in Bishop's presence
You practice it again & again
Notes are correct, lsn't it?
Notes are correct, I think mother
didn't say about notes
Mother expects some
more feeling
How is it possible to rememeber the
notes & lyrics at the same time?
My body shivers in the presence
of Mother Superior
For whom are we singing? Neither for
mother superior nor for the audience
We've to sing for Him
We have to sing only
for the Almighty
When the rain of sympathy drenched
the world the divine figure appeared
He glittered like diamond
lying on the straw
Sun can't appear in front of
stars, but God appears at anytime
To wipe off the tears with his blood
child Christ appeared
Son of God appeared to bloom flowers
on the earth which is ruined by war
He bloomed like a flower
on the rocks of Calvary Hills
He appeared as light to eradicate
the darkness of centuries
He appeared to change the
hard hearted into soft hearted
desert into an Oasis
Being a motherless child, Amalraj
entrusted her to me
That's Priya
Nobody can teach devotion
& faith
That's an inborn quality
You tell Priya to sing the
main voice
If I knew that she'll turnup so beautiful
I would've cajoled her then itself
I wasted my time in
childhood itself
You can't meet girls
Please, I want to see Puppy
Puppy-I don't know
Priya? Singing Priya?
I don't know
She'll always be in the
music class
No, Don't stop it
I am going back today
Flower
Priya we had played so much
in our childhood
We had quarrels also
But now while I am seeing you...
I am hestitating to meet you
face to face
I don't know how to say
I know one lady will
come in my life
That would be you
I've decided it today
Now only I am realising
why I came here
Realised, realised
Realised? -Yes realised
Priya-Yes I am Priya
No-Have you come to my college
to attract my students?
You don't wait a minute more here
Aunty sorry... I am...
- get out
This is very beautiful
Old man is well trapped, You don't
back of the car let him go back
You sit here, I'll see
- where are you going...
Elderly man, I have to
give him respect
Yes old man, big man, How's it within
a week Public road became his own road?
Elderly man, Aged man...
- No, No, I haven't finished yet
The same elderly stubborn man
now became uncle
Elderly man... - simply chanting
elderly man, stop it, you listen to me
Do you know what it means
L.O.V. E... P.R.I.Y. A...
Father you don't say like that
Nothing doing
Don't feel shy, my sister told me
everything on telephone
You started loving my
master's daughter?
Father, once upon a time he was
your master not mine
Oh! Only now you're proving
that you're my son
I am feeling very happy
Exactly your personality and
her personality is perfect
They'll say something like
matching, lsn't it, like that
Cajole her
We'll merge both the factories
Dad in between there's a road
Son we'll construct a Bridge
Where's the Mason?
Hey! Where's the Engineer?
Everyone stand in the
order, please
Put your cap properly
It's you, put your cap properly
Everyone face the camera
with a smiling face
Everyone smile, please
The Madam who's in the middle
please smile
Smile please
Let this be with you
as our memory
After leaving this convent
I think my daughter will
suffer a lot
Because, she'll miss your
love & affection
I don't know how to thank you
In this generation
Talent, knowledge, obedience, culture
It's very difficult to see all
these in one
I'll ask you the same question which
I've asked every student
Within 10 yrs, what'll you become?
As a mother for
two children
Are you going to
settle as a wife?
Do you want to become a great scientist
in the Nuclear Research Centre?
My family business is there
but she...
Priya should continue your family
business, isn't it?
Will she be able to manage
family & business?
There won't be any problem if you
get a groom from your field, lsn't it?
He'll understand, isn't it?
I am not telling that she should
continue our family business
Even Government job is Okay
Even she can become
an I.A. S Officer
No need, she has to meet the
politicians daily isn't it?
If you want what about?
Doctor's course?
Let her study
I'll build a hosptial for her
with all latest equipments
Good Profit
And with that, if she gets married
to a Doctor
They both can manage the
hospital as a team
And they can even manage the family
That'll gain us a huge profit
than Rahim's factory
I want to become a Nun
Are you mad?
I thought you'll educate &
lead her in Right path
Now, you're trying to
make her as a Nun
Please understand my feelings
You've mistaken
That only if we become a Nun
we can achieve sanctity
Go & tell her, madam
She won't listen to me
She wouldn't have taken
this decision in a day
Priya, you were brought up
in the hostel
From hostel to house and
house to hostel
You shouldn't think that
only this is life
For my sake please think again
Hey, Reduce the volume please
What to do, sir?
I am cutting hair by
listening music
There's no respect for the
profession, itself
Even the girls who visit here
are interested in that sir
Okay close that door
Hey, close that door &
stop this music
Food is closed, smile is closed
And everything is closed
Love failure for this Thomas
If it was another girl, she would've
praised me for sacrificing
Or is it wrong to love?
You be in her position
The decision she has taken
is great thing
How tensed she would've been?
Between this, how can I
express my love?
Then, are you not going to
express your love?
Hey, I should express
Should express
I'll express
But I couldn't express it
While talking, I'll hold her
like this and...
Kiss her
Then...
Even if earth & sky merges
If sea & air get separated
You & I...
To tell it simply...
Is 5.30 mass over?
This's the 5th time you're asking
Even if you ask for 50 times
the time won't chage
I shouldn't blabber, due to tension
I've to tell her as, I memorised
I've to tell little boldly
Look, I'm sweating
Mass is over
Are you coming from the Church?
For Mass?
Even I...
Hasn't your father come?
He considers it as a sin for a
teenage girl to go to the Church
Then, how can he accompany me?
No, he had left you in the hostel
in your childhood
So, he may have some feeling that he
didn't take good care of you
Look, I didn't go in
a wrong path
Since my childhood
I was having the feelings that
God is with me
I was brought up with that hope
But if you become a Nun
you'll have to suffer, lsn't it?
I know, Thomas, I know
I know, the life of a Nun is
not an easy task
When everyone is jealous of
money & the position
It's wrong to see that
I am sacrificing, lsn't it?
Thomas, you tell me
Is it wrong to become a Nun?
No
Baby has prepared all the items
A very good cook
Priya is a very good cook
Don't you see the
changes in the house?
It's all because of
Priya's touch
He's Mr. Arokiadas
Since generations, they're
doing yarn business
He is his only brilliant son, David
He has many new ideas
Mr. Arokiadas should be very lucky
to beget him as his son
In the Garden, I've put
Korean grass, shall we go?
First, I was managing
the yarn factory
Father asked me to manage
yarn dying
That's why I came there
Father said, we'll export
yarn in future
Has anything fell down?
What?
You are very smart, more than
what I expected
Father only asked me to
wear this red tie
I am feeling very shy
In this alliance...
Alliance?
Did father say this?
Yes
Shall I tell you
one thing?
Your first interest is yarn
Second Interest is yarn dyeing
Third interest is yarn export
My first interest is God
My second interest is Prayer
My third interest is Social Service
You sacrifice your life
for yarn
I'll sacrifice my
life to God
Father
So, you came directly
over here
You didn't tell your father
Mother, there's no other way
Father very well, knows that
I want to become a Nun
Then, why should he
search for a groom?
Tomorrow, lf you don't like
anything here
Will you get angry & go to your
father's house?
The life of a Nun is not an
easy task as you think?
We've to obey without
asking any questions?
We've to be a Spinster forever
We should live in simplicity
without having any property
Mother, I am prepared to
sacrifice everything
Do you know what
you're sacrificing?
What do you know about the
outside world to say "No"?
Priya, keep one thing in mind
If the doors of this convent
closes for once
It won't open again
Your contract is neither with me
nor with this Church?
It's with the God
Go, & help your father
Sing nicely, smile nicely
Look at others the way they live
After that, Even if you think
there's no meaning in that life
Within you
If you think there's
only God
Come to me
Did you go alone?
Even he came with me
Don't keep on chatting
Go & attend the customer, Go!
We shouldn't talk, sit
& stand
Look at the conditions,
for this salary
It's hair cutting, isn't it?
You've to cut for me
Isn't it?
Oh! God! My hair!
Sandhya has bungled it
She has cut the hair of the
person who came for facial
My husband doesn't like this
Are you running
a Beauty Parlour?
Will you cut whoever comes in?
Do you know who
my husband is?
I'll get everyone arrested
From top, you look like Madhuri film star
And bottom, film star Sridevi
Who are you?
God
Now, Commissioner is at
your custody
You look 10 years younger
Here, take this
If you would'nt have come
I would've lost my job
There's nothing to cut
Okay, Then lengthen it
I want
She's inserting it
she has inserted it
Oh God! I can't control it
I'll cut hapazardly
she'll end up ugly
Sorry Madam You're finished
Where's your Son?
Isn't he coming for lunch?
I don't know what has
happened to him
He's always saying that
he's not feeling hungry
He's talking something
by looking at the wall
You do something for him
What? Pig
Even son is looking very
handsome like father
And If you say Pig etc,
If won't look nice
You first switch on the machine
Are you asking that
am I a human being?
After so many years, are you
asking that am I an animal or human?
Is it Justice?
First switch on the Machine
He doesn't feel hungry
If I ask you, to do something...
That's all, lsn't it?
I am not totally deaf
but a little...
Son didn't have
his Lunch
I've to convince him
That's all, lsn't it?
Have it, son
Why?
Father, My throat is paining
If you don't eat, what'll
happen to your health?
Son, You're the one who's
slim in our clan
Your mother is very much
worried, have it
I said no, lsn't it?
Son, Don't get tensed
To reduce this anger there's
only one way, that's marriage
If you get married, everything
will become alright
Did you show him
the Photos?
Nothing, there's an enquiry
from Kovilpatti
Hey! Don't stare
She's not a country brute
but an educated girl
Even she has gone
to London like you
Hey, What's her Qualification?
She has studied Textiles...
If you both get married, you
both can speak in English
She'll even be useful in
our business
Father, this is not business
this is love
What did he say?
Yes, We don't know
about love
Hey! Son, We'll feel happy
if you get married to Priya
Isn't it so?
But that should happen
Isn't it?
To change your aunty's mind, do
you know the difficulties?
Tell him
At that time, do you know the
strength they had?
Your father tried to convince
but nothing happened
In this, you shouldn't suffer
We can't bear that son
Hey, I asked him for
Pista Ice-Cream
But he gave me Vanilla
Didn't I eat it?
That's about it
You marry another girl
In the Beginning
lt'll be difficult
But after a child & a family
We can adjust everything
Even life itself is an
adjustment
I don't want adjustment
You don't understand
one thing
This problem had arised
because of you
What?
This wouldn't have happened
had you not sent me to the convent
Oh God!
Gentlemen, please listen
I asked him to go to the
convent to get blessings
Hey be quiet, Be quiet
He got trapped in
Love & is blaming me
Who's mistake is this?
Sir, Please tell me
Is this my mistake?
Father please sit
Then what?
Mother, how could you manage
him for so long...
Hey Ice-cream is getting wasted
Hey leave, I'll eat it
Switch it off, Please
Please, some one switch it off
Hey, lt's Sunday
Hey, lazy fellows
Are you sleeping instead
of mixing dough?
Do you consider this as a
charitable trust, Get up
Oh God!
Get up
Hey, Today its Pramodh's
marriage
We've to go for the programme
Everyone are sleeping by
forgetting that
Programme? In this stage
Programme?
You go jump over the streets
& come, I'll serve you
Hey Guru, I don't like
all these guys
First, chase them out
Uncle, I don't know whether they're
singing the wake up Hymn at Tirupathi
You're singing daily for us
Yes, you all are God of Tirupathi
isn't it?
I'll tell you onething
very meaningfully
God of Tirupathi will get Sweets
And we get Scoldings
Gurumuttu have you all kept
this room tidy?
Vegetable Market will be
better than this
What's this, Lines drawn?
Oh God! Please don't
touch this
Why?
Guru has written Music
which he has composed
Is this Music?
No need
What's this? He's not allowing
me to see
No need
Is he begging or Pampering me?
He's saying "No"
Uncle, that's not an
ordinary paper
In future, they're going to
place that in the Museum
Hereafter from streets
to streets
And from State to State
They're only going to
sing my song
Keep that paper safely, I'll
go and have a bath
Don't touch it
Only this work, I didn't
do for these stupids
I'll keep this also safely
Hey, move
Have your bath soon?
Will it look good if we go late
for Promodh's marriage?
It is a problem for 4 people
to share 1 shower
Ask your uncle to put 4
showers for 4 of us
Yes, we're staying with others cost
without paying rent
For that, one shower
for each
If there's a little leverage you'll
ask for girls to wipe your hairs
We got this chance, because
Promodh is our friend
Even the bride doesn't
like us at all
If we do it hapazarosuly
she'll bite us, that's all
Have, you arranged for that
Blue Guitar?
Hey! Lt has already gone
Then, I'll get a
broken guitar
I can't play with that
Oh! Yes, he's great singer Michael Jackson
he'll play only with that
Play with what you get
Hey! Get ready soon
Here...
Yes, there... there only
I should buy a dress like
this if I get money
What's this?
That girl is in tension
Hey, groom
Where are you going?
Sandhya, ran away
She said, she doesn't want
this marriage
Oh! God! Atleast for the Programme sake
Please conduct this marriage
Wait, what did you do?
I didn't do anything
Then, why is she running?
Welcome
Sandhya's best friend Geetha
Isn't it
Yes
There was a connection
between me and her
Hey! Do you've brains?
For whom?
For him
Hey, come here
Hey, you're having connection with
bride's best friend
That... you only have to
do something for this
What can I do?
You've done everything
Isn't it?
Someone save her
Please move
According to the report
groom is a...
He's having contact with the
bride's best friend
Contact means?
Fully?
Yes sir
She's going to jump exactly
at 10.30 A. M
Why?
Auspicious time, sir
Those idiots are having set ups
at many places
And troubling us, Lastly
I'll arrest that groom & get him
a severe punishment
Please come down
According to Law, committing suicide
is a great offence
I'll even arrest you
You can come & arrest
me there
Hey, who's he?
How's the view?
Is it Superb?
Hey, you shouldn't come
near me
Don't try to come
I'll jump
You jump, but a small advice
While you jump hold your
head downwards
Then only, your head will hit
and that'll scatter
Yes, your brains will scatter and
you can reach heaven soon
What? Don't think, jump
If your legs get fractured first, then
you'll become a hopeless case
And forever everyone will address
you as lame sandhya
I've a feeling, that atlast
you'll die
But your would be along
with geetha...
Is it?
Is he a human being?
He's the one who'll admire even the
stick which is covered with saree...
How did you...
This's okay!
Geetha is looking soft
like a Dunlop Bed
Wait, I'll come
Please, Tell
Splinted eyes prema
Prema? How he went to her?
Even I can't understand that
Actually, lf lights are
switched off
Even she can't find out
the difference
But, that lean Asha
I don't know how did he
get this mood
Don't touch me!
No!
Let me dress the flowers &
you can reach heaven decently
lt'll be better if you go
after knowing the matter
He told me another
thing also
You're like an angel
You're very beautiful, worthy
of worshipping
He told me you are a
divine girl
Really, did he say?
Really!
He's a Superb Person
He changed that girl's mind
by talking cleverly
Then, without you, there's
no life
Something he said...
Did he say that he
loves me!
Yes, he said but, why that's
needed now?
Deva, don't leave me
No
That's all, shall we do
one thing
We'll go & ask him
what was it?
Come... Come...
Come, we'll marry
He's a waiter at the
five star hotel
He's not a waiter
but a Barber
He's not Barber but
a Hair Stylist
He's my friend, Deva
What's his Qualification?
He has studied the mind
of the girls
He'll cajole the girl
whoever she may be
You don't worry, Sir
For friendship sake, Deva
will do anything
Sir, for me, friendship is
important
Suppose I am going to start
a saloon tomorrow
I am seeking help from
some one
lf, I'll seek your help
Won't you give me the old A/c
machine from your house?
Won't you give?
You'll give!
You're a good person
Sir, girls are of 3 types
One type is they need
Love always
Another type is they need
Love very rarely
And third type is the one
who Love always
Sir, ln this which category
does your love belong to?
She's not like that
A very sacred one
Even my mother is
very sacred
But the Pregancy matter... Sir
Which occurs Unknowingly
Not that, Deva
Which?
She's not interested in
those things
Then, She may have interest with
someother person
Can be like that
Tell me his name
I'll damage his weak point
And throw him out & fill
you in that place
That's the problem
There are no weak points
We'll create, Sir
You tell me his name?
God
She wants to become a Nun
As a Nun?
Wearing black & black dress
What?
I don't want your friendship
& old A/c Machine
Sir, can't change the
devotion
You can change, Deva
Sir, you're an educated person
& you know everything
Who am I?
I am a local Barber, sir
I know only cutting, step cutting
& curling, sir
I used to play a little
with girls
But, shouldn't play
with God, Sir
Hey Go! Bullock cart
You made me to go & meet her
You provoked love in
my heart
Now, you created an interest in
her to become nun
Why?
Are you testing me?
Or are you punishing me?
I can't understand anything
that's why...
What should I do now?
Should I forget her?
Or should I go & try
her for once
Tell me
If you can't say, atleast
show some gestures
Oh God! It's you...
Like an Onida devil you're
distrubing me always
Sir, no need this, god will
curse us
I asked God itself
What did he say?
I prayed to god to give me
strength to forget her?
When I turned back
God placed priya next
to me
He has many requests, sir
God is in confusion
I can't forget priya
She's an angel, that's it
Isn't it
Go somewhere and enjoy
happily for a week
Then you can forget priya
I am not talking about that
this is love
Sir, you're of the type of setting
with family & child
Wipe it & give
Sir, is a very decent
person
Sir is very sweet like a
five star chocolate
Is it good? Lt'll be
good sir!
Sir, What I am trying
to tell is...
One colourful snap of yours
We'll advertise that snap
in all the papers
We'll advertise it in all
the media, sir
Wanting Brides
A beautiful intelligent
& rich
Why won't you get a girl?
I don't want any other girl
Then...
I want only this girl
You're pestering me, Sir
What's there in that
girl?
Deva, lf you meet her, you
won't speak like this
Have you seen the
lightening sparkling?
Look at her smile
Will I get shock, lf I
touch her?
Don't touch
You'll get shock if you
just see her
Deva, have you seen both suns
one after another
I've seen
Look at her eyes
Then, you'll understand what I'm
trying to explain?
Let the eyes be, sir
Girls are not like a star, which
disappears when sun rises
Throw the silver coins
& see
You'll hear the noise
of her laugh
Hey guru, we've heard this tune
somewhere, lsn't it?
Yes, very good line
Isn't it
This's my tune
Has someone robbed it?
Who's it?
Who's that singing my
tune?
How did you know this?
It was on the parcel paper
Parcel?
Sinners! I thought of becoming
a popular Mozart
But they used this paper
as wraper
Have you composed it
on your own?
Really, it's me
Hey, someone please
tell her
It's very beautiful
Thank you very mcuh
Recording company doesn't understand
as you understood
Remove the sorrow from the
face of the moon
And replace it with smile
lt'll look like my priya
Hey, Look there, priya is there
Sir, what lovely hair
she has got?
If she becomes Nun, they'll
cut it, lsn't it?
Yes! Go & do something
I won't leave her
Your name?
Very good name
You read the next composition
lt'll be very good
Who's he?
Who?
He's looking at me itself
Who's that?
He's staring at me
By looking at the eyes of the girls
he'll say what's on their mind
Then, what's on my mind?
Your eyes resembles
You're an angel
You're born with a silver spoon
You're like an apple in the refrigerator
You have your food in a golden Plate.
Benz AC car
Even then, what's the burden in your
heart which you can't express?
Loneliness is
happiness to you
And youth is
a torture
What sorrow do you've which you're
not expressing through eyes?
Hey! Why isn't there
any reaction?
How will she hide
her beauty?
How'll she unite her
dreams & wonders?
You'll get mad and shall
I give you the treatment?
I am not mad, I don't need
your treatment
There is no one mad even
in my ancestors
And there are no confusions
in my mind
I didn't have a thought
of serving my husband
But in social service, there
is no any harm in it
I am not a burden for
anyone in this world
There are no darkness
in my eyes
Loving a person Yesterday
Having a husband today
I don't wish to suffer
in the kitchen
First garlanding and then
handcuffing
I don't wish to get
married
Oh God! She doesn't want
to marry
Change the route
Oh, What lovely eyes?
Oh, What lovely golden
Lotus cheeks
Oh, what lips?
The colour of the
cherry fruit
Only nose is of
over size
It's okay, you do plastic
surgery for it
Hey, spring hair, come here
Do you've the pratice of looking at your
face in the mirror in the morning?
What'll be seen?
My beautiful face, Dear
No!
A monkey which had escaped
from the Zoo
The one who has created my
nose of a big size
Is the one who had created
little brains for you
Are you a human or monkey?
Guru, why do you keep the one in the
Bakery which should be in the Zoo?
Looking as if very
proud girl
Hey, can she speak irrespectfully
by seeing our Deva?
Pour some more
She'll reform, if we make her
starve for 4 days
I'll tell you one thing
meaningfully
You got nose cut by talking
about face cut-you
Gone! Even this plan has
been destroyed
I'll agree! Something is
there in her
You don't worry, sir
Deva will provoke love
in her heart
I'll make her to love
you sir
I'll swear sir
I am telling you
surely sir
What's the problem
doctor?
He's saved! But he's in
a serious condition
Shouldn't give him any
tension
House tension
Does he have any son?
I am his daughter
But, to look after the
business
Do you've any brothers?
I'll manage the business
She's well educated, she'll
manage it
But, they told that you're
going to go somewhere?
I'll manage business
Doctor, has done
excellently
He acted like film artiste
shivaji
She believed it, completely sir
Sir, you can act in Movies
Sorry, I made you to act
like this
I've acted in college
dramas
We're manufatcuring this
for 30 yrs, Baby
But no one is buying
this, baby
Why?
Because they're manufacturing
colourful ones in the market
Like this, small one
very modern
It seems public is liking
this only
You yourself tell me
baby
Is this looking beautiful
or ours?
What's the beauty in that?
Go... Go... Go
Oh! God why can't we do
another business?
We should ask that to
our boss
Shall I ask him?
"No"
Why can't we manufacture colourful
ones like this?
For that we've to start a
dyeing unit, baby
It may require huge amount
of money, baby
Shall I ask the Boss?
No need
Father is unwell &
he's at home
Don't disturb him
We can create new designs by
buying new machines
In older designs, we've produced in
lot & kept it in the godown, lsn't it
What to do with that
Baby?
Why did you manufacture
so much?
We should ask that to
our boss
No need... No need... No need
Draw the designs &
show me
Sir, tomorrow...
No, you'll simply nod
your head
Draw & show me now
I need that within 1 hr
Sir, Look here... at
this plan
No, you didn't disturb
me at all
No work, I am free now
If there's any doubt you can
ask me at any time
I'll come there
Don't promise simply
The condition in which my
office is now
I'll ring you up for every
half an hour
I'll come immediately
Sir, Then what happened?
Tell me sir?
Then what? That's all
Didn't you tell her?
Oh! God! Sir has missed
the chance
Hey okay!
What can I do?
Whenever I meet her, I am
becoming speechless
I think something will happen to
the persons who love
They'll call it as
Love sick
I became sick on the very
first day I met her
I'll tell you one thing
meaningfully
We'll get a kick if
we drink Beer
We'll get sick, if
we love
Deva, what did you do?
When you fell in love?
Love? I didn't even pass
that side
Sir, he's lying
He'll write a book about love
& he didn't fall in Love?
Sir, shall I ask you
one thing?
Can we become a heart doctor
only if we get heart attack?
Sir, don't listen to it
I'll tell you, Deva's
love story
I'll kill you, Dog
Superb girl, sir
Purse is fit & her blouse
is fit
Instead of doing hair cut
for her
He trapped her
Hey, what do you all think
of yourselves?
That's all, I can't run beyond
this
Sir, don't believe them, they've
come to spoil my name
Guru, you tell him
One day, she asked me to come for tea
without her father's knowledge
...Where?
To her house...
When he went to her house, Tea
as well as the Girl both were hot
My temperature also increased
- Then? -He hugged her
What happened?
- Father enters...
Girl introduced him saying he's
working in the 5 star Hotel
He asked,"What's your work"?
Do you know, what the Father did?
Whipped out a knife?
No, He took out the purse & gave
Rs.100 for Hair cut
From that day the boy says no
to love, Hey keep quiet...
What are you talking about me?
That fizzled out isn't it?
Talk about sir's love
Yes, we'll talk
Tomorrow you become
a brave man
Tomorrow blind Guru is
going to fall before a car...
You're...
She will see from there & will
be flattered
For manhood, use our
Tiger skin, underwear
For ever youthfulness
flower underwear
To impress wives
yellow underwear...
Sir, everything is ready, do you
see the white car?
Seems to be
a purshcart model
lt'll race even in Sholavaram
There, Guru is standing...
Car will start, he'll fall
infront of the car...
You'll run and save him
How will Priya know that
I've saved him?
Sir, already I've paid advance
everything is ready...
As soon he saves him...
You all must say
"Brave Man has saved, longlive"
When should we say this?
When you hear screeching loud brake
noise, its enough if you say it then
Aha! Brave man...
after hearing the brake sound
Car is ready, do what I said...
Don't bungle...
...Go...
Oh! Thief... Pickpocket...
- No... l'm Priya...
Don't go... Don't go...
Listen to me...
Everything has collapsed...
Longlive Braveman
What's that noise?
I've composed a nice tune from
Spanish folk will you listen?
Longlive Brave man
You're a jolly type, isn't it?
Yes... l'm a jolly type
Then, why are you singing sadly?
That's... my situation is
like that...
On the branch of Mango tree
at 'Mana Madurai'
What was the question put
by the Parrot?
Are my eyes beautiful?
Are my wings beautiful?
What can I sing if it
asks such question?
In the western street
on the bullock cart...
Hey! One maiden is going...
I asked her, what's the
saree you're wearing?
She said, it's a rainbow
As rain drops fall gently on the Earth
a distinct fragrance emanates
Sometimes that fragrance takes me
to the Rainbow on the Horizon
He gave us Air & Rain
for all of us to live
... He gave us a song for
everyone to sing
Like a child...
There'll no sorrow if we've
a heart like a child
Like a Bird...
If we have a body like it
There won't be any fear
He gave us Earth in ourhands
to live prosperously...
He gave us fruits to eat
and made human beings sweet
He gave us singing cuckoo &
Poured honey in our ears
Art is seen in
the lights
I'm visualizing a picture
in my heart
He gave us cluster of clouds
and Thunder as their Rhythm
My son created a sensation
in the Trade fair
He's very intelligent
- He's your son, isn't it?
He is not only white, even his
thinking is like white people
Now in Japan, a Trade Fair
is going to open-What?
Now, it's going to take place
- Let it take place
I told him to put up
2 or 3 stalls there...
Hereafter, Every foreigner will
wear only our underwears
Give me 2 scotch
- for me?
For you also don't over do
That too in my account
Doctor said, lndian Drinks are
not good for health
Don't we know without his telling us?
But foreign drinks are excellent
He's our guest, How can
you call him indecently?
If you wear black suits, Do you
think you become a 'Great Man'
I won't leave you, I'll go
upto higher level
Battery must be switched off
Ask him to switch it on
You should only tell him
Sir, switch on your machine
What?
Switch it on...
How do you know?
Sir only...
Greetings sir, I didn't see you...
I was talking to my Foreign friend
regarding business...
You're very trim, then
How do you get a Heart Attack?
All were saying in the town...
Our Cina Tana was saying that we've
to change the Club President immediately
I told him that after Amalraj's
death only we'll have Elections
I'm your efficient man, isn't it?
Sir, why are you drinking?
I came here to be in peace
Don't you've peace in
the house?
Sir, don't worry...
After Puppy's marriage, everything
will be alright
Now, Puppy & Thomas are very close
Repeat it once again...
You too don't hear properly?
Puppy & Thomas are very close
Puppy is looking after the factory
Thomas also looking after the factory
Two parties have connection...
...That's... Co-operative business
In Rs.10 Lottery ticket
A beggar becomes a richman...
The one who drank arrack
can drink Scotch
But... you should have culture
in the blood
It should come from generation
to generation
We've an account...
Excellent...
They've recorded our song which
we had sung in the Trade Fair
Very nice, isn't it?
Sir, You've recorded nicely...
Sir is an Agent of
Recording company
He has come to book us
Sir, Sit down...
Hey! Bring milk for Sir...
Yuck! Bring Cola for Sir...
I showed this video to my boss
He was impressed
Every tune was original...
That girls voice is nice...
That girl?
Which girl?
Our Priya...
It's obvious from
their dress
Sir, that girl is going
to become a Nun
If you want to get a chance
that girl should sing
If you're ready, contact me
on this number...
Deva, can I forward
the application?
I should...
Everything is God's wish...
Guru, your mother's dreams
are going to come true
Do you know who they are?
They're going to become
great singers
They've got a recording contract...
Don't say 'They', say 'Us'
Me...
Baby is going to sing?
From childhood itself
she's a great singer
Sagayam, keep quiet...
...I can't...
It seems madam can't sing...
I'll go...
Don't be in hurry
madam also
From her childhood, madam has
been very eager to sing
Now... She's a Nun...
God... serve...
Your service is very important
to we poor people also
If she accepts also
will she sing duet songs?
It's enough even if she sings
only devotional songs
What are you doing?
Please, you should only save us
There's a catch in the neck
Hey! Don't hurt me
Deva, What happened?
Some other sound is coming
Big house... ls there a witch here?
Nice! What's going on here?
Accept it... Accept...
Should I've to sing?
Yes... Yes...
Till you get another singer...
Hey! Useless fellows...
Don't you've any other time
for this uproar?
I had asked you to prepare Roti
and you're hitting this?
Uncle, I'm telling you an
important thing...
If we prepare breakfast we'll get money
If we hit this, song will come
Do you want money or song?
If I hit you, you can count
your bones...
Uncle, when they release their
song cassette, they'll become popular
Then, you'll be honoured for
their popularity
They'll paste our poster...
If you want, we'll give a place
for your photo
Don't act too smart with me...
I've seen many...
What British man had said?
Atleast today, give me leave
Give...
Only few days are more
for audition
We've to rehearse day & night
Today is Sunday?
In Church, on Sundays
they'll have Mass
I've missed it...
Now, it woul've been over
Sir, still how many days you're
going to put up Heart Attack drama?
Till Puppy changes her mind...
There is change in
Puppy madam's activities
She's putting lipstick
she's laughing loudly...
She's joking...
You shouldn't delay
in her marriage
Start the marriage matter...
I can recognise her change
But, will she accept for marriage?
If we find a good groom
she'll accept for marriage
Last time, the groom who came
was so thin...
Groom should've personality, isn't it?
I'll bring a Groom
of good personality...
Let's see whether
she accepts...
Priya will cook nicely...
He's Mr. David Vector Appasamy
From generations, they're boiling...
I mean... they're boiling sugarcane juice
& he's a Owner of the Sugar mill
I've put Korean Grass in
my garden... shall we go there?
What's it?
...Didn't listen to you?
...I thought, I didn't want...
He's having children...
...Okay... carry on...
I heard that you're
a peculiar man
I'm also like that...
It seems, you're looking
after the factory
Do you've any problem from Union Leaders?
I'll bump them off...
Not in Union
everyone is good
Do you've enemies apart from
your business?
No... let's talk... lf they didn't
listen, we'll bump them off
You should bump off someone
only then, they'll fear us
If I didn't accept for marriage
Will you bump off me too?
You're very peculiar
Will she accept?
If Priya marries someone else?
Sir, Why one you talking like this?
Sir, she's only for you
There's no doubt in it
Priya is a nice girl
But sometimes
To make a father happy
Girls will accept for marriage
as their father's wish for
If it happens like that
There's no meaning of my living
Sir, what's this?
Sir, cost of a Litre?
Take this... Fill the tank as much as
you can... fill the tank
Ensure it Zero & then fill it
Don't believe these persons They'll
steal a point & build another station
Sir, leave it... Don't get tensed...
Forget it...
Sir, I had taken so much
pain to setup that girl
In between, lf someone takes her...
will I leave him?
Directly, I'll kill him...
Hey! Think while you talk...
He's a big shot in Madras
Not only you, he'll kill your father
Grandfather and grandmother
...He'll kill...
There's no change, Go!
Those who come in Benz car
Don't have change means...
You've good time
Wait... l'll come... wait!
Go...
Sorry, Yesterday, I was
not able to come
Tomorrow at 10am I'll come
Take this...
Have it... Go... Go...
Sir, You're a peculiar person...
Morning, you're doing business
with foreigners
And in the night, You're doing
business with beggars
I can't understand you...
No... We've many small clothes
in the factory...
I'll stitch shirts from them
And I'll give it to them...
Then, Priya?
Where will you give?
At the backside of the station
Then tell Priya's father
- When?
At 10.00am
Your uncle would've drank
and slept somewhere
What? How did you get hurt?
Sir, I don't know, car driver
hit him and went away...
He didn't stop!
Nearby, ls there any hospital?
You should go there...
Before carrying him, dog will die...
I can't understand about them...
Madam, What's it?
Half of the time, they're
spending to earn money
Another half of the time
they're spending that money
Why do they lead a false life?
Life is to do service to others!!
Madam, There's no doubt about it...
I'll introduce you the future
Princes of your aim...
Take him... He had left the
house at the age of 8 Yrs itself...
Now, from corporation, they're
going to give a degree
...of 'Doctorate of Garbages'
He's working hard whole night
Why?
To smoke Cannabis
Madam, come here...
He is...
Madam, not he... Next to him...
Is it him?
Only 17 Yrs
Boys will buy cotton candy
And groundnut candy
He has bought Aids
He's distuributing it daily...
Madam, truely this boy
is poor...
His mother had leprosy
So, they have thrown him also out
What's this injustice?
The leader who is
sleeping there...
He drank & slept on the bridge...
He lost his legs
Madam, so soon
you get disgusted!
Hereafter, you're going to
stay with them, isn't it?
So, what I'm trying
to say is...
Marry a handsome guy...
Instead of coming in the
A.C. Car...
You're thinking of
doing services...
So, do you think, my services
are a waste?
Madam, there's no doubt in it...
You don't know about me...
So?
Till you say 'enough'-
Shall I sit here itself
And how you?
Madam, I am angry
No one cares for him...
Let it be any party
Their place is platform only
Madam, they're very poor
Mother Indira
What a brave Woman!
If I was in her period I would've
done different hairstyles for her...
If I put plait for you
lt'll be nice
Go...
Just try it once, if you don't
like, leave it
Madam, try once...
He'll be coming late
- Who?
Moon will appear late...
It's visible
infront of my eyes
What?
One big Church
There you're coming
like an Angel...
A handsome husband
is standing near you
You're always talking about marriage
you become a broker
If you talk further
I'll go
...Don't talk...
Oh Moon! Will you come out
from the Sky?
I need a pair to play
Before anyone sees on the Earth
I'll send you back early in the morning
This is neither a night
Nor a day...
This is the Golden time which
doesn't represent either of them
Don't tilt your head
Don't close your eyes...
Suddenly some buds
will blossom!
Oh! Maiden... Oh! Maiden!!
After everyone sleeps
on the Earth...
We can hear the flowers
talking to the grass
We'll be children on
the lap of the night
Moon is there to sing
lullaby for us!
Who has placed the Moon?
So far away
Who has created Air
which can't be trapped in our hands?
By thinking about these
I'm astonished about nature!!
Who has placed the Moon?
So far away
Oh! Maiden... Oh! Maiden...
Without the knowledge of the Breeze
We should blossom the flower!!
Even without the knowledge of flower
We should taste the Honey!
I should admire the world
Along with a girl like you!!
Hey! Thomas Sir!
Don't be in a hurry...
Everyone will get...
Sir, today, why did you come late?
On the way
The dog got hurt...
What are you doing here?
That's... This song... No
I've laid a bet with my friends
Full night here...
Cheeks have become Red...
What? Cheeks...
No...
I'm feeling cold and
I am shivering
Take it...
Thomas! What happened?
Nothing! While coming
A dog got hurt
It's dog's blood...
Helping others and giving charity...
It is like a eating sweets for him
Deva, do you know him?
I know him very well
But, He doesn't know me
I'll see him here frequently
He'll come sharply at 10.00
He'll buy cakes & clothes for
The boys whom we've seen
But, Sir is little late...
Is he your friend?
He's Deva
Good Musician
That's part time...
You'll cut for gents or ladies?
Both!
You've an AC car
isn't it?
If you drop madam
You know her home, isn't it?
It's getting late for madam!
Don't mistake me for leaving
You infront of the gate
I don't know whether uncle
will like to see us together
So what?
I like Thomas
You're helping me very much
If I didn't talk to you
How will it be?
Whether he likes or not
I won't give up your friendship
It was right to meet
her & speak with her...
But, we shouldn't have sung...
Deva, you've lost your control...
you've lost...
Why do I need it?
What's the relationship between
me & that girl?
I can't understand her talk
She suits only Thomas
Slowly, I should steer her towards
Thomas & I should move away from them
...I must move away
100's of girls are there for me to love
why do I need her?
That girl... she has something
in her eyes isn't it?
What are you blabbering?
Didn't you sleep?
You'll sleep off as soon as
you lie down
Did you come just now?
Has our plan worked out?
- Yes somewhat...
Somewhat means?
Didn't Thomas come?
He came... but little late...
So what if he came late?
Priya saw him giving alms, isn't it?
Then, she'll Love him... Has she
started loving him?
Yes, may be...
Thomas is a nice person...
Priya also is a good
natured girl
Hey! They're a good pair, isn't it?
Why are you getting irritated?
No... This moon... is dazzling
my eyes
Sometimes, it's good to be Blind
Come & see, who has come here...
You didn't expect me, isn't it?
I was going for Easter retreat
On the way, I came here
to see you...
I find there's a glow
on your face...
Home food & Father's care...
No, she's only taking care
of me
Now, look at the house, it has
acquired vibrancy
Her mother, used to keep like this...
I can feel the touch of
Priya everywhere
Truely, I find it very difficult
without you in the Church
Sister Agnes has sent her
regards to you
Now, Sister Agnes has changed
But... only slightly...
We always talk about you...
About your devotion
your concentration...
She's giving so many new ideas
She has got a good
business sense...
Near the factory... She's going
to build an orphanage for children
We know her aptitute for
service very well
She has the blessing of Jesus, we've
the building plan, where is it?
I'll bring it...
What's the confusion in
your mind?
No, Mother... I was
slightly busy...
That's why, I didn't write
a letter
I'm just the same...
After finishing this work, I'll
comeback to the convent
I'm not talking about that...
God knows everything
There's no need for me
to tell you...
Prayer is the only solution
for all problems
Let God show you the
Right Path
Look, last night we went
little overboard
Let us consider everything
as a dream
Truely, All ladies are like
my sisters
Thank God! She's in Good mood
I should tell her everything...
I shouldn't see her eyes
Hey! Bravely tell her...
Look... for me, all the ladies...
Don't see her eyes...
It's hot, sour... Why are you sad?
...Tell me
If you tell me...
What Research? I
can't uanderstand...
There's no one to
discipline you
Then, what?
What defect has God
given you?
You've tons of money & you've
a house like a Palace
If you don't know to utlise them
you're a waste
Madam... Madam... Look...
Don't call me 'Madam'
Call me 'Puppy'
Puppy? It sounds like calling
a... pup
Oh God! How beautiful she is?
Deva, Don't look at me like this...
I'm feeling a bit
Then, you'll tell eyes are not good
& ears are not good...
Oh! God! I had blabbered
something
Don't take it seriously
If you ask me personally
How beautiful you are...
I meet so many in my parlour
I can Judge just like that
But... you...
This eyes... this hair...
or this ears...
I don't know how to
describe...
You are like...
...How?
You're a respectable lady...
The result of your research
is 'I am an Angel'
If I want to talk to you I
should keep a Dictionary with me...
...I don't know why?
If I'm with you, my mind
is at peace
What eyes she has?
If I'm with you for my entire life
- Hey Boy, you've bungled everything
I can be happy forever...
What's my beauty?
What's my job?
Why did you develop
love on me?
I was flowing like stream when did
the electricity got produced in it?
Oh! Maiden... Oh! Maiden, My day & night
I am troubled by your memories
No bee sleeps on the
flowers on rail track
There's no place in Philosophy to say
whether it's right or wrong...
Oh! Moon! Don't get frayed
like me...
Are you also suffering from
'Love Disease'?
I had kept my heart
like a Garden
Who's that who striked as a
cyclone and disrupted it?
What's the use of knowing
world news?
You don't know what's happening
in the house?
Again, Puppy Madam's mind
has got confused
You should've arranged her marriage
when she was in good mood
Whichever groom we're proposing
she's not liking him
Why should we select the Groom
Puppy herself has selected... one
What's lacking in Thomas?
Puppy is also in love
with that boy
Our girl should live happily
That's what we must wish isn't it?
Don't spoil your daughter's life
because of false prestige
Go to that Thomas
- Don't utter his name again
...l'll not accept...
Who has come man?
At this odd hour...
sir... Greetings... you?
Hey! Call madam... Look
who has come...
Madam has gone to the club
There's no other work for her...
Sir, if ladies get money, they'll never stay
at home, they'll go to club
Go & bring coffee for sir-Okay
Don't add sugar, he has
Diabetes
...Greetings sir... First time
you've come to my house...,
Sir, did you see this?
'President's Award'
This is me at that time
I was wearing silk shirt...
This is Mr. Sanjeev Reddy, President
Sir, I got 'President Award'
please sit down
How are the furnitures?
I went and personally flew it
from Delhi
...Nothing, Thangadurai... That is...
Your son is looking after
your business
My daughter...
She's looking after my Business...
So, what I am thinking is...
Thangadurai, you want Thomas
to get married... isn't it?
I want Puppy to get
married...
We both can become
Kinsmen isn't it?
Sir, How is it possible?
You're heriditorily rich and we're
heriditorily Poor... it's impossible sir
Moreover sir...
Sir, about that Blood lines
you had mentioned about to me
It's very difficult to change
my blood line with your blood line
You won't get... where will you
get blood for such a big body?
Sir, you should bring
tank loads of blood
Now, don't talk about the past...
Thangadurai, you know... that
Puppy wished to become a Nun...
But, now puppy... loves Thomas...
She doesn't know how totell me
I am also unable to ask her...
Now everythng depends
on your son...
He should get her acceptance
Next month itself marriage...
Hey! Tell Engineer...
We'll ask him to build
a bridge connecting our factories
It's long since I ordered for Coffee
Hey! Where are you man?
...But... Sir, if Priya becomes your wife
will she sing with us?
...For the voice of Priya...
She should never stop singing
What's wrong in her
singing with you?
You all are like
brothers to her!
Deva, the plans given by you
were all successes
Now only one last plan
For which, Priya must say okay to it!
Tell me the plan!
Sir, tell her directly
Yes, tell her sir
I am asking you for a plan
Just because, I can't talk to her directly
Sir, Kiss her!
Hey! Yuck! Come on tell him
- He's blabbering
No Sir! Lt'll work out!
That's what the expert
has said, isn't it?
Take her out
somewhere alone
Where? Where should
I take her?
Sir, take her to some
Hill place
They say they get into mood
at such places
They say there's a Tall Tower
in Paris also, What's that?
It seems you'll find a
Lot of couples kissing...
Then, are you asking him
to go to Paris!
I just repeated lines
Some one had told me
Then, what shall we do?
Push her into cold water!
She'll wet her clothes
Body will become heated
...She'll hug you hotly!
You tell me!
Do you like that Sir
...lt'll happen!
Didn't I tell you?
Sir, there's water fall
in Talacona
Excellent place
Deserted place!
Where are your friends?
Who?
Be careful! Be careful!
They'll come! On the way
...in the car...
Golden Lotus Maiden
come near me!
My heart is jumping in joy
come to me, Oh! Beauty!
A flood has struck and a small
crack has developed in my heart
All this happened
Because of you!
Standing coloured pink
with bewitching beauty, Honey!
I've come overwhelmed
by a desire!
With fear in eyes you're sucking
life out of me, Oh my doe like beauty!
I've lost myself in the forest of
thick black hair
A flash light is burning
inside my heart!
How am I going to
safeguard myself?
Shall I touch you
to relieve me?
It's rainy season for the
Beetles to visit the flowers
It's time, croaking frogs
to find a partner!
It's time, separated parrot
searches for a partner!
It's a time which unites
the separated lovers
Oh! Shy maiden! My desire
will not be fulfilled!
If I follow the protocol
I'll not be able to fulfill my wish
Closeness is the langauge
of Love
Thomas, what are you doing?
Priya, don't you like me?
You like me isn't it?
...You've misunderstood my
friendship with you
Don't say like that Priya!
I'll wait for you
any number of years
Not just today or now itself!
Some day your heart will change
I'll always keep you happy
Be careful!
Don't touch me! Don't touch me
Go away! Go away!
Look, You're hating me
you're avoiding me!
...Priya, I am not
a bad person
...You don't know how much
I love you!
What happened to you?
Why are you talking like this?
Go away, before they
come here!
No one will come here
They know that we are here!
I should've thought about it
It had happened, because of them only
Because of whom?
All because of Deva!
He's the one who gave me
ideas from the beginning
Till that Trade Fair!
...Making you to see me giving
Clothes to Orphan children
...Today, he only told me to...
Priya don't avoid me...
Don't hate me... Don't hate me
Hey! Come... come here
Where's Priya?
Deva, where's Priya?
How do I know?
What do you mean by it
You could've brought her, isn't it?
Is, she is a baby
to pick her up!
You could've picked
up her, isn't it?
Why are you asking me?
Ask everyone?
Don't get tensed up!
Sir, they're ready
for the Audition
Didn't we release a new CD in
Singapore? -The sale is excellent
Is it so Sir!
Very nice Sir!
Are they still tuning?
...Orelse, is this their Music?
Now in the name of Music
They're creating different new sounds
- Don't we know about it?
...That lady singer...
has not yet come!
...She'll come...
She'll come right now!
Just 5 minutes Sir
- I can't wait for these jokers!
She'll come now...
What were you doing?
Isn't it your duty to check it?
...Can't you plan a
simple programme?
Hey! You don't have
to come up in life!
Why are you spoiling
my life?
...Go and roam on the streets side!
Gone! These type of rich girls
are like this only!
They'll smile when required & throw
us once they find we're not required
Cheaters!
Hey! Why are you talking filthy?
Since, When you've started
finding our talk filthy?
Have you become reformed after
roaming around with her?
Don't be in a haste!
Hey! Why are you changing yourself
On seeing a girl? Yuck! Come!
Don't go Priya! Don't go...
Why are you going away
from me?
Will you go away like this
If your Mother had been alive?
What do you want? I'll build a
Church in this place
Do you want me to convert
into a Orphanage?
I'll do anything! What am I
Going to do without you?
Jesus, Why are you testing
me like this?
Mother... Mother...
Don't cry my child? Don't cry...
Thank you Sagayam!
...Thanks for everything!
Look after father!
Are you going? Are you going
off to do Social work?
You could've come and sang
only once for us!
God is only important, that God only
has gifted this voice, isn't it?
With that Voice you're...
to somebody...
Poor soul Guru!
Not for us, You could've
atleast sung for Guru, isn't it?
How much belief he
had on you?
Then, I am the deceiver!
I am a bad girl! I had
deceived everyone isn't it?
A doll which you got
to play with!
If you give key, I must
clap hands... dance!
Don't talk like that madam?
Don't call me as madam?
Madam, I did all this for
your well being only!
Only Thomas is the best
match for you
Who are you to decide about
My good and bad?
...Or who's that Thomas?
None of you can't understand
A Woman's heart!
I thought you
know everything!
Do you know what
you had achieved?
You made me to laugh
You made me to feel shy
...You made me to realise
my Womanhood!
...And made me to dream
for the first time!
I give my heart to you!
...But, Deva, you came off leaving
behind everything, isn't it?
A Guitar to a friend! A recording
chance for another friend
But, Did you ever think
about yourself?
...About myself?
I'll always treat all my
customers as Queens!
I'll think they're the most
important in this world!
...l'll forget about myself
...Everything is a dream madam!
...They'll wake up me from dream and
pay Rs.50 as tips and go away
Even, if I see them again
I shouldn't recognise them!
I shouldn't smile to them!
I've learnt to live without
falling in Love!
...They've taught me, madam!
Then, am I also one
of your customers?
I had only misunderstood it!
You not only changed my hairstyle
...but my life style itself
You've broken my heart!
Deva, it's paining!
It's paining!
Your work is over, isn't it
Why are you still here?
Take it... take this...
your Rs.50 tip!
Take it... Go away!
It seems he has
severe head injuries
Back bone, hands &
legs have fractures
Doctor says his survival
chances are thin!
Even if he survives, it seems He'll
not be able to move like earlier
Madman!
Why should he hang outside
a running train?
Is he a Hero?
What can he do?
He loved Priya
...Why sssh?
Thomas is here only!
Sir, I had a small
doubt earlier itself!
I should've told you
But, in my desire of becoming
a famous musician!
...Me...
Die man... die man...
You know how much
I Love her, isn't it?
Couldn't you find another girl?
What do you know
about Love?
Can you keep her happy?
...Can you
you can't!
What's your education?
What will you talk
with her? About hair?
One drop of tear...
Even if one drop of tear comes
out of her, I won't leave you
What do you've, that, which
I don't have?
How could it?
You could've told me about this
earlier itself, isn't it?
I would'nt have got deceived for
so many days?
How will you tell it?
It's all my fate?
This is uniform for you to
get trained as a Nun!
Apart from Jesus and prayer
there shouldn't be anything in your mind!
If you've any doubts
consult me!
Let Jesus show you
the right path!
Jesus! Somehow please
save Deva
Please give back
Deva's life!
...ln return for his life
I'll sacrifice my life!
...l'll sacrifice my life!
These are three things that a
Nun should follow in her life
She must have self-control!
. She shouldn't allow the thoughts to be shattered
Deva! Are you okay?
A letter has come from Priya
She has enquired about you!
Tomorrow only Priya is going
to become a Nun isn't it?
Shall we go?
I am not interested Sir!
Lt'll be grand
like a marriage
Those who are going to become
a Nun will take an Oath with the Bishop!
Once they give an Oath...
- they can't take it back!
Before that we can go...
Meet her, can talk... if we wish
No Sir... No Sir!
You too said something
isn't it?
...When she becomes a Nun...
You had joked that
You'll give her a haircut
...That's... For joke... because
She sang with us for few days...
Oh! For joke?
What she had sung?
Guru's tune was very nice
That's why, ordinary voice also sounded great...
Okay, Now, why should we
talk about her?
She is a fraud isn't it?
I don't know, Sir!
You know very well about
a Woman's heart, isn't it?
Couldn't you find out her heart?
Whether you know or not
But, I know it
She's a big fraud
Everything was a drama
Deceive man and make them mad
Look even in that they
have a happiness
Now she's going to
deceive God...
Don't talk like this about her
She's not like that...
You didn't get her...
I too didn't get her...
You don't know one thing...
I still love her... love her...
Deva, I know...
I know...
Till now, I was waiting
to hear this from you
Today 12 sisters are going to
dedicate their lives to the Lord & Church
Now, those sisters...
Will promise to keep up Chastity
Obedience & Simplicity
On behalf of Mother superior
Therasa Jebamony of the Church-
I, Sister Agnes, promise you to keep up
Chastity, Obedience & Simplicity
I accept your promise in
the name of the Church
Sisters who've prepared
themselves to become Nuns-
They are accepted as
Spinsters
Thomas stop...
It should not happen
Thomas, stop...
You shouldn't go inside
- it shouldn't happen
I can understand your feelings
But, we can't get all
that we desire
Oh God! She didn't love me...
This is not for me...
For someone else...
Thomas, no... it should happen
only like this...
This is God's wish...
This is untrue, you've surmised
wrongly
You're trying to deceive God
Do you think God doesn't
know your feelings?
I always wished to be
a Nun
...lt was at that time...
Just because God saved
Deva from Death
You're ready to sacrifice
your life...
This matter is between
God & me
He has fulfilled my Prayer
Now, shouldn't I fulfill
My promise to him
You shouldn't do business
with Jesus...
You should Pray only for
his mercy
We should accept everything
given by him
That is the true devotion...
Priya tell me... Do you love
anyone?
Priya, tell me... tell...
...Tell me...
God only created fire, but he
never said us to touch it
We should realise that...
God only created Man & woman and
the same God only created 'Love' also
Why should he create me?
Why did he made us to
meet each other?
Why should I?
Why did I make Deva to
interfere in this?
Why should you love Deva?
And why I should be here?
This is not my or your question
Priya tell me... tell me the Truth
...Tell me...
Priya, tell...
...Tell...
- Yes... yes...
Priya you marry! Go and marry
Till now, I hesistated so much
to talk to her! Now, how could I?
From where did I get
that power?
After few years...
Many girls, more Beautiful, Rich
and Intelligent than Priya
...Lost their nights with the
thoughts of Thomas
...Their dreams got shattered
...But...
...The search for Love of
Thomas didn't stop
Atlast, he found out where
his love was
...He dedicated himself into
the service of God
The intelligence of Rev. Father
Thomas Thangadurai
...His knowledge of Bible
Conducting the Church...
...He has every quality
to become a Bishop
...So the talk goes around
the Church
He had only Baptised
Deva & Priya's child
Her name is Nisha
Say bye to uncle
James Thangadurai's desire of building
a bridge became a day dream
The money he saved by Pennywise
is now shelling it out in Pounds
Mr. Amalraj even now calls
friends to home
...He serves tea and boasts
about Grandfather's car
The young hearts were drooling
hearing this voice
The critics are saying that
after P. Susheela, its Priya Deva
If she hadn't came into
Music field
If would've been a big loss to
Music world, so says Subbudu
Guru has become a
Music Director in Cinema
...He has 4 films on hand
There are 4 cases also in Court
for copying A.R. Rehman's tunes
Mechanic Raja is now owner
of a Petrol Station
He has all the qualities
of a Neo Rich
Even in hot climate
he'll wear a coat
...He takes the Cell phone even
to the bathroom
If you dance little and
crack a few jokes...
That's enough... You can become
an anchor man on Satelite Channel
...ln Top 10,Mani's
Programme is No:1
Deva not only understands a
woman's heart
...He has understood white people's
hearts also
Father-in-law's dull business
after the entry of Deva
...Has become a Multi Million
business
But, he hasn't forgot
the old profession