~ Tulou... ~
Pardon us...
~ Oh Tagaloa ~
~ Sei e va'ai mai ~
Look down...
~ I le tātou lalolagi ~
Upon our world
~ Sei e va'ai mai ~
Look down...
~ I le tātou lalolagi ~
Upon our world
~ Sei e mālamalama ~
The light
~ Ko au e tu atu ~
I stand before you
~ E lelei ma le mānaia ~
It is good and beautiful
~ Sei e va'ai mai ~
Look down...
~ E taunuku te malaga ~
The journey has begun
~ Mānaia o le tātou ōlaga. ~
At how beautiful our lives are.
This Subtitle was Transcripted by
~ Penny Hamada ~
Lyrics was Translated from
www.lyricstranslate.com
In the beginning,
there was only ocean
Untill the Mother Island image...
...Te Fiti.
Her heart have a greatest
power ever known...
...each could create life itself.
And Te Fiti share it with the world.
But in time,
some began to seek Te Fiti's heart
They believe that they could possesed
the great power of creation would prevails
And one day...
The most tearing of them all.
A boy across the ocean to take it.
He was a demigod
of the wind and sea.
He was a warrior.
A trickster!
A shape shifter who could change
form with the power of his magical fish hook.
And his name...
...was Maui
But without her heart,
Te Fiti began to crumble.
Giving birth to a
terrible darkness.
Maui trying to escape,
but was confronted by another...
...who soak the heart.
Te Kā!
A demon of earth and fire.
Maui distract from the sky.
Never to be seen again.
And his magical fish hook
and the heart of Te Fiti...
...were lost to the sea.
Were even know,
a thousand years later...
Te Kā and the demons of deeds...
...Still hunt for the heart.
Hiding in the darkness
that will continue to spread...
...Chasing away our fish...
...Drawning the life
from island of the island...
...Untill every one of us...
...is devoured by the bloodlusted joys
of inescapeable death!
But one day,
the heart will be found...
...By someone who would
journey beyond the reef...
...find Maui, deliver him
across the great ocean...
...to restore Te Fiti's heart
and save us all.
Woo! Ho! Ho! Thank you, Mother.
That's enough.
- Papa!
- No one goes outside the reef.
We're safe here.
There's no darkness.
There's no monsters.
- Monsters! Monsters!
- There's no monsters! No monsters!
- Please, monsters. Don't eat us!
- Ah, hey! Ah!
No there is nothin' beyond our reef
but the storm and rusty...
I'm gettin' throw up!
As long as we stay on our
very safe island, we'll be fine.
The legends are true.
Someone will have to go!
Mother, more two new years paradise
Who would want to go anywhere else?
Shoo! Shooo!
~ Ou mata e matagi ~
I would wind
~ Ou loto mamaina toa ~
I will clean the hero
~ Manatu atu ~
Consideration
~ Taku pelepele ~
Taku the dearest
~ Pa mai to mafanafanaga ~
Explosion took comfort
~ Saolotoga tenei ~
Freedom of tenei
~ Manatunatu ~
Consider
~ Ki tamafine ~
Key of tamafine
~ Maua ai te lumanai ~
Have you come
~ Ki tamafine ~
Key of tamafine
Moana!
~ Ou mata e matagi ~
I would wind
There you are, Moana.
What are you doing? You scared me.
- Moana wants to go back!
- I know. I know...
...But you don't go out there.
It's dangerous.
Moana, come on.
Just go back to the village.
You're the next great chief
for our people.
And you'll do wonderest things!
My little minno!
Oh yes. But first, you must learn
where you meant to be.
Moana
Make way
Moana it's time you knew
The village of Motunui is...
...All you need.
The dances are practicing
They dance to an ancient soul
Who needs a new song?
This old one's all we need
This tradition is our mission
And Moana there's so much to do
Don't trip on the taro root
That's all you need
We share everything we make
We make!
We joke and we weave our baskets
Aha!
The fisherman come back
from the sea
I wanna see
Don't walk away
Moana stay on the ground now
Our people will need
a chief and there you are
There comes a day
When you're gonna look around
And realize happiness is
Where you are!
Consider the coconut
The what?
Consider its tree
We use each part of the coconut
That's all we need
We make our nets from the fibers
The water is sweet inside
We use the leaves to build fires
We cook up the meat inside
Consider the coconuts
The trunks and the leaves
The island gives us what we need
And no one leaves
That's right, we stay
We're safe and we're well provided
And when we look to the future
There you are
You'll be okay
In time you'll learn just as I did
You must find happiness right
Where you are?
I like to dance with the water
The undertow and the waves
The water is mischievous
Ha! I like how it misbehaves
The village may think I'm crazy
Or say that I drift too far
But once you know what you like, well
There you are
You are your father's daughter
Stubbornness and pride
Mind what he says but remember
You may hear a voice inside
And if the voice starts to whisper
To follow the farthest star
Moana, that voice inside is
Who you are
Dad!
I was only looking on the boat...
...I wasn't get on 'em.
Come on! There's something
i need to show you.
I've wanted to bring you here
for the moment to you open your eyes.
This is a secret place.
A place of chiefs.
There will come a time...
...When you will stand on this
picken' place...
...A stone on this mountain...
...Like i did.
Like my father did.
And his father and every chiefs
that is ever been.
And you'll meet the day
when you at your stone.
You will raise this whole island
higher!
You are the future of our people, Moana.
It's time to be
who they need you to be.
We make our nets from the fibers
The water is sweet inside
We use the leaves to build fires
We cook up the meat inside
The village believes in us
That's right!
The village believes
The island gives us what we need
And no one leaves
So here I'll stay
My home, my people beside me
And when I think of tomorrow
There we are
I'll lead the way
I'll have my people to guide me
We'll build our future together
Where we are
'Cause every path leads you back to
Where you are
You can find happiness right
Where you are!
Every storm, this roof leaves
no mather how many fronts i add.
Fixed!
Not the fronts...
...Wind shift to the boost.
That's good work!
Ate me!
No, i wasn't.
What? They're going in
so i gotta... bye!
- You're doing great.
- Is it done yet? Aw! Aw!
- So close!
- Aw! My aw! Aw!
I've curious about that
chicken eating the rocks.
He needs selectives intelligence
required. Pretty much everything?
Should we maybe just...
cook him?
Uhh... sometimes our shames like
beneath the service.
Far beneath...
in some cases...
But i'm sure there's more than
hey hey and miss the act.
It's the harvest, this morning
i was husking the coconuts and...
Well... we should clear the
desease trees.
And we will start a new grow...
...There!
Thanks, Moana.
She's doing great!
- This suits you.
- Chief!
There's something you need to see.
Our traps in the east laggon
They boobing up recentless fish.
Then we'll...
roated the fishing grounds.
Uhh... we have...
There's no fish.
Then we'll fish the far side of the alley.
- We tried.
- The side?
We've tried the whole lagoon.
They're just...
gone.
I would talk to the consult
I'm sure we can...
Why didn't we fish beyond the reef?
- No one goes beyond the reef.
- I know! But...
- If there are no fish in the lagoon...
- Moana!
- ...And there's a whole ocean
- We have one rule!
An old rule when there were fish!
A rule that keep us safe.
Instead of dangering our people...
So you can run right back
through the water.
Everytime i think you're pass this.
No one goes beyond the reef!
Well, it's like what you said
in front of your dad.
Standing on the boat.
I didn't say, "Go beyond the reef!"
Because i want to beyond the ocean.
But you still to.
- He is hard on you beacuse...
- Beacuse he doesn't get me.
Beacuse he was you.
Drown to the ocean.
Dawn by the sure.
He crossed the reef.
And founded unforgiving sea.
Waste like mountains.
His best friend beg to be on that boat.
Your dad couldn't save him.
He is hoping he can save you.
Sometimes who we wish we were
What we wish we could do.
It's just not meant to be.
Okay, Pua.
I can do this.
There's more fish beyond the reef.
There's more beyond the reef.
Not so bad.
Pua!
Whatever just happened...
...Blame it on the beg.
Grandma!
Are you gonna tell dad?
I miss mom.
I don't have to tell her anything.
He was right...
...About going out there.
It's time to put my stone
on the mountain.
Okay!
Well, then head on back!
Put that stone up there.
Why don't you try talk to me out of it?
You said that's what you wanted.
It is.
When i die...
...I'm going to come back
one of these.
Or i choose the wrong tattoo.
Why are you acting weird?
I'm the village crazy lady.
That's my job.
If there's something you want to tell me.
Just tell me.
Is there something
you want to tell me?
Is there something you want to hear?
You've been told all our people
stories...
...But one!
What is this place?
Do you really think our ancestors
stayed within the reef?
What's in there?
Diansa.
To the question you keep asking yourself.
Who are you meant to be?
Go inside,...
...Band the drum,...
...And find out!
This sub is transcripted by
P E N N Y H A M A D A
Band the drum.
We read the wind and the sky
When the sun is high
We sail the length of the seas
On the ocean breeze
At night we name every star
We know where we are
Aue, aue
We set a course to find
A brand new island everywere we roam
Aue, aue
We keep our island in our mind
And when it's time to find home
We know the way
We read the wind and the sky
When the sun is high
We sail the length of the seas
On the ocean breeze
At night we name every star
We know where we are
We know who we are, who we are
Aue, aue
We set a course to find
A brand new island everywere we roam
Aue, aue
We keep our island in our mind
And when it's time to find home
We know the way
Aue, aue
We are explorers reading every sign
We tell the stories of our elders
In a never-ending chain
Aue, aue
We keep our island in our mind
And when it's time to find home
We know the way
We were voyagers.
We were voyagers!
Why'd we stop?
Maui...
...When he stole from the mother island.
Darkness felt.
Te Ka awoke.
Monsters looked and both
stop coming back.
To protect our people,
the ancient chief forbid voyaging...
...And now we have
forgotten who we are.
And the darkness has continued to spread.
Chasing away our fish,
Draining the life from island after island.
Our island.
But one day,
Someone would journey beyond our reef.
Find Maui,
Deliver him across the great ocean,...
...To restore
The Heart of Te Fiti.
I was tell that day,
the ocean choose you.
I thought it was a dream.
Nope!
Our ancestors believes
Maui lies there.
At the bottom of his hook.
Follow it, and you will find him.
But why did it choose me?
I don't even know
how to make it pass the reef.
But i know who does!
- The crabs are turning black!
- What about the fish?
- This is happening all over the island.
- Please, please, settle down.
- What do you going to do?
- We would take new field
- We will find a way to...
- We can stop the darkness!
Save our island!
These are covered the boats.
Huge canoes!
We can take them,
find Maui.
Make him restore the heart.
We were voyagers.
We can voyage again!
You told me to help our people.
This is how we help our people.
Dad? What are you doing?
I should've burn those boats
a long time ago!
No! Don't!
We have to find Maui!
- We have to restore the heart.
- There is no heart!
This?
This is just a rock!
No!
Chief!
It's your mother!
Mother!
- What can be done?
- I don't know. I kinda something...
Go.
Grandma?
Not now. I can't.
You must.
The ocean choose you.
- Follow the fish hook...
- Grandma?
And when you find Maui...
...You grab him by the hear.
You say...
"I'm Moana of Mautunui...
...You will board my boat,
sail across the sea...
...And restore
The Heart of Te Fiti."
I... I can't leave you.
There is no way you could go
that i want be with you.
Go!
There's the light where the sky
meets the sea
And it calls me
But no one knows
how far it goes
All the time wondering where need to be
is behind me
-
Every turn I take
Every trail I track
Is a choice I make
No I can't turn back
From the great unknown
Where I go alone, Where I long to be
See her light at the night and the sea
She calls me
Yes I know!
That I can go!
There's a moon and the sky
And the wind is behind me
Soon I'll know
How far I'll go!
"I am Moana of Matunui...
...You will board my boat.
Sail across the sea...
...And restore
The Heart of Te Fiti."
"I am Moana...
...of Matu...
...Nui...
HeiHei?
:'V
:'v
It's okay... You're alright.
Yeah, see?
There we go, nice water.
The ocean is a friend of mine.
HeiHei?
HeiHei!
Stay!
Okay, next stop,
Maui.
"I am Moana of Matunui...
...You will board my boat.
Sail across the sea...
...And restore
The Heart of Te Fiti."
"I am Moana of Matu...
Wonder boat!
Oh no.
No! No! No! No! No!
No! Argh!
Uhh... Ocean?
Can I get a little help?
No!
Please! Come on!
Uhh!
Help me!
Please!
Umm...
What?!
I said help me!
And wrecking my boat?
Not help me!
Fish pee in you!
All day...
So...
What?
Maui?
Maui!
"Maui, demigod of wind and sea...
...I am Moana of Matunui...
...You will board my boat..
No!
You will board my boat!
Yeah!
Hi! I'm Moana of Matunui...
You will board my...
Boat!
A boat!
The god have given me a...
AAARRRGGGHHH!
Maui...
Shapeshifter
Demigod of the wind and sea...
- I am Moana of Matu...
- Hero of man.
- What?
- It's actualy Maui Shapeshifter...
...Demigod of the wind and sea.
Hero of man
Hero of man. Go!
- I am Moa...
- Sorry... Sorry...
...And women.
Man and women.
Both all. Not only a guy or girl or thing.
You know, Maui is a hero to all.
You do it great.
What? No!
I'm here to...
Of course! Yes!
Maui always has time for his fans.
When you use a bird to ride with...
...It's called tweeting.
I know not everyday
You gotta chance to meet a mature hero.
You are not my hero!
And i'm not here so you can
sign my orb!
I'm here 'coz you stole
the heart of Te Fiti.
And you will board my boat...
...Sail across the sea
and put it back!
It almost sounds like
you don't like me...
...Which is impossible because
i stuck here...
For thousand years try to
get a hard as a gift for immortal.
So you can have the power
to create life itself.
Yeah, so what i believe
you were tryin' to say...
...Is thank you.
- Thank you?
- You welcome!
What? No! I didn't!
I wasn't!
- Why would i ever say... I mean...
- Okay... Okay...
I see what's happening yeaa
You're face to face with greatness
and it's strange
You don't even know how you feel
It's adorable!
Well, it's nice to see
that humans never change
Open your eyes, let's begin
Yes, it's really me, it's Maui
Breathe it in!
I know it's a lot: the hair, the bod!
When you're staring at a demi-god
What can I say except you're welcome
For the tides, the sun, the sky
Hey, it's okay, it's okay
You're welcome
I'm just an ordinary demi-guy
Hey!
What has two thumbs
that pulled up the sky
When you were waddling yay high
This guy!
When the nights got cold
Who stole you fire from down below
You're lookin' at him, yo
Oh, also I lassoed the sun
You're welcome!
To stretch the days and bring you fun
Also I harnessed the breeze
You welcome!
To fill your sails and shake your trees
So what can I say except
You're welcome
For the islands I pulled from the sea
There's no need to pray, it's okay
You're welcome!
Ha, I guess it's just my way of being me
Well, come to think of it
Kid, honestly I can go on and on
I can explain every natural phenomenon
The tide, the grass, the ground, oh
That was Maui just messing around
I killed an eel
I buried its guts
Sprouted a tree, now you got coconuts
What's the lesson
What is the take-away
Don't mess with Maui
when he's on the break-away
And the tapestry here on my skin
Is a map of the victories I win
Look where I've been
I make everything happen
Look at that mini-Maui just tippity-tappin'
Well, anyway let me say
You're welcome
For the wonderful world you know
Hey, it's okay, it's okay
You're welcome!
Well, come to think of it, I gotta go
Hey, it's your day to say
You're welcome
'Cause I'm gonna need that boat
I'm sailing away, away
You're welcome!
'Cause Maui can do anything but float
And thank you!
Hey! Let me out!
You lying! Slummy! Son of a...
You're welcome.
Ha! Ha!
No!
I'm not going to Te Fiti
with some kid.
I'm gonna get my hook.
You had yours and i'm not Maui
without mine.
Talk to the back.
Boat snack!
You're radience
Oh no! Don't look at me like that!
It's a beautifull cave
She's gonna love it.
Now i'm going to love you...
...In my belly.
Now let's fetch you up, dumb stick.
I could watch that all day.
Okay, enjoy the island!
Maui out!
No! Stop! Hey!
You will put back the heart!
Did not see that coming.
I am Moana of Matunui
This is my canoe
And you will journey to the...
Alright, get over it.
We gotta move.
And she's back.
I am Moana of Matunu...
- It was Moana, right?
- Yes...
...And you will restore the heart.
Alright, i'm out.
Argh! Come on!
What is your problem?
Are...
...You afraid of it?
No!
I'm not afraid.
Stay out of it,
or you'll sleeping in my armpit
You stop it, that is not a heart...
It is a curse, last time i took it...
...I got blasted out of a sky
and i lost my hook...
Get it away from me!
- Get... this away?
- Hey! I'm a demigod, okay? Stop that!
I will smite you!
You wanna get smote?
Smoten?
Listen, that thing doesn't give
you power to create life.
It's a homing become of death.
If you don't put it away back,
things will gonna come for it.
Come for this? The heart?
You mean this heart right here?
COME AND GET IT!
You are gonna get us killed!
No, i'm gonna get us to Te Fiti.
So you can put it back. Thank you.
"You're welcome!"
Kakamora!
Kaka... what?
Murdering little pirates!
Wonder what they're here for.
They're kind of cute.
T H I S S U B T R A N S C R I P T E D BY
^~ P e n n y H a m a d a ~^
Ocean? Do something!
Help us!
The ocean doesn't help you.
You help yourself.
You can't sail?
I... uh...
I am self-thought.
Whoa!
Can you shapeshift of something?
You see my hook?
No magic hook, no magic powers.
Their boat is starting into part boats!
Yup! I just did that.
No! No! No!
HeiHei!
Maui!
They took the heart!
- That's the chicken.
- The heart is in it! UURRGGHH!
We have to get 'em back!
Maui!
There! Right there!
You turning?
What are you doing?
Uhh... escaping?
- The heart!
- Forget it! You'll never get her back!
Besides, we've got a better one.
Hey! What did i gonna sail with?
They're just gonna kill ya!
Coconuts.
Huh! Got it!
We did it!
Congratulations on peeing that curly.
You suprised me!
But i'm still not taking that thing back.
You wanna get to Te Fiti?
You gonna go through whole ocean
Not to mention Te Ka!
The Lava Monster.
Ever defeat The Lava Monster?
No...
...Have you?
I'm not going on a suicide mission
with some... immortal.
You can't restore the heart without me.
And me says "no".
I'm getting my hook.
End the discussion.
You'd be a hero.
- That's what you all about, right?
- Little girl...
- ...I am a hero.
- Maybe you were...
But now you're just a guy who
stole the heart of Te Fiti.
The guy who cursed the world.
You're no one's hero.
No one?
But...
Put this back, save the world
You'd be everyone's hero.
Maui! Maui!
Maui!
He's so amazing!
We'll never make it without my hook.
Not pass Te Ka.
Then we'll get your hook.
We get your hook, take out Te Ka,
restore the heart.
Unless you don't wanna be...
...Maui?
Demigod of the wind and sea.
Hero to... all?
- First, we get my hook.
- Then save the world!
Deal?
Deal!
Worth the shoot.
Okay, we go east,
to the layer of Tamatoa.
If anyone has my hook,
is that Bitty Eye Bottom Feeder.
Teach me to sail!
My job is to deliver Maui
across the great ocean.
I should...
- I should be sailing.
- It's called "Way Finding", princess.
And such as sails and nuts.
It seeing where you going in your mind.
Knowing where you are
by knowing where you been.
Okay, first, i'm not a princess.
- I'm the daughter of the chief.
- Same difference.
- No!
- If you're well dressed...
...And you've an animal side kick.
You're a princess!
You're not a way finder,
You'll never be a way finder...
You'll never be a way...
Really?
You are a bad person.
If you can talk, you can teach.
Way finding. Uhh...
Lesson one, hit it!
Hold the sheets.
Not, the sheets!
No!
Nope!
Nope! No!
Tryed that one already.
You measuring the stars,
not giving the sky a high five.
If the currents warm,
you're going the right way.
It's cold.
Wait! It's getting warmer.
Argh! That's disgusting!
What's wrong with you?!
We're here?
See? Told you i can do it!
Matunui?
I'm home?
Moana!
Dad?
Mom?
Help!
No!
Moana!
Enjoy your beauty rest?
You know, a real way finder
never sleeps.
So, they're actualy get where
they need to go.
Bustle up, butter cop!
We're here.
You sure these guys
gonna have your hook?
Tamatoa all he have it.
He's a scavenger, collect stuff,
things he think it looks cool.
And for Tamatoa, trust me.
My hook is the coolest collective.
And he leaves up... there?
No, that's just the entrance.
To umm...
- Realm of Monsters.
- Realm of Monsters?
Realm of Monsters?
We're going to Realm of Monsters?
We? No! Me!
You're gonna stay here
with the other chicken. Backya!
That's what i'm talkin' about.
Gimme some!
Come on! That was a good one!
How'd you not get it?
I called her a chicken.
There's a chicken on the boat.
I know she's human. But that's not a...
You know what? Forget it!
I'm not explaining it to you.
'Cause that is not funny.
So, daughter of the chief.
I thought you stayed in the village.
You know, kiss some babies and things.
Hey, i'm just tryin' to understand
why your people decided to send...
...A horrible princess.
You!
My people? Didn't send me.
The ocean did.
The ocean? Make sense!
Your what? Age? Can't sail?
Obvious choice.
It choose me, for a reason.
If the ocean so smart, why didn't he
just take the heart back to Te Fiti itself?
Or bring me my hook?
The ocean stride up, cookie dukes!
But i'm sure it's not wrong about you.
You're the choosen one!
ThisSub100 %TranscriptedBy
^~P.e.n.n.y~H.a.m.a.d.a~^
The ocean choose you for a reason.
If you start singing,
i'm gonna throw up.
So, let's sing at entrance.
Yes, because it only apears
after a human sacrifice.
Kidding! Haha! So serious!
*~ReadingSomeMagicFormula~*
Don't worry, it's a lot far
there down than looks.
I'm still falling!
Go!
And he sticks the landing.
Huh?
What? Dumb, dumb,
she's not even here.
No immortals gonna
jump into the realm of...
Well...
She's dead.
Okay! Let's get my hook!
Ew... Ew... Ew...
Maui's fish hook.
Yeeeaaahhh...
Sorry... i thought you're a monster.
What? I found your hook and...
...You were right this time
i fool i really like the dis...
- Stay!
- What? No! I'm the one who...
Listen, for thousand years i've only
thinking to keep this hair sooky...
...Getting my hook
and being awesome again.
And it's not getting screwed up
by immortal who has no business...
...Inside of a monster cave.
Except...
You made us beat.
Wow... shiny glittering cave.
And just like me it is covered
in sparkly treasure.
Sparkle... Sparkle... Sparkle...
- You're not sail at it!
- This is stupid!
- I'm just gonna walk up and get it.
- You go up there, he will kill you.
Just stick to the plan.
Oh, when he shows up
keep him distracted.
Make him talk about himself.
He loves breaking about how grave he is.
You do it to us get along
as well.
You're right in the top of his leg.
Maui?
Hohoho...
What do have we here?
It's a sparkly... shinny...
Wait a minute...
It's a human!
What are you doing down here?
In the Realm of the Mons...
Just pick an eye, babe.
I can't... I can't consentrate...
...On what i'm sayin' if you keep...
Yup! Pick one! Pick One!
You're a funny looking
little thing, aren't you?
- Don't! That's my grandma's!
- "That's my grandma's..."
I ate my grandma! And it took a weak
'cause you was absolutely human just...
Why are you here?
'Cause you're amazing!
And we immortals have heard
of a tale of the crab...
...Who became a legend!
And i had to know...
How... you... became... so...
...Crab?
Clueless...
Are you just trying to get me
to talk about myself?
Because if you are...
...I will gladly do so!
In song form!
Well, Tamatoa hasn't always been this glam
I was a drab little crab once
Now I know I can be happy as a clam
Because I'm beautiful, baby
Did your granny say
"Listen to your heart...
...Be who you are on the inside"?
I need three words to tear
her argument apart
Your granny lied!
I'd rather be...
Shiny
Like a treasure from a sunken pirate wreck
Scrub the deck and make it look...
Shiny
I will sparkle like a wealthy woman's neck
Just a sec!
Don't you know
Fish are dumb, dumb, dumb
They chase anything that glitters
Beginners!
Oh, and here they come, come, come
To the brightest thing that glitters
Mmm, fish dinners
I just love free food
And you look like seafood
No!
Hey! Crab cake!
I'm back! Mmuah!
It's Maui time!
What do you say, little buddy?
Giant hawk? Comin' up!
^^~WAIT! THAT'S KRISTOFF!~^^
(from Frozen)
Well, well, well,
Little Maui having a trouble with his look.
You little semi-demi-mini-god
Ouch! What a terrible performance
Get the hook
Get it?
You don't swing it like you used to, man
Yet I have to give you credit for my start
And your tattoos on the outside
For just like you I made myself
a work of art
I'll never hide
I can't, I'm too...
Shiny
Watch me dazzle like a diamond in the rough
Strut my stuff
My stuff is so...
Shiny
Send your armies but
they'll never be enough
My shell's too tough
Maui man, you could try, try, try
But you can't expect a demi-god
To beat a decapod
Give it up
You will die, die, die
Now it's time for me to take apart
Your aching heart
Far from the ones who abandoned you
Chasing the love of these humans
Who made you feel wanted
You tried to be tough
But your armour's just not hard enough
Maui
Now it's time to kick your...
Hiney
Ever seen someone so...
Shiny
Soak it in 'cause it's the last
you'll ever see
C'est la vie mon ami
I'm so shinny
Now I'll eat you
So prepare your final plea
Just for me
You'll never be quite as...
Shiny
You wish you were nice and...
- Hey!
- Huh?
I've got something shinny for ya!
The Heart of Te Fiti.
You can't run from me!
Oh, you can't.
You can't suprising me!
There's only so far you can get
on those two little legs.
The power of creation
for the frustation!
Where is it?
We gotta go!
- What about the heart?
- He can have it.
I've got a better one.
Yes! I have the...
Wait a minute... Argh!
I see she's takin' a bonicle
and she's covered it biolumination-elgy.
Has a division!
Come back here!
Hey! Heeey!
Did you like the song?
We're alive!
We're ali.... huh?
Listen, i appreciate
what you did down there...
- ...Took guts...
- Mmhmm.
But, uh... I'm sorry i'm tryin'
be some seer for once...
- ...And it feels like you're distracted.
- No! No! No way!
Really? 'Cause you lookin' at me
like i have a... huh...
Shark head.
- Do you have a shark head? 'Coz you...
- Look, the point is...
...For a little girl... child...
thing whatever...
Who had no business being down there...
You did me a solid.
But you also almost died.
And i couldn't even beat the dumb crab.
So chances of beating Te Ka...
We'll never make it to Te Fiti.
This mission is cursed.
It's not cursed.
- Sharkhead.
- It is not cursed.
Cursed.
What can i say except,
"We're dead soon..."
We're dead soon...
Can you at least... try?
Giant hawk!
Hey! It's okay! It's okay!
We're dead soon...
Alright, break time's over.
Get up!
Why? You gonna get me a speech?
Tell me i could beat Te Ka
'coz i'm... Maui?
Take a high, tiny.
How do you get your tatoos?
They showed up,
When i earn 'em.
How do you earn that one?
What's that for?
That's uhh... Men's discovery of Nania.
- What's Nania?
- None of your business.
I'll just keep asking.
What's it for?
You need to stop doing that.
- Back off!
- Just tell me what it is!
- I said back off!
- Is it why your hook's not working?
You don't wanna talk...
Don't talk.
You wanna throw me off the boat...
Throw me off.
You wanna tell me,
i don't know what i'm doing...
I know i don't.
I have no idea why the ocean choose me.
You're right...
But, my island... is dying.
So i am here.
It's just me and you,
and i want to help.
But i can't... If...
You don't let me.
I wasn't born...
...A demigod.
I had human parents.
They uhh... They take one look
and decided...
They did not want me.
They threw me into the sea.
Like i was...
...Nothing.
Somehow, i was found by the gods.
They gave me the hook.
They made me...
...Maui.
And... back to the humans i went.
I gave them island, fire, coconuts.
Anything that everyone want.
You took the heart for them.
You did everything for them.
So they loved you.
It was... never enough.
Maybe the gods found you for a reason.
Maybe the ocean brought you to them.
Because it's someone who
is worthy of being saved.
But the gods aren't the one
who made you Maui.
You are.
Okay... Okay... Hey...
I love you too, buddy.
Do you remember when we did all that?
The sway, the energy
expressed in the dance.
Come on, let's go
Give me your hand
Come let's dance
Come on, let's go
Give me your hand
You are the only one that I wish for
Round and round spinning round
Hey, my head's getting dizzy
Do it again it'll soon clear
Smile my way
My way
Keep on dancing
Listen to the pate
Aue
Smile my way
My way
Keep on dancing
Listen to the pate
Aue
Listen to pate
Keep on dancing
Next stop... Te Fiti.
Smile my way
My way
Keep on dancing
Listen to the pate
Aue
Smile my way
My way
Keep on dancing
Listen to the pate
Aue
- What?
- I figure it out.
You know the ocean used to love
when i pulled up islands.
'Cause your ancestors would say
resease... find them.
All those new lands, new villages...
...It was the water
that connected them all.
In the bioworthy ocean,
i think i'd be looking for uhh...
...Curly haired, non-princess...
...To start that again.
That is literary nicest thing
you've ever said to me.
Probably you should've said
that to Te Fiti.
I did.
Moana of Matunui, i believe you have
officially delivered Maui across the great sea.
Moana! Moana! Moana!
She's so amazing!
It's time.
Go save the world!
Maui!
- What you... What are you doing?
- Finding your better way in.
- We won't make it!
- Yes we will!
- Turn around!
- No!
- Moana stop!
Are you okay?
Maui?
I've told you to turn back.
I thought we could make it.
We?
I thought... I could make it.
- We can fix it!
- It was made by the gods.
You can't fix it!
Next time we'll be more careful.
Te Ka was stucked on barrier islands.
It Lava, it can't go on the water.
We can find a way around.
I'm not going back.
We... We still have to restore the heart.
My hook is cracked.
One more hit and it's over.
Maui, you have to restore the heart!
Without my hook, i am nothing.
That's not true!
WITHOUT MY HOOK, I AM NOTHING!
We're only here because
you stole the heart in the first place.
No, we're here because the ocean
told you "You're special" and you believed it.
I am Moana of Matunui,
You will board my boat...
Goodbye, Moana.
- Sail across the sea...
- I'm not killing myself so you could...
- ...Prove your something you not!
- ...And restore The Heart of Te Fiti.
The ocean choose me!
He choose wrong.
Maui!
Why did you bring me here?
I'm not the right person.
You have to choose someone else.
Choose someone else!
Please...
You're a long way pass the reef.
Grandma?
Guess i choose the right tattoo.
Grandma!
I'm trying, grandma.
I...
I couldn't do it.
It's not your fault.
I never should've put so
much on your shoulders.
If you are ready to go home...
...I'll be with you.
Why do you hasn't named?
I don't know.
I know a girl from an island
She stands apart from the crowd
She loves the sea and her people
She makes her whole family proud
Sometimes the world seems against you
The journey may leave a scar
But scars can heal and reveal just
Where you are
The people you love will change you
The things you have learned will guide you
And nothing on Earth can silence
The quiet voice still inside you
And when that voice starts to whisper
Moana, you've come so far
Moana, listen
Do you know who you are?
Who am I?
I am the girl who loves my island
I'm the girl who loves the sea
It calls me
I am the daughter of the village chief
We are descended from voyagers
Who found their way across the world
They call me
I've delivered us to where we are
I have journeyed farther
I am everything I've learned and more
Still it calls me
And the call isn't out there at all
It's inside me
It's like the tide
always falling and rising
I will carry you here in my heart
You'll remind me
That come what may, I know the way
I am Moana!
T
Th
Thi
This
This s
This su
This sub
This subt
This subti
This subtit
This subtitl
This subtitle
This subtitle w
This subtitle wa
This subtitle was
This subtitle was t
This subtitle was to
This subtitle was tot
This subtitle was tota
This subtitle was total
This subtitle was totall
This subtitle was totally
This subtitle was totally t
This subtitle was totally tr
This subtitle was totally tra
This subtitle was totally tran
This subtitle was totally trans
This subtitle was totally transc
This subtitle was totally transcr
This subtitle was totally transcri
This subtitle was totally transcrip
This subtitle was totally transcript
This subtitle was totally transcripte
This subtitle was totally transcripted
This subtitle was totally transcripted b
This subtitle was totally transcripted by
P
P e
This subtitle was totally transcripted by
P e n
P e n n
This subtitle was totally transcripted by
P e n n y
P e n n y H
This subtitle was totally transcripted by
P e n n y H a
P e n n y H a m
This subtitle was totally transcripted by
P e n n y H a m a
P e n n y H a m a d
This subtitle was totally transcripted by
P e n n y H a m a d a
I am Moana of Matunui
I'll board my boat
I will sail across the sea
And restore The Heart Of Te Fiti.
Te Ka can't follow us into the water.
We make it pass to the barrier island.
We make it to Te Fiti.
None of you will understand.
Because you're a chicken.
No!
HeiHei!
No! No! No! No! No!
Nice thwack!
Te Fiti!
Maui!
You came back!
But your hook...
One more hit and...
Te Ka's gonna catch me first.
Hey, i got your back, the choosen one!
Go save the world!
Maui...
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Hot! Hot! Hot!
Hey, Te Ka!
Shark head!
Moana!
Get the high to the spiral!
Te Fiti...
It's gone.
TE KA!
Let her come to me.
~ Ou mata e matagi ~
I have crossed the horizon to find you
~ Ou loto mamaina toa ~
I know your name
~ Manatu atu ~
I may have stolen the heart from inside you
But this does not define you
~ Manatu atu ~
This is not who you are
You know who you are
Who you truly are.
Te Fiti.
The chicken whips.
I'm sorry about your hook.
Well... Hook. No hook.
I'm Maui.
Te Fiti! Haha!
How have you been?
Look, what i did was... wrong.
I have no excuse.
I'm sorry.
You know, it'd be rude
if it's a gift from a gods.
Thank you. Your kindness
is deeply pleasured.
~ Sei e va'ai mai ~
Look down...
~ I le tātou lalolagi ~
Upon our world
~ Sei e mālamalama ~
The light
~ E lelei ma le mānaia ~
It is good and beautiful
~ Sei e va'ai mai ~
Look down...
~ Mānaia o le tātou ōlaga. ~
At how beautiful our lives are.
- Got a mission, drum stick.
- You can come with us, you know.
My people are going to need
a... Master Way Finder.
They already have one.
See you out there, Maui.
See you out there, Moana.
- Mom! Dad!
- Moana!
I may have gone a little way
pass the reef.
It suits you.
- She's back! Moana!
- Pua!
Welcome home!
This subtitle was Transcripted by
~ Penny Hamada ~
Follow me on Instagram
@PennyHamadaID21
Add me on Facebook
Facebook.com/Penny.Hamada
Watch me on Deviant Art
PennyHamada.DeviantArt.com
Ask me anything
Ask.fm/PennyHamada21
There are a lot of bugs that needs to
be fixed. Please, contact me at one of
my social media if you wanna fix it:D
~ Tulou... ~
Pardon us...
Aue, aue
We set a course to find
A brand new island everywere we roam
Aue, aue
We keep our island in our mind
And when it's time to find home
We know the way
Aue, aue
We are explorers reading every sign
We tell the stories of our elders
In a never-ending chain
~ Aue, aue ~
~ Te fenua, te malie ~
~ Na heko hakilia ~
We know the way
^^ Thanks for using this subtitle! ^^