Laxative
Have you finished? It smells!
I told you not to use laxative!
This is disgusting!
What are you cooking?
But the kids hate vegetables...
I can't come now
I'm guarding a prisoner on the toilet
Got to go, bye
Hey, shit it out...
can't be anything left in there!
I'm done
Hey, this isn't real gold!
Yeah, this is fake!
I chased you all day for this?
You deserve a good kick!
You bastard!
His name is Pan
He's from my village
but I haven't seen him in years
I never thought I'd see him again!
Life is so unpredictable...
Hey, no legs outside the bars!
Some people are wicked as hell
but never get punished
Some of them do so well
they make you jealous!
Meanwhile, good people...
like Pan
strange as it may seem
it's as if God's mysterious foot
keeps them down...
all the way down
to this hellish shit hole
Strange, isn't it?
The May dewdrops tell me...
my true love is near...
But if you reject me...
the dew just trickles away
Love can turn to something else!
A room can shrink to a mouse hole!
A love filled home...
can become cold and empty!
How much? It's paid for
Who paid?
Hi, Sia Noi!
Hi, Sadaw!
You look lovely tonight...
Who made this blouse for you?
I bought it
I...
can't take my eyes off your beauty
Why do you transfix me so?
Why must I stare at you?
Why does my heart pound so?
You shine like the full moon!
Your beauty pierces my heart!
Whenever you're within my sight...
I can only gaze in rapture!
You look so great!
You could be a model
Every goddess pales beside you!
This world's greatest beauty
comes second to you!
If you came face to face...
Don't embarrass me!
Why are you alone?
Sweethearts...
should make couples...
Should nurse each other
through sickness...
Have a child care for them
It's their duty to the nation!
Why are you alone?
You'll meet death in the end
Can you be reborn
if you spend your life alone?
Living is all about
finding true happiness!
Don't waste your lives! Get married!
Sadaw!
You're very beautiful
Watch where you're fucking going!
Stop gawking and wipe it off!
Bastard!
You're still alive, then?
Stay still
Stop that! There's blood!
It's okay, it will wash out
My blood doesn't wash out so easily
Why not? You've especially bad blood?
You looked happy dancing with Sia Noi
Every time I looked, you were smiling
I should look stern while I'm dancing?
You didn't smile or say a word
when you danced with me
Neither did you!
I'm not crazy, I don't talk to myself!
I know...
I'm poor...
so I'm nothing in your eyes...
I have no car...
so you don't care...
Though we used to love each other...
All I can give...
is my true heart...
I have no diamonds to satisfy you...
What the hell is going on?
Hello... Dad
You're not my damned son!
So it's you, Sadaw!
Sadaw's did not, Dad
Quite the hero, aren't you?
Come on...
Where are you going?
You're dead!
You'll float in the canal
like a dead dog!
MONRAK TRANSISTOR
Oh, it's you... Oye
You're up early this morning
Yes... this is for you, from Pan
What is it? Open it!
FOOT POLLEN
Why the hell are you digging
that pond? I hired Noi to do it!
Noi is sick. I'm replacing him
Dad... Stop calling me Dad!
When did I fuck your mother?
What are you doing?
Can't you see? I'm washing clothes
Sadaw, you're so cute
even when you tease me
Sadaw...
there's something I must ask you
I know it may not be the right time...
What's on your mind?
It may embarrass you...
or make some difficulty for you...
Tell me! I'm listening
Can you pay me in advance?
Oye needs it to buy Osha rice
they'll only sell it tomorrow
All right
Sadaw...
Massage my waist will you?
Just here
On the waist
I know a ghost recipe potion
My Grandpa told me about it
What crap is this now? Ghost recipe?
It's real!
A relative of mine drank it...
and he got back on his feet!
You think you can trick an old man?
Why would I want to trick you?
It's real!
If it doesn't work
I'll dig without pay!
So what is it?
It helps you live longer
It's made of four plants:
Elbow Tree, Knee Flower
Toe Root and...
Foot Pollen
Foot pollen? Yes
Bastard!
Did I say something wrong?
Get the hell away from me!
You should show me some respect!
Sadaw, what about my cash advance?
Here is your cash!
Get away from me or you'll
feel my foot
I haven't kicked you yet!
What's wrong? You look so angry
Give this to Pan
it's his pay for digging the pond
He wasn't kidding
about the ghost recipe...
What kind of medicine's
made from feet?
I'll tell you...
Elbow Tree is lemongrass
it's the length of a forearm
Knee Flower is a real flower
Toe Root's from the roots of bean plant
It grows in our yard
Foot Pollen
comes from a plant with leaves...
as curly as birds' feet
I see... But why not call them
by their real names?
My Dad thought Pan wanted him
to eat some feet!
It's a Ghost recipe...
The ingredients have mystical names
with mysterious power to cure
Here, this is from Pan
Sadaw, my love...
the May dewdrops are here...
Aren't you cold? When will you choose
someone to plough with you?
As the days grow longer, things change
Sadaw, my pretty one
I long to hold you in my arms
but heaven plays funny tricks on me
My heart is in great pain
People are born with ears and eyes
Even though we have different skin
color and sex, we are all still human
I hope, my sweet one
that you will truly understand
what I'm saying
Last, if you really love me
on the night before the new moon
there'll be a likay performance
at the temple... If you are alone
I'll swim across the river to you
May you be happy until that day
Love you as big as an elephant... Pan
You're so rich
you can fire off pellets at random?
It wasn't at random
I was aiming at a water ghost!
You aren't watching the likay?
No, I'm not feeling well
Not feeling well...
or are you waiting for me?
Crazy!
Shall we stage a likay?
Sure, you play the villain
I force myself on the heroine
You can't escape, I'll do it now
I'll smother you with kisses...
Get off!
Aren't you afraid of ghosts
being on your own?
No! What are you doing here
at this hour?
I keep you company
Leave now...
or we'll be caught
I can be alone
But I can't...
Later on...
Old Chuey came to hate Pan
less than before
But he still didn't really trust him
Quiet! You rascal
What the hell do you want now?
I've got some soup from Oye
Wait here
Come up, Brother!
See? My daughter calls
him Brother now!
Naughty girl!
What soup did you say it was?
Old Chuey thinks
that Pan lives only for the moment
He's too fond of entertainment
doesn't respect elders
and doesn't know when to stop
But no matter what the old man thinks
one day he finds himself
blessing the bride and groom
Blessed be the Buddha
blessed be the monks...
May you both grow old together!
Go forth and multiply!
You're taking her from me, damn you!
Sadaw...
Thanks, dear
Guess which singer?
Sayan Sanya! Wrong
Chaiya Mitchai then! Wrong
You know what you get
for guessing wrong?
What? Kisses
Then... Yodrak Salakjai!
Before long, Sadaw was pregnant
Had Pan's story ended here
it would have made
a charming short film
You'd be on your way
to the exits by now
But not yet!
Pan's story is just beginning
When Sadaw
was a few months pregnant...
All the young men in Bangnamlai
had to draw lots for conscription
Yoi was lucky...
Jon, too, Muek, too
and even Dang
Guess what Pan drew?
I promise I'll write to you every day
I promise...
Never!
I'll never forget!
As the moon never forgets the sky...
I'll never forget when we made love
I'll never forget our time together
As long as I live, I'll never forget!
Never, never, never...
Never...
No matter how many months or years
I'll never forget our joyful love
I'll never forget our shared dreams
Months or years, I'll never forget
Don't forget before I do!
I promise I won't forget!
I'll always remember the sweetness
which freshens my heart...
During the first six months...
only Pan's letters could
bring smiles to Sadaw's face
Pan knew this well
so he went on writing and writing
Though far from each other
Pan's heart
was in every letter he sent her
From the Gutter to the Stars
a contest for folk singers
two winners will join the troupe
of top star...
Plern Praewsupan
A place in Plern's troupe!
The tiny house I live in
Should I survive on salt alone
I shall never leave it
Even if I grew rich
No matter how rich
Nothing could take me away
From the tiny home I love!
Let's hear it for Plern Praewsupan!
Our young and handsome singer
Let's not waste time
Next we have our contest:
From the Gutter to the Stars!
Onward and upward!
Lots of contestants tonight!
I saw several baskets of
them backstage!
Singers? Singers
How strange!
But only two will be winners!
So let's hear first from Miss Dao
Ladies and gentlemen, Miss Dao!
She is our first contestant
for tonight
Miss... Dao!
She's as light skinned as a Burmese
and has pretty Indian eyes!
When the sun goes down
When I'm famous, I'll leave for home...
I'll bear every hardship
to become a country singer
and sing for my peers and my fans!
Pan! You're on next! Okay!
Ask him which song he's going to sing!
What are you singing?
I'll sing...
The Sad Soldier
Ho! What song's that?
No such song!
Anyone in the band know it?
Can you play it? He can't
Sorry, guy, we don't know your song
Change it! Sing something else!
No, I want to sing this song
But the band can't play it!
I can do it without music
Hey, this guy is great!
I want to hear him!
He has balls!
Pan! Let's get back to the camp!
The hot winds wafted
over the rice paddy last April
I had to leave
when the hot winds came
Sad soldier, I had to leave
I hugged you, telling you not to cry
Seeing your tears wrung my heart
I felt sorry for you, I felt so sad
From now on, who would help you plough?
I worried about you
I didn't want to go
I remember it so well
at New Year last year...
I wore a beautiful shirt
And you, my sweetheart
you wore a blue blouse
I recall the fragrant scent
on your cheeks
So nice it made the moon envious
I promised
to be back next New Year
The full moon of April...
is back now
But this New Year I'm alone
thinking of you far away
Sad soldier, I long for you
I have to spend
New Year alone without you
We've arrived!
Thanks
Hey, don't go in empty handed!
Carry this!
Hang on, there may be cash in there
No, not this time! Go on!
Never...
I'll never forget
as the moon never forgets the sky...
Yes sir!
This is not a hotel!
Why are you lying here
did you get kicked out?
What's your name? Pan, Sir
Pan who? Pan, the singer...
Oh, right, Pan from last night
Good! Follow me!
My name is Suwat
People in this business
call me Daddy
You've probably never heard of me
I stay off stage
I never take credit for what I do
Surapol, Sornkiri, Sayan, Chaiya
I'm the one behind them all
You know Sayan, right?
When he was starting out
he kept changing his style
His songs didn't really click
He asked me for help
Daddy, I need your help
It's been three years now
I want to send 10,000 baht home
I've only managed to send husks
Daddy, please help me!
You know what I told him?
Grow a beard
A beard?
That's all it took!
Now he coins it in!
Listen to me, Plern
It's Pan, Sir
Yes, Pan, listen to me
All the famous singers I've made:
If they were good, they did well
Remember: Be good and you'll do well
Obey me and you'll make it
Remember that
I've seen plenty of stoneheads:
Believe me
they didn't listen, they failed
My karma is a burden to me
Whenever I make someone famous
they forget all their gratitude to me
When they can fly with their own wings
they forget the nest
in which they were nurtured
People like that
will never go very far, I tell you
Take off your shirt
Come on, take it off!
Don't you want to be famous?
Are you sure of your career choice?
Yes
Good, in order to become a singer
you need to work very hard
Sir, I'm used to that
Good!
Start with the magic word: Endurance
Hang on to it
and your wishes will come true
You'll get all you want!
A house... Girls...
Whoever, whatever!
You like girls, I suppose?
I think I'd like
my wife and child with me
You're married! Nice!
It's good to have a loving family!
Can I put on my shirt?
From now on, call me Daddy
You can stay here for now
I will move you to my house later on
Don't forget, Plern...
It's Pan, Sir
Don't forget, Pan
remember what I said
Be good and you'll do well!
I don't like stoneheads
I've never been ungrateful, sir
When can I start singing, Daddy?
What?
There's no rush!
First things first...
Handsome!
Bring my girls some water
On the double!
Fifteen minute break, girls
Handsome! Buy me a Krathing Daeng!
One bottle
And cigarettes for me!
One month later
You ran away from the army?
Yes, so I have to stay
If I go back, they'll jail me for life
Never mind the jail
They'll shoot you!
What?
Shoot me? Damn right!
14 months later
27 months later
Stop, stop!
How annoying!
How many times must I tell you?
Together now! 5, 6, 7, 8...
Please think of me
O please...
Do you still think
of me...
Never forget, never for...
we are apart, but our hearts are close
TITS, ASS, BALLS
She takes on all comers!
She can crush the balls
of any male star...
She can overtake Dao Mayuree
Morning and night
she can suck for James
challenge Arpaporn Nakornsawan
crush the balls of Chaiya Mitchai
grab the guts of Roong Suriya
split the legs of Siriporn...
Is she a hooker?
She's a singer! A singer?
Her voice is so sexy!
She is...
the new sensation:
Dao Saosuantang!
Give her a big hand
ladies and gentlemen!
Here she is...
With more than twenty dancers!
When I least expected it...
In just one glimpse
it blinded me
Everything about him is perfect
He makes my heart pound
I don't know or care
I wait for him to smile
To come closer
and whisper sweet nothing...
How is it going, Pan?
There...
Bring the rest of them...
Love came suddenly
when I least expected it
In just one glimpse
it blinded me
Everything about him is perfect
He makes my heart pound
I don't know or care
if he's good or bad
I wait for him to smile
To come closer
and whisper sweet nothing
My song is the breeze
that blows towards him...
When I arrived here
Daddy said my dreams would come true
I'd become famous
I'd have my own house and car
But after two years
I'm still mopping floors
You know
wannabe stars like you
I've seen lots of them here
None of them made it
My heart was full of dreams too
when I came here
You... a singer?
Yes
You must have been a handsome man
See, you're the wrong sex
You see...
Look at the girls here...
They can go far, fast
Because they have tits and asses
What have you got? Balls
Right
Pan, what's the matter?
Well...
I...
When will I get a chance to sing?
You said you loved this career...
I do
It takes time to prove true love
But I've been here two years
You think we're folding
paper bags here?
Let me tell you
the economy is bad right now
I can't afford to take risks!
Do you know how much we owe the bank?
If we went bankrupt
how many people would be out of work?
I'll tell you what, Pan
tomorrow you will have...
a job
food on your plate
and a bed
Be grateful for it!
You told me you were not ungrateful!
But now you're starting
to behave selfishly
I'm sorry
But what about the girls?
Why do girls get ahead?
They have tits and asses...
You only have balls
Is Dao here?
In her dressing room
Here, clean my car
Stay with me
I love it when you laugh!
Here sir Thanks
Hang on!
Dao! Dao!
Balm!
Rub balm on my temples, Pan
That's nice...
Pan, massage me here...
SURAPAN PETNAMLAI
How do you expect to find him?
There are millions of people
It won't be easy, you know
They live in buildings
and there are
hundreds of thousands of buildings
How will you know which one he's in?
He said something like
Buppasawan Lane
it can't be that hard to find
What should I take him as a gift?
Maybe a bullet or two! That bastard!
Once he's doing well
he forgets his family
She could have died without us
Rainwater
What about rainwater, Dad?
It's less tasty in the city!
The city is damn filthy!
How can rain taste good?
Oy! Yes?
Take care of my baby
Of course, and I want to see
Pan's blood when you get back!
Can I help you?
We're looking for the singer Pan
Pan?
My husband!
I've brought him rainwater
There's a show at Wat Mai tonight
they've all gone to prepare for it
Shit! How can we get to that temple?
You could take a water taxi
Or the number 40 bus
Is Pan famous yet?
You'll see...
What are the Four Virtues?
1: Food to eat 2?
Place to stay 3?
Hole to pierce 4?
Staying power!
Where's Plern?
There's a big crowd waiting...
Found him yet?
Not yet, dunno where he's got to
Go find him!
The bastard!
He's pulled this act once too often!
I'll tie up his balls
with a rubber band!
This singer was a born genius
How do you know?
He's born with a mic in one hand
notes in the other
and a keyboard in his mouth!
He was born to...
kill Sayan
push out Surachai
turn on Poompuang
split Somying's legs
squeeze the tits of Banyen
suck on Pornsak
take out the guts of Arisman
smash Surachai's balls
to go between Sangrawee's legs
and take her on...
The man I'm talking about here
is Surapan Petnamlai!
Please give him a round of applause!
Together with his dancers!
O please don't turn away from me
listen to me
I'm in the wrong, I'm bad
I abandoned you
I was cruel
I destroyed our love
I took a mistress
and betrayed our love
whereas I never did you wrong before
I hear you cry
and my heart breaks
I feel weak thinking of you
I was wrong
I feel guilty about my mistake
I long for you
A hundred casual flings can't
compare with your steadfast love!
A thousand other women
cannot match with you!
I'll never turn away...
from my dear chili dip again!
I love you with all my heart!
I know I've done you wrong!
I know now I have disappointed you
My dear, have you forgotten me?
I have made the biggest mistake ever
I'm coming back to you
O my love, don't flee from me
let's start all over again!
Please forgive me for the past
Pan, Pan...
You're going to make it!
I'm happy for you, Pan!
Pan!
Sadaw!
What are you doing here?
I came with Dad... He's taking a pee
A pee?