و They say
that falling in love و
و Is wonderful و
و It's wonderful و
و So they say و
و To hold the girl
in your arms و
و Is wonderful و
و Wonderful و
و In every way و
و So they say و
We develop short investments
by analyzing the level of
a particular stock's overvaluation,
then assigning a rating.
I don't need to know
your homework technique, son.
Give me something
I can chew on.
Don't worry, Mr. Beretsky,
I'm about to give you a mouthful.
According to the research
compiled by Miss Webster here,
more than 60 percent
of your current portfolio
is rated at mid-risk
to dangerous.
You can find weak spots
in any company.
None of this means anything
until we verify it.
These companies
have been stable for years.
Check out everything
if you want.
It'll take weeks.
Meanwhile,
state regulators
have investigations pending
on both Klasco and DeBridge,
which, I believe, are two
of your biggest holdings.
Due respect, sir, but
without some serious hedging,
you're ripe for a big fall,
and soon.
I've heard enough.
Carl, wait, uh, we have
other investment ideas.
Better ones.
Formulated
by better brokers.
Let me introduce you
to a few...
I'm not interested
in other brokers.
I like the way
he thinks.
That went
fantastically well.
Yeah, you think
Holtzman trusts me?
Forget Holtzman
He isn't smart enough to trust you.
Beretsky does.
That's what's important.
A whole new part of your life
is starting right now.
After this, it's only a matter of time
before there'll be
a handful of Carl Beretskys begging you
to take care of their money...
at the investment firm of
Nate Holden and Associates.
Well... Go on.
Go on. Get going.
No, wait. Here. Here.
Got it.
و At last و
و My love has come along و
و And my lonely days
are over و
و And life is like و
و A song و
و At last و
و Skies above are blue و
و And my heart
was wrapped up in clover و
و For you are mine و
و At last و
Frank D., everybody,
right here at The House.
Stevie Cotter on guitar.
Tony Banda, Ramon Banda.
Our special guest this Friday
and Saturday, Khani Cole.
- Nate, where you going?
- I'm sorry, Frank. I gotta go.
Are we gonna see you
for an entire show?
You're lucky I could
stay for the set.
We got this new big shot client.
He has me up to my ears.
Alright. Well, did I tell you Junior's
starting private school next month?
Hey. Don't worry, Frank.
I'll take care of you.
All right.
و
و When I fall in love و
و It will be completely و
و Or I'll never fall و
و In love و
و In a restless world
like this is و
و Love is ended
before its begun و
- و And too many و
- و Moonlight kisses و
- و Seem to cool و
- و With the warmth of the sun و
و When I give my heart و
و My heart و
و It will be forever و
و Forever و
- و Or I'll never give و
- و My heart و
و And the moment و
و I can feel that و
و You feel و
و That way too و
و That's when I fall و
و When I'll fall in love و
و With و
- و With you و
- و You و
و
Yes!
Yes, yes! Hil-Co.
I think we might have something here
with the reshuffling at Hil-Co.
Feels like a smoke screen to me, like
they're changing the band on the Titanic.
What do you think?
Sorry. What?
Did you read
the Hil-Co story?
Uh, no.
I haven't gotten to it yet.
Something about it feels right to me.
Sorry, Mr. Holden
has a phone call.
Take a message.
It's the police.
Nate Holden.
Hi, Mr. Holden?
This is the Weehawken Police.
There was a break-in at a residence
that's registered in your name.
We're gonna need you to come down here
and speak with the detectives.
As far as we can tell there's at least
three other houses
in your neighborhood
that were hit last night.
I don't know if you have an inventory
of your valuables or not.
No, this was
my mother's house.
There weren't
many valuables.
Well, as you can see, they turned
the house upside down pretty well.
- Yeah.
- Though there is a room down the hall
where the door's locked.
We're not quite sure
about that.
We could pop it open
and take a look, if you'd like.
No, no,
that's okay.
Nate, go take a look.
Thanks anyway.
Well, suit yourself.
Take a look around.
If you change your mind,
let me know.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
My God.
What?
I took this photograph.
You remember?
Yeah.
- Why isn't this at your apartment?
- I don't know.
- Well, here. Take it with you.
- Look!
I don't want to deal
with this right now.
Well, you're not just
gonna leave it here.
That's the plan.
Here you go.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Excuse me.
Are you Nate Holden?
- Yes.
- I thought so.
My father hates you.
Uh, did you and I date?
His hatred for you
is strictly professional.
Hi, I'm Marie Devrenier.
My father's Robert Devrenier.
The CEO of Duocon.
They had kind of
a rough patch last year.
Yes, which you rode
all the way to the bank.
Yeah. Look, uh, it's been
kind of a long day,
and I don't really like to talk
business while I'm here, so...
I'm sorry. Yeah.
Neither do I.
Would you like to have a drink
with me and my friends?
We won't talk business.
I promise.
Uh, maybe some other time.
Wow. You're not selling me
short, too, are you, Nate?
No, really,
it's nothing personal, and, um...
like I said,
hopefully some other time.
Okay. But I'm gonna
hold you to that.
Bye.
So, Nate, what are you
doing tomorrow night?
You free? I'll be
in your neighborhood.
"Chloe sings. The Last Stop".
Come on, Frank. I gotta work.
Ah, all right.
Is, uh, everything okay
between you and Charlene?
Of course. Why?
Oh, you know,
I'm just wondering why
you're wasting your time driving
halfway across the city on your night off.
- Who says it's a waste of time?
- Aw, come on, Frank.
There's got to be 2,000 girls
in this city
making up little postcards and singing
at rundown joints like the Last Stop.
And, okay,
maybe in the end,
one of two of them have got what it
takes to sing in a place like this,
but come on,
do the math.
The odds are a thousand to one
this girl is not wasting your time.
Have a good evening.
It's yours.
That's Chloe.
You didn't know that?
- No.
- You know, Nate, music isn't money.
Somebody gave me a shot once,
I wanna return the favor.
- That's the way it works.
- Excuse me.
Hey, Chloe. I think this
just came off your bracelet.
Oh. Thank you.
You need to apologize to her.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Do you need a ride?
'Cause we're going across town.
No, Jesse'll be here
any minute. Thank you.
- Do you want us to wait?
- No, that's okay.
You guys go ahead.
I'll see you on Friday night?
- Okay.
- Okay. Bye.
Can I give you a ride home?
No, thanks.
Uh, all right,
I'll walk with you, then.
I'm fine.
Just leave me
alone, okay?
و When I fall in love و
و It will be forever و
و Or I'll never fall و
و In love و
Thank you.
Found that outside
my window.
Where you sang with me.
Look, I hope...
you didn't take what I said
before too personally.
- I...
- Ugh.
Hey!
Wait!
Look, I spend all day and most
of my nights predicting failure.
It's my job.
I'm very good at it.
- Well, I'm sorry for you.
- Well, I'm not.
I believe
in what I do, but...
I need music
to keep me sane.
That's why I go
to the club every night.
That's why I play
a song or two before bed.
It helps me...
I don't know,
it helps me keep in touch
with a part of my...
- A part of your soul?
- Yeah!
Yeah. Do you know how many drunken
confessions I hear from suits like you?
Every week.
"Oh, I hate my job.
I should have been a musician".
Look. You apologized,
and I accept your apology.
So let's stop this before it
gets any more annoying, okay?
But I'm not drunk.
And I'm not
confessing anything.
I just want you
to play music with me.
- That's...
- No, thanks.
- I don't do charity work.
- It wasn't charity work the other night.
No, it wasn't.
It was a vocal warm-up.
Excuse me?
I play a gig
near your house.
I was warming up.
You're a decent piano player, but there
are a lot of them in this city
that I should be playing with before you,
including my boyfriend.
Yeah, right.
- What is so funny?
- Come on.
You're walking home alone late
at night in this neighborhood?
There is no way
you have a boyfriend. No way.
Look, I don't have to prove
anything to you, Mister...
- Just call me Nate.
- But since you asked, here.
Photograph
doesn't prove anything.
Here. You should
read the back.
It's kind of cute,
actually.
Anyway, this is
my building.
Thanks for
the walk home... Nate.
Yeah.
- Morning.
- Morning. You should take a look at this.
Okay, but before I forget,
this is Sunset-Western and DEK.
I'd like you to take
a look before lunch.
- Sure.
- And one more thing.
- I'm sorry about yesterday.
- Oh! Stop it. Stop.
- And I appreciate your concerns.
- Stop it.
No. Look.
I think I got a little overwhelmed
there for a couple of days,
but it's over and done with,
so thank you.
Well...
Come on!
They're lovely.
Speaking of which, this is
what Vogler gave us on Hil-Co.
That's it?
Don't waste
my time, David.
I know you have more on Hil-Co
than two quarterly breakdown sheets.
I did, but I don't anymore.
- Where is it?
- I honestly don't know.
Right.
You lost the research.
I don't have what you're looking for
You could check my files.
No, no. I'll let
Holtzman do it.
Wow.
You're first really big case,
and you're running to Holtzman
with some lame conspiracy theory
that I'm, what,
shredding documents?
Not the best show of poise
under pressure, kid.
I mean, you might want to do
your own research.
That is, if you don't find
what you're looking for here.
Life gets a lot easier when you're not
betting against people.
We should do lunch sometime.
Is Chloe coming on soon?
Yeah. Should be.
Comin' right up.
All right.
But I just talked to him.
He's gonna be here any minute.
- Don't lie to me.
- Please?
Look, I know
it's annoying,
but Jesse just needs to feel
like people are waiting on him,
but then he's fine.
Three nights in a row
he's been AWOL,
while you and I are
wasting our time here.
You gotta stop
doing this, Chloe.
What Jesse needs is help.
I know. I know.
If I...
From somebody
other than you.
You're too nice
to be in this business.
I can't afford
to lose this gig, Rudy.
Rudy...
- Hey, Rudy, how ya doin'?
- How ya doin'?
Good night.
- Hi.
Do you know
"In The Wee Small Hours"?
Uh... yeah.
Can you play it?
"A" flat?
Uh, well, actually,
I was just doing some work.
و In the wee small hours
of the morning و
و While the whole wide world و
و Is fast asleep و
و You lie awake و
و And you think about the boy و
و And never ever think of و
و Counting sheep و
و When your lonely heart و
و Has learned its lesson و
و He'd be here و
و If only he'd call و
و In the wee small hours و
و Of the morning و
و That's the time و
و You miss him most و
و Of all و
Do you want a glass
of wine or something?
If you're still interested
in playing together,
I can be back here tomorrow night
at the same time.
Did something
happen to you?
Look, if you don't mind,
I'd like to keep this about music, okay?
Sure. Same time
tomorrow night?
Yeah, same time
tomorrow night.
Pick up a hundred thousand
on the first uptick.
- Ten thousand-share increments?
- Right. Now it's at 72 and a half.
- So, say we start at...
- Sixty-eight.
Exactly, and watch it
drop like a rock.
Good, good. That's great.
و Love walked right in
and drove the shadows away و
and brought my sunniest day و
و One magic moment
and my heart seemed to know و
و That love said hello و
و Though not a word
was spoken و
و One look and I forgot
the gloom of the past و
و One look and I had found
my future at last و
a world completely new و
و When love walked in
with you و
So far we're
ahead of schedule.
Good.
We're gonna build it
around Hil-Co.
Hil-Co was Vogler's baby.
He give you any problems?
David's been great.
Thanks.
I'm gonna work
on these at home.
- Snappy.
- و Ah ahh و
Right.
Can I at least
give you cab fare?
No, I'm fine.
I'll see you tomorrow. Bye.
Reinhardt, it's Holden.
Oh, boy, have I got a story to tell you
about a company called Hil-Co.
و Love walked right in
and drove the shadows away و
So, listen. Rumor has it that
you're shorting Hil-Co.
Where'd you
hear that?
Nate, come on.
Don't tease us.
We pay our secretaries
good money for that.
و love said hello though not
a word was spoken و
You have a good night.
See you tomorrow.
و One look and I had found
my future at last و
و One look و
و And I had found
a world completely new و
و When love walked in with you و
Hey, Dot.
Oh. Excuse me.
- Cream?
- Oh, thank you, I...
Say when.
Uh... when.
Sugar?
Oh. No. Thank you.
Sweet enough already, huh?
- Ready, Terry?
- Sure thing.
Have a great day.
These guys could hire
Superman to run their company,
and they'd still be looking
at 12 to 15 months...
of tough times.
Oh, yeah, we're talking about
years of dysfunction here.
- One minute.
- Right.
Uh, Jimmy, I'm gonna
have to call you back.
Yeah, thanks. Bye.
Nate, I want you
to meet a friend of mine.
Terrence Hill,
this is Nate Holden,
our brightest young
portfolio manager.
What a pleasure
to meet you.
Well, any friend
of David's is...
Terry is the CEO of Hil-Co.
So, this is where it all happens.
Word is you see our stock dropping
35 percent in the next two quarters.
We run
a family business.
When you tell the business world
we are mismanaged
or irresponsible,
not only are you doing
damage to our company
but to my family as well.
Well, facts are facts,
Mr. Hill.
These people you love have made
a series of financial mistakes,
and this little ambush that
David has set up here for us
won't change that or the negative impact
it will eventually have on your stock.
Which you have
no qualms profiting from.
David, please.
This is not an ambush,
Mr. Holden.
- No...
- This is an invitation.
I'm here simply to invite you
to consider our approach,
to think as we do.
It's easy to focus on
the mistakes of the past.
But we believe the changes we've made
make us strong for the long term.
The question is whether you have
the foresight to believe it.
- Have a great day.
- Yes. Thank you.
An invitation.
Thank you, David.
Who is that man?
Terrence Hill.
Oh.
Uh, as in...
Hil-Co.
What happened?
He stuck up
for his company.
I can't figure out why David
is hell-bent on protecting them.
He's jealous.
You're young, you're single,
you're attractive,
and soon you'll be
twice as rich as he is.
- Come on.
- Shall I call for takeout?
No, no, I'm gonna grab
something later at home.
I don't want
to stay here too late.
But we're making
good progress, don't you think?
Yes, I suppose we are.
Good. Have a good night.
و You go to my head و
و Like a sip of
sparkling Burgundy brew و
و And I find
the very mention of you و
و Like the kicker
in a julep or two و
و The thrill of the thought
that you might give a thought و
و To my plea
casts a spell over me و
و Still I say to myself و
و Get a hold of yourself و
و Can't you see
that it never can be و
و You go to my head و
و With a smile that makes
my temperature rise و
و Like a summer
with a thousand Julys و
و You intoxicate
my soul with your eyes و
و Though I'm certain
that this heart of mine و
و Hasn't a ghost of a chance و
و In this crazy romance و
- و Oh, you go to my head و
- و You go to my head و
و You go و
و To my head و
I should go.
Why? Because we
almost kissed?
We didn't almost kiss. We were just
in the moment of the song.
It's nothing personal.
Oh, come on.
Everything is personal with you.
Oh! Is everything
so simple to you?
"That's a waste of time".
"It's personal".
Does everything become black
and white when you have money?
- Can you tell me that?
- I guess I tend to think in absolutes.
My life isn't
like that, Nate.
Well, tell me
what it's like, then.
No, thank you.
Right.
Is there anyone you can tell?
- Huh?
- Fine.
I'm in love with somebody
who doesn't love themselves,
so it makes it hard
for them to love me.
And every day, because I love
this person, I lower my expectations
until just getting him
to sit upright and be alert
is... a really good day.
Actually, I think
I know how that feels.
Yeah, of course you do.
I'm sorry.
You don't know me either.
Let's just
keep it like that, okay?
On the night that Frank D.
showed up to hear me sing,
my piano player didn't.
And I can't afford
to lose that gig.
And you want me to help?
Yeah.
It's, um...
on Wednesday night.
And it's late, so...
Right.
What's the big deal?
I... I don't play out.
Why not? I thought you said
you wanted to play music together.
No, it's not
about that. I...
I don't like performing.
Can you make
an exception?
One night.
Three songs.
And what happens after that?
Well, then Frank D. gives me a gig
at The House, and I play with him.
Oh.
Frank D.'s coming.
Right.
Well, that's
why I came here
'cause I already
blew it with Frank D.
But I figured he was your friend and he'd
show up to hear you play.
You figured?
Yeah. Still personal?
That's just not gonna
work for me. I can't.
Oh, come on. I thought you wanted
to play music together.
Of course I wanna
play music together,
but I don't wanna be in
a position where I'm playing music
for the benefit
of someone else.
Especially not Frank D.
The guy doesn't even know that I play,
and that's the way I wanna keep it.
I can't believe that you don't get this.
Music is a gift.
Don't start
with that, please.
When somebody plays,
when Frank D. plays,
he is giving you
a piece of his soul,
and the greatest thing is to be able
to give that right back to him.
I've given back to Frank D.
more than a few times.
With what,
financial advice?
Is that what your soul
is made up of?
Is it?
What if it is?
Then I'm sure you're
very good at what you do.
و Fool that I am و
- و For falling... و
- و falling in love with you و
و And fool that I am و
و For thinking
you love me too و
و You took my heart و
و Then played the part
of little coquette و
و And all my dreams
just disappeared... و
و just disappeared و
و In all the smoke
from our cigarettes, oh و
و Fool that I am و
و For hoping you'd understand و
و And thinking you
would listen to و
و All the things
I had planned و
و But we couldn't see
eye to eye و
و Darling, this is goodbye و
و But I still care و
- و Crazy little fool that I am و
- و What a fool I am و
It's clear there are
gonna be cash-flow problems.
Yeah, I suppose. I guess I'm not sure
they can't weather the storm.
May I just point out to you
that Cytek is just as vulnerable
as Sunset-Western and DEK,
both of which are on the board.
Nate?
Nate, Angelica. Someone you might
want to say hello to.
You remember
Marie Devrenier.
Yes. We've met before.
Nice to see you again.
Likewise.
Miss Devrenier is here on behalf
of her father, Robert Devrenier.
CEO of Duocon.
Well, he must hate us.
He's over it. But now he'd like
to take his personal investments...
in a new direction.
Which would be you, Nate.
If you're free this evening, I'd like you
to take Miss Devrenier to dinner
and convince her that her father's money
should be with us.
I'm sorry for the short notice, but my
father likes to wrap things up quickly,
and I'm headed out of the country
tomorrow for the next two weeks.
Sure, sure.
You're still ahead of schedule
on the Beretsky plan, right?
- Uh, well...
- Yes, we're ahead of schedule.
Good.
Then you're free.
I'll leave you two
to iron out the details.
Uh, Marie,
this is Angelica Webster.
- Pleasure to meet you.
- How do you do?
Uh, just leave it open,
thank you.
- Angelica, it's fine.
- Why be fine when you can be perfect?
She's a beautiful girl.
And smart.
I don't know why
you're not more excited.
- You could use a woman in your life.
- Debatable.
- Oh, come on.
- I'm just not in the mood.
Well, find a way
to get there.
Devrenier would be
a huge client.
This girl could be
the key to your future.
So... do the right thing.
Which is what,
exactly?
Make her happy.
Go on.
و
I'll take those. Here.
You just keep this part,
and I will, uh...
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Okay, great, great.
- Let's sit over here.
- I want to talk to you.
- Huh? I'm sorry.
- I want to talk to you!
- Sorry, I can't hear you.
Hey, come on.
Let's go.
- Here. Ticket.
- Thank you.
Just bring it
back later.
Band is gonna take a short
break. They'll be right back.
Yeah, the band was great.
This is great,
guys.
So, Nate... tell us.
Come on, please.
Stop with the questions, you guys.
Sorry. We're all
a little fascinated by you.
Yeah, we were all there
for "the rejection".
- Rejection?
- Oh, come on. You remember.
- Oh, that.
- Right.
That doesn't happen
to Marie. Ever.
What were
you thinking?
Well, I was thinking...
what a horrible mistake
I was making.
Right.
Smart boy.
Here's to that.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
Great glasses.
و
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Have a good night.
- You, too.
Hey.
Ticket.
- Why are you so upset?
- I'm not upset.
- She's a client.
- Who's a client?
- The woman I'm with.
- You're with a woman?
Very funny. Look, I need to talk
to you about last night.
Please,
no more talking.
It's exhausting.
- Hey, you ready to go?
- Ticket?
Yeah, ready.
I'll see
you guys later.
Okay, huh? You two have a good time.
Here you go.
Have a good night.
Yeah, nice meeting you.
Next. Hi.
What do you think?
Is this supposed
to prove a point?
No. I thought it might be a nice
play-out on Wednesday night.
I was trying to tell you
at The House,
but you were too busy
not being upset.
- How's your client?
- I dropped her off.
So, you like
the music or not?
Well, it's not how
I would have done it.
So?
So, I don't know.
You can't expect me
to just instantly like something
that's not what
I've been imagining. Sorry.
When you figure it out,
you know where I live.
Wait.
Will you
play it for me?
Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Okay. Thank you.
و Why do I let you do
the things you do و
و 'Cause, baby,
when it comes to you و
و I should know better و
و Once upon a time your love
was my great passion و
و Shined just like
the colors of a rainbow و
و Happiness
Ours for the asking و
و I remember
when you loved me و
و And then I looked around و
و And without a sound و
و Love is gone و
و Still I can't let go و
و I keep holding on و
و When I know
I should go و
و Why do I let you do
the things you do و
- و Things you do و
- و 'Cause, baby و
- و when it comes to you و
- و 'Cause, baby, when it comes to you و
و I should know better و
و Once upon a time your love
was my great passion و
و Shined just like
the colors of a rainbow و
و Happiness
Ours for the asking و
و I remember
when you loved me و
و Then I looked around و
و And without a sound و
و Love is gone و
و Still I can't let go و
و I keep holding on و
و When I know I should go و
Yeah.
That's just about it.
I mean... the bridge could probably use
a little bit of work,
but otherwise it's...
What do you think?
It's in pretty good shape, right?
I didn't make
a hard copy of that.
Good.
I wanna go long with
Beretsky's investments.
- You what?
- I spent the entire night
thinking about what we've
been doing here, Angelica,
and I'm tired of it.
Do I really want to spend
my entire life finding failure? No.
But, Nate, it's what we do.
We sell short.
We're good at it.
Maybe it's time we got good
at something else.
I don't think it's time.
We're a couple of days away
from finishing a $40-million portfolio.
Now is definitely not the time
to go back to square one.
I know I'm pulling the rug out
from underneath you here,
but I wanna do this,
and I want you to do it with me.
Okay.
I want you to tell me
what's going on.
- Angelica...
- You don't just wake up one morning
and decide that everything you've been
doing for the past 5 years is wrong!
Well, how else
does it happen?
I don't know!
You haven't been yourself
since your mom's house was broken into!
- Aw, come on...
- I was concerned about you then.
You told me not to worry,
and I tried not to, and now look!
- This is totally reckless.
- Well, maybe it is.
Maybe I'm losing my mind.
I don't know, but...
it just can't be any other way.
You're my best friend.
I love you. Let's do this.
Just stop it!
- Angelica?
- Stop it!
We'll start with
Buchanan's newsletter.
He's an optimist,
but he's not blind to reality.
- I'll get the last three months.
- Good.
And I love you, too.
Yeah, right away, please.
I think so.
What have I got for you?
Well, how about Hil-Co?
No, I'm not joking.
Five years' time,
they'll be swatting
everybody else away like flies.
These are the stocks
I'd bet on for the long term.
I know what I said before,
but I don't care.
I'm over it.
Okay, yeah, I trust you.
You're right.
Explain how I'm supposed
to feel comfortable
buying a stock that just last week
you told us to sell short?
Look, it's simply
a question of perspective.
That's right. What do you
say you return the favor?
All right, what do you got?
Sixty-six and one-eighth.
January, right.
Now I have a favor
to ask you.
Up three points?
Up three points.
No, that's driven
them up, right?
No, it's going up.
Up. Yeah.
- We did it!
- We did it.
They're solid
investments, Paul.
That isn't really
the point.
The point is Carl Beretsky bought into
a strategy of short-selling,
and you're giving him
something completely different.
In fact, you're giving him
the opposite.
With all due respect, Mr. Holtzman,
Beretsky didn't buy into a strategy.
He bought into Nate. He was worried
about his financial security,
and Nate
gave him hope.
I doubt he really cares what we do
with the money as long as it grows.
It's not that simple, Angelica.
I have to tell Carl we
completely reversed the field.
He could fly off the handle
and pull all his money.
Not if you believe
in the plan yourself.
With all due respect,
your number one man did all the work.
All you have to do is trust him.
How easy is that?
You were amazing.
That speech was inspirational.
Now that we've got
the basics ironed out,
we ought to talk about some
designations for Beretsky's general fund.
I had ideas for creating tax protection
I wanted to run by you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Slow down.
We've been working
our butts off for weeks.
You know what?
I want you to take the day off.
Don't be silly.
There's plenty of work to do here.
I'm taking the day off.
I want you to do the same.
Well, what are you gonna do?
Hello.
- Hi.
Uh, Angelica,
this is Chloe.
Hi.
It's really nice
to meet you.
Likewise.
They're, um, fancy digs.
Would you like the 25-cent tour
before you two go?
Oh, thank you.
I would like that.
- Yes, thank you.
- Okay. Let's go.
Wow, you guys work here?
Sometimes.
Oh, my...
Is there no nonfat milk
in this place? Shee.
و I don't know why
but I'm feelin' so sad و
و I long to try somethin' و
و I've never had و
و Never had no kissin' و
و Mmm, what I been missin' و
و Lover man,
oh where can you be و
That's for you.
Come on. Sit down.
و The night is so cold و
- Yeah?
- I didn't know that.
و And I'm so all alone و
و I'd give my soul و
و Just to call you my own و
Oh! My heart.
و Got a moon above me و
و But no one to love me و
و Lover man,
oh where can you be و
و I've heard it said و
و That the thrill
of romance can be و
و A heavenly dream و
- What do you think?
- Oh. Hmm. Well.
A new man?
و One day we'll meet و
Thank you.
و And you'll dry all my tears و
و And whisper sweet
little things in my ears و
و Huggin' and a-kissin' و
و Mmm, what we've been missin' و
و Lover man,
oh where can you و
و Be و
You still want
"A" flat, right?
Yeah.
Give me a hand up?
Thanks.
Hi.
Welcome to the Last Stop.
Hit it.
و
و Here I go again و
و I hear those trumpets
blow again و
و All aglow again و
و Taking a chance on love و
و Here I slide again و
و About to take
that ride again و
و So starry-eyed again و
و Taking a chance on love و
و I thought that cards
were a frame-up و
و I never would try و
و But now I'm
taking that game up و
و And the ace of hearts
is high, oh و
و Things are mending now و
و I see a rainbow blending now و
و We'll have
our happy ending now و
و Taking a chance on love و
و
Thank you.
Yeah, sorry.
They were friends.
You know
what I'm worried about?
Now that you're
gonna be singing with me,
I have to bring
my "A" game every night.
- Yeah, Frank, no more slackin' off.
- Well, here's to the "A" game.
- Cheers.
And, you, I don't
even know you anymore.
- You want a gig, too?
- No, Frank, I'm retiring.
Goin' out on top.
Well, you're gonna have to come
play a duet with me sometime.
You're not just
gonna sit there.
- Yeah.
- All right.
- Yes, yes, yes, yes. Yay!
- Alright, alright, alright.
- Cheers.
- That'd be great.
But I don't want you singing.
You just stick
to the organ, Frank. Okay?
Mmm...
You're like a piano.
Play something on me.
Like what?
I don't know.
You choose.
Okay.
What is that?
Schubert.
Mmm. It's wonderful.
My mother used to play this
every time she sat down to practice.
Which was right about the time
I got home from school.
So...
I must have heard that
hundreds of times.
Used to hate it.
Now it's what I think about
every time I look at a piano.
Mmm.
Do you miss her?
I wish she hadn't
died unhappy.
If I could figure that out,
that would probably lead me to
knowing whether I miss her or not.
I...
Well, that's a pretty
complicated answer
for somebody
who thinks in absolutes.
Well, I thought I had
everything figured out.
And then I met you.
Holtzman's been here for 3 hours.
This doesn't look good.
- Good morning.
- I've gone over everything.
About half of Beretsky's portfolio
can absorb some overall market damage.
The other half I would
classify as vulnerable.
- Mm-hmm.
- We have two options:
short anything that gets
an initial uptick,
or we just dump everything right away and
start again once the market's stabilized.
What do you wanna do?
We don't have a lot of time.
Well...
I think we should
just ride it out.
Ride it out.
Are you kidding?
No. I like this portfolio
for the long term.
Nate, you're gonna lose his money!
We need to sell everything in the Beretsky
portfolio as soon as the market opens.
I'm not gonna
do that, Paul.
Excuse me?
I'm not going to give up
on a good thing
because I'm scared that
something bad might happen.
I believe
in the stocks we chose.
I don't have time to get
into this with you right now,
but we have 40 million dollars...
tied up in a market
that's about to crash.
So if you don't mind...
You don't know that,
and even if it does,
this portfolio
can withstand...
Beretsky will lose
half his money by noon!
And I can't
withstand that!
So just dump
the damn stocks!
Or I'll find
somebody who will.
You better
start looking, Paul.
- You got five minutes.
- Stop it! You made your point!
It's not about making a point.
I am not going to be bullied
into doing something
I do not believe in.
That's fine.
I'll sell
the Beretsky portfolio.
You clear out
your desk.
You're fired.
Excellent.
Mr. Holtzman, wait.
I haven't
got time to wait!
Mr. Holtzman!
Aw, come on.
Angelica, let him go. It's okay!
Hi. No, it's okay.
You don't have to be afraid of me.
I'm-I'm here to help.
I don't need any help.
Well, I'm here
to help Jesse.
I don't know
where Jesse is.
Well, I do.
He's in the bedroom.
I would give it
a couple of hours.
It's not really
a good time right now.
What did you do to him?
Who are you?
No...
I'm Vince.
Jesse didn't tell you
about me, did he?
No.
I'm the guy people call when...
when they can't get clean.
Call me tomorrow.
Holtzman will have cooled off by then.
- I'm sure I can get him to reconsider.
- Don't bother.
Nate, you need this job.
You need it so that you eventually
have the leverage...
to start something
for yourself.
I already have started
something for myself.
Finally.
And... I have
all the leverage I need.
Seeing as Holtzman
had to have the last word,
I should get
a pretty good severance.
That's not
gonna last forever.
Well...
who knows?
Call me!
Life's gonna be
pretty simple for Jesse.
He's gonna have
two kinds of people.
People that
help him stay clean,
and people that don't.
It's your choice.
It is your choice.
I haven't seen Jesse
for a few weeks,
and I didn't know...
when he was coming back.
And, um...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Um...
You were already gone,
weren't you?
You're already outta here.
Yeah.
Oh...
I'm sorry. I should have said this
from the beginning.
You don't have to do this.
You don't.
Can I help you?
Uh, I'm looking for Chloe.
Is she here at all?
Chloe's not available
right now.
Can I give her
a message?
Is she here or... not?
She's here,
but she's not available.
Is there a message
I can give her?
Yeah, just tell her
Nate dropped by, I guess.
Nate. Okay, Nate.
I'll tell her.
All right?
Thanks.
Nate? Hey.
What's going on?
I'm going to explain.
Um...
You wanna grab some breakfast?
I need to talk to you, too.
No, I, um...
I have to stay here.
What's the matter?
Um, that man
that you met upstairs
is here to help us
get Jesse clean.
"Us"?
Yeah, Jesse and me.
He came back
last night.
Um, and the next few days are
supposed to be kind of crazy,
so Vince is gonna hang around
for a couple of days
and make sure that nothing bad
happens to Jesse.
What about you?
I'm-I'm going to help.
Oh, Chloe.
It's not what
you're thinking.
- You're doing what we always do.
- No, I'm not.
Yes, you are!
You just can't see it!
If you had a chance to go back right now
and try to help your mom,
you would do it no matter how bad
the odds were.
That's different.
That's totally different.
That's only because it's too late.
I'm sorry.
و The thrill is gone و
و I can see it و
و In your eyes و
و I can hear it و
و In your sigh و
و Feel your touch and realize و
و The thrill is gone و
- I'll get Vince.
- Stay.
و This is the end و
Jesse?
و So I pretend و
و And let it linger و
It's gonna be
one hell of a write-off.
Here's your receipt.
و On و
و The thrill is gone و
So, you know, basically I'm just
exploring my options right now,
figuring out what I'm gonna do.
There's no rush,
right?
Did you quit,
or were you fired?
Which one was it,
'cause I'm not totally clear on that.
Uh, uh, I quit.
Well, you know, for all
intents and purposes, I quit.
Right.
Ah.
Hey, Nate, it's Frank.
I haven't seen you around
The House lately. Where you been?
Where's that gig you promised me?
Give me a call.
و Why do I let you do the things you do و
و 'Cause, baby,
when it comes to you و
و I should know better و
و Once upon a time your love
was my great passion و
و Shined just like
the colors of a rainbow و
و Happiness
Ours for the asking و
و I remember
when you loved me و
و Then I looked around و
و And without a sound و
و Love is gone و
و Still I can't let go و
و I keep holding on و
و When I know
I should go و
- Up.
- Uh, what...
What is...
What's that?
What's what?
It's soup.
Not the sou...
The tune you're humming.
What is that?
Oh. Was I humming?
Yeah.
Oh.
You didn't know
you were humming?
No, I didn't know
I was humming.
I knew you were humming.
Mmm.
- You know, I was thinking...
- Don't think. Eat.
I'm serious.
I was... I was thinking
we should get outta here.
Are you sure
you're up for that?
No, I mean, um...
"out of here"
out of here.
I can't be in
this city anymore, Chloe.
It's not healthy.
I wanna go somewhere else
and start all over.
The right way.
With you.
My little lady.
What do you think?
Um...
و What's new و
و How did that romance و
و Come through و
What'd you expect?
You don't return any of my phone calls.
Super let me in.
He mentioned, by the way, he loves
what you're doing with the place,
and I have to agree.
As good
as that looks, I...
I'll just stick
to my glass of wine,
but thanks for the offer.
What, are you mad at me?
I'm on your side.
I'm not mad at you.
I'm just...
I don't have anything
left inside of me.
I don't have the energy
to return my phone calls or...
sit on the couch and talk about
what's going on in my life.
Sorry.
It's the girl.
You know, when we met, I thought
there was something so familiar about her.
I couldn't figure it out,
and then just last night,
it occurred to me how much
she reminded me of your mom.
That's ridiculous.
She does.
You remember your mom.
Before she got depressed,
she had that same sunny,
optimist...
Of course I remember!
I moved on!
You should be trying
to do the same thing, Angelica.
You're not
exactly young anymore.
Maybe you should sit down
and try to figure out
what's really going on in your life,
what you're going to do,
instead of just playing
my wet nurse.
Everybody deals with
heartbreak in their own way.
Some people drink.
Some people eat sweets.
You...
you just push away
everything you love.
And everybody, too.
و
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Just one.
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
Thank you very much.
We're gonna take a short intermission.
We'll be right back.
Hey, Frank.
How ya doin'?
- Nate, how ya doin'?
- Good to see you.
- Sounding pretty sharp up there.
- Thank you, thank you.
Yeah.
Frank, what?
I did what I had to do, and that's that.
I'll be fine, okay?
I'll find something else.
All's I'm sayin' is you could have thought
of me before you did something rash.
I have a feeling you'll be okay.
Ah, anyway,
it's good to see that you're back.
- Cheers.
So what's the plan?
I'm not sure.
Look, have you seen
Chloe at all?
No. That girl,
she just vanished.
Anyway, I hope
you've been practicing.
I got you booked here
for next Wednesday.
This is Nate Holden.
Please leave a message.
Nate, it's Angelica.
Forget about
the other night.
There's a new firm looking for a partner,
and they're asking for you.
Hello. Hi.
No, look, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
No, I really appreciate it,
Angelica. I do.
Wait a minute. Who?
The crash.
The crash was really
more of a fender bender.
It had
a healthy rebound.
All I did was reinvest
Beretsky's funds
into what pretty much amounted
to the portfolio you created.
It went up 12 percent.
And this...
this I've been planning
for quite some time.
But it was your investments that gave
me the push I needed to make it happen.
I mean, you and I together,
I mean, we could make
an incredibly strong team.
And I know Beretsky
feels the same way.
The only question is...
how do you feel?
- How'd it go?
- Incredibly well.
Now, would you meet me...
at this address tonight?
Here.
What is this?
And in the meantime,
David wants to see you.
- What for?
- Just go on in. He's waiting for you.
Me?
You're gonna be great.
Go on.
He's expecting me.
Why do I let you do the...
- Hey.
- Hi.
Did you, um,
finish up in there?
Does, um, that have anything to do
with this sheet music?
You, um,
love him?
Jesse...
You know,
it's funny when...
I mean, when you think
you've lost everything,
you find out you can, um,
always lose a little more.
Hey...
و
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
At this time, I'd like to bring
a very special guest up,
personal friend of mine,
Mr. Nate Holden.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please make him feel welcome.
It's his first time
here at The House.
Thank...
Excuse me. Thank you.
و
Hey. Angelica? Hi.
Oh!
- What a pleasure to meet you.
- Hi. Pleased to meet you.
و If the nightingales
could sing like you و
و They'd sing much sweeter
than they do و
و For you brought
a new kind of love و
- و to me و
- Hello, let's hear it for Chloe!
Microphone. Yeah.
و And if the sandman
brought me dreams of you و
و I'd want to dream
my whole life through و
و 'Cause you brought
a new kind of love to me و
و I know that I'm the queen,
you're the king و
و Still you can
understand و
و That underneath it all
I'm a girl و
و And you, you're only a man و
و I would work
and slave my whole life through و
و If I could
hurry home to you و
و 'Cause you brought
a new kind of love to me و
Yeah.
و You brought
a new kind of love و
I love you.
I love you, too.
و Love walked right in
and drove the shadows away و
and brought my sunniest day و
و One magic moment
and my heart seemed to know و
و That love said hello و
و Though not a word was spoken و
و One look and I forgot
the gloom of the past و
و One look and I had found
my future at last و
a world completely new و
و When love walked in with you و
و Love walked right in
and drove the shadows away و
and brought my sunniest day و
و One magic moment
and my heart seemed to know و
و That love said hello و
و Though not a word was spoken و
و One look and I forgot
the gloom of the past و
و One look and I had found
my future at last و
a world completely new و
و When love walked in with you و