dd [Humming "There's
No Place Like Home"]
dd [Continues]
[Hissing. Wolf Whistle]
Tea time!
Oh. Good.
[Rumbling]
Oh.
[Gasping]
What under earth?
Oh! Ooh!
Oh! Oh. Ooh!
- Whoa!
- Ooh! [Whimpers]
- [Loud Clattering]
- Oh, help!
Ooh! Aah!
[Grunting]
- [Motor Rumbling]
- Aaah!
Aaah!
Ooh!
[Grunts]
[Panting]
Oh.
- Hello. Mole!
- Oh. Hello. Rat.
Care for a mess about
on the river?
It's a perfect day for a picnic.
I hate to bother you. But...
something terrible is going on.
Something terrible going on?
- Hello. Otter.
- Oh. Hello. Ratty.
Ooh-hoo!
Hello, Ratty!
- Careful. You rabbits.
- [Bicycle Bell Dings]
Beautiful day.
My dear Mole. There's not
the minutest thing terrible going on.
It's a lovely. Glorious day
for a picnic. Jump in.
I-It is a lovely day...
except my home
has been knocked in.
Who knocked in
your home. Mole?
That's what I want to
ask Mr. Toad.
- Toad?
- It was in his meadow.
You won't get any sense
out ofToad...
whereas a picnic might
well steady the nerves.
It wasn't very grand.
But it was my home.
Well. You... you can come
and live with me. Mole.
I did love it so. Rat.
But the hamper's all packed...
and the sandwiches are cut
and... and...
- Oh. All right. Come on. I'll take you to Toad Hall.
- Thank you. Rat.
We can have the picnic there.
- Oh! Mind the varnish.
- I haven't been in a boat before.
What?
You've never been in a...
Well. Shiver me whiskers.
- You poor creature.
- Is it as nice as all that?
It's the only thing.
My dear young friend.
There is nothing...
absolutely nothing
half as worth doing...
as simply messing about
in a boat.
Simply messing...
messing about... in boats.
d There's plenty to do
and lots of time too d
d Messing about on the river d
d Wherever you go
you go with the flow d
d When you're messing about
on the river d
d Whether you get there
or whether you don't d
d You think it would matter d
d I tell you it won't d
d Lots to be done
and it's all of it fun d
d When you're messing about
on the river d
[Low Voice]
d I'm on my way to a sea. Come with me d
- d I'm on my way to a sea dd
- The river's my whole life.
I don't want any other.
What it hasn't got
is not worth having...
and what it doesn't know
is not worth knowing.
What's that?
- [Bird Shrieking]
- [Rat] That? That's the wildwood.
Uh. We don't go there very often.
We riverbankers.
Are there
very nice p-people there?
Well. The. Um...
the squirrels are all right...
and the. Uh... the rabbits.
Some of them.
And there's Badger. Of course.
He lives right in the heart of it.
Dear old Badger.
But it's not for the likes
of you or me.
W-Why not?
There are others...
weasels. Particularly.
They're all right
in their own way. But they're...
They're just out for themselves.
They don't give a hoot for anyone else.
And, uh, beyond the wildwood?
Beyond the wildwood
comes the wide world.
That's something that doesn't
concern either you or me.
Please don't ever
refer to it again.
Oh. Rat thinks life's one big picnic.
Wait till we take over the riverbank.
He won't find it so easy then.
- Excuse me. Sir.
- Keep still in there.
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
There's Toad Hall now.
Finest house on the river.
Though we never admit
as much to Toad. Of course.
Hello.
I see the boating craze is over.
First it was sailing.
Then he tired of that.
He took up punting. This year
I've been giving him rowing lessons.
Come on.
Let's meet Toad.
[Mosquito Buzzing]
Oh! Hurrah! Splendid!
Toad. This is Mole.
Just going to send for you.
Both of you.
My young friend's
just lost his home.
Has he?
What a stroke of luck.
- No. No. No. It was dreadful.
- You can live with me.
He's going to live with me. Toad.
No. I just acquired the latest thing!
Come and see!
Toad.
- How's the boating?
- Boating? Oh. Pooh!
Silly. Boyish amusement.
Gave that up ages ago.
[Toad Chuckling]
Don't mind them. Bit of a stuffy lot.
The finest house on the river, what?
[Snorts]
Yes.
I was hoping you'd help me
get my home back.
It was in your meadow.
You see. Toad.
Pooh! Not my meadow any longer.
Sold it off.
I needed a spot of ready cash.
He sold off my hole.
Now. Iook here. Toad.
That meadow belonged
to your father.
Moles have lived there for centuries.
You can'tjust sell it off.
Behold your new home. Moley!
- What is it?
- Very heavy.
It's the latest thing!
But I don't want
a new home. Ratty.
The open road!
The dusty highway!
Heath and hedgerow
and rolling down.
- Here today.
- Off to somewhere else tomorrow!
It doesn't bear thinking about.
- I-It's a caravan.
- Ooh, finest cart ever built.
Designed it myself. Of course.
And we can set off after lunch.
- Oh. Stop there. Toady.
- Travel. Change. Excitement!
Did I just hear you say "start" and "we"
and "after lunch"?
Oh. Dear old Ratty. You can't just stick
to your fusty old river all your life.
I want to show you the world!
I don't want to see
the world and I'm...
going to stick to
my fusty old river.
Moley and I are going for a picnic on it.
Aren't we. Mole?
- Y-Yes. Once we found out
what happened to my home.
- Oh. Absolutely.
Then it's all settled.
We set off after lunch.
I say. Horsey. Faster!
It's very kind of Mr. Toad.
Of course. But...
it's not like having my own hole.
Don't worry.
He'll soon get bored with it.
[Loud Yawn]
[Rat] Toad, when you say you
sold off your meadow...
who did you sell it to?
Oh. Some weasels. I believe.
Weasels? Toad!
Oh. Don't... don't start lecturing me.
You know perfectly well
the weasels are after Toad Hall.
- It was only a meadow.
- It was Mole's home.
- Oh. Pooh! You worry too much.
- [Disgusted Sigh]
Uh...
- [Horn Honking]
- Uh... Look out!
[Horn Honking]
[Whinnying]
[Horn Honking Continues]
- [Honking]
- Scoundrels!
- What was that?
- [Rat] Road hogs!
Toad. Come and give us a hand.
- Boop, boop!
- Toad?
- Boop. Boop!
- Toady.
- Are you all right?
- Boop. Boop!
There. Don't worry.
They've gone.
We'll go straight down to the police station
and lodge a complaint.
Complaint? Me. Complain of that
beautiful. Heavenly vision?
- The cart's not too badly damaged.
- The cart? Oh. Pooh!
Horrid little cart.
Common cart.
Canary-colored cart.
Poetry in motion.
The only way to travel.
Here today. And next week tomorrow!
Whoo-wee!
Villages skip.
Towns and cities jump.
- [Chicken Clucking]
- Whoop! Always someone else's horizon.
Oh. Bliss! Oh. Pooh. Pooh!
[Horn Honking]
- Toad!
- Ooh!
Whoo! Whoo-hoo-hoo!
- Ooh! Aah!
- Toad. You idiot!
- [Rat] Oh, no!
- [Yells]
Look out!
[Toad Hooting]
Whoo! Ho-ho!
- [Toad Continues Hooting]
- [Horn Honking]
- Hang on!
- Toad. For goodness sake. Slow down!
- Whoo! Ha-ha!
- [Mole] That's the wildwood!
- Hang on!
- Toad. You're driving into the wildwood!
Yes!
[Hooting]
Toad.
[Rat]
Toad. Stop this car at once. I insist!
- Ratty!
- [Hooting]
Ooh!
Hang on. You lads...
Funny. Wonder where they went.
Oooh. Hmm.
Oh!
Oh! No! Ooh!
- [Loud Crash]
- [Clattering]
Help!
[Blubbering]
Help! Help! Please!
Chief. Toad's crashed another car.
That's the seventh he's smashed.
That green head's playing
right into our hands.
[Bird Shrieking]
- [Sun] Cheerio!
- Oh.
Wait... Wait a minute.
Sorry. Can't stop.
[Whooshing Noise]
Well. Well. If it isn't little Mole.
I'm not afraid of you weasels.
M-My friends will
be along any moment.
- [Chuckles]
- Friends?
- Yes.
- [Chief Weasel] Listen, Mole.
There is no such thing
in this world as friends.
Everyone's only out for themselves.
Take us weasels.
[Together]
First you see us.
Then you don't.
Now you hear us.
[Quietly]
Now you won't.
d It's our secret of survival
in a very nasty world d
d Now you feel us
Now you can't d
d Are we real
Perhaps we aren't d
d It's our secret of survival
in a very nasty world d
Is it really such a nasty world?
Oh. Yes. A very
nasty world. Indeed.
[Together]
Nastier than you could ever dream of.
- From up above!
- And from beneath.
- Eyes! Jaws!
- Claws and teeth.
d Ready to attack you
You're a snack. You'd better run d
d Don't come walking in the wildwood
if you haven't got a gun d
[Cackling]
d Every creature for survival
has to look out for itself d
- d Oh. No nannies here d
- d Or grannies here to look after your health d
d You're in the wildwood d
d And every child would tell you
that you've got no business to be here d
d First you see us
Then you don't d
- d Now you hear us d
- [Quietly] d Now you won't d
d It's our secret of survival
in a very nasty world d
d Now you feel us
Now you cant't d
d Are we real
Perhaps we aren't d
d It's our secret of survival
It's our secret of survival d
in a very nasty world dd
Listen. Mole.
You tell your friends
to stop meddling in Toad's affairs.
Yes. It's our meadow.
And we're going to build a really big...
Shut up!
If Toad wants to sell his property to us.
That's his business.
Right. And when he sells us Toad Hall.
We'll call the shots around here.
- Why don't you tell him all our plans?
- Well...
at first we make Toad Hall
a weasel-only area.
- Then we ban picnics along the whole riverbank.
- Garbage brain!
It's meant to be a secret!
Friends?
You're a spineless nobody. Mole.
Who'd want to be your friend?
[Rat]
Mole! Where are you, Mole?
[Bird Shrieking]
Where are you, Mole?
There you are. Mole.
Are you all right. Moley?
I am. Now you're here. Ratty.
But are you all right?
Oh, I'm fine.
Tuck your scarf in.
- You don't want to catch your death of cold.
- Yes.
Hello. That's handy. Right.
Now, we better go and find Toad.
It's not safe in the wildwoods.
You know.
- Yes. I...
- It's not safe at all.
- Pooh. Pooh.
- Come, come.
- Who's there?
- Mr. Toad.
- Waah! It's you!
What an honor for the wildwood.
Good lord. How did I get here?
I understand you need finance
for another motorcar.
Another motor? Oh. Yes.
We have a little
business proposition.
Oh. Ratty. We're not lost. Are we?
No. No. No. No. No.
It's. Um... It's this way. Old fellow.
Brace up. Moley. Look!
It's Badger's place.
[Bell Rings]
[Knocking Continues]
- [Bell Ringing]
- [Knocking Continues]
[Ringing]
[Knocking, Ringing Continue]
[Snoring]
What... What the devil?
- Don't worry. He's not that fierce.
- "Fierce"?
Come on.
What time is it.
For heaven's sake?
Knock. Knock. Knock.
I'll give you knock. Knock. Knock.
[Loud Knocking]
What is the meaning of this?
- Um...
- Sorry. Badger.
- It's me. Ratty.
- It's the middle of winter.
- And my friend Mole.
- And the middle of the night. By the looks of it.
Yes. Well. We're lost
in the wildwood.
Oh, it's you, you say, Ratty.
Well. Obviously. Badger.
And. Uh. Mole.
Y-Y-Yes. Sir.
- Well. Come in. Come in.
- Thank you. Badger.
Were the weasels
beastly to you. Moley?
Mmm. They said they were going to turn
Toad Hall into a weasel-only area.
- Did they?
- Mm-hmm. And ban picnics on the river.
Ban picnics?
Mmm. And they said they were going to build a
big something on the meadow Toad sold them.
Toad sold his meadow
to the weasels?
That's why they
knocked in my home.
Ah. It's all right. Moley.
You can come and live with me.
He's going to
live with me. Badger.
It was only a small.
Dingy little place.
Not like here. Badger...
or your cozy quarters. Rat...
or Toad's beautiful hall.
But it was my own.
My very own little hole.
That good-for-nothing Toad!
And now he's crashed
yet another motorcar.
- How many is that?
- Cars or crashes?
It's the same thing with Toad.
- This is the seventh.
- [Knocking]
- [Bell Ringing]
- This is an outrage.
- Oh. Ow! Ouch!
- I've had quite enough visitors for one winter.
I was attacked by weasels.
Hundreds of them.
Did they sing a dreadful song?
They wanted me to put up Toad Hall
as collateral against a new motor.
- Toad. You didn't!
- Of course not.
- The old place is worth at least six new motors.
- Six motorcars?
It's time you stopped
this motoring craze.
It'd cost the earth. Toady.
- You've squandered the money
your father left you.
- Haven't. There's tons of it.
Your father was a particular
friend of mine. Toad.
And I promised him on his deathbed
that I would ensure...
that you looked after
your inheritance.
- I was only having a bit of fun. Badger.
- So you're a nincompoop.
Oh. Thank you. Badger.
Toad. "nincompoop"
is not a compliment.
Oh. Isn't it?
Take off those ridiculous goggles.
- Shan't.
- Rat.
[Gasps]
I say. Badger!
- Now the driving gloves.
- Oh. Not my gloves.
Oh. No. They're brand new.
Cost a fortune.
Exactly.
- [Toad] Ohh!
- Now you will accompany me in there...
where you're going to hear
a few facts about yourself.
- [Door Slams]
- [Badger] Pull yourself together!
- [Toad Whimpering]
- You're light-minded,
incompetent, irresponsible...
impractical with your property!
[Yelling Continues, Faint]
Goodness only knows
what your father would have said!
- [Toad Crying]
- Don't give me "boo-hoo-hoo"!
It's no good
"boo-hoo-hoo"now!
You should have thought of that
in the first place...
before you started squandering the money
your father left you!
[Clock Bell Dinging]
[Door Opening]
My friends.
I'm pleased to inform you...
that Toad has something important
to say to you both.
Sit down. Toad.
Right. Toad.
Begin with the "how-sorry-l-am" bit.
"Oh. How sorry I am that
I have been so foolish."
B-But I'm not sorry.
It wasn't foolish.
It was simply glorious.
But didn't you just
tell me in there...
Oh. Yes. Yes. In there.
I'd have said anything in there.
You backsliding wretch.
Oh. Dear Badger.
You're so eloquent.
You can make me say
whatever you like in there.
But I've been thinking
it over out here...
and I find that out here
I'm not the least bit sorry.
So it's no earthly good
saying I am. Now. Is it?
So you don't promise never
to touch another motorcar again?
On the contrary.
I promise the very next motorcar I see...
Pooh. Pooh!
Pooh. Pooh! Off I go in it!
Ooh! Ooh!
Very well. Gentlemen. It's plan "B."
Plan "B"?
Yes. Ratty. Plan "B."
- Hey. Badger!
- Behave like a nincompoop...
you'll be treated
like a nincompoop!
[Toad]
Oh! Oh! Ooh! Hey!
[Toad] Where are you taking me?
This is no way to treat a Toad.
- I've never been treated so atrociously.
- Shut up. Toad.
How much further is it. Badger?
This tunnel will take us
right to Toad Hall.
We're under his meadow now.
How under earth did you find
the time to do all this. Badger?
Oh. I didn't.
Long. Long ago. There
was a city of humans right here.
They thought their city
would endure forever...
but humans can't
let things rest.
Greed. You see...
that's their undoing.
But we remain.
There were badgers here before...
- and there'll be badgers here still.
- [Metal Clanking]
[Weakly]
Tea time.
Shh.
We'll teach those weasels. Moley.
[Toad]
Come on, you chaps. Just let me out.
You know you can trust me.
Please! Please, let me out.
[Weeping]
Ooh! Let me out!
Let me out! Ooh!
- What's going on? I shall write my solicitor!
- Shut up. Toad!
- You want the servants to hear?
- Is this Toad Hall?
- Shh!
- I'll be the laughingstock of the kitchen.
- Then shut up!
- [Both Grunting]
- I'm sorry. Sir. I just don't know.
- [Sighs]
- Oh. Good day. I am looking for Mr. Toad.
- He's not here.
Ouch!
I have six new motorcars for him.
- Toad!
- You reprobate.
My new motors!
Oh, are they brand new?
Oh, I must see them! Let me out!
- Mr. Toad will not be requiring
any new motorcars. Thank you.
- Yes, I do!
- I love them! Let me out!
- H-He's not well.
Ooh, I can see them!
Oh, they're wonders!
- Hurrah!
- He's suffering from a mania
brought about by motorcars.
It's not a mania.
I love motorcars.
As his physician. I have ordered
he be taken and locked in his room...
until this mania
has run its course.
- Those cars are my life,
my soul, my raison d'etre!
- Shh!
Mr. Toad owes me money.
[Chuckling]
I love motorcars! Please!
- Let me out!
- Can I make a proposition?
- We're always open to a deal.
- How's this then?
If you remove these
machines forthwith...
I promise not to insert
one part of them...
into any portion of your anatomy.
Right.
Fair enough.
It's a pleasure
doing business with you.
Let me out!
Oh. Dear! Stop them!
Stop them. Somebody!
Oh. They're driving off.
My lovely motors!
[Crying]
All brand-new and shiny.
[Crying Continues]
So. Badger thinks he can cure Toad
of motorcars. Does he?
- We don't want him to do that. Chief.
- I know.
- We want him to spend every last penny he's got.
- So he has to give us Toad Hall.
- What are you telling me for?
Well. Uh...
- Cheese brain.
- Thank you. Sir.
- [Squeals]
- [Clears Throat]
Chief. I'll make sure
Toad doesn't forget about motorcars.
- Yes. We have a plan.
- I have a plan.
- We both thought of it.
- No. You didn't.
Just do it!
[Car Horn Honking]
- Oh. Iook. Frank. One of those!
- Oh. What fun!
[Horn Honking]
- That was fun. Frank.
- Yes. Ripping.
[Toad]
Pooh, pooh. Pooh, pooh.
Get out of the way. Officer!
Oh. Nincompoop!
[Tires Screeching]
Ooh! Ow!
Seems to be a lot
of traffic today. Toad.
Third crash this morning.
Come on.
[Grunts]
Toady. I wish you'd get better.
You know. It's been months now.
[Groans]
Perhaps if l... Oh. But. No. I mustn't ask.
- What?
- I was just thinking I might improve...
with a little fresh air.
Oh. No. No. No.
I can't let you out of this room.
You're quite right. Ratty.
Although I was only thinking
of a little stroll...
along the river.
The river.
Oh. It's so beautiful in the snow.
- [Water Running]
- But you're quite right.
I should stay here safe indoors.
Besides. You can't have a picnic
in the middle of winter.
Oh. But you can. Everybody thinks you can't.
But you can have a picnic anytime.
In fact, winter picnics
are my speciality.
All you need
is a hot thermos. A warm rug.
I know the most perfect
little hollow where you can get all snug...
and watch the snow.
- I mean. If anything could take my mind off...
- Quite. Quite.
A picnic on the river certainly
would do it. A winter picnic too.
There's a picnic hamper
in the cellar all ready.
N-No. No. Toad. I can't.
- It might be the very cure.
- Well. Of course. A picnic
on the river cures anything.
Oh. Toady. If you
promise me faithfully to behave.
Oh. You know me. Ratty.
A picnic on the river!
- Why didn't we think of it before?
- You'll have to go...
right down to the cellar
to get the hamper.
Look. Um. Toady...
best not mention anything
about this to Badger.
Oh-ho-ho. Wouldn't dream of it.
Old fellow.
Right.
d Oh. The clever men at Oxford d
d Know all there is to be known d
d But then none of them know
what half as much d
d As clever old Mr. Toad d
d Now the world has
hailed great heroes d
d As history books have shown d
d But never a name
to go down to fame d
d Compared with that ofToad d
d The army all saluted d
d As they marched along the road d
d Was it the king or the president d
d No. It was Mr... dd
Hello.
Hmm. Hmm.
[Dog Barking]
[Horn Honking]
- Bother!
- What rotten luck.
Oh. Well. Might as well
have a spot of lunch.
Ah. Landlord...
table in your snug.
If you'd be so kind.
- Certainly. Sir.
- Thank you.
Darling.
Oh. Oh. My. Oh. My.
Oh. I wonder.
I wonder if they'd... sell it.
Of course. I'd...
I'd have to test it first...
- just to be certain I really liked it.
- [Engine Starts]
Oh-ho! Oh-ho!
Pooh. Pooh! Look out!
- [Horn Honks]
- It's Toad on the road!
Oh-ho! [Laughing]
Look out. Everybody!
Whoa, look at Toady!
Whoo... Brakes!
- [Tires Screech]
- [Loud Crash]
[Clattering]
[Steam Hissing]
The full penalty of the law
is hardly sufficient...
for the heinous. Callous.
Unmitigatedly evil crime...
perpetrated by the sniveling wretch...
we now see cowering
before us in the dock.
Hear! Hear! Hear!
Thank you. Thank you.
I rest my case.
I understood that you were
counsel for the defense.
Indeed. I am. Milord.
But his crime is so blackguardly...
that this is. In fact.
The best defense that can be offered.
I see. Counsel for the prosecution...
do you wish to add to what counsel for
the defense has said?
No. Milord. I would just like to wag
my finger at the accused a few times.
Certainly. Certainly.
Tsk. Tsk. Tsk. Tsk. Tsk.
[Murmuring]
Are there any witnesses
for the defense?
Witnesses. Milord? How can there be?
It is an open-and-shut case.
- He even insulted an officer of the law.
- He called me a nincompoop.
I demand the severest
sentence that milord can cook up.
- [Weasels] Hear! Hear!
- It's not much of a defense. Is it?
Not much. Milord. No. But the best
that can be done in the circumstances.
See the very word guilty
indelibly imprinted upon his brow!
[Weasels Yelling]
- Couldn't the prosecution say something else?
- Silence!
Milord. I should like to speak on behalf
of the defendant.
- No. Sit down! Sit down!
- Do you really want to?
- Oh. Very well.
- Thank you. Milord.
The gentleman you see before you
has not been in his right mind...
- for some time.
- Have.
- Shut up. Toad!
- Uh. Silence in court.
He's suffering from a dementia.
That's a form of madness.
- It's not madness.
- Brought about by motorcars.
Motors are what
make life worth living.
The speed, the thrill.
I'll never give it up.
It's simply... glorious!
Guilty! Guilty!
That's it. That's it.
I am never going to try to help
that worthless animal again!
I've heard enough.
Before I pass sentence upon the prisoner.
Would the jury care to find him guilty?
- [Murmuring]
- I object!
One of those rabbits is a weasel.
No. I'm not. I'm a rabbit.
- Look. He's never a rabbit.
- Is he a rabbit?
- Say I'm a rabbit.
- [All] Yes. He's a rabbit.
Oh. Very well.
How do you find the accused?
Guilty!
I am asking the jury!
Well?
- Say guilty.
- [All] Guilty.
- Guilty.
Prisoner at the bar.
It is the sentence of this court...
that you be taken hence to a place
of lawful execution. There to be hanged...
- What?
- You can't hang him. Milord.
Oh. Oh. Well.
In that case. I sentence you
to as long in jail as I possibly can.
Say, 12 months for theft...
three years for dangerous driving...
and 15 years for cheeking
a police officer.
- He called me a nincompoop.
- So you've told us before.
Nincompoop? Me? Ha.
So 18. uh. 19.
Let's round it up to 20.
Twenty years in the rankest jail
that His Majesty can provide.
[Cheering]
Has the prisoner anything to say?
Yes! Nincompoop!
What?
You're all nincompoops!
- Toad!
- What did I tell you?
I increase the sentence to 25 years.
What do you know
about life. About freedom?
- You're all miserable. One-eyed nincompoops!
- Thirty years!
- What right have you got to judge me?
- Take him down. No. Wait.
- I'm Toad.
- Forty years!
The handsome Toad!
The unstoppable Toad!
d The world has hailed great heroes d
d As history books have shown d
d But never a name to go down to fame
compared with that ofToad d
- Fifty years!
- d The army all saluted d
d As they marched along the road
Oh. Was it the king or the president d
d No. It was Mr. Toad d
d The judge was apoplectic d
- d He thought he might explode d
- Sixty!
d He'd never been faced
with a prisoner as bold and brave d
- d As Mr. Toad d
- [Judge] Seventy!
- d The police could never catch him d
- d He was so nimble-toed d
d He escaped from their clutches
where none has as much as d
d The amazing Mr. Toad d
- Eighty!
- d The officers couldn't believe it d
- d They ooh'd and ah'd and oh'd d
- Oh! Ah! Ohh!
dAs high up above them
he flew like a bird d
d The incredible Mr. Toad dd
Ooh.
- Ninety!
- [Weasels] One hundred!
Done! One hundred years!
Take him away!
No! Have mercy!
Do not incarcerate me
in the dark. Noisome dungeon!
Oh. No! Do not immure me
from the precious light of the sun!
I'll reform!
Oh. Dear! Dear me!
[Thunderclaps]
[Rat]
It's all my fault. Mole.
If only I hadn't left Toad alone.
All for a picnic.
There must be something
we could do.
The minute we leave Toad Hall empty.
The weasels will be in here like...
weasels.
- [Thunderclaps Continue]
- Ratty.
I-I don't know.
Couldn't we spring Toad from jail?
Well. How? He's in the strongest prison
in the land.
I-I may not be very b-brave. But...
I could dig a tunnel.
- [Clattering Sound]
- Moley!
- What was that?
- Just my whiskers.
No. I-I heard something.
We had best stay here
and guard Toad Hall.
After all. With good behavior.
Toad could be out in...
seventy years.
Look out!
[All Yelling]
You're trespassing.
This is a weasel-only area.
And that means nobody's allowed here
except weasels.
- What else could it mean?
- Just making sure they got the point.
[Angry Growling]
[Grunts]
All unloaded. Chief.
You idiot!
Those are meant
to be unloaded here...
and the bones
are to go over to the factory.
Sorry. Chief.
I'll change 'em over.
After dinner.
What do you think
they're after. Ratty?
Whatever it is.
Let's give 'em a hand.
Uh. Why are you
doing that. Rat?
If in doubt. Mole. It's often best
to help keep the weasels confused...
stay one step ahead of their game.
Whatever it is.
Wise old Badger. Sensible Rat.
I should have listened to you.
Oh. This is the end. Toad.
[Weeping]
Buck up. Toad.
I brought you some bubble and squeak
for breakfast.
- Oh. Wretched and unhappy...
Did you say bubble and squeak?
- Mm-hmm.
- Made it myself.
- Oh. What do I care for the pleasures of the flesh?
- Oh. I'll take it away then.
- You don't want to waste it.
[Moans]
I shall never see Toad Hall again.
Toad Hall? That's the place
they're gonna knock down. Isn't it?
I didn't quite catch that.
I thought you said "knock it down."
That's right. The new owners
have decided to knock it down.
New owners?
What are you talking about. Girl?
The old place is mine.
Been in the family for years.
"Toad Hall. The ancestral residence
of the now disgraced Toad family...
is due for demolition
tomorrow morning."
"Weasels. Who say they took
the property over from Mr. Toad...
"when he defaulted on repayment
of six new motorcars...
say it will be reduced
to rubble in 15 seconds."
- They're gonna blow it up.
- Blow up Toad Hall?
It's wonderful what
they can do now. Isn't it?
My father's house.
My sacred trust...
blown to smithereens.
And it's all my fault.
Well. Toad. You'd better stop them.
Talk sense. Girl.
What could I do. Incarcerated here?
Unhappy Toad.
Oh. Toad.
I can't help feeling sorry for you.
- In fact. Truth to tell. I'm really quite fond of you.
- Yes. It's true.
Ladies find me irresistible.
Ouch.
- My aunt's a tea lady.
- That's nothing to brag about.
She's very poor and you're very rich.
Or so you keep telling me.
Oh. Yes. I have
absolutely pots of money.
Well. Then.
- Mole!
- Oh! Oh. Rat.
W-We're nearly there.
I could hear Toad's voice right above me.
Well done. Mole.
- Well. Come on then.
- Oh. Ratty.
This was your idea. Mole.
- Y-Yes. But...
- We can'tjust leave Toad
in there, twiddling his thumbs...
while the weasels
blow up Toad Hall.
You don't expect me
to dress up like that!
Oh? Then you can sit here.
Twiddling your thumbs...
while the weasels
blow up Toad Hall.
Oh. No. No. No. No.
Here's your five guineas.
Right. Get that off.
Careful with that. It's got
all me money in it. What's left of it.
Oh.
Oh. Ratty. There are
two women with him.
Two women?
What are they doing?
Taking his clothes off.
What?
[Woman Grunts]
Now they're dressing him up
in women's clothing.
Perhaps it's some sort of torture.
There. The spitting image.
- I don't look like that.
- It's me that doesn't look like that.
Shut up. Now. You tie Auntie up
while I make sure the coast is clear.
If I thought I looked that ugly...
I would be more than happy
to stay in jail.
- And don't forget to gag her.
- Nothing would give me greater pleasure.
Aah! I mean talk about
the back of a bus.
I'm surprised people don't
catch you to Trafalgar Square.
Silence. Old hag.
Your cries are of no avail
against a desperate Toad! Ha-ha!
- Psst! Toad!
- Who's that?
- It's me.
- Ratty. What on earth are you doing there?
Rescuing you. Come on.
Oh. Don't need rescuing. Old chap.
Got a clever plan
all worked out meself.
But. Toady. All you've gotta do
is follow me. Mole's built this tunnel.
No. A tunnel is no way for an animal
of my mettle to escape.
Us Toads do things
with a bit more dash.
A bit more zing.
Toad!
- Yes?
- Good luck. Toad.
Oh. Right! Thanks a lot.
[Muffled Yelling]
- Ha!
- [Gasps]
If it isn't my sweetheart.
Would you like a cup of tea?
- Where's my kiss?
- Kiss?
- I'll give you a thump.
- But you always give me a kiss.
- You must be mad.
- You're not quite yourself today. Are you. Granny?
[Laughs] On the contrary.
I'm more myself than usual today.
- How's that?
- Because when I'm really myself...
- Yes?
- I give cheeky guards something special.
- And what is that?
- My warmest regards.
- [Steam Hissing]
- Aaah!
Oh. Cripes! Ooh!
Stop! Escaped... prisoner!
Stop!
[Blubbering]
- Up there!
- Up there? Stop! Stop!
[All Shouting]
[Guards Yelling Ferociously]
Stop right there!
[Laughing]
You can't escape.
Oh! Nincompoops!
Ah. That is gross.
Disgusting. Ugh!
- Oh. Hello. You fellows.
- [Alarm Blaring]
Come on!
[Alarm Continues]
[Rat] Why on earth did you insist
on escaping on your own?
You don't think I'd stay there
twiddling my thumbs...
while the weasels blow up
Toad Hall. Do you?
No. No. Of course not.
[Train Whistle Blowing]
Three to Toad-in-the-World. First class.
First class is five
and nine pence each. Granny.
Five and nine pence?
Oh-ho. That's nothing to me.
I can assure you.
I've got it right here... in my...
pocket.
Do get a move on. Madam.
Look here. My man. Give me the tickets
now and I'll send the money on tomorrow.
- Next. Please.
- This is an emergency!
Excuse me. Madam.
- Look out!
- Ah! The hounds of the law!
Save me. Ratty!
[Excited Chattering]
- I can't go in there.
- [Scoffs]
- Look around! This way!
- [Gasping]
- [Train Whistle Blowing]
- [Groaning]
What are we
going to do. Ratty?
I'll never see Toad Hall again
except in a heap of rubble.
[Blows Nose]
Oh. Oh. Oh!
I'm so sorry. Madam.
I didn't see you there.
I'm a poor old tea lady
who's lost all her money.
Unless I get back tonight.
I'll lose my home as well.
- [Conductor] Oh, that's terrible.
- [Sobbing]
A wicked landowner's blowing it up.
[Sobbing]
Aw! I'll let you and your children
ride in my cab.
- Children?
- Ride in your cab?
Oh. Rather! Oh-ho!
- It's strictly against regulation. But...
- [Train Whistle Toots]
- What... Hey. Hey! Hang on!
- No room for you. Cod face!
- Cod face?
- Toad!
- Toad?
- Oh. Yipes! How does this thing work?
Don't touch anything. Wait!
Ho-ho. Faster. Faster!
Make it go faster!
- Toad. You're supposed to be our mother.
- Oh. Phooey.
Hey!
Why is that man waving at us?
Stop this train!
- Crikey. They're on the train.
- Who's on the train?
Stop this train!
Hmm. I'd better see what they want.
No. Don't stop the train. Good.
Kindhearted Mr. Engine driver.
You'd better tell me
what's goin' on.
Alas. I'm not the simple
tea lady I appear to be.
And we are certainly
not his children.
I am a Toad. The well-known and popular
Mr. Toad. A landed proprietor.
- And who are they?
- My evil. Haughty tormenters...
who wish to drag me back
to their loathsome dungeon.
Ajailbird. Eh?
All I did was
borrow a motorcar.
- I don't hold with motorcars.
- Neither do I.
- [Gunshot]
- What's that?
They've no respect for
public transport. That lot.
All they care about is motorcars.
Well. Nobody shoots at my engine!
Hey. Stop that!
Stop this train!
- [Gunshot]
- [Clang]
Oh! That paint was brand new!
I'll show them.
I'll teach you to shoot at my train!
Ow!
- Ooh!
- Ow!
- Oh!
- Motorists!
- [Conductor] Headlight flashers!
- Look out!
I'll show you road lovers...
Hey! Hey! Hey!
You bring back my train. You!
We've lost the driver.
Yippie! Hoo-hoo-hoo!
I found it. I found it!
- What. The brake?
- No. The accelerator.
- Yah! [Whooping]
- Toad. No!
Leave it to me. I'll get 'em.
Ow!
- Ooh!
- Keep me covered. Moley.
I can't throw for toffee.
Just throw it.
- Eighty miles an hour!
- [Whistle Toots]
- Ow!
- Sorry!
Eighty-four miles an hour. Eighty-five!
I wonder if it'll go a hundred!
- Look out!
- Drop that or I'll shoot.
- I wonder what that does.
- I have given you the official warnin'!
- [Screaming]
- It's the brake.
- Toad!
- Mole. Come and give me a hand.
- I can't!
Yes. You can. Mole.
Come on!
Ninety-one, ninety-two.
Why won't it go any faster?
- [Screaming]
Oh. Crikey. Uh...
Wh-What should I do now?
Uh. Ratty...
- Uh... Uh... Oh! Uh...
- Hang on. Mole.
Uh... Help!
[Groaning]
Oh-ho! Uh. Uh!
Now!
[Toad]
Ninety-five, ninety-six!
It is going faster! Hooray!
Oh. Come on. Come on!
Hee-hee!
I'm so sorry. Ratty.
You did your best. Moley.
[Toad]
Hoo-hoo! Hoo-hoo! Hoo-hoo!
I always mess things up.
All right, you two, hands up.
[Thud, Crash]
[Toad]
One hundred and twenty miles an hour!
Hooray! This is fantastic. Ratty!
Ratty? Ratty?
Ratty. Where are you?
Ratty? Oh! Oh!
[Loud Crash]
Pooh. Pooh.
d Oh. Nobody knew
how to catch him d
d So clever and nimble-toed d
d They couldn't snitch or snatch him d
d That elusive Mr. Toad dd
Right. We'd better go
and find Badger.
That way...
Moley? Mole.
Mole!
Moley.
I'm not brave like you. Ratty...
or strong and fierce like Badger.
You are very brave. Moley.
I'm just a spineless nobody.
- You don't want someone like me as a friend.
- Moley.
I'm going home. Ratty. I'm sorry.
Moley!
Oh! Ouch! Bother.
Oooh!
- Going home. Are we. Toad?
- Yes.
Better hurry.
I'll be setting soon.
How far is it to Toad Hall?
Oh. A long way yet.
[Groaning]
Yes. I can see everything
from up here.
That's the great thing about being... the sun.
[Chuckling]
Can you see what
those weasels are up to?
They're putting the dynamite
into Toad Hall.
Dynamite.
Ohh. I'm beginning to set.
[Sobbing]
All is lost. Wretched Toad.
Shouldn't have gone around
stealing motorcars.
- Didn't.
- Did.
- Didn't!
- I saw it all! Did.
- Oh. Go away!
- Not until it's time.
[Car Horn Honking]
Ha-ha! Toad's luck holds again.
I'll spin up one
of my highly sophisticated yarns.
[Honking]
- [Honking Continues]
- [Brakes Squealing]
[Groans]
Help.
I'm a poor old tea lady who can't...
Oh. Yipes! It's you lot.
Toad. What are you
doing out of jail?
Hmph! I escaped by great daring
and cleverness.
And I demand you hand back
Toad Hall immediately.
- Of course. It's all yours.
- Oh.
We were just looking after it for you.
Toady. While you were in jail.
- Oh. Thanks.
- Toad?
- Yes?
- Why are you dressed like this?
Oh. Master of disguise.
Fooled everyone.
You're a clever one
and no mistake, Toad.
Yes. Drove a train. Just like that.
Did you? Well. We've got a new motor
we'd like you to... test for us.
A new motor? Oh. Rather!
- It's got a motor.
- Sort of experimental. Is it?
- That's it.
- Oh. Yipes!
[Toad]
Pooh, pooh!
Badger?
Yesterday. Mole End.
Tomorrow. Toad Hall.
Today they're in the wildwood.
No.
No. I can't have that.
Oh. No.
Oh. Funny-looking motor.
How's it work?
Let me show you. Toad.
This motor drives...
this wheel here.
That turns the axle
attached to which...
are these blades here.
- Oh. Yes. I see.
- They rotate...
and the screw squeezes the raw material
through those holes.
Oh. Sort of mincing machine. Is it?
Smart fellow.
Yes. Always was quick
on the uptake.
But tell me. Where do I fit in?
- [Weasels Laughing]
- [Wheezing]
[Chattering, Shouting]
dd [Drunken Singing]
dd [Singing Continues]
- They're all drunk.
- Good.
Then they won't be
expecting anyone.
You stay here.
[Thuds]
I say. Badger.
[Shouting, Cheering]
Hang on a sec. Badger.
What on earth
are you doing there?
Just confusing the weasels.
Tried to be like you. Ratty...
but I'm not.
I belong here. Underground.
Tea... time.
I'm so sorry. Ratty.
My dear friend.
[Burps]
You're missin' the party.
- [Badger] Evening, friend.
- Funny-lookin' weasels.
- Eeeh!
- Ow!
Here. You're no weasels at all.
Who are they then?
Oh. Dear. You can get that off
with a little bit of salt.
- Let's find the Chief Weasel.
- He's right behind you.
What under earth?
"Dog food factory."
They destroyed my home...
to build a dog food factory.
Move it!
Come on. Get in.
Oh.
Dog food factory.
No! This is... Help!
You wanted to see how the mincer works.
Toad. From the inside.
- [Toad Whimpering]
- Fly eater!
- Put me down!
- Pond lover!
Oh! Put me down! Stop!
Oh! Put me down! Please!
- Oh. No! Stop!
- Oh!
Oh! Oh-ho!
- Put me down! Oh!
- [Shouting]
[Whimpering]
Wait!
I've got a better recipe.
Put 'em all in together.
Ooh-la-la! Tres haute cuisine.
Shut up!
You know. You've convinced me.
I'm not going to blow up Toad Hall
tomorrow after all.
I'm gonna blow it up tonight!
Make 'em into sausages
and slice 'em up!
[Toad Whimpering]
Oh. Help! Help! Save me!
[Toad]
Oh! Stop it! Stop all this now! I insist!
Uh! Oh! Uh!
[Gagging]
[Screaming]
[Cheering]
[Toad Whimpering]
It's out of order?
I don't know. Down!
Help me. Ooh!
[Whimpering]
Oh. It's...
[Disgusted Groan]
Oh.
- Better put that down before
someone gets hurt. Moley.
- I-I-I'll shoot.
But you've only got one shot.
Give me the gun...
and we'll all be friends.
Friends? I thought you said
there was no such thing.
Oh. Come on!
That was just an intro to a song.
- [Cocks Gun]
- You destroyed my home to build
a dog meat factory.
The area needs one.
Our market research shows...
- You put my friends in a mincer!
- Just a harmless joke.
- Steady on. [Stammering]
- [Badger Laughing]
I say. Badger!
I'm not really a weasel.
I'm a rabbit.
They forced me to work here.
And you saved me.
- Oh. Thank you. Thank you!
- Shut up. Keep moving.
"Auto." Oh. Good.
We can drive home.
No! Don't touch anything!
[Alarm Blaring]
- Hmm?
- [Clanging]
[Screaming]
[Cheering, Shouting]
Quiet!
- Shh!
The chief has
an announcement to make.
Yes. Quiet! The chief has
- Shut up. Geoffrey!
- Gentlemen!
Fellow members of
Weasel Development Limited.
The dog food factory
is in production...
as from a few moments ago!
[Cheering]
The demolition ofToad Hall...
has been brought forward
to tonight!
[Cheering]
In its place...
we will build a slaughterhouse...
capable of processing all forms
of river-dwelling life.
[Cheering]
Oh. Settle down!
In exactly 15 minutes...
Toad Hall will be...
- history!
- [Cheering]
- [Badger] You imbecile. Toad!
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
I am never going to try
to help you ever again!
Call Mummy Weasel.
I'm going to get minced!
[Cheering. Shouting]
I'm blowing up this place
in ten minutes...
whether or not you lot
are out of it!
Chief. Wait!
The boys have got a little...
surprise for you.
Surprise?
It can wait ten minutes.
No. No. No. We think
you'd like it now.
[Toad Whimpering]
Help! Somebody!
Oh. Dear. Oh. Dear.
I can't throw for toffee.
Moley. Did you do that?
Yes. Rat.
[All Chattering]
- Happy birthday, Chief.
- d For he's a jolly good weasel d
[All]
d For he's a jolly good weasel d
d And so say all of us dd
Three cheers for the chief!
Hip-hip!
Hooray!
How did you know
it was my birthday?
Aren't you going
to blow them out?
Too bad you couldn't
stick around...
'cause I'm in charge now.
[Laughing]
- No. No. No. I'm in charge now.
- What?
- Grab 'em. Boys!
- [Shouting]
You devious...
Too bad none of you
could stick around!
- Did you let them in here?
- Of course I didn't.
Yes. You did.
- Oh. No. I didn't.
- Bother.
Didn't.
[Laughing]
Aaaah!
d It's a pleasure to have you here
Mr. Badger d
d So good of you
to ask me. Mr. Toad d
d And as for dear Mole
I'm so glad you left your hole d
d And came to join you here
in your abode d
d We were born
on the same riverbank d
d What's mine is yours is his d
d Raised where the willows
slip into the water d
d We get along
like cheese and porter d
d Every morn we each
give a thank d
d For friends is what we is d
- dd [Continues Faintly]
- You've got it comin' to you.
You garbage!
d Helping each other
like friends all ought to d
dd [Continues Quietly]
Uh. Toad.
You do the countdown.
Why. You...
you. You. You weasel!
Come on, Toad.
You can count down from ten, surely!
Ten. Nine...
Where are you. Toad?
I'll have to do it myself.
Eight. Seven. Six...
Toad, can you hear?
Five... Only four to go.
Then it's good-bye to Toad Hall.
Four... Now what comes after four?
Oh. I know!
Three. Two. One!
Aaah!
- [Toad Gasping]
- Blowing up Toad Hall is only the beginning.
You won't recognize
this dump when I'm finished!
- But why? Why destroy this beautiful place?
- Why?
Because it will make me
extremely rich.
- Aah! Aah!
- Ow!
[Screaming]
Sorry you couldn't stick round
for the fireworks.
Badger! Ratty! Mole!
d Every morn we each give a thank d
d That friends is what we is dd
Ratty! Moley! Get out!
Ten. Nine. Eight. Seven. Six.
Five. Four. Three. Two. One.
Oh. My friends.
It's all my fault.
Badger. Ratty...
dear Mole.
[Sobbing]
All my fault.
[Running Footsteps]
[Badger]
What the devil was that?
Well. looks as if we certainly confused
those weasels.
You mean... you swapped the...
And they put the explosives
in the dog meat factory.
And then...
Oh. You clever old Ratty.
Oh, you did well, Rat.
- [Laughing] Oh. Boy!
- [Laughing]
And so Toad Hall was saved...
by my daring and cleverness.
I shall now narrate how I escaped
from jail. Stole a train...
and single-handedly defeated
the weasels' plans...
to destroy the riverbank.
- [Applause On Gramophone]
- Thank you.
But first. A little song.
Oh. No. You don't.
- Oh. Hello. You chaps.
- Toad. What are these?
- Oh. My invitation cards. Something...
- They're disgraceful.
"Program of entertainment:
Speech by Toad;
"song by Senor Enrico Toado;
"conjuring tricks.
The Great Toadini;
juggling. The Amazing Toadisto!"
Now. Iook here. Toad. Understand
there are to be no speeches and no songs.
May I sing just one little one?
- Toady. You know your songs are
just full of self-praise and...
- Gas.
You've got to turn over a new leaf.
For all our sakes.
My friends. I am a proud
and stupid Toad.
Henceforth,
I will be very different.
No more boasting. No more fads.
I know now there's more to life
than motorcars.
I certainly hope so.
[Together]
Sing us a song. Mr. Toad.
- [Crowd Murmuring]
- No. No more songs.
- Oh. Go on. Mr. Toad.
- Shh!
Well. Maybe just one little one.
- [Crowd Murmuring]
- No. Toad!
Come on. And you. Moley.
d We were born
on the same riverbank d
d What's mine is yours is his d
d Raised where the willows
creep into the water d
d We get along
like cheese and porter d
d Every morn we each give a thank d
d For friends is what we is d
d We have sworn
by the same riverbank d
d What's mine is yours is his d
dd [Continues Faintly]
Ah. Mr. Toad.
I'm afraid I could only
get you the one.
d Every morn we each give a thank d
d For friends is d
d What we is dd
- [Applause]
- [Airplane Approaching]
- [Crowd Exclaiming]
- It's Toad!
[Laughs]
Hello. You chaps!
Ooh. Sorry. You rabbits.
That's the last time I ever try...
to help that. That...
- Pooh! Pooh!
- d Ooh, ooh, miracle d
d Ooh, ooh, miracle d
[Man]
d You know his name and he's conceited d
d Drives the wrong side
of the road d
d From his brains
down to his feet it's clear d
- d He's just a foolish Toad d
- Whoo-hoo!
- d Even though you know
the games he's playin' d
- Careful, Toad.
- d And he'll drive you round the bend d
- [Engine Sputtering]
d Somewhere deep inside
a voice keeps sayin' d
d He's a friend d
d There's a candle
in the darkness burning bright d
d Ooh, ooh
Candle burning bright d
d A fireside welcome
in the stormy night d
d Ooh, ooh
In the stormy night d
d Thats's the way the story ends d
d It's the miracle of friends d
d There's a candle
in the darkness burning bright d
d Ooh, ooh, miracle d
d In the world so full of strangers d
- d Everybody needs a friend d
- [Toad Hooting]
d Someone to help you
through the dangers d
d Wait around the bend d
d Even when the dark
is all around you d
d Not a star up in the sky d
d Wait until the light
of friendship's found you d
d You'll get by d
d There's a candle
in the darkness burning bright d
d Ooh, ooh
Candle burning bright d
d A fireside welcome
in the stormy night d
d Ooh, ooh
In the stormy night d
d That's the way the story ends d
d It's the miracle of friends d
d There's a candle
in the darkness burning bright d
d Ooh, ooh, miracle d
d Ooh, ooh, miracle dd