---DVDrip and Subs by bObleJet---
Good morning.
You lie to me!
It's not the first time anymore.
Last week the property transaction
was more than $400,000.
True?
And?
I've expected you
to know the other $300,000.
I'll transfer to you anyway.
You know I must check,
why do you try to play tricks?
You're a smart girl!
But in a case I've played some tricks on,
and you'll never know.
Kelvin's case, $500,000.
Anyway, I'll give you a share.
As our 5th Anniversary gift. Like it?
It's very difficult for you
to find a husband as honest as me.
Hello, yes! Don't panic,
I think the market is good.
I think I can't make it. Mr. Chu.
Hi, good morning!
Today is really nice.
I'd just finished an American breakfast
with my wife downstairs.
- That's why we come to visit you!
- Yeah...
Good business?
Have you received
that 10 million dollars yet?
Go home first, alright?
I'll wait for your call.
Please wait...
Wait.
Good morning.
Mrs. Yau, they are waiting for you
in the meeting.
I know it.
Ha...someone sent you flowers.
Who sent it?
I don't know.
Do you know who is the father?
I know, it's my husband!
It's really put yourself to hell
to have baby in these days!
OK, meeting adjourn! Let's continue
to make money for the company.
The meeting is over yet?
We've waited for you for an hour already!
It's not over yet,
I've a case to discuss with your guys.
I'll take care of the Chung Chi's case.
Only if we give them
3 million dollars bribe money.
Then they will give us
all confidential documents.
I've decided to give this case to Roy.
Give it to him! Are you sure?
I've my acquaintance in Chung Chi,
I'll win this case definitely.
Save your trouble,
I've just confirmed the deal
with the chairman of Chung Chi.
Who do you know?
The one who handle rubbish
or the one who clean the toilet?
Why are you so eager to grab every case?
Let me ask you,
how many cases
have you won these 6 months?
Do you know your own record?
Zero! It's zero!
You're in bad luck,
why don't you take a vacation?
I just come to inform you,
I'll take care of everything.
I'm not trying to solicited the job.
It's company business,
we cannot transfer it between us.
It's from here, by brainstorming!
Let me ask you guys,
who makes the most profit
for the company?
Boss, I begin to question your judgement!
Oh yeah, you said
you'll have your vacation before retired,
how come you're still in the office?
Boss, are you OK?
Boss...
What makes you so angry?
It's personal matters!
What's the matter? You haven't made love
with your husband, have you?
It's not your business!
Don't you like man to send you flowers?
I don't like man-playing tricks.
This is my style.
The stronger the woman,
the more I want to push her down...
To see how she behaves in bed.
You're disgusting.
I'm more disgusting than you may expect.
I want you teach him a lesson.
Here is the toilet.
I know.
You got to wash your hands and face
in the washroom.
Mr. Yau, I just come to let you know,
this is my last day!
Do you feel
there's no prospect in this office?
No...
Thank you, Mr. Yau.
Young man ought to
see more about the world.
Leave me your telephone number.
- When you're rich, give me a treat.
- Sure...
- Mr. Yau.
- Go back to work.
Attorney Lau...
I've found what you asked me to get.
I've found the paper
with doctor's signature.
See where is it...
This and these are other documents.
My sisters said, you'd have lucky money
before proceeding to court.
This is three hundred.
It should be alright, shouldn't it?
Call for the first defendant
Chan Ngan Sun.
Regarding this patient Yu Ping Wah
was injected with...
wrong medicine and causing paralyzed.
With my deepest regret to his family
on behalf of the hospital.
And I hereby
declared as a practicing doctor.
I've not signed any such authorization,
and I've not given any hints
to Madam Ma to give injection.
I've worked in this hospital
for 13 years.
And my principle is:
More job, more mistakes; less job,
less mistakes; no job, no mistake,
so how would I bother to
give injection to the patient?
If you didn't give me the authorization,
I'd not have done such thing!
According to the record
from the hospital.
You've been complaint
by patients' families,
for 18 times in these 13 years,
including your bad attitude,
yelled at patients,
stole their food.
And watched TV in the private wards,
and to smoke during your shift.
According to these evident,
it is proven that the defendant
is not just a heartless...
but also and irresponsible nurse.
So, it is not surprising
we accuse the second defendant...
of misinjection.
Why don't you talk about something nice?
Many patients have come to visit me
after they left the hospital.
They also bought me lots of food.
The defendant please control yourself.
Sorry, but I've evidences.
I've got the authorization
with Dr. Chan's signature,
I've got it!
Attorney Lau.
Here are the documents
presented to the court,
but there is no such document!
No? How come? Attorney Lau.
It's not true! I've given you by hand
just at the entrance!
I really have such document.
My verdict is:
the first defendant
Chan Ngan Sun is not acquitted,
and the second defendant
Ma Mei Chun is quality.
I sentenced her
to pay $400,000 as compensation.
Attorney Lau...
- Thank you very much.
- Don't mention it.
I've got your cheque already.
But remember to be careful the next time.
OK...thank you.
Why do you keep it? Burn it!
OK...Burn it...
Bitch...
Bitch...Damn you...
- Claim down.
- Get lost!
You make me lose everything!
Bitch, don't let me see you again!
Or else you must die!
A tooth for a tooth, an eye for an eye!
You said you're going to
have lunch with my wife?
What is the 10 million US dollars
mentioned by my hubby this morning?
Haven't I told you not to be fussy?
OK! lt'll be alright!
Anyway, I'll give him more pressure
in the court tomorrow.
I've your money,
of course I know what to do.
OK, trust me. Bye!
What are you doing?
Looking for something?
You've taken my 10 million,
haven't you?
I've tried to
give you a chance this morning.
I thought you'd be honest to me
about the money,
but you didn't, you even lied to me.
You're really cunning.
You helped the Thai
to wash the black money?
Even up to 10 million US dollars?
Give me just half million
as anniversary gift?
Thank you!
To be honest. How much more
are you trying to hide from me?
So, this 10 million will be mine,
as a compensation.
Do you know
how important this money is to me!
The Thai is not ordinary guy,
they'll kill me.
I guess you don't want me to be killed.
We're still a couple, right?
Couple?
Do you remember
the last time you sleep with me?
Have you tried to treat me as your wife?
Couple should sleep in separate rooms!
I don't even have the key to your room!
I almost forgot how your dick looks like!
Guess I have to ask Chu's wife.
She knows it better!
- Have you finished yet?
- No!
OK! I've slept with other woman,
and not just one, alright?
Why don't you look at yourself?
Do you expect me to sleep with you?
What do you want me to do?
Come on! Hit me!
Shoot me! Come on! Shoot me!
I don't think you have the guts to do it!
Do you know what you're good at?
Cheat woman's money
and cozy woman to bed!
You looked pale
when I mentioned the Thai!
Son of a bitch!
Come on! Kill me!
If you can't, I'll go!
I don't want this 10 million!
I call the police
and tell them everything, damn you!
Hello. May I speak to Fan Shu Hung?
I'm Mr. Yau.
Well, I want to see you.
You're alone?
Well, I've something to talk to you.
You know my address, don't you?
OK, see you later!
Mr. Yau, what is it so urgent?
Please come in!
I had lots of thing to do in the office,
so I was home late.
When I opened the door,
I heard my wife shout upstairs.
I didn't know what's happening.
I saw her run down...
Mr. Yau, is this modern art?
Isn't it expensive?
Sorry! Go on!
Where am I?
I heard my wife from upstairs. Oh no!
She ran down and rushed to the door.
I saw her hand with a gun.
I didn't know why we fight together,
anyway, I...Got her gun. I shot her.
Have you learned Karate?
I've too! Go on!
I've learned Karate,
but that was long ago.
Sir, the woman is still alive.
The patient got a shot in the forehead.
The bullet got through
the brain nervous system.
This thief is really cold-blooded.
Where am I up to?
Oh yeah, it is Pathology,
caused by the bursting of blood vessel,
and blocked the circular system
in the brain.
If it is just a temporary lack of oxygen,
it won't cause any permanent disability.
But, Mr. Yau
I hope you will get prepared.
Your wife may become coma.
Dr. Lee, I don't care how much money,
you must cure my wife.
"INTENSIVE CARE WARD"
Sorry!
Sorry! You know I don't want it.
You're my wife,
we've married for so long.
How will I hurt you?
But don't provoke me,
you can't put me to test.
Anyway, it's over, let's forget it!
Please tell me where you hide the money.
The money is very important to me!
You don't want me to be killed.
Where is the money?
Don't pretend,
I know you hear what I'm saying.
Call Dr. Lee immediately.
Let's rush to see her!
OK, please tell Mr. Naichai,
I'll go to Bangkok tomorrow.
I'll explain to him.
OK!
- Please give this report to Dr. Wu.
- Yes!
This patient in the ward
has been unconscious for several weeks.
You may come to
exercise her legs and arms!
You're almost the Nurse-in-chief
in your previous hospital.
You ought to know how to do!
I'll leave this to you, I'm leaving.
Hello, aren't you dead?
God! So young!
I help you to exercise!
Come on!
You bitch!
You made me lose my position,
and made me lose my job,
and have to listen to people's order!
Go to hell!
Bitch! I must kill you!
Shut up.
How strange, she shouldn't be awake.
Quick! Call her husband.
Her husband is not in Hong Kong.
Miss Ma, how did you wake her up?
I...I told her to get up...
and enter the Miss Hong Kong Pageant.
Then...then she become conscious!
Oh! Don't bite me!
Stop...
I said, "stop", and she'll stop.
But you can't speak in Mandarin "stop",
she won't stop, you have to say "Stop!".
Mrs. Yau, please have a seat!
Stop...
Why don't you remember what I told you?
See what have you done?
You wanna ruin yourself.
Delicious...
It's really delicious.
How are you?
That's right. Take the medicine!
And you'll regain your memory.
Drink the water! Drink it!
I made the promise before I went abroad,
of course I can do it!
I even went to Thailand
and explain it to you.
Why are you so mysterious?
Haven't I seen you for 2 weeks.
Where have you been?
My husband told me
you're not doing so well lately.
Do you need any help?
My husband also said...
Have you said enough?
You've been talking about your husband
since you came up.
What's so special about him?
He's just a dog.
One of my dogs!
Oh, I'm sorry,
I won't dare, don't get mad!
I won't mention him again!
Do you want?
Don't, it's bad luck
if we do it in the office.
Hello, yes, who's calling?
Pardon?
What did you say?
Why don't you let me know immediately
that my wife is awake.
Once you're back,
you said not to be disturbed,
how can I tell you?
Did my wife mention anything about me
when she woke up?
Mrs. Yau won't remember a thing now.
Actually, I think it's a miracle
that she can wake up.
Now, it all depends on you
to stimulate her memory.
I've arranged somebody
to look after her 24 hours.
Darling.
Sit!
Patient losing memory
normally will attack others.
However, you don't have to be afraid,
Miss Ma will handle her.
Sit!
You scared me to death,
what do you think you are doing?
Bye. Never want to see you again!
What's happening?
Help...
This woman is crazy, she beats me!
Yes, she's always like this!
- Luckily, you didn't break your leg!
- She is crazy!
Let it be...
I'm scared.
Is that true?
Is it really $100,000 per month!
He gives me $100,000 per month!
You go and tell the Chief,
I'm taking a vacation!
$100,000...Bye!
Sit!
This money is hard to earn.
She is hard to be looking after!
This house is great!
So large and beautiful!
Though there's not many people in it.
Are you thirsty?
Hold it...
Do you want to drink some water?
The kitchen is over there.
Help yourself! Go!
Mr. Yau, even if I ask for $100,000 more,
you still have to give that!
What's wrong?
You can't take it for granted.
She's my wife, I can handle her!
If you can last 10 seconds,
then you're great.
Come in.
I quit!
I'll pay you $30,000 more each month?
OK, I'll stay.
Come on, I'll drive you home
and pick up your clothes.
I'm not used to strange beds.
How much more do you want
to stay overnight?
- $3,000.
- OK! Dead!
What if I ask for $4,000.
I expected you to say $40,000.
Shit!
Go.
From now on,
you have to report to me of what...
she eats, does and says.
I'll give you $3,000
for every useful news.
I'll be back any time!
Mr. Yau, don't you live here?
Are you two OK? Why did you say that?
We're friends, you can tell me!
Calm down!
It's so frightening, I had a bad dream.
Someone wants to kill me.
What's wrong with you?
I just had a bad dream, and I'm scared!
Don't be frightened! Go back to sleep!
I can't, I'm too scared!
OK, don't go to sleep.
But I'm sleepy, stay with me please.
You're troublesome. Come on, sit here.
Sit here and sleep,
you won't have bad dream anymore.
If you have any more bad dreams,
I'll eat them up.
I'll be with you, be quiet!
Or else, I'll kick you!
Be honest,
this medicine was banned in the States,
because the side effect is very strong.
The patient many have headache,
if worst, it may be fatal.
Who are you going to give this to?
Your wife?
No, you said it's got side effects!
Of course,
I won't give this to my wife. Stupid.
Then don't!
Hey, don't forget
I bought you the doctor license.
- Mr. Yau.
- Listen.
Remember to give this potion to Mrs. Yau.
Four times a day!
Time to take the medicine.
Hold it yourself.
Mr. Yau, Mrs. Yau is taking the potion.
Go to bed.
Mr. Yau, would you like some coffee?
Mr. Yau, here's the report.
The first one must worth $3,000!
Mrs. Yau screamed
in her dream last night at 10:45,
she said...
What did she say?
Then this will be the second news.
So total $6,000 Mr. Yau.
She said she was chased by somebody.
Mr. Yau, I see you're not a mean guy.
I give you another goods news.
Mrs. Yau has just gone out.
Happy Birthday to you...
Thank you.
Make a wish before you cut the cake.
- Really...
- It's not necessary!
You have to!
Then, do I need to close my eye
to make the wish?
- Of course...
- As you wish...
What wish should I make?
OK...I hope my husband will love me more!
My daughter will have lots of boyfriends.
That's all!
Mrs. Yau.
Oh, it's good to have you back!
You're back, I can retire now!
Do you know
the Chung Chi's case is a tough one!
Chung Chi? Who is he?
Chung Chi Enterprises. Remember,
we've earned 10 million for this.
Don't you remember?
Please feel free to walk around,
make yourself at home.
Make yourself at home.
I'm going to a meeting. Excuse me.
Mrs. Yau, would you like some cake?
Am I really that dreadful?
Please tell me. I want to know.
What is this?
This is your past record file.
This girl is cute.
She was raped by several rich guys.
And then?
You helped those guys
to win the case and got 5 million.
Then what happened to her?
That girl finally jumped off the window
and killed herself.
Don't you remember?
And this, a 80 years old man was
forced to move out from his apartment.
Not only he couldn't get any money,
you even sued him,
and put him to jail.
Don't worry! Look at her!
She's insane, she has lost her memory.
How would I get her back?
Don't worry!
Are you OK?
- Who are you?
- Me?
I'm your only friend here.
Let's go for a drink!
Here is very windy. Let's go to my place?
Oh no, I want to go home.
You really lost your memory?
I've never heard
you saying you want to go home.
Really, how come I don't like going home?
You have also done many things.
Like what?
I'll do it again,
so you may remember the past, alright?
My head is killing me!
Don't touch me, go away!
What are you doing?
Nothing...
is there anything wrong with you?
Sorry!
I just want you to know.
No one can take away anything
that's mine.
OK, it's my fault. Sorry.
I won't do it again. Sorry!
Attorney Chan!
How come you're so cheap,
if you want to date other's wife?
Don't you think you deserve it?
Thank you!
It's ridiculous, he said he's my friend,
but how come he treats me like this?
Then why did you believe him?
It's so good that you show up on time.
Where is Miss Ma?
Come and drink it. It's good for you.
- I don't want to drink it!
- Come on!
Sorry. This medicine is good for you.
It can make you remember the past.
I don't want to remember! I was so bad,
why'd I remember all these?
- I don't want it!
- Mr. Yau.
Mr. Yau.
Where have you been?
My friend's getting married.
I just go to buy her something.
Did I pay you to shop?
No.
Give her the medicine.
OK, Mr. Yau.
You're a trouble-maker, you're worthless.
Come, come and have your medicine...
Go to hell!
That doctor gave you $250,000,
then you kept the evidences.
You made me broke!
What sort of woman you are?
Bitch!
Bloody bastard! No one likes you.
No one wants to get close to you.
You devil, you harmed everybody!
Why did you wake up?
Damn it! Why not remain coma and die?
What's this bloody picture, all white!
Is this art?
Bitch, open the door!
What happened? How come you
don't open the door for me.
My hands are occupied,
how can I open the door!
Why are you crying?
You've already got all the best!
Get up and take your medicine.
You're so bad!
Don't be lazy, get up! I said get up!
What's happening?
- I'm so worst...
- What makes you likes this?
You've got everything you want,
why do you want to die?
How about those who's got cancer?
And the sick who lost all their hair?
Why do you have to die?
What the hell are you doing?
Death can't solve anything!
You'll even hurt me if you dead!
Don't you know it?
Remember you've made me suffer once.
Do you recall it?
It's better to forget everything
and start all over again.
You don't have to do it? Understand?
You see, your skin is so nice.
It's no good to have a scar here!
I know you were very bad!
But so what, you're smart.
You can start again.
You can help the need.
It's good to be able to help! Right?
Like a goddess, alright?
Now, alright, don't cry any more.
I'll fix you something to eat, OK?
Now remember, be a good girl,
and don't tell your husband about this.
Or else if he fires me, I'll be dead!
Then I won't be able to
take care of you again, right?
Stop crying...
Oh shit! It's awful,
I don't remember how to wrap it!
Coffee.
Brother Lung, I'm so scared,
you've got to help me.
What's up?
That guy from Thailand
called me this morning.
I was shaking all over
when I picked up that phone.
My hands are still shaking now, you see.
Why didn't he call me instead?
Yeah, that's why I feel so strange.
I told him on the phone
that you are my big brother.
- I only listen to you.
- What are you talking about?
I'm talking about money.
That 10 million dollars.
He asked
why hasn't he received them by now.
That's funny.
OK, ask yourself. You've co-operated
with that Thailand guy for so long,
and you've washed so much black money
for him. It's OK so far.
Now it's only 10 million dollars.
I really can't stand it.
Brother Lung,
are you really doing OK now?
Tell me, see if I can help.
I'll handle it myself.
You don't have to do it this way.
It's money. I've got to be more careful.
What are you talking about?
You told me so.
I memorize that since then.
Now.
Talking about that 10 million dollars.
What happens to my share?
You know I've got 10 apartments
in Hung Shan Peninsula.
I can't take it anymore now.
Is this beautiful?
It looks good.
This shirt is very expensive. Thank you.
Do you think Mr. Yau would mind
if I don't wear uniform?
You don't have to bother about.
I like you dressing like this.
I don't like you wearing uniform.
I'll buy you
the matching trousers next time.
Good. Thank you.
Why are you always looking so angry
when you take a photo?
Where are your photos with your husband?
Is this the only one?
Where are your wedding pictures?
I don't think we have taken that.
Are you serious?
You don't even have wedding photo.
Oh, no, I really don't think
I've taken any!
It's OK as long as I've got a husband.
Is that true?
How can it be so ugly?
Did your husband give you this?
I just picked it up.
When I was young,
my family was very poor,
there's no money to buy any dolls.
My father left us long time ago.
This doll was picked up...
by my mother in the market.
It's head has already fallen apart!
Then my mother said
she would mend it for me.
However, she was dead
before she could fix it.
I remembered when she's dying.
I've made a vow that...
I must be rich...
and I was going to buy a thousand dolls
to put beside her tomb.
I succeeded in doing this when I was 20.
The money come from...A man gave me that.
I went to bed with a fat and ugly guy.
It's him who gave me money
to go to university!
What do you think of this color?
Any color is better than the old one.
That's true, I just don't understand
why your husband like this stuff.
Don't mention my husband all the time.
Do you have a husband?
I wanted to!
But I've never had any date before!
I don't think I'll get any chance.
I'm old and ugly.
- I won't take the medicine.
- Even if you want to, nothing is left.
Remember? When you tried to
kill yourself last time.
You kicked it over!
I've gone to the hospital to
get some more. But, don't tell Mr. Yau.
Is Mr. and Mrs. Yau here, please?
That guy was quite good looking.
Why did he have to be a thief?
She doesn't know anything.
He's got a gun.
Why didn't he rob a bank or a goldsmith?
But robbed her?
She doesn't know anything.
Mrs. Yau, I just come to
ask for more information.
She hasn't recovered yet,
I don't think she can help you any way.
OK, then, I'll go now, Mrs. Yau.
I am cooking some fish, shrimps and soup.
Why don't you stay over for the meal
and we can talk.
May be we'll come up something.
Come on, sit here!
Oh, no,
my wife is waiting for me at home.
Mrs. Yau,
we are suspecting
that dead man coming in...
did not just come to rob, but...
So what? If you got anything to say.
Talk to my lawyer.
Could you stop disturbing my wife?
Mr. Yau, it's only our procedure!
Mr. and Mrs. Yau. I'll go now.
Shrimp.
Yes, I'll tell my wife
to cook some shrimps tonight.
I'm felling better now.
It's all Miss Ma's help.
She taught me how to make this soup.
Is she good to you?
- Did you say she's fierce?
- No, I haven't.
Today, I remembered
many things about my childhood.
I think I'm going to gain back my money.
Do you want to have some more?
You go on, I will take it myself.
Mr. Yau, you want some more soup?
This's delicious. My wife told me
it's you taught her to make the soup.
Yes, that's right.
- I can do it myself.
- OK.
She's feeling better now. Thank you.
Don't mention it. Mr. Yau,
I've got your money, so I will do it.
Do you feel that
she's not so scared about me recently?
Yes, that's good.
Starting tonight,
I'll keep her companion myself.
Good.
You want to fire me? Mr. Yau,
do you really want to fire me?
Not enough?
No, it's more than enough.
Thank you, Mr. Yau.
I can retire now.
When should I leave?
I'll leave tonight!
I just don't understand
who do you leave now?
If you really want to go,
why not wait till tomorrow.
Where can you go now? It's so late.
I will be going back to my doom.
Mr. Yau, he said he would come back
to take care of you himself.
That's good, right?
Don't look back!
Turn a new page, OK?
You two will go fonder after
you're separated for a little while.
You can walk around naked at your home.
Right?
It's not convenient if I am here.
Is that true?
Can I see you again?
Of course,
you can treat me lunch or dinner.
And I can come
and visit you again some time, OK?
Don't be upset, go inside.
- I will walk you out!
- There's no need.
Go inside and have a good time!
Go inside, bye.
After Miss Ma left, there will be
only you and me in this house.
I really want to help you
to remember all the past.
You've got to help me.
How are we getting along in the past?
We seldom stay home together.
I must be always working
in my lawyer firm.
I'm definitely not a good wife.
Why did you marry me?
Because I'm worse than you!
I pretend to be a broker,
but I'm really helping someone
to wash black money.
Other than Hong Kong,
I've also got many clients
in USA and South-East Asia.
Do you know that
the money earned by my company,
you can have a share.
I also have a share?
Thailand guy asked me
to wash 10 million black money.
And you've hidden the money
before you lost your money.
Why did I have to
hide your 10 million dollars.
Because you wanted to set me up.
Do you know that the Thailand guy
is forcing me to return the money.
If you can't remember
where you have put it,
then we will be in big trouble.
I can't, I can't remember.
Don't think of it now,
you can't remember that this way.
I'll take you to play a game.
It is exciting!
What would we be playing?
It's what we used to play.
You must love it.
Sorry, we're closed!
- They've closed already!
- Please come again tomorrow.
Pack up your stuffs.
Cover up your face.
- What?
- Cover up your face.
Don't move. Freeze!
Give me all the hamburgers!
I told you to cover up!
I don't want money.
I want hamburger! Hamburger!
OK! Give them all the hamburgers.
No need for chips, I don't like chips!
Hurry, pack this up!
I caught him...
Put it down. Come on! Be careful!
He wants to call the police!
Let's flee with the hamburgers.
- Quick!
- Come on, hurry up!
Come on, hurry up!
It's very excited. Let's try again!
OK! Let's play murder next time!
It's not this? Go this way.
It's dangerous! Very excited!
Go...
See how scared you're!
Of course!
We've just committed a robbery.
Do you find it excited?
It really does! But it's not right!
That's what you told me
when you first defended me.
What's the result?
So you became my legal consultant
and my wife.
Oh yeah! It's real excited
to deal with the ICAC.
You recall something?
A little bit.
I don't know why I always recall...
something unhappy.
Then forget it.
See what we've stolen.
- What do you want to eat?
- I want chicken.
Chicken? There's only one here.
I want it...
- What do you want?
- Oh...
Come on...Here...
No! I've got it, it's mine!
You've cheated much money from me.
I've taken the 10 million US dollars,
they're mine.
Give me back the money!
Mister,
there're eight sorts of ice-cream.
Can I have half cone of each?
What about you take one for each?
Oh no! It's too rich!
Let me think about it!
Sure, no problem.
Delicious!
You look strange!
Someone is dating me!
That's wonderful but don't tease me!
He is six years smaller...
and he treats me very good,
although he is ugly, he is very gentle.
I'll introduce him to you next time!
Let's talk about other,
what do you want me for?
- Let's take a look.
- What's that?
It's the authorization paper,
I can sue the bloody doctor now.
I have remembered you told him
to burn it away.
- That was a phony one.
- Really?
This is the original.
So you remember everything?
Oh no, I just happened to remember this,
then I forgot the others.
Never mind, it makes no harm,
it doesn't matter.
What do you think about
your husband now?
I don't know! I really don't know.
He's a bit strange, but he's nice to you.
He loves you and cherishes you.
So you shouldn't eat too much ice-cream,
or else your boyfriend may dump you.
He doesn't mind if I put on weight!
Like it?
Yeah. You painted it?
Of course not, I asked people to do it.
You said you didn't like the old one.
I just went to have ice-cream
with Madam Ma,
and I've a bucked for you!
That's good!
I'll take the call first!
Hello, Chu, how is it?
What?
Are you crazy?
What did you say?
OK!
Brother Lung, I've got trouble.
I have subscribed the whole thing.
Please help me, I can't take it any more.
You thought I was better off?
No kidding, man?
I've got any share
of the 10 million US dollars,
it's not possible!
I'll take care of you!
What's the use? No money no talk!
Even your wife will betray you!
What have I done?
Who seduced your wife?
You know I'm nice to her
and I really love her.
Stay cool, man!
We've got through lots of crises.
How come you change like that
for a woman,
- Is it worth?
- I really loved her very much!
Man shouldn't cry!
It's only a woman.
OK! I'll check this man out.
Then we'll give him a lesson!
So, settle now!
You played my wife.
You don't give my share.
You owe me money, I want to kill you!
Damn you! You sleep with my wife!
You said I'm your dog.
Band on the floor.
I made you a dog, I've to smash you.
Bitch...
I want to kill you now.
Don't move! Bitch, you dare to hit me?
You both are the same shit!
Cool down...Listened?
I asked you to calm down!
Call the ambulance!
He's dead!
Not yet!
We've killed him?
It's him who tried to kill you first.
If we're discovered, I'll take the blame!
No...
Oh, that police! Don't look back!
You've got blood stain!
You're stained too! Get calm!
- What should I do?
- It's OK!
No, he'll go after us, what shall we do?
Mrs. Yau, Mr. Yau...
Calm down.
Let me hit you!
What are you doing?
No! Oh I can't remember! Oh!
Let it be! OK! It's OK!
Mr. Yau, are you alright?
It's OK? She will behave like this
every now and then.
Is there anything you want from us?
About the dead man Fan Shu Hung.
On that night,
he left after he's received the call.
We are going to find out who called him.
You better take a rest!
You're bleeding.
It's OK...He's left, it's alright!
Don't panic.
You don't need to remember the past,
and where you hide
the 10 million dollars.
I've decided to
sell this house and leave.
Do you take me with you?
Of course! You're my wife.
Did you treat me like this before?
It doesn't matter now.
Anyway you have forgotten the past.
What about the future?
Will you love me?
- Three.
- Four.
- Five.
- Six.
- Seven.
- Eight.
- Nine.
- Ten.
Eleven.
You lost! There's no eleven.
You look so red.
Oh no! You're sitting on my saline pack.
I can't take it any more!
Oh, sorry!
You naughty guy!
We are waiting for you for operation.
How come you hide inside Madam Ma's room?
The medicine that you gave me
was banned in the States for years.
The side effect is very severe.
It'll kill you if you over-dosed.
Where did you get it?
Hello! Sister?
Miss Ma, what's the matter?
Your medicine...
Is your husband there?
Yes, please hold on.
It's for you! It seems very urgent.
Mr. Yau, the medicine
you gave it to your wife,
was banned in the States for years.
Overdosed will cause lots of
side effects, and is very harmful!
You wait for me in the hospital,
I'll come over.
What's the matter?
She said there's something wrong.
What's the problem?
She said, there were some problems
with your medicine.
Really?
I must see her. It should be alright!
Mr. Yau.
- Have you called the police?
- No! But I'm going to.
Oh...Get in, get into my car.
Give half million as my anniversary gift?
Anyway, we are a couple.
Do you remember
the last time you went to bed with me?
Do you expect me to sleep with you?
Back to business! You turned pale
when mentioning the Thai.
- Just like a dog!
- Have you finished yet?
Hit me, come on beat me, come on!
Mr. Yau...
Do you know that bloody doctor?
Not quite.
When he gave you the medicine,
did he mention that it was harmful?
No!
Are you sure?
How come it would like this?
It's a matter of life. You can make joke,
but you can't abuse medicine!
You're too careless.
Is that doctor one of her enemy?
Not to mention that doctor.
Even I also wanted to kill her, right?
Oh no! We must do something.
We must call the police!
- Let's make the call!
- Does it help to call the police?
It may not be, in fact I've tried before.
Let it be...
Anyway I'll never give this to her,
and I'll never see the doctor again.
Let it be!
Let's find some place to eat?
Where?
You got the money. You can nail him!
Come on, call the police...
How to operate the phone?
- Don't do it.
- Why?
Let's go to the police directly.
Yes, that's right!
It's better we go in person!
The road is temporary closed,
please use the other route.
Let's turn the other way!
Don't kill me!
I'm going to married!
Don't kill me, I've no money.
Why do you have to kill me.
Don't...please don't...
You finally recall
where you put the money?
I remember everything.
I've tried to figure out
what should I do.
I've three alternatives.
I can call the police,
or shoot you dead,
or we can give the Thai back
all the money.
Then we sell this house and leave here.
So what have you decided?
I shouldn't be forgiven!
I deserved it.
I've decided to forget all the past.
Let's give them their money and leave!
No problem...
Mr. Yau, Mrs. Yau.
I saw your back door was unlocked.
I'm afraid someone may break in,
so I come from the back.
Did I scare you?
Mrs. Yau, you look much better now!
It's good to change the color!
Mr. Yau, please excuse me.
I think there is something wrong
with your house's Fungshui.
Last time,
I just stayed here for a while,
then I'd quarrel with my wife.
Then I had to sleep in the dinning room
for two nights.
Anything to drink?
Oh, thanks.
Mr. Yau.
Have you seen Chu Chung Hong lately?
No, what's the matter?
Well, Chu Chung Hong was missing.
Before that,
he had beaten up his wife.
Surprising his wife called your name...
instead of her husband,
when she regained consciousness.
How come it's like this?
I think may be Mrs. Chu
is one of our best friends,
especially for me,
we're just like sisters,
she was beaten up by Mr. Chu,
she must want us to help.
I understand...
You two are really very affectionate,
please teach me
how to maintain this relationship.
I...I just get married.
Mrs. Yau, in fact I wanted to discuss
Madam Ma's case with you.
- I hope you'll get prepared.
- What is it?
Ma was killed at the entrance
of the Junk Bay Tunnel an hour ago,
and she's got several wounds.
Why did you do it?
Do you understand, she's my only friend!
I don't mind what you've done before.
I don't care even you had killed me,
but you can't kill her.
Mr. Yau, excuse me.
Open the door...
Cool down!
Don't get too impulsive!
We've solved
a lot of difficulties before.
How can you give up now?
Get lost! If you don't go away.
I'll kill you.
Don't you understand?
I was forced to kill her.
She threatened me
to disclose all my secrets!
I don't care if I've to go to jail,
but I don't want to get you involved!
Go away! You're insane! Go away!
I must kill the police downstairs!
Sooner or later he'll find out
we've killed Chu, don't you understand?
Don't you understand?
You...
You've shot me already?
What do you scare of?
There're only two options.
We've only two choices.
Either we die, or we go away together.
We've no other alternative.
Think it carefully,
we've no turning back.
You've to believe me.
And I've trust you.
Put down the gun!
Put it down!
Let's start all over again!
We can start it over!
We used to have deals between us,
but it is different now.
Let's flee together!
With the 10 million dollars. Let's go!
You liar!
Congratulation!
At last you've recovered!