Don't play the fool
with me
Do you think everyone is
scared of Muthu!
He's also a servant like
you and me
Welcome Muthu
That's Muthu
He's not like us
He's different
It's quite sometime since
Mother sat for the Prayer
If the Landlord doesn't come,when
she performs the final ritual
We'll not only
get scoldings
Even the birthday benefits
will be with held.
Go,wakeup the Landlord
Don't talk rubbish
Rathi Devi.
Can anyone wake him up
other than Muthu
More over when Landlord
gets up
Mother's order is,he must see
Muthu first,don't you know this
I know that
But today is not
an ordinary day
Today's Landlord's birthday
The Prayer is only for him,should'nt
he be present then
What am I to do?
Muthu Isn't here!
Where is Muthu?
On the birthday of Landlord
where'll Muthu go?
Oh God!let everyone without hassels
be peaceful & happy
Y DD
The Almighty is the master
rest of us are his servants
Fools brood over fate
wisemen succeed it
Why weapon to conquer earth
or tool to pluck flower
Battle not for Wealth,control
desire to conquer earth
Y DD
Man desires for soil
soil desires for man
Soil succeeds at last,But
Mind refuses to accept it!
Sufficient money makes
you its boss
Surplus money becomes
your boss
Understand the meaning of life
and imbibe it completely
Y DD
Heaven to earth everything is
yours why to War on border problem
Nature invites us to live
sufferings in life are artificial
Birds enquire my
well being
Buds call me by name
when they bloom
I'll never age nor,sweetness
ever will be lost.
Y DD
Where's the Landlord,I'm going
to light the lamp
He'll come right now
It's getting late for Prayer
where's Muthu?
Who's pushing me?
Landlord is ready
he'll come now.
We were getting bothered about
what Mother will say
You've removed the
cause of my pain
Thank God,Muthu
has come
How did you get in here
without anyone's knowledge
No one knows how and
when will I come
But I'll be there at
the expected time
What is this?
Master is coming
An I not on time,Mother?
What is this?
Who else will bless him on his
birthday other than you
First let him be obedient
to his Mother
Then I'll bless him
Master,she's angry that you're
not married yet
Mother,this year everything will
happen as per your wish
For your next birthday
not as single
But three persons will get
blessings from you
His Wife,Child and himself.
She's laughing,get her
blessings immediately
Let everything happen fine as
what Muthu has said.
OKay I'll take leave,Mother
Where to...for the drama?
Not at all,I don't go for
drama now a days
Didn't you go for
drama yesterday?
No
Muthu you tell me
We didn't go Mother.
Promise on yourself
and tell me
We didn't go
for drama
When have you Brothered
about yourself?
Promise on Raja
Tell me now
Tell me
We went for the drama
at Travancore
We came back at 4.30
in the morning
Since it's your birthday
you can't go for drama today
The whole town is waiting
for you outside
We've arranged a
grand party for them
Today,you can't
go out anywhere
No drama today,we
can sleep early
We are going
- for the drama?
No Mother,to the Temple
Only to the Temple
Isn't it?
Yes only to the Temple
Why do you do this?
Haven't I told you
not to do this
He doesn't listen
to it at all.
What is there in it?
My existance is alms
that you've given
Who else am I going to
serve otherthan you
Landlord long live
Landlord long live...
You go and arrange
flowers for the God
Its already done
Check whether preparations are
going on in the cusine
I've checked that too
Why do you send me away whenever
big master comes
Today is Master's birthday
I won't go leaving him alone
Welcome Uncle
Birthday Wishes
Long live Landlord
Ambalathar longlive,Landlord
longlive,Ambalathar longlive
The garland is put to greet
the person or to make him fall
Muthu you both wanted to go to
the Temple,Isn't it, go
Okay Mother
- Go
Brother Veerapan
- Yes Muthu
Hold this garland
- Okay give it
We'll go
- Muthu save me
Where's Brother
- I'm down here
Come Muthu
- Yes master
Have they put garland
or Mountain?
Leaving,A palace like
Taj mahal
Yet you're in this hut
I'm fuming inside
Why do you let the
servants speak
The God has made us superior
and them inferior
But you don't know
where to keep them
Why,have you forgotton
the past?
I'm telling this because
we are inter related
Has your daughter finished
her studies?
Intelligent sister.
What if my daughter completes
her studies or not
I'll send her here
You make her your
daughter-in-law
I'll become your Kinsman
Dear,don't mistake me for asking
you again and again
Do you have any secrets
which I don't know
Tell me,what the secret is
I'll suppress it completely
It there anything
which I don't know?
Then I'll make it known to
the whole town
I'll leave now
Are you taking care
of everything
Yes Master,just
as you've said
Have an eye on that
servent Muthu
I already have one
eye on him
Since you've mentioned it I'll
have both the eyes on him
No one knows,who you are
isn't it
How will they know?
Don't shout you idiot
Master why do richmen alone
celebrate birthdays
Is it to spend
their money
No,not only that
To make everyone happy on their
birthday,That's why
He makes everyone happy
except his Mother
Always going for drama,cinema
and other entertainment
I also have to
suffer with him
What are you murmering
over there?
Talking to my Friend
When is your
birthday,Muthu
My birthday...
Good question,master
I don't know,who my parents are
how will I know my birthday
What's this,have we come for
theatre once again
What is this?
Who is this Mother?
What,have you forgotton?
Your Uncle's daughter,Padmini
Is this our Padmini?
She's looking
much grown up
Look...She's feeling shy
She has bumped on her
groom,isn't it
That's why she's
feeling shy
Why do you always talk
about my marriage
Unlike her Father she's a
very nice girl
I called her here,only
to know your opinion
Am I not telling
my opinion often
I'm not prepared
for marriage
Send her back first
What happened Padmini?
for this hiccups
What do you know about hiccups
what do you know?
Dear
She's always like that
She'll have hiccups for anger
happiness,temper and cry
It isn't quite easy
to stop it
I shall stop it,Mother
Just like this
when I was a child
I got hiccups quite often
You know,what kind
of hiccups
Mother will give me water
I'll drink it
in one gulp
In a short time hiccups
would stop
Mother look the hiccups
have stoped
That's why I
frightened him
Hey!chinnapanne,your lower garment!
come on take it!
Rathi,why am I doing
all your duties?
You must see me
I must see you
And our love must grow,but instead
of that you're dreaming about someting else!
I'm getting a
dream quite often
In that dream,a prince always
comes with a Sugar cane
Since,its dark always,I am
not able to recognise him!
It's none other than me
Since he's black I can accept
it may be you.
But,he's very thin!
Am I not longing in
your thoughts?
That's why,I look thin
in your dream
Master,our little madam
- who's little madam?
Padmini madam she's just like
actress Padmini
Yes-Yes
She's more bashful compared
to me,master!
Yes-Yes
Without any discrimination she's
affectionate towards everyone.
Is it?-Yes
Master look here this side!
Look at the nature
God's creation
Doesn't it look as a green carpet
spread on the earth!
Yes
Gone case
Master,look at the sky
Doesn't it look like a silver Bedspread
which has been spread on us!
Yes
My God where shall I ask him
to look at now?
Master,look at the earth
I've seen the Green carpet,silver
Bedspread and the posters also!
Today, I must see that
"Pricess of Madurai"
Ride the carriage straight
to Kovilur!
Yet another sleepless night!
Is he the hero
- Yes
Minister haven't you found a
suitable bride for me
Painful,ashamed,humiliating
For a girl to suit your beauty
- stop
What you said
wasn't audible?
Repeat it once again
For a girl to suit
your beauty
There's no one to equal you
in the whole world
If so,I've heard about world beauties
like cleopatra,Jhansi Rani!...
Give whatever is needed to the
poor waiting outside
Did you approach them?
King,We saw them.
But,they wouldn't stand before
your Golden colour!
So we left them
Wouldn't I get a
girl at all
The good fortune of Marrying
you besttowed on only one girl!
Who is that?
Princes Malar Kodi
Is it? Malar Kodi?!
For my handsomness,is she
suitable for me?
King don't underestimate her
Her walk is like a swan!
Her lips are intoxicating
Her face is like Lotus
Her body is Honey fruit
Her age is 18
On the whole she's a
never withring bud!
Then I must see
her immediately!
We must,we must
Princess,the King of Pandyas
has come to seek your hand.
Is it so,ask him to come
I'll meet him
As you order!
Princess,the King has come
look at him
Pained,ashamed,humiliated
Isn't this my dialogue
To succed we must repeat
the dialogue
Beauty queen,fascinating
princess
I've got the figure that
men are attracted to
Is he my bridegroom who looks like a
corpse walking out from grave yard!
When the King's are ready to
leave their Kingdoms,for my one smile!
How dare you've come to ask
for my hand,you coward?
...On this earth...
How dare you've come
to me,you coward?
Not only in this world,even in 7 worlds
no mad girl will dare to marry you?
How dare for a beast to
desire for a beauty?
What do you think
of yourself?
You are sneezing from
the beginning
I'm talking only
to you
You don't bother
sister
I've been watching you from beginning
you're sneezing continuously
What do you think
of your self?
Is it a crime,even to sneeze
in this country?
That's it!
It isn't a crime
to sneeze...
But when a beautiful girl is
performing on stage
Madam,sneez,cough
hiccups,yawning...
Good,bad,hungry,sleep,birth
death,money,merit,position...
All these you wouldn't
get by asking!
....It'll come to you
on its own!
Neither we can ask why it has come
not ask why it goes from us!
This is known as dialogue!
Muthu,you were brilliant!
Even you too utter
dialogues
It's easy to talk from
down there!
Deliver it from here,shiver's will
run down from your back!
Who'll shiver?what do you
think of our Muthu?
The whole town is mesmerised by the
style of his Riding the carriage!
He can ride carriages,can he
manage to get on to the stage?
Whom are you questioning
like that?
This is nothing for him
he'll get on to any stage!...
...Speak boldly,Sing & Dance
Do you want to watch it?
Why do you put me
in to a fix,boy?
Shut up Muthu,you don't
know your potentials!
If he's such a Bold man
Tell him to come to stage
let him Sing & Dance,let's watch!
Muthu how can you keep quiet
when she's challenging!
Show your talent
on the stage
Brother,I don't want all this
unnecessary trouble!
Don't you want them to see
your talents?come on,Master!
Hey!keep quiet!little girl
challenged unknowligly!
He wouldn't
listen to us
Lets get him on stage
by force
Why is she so hot?
You've got me here
how'll I manage her?
Show them their places
we are there to back you!
Master
Oh!Princess!You've hurt a King
who had come to seek your hand!
Don't seek a man's beauty on
his face,but in his heart!
Instead of hurting
others heart
The words of your reply...Repeat them
with a smile and watch the result!
You'll understand the
sweetness in it
That's good for you and
your family
That's the merit of
language Tamil
Don't be arrogant,it
will spoil you
Sir,Wonderful
Don't think you're great
because of the applause
Only those applauses
have made men great
Have you come to see drama
or pick up a fight?
I'm not picking up a fight
Is this Pride?
I don't have that
Then do I have?
I don't say so
What do you think
of yourself
Generally my heart
is Gold
When it comes to competition
I'm a Lion
I'll speak the truth and
do Good deeds
There'll be Victory
over Victory
Let's Sing,dance and
celebrate
Let there be joy always
Ranga Nayagi for our
Sakthi drama troupe
We've got a big asset
I mean a new Hero
Invite him to the troupe by
Garlanding him,hold it
Carefull it might sprain
too much
You seem to be very Happy
You used to ask me often
Isn't it
That when I'm going
to Marry
Now I've...
Decided to get Married,Mother
Landlord has accepted
for Marriage
Everybody come here
Muthu,Landlord has accepted
for Marriage...
Having seen a fish the crane
withdraws its fasting
A fish has broken the Penance of
a Crane,Praying on leg!
There's no eligible bachelor here!
Without'Love'there's no life here!
You can't cover a sky!The love in
your eyes is taking steps!
Y DD
Youthful young boy!Listen
to granny's words!
There are rules in
Love life
12 times express Love to
your wife in words
Kiss her 6 times a day!
Make her happy
thrice a day
If this happens daily,she'll be at
your back & call all the time!
Y DD
Old Beauty,High priestess
of Love!
You're a Doctorate
in 'Love Life'!
Olden times were Golden Times!There
was only one thing that's'Love'!
Presently men are struggling
Even for food!
Nobody's living comfortably
to enjoy pleasures of life!
You've time to Gossip about the town
What's life without a wife?
Y DD
What's up Sister? Dance,so
much of happiness
Happy news Brother that
too for you
What's that?
- Father
Beloved
Has accepted for Marriage
Only this
You don't seem to react
We are so much excited
I knew he would accept
That's why I send my
daughter here
If not,I would have tried
some other way
Fools have only one way
This Ambalathar has
thousand ways
But he hasn't given
me much trouble
Give me the bottle
Bridegroom...
Welcome Bridegroom
For others age goes up,for you
it comes down
You look just the same
My friend got this from
Singapore,have it
what's this Master?
Foreign Liqour
Oh God,Master doesn't have this habit
don't teach him please
Have it-No master
Take your hands away
- No master
I said take your hands away
- no master
You bloody slave-Brother
Ask pardon to muthu-what?!
Should I ask Pardon
to a servant?
No one is a servant here
I treat everyone as
my Children
Though I show all concern I've
never been rude to them
How could you slap him?
You might be my brother,you
have all rights over me
But you don't have any
rights on them
Ask pardon to Muthu
Ambalathar has never asked
anyone pardon
But I'm father
of a girl
Pardon me
What's this Ratidevi?
Your hands are so soft
why do you work?
Am I not there for you?
give me,I'll do it
Shall we....
Don't you have
any other work?
Why do you wander like a dog
you broom
Wait!why do you shout like goat
that's to be slaughered
Yes,I am a dog
Not an ordinary dog
but a Jackal
Do you know what a
Jackal would do
What's this,troubling women
Then,can we trouble men
Trouble me...trouble me...
I've come to work
But I've not come for work
but to trouble
Trouble me
Brother Kali you're
quite strong
But wouldn't I hit once
if you hit me ten times
You'll hit me, let me see
hit me
Don't ask me like this
then I sure will
You'll hit me
then do it
Okay,come stand here
I never take back what
I say & what I give
My God!such a result for
one blow itself
How dare you lay
your hands on me
Madam is coming
madam is coming.....
Where's madam
- just for fun
Should you fight with him
don't we have other job
Muthu,come here
What I have in my brain you
have in your bone's
It's all your blessings
- It's always with you
Oh God!I've forgotton to
give coffee to master
Coffee,I thought Cockroach
Isn't there any Vehicle?
Sister,there's a charriot
stop it,stopit...
Oh my God,its them
my friend keep going
Master
Stop the charriot
- okay master
It's stopped can the charriot
move after seeing us?
Greet him
- Greetings
Do you remember me?
Even in your last drama the
garland on my neck
Yes... I was bit rude
that day
Please forgive me
Why are you standing
here?
They don't have a better job
master
They're enjoying breeze
come,we'll go
No,to stage a drama
in Anganoor
We were coming
in the Car
You both came in a car
you both came in a car
Don't lie,master
we'll go
Look there
This is real
this is dream
Who can win over me
in this World
Master gave money for petrol
to go for drama
But he boosed and dashed
against a tree
We don't know how to
go to Anganoor
Also no Vehicle passes
by this way
So if you can
drop us there
Just dropping you there -
I'll stay to see the drama
only then,I'll leave
Shall we go,its getting
late for you
Yes we shall
Valayapathy useless guy
come quickly
Carry this,Brother can you
carry this
No need,I'll carry
it myself
Everything is happening
up side down
Didn't we come in the car
where's it?
Who has tied horse
to the car?
Who hit me?-I saw you
Is it so powerfull
Okay where's the make
up room?
It's over there,Prince
Where?-there
Why they need this
for a car?
Didn't I ask you where the
make up room is?
How come you've got over
so quickly?
Shouldn't there be a
stearing over here?
Should we take them
with us,master?
Won't you ride -when
did you come here?
What's pricking me?
Driver I've got
a doubt?
What?
Don't you know Tamil as if
like a English woman
You look very Stylish so I
thought you knew English
No,I don't know
What's your name?
I've never got
what I've desired for
Will I get it?
Your name?
What you are destined to get
you'll get it & vice versa
Master
What Muthu?
I can't ride if she sits here
ask her to change place
Sister won't you behave youself
come this side
Driver,I've got
a doubt?
Careful let it not
fall on me
Look here,maintain
a distance
As if you're
mr.Handsom
As if you're Miss Beautiful
look at your face
Muthu,what's wrong
with her face?
Men are longing
for her sight
Madam,let me do
my work properly
Why do you trouble me?
You'll only suffer later
You can't be on time
for the drama
Yes Rang,its late for Rehersal
don't argue
Oh God!I didn't do
anything
Let me not argue
with him
Sir,can I sit here?
Valayapathy,what
happened?
I can't tell you this
keep quite
Let my problem be
with me
Driver move aside and sit
- why?
Aren't ladies sitting
over there
What?ladies over there
Horses won't do anything
Isn't it?
What with horses?
What are you going
to do?
What am I going to do?
you can control your anger,but...
Can you control Uri..
- Hey!..gone!...gone...Yuck!
Nuisance-This is also
poking me
Driver am I not asking you a
doubt since a long time
Did you ever try
to clear it?
Come an ask?..why do we need
a lynch pin for a car?
Yes master!-Take them to
the river-why master?
Okay!
Come quickly or else
I'll start
Didn't I say not to
give them a lift
It's freezing cold even to
dip my finger into it!
What will happen to me if my
whole body gets into this water?
I'll freeze to death!so I've take
bath outside carefully!
What Hero?... playing
water games?!
Though there are gores
of fair men around
I who was never inclined to
Marry... the moment I saw you...
...I had decided to
Marry only you!
You don't have any objections
isn't it?
After the drama,if you come
alone to my house...
I'll take it as your
acceptance
I'll tell my Mother at a proper
time and Marry you!
Okay Muthu in coming,he doesn't like
Drama & Artists!keep it a secret!
Every word you had uttered was
like honey to my ears
At this young age,such
Love talk,unseen Love!...
This man who made me hear it
& see it and blossmed Love in me!
...Was by him!
Ranjithan,my friend...Hey
I'm calling you
When I approached you like a
waiting crane approaching a fish!
But,you're talking about
some coward!
Have you forgoton,that
I am a cheat?
And have you forgotton to notice
the 2 Rowdies behind me?
King,why are you calling
as Rowdies?
You're just head of this Troupe
I am cheif of this town!
After borrowing money from me,you
may have forgotton your words
But I haven't forgotton
what you've said
Stop your speach
Or I shall stop your breath
with a sword!am I right?
Whatever you say
you're right!
Right now the rehersal is going on
I'll send immediately after that!
...Sir,please go for me
Now,you'll say,after rehersal after
that,you'll say after Drama...
Finally you'll
say she's gone
Do you think this
will be good to us?
Order me king
order me...!
My bravery will get
rewarded!
No way-how can you
say that?
You'll get what's destined to you!
you won't get what isn't destined to you!
Dialogue is quite good,our Director
wouldn't write so nicely?
Muthu said this
while coming
Abduct the girl and come
to my forest Bunglow
You ride the carriage?
Sir,why so many for this?
I've never lost before I've to be
here who ever may go away,bye!
Who's there?
Immediately abduct this princess
to my palace!
How can you come in without
proper costumes?
Get lost!
Why are you hitting them?
I think they're really
hitting them
Yes Master,this is the most
interesting scene of this Drama!
Leave me!
Look,how naturally
she's acting!
Sir,no they're hitting us
really!please save us!
Hit him he thinks
he's Kamalhasan
They are beating up even
the Director,some thing's fishy!
They are taking away
Ranga Nayagi
Let them leave
it Master!...
Muthu save Ranganayagi
- yes master!
Hey!I'll tear and cut
you into pieces!
Just for fun,don't take
it to be real!
Brother,poor girl,they're eking their
livlihood by staging plays!
..Why do you trouble them?
go peacefully from here
Master I've saved them!
What's it brother?
Who did you save
this girl?
Save her,let me see that
What's this brother?I've come to talk
peace & you're hitting me!
...What?....
What do you think
of yourself?
How dare you call me
like that?
When did I?
While you were
sitting here
Something happened to me when
I sat here,so I blabbered
How can that happen?
Brother,wouldn't I hit once
if you hit me ten times
Will you hit me?
come..let me see
I'll-let me see!?....
Okay come this side
Neither I take back my words!
nor the charity given by me!
Master
Leave me...
He'll pay all our dues isn't it
- how can he get away?
Leave me...
...You?!....
Master...master...!
Muthu,this is their area
their men are coming...
Take Ranganayagi away
from here
Let anyone come..
we'll manage!
No one's hand should
touch Ranganayagi
First take her away
Then,what about you
- I'll look after myself
Master-keep going
- alright sir!
Don't fuss much
Where did he go?....diappeared?!
search in the bushes!
Vanished again?! look here....
look there...vanished again?!
Stop!only chariot is going,where's
he?..look here..there!...
What's that hissing sound?
What?don't trouble me I'll
push you down
What did I do?always wantonly
abussing me!you don't like me!
Come fast-don't you see
snake there...I am scared!
Why are you afraid of a snake?
watch!I am going!
Everyone's scared
of my whip
Sssn....-what Sssna...?
Ssssss....NAKE!!!?
Will you put down
the snake?
Throw it off your hands!?
Throw off that snake
from your hands
There's an abyss ahead
Abyss is fast approching hold this
and stop the carriage!abyss is approching!
hey!look!he has flown
over the mountain!
Come let's go & catch him
going round the village!
Hey!what's this you're
keeping on going?
Haven't we crossed
the mountain?
We have to go around,e'll
reach town by morning
That's alright!are we going
on the right path?
Who knows?
I've never bothered
the way I go
I trust God and go in the
route he takes me
Why are you sitting closer to me?
go to the back side!
Oh!God!this is too much!
Sister...come faster!
Which place is this?
where have you come?
Sir,Greetings,which place
is this?
What is he asking us?
I feel he's asking for the
God's offerings!
Okay,we shall give him
God bless you,we'll go
- let's go....
I'm asking for route & you're
going off after giving flowers!
Hey!-what?
Feeling very hungry!
Lot's of green leaves & grass is
there!pluck & eat!
Did I ask for the horse?I said
I was feeling hungry
look,there's a tea shop
Sister,who's that girl?
- I don't know
Why,do I need to ask you anymore?
I'll go & eat,go my Emperess go!
Eat without money and
get bashed up!
I know
This is Queen of Travancore
last year,I had seen her!
It's a blessing that she is
coming to our shop!...come!...
Slowly it might sprain
Whom are you taking about
- about myself!
Most welcome Queen!
It's my great fortune that Queen of
Travancore has come to our shop!
What is he saying?
What?-who's this Queen?
He's a servant in my Palace
He's hungry
That's why,I'm here
How come she's speaking
this language?
She roams places
isn't it?
Servant move aside
Queen please come in...
Get me tea
I don't want all this,give
this also to the princess
Oh!tea
- yes go
You look like a king not
like a servant
You like a king...
Ask for money ask
for money
What?
Ask for the money...
What,I should ask
her for money
So generous,offering bronze
Sister,look here gold
That's not gold
that's bronze
Yes the same
long live Queen
Long live queen
Thank you Queen
Did you eat properly
speak something
You used to speak a lot why
speachless,I am talking to you
I don't talk to Queen
That's for fun
don't mistake
Brother....brother....
Brother,please stop
Which place is this?
Oh!the time is twelve
Come here.
What place is this?
This is board
Break your head,don't I
know this is board.
I'll take your
Moustache away
What's this?
Oh!This is Kuluwalee
Your place is Kuluwalee
My place is Kalipatti
My God,patti Means Dog
How to go?
What Patti/-Yes patti
Am I a dog?
How dare you
call me dog?
Yuck,God,what nuisance
is this?
Yuck,don't Know whom to ask
how to ask?
So sad,you give
me a kiss.
What did you say?
For a kiss/-That means?
It means,to ask for route
in this language.
Then how to ask
for Kalipatti?
Hug tight and kiss me.
But Kalipatti isn't there.
Hug tight means Kalipatti
Hug tight and kilss me
Why didn't you say
this earlier?
Why didn't you ask
me earlier?
Just an ego problem
Sister,please stop
Hug tight and kiss me
Probably I musn't ask
samll girls
Brother,Greetings/-Greetings.
I'm from TamilNadu.
You look very Handsome.
Hug tight and kiss me?
What?
Hug tight and kiss me.
Shouldn't ask
small boys also.
Here is a Mother with a son
should ask only her
Mother wishes-wishes
Your son....looks beautiful
Hug tight and kiss me
- What?
- Kiss you
I was asking for way
What mistake did I do just
for direction asked
Ants are biting me
Please help me get down.
I mentioned Kuluwalee
not kiss.
He even asked me a kiss
- to you too!
I asked him also
for direction
Please leave him brother
I'm a drama artiste-
Why are you here?
To take him with me
Do you know what he
asked my Sister?
What he asked her?
He asked her for
a Kiss
My God,its only
because of me
Brother,please
forgive him
Who are you
to say that?
His wife
How do I believe that?
This is our Wedding ring
Should I leave him,Just because
he's your husband.
Let me better say he's mad
he's mad
Mad!This man....He's
a mad man
Make him get down.
Some of you go to agri farm
- Okay
Some of you go to coconut farm
Some to the banana farm
Do you want coffee?
Were you remembered of me
only now,get me some
But poison cannot be
drawn from its hood
See what time
she's getting up?
Don't bring for me alone
We're totally 17 here
Am I right,bring for
all of us
Madhava,why work wasn't
proper yesterday
Whom did you
take with you?
Sir Greetings
- Greetings
Who are you
what do you want?
Sir wishes of a Tamilian
- Oh!You're a tamilian
How are you
what do you want?
You must tell me meaning of what
I ask-Okay ask me
You musn't scold,spit
or hit me later.
Sure
- Comeon,ask me
Hug tight and kiss me
See to your work
go from here
What did you ask me?
You won't harm me right
- Yes!
I'm afraid
- don't be.
Hug tight and kiss me
Yuck,What kind of a man are you
to kiss another man.
You only had asked me to hug
you tight and kiss you!
When did I ask you?
What you had asked
meant only this
I kissed your checks because
you're a man
If it was a woman I would
have kissed her lips
I am man,Isn't it
- No doubt
You said that for fun
I would have left it likewise
But.....
But that Mudaliar irritated me
so out of anger
A bud has blossomed
in Kuluwalee
Y DD
A bud has blossomed in Kuluwalee
due to the knoking of the bee
It's time to suck honey
the angel is feeling shy
Muthu's kiss has created
Cyclone inside a flower
Y DD
Ranganayagi,you've taken away
brother-in-law's heart
You've disturbed my heart just
the way you disturb your hair
Am I so attractive
don't lie
Y DD
What party is our party?
What party is ours
ours is the love party
Why we need a party now?
Let time answer that.
You have some plan but
let the time favour you
Y DD
What happened?
My master will be
waiting for me
Tell me where your troupe is
I'll drop you there
I don't know where
they are
But I'm not going
back there
Why?
Because my,drama's boss intends to
sell me anytime
Yes,tell me where your parents
are?I'll drop you there
What do you say-
Both aren't alive
I'm also an orphan
like you
I was brought up
by my sister
She's a wonderful woman
but my uncle....
Sister.....
I'll tear you apart!
My sister,used to suffer like
this everyday!!
Brute!When I am out,will you
bring other women to home?
What's wrong in doing that?
Leave...Leave..
- Will you beat me?
Watch out there!
Is she dead?
Dead?!.....Get lost!
Hey!Why do you look at me like that
Is it because your sister's dead?
Hey!Why are you standing
still?
Let her die!Why do you
feel sorry for that?
What's the problem?
Hey!Where are you going?
Hey!Why are you escaping after
killing your sister?
Hey!You...stop...Hey!...
..I am away from there to
join this Drama troupe.
Getting saved of my brother-in-law,I am
living a life of wearing disguises!
Don't worry,Ranganayaki!God is there
He'll never let down good people!
We shall do one thng
my master is a nice man
He can help you get a job
You stay with me there!
But on one condition
- What's that?
Till my master gets married,No one
should know what's between us
What's there betweeen me?
Isn't there anything
between us?
What could be there?
That's why,I always say girls
should never be trusted!
But,I trust only you
What happened?
Some strange feeling is
tingling inside me!
My sweet Robber
Sweet kisses!
Nothing,Nothing...Boys!
After the drama If you come
to my house alone..
I'll take it as your
acceptance
Muthu,You are safe
isn't it?
Is everyone safe?
- Yes master
What happened,you went yesterday
but you are coming only today?
It's a big story,Master
We lost our way and went
into other state!
Like a stranger lost and
got beaten by few people also!
I had never faced such a
situation in my entire life!
Has the carriage come empty?
Greetings!
This Lady as a Heroine?!?!!
What's this nuisance
master?
Not only just saving her!It seems
we've to give her shelter also!
Because,She doesn't have any
other place to go,So she says..
She says the troupe is else where
and no place to go!
..And asked me to take
her to my home!
I said a big'No'to her!
She insisted an taking her to you
So I've done that!
Clever girl!
Master
There are many workers here! Let her
also stay here as one among them!
That's your wish,Master
I am not concerned with it!
You go inside
- Yes,go inside...go!
Everything's is a drama
life is a drama
..No...No...Not that one...
take that one!
Keep it,there.
Not there,here
Please,place it here
Not here...place it there!
Oh!God!Madam,decide and
tell one proper place!
I'm going to be the Lady
of this house
If you don't work properly
I'll dismiss you
Where should I keep it?
- over there
Lady of the house
is always right!
Who are you all?
Sister
What happened sister?
Without you we couldn't stage
the drama
The lazy owner has
sent us away
Stop,What's this funeral elegy?They're
singing funeral elegy,Ask them!
I'll punch your face
Are you staging a drama here
- No?
We could'nt stage dramas
without RangaNayagi!
But,Still we tried this
Lady as Heroine!
They would've thrown bricks
at her,isn't it?
Yes,a lot,so much that I
could build even a house!
..They chased by showing us
with so many bricks!
Finding no other way,We've come
to take Ranganayaki with us!
Lots of people are depending
on you for their livlihood1
If you give them some work
They'll survive....Poor souls!
Don't you know that I like
dramas and artists.
Assign them job and arrange
place for their stay!
What Role were you playing
in the plays?
...I was the commander!
Clean the chairs
over here.
What was your role?
- I was the spy!
You'll remove all
the cobwebs.
What was your role?
- I used to sing playback!
You sweep the backyard.
What you do?
- Flattering!
Then be with me
And you?-Drums!
- then work on the first floor!
And you?-I'm a stand by heroine
You water the plants!
You'll draw water from
this well!
At the palace?
- No at the backyard
Will Muthu come?
I'll take care
of you later!
Why are you giving poses?
what role were you playing?
Royal Roles
- what does it mean?
Can't you understand?I'll play king...
when I was riding this Horse!
Stop it.Do you come
on a horse?
From today you'll clear
all this Horses Dung!
Dung?!-Yes!
Impossible!If I do that I'll
lose my honour!
Look out for some other!
If you don't listen to me
You'll lose your livlihood!
Brother!
Beloved
Rathi aren't you ashamed to
hug Third rates
No he's the prince
of my Dream
Prince...my foot
How do you call
him a Prince?
The same thin structure
The similar dot
Similar Beautiful hair
I'll cut all their
hair tonight
Tie the Cow to the cart
Taking hold for agri
Plow the land Chellakanu
"MY DEAREST -THIEF"
Muthu what are you doing
WOR...WOR...WOR. Working
Idiot,Idiot,Idiot
What did I do Idiotic?
I just informed that Landlord
likes the servant maid,for that
I didn't mean you
I blamed myself
The moment he accepted to
Marry my daughter
I should have performed
their marriage
If so I would have accquired
Wealth equal to this
I've delayed it
Should raise the bridge
before Flood comes
Who's that servant maid?
Her name is Ranganayagi
She was acting in Dramas
Beloved
Why are you Crying?
What you liked
the most in me?
Has been cut over
the nights
Don't worry beloved
Even if it's dead,a Lion
is a Lion
Even if you have lost your hair
you are my beloved
You've everything that I need
- is it
You're always my beloved
Ha...ha...ha...
I'm flying high hearing this
I'm really flying
I can't see the
World clearly
You can see clearly
you dog
Are you trying to tap her?
Come with me... Come
Where to?
To throw you into
the Well
Who are you?
Walking in without
permission
Go out
Don't you hear us
He's not listening to us
- Who is he?
Old man stop,am I
not telling you
Who's that,stop!
Am I not telling you
Doesn't he look
like a sage
He looks like a mad man,you're
calling him a sage
Elderly man.Who are you?
I'm trying to
find only that
I don't understand
I'm a puzzle for those who
don't know me
A Cyclone for those
who know me
Who knows you well
The Madam of this house
Madam is not at home
Where is she?
She has gone to the Temple
What for?
Why do people go to Temple?
To Worship God
Then who's he?
God is inside,they're
searching him outside
Why is everyone idle
go and work
If we are not here
everybody turns idle
That's why I'm bit strict
don't mistake me
sir everyone is mad
in this World
Some are mad after Money
Some are mad after Women
Some are mad after position
You're mad after your
Uncle's daughter
How does he know what
I'm thinking-He is God
Wishes Mother
Tonight at 10 o'clock
Meet me alone
in the Garden
Deepavali gift
is awaiting you
Come... you come
It's not far away
You come
Tonight at 10 o'clock meet me
at the Garden alone
What Muthu
Why are you longing
like this
Haven't I told you
several times
What's to be obtained
wouldn't be lost
What isn't to be obtained
would be lost
I've accquired it
- how come?
I won't tell you
Deepavali gift awaits you
Very Strong man
Tonight at 10 o'clock
Meet me alone at the Garden
Deepavali gift awaits you
Master
Get the charriot ready
we're going out
Come quickly
- Yes Aunty
Why hasn't he come yet
It's festival of lights,if
you laugh
Who,s that?
Let my beloved come,I shall...
Why is this man here?
Where is she?
She'll come
Festival gift is also
awaiting me
She'll surely come
I won't leave you
I'm a dangerous man
Got to be that
why is he here?
This Palace is big enough
to pain my legs
He came this way
where did he go?
Looking for Scorpion
I've found honey
He might see
keep quite
Are you here
Master
Why has he come
at this time?
Unnecessary I came &
I've got caught
Never again,I'll
follow anyone
Why is Madam coming
over here?
Ya...she came to
meet Master...!
My God,Landlord is
coming this side
Oh!why is he hiding?
Wow!...My sweet heart
is coming...
Oh!God!what will happen
if some one sees?
Why has she come here?
Where's the Festival gift
Madam-first give
me Festival gift.
Brother-Brother-come
this side
Who's this?My God
My God,aunty is coming
Who's giving Festival
gift to whom?
Come out rascals!
Come out or I'll shoot
Whom?isn't me
No.... Use....You shoot
So many people
Why so many people
- have come here?what for?
I shall tell you Mother
MUTHU-Brother-Move aside
This fool only told to play new
drama for Deewali to get sound sleep
Mother No way I'm involved with
this gathering-promise Mother!
By the way Mother,why all are here
at this place,at this time?
Why? Mother!
What... Why?
All of you came here only to
dance and sing... carry on...
Y DD
Are you sweet as honey
my heart beats with a rythm
The Cuckoo bird pampered me
& my heart beats with a rythm
It's you who have got me in ties
at your very sight
Cupid has taxed me to
make love to you
Y DD
Though from a village
you're a Genius
I've always felt like touching
you while speaking
I'm innocent and I dwell in
the heart of masses
I'm for you,take
me completely
Accept,learn,play even if
I'm over you
Should cover my face
in your chest
Our relation should stand
the test of time
Should be together without
any hindrence
Y DD
Why have you loved a
dark man like me?
Even the colour of the
Sky & ocean are dark
I'm remembered of you when I see
the sky and the ocean
Because of you,without henna
I'm turning red.
Your eyes are mesmerizing
I've fallen in your trap
I'm trapped because of
your love!!
I'm a wild bull which
is calm because of you
Y DD
He has got up
Oh!sage bless us!
Great regards!God man!
Do you remember me?God man!
15 years before I got your
blessings in Kasi
After that I've become
very Wealthy
I heard,that you're here
Hence I came to see you
This is my offerings
What is this?
What will this sage
do with this?
Having known every thing
why do you tell like this?sage!
We can't live in this
World without money
We can buy anything with this
What do you want now?
With your blessings
I'm quite well off
But I don't have
peace in life
You said we can buy
anything with money
Can't you buy peace?
By keeping all people's money
how can you get peace?
Keep less you need,rest give to
other's then only peace comes freely
These who stock money
don't have peace at all
One who stores good deeds
gets peace!
We never brought anything
while coming
We'll never take back
anything while going
Why in the middle do we
long for Wealth
Go... Get Lost....
Take this and give it to the
needy people and go
What do you want?
We came to see you God
God?!
You've seen right,now go
Go and look after your work
...Work is God!
Let's go or he'll be angry
Brother move aside
Greetings
What do you want?
I'm in Love with a girl
I want to Marry her
Okay Marry her
But there's a problem in it
What's the problem?
If only my Master gets Married
I can get Married
So I want you to bless that Master
gets Married soon
Yes sir,he also wants to
Marry soon
Crazy guy the game
will start now.
I've come only to see that
I don't understand you
Go home you'll understand
See you sir
Stop. Who are you?
Where are you going?
I'm asking you
isn't it?
They are Andhra Police
I've answered,isn't it
Why are you standing?
Someone by name Ranganayagi
Has absconded from home
& she is working here
Her uncle has come
with a Batalian
Oh!Oh!Who is it
Andhra will shiver
hearing his name
He was about to create a
big trouble
To stop that,I've
brought him
Don't talk law,send
her with him
Now I'll leave
Who are you?
You bloddy are you thinking
that I am mad?
I will see your madness,let us go
- Oh God
Stop that fellow!
Save her!
Stop him,Save her.
Oh!God no I'll not
come with you-
Hey,who are you
Where is it? It is here!
my name is Rayudu-
My place is Chittoor
This is my sister-in-law!
My dear come on
...let us go....
No please,don't send me
with him
You can't take her without
her will
You mean,You want me leave her
- Okay
Sister-in-law,I've
left you.
Who is this fellow?
How dare you lay
hand on Master.
You mad fellow-put an
end to his madness
"Brother"
I know everything
about you
If you come once again looking
for Ranganayagi
No... No.
I'll make you
into pieces
Still to make pieces nothing
remained in my body,brother!
Every thing is already
torn to pieces
Promise,In future I'll never cross my
town & put my step here in Tamil Nadu
Brother.Let me take my glasses &
Cigar without which no respect for me.
You fools,start the Vehicle
- let us go
They came to take
their girl
You should have send her
Don't we have any
other servants?
Why did you fight
for her?
What'll I do if something
happens to you?
Get me some Water
Nothing will happen,Mother
What,nothing will happen?
His face was looking
horrible
First send that girl
back to her house
How is it possible,Mother
I was against
getting Married
I changed my mind
Only after seeing
Ranganayagi
Because she was a
Drama artiste -
I was scared whether
you'd accept or not
Hence,I never told you
What are you saying?
Didn't you accept to
Marry Padmini?
What are you saying,Mother
I never had such an Idea
I thought you wanted
water for thirst
But
You've washed your hands
That's Okay,I'll leave
Padmini don't be in a haste
I shall...
I heard everything,aunty
Dear-No aunty
I'm not feeling sad
about it
See,there aren't
any hiccups
You don't know
about your uncle
Do you know what
he's capable of?
Whatever happens
I'll marry only Ranganayagi
If not
There's no life for me
Did I send you there
to come back like this?
Since you were so much
in Love with him
I asked pardon to
a servant
Do you know the pain I took to
bring Ranganayagi's uncle
Why?...Why?
Why did Muthu...
Why did Muthu hit
Ranganayagi's uncle?
Why does he support
her so much?
is it because,she's a
co-worker?
Not that,she's in
love with him
Might be because of that
Why didn't you
tell me?
Earlier when I said
you hit me
That's why I didn't talk
about that servant maid
Okay,you didn't tell me
But why didn't you tell
your master
From tomorrow your post
should raise
For which,tell your master
what ever you can
Where's Ranganayagi?
She went back just now
Why are you crying
like this?
I'm scared about
my uncle
He knows where I'm
right now
That's it,anything
might happen
He won't leave
this so easily
Tomorrow itself he might force
me to marry someone else
Nothing will happen
Ranganayagi
Look,anyone else,other
than you-
Who tries to tie the
auspicious thread....
It wouldn't be the auspicious thread
for me,but the lasso of execution
Why do you speak
like this?
Did I say,I wouldn't
marry you
Look,you know quite well
For me everything is
madam and master
I'll marry you when master
get's married
Always master,master....
If he doesn't marry
wouldn't we marry too
Ranganayagi,listen to me
Take your hands away
don't touch me
Look master she's
not accepting
But Muthu is threatening
to kill her
She has got some one
else in her mind
Even the he's forcing
her to marry him
He threatens,he'll
kill her
She's suffering this torture
everyday
If you don't inform madam
tomorrow about our marriage
I won't see you
nor speak to you
look here,Ranganayagi.....
I think,he won't
leave her
Not only this,there's
much more
He's being very unloyal
to you
That's what is hurting
me the most
But I am not supposed
to reveal all those
Tell me
He has complained mother that you are
spending most of your wealth on drama's
And has got half of the
wealth on his name
Acting like a son,he has
cheated you and mother
Master,it isn't moving
He was taking care isn't it?
it'll be only like him
Thrash nicely and
bring it here
How dare you raise your
hands on my horse?
Who gave you the permission
to get on my charriot?
Stop it
I gave him the permission
Master-don't call
me like that
Your hands musn't touch
the charriot again
Your feet musn't touch
this soil
You musn't come into
my sight
For the sin you have committed
I must have burnt you alive
But since you've been with me
I let you go
Better leave from here
What mistake did
I commit master?
Don't speak
I don't understand anything
Ay,Why are you simply standing
throw him out
Come dear
Charriot has come
without Muthu?
Come
If he doesn't go
even after this
I must drive him out
Is this life an enigma
who shall solve it
Will my hands hit me,will my
fingers hurt my eyes
Tears rolling down from my eyes
like river which never has happened before
I have no right
to question!
There's no justice
for the poor
Cow can become snake
due to false witness
Y DD
Your blood will ask you
What crime have I done?
What happened?
Where is Muthu?
Madam
- Come here
What Happened?
Where is Muthu?
Tell me?
Master has drived Muthu
out by force
Why did you beat Muthu
tell me?Why did you,tell....
Having sent muthu out
don't call me so
Is muthu more dearer to you
than your own son?
Yes,he is more
dearer to me.
If you come to know
what he realy is?
You wouldn't say so
What do you know
about Muthu?
Even after knowing
I love Ranganayagi
He has forced her
to marry him
I saw that myself
If you want,ask her
Why to ask her,you fool
I'll tell you
Ranganayagi doesn't
love you
She loves only Muthu
What Mother says is
I thought he cheated only
botht of us
He has cheated her too
What has he cheated?
Don't speak as if you
know nothing
He spoke ill about me
deceived you
Hasn,t he written half of
our wealth on his name?
Yuck,shut your mouth
Muthu hasn't cheated us
we are cheating him
We're living only
on his wealth
You've asked him not to step
on this soil
Only we must not step
Because he's the Owner
of this soil
He's the one who has to
rule this soil
An Old man came here
like a beggar
Do you know who he is?
You know how he was
once upon a time
Why are you so happy
brother-in-law?
Because I'm going to become the
lord of a big Kingdom,that's why
Is it because he has
adopted your child?
You only paved way
for that
Will I play with you?
Not only because of that
Also his wife expired who
could be a hindrance
The one who went away
was not a hindrance
Only her baby
is a hindrance
If you think your son will
inherit this wealth
Then you're wrong
After Landlord's death
His son will inherit
the wealth
Then,what about you?
What about my Sister,who's
depending on you?
What about me,who's depending
on you both?
What are you thinking?
Fools have one way
Ambalathar has 1000 ways
come here
Brother-in-law,Careful
documents
Ay,Work slowly and
carefully
Sir is in prayer
Isn't it
You had Promised to get 100 couples
marry & donate land to them,Isn't it!
If you sign these documents
Rest could be taken care
Minister
He's arranging for the
Mass Marriage!
Where will we go?
What are you watching
Chase them out
Oh God!Order them
to stop it!
Hubby,If Landlord comes to
know,he'll get angry!
Order them to stop
Be quiet!
Stop it!
What happened?
Why are they beating you?
You give us without
we asking you
When injustice happens to
you,we can't stay idle!
When we come to tell you the truth
but they are not allowing us inside.
They're beating and
chassing us out,Boss!
Injustuce to me? What are
you saying?
The land document gifted by you
in our marriage proved invalid!
Why?
Because those lands
are not on your name
Then on Whose name is it?
On your most loved cousin
Rajasekar's name
Not only this,boss,we are being
cheated on many counts!
Boss,we are not getting any of
the benefits anounsed by you
This type of mistske will
never happen in future!
Please come up
Minister
Hubby
He's calling you,go
I didn't see you
as my cousin
I saw you as my
own brother
You shouldn't have
done this
What didn't I do for you
Since we didn't have a child
we adopted your child
Is it game of fate
or God's will
My Wife,that Goddess!
...Before dying presented
me an heir!
We never take back what we've said
and what we've given
The day my child
was born
That day itself I've transfered all my
Wealth on your child's name
I haven't given any charity from
the property given to your Son!
To upkeep my ancestors tradtions
I had kept separately 100 Villages!
Now I shall transfer even that
on your name
This is the will on
your son's name
This is the life
of the poor
Mr.Rajasekar,I've forgiven
you for cheating me!
But for what you've done to the
poor even if we forgive
I'm going
Brother where are
you going?
The World is too big
Brother,please don't leave us
and go away
He had committed a mistake in
the avarice for the property!
Brother,we don't want this
property!Please don't leave us & go
We never take back what we've said
and what we've given
Brother
When you decide something,no
one can alter it!
Everyone knows it!
I'll ask you one thing
for the last time!
Will you give me?
What's there with me now
to give you?
Your... Child
By bringing up your son,we'll get
atoned atleast from few sin's!
Give me atleast
that opportunity!
But on one condition
Bring him as an
Ordinary man
Even shadow of Money
musn't fall on him
I'll come back one day
Untill then,no one should know
the truth whose son,he is?
This is a promise on me
Father
You used to say that cheated
is more siner than the cheater!
I had been cheated
Father
I stand before you
as a convict
Forgive me
Is this life an enigma
who shall solve it
This is your Kingdom,don't
part with it,good man
If you're there to perform good
deeds,problems won't be seen
You gave happiness in life,why do
you give tears in eyes now
When epics are waiting
to speak your life
If you head north
seeking for life
Madam!
To keep up the
Landlord's promise
And to save Muthu
from my brother
I showed a servant
maid's dead child
And lied that Landlord's
child is dead
Without anyone's knowledge
we came here
The one who's looking
like a beggar
This is only part of the
alms he had given
Where will the old man
be now,Mother?
One who has to be a King
is under a tree now!
I had called him home
several times...
I'll go and call him,Mother!
I thought!in the Beginning
itself,I thought
I suspected that Muthu
looks like Landlord
It's right
She has cheated me,my
Sister has cheated me
She cheated me lying that
the child died
I won't leave this
I won't be fooled
once again
Hey!come we'll kill
my son-in-law
The Landlord...-Who's
the Landlord?Hey fool!
I know law more than
the supreme court judge
If Muthu complains that everyone
cheated his Father
He'll get back all
the property!
Before that,we'll kill
your Master
Then,we'll put the
blame on Muthu
Then see...
Public will beat him for
killing the Landlord
In between the chaos,let
our men kill him
Then wealth goes to my
childless sister
We'll send her up
after sometime
Then I'm the King &
you are the bishop
Stop
Don't we need evidence
for his death?
Remove his Slippers
Now throw him away
Not even a piece of Bone
should be recovered
They had killed
the Landlord!
I found only this Towel and
Slippers by river side
Muthu has murdered the Landlord
everybody come
I found only this Towel and Slippers
by river side!
Muthu has murdered the Landlord
everybody,please come!
Where is the Master?
You had killed him
Tell me,what did you
do to my Master?
You had killed him
Look here,nothing has
happened to him,isn't it?
He's alive,isn't it?
Tell me,where is he?
Sinner,you had beaten
him to death
In a angry mood he
ordered to beat you
For which you had killed and
thrown him in the River,Sinner!
It seems the Landlord
is dead
Muthu and Kali
are fighting
Don't harm me!Don't
harm me,Muthu
Don't harm me,Muthu
I only killed the Landlord,But
only on Ambalathar's word,I did
Why did you kill my son?
oh God!
Hey!are you scared?
You had killed the Landlord and
have beat him badly
Why won't he take the
blame on himself?
Are you watching fun
hit him
Hey!Ambalathar is escaping
Catch him
Son-in-law
You said,you won't Marry
my daughter
That's why in the anger I
did all this
!
Please forgive me
Not only you
We all have done injustice
to Muthu
He only has to
Pardon us
Master,nothing has
happened to you
You're safe
How much ever I
insulted you....
Forgive me,Muthu
Why asking my forgiveness?
Come dear
I was about to tell you,but you
yourself understood it.
But now-a-days,I am unable to understand
What & Why its happening?
It's better that you don't
understand something!
Mother wait,we'll get
blessings
You shouldn't get
blessing from me
What's this Boss?Who else
will bless this Orphan?
You Father!
Yes Muthu,your Father
saved me
What are you telling
me Master?
Where is Father?
Doesn't he like
to see me?
I didn't do anything wrong,he could
have blessed me atleast while going
Don't worry son
Where ever he is,his
blessings will be with you
How long I've waited to see
you like this
What's this Thenapan
Brother?
What appearance is
this?
The girl whom I was
in love with
Has been taken
away by that Crow
Sage musn't speak
like that?
Shouldn't speak like that
isn't it-Yes!
Why to bother?
Yes,why to bother,you
used to say often,Isn't it
What's to be obtained
wouldn't be lost
What's not to be obtained
would be lost
I got only this
get my blessings
No one can dislodge
Master-No,always
you are the Master
Muthu is ever and always
A servant to all
You're my Master!
Longlive Master