We can output more than 250 automobile per day
I know
What if I want you reach 300
We could finished it 3 month before the schedule
Really?
Kidding! 300 was perfect
Boss
Here you are
Take it slow
I find it
find what?
that lady you want
Ning?
ya
What r u waitting for,get my car ready
But we got no car left
No car?
We got thousands of them~
get going
Seems like her Truck
She should be here
Please
what's happen here?
Where is Ning?
she was there! i know
R u hungary?
No
U seems hungary!
peanut?
Thanks
Ning... the money for the food
forget it ok
We are good friends aren't we?
She will never pay us
ok
Where is Ning?
overthere
Ning...
Boss over there
miss Ning
miss
I'm your daddy!
that way
Who are you these guys?What you want me to do?
I'm your father
look at the picture
milord
so this is your daughter?
Nice to meet you lady
Like the movie
Form now on! thsi is your house
take a look
ok
it's your room
so huge?
you like it?
so which room you live?
over there
if you don't like it !
we have other romms for you
No no!i feel it too good for me
look at this bed!
where is boss?
upstair
take Ning's other staff here
quick
ok
Boss boss
Miss
Boss these....
keep it?
throw them away
I need them
Boss?
okok keep what ever you want
Daddy
Everyone!
She was my dear daughter!Ning
Hi every one
Nice to know you
Me too
hi
Ning
you looking for me?
Why you sleep on the floor
I like hard place
Where is your night-suit?
I feel hard for wearing that
So i dress myself
you don't sleep good?
ya
may be you should try the floor
ok
Ok! "I will try the floor
you try the bed ok?
I wanna sleep here
Sleep
I will try it tomorrw
Ning need a new visualize
She try her best
Miss zhou?
U think she have the promble of show herself
about this
Find someone to slove this
From hongkong
So
do it for me
Find someone there
ok!leave it to me
What about yourself?
I'm cool
Nothing
Thank godness you weren't my son
Morning
Wanna a Job?
always Job find me
sit down
which job you want?
Nuclear plant's manage
Weapon master
virus tester
we wanna you
I come early
acturlly!I I...
you speak mandarin?
yes
talk to me
I have learn it for 5 more years
How much you gonna pay me
12000to the mainland
I really interesting in this job
i offer 10000
I wanna ask
when will i get promoto
when?
i can offer 10000
ok
u speak awful mandarin
us your tone!
Tone
10000 is ok
where you form?
it's fine
you are a cook?
We wanna a fashion adviser
we don't want the cook
Pls
I will try
Mr ling?
10'o tomorrow morning
you will have a interview there
fill this table and bring it with you tomorrow
My?
We will call you when we need you
Me?
Give me your card
ok
hope you can find a nice job today
He never find a job?
yes
Why you treat him like this
He was really good to me
hei
I 'm happy
come and celebrate with me?
you really good
ok i will gome soon
He find his job
Thank god
Get off the car
What?
He wanna see me at the first time
Bu this car was mine?
you wanna a texi?
you still take your clothes?
U can buy anything in Shanghai
Like it?
It's good
You just start your job,be more energy
Don't let them feel you were fool
They call it dump
But anyway you was a manage
I will clean it after your leaving
departure time
Don't be worry
if you feel hard there
just came back
Jing's number
They will catch you there
thanks
Byebye! and remember don't cry
i will not
you wouldn't
when we just met
I just left you somewhere you don't know
you cry like a baby
Time change me
ok here is the left
byebye
careful
don't cry
See you! I will call you when i get there
Wonderful! at last he leave
Why are you hiding here?
can't wait to see you
Hello
I know you love me
one more
byebye
I'm really leaving
he will never be back?
Can't say it
We will see
should we?
we will
i would rather be her
if you like me!you will know it
I understand
Where you going?
you could meet him down there
that way ok?
ok
the copter
byebye
What's your girlfriend doing?
She was fool
People like beautiful things
I really love this place
it's funny
She's really funny
do you listen to me ?
I said i love this place
I know i know
take you staff
help me ok?
Mr wang?
I can handle it
you are fashion designer?
no!seems not like
I said i will handle it myself
That's ok
what's the matter?
i'm fine
Barbie may have some promble
youshould watch over her
are you ok?
sorry madam!i wanna go into here
do me a favor
i can hold my pee
sorry!really sorry
your skin have some kinds of hypersusceptibility
it's none of my business
sorry
Don't worry
Bu i don't like dirty things
Where we drop them?
give it to me!i will help you
Thank you
Her was the fashion designer we retain form hongkong
Our boss
LIng zu
sit down
Mr ling
I wanna you change some kind of dirty girl to a modren women
Just like those hongkong girl
or the Paris' girl
For how long
how long?
severl month
only 3 months?
i'm afraid..
just do your job well ok
I will promto you soon
like the car design?
car?
kidding
I have fully confidence of my success
I'm the expert
you must meet my daughter
ok
Boss
What you think of her?
she was ...perfect
I'm sorry! i quit
bye bye
other man?
only him
catch him
Mr ling! Mr ling!!!!
Please stay
I can change
how old are you?
23?
you are too old to change
Sorry!you could find someone else
But! I like you
Why?
Because I like you
you are an honor man
You shouldn't trust me
Please help me
don't push me
I will give you double money
Sorry too much
we give you triple
how?
I will tell boss
you get her first
Form hongkong?
you know?
absoulutely
My seventh year in shanghai
great
But she seems unhappy
just do you job
triple money
done
relax
smile
more
ok!catch this feeling
I feel a little better
no no
you like ugly ?
Ju?
helle Ju?
know what i'm doing?
I don't know
listen
i'm driveing
Done! piece of cake
my job was simple
She was a countryside girl
bad skin
so .... bad
but she trust me
really?
one left thing
what?
prise me
you are so great
you are so smart
i'm proud of you
I will call you later
ok
byebye
what?
nothing
nothing what
so kiss me
ok
hurry
from right
Lin here
turn back
you just ack like a bitch
........
you look lke shit
look at me
relax
come on like me
ok stop
open your army
an this was the most important part
yes
it important
keep doing it
great
Form today you shoud change yourself
form head to you leg
trust me
do the faceshow ok?
cheap a little ok?
but it's cheap
ok
her skin was so bad
a man like me need how much?
double as her
pay the oney
ok
Card please
thank you
first time see you
you change your show everyday
like the windy
like the cloud
you change everyday
yes
better you know it
but i trust you
short hair suit you
i believe you
ok cut it
take a photo
everyine looking at me
you are so beautiful
like a star
nobody like me before
yes
She was pretty
you just pay the money
Who clean my car today?
it's me boss
you?
seeing...
great
thank you boss
boss
miss zou?
something you wanna tell me?
That designer?
I feel he was such a lier
only to steal your money
Mr tang
more lier in hongkong??
i dno't know much about them
but my daughter feel happy
you feel happy for her?
find a boyfriend
boss
i like him
hello
hello mr ling
what's the promble?
nothing
i like thos things you buy for me
that's all?
no i wanna ask you do you like miss zhou?
she?
i feel she was lonely
but she was good at work so do i
so she should go back ok?
ok!i will tell my father
dismiss her
i will srerv you 24h
So
Can we be friends?
but
people don't lkie me
can i?
times
give us time
we will be close friends
sorry to bother you
i will call you later
see you tomorrow
ok
byebye
bye
Friends ?how could we?
here comes
you sleep?
What you think who i am?
be my guest
MichaeIJacksoM's home ??
you can only afford the rent
you come to check my home
no just come nearby
these was for you
you work hard?
but!i like easy job
i know
so i come to tell you
just remember
you can't do it like this
thank you for your advice
why are you telling this
late !i'm leaving
we cheack your background
you are not the fashion designer
bu youdo your job good
thanks
good night
what you feel boss?
too many promble
find out yourself
boss
hi boss
you was good
but you looks good
form now on!you will be free
she was busy
what about the money?
i will give you
great
why you hongkong like money
please
we all do the same job
and we all chinese
i will open a party next week
you better give her a better design
i think we done
try you hard ok?
ok
go ahead
byebye
thank you daddy
good
cheers
in the city
eating manner was important
so i will teach you how to use the folk
and your spoon
from outside to insider........
you konw it?
you try it?
it's easy
i saw it on the movie
watch yourself!be more quite
try slowly
let's play a little game
eat these egg without other things
it's inpolite
it's rude
you can't suck it
i will tell you
i hope you
be more normal like other girl
wew don't have much time
you are funny
i'm not kidding
i wont teach you if you lost it
i will try my best
one more question
can i turn back?
no
sleep?
you change less
hot coffee please
get up
he is dead
what?
his heart dead
hello
Barbie brake with me
i saw she with other guy
it 's good to you
leave her alone
what
you know ivy?
yes
haven't seen her for 5,6 years
oh
she now was
a manager of some big company
great
an she was over here
have tea??
who's this girl?
new girlfriends?
hi?
long time no see
play around here?
no work
fo what?
he was
make me
do my fashion designer
he changes a little
really
my card
card?
byebye
do i bother you?
nothing
what about you?
get away
look at you
it's ok
leave
hei you
me?
yes
sorry i
i was a little ...
who was that girl
my ex girlfriend
really
yes
am i ugly
so you need my help
you was ugly
you made me like this
wait ! bu i like you
i wanna be perfect
ok
an i will make you best
trust me
ok
let's go home
hurry
nice to know you
do you know how to drive?
you was my little girl
thi spic take when you was only 6
that's your mon?
i can't remember my father
happy to see you
bu we change everyday
if you can't stand alone
you can't survive in modren life
i don't know it before
but after now !i get it
have any girlfriend?
ya
quite many
-
this where i used to live
u wanna eat this?
give me 2 of them
careful
thanks
Qian
I'm Ning
Sorry
come
sit
they can't reconize me
your money
ok
it's too much
i own you before
come on !it's my favour cook
smell good
great
i like it
boss
I have finish the job
the English ambassador will come alone
but he will leave soon
you can talk to him later
but the france ambassador won't come
he send his secretary to meet you
where is my daught?
upstair
what about this one?
beautiful
come quick
Am i beautiful
what u feel?
great
each one was great
every one of them
change another one
change again?
hurry
you don't like me?
please tell me
am i looking good>
en
what r you laughing at?
tell me
we should see her
I don't wana give her press
ya
so we stay here
we will be back soon
Maybe she love him
Aorry!i'm looking for miss yang
I call her before
she was having a meeting
please wait
for yours
they are preferssion
i was taught by you
tell you the truth
please
help me this time
you change a lot
you mean before
don't remind me of it
but now we can eran a lot of money
i really miss you after lost you
I know nothing
only thing i can do was crying
don't you know?
i know
so please
but i lose my job for  9 months
if you don't help me
i will lose my job tomorrow
soory
i'm really sorry
to make your heart broke
forget it ok
i will give you a chance!
you can do something for me?
i will help you ok
i won't push you
i noly to help you
remember!
be to your self
sorry
I rally can?
waitting for your daughter
mys on Frankie will wait her here
i know sorry
i don't know what happen to her
what?
but thanks for your coming
byebye
see you
thanks
goodbye
i have called them
but his cellphone was close
if anything happen !
i don't wanna see that lin again
i c
Boss the miss return
thank gods
everyone ! this was my daughter
hi miss zhang
I'm son of english ambassador
i study chinese at qinghua Univercity
let her handle it
you speak chinese?
give her confidnce
can you read poem
yes i can
sit down
I was readding some chinese poem these days
scholar
i am agree with him
Reading......
great
See you
Boss you see
Frankie he maybe like miss
relax!
We got the room
congratulation!you look so beautiful today
you preforms well
too late!i will leave
yes
boss you have date Mr tang tomorrow morning
I give you the morning call
byebye
boss! i'm leaving
See you! Good night
boss i will go with them
don't go! let's talk
he have design some car
you should see
where is Ling?
he was leaving
what he told you?
he says he go with miss zou
i will go home byebye
i only trust you
because
I don't trust you
you was an honest man
i tell you
don't trust other people ok?
You know how sadness i feel
i know nothing
it's doom to me
I cry and cry
remember
you should work hare to keep your job
i wanna prise you last night
why you quit
my personal reason
you wanna double you pay?
i will consider of it
not this time
10000more for a week
Miss zou
give him a little more money
more?
thanks
i should show some respect for you
you needn't
hi time to say goodbye
you are so kind
i always kind
you don't feel before
i can walk
come on man
come
what you doing here
he  came here for how long?
let me show you some real nice food
the Shanghai steamed bread
sit
help yourself
taste good
Sorry
what's wrong with you
sorry
you eat shit man
don't be so loud please
look at my boss
sorry
let's go
to where?
to the airport
you
eat it as your won will
it won't be long
so delicious
don't play with me
you sit down
i check out you before
we were form same school same block
really?
yes
so you give me a ride?
no
just wanna tell you!be yourself
you understand?
yes
so
you must hold on
daddy?how long since he left
1 hour
why don't you keep him
i tried,but he refused
where he goes?
back to hongkong
Where you going?
milady
Ning
boss
i gonna goto the airport
what?
get in
let him drive
i can drive fast
don't be afraid
i will call for help
hello i'm your boss
send me a car
right here
we can't make it
we could
what you doing?
i can repair it myself
don't worry i can handle it
let's do it together
sorry
it's ok!i love you daddy
listen to me
you dare to play with me?
catch me if you can
you be dead if i can
kiss my left face
don't go
what r you doing?
feel good?
Winnie
Winnie¡¯i'm back£¬Winnie
that fool
hello!where is winnie?
thanks
i lost my key
come in
hurry
you can't see me here
this was nice place
you really upset me
allright
i wanna talk to you
me too,but not here
let's leave
out?
no! hide here
back?
my name was ZhangNing
I'm tian
tian?
ya!i'm back
you s
sudden what?
you came back early
i quit my job
don't worry
come in
so soon?
ok
i will leave first
who's that girl
her girlfriend
who r you?
nothing
i am a stupid man
hahahahaha
drink?
nice place
i can fluting
really?
who r you?
he is tian
who is this one
it's me
let me explain
i don't wanna listen
we fall in love before she met you
enough
some thing for you
form shanghai
take it
you like it?
come on
nice
leave
wake up
you don't understand
i don't love you anymore
he was a good guy
i love him
just leave
ok
i'm sorry!
really sorry
my fault
i wanna grow up
bu i can't
so!you two should be together
remember to treat her well
your girlfriend?
i like you
i don't know
what it feels like to love someone
until i met you
i know it's you
i like you
Frankie loves me
but i love you
come with me
i can't live without you
you don't like me
no
i just want your daddy's money
see you
don't love me please
i got a lot of girlfriends
bw wise
byebye
boss
slow down
i must learn how to repair my own car
it's good to me
i can live again
i can keep my own personality
let's see it
what you feel
what you feel now
form the basic?
i will go first
i don't like you
you should really make a change
so other people will like you
show them the really you
ok
you should tell me early
because i  love you
it's boss
anybody?
no one there
soft
what that hard thing
the phone
you are ning's boyfriend?
we may met before?
i don't know you
you are the cook
yes?
find your job?
no
what?
nothing byebye
what's your major in?
beijing duck
give me your card
sit down !let's talk
ok
it's the deal
you are really good
what's show on tonight?
no
HeIIo
come on! quick
find someone you love
try
byebye
have fun
hello
ok tomorrow
this way
i have too many thing to tell you
2 years
time to forget him
give yourself a chance
ÎÒÃÇÖØÐÂ¿ªÊ¼?
cook?
please marry me?
feel good??
am i disturb you?
what you mean?
me?
you was so hard?
you don't know i gonna foget you today
but it's my restaurant
yours?
you
you run this restaurant ?
ning?
talk to her
i get it
she still like you
me?
just go
after her
go and get her
she likes you
it's you
go
make up you mind
come on
go
stay away
calm down
i'm sorry
i know it
2 year
what the
you know?
i wanna find you
but we meet again
i don't know
i feel maybe we should be together
it's destiny
stay away
it's for you
hit me if you want
not my head
hit me
fool
but i love you
push me
i buy it for you
like it?
no
only love you
do you know what i feel?
no