When we come into this world...
God shows us everyone around us.
Grandpa, Mummy, Papa...
aunt Maya, uncles and aunts...
the tiny kids...
and my best friend Rhea
But there is that one face
that He does not show us.
I wonder why
That one face He hides from us
The face we come
to fall in love with
NEITHER TOY NOR I CAN KNOW
* Daughters are treated like Queens
* by their fathers
* Theirs is a story
* so loveable and beautiful
* They're delicate little dolls...
* and there's no saying
* who will take them away
* Daughters are treated like Queens
* by their fathers
* Theirs is a story
* so loveable and beautiful
When I left my house and came here
for the first time, I had wept.
And now that it is time
to return home...
tears flow from my eyes again
* Daughters are treated like Queens
* by their fathers
* by their mothers
* Theirs is a story
* so loveable and beautiful
* God is their protector...
* they spend a childhood
* in innocence...
* they're innocent even
* in adolescence
* Daughters are treated like Queens
* by their mothers
* Theirs is a story
* so very loveable
* They rule every heart.
* They're treated like queens
* They're birds who will
* one day fly away
* Let no one leave their hand,
* let no one hurt them...
* they're blessings from God
* Daughters are treated like Queens
* by their fathers
* Theirs is a story
* so loveable
I have everything, but I don't know
who will come into my life...
and belong to me
Dear God, to begin with,
I'm sorry...
for not writing to you
in all these days
I missed my family very much
while I was in the hostel
I'm sure You looked after everyone
while I was away
In fact, I think You have
paid more attention to grandpa
He has put on weight, hasn't he?
With lots of love - Esha
To Him... like this.
If you don't pray to God,
how will He protect you?
You can protect me. That's the duty
God has assigned to you.
Didn't He tell you...?
- Esha!
Grandpa, I don't even know
if God actually exists.
You are the one I see all the time.
So whenever I have a problem...
won't I come to you?
- Trust in God and you will know...
that He's always with you.
- But I haven't even seen Him.
So how can I have trust in Him?
- Trust doesn't flow...
out of what you just see, Esha.
It comes from the heart, from belief'
Close your eyes and pray to Him...
and you will yourself believe
Karan is the most handsome guy
in the world!
Karan, have uncle and aunt employed
a new chauffeur?
Esha, Priya's in love again.
- How will she know what love is?
Oh yes.
Esha won't even talk to boys.
And that's because she
can talk only to Tutu
To fall in love, you must
first like the boy...
followed by endless chats,
friendship and...
And?
- And love happens on its own
You belong to me
I realise today how everything
changes on someone's arrival
When I'm asleep or awake, there's
someone with me all the time
I felt lonely in a crowd earlier...
and although I'm all alone now,
I feel someone's presence with me
Do you feel that too?
I belong to you.
Who is it? When did you meet him?
This is Bingo and you're listening
to your favourite show...
falling in love
while listening
If there is something you want to
convey to someone, do it through us...
with all your heart and love...
and we will carry your message
to the one you love
Who knows...? You might
fall in love, while you listen!
Who am I talking to?
I can't talk to a crowd
Can you play any song for me?
Of course! I can even sing for you.
"Is this love?"
- Sure, if you keep calling in
You haven't told me
your boyfriend's name
The one you want to play a song for.
- I don't have a boyfriend
But there is someone
I want to play this song for
He's the one I think about
some times
The thought of it brings
a smile to my lips
Whose voice I know,
deep down in my heart
I wait for the one...
who's in love with love.
- What's gotten into you, Esha?
Since when have you been thinking
about these matters of the heart?
Don't give me those looks, Rhea.
I haven't written this
I found it in a book
in the college
I didn't even know
who had written it
But it felt as if it was
meant for me
And when I heard his voice,
I was convinced...
I want to say something to the girl
who called from Simla Boarding College
Simla? There was no call from Simla.
- It's the one who requested...
my favourite number,
"Is this love"?
Not yet... but if she's listening
to this programme...
she'll surely be.
- I don't know who you are
But I have a feeling that maybe
you are the one I wrote that for
The one I wait for. The one
who's in love with love, like me.
I don't even know
if you're listening to this...
but Bingu, I really wish
I could get to meet her
I think it's possible. In fact,
I can do something about it
I want the two of you to come to
my studio at 6 pm on November 12
Let's hope she's listening
to this programme
I knew it! She had to fall in love,
even while she listened!
On November 12 at 6 pm
Bingo, there's someone here
to see you
Is she...?
She's been waiting for you
since last evening
She hasn't come personally.
She has sent this note for you
A note?
- Yes
Did he show up?
- He did
And maybe you want to know
what he looks like
6 feet in height and...
- Bingo...
I don't want to know
anything about him
You ought to have met him
I'll surely meet him some day
When I heard your voice on radio,
I badly wanted to meet you
But then I thought, it wasn't right.
I study in Simla...
in perhaps the same college
that you have you studied in
My house is in DehraDun.
I'm away from home, no doubt...
but I carry the faith
of my folks with me
I can't tell you anything about myself
right now. Not even my name
And I won't ask you your name either,
or where your house is...
or what you do for a living.
But I sure want to be friends with you
The day I am confident that I can
introduce you to my folks...
I will tell you everything
about myself
Till then, we'll write
to each other
You might probably not even
want to write to me...
for all the conditions I impose.
However, if you wish...
you can write to me at PO Box 235
I want a post-box.
Fill up this form and
pay a deposit
Sir, why do they go in
for a post-box?
A post-box is meant for those who don't
want to reveal their name and address
With every post-box, we give
them a number and a key
This number becomes their address.
- And the key?
The one who receives mail can
open the box and take it away
Four years ago, when I jotted
something on a book in the college...
I didn't even imagine
someone would find it
Least of all, someone who
thought so much like me
I have faith...
that God has decided something
for each one of us
He knows when, where and how
we will meet someone
Maybe He has decided something
for the two of us, too
Let's see how He brings us together
There are things we
must leave to Him
If this letter brings a smile
to your lips...
we are friends already. You don't
want to know anything about me...
but there is something
I want to tell you
I'm a dreamer
And maybe I have already met you
Why didn't you tell him your name?
I can't break grandpa's trust
for the sake of my love, Rhea
Our relationship needs
some more time
Until I to trust him enough to
introduce him to Grandpa...
I will not meet him too
But he can meet you, can't he?
He has your address
No. Every student at the college
has a separate post-box number
What will I do over here?
We'll go to the post office tomorrow
and hire a post-box
Two, not one. I think I must
start writing to Karan too
Esha, don't you want to know
what he looks like?
I know how he looks...
want to see his photo?
* I felt as if I had met him
* I felt as if I had lost my heart
* Who is he...?
* Tell us
* How and where did it all happen?
* Your sleep...
* he has vanished with
* Dreams...
* he has given me
* It shouldn't have happened.
* But it's true
* Days have shortened...
* my nights are longer
* Who is he...?
* Tell us
* I felt as if I had met him
* I felt as if I had lost my heart
* Who is he...?
* Tell us
* How and where did it all happen?
* What happens now...?
* It has already happened
* Your heart...
* I have already lost
* He's mad.
* He has driven me crazy too
* I've survived, but he has left me
* wounded in the heart
* Who is he...?
* Tell us
* How and when did it all happen?
* I felt as if I had met him
* I felt as if I had lost my heart
* Who is he...?
* Tell us
* How and where did it all happen?
Close your eyes.
- What for?
Monty!
No... I'm Akshay
No! Monty!
Who's that?
- My boyfriend
Stop him someone!
Madam, how will he shoot?
Your kid won't stop hollering
That's how my kid is, lady
He has done 50 ads already
For sweets and vegetable dishes
I don't know what's gotten
into him over here
Know what? He's Sunny Deol!
He'll grow up to be Dharmendra!
Shut up now, or I'll give you
a slap when we get home!
You're embarrassing me!
- What happened
This child won't stop crying
He's laughing already!
Are you married?
- No
Hold the kid, girl...
what are you doing?
Rahul, you're so handsome!
Know what...?
The sight of my husband's face,
scares him.
But he was happy to see your eyes.
You have lovely cheeks...
and a great smile.
I wish you had married me!
Will you marry me?
At least give me a kiss!
Save me, please...
- One moment. I get it
Who was it this time?
- It's Monty
Congratulations! You now have
boys chasing you too!
He has boys chasing him?
What a loose-character!
What have you done now?
- I've done nothing
How was I to know that
there was a boyfriend?
Monty's boyfriend?
- Not Monty's! Tina's!
Had those hands got to me,
I wouldn't have a bone in order
Tina's...?
- Monty's!
I wish, I had not kissed her
on the very first date
Kissed Monty?
- No! Tina!
Who'd want to kiss Monty!
She has lips like grapes,
raisins for eyes...
and pomegranate seeds for teeth
and cheeks like apples from Kashmir!
Is that a girl or a fruit-salad?
Watch it, just watch it
I am a-kela (alone and a banana)
Just save me!
- From whom?
From Monty
The bloody ape! Ass, elephant,
a two-legged rhinoceros!
He wants to marry Tina!
The Moron!
I hope Monty's deaf, too.
- He's actually Monty Mehra
Mehra? You're getting beaten up then.
- Why?
You're going to get a thrashing.
- But why?
One minute...
Break his bones, if you must.
But not things around
What's up with you?
We've only been talking... I swear
Misuse your eyes,
and this is what will happen
Mustn't I return the look,
if someone looks at me lovingly?
Sure, go ahead. But how often?
And this isn't love that
happens all the time
You talk as if you've fallen
in love many times
Have you made a single girlfriend?
- A single...? Great!
Idiot! A single girlfriend
is all you need
A single girlfriend...?
What if she takes ill?
Which means there is no girl
you can ever fall in love with
That's the one I'm looking for.
- You won't need to look
When you see her,
you'll know that for sure
Maybe I will.
But how about you?
What?
I always meant to ask you.
You meet so many girls...
but who's she going to be?
She's going to be someone
with child-like innocence...
but have the maturity
of an adult too
She's going to be so beautiful...
that I'll want to keep
looking at her
Her smile will bring
a smile on every lip
Whose eyes...
won't ever make her
want to lie
That's how she will be
* I'm a crazy Jat...
* I couldn't see the obvious...
* that she's in love with me
* that she could die for me
I was trying to tell you that
there was a letter for you...
but you just wouldn't understand.
- My letter!
Let's decide on a signal first.
- A signal?
Yes. This is what I'll do
when there's a letter for you
There are times when you don't
need music to listen to a tune
There is no need for rains
for a flower to blossom
To listen to what the heart says,
you don't need words
Tell me... what is
your favourite colour?
My favourite colour? Blue.
That's mine too.
What is it that brings
a smile to your face?
Rains. And hot jalebis.
I love the rains.
And...?
- And...
I love the laughter of children
When do I get the feeling that your
laughter is like that of a child?
I don't know. Maybe it is
And what do you like?
- Me?
I like you
Tomorrow's my birthday
So send me a birthday present
I wish I'd find you when I open
the envelope for your letter
I can't come personally,
so I'm sending Tutu to you
He has been with me with
ever since I was a child...
and he'll now remain with you forever
It's amazing, we're alike
in everything
But there's something else too...
which both of us have.
- What?
Who marries so early?
I lead a free life. I come home,
have fun, chill out...
If I were married, the moment the
door opened, my wife would say...
Akshay! You're so late!
I hope this is my house!
Akshay, you didn't tell me
you have approved of a girl?
Rahul, you didn't tell me either.
The two of you are as thick as thieves
How was I to know that you're in such
a tearing hurry to get married?
When did I know that either?
- My child...
won't you introduce Akshay
to your Mummy and Papa?
Mama, Papa, this is Akshay
Hello, son
This is Rahul, Akshay's friend.
But he's like my son too
Rahul and Akshay have been together
since they were kids
Even brothers fight.
But between the two of them... never
Here's your opportunity.
Tell them that I'm a terrible guy
We've heard Tanya telling us
so much about you
Akshay is all praise for you too
But this is the first time
we're meeting Akshay
Really? But you don't know, uncle.
Akshay always wanted to meet you
But he's one of those shy-types...
so he didn't come to you
I'm glad you came here. Had he asked
for more today, maybe he'd have got it
You can't even imagine how happy I am
Look at them. They look so good
together... Akshay and Tanya
What's happening here, Tanya?
- We're getting married
You told me that we would
be getting married soon
Sure, but I didn't mean to say
it'd happen in a day or two
But what's the problem?
Will you be able to bear the shock?
So listen!
My mother is the typical
mother-in-law
She's giving a smile right now.
But deep down in her heart...
she must be planning to
torture you
As for my dad...
I don't even know what
a father's love means
Money means everything to him
He wants a Ferari in dowry,
a flat in London...
and lots of cash!
But you need not worry
The day I get to stand on my own
two feet, we'll get married
lt'll be only you and me...
at my beach-house
But right now, we must stay away
from each other
You understand, don't you?
Let's go.
- What happened, my child?
Aunty, I do want to be
your daughter-in-law...
but I can't marry your son.
Because he's a liar
Akshay, you should have tried
telling me the truth
I fell in love with you
without any conditions
But you won't understand that
because you have never been in love
A girl like Tanya can't...
Don't worry, Ma.
Everything will be all right
What will be all right?
He's not going to marry
a girl of our choice
As for deciding it on his own,
this is an everyday affair...
Listen to me, Ma.
I'll find a girl for Akshay
Just the kind of girl all of us want.
And Akshay will marry her too
And know what?
She'll be such a chatter-box...
she's going to come out of your ears!
She'll make you laugh so much...
the laughter will resonate
in the household
She'll feed you so much,
you'll put on more weight!
And know what?
You'll love her a lot too
But you must promise me something.
When she arrives...
I won't get lesser love, will I?
This year, we've got to
find a photographer...
for our departmental store's
fashion magazine
But we've got to be very careful
with it, because...
this magazine will carry
only bridal pictures
Do you like any of them?
- I like this one very much
Why?
- In this photograph...
the bride's apprehensions and happiness
are very effectively captured
I think whoever the photographer is,
he knows a girl's mind very well
Wow, my child! You've looked at
something all of us missed out
The responsibility of this fashion
magazine, I entrust to you
Grandpa, why don't we do
a music video?
Everybody watches tv nowadays.
It'll be good for our store too
That's a good idea.
But who will do it?
Anna! Remember, she did our
fashion show last year?
She must surely know someone in Mumbai
who can do a music video
I'll telephone her right now!
- Make a call to the photographer too
Sure
Can I speak to Mr Rahul Sharma?
- This is Rahul here
I'm Esha Malhotra
We come out with a fashion magazine
for our departmental store every year
We want you to come over this year
and take photographs for the magazine
Interesting. What's the theme?
Have you chosen the models?
- No
But we're holding an audition here.
You can come over and select them
And where are we shooting it?
- In DehraDun
DehraDun?
- I know it's far away from your city
But it's only for a few days
I'm sorry, I won't be able to come.
- Why not?
I forget all about a promise
I made to someone
Honestly, I can't come
even if I want to
They loved your idea
of a music video.
Have you spoken to the photographer?
- I have, grandpa. But I think...
This is Rahul here.
Rahul Sharma
I've called to tell you
that I can come over
When are you coming?
- I'll fax all the details to you
But there's a problem.
- What?
Call me just Rahul
It was great fun!
I've personally painted it
Is this a guest-house?
This is the rehearsal hall
I've called a lot of models for
the fashion magazine's audition
I called so many times...
Go upstairs, Rahul.
It's on the first floor...
No, the second door...
and Esha's waiting for you
I'm terribly angry with you.
- I'm angry too!
I called so many times.
And where were you?
He sure has ruined the mood!
You're here for the audition?
Do you have your photographs?
No photographs,
but I do have a camera
I'm sorry, I didn't recognise you
This is the first time we've met.
How could you recognise me?
I thought you were a model
Look at my face again...
do I look like a model?
Is this how they celebrate
birthdays here?
When is yours?
Rahul, this is Esha's Papa
This is Esha's brother, Tinga
Here's the uncle and aunt...
and they're Esha's cousins,
Teeny and Binny
This is Esha's aunt, Maya.
- Greetings
And this is Rahul
And that's...
- Esha's Mummy
Mummy, this is Rahul
Rahul, have lunch and dinner
with us from today
Take a family photograph
for us, please
Grandpa, we don't have a single
photograph of the whole family
Just one thing missing
What?
Come on!
Where's the letter, Priya?
- No letter
But you signalled to say that
there was a letter for me
That's because I saw Rahul
Seriously, there's no letter
There's something else this time
Ask him not to send such bulky things.
- What is it? Tell me!
Esha, Rahul is leaving
Writing to you today,
I feel as if...
I can feel your face
with my hand
You are very close to me.
So close...
that you melt in my arms
when I stretch them out for you
All this can come true.
I'm sending something for you
Whenever you are reminded of me,
it'll draw you close to me
* Why did you call out to me,
* from the depths of your heart?
* God! What have you done?
* Why did you call out to me,
* from the depths of your heart?
* God... what have I done?
Rahul, your call to Mumbai
has gone through
I went to the post-office.
- Any letters for me?
Yes, sir. There was a letter for you
in your post-box
Send it to me at this address here
Today
This is for you. We have a reunion
party at our college
There will be music and
a lot of interesting people
The dress code is blue...
you will come, won't you?
I was in another class.
I wouldn't know anyone here
You know me. You know Esha too.
And Esha's coming with us
Where?
There's a party in my college.
Please don't refuse, Esha!
I gave these girls one last
opportunity to talk to me today
They took notes from us at school.
And they won't even recognise us now!
They ought to be taught a lesson.
- How?
This is how.
- Booze!
Not booze.
This is Rahul, my best friend
Meet Rahul, my childhood friend.
- I've never seen you earlier
Actually we've met today
after our childhood
This is Rahul.
- We're childhood friends
You aren't getting bored, are you?
What's gotten into Esha?
She's drunk!
Do something, Rahul
What can I do?
- If grandpa gets to know...
how Esha behaved at the party,
all hell will break loose
Go and do something
Wait... where are you going?
- To stop her of course
No, that won't help.
- Meaning?
Esha's a very stubborn girl.
She won't listen to anyone
If you stop her in that state,
there's no saying what she'll do
So then?
So early in the day today?
Rhea told me about last night
It doesn't appear likely that
you'd be fond of such things
Such as?
I didn't know that drink
was laced with something
It was the first time
I had a drink like that
Oh really?
- Really
After the drink,
you danced very well
I know what happened last night
wasn't right
You do realise your mistake...
It wasn't my mistake.
- Whose mistake is it then?
It's the guy who laced
my drink with something
Esha, you mustn't accept a drink
from a boy you don't know
Please! Stop lecturing me now!
Rhea was right.
- What?
You're a stubborn girl.
Very stubborn
Is that what she said about me?
I'll set her right!
She was right too.
- Not at all!
Rahul, you won't tell grandpa,
will you?
Okay, I won't tell him
But I have a condition.
- What?
We were looking for a bride
all these days, and here she was
I did that only to stop you
from telling grandpa anything
I wouldn't have told grandpa anything
even if you hadn't done this for me
Because your friends' secrets,
are not to be told to anyone
Are you my friend then?
- Are you feeling sorry then?
Is everything all right?
- Today's a full-moon night
Rahul, I forgot. We're leaving
for Mussourie at 6 tomorrow morning
Yes, Anna has organised everything
to shoot the music video there
What's up?
- Nothing's right
I quit
Hero and heroine. They're missing.
- The heroine has made it on tv
Landed a double role, playing
daughter-in-law and mother-in-law
And hero?
- Gone too. And now me too
Anna, do something!
- Do what? Every other model is booked
But we're still shooting.
- How?
Just found myself my hero-heroine.
- Really? Who?
Us...?
Madam, don't do an Adam! You're
replacing the heroine, not the hero
Madam! It's a dance! Romance
Not action
What's going on?
How can anyone shoot like this?
I quit
In tears?
Crying? Over a dance?
- Not about the dance
Then...?
- My feet
Everyone was laughing about my feet.
- Feet...?
You don't know! I know!
I got clod feet
Everyone laughed about my feet.
And you too
I don't think anyone even noticed
your feet
Not clod, just a bit different.
- I'm so full of defects
Everyone has defects.
- And I got one too many
I got a lot of defects too
Isn't your nose a bit too long?
Nose?
Mine?
And your ears. Just like a monkey
And your haircut. Oh-so-common.
- One minute. Everyone says...
this haircut looks perfect on me.
- They say it to please you
Take your lips.
- One minute. Long nose, monkey-ears
Haircut, oh-so-common.
And my lips aren't nice either?
Your chin is crooked too.
- Crooked chin?
Your eyes...
- Squint? Or cross? Or toady?
are so nice
Just like you
* I come to you...
* holding my heart
* Come on, if you want to come
* I want to
* There's no going back for me
* No going back?
* But keeping this promise
* is going to be tough
* Think it over, my friend
* If the going is like this,
* I'm going to end up crazy
* Let's lose ourselves in each other
* no one will ever find us
* I've said what I wanted to say
* I've heard what I wanted to hear
* Come on, if you're coming
* I'm coming
* No going back for me
* No going back!
* Keeping this promise
* is going to be tough
* Think it over, my friend
* I come to you...
* holding my heart
* Touch my veil
* Become my lover
* Sit before me
* Let me hold you in my heart
* I've had all I wanted
* I've lived and I've died
* Come on, if you want to come
* I want to
* There's no going back for me
* No going back?
* But keeping this promise
* is going to be tough
* Think it over, my friend
Wonderful
The day Esha won her first trophy,
I was glad
The day Esha topped her school,
But today, I haven't words enough
to describe my joys
Esha, ever since you were a child,
you gave me much to be happy about
One after another, you always
gave me something to smile about
Found this letter for you
at the post office
Why do I feel you're always close
to me? Is it because I'm in town?
I'm not going to try
looking you up
But if you feel like seeing me,
just look over your shoulder
You'll find me right ahead
What...?
What happened?
Grandpa wants to see you
There was girl
and her parents doted on her
Her laughter and the chime
of her anklets filled their house
Then one day, she got married and
she had to leave with her husband
She had tears in her eyes
when she asked her father...
why she was being sent away.
Didn't her father love her anymore?
Her father choked on his tears when
he said, not today, he'd reply later
Years later, there she was,
happy at her home
And her father arrives and he says,
how much he misses her
He pleaded, come home with me.
And his daughter said...
how can I leave my home?
Won't my husband miss me?
And who will take care
of my home?
Here father laughs and says,
there, you got your answer
That was just as well, because
I would've missed her sorely
Grannie
Yes, your grandmother
Some day, every girl must cross
that threshold, she must leave...
to make for herself
a beautiful world...
among those to whom she belongs...
ones who will miss her
Esha, I've found a boy for you.
He's known to us
Aunt Maya's friend's son.
Very nice family
And best of all,
in their family...
you will be more a daughter
than a daughter-in-law
That's how dearly
they will love you
I hope you didn't tell him anything?
- No, but I think I must
Not a word to Grandpa!
- I must! He's considering marriage
Then say that you aren't marrying
some stranger
Aunt Maya's friend's son!
- But you never met him
Aunt Maya has, and she approves!
- Who's marrying? You or Aunt Maya?
Rhea, I don't want to marry.
I can't even think of anyone else
He's the only one I'm in love with.
And I'm telling Grandpa
Tell him what? About post box 143?
- Then what am I to do?
Enlist Rahul's help. He's from Bombay.
He could find out something, at least
Once Rahul has found out about him,
you can tell Grandpa everything
But can I trust Rahul so much?
- You trust someone you've never seen
And after all these years,
are you suspicious of Rahul?
Answering machine speaking.
Drop your message after the beep
Ma said, you approve of my match with
Esha. But do I approve of her?
Yes, I sent you over
to look up Esha
And I even said I'd marry her
if you happen to approve of her
The thought of marriage
is driving me nuts
For a lifetime, can I possibly
be in love with this one girl?
Anyway, if you say Esha
is the one...
Hey, call me up
You came to find out...
how much Esha Malhotra scores
on the eligibility grades?
You were marking me all this time,
sizing me up for your friend?
So you approve? Is that why you wanted
to strike up a friendship with me?
I can't make you out anymore.
Are you what you came across as?
Or are you what I see now? But
at least I know, you're no friend
How can I marry your friend?
- She is Maya's niece
Whatever she is, I can't marry her.
- Will we ever find such a nice girl?
She must be nice
Then get to know her
She's Esha
Innocent and lovable
Smile's cute too.
Also, nice voice
Made it all out from the photo?
Even heard her voice? Strange!
- Talked to her over the phone
Wants a photographer
for her fashion magazine
You like her?
In my place, what'd you do?
- Say yes, what else?
Now you're in my place.
Ma, Rahul approves of her
Get him married. Fast
I got to know her
Maybe take a holiday with her,
some sunsets, sunrises together
Until then, how will I know
whether I want to marry her?
A little carelessness can wreck
a wonderful friendship
They won't approve of a courtship.
- The let Rahul look her up
Why me?
- If Rahul approves of her...
I'm willing to marry.
- Why me? I'm going nowhere
You're the one who's invited
Look Rahul, I don't even know
what kind of girl I want
As for you, you always know
exactly what's right
You know me through and through.
So why don't you decide?
Is she the one
I'll fall in love with?
If I approve, you will agree?
- Yes
You aren't lying?
- I only lie to girls
Akshay, this is no joke.
- I know. That's why
Hi! I'm Rahul. Rahul Sharma
I called to say,
I'm available
How long have you known him?
- Quite long
And you're telling me now?
- I wanted to get to know him
So you've gotten to know him?
- Yes
How many times have you met?
- Not once
What does he do?
- I don't know
Where does he live?
His name? A family?
- I don't know
Then what do you know about him?
That I can trust him.
- Someone you've never even met?
A trust is given, not seen.
It comes from the heart
I just got to shut my eyes and
think about him and I believe him
Please meet him, for once Grandpa
Dearest, I don't think we'll have
to write letters any longer
I want to see you.
I told my grandfather all about you
He wants to meet the person
I've chosen for myself'
28th July, 4 pm.
DehraDun Boat Club
My grandfather and I will
be expecting you
Yours, Esha
After so long! How come
I don't know you're coming?
We went home and we found out
you're here
And I thought, why delay
introductions? So here we are
Dug out the your childhood friend?
- We can't live without each other
She's the one who deserted me
and made off for Australia
How long could she stand you?
Not everyone is like me
Can you make him out?
The same roly-poly fat boy
Akshay
And this is Grandpa's apple of the eye.
Esha
Is Esha the girl
you'd give up everything for?
Yes
Why?
- Because she's just like you
Am I going to end up with
someone like you?
We ought to get married
on the same day
But not to the same girl
Were it not for you, I'd never
have found out what love is like
And I'd go through life
without love
You mean so much to me
You're a brother
A friend
Aunt Maya said, they approve
Akshay is a very nice boy.
We've known the family for ages
Esha, I think you should consider him.
- But Grandpa...
maybe he never got my letter
Esha, I approve of Akshay too
What do you want?
- To see you happy
Rahul is like a son to me.
Akshay and Rahul are childhood friends
We've known Rahul for quite sometime,
but we never knew he's family
This one.
- Oh no
But you must,
this is part of the ritual
For you. We'd like to see you
wearing this for the engagement
I think you'll look gorgeous.
I'm keeping it here
Everyone is waiting outside. For you.
Akshay is here too
I've never seen him so glad.
He wants to get married right away
I never came to size you up, Esha.
I just wanted to find out...
whether you're the girl whom Akshay
would care for, all his life...
whether you're the girl who'd evoke
anyone's feelings
And you are that girl, Esha.
I didn't mean to hurt you
Trust me, Esha
Why should I trust you, Rahul?
Look at me, could I ever lie to you?
6 months?
No, he's the astrologer
How can some astrologer decide
when I get married?
But there are no auspicious dates.
- Then I stay here for 6 months
When I didn't want to get married,
you were after me. Now I'm willing
Why are you taking so long?
- Not so soon.
No one will be able to make it from
Bombay. How about an engagement?
Engagement?
I'm here, Esha is here.
Rahul is here, you're here
Who needs anyone else?
- As you wish
We'll talk to Maya right away.
- The talks are over
Now, engagement
Where's Esha?
- Over there
He never received your letter.
He wants to see you. Today
No word from you in quite some time?
I wondered, if providence
has drawn us close, we must meet
But this is taking too much time.
I can't wait any longer
Whenever I shut my eyes
I can see you
I open my eyes
and you're lost
I hope I don't lose you
before we have met
I want to see you.
August 10
8 pm. At the Ram Temple.
I'll carry the doll
You carry the plane
I sent you
Will you come?
* Your beloved stands
* at your doorstep...
* he brings love
* Your beloved stands
* at your doorstep...
* he brings love
* Your beloved stands
* at your doorstep...
* he brings love
* Your beloved stands
* at your doorstep...
* he brings love
* He says, don't wait,
* come with me...
* we're losing our years
* Your beloved stands
* at your doorstep...
* he brings love
* Your beloved stands
* at your doorstep...
* he brings love
* Let's make love first,
* you can act coy afterwards
* Give me my moments of joy, you'll
* still have the rest of my life...
* to make me miserable.
* What kind of a lover will you make?
* Are you naive?
* Are you crazy?
* Lightning sears
* through my heart
* Your beloved stands
* at your doorstep...
* he brings love
* Your beloved stands
* at your doorstep...
* he brings love
* The bride is yours
The girl presents the ring to the boy?
- Right
Son...
One minute
I'd like a word with Esha
in private
What is the matter?
- I'd like to ask her something
I always thought, girls are two kinds.
Those we romance and the one you marry
For me, you're the only girl
I could romance and marry too
I've had girls. But for the first time
I feel love
Maybe, you too have a past?
Someone you have loved?
But I don't care to know about him.
All I know is...
we got a lifetime ahead. Together.
Esha, will you marry me?
Hurry, there's the car
This astrologer is something else.
Finds a date ages away
If you say so, I could stay back,
a while...?
We could chat over phone. No problems
at your end...? Shouldn't be
I think Grandpa is suitably
impressed with me
But one problem. I don't know
how you find me
Trust me, I'm not that bad
Akshay, why are you doing all this?
I haven't said yes about marrying you
Neither did you say no
Yes?
See what's happened to me.
- What's happened?
Take a good look.
- Sure, so what?
I'm looking like an ass.
- Same as always
Only more stupid
I'm looking like a monkey.
Get me some clothes. I haven't any
Been in that all your life?
- You don't get me
What would wear when you're going
to date your favourite girlfriend?
What she'd like, obviously.
- Like...?
Well, she likes just about
whatever I wear
You saved me! I was about
to wear the colours of spring
But where are you going?
- To see Esha
She's arriving in Bombay
I never slept all night. What to say,
never been in love before
I'm getting sentimental
Let me introduce you
Introducing the whole lineage
What do I tell her?
I've managed the introductions.
Upto you to strike a friendship
Rahul lost his mother at three.
His father migrated to Canada
Left him with the grandparents.
- Why didn't he take Rahul along?
Rahul reminded him about his mother.
Then he asked Rahul to migrate
But Rahul couldn't bear to leave me
Doesn't seem as if he hides
a sorrow behind that smile, does he?
He's always making people laugh.
- That's my Rahul
Akshay and Rahul grew up together.
They're inseparable
For each other,
they'll do anything
What a friendship!
They never needed another friend
Their likings are similar too
They love each other so much,
they're inseparable
I worry for Rahul. He never
makes his feelings obvious
Akshay demands whatever he wants.
But Rahul...
will even forego
what he's entitled to
Only 3 things for a happy life.
Nice food, nice cars and nice women
My birthday, isn't today.
- Hardly matters. For me, it's today
I've missed the whole lot of them,
let me make up for all of them
So much food?
That's one huge...
Fish?
- Pick of the trawlers
The flower is for fragrance
Do you expect me to start?
No Indian-woman tripe
I'm a vegetarian.
I don't eat non-veg
Hadn't an inkling you're a vegetarian.
You never eat non-veg?
Suppose your lover asks you
to eat non-veg, what would you do?
If he loves me, he'll never say that.
- Welcome sir
You never try to change
someone you love
Akshay, why do you want to marry me?
- What a question
Anyone would want to marry you
For marrying me,
so much is enough?
It was love...
at first sight
So it's my features that you love
Once I'm fat, you won't like me
That'd be the end of your love?
- How fat...? Won't happen
No dearth of health clubs
and beauty parlours in Bombay
You don't even know me,
we haven't even had a conversation
How do you know you'd like to spend
the rest of your life with me?
My heart tells me, you're the one.
- If you could trust your heart...
why did you send Rahul
to size me up?
When Tina was angry,
I gave her a diamond bracelet
When Rupali was cross,
I sent her flowers
But how do I woo Esha? Beats me
I sent you to look her up,
that was my only fault
One thing she didn't know?
- I was about to tell her
A few kids later,
I'd tell her, no?
What do I do?
This once, I can say nothing.
- Should I ask the girl in black?
Akshay, if you really are in love,
put the question to yourself'
Yes, we're at the hotel.
Yes Pratap, all of us
Pratap is an old friend of his.
All our friends are coming
Everyone wants to meet Esha.
Where is Esha?
Should be coming. She was nervous
about meeting so many people
And Maya?
- Went to the beauty parlour
She'll come to the party directly.
- Yes Pratap, coming in
Dad, why don't you go on?
- But Esha is expected
Rahul and I will receive her
Let's go in
How sweet of Uncle Pratap
to throw a party for you and Esha
I hope Esha likes the dress
I took from that model
I even asked the model what her
favourite perfume is. One second...
What's up?
- I'm dead
Another...?
If Esha sees me with them...
I'm done for! Are you laughing?
I'm off
Tell Esha, something urgent came up.
Please, handle this
* God...
* show me money
The next song will be played
on the request of Pappu, Anupam...
Aditya, Uday and Akash.
* Is this love?
* Yes, this is love
* Without you, nothing amuses me...
* time doesn't pass
* Is this love?
* Yes
* Yes, this is love
* Without you, nothing amuses me...
* time doesn't pass
Let me tell you something, dude.
Your girlfriend is drop-dead gorgeous
Look...
- Isn't she your girlfriend?
Rahul, let's go.
Well tell me, what's her price?
Leave her for me after you're through.
- Damn you!
No use, Rahul. Let's go, please.
People are waiting for us. Please!
Hey man, no hard feelings.
I wish to give you a good news.
Akshay, my very old friend's son,
is engaged to Esha.
She's the daughter of DehraDun's
famous businessman, Inder Malhotra.
I want all of you to warmly welcome
our new family member.
Now, Akshay and Esha
will begin tonight's dance.
* Why did I...
* fall in love with you?
* I didn't find you
* Now I'm lost
* You never walked out of my dreams
* Neither did you walk into my arms
* Why did I...
* fall in love with you?
* I didn't find you
* Now I'm lost
* You still linger in my dreams
* But I never had you in my arms
* I have no complaints against you
* I rue my fate
* Why does heaven...
* decide the fate of hearts?
* You never walked out of my dreams
* Neither did you walk into my arms
* Why did I...
* fall in love with you?
* I didn't find you...
* now I'm lost
* Why I am ruined...
* I could never tell
* I cried so much...
* but not a tear I could shed
* I could shed no tear
* You never walked out of my dreams
* Neither did you walk into my arms
* Why did I...
* fall in love with you?
* I didn't find you
* Now I'm lost
* You could never walk
* out of my dreams
* Neither could you...
* walk into my arms
Rahul, take me away.
Everyone is ogling at me.
They're watching you, for
you're looking so pretty. That's it.
Look into my eyes
and say that you aren't lying.
Akshay is your friend.
For his sake you'll lie too?
Akshay loves you dearly, Esha.
And that's no lie.
Had you been in love with me,
would you bring me here like this?
Esha, I want you to meet someone.
What're you doing?
Never mind, dear. Our house
is nearby. Take her home, son.
Go home and have a change, dear.
Akshay, I can't marry you.
I'm going back tomorrow. Only you
can stop this wedding from happening.
Somehow stop this wedding, please.
What're you saying, Esha?
I can't do this.
I...
- I don't love you.
Why do you want to marry a girl
who doesn't love you?
Akshay, I tried hard to reason.
But you aren't the one with whom
I can spend a lifetime.
Are you in love with someone?
You won't understand.
Who is he, Esha?
- I don't know.
All I know is that I love him dearly.
How is it possible?
- We used to write to each other.
Slowly, I fell in love.
Haven't you spoken to him yet?
- No.
Not even over the phone?
- No, but I've heard his voice.
D'you have any photograph of his?
And his name?
I don't know.
I told you, you won't understand.
No, I understand everything.
Then you'll stop this wedding,
won't you?
No.
Because I figure,
there's no such boy.
I also understand that someone
has taken you for a ride.
This isn't love, Esha.
Mere letters don't stem love. To love
someone you need a real human being.
Whom you can see, you can feel,
with whom you can talk to.
But the boy, whom you are
talking about, doesn't exist at all.
He exists. I just got to
spread my arms and reach for him.
Then spread your arms, Esha...
go and find him.
You'll find only me.
So you aren't stopping this wedding?
You'll not marry me?
No.
All right, Esha...
I'll stop this wedding.
But on one condition.
Find the one you love and
bring him to me.
Then I'll stop this wedding.
I promise.
What happened? Where to find him
is your problem, isn't it?
You said you know. So go,
find him, Esha. I won't stop you.
Believe me, more than you,
I shall await him.
Can you tell me post box 143
belongs to whom?
Sorry madam,
it goes against our rules.
I have no other way to contact him.
Please tell me.
Look madam, I can tell you nothing.
Why don't you ask him who he is?
Stay here and relax, wait for him.
He does check in once a month.
I want to close post box 143.
- All right.
But first you must empty the box.
* God...
* What have You done?
Dearest, this is my final attempt
to find you.
I want to meet you.
At least for once...
at least for the last time.
I'm about to get married.
But I'm not marrying
until you meet me.
Because, I can survive without you,
but I cannot live with someone else.
Esha loves someone else.
D'you know who he is?
I know.
You.
Look Rahul, I want you to call her up
and say that you don't love her.
Rahul, Esha is in love with someone
whom she hasn't even seen.
Nor has she ever met him.
Nor does she know his name.
Mere letters made her fall in love.
But who will reason with Esha.
That's why, pretend to be that guy
and call her up.
I can't do this.
Why not?
- This is wrong.
What's wrong about it?
You don't love her...
I can't do it. Period.
If you don't help me,
I don't know what I'm going to do.
Let alone love, I can't even
look at any other girl.
I know this is wrong.
But I really love her, buddy.
All my life I'll look after Esha.
Even if I find flaws in her,
I won't complain.
I'll do what she wants me to.
I'll become what she makes out of me.
I'll give her all the joys,
she'll forget sorrows and pain.
And you know, if she's with me,
she'll forget him.
You love her so much?
- Dearly.
Even if I had been in love with her,
I'd have given her up for you.
You!
I wish to say something.
Who are you?
Now there's no need to know who I am.
What's important is...
we can't ever meet.
What...?
I'm going.
You can't do this.
This is what I have to do.
This is what's right.
For us, you have no right to
decide all by yourself.
Some decisions are not in our hands.
It's up to me to wait for you.
To love you is up to me.
Love...?
You made me trust you.
We never met, but I always felt you
by my side.
As if, you're watching me
every moment.
And now, you want my feelings back?
I can give you nothing.
All I want is your company.
Impossible.
Why are you doing this?
I never asked you anything.
Please...
Ask me nothing.
Can I ask, you love me?
Have you ever been in love with me?
If you can't read my silence, how
can you understand my words, Esha?
At least you can speak out my name.
I don't even know your name.
What's your name?
What is your name?
I can't tell.
- Why can't you tell your name?
Won't I ever get to know the name
of the person I love?
Tell me your name, please.
You know my name.
There are many who have my name.
What is your name?
Why can't you tell me your name?
I'm ready to forget everything.
No matter if you don't meet me...
No matter if you don't love me,
but for once...
just once, tell me your name. Please.
Just for once, tell me your name.
* Go sweetheart,
* I have faith in love
* I shall wait for you
* Go my love,
*I have faith in love
* I shall wait for you
* I shall go farway...
* far away from your thoughts
* Although, my love...
* I shall not be able to forget you
* In you, I found a reason to live
* Oh, but what has it come to be?
* I'm still living without you
* How unfaithful of me
* Go away, my love,
* for happy days to return...
* I shall wait for you
* Yes my love,
*I have faith in love
* I shall wait for you
* I shall go so farway...
* far away from your thoughts
* Although, my love...
* I shall not be able to forget you
* I shall go so farway...
* far away from your thoughts
* Perhaps, somehow...
* if you find news of me...
* just remember me...
* if you can
* Go my love,
* my life is with me
* I shall wait for you
* Go my love,
* I have faith in love
* I shall wait for you
* I shall go so farway...
* far away from your thoughts
* Although, my love...
* I shall not be able to forget you
Rahul, how does one fall in love?
- Love...?
Love just happens.
How, you and I never know.
Namaskar to all Indians in Canada.
Let me tell you something important.
An Indian photographer Mr Rahul Sharma
staying in Vancouver...
for the last four years is
exhibiting photographs today...
in Richment shopping mall.
You must go and see his works.
Because, you will find an
Indian bride's image...
through the eyes of Mr Rahul Sharma.
Stop, Rahul. C'mon, stop.
I looked for you everywhere.
Four years!
You're in front of me, I still
can't believe my eyes.
Are you angry with me?
How are you?
Buddy, I know what I made you do
was wrong.
You asked me to get married,
and then you vanished.
Didn't you ever miss me?
You always said, I'd really
fall in love someday.
But...
- No buddy, I couldn't marry Esha.
Maybe we were not made
for each other.
I was in her sight, but her eyes were
always searching for someone else.
She was before me, but not with me.
Then how could I marry her?
And Esha...?
She's still waiting for him.
I reasoned with her. But she feels
he'll come someday. Can't help it.
I find the guy strange, too.
He's in love with love...
he talks with the wind,
he lives in the skies, he flies.
Wonder who he is.
All I want to know is that...
if he loves her truly,
why hasn't he appeared as yet?
Why didn't you tell me?
- Had you been in my shoes...
what'd you have done?
She still awaits you.
Go.
You know my name.
I'm Rahul.
And I madly love you.
>