This dance is dancing.
It's nothing if it's
not for dance.
What is its relation with breath?
In fact, this is breath.
It's in the drifting heart.
Indeed, it's dance!
It's in the whole life.
It's in the rhythm of the tunes.
Indeed, it's dance!
I've achieved it.
It's my shadow.
It's in all my veins.
It's in every particle of my body.
Dance.
It's in the flash
of the eye-lashes.
It's in the thumping of the hand.
Indeed, it's dance!
It's in my passions.
It's in the yearning
of the spirit.
Indeed, it's dance!
It's compassion.
It's the material desire.
It's a dream and it's a reality.
Verily, it's the need as well.
Indeed, it's dance.
Dance!
So, what can i do?
Thank you.
Have you directed in
any film? - Not yet so far.
Any experience? Any training under
some established dance director?
Sir, i don't feel that any
training is needed...
...to become a choreographer.
Why is that so?
Sir, i know dance.
You can take my audition
if you want to.
Look, whoever comes here
is no doubt talented.
Anyway, take this song cd.
And, you know, compose something
and show it to me. - Fine.
Look, i won't promise you,
but if i like your work...
...then, maybe, we can move ahead.
Is that clear?
- Okay, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Who is it?
My world is by you.
And, my life is by you.
And, what more should i seek?
As, all the bliss is mine.
I've become the colour
that you created.
Hi.
I think i saw you in the office
of shaan productions.
Do you work there?
No.
I'm an actor. But, haven't
acted as yet.
I went for that film.
But, they wanted a dancer hero...
...and, i don't know how to dance.
You?
I'm a dance director.
But, haven't directed
any dance as yet.
Superb!
Great!
Fantastic!
If there's a demand
in the industry...
...for an actor to be a dancer...
...then who am i to say
anything about it?
And, i still find all
this a bit silly.
One, two three, you know?
Sorry. I didn't mean
to degrade dance.
By the way, which institute
did you learn it from?
I never learnt it from any
institute. - You mean?
After hearing you out, it's
for the first time...
...that an interest for dance
is developing in me.
Can you teach me?
I don't teach.
Why?
Don't you feel that; if
you have something...
...that is worth teaching then
you should teach it!
Nice meeting you.
Abhi.
Abhinav.
Reva.
Who are you?
My world is by you.
And, my life is by you.
And, what more should i seek?
As, all the bliss is mine.
The memories have wiped out.
And, i've recoiled as such.
Now, your way is my way.
It's in your love that i...
i think you're perfect.
I'll do a screen test of yours
and show it to my producer.
Hanif-samar! They have done
50 super-hit films!
And, you...
you want to say that you need
some changes in their music?
Sir, i didn't mean to...
...and what do you think of yourself?
If you want to dance, then you wll
do it on this music itself!
Sir, then i won't be
able to do this song.
Sorry for wasting your time.
The producer saw your screen test?
And?
What?
He went crazy at your screen test.
I'm damn happy for you and...
i'm happy for myself.
Great! Superb!
Fantastic!
You know to dance, isn't it?
I'm out of practice.
Give me two weeks.
Reva...
reva, i don't feel
nice to say that...
...but, the rent of two months
is still pending.
Sorry. What should i do?
Why do you say sorry? It's my fault.
If you can give me two more weeks...
hello?
- Hello, reva?
Hi, abhinav here. The bus guy.
I got your number from
shaan productions.
Look, there's a new director
called sandesh.
I've got a break in his film.
It's very big film.
And, yes, yes, yes. I've
to know how to dance.
And, i've decided
that i'll learn it.
And, i'll learn it only from you.
So, please, don't say no! Okay?
And, yeah! It's not that
i'll learn it for free.
I'll give you the fees. But,
i won't be giving much.
So, please agree! Please,
reva, please!
I've achieved it.
It's my shadow.
It's in all my veins.
It's in every particle of my body.
Don't stop.
It's just, that i feel
like keep watching.
One thing is for sure.
After watching you dance,
i feel like...
...i can never even reach
till the 'd' of dance.
I won't be able to do this.
It won't happen.
I don't like that word.
- Which?
'No.'
Okay.
Point noted.
Where's the music?
Music isn't needed to learn dance.
What?
Raise your hands.
Now?
- Keep standing like that.
Can i lower my hands, now?
- Why?
Is it paining?
No.
I'm looking like a fool.
Do you feel that i'm
making you do that...
...so that you should
look like a fool?
No.
Do you trust me?
What else can be the reason
for me to stand here?
Who are you?
- What?
Did you fall from the sky?
- Goa.
And?
The thing, that i want to do...
mama and papa were least
interested in that.
So, i left the house.
And, came here.
I know that you won't be asking,
so i'll tell it myself.
My parents have expired.
And, i've one sister,
who stays in nainital.
But, there was no question
of staying with her.
Because, i had already
decided that...
...i would be coming to mumbai and...
...would be ruling over
this film industry.
I've got a job in nfd computers.
Part-time.
From 4:00 to 7:30.
Job?
I'll get some money.
Whatever i brought with
me; is almost spent.
I can't do a full time job.
As i need time for my dance as well.
Dance!
Want to see a movie?
How did you find the film?
Great! Superb!
Fantastic!
Action, comedy, romance, tears;
everything was there in it.
That's why, it's a super-hit.
That wasn't the reply
to my question.
Reva, i want to become an actor...
...because, i want to
earn loads of fame.
And, money as well.
So, it's in my best interests
that i should quickly learn...
...whatever that is usually
needed over here.
The film was just rubbish.
Are you mad?
You won't be getting such
a big offer too often.
Reva, please take my word
and say yes to it.
Do you have any idea as
to how far will you go...
...by associating with this company.
You can obtain work from
the whole of the world.
Abhi, you know it
that i don't work...
...just for the sake
of obtaining work.
I haven't come here to
earn money or fame.
And, dance...
had i just wanted to dance, then...
...i could have done
it in goa as well.
Abhi...
the form in which i want
to perceive dance...
...is only possible in films.
Lights, sets, set-designs,
costumes, camera...
i want to perceive dance in
my own way through all this.
I want to show it.
And, had i come here just for the
sake of living a routine life...
...then, whatever you said;
might very well apply.
To give what the industry wants.
And, walk off after taking my money.
But, abhi, that is not my objective.
Do you know this industry?
Do you feel that these people
need your innovation?
Abhi, it's not that
they don't want it.
It's just, that they are unable
to see it through my eyes.
And, to show them and explain
them; is my responsibility.
Abhi, do you feel that
whatever i want...
can i be able to do it ever?
Seriously?
No.
Reva...
the day you get what you want...
i'll be happier than you.
I know.
I like your style.
Have you ever done a film before?
- No.
Very original.
Actually, i want to do something
similar in my film.
I've got a song recorded
for my film.
I'll send the cd along with abhi.
Let's see, what you can do.
I've the passion in me, so i'll
face whatever comes ahead.
Whoever comes to face me,
can never be like me.
And, at my feet lies
the whole world.
The whole. The whole.
The whole.
I've the passion in me, so i'll
face whatever comes ahead.
Whoever comes to face me,
can never be like me.
And, at my feet lies
the whole world.
The whole. The whole.
The whole.
I love it.
Yes!
I love you.
I love your eyes.
I love your lips. I love your ears.
I love your hair.
I love your coffee.
I love your voice.
I love your ear-rings.
I'm not wearing ear-ring.
I know.
But...
when you do, i'm sure
i'll love them.
And, what else?
I love it that you're short.
I love you because you're
very boring.
I love that.
Whatever it is.
I love the way you never smile.
So...
here's your house.
You're safe, sound and dry.
And, i'm out of here. Good night.
Want some coffee?
Abhi...
life is uniting with
someone as such.
Life is uniting with
No, no.
Never ever.
Never ever i deemed it this way.
Life is uniting with
someone as such.
No, no.
Never ever.
Never ever i deemed it this way.
Hey, dance.
The foot.
When i keep it.
I find that i'm waiting for him.
The foot.
When i keep it.
I find that i'm waiting for him.
Do it and don't stop.
And, life will be all set to move.
Life gets united with
someone as such.
Sometimes, here.
Sometimes, there.
Sometimes, somewhere else.
It gets united.
Hey, dance.
Camera...
...is gradually zooming
into your face.
And, your gaze is fixed
far away on the traffic.
Suddenly, the camera
is swish-panned!
Great. - It is to be seen with
sound and music.
You have to give a trial of
the costume too. Don't forget.
And we have to remove
the instances...
prasad will look after everything.
And yes...
tell that girl that she cannot
do this film. - Which girl?
That... that choreographer of yours.
- But...
but why?
Because the heroine ayesha wants...
...to work with the dance
director shaheen.
Do you want to see sandesh's song?
According to your character in...
...the film you shouldn't
dance at all.
The way i am seeing it...
think that there is such a set.
The world is at your feet.
In senses...
who will be?
Like me...
there is fire in the senses.
It is to be seen...
whatever will be.
There will be nobody like
me who will face me.
The whole world is at my feet.
The whole...
there is fire in the senses.
It is to be seen...
whatever will be.
There will be nobody like
me who will face me.
The whole world is at my feet.
The whole...
you have such a colour
and attitude...
we haven't heard or seen it ever.
The one who is with you...
will bloom.
Your colour is such...
it falls on everyone.
Yours...
you have such a colour
and attitude...
we haven't heard or seen it ever.
The one who is with you...
will bloom.
Your colour is such...
it falls on everyone.
Yours...
i don't want anything incomplete.
I want everything.
Whatever is the best is here...
here...
i don't want anything incomplete.
I want everything.
Whatever is the best is here...
here...
how much ever strength
anyone has...
the person gets more.
Who will live on today,
tomorrow and day after?
Never...
how much ever strength
anyone has...
the person gets more.
Who will live on today,
tomorrow and day after?
Never...
just once...
see what she has done just once.
It must be fantastic.
- It is.
Abhi... you understand this.
The industry doesn't
work just on talent.
The choreographer shaheen khan.
He is very ordinary.
But his networking is very strong.
The right parties...
page three.
You know what i am talking
about? Zee... screen.
He has got two filmfare awards.
The producers think
that the value of...
...the movie increases
due to his being in it.
And... he is a good friend
of the superstar ayesha.
And i have got this first
break due to all these.
It was my mistake.
I was excited looking at her dance.
And i committed to her.
Why are you so quiet?
You are quiet since evening.
Is something wrong?
What happened, abhi? What's wrong?
They have taken some other
dancer in your place.
Not because sandesh didn't
like your place.
But ayesha...
- i don't want to hear.
If they don't want me.
They don't want me.
I am not concerned with
their problems.
I tried to convince sandesh...
- abhi, i...
we will not speak about this.
As far as i am concerned.
This topic is over.
Even i will leave this film.
Don't talk nonsense. Abhi.
Our work and we are different.
Don't mix the two.
I want to be alone for a while.
Dance...
dance...
you wanted to be alone.
So i left you.
Now i want to be with you.
It has started relating
with someone like this...
this life.
It has started relating
with someone like this...
this life.
Should i bring more vegetable?
No... no...
no... no...
never... never...
i had never thought about it.
Dance...
dance...
there is fire in the senses.
It is to be seen...
whatever will be.
There will be nobody like
me who will face me.
The whole world is at my feet.
The whole...
there is fire in the senses.
It is to be seen...
whatever will be.
There will be nobody like
me who will face me.
The whole world is at my feet.
The whole...
it looks like a circus.
Sir. The public will
like it. Guaranteed.
Sir...
there was a similar song
in kal raho na no.
It had worked for just fifty weeks.
It is bad...
but it is business.
The whole...
cut it. Yes. That was
a very nice shot, yes.
Not now. Get out.
This was nice. We will take the...
...next shot from up there.
Yes...
- autograph please.
He is so cute.
- I know.
Abhi... is it so important for you?
- What?
That everyone should know you.
And that everyone should
appreciate you?
See. Everyone doesn't want
to become like you.
I am a normal man. I don't
want to become god.
I want many fans that come
and take my autograph.
I want many awards and i want
a lot of money. Okay?
Don't say things that
you don't mean.
No. I mean it. - You don't.
- I do. - you don't. - i do.
You don't.
- Yes, i do.
- No, i don't.
Hey... hey... move...
autograph... autograph please...
please... autograph...
hello?
Yes. I am reva here.
Reva...
- i got a call from a producer.
He is very excited
looking at my work.
Wow... excited?
Of course i am excited.
Congrats...
excuse me, sir?
- Yes? - the shot is ready.
Anyway. See. My shot is ready.
I will meet you later, okay? Bye.
Please... please reva have a seat.
I am rakesh.
- Thank you, sir. - yes. - please.
Anyways.
You must not have heard about me.
Because i haven't made
a film till today.
But i want to make a film.
A different film.
A film which stands out.
What will you have? Tea,
coffee or cold drink?
No, nothing. Thank you.
No. You will have to take
something. Coffee?
Good.
Yes, send two coffees.
I have seen your cd. I have
seen your show reel.
Superb. Original. Believe me.
Mind blowing, it was.
- Thank you, sir.
Even we have recorded excellent
songs for our film.
The poet sameer is doing the music.
- Okay.
And we want the newest style.
And you will be giving it to us.
This is the script. This is the cd.
Once you understand the script.
You will be able to put more
motion into your dances.
Yes!
The kind of style
that i saw in you...
reva... think that you were
made for this film.
Okay, sir. I will listen
to the songs.
And i will get something
ready and meet you then.
I will call you, sir.
- Reva... i have ordered coffee.
Here. The coffee has come. Have
it and go. - Okay, sir.
Reva...
abhi...
i have heard that you
know abhi very well.
Yes. Sir.
Yes.
The hero has a strong
role in this script.
Very... it means... it is
a fit role for abhi.
Sir. Is abhi working in your film?
That is what i want too.
But reva, you know. Abhi
is so busy nowadays.
It is very difficult to meet him.
Therefore... i was thinking.
If you tell abhi to read
our script once, maybe...
sir... it isn't my work to lead
the actor to the script.
You are misunderstanding me.
It isn't anything like that.
Please don't misunderstand
me. It is like this.
If a star like abhi works
in our film once...
...four people will invest
money in the project.
What after that? The
film will be made.
Just once...
you make abhi say 'yes'.
Your work will done and
ours will be done too.
What do you say, reva?
Will you speak to abhi?
No, sir.
Thank you very much for your time.
Everything makes a difference.
I guess you don't know who i am.
From today... your feet won't
be on the floor ever. - What?
Because your prince with
the blue horse has come.
A car.
A brand new car is waiting
by your door.
And it is waiting
for you restlessly.
So go quickly and change. We
are going for a drive.
Come on.
Hello, mr. Abhinav.
Hi! I saw your film.
It was very good.
- Thank you.
Reva... your three month's
rent is pending.
Even the last month you...
- if you could give me...
...a couple of weeks
more. I thought...
...that the money would come in.
How much is it?
- Nine thousand.
Abhi...
- relax.
Here it is. Take the rent
from me from now on.
Okay? Come on. Come on!
Here is your car and
this is your husband.
I mean... your chauffer. Come on.
You shouldn't have done like this.
Oh! Shut up! Come on! Come on!
Did you see the pickup? Oh!
That's a great car.
And the suspension. The
road is butter, butter.
Power steering.
I can move the car with one finger.
What happened?
Why are you so silent?
Nothing.
Now don't tell me you are
still thinking about the rent.
Okay, so what should i have done?
I should have seen the
drama standing there?
Abhi... why don't you
try to understand?
Reva... you try to understand.
We love each other. We're together.
Why do you make an issue of
all these small things?
Why?
Fine.
I am sorry.
Can we forget all this right
now, please? - Yes.
Thank you.
Okay... what happened about that...
- who?
That producer. Who wanted
to see your show reel.
They didn't want me.
They wanted you.
What do you mean?
They came to know from somewhere...
...that i knew you. So they wanted...
...that i bring you into the film...
then they would give me the work.
Okay.
I will meet them.
Why?
I don't know. Maybe they
have a nice story.
Tell them that i will meet them.
You tell them yourself.
You call them yourself.
Why are you so difficult, reva?
What is the problem?
Can't we help each other?
Abhi. I don't need anyone's help.
I am telling this once.
I won't repeat it.
I won't sign any film
which is based...
...on your recommendations
or contacts.
Not now. Not ever.
Abhi those people don't understand...
...my work and my ideas. Not at all.
I cannot work with these people.
And i thought that you
understood all this.
Yes, i understand all this. But...
...there is a limit to
your adamancy too.
What do think? The industry
works just like this?
People invest lakhs and
crores into a movie.
Even they have to see their
commercial interest.
They have to...
they have to bow to the
audience's tastes.
They cannot survive like you.
On thin air.
She has come
forget all this drama, reva.
And look at reality.
Abhi, forget it. You
never understood.
What do you mean to say now?
That you are the only real artiste,
bathed in milk?
And the rest are useless
and good for nothing.
I am talking about myself.
Not about others.
Who are you?
What do you think about yourself?
That people will move
around you with work...
...and you will kick them for
your great principles?
Please, don't be ridiculous.
Just forget it.
We are very different. Abhi.
We are very different.
I am successful today because
i am not a fool like you.
And...
because of my principles,
i don't want to starve.
On the contrary, i am
famous and rich today.
What do you think?
By making me away from yourself...
...and relating me to the world,
you will hurt me? Is it?
No way.
Not with me.
I have reached here
with my hard work.
And no one can take it away from me.
Not even you, with this
great talent of yours.
Reva...
reva...
dance...
sir... it will take twenty minutes...
...for the shot to be ready, okay?
Excuse me... sir. Excuse me... sir.
Sir, my name is lakshmi. I am
waiting for you since the last 2 hrs.
Oh. Come in. Come in.
- No, sir. I am really...
just come in, i am really...
- just come in. It's raining.
Thank you, sir.
I am so sorry, sir. I am
a costume designer sir.
I can make anything. Sir.
Anything you want.
Just... try... sir... you...
please help me, sir.
Abhi. I don't want anyone's help.
I will not sign any film which...
...is based on your contacts
and recommendations.
If i help you... will it be wrong?
Wrong? No sir, why?
Everyone wants someone's
help, isn't it, sir?
Why doesn't she understand this?
What, sir? I am sorry.
Lakshmi. Meet me tomorrow.
We will work something out.
Really, sir?
- Yes.
Thank you, sir. Thank
you so much sir.
Bye, good night.
Bye, sir.
Hello, sir.
Sir, my name is reva. I had...
...talked to you over the
phone today morning.
Reva...
- yes. - sit down. - thank you.
What did i say after i heard
her voice on the phone?
Yes? - What did i say?
- Yes sir. Yes. Sir.
When her voice is so good,
now beautiful will she be?
If the voice is good,
the girl is good too.
Have you brought the photographs?
- No, sir.
- Sir. I am a choreographer.
You are star heroine material.
Don't be so innocent
too. I can make.
Heroine.
- Yes. Sir. Yes, sir.
Cent percent.
Sir, phone.
- I will talk later.
Hey...
how did that rajesh look when
he came the first time?
Raju...
body...
you have a nice body.
Have you learnt acting?
I don't want to act.
I am a choreographer.
I have heard that your film
needs a choreographer.
I had talked to you
in the morning and...
what are you talking about?
You are a heroine material.
Why are you wasting yourself?
There is no hurry. We will
know each other nicely.
I have an office. Come there.
In the night.
There is a room there.
There is an ac there.
We will sit there
and speak... openly.
You understand, don't you?
Excuse me.
Call kamla.
- Yes. Sir.
Hey, is the shot ready?
This is a balloon of blood.
It wanders around day and night.
It wanders!
People have called
it a vagabond.
People with a heart have called
it a vagrant.
Yet others have
called it an ember.
People have called
it a vagabond.
While the happy go lucky
have termed it as an ember.
You and i have drunk.
Drunk in happiness and sorrow.
Friend... it is...
a fountain!
Dance...
show us your dance.
Beauty... dance...
aroma... dance...
dance... thunder...
dance the dance of seduction.
The poisonous dance.
Dance...
this is a balloon of blood.
It sets afire to half the body.
It makes the incomplete
mind insane.
In the veins of breath,
it breaks it's life.
In your heart, it disappears
my reflection.
Dance.
Dance unconscious.
Dance restless.
Dance without sadness.
Dance exquisitely.
Dance without customs.
Poisonous dance.
We are lost in your love.
God made you. We are yours.
- You look very handsome.
We are lost in your love.
Thanks.
And how do i seem?
Great.
Fantastic. Superb.
You look anarkali's mother.
Do i seem old?
Sorry.
You seem very beautiful.
Okay, payal is throwing
a party today.
Will you come with me?
Payal, who?
Payal... that socialite.
I have heard, sir, richard
gere is coming there too.
It will be fun. Promise.
Let's go. Please.
Please... please... please...
hello? - Hello, reva. Reva,
this is sandesh.
Reva, i have a friend, diwakar.
Shaan music industries?
The owner's son.
He is a very intelligent man.
He met me and he told me that...
...he wants to make a music video.
On the theme of dance.
I remembered you.
Yes. I told him about you.
He wants to meet you.
What is the meaning of doing...
...something different
to seem different?
I don't say that one
should be different.
I am saying that one
should be right.
Every song has its own tempo.
Every dance has its own reason.
We do not set this reason and tempo.
The song itself decides
it and makes an identity.
Just like that.
Even your music video should...
...have an identity too.
- What?
To know this, we should know
the reason of the song first.
Your thoughts... the
people will like it.
What guarantee can you
give me about that?
There is no guarantee for that.
Your thoughts are very different.
And ahead too.
It is very ahead.
I can't say that i understood...
...fully what you are trying to say.
But i can say...
...that your thoughts and
respect for dance...
...your understanding
is much more than me.
Okay. Reva.
Whatever you want to do...
...however you want to
do it. Let's do it.
The recording of the songs.
Music. Sets.
Everything will be done
like how you want it.
We will have rehearsals
and then shoot. Okay?
Thank you.
Reva, it is impossible for any
other girl than you to do this.
I don't understand.
Means?
I mean... you will have to
act in this music video.
Absolutely. The expressions
that you are showing...
...the type of dance
that you are doing...
...from where will we bring all this?
Whom will we bring to do all this?
As it is, what is your problem?
You wish that this music video...
...should be just like
how you want it?
That will be done when you
do it yourself. That's it.
Dance and shake the world.
Since so many years...
the whole world seems so still.
There was thunder and lightning.
...from one thought so you...
dance and shake the world.
Dance and shake the world.
Love... love...
i have made you wear
the costume of love.
It is fire. It is water.
Whoever feels like...
can make it bow.
Lift it with ambition.
Bow the highest of storms.
Bow the highest of storms. You...
dance and shake the world.
All the directions
will start speaking.
There will be a new sun rising.
All the directions
will start speaking.
There will be a new sun rising.
There is a fire in these eyes.
The one who touches them
will be set afire.
There is a fire in these eyes.
The one who touches them
will be set afire.
There will be a word then.
Melt the stone with the gaze.
You... '
dance and shake the world.
Dance and shake the world.
Show what your ambition is.
Do something and show us.
Which has been heard or seen.
But it is different from
everything else.
Just work your strength.
Write a new history.
Write a new history. You.
Dance and shake the world.
Raise the heads of ambition.
Bow the highest of storms.
Dance and shake the world.
Melt the stone with your eyes.
Show what your ambition is.
Dance and shake the world.
There was a fog and storm
from this thought.
You...
Iove and shake the world.
Love and shake the world.
Umeed singh says...
if you are not mine, you
cannot be anyone's.
He has tears in his eyes
and a gun in his hands.
Focus in from his point of view.
Nisha is standing in front
of him. With moist eyes.
There is no way out.
Superb.
Sir... sir... sir... how
did you like it.
I am sorry. I wasn't
hearing it properly.
I was seeing the video, sorry.
People make anything nowadays.
Making something different...
but i have heard that this
song is a super hit.
The shaan music company was ruined.
This song has done such business...
...that their three year's
business is done.
The music industry people
say anything.
One song...
if one song is hit... a
whole industry... no.
Sir... will you please tell
me your scene once again?
Okay. Umeed singh says...
...if you cannot be mine,
you will be nobody's.
His eyes are teary. And he
has a gun in his hands.
A focus in with his point of view.
Nisha is standing in his presence.
With moist eyes.
There is no way out now. Music.
A nice concept. A lot of hard work.
And a lot of love for
music and dance.
All this is seen in dance.
This video has taken that leap...
...of success that the
rest are all stunned.
Many music videos have
achieved success...
...but dance is something different.
Choreographer reva
has become a star.
Her fashion and style has taken
over the world overnight.
Her dance 'naach naach ke duniya hila
de (dance and shake the world)'...
...has actually made the world shake.
We will see one scene.
Dance and shake the world.
Since so many years...
the whole world seems so still.
Hello?
- Hi, handsome.
Hi, mamta. What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Then, shall we do something? What?
Anything. Like...
we will go to dinner.
Why? Is it something
special tonight? Hey.
Super star abhinav... and the
super super star mamta...
they are going for dinner. What
can be more special than this?
Okay. People think that putting
four songs make a musical.
But we haven't been able to make...
...a musical in the true
sense of the word.
And looking at our
video's response...
...i think that the audience
is ready for such a musical.
Ya. And a special actor is
needed for such a film.
Behind the lecture, what
i want to say is...
i want to make a musical.
With you.
Hey... diwakar...
hi, abhi.
I saw your video.
What should i say?
It was very nice.
- Thanks.
Abhi... why don't you join us?
We have a booking in an
italian restaurant.
We should get going.
Enjoy your meal.
Really nice guy.
- Yes.
Abhi... what does she think she is?
A song has gone a hit
and she is flying.
Mamta... i want to go. What?
You are joking.
And dinner?
No. I am going.
For god's sake, abhi. Abhi! Abhi!
Reva...
you are very special.
If you weren't there... this...
can't we stop these formalities?
Okay. If you weren't there...
come on. We will stop
praising each other.
Seriously, reva. Thank you.
For being reva.
Good night.
- Good night.
Hi. Hi.
Can i come inside?
Nice place.
Want some coffee?
Congrats. For what?
The people have liked your video.
And...
you have done all this
in your own way.
Like how you were saying.
Yes. Congrats.
You have said it.
I know... i...
i wanted to say it once
again. That's all.
Reva... i love you.
I committed a mistake that day.
Can't we just forget whatever
happened that day?
Hello, diwakar. Hi, reva!
That writer is coming
to the office...
...at eleven in the morning,
to tell the story.
Yes, okay. I will reach there.
Is that okay? Sure.
Okay. I will see you tomorrow.
- Bye.
Reva... i...
go, abhi.
I think you should leave.
Sir, phone.
Hello? What do you think
you are, abhi?
How could you do like this?
Mamta, not right now. What do
you mean by not right now?
If you act like this...
- what? - then... we...
we?
Mamta... we were working
on a film together.
That film is over now.
There is no we.
If we get a chance to work
together again, we'll see.
Okay?
I hate you.
I am sorry.
As an answer, shekhar looks at her.
But he doesn't say anything.
Even shweta looks at him.
Just looks at him.
And then she too walks away
not saying anything. Than end.
It's fantastic.
Who is doing the role of shekhar?
I think that abhi will be
perfect for this role.
Perfect choice.
Do you think that i will
be able to do this role?
What else can my coming here means?
And... what about the rest
of your team? - Team?
Yes.
Your cameraman. Writer.
Reva and the others.
All of them think that you
are good for this role.
And reva thinks that there isn't
anyone better for this role than you.
Professional.
There should be intoxication.
There should be fun.
There should be breeze.
There should be smoke.
This life is colourless.
This life is colourless,
i want a companion.
This life is so slow,
a speed is needed.
I want to become crazy, live
and die in this love.
I just want love and music.
Colourless.
This life is colourless,
i want a companion.
This life is so slow,
it needs a pace.
I want to go crazy, live
and die in this love.
I want to go crazy, the
desire of some heart.
Everyone should stop and stare.
I just want a beloved like that.
Colourless.
Life... life is not life...
the one that doesn't have love.
'Let the heart love, let the
heartbeat come closer.
The one that doesn't have love.
'Let the heart love, let the
heartbeat come closer.
There is silence, i need
rhythm in this silence.
Colurless.
This life is colourless,
i want a companion.
This life is so slow,
a speed is needed.
The breaths are going on but...
where am i living here?
Let me have fun, let
the heart become hard.
An actor is alone,
he wants an actor.
Colourless.
This life is colourless,
i want a companion.
This life is so slow,
a speed is needed.
I want to become crazy, the
ambition of some heart.
I want to become crazy, live
and die in this love.
Some love... some love...
some love is needed.
'Colourless.
You are very good.
And i was very bad.
That's not true. You were good too.
Reva, don't you think
that abhi worked well?
You were good, abhi.
In fact, you were very good.
And you too.
Mahesh must be waiting in
the office. We will go.
Bye. Abhi.
I haven't seen a talent
like reva before this.
And... as a director i feel
lucky that reva is with me.
Mr. Diwakar had faith me.
Is anything else needed to be said?
Diwakar. Abhi...
i was thinking about the goa song...
i was seeing you on television now.
You... were speaking about reva.
Oh, that!
That is the truth, abhi.
An artiste like reva doesn't
come everyday in life.
I know that.
As i was saying... when we
will go for that song...
...there will be a lot of people
and a lot of things...
diwakar...
we will take later, i am busy. Okay?
Hi. Hey, bring the chair. No.
I'm sorry.
- Why?
Because, i was rude on
the phone yesterday.
That's okay. Perhaps, you were busy.
Yes, i was. Still, i shouldn't
have done that.
Hi.
- Hello.
Anyway, sorry to disturb.
Is there something between
both of... - nothing.
Sir, there is this rumour in the
market regarding your price.
So, what would you like
to say about it?
What shall i say?
It's just a rumour.
But, the rumour is same, sir.
You asked a question
and i replied to it.
Sir, look, we journalists
very well know...
...as to how much is the
reality behind a rumour.
Forget it. Who's the
heroine in this film?
Reva. Reva!?
Is she the same video album girl?
She dances quite good, sir.
But, sir, what do you feel? Will
she able to act the same way?
Why are you asking this to me?
Better ask the director
and the producer.
As they are the ones who
signed her, and not me.
You said it right, sir.
I'll find out about
reva from diwakar.
You know, sir...
reva's affair with diwakar...
in a way it's a rumour, sir.
- What?
You know... there's this
rumour in the market...
you might be aware of it, sir.
What are you doing? You're
hitting a journalist!
Do you know what it means?
- What did you say?
I'll sue you in the court. Abhi!
Abhi! I won't leave you! - Get out!
You're hitting, right?
- Get out!
Abhi, just stop it!
Abhi, is this the way to handle it?
You don't know anything!
So, don't intervene!
Abhi! I'll see you!
Just watch tomorrow's paper!
You freak out like a big star!
Where is mr. Diwakar?
He's inside. In the make-up van.
Along with miss reva.
Give this to him.
Okay, sir.
It's the heat of love!
Life gets heated up if it
feels the heat of love.
The colour of love is bright; so
the eyes turn bright as well.
The craze hits so as.
The heart clinks like an anklet.
And, the drive goes all haywire.
Life gets heated up if it
feels the heat of love.
The colour of love is bright; so
the eyes turn bright as well.
The craze hits so as.
The heart clinks like an anklet.
And, the drive goes all haywire.
It's the heat of love!
Life gets heated up if it
feels the heat of love.
Love! Love! Love!
Is all that we've got to do.
Love is fire.
And, we've to go through.
Love! Love! Love!
Is all that we've got to do.
There's no limit.
And, we've to go through.
Even if there are blues in life.
And, hence it turns all crusty.
It's the heat of love!
Life gets heated up if it
feels the heat of love.
The craze hits so as.
The heart clinks like an anklet.
And, the drive goes all haywire.
Life gets heated up if it
feels the heat of love.
The gaze writhes and gets
locked as it's affected.
And, there's no idea; when
or where might it get locked.
The gaze writhes and gets
locked as it's affected.
And, there's no idea; when
or where might it get locked.
Even if there are blues in life.
And, hence it turns all crusty.
It's the heat of love!
Life gets heated up if it
feels the heat of love.
The craze hits so as.
The heart clinks like an anklet.
And, the drive goes all haywire.
Life gets heated up if it
feels the heat of love.
The craze hits so as.
The heart clinks like an anklet.
And, the drive goes all haywire.
Life gets heated up if it
feels the heat of love.
Mahesh, tell abhi that
the shot is ready.
Sir, he went away.
Went away? Where?
The production guys say that
he has gone to mumbai.
Mumbai?
Sir... diwakar-ji has
come to meet you.
Hi, abhi.
How are you?
Abhi, i don't even know as to
what's happening between us.
If there's some misunderstanding,
then...
diwakar, i don't want
to do your film.
Don't ask me the reason.
I won't do the film.
And, whatever your losses are...
...tell them to me,
and i'll reimburse.
How can you be this unprofessional,
abhi?
Abhi, i did tell you before.
That our profession is on one hand.
And, we're on the other.
So, don't mix them up.
And, i also told you, reva,
that i'm not great like you.
Abhi, don't ridicule me!
I'm not ridiculing.
Do you want to know, why i
don't want to do your film?
I love reva very much.
Since, always.
She was everything to me.
And, one day i lost her.
In the beginning i used
to think; so what?
I can live without reva.
But, i was wrong.
You were right.
It was my fault and...
now, i've to bear for it.
I cannot live without you, reva.
But, i can understand this.
Diwakar is the right person for you.
He understands you. And,
he has supported you.
But, this understanding
means nothing to me.
Because, i don't find
a solution for myself.
The space that i've
for you in my heart...
...what should i do with that?
I can do nothing.
I'm getting insane day by day
as i see you both together.
I'm unable to bear it!
And, this has an effect
on my profession.
I'm unable to do anything right!
I know...
i know, reva, that this film
will ruin because of me!
So, before it is too late,
i've decided that...
...i'm opting out of this film.
Do you know, diwakar, that i...
...always told reva that i want
loads of money and fame.
I've earned everything
and i'm not happy.
And, that is because...
...my happiness lies in you, reva.
And, you're not near to me.
Now, i don't want anything.
Neither film nor money. Nothing.
I just want to go back.
I want to go back.
That's it.
And, i'm very sorry.
Abhi, when we met...
...you were able to
see me the way i'm.
And, this was the very reason
for your love with me.
And i love you because.
And, you were able to understand...
...everything about me, that
others were unable to.
But, that day...
...that day, in your car...
that day, it was your success
that was doing the talking.
And then the other day, when
you came home to wish...
...that day as well your success
did all the talking.
Whatever you said that day,
it was because...
...you were successful in
the eyes of the people.
But, today...
today, i can see the
same abhi, who...
...saw me in the bus that day.
Diwakar...
diwakar wants to work with
me because of my talent.
And, there's nothing between
us other than that.
In fact, i was just waiting
for you, abhi.
And, if you had gone away
without saying all this...
...then too, i would have
only waited for you.
Forever.
Do you want to say that...
...you still love me?
What else?
I'm... i'm sorry.
I misunderstood you.
Oh, i'm stupid!
You didn't misunderstand
me entirely.
It's true that i'm working
with her because of talent.
But, it's true as well
that i love you.
It's just that i was looking
for a chance to express...
and, now...
abhi, if i say that
i'm happy for you...
...then, i would be a liar.
Yes.
But, i'm very much happy for reva.
Because, reva should get
that all she longs for.
And, she longs for you.
Congrats, reva.
And, abhi, we'll meet
tomorrow on the shoot.
See you tomorrow. Bye.
Diwakar...
reva?
I never felt the need to say.
Thank you.
Thank you too.
You okay?
Great.
Fantastic. Superb.