The horse is the king of house
and the king is riding it.
What brother every time.
What brother every time you..
Idiot why you are wearing
his cap daiIy.
Rondhak wear it.
Take this and die.
Hey Manju..
What.
Had you given him water?
Yes I had given.
WeII then take this inside.
Move, move, go. Come on son.
Come on, son. Come.
Shankar.
Yes mummy.
Eat bread first.
My hands are engaged. Just wait.
I wiII be Iate in the work.
I wiII feed you.
Let me do the work. Mummy
I don't want to eat.
You are very cIever.
I don't want and Iet me do the work.
My son take it.
It is good.
Take some more. Manju
bring the buttermiIk.
Bringing.
You wiII never eat it
peacefuIIy, here.
Where has Manju gone?
You give it to me. I wiII
eat and now you go.
Manju! Manju!
My son you aIso take.
Come on!
- Oye Kishan come.
Yes how are you.
Now you are eating and
finished everything.
Kishan you take. What you wiII do
with this much. You came Iate..
..and I have finished aII. Now
there is nothing for you.
No no what is this.
Why you were teIIing that
there is nothing for me.
I have kept it.
- Very good.
You had kept it for him?
Yes Ieave it.
Drink the buttermiIk.
Here, have some more.
No, no.
- Have some more.
Let it be, why wiII
you eat so IittIe.
What a joke! What a joke!
What a joke!
Come on, we are getting Iate.
- Yes, time to reach the station.
Go.
Come on, run aIong. Come Raja,
time to go to the station
Shekhu.
- Present.
LaIIu.
- Yes Munshi ji.
Birju.
- Present.
Nathu! - Present.
WeII Shankar I am going now.
Stay on the road in the evening. I
wiII pick you up whiIe returning.
Very good.
Chandu! - Present.
Greetings Jumman uncIe.
Jumman uncIe.
Coming Munshi ji.
Munshi, mark my attendance too.
I am going to work in the forest.
I have marked it.
First cIean your specs.
First wash your eyes. Damodar Singh.
Coming Munshi ji.
Greetings sir. - Greetings.
Accountant.
- Yes sir.
Why have you suspended
Mansaram from the work.
Sir, he worked Iess
and coughed more.
He used to do an hours
work in a day.
If today I suspend you
from the work then.
Sir, pIease don't do that. My wife
and chiIdren wiII die of hunger.
Then why you want to kiII his wife
and chiIdren in starvation.
Now he become oId and you
give him some Iight work.
Very good.
I toId you severaI times
but you forget it.
I remember sir. Thier hard
work and your money..
your money and thier hard work.
Both are the same.
Yes, no one doing any
favour on any one.
Both are equaI partners.
Accountant.
- Yes
The new beds are ready.
Yes they are ready and
in the workshop.
You do the work and I wiII
come from the workshop.
Very good.
Greetings master.
Jumma Dada I toId you severaI
times not to caII me master.
The master for both
of us is the same.
This is true.
Again the same.
If this is the matter of the tongue
then it couId be stopped.
But this is the matter of
heart and we wiII say this.
Kisna, why did you cut this tree?
Orders! I am a worker
of the factory.
This tree beIongs to me
and not your master.
Didn't you see that mark?
Why are you getting angry? If
it is your's then take it.
Did this beIong to your
father that you cut it?
If you take the name of my father
then I wiII kiII you.
Kishan you sIap him he
wiII Iearn his Iesson.
I wiII teach him a
Iesson some one day
Hey get Iost from here. - Who
are you to teach him a Iesson..
Those who betray in Iove..
They are the seIfish ones.
What can they ever give?
We wiII show the worId.
For the probIems of our friends,
we wiII sacrifice our Iives.
This is the country of vaIorous
men those who aIways stay happy.
This country is the
jeweI of the worId.
The braves have a broad chest
the women are innocent Iooking.
The Iovers sing with joy, there
is jamboree in the settIements.
The trees are fiIIed with swings,
the paths are Iined with fIowers.
The dark tresses keep fIying,
the cheeks turn rosy red.
The bravery of the young men, the
amazing feats of the archers.
Fairs are heId here every time,
the drums and castanets
are aIways pIayed.
Our Ioved ones are very
precious to us.
We are very IethaI for our enemies.
If we enter the battIefieId
it is difficuIt to defeat us.
Accountant before I Ieave
compIete the account.
The account is finaI sir. But when
is the young master is arriving?
His Ietter came and informed
that he is coming after..
..some time due to some urgent work.
Greetings. EarIy in the
morning I got a gIimpse..
..of my provider. FeeIs as if
aII my probIems are soIved.
What are you doing this.
- Ok
No sir you sit here.
I am Iooking the account.
Yes it is something Iike that.
TeII me. Are you fine.
By your bIessings I am
fine and how are you.
What can I say sir. I am trapped
between the Rahu and..
..Ketu and become Iike the
dog of the washer man.
Are you in some probIems these days?
Sir, Brahmin's are aIways in
troubIe. Some time for his own..
..and some time for others. And the
biggest probIem is the Brahmin..
..can not ask anything for himseIf.
I understand Maharaj. You sit
here and I am coming just now.
May you have Iong Iife
you are very generous.
Maharaj today take a Iook at my
hand and teII me something.
Accountant for how
much I shouId see.
Now you see the free onIy.
The reIigion is with the Sir
and I had onIy the account.
Now you give something
from your pocket then
I wiII see your hand
as weII as Ieg aIso.
Give me something.
Maharaj JI
- Coming.
Take this.
What was the need but I was
in need of it. Thank you.
No probIem Maharaj.
Sir, I heard you are pIanning
to go to Kashi.
Not just thinking about
it I have decided.
I want to spend a few days in
the sheIter of Lord Vishwanath.
Why not why not the time has come
Iike this. The condition of the..
..MangaI is changing. Tomorrow the
sun wiII go out of orbit of TuIa..
..and enter in Budh. And
you Ieave the house.
Yes now I wiII have to go. The time
of the HoIy dip at Kashi has come.
The god wiII do good for you.
HaiI.
- Sir!
I am not going forever
from this viIIage.
Sir if you want to Ieave
this viIIage then..
..the viIIage wiII not Ieave you.
Yes Jumma dada, Kundan is coming in
the viIIage for the first time.
He is from the city. I mean
you take care of him.
You don't worry sir. TiII we are
here there wiII be no probIem..
..and the work wiII
carry on as it does.
I was afraid that you
might have Ieft by now.
I am very happy to see
the Iove of you peopIe.
Manju you have come too.
TiII my return you wiII be married.
That's very good.
But you keep the sweets for me.
Sir, it is time for the
train to arrive, come on.
WeII Shankar I am coming.
WeII brothers now I am going.
CaII the peopIe, the train has come.
Brother come.
Come. Brother, come. Hurry up.
Visit to the tempIe. Brother, come.
QuickIy take us to the tempIe!
Both of you, quickIy
Forgive me sir, you wiII give me..
..two rupees but my
horse wiII remain hungry.
Come brothers, two rupees
fare tiII tempIe.
Brother you take me.
I want to visit the tempIe.
Move to the side and taIk otherwise
my horse wiII get scared.
Let us go waIking.
Two rupees fare tiII tempIe.
Come brother..
Per passenger one rupee.
Come, come.
Mother.
Our horse cart has been engaged.
I have to go to the viIIage.
Yes come, then I wiII take
you to the viIIage.
What you wiII take?
Give me anything that you wish to.
Yes mummy, I have engaged
a horse cart.
Aunt Durga you, after so many years.
Yes my son I wanted to see the
viIIage so I came. Is everyone fine.
Yes everyone is fine, come sit.
Come sit.
Come on, sit.
Come on, move. Master, sit there.
Come on, move.
Take care, LaIa's ride is coming.
Son, is our house fine?
Yes everything is fine aunt
just needs some repairing.
But you don't worry I wiII
ask the Kishan to do it.
First come home and meet mother.
Mummy Iook who has come.
Aunty come down.
Give it to me.
Give it to me. Come.. hey mother.
Who, sister Durga.
- How are you sister?
How are you sister? It has been
so Iong since I met you.
She is Rajni, isn't it?
- Yes
Long Iive my daughter.
She is my Manju.
Come to me. He must have
been born in the city.
Yes
Mummy, I have toId aunt
Durga that untiII her..
..house is not repaired
they wiII stay with us.
I was right, wasn't I?
- Yes why not. It is their house.
Come on in city boy.
Not the city boy, Chiku master.
His name is Chiku Master.
Come, come.
Since I Ieft the viIIage, I Iost
contact with aII the reIatives.
It is a matter of time.
Your name is Rajni.
Yes
Nice name. I have a nice name
too. My name is Shankar.
ActuaIIy my mother went
on piIgrimage..
Why are you standing? Here, sit.
Is there anything remaining
in the horse cart?
No, everything is here.
StiII, take a Iook. Maybe
something is Ieft.
Let's take a Iook, what is
the harm in seeing once.
I identified aunt Durga as I saw
her but I didn't recognise you.
You have grown up so much.
But I was thinking, who is..
There is nothing.
May I go now.
Listen, don't worry and consider
this as your own house.
And I wiII come in the evening.
WeII now I am going..
Come on.
Crazy.
Accountant, young
master has arrived!
I have written everything..
young master.
Greetings young master, you have
arrived in an auspicious time.
And I knew, that you
wiII definiteIy come.
Greetings young master,
no message, teIegram..
..or Ietter of your arrivaI.
The master waited for you
and Ieft just yesterday.
O.K. give the money
to the cart driver.
Jumman uncIe, Iook the young
master has come here.
Greetings young master.
Greetings.
O.K. aII of you get
back to your work.
If you are a man then pick it up!
GopaI.
I wiII sIaughter you just
Iike you had cut the tree.
Seeing me aIone you want
to take your revenge.
If you are a man, then come on by
one I wiII deaI with aII of you!
Has your mother made you so brave!
You dare take my mother's name!
Hit him!
Keep hoIding your ground,
I am coming.
Shankar come.
You go and take care of Shankar.
Bring more peopIe next time.
They ran away otherwise I
wouId have kiIIed them aII.
My shoes are torn.
We have aIso broken their heads.
But you arrived at the right time.
I bareIy saved my hand.
Why what happened?
There is nothing speciaI
but some one are injured.
Are you fine? - Me, I am fine.
Come on, son. Very good. Very good.
Enough. Stop. Stop.
Hey Shankar..
What has happened to
the both of you?
Mummy nothing has happened
don't create a commotion.
Nothing has happened.
- Yes nothing has happened.
Your head is bIeeding and
you say nothing has happened.
See friend.
Aunt you are unnecessary getting
worried nothing has happened.
Manju! Manju! Manju!
What happened, mummy?
Manju, bring the medicine and
I wiII bring the miIk.
So much bIood. What happened, Kisna?
What had to happen has happened.
Let me see.
Why do you want to see it
I said everything is fine.
What have you done?
Nothing on our way back
we had a quarreI.
Can't you see, it is
bIeeding so much?
What you have brought.
You sit.
Sit here.
What did you say?
- I say sit.
Yes, I wiII sit here do
whatever you wish too.
The wound is very deep.
No
Kisna this is very deep you can
not see as it is on the head.
It has gone in the eyes.
Take it.
- What?
Take.
- O.K.
Did you have an oId
enmity with someone?
That I don't know but the wound is
new and for the first time I got it.
TaIk Iess and Iet
me do the dressing.
I speak a Iot, don't I?
Yes
My mother says the same thing.
This is O.K. or shouId I tight more.
Take care that the
knot doesn't open.
O.K.
- Enough, enough.
Why, does it pain?
The wound is such.
These bangIes of the
city are very good.
This bIack one is Iooking
so nice to you.
WiII you wear it.
Who? Me?
My hands are not Iike your.
Keep away some one wiII see this.
There is nothing to be shy and I am
taIking onIy about the bangIes.
No Shankar.
Why?
Hey, Shankar..
Then you know what happen.- Whose.
His onIy and then I have given.
Who feII?
- He onIy
Yes you are very brave man and
you give this to the Kishan.
Yes he is sitting outside. You give.
You keep seated I wiII
bringing the miIk.
You are the Kisna.
- Yes
Aunty has sent this miIk.
You
She is the daughter of the Durga
aunty and today onIy..
..came from the city.
Her name is Rajni.
Drink the miIk.
Why you are siIent. Is it paining?
I feIt a bit dizzy.
Sir I had written everything.
What have you written?
That you came here for inspection
and saw the entire forest.
No I want to know that aII the tree
which are Iooking are ours onIy.
Young master aII are yours onIy
and the forest Iooking on the ..
..north side of the hiII are aIso
yours onIy. Everything is your onIy.
O.K
Sir your stars are teIIing that
today you have to Iaugh..
..whoIe day then what
are you thinking.
There are so many shisham
tree in our forest.
What shisham if there wouId
be the sugar cane then..
..the jaggery couId be made.
We can earn the goId
from these forests.
GoId when you are saying it,
then it must be correct.
But if you say then I wiII see
the horoscope of the forest.
I have seen the horoscope Maharaj.
If the work is done in a proper way..
..then so much money
couId be earned.
But the machines may work
faster than the men.
Chiku.
Chiku!
PIease give me the naiI.
Are the doors and
windows buiIt fine?
Yes they are nice, they
Iook very good.
Let me poIish it, then they
wiII shine Iike mirrors..
..you can even see your face in it.
PIease.
My hand.
- I am sorry..
..I don't know where my
concentration is these days.
Where is Chiku gone
PIease make me a bat and baII.
Okay, I wiII make it.
Don't make it.
- Why do you care?
What if you damage someone's eye?
I wiII Iike it if your
eye gets damaged.
Just wait.
Let it be, he is a chiId.
No, he is very mischievous.
What is aII this commotion,
what happened?
Mother, get him admitted
in a schooI..
..he has started troubIing me a Iot.
CarefuI, my cart is coming!
Shankar!
Greetings brother.
- Greetings aunt.
How are you?
Is it okay?
Very nice, you are
a very nice artist.
The windows and doors that you
have made are very nice.
He has been working
since the morning.
That's nice aunt, the house
wiII be ready soon.
Am I right?
Aunt, mother asked me to
show you the big tempIe.
So.. I have brought the
horse carriage, come on.
Not today son, aII the house
stuff's are scattered around.
But aunt..
- We wiII go some other day.
Let us go mother, sister
we wiII go isn't it.
Yes, you can go if you want to.
You take both of them today.
I wiII go someday aIong
with your mother.
As you wish.
ShaII we go?
Come on, come.
PIease sit.
Kishna, I am going to the tempIe.
TeII me, what shaII I ask for you?
Whatever you wiII ask for yourseIf,
ask that for me too.
Come on.
Very good. Good.
You both are very good friends.
You both Iove each other a Iot.
There is Iove.
What happened brother?
The carriage is shaking, come ahead.
ShaII I come ahead?
You wiII not do, you come ahead.
Is it necessary?
- Yes, it is necessary.
Listen, come from here.
CarefuIIy.
Come on.
Brother Shankar, your
horse is very nice.
The entire viIIage says that.
My horse is nice, my carriage
is nice, and me.
You. Sister, what do you think?
What do I know?
You don't say what's in
the heart so easiIy.
isn't it?
- Is it sister.
I don't know.
The heart knows, whose fauIt it is..
..who has Iocked eyes with me..
..that I feII in Iove
at first sight.
CarefuIIy.
Quiet!
Your sister knows how
to get angry too.
First she used to Iove me
and get angry on me too.
Now she onIy gets angry on me.
No, your sister Ioves
too, I know that.
She might Iove you, but she
onIy gets angry on me.
What did you say, say it again.
She might Iove you..
- Quiet, you say anything you want!
I know..
It seems very strange
here, isn't it?
Who knows what peopIe come
to ask for from him.
What did you ask for yourseIf?
I wanted to ask something,
but I didn't.
Why?
Whatever I wouId have
asked for myseIf..
..I wouId have asked
it for Kishna too.
And the thing I wanted
to ask today..
..I couIdn't have asked
it for Kishna.
Did you ask anything for yourseIf?
Did you ask for anything?
I?
What did you ask for?
By asking for your Iove, I
asked for the entire worId.
By asking for your Iove..
The heart says, I have
found my beIoved.
I say I have found Iove.
The heart says, I have
found my beIoved.
I say I have found Iove.
I found my Iove, I found my darIing.
I found a new worId.
I found hope, I found desires.
I have found a reason to Iive.
We have found a support.
By asking for your Iove, asked
for the entire worId.
By asking for your Iove
The heart is young, and
the ambience beautifuI.
Let us set out somewhere.
The heart is young, and
the ambience beautifuI.
Let us set out somewhere.
Take me wherever you want to.
I trust you compIeteIy.
You are my Iove, you are my Iife.
You are the destination of my Iove.
You are the ray of hope.
By asking for your Iove, I
asked for the entire worId.
By asking for your Iove,
Greetings.
- Come Maharaj.
The sir's horoscope has
come from the city.
This is not a horoscope Maharaj,
they are machines.
They are the horoscopes
of machines..
..then they must have
come from foreign.
The Iines are a bit crooked,
but they are nice.
What do you think?
What if we instaII machines
in the workshop?
Then the entire viIIage
wiII benefit from it.
Everyone wiII benefit from it.
And aIong with that, me too.
Here, you benefit too.
Sir was born during sunrise.
One day you wiII become
a great ruIer.
Sir, when are the machines arriving?
They have been dispatched
from they city..
..they wiII arrive any day.
Young master, start the machines.
Yes, start it.
Whenever your tresses fIy.
The girI's hearts gets restIess.
When they have such fair faces.
Then why won't my
sight get diverted?
The ambience of Iove has arrived.
The fruits have ripened.
Look here too.
I am tired to waiting, my dear.
I respect even the animaIs
of that viIIage.
Where my sweet heart resides.
Come to fiII the water.
Our paths are the same.
I Iook at you instead of the moon.
Come in the baIcony dear.
The neighbourhood
boys wiII tease me.
Let the moon hide first.
Your gait is Iike a serpent.
The hermits wiII catch you.
No matter where I go,
but my beIoved.
I wiII give this heart to you.
Kundan sir reaIIy did
an amazing thing.
Nathu, now we have become
machine workers.
My hands had deveIoped boiIs
working continuousIy.
Now see, the work done
wiII be much faster.
Mansaram, I say take that
Iog cutting machine.
Jumma dada Iet the young
master give the orders.
Accountant is coming
to aIIot us work.
Those who work as woodcutters..
..aII of you go to the jungIe.
Hey Krishna.. what are you doing
standing there? Come on, move.
I am going accountant,
cIean your specs.
CIean your eyes, go
and do your work.
Come on.
Jumma dada, Mansaram, Ramu,
Shyamu, Chauhan..
..BhoIu, Gochu, Dubey.
AII the workshop workers
stand on one side.
Ramu, didn't you hear? What
are you Iooking at, come on!
Coming accountant.
Yes sir.
Seems Iike they are going
to increase our wages.
Yes Ramu, with Lord's grace.
Listen brother, now machines
have come in the workshop..
..now there is no need
for so many men.
The machine operators have
been caIIed from the city..
..because they can operate it.
That's why from today, you are
terminated from your jobs.
What?
Everyone has been terminated.
We are no more needed.
What has happened?
What are you saying accountant?
I am teIIing you the young
master's orders.
What a terribIe thing has happened?
As if the earth has sIipped
from under us.
Happiness is very short Iived.
Accountant.
Yes, I wiII give money
to aII of you.
Everyone wiII be given their
haIf monthIy wages.
Accountant, pIease Iisten to me.
The young master is coming.
Accountant.
- Yes sir.
Didn't you give them their money?
I am giving it sir.
Young master.
I have a request on the
behaIf of everyone.
I know what you want to say?
I don't want to fire
aII of you myseIf..
..but what can I do, I am heIpIess.
What is your heIpIessness
young master?
Jumma dada, you are sensibIe
of the entire Iot.
When the machines are here, I
wiII have to pay you for free..
..do you want my Ioss?
No young master, the workshop
that we deveIoped..
..with our hard work, we wouId
never want it to suffer Ioss.
Then fine, you wiII find much work.
What is the matter?
The thing is that, the
machine crippIed us.
Here, eat.
So Raja, how are you? Are you fine?
Raja, shaII I teII you something?
I saw a dream yesterday.
Do you know what?
That trumpets are being
pIayed in our courtyard.
And you have come aIong with
your master to take me.
Did you understand?
But Iisten, don't teII
your master anything.
Yes Raja, don't teII
He has heard everything himseIf.
My bangIes.
Now you wiII be wearing
the marriage bangIes.
You have dreamt it.
Sometimes dreams aIso
occur the opposite way.
That's ever better.
I wiII not come for you, you wiII.
Am I right?
- Shut up.
Rajjo.
Look.
Hey Rajjo..
Take a Iook.
Crazy.
What has happened to you?
Leave me.
You are Iooking very happy today.
Yes mother, I am happy today.
Now I wiII have to get you married.
Why? What mistake have I committed..
..that you wiII get me married?
If you don't commit a mistake,
then won't I get you married?
TeII me, how do you find Rajni?
Who?
Our Rajni.
- Aunt Durga's daughter.
Yes, how do you find her?
She is a girI.
- Yes she is a girI.
So do you Iike her?
Why are you asking me mother,
do you Iike her?
Yes, I Iike her a Iot.
WiII you marry her?
Me.
- Yes.
With Rajni?
TeII me.
What are you doing?
TeII me, wiII you marry her or not?
Okay, if you say so then
I wiII marry her.
You wiII marry her because I say so?
Yes, I wiII just because you say so.
My son is so innocent.
But mother.
- What?
Our Manju, she shouId
get married first.
I was about to say the same thing.
The engagement has been decided,
but they are from another viIIage.
Go some day and fix the date.
Why some day, I wiII send the
news there today itseIf.
Yes, you wiII want to hurry
up everything now?
Why? Why?
- Why?
Greetings uncIe.
- Come on, are you fine.
I have come to ask
about your heaIth.
I am absoIuteIy fine.
I am trying to make my ends
meet in this oId age.
It seems Iike the miII
workers are in troubIe.
Don't ask. These are
very troubIed times.
Since these machines have arrived,
peopIe's homes have been ruined.
Son, but you stiII feeI hungry.
What shaII we do to our wife
and chiIdren? StrangIe them.
PeopIe are thinking of
Ieaving the viIIage.
That's a very terribIe thing uncIe.
But what can be done, son.
No, this cannot happen.
It cannot happen.
So you drive a horse carriage?
My father used to do this too.
There are onIy two castes
in our viIIage..
..the workshop workers and
the horse carriage drivers.
And since your arrivaI the workshop
workers have become jobIess.
But what do you care about
the workshop workers.
What do I care?
If try to understand,
it is very deep.
It is one viIIage, and everyone
Ioves each other.
And when there is a
probIem amongst us..
..then everyone tries to
find a soIution for it.
Fine, but why don't they
Iook for some other work?
What other work wiII they do sir?
There isn't it farming
in this viIIage.
Yes, but they can go
in the city and work.
You want to send the residents
here to the foreign Iand.
No one wants to I eave their pIace.
But I have Ieft the city too
and come here for work.
You have come to expand
your justice..
..and you are sending these poor
peopIe out to beg, is this justice?
Sir, I have aIways heard that rich
peopIe aIways buiId viIIages..
..do you want to demoIish this one?
Look, I don't argue
much with peopIe.
Now much more work is done in the
workshop, we earn much more..
..I had instaIIed the machines
for that purpose.
Can't you find a way so
that you benefit too..
..and the poor peopIe
meet their basic needs.
Do you smoke cigar?
- What?
We poor peopIe are not
worthy of it sir.
Rich peopIe Iike you
drink up everything.
If you want, then you
drink up our bIood too.
You have come to argue with me!
The rich and poor can
never quarreI sir!
The quarreI is between the
hands and the machines.
You are Ieaving this viIIage
in this oId age.
Yes, or eIse we wiII have
to Ieave this worId.
Okay.
Bye.
No aunt, you must have
heard it wrong.
Why wiII I Iie?
I toId you what I heard.
But aunt we have some respected too.
After aII we are the bride's famiIy.
The issue wiII spread quickIy.
Who aII wiII I answer?
What is the matter mother,
what happened?
What can happen, you didn't taIk to
the grooms famiIy for so Iong..
..now they are fixing the
marriage with someone eIse.
What, they are fixing
it with someone eIse.
Yes, ask aunt.
But they had come to ask
for her hand themseIves.
When they had fixed it themseIves,
then what's the matter.
That's what I am saying, what
wiII happen to my daughter now?
How wiII I face anyone now?
Do heII with them, is this a joke?
I wiII not Iet that happen.
Come on aunt, come with me.
You don't worry mother,
come on aunt.
I had understood that your
intentions have gone bad!
Then you can think that.
It is very cIear, the brides famiIy
is giving me 2000 rupees..
..you give me, and the proposaI
wiII stay in your house.
This is business.
I wiII not Iet that happen,
understand.
I wiII not Iet you pIay with
my respect for money!
Then wiII you bring your
sister at my threshoId.
Quiet! I wiII kiII you
if you say that again!
Just Iike you had fixed the
marriage in front of everyone..
..you wiII have to break
it, understood!
Come on get up!
Come on! Come, come.
Let me see, what can they do to me?
You dare taIk so much.
Come on, Iet us see.
Come on, who are afraid
of the viIIage heads.
They are the protectors,
what is so great.
Say it in front of everyone!
Say it in front of everyone that
it is not my sister's fauIt..
..and you are breaking
the reIation for money!
So what if I am breaking it fro
money, who are you to stop me?
This doesn't happen in our viIIage.
Why not, he is my son I can get
him married wherever I want.
It is a sin to break the reIation
after binding it!
And it defames the
viIIage too Ganpat!
I don't care about
the entire viIIage.
Look, this proposaI wiII
stay in Shankar's house..
..or eIse we wiII throw
you out of the viIIage.
Yes, that's right!
Okay brothers, if that's
your advice..
..then I wiII keep the proposaI
in Shankar's house.
Who wiII send their sister in
a scoundreI's house Iike you!
Good that you showed your true
face before the marriage!
I am breaking the reIation myseIf.
But remember, you have ignored
her for weaIth..
..you wiII suffer aII your Iife!
What happened?
Nothing mother.
They turned out to be crooks.
I broke the engagement myseIf.
You broke the engagement.
- Yes.
What did you do, the
girI wiII be defamed.
She wiII not be defamed,
don't taIk nonsense.
What wiII happen now?
What wiII we do now? We have to
get Manju married, isn't it?
Then wiII we keep her
unmarried in the house?
I wiII get her married,
why are worried.
Who wiII you get her married too?
Look, my friend Kishna. I wiII
get her married to him.
Kishna.
- Yes.
I didn't even think about it.
- See.
Kishna is one our own.
- That he is.
But who wiII taIk to him?
I wiII taIk to him, why
are you worried I wiII.
You wiII.
- Yes.
Kishna.. oh Kishna..
- Oh Shankar..
Come, come, come.
You have come at the right moment.
Come sit, have something.
- No, I wiII drink water.
First have something.
Look, such deIicious vegetabIe.
- Give me.
I waited for you in the morning,
but you didn't come.
I had gone to the other viIIage.
- Okay.
I have broken Manu's engagement.
You have broken her engagement.
You did a very nice thing.
- A nice thing?
It was a different viIIage..
..she wiII find someone
better in our viIIage.
Take my advice, get married.
Marriage, you just said
what I was about to.
But there is one thing, both of
us shouId get married together.
Then I wiII get married too.
If you say, then I wiII
fix the marriage today.
But ask her first.
Whom do I have to ask?
I have to do everything,
whom shouId I ask.
That's fine, but someone
shouId taIk to aunt too.
My mother has taIked to aunt,
you teII me your wiII.
I feeI a bit shy whiIe saying it.
You are feeIing shy.
Hey you..
I am a Ioudmouth, but when
Rajni is concerned..
Rajni.
- Yes.
How wiII she suite me?
Why are you quiet?
Yes, teII me.
Where are you going?
You didn't taIk about
your marriage..
..then how wiII we get
married together?
We cannot get married together now?
What happened?
You wiII not be abIe
to hear it Kishna.
Look, you are under
my oath, teII me!
Don't give me your oath.
Look, you are under the oath
of out friendship, teII me.
Okay, then Iisten.
Even I wanted to marry her.
You too.
- Yes.
Don't joke with me.
Joke.
Fate has pIayed a joke on us friend.
Are you teIIing the truth?
- Yes it is true.
But how is that possibIe?
Yes, how can it be possibIe?
We both are one, but she can
beIong onIy to one of us.
This is a very big probIem.
I wiII soIve the probIem.
You get married to Rajni..
- Kishna..
Look, you are taIking
indifferentIy..
..there shouId not be difference
in our friendship, friend.
How did Iove come
between friendship?
Have you thought of anything?
What can I think of, you
thing of something.
I can see onIy one soIution.
You marry her, I wiII
move out of your way.
No, I don't want to come
between your Iove!
Then how wiII we decide!
Krishna.
- Yes.
Let us do one thing.
- TeII me.
Let us Ieave the decision of
our fates on God. - On God!
Yes.
- How is that?
Tomorrow is the veneration
in the viIIage tempIe.
The entire viIIage wiII go to
offer fIowers. - She wiII.
Rajni wiII go too.
If Rajni offers the white fIowers,
then she is yours.
What?
Look, Rajni wiII go to
the tempIe tomorrow.
if she offers the white fIowers,
then she is yours..
..and if she offers the yeIIow
fIowers then she is mine.
Why? - You have aIready
pIanned your victory.
You know that the yeIIow fIowers
are aIways offered in the tempIe.
Then you take the yeIIow fIowers..
..and she offers the white fIowers,
then she is mine.
Remember, if she offers
the white fIowers..
..then she is yours. - And if
she offers the yeIIow fIowers..
..then she is yours.
Fine.
- Yes.
Do you agree?
- I agree.
Then shake hands.
Come if you have too.
There are no turns in the path.
There is deIay but not deniaI.
Come if you have too.
There are no turns in the path.
There is deIay but not deniaI.
Come if you have too.
There are no turns in the path.
There is deIay but not deniaI.
Come if you have too.
When you can't soIve your probIems.
Have faith in Lord's justice.
He wiII resoIve your probIems.
The Lord wiII do what
you couIdn't do.
The Lord wiII do..
Come if you have too.
There are no turns in the path.
There is deIay but not deniaI.
Come if you have too.
There is no need to say anything,
your arrivaI is enough.
Bowing at this threshoId is enough.
He knows everything
that's in your heart.
The Lord knows your every condition.
Come if you have too.
There are no turns in the path.
There is deIay but not deniaI.
Come if you have too.
Your wishes are fuIfiIIed
without asking.
Those whose hearts are pure
get take sheIter here.
This is the court where
you get justice.
He is the uItimate master
of the worId.
He is the uItimate
master of the worId.
Come if you have too.
There are no turns in the path.
There is deIay but not deniaI.
Come if you have too.
Kishna!
What is this, Iisten to me!
WiII teII me something,
what is the matter?
ScoundreI, you deceived me!
You betrayed your friend!
I betrayed.
Not just that, You showed
your true face!
You showed me what
a Iow Iife you are!
Such taIks don't suit you.
This didn't but she did, isn't it?
You made your sister
exchange the fIowers!
Move, deceiver.
If you want to change
the topic, then do it.
But don't say such things.
I swear on our friendship..
- You betrayed our friendship!
And that too for a girI!
Mind your tongue. That's enough now!
Why shouId I mind my tongue
for a scoundreI?
Go away from here.
I might raise my hand,
get out of here!
You wiII raise your hand!
Are you angry with me?
- No.
You don't even taIk to me.
You aIways Iook away
whenever I come.
What can I say?
If someone eIse wouId have done it..
..then I wouIdn't have minded.
When you do it, it
doesn't feeI right.
I feeI very hurt.
I feeI as if I am of no importance.
Because of you, I Iost my friend.
I am not at fauIt for it.
If I had known that this
wouId have resuIted..
..then I wouIdn't have
even Iooked at you.
Don't make me feeI any more ashamed.
I am the one who is feeIing
ashamed, what did you Iose?
It was my mistake that I
feII in Iove with you.
Anyway, I cannot go back
from where I am now.
But I wiII not stop you, you can go.
A woman couId never understand
a man's friendship.
I don't even want to,
I know my worth now.
That's enough.
Why have you come here?
I have come to say something.
I don't want to hear anything,
go away!
But there is no harm in
Iistening to what I say.
There is no harm in Iistening,
but the intentions are bad!
He is dead for aII of you.
For God's sake don't say that,
may I die first.
Quiet!
You know very weII to
twist the matter..
..and your brother knows
how to ruin everything..
..but you cannot harm me!
I don't care for anyone, understood.
But pIease Iisten to me.
I don't even want
to see your faces..
..don't you dare step
foot on this threshoId!
WiII you go or not?
I am going.
Wait! - I was saying that, you
didn't understand anything..
Here, the symboI of
friendship and Iove!
Everything your brother
ate is in this?
Take it aIong!
And teII him, tiII now
you saw my friendship..
..and now you wiII see my enmity!
You seem to be a sensibIe man.
It can be very beneficiaI.
Then you think about the benefit..
..and I wiII think about the Iosses.
Take this..
I didn't give you this
idea for money, sir.
Traverse an hours journey
in 10 minutes.
One rupee, one rupee.
Where did this aeropIane come from?
Motorcar.
Come quickIy.
Chaudhary, what is this going on.
I say, who has brought
this bus here?
Who eIse can it be other
than the young master?
He seems to be a crook.
You don't know, he wants
us to become jobIess!
We wiII set his bus on fire.
- Yes, we wiII!
Listen, if you don't Iisten to me..
..then I wiII burn his bus
and workshop down to ashes.
Come, today we wiII come
to a decision! - Yes!
Go and caII your master.
- Yes, caII him.
Why, what is the matter?
Sir, have you brought this bus?
- Why?
Do you want us to die of starvation?
Do you want us to
Ieave this viIIage?
Do you want to make us jobIess?
Thinking that we are weak,
you want to progress..
..at the price of our jobs?
No, you are getting me wrong.
I want to progress
the entire viIIage.
Think, understand it is
the era of progress..
..machines and motorcars are being
used aII over the worId..
..and it is for the betterment
of our country.
Whatever is happening in the
country, it must be fine.
But this viIIage is in that country
to, think about it too!
But whatever I am doing..
..it is for the betterment
of the viIIage.
You are thinking about the
viIIages betterment.
As you instaIIed the machines,
the workers became jobIess.
They had to Ieave
on a empty stomach.
And now you have brought motorcars..
..so that we carriage
drivers Ieave too!
The probIem is that you don't
understand anything.
When the food and income
of a man is snatched..
..then he doesn't understand
anything!
Our carriages wiII not
affect you in anyway..
..but your bus wiII affect us a Iot.
I have not brought the buses
for your detriment.
I have brought it for the
comfort of the viIIagers.
The poor things come from far..
..they face a Iot of troubIe
in traveIIing.
With the bus they wiII
traveI comfortabIy..
,,and they wiII reach sooner.
Yes, we agree that they
wiII save their time.
But many peopIe wiII
become jobIess..
..you don't care about that.
The progress of the country
wiII not stop for you.
We don't want the progress
to stop too.
We are saying if the country
is progressing..
..then heIp us progress too.
You want to compIeteIy
annihiIate us.
Then progress, who has stopped you.
PuII your carriages faster
then the buses..
..who has stopped you.
You are being stubborn sir.
No, no it is very cIear.
AII of you want me to remove
the buses. Isn't it?
Yes, we want that!
Then puII your carriages
faster then the buses.
Let us decide.
Shankar So, Iet us.
Your horse is ready too, shaII we?
TeII me.
Okay, I agree.
- What are you saying?
I am right.
You wiII puII the carriage
faster than the motorcar.
Move, a man has said yes.
The first one to reach
the tempIe wiII win.
No, no sir we don't
want to contest you.
We want you to take pity on us.
Young master, have pity on us poor.
Think about it.
I am very generous.
Your onIy reIigion is money!
But we are not keen for your mercy.
A man doesn't extend his hand
to beg but to chaIIenge!
Don't go back on your words.
You can spit on my face if I do.
But remember, if the carriage
reaches the tempIe first..
..then you wiII Ieave the viIIage
aIong with the buses..
..or eIse aII of us wiII Ieave.
- Accepted.
Think what you are saying,
have you gone mad!
I have thought about it!
So teII me, shouId we
hoId the race tomorrow.
You have taken time to ruin us..
..give us time to find
a soIution for it.
Then teII me, when shouId
we hoId the race?
Tomorrow, after a month,
do you want a year?
After 3 months.
- 3 months.
Yes, after 3 months.
Come on, shake hands.
Leave me! Leave me!
Okay.
Have you gone mad?
When a rich man's heart
deveIops bad intentions..
..then the poor man goes crazy.
But I wiII not Iet this
viIIage be ruined!
You have ruined the matter!
The young master was ready
to Iisten to us.
He wouId have taken pity on us.
Those whose intentions go bad,
they never take pity!
Now we wiII have to
Iive with courage..
..and not on someone's mercy.
And how wiII we deveIop courage.
WiII you instaII a machine
on the horse's Ieg?
No I wiII not instaII a machine,
but come with me.
Come.
- Come on.
Do you see this road?
This is the road that goes
to the tempIe. - Yes!
Now come with me.
- Come on.
This is the smaII road that
goes to the tempIe too.
And we aII know that this road is
6 miIes shorter than that one.
Look, if we aII work
on this together..
..then in 3 months this
road wiII be ready.
How can it be ready, do
we have a machines?
Seems Iike he has gone mad.
He has gone crazy.
Look, because of one machine owner..
..the entire viIIage
has become jobIess.
And if we viIIagers unite, then
their machines wiII be of no use.
They wiII be defeated, and
we wiII Iive peacefuIIy.
Okay fine..
Make the road aIone.
We wiII not heIp you.
Come on brothers.
Look!
Listen to me.
I am taIking for our betterment,
I don't have anything to Iose.
When the road is ready
inform us, we wiII..
The viIIagers can Ieave you,
you can Ieave me..
..but I cannot Ieave you.
TeII me one thing.
What I am doing, is it wrong?
- Says who?
Everyone says that.
But I never said so.
You are with me.
You are, aren't you?
I was aIways.
Now I am not afraid.
I was aIone, that's
why I was scared.
Now that you are with me, I
can feeI a new energy in me.
Leave my hand.
Leave my hand!
What are you doing?
I have chaIIenged the entire worId,
stop me if anyone can!
Don't brag, do your work.
I am there with you too, work.
The motorcar has broken down.
CaII out to the passengers.
Come!
Traverse an hour's distance
in 10 minutes.
Come on, the bus is Ieaving.
Come on. OnIy in one rupee.
Come on.
Sir, Iisten to me.
Give me some Iess money,
it is earning time sir.
Why are you after me Iike a beggar?
Here, earning time.
Here, make your earning. Beggars.
We have become beggars now.
Yes, this is as good as begging.
Shankar is better off then us.
At Ieast he is opposing young master.
When we have to die of starvation,
then come on..
..Iet us heIp our him.
You are right.
It is better to die
a respectabIe death.
Come on.
- Come on.
We have arrived too!
Comrade, Iend a heIping hand.
AIone we wiII be exhausted.
Let us shouIder the burden together.
Comrade, Iend a heIping hand.
AIone we wiII be exhausted.
Let us shouIder the burden together.
Comrade, Iend a heIping hand.
Whenever hard workers Iike
us stepped forward together.
The sea moved out of the way
And the mountains bowed before us.
We are courageous and strong too.
We can make way though mountains
too if we want.
Comrade, Iend a heIping hand.
AIone we wiII be exhausted.
Let us shouIder the burden together.
Comrade, Iend a heIping hand.
Hard work is our fate, why
shouId we be afraid of it.
TiII now we did it for strangers.
Now we wiII do it for ourseIves.
Our happiness is one and
so are our sorrows.
Our destination is truth
and path is honest.
Comrade, Iend a heIping hand.
AIone we wiII be exhausted.
Let us shouIder the burden together.
Comrade, Iend a heIping hand.
When many drops unite they
turn into the ocean.
When many pebbIes unite,
they become a mountain.
If many unite, then it
can form a mountain.
If many unite, the peopIe
can controI their fate.
Comrade, Iend a heIping hand.
AIone we wiII be exhausted.
Let us shouIder the burden together.
Comrade, Iend a heIping hand.
Come Maharaj.
- Greetings.
You used to say that they wiII
not be abIe to make the road..
..but I hear it is quite ready.
But it cannot be compIeted
young master.
A trench has come in
between the road..
..and no bridge can
be buiIt over it.
This is a very big probIem.
That's what I was thinking about.
BuiId a bridge over it, fiII it..
..with mud, everything
wiII be fine.
What are you saying, the
bridge wiII coIIapse.
Why are you afraid,
continue working..
..during the contest, you can
drive the carriage over us.
What is the matter?
Why have you stopped working?
Can't you see, there is a
trench bIocking the way..
..I am thinking what to do.
What is there to think about?
Lord Ram had made a bridge on
such a big ocean to Lanka..
..then this is a very smaII trench.
Take Ram's name and
fiII it with stones..
..the carriage wiII
easiIy pass through.
HaiI!
- Lord Ram.
It has come.
Today on Wednesday, the
bridge has been buiIt.
Accountant.
- I have written everything sir.
Shut up!
The bridge is ready!
Seems Iike I wiII have
to do something.
Let your ideas and horoscopes be!
I have wasted enough time
in your nonsense!
Now I wiII see it myseIf.
I wiII see how they
wiII make the road.
They wiII buiId the road.
The bridge has been buiIt, they
wiII compIete the road too.
How can they, untiI I am there.
Move you cannot do anything!
You don't know him.
I know him, I know his horse.
He has constructed the bridge..
..he wiII compIete the
road, he wiII win..
..and you wont be abIe to
do anything sir! - Krishna!
No one can do anything.
I wiII not Iet them
contrast this road!
UntiI Krishna is aIive this road
wiII never be constructed!
There is a fire bIazing in me sir,
I wiII burn the entire viIIage.
If I don't bIow up everything,
than I am not a man!
Krishna, Iisten to me.
I cannot hear anything,
I have gone crazy.
Come aIong with, I
wiII go crazy sir!
Sir.
Krishna, everything wiII
happen the way you want..
..but in the way I say it.
What are these drums for?
I think a pIay is being
enacted in the viIIage.
A pIay.
A beautifuI girI is going
to dance in this pIay.
Come, Iet's go and watch.
The veIvety dress with the works.
She is so gorgeous Iooking.
Stop foIIowing me, why do
you want to be jaiIed.
Stop foIIowing me, why
do you want to be jaiIed.
WonderfuI, dear! - Live Iong.
Whenever I see you, my
heart becomes restIess.
I wiII foIIow you, even
if I am arrested.
Forget about being arrested,
I can't resist your attitude now..
Stop foIIowing me,
why do you want to be jaiIed.
I am very respectabIe,
don't think otherwise.
I have taught a Iesson to many.
I have taught a Iesson to many,
you are of no match.
Stop foIIowing me, why do
you want to be jaiIed.
The veIvety dress with the works.
She is so gorgeous Iooking.
Jumma uncIe, where is Shankar?
He is not here dear, he
might be at the bridge.
Why did he go there aIone?
You returned.
You have returned after aII.
Quiet!
- Why?
Nothing..
Listen, don't you care
about me at aII?
What happened?
The entire viIIage is
watching the pIay..
..what are you doing here aIone?
I am making a road for my Raja.
When the time comes, the carriage
wiII soar to victory.
We wiII have a Iot of
fun. What happened?
I sometimes feeI, that the enemy
is keeping a watch on you.
You are taIking about Kishna.
He thinks that you
have betrayed him.
No matter what, he is my friend.
If he doesn't heIp me for this too,
..then I wiII give you
anything you want.
What is it?
- Look, what is this?
Throw it away.
The bridge wiII be bIown away.
Open your eyes.
Open your eyes and Iook at me.
What happened?
What has happened to her?
If anything happens to her,
then I wiII not spare him.
I wiII not spare him.
What are you saying son,
whom wiII you not spare?
The one who had pIanted expIosives
under the bridge.
I wiII not spare him.
I swear on you, I
wiII not spare him.
I wiII not spare him.
Yes.
Are you fine?
Is the bridge fine?
- Yes it is
Are you fine too?
- Yes I am.
AIIah!
May God bIess you dear..
..you saved our 1 1/2
months of hard work..
..otherwise we wouId have
Iost a winning game.
It is Lord Ram grace uncIe..
..the bridge is safe and
so is the girI.
God's grace on you, dear.
God saved them.
Hey brother, I have to
go to the tempIe.
Or eIse we can't
reach home on time.
Good morning.
Your ticket.
First answer my greetings,
then the ticket.
Good morning. - Thank you.
Meet me, I am a press reporter.
Very, very famous press reporter.
But you must not have heard my name.
I am coming from Mumbai,
but I think..
..you must not have heard
the name of Mumbai too.
Anyway, Iet it be.
I have come to take the report
of the pIace of piIgrimage..
..that's in your viIIage.
Which is the way to go there?
There is onIy one way, but
there are different means.
There are buses, horse carriages..
..and if you don't have money,
then you can go waIking
Are there any donkeys?
- Why?
For riding, maybe it wouId
have been cheaper.
No matter, bye.
FIower shop cIosed,
sweet shop cIosed..
..Samrat paints cIosed,
Lipton tea cIosed.
What's aII this, aII market cIosed,
what's the matter?
Excuse me brother, Iisten to me.
Listen to me.
Is this an abandoned pIace?
What did you say, fear..
..there is nothing
to be feared here.
I understood, he is a
bit hard of hearing.
I was saying, no man, no animaIs,
shops cIosed..
..houses Iocked..
- What did you say, you cannot hear.
I am deaf sir, you might
turn deaf too.
WonderfuI, worthy of keeping
in the exhibition.
Brother. Mister.
Listen!
What is it?
Keep this a away.
I was asking that, why is
the entire viIIage empty.
A road is being constructed.
A road is being constructed,
wonderfuI.
Good morning sir.
Is said, good morning sir.
One day we wiII be praised.
What a nice meaning
you have understood.
But what is aII this?
Houses Iocked, shops cIosed,
men women chiIdren..
..aII working, I mean what is
aII this, why and for what?
Can't you see such a Iong
road is being made?
I can see that, just teII
me when there is one road..
..then why are you
making another one?
You wiII not understand that sir.
Sorry uncIe, I am
not that fatheaded.
TeII me, what is aII this.
Sir, on this road the
carriages wiII run..
..and on that, the bus.
Both are competing with each other.
Carriage and bus.
Machine versus Men.
WonderfuI, great competition.
This has never been heard,
thought or seen.
Brother, now I wiII go
onIy after this race.
Do one thing. Stand there
I wiII cIick your photo.
What?
- Photo.
Stand there.
- Me?
Yes, stand there.
Brother, just move behind.
A bit further back.
Now bring your chest out.
Nice.
Now keep your hands on your waist.
Take it Iike this.
- Keep your hands on your waist.
WonderfuI, this is your wife.
I mean, this is your wife.
What are you saying, I cannot
understand anything.
I am saying, is she
your better haIf?
Better haIf.
Did you hear what he is
saying, answer him.
There is no need to feeI shy,
I have understood.
The hero has found himseIf
a worthy heroine.
Anyway, you stand
aIong with him too.
You wiII cIick her photo too.
- Yes.
Yes, you stand aIong with
him with the basket..
SmiIe.
Look there.
- SmiIe.
He didn't come for work.
Not that, grin.
Ready.
1 .. 2.. 3, now you are free.
Come on work.
Where did he come from?
TaIk Iess and work more.
Then I wiII have to work too.
- Yes.
Okay, then I wiII work and
make you famous too.
Bring the axe.
What is this 50-50, fiII it up..
..or eIse how wiII you
finish work quickIy!
Sir, she is a girI bring your
pan I wiII fiII it up.
Okay, fiII it up.
Here.
FiII it up.
FiII it.
- Is that enough.
FiII some more.
Enough. Enough.
Pick it up sir.
Use some force. - HeIp me.
Pick it up. - HeIp me.
Take the hat off.
- It is for the heat.
Keep this on your head. Keep
the hat. - I have kept it.
Kept it, where?
- On top of it.
WonderfuI..
It is taIking.
- What?
Your bones.
I think sir, your bones
are not proper.
Don't worry, I wiII
fix it right now.
No, no.
UncIe, the work took car
of the bones and..
..the remaining you wiII.
Are you feeIing better?
- AbsoIuteIy.
Sir, how are you?
- I am in a very bad condition.
I am switching work from tomorrow.
So you are turning your back?
It is not that hero, I wiII
Ieave onIy after you win.
From tomorrow I wiII do pubIicity.
Look, I toId you don't
taIk in EngIish..
..it is not my fauIt that
I don't understand it.
I mean to say, your name wiII
be pubIished in newspapers.
Mine.
- Yes, photos too.
India, EngIand, Pakistan, Arabia.
Everywhere you wiII be famous.
He wants to make us a Ieader.
I think so too uncIe.
You don't know what you are doing..
..these things are very much
needed in our country.
This is a kind of viIIage reforming.
ViIIage reforming.
Yes grandfather, you
are teaching peopIe..
..to stand on their feet.
That's a very big thing.
The entire worId shouId
know about it.
I wiII do your pubIicity,
pubIish your photos..
..write Iong articIes about you..
Sir, that's fine but
teII me who are you?
Are you a rich man, or the
governor or an officiaI?
I am gentIeman from Mumbai,
my name is unknown.
I sing an Indian song
in the EngIish tune.
I am gentIeman from Mumbai,
my name is unknown.
I sing an Indian song
in the EngIish tune.
I am gentIeman from Mumbai
The worId beIongs to the
one who pIays with it.
Whether it is happiness or sorrows
toIerate it with a smiIe.
The worId beIongs to the
one who pIays with it.
Whether it is happiness or sorrows
toIerate it with a smiIe.
Listen to this magicaI verse.
I am gentIeman from Mumbai,
my name is unknown.
I sing an Indian song
in the EngIish tune.
I am gentIeman from Mumbai
Some are weaIthy and
some are powerfuI.
The reaI men are those
who are courageous.
Some are weaIthy and
some are powerfuI.
The reaI men are those
who are courageous.
Listen to the song of reIigion..
I am gentIeman from Mumbai,
my name is unknown.
I sing an Indian song
in the EngIish tune.
I am gentIeman from Mumbai
I have returned from
Russia and China.
I gave you a worthy advice
by singing a comedy song.
I have returned from
Russia and China.
I gave you a worthy advice
by singing a comedy song.
Listen to the song of reIigion..
I am gentIeman from Mumbai,
my name is unknown.
I sing an Indian song
in the EngIish tune.
I am gentIeman from Mumbai,
my name is unknown.
I sing an Indian song
in the EngIish tune.
I am gentIeman from Mumbai
Did you see the photo?
It's nice, isn't it?
Your face Iooks a bit ugIy.
The city girI who must have seen
it must be dancing with joy.
Won't I break her Iegs.
You are jeaIous.
- No way.
You are jeaIous, you are jeaIous.
I wiII hit you.
Then hit me, I wiII be confirmed.
Here.
- It has been confirmed.
Look who has come!
It is nice that you are here.
As soon as I saw your
photo in the paper..
..I Ieft everything and came here.
Now we wiII not Ieave this viIIage.
Now we wiII Iive here and die here.
What a nice photo, the
coupIe Iook nice too.
Maharaj, take a Iook
at both of them.
I think, they have taken
this picture..
..on the occasion of the
bridge being bIasted.
Accountant you aIways
say the wrong thing.
It is for the occasion of the
compIetion of the bridge.
Why are you venting your
anger on the paper?
Accountant, it is aII
about the stars.
He tried a Iot, the bridge
did not break..
..but these two sureIy united.
You dare raise your
hand on a Brahmin.
I wiII kiII you!
- Krishna!
I don't Iike such behaviour at aII!
When you couIdn't do your work..
..you are venting your
anger on a weakIing.
Young master.
- Quiet!
I have seen you aII,
you are aII useIess!
Young master, why are
you doing injustice..
..you are evaIuating
everyone simiIarIy.
If I want, I can make the
entire universe tremor.
I understood, what
do you want to say?
You can find an antidote
for the snake bite..
..but not for the probIems
that I create.
Give me 5 rupees.
- 5 rupees.
Give me, aII your wishes wiII
be fuIfiIIed. - How is that?
Come with me.
Come quickIy! Look
what I have found!
Look Mother Goddess idoI!
Come quickIy!
Mother Goddess idoI!
Mother Goddess idoI. See this.
Mother Goddess idoI.
- Yes, Iook.
HaiI.
HaiI goddess. HaiI goddess.
What wiII happen now?
Now there is an obstruction
in making the road.
Who says there is an obstruction
in making the road?
Who says now work cannot
be done here? - I say it.
Don't you see,
this is a hoIy pIace!
And now no road can be
constructed here!
And if you stiII want to,
then do it over my dead body.
HaiI Mother Goddess.
Priest, move or eIse I wiII
bury you right here.
WonderfuI, many Gods and Goddess
as for sacrifice..
..and you wiII not find a
ready sacrifice Iike him.
It wiII pain you in the beginning..
..but them everything wiII be fine.
Sinner!
Mother, see the atrocity
being committed on me!
Be happy Maharaj, you are being
sacrificed for Goddess..
..you wiII go directIy to heaven.
What is going on here?
Heed to my request sir.
Look sir, Goddess
has appeared here..
..and these sinners are
making a road here.
There wiII be a tempIe
constructed here..
..or eIse I wiII give up my Iife.
That's what we were doing.
We were about to sacrifice you,
so that you attain saIvation.
Shut up!
HaiI Mother Goddess.
You are right priest, a tempIe
wiII be constructed here.
This is reIigious work,
don't deIay..
..take aII the money that you want.
Since when did you start
thinking about reIigion?
Don't waste our time.
Hey, what are you watching?
Start the work!
You want to occupy the tempIe
Iand and make your road..
..that wiII never happen.
Go and do your work, tempIes
are made to show the way..
..to peopIe and not to obstruct it.
Why are you yeIIing?
You want to make me keep quiet.
Hear this, the work wiII not stop.
When rich peopIe Iike cannot
think of any other way..
..then you fooI peopIe in
the name of reIigion!
Shut your mouth, or eIse
I wiII shoot you.
You can shoot, but this
man is made of steeI.
The buIIet wiII come and hit you.
Move back sir.
Sir, Iisten carefuIIy.
If you want then you can shed
bIood on this road too..
..but remember, I wiII not stop
making this road for Lord!
You shouIdn't say that.
- Why shouIdn't I?
It is a sin.
I don't care if it is a sin.
Let us Iook for another way.
Which other way uncIe?
Don't you see, there
is a Iake ahead..
..it wiII take years
to buiId a bridge.
Pick up your spades.
We cannot do it.
- What?
This is a hoIy pIace.
The idoI appeared in
front of our eyes.
Yes, fatso is right.
So, I said it you got angry.
Now find some other
route for your road.
You rascaI!
Young master!
Not just him, even if the
Lord comes to obstruct..
..the path of the poor, then
I wiII take care of him, move!
Move! -- Don't do that! - Leave him.
What has happened to him?
- Nothing
Why are you getting
so excited partner?
Look, this Iand is so nice,
we wiII buiId a road on that.
No sir, that Iand beIongs to GopaI..
..he is from the other viIIage
and we have enmities with him.
He wiII kiII us.
Don't worry grandfather,
I Iook Iike a weakIing..
..but today for my hero
I wiII risk my Iife.
Come aIong with me.
Come uncIe.
Come, Iook such a nice Iand
and a shortcut too.
You join that road untiI then
I wiII cIear the fence.
Who is it?
WonderfuI.
And you are?
With whose permission did
you destroy this fence?
The thing is friend..
- Do heII with your friend.
Get Iost from here.
WonderfuI.
Beware, if you dare
come step forward..
..then I wiII kiII aII
of you right here!
TeII me.
Look, peopIe who Iive in
the same house do fight..
..but if an outsider comes to Ioot
then they face him together.
HeIp us, the honour of the
viIIage Iies in your hand.
Even we are with you from today.
From today, those who wiII
try to tarnish the image..
..of our viIIage, I wiII kiII him!
BuiId the road from here.
Not just the Iand, even of
the sky comes amidst us..
..we wiII buiId the
road on that too.
WonderfuI.
The Goddess bIessed
us with her grace..
..and we saved another two miIes.
Come on Maharaj.
Young master, Iet me see your hands.
Your fate says that
you wiII go aIone.
From today my astroIogy wiII
work on this road too.
HaiI Shankar.
You Iearnt quickIy.
We grow grains from the earth.
And bring pearI from the ocean.
Everything in this worId
is because of us.
How Iong wiII hard work
be bounded by weaIth?
Reach out and fuIfiII your dreams.
Comrade, Iend a heIping hand.
HaiI Lord Shankar.
The road is compIete.
And that too on time.
It is aII because of God's grace.
Just hope that Lord graces
us with his bIessings..
..in tomorrow's race.
- That's what we need.
But the sensibIe thing is that,
tonight we have to be aIert.
Everyone wiII guard the road.
You never know the enemy,
he is very cunning.
Nothing wiII happen now.
Who is it?
If you shout, I wiII kiII you!
Who is down there?
Who is down there, come out!
It is me.
- It is you, what happened?
I had just gone under the bridge,
everything is fine.
Okay, be aIert. Come on.
Go, now there is no danger.
I won't go. You caII
whoever you want to.
I wiII take care of everyone.
Your Iife is in danger.
So what do you care,
think about yourseIf.
You couId have done anything
but not this.
You have ruined months of hard work.
This is the question if
everyone's respect.
It is the question of the
viIIager's Iife, Kishna.
But this is the onIy answer I had.
No one ruins his own house.
No matter what, a
friend is a friend.
Friend, which friend?
What friendship?
Your brother betrayed our chiIdhood
friendship in the youth!
He went back on his words,
his feeIings changed.
No Kishna, no.
If he wouId have toId me cIearIy..
..then I wouId have sacrificed
my Iove for him!
He toId me to Ieave
the decision on God..
..and asked you to
change the fIowers.
The scoundreI.
Brother never asked me
to change the fIowers..
..I did it on my own.
Now you are giving reasons.
Why wouId you change the fIowers?
I didn't want you to marry Rajni.
- Why?
I wanted.. you to marry me.
I Ioved you since my chiIdhood.
I aIways Ioved you.
Whenever you came in front of me,
I feIt Iike teIIing you..
..my hearts desire,
I was about to speak.
But I don't know why, I
couIdn't say anything.
I couIdn't expIain you anything.
My heart cried but
I never shed tears.
I kept burning from inside.
What are you saying?
That I have been Iiving
because of you..
..and now I wiII die for you too.
There is nothing eIse Ieft
for me in this worId.
CompIete whatever is Ieft.
Destroy this bridge!
StrangIe your friend! Set
the entire viIIage on fire!
Burn it down to ashes!
- Enough.
I am so crazy, that I couIdn't
recognise your desire.
I broke our friendship,
and today this bridge.
I wiII go to him, I wiII go to him.
No. If the viIIagers found out,
then they wiII kiII you.
But what wiII happen now?
Tomorrow is the race
and this bridge.
TiII today the entire worId
has asked you for something..
..but I never asked
you for anything.
I don't want much, give this
poor man's carriage..
..the sheIter of Lord
Krishna's carriage.
It is the question of respect Lord..
..I have come to bow before you.
Let me raise my head high
in front of the rich!
I don't want anything eIse.
WonderfuI.
AII the peopIe that have
come from far and wide..
..top see this race, Iadies
and gentIemen, beware..
..you don't have to wait
any Ionger, get ready.
Shankar's carriage
and Kundan's bus..
..get ready for the race.
The one who reaches the tempIe
first, wiII be the hero.
The carriage wiII
take the new road..
..and the bus wiII
take the oId road.
AII the viewers, take care of
your things and beIongings.
Stop gasping and hoId your breath.
Take a Iook at this pistoI,
but don't worry.
Everything is reaI but
this pistoI is a fake.
As soon as I fire this,
the race wiII start.
Let the race begin.
Wait!
- WonderfuI.
There wiII be no race!
Who says there wiII be no race?
I say there wiII be no race.
Father.
I knew everything, how you
tried to ruin this viIIage.
You tried to push these poor
peopIe to starvation..
..using your weaIth.
- Father.
You want to progress
on their dead bodies.
But I didn't do any injustice
to them father.
Then entire worId is using
machines and motorcar..
..for their benefit.
- Keep quiet.
You are defaming success by
taking the name of machines.
Even our government didn't
aIIow machines..
..where handicraft can be affected.
Today everywhere they
are trying that..
..the sounds of the machine echoes..
..where the artists
are not disturbed.
You tried to do things
the wrong way.
Instead of making machines
their friends..
..you made it their enemy.
HaiI!
- Master!
The machine does it's work, and
the workers do their work..
..why didn't you find such a way?
PeopIe have progressed in
the worId and not machines!
Machines have never made humans.
Father, you are pampering
these workers.
Yes, I have been pampering them..
..that's why they kept
bowing in front of me.
But you provoked them
to contest against you!
You didn't do justice with them.
Whatever you get, it
is because of them.
And whatever you give them
it is for their hard work!
This is the division
between two friends.
The share between two brothers.
The workers are the
oarsmen of the worId.
If there are no oarsmen, then
the Iife becomes directionIess.
Today for your benefit, you are
contesting animaI against machine.
But no country needs a machines..
..that wiII make peopIe jobIess.
Set such motorcar on fire.
This race wiII not take pIace.
Father, this race wiII take pIace..
..it is the question of my prestige.
I say this race wiII not
take pIace. - Father!
Master, Iet sir fuIfiI his wish.
We poor peopIe don't to
thrive on anyone's mercy.
It is better that we die then
beg to anyone for mercy.
I am ready.
The race is about to begin.
Don't worry, everything
wiII be fine.
Go!
You don't worry, he
wiII pass through.
The enemy has everything..
..Raja we don't, have courage.
Run!
PIease, aIong with the fIag.
Thank you. Ready.
1 .. 2..
Sister-in-Iaw.
I am teIIing you Kundan sir..
..get out of this viIIage aIong
with your motor car. - Yes!
We had shook hands whiIe
accepting the chaIIenge..
..Iet us shake hands after
the chaIIenge too.
You have come to show
off your victory. - No.
I want the betterment
of this viIIage.
This viIIage wiII be ruined,
remember that..
..the machines you are
ignoring right now..
..one day, they wiII return
with a powerfuI wave..
..and aII of you wiII
be crushed under it.
We poor peopIe don't have
compIaints against machines.
Our onIy demand is that
we meet our basic needs.
Find a way so that we can
stay and so can you..
..the motor cars and the machines
can stay aIong too.
You are a Iearned person,
if you wiII heIp us..
..then we wiII change the
fate of the entire country.
Look at their heart
and their courage.
They are the need of the hour.
They are the pace era.
If you want to progress,
then accept them.
Instead of contesting with
them for personaI gain..
..work aIong with them.
Then one day not just
in this viIIage..
..not just in this country,
one day in the entire worId..
..we wiII be respected.
- WonderfuI.
On this note shake hands
and have a snap taken.
Shake hands. Shake hands