This is a story that takes place
In fair Paris in the year
of our Lord
A tale of love and desire
We the artists of stature unknown
In sculpture and verse
Will attempt to transcribe
This story for you and posterity
The time of the cathedrals has come
As the world is entering
A new millenium
Man reached for the stars
To write his story
In glass and stone
Brick by brick, day after day
Century after century, with love
He saw the raising of towers
That he built with his hands
Poets and minstrels
Sang songs of love
That promised better times
For all of mankind
The time of the cathedrals has come
As the world enters
A new millenium
Man reached for the stars
To write his story
In glass and stone
The time of the cathedrals has come
As the world enters
A new millenium
Man reached for the stars
To write his story
In glass and stone
The time of the cathedrals is gone
Hordes of barbarians
Storm the city gates
Let them in, the pagans and vandals
The end of this world
Is predicted for the year 2000
We are
foreigners
Without passports
Men
and Women
Homeless
Oh! Notre Dame
we beseech you
Asylum! Asylum!
We are
foreigners
Without passports
Men
and Women
The Homeless
Oh! Notre Dame
we beseech you
Asylum! Asylum!
We are a thousand or more
Pressing at the city doors
Soon we'll be
10,000 and then 100,000 more
We'll be millions
Beseeching you
Asylum!
We are
foreigners
Without passports
Men
and Women
The Homeless
Oh! Notre Dame
we beseech you
Asylum! Asylum!
We are vagabonds
At the city's doors
And the city is an island
In the island of the city
The world will change
And intermix
And we will play
On this island
We are
foreigners
Without passports
Men
and Women
The Homeless
We are
foreigners
Without passports
Men
and Women
The Homeless
Vagabonds
We are
foreigners
Without passports
Men
and Women
The Homeless
We are
foreigners
Without passports
We are
foreigners
Without passports
Men
and Women
The Homeless
We are
foreigners
Without passports
Men
and Women
The Homeless
Oh! Notre Dame
we beseech you
Asylum! Asylum!
We are
foreigners
Without passports
Men
and women
The Homeless
Oh! Notre Dame
we beseech you
Asylum! Asylum! Asylum! Asylum!
Sir Phoebus de Chateaupers
captain of the King's archers
I summon you to chase away
All these outlaws
By all means, we have to stop
this horde of strangers
Who disrupt the peace
Of the citizens of Paris
By your orders, my Lord Archidiacre
In the name of God I'll slay
And chase from your sight
All those louts with no standing
Where are you from, lovely stranger?
Daughter of the stars or the earth
Fair bird of paradise
Why are you here?
Gipsy
Nobody knows my land
I'm a child of the road
Gipsy, Gipsy
Where will I be tomorrow
It's written in the palm of my hand
My mother told me of Spain
As if it were her home
About the bandits in the hills
In the hills of Andalusia
My father's gone, my mother too
Paris is my home
But when I dream of the sea
I'm transported far away
To the hills of Andalusia
Gipsy
Nobody knows my land
I'm a child of the road
Gipsy, Gipsy
Where will I be tomorrow
It's written in the palm of my hand
My childhood passed
Barefoot in the hills of Provence
For gipsies the road is long
The road is long
And I will keep on walking
Beyond the roads of France
I'll walk them
to the end of the earth
To the end of the earth
An Andalusian river
Runs in my blood
Runs through my veins
Are the skies of Andalusia
Worth
Going back to?
Gipsy
Nobody knows my land
I'm a child of the road
Gipsy, Gipsy
Where will I be tomorrow
It's written in the palm of my hand
You know, Esmeralda
You're no longer a child
And sometimes I look at you
With different eyes
You were only eight years old
When your mother left
Taken by death
To her home in Andalusia
She trusted you to me
And with jealousy
I watched over you
Until today
You know, Esmeralda
Men are wicked
Be careful when you run
In fields and streets
Do you understand me?
You're about to discover love
Nothing is the same as before
My fourteen summers
are for you
This diamond necklace
is for me
If your words and promises
are lies
I won't believe them
Your maiden's heart
is mine
Your eyes like a dove
are for me
The stars twinkle
in the skies
Less brightly than these eyes
He who my heart desires
Is a fair knight
Who doesn't know
The realms of my love
If I didn't know it
I can see it in your eyes
The one who wins your love
Will be a lucky man
Stop your search
Love is here
Here forever
So it is
The day will be merry
the day
When we marry
All the gold that still lies deep
Beneath the earth in veins asleep
I'll use to clothe your body
Your body that you'll give to me
All those lovers' lines
All those songs of desire
Better than any troubadour
You will sing to me
Stop your search
Love is here
Here forever
So it is
The day will be merry
the day
When we marry
Stop your search
love is here
Here forever
so it is
The day will be merry
the day
When we marry
The day will be merry
the day
When we marry
Feast of fools!
I will preside
Over this feast of fools
Like we know how it's done
and we know how to have fun
Feast of fools!
Take the ugliest
Of those on the street
Let them parade
on the city's main square
And the one in that crowd
That conjures up
The ugliest face
will get the crown
The Pope of Fools!
He will wear the crown
The Pope of Fools
The
Feast
Of
Fools
The Feast of Fools
But who is that there
Hiding in the back
Is he not the monster
that will wear the crown
The Pope of Fools!
He will wear the crown
he will wear the crown
The Pope of Fools!
He's the bell ringer
The hunchback
He's certainly the ugliest
he is Quasimodo
Now he starts giving
Poor Esmeralda the eye
Hunchbacked gimp, missing an eye
he's the one who'll wear the crown
The Pope of Fools!
He will wear the crown!
he will wear the crown!
Qua-si-mo-do!
He will wear the crown!
he will wear the crown!
The Pope of Fools!
He will wear the crown!
he will wear the crown!
Qua-si-mo-do!
The Pope of Fools!
Little girls
you won't mock anymore
When you see me on the streets
I'm Quasimodo the Beast
They've crowned me
The Pope of Fools
Today is the Epiphany
And for one day
I've the power of a king
Will you love me,
Esmeralda?
Will you love me?
But you don't care
Esmeralda
Oh! You couldn't care less
That they crowned me
The Pope of Fools
Little girls
Singing rondos
Mocking Quasimodo
The hunchback
How does it make you feel
That I'm this ugly?
I hate the parents
that gave me birth
And abandoned me without love
Will you love me,
Esmeralda?
Will you love me?
But you don't care
Esmeralda
Oh! You couldn't care less
That they crowned me
The Pope of Fools
Beware!
this girl is not from here
She's a gipsy
a witch
She's a bitch
a streetcat
An animal on the prowl
barefoot and homeless
Mortal sin incarnate
She ought to be imprisoned
To stop this pillage
Of the hearts and souls
of the children of Notre Dame
Tonight we'll chase her
in the alleys
Tonight we'll take her away
We'll lock her in the tower
And teach her
The only true religion
Of Jesus and The Holy Mother
You can ask of me
anything
And I will do it for you
Anything you like
you know
Anything at all
I will do it for you
You who took me in
Adopted and fed me
Me, the orphan
The child abandoned
By parents who were shamed
To have brought into this world
A monster
You who watched me grow
You who watched me suffer
You who offered protection
From this cruel world
You gave me my existence
By naming me ringer
Of bells
You taught me to speak
To read and to write
But I can't read
Your true feelings
I belong to you
to the depths of my soul
Like the deepest love of a dog
For his master
I belong to you
to the depths of my soul
Like the deepest love of a dog
For his master
The gates of Paris
Are closed at dusk
When nighttime's shrieks
And laughter in the dark
and nocturnal desires reign
Nights where every vice
are satisfied
In the heat of Paris
A showplace of lust
On the Pont-au-Change tonight
An angel I did meet
That smiled at me
Then disappeared
On the streets of Paris
I followed her and lost her
Pursued her into the night
lnto all the laughter
and carnal desire
Nights where every vice
is satisfied
In the heat of Paris
A showplace of lust
The gates of Paris
Are closed at dusk
When nightime's crimes
And laughter in the dark
And nocturnal desires reign
I am the captain
In charge of the peace
Of all citizens
Men and women alike
Allow me to escort you
Outside the city gates
Where the gipsies live
Men and women alike
Go your way
You've clearly made a mistake
Esmeralda,
good Sir, is not a soldier's girl
At dusk tomorrow
Tomorrow's end of day
I'll be there to see you
In "The Valley of Love Caberet"
Here we are, brothers all
In misery and joy
Here there is no heaven or hell
No heaven or hell
Here we're just like worms
Worms in the rotten earth
Wine and blood share the same color
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
Prostitutes dance with hoods
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
Beggers and bandits dance alike
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
We're all gallows' birds
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
We're all the same breed
Of the homeless seed
You won't find here
a nation or creed
No nation or creed
Our rags, our flags
The color of my skin next to yours
Gipsies and villains
sing the same song
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
We're all on the lam
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
Thieves and killers drink
from the same cup
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
As we are all outlaws
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
Gringoire the Bard
You will hang
Convicted
of trespassing
Upon our sacred ground
Here in the den of thieves
Trespassing on our sacred ground
here in the den of thieves
Unless a woman
Takes you for her husband
Be aware
I say to you
The poets of France
Are only fit to hang
are only fit to hang
And you my beauty
My lovely Esmeralda
Will you take as husband
This worthless minstrel?
If he's free, I'll take him
He's yours
as spouse but not as a lover
Wine and blood share the same color
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
Prostitutes dance with hoods
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
Beggers and bandits dance alike
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
We're all gallows' birds
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
Gipsies and villains
sing the same song
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
We're all on the lam
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
Thieves and killers drink
from the same cup
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
As we are all outlaws
Here in the den of thieves
here in the den of thieves
Now may I know
Who I've the honor of marrying
I'm Grignoire the Bard
the prince of Paris's streets!
He's the prince of Paris's streets!
I'm not a ladies man
if you desire, I will make you
My nymph, my muse, my lady
You, who can read and write
You, the poet, do you know
What Phoebus means?
By Jupiter
who on this earth
Dares to go by this name?
He's the one
for whom my heart beats
If I recall
my latin
The word Phoebus means sun
Phoebus means sun
He's bright as the sun
Is he a prince, the son of a king?
I feel love
Deep inside
Stronger than myself
He's bright as the sun
He's a prince, the son of a king
Of a king......I think
He's bright as the sun
He's a rascal, a soldier
When he holds me tight
I want to run away, but I can't
He's bright as the sun
He's a rascal, a soldier
A soldier of the king
He's bright as the sun
My wonder, my man
He'll take me in his arms
And love me all his life
He's bright as the sun
My wonder, my man
Bright
As the sun
Torn
I'm a man divided
Between the two women I love
The two women who love me
Do I have to tear my heart in two?
Torn
I'm two men in one
Between the two women I love
The two women who love me
Is it my fault that I'm happy?
One for the day
One for the night
One for love
The other for life
One for forever
Until the end of time
The other for a certain while
Perhaps a little less
Torn
I'm a man divided
Between the two women I love
The two women who love me
But I'm not complaining
Torn
I'm two men in one
Between the two women I love
And the two women who love me
Is it my fault that I'm normal?
One for heaven
One for hell
One for sweet
One for sour
One to whom
I swore every oath
The other with whom
I undo them
Torn
I'm a man divided
Between the two women I love
The two women who love me
Do I have to break my heart in two?
No
Torn
I'm two men in one
Between the two women I love
The two women who love me
Is it my fault that I'm happy?
Torn
I'm two men in one
Between the two women I love
The two women who love me
Do I have to break my heart in two?
Torn
Who is this girl
who dances
Her dance of shame
before the Notre Dame?
The girl is my wife
Given to me
By the King of the gipsies
Did you touch her
Servant of Satan?
I wouldn't dare
And I forbid you
I would like to show you
An inscription here engraved
On a stone beyond
The Gallery of Kings
What does it mean-
this word "Anarkia"?
You're a man posessed
The Greek word "Anarkia"
signifies "Fate"
Is that not Quasimodo
That they're taking away?
He's got himself arrested, the fool
And only God knows why
Hunchback! Rapist! One-eyed & lame!
Damned ringer of the bells
Pray for him, the poor sinner
Have mercy on him, good Lord
Mercy
for poor Quasimodo
Who carries on his back
All the world's woes
And asks you only
for a drop of water
Have mercy, public
for this servant of the Lord
A drop of water only
For Quasimodo
I'm thirsty!
Give me a drop to drink!
Give me something to drink!
Beauty
It seems a word invented for her
When she dances, revealing her body
Like a bird
spreads its wings to fly
I feel the devil
take me by the feet
My eyes gazed
under her gipsy dress
What shall I pray to Mary for?
Who
Will cast the first stone at her?
He who does not deserve to live
O Satan! Oh! Let me just once
Pass my fingers through her hair
Beauty
Is she the devil incarnate
Leading me from the Eternal Lord
Who has bewitched me
with carnal desire
To turn me from heaven above?
She carries inside the original sin
Am I a criminal if I desire her?
She
Who all thought a whore,
a girl of the street
Suddenly seems to be
humanity's burden
Oh! I beseech you Our Lady
Oh! Allow me just once
The entrance to Esmeralda's garden
Beauty
Behind those eyes that cast a spell
Could the girl still be a maiden?
When the moves she makes
promise me the earth
Underneath her rainbow skirt
My betrothed,
leave me one infidelity
Before we're joined by God
What
Man could resist gazing at her
At the risk of becoming transfixed?
Oh! My Lilly Flower
I'm not a man to trust
I'll pluck the flower
of Esmeralda's love
My eyes gazed
under her gipsy dress
What shall I pray to Mary for?
Who
Will cast the first stone at her?
He who does not deserve to live
O Satan! Oh! Let me just once
Pass my fingers through the hair
Of Esmeralda,
Esmeralda
My friends, the gargoyles,
are watching over you
They'll protect you from any fool
Whenever you need shelter
Come to me, I'll protect you
The Notre Dame of Paris
Is my house, my nest
It's my city, my life
My air, my roof, it's my bed
It's my song, my voice
My reason, my folly
My passion, my country
It's my prison, my homeland
Your friends the gargoyles
are my friends too
They make me laugh
on days when I'm bored
You're like them
and I like you for that
Even though I'm scared of you
most all the time
In my house
It's always comfy
Warm in the winter
In the summer it's cool
You are always welcome
Any time of the year
If you like, my house
Could be yours
Whenever you need shelter
Come to me, I'll protect you
In my house, in your house
It's always comfy,
it's always comfy
Warm in the winter
warm in the winter
In the summer it's cool
in the summer it's cool
You are always welcome
I'm always welcome
Any time of the year
any time of the year
My house, if you like
your house if i like
Could be yours
Could be mine
Ave Maria
Forgive me
If before you
I don't kneel
Ave Maria
I who won't go on my knees
Protect me
From misery, evil and the fools
Who rule the world
Ave Maria
Foreigners are everywhere
Listen to me
Take away the walls between us
Between brothers everywhere
Ave Maria
Watch over me day and night
Protect me
Guard my love and life
Ave Maria
I feel my life slipping
lnto some unknown world
I feel the crowd receding
When I walk the streets
I'm stripped bare
Stripped bare
This ocean of passion
pulsing through my veins
Causes all my madness
my loss, my bad luck
Softly I'll plunge into it
without a hand to save me
Slowly I will drown
without a bit of remorse
You will destroy me
you will destroy me
And I'll curse you
to my death
You will destroy me
I could have foreseen
from the first day
From the first night
you will destroy me
You will destroy me
My sin, my obsession
tormenting mad desire
Making a fool of me
tearing me apart, haunting me
Little pusher of illusion
I live with only one hope
Of seeing your skirt fly past
while you sing and dance
You will destroy me
you will destroy me
And I'll curse you
to my death
You will destroy me
you will destroy me
I could have foreseen
from the first day
From the first night
you will destroy me
You will destroy me
I thought it was the autumn of life
and here I am, a young tree again
I thought I was a man of steel
far from the heat of flesh
I'm on fire, I'm burning
for the eyes of a stranger
That conceal much more mystery
than the light of the moon
You will destroy me
you will destroy me
And I'll curse you
to my death
You will destroy me
you will destroy me
I could have foreseen
from the first day
From the first night
You will destroy me
you will destroy me
Who is that man
Is it my shadow behind me
or a ghost in the night
Why would my shadow
Wear a coat
wear a hat
Who are you?
Unmask yourself!
Come closer!
ldentify yourself!
I'm your conscience
heed my words
If you want to escape
the gallows
Soldier of the King
Go away
from the place
You are about to enter
A soldier of the King I am
But tell me
You who've followed me
Here
Are you not God's servant?
Of course!
Up the street of St. Denis
There is a blessed place
You can see the candles burning
as evening falls
There in the middle of the plain
If you go there once
You'll want it everyday
at The Valley of Love Cabaret
At The Valley of Love
the girls who serve
Will cater to your desires
for pennies
No need for gold
nor for jewels
No need for speeches
or words of love
Only a few pennies
to make love
With the girls who serve
in The Valley of Love
Andalusians, Jews and Moors
arrive from every port
Travelers and merchants
rest there for awhile
Catalonians and Flemish alike
blow all their money in one night
The girls who serve
Listen to this minstrel's song
Crying out his lovesickness
in The Valley of Love Cabaret
Beat those drums
in the neighborhood
Hurry along
to The Valley of Love
No danger
of falling in Love
With what's under the clothes
in The Valley of Love
You wil find
under the velvet
Flowers for one night
pleasure for one day
When I feel lovesick
I'm off to the Valley of Love
You stay there 'til break of day
at The Valley of Love Cabaret
Pardon me girls
I'm waiting for lovely Esmeralda
She saw her destiny
in the palm of my hand
North city door
on the outskirts
At the crossroads
of Popincourt
All the thieves
all the rogues
Meet each other
at the Valley of Love
Noblemen
dishonour themselves
You'll see them drink
'til they're dead drunk
At The Valley of Love
the girls who serve
Will cater to your desires
for pennies
No need for gold
nor for jewels
No need for speeches
or words of love
Only a few pennies
to make love
With the girls who serve
in The Valley of Love
In the Valley of Love Cabaret
Sensuous
For me voluptuous delight
From this pure body
For me all these delights
Nobody else but me
Will touch you
Black angel of mine
I'll love you
in the depths of night
With just one look
you set me on fire
Our skins of two colors
Like
a burning torch
I'll love you
love you even if I die
Take me
take me if that's my fate
Let us see
let us see if that's your fate
Phoebus
Esmeralda
Fate
Mistress of our destinies
When you cross our path
Fate
prince or pauper
Queen or prostitute
Fate
You hold our lives in your hand