This is the last day of Carnaval.
Let your hair down!
Let's dance
and have a great time!
I say hello to Pelô,
Liberdade, Curuzu...
Piatã, Paripe, Peri-Peri!
We're still backing you up on
the last day of Carnaval in Bahia!
But pay attention
to this message:
Carnaval
is about peace and love!
If you wanna screw, use a condom.
If you wanna drink, take a taxi.
Don't give violence a chance!
Let's enjoy in peace!
I'll be bringing you the hits
until the end of Carnaval.
It's summer in Bahia!
The sun is scorching!
Listen up now, men,
boys and girls.
Turn your stereo up!
"It's Oxum"!
In this city
Everyone is
Oxum's
Man, boy, girl, woman
Everyone radiates magic
Present in the fresh water
Present in the salt water
And the whole city shines
Whether it is a lieutenant
Or the son of a fisherman
Or an important judge
If they are there
They are the same everywhere
The force
That resides in the water
Does not differentiate by color
And the whole city is Oxum's
The force
That resides in the water
Does not differentiate by color
And the whole city is Oxum's
Oxum's
I'm going to navigate
I'm going to navigate On the waves
Of the sea, I'm going navigate
I'm going to navigate
I'm going to navigate On the waves
Of the sea, I'm going navigate
Oxum's...
I need your services.
Tell me, honey,
how can I help you?
Paint me for Timbalada.
Look at this.
"LOOK AT THIS"
Hey, Cosme,
where is Damião?
Don't!
You little pest!
Walking down the hillside
Easygoing
Get out of here,
you little devils!
The devil is everywhere,
Dona Joana!
FORTUNE TELLER
What a group of ugly misfits!
Hey, witch! What's all that smoke?
Are you smoking pot, huh?
What a mouth!
Leave me alone!
When the police
start shooting...
I hope you get hit
by a stray bullet!
Go take a shit!
I wanna know where you'll make
your potion, you fake witch!
Leave me alone!
Get ready.
- You both took so long.
- The sermon was really long.
- Yeah? Tell me about it.
- It was nice. Really nice.
- But what did he talk about?
- He talked about a lot.
Come on, boy,
what did he say?
- He talked about the cross.
- The cross.
About the cross?
On the last day of Carnaval?
Jesus nailed to the cross, people
down here celebrating Carnaval.
That can only be a sign...
to warn me to keep you
locked up at home...
far away from this shameful
cross that Carnaval is!
- Hallelujah! Jesus!
- Hallelujah!
Hallelujah! Hallelujah!
Not again...
Right in the middle of Carnaval
she decides to shut down the water!
For God's sake,
turn it on, Joana!
Turn the water on,
for Oxalá's sake!
Calm down, sister.
The pump's broken.
If I didn't shut it down,
there's no way I can turn it on.
Leave me be!
There's nothing broken.
Don't I know you?
Give me a break!
Damn woman!
- Hey, Neuza, what's up?
- I see you're slutting around.
- Come on, it's Carnaval!
- It's Carnival!
You haven't met Rosa,
have you?
She's the daughter of a friend of mine.
She'll stay here for a while.
She's a great dancer from Juazeiro,
you know.
Dances like hell.
This is Roque, Rosinha.
First-rate painter.
Poet and talented singer!
Right, buddy?
Roque! Roque! You're late!
Let's go! It's on the other side!
You're staying here?
- Hey, Neuzão.
- You're pushing it.
- You're pushing my patience.
- Who's the honey, Neuzão?
- She's my God-daughter.
- Hi.
Daughter of my midwife.
- Don't look at her, Reginaldo.
- Your nipple is showing.
Listen... if you need me to paint
you again, let me know.
It's all included.
- It is, huh?
- Everything.
Hey, Roque,
hey, Reginaldo...
I'm not gonna stand there
just like a palm tree!
- Get this fag outta here!
- I'm not a fag, I'm a woman.
- Blessings from your auntie.
- Let's scram!
When I see you
Your stare makes me halt
What I most desire
Is to kiss you
To feel your body
And be sheltered in your warmth
What I want
Is to conquer your love
And here I am
Wishing for your pleasure
I can't stand
A minute without you
Your mere presence
Fills my heart with joy
I wrote this song for you
Come, my love
Take this loneliness away
Come to Olodum
Come dance at Pelô
Come, my love
Come and give me your hand
Take this loneliness away
Come, my love
Come to Olodum
Come dance at Pelô
Come, my love
Come and give me your hand
And here I am
Longing for you
Waiting that
One day you'll realize
And take away this loneliness
And that's how
I'll conquer your heart
Come, my love
Take this loneliness away
- Come, my love
- This feels so great!
Come to Olodum
Come dance at Pelô
Come, my love
Come and give me your hand
When I see you
Your stare makes me halt
What I most desire
Is to kiss you
To feel your body
And be sheltered in your warmth
What I want
Is to conquer your love
And here I am
Wishing for your pleasure
I can't stand
A minute without you
Your mere presence
Fills my heart with joy
I wrote this song for you
Come, my love
Take this loneliness away
Come to Olodum
Come dance at Pelô
Come, my love
Come and give me your hand
- Take this loneliness away
- This one is by Pierre Onassis
Please, please.
Visit the shop.
Come to Olodum
Come dance at Pelô
Come, my love
Come and give me your hand
And here I am
Longing for you
Waiting that
One day you'll realize
And take away this loneliness
And that's how
I'll conquer your heart
Come, my love
Take this loneliness away
Come to Olodum
Come dance at Pelô
Come, my love
Come and give me your hand
That's the
Rosário dos Pretos Church.
The Black Church. Black people.
Wonderful, wonderful.
- What's up, my Lord!
- Hey, bro, how's it going?
Hey, Raimundos!
What y'all have to say!
If you're from the slums, say it!
I am
I'll get it, Mom.
- Who's there, Damião?
- It's a message from the Church.
- For me?
- No, for us.
For us. They tell us to go take part
in a praying session...
in front of the house of a girl
who's been possessed.
Praise Jesus!
Tie up the evil!
- Let me go, mom, tie up the evil.
- You...
are so little. How can you
tie up the evil, my son?
- I can do it.
- You guys make me laugh.
All right, you can go.
But come back straight home. Hey!
Come back here!
Where do you think you're going
without your Bibles?
That's a good one,
"tie up the evil".
You pests!
Get out of here!
- Good morning, Reginaldo.
- Good morning, Maria.
I'm livid! You know that crab
upstairs turned off the water again?
- You're acting up on me again, right?
- Me?
What the heck have you been
planning in that head of yours?
Because now you leave one morning,
you come back the next day...
and you even carry your damn
toothbrush in your pocket?
Are you crazy, Maria?
I got here late last night,
came into the kitchen...
made noises and all and you
never woke up! So I just sat here.
Do I look like a toilet to eat all
your crap? That's gotta be it!
Maria, come on.
You are my wife, I love you.
You're the mother of my kid.
You're my main office!
Your main office?
No main office...
no branch,
and no vending station!
You keep wandering
around the house.
Your taxi is at the body shop,
falling apart. You don't care.
Maria, that taxi is dead and buried!
Get over it!
The plate is all that's left,
and I'll use it on a friend's car.
- I start today.
- My God!
You're involved with gangs.
Who said anything about gangs?
The guy's a cop.
- A cop, Reginaldo?
- A policeman.
Reginaldo,
what damn car is that?
- It's a Quantum.
- What?
A Quantum.
And to keep the car for good...
I have to wet
the cop's hand.
You know what I was thinking, honey?
Sit here. You know what?
We could take that
house at Urbes...
...and give it to him.
- Give it to him? You're not giving it...
selling it, nothing!
I have nothing to do with it!
The Quantum
of the car is yours!
The organized crime
was committed by you!
Reginaldo, I've already told
everyone we're leaving this place!
- What am I going to say...
- Let her go alone, Reginaldo!
- Look at this.
- You have to scream!
She's up there,
eaves dropping!
I'm gonna buy an iron
and burn out your eyes!
- Careful, Maria, the baby.
- Reginaldo...
you'd better solve your problem,
and get outta my face!
What the hell, Maria!
Don't touch it, boy!
Go!
- How much is the umbu?
- R$ 1.50.
- And the serigüela?
- And the acerola?
- R$ 1.50.
Have you lost anything here?
Don't come hounding my stand.
- We're hungry.
- Don't you have food at home?
- No. We haven't had breakfast yet.
- That's awful.
- This umbu is rotten.
- Take it and get outta here.
- Leave now!
- Thanks! May God help you!
Auntie, don't you have any nuts
that fell out of the bag?
Aren't you two Joana's kids,
Cosme and Damião?
- We are.
- How do you know our mother?
- From the Church. Praise the Lord.
I remember you.
I think we met before.
- Does your mother know you're here?
- She knows. She knows.
Haven't you heard?
My mother is sick.
- Really?
- She fell sick.
- She's sick.
- Oh, my God.
She told us to go buy
some stuff at the market.
Here.
She won't be at the church.
Share the nuts.
Take this to your mother.
Tell her it's from Dalva.
- God bless you.
- May God help you.
Amen, you too!
Good morning, Jerônimo.
- Good morning, officer.
- How are you doing?
I wanted to talk to you.
May I sit so we can talk?
- Please.
- Excuse me.
You know, Jerônimo, I'd like
to talk about the money I owe you.
What can you do for me?
I'm late on rent this month.
I have 5 children, as you know.
Maybe you could...
All right, all right.
Feel at home
I know you cops
are fucked.
Your salary is crap, right?
- That's right.
- You're just like toilet paper:
When you're not tied up,
you're blotched with shit.
Let's forget about that.
You can pay me with other deeds.
You know those kids
that fool around my store?
- Yes.
- I want you to give them a scare.
Got it.
Don't worry.
As far as I'm concerned...
your shop will be protected.
You do that.
Thank you, Jerônimo.
Have a good day.
- This is Saint Sebastian.
- Hi, Jerônimo...
do you have any money for me?
Excuse me.
- God bless you.
- Amen.
Transition period, 18th...
Are you all set, Peixe Frito?
Yes, the bottles are loaded,
at your request.
- People will only drink your coffee.
- But keep your mouth shut, Peixe.
If you tell anyone,
I'm fried, and so are you.
My lips are sealed, Boca.
I won't say a word.
I'll fry you!
Dona Joana, come on in!
- Good morning, Jerônimo.
- Good morning.
Would you like some coffee?
Thank you,
but I can't stay long.
Won't take a second.
Maria José, bring us some coffee!
Jerônimo, your store looks great,
so full of things!
This time of the year,
so many ships arrive.
We must have variety.
Like this silver crown,
from the 18th century.
- Truly beautiful, Jerônimo.
- Excuse me.
- Coffee's here.
- The best coffee in Bahia.
Jerônimo,
I never said anything...
but something about
you amazes me.
Until this day...
you wear your late wife's
wedding ring.
Well...
when we love someone so deeply,
like I loved my late wife...
...that love clings to us for life.
- I know...
but, nowadays,
people don't care about that.
Nowadays, all they care about
is being naughty.
- The world is doomed, Dona Joana.
- You're right about that.
But I must go now,
I can't stay.
- Thank you very much.
- It's early still.
No, I have to go.
I'll come back some other time.
- You owe me another visit!
- Of course!
Good-bye.
- Lúcia?
- Sir?
- Go get an abará for me, please?
- Right now?
Yeah, I got up early today
and I'm hungry.
But no chit-chat on the hill,
or you'll be here tomorrow!
Don't worry.
- Roque Nascimento dos Santos!
- What's up, Boca?
- Is it safe?
- Yep.
- Straight?
- No way, man.
Straight business
is for the fool, right?
Dude, you and Reginaldo
really fucked me over.
It was the last time.
I just did it...
because Reginaldo
was in need.
Cut the crap. Show me
the shit you got, Saint Roque!
Here, I don't want to brag, it came
out sweet. Check the stripes.
Nobody will say
they're fake.
I hope Reginaldo
won't have any problems.
It looks like a real taxi,
doesn't it?
It's the spitting image!
- Look, don't fuck me up.
- Come on, brother.
Are you Bahia
or are you Vitoria, Afro?
Are you crazy, man?
Let go.
- Where are the trolleys?
- There.
Why the hell you care
for selling coffee on a trolley?
- Mind your business.
- Such a small business.
You can make some money during
Carnaval. So, are they ready, bro?
Almost.
I just need to install the...
What time did I ask them for?
- Boy, it won't take long.
- Five o'clock!
- Right?
- Calm down, brother.
Don't be a frigging nigger
and botch things up, brother.
I'm not your brother, or boy...
and you're the one
botching things up here!
- Come on boy, I'm joking with you.
- Fuck this shit!
- Calm down, my brother. Nervous?
- Brother...
I already told you I'm not your
brother, my brother. Are you deaf?
You're deaf.
You bastard.
The deal was to deliver them at 5.
They'll be ready, if you pay.
I only took this job,
worked all night along...
to buy my
fucking costume.
5 o'clock I'll be back
to get my fucking trolleys.
My brother.
Watch out, my brother.
This fucking Pelourinho
is full of crazy people.
You hit one of them,
I bet The Human Rights shows up.
Hi-quality! What's up?
What's the matter?
Your friend Roque can't take a joke?
What a hothead!
That's how artists are.
They're born with that anger!
- Fuck his anger.
- What have you done to him?
Nothing.
But I should have.
Take a look.
- My brother!
- But that's the thing.
The deal is 50/50
of what you get each day!
Greedy, huh?
No way, sir. That's mine.
- Forget about Roque, Boca.
- Go fly a kite, man.
- Good day, Baiana.
- Carmem, you're so dressed up!
You look like
a laundry donkey.
I'm going to pick up Psi, my sister.
She's coming home from abroad.
And that bitch Joana
shut the water again.
That woman is nasty, girl.
Baiana, are you going
to do that little job for me?
Have you ever seen a fag
become a man?
Not even an Orisha God
can fix that, Carmem.
Let me remind you both...
that your rent is due today.
And let me remind you...
that we don't
have any water.
That's how Carnaval is, honey,
bad things happen.
Check these out:
Three stiffs.
- They look like Faustina's sons.
- What do I care about her sons?
I care about mine, woman.
If you popped it out, raise it!
I take good care of mine.
They're on a short leash.
I'm very strict.
And when Mario's back, he will see
I did a good job with our kids.
And all by myself.
"When Mario's back".
Once away...
who would be crazy enough
to come back to this bitch?
- Good afternoon.
- What are you doing here, Joana?
Well, same as you:
Fulfilling
my duties with God.
If you're sick, you have no
obligations to the church, no ma'am.
Who's sick here, woman?
What are you talking about?
I saw your boys in the market
earlier today...
and they told me you
delirious with fever.
- I was so upset.
- Say what, Dalva?
Like I said. They told me they
were there to buy things for you.
- Dalva, say that again.
- Just like I said, Joana.
- Like you said, huh?
- That's right.
We'll see.
No.
Hey, you!
Give me two reais.
- Two?
- Yeah.
- Give me one.
- He just wants one.
You sister won't recognize
this place. Everything's changed.
In the old days, black folks
would come and just party.
Now, with the white folks,
it's all about...
...feeling people up till morning.
- Jesus Christ, Baiana.
Was I talking to you?
Girls, now Pelourinho is fancy!
I say that
because you know. Pelourinho...
was one
of the last hideaway for niggers.
- What the hell you saying?
- Pelourinho now is ACM:
Action, Competence and Morality.
And it is all covered in Barbie pink.
Isn't that fabulous, Baiana?
What do you think,
you cheap abortionist!
Why, dear,
do you need my services?
Me? No way.
And don't you grow all big on me...
because everybody here knows...
that you've forgotten garden scissors
inside a woman belly!
What the hell
are you saying about me?
Everybody here knows your womb
looks like a sieve now...
because of all the
gringo babies you've aborted!
Did you hear that, Baiana?
She's got a venomous tongue!
Listen, girl, you want me
to throw a fit right here?
I won't give you that pleasure.
I'm not going down to your level!
Baiana,
I'll be back when she leaves.
Now there's two.
What fuss is that with
your name, Carmem?
Can you believe that? A low-life
like her trying to ruin my name.
Look, this chick is crazy.
She loves trouble. Stay away.
- I know that. I know.
- Stay away.
- Hey! What's this, Carmem?
- There he is.
You letting your sister wait,
with a suitcase in her hand?
Go!
What a fucking
disaster this guy.
What a fucking piece of crap,
let me tell you something.
- The abará, Baiana?
- Be patient.
I ain't no McDonald's joint.
Do you want this?
I'm all woman, come check it out.
Go home, man.
Go home, you fag.
Can you believe this fag?
He has no... Go rest!
Shit!
I talked to my friend,
and you can collect cans tonight.
Last day of Carnaval,
but what can you do?
You have to be licensed to do that,
but he's sick, so I got his.
Show! Show!
- God bless you, Roque.
- I've been waiting for that.
Bow look,
I will go get us some food.
Show.
- A customer, Ma, a customer.
- Hold on, son. Hail Mary.
Forget it, Ma.
It's Roque.
It's you, Roque?
Come on in.
The smell of your food
guided me here.
I have to tell you something.
Cut the sweet talk.
- What?
- Have you seen...
...that trash in the hallway?
- You, too?
You're a psychic,
you should care for him.
Me, care for that garbage bag?
The poor boy makes no harm.
What about the one upstairs?
- I don't know.
- She turned off the water again.
I'm loving it,
you hear, sister?
I don't know why I'm shouting.
At this time,
that bitch's at the fucking church!
Just talking about it
gives me the creeps.
She's been on my case, Roque...
but let me tell you:
I won't leave...
...and God won't get me out of here!
- I make mine your words.
I'm not leaving either,
you know why?
- Why?
- Because of your food.
- Dear Lord!
- Stop that nonsense, boy.
Let me tell
you one thing, Roque:
It's hard for me
to buy food.
I can barely feed myself and
Raimundinho. Look how thin he is.
I can't be feeding
your little bum friends too.
Mother Raimunda, what's enough
for three is enough for four.
It's all about the heart
of the cook behind the door.
See you later!
Look at this.
Be that way.
- Jesus loves you!
- Jesus heals you!
- He frees you!
- And bans devil!
- And bans the devil!
Get up, you devil!
Get up!
Leave her body!
Out, you devil!
Out!
Leave, devil!
Leave! Leave! Leave!
Lord of glory, hallelujah.
You're free now, thanks to
the glory of Lord Jesus Christ.
Hallelujah, Lord!
Dear sister,
let me ask you something:
have you ever used drugs?
No, sir.
- Have you participated on Carnaval?
- No, sir.
- No, she's a righteous girl.
- Praise the Lord!
How has the devil
seized her soul?
Let me tell you:
This girl used
to be nervous and impatient.
Her family, in order
to help her...
resorted to the so-called Orishas!
In the name of Jesus,
protected us.
And what are the Orishas?
The Orishas are shapes
assumed by the devil...
to snatch the souls
which belong to Jesus.
What about Carnaval?
And what is Carnaval?
It's the different forms
assumed by the devil...
to steal thousands of souls...
which belong
to Lord Jesus!
Carmem!
I missed you so much, my sister!
I can't believe you're here!
I love those Bamboo trees.
There's nothing
like that in the world.
- Really, Psi?
- Not even in Paris.
- You look prettier, Psi!
- I do, don't I?
- Fabulous.
- What did you say, Reginaldo?
This car, it is fabulous.
It's my life abroad.
I eat well...
live well,
riding on a plane everywhere...
Woman, cut it out! I heard
you were washing dishes in Europe.
Look at this.
People can't stand other's success.
No, they can't.
- Sorry.
- That's gossip!
Gossip from those who have never
been on a plane, had any snails...
or a dab of caviar.
Of people who stayed here and
ended up expelled from Pelourinho!
- It's pure envy!
- Never mind, my sister.
All right,
tell me about your foreign lover.
You tell me about your life,
Carminha. How are the kids?
The kids are fine.
I've got 7 now.
- Seven!
- All grown up, at school.
- Remember the twins?
- The twins.
They're playing Olodum.
- Olodum.
- Yeah.
And I've adopted a little girl.
So beautiful!
I'm mad about her.
- How lovely.
- But you wouldn't believe.
She was all covered in pustules.
I took care of her...
and now the mother wants her back.
But I won't let it happen!
I sure know you.
Your husband?
I couldn't bear him anymore.
Sent him off.
- Alone again?
- I'm a hard working woman.
I don't care what people say,
I know what I do is important.
It's not my fault people screw
around and I have to fix the job...
God himself set up
for those miserable people.
I have a soul,
I'm not like Him.
And I even gather the stray sheep
He leaves behind.
Well, for me, you have
always been much more than that!
More than a mother.
Thank you, Reginaldo.
Very emotional!
Tell me, Psi.
Tell me about the gringo.
Carmem...
I'm dying for an acarajé!
So early in the morning?
Desire never sets up a time, Carminha.
Isn't that so?
You're right, Reginaldo.
- Take us to the Baiana.
- Let's go, then.
Fuck!
How do you like that?
- Come friend, fight
- Check this out!
Come, friend, fight
Come, friend, help us out
Or we'll end up losing
What we already won
Come, friend, fight
Come, friend, help us out
Or we'll end up losing
What we already won
Come on
Get up and fight
Get up and help
Come on
Get up and shout
Come on, get up now
Life doesn't stop
Life doesn't stop there
Hey, Baiana!
Where's Mateus?
Won't you say hi to me?
Hey, Maria, is this baby
coming out or not?
Not now! I'm 7 months now
and look how big I am.
- Looking good!
- Ain't it?
- It took you so long today, Roque.
- I was working.
But coming by here is a must.
That's how I unwind.
- Check it out, Roque.
- Yeah?
Three corpses. Don't
they look like Faustina's kids?
This is never gonna change.
It seems like God
has forgotten this place.
He has turned his face
a long while ago.
What are you talking about?
I'd like to go sightseeing.
You busy today?
Not anymore.
What time?
Three o'clock, is that okay?
I'll be back!
Delicious!
Huh!
What the fuck!
Baiana, Maria,
do you recall Psi?
Hey, Baiana, hey, Maria.
Looking good.
Baiana, please, I'd like an acarajé
with everything on:
Caruru, vatapá, shrimp,
lettuce and a lot of hot sauce...
to kill this burning desire.
And please
spread on my acarajé...
a little bit of this mustard.
I'm addicted to French mustard.
Who told you I'd have acarajé now?
It's available in the afternoon.
Baiana, my darling,
give me a break.
I just arrived from Switzerland
and the first thing I wanted to do?
- To eat acarajé.
- No chance at all.
I'll pay in Euros!
Get a grip, my child.
Here, take a look:
Three stiffs!
- Carmem, stiffs?
- A murdered kid.
Hello, we haven't met yet.
How are you? My name is Lúcia.
Don't bother, honey,
I speak the language. "Piacere".
- Nice to meet you. Psilene.
- I overheard you.
You have been in Europe?
Miss Psilene,
I've done everything to go abroad.
I studied English,
got a passport...
bathed in leaf infusions,
but nothing!
Right, right.
Listen, love.
You don't need all that, you don't
even need to speak English.
You know what? What gringos
like is big butts...
and big boobies. You know, boobs
like this, with a lot of silicone.
Silicone?
That's fancy!
Can you tell me how...
Lúcia, your abará is ready.
How efficient.
I'm sorry.
- I'll talk to you later.
- Sure.
Bye, darling.
What an immature girl, Baiana?
Know what
she will do abroad?
Wash dishes for gringos...
be a nanny to gringo kids...
get laid with gringo men!
After they're done with her...
they'll send her ass
back to Brazil, if that much!
Otherwise, she will have
to work her ass off...
as a hooker, in order to save
some money to come back home!
So tell me,
why did you come back?
Baiana, when the acarajé is ready...
tell Zinho to take it down
to Neuzão's bar.
It's gonna take a while.
I'll wait for this acarajé,
just like one waits for Jesus!
Jesus, on my baking dish?
I'm not worthy!
This is the Carmo Convent
built on the 16th century...
when the Portuguese
arrived here in Bahia.
Portuguese arrived in Bahia.
Now they are returning,
recovering everything.
Come back, the Portuguese.
They're coming back to the wonderful
land they have once discovered.
And who wouldn't, tell me?
Who wouldn't?
- A toast to Psi!
- To Psi!
- Hi, Neuza.
- Will you excuse me?
Teacher! I wanna talk to you.
- You look cute. For Carnaval?
- You like it?
- It's nice.
- This is serious.
After Carnaval, I'm going
to pass a petition around...
for the Vivaldo
Costa Lima School.
No need to go any further.
I'll sign
it in any way you want...
...whatever you want.
- Dona Neuza, please.
- Hey, Matias.
- Hey, Teacher.
Look, Matias, I've got
a petition here for the Vivaldo...
I'm not signing
no fucking petition!
You teachers go on strikes
all year around.
My kids go to school to study.
- Oh, yeah?
- Not my fault you make no money.
You get paid to teach...
not to hang out
here in the bar.
I'm not hanging out, I'm being
yelled at by an ignorant stupid man!
- Fuck, I'm not...
- Don't you go yelling in my bar!
Get the hell out of here,
damn it!
Look how upset she is now. Rosa,
get the teacher a soda. Have a seat.
Good afternoon.
Neuza, where are my oysters?
I got only sprats, man.
Things been tangled here!
- What the fuck, Neuza?
- I told you I'm stressed, man!
- Neuzão, my friend.
- Reginaldo, my man!
- My brother!
- Where is the cab?
It's out there.
Take a look.
Neuzão!
- Hi, miss thing!
- Hi, Big Beyoncé.
Looks who's in the house!
What's up, Neuzão
Let me make a proposal
Don't know if I can
Don't know if I do
To make a gig
Right here for you
You know what, Raimundinho?
I'm still conquering costumers.
I can't.
Are you pulling my leg, Neuzão?
What are you doing there,
Beyoncé?
- Measuring the room.
- Measuring the room?
You crack me up.
Go ahead, my brother.
C'mon, everybody!
One, two, three.
I'd like to know
Where she's now
If she thinks about me or not
Oh, Lord
I wanna give her all my love
My life, my heart
I want to please her
I wonder if I'm right?
Or must I try to forget her?
Be here with me, darling
Oh, bring me, darling
Your sweet kiss, darling
They have no shame, you see?
Such an old woman
behaving like that.
Lord will punish her.
I'd like to know
Where she's now
If she thinks about me or not
Oh, Lord
I wanna give her all my love
My life, my heart
I want to please her
I wonder if I'm right?
Or must I try to forget her?
Be here with me, darling
Oh, bring me, darling
Your sweet kiss, darling
Stop it now!
This is not a whorehouse!
I've warned you already!
You'd better scram!
Neuzão, so many customers.
500/0 of the cover charge.
Neuzão, I can see it now.
"Beyoncé and The Refugees".
Refugees?
Get the fuck out, Raimundinho!
Let's go, guys.
- Come over here, Roque.
- What's up, sweetie?
This is my sister, Psilene.
She arrived from Europe today.
Sweet.
Have you been away for long?
- So long I lost count of the days.
- Too long.
One day I will also
travel around the world.
Roque is a singer.
He sings like hell, Psi.
- Is that so, Roque?
- Modesty aside...
when I hold the mic,
the crowd goes crazy.
- Did you speak to Tatau?
- Tatau, the Araketu singer?
We grew up together at Tororó.
His fame hasn't changed him at all.
We are still friends.
- I'm sure.
- So, how did it go?
I sent him the song:
Who told you Bahia
Is just about happiness
- Let's see if he likes it.
- He sure will.
If Carmem says you're good,
it's because you are.
And listen:
When you become
a star in Europe...
I insist that you stay
at my place in Switzerland.
Ah, thanks a lot.
Now, you hit it hard.
One must dream, right, Carmem?
It's only our right.
Psi is the dreamer one.
I'm alert even when I'm asleep.
Dream on, Roque, dream on.
You know why?
He who doesn't dream
won't ever board an airplane.
Virgin Mary!
Listen...
"I know I'm nobody
And I may never have everything...
Apart from that
I carry all the dreams within me"
How beautiful, Roque!
It's not mine though,
it's Fernando Pessoa's.
- Hey, girl.
- I changed it a bit.
Come over here.
- Fernando Pessoa?
- Excuse me now. And welcome!
My pleasure.
Sweet honey, would like to work
at my place, for 2 or 3 months?
Maria is going to have the baby,
and we need someone.
You can even sleep over,
if you like.
- Breakfast included and all.
- You think I'm easy, Reginaldo?
You like to play the macho, but we
know you like to fuck the faggot.
- And you like to "lick the carpet".
- Get him, godmother!
Calm down, Neuzão!
Relax! Relax!
Reginaldo!
You leave with me now!
That's right, I'm leaving.
I offered her a job...
and she thinks it's something else!
Bunch of ignorant people!
Fuck ignorance.
I'll cut you!
Fuck off!
See you at 3.
Reginaldo!
You're such a hit!
Three suitors as soon as you arrive.
- Three?
- The God-mother included.
How can the sun
fit into such a small sphere?
Beautiful. Loved that.
Did you? It's not mine.
It's Gregório de Matos'.
Only you.
For Carnaval
or for good this time?
You know I've been here before?
Every time you come,
I see you.
- Where?
- Around.
- You don't remember me?
- No, I don't.
Cool.
You don't remember me,
but I haven't forgotten you.
I came for good this time.
Juazeiro was too stifling.
Juazeiro?
Why stifling?
Everybody minds
other people's business.
Salvador is better, then.
Your secrets are safe here.
My godmother
told me you are a singer.
That's right. One day
I'll be as famous as Tatau.
Then sing something.
Only if you dance.
Aren't you a dancer?
Fair enough.
I'm leaving
Disarmed
And in the chest a heart
I don't have anything
I'm leaving a dream
Emotional adventurer
I forget everything
To freely live
A new passion
Are you with, Rosa?
Wandering around
I find a world
With an open book
What?
Waiting for the lesson
It was for love
All this time I spent
Everything that happened
Made me feel
Moments of happiness
So far away
The longing raised the pain
A blind razor that love
Left behind
In pieces of kindness
So far away
The longing raised the pain
A blind razor that love
Left behind
In pieces of kindness
I am a pioneer in life
Everybody!
My love
I make pleasure the first
And you
Seduction
I want you with my entire body
So the dream
Conquers the moonlight
I am a pioneer in life
My love
I make pleasure the first
Seduction
I want you
With my entire body, Rosa
So the dream
Conquers the moonlight
Come, come,
Come and shake it, honey
Come, come
Araketu has it all
It has the gift
Of making eternal
Everything illuminated
For us to love
Come, come,
Come and shake it, honey
Come, come
Araketu has it all
It has
The gift of making eternal
Everything illuminated
For us to love
Come, come,
Come and shake it, honey
Come, come
Araketu has it all
It has
The gift of making eternal
Everything illuminated
For us to love
Shake it, honey
Araketu
Eternal
Illuminated
Love
Shake it, honey
What block are you parading on?
Damn it.
- I'm on Araketu.
- Araketu, huh? Cool.
Yeah.
Every year, like a religion.
There's something everybody
does at the end of it all...
no matter what's your race or color:
Go to Castro Alves Square.
- Castro Alves Square?
- Castro Alves Square.
Whoever chooses not to may
be punished by the Orishas.
By the Orishas, right?
I wouldn't dare,
if I were you.
- Better not.
- Better not, man.
Bye now.
Reginaldo, I have so many orders...
that I don't even know
what to buy first.
Buy it all.
There is nothing worse to carry
on an airplane than a berimbau!
I don't know why Europeans
re so crazy about it.
I have to take 3.
Can you imagine it?
I can't imagine you leaving.
I won't miss
the berimbaus really.
- Reginaldo...
- Aren't you taking the berimbaus?
I'll buy at the airport...
so I spend the least time
possible with them.
- I see.
- Let's go, have lots to see today.
Hey, guys?
- So, making money with the gringos?
- Yes, we are.
We pose for pictures for a buck.
- You want to take a picture with us?
- Psilene...
they are Dona Joana's kids, owner of
the shared house. Cosme and Damião.
They are so cute.
How lovely!
Will you take a picture with them?
10 bucks.
Of course.
Cosme and Damião,
my patron saints.
Please, make it look good.
I'll treasure this forever.
Say cheese!
Thank you.
Here's the 10 bucks.
Listen.
Go have fun with it.
Thank you very much.
Go home!
Your mother's waiting!
The Lacerda elevator, Reginaldo.
- Beautiful, no?
- I missed it so much.
Geneva should have one of these,
to go up the Alps.
- Isn't it beautiful?
- Psilene...
you're a whole lot of woman.
No need for help to go up.
Check it out.
What a great view!
- Moisés, you scared me.
- Don't call me Moisés.
Nobody can know that's my name.
My name here is Boca.
- What is it, Boca?
- Brunette, be a doll...
and bring me a beer.
Don't bring me a flat beer.
I want it freaking cold!
Get the one at the bottom
of the freezer.
What's the matter?
Where have you been?
I had to stay away because
there was a situation, all right?
All right, but when you disappear,
I get insomnia.
I can't sleep, man.
What's that now?
Go to sleep!
You think I'm lying to you, huh?
You want me to put you to sleep?
I can sing you a lullaby.
You're mixing things up.
- Brunette, what's your name?
- Rosa.
Rosa, as in "rose".
Then go get me a pink egg.
I have to talk
to your godmother.
- What's your problem?
- I came here to tell you...
that you, baby...
that you...
are the only person who cares
for me in the whole Pelourinho.
Really, Boquinha?
Now, you're gonna
make me cry.
- This pink egg is awesome.
- Awesome.
Shit, the shell.
- It's great today.
- Better peel it first.
The chicken
lays eggs this pink?
Now, you are pushing it.
Good afternoon, my darlings.
- Good afternoon.
- Did you pray a lot?
- Too much.
- My arms are tired.
The demon didn't want
to leave the girl's body.
Really?
In fact, it's really hard...
to remove the father of the
lies out of a child's body.
- Pretty hard.
- That's right. Your mother here...
has a solution
that's better than praying.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, a good beating, well done...
to remove Satan from you brats!
Get 'em Yolanda!
Cosme! Damião!
- Get 'em, Yolanda!
- Calm down, Joana!
How can they do that?
They lied to God, to everyone!
And they even
used my name to do it!
You were used, honey?
Show me some respect.
Get out now.
Give me a bucket of water.
I'm all sticky!
Pay the bill and a waterfall
will pour down on you.
Can I pay in my usual way?
I have new spicy stories
that will blow your mind!
Really? But not today,
I'm too upset for that!
You'd better leave
before I get mad at you too.
I'll tell you all later, woman.
Dollar, please. Dollar, please.
Money, money.
Get out of here, come on!
Look at this. It's like this
every day in Pelourinho.
Look at this.
It's no use! I've told them
to stay away! They won't listen!
Where's public safety
when we need it?
I've told you already.
Say the word...
and I'll become a bouncer for you.
If the traders down the street
do this, it's their problem.
I pay tax so that
I'm entitled to public safety.
You know I can't
stay here all day long.
You promised you were going
to find a solution, so do it!
Light it up somewhere else.
I have no lighter.
- Daddy.
- Boca.
- Give me a coffee, will you?
- Will do. It's really warm.
- Sweet little TV you got there.
- That's the marketing business.
- Have you made up your mind?
- Definitely.
You'll sell my stuff tonight?
I'm out, Boca.
I've got a wife and kid.
You don't know what
a family means, but I do.
You're fucking lazy, man.
You sent the cat after the mouse
and then you eat the cheese.
What's your problem, Boca?
Come on. Sorry, but I can't.
Raimundinho!
You mother's looking for you.
- Here comes the monkey of Pelô.
- Hey, Boca!
- The sheep.
- Your true herd, Boca.
How'd like to sell some "candy"
at the parade?
- Are you mad, Boca? No way?
- You're the mad ones...
making 14 bucks to hold
that damn rope all night.
Boca, we just wanna score!
Get the girls, kiss their lips.
You don't score!
Go get your hair cut!
What hair cut?
Scram, brother.
Too many saints around here.
Get yourself some rest, Lia.
- Take good care of yourself.
- Okay, Carmem.
I'm not partying tonight.
I don't feel so good.
You said that 3 months ago,
on your last time here.
Don't worry, Carmem.
I'll pay attention.
You have to pay nothing!
You gotta wrap his dick with latex,
condom!
It costs a pittance.
- Use your head!
- Use my head? No.
You know how much I like men.
- Maybe too much.
- Just don't do it anymore.
I won't be able to help you out
again until you're legal, Lia.
Yeah, I know.
Here you go.
Thanks a lot.
Bye.
You're welcome, Lia.
- Do you think this is right?
- Mind your own business!
It should be mummy.
- Hi, Carmem.
- Did they give you a hard time?
They're used to me by now,
you know that.
Hold on.
Hold on, I'll give you your pay.
No need for that, Carminha.
Sure, right. Let's go home.
I have to change for the parade.
- Thank you, Rai.
- I fixed them all up, hair and all.
They're gonna look great tonight!
To this corner of the world
Where is it coming from?
From my profound dream
Or from the depths of the sea
With what voice will you sing
With what light will you shine
It will come
Be that as it may
To this corner of the world
Where is love coming from?
In this empty life
What's taking
My honey so long?
An immense gladness
Being saved for whom?
Be it an angel of the sky
Or a monster of the sea
Coming in flying saucer
But I know that it is mine
The moment I see it
For the biggest enchantment
In this corner of the world
When is love arriving?
My
Love
- I'm off, godmother.
- You look really nice.
I gotta go cause I got paint
my body before the warm up.
That's a pretty short skirt
you have, Rosa!
- You look gorgeous, Neuzão.
- I do, don't I?
Fab! Listen,
can I still have a drink?
I was about to close.
You'd better pay up front.
I'm only doing this because it's you.
I know, my friend,
for old times' sake.
Our consideration,
When we cannot
put out the body's fire, Psi...
...light up the soul.
- You know it all.
I'll have a double, Neuzão!
Miss thing,
it's so damn hot!
What the hell?
You can't just barge into my place.
- What you're so upset about?
- I am!
I'll leave, then.
Honey, tell me something.
Where's Regi?
Regi? His name
is José Reginaldo.
You'd better come off it,
because he's my burden!
He took me from my house!
So get the hell outta here!
You keep on yelling, sweetie.
That's why Regi seeks me.
- What?
- You know why?
He likes a woman
who knows how to make to love.
- Not like you, chatterbox!
- Get outta here!
You scum! You pest! Out!
Out! Out!
Boca is coming.
Get the trolleys, boys.
No one touches anything.
The money first.
Okay, cool.
Let's talk, brother.
My car was nearly towed when
I parked up there...
you know.
The cops came,
stopped me, and I said...
"Come on, you!"
So I had to grease...
the cop's hands.
Know what I mean, old chap?
I've only got
half of the money.
I pay the rest in 5 days.
I hope you understand.
In 2 days max...
I'll give you the rest.
No way, Boca.
A deal is a deal.
You take the trolleys if you pay me.
That was all very clear.
Can't you see it's not
my fault, brother?
Not mine, either.
Pay what you owe me
or you get nothing!
What am I gonna say to these
kids' mom? Step inside, boys.
What am I to say
to their mothers?
The boys need to work.
- You got no heart, man?
- Good one.
- Does the devil have a heart?
- Brother, I'm begging you!
Tell me why I should help you!
You come here, you mock me,
now you want me to help you?
Why would I do that?
What if one of these boys
you treat like slaves...
didn't pay you?
What would you do?
You say that
because you're black...
'cause you never had a break!
Now, you wanna
make money this way?
I've had enough of your scorn.
To endure is my race's faith.
I want all the money now.
Try and get the trolleys out.
You're an asshole.
- I follow your example.
- What example? You're a nigger!
A nigger, a nigger,
a nigger, all right?
You're a nigger, a nigger, a nigger,
a nigger, a nigger...
- A nigger!
- Yes, I'm black...
but doesn't
a black man have eyes, Boca?
Doesn't he have hands,
a dick, five senses, Boca?
Doesn't he eat the same food?
Doesn't he have the same diseases?
Doesn't he need the same cures?
When we sweat, isn't our body wet
just like the body of a white man?
When you prick us,
do we not bleed?
When you tickle us,
do we not laugh?
When you shoot at us,
do we not die?
If we are the same all over,
we are the same here too, damn it!
Fuck you!
Fuck your poetry.
Raimundinho, please,
if your guys work for me...
I'll double any offer!
Get the trolleys.
You work for me now, all right?
Go ahead, get a move.
Here's your fucking money, man.
- Son of a bitch!
- Get...
the damn trolley, boys!
- Just take them!
- Take your trolleys.
Come on, get a move on!
Move your asses!
Move, move, go!
- Let him take it.
- Get a move on. Out.
Get out!
Scram!
You cheap bastard.
Bastard.
Unbelievable!
Thank you, guys.
Thank you.
- Whatever you need...
- Cool.
For God's sake! Thanks, you guys!
Thank you, brother!
Thank you, guys!
- Lf you need us...
- Cool.
- Good afternoon, Maria.
- Don't talk to me.
- How come?
- You left saying...
...you were going to get your cab.
- I did.
I saw you dancing with a guy.
What's that, Maria?
You misunderstood.
- Wasn't everybody dancing?
- That's right...
everybody was dancing, Reginaldo.
Everybody was dancing...
but he came here
and called you Regi.
You're a father.
You should show some respect!
You're going to believe
what people say now?
People, Reginaldo?
He come here in my house...
and told it to my face, in my house
that you slept with him.
- What?
- Yeah.
He will get it!
I'll show him right now!
Reginaldo, you're gonna
leave your house...
to settle a matter
with a faggot?
You stay there...
or you gonna have it too!
You're gonna get it!
- Dear Lord!
- I'm a man!
What are you thinking?
- You there?
- Come on in, it's open.
- You fuck!
- Come here!
Why on earth did you
go to my house...
go my wife
and wag your damn tongue?
- Me?
- No, my mother!
I'm warning you:
It was the first and last time
you go around...
telling things to my wife!
What is this, Reginaldo?
You think you scare me?
Well, you don't.
Bug off,
don't come here bother me...
or I'll slash your mug!
I'll cut your nuts off first!
My ass.
I'll tell you why you are angry.
Why are you so angry?
Because when
you come home drunk...
...where do you sleep? Tell me.
- Easy.
- Where do you fuck?
- Hold it, hold it!
You'd better stop fighting!
- It's him, Dona Joana!
- This is a family.
I want no trouble
in my building!
Trouble is what you're gonna get
if you don't release the water.
Turn it on now!
Let's open it ourselves!
What's this?
You look like the police.
Are you gonna murder me now?
You know what?
Today is Carnaval...
and you cut off the water!
Know why?
The water bill is right here...
and so far, nobody...
Actually... actually...
Roque, there's some water
here for you.
What do you mean?
He is the only one with money?
He's the only one who pays?
Open it now!
Don't you see what's going on?
- She only cares for men.
- That's right!
Now, I understand.
You stand there,
pretending you're a saint...
...but your mind is perverted.
- Never!
Wait, hold on, hold on. This is
not the way to solve a problem.
- And how is that?
- We must use some diplomacy.
- Reginaldo...
- Diplomacy.
Let's talk.
Excuse us.
Reginaldo, step aside.
You guys love to make a fuss.
Dona Joana, please.
I know we care for each other.
- A lot!
- So please...
turn the water on...
so this creature
can have a shower. He stinks.
Thanks to Roque and Reginaldo...
...I'm turning it back on.
- Yeah!
I'll spit on the floor and when
it dries out, I'll shut it down.
- Yeah!
- I'm going to shoot
The one who's using my drawers
As a dish cloth
Let Jesus do His work.
The Blood of Christ is powerful.
Do you any need help, sister?
- These cobblestones.
- Right, the stones.
Carrying suitcases,
one may fald.
Aren't you Carmen's sister,
the one living abroad?
Are you the famous Dona Joana?
I know nothing about this fame,
my child.
It crossed the Atlantic Ocean!
The Atlantic Ocean?
That explains...
that flood face of yours.
- What I am is dizzy with exhaustion!
- I see.
That's why I'm staying here tonight.
My sister's house
is packed with kids.
Your sister acts like a fool.
She adopts kids
in a snap of the fingers.
My sister,
Dona Joana has a huge heart.
The house is tiny, though.
Would you kindly have a place
I could keep my bags at?
Only for tonight.
Girl, where the hell
have you been?
I was talking to Neuzão, and she...
You know how it is.
I was waiting for you,
and you were with Neuzão?
I was at the bar.
I lost track of time and I'm...
...jet-lagged.
- Here. Here is your costume.
- Let's go?
- I'm not coming, Carminha.
I'm exhausted.
I left the bags at the hotel...
but I'm staying here tonight.
Go to a hotel if you never
want to see my face again.
My house is your house.
Thank you.
Cheer up, all right?
- Cheer up.
- Enjoy yourself, love of my life!
I will.
Bye.
- Reginaldo.
- Dona Joana, what's up?
Try to find my kids
while driving the truck.
- I'm really worried.
- Don't worry...
if I spot them,
I'll send them straight home.
Please do.
May Jesus bless you.
Thank you.
Amen, Dona Joana.
I have to hurry.
Go, go.
Only Jesus.
Only Jesus can work in your life.
Honey, can you spare me your shirt
so I can get inside?
Please, come on!
Lord! Lord Black!
Put me in there, will you?
Come on, Lord.
You're all puffed up because
you have a special place?
I see you have no authority here.
- I'll have to throw you out.
- That's right.
- You're nothing but a doormat.
- Don't force me to throw you out.
- You know better than touching me!
- Please leave.
What's your problem?
Are you feeling better?
Refreshed, Dona Joana.
Refreshed.
Tell me,
is this building yours?
Mine and my husband Mario's.
We got here first.
This was all abandoned,
crumbling to pieces.
Mario decided...
to ask everyone who lives here
now to help him out.
How nice,
everyone taking part.
No way, my child,
he did it all by himself.
I remember it very well.
When it was over,
all the lazy trumps moved in.
And where is your husband?
Has he passed away?
Please, don't say that.
God forbid.
- Amen.
- Mario is alive and kicking...
and I miss him a great deal,
let me tell you.
- You do miss him.
- Yes, but he's coming back.
He's solving a family problem
in the country...
...but he'll be back soon.
- He will.
Now you tell me...
what's your foreign husband like?
Dona Joana, he's much better
than I could ever imagine.
- It's just like in the movies.
- Tell me all about it.
When I first got there, Dona Joana,
and I saw that mansion...
I had to pinch myself.
The garden, the living room,
the dining room,
the library, the home theater,
the fireplace.
My bedroom alone
looked like a palace.
Now, tell me, my child,
what's it like with a foreign man?
How's the thing?
- You wanna know about the...
- Yeah.
Ah, Dona Joana...
it's just like the others.
A little more gentle, romantic.
When he wants it, there's
no holding him back, you know?
He comes near and whispers
in your ear, in a moan.
"Je t'aime, mon amour".
Je t'aime.
Viens, mon amour, viens. "
Jeez, girl, you sent shivers
down my spine!
- Now, I feel like I want to...
- Like you want what?
I feel like meeting Carminha and
the twins at the Olodum. Let's go?
No, my child, I'm not going.
I'm a religious lady.
I don't like the Afro blocks.
I'll stay here,
waiting for my kids.
But when they get home,
they'll get it. They'll get it hard.
- Soften this heart of yours,
- Not this time, my child.
I'm off then.
Life is short
and time won't wait for me.
Thank you very much.
Delicious coffee.
I wonder.
The woman travels abroad
and comes back such a wreck.
"Je t'aime.
Viens, mon amour. "
Give it, give it.
- Come on, hurry up. Let's go.
- Take it, take it.
- Hurry, hurry.
- Stop.
Hurry, boys!
Take it, take it.
Hurry! Hurry!
It's the cops!
Look who's here:
My old friend!
We grew up together at Tororó!
He's a talented brother.
Roque, come up here, brother.
Come on, brother!
You, Roque, come on up!
Brother Roque!
Dude, come sing with me! Come on!
It's been so long, man!
This is a good friend from Tororó.
Hello, Salvador!
We're gonna shake this place!
Move your feet, come on!
Show me!
I cannot hide
What I feel for you, Ara
I can't
I can't, I can't, I can't
I cannot hide
What I feel for you, Ara
I can't
I can't, I can't, I can't
All I know
Is that my body shakes
My legs don't answer to me
We have to dance
It's subconscious
Smart one!
Since he was a little boy!
All I know
Is that Araketu is too good
Show me how you do
your samba now, come on.
That's right!
He knows it all!
I cannot hide
What I feel for you, Ara
I can't
I cannot hide
What I feel for you, Ara
I can't
I can't, I can't, I can't
All I know
Is that my body shakes
Go, people!
It's subconscious
My old time friend,
from my neighborhood!
- All I know
- Hands in the air!
Hands in the air!
Wonderful, Roquinho!
Thank you very much,
thank you.
I cannot hide
- Feel fresh now?
- Absolutely. I'm going to bed.
Could you do me a favor, please?
At this hour?
You know my kids
haven't come home yet.
Of course I know it.
I saw you wandering
around the door.
That's right.
Do me favor, then, for God's sake.
- Check your shells, will you?
- What, Joana?
Please, please.
What did I tell you?
What was our deal?
Not the local ones.
We take care of those!
We'd talk to their mothers, uncles.
We'd do something!
If the community
finds that out, I'm fucked.
Jerônimo, I've done this
for more than ten years.
I do it well.
Is this what you call well done?
My shells!
My shells are sizzling.
My hands! My hands!
My hands are burning.
What's that on your dress?
Your dress is red. Red. And you!
Leave! Get out!
I don't want you here!
I don't want it!
This is not for me!
I don't want it no more!
No! No,
- Dona Joana.
- Jerônimo!
Jerônimo,
read this here for me, please!
I'm very nervous.
Just read it, Jerônimo.
Read it.
Just read it.
Just read it, Jerônimo.
"Ten black boys in a cell...
One of whom ceased to move
They flew in the morning.
But then they were nine
Nine little black boys fled
The boldest one of all
- He had no luck... "
- Dona Joana! Dona Joana!
Your kids, Dona Joana...
Look at this.
Strength and morals
Liberate the people of Pelourinho
The mother who is a mother
Feels pain in childbirth
And here I go
Here I go
I declare to the nation
Pelourinho against prostitution
With a protest
And a demonstration
- And here I go
- Here I go
It has expanded
And now terror dominates Brazil
Olodum
Denounces Pelourinho
And here I go
Brazil leadership
The leading force in pollution
In pointing out
The Cubatão terror
And here I go
Here I go
Here in the northeast
It is Ethiopia in Bahia
The country turns its back
On the northeast
And here I go
But we are able
Our God
Brings truth
Monument of strength and peace
Where I go?
And here I go
Here I go
Desmond Tutu
Against Apartheid
In South Africa
Comes and honors
Nelson Mandela
Olodum
And here I go
THIS FILM IS DEDICATED TO
BANDO DE TEATRO OLODUM
CAPTIONS BY VIDEOLAR