Mosfilm studio
and the Creative Association
of TV fiilms presents
a film made to the order
of Gosteleradio
A USUAL WONDER
Part One
Based on a play by Yevgenyi
SCHWARZ of the same name
It's her. It's her footsteps.
I've been in love with my wife
for 15 years. Like a schoolboy.
Hello, my wife.
- Are you sore with someone?
- You.
The boor. My God, what have
I done this time?
What's all that mess in the
hen-house?
I did that out of love.
And who promised to live like
everyone else?
Live like everyone else!
- Are you sore with someone?
- You.
The boor! What have I done
this time?
What's all that mess in the
hen-house?
I did that out of love.
And who promised to live like
everyone else?
Live like everyone else...
But after all I am a magician.
I'm entitled to an
occasional prank.
You could have done something
useful for the household.
They brought sand to
sprinkle the walks.
Why don't you turn it into
Sugar.
What kind of a prank is that?
Or else turn the stones, piled
up at the barn, into cheese.
Cheese? That's not funny.
What am I to do with you?
No matter how hard I try, you're
still the same crazy man.
- Who are you waiting for?
- No one.
- Look me in the eyes.
- I'm looking.
Tell me the truth. What
guests are we expecting today?
Will those be people or ghosts,
that will come to play with you?
It's all right, it's
all right...
Soon, soon!
Who are you waiting for? You
think you can fool your wife?
Tell me! Now!
We are having very unusual
guests today.
This time I'm up to something
more than pranks or jokes.
Please don't be sore.
I knew who I was marrying.
It's him. It's him!
I've been expecting you.
Come in.
Hello, son.
Seat yourself at the table,
have some coffee.
What is your name?
Bear.
Bear...
That nickname does not
become you.
It is not a nickname.
7 years ago your husband put a
spell on me and made me human.
He did a wonderful job.
He has hands of gold.
Thank you, son.
Is that true?
Why didn't you tell me?
I forgot.
I was walking in the forest...
And I saw this young bear cub,
funny looking chap.
Broad forehead, clever eyes.
- I liked him.
- Stop it!
I hate it when people abuse
animals out of fun.
They make elephants dance,
lock nightingales into cages,
and teach tigers swing on
a swing.
Life is tough, son?
Yes.
It's not easy to be a real man.
You're laughing?
I'm happy.
Admiring my work.
A man makes a statue out of a
dead stone, and
it makes him proud if it comes
out beautiful.
But try turning a living
creature into an even more
living one.
That's a challenge for you!
That's what I've been waiting
for for many years.
For many years.
Turn him back into a bear this
very minute,
if you love me.
Set him free.
Don't worry!
That's what he's here for -
to be turned into a bear again.
I'm glad. Will you do it right
here?
No, that's no fun.
Everything will be wonderful!
It will be different.
It will be absolutely different.
- It will be different.
- Will it happen now?
No, it's not that simple.
I will turn back into a bear,
when a Princess...
falls in love with me and
kisses me.
- Did you think of that?
- I think it's good, don't you?
- But that's awful!
- I didn't please you again!
- Did you think about her?
- It's healthy to fall in love.
She will fall in love, and he
will turn into an animal.
- That's nothing unusual. - He
will run away into the forest.
That happens too, they run away.
You will leave a girl who is in
love with you, son?
Soon as she sees that I'm a
bear, she will fall out of love.
Not that I want to frighten you,
but it is a dangerous game.
I though I could take anything,
but this time I'm afraid.
But what can happen?
You're afraid she won't fall in
love? Of course she will!
Look, how charming he is.
What if...
It's too late anyway!
I've arranged it so that one
of the kings...
would want to make a detour
and visit our house.
He's on his way here now.
Go hide yourself, son. We will
meet them ourselves.
I'll call you when the time
comeS.
- I don't believe it! A king!
- Wait till you see him!
He's a boor and a churl!
He'll make a nuisance of himself
and order us about.
Good day.
My friends, I am a King.
Good day, Your Majesty.
For some reason I found your
house extremely attractive.
So allow me to visit with you
for a couple of days.
I must warn you, we're a
troublesome bunch.
I am an impossible person.
A tyrant, a despot. Insidious
and unforgiving.
Someone - come here!
You, for instance!
Say hello to them.
See, what I'm doing?
And the interesting thing is,
it's not my fault.
That's the truth.
Now beat it!
I'm not to blame!
It's the ancestry.
Great grandfathers, grand-uncles
and all sorts of aunts,
all my ancestors always behaved
like complete pigs.
And now I have to pay for their
past.
What can I say? Parasites!
Pardon my language.
Parasites! That's the word.
By my nature I am kind and
gentle.
I'm into poetry, prose, music,
art, fiishing.
I like cats.
But occasionally I can pull
something weird.
- Like this, for instance.
- Joker!
You're a funny man yourself.
Mistress, give us three
goblets.
It is the King's vintage wine
that's 300 years old.
Let's drink to our acquaintance!
Here's to us!
Bottoms up!
- Don't drink.
- Why?
- You don't respect your guest?
- Quiet, you're not at home.
Don't order me about!
I blink my eye, and the
ministers will act,
and express their condolences,
and that'll be it!
Don't! The wine is poisoned.
- Well listen to the scoundrel!
- Then you drink first.
All right, the wine is poisoned.
Why through it away? Pour it
back into the bottle.
This is high quality poison.
Hard to get.
Can always come in handy.
- Shame on you, Your Majesty!
- I'm not to blame!
- Who is?
- My uncle.
He would often talk too much,
slander himself, and with
his delicate and vulnerable
soul, you know, to spare himself
the agony of remorse, he would
afterwards poison his vis-a-vis.
- Bastard.
- Animal!
- You ought to be ashamed.
- Oh, don't start.
Now you're gonna say, I must be
responsible for my own actions.
And not put the blame on
friends, neighbors or relatives.
I'm only human! It's more
than I can do!
I am a King. Just your
ordinary King.
There are thousands like me.
We understand one another.
Why pretend?!
And don't frown!
We're alive and kicking!
We're staying here!
Courtiers! Make yourselves
comfortable! Put the music on!
If I may ask, King, is the
Princess also...
Of course not! She's not like
that. She's kind and sweet.
Living with me is hard on her.
Her mother died when she was
only 7 minutes old.
- So don't you be rude to her.
- Your Majesty!
I stop being a King when I
think of her or see her.
Dear friends!
I'm so happy that I love...
my child so much!
How funny and crazy,
Absurd and untimely...
And how wonderful!
Without any reason or
Meaning
At all!
There comes a day,
There strikes an hour,
There comes a moment,
There comes the right time,
And the connection breaks.
Granite boils,
Ice catches fire,
Light down
Knocks you off your feet.
What madness?!
Weeds blossom,
The old owl sings like a
nightingale,
And even the thinnest of
threads
Can not be cut in half
By a steel blade,
By a steel blade!
How funny and crazy,
Absurd and untimely
And how wonderful!
Without any reason or
Meaning
At all!
There comes a time,
And it brings
Shivers and fear,
And a secret fever,
Power and delight,
Pain and laughter,
Light and shadow,
All thrown into one fiire,
Into one burning flame.
What madness?!
And out of this mirage,
Out of nothing,
Out of my own wild fantasies
Appears someone's face,
And it acquires shape and
Color,
Flesh and passion,
Flesh and passion!
How funny and crazy,
Absurd and untimely,
And how wonderful!
Without any reason or
Meaning
At all!
She is extraordinary!
Not at all like a King's
daughter.
She's extraordinary!
Not at all like a King's
daughter.
I used to come to the nursery
and, believe it or not,
I felt better about myself.
Or I would sit there signing a
death sentence,
and laugh at her little
pranks.
I know, I'm a self-centered
bastard!
I got so used to warming my
heart being next to her,
that I started to protect her
from anything
that could stain her pure soul.
Surely you know what a royal
court is like.
Every day they strangle their
own brothers and sisters.
That's right, strangle them.
In other words, there's this
usual everyday life going on.
But once you enter the wing
of the princess,
there's pleasant conversation,
poetry, music.
It heals your soul.
And that tranquil world
collapsed because of a trifle.
I remember it clearly.
It was Saturday, I was doing
my homework,
looking through cavils of
my ministers,
When there was a knock at the
door. My daughter was by my side
embroidering a scarf for my
Birthday.
It was all so calm and peaceful,
birds were singing.
Then the Master of Ceremonies
breaks the bad news.
Says, her aunt, the Dutchess,
was coming to visit.
I always hated her shrill
voice.
So I tell him to tell her,
we're not in.
That's not anything unusual
for us,
because we're ordinary
people.
But my poor little girl
fainted.
''Her daddy told a lie!''
That's how it all started.
She became thoughtful and looked
bored. I didn't know what to do.
Then the genes of my great
granddad awakened in me.
Whatever trouble happened, he
didn't do anything at all,
but waited for it to pass.
When they were strangling his
beloved wife before his eyes,
he stood there and begged:
''Hold on, it'll pass''.
- Nice man!
- Oh sure!
But then I woke up one night
and I said: Harness the horses!
And at sunrise we were already
rushing in the direction of
the Carpathian Mountains.
We don't know anyone here,
so you will have to bear
with us,
until we build a castle with
all the conveniences,
a garden, a prison cell,
and a playground.
- I'm afraid...
- Don't be.
Your Majesty, I will show
you your roomS.
Careful, watch your step.
This way, your Majesty.
Just imagine him turning into a
wild beast before her very eyes.
- It's good to fall in love!
- I won't allow this.
That would be painful even
for a mature woman.
- Tell me it's a joke.
- It's too late!
No! I will ask the
Bear to wait,
until we find another princess.
I need to talk to you in
private. In the garden.
Quick!
I'm sorry if I hurt you,
charming young lady.
What is it? Did I scare you
so much?
No. I'm just a little shaken.
I have never been called
''charming young lady'' before.
I didn't want to offend you.
I'm not offended.
It's just that I can't
tell a lie.
If I see a charming young lady,
I tell her so.
- Are you the owner's son?
- No, I am an orphan.
Me too.
I mean, my father is alive,
but my mother died
when I was only 7 minutes
old.
I'm sure you have many
friends.
Why would you say that?
I think, everyone should love
someone like you.
You are extraordinary,
you are gentle.
Have I offended you now?
No.
Then I will tell you,
that you are beautiful.
And that I came to
like you.
Very much. The moment
I saw you.
Do you fiind me funny?
No.
I think, everyone should love
someone like you.
You are so extraordinary,
so gentle.
- Have I offended you now?
- No.
Then I will tell you,
that you are beautiful.
And that I came to like you.
At first sight.
Do you fiind me funny?
No.
You must be tired and hungry.
There's milk fresh from a cow.
Have some.
- Is it some holiday today?
- I don't know, maybe.
- Are you one of the King's
suite? - No.
Then one of the Princess's
suite?
What if I am the Princess?
What is it? You grew so pale!
No, you can't be the
Princess.
No!
I roamed the world.
I saw many princesses.
You don't look like any
one of them.
Please...
Don't tease me.
Touch on any subject but
this one.
My god! I forgot all about
them.
The suite has arrived.
Yesterday's homely faces.
Let's hide from them.
Run! Fast!
My god!
Why is it that I cry and laugh
like a child!
How dare you? I begged
you not to.
Hello there, beautiful!
Sorry for the intrusion.
I hope I'm not interfering with
anything? You want me to leave?
No, of course not!
Please do sit down.
- May I put down my bundle?
- Well of course!
You are so kind.
What a charming cozy home!
There's a handle for the spit,
and a hook for the cattle.
You must be the King's
cook!
No. I am the King's First
Minister.
- Who?
- The King's First Minister.
There was a time when everyone
recognized me.
I was so brilliant,
so grand!
Experts say, it was diffiicult
to tell,
who had more stature:
me or the King's cats.
Now I dance stupid dances
for everyone's amusement.
I'm no longer good
for anything else.
Am I any good?
- I don't think so.
- I don't think so either.
I'd say, quite mediocre.
What brought you to
such a poor state?
It's the traveling,
my lady.
For certain reasons we,
a group of courtiers,
were torn away from our
habitual atmosphere
and sent away to a foreign
land.
And to add insult to injury
there's this tyrant.
- The King?
- No, of course not!
We've gotten used to his
whims.
The tyrant is the Minister
Administrator.
He alone knows how to
travel,
get us horses, feed everyone.
He does a rotten job, but thinks
everyone else is no good.
Only don't tell him I was
complaining.
Or he will leave me without
dessert.
Why don't you tell the king?
As they say in the business
circles, he services and serves
the King so well, he doesn't
want to hear anything about it.
What a shame! What a disgrace!
What a bedlam!
What is this anyway?
He'll starve everyone
to death.
I wish he were dead!
But that's wishful thinking!
What can you expect of the
parasite!
What do I need my head for,
If I hadn't washed it
For three days!
Where's the soap? Where's
The bast? Where?
Where's the cream? Even
A shaving cream would do.
One who economizes on
Being clean
Is either a thief, or
A swine!
He is either a thief,
Or a pig!
Where is the soap? Where is
The bast? Where?
Where is the cream? Where?
One who economizes on
Being clean
Is either a thief, or a pig!
Damn him, when will
this torture end?
We will all become mangy
before long,
before this venomous creature
will deign to give us soap.
Allow me to introduce
the First Court Dame!
Maids of honor,
Orynthia and Amanda!
It's outrageous!
Today His Excellency,
damn him,
refused to give us soap,
powder and perfume!
I am sure he sold all
that to the natives!
When we left, he only had
a hat box
with a sandwich and old torn
drawers,
and now he has 33 small coffers
and 22 suitcases!
- Would you like to take a bath?
- But we don't have soap!
- We have soap and hot water.
- Hot water?!
She's a saint!
A bath! Memories of our
old settled life!
- What utter joy!
- Tss! He's coming!
He's almost here!
Please, not a word!
I didn't tell you anything!
Hello.
- I said, hello.
- I already saw you today.
- Where is our luggage?
- Look at these people!
They only think about
themselves!
If you bother me again, I'll
leave you without your lunch.
That goes for everyone
else too.
4 pounds to the courtiers.
Minus 2...
3 pounds to the King.
Minus one and a half.
1 pound to the Princess.
Minus half a pound.
All in all 6 pounds today so
far. Not bad.
- At midnight.
- What?
Come by the barn, you
won't regret it.
I don't have time for
courtship.
You're an attractive woman.
I am an extremely
attractive man.
Why waste time?
I'll be there at midnight.
- How dare you?!
- Always, darling.
You're crazy?
On the contrary, I'm as
sane as a man can be.
- You are a bastard.
- Yes. Who isn't?
Today, for instance,
I see a butterfly flying.
Small head, no brains.
Flips her winds - tit, tit, tit.
Can't be any more stupid.
The sparrow was no better.
The birch tree - a dim-wit.
The oak tree - a moron.
The river - an imbecile.
The clouds - idiots.
All horses - traitors.
All people - swindlers.
What to do? The world is such,
we shouldn't think twice.
It is good if there is
a woman around.
A lady, a dame, signora,
Le femme.
And the most important thing
For a woman is her good honor,
When there's a Man around.
And everywhere, especially
Here,
Where nature is tranquil
And innocent,
And the butterfly goes:
Tit-tit-tit,
And the sparrow chases her:
Tat-tat-tat,
And he catches the baby:
Dang-dang-dang,
Yummy-yummy-yummy,
And goes: split-split-split.
The butterfly flips her wings:
Tit-tit-tit,
The sparrow chases her;
Tat-tat-tat,
He catches the baby:
Dang-dang-dang,
Yummy-yummy-yummy!
And goes: split-split-split!
You are my angel,
You are my ideal,
My shining star,
My luscious berry,
Your teeth are pearls,
Your lips - corals.
Your breasts and your smile
Are not bad either.
I've never met anyone like you,
And I want to correct that
mistake.
The butterfly flips her wings:
Tit-tit-tit,
And the sparrow chases her:
Tat-tat-tat,
He catches the baby:
Dang-dang-dang,
Yummy-yummy-yummy, and he
Goes: split-split-split.
The butterfly flips her wings:
Tit-tit-tit,
And the sparrow chases her:
tat-tat-tat,
He catches the baby:
Dang-dang-dang,
Yummy-yummy-yummy, and then
he goes: Split-split-split.
So you will come then?
That is out of the question.
Wait till husband
turns you into a rat.
- What is your husband?
- A magician.
You should have told me.
I was wrong. Blew my top.
Let's consider this
a misunderstanding.
I ask your permission to let
me redress my wrong.
Music!
I say, I really like it here!
This house is so full of good
attitude and love!
I could take it for myself.
Honest to god!
It's a good thing I came
here.
At home I would most probably
lock you away in the Tower.
That's the one in the Market
Square. Awesome place.
You remember? Hot in the
daytime, cold at night.
The inmates suffer so much,
the even the warden cries.
Cries out of pity, you
understand?
I could jail him for that.
- Sure! And take his house!
- Monster.
I am a King - from head to toe!
He thinks there are
better kings than I am.
We're all monsters!
Alike like twin brothers.
My lady, please.
Where is my daughter,
anyway?
The Princess asked us to
leave her alone.
Her Highness wanted to pick
flowers...
in solitude.
How could she leave my
child all by herself?.
There can be snakes in the
grass, she may catch cold.
- How come?
- Because the river is cold.
There she is.
Safe and sound.
There she is!
My daughter!
My only child! She's
smiling!
- Now she's contemplating!
- She smiled again!
What a charming smile!
Who is that young man
with her?
I can see she likes him!
Then I like him too.
- Are his parents still living?
- They passed away.
That's wonderful!
- Any brothers and sisters?
- None.
I shall grant him a title
and make him rich,
and let him travel with us.
He can't be all too bad,
since my girl likes him
so much.
- Is he a good boy?
- Very! But...
No ''buts''!
I haven't seen my girl
so happy for years.
There can be no ''buts''!
Today I'm having a ball.
I shall be joyful and
good-natured,
and allow myselfjust a
few harmless pranks.
Get the chinaware ready.
I shall break plates today.
Take the bread out of
the barn.
I will set the barn on fire.
Hello, everyone.
I saw all of you today, but it
seems it was ages ago.
Ladies and gentlemen!
This young man is my
best friend.
I always envied girls,
who had brothers, but now I
think it was silly of me,
because I like him more
than a brother.
They fight with brothers,
but I couldn't fight with
him.
He loves the things
that I love.
He understands me and I
understand him, like myself.
You see, he's sore with me?
You know why?
Because I didn't tell him
I was a Princess.
And he hates princesses.
Yes, that's true!
You know, I would want him
to see, how different I am
from all the other princesses.
I hate them too, darling.
Don't be so terrified.
You're scaring me!
Would you like me to kiss you?
No.
Not ever!
I have to go.
You will never see me again.
Get him! Stop him!
You know him well.
Was it something I said?
No, sweetheart.
You didn't do anything wrong.
He didn't like it when I said
about the brothers.
I must have been too
straightforward!
And then...
How could I have forgotten
myself! The most shameful part!
I offered to kiss him.
- And he... - He saddled his
horse and went away!
On that crazy horse of his!
Off into the mountains!
With no road lying ahead.
Daughter... Where are you
going? Come back!
Come back!
Executioner! Get ready!
Courtiers! Say your
prayers!
The Princess locked herself in
her room. You will be executed.
Your Majesty, I think...
The sand-glass! Fast!
I shall spare the life
of anyone,
who, while the sand runs
in the sand-glass,
will teach me, what to do
with the Princess.
Think!
Think! The sand runs fast.
Take your turns, and speak
plainly and clearly.
The First Minister!
Your Majesty! In my opinion,
parents should not
interfere in the love
lives of their children.
You will die first.
Speak, my lady.
Many years ago, Your Majesty,
I stood at the window, and
a young man on a black horse
was rushing away along a
mountainous path.
It was a quiet moonlit night.
- And a clatter of hoofs...
- Get to the point, you fool.
- The sand is running.
- Don't interrupt her.
- But there are many of us.
- And only one sand-glass.
What will be left for us?
Go on.
I never saw him again.
And I married someone else.
And here I am, alive and
at Your Majesty's service.
You too will have your
head chopped off.
Your turn.
The best way to console
the Princess -
is to let her marry someone,
who is loyal to the King,
has some experience in life
and an administrator's skills,
and who is one of the
King's suite.
Are you talking about
the executioner?
God no! I don't know him
that well.
You will.
My child! What is it?
You are frightening me?
Where are you going?
I won't tell anyone.
Good girl!
Child, we are going
with you!
Father!
I love you so much.
Don't be sore with me,
but I'm leaving alone.
Stop her! Fast!
I swear!
I will kill anyone who
follows me.
Remember this.
I have my own life now,
and I want to be left alone.
Stop her!
Stop her at any cost!
What a girl!
In the mountains she'll catch
cold and lose her way!
she will fall off the horse,
tangle her foot in the stirrup!
Don't just stand there!
Go after her!
She will shoot anyone,
who follows her!
I will follow her, hiding
behind big stones.
What are you talking
about?
I shall crawl in the grass
like a snake.
But I shall not abandon
her!
- Follow me!
- Wait!
Are you happy now?
Lousy weather!
All my life I lived here,
on the mountain peak,
amidst eternal frost,
but I don't remember such
a hurricane.
It's a good thing this
tavern was built strong.
Strong like a castle.
Tavern called ''Emily''.
Emily...
She must be grey-haired
by now.
And probably happily
married.
But I still dream...
of hearing her voice
one day.
Welcome, ladies and
gentlemen!
Please come in and make
yourselves comfortable!
Sit by the fiire!
Don't cry, my lady.
I will help you.
There, hot wine is good
for you.
May I know who you are?
Even though...
I'm used to travelers
not telling their names.
Nonsense! I'm a King.
Good evening, Your Majesty.
Good evening, innkeeper.
I am very unhappy.
That happens.
My daughter is gone.
Idiots. Spongers.
They left her unattended.
She fell in love,
they had a fight.
She put on men's clothes
and disappeared.
Spongers! Idlers!
Who lives in this tavern?
A famous hunter and his
apprentices.
Hunters? Maybe they saw
her?
They're hunting everywhere
around this place.
This hunter does not
hunt any more.
- What does he do then?
- Certifies his skills.
He already got himself
50 diplomas, that prove
that he is famous.
- What does he do in life?
- Nothing.
To prove you're famous! That
can be a very tiresome business.
The hell with him!
You, awaiting death penalty!
We're off!
- Oh, my god!
- Take to the road!
To go up into the mountains in
such weather! That's a killer.
We have no choice.
There's the key to your room.
- What will I do there?
- Do nothing.
And at sunrise we will set
off in search of her.
You will all get your keys.
Everyone should get their sleep
and prepare for tomorrow!
Follow me!
Don't be afraid, there's
no one here.
If those are the hunters,
I will kill you.
Hunters everywhere!
I hate them!
Their wives start
discussing hunting!
Apprentice! Did you
deliver the letters?
- I did. - To the Chief of the
Hunting Ground?
Yes, sir. And when I was coming
back I saw a fox's trails.
The hell with it!
That's a waste of time,
and meanwhile envious people are
masterminding a plot against me.
- Maybe they're not?
- Sure they are.
Everyone's against me.
Let them! Why don't we
shoot us some game!
Let them do whatever they want,
we'll be the winners.
We'll be the good guys,
and they'll be the bad guys.
You fool!
They'll scrutinize my every
shot.
They'll say I shot the fox same
way as last year.
And that I didn't introduce any
innovations into hunting.
And what if I miss?
Me, who never missed
in his whole life.
You better not say anything,
or I'll kill you.
- Where's our new apprentice?
- He's cleaning his gun.
That a boy!
You always praise every
new apprentice.
It's the hunter!
Open up, you fool!
- Is this a hotel? - The owner
will be with you in a minute.
- Are you a hunter?
- God forbid!
I don't like hunters.
Me too.
I hate them! Even though I'm
one myself. A famous hunter.
Too bad.
Not to mention small game,
in my lifetime,
I shot 500 deer,
500 wild goats, 400 wolves,
and 99 bears.
Killing bears is no better
than killing children.
Did you see their claws?
They're shorter than a
hunter's dagger.
- They're so aggressive!
- Not if you don't tease them.
I'm so enraged, I'm speechless.
We will have to shoot.
My new apprentice!
Get my rifle!
- I will kill you now.
- I don't care.
Let's get on with it then!
There, my new apprentice,
watch and learn.
Now this boor and ignoramus
will be killed,
for he knows nothing
about art.
Very well! But why don't you
eat these sausages fiirst.
I shall not eat when this
boor is staring at me.
Take these sausages to my
room,
and I will kill him after
dinner.
I beg your pardon, do you
have a sister?
You remind me of I woman,
I have to forget.
Where are you going?
I don't want to remind you of
something you need to forget.
And this voice!
The voice is just like hers!
You must be hallucinating!
Perhaps. My vision is hazy.
I spent three days in
the saddle.
When I was passing by this
tavern, my horse started crying.
What did you flee from,
like a criminal?
- I fled from love.
- What a funny story!
Please don't laugh!
There was something I found
out about this girl...
And when she said
she would kiss me...
Foolish girl!
How stupid of her!
- You don't dare say that!
- She deserves it!
- Boaster and windbag!
- Who, me?
To boast of his victories
in front of a stranger!
- She's a fool!
- Don't say that about her!
- What did you say?
- She's a fool!
Impudent people ought
to be punished.
- Defend yourself.
- I'm at your service.
Daddy!
Princess!
It is you!
I'm so happy!
Why are you here?
I followed you for 3 days.
Yes!
To tell you that I don't care
about you in the least!
I had no intention of
kissing you!
Or of falling in love
with you!
You hurt me so much,
that I want revenge.
I will prove to you,
that I don't care.
I'll die but I'll prove it.
Run away...
I have to run away!
Miserable bear!
Run away, and save her
and myself!
Coward!
How funny, how crazy,
How untimely,
And how wonderful!
Without any reason and
Without any meaning...
At all!
There comes a day,
There strikes an hour,
There comes a moment,
There comes a time,
And the connection breaks,
Granite boils,
Ice catches fire,
Light down knocks
You off your feet,
What madness!
Weeds start to blossom,
The old owl sings like a
Nightingale,
And even the thinnest of
Threads...
Can not be cut in half
By a steel dagger!
How funny, how crazy,
How untimely,
And how wonderful!
Without any reason
And without any meaning...
At all!
Cast:
Oleg Yankovsky
Irina Kupchenko
Yevgenyi Solomin
Yevgenia Simonova
Alexader Abdulov
Ekaterina Vasilyeva
Yuri Solomin
Andrei Mironov
and others
Scriptwriter and director
Mark ZAKHAROV
D.O.P. Nikolai NEMOLYAEV
Set decorations
Lyudmila KUSAKOVA
Music composed by
Gennadyi GLADKOV
Lyrics by
Y. MIKHAILOV
MOSFILM studio
and the Creative Association
of TV Films present
a film made to the order
of GOSTELERADIO
A USUAL WONDER
Part Two
Based on a play by Yevgenyi
SCHWARZ of the same name
There comes a day,
There strikes an hour,
There comes a moment,
There comes a time,
And the connection breaks,
Granite boils,
Ice catches fire,
Light down
Knocks you off your feet.
What madness!
Weeds start to blossom,
And old owl sings
Like a nightingale,
And even the thinnest of
Threads...
Can not be cut in two
By a steel dagger!
How funny, how crazy,
How untimely,
And how wonderful!
Without any reason
Or meaning...
At all!
There comes a time,
And it brings...
Shivers and fear,
And a secret fever,
Power and delight,
Laughter and pain,
Light and shadow,
And throws it all into
One big fire.
What madness!
And out of a mirage,
Out of nothing...
Out of my own wild fantasies
Appears someone's face,
And it acquires shape
And color,
Flesh and passion,
Flesh and passion.
How funny, how crazy,
How untimely,
And how wonderful!
Without any reason
Or meaning...
At all!
Have you been talking to
someone?
I don't know.
Maybe.
I know I'm not well.
- Can I help?
- I doubt it.
- Unlock the door, I'm leaving.
- That's impossible.
Do you hear how quiet
it is?
I tried to go out, but
I couldn't.
We're buried under the snow.
- I can't leave then?
- No.
Then lock me in.
I can't meet with her.
I love her.
The Princess?
- How did you know?
- I just asked.
Is she in this tavern?
Yes, disguised in a man's
outfit.
Now I understand how she
insulted me.
- Did you hear what she said?
- No, I haven't.
But I've lived a long life,
and I understand everything.
I won't say another word!
I thought I was talking to a
young man who looked like her.
That was a mean thing to do!
It is over now!
- Lock me in.
- Here's the key.
I won't lock you in.
I wouldn't want you to
break my new lock.
Good night.
Where will you fiind peace?
You won't.
Lock yourself in a monastery, -
solitude will remind you of her.
Set up a tavern by the
road, -
every knock at the door will
remind you of her.
Damn! The candle keeps
blowing out.
Well of course it is.
I was thinking of you.
Emily...
Well I'll be damned!
Do you recognize me?
Emil?
Yes.
That was the name of a young man
whom a very mean girl forced to
flee to no-man's land.
Don't look at me like that.
My face is wind-beaten.
I see you like you were
20 years ago.
I forgot how to cry.
I became mean and callous.
I smoke sailors' tobacco,
devilish stuff.
That's what became of me.
You were always like that.
Stubborn and proud by nature.
It's just a new form it
acquired, that's all.
That's the whole difference.
Damn!
At every crowded
masquerade...
I would recognize you
under any mask.
You remember?
Yes.
My lady, don't you think
The weather is better
Than ever?
I will answer, my lord...
I do find...
That the weather is quite
Unusual indeed.
My lady, why is it...
That this evening is so
Extraordinary wonderful?
My lord, perhaps...
It is not easy to explain,
But it is probably because
You are with me tonight.
Oh, my lady,
When we are together,
All the flowers blossom
In the meadows,
I will say this, my lord...
It is time for me to go,
But I can't hurt the feelings
Of the little flowers.
I fiind it pleasing and
Amusing,
That you like me,
And I like you even more.
That is wonderful!
Ding-ding-dong!
And this is just a mask
time has put on you.
Why? Oh, why?
Why were you mad at him
then?
- Why?
- You kissed him.
He passed away long ago.
But why did you kiss him?
Only to avenge you.
You danced with the general's
daughter.
- Dancing is not a sin.
- No.
You were whispering something
in her ear.
I was whispering:
one, two, three...
She couldn't follow the
rhythm.
- Funny.
- So funny I want to cry.
Can you forgive my wicked self
for kissing him?
I am so happy to see you.
How stupid.
I forgot how to cry.
Let's talk about something
else.
There is one important
matter.
There are two young people
in this house,
who will die if we don't
do something.
The Princess and the young man,
because of whom she ran away.
- They met?
- And had a fiight.
Hit the drums!
- Blow the pipes!
- What pipes?
Don't pay attention, it's just
a court habit.
Get your swords out!
Prepare for battle!
Get up and going!
I get it.
Emily was married to the
palace commandant.
Hit the drums!
Get up and going!
He didn't know who
he was married to!
May his soul rest in peace.
- Did you see her?
- Yes.
She must be pale and weak?
She's tanned and running around
dressed like a boy.
- Is he here?
- Yes.
- Still in love?
- Very much so.
- Hurting?
- Indeed!
He deserves it, the bastard!
Heart drops, fast!
My apprentice is not
feeling well.
Give me those drops! Quick!
- He's not feeling well.
- This one?
Oh really! He won't notice
it if I die.
The new one! He won't eat, won't
drink and won't answer questions.
It is my daughter!
Oh my god!
- Who is your daughter?
- The new apprentice.
- It's the Princess in disguise.
- Well I'll be damned!
I almost hit her.
Can't you tell a boy
from a girl?
- And what about you?
- What?
All right, enough of that.
Where's the Princess?
Hey you! Don't shout at me!
My job puts me under
great pressure.
I don't like being shouted at.
If you want to show me my
mistakes, compliment me first.
Scoundrel!
He's a King.
Forgive me, Your Majesty.
I'll forgive you later.
Where's the Princess?
Sitting at the fiireplace,
looking at burning coals.
Take me to her.
I always remember your stories
about hunting.
Please be careful!
You have to take of yourself
for our sake!
We love you so much'
Your Majesty!
She'll open fiire.
The Princess said she will
shoot anyone, who...
She won't shoot her own
father.
I don't think so.
I doubt it she will spare
even her own father.
Now he will shout at me
again.
Jesus, my throat is sore!
There's no job more hazardous
than the job of a courtier.
How true.
I am in terrible anguish!
I warn everyone.
She is sitting there, all
sad and miserable.
There is no way I can
help her.
That's how it is.
Who will dare to approach her,
talk to her,
console and comfort her?
Who?
- She will open fiire.
- That's for sure.
So what?! You've been sentenced
to death anyway.
- Who will go first?
- Allow me.
That a boy!
No, you can't!
It's better if one of her close
ones went there.
For one who is in love the
closest seem the most distant.
The world has changed, but
they are still the same.
Gee, I haven't thought
about that.
But I will not cancel my order,
because I am a stubborn tyrant.
I feel the genes of my aunt
awakening in me now.
She was a hopeless fool.
Give me a hat and a
scrap of paper.
We shall draw lots.
we shall draw lots.
Ready.
Whoever draws the one with the
cross, goes to the Princess.
She is armed.
Let me talk to the Princess.
- I know what to tell her.
- My answer is ''no''.
I'm having one of my fiits
of stubbornness.
Am I a King or not?
First Minister, you draw fiirst.
- Alas!
- Thank god!
There's no cross here.
Why did you say ''alas'',
you idiot?
Quiet!
Your turn, my lady.
- I have to go!
- Congratulations!
And may your soul rest
in peace.
Show me that paper.
You liar!
Look at these people!
All they know is how to
cheat on their King.
Next!
- Next!
- What are you shouting for?
Draw the lot!
What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
Open your eyes,
the hat is right here.
Alas, no cross.
How unfortunate!
- Next!
- Come on, show me that.
- What?
- Give me that scrap of paper.
- No cross?
- No.
- What's this then?
- You call that a cross?
Nonsense! This is not a cross?
This looks more like an ''X''.
No, this is not an ''X'',
it is your lot.
Go ahead.
Your Majesty!
Be reasonable. What do you want
me to risk my life for?
For a whim, for some kind of
a stupid prejudice?
For love!
What love?
Did you see it?
Don't be selfish and
don't keep us waiting.
When a smuggler crosses a
canyon clinging to a perch,
or a merchant sails across the
ocean in a frail boat,
that is understandable,
that is noble.
These people are making money.
But what's there for me
in this?
What you call love, my lady,
can be a lot of fun and
a little absurd.
- But to risk my life!
- Shut up, you despicable fool!
Tell her not to abuse
me.
What are you staring at me!
As if you really believe
what you're saying.
I've seen enough of
noble sufferers,
and the torturers of
human souls.
They push the deceived fools
to their sure death.
It is them who invented
love!
There is no such thing as
love, Your Majesty!
Trust the word of an
experienced man.
All right, you said your
fiinal word.
Now go. Don't expect me
to pardon you.
Go, or I'll shoot you myself.
Why did I listen to him!
Now he awakened the aunt
in me.
The one who could be easily
convinced by anyone.
The poor thing was married
18 times,
not to mention fleeting
affairs.
Maybe love doesn't exist
after all?
Maybe the Princess is suffering
from a case of severe angina?
- Your Majesty.
- Shut up!
You are an honorable and
devout woman.
Let us listen to the
young.
You...
Beat it.
For good.
May his soul rest in peace.
- She may have missed!
- Never! She's my student!
Quiet! I personally am happy.
My daughter behaves
like all normal people.
She's feeling low, and
she starts shooting around.
She missed!
- Why are you still alive?
- Because I fired that shot.
That's right.
- Who at?
- At the Princess.
Oh, she's alive, don't worry.
Hey you! Get me an executioner's
block and a shot of Vodka.
Vodka for me, the rest for him!
Move it!
Not so fast.
Listen here, father.
The princess is my
fiiance.
He's crazy.
Not in the least!
Tell me everything,
or I'll kill you!
I like to tell about
deals,
that worked out fine.
I go there, I open the door
And wait to be shot at.
I don't want to die,
just like anyone else.
So I stand there,
I stand and I think,
I think something like that:
Now is my hour of death.
And life is so good,
Oh, so good,
And I don't want to die,
Just like anyone else.
The girl jumps up,
She rushes to the door,
I grab at my gun,
And I fire a shot at her.
What was I to do?
I fiire at her,
At the sweet little lady,
Because of the circumstances,
Not out of spite.
She didn't shake,
She didn't shiver,
But instead she said
In her gentle voice...
I said to myself that I will
Marry anyone who comes fiirst,
I don't really care who.
So you have come fiirst,
She said.
Yes, that's what she said
To me, the sweet girl.
You are the fiirst one I see,
And I am yours forever.
And in the midst of
All that fire and smoke
I planted a kiss on her
tender lips.
Please stop, or I will
kill you.
No problem! They already
tried to kill me today.
- And look what happened!
- One hell of a mess!
Look for some medicine
in the fiirst aid kit.
I nearly fainted, and all I
got left is feelings.
Delicate, fragile,
feelings I can't explain.
Is it music or flowers I
want, or to stab someone?
I know, something strange
has happened to me.
And I'm afraid to face reality.
Daddy!
- Good evening, daddy.
- Good evening.
I'm getting married.
Who to, my child?
To this one.
- Give me your hand.
- With great pleasure.
Don't play the fool, or I'll
shoot you.
You're OK!
I'm proud of you!
The wedding is to take
place right now.
A wedding is always a
happy occasion.
Why postpone it!
My sword!
I ask you to be my wife.
I am young and healthy.
And I will make you happy.
What is this?
- Will you marry me?
- Don't answer him.
You can do this,
and I can't?
I swore to marry the
fiirst person that comes by.
- Me too!
- I don't care.
Ladies! You will help me
put on my wedding gown.
Gentlemen! You will help
me set the table.
Think of a pretext and make
the Princess come back.
I will bring her back by
force if I have to!
I ask you to marry me.
Which one of us are you
proposing to? There's two of us.
Sorry, I haven't noticed.
To come near two people in love
when they're fiighting
can be lethally dangerous.
- Have pity on the girl!
- Does anyone have pity on me?
A couple of kind gentle
words,
and you will both be happy!
Tell her you were wrong
and kiss her.
- Don't be stubborn.
- No!
Don't waste time!
I hear Emily's footsteps.
She's bringing the Princess.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Please accept my congratulations
on this happy occasion!
The wedding of the Princess
and the Minister
will take place right now.
Emily, what are you
saying?
That's an order!
What's gotten into you,
Emily?
Don't touch me!
What's with me?
- What's with you, Emily?
- Don't touch me!
I'm on duty! I'm doing my job.
What's gotten into me?
I'm only doing my job!
God damn me!
Everything's ready,
Your Majesty.
As honorary Saint,
honorary Martyr,
and honorary Pope of our
kingdom
I take it upon myself to
perform this pleasant duty.
I ask the bride and groom
to join hands.
No!
What do you mean, ''no''?
Go ahead, say it.
Leave us alone, I have to
talk to the Princess.
The impudent young man!
Boor!
What a boor!
Look at that boor!
Please leave, everyone.
And leave us alone.
I think we should go.
I would leave,
but I'm dying to know what
he will say to her.
Please, let's do what
the young man asks.
We can do that,
the more so that we can
eavesdrop through the keyhole.
Let's go, gentlemen!
I will tell you the truth.
Our encounter brought
us disaster.
We shouldn't have fallen
in love.
It is terrible.
We fell in love.
We fell in love...
We fell in love with
each other.
If you kiss me, I will
turn into a beast.
I will turn into a beast.
If I kiss you...
I will turn into a bear.
- A bear?
- Yes, and I don't want that.
I couldn't bare it.
I swore that sooner I'd
die than hurt you.
Forgive me.
- The moment I kiss you?
- Yes.
And you will walk around
the room in silence,
like in a cage?
Yes.
And you will never talk
to me in a human voice?
No.
How terrible that this
should end in this way!
Father!
- Father, he...
- I know.
I was eavesdropping, daughter.
How terrible!
Let's leave, father.
Something's happening inside me,
something frightening and kind.
It's scary!
Maybe we shouldn't send him
away? Look at how others live.
After all, he's a bear,
not a ferret.
We could tame him,
brush his hair.
He could dance for us
once in a while.
No! I love him too much
for that.
Good-bye forever.
Forever.
Let's say good-bye
In a soft voice,
Say good-bye in a low
Voice,
Say good-bye with a light
Heart.
A week or two,
And it we'll get over it.
Everything will remain
In the past.
Even though it is sad!
It is senseless and
Meaningless!
Oh, how good it would be to
Start all over again!
But that is impossible,
That is unthinkable,
Don't even dream of it,
Forget it.
Let's go back to our lunches,
Back to our clothes.
Fill our days with little
careS.
It is easier that way,
It is much more simple,
Isn't it?
And it hurts less,
Let's not invent ways,
Let's not count on our destiny,
It's not worth the effort,
Believe me.
That's true, gentlemen.
Not ever, not in your dreams.
It will never be.
Oh, how charming,
Oh, how good it was,
It was, and it is no more.
I brought them to this hotel,
Heaped up all entrances
and exits with snow.
I was so proud of my
resourcefulness.
And you didn't kiss her.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the hotel is closing down.
I'm leaving.
The keys! I'll lock the place
myself.
Go tell the hunter to hurry.
He's packing his diplomas.
How dared you not to
kiss the girl?
How could you do that?
You know what that would
lead to.
I don't! You don't love her.
That's not true!
You don't love her,
otherwise the power of passion
would have taken over!
Who can tell what will
happen,
when someone is seized with
strong noble emotions?
Poor unarmed people
overthrow kings!
Out of love for their
fellow brothers.
Out of love for their nation
soldiers defy death.
Men of wisdom rise to the sky
and plunge into hell.
Out of love for Truth.
And what have you done out
of love for a woman?
I gave her up.
Once in a lifetime there
comes a day,
when everything lovers do,
works.
You missed your chance.
So long.
I won't help you any more.
I lost interest in you.
Want to kill your 100th bear?
I will find the princess
and I will kiss her.
And I will turn into a bear!
I see.
A 100th bear?
Sounds tempting!
Interesting idea.
I hate to abuse your kindness.
Don't feel awkward, I
volunteered to be your victim.
- What about the Princess?
- She will be happy.
Well as they say, the Art
demands sacrifiices.
- How true!
- Thank you, my friend!
I am starting to forget
that tune.
It's all right.
You wrote a bad story.
It's time to forget it.
Time will come and you will
write another beautiful one!
A merry one!
No. I don't think I can.
This was my last story.
- What does the doctor say?
That the Princess may die.
We don't believe that.
That would be too much.
- You promised to forget.
- All right, I will.
Coffee, please.
No use thinking about something,
that can't be brought back.
We promise, we won't.
- When did he come back?
- He didn't.
It was the Hunter. No one
knows, where the bear is.
- Is he hunting?
- Of course not!
He is busy writing a book on
the theory of hunting.
- When will it come out?
- No one knows.
He's only written a few
chapters so far.
He's in charge of the
King's Hunting.
Recently married maid of
honor Amanda.
They have a daughter too.
Name Bullet.
The hunter's apprentice married
Orynthya. They have a boy.
They called him Target.
- Did you invite them?
- Orynthya with her son?
They never wait for an
invitation.
They come whenever they
please. Just like you.
And feel quite at home here.
He's busy and he doesn't
feel well.
And he promised, that's over.
- You understand?
- I do.
But I can't do otherwise.
They can't.
And I can't do without
them.
Every story has to have an
end.
Some kind of an end.
Sad, happy, funny, stupid.
Whatever. But there has
to be an end.
They will all come back here,
all except for the Bear.
I don't want to see him.
I erased him from my
memory.
Amanda with her daughter!
Yes...
The princess is suffering,
but life goes on its usual way.
Yes!
The fiish here is cheaper
than at home.
But beef is the same
price.
What about vegetables?
The vegetables are
unbelievable!
They lease pumpkins to poor
families.
They live inside and they
feed on them.
They tried to rent watermelons
too, but they're too damp.
Let's say good-bye
In a soft voice,
With a light heart.
A weak or two,
And we will get over it,
Everything will remain
In the past,
You know very well...
What's going on.
You could help us.
The Administrator became
a Prince,
and he prevents the Bear from
seeing the Princess.
It is not the Administrator.
- It is me!
- I don't believe you.
I'm only doing it to make these
lazy people do something.
What a shame.
Don't be sore with me,
my lady.
It was all my fault
in the fiirst place.
A Minister's duty is to report
the truth to the King.
But I was afraid to grieve
His Majesty.
The King must know the truth.
Hello!
What a beautiful morning!
How is everything?
How is the Princess?
All right, don't bother
to answer.
I know everything's well.
There, look!
- Your Majesty...
- Don't!
Farewell.
- Listen to me!
- I want to sleep.
If you won't help
your daughter,
than who will?
Don't you see what's going
on around here?
A swindler and an impudent man
without a heart and a mind
has seized power in the
Kingdom.
Everything and everyone
serve his purse.
His people are all around
the place,
carrying bales with goods from
place to place.
You have to order to oust this
the Prince-Administrator,
and the Princess will feel
better,
and she will no longer be
threatened by this foul wedding.
- Your Majesty!
- No.
- I can't do anything.
- But why?
Why?
Why! Because I am degenerating!
I say, you are a fool.
You have to read books, then
you'll know, you can't ask a
King more than he can do!
The Princess will die.
Let her die.
If I feel that something like
that is coming on to me,
I'll kill myself.
I keep poison especially
for that purpose.
I tried it on my partner
just the other day.
We were playing a game
of cards.
The stuff worked wonders!
He died without noticing it.
Why all the shouting?!
- You needn't worry about me.
- We worry about the Princess.
You're not worrying
about your King?
No, Your Excellency!
- What did you call me?
- Your Excellency.
You addressed the greatest of
all kings by a general's title?
- That is a riot! - Yes I have
raised my voice against you.
I'm standing up to you!
And you are not the
greatest of all kings!
Just an outstanding
one, that's all.
What, are you gonna
bite me?
Outstanding, but not more!
And you're not worthy of the
title ''honorary Saint''.
You ma be a hermit,
but you're no saint.
- Call the executioner!
- He won't come.
He writes poems for the
Administrator's newspaper.
- You're not coming?
- Nope.
Call the Administrator
Minister!
No respect!
But why?
For what reason?
Who dares to mistreat
the ruler,
our little homely King!
They don't show me any respect,
they want me to get rid of you.
The lousy plotters with
their intrigues.
- They're scaring me.
- What with?
They say the Princess
will die of love.
What utter nonsense!
Gibberish, as I call it.
Our family doctor,
mine and the King's,
examined the Princess and
reported on her health condition
He found no symptoms
of any love disease.
That's fiirst. And second...
All love illnesses are
a mere trifle,
and a cause for jokes,
but they're nothing lethal
and easily curable.
If you don't neglect them.
- What's this talk about death?
- That's what I'm saying.
The doctor knows better!
The doctor is certain, the
Princess will get well soon.
- Must be the wedding fever.
- As they call it.
As I call it.
- Here!
- What is it?
- The doctor ran away!
- That's impossible!
I went to see him about
the calming drops,
and I find rooms unlocked,
drawers open and wardrobe empty.
And a note on the table.
Don't show it to me.
I'm afraid!
How do you like that?! No
executioner, no gendarmes!
You are pigs, and disloyal
at that!
Don't follow me!
I won't listen to you!
I am not listening!
- Show me that note.
- Read it to me.
''Only a miracle can save
the princess...
''You make her suffer, but I
will be the one you will blame.
''Doctors are human beings too,
they want to live. Good-bye.''
Damn! The traitor!
How inopportunely!
Doctor!
Call him and say it is all
his fault. Quick!
No, please, don't stand up,
my friends.
Today is such an
extraordinary day!
Today whatever I try to do
works.
Things, that I thought were
lost, somehow appear again.
If I think about the past,
only the best comes to mind.
In this way life must
be saying good-bye to me.
Did they tell you I am
going to die today?
But Princess...
Yes, it's even more frightening
than I thought.
Death is gross and dirty.
It comes with a sack full of
loathsome instruments.
But how do you know all
that, Princess?
Death came so close,
that I could see it all.
But that's enough.
Talk to me as if nothing
happened.
Joke, smile, tell me
stories.
I just don't want to think
about what's going to happen.
Who is that?
Who?!
Who is it?
Who is it?!
Do you hear it?
- Do you hear?
- Yes.
I'm sorry, I was afraid
of being late.
Leave, everyone,
except the Princess.
How did you get here?
I isolated you.
Please leave now.
Or I will want to
kill you again.
Only this time I will
really do it.
He will do it.
Please leave now.
Why are you crying?
I'm crying of happiness.
Now I have a secret,
with which
I wouldn't trust anyone,
not even the closest friends,
only you.
I love you.
That's the truth!
I love you so much
I will forgive you anything.
You want to turn into a bear?
Very well.
Only don't leave me.
I couldn't bare to be
alone again!
What took you so long?
No-no, don't answer.
I won't ask you.
If you didn't come, that's
because you couldn't.
I will not reproach you.
I will be patient.
Only don't leave me.
Today death came very close.
That's true.
But I am not afraid of it.
I am so happy, I don't know
anything about death and grief.
Especially now, when you are
standing so close.
No one ever came this
close to me.
close to me,
and no one ever held
me tight.
You are holding me, like
you have the right to,
and I like that.
Let's go to my room.
I'll show you the room, where
I spent so many hours crying.
The balcony from which I looked
to see if you were coming,
A hundred books about bears.
Bears were all I could
read about.
It is all my fault.
We can't do anything
about that now.
Yes, it is your fault.
Why did you do that?
I warned you, didn't I?
It's the way I am.
I wanted to talk to you
about love.
But I'm a magician.
Remember, what you said?
- Do you?
- I remember.
So I took all these people
and reshuffled them.
And they lived, so that you
would laugh and cry.
I am crying.
Some of them worked better,
Some worSe,
but I've grown used to them.
I couldn't cross them out,
could I?
They're not words -
they're people.
Sometimes I even let them
argue with me,
and disobey me.
Sleep, darling.
Unfortunately, I am
immortal.
I will have to outlive you,
and forever miss you.
But now you are with me.
Glory to the brave ones,
who have enough courage
to love,
knowing that everything
has to end.
Glory to the daring,
who live as though they
will live forever.
- Why aren't you asleep?
- Don't scare away the bear!
- Let's go back.
- No.
- Let's go to your place.
- I'm scared.
You're hurting me.
No, please, don't be
offended.
Let it be the way you
want it.
God, I'm so happy that I
have decided everything!
Foolish me! I didn't know it
could be that good.
let's do it your way.
Well!
I'm terribly sorry.
I don't want to interfere
in your work,
but I think just now a
miracle happened.
Very well could be.
Why are you surprised?
What's going on?!
I was promised,
that he will turn into
a bear.
- You confiirmed that.
- I did.
So where's the bear?
I confiirmed it, because I
was not too clever.
But I don't regret it now.
I found your last story
very amusing.
At least it is good.
Perhaps even the best.
Let's say good-bye
In a soft voice,
In a low voice,
Let's say good-bye
With a light heart.
A week or two,
And we'll get over it,
And everything will remain
In the past.
It is sad,
It is senseless and
Meaningless.
Oh, how good it would be
To start all over again.
But it is impossible to
Go back to where it started.
Don't even dream about it.
It was charming,
It was fun,
But it slipped away, and it
Is not there any more.
Cast:
Oleg Yankovsky
Irina Kupchenko
Yevgenyi Leonov
Yevgenia Simonova
Alexander Abdulov
Ekaterina Vasilyeva
Yuri Solomin
Andrei Mironov
Ervant Arzumanyan
Vsevolod Larionov
and others
Scriptwriter and director
Mark Zakharov
D.O.P.
Nikolai Nemolyaev
Production Designer
Lyudmila Kusakova
Music by
Gennadyi Gladkov
Lyrics by
Y. Mikhailov