"How to Become the Richest Man?"
Please mind the gap
between train and platform.
Sorry.
Good morning. Free newspaper.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Morning.
This way, please.
Please make way for her.
- Take your time.
- Morning.
Morning.
Not everyone can take this elevator.
What do you mean?
If you want to take this elevator,
come before 7 am
or after 10 pm.
It takes you directly to 71st floor.
If you're in it, it guarantees
your future success.
Otherwise, you'll lose your job.
- Morning.
- So early today?
Ready.
Okay.
My name is Lee Xiang.
Lee for Ang Lee, Xiang for dream.
24 years old.
Nice to meet you!
Kat.
I'm in the Sales Department.
What about you?
The boss will decide after my probation.
Why can you take the direct elevator?
I'm Ben.
You are?
Kat. Don't be afraid. I don't bite.
Lee Xiang, Lee for Ang Lee,
Xiang for dream.
What's going on?
He's Howard.
Why they come at
our busiest hours?
- I'm Lee Xiang...
- Follow us.
Xiang for dream.
Look.
This is our office.
Everyone is working hard.
Look, our colleagues are so efficient.
All of us share the same belief in
getting off work early.
Here is photocopy room.
Smoke on the rooftop.
Die in the executive office.
Loiter in the toilet.
Gossip in the pantry.
Listen carefully!
Remember!
Black coffee for CEO Chang,
hot milk for Sophie,
latte with three spoons of sugar for John,
oolong tea for Kevin,
Diet Coke for Kar-ling,
double expresso for David,
and water for everyone.
Got it?
Here you have to learn it the first time.
CEO Chang likes black coffee,
hot milk for Sophie,
Kevin likes oolong tea,
latte with three spoons of sugar for John,
Diet Coke for Kar-ling,
double expresso for David,
and water for everyone.
Here! Here they are!
The IPO team is here!
Excuse me.
Up how many points today?
Good.
- The other two stocks?
- David,
please hand in the
2007 account.
Chang wants it immediately.
They're here?
Yes.
Bankers have sharp eyes for money,
as befits bankers.
I foresee the market
price of our IPO.
Lawyers are dressed lawfully
in black and white.
Such boring attire in
youth creates no delight.
Marry one lawyer and we'll never
worry about the legal fight.
Nice to meet you. When I see you,
I see my future bright.
We'll help you secure your
well-being and avoid plight.
We're so professional that
we do things with might.
Look, we belong to the same team.
Look, we're social elites.
Fight, going public is difficult.
Our strong will leads us to light.
We're the accounting team:
Miky, Mary, Michael, Martin
I'm Sophie.
I don't have an English name.
We'll do a financial checkup to check
if you're sick or not.
We'll do an accounting blood test
to see if it's clean.
With our Midas touch
you'll have no problems.
All the numbers will become artworks
under your cooperation.
We're so professional that
we do things with might.
Morning, Chairman.
David, you look fit!
Thanks a lot, Chairman.
We've been busy going public.
Not much time for exercise.
Do you know the relationship
between Chairman Ho and CEO Chang?
Chang used to be Ho's secretary.
She's been working for him
until he becomes a big shot.
She's also his mistress.
Stop it.
They've been in love for 20 years.
Ho's wife is a big shot.
Her family is the financial source
of our head office.
Poor Chang is just a...
CEO.
Why no one dares to speak louder!
Let me introduce Jones & Sunn.
It grows from a small agent
to the biggest trading company
going public today.
It's all about guts.
What others dare not do, she dares.
What others can't think of, she can.
Where others are afraid to
take accountability, she's not afraid.
From fancy food,
foreign wines, house appliances,
to the indispensable cosmetics for women.
Supermarkets, department stores,
the most eye-catching shelf space.
It is the joint effort of all of you.
My elite team is aiming for...
...a more ambitious goal.
Listen, the loyal
chant is charming.
Listen, the money is mellifluous.
Look, we'll build a
financial empire,
with one heart.
Raising money,
expanding business,
reigning over Asia, going international.
Look, we belong to the same team.
Look, we're social elites.
Look, we'll build a
financial empire
with one heart.
All employees will be given
pre-emptive rights as bonus.
We're one big family
with one heart.
You two are lucky...
...to learn from me.
Can you make it or not?
Say it out loud!
I dread seeing youngsters,
who only shake or nod their heads,
or show me silly smiles.
You got to talk in our business.
It's important to be talkative.
We can make it.
Draft an email for me
to the wine factories in France.
I'll tell you the address.
Tell them:
although the government announced
wine tax relief months ago,
the exchange rate of Euro remains high.
Our profits haven't
increased in proportion.
Besides, we have fierce competitors
in Hong Kong
and we've built more wine warehouses.
In the short term,
our profits won't be much higher.
For the present price,
we would ask for a six-year contract.
If they insist on a three-year contract,
tell them to lower the price.
Can you finish it in half an hour?
It's ready.
Show me.
Where did you graduate from?
An economics major at Harvard.
Tell me, with your credentials,
why you work here as an assistant?
Tell the tell able truth.
Because I'm inexperienced,
I would like to learn more.
You went to Harvard.
Your family must be rich.
What do your parents do?
Be brief and vague.
They do business.
What kind of business?
My father owns a siu mei restaurant.
Make it more convincing.
The landlord's raising the rent
and my father's worried.
Evade by asking questions.
David, do you need any documents
for tomorrow's meeting?
Maybe Lee Nian and I can help you?
Yes! We can prepare something for you.
The applicants' CVs
normally come through me.
But I don't recall seeing yours.
Did Chang interview you herself?
Or you're hired by the head office?
Do you know anyone from the head office?
My name is Lee Xiang,
Lee for Ang Lee, Xiang for dream.
David.
Busy?
Not really.
You're free to ¿o!
Someone will come to your rescue
if you need help.
Sorry.
I misremembered your name.
I remember now, Lee Xiang.
Come over, quick!
Marketing is all about efficiency.
These products are misplaced.
This is too high, that is too low.
Look carefully and take notes.
How's the sales?
Which is the best-seller?
Look carefully and take notes.
Don't just look at the crowd.
How many carry our bags?
Look carefully and take notes.
Customers' eyes and minds.
David, I'm busy now.
Looking at these brands,
I feel the urge and the regret.
It's like falling in love.
I'm dazed by their look.
If I don't lose my control,
I would be too hypocritical.
I don't have enough money to buy.
It's sad but maybe
I will in the future.
Don't say I'm materialistic.
Without famous brands,
your personality and life are fake.
I'll work hard.
I can do everything in
exchange for my love.
No purchase, no happiness.
I love this, I love that
I want to take them all home.
Unless you suffer
from personality disorder,
you should profess your love.
I purchase, therefore I am
It's good to show
off to earn respect.
Told you so many times.
Not that I don't want to get married.
I got a raise and was promoted.
How can I leave?
I want to buy a flat.
You want to ¿o to Shanghai.
And the car loan.
And your parents.
We'll have children, right?
How much it takes to raise a child?
Hold on.
Hello? It's Sophie.
Manager Wu? I've been looking for you.
Hold on, please.
Got an important call.
I'll call you back.
Mom,
Mom, you're smiling.
Daddy, Mom's smiling.
Do you hope that she wakes up?
She's in a coma because she's mad at you.
It's the obstructed
blood flow in her brain.
She's not mad at me.
She's mad at you.
I don't know what you're thinking,
or what you've heard.
Don't believe in gossip.
I don't want to be ordinary.
I want to become closer
and closer to my dream.
I want to talk to my boss about
my life, my dream,
and my belief.
Is it good?
It is good.
I want to be the pillar of society,
to think, to do,
and to take responsibility.
I want to be enthusiastic,
to shine,
and to be a model employee.
I want to be promoted
and successful,
but I'm anxious about it.
This is the dream that obsesses me.
I want to rush to pay
the bills for my friends.
Let me take the bills.
I want everyone to
see me doing great.
I want to tell everyone that
I'm busy but I'll be
busier tomorrow.
I'm everywhere every day.
I'm indispensable,
not an egg-laying chicken.
I'm Lee Xiang.
Morning, Ms. Chang.
Hot lemon water, thank you.
OK, I see you.
I'm in a rush to trade.
- Sorry.
- Your coffee.
Good morning. Thanks.
What's new?
Lehman Minibonds are sure profitable.
This accumulator is hot.
HSBC just distributed dividends.
Perfect time to buy.
Great!
OK.
Chang told me to sell 005.
But I expect it to ¿o higher.
Sell it
and buy what you just said...
- Accumulator?
- Accumulator
How much?
All in.
All in? Have you asked Chang?
Put them all under my account.
It's OK.
If it keeps rising,
profit will double in less than a month.
Double!
Cheers! Double!
Black coffee for CEO Chang.
Sophie...
Milk.
Hot milk for Sophie.
Kevin...
Oolong tea.
So exciting! It's like
going to the battlefield.
Can you tell who Kevin and Sophie are?
And the rest?
Get upstairs first.
I don't think those teenage girls
have the money to buy cosmetics!
We shouldn't neglect
the buying power of teenage girls.
Lancome wants to open
a specialty store this year
because the department stores can
no longer accommodate
the increasing sales of cosmetics
and the cutthroat
competition between brands.
Another issue is
the rising cost of samples
distributed at department stores.
Who said oil price couldn't
rise above USD 100?
-005 up again!
- David.
Cosmetics is not my forte
but I heard MADAME
won't renew their contracts with Fungchoi.
Is the image of MADAME
too similar to Lancome?
More brands we represent,
more international we become.
It's easier said than done.
Who should make it work?
John, have you counted
how many bottles to sell to teenagers
to match one eye cream of MADAME?
Have you calculated?
MADAM E's eye cream is priced at $880.
And we buy it for $150.
Why didn't you answer my call?
You don't reply to my text and
your phone is always off.
Chang,
I'm taking leave to ¿o back to Hangzhou.
Is Fungchoi not renewing
contracts with MADAME
or the other way around?
Of course MADAME is not renewing
contracts with Fungchoi.
Fungchoi can't break
into the Mainland market.
It's all rumor.
They've been in partnership
for over 10 years...
Business is just about making money.
Ben.
Yes!
Didn't I say I don't drink decaf?
Or you don't know how to train new hires?
Sorry, my bad! I made the coffee.
I don't know what is decaf or...
..."hi-caf."
You're?
Lee Xiang!
Remember,
I only drink regular black coffee.
Can you remember such a simple fact?
Yes.
When can I give you
such an expensive gift,
like the one given by Chung-ping?
Stop dreaming.
You two are not in the same league!
Sell all the stocks
and get the money back.
Before going public, we need to have
a clean accounting record.
We'd better take in one famous brand
before going public.
You and me.
Have you ever been shortchanged?
Tell you an inside information:
the stock price will be rising.
But we need to sell it all by next week.
Who told you this?
Ho Chung-Ding?
Your eyes are shining
when it comes to money.
Smart guys control money,
stupid guys are controlled by money.
Is money ever enough?
Can you resist the temptation?
Hasn't Sophie been
chasing you for the money?
Don't worry. I know what I'm doing.
Sorry,
I have to ¿o back to finish my work!
Bye.
Typhoon Signal No. 3 is raised.
Signal No. 8 may be raised tomorrow!
No need to work.
Cheers!
Sorry.
Where are you going?
Sophie, poor Sophie.
I've heard her fiance is leaving her.
Why? Why?
Because she doesn't want to
give up work and get married.
That's why her fiancé
is pissed off.
Sophie and her fiancé had a fight
because she wants to stay in the city.
No.
Sophie wants to stay in the city
because she fell in
love with someone else.
Who is he?
David.
David?
How dare you spell it out!
How's work going?
Hi!
It's all right.
How's work going?
I'm surviving.
Big mouths wait to be fired.
Chirping birds take the bullet.
Too easy to find new hires.
Difficult to pass probation.
Too many are after this job.
Use your brain, not your age.
Bad mouths may well be fired.
A well-dressed hen
with a high salary
has a high risk of being fired.
Calm down!
Are you fine with being
a corporate slave?
It's a must.
Are you fine with
working till you drop?
Perhaps.
Are you fine with being
a corporate slave?
We're enjoying it.
Are you fine with
working till you drop?
If you two survive,
others will be fired.
I work such long hours for my baby
who doesn't even know his daddy.
I'm turning 40 but without man
or money by my side.
I'm obliged to my
parents in their old age
and obliged to the
bank until my old age.
Let's not compare with one another
in jobs or for survival.
Even diligent pigs want to
live a decent life.
Dogs have their
worries, just like us.
Never intent on fighting,
we only want to be fed.
Show me the money
and I'll bow to you.
Are you fine with being fired?
As long as it's not me.
Cheers!
Don't bite your fingers.
Such beautiful hands.
Why so nervous?
You're troubled.
Can I help you in any way?
I heard that you...
I don't need consoling words.
I don't need anyone.
Sweet talk
doesn't work with me.
Anyway, thank you for driving me home.
Please settle the accounts immediately!
I have a lot of works to do.
Why you hate me so much?
Do you think I have nothing to do
so I drive you home in such wind and rain?
Morning, Ms. Chang!
- This elevator isn't for you.
- I'm in a rush.
Let him in.
Thanks a lot.
Why so early?
Many cosmetics
are bound for shipment
so I come earlier today.
How long have you been here?
Almost a month.
Your supervisor is...David?
Yes, David.
Can you pass the three-month probation?
Of course.
It's not easy to please David.
No problem!
I can make it!
Chang, do you remember who I am?
You are Lee Xiang.
You're loyal to your colleagues.
I remember you.
Thanks a lot.
Ms. Chang, may I have a small request?
Say it!
If I pass the three month probation,
can I take the direct
elevator with you again?
Sure!
Let's bet on
whether you can make it!
Howard.
I'm meeting a client at 2 pm
in Eastern District.
No, you can't.
We have to inspect
all our Southern
District counters by 2:30 pm.
Move the afternoon
schedule to morning, can you?
Ben,
- Terry.
- Yes!
Have you fixed my battle shoes?
The heels of your shoes
are broken.
It takes a few days to repair.
My feet will be broken.
- Band-Aid.
- Kar-ling
wants to swap her schedules. Understand?
- Go!
- Bring the Band-Aid.
Band-Aid.
Follow me!
Oh my!
David, something went wrong.
What happened? Oh my...
- Kevin, Kevin.
- Yes.
- Please come here.
- OK.
Gray & Young has finished
the first phase of audit.
I've handed out everything
except for the 2007 account.
What happened?
Chang, should we consider changing
a shipping company?
Our goods were stolen again.
- Get back to work.
- Yes.
John,
what did the claims adjusters say?
Those bastards
mainly stole shipments to Mainland.
They don't steal much.
10 to 20 containers.
Call TGS
and ask them to give us a thorough report.
This isn't the first theft.
Figure out how the goods got stolen.
Follow up on this.
Also find out how much to ship
directly from Europe.
Yes.
David.
Have you read these proposals?
I've seen the same proposals
for the past half year.
What did "Research and
Development Department" do?
Their ideas are all about endorsement.
I don't want an advertising firm.
I want unique ideas.
The management from MADAME
will arrive next week.
Which level of executives?
Vice President, Mr. Greenberg.
I've arranged dinner with him.
OK, good.
Shall we bring Kar-ling and John?
Don't we have other talent?
Bring Kat and Lee Xiang.
Lee Xiang?
Vice CEO Wang,
you've been too busy investing in stocks
to know your new recruits?
Lee Xiang, Lee for Ang Lee,
Xiang for dream.
He reminds me of a younger you.
Auntie.
David said it's urgent.
Please sign it immediately.
Take it to my secretary.
I thought you were leaving.
I don't sign documents
without reading them first.
By the way, address me as Ms. Chang.
There's no such thing
as Uncle or Auntie here.
Sorry.
And don't ask your
driver to drive you to work.
Learn to take the subway and bus.
Don't wear brand-name clothing.
People will suspect your true identity,
or think you have part-time jobs.
People gossip-
No one else will look out for you.
Understood.
We are very pleased to have
the Vice Chairman of MADAME,
Mr. Greenberg,
and his wonderful team
to be here with us tonight.
Thank you for coming, welcome!
I hope you'll enjoy the champagne
we've chosen for you.
Ms. Winnie Chang
apologizes for her absence,
but she did pick the restaurant
and the wine herself.
Anyway, Mr. Greenberg,
Our company takes this meeting seriously.
I'd like to introduce
you to this elite team
that will help you
develop M Cosmetics.
And please join me
to look at this direction.
The direction of China!
And yes! The whole world is now
looking at this direction!
I'm sure you know that our head office
has been doing business in Mainland
for more than 15 years.
Translate.
Mr. Greenberg,
You're now looking at the best team
your company can rely on to expand
the growth of MADAME cosmetics.
Also, I'd like for you
to look this direction,
which is the direction of China!
I told you sooner or
later the American system
of spending future money would collapse.
It takes a formidable amount of money
to rescue the "subprime mortgage crisis."
It won't affect China!
Mr. Ho, is your inside
information reliable?
- Will it affect your IPO?
- Don't worry.
But the Lehman Brothers bankruptcy
will more or less affect the
whole world economically.
My company is simple and clean,
no records of deficits.
Will there be any
problems with going public?
That's good!
That's great!
Cheers.
Thank you again for coming.
To new venture!
There won't be any problems. Cheers!
Excuse me, Mr. Greenberg.
If you're free,
what do you say we
meet sometime like Tuesday?
Tuesday is great.
I've got some small gifts for you.
Hope you like them.
You're too kind.
Everyone has one.
This is impressive!
Since we're enjoying this wonderful wine,
I think...
A toast to new friends...
- ...and working closely together!
- Sure.
How's the wine?
- Which vintage year?
-1982
1982?
Should be alright.
What era is it now?
What era?
It is an era of financial dominance!
Come on, be smart.
Working is nothing.
Look at me.
You don't have to be that hard-working.
I make a few phone calls and
earn more than my salary.
It's gambling. The stake is too high!
Life is gambling.
Your future depends on
how much you put in now!
Hubby, look at my bag. Good?
Women are happier with bags
than with husbands.
You know nothing about bags.
This is a limited edition.
Only ten of them in the world.
Your limited edition hubby
is one of a kind too!
An accumulator allows you to buy
in stocks at a 70% discount.
You can sign a half-year, 9-month,
or one-year contract.
Best of all,
you only need one third of the principal.
If the stock rises by 5%,
the contract will be terminated.
Profits...
...are in your pockets.
- I don't get it.
- Never mind!
Join the game if you dare!
- Come visit us in Shanghai,
- Thanks for coming.
- Mrs. Ho.
- Take care.
We can ¿o to Hangzhou together.
I love Hangzhou.
Come in September and we can have
some seasonal crabs.
- Thank you!
- Yes! Crabs are so tasty!
Thank you everyone again.
Thank you.
Thank you Ms. Chang and Mr. Ho.
Is your inside information true?
Do you think I would lie?
Is it a good time to ¿o public then?
It's time to see what we've got
and to revamp our company.
Some will leave, while others will stay,
It's going to be bad but you can
thrive in adversity.
Don't worry,
thriving in adversity is my forte!
Good.
Ms. Chang, please sign here.
A calls me Mrs. Ho.
B calls me Mrs. Ho.
Where's she from? I don't know.
Mrs. Ho, heigh-ho, heigh-ho!
Such music to my ears
makes me glow.
Chung-ping,
the way they address me
as Mrs. Ho
is so natural.
Hello?
A perfect battle.
We've defeated the enemies totally.
I just sent them back to hotel.
Mr. Greenberg is meeting you on Tuesday.
Good job!
See you on Monday.
Wait,
I'm coming over.
I drank too much.
Don't want to drive all the way home.
Sorry.
Not tonight.
Don't drink and drive.
Take care.
Good night.
Do you care at all?
It's David.
He said everything was OK.
Be careful with MADAM E's
financial situation.
What do you mean?
In a recent wine auction,
they've sold all their best wine.
Really?
Short of cash?
I don't know.
We should be careful.
We can negotiate in another way.
All depends on you, Mrs. Ho.
Good evening, sir.
Coffee and a pack of cigarettes.
Please place your Octopus Card here.
All set.
Your coffee is over there.
This way, madam.
Cash or Octopus Card?
Place your card here.
Hey!
You shouldn't be drinking and driving.
Why don't you take a rest on the couch?
Leave after you're no longer drunk.
Hey!
Don't think too much.
We're just colleagues.
You're drunk for our company.
Dong calling
Vibration to loud
How was the champagne and wine?
Steak should've been good too.
Have you looked into MADAM E's
sales figures in the States?
We only have the Hong Kong sales figures.
So you don't know?
Let me tell you.
This brand is famous
but it's declining in American,
even South Asian market.
They're facing fierce competition,
but without a sense of direction.
The name is its sole valuable asset.
So, what do you think?
You haven't done your homework
but at least you have some thoughts on it?
Stock market is looking good,
continuing the rising trend
for the past two days.
The Hang Seng Index hit
a top of 20,909 points
HSI temporarily
reports at 20,803 points.
Turnover of 33.4 billion.
Have you come up with new ideas?
I don't ask you to be ingenious
but at least do use your brain.
David!
Stop looking at the stocks!
Dong calling
No cellular phone during meeting.
Sorry, it's family emergency.
Talk outside.
Morning. Here.
Morning.
You're late! Take it.
Go in as
if nothing happened.
Give me you bag. Go ¿o ¿o!
Tell Chang Ms. Yip would like to see her.
Ms. Chang...
What if MADAME stopped selling cosmetics?
They would just ¿o out of business.
What are you getting at?
I saw on the Internet greeting cards
manufacturer Hallmark
started selling clothes.
I was wondering what kind of
clothes they would sell.
Ms. Chang, Ms. Yip would like to see you.
Wearing their clothes, you would look like
a Christmas card.
What if MADAME
started selling lingerie?
What's so funny?
Does she want to partner
with MADAME or not?
What's on her mind?
What she says may
not be what she thinks.
You'd better be careful.
We can only guess what she wants.
Her mind is fickle with emotion.
She may think yes but says no.
We'd better watch out.
Naive as you are,
how can you read her heart?
You're also a big shot,
as powerful as her art.
She seems cool. Isn't she lonely?
She's a supermodel.
We worship her. We obey her.
She's a judge.
She dispenses justice.
Can she feel nothing?
She's a valuable investment,
worth buying in and being with.
To become her confidant,
shall we write her a love letter
or concede defeat?
I don't want to become her.
She seems admirable
but deep in her heart
Guess! Under her nose,
what are we allowed to think?
Guess! In her mind, what does she want?
What's on her mind?
"Kat Ho"
Is this the final version
of the stakeholders?
Seems to be different from
what Mr. Ho has told me.
This is the final version
from the head office.
Should be right and won't be changed.
Your name is on the
senior executives page.
The subway was so crowded today.
I almost couldn't get on the train.
You don't believe me, either?
You could've asked your driver
to drive you here.
Kat, who are you?
Your dad is selling siu mei,
but you have a driver.
You carry a branded bag
to ¿o directly to 71st floor!
You speak better English than David.
Who are you?
If I tell you the truth,
will you keep my secret?
My dad doesn't sell siu mei.
Actually...
He drives for the rich people
living in the peak.
He loves me so much that he secretly
drives me to work sometimes.
Do you understand now?
Too many lies and too little love.
Am I blushing?
She's mysterious and beautiful.
How can she become my close friend?
The rich family is kind to us.
They gave me the branded bag
that they didn't want.
The direct elevator to
71st floor was one-off.
That security guard is my dad's friend.
I was about to be late so he helped me.
He almost got fired because of it.
My better English comes from hard work.
I'm the only child.
I want to prove that
I'm a good daughter.
Do you understand?
Yes.
We all want to prove
ourselves to our families.
Do you believe me?
I'm not myself.
I don't like my real self.
Do you believe I like myself only
if I'm unlike myself?
I do because I love you too much.
I believe you.
What are you angry at?
Told you to sell the stocks. Did you?
Dare I not?
I hate myself for not being capable
nor informed enough for you.
Know you place. Don't ask for more.
I got what I asked for.
I should've known better.
Lee Xiang is still green.
With me, he'll be bad.
With you, he'll become as immoral as me.
Give him
a chance to live!
You pretend to be kind?
David, we are the best partners.
How can we harm each other?
I just said he reminded me of you.
What are you afraid of?
Don't be afraid
Asian stocks plummet.
Japan stocks falls 5%
to 3-year low.
Korean stocks drop over 6%.
Taiwan stocks drop almost 5%.
The offshore stock
market drops so much that
The People's Bank of
China cuts interest rates,
but it doesn't help
the Mainland stocks.
Shanghai Stock Exchange Composite Index
falls below 2000 points
to 21-month low.
The U.S. government is likely
to take over the biggest two...
The U.S. government is considering
a bailout plan.
Their stocks plunged
and the stock market suffered.
This account should be
in 2006 rather than 2007.
No, this account was
forwarded to us in 2007
from the head office.
What do you mean?
This was forwarded to
us from the head office.
Are we waiting for
the head office accounts?
It's stated clearly here.
OK, if the account belongs to 2007,
then 2006 should be all completed.
Let's begin looking at 2007.
Sorry can we take a break?
I'd like to...
We can't sell it now.
If we sell it now, we're finished.
Why?
Why does it plunge so rapidly?
Didn't your analysis indicate
it would rise by 5%?
Damn! Aren't you a financial specialist?
Are you alright?
I have medicine.
David, may I smoke with you?
You alright?
Sorry.
I don't smoke.
Then why you smoke?
People smoke, whether happy or not.
What for?
Lucky that it's just a cigarette.
Where's your hometown, Sophie?
Your hometown?
My hometown has good
feng shui. A good place.
Youthful dreams carry me
away from the old home.
The road in my hometown
is not as wide as here.
Yet people on the road
don't clash with one another.
It's a desire-free paradise there.
Time is slow and flowing there.
- In my hometown,
- There are...
- we study the colors
- meandering brooks
- of the heavens.
- lush reeds.
We read the origins
of the universe.
- Facing adversity, we fall in love
- We grow old here.
- with the old home.
- It turns into the old home.
There's adversity
- Everywhere is the same.
- everywhere.
- There's adversity everywhere.
- There's discontent everywhere.
The desire-free paradise
is to blame because
we have too much time
to imagine and desire,
to imagine and venture.
Venture out into the old home
that buried our youth.
Where to venture?
Where to rush? Where to be busy?
Where to imagine?
Call the factories according to the list
Ask in detail about
their scale of production,
their maximal capacity
and minimal order.
I'll ask David
to visit the factories with you.
You will observe the
factories and executives.
That's the best way to learn.
Got you.
Don't tell your colleagues about this.
Hello?
Is David here?
David and Kar-ling are out of the office.
Yes.
Haven't found David?
I think he killed himself!
Oh! My feet ache from rubbing.
Howard's gone.
No one can get my
battle shoes back for me.
Kat,
¿o get them tomorrow.
Awesome!
You're a real mimic.
Kar-ling's far more
capable than we imagine.
Her voluptuous figure
does a disservice to her.
Don't look down upon women with big boobs.
I got brain as well as boobs.
Kar-ling, you're jealous
of wise women like us.
We use brain rather than breasts to think.
Lee Xiang!
Learn from David.
Be smart
and adventurous.
Lee Xiang,
don't tell others
what I've told you.
Understand?
What did she tell you?
I can't tell you.
Not interested at all!
Nothing. She...
She asked me to visit lingerie factories.
MADAME is into the lingerie industry?
Have we signed the contract?
I don't know.
Finally we meet.
I've heard so much about you,
Madame Winnie Chang.
How are you, Mr. Greenberg?
Very well, thanks.
Only three of you?
Don't you think it's enough?
You met David, Lee Xiang.
We don't really need any
unnecessary sit-in staff, do we?
As you say.
Do you know why she wants us all out?
I don't know.
Because we can only know
what she wants us to know.
We only need to know
what we're supposed to know.
Don't think that a proposal
can make you succeed.
Not till you drop!
Feeling a sense of achievement?
Being in the same meeting with us?
No.
No?
You dare not say yes?
- I look down upon you.
- Yes.
You even made me translate your proposal.
You want to replace me?
Chang said you
reminded her of a younger me.
I don't quite remember.
If you want to destroy someone,
give him lots of benefits...
...and then take them all away.
Promotion and destruction are
two sides of the same coin.
Remember my words.
Nice meeting you, Mr. Greenberg.
The pleasure is all mine.
Mr. Greenberg,
it's my great pleasure
doing business with you.
MADAM E's future can't rely on
the traditional marketplace.
Bygone benefits are bygone.
Facing unknown crisis,
we need to attack as well as defend.
MADAM E's market is threatened.
Let's create a new beginning.
A new beginning Ho
Chung-ping isn't aware of.
A brand-new independence.
MADAM E's new product:
Taking care of you, thinking of you.
The body-Warming, heart-warming
MADAME lingerie.
Morning, Chairman.
Morning!
Lee Xiang?
Have a seat.
I came as soon as I received your call.
Am I late?
People speak highly of you,
young, energetic, proactive, and sincere.
It was Ms. Chang who
gave me the opportunity.
She told me you have
lots of innovative ideas
I want to hear it from you in person.
You mean the heart-warming
MADAME lingerie?
Heart-warming rather than body-warming?
Ms. Chang says women
love heart-warming lingerie.
I have a proposal here.
I've been visiting factories
and comparing prices.
May I have a look?
Sure.
No wonder MADAME is happy.
We have fewer hands in the company
and need to open a newline.
Are you overworking?
No.
The team in the company
takes care of MADAM E's cosmetics
As for the new product,
Ms. Chang asked David and I
to produce it in small quantities.
Our colleagues know nothing about it.
Business secret.
The meeting between
us is business secret, too.
Don't tell anyone.
Sure.
Young man!
I knew I could believe you
from the instant I saw your eyes.
Really?
Thank you, Chairman!
Thank you.
Hello?
How was the deal with MADAME?
Too early to tell!
What did they say?
They're tough and demanding.
Not necessarily a sure success.
Are they?
Yes!
The market isn't good.
There's no hurry.
Right.
I agree with you.
OK, bye.
The wind blowing from the
north-southwest is invisible.
I want to ask which
pig is not vulnerable.
The League of Lehman Brothers
Victims Protests on the Street
Look, the big gray
wolf goes hunting.
Why eat and sleep and
hear only the thundering?
The wind blowing from the
north-southwest is inedible.
I hear the big gray
wolf fears thundering.
It is the heart of the most
brilliant pig that is in turmoil.
The one who doesn't stop eating
ends up in the wolf's entrails.
Look, who's the storyteller
that fears the wind?
Look, who doubts the story
after hearing the story?
The wind blowing from the
north-southwest is changing.
The pig grows smarter after
hearing the shout of a tiger.
Mrs. Ho is awake!
What a wonderful day.
- Look, who's the one
- Hello?
who ends up devouring the wolf?
Who can tell between predator and prey,
between pig and wolf?
Early Hong Kong morning,
the fourth largest U.S
investment bank
Lehman Brothers suddenly
declares bankruptcy.
Japan, Hong Kong, Singapore
and other major Asian stock markets
crashed when market opened this morning.
HSI plunge 1,052 points
The lowest record of
the past 22 months.
Bye.
Prepare defibrillator 200 joules.
200 joules ready!
Charge.
200 joules, clear.
360 joules, charge.
Clear.
We're late.
She had been awake for only 15 minutes.
Ten minutes, five minutes,
even one minute.
I wish I could've made it.
She's unwilling to let ¿o because of us.
We're family.
My love toward you and
Mom will never change.
You always say so.
I can't pretend not to hear the gossip.
I can't pretend Chang isn't there.
Daddy,
do you love Chang?
Do you know what's on her mind?
What she's doing behind you?
What should I know?
David's always with her.
The naive Lee Xiang is busy
with her secret MADAME plan.
Do you know it?
There are things I don't need to know.
There are things I don't want to know.
If I want to know,
who can stop me?
I knew it.
I knew you can't stand being lonely.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
Is this the love we used to believe in?
Imagine you passing through
the crowd towards me.
Should I look forward to it
or fear waiting for you?
Love is between "already" and "not
yet," between presence and absence.
You just stand in the wind imagining
where I could've been.
I'm looking at you looking at the
distance between our gaze.
I can't hear what you're hearing.
Can I truly love you
without really knowing you?
I love "my ideal self. "
Not that I don't care.
I do care about what
lies ahead of us.
Not that I'm not
willing to say I do.
But I prefer to remain silent.
We're not yet in a relationship
but already afraid of ending it.
Not that I don't worry.
But I prefer to be carefree.
When I'm imagining you,
your eyes keep me company.
When I'm looking at you,
your face encounters mine.
I don't really know you.
I don't know if I've been in love
with you for a long time.
We love "our ideal selves."
We love "our ideal selves" only
because you love them too.
I've been waiting for you
for over half an hour.
I missed the previous ferry.
Please don't be angry.
I am too busy today.
Do you know how many lingerie
factories I visited today?
Look at the camera
It's a gift from Chang.
If you're busy, don't ask me out.
Why didn't you call and tell me that
you would be late?
Let me take you to a pizza restaurant.
No, I'm going home.
Let me see you home.
No.
Why don't you let me see you home?
I want to see where you live,
what's your daily life like?
Is your family going to like me?
Lee Xiang,
you've changed.
Kat, I haven't.
I haven't changed.
I'm honest with you.
I told you everything I knew.
Is being honest so difficult?
Isn't this the principle
we've learned at home and at school?
You mean I've changed?
Hello? Mr. Lin.
Are you out of your mind?
I've looking for you in your factory
and you were not there!
Please show up tomorrow.
I'm waiting for your bank slips.
Have to submit the
"Profit and Loss" of 2007.
Let me see.
See what?
Let me see if the account is right.
I broke up with Dong.
I decided to break up with Dong.
Is the account right?
I made the decision
and was sad.
I really feel sad.
The only thing
I wanted to do is find you
and tell you that I'm not marrying him.
Great!
- Is it great?
- Yes.
Is it?
We're the perfect match.
You're the woman of my life.
I won't let you feel lonely anymore.
Help me out of this crisis.
Fill in the number.
Change the total number.
I'll find the receipts later.
What are you talking about?
What am I talking about?
About our future!
You're the only woman who cares for me.
After IPO, Chang will have other plans.
As soon as she leaves,
I'm the one who can replace her.
You'll never see me again
if anything goes wrong now.
Or you don't want to see me again?
I'm so stupid.
You've never loved me.
I thought you did.
OK.
Do you have any idea
what you're asking is illegal?
It's temporary.
I'll put the money back soon.
What?
You're taking advantage of me.
Your relationship with Chang is dubious.
If we're in a dubious relationship,
I would just ask her to solve this.
Because of you, I want to keep
a distance from her.
I want everyone to know I love you.
Don't bite your nails. Fix it for me.
I'll take full responsibility.
Don't bite your nails!
- Hit me...
- Stop it. That's enough.
If I didn't hit you,
how could I see who you are?
Look at me.
Let's see each other clearly...
We are in need of each other, Sophie.
You need someone
who knows you better.
I won't leave you.
Help me...
Help us.
I need your love,
just as you need my devotion.
Mutual love
- means keeping promises
- Mutual love
- which are priceless.
- Is a fair solution.
Perhaps
- only you know my heart's motion.
- Only I know your heart's motion.
- Let's face difficulties together
- Let's strive together
- and start a love revolution.
There was a time
when we were attracted to dreams.
When we were in the mood,
we had no worries.
Now, we can only
rely on each other.
Why don't we confide in each other
until the sky's cleared up?
- Deep as our friendship is,
- Merciless as our world is,
- we can exchange love.
- we can exchange more than sympathy.
- Let's sing love songs
- The more we sing,
- to each other.
- the more music to our ears.
- We're made for each other.
- You have my word.
We're made for each other.
- We shouldn't waste the beautiful future.
- We will win the beautiful future.
In the remaining days,
we will depend on and
believe in each other.
Hello?
I'm sorry. David is not in office.
Securities firm?
Yes.
Hello? Jones & Sunn.
Sorry, David is out.
OK.
Excuse me, Sophie, please come here.
I need the one for June, 2007.
It's the wrong file.
Morning.
David is out.
Yes, he's out. Who are you?
The bank?
Hello?
Tell David Wang
if he can't return the money by Friday,
we'll ¿o look for him in the company.
Let him decide whether
he wants his left or right hand.
Who are you?
Why the A.C. is so cold?
The A.C. is centralized.
Of course I know!
Can't you turn it off?
Idiot!
Have you found Mr. Greenberg?
Mr. Greenberg,
anybody knows where Mr. Greenberg is?
He's been missing for several days.
Kar-ling!
Yes!
Where is Mr. Greenberg?
I don't know.
Where did you hide him?
In your skirt or underwear?
Find him before you get off work today!
- Lee Xiang!
- Yes.
- Got a cigarette?
Let's ¿o.
Quick.
You've heard what she said about me.
You all heard it, right?
I resign now.
Kar-ling!
Kar-ling, calm down!
- It's hard to find a job
- What are you doing?
- In such bad environment!
- Give it back to me!
- Calm down.
- Give it back.
I can't bear it anymore!
Kar-ling!
Your shoes.
Chang's enemies have to leave.
I'm not going to be
others' obstacles.
We want a better job but
the outside world is ghastly.
After buying all the famous brands,
I find my existence not necessary.
Why this tolerance if it only
leads to subservience?
I toil here for my
future independence.
for my future affluence.
for my future success.
for a beautiful future
in the eyes of others.
The up-and-coming Lee Xiang wants to
replace the missing David.
It's said that David
owes an enormous debt.
A million...just a million
Can I pay you back in one week?
And brought Sophie along with him.
Listen, the loyal
chant is charming.
Listen, bonuses are
music to my ears.
Look, with one heart we'll build
a financial empire.
We're one big family.
Pay you half a million first.
The rest comes later.
I only got half a million.
You get nothing if I die!
Ms. Chang, we've received
the order from Mr. Ho
to call off the IPO.
How come?
You should ask the accounting firm!
I shouldn't comment on this.
Why are you taking all our documents?
Mr. Ho, please
Sorry, Ms. Chang, Mr. Ho went abroad
the other day.
Where? When will he be back?
Sorry, I don't know.
What do you want?
What's this?
My resignation letter.
Let me tell you,
I can fire anyone,
except for you!
You're not firing me. I want to resign.
I want to leave.
Do you remember who hired you?
It is Chairman Ho Chung-ping.
As a CEO, I can't let you ¿o.
If you think you can
come and ¿o as you wish,
maybe you're too naive!
I can decide for myself.
I tender the resignation
only out of politeness.
Tell me
when you can decide for yourself.
You were arranged
to work here!
I suggest you work hard
rather than be angry with me.
Think of it as a way
to pay back to your Dad.
Go!
Everyone is looking at you.
Your dad doesn't want people
to know you're his daughter.
You can tell everyone that
I urged you to stay sincerely.
And may offer you a better salary.
So you decided to stay.
Chang calling
Sophie calling
Sophie.
David, where are you?
Help me transfer five million to the bank.
Two more days and we'll be free.
How can I have five million?
Our company has called off the IPO.
Use the company's money
to solve this problem for me,
help me.
Otherwise we'll both be finished.
The accountants have
taken the accounts away.
Where are you?
You will incriminate all of us!
Give me 5 million!
No! 20 million has gone.
David, come back!
David, you must figure something out!
Quick, figure something out!
You must...
What for?
I've been betrayed by
my own price.
Why has my dream
destroyed me before I arise?
What for? Hugs and rewards?
Where's my love?
Contracts and promises?
What are the consequences?
What for?
I don't want to choose
what I'm offered.
What for?
I didn't expect I would
be dying to survive.
Sophie, what happened?
Nothing.
Sophie, did the accountants from
Grey & Young tell you anything?
I'll ¿o back to work.
Sorry, I'll ¿o back to work.
What happened?
Ms. Chang, don't answer it.
David calling
Sophie, you won't want
me to beg that woman.
You won't.
Help me.
Wait on the rooftop.
We will solve the problem.
I changed my personality
to realize my unchangeable dream.
Eventually my personality
changed my sense of morality.
I've built my connections
and then kidnapped by them.
ls the deal worth it?
The borrowed desire
is so magnificent
that I've forgotten
I'm living like shit.
What for?
The balloon I blow up blows up
before it reaches the sky.
What for?
The tomorrow I've invested in
tortures me before I enjoy it.
David.
What for? Hugs and rewards?
Where's my love?
Contracts and promises?
What are the consequences?
What for?
I don't want to choose
what I'm offered.
What for?
I didn't expect I would
be dying to survive.
Told you cleverness would be your undoing.
You just wouldn't listen. Look at you!
Help me.
My help harms you.
No, I won't make the same mistake.
I'll listen to you in the future.
I need your love and
you my devotion.
Mutual love is a fair solution.
Only you know my heart's motion.
Let's strive together...
...and start a love revolution.
Police department?
I'd like to take this opportunity
to thank you for your hard work
and to clarify our company's
future development.
Due to the financial crisis
and unstable market,
the IPO has been temporarily called off.
But during the process,
our excellent accounting team
has found out some incidents
that shouldn't have happened.
This is absolutely the fault
The executive in charge
should be held accountable.
I feel regret for our colleagues
who have left us
and those who
will be leaving.
Come!
Let's drink for parting.
We toast for the past
as well as for the future!
I have an important announcement to make.
The head office has struck a deal with
MADAME Chairman Mr. Cohen
to establish MADAME CHINA
and open new lines of products
besides cosmetics.
The first plan is to produce
heart-warming lingerie for women.
I want to acknowledge
Lee Xiang
for coming up with
such a great idea.
We need more young talent.
I have a habit that
if I encounter new recruits,
I always pay attention to their eyes.
Because in their eyes,
I can see energy and fire!
We need
younger leader
to succeed in fierce competition.
Let me introduce you to the new leader
of Jones & Sunn and MADAME CHINA.
My daughter, Kat Ho.
Kat, come here.
I think you are all familiar with her.
She is your good colleague
and my good daughter.
It's not easy to get acquainted.
It's not easy
to work together, either.
We should cherish
and help each other.
We don't have to feel sad
if someone is leaving.
Don't know if I'm getting senile.
I've been feeling sentimental.
I feel that we haven't had chance
to say goodbye properly.
We should seize the present moment
and reminisce
about the good old days.
Nothing is better than the present moment.
Carpe diem!
Do YOU agree?
Help me.
I need you.
You lied to me.
I didn't mean to.
- You!
- You know Chang will leave
because you've betrayed her.
I didn't.
You didn't mean it.
- Winnie.
- Stop it.
You've taught me everything.
I know what I'm supposed to do.
Let me enjoy our last dance.
I didn't mean it.
This is not my intention.
I know.
We didn't mean it.
Right.
You win.
Ms. Chang, I'd like to explain.
Goodbye, Ms. Chang.
You've passed your three-month probation?
Long time ago.
Farewell!
Young man,
what's your name again?
Lee Xiang!
Lee for Ang Lee. Xiang for dream.
Hope you'll remember it.