Sailing along
With the moon
In our eyes
Sailing on
To a paradise
On an island with you
See how the sea
Throws a kiss
To the shore
How I long
To belong
In your arms ever more
On an island with you
On an island
With you
- Like it?
- Love it.
Get away from him, malo.
I will not get away from him.
Oh, yes, you will. He belongs to me.
If he belongs to you,
let's see you take him away from me.
I don't have to take him away from you.
I already have.
- I'm sorry, I forgot my next line.
- All right. Cut it.
- Print the last two takes, Jane.
- Okay.
I'm sorry, George.
I just couldn't seem to remember.
Don't worry, Roz. We'll pick it up later.
You were supposed to say that
when you love a man, you fight for him.
I shouldn't like to have you
forget that line. Ever.
You know I wouldn't forget, Rick. Ever.
Where's Buckley?
Probably on the phone,
trying to explain to Mr. Fitz...
...why we only got three scenes yesterday
instead of six.
Yes, Mr. Fitz.
I know, Mr. Fitz.
But we couldn't get
any more scenes yesterday.
We ran out of sun.
Maybe it was shining in Hollywood,
but it wasn't shining here.
It came out for a little while,
then disappeared.
But, Mr. Fitz,
I'm only the assistant director.
What do you want me to do,
tell it to go out and come in again?
All right, Mr. Fitz, I'll try.
But we couldn't get any more scenes.
All right, Mr. Fitz.
Goodbye, Mr. Fitz.
How do you like that? Now I'm responsible
for the sun going down.
Yes, sir.
Get me Lieutenant Kingslee.
Lieutenant Kingslee's
in the barbershop.
Barbershop? That's ridiculous.
They got barbers in the Navy.
He'd better not put that
on his expense account.
Oh, Mr. Buckley, we're ready.
Mrs. Peabody, we don't shoot
the wedding scene for two weeks.
Go ahead, Penelope.
Something old, something new
Something borrowed, something blue.
That's what every bride should do.
Too British.
She's supposed to be an American kid.
But, Grandmother,
how can one possibly be too British?
Lieutenant. Lieutenant, we're waiting.
Looks like you're in dry dock for repairs.
Oh, just getting shipshape. Gotta uphold
the honor of the Navy, you know.
That's not the Navy I know.
- Besides, you're holding up production.
- Oh, how is Miss Rennolds?
- Fine, fine.
- Is she expecting me?
Lieutenant, Miss Rennolds is expecting
a technical advisor, not a leading man.
Well, how is she feeling?
Fine. Hey, wait a minute,
I just answered that.
Listen, admiral, you're here to check
on uniforms, not the leading lady.
That's right, uniforms.
But she is beautiful, isn't she?
Sure, she's beautiful,
so stop wasting time and come on.
Wait a minute.
Have you got some change?
- Sure.
- Take care of them, will you, for me?
Use a little discretion, son.
If you must go, Bill,
please take me with you.
Sorry, Tanya, not this time.
Maybe when I come back.
All right, cut it.
- Where's Buckley? Isn't he back yet?
- I'm right behind you, George.
And here's your Navy. Lieutenant Kingslee,
Mr. Blaine, our director.
How do you do?
- Well, how do you do, lieutenant?
- How do you do, sir?
- This is Jane.
- Hello.
- Eddie. Martha.
- This is Yvonne.
- Hello.
Miss Rennolds, Mr. Montez.
Lieutenant Kingslee.
How do you do, lieutenant?
Hello, Miss Rennolds.
- I thought I'd never get here.
- Hello, lieutenant.
- Oh, you haven't changed a bit.
- Haven't I?
- It seems like only yesterday.
- Yesterday?
Yes, yes, of course.
- You don't know how much...
- Lieutenant.
Never mind the tête-à-tête.
Just tell us if the ribbons are right.
The ribbons, lieutenant, are over here.
Over here.
Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
They're authentic, but upside down.
- Do you mind if I fix them?
- No, not at all.
I am grateful you're here
to see that everything is authentic.
So am I, Mr. Montez.
- Thank you very much.
- You're welcome.
An American Naval lieutenant
with that accent?
So he was born in South America
and joined the Navy.
Don't worry about it.
- What does Miss Rennolds think?
- She picked him.
Places, everybody.
All right, Martha, she's pretty enough.
I'll let you know when I'm ready.
- I'm ready.
- Places.
Are you ready, boss?
- Roll them.
- Action, please.
I love you, Bill.
I'll always love you.
You can't leave me. I won't let you.
You're beautiful, Tanya.
Beautiful and dangerous,
which makes it all the harder to leave.
Then take me with you.
No, Tanya.
Maybe sometime in the future.
But for the present,
I'm going to have to forget you.
- Oh, no.
- Cut it.
Something wrong, lieutenant?
- Wrong? I'm sorry, sir...
- Lieutenant, please.
You're here to worry about ribbons,
uniforms, the plane, that's all.
Just a minute. If something's wrong
with the scene, I wanna know what it is.
What's bothering you, lieutenant?
Well, sir, so long as you asked me.
She's a beautiful girl...
...and, well, if she were mine,
I'd kiss her and take her with me.
- Oh, you would?
- Yes, sir.
Tell you what you do,
you play this scene.
After all, Rick's playing a Navy pilot.
We'd like to be authentic.
- Do you mind, Roz?
- Of course not. Come on, lieutenant.
Stand right over here, lieutenant.
Jane, come here.
Give him your line, Roz.
I love you, Bill. I'll always love you.
Give the lieutenant his line, Jane.
"You're beautiful, Tanya.
Beautiful and dangerous,
which makes it all the harder to leave."
You're beautiful, Tanya.
Beautiful and dangerous,
which makes it all the harder to leave.
Well, then, take me with you.
"No, Tanya.
Maybe sometime in the future."
You're the most wonderful girl
in the world.
I've never stopped thinking about you
from the first time we met.
I've wondered if you felt the same way.
Hoped that you did.
All right, lieutenant, that'll do.
Thanks for showing us
how it's done in the Navy.
Oh, you're welcome, sir.
I'd be glad to do it the rest of my life.
He must have been at sea a long time.
All right, boys and girls,
let's try another take.
Well, come on, Buckley.
What are we waiting for?
Martha, any time. Any time.
I'll let you know.
There's a million lieutenants in the Navy,
and I had to pick you.
You don't know how grateful I am, sir.
You've won yourself a friend.
That ought to teach me not to gamble.
Don't be afraid of my little Chihuahua
He's only a little wow-wow-wa
He never will fight
And he never will bite
Till you give him tequila and agua
He's not as long as your shoe or huarache
But one look from him and he's gotcha
And I'll feel morose
When he tells me adiós
On the day that he meets his muchacha
Why, he's smarter than a rabbit
And wiser than an old owl
And when he's not held close
In someone's arms, he'll howl
Though he's as strong as a big caballero
And wilder than any bolero
He's scared of the dark
And I know that he'll bark
At the drop of your newest sombrero
He's not as long as your shoe or huarache
One look from him and he's gotcha
Oh, I'll feel morose
When he tells me adiós
Why, that's the dog song
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Tonight we have with us
some of Hollywood's finest personalities.
They're here making the motion picture
On an Island with You.
First, I want you to meet
that very lovely lady of the screen...
...Miss Rosalind Rennolds.
And sitting close to her,
and I don't blame him...
...is her costar and soon-to-be-husband,
Señor Don Ricardo Montez.
And sitting at the same table
is a man who works behind the scenes.
The guiding handle of the picture.
He's a man that works very hard,
but we never see him.
One of our finest directors,
Mr. George Blaine.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
we invite you to dance.
Don't you worry, Yvonne,
he didn't introduce me either.
Would you like your entrée now?
If it comes with the dinner,
just bring it on, à la carte.
Excuse me.
- Hello, Mr. Buckley.
- I know what you're up to. It's no good.
Look, you joined the Navy to see the world,
not Miss Rennolds.
I just wanna ask for a dance.
She's got someone to dance with.
Now, come on, before you manugle around
and get us both into trouble.
This is a nice, cozy table for two.
You and me.
If you wanna dance with someone,
why don't you ask Yvonne?
Because I wanna dance
with Miss Rennolds.
Why not Yvonne?
She's a wonderful terpsichorean.
And besides, she's a wonderful dancer.
You know what?
I think she's kind of lonesome.
Hello.
They're very much in love, aren't they?
Yes, I'm sure they are.
They're gonna be married soon.
Very soon.
He's very lucky to have someone
as wonderful as Roz.
They're both very lucky.
You know, the word "lucky"
is misused so often, Yvonne.
You see, we waste a lot of life
wanting something that somebody else has.
Life isn't quite that long.
Yes.
That's what my grandmother
used to tell me.
- Oh, that was wonderful, Rick.
- Thank you.
- Would you like to dance, Yvonne?
- Do you mind, Roz?
- Of course not.
- I'd love to.
You got everything straight?
You're gonna forget Roz
and concentrate on Yvonne.
Oh, waiter.
Bring us two double maraschino specials.
- Where you going?
- I'm gonna dance with Miss Rennolds.
Oh, son.
Never mind. Make it one bromo.
- Good evening, Mr. Blaine.
- Hello, lieutenant.
- Miss Rennolds, may I have this dance?
- No, thank you.
No?
- Well, you do dance, don't you?
- Well, of course I dance, but not tonight.
It'd mean a great deal to me,
and I've waited such a long time.
I'm afraid you're gonna have to wait
a little longer.
Good night, lieutenant.
Miss Rennolds, the music's wonderful
and everybody's dancing...
Look, lieutenant,
I just don't care to dance.
Maybe some other time, huh?
Lady said good night, lieutenant.
Thank you, Miss Rennolds.
Maybe some other time.
Why didn't you dance with him, Roz?
I don't know. After what happened
this afternoon on the set...
...I thought it was better
not to encourage him.
- Was I rude?
- Let's just say you were firm.
You know, he does look familiar to me.
I wish I could remember
where I've seen him before.
Rick's a wonderful dancer, isn't he?
Yes, he is.
Don't feel so bad, kid.
You made a mistake.
We all have a foolish five minutes
when we make mistakes.
I haven't made any mistakes.
Just give me a little time.
Time for what?
I'll dance with her yet.
Lieutenant, look...
...if it'll make you happy,
I'll dance with you.
What's the matter, lose a customer?
No. Mr. Cugat lost his little dog, Chita.
She always runs away.
You mean to say he's upset
over losing that cockroach?
Lieutenant, did you just kick me?
Of course not.
Now, wait a minute.
You'd better get back to Mr. Cugat.
You know, you could be mistaken
for an hors d'oeuvre.
Oh, there you are.
You shouldn't let this mouse
run around the floor frightening women.
A mouse? You call my Chita mouse?
I want you to know that my Chita
is a full-blooded, pedigreed canine...
...fathered by Canary Fluff.
Fathered by Canary Fluff?
And you're mad at me
for calling it names?
I think you should apologize.
You hurt my feelings.
I hurt your feelings?
What about mine?
I was sitting at the table too
when you made those introductions.
Well, when you are a famous man,
I'll introduce you too.
I admit, I'm nobody now...
...but years ago, the name of Buckley
meant something in show business.
Used to be a trio:
Clayton, Jackson and Buckley.
Ask any booking agent.
We headlined every theater
from coast to coast.
And we played Europe too.
Mr. Cugat, we did all right in vaudeville.
Mr. Buckley, vaudeville is dead.
Don't say that.
Vaudeville isn't dead, it's just resting.
Why, in little towns all over the country,
before radio and pictures...
...it was their only source
of entertainment.
Mr. Cugat, maybe vaudeville
didn't shape the destiny of our country...
...but it certainly gave it
a sense of humor.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...a while ago I introduced to you
some very charming people.
But Cugat is very sorry...
...because he forgot to introduce to you
a great personality...
...a member of once-very-famous
vaudeville team:
Buckley of Clayton, Jackson and Buckley.
Let's give him a big hand.
- Let's go with a tango, boys.
- Thank you, Mr. Cugat. I'm very flattered.
Yes, I'm very flattered.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...l'm gonna sing a song
I sang many years ago.
Yes, it was many years ago
that I had an argument with Ziegfeld.
Corner Broadway and 43rd.
Ziegfeld said, "Do you know who I am?"
I said, "Do you know who I am?"
He said, "Who are you?"
I said nothing. I was trapped.
But it makes no difference
What I started out to say
This is what I wish to convey
Now, I know darn well
I could do without Broadway
But could Broadway do without me?
No! No!
Herald Square. Times Square.
Columbus Circle. 96th.
What happened?
I must have passed my station.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
You're supposed to follow the music,
not chase it all over the joint.
Herald Square. Times Square.
Columbus Circle.
It brings back memories
of the mustache cup...
...the barbershop quartet...
...and lest we forget, the bustle,
the secret of that era.
One night,
after finishing my performance...
...I was leaving the stage door
with a beautiful gal on my arm.
It's possible.
My nose was much younger in those days.
I stepped into my hansom cab.
The lady preceded me, of course.
And as my trusty steed
turned his head for instructions...
...I grabbed the reins,
and this is what I said:
Jog along, Mr. Dobbin
And keep this carriage a-bobbin'
We can't be late
For we have a date
I'm taking Miss Mary to the ball
My, oh, my, but she's pretty
The sweetest gal in the city
How grand she'll look
When her picture's took
I'm taking Miss Mary to the ball
- Gee, romantic, isn't it?
- Sure is.
See those two lovebirds
sitting on that branch over there?
- I sure do.
- Well, doesn't that give you any ideas?
Yes, but do you think that branch
is strong enough to hold the both of us?
Jog along, Mr. Dobbin
And keep this carriage a-bobbin'
We can't be late
For it's her first date
I'm taking Miss Mary to the ball
Everybody!
Jog along, Mr. Dobbin
Let me hear you.
And keep this carriage a-bobbin'
More melody.
We can't be late
For it's her first date
We're taking Miss Mary to the ball
Jog along, Mr. Dobbin
It's very melodious.
And keep this carriage a-bobbin'
We can't be late
For it's her first date
We're taking Miss Mary
A very merry Mary
We're taking Miss Mary to the ball
Mr. Buckley, I can call on you again, no?
Mr. Cugat,
you can call on me again, yes.
But I still say it's a mouse.
- I can't believe it.
- What do you mean?
I used to get twice as much applause
when I played the Palace.
Oh, so that's it.
Come on, lieutenant.
What you need is a change of scenery.
- What's that?
- Courtesy of the house.
- Is that a drink?
- Sure.
Never touch the stuff.
Drink is the greatest wrecker of men
since women was invented.
Oh, come, now, Buckley,
what have you got against women?
Their feminine sex.
You can't trust them.
It's the same in the animal kingdom...
...from the biggest elephant
right down to the littlest spider.
Now, take the spider family.
You've heard of a black widow,
but did you ever hear of a black widower?
- No, but...
- And consider the busy bee.
Who's busy? Not the queen.
She's sitting on her throne all day,
sipping honey.
And what's the male bee doing?
He's out knocking himself silly,
crash-diving at the petunias.
Women.
I just can't believe it.
I can't believe
that she doesn't remember me.
How could she forget someone
who loves her so much?
Wait a minute.
Who are you talking about?
- Rosalind.
- Sure.
Who else would you be talking about?
Buckley, I know what you're thinking.
You're wrong.
This isn't just a flirtation or a whim.
This is the real thing.
I'll never forget the first time I saw her.
Just three years,
two months and four days ago.
She came down to our base
with an entertainment troupe.
She looked wonderful.
And tonight,
she wouldn't even dance with me.
She didn't remember.
Look, son, let me tell you something.
You were just one of a thousand
homesick guys.
How could she remember?
Besides, she's got somebody
to remember: Ricardo.
They're gonna be married.
- Now, forget it, will you?
- I won't forget it.
I'm in love with her,
don't you understand that?
Besides, I'm stubborn.
I won't give up
until she's walking down that aisle.
I understand, kid.
When I was your age, I was in love too.
- Yeah? What happened?
- She married someone else.
But the Buckleys are stubborn too.
I didn't give up
till she was walking back up the aisle.
Buckley,
you and I have got a lot in common.
Yeah, we even look alike.
Oh, now, wait a minute.
We've both got classic profiles.
Of course, yours is a little classier.
Say, maybe we're cousins.
Maybe we are.
What'd your family do?
Mine's been at sea for generations.
Mine never knew
what was going on either.
They were strolling actors.
They trod the boards.
A toast to you, Cousin Buckley.
- One for all.
- All for one.
- You for me.
- Me for you.
- Inseparable.
- Like ham and eggs.
- Like brandy and soda.
And as the French say:
And a charlotte russe to you too,
Cousin Larry.
Oh, what a night
to be with someone you love.
- Did you notice the moon, Buckley?
- No, what's it doing?
It'll keep me awake all night.
Me too.
I got no curtains on my windows.
Come on, Roz. Come on.
A thing like this
could lead to pneumonia.
She's beautiful, isn't she?
You've said that before.
Your vocabulary is very limited.
Least she could have done
was to have danced with me.
Cousin, you're trying my patience.
Forget it, will you?
I already told you, I can't forget it.
- I'm still gonna dance with her.
- Sure. Sure, you're gonna dance with her.
But now you'd better turn in
and get some sleep.
You gotta fly that plane tomorrow.
That's right.
- I've gotta fly that plane tomorrow.
- Well, let's get going.
- Roz, I've got an idea.
- What is it, Rick?
We're going to have three days off
after tomorrow.
Let's not wait until we get home.
Let's get married here. Now.
- Will you, Roz?
- Oh, Rick, you know I would...
...but Mr. Fitz promised us a big wedding
right after we finish the picture.
We can't disappoint him, can we?
No, I guess we can't.
He's been pretty swell.
- Everything's all set for the pagan number.
- All right, get your people in position.
- Rick, Roz.
- Everybody on the set.
Dancers, take your places.
Now, this is the dance given in honor
of your leaving the island, Rick.
Roz, you're still hoping
that Rick's gonna take you along.
You watch the dance.
You're interested in it.
And, Roz, you're more
interested in Ricardo.
- All right, George.
- Okay. Take your places.
Everything ready?
- Okay.
- Roll them.
Don't forget what he said.
You're interested in me.
Drums.
All right, cut it.
- Print it, Jane.
- Okay.
All right, everybody.
Next setup at the airplane.
Lieutenant, in this next scene,
you double for Ricardo...
...so listen carefully.
I want you to get in the airplane.
Tanya, that's Miss Rennolds,
unknown to you...
...will crawl in the gunner's compartment
and stow away.
I want you to take off, circle the field...
...wave to the natives below,
then head due north.
- Do you follow me?
- Yes, sir.
Miss Rennolds stows away in my airplane,
I don't know she's there.
I circle the field,
wave and head due north.
Keep your radio on. We'll give you a call
the minute the shot is over.
I want you to come back in and land.
Got everything straight?
Yes, sir.
I certainly have.
You'll enter from there
as soon as the officer's back is to you.
Lieutenant, I want you
to start from here on "action."
- Be careful, will you?
- Yes, sir.
- Buckley, is that other camera ready?
- Yes.
Okay. Places, everybody.
- Are you ready, boss?
- All ready.
- Roll them.
- Speed.
Action, please.
Cut it. Fine. Wonderful.
Okay, get them down, Buckley.
Next setup at the pool.
This'll be the jealousy scene
between you, Yvonne and Rosalind.
Right.
Calling Lieutenant Kingslee.
All right, lieutenant, come back now.
Larry, come back.
Lieutenant.
Larry. Coz!
Larry. Coz...
Give that a little twist, will you?
- Lieutenant.
- He must've misunderstood our directions.
- Larry, coz.
- Why doesn't he come back?
- Where is he going?
- Maybe he's taking her for a ride.
Sure, that's it.
He's taking her for a little ride.
Taking her for a ride?
Maybe she doesn't want to take a ride.
Can't you get him to come back?
- Buckley, get him back.
- Better get him back.
- Tell him to cut out the kidding.
- "Yeah, Buckley, get him back."
Who do you think I am, Superman?
What do you suppose we should...?
Look who I'm talking to.
Yes, sir.
Lieutenant.
Hello, Navy 2011. Go ahead.
This is Navy 2011 reporting.
No plane sighted. Over.
Roger. Hello, Navy 5001.
What could have happened?
Where could they be?
- Why can't we do something?
- Everything possible's being done.
They couldn't disappear.
They have to be someplace.
We have search planes
covering every possible territory.
Hello, Navy Tower.
This is Navy 5001 reporting.
- What is it?
- Nothing on Kingslee's plane.
We're continuing the search
to the northeast.
- Roger.
- Nothing to report.
All I ask is that they find one plane,
and he has nothing to report.
Ricardo, you can't help matters any
by getting excited.
Now, sit down, relax.
All we can do
is wait and hope for the best.
My future wife has disappeared in the air
and you ask me to sit down and relax?
Relax.
Buckley, you know
this Lieutenant Kingslee.
- You don't think he would harm her?
- Harm her?
Of course not.
He wouldn't harm a kitten.
What do we know about him?
Where did he come from?
- Who picked him?
- I picked him.
- You picked him?
- Sure.
They said they wanted a clean-cut,
nice-looking lieutenant who could fly.
- But what about his character?
- In uniforms, their characters didn't show.
So I picked the one
that wanted the job the most.
How did I know he had a crush on Roz?
He had a crush on Roz?
What's wrong with that?
She's a gorgeous girl.
Lots of guys got a crush on her.
I got a crush on her.
Even he's got a crush on her.
Yes, sir.
I'm not getting out of this plane.
You turn right around and take me back
this minute. This minute, you hear?
I'll take you back, Miss Rennolds.
I'll take you back in one hour.
If you're good
and get out of the airplane.
Give me one good reason why I should.
Because I won't take you back
unless you do.
Do you promise to take me back
in an hour?
Promise.
All right.
Never mind. I'll get out the way I got in.
I don't need your help, thank you.
Follow me.
Oh, no.
You're wasting time, Miss Rennolds.
It'll be an hour and 10 minutes.
Won't you sit down, please?
Miss Rennolds, may I have the pleasure
of the next dance, please?
Did you fly all the way out here
just to dance with me?
That's right.
I promised someone very close to me
that I'd dance with you.
- Who?
- Me.
Lieutenant Kingslee, are you crazy?
Yes. About you.
Did you really fly me clear out here
just to dance with me?
That's right.
I like to dance.
Especially with you.
- Thank you very much.
- You're welcome.
Now, will you please take me back?
All right, Miss Rennolds.
I'll take you back.
Okay.
- This isn't the way we came.
- No, it's a shortcut.
Lieutenant, are you sure
you know where you're going?
Of course I know.
Does this look familiar?
- What's the name of this island, lieutenant?
- Kulowama.
Kulowama.
Three years, five months,
two days and about six hours ago...
...you flew in here with an
accordion player and a bathing suit.
When you put the bathing suit on,
nothing else mattered.
Well, wasn't there a diving board
fastened to a tree?
Yeah, that one.
You dove off and swam around
to the accordion, you sang a little song.
- "If I Were You."
- Now I remember.
I called for a volunteer to come up
and play in a little skit.
That's right, 500 hands went up.
I know. Didn't make any difference.
I had him all picked out beforehand.
The commandant used to tip me off.
It was always the shyest,
the most bashful or...
Or the one who was craziest about you.
- That was me.
- It was?
It still is.
- Do you remember how it ended?
- The skit? Of course. You kissed me.
You kissed me back.
Well, that was all part of the act.
It didn't mean a thing.
It did to me. What about that night
when I walked you to your quarters?
- What about all those nice things you said?
- Larry...
Lieutenant, I don't remember what I said.
There were so many islands,
so many boys.
It was all part of the war effort,
keeping up their morale.
Well, it sure shot mine full of holes.
Lieutenant, I'm sorry. Really, I am.
And what about yesterday?
You did the same thing.
You kissed me again.
Well, in the first place, I didn't kiss you,
you kissed me.
And secondly, I was acting.
Why, it was just exactly
like kissing cardboard.
Thanks a lot.
You don't understand.
Look, when I'm playing a scene,
my head controls my emotions perfectly.
Why, I could kiss you right now
exactly the same way.
All right, go ahead.
- What?
- I said, go ahead.
What's the matter, you afraid?
Well, certainly not. That's ridiculous.
See what I mean?
It's nothing.
Let's go home.
- Well, you don't have to walk so fast.
- Sorry, I thought you were in a hurry.
- What's the matter?
- Plenty.
The wheel's gone.
They certainly helped themselves.
Do you mean we're trapped here?
I'm afraid so, until I can find the stuff.
How dared you bring me here?
This whole thing is your fault
and you know it.
- Of all the stupid, meddlesome, blundering...
- It was a mistake bringing you here.
A big mistake, and I'm very sorry,
but that isn't gonna start the airplane.
This is just another trick
to keep me here.
I wouldn't be a bit surprised
if you didn't hide that wheel yourself.
You seem to forget I haven't been
out of your sight since we landed.
Then what happened to it?
Where did it go?
- It didn't just get up and walk off by itself.
- My guess is the inhabitants took it.
Inhabitants?
You mean people live here?
Yes, a native settlement
on the other side of the jungle.
They're probably headhunters
and I'll never leave this island alive.
I just know it.
Oh, please, Miss Rennolds.
Please don't worry,
I'll get you home safely. I promise.
Won't you climb into the ship
till I get back?
- Back? Where are you going?
- To the village.
- You're not gonna leave me here alone?
- I can hardly take you with me.
It's a long, hard trek
straight through the jungle.
Now, please, get into the airplane.
First you want me to get out of it,
now you want me to get back in.
Well, I won't. I'm going with you.
Look, a tropical jungle
is not like a movie jungle, Miss Rennolds.
They have all kinds
of strange things like leeches...
You meet those everywhere.
Come on, let's go.
Very well, but remember,
this isn't my idea.
Keep up with me.
We gotta get there before dark.
By all means.
Oh, what's that?
Just a kiamishi bird calling to his mate.
Don't tell me he ever gets an answer.
Miss Rennolds, for every male kiamishi,
there's a female kiamishi.
See what I mean?
Miss Rennolds?
Rosalind?
Rosalind, where are you?
Rosalind? Answer me.
Over here.
Lieutenant.
- Miss Rennolds, are you all right?
- Oh, of course I'm all right.
- I'll be right down and help you up.
- No. No, you won't.
Give me your coat.
Oh, believe me,
if I ever get out of this place alive, I'll...
- Oh, I'll...
- Here, you got it?
- Yes.
- Okay, tell me when you're ready.
I'll let you know when I'm ready.
And when I do, there'll be
one less lieutenant in the Navy.
All right, now, give me both hands.
Easy.
You all right?
Oh, I'm fine. Wonderful.
Couldn't be better.
Lieutenant Kingslee,
if you had to join the Navy...
...couldn't you have been happy
in a submarine?
Did you have to take up flying?
Oh, I'm terribly sorry, Miss Rennolds.
I really am.
- Do you hurt anyplace?
- Oh, I hurt everyplace.
Don't you touch me.
- Miss Rennolds, you're hysterical.
- I'm not hysterical!
I loathe hysterics.
I've never been hysterical in my whole life.
Then why are you crying?
Because I hate you, that's why.
I hate you.
If you'll put your arms around my neck,
I'll carry you back to the shack.
If I put my arms around your neck,
I would choke you.
Don't you touch me.
Miss Rennolds,
is there anything I can do for you?
You may as well know it right now,
there's nothing you can do for me.
You've done everything
you could possibly do.
Yes, Miss Rennolds.
- Are you hungry?
- Yes. But I'm not speaking to you.
Excuse me.
Larry!
- What's the matter?
- Get him out! Take him away!
- Who?
- That!
Oh, Miss Rennolds, that's only a land crab.
He wouldn't hurt a fly.
What's the matter? Did she frighten you?
Oh, get him away from me.
Oh, Miss Rennolds, you're a big girl now.
I brought you something to eat.
I hate bananas.
I hate coconuts too.
I hate you most of all.
As far as I'm concerned,
you can take those out and bury them.
Bury them. Wait a minute.
That reminds me of something.
Spam. We used to bury it.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
...eight...
...nine...
Eleven.
- Will you have your dinners now?
- Just bring us coffee, please.
- Again?
- Yes, again.
Is there any news? You heard anything?
No, nothing.
All we can do now is wait till morning.
Why? Why can't we continue
searching tonight? Why must we wait?
There's so many islands, Rick.
They couldn't possibly find them tonight.
They'll find them.
People are beginning to ask questions,
and I ain't got the answers.
Now may I serve your dinners?
Just keep the coffee cups filled, Tommy.
That's all.
- Oh, you're waiting for Miss Rennolds?
- Coffee, boy.
See what I mean?
Buckley, give everybody
a 9:00 shooting call for tomorrow morning.
Shoot Rick and Yvonne's love scene.
- You mean we work tomorrow?
- Yes.
Oh, I couldn't work, George.
Look, Rick, if we could help matters any
by not working, we wouldn't...
...but there's nothing we can do.
I tell you, I can't. I'm sorry.
Rick, in show business,
you work whether you feel like it or not.
Nobody cares
about your personal troubles.
There are times when you feel like crying,
you gotta laugh.
And when you feel like laughing,
you gotta cry. That's show business.
Okay, George, I'll have everybody
on the set at 9 sharp.
Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. Buckley said
we can call on him anytime.
How about it? Would you like
to have him sing a song for you?
You see, Mr. Buckley,
everybody, they want you back.
Maybe you have another song for us, no?
Go on, Buckley.
- No, not tonight.
- That's show business, remember?
Yeah.
I don't see how he can do it.
When you've been in this business
as long as he has, you'll understand.
I just got back from Washington today
And really, folks, I've got a lot to say
While I was there
I met the adjutant general
And what he told me put me in a daze
Why, for days and days
And days and days
For a week
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
I'm working here too.
The adjutant general said:
"Jimmy, you've been invited
to entertain at the White House."
He said, "lt'll be a gathering
of the intelligentsia...
...the hoi polloi, the 400, the 500,
the 600, the 700, the 800."
How do you like that?
Everywhere you go, critics.
Then he said, "Jimmy, what'll you do
when you're called upon to entertain?"
I said, "Mr. Adjutant General,
what'll I do? I'll tell you."
Why, in the midst of festivities,
I'll get up, I'll get up.
And do my strutaway
In my cutaway
It's just a hop-away
A slide-away and a scram-away
And then you skitter right down
Then you go to town with a twist-away
Now, when you strutaway thisaway
It's a holiday
You know, I was dancing the strutaway
with a girl named Suzette...
...when she accidentally backed
into a hot radiator.
Crêpe suzette.
It's a dance that's gonna gain
Great renown
You know, a beautiful girl invited me up
to her apartment to teach her this dance.
I wasn't in the apartment 10 minutes,
when who walks in? Her husband.
Kind of perturbed. He said,
"What are you doing here?"
I said, "I'm puttin' on my white tie
I'm puttin' on my top hat
I'm puttin' on my topcoat
To make my getaway"
Doin' the strutaway
Did you ever have the feelin'
That you wanted to do the strutaway?
The hop-away
The scram-away
And then you skitter right down
And you go to town
Doin' the strutaway
The hop-away
The scram-away once more
Señor Buckley, you are magnífico.
And in appreciation, Cugie likes
to give you something very dear to him.
- Take Chita.
- Oh, no.
I wouldn't take him away from you.
I'm not his type.
Thanks, Mr. Cugat. Thanks a million.
- Any news, commander?
- No news.
Did you know that Lieutenant Kingslee
had met Rosalind before?
He did?
According to the boys at the base, he met
her on one of those entertainment tours.
- Yeah?
- And another thing:
You didn't pick him, he picked you.
He bribed his entire squadron...
...so that when you asked for a volunteer,
he'd be selected.
- No.
- Yes.
I should have stayed in vaudeville.
Then this never would have happened.
Lieutenant, I'm sorry
about this afternoon.
I was hysterical.
I know. I don't blame you.
I shouldn't have brought you here
in the first place.
Well, at least the hole I fell into
wasn't your fault.
You didn't dig that.
Miss Rennolds,
it's quite possible that I did.
I used to dig foxholes out here
all day long.
And at night,
I used to lay out under the stars...
...and pretend you were with me.
Every morning at dawn,
we'd go swimming together.
Dawn's the most beautiful time of all
on the island.
Then we'd just stretch out
in the sun and talk for hours.
How about some more food?
Oh, couldn't eat another mouthful.
Oh, come on.
One more bite, like a good girl.
You know, lieutenant,
you'd make a wonderful mother.
I've always thought the same about you.
Good night.
- Miss Rennolds.
- Yes?
You can use this cap as a pillow.
Might be a little more comfortable.
Thank you. Good night.
Larry?
Yes?
When we used to stretch out
in the sun and talk for hours...
...what did we talk about?
Our future.
I'm spending my future
with Ricardo, Larry.
I know. But you spent
an awful lot of your past with me.
Good night.
Larry. Lieutenant.
Lieutenant.
Oh, Larry. Come on, Larry.
Hurry up, Larry.
Admiral, attention.
Lieutenant, at ease.
Fleet, attention.
Maneuver to the right.
Throw out your anchors.
- He can't do that. She's my girl.
- Oh, yes, he can. She's his girl.
There's the girl for you.
Wonderful, isn't she?
I know she's wonderful.
But that's the girl for me.
- Look, coz, it won't work.
- Why not? I'm in love with her.
- Are you?
- Am I?
Come on, lieutenant.
I'm sorry, Larry.
I met you too late in my life.
Lieutenant.
Wake up.
It's late.
Please, Roz, don't say that.
It can't be too late.
It'll never be too late.
What?
Oh, Miss Rennolds.
I must have been dreaming.
Well, you'd better stop dreaming.
It's time we went after those plane parts.
"We"? Oh, no.
I think you better stay in the shack.
- Well, how long will you be gone?
- I'll be back in a couple of hours.
Promise me you'll stay here till I get back?
There's nothing to be afraid of.
All right.
- Miss Rennolds?
- Yes?
Miss Rennolds, if I'd met you
before Ricardo, would I have had a chance?
I did meet you before I met Ricardo,
Larry, a long time before.
Did you ever do any flying before?
No, and if I had my way, I'd have had
the stork that brought me walk.
Looks like this is it.
Keep your fingers crossed.
We're going down.
I ain't had them uncrossed
since I got into this eggbeater.
Oh, darling, are you all right?
I was so worried.
- You're not hurt, are you?
- No, dear, I'm fine, really.
Oh, Buckley, are you here too?
You used to be afraid of airplanes.
I still am, Roz.
Where's that crazy lieutenant?
He went through the jungle looking
for some native village he talked about.
- Pardon me, I'm Commander Harrisen.
- How do you do, commander?
Would you mind telling me exactly
what happened? Were you forced down?
Commander,
I know it's gonna sound a little silly...
...but that lieutenant flew me
all the way out here just to dance with me.
You mean he flew you 500 miles
just for a dance?
That's right.
You have any idea
where he was taking you?
No, it was a complete surprise.
I was furious at first.
Then it struck me as rather funny.
When we went back to the plane
and saw it was damaged...
...and realized we couldn't get back,
I was frantic.
Thank you very much. That'll be all.
- Well, what about Larry?
- We'll take care of him.
- May I take her back to the plane now?
- Yes. I'll join you in a moment.
You men know this island.
Find Lieutenant Kingslee and arrest him.
- I'll send another plane to pick you up.
- Aye.
Come on, Mr. Buckley.
If you don't mind,
could I go along with the boys?
It's all right with me.
All right, but be sure to keep up with us.
This jungle's pretty tricky.
If we should get separated,
just bear north.
I bet I could trace you
back to my family tree.
Navy.
Navy!
Navy! Navy!
"Bear north," they said.
North. Of course,
they didn't tell me where north is.
Wait a minute.
When you got trees, you got moss.
And moss always grows
on the north side of a tree.
How do you like that? No moss.
Maybe it's the altitude.
Oh, no. Larry, coz.
I'm too late. Poor coz.
- Hi.
- You hungry?
Not me. I just lost my appetite.
We hungry.
You wouldn't like me. I'm all muscle.
When we hungry, we eat.
That's what's worrying me.
Larry! Coz!
Buckley!
- Coz.
- Gosh, it's good to see you. How are you?
Chief, friend. Friend.
Coz, am I glad to see you.
I didn't know what happened to you.
Thought they cut you up
and was serving you under glass.
- How did you get here?
- Never mind. What are you doing here?
Trying to get parts back. Chief wouldn't
give my compass till I feasted with him.
Oh, they're killing me with kindness.
How'd you ever find me?
I flew in with the Navy.
From there on, I followed my nose.
That took me halfway.
Did you see Roz? Is she all right?
Of course she's all right.
She flew back with the Navy.
Did she leave a message for me?
Anything she had to say,
she said to the commander.
The commander?
- Well, she wouldn't just leave without...
- No. She wouldn't just leave.
She loves it here.
She just went back to the hotel
to get her pressure cooker.
Give us a little smile, folks.
Let's make it look good.
- Okay, hold it. Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Had you known this flying Romeo before?
- Yes, I met him once.
Did you have any idea
why he was taking you to the island?
No, it was a complete surprise.
Are you still planning on getting married?
- Of course.
Will Lieutenant Kingslee
still be technical advisor on your picture?
Certainly not.
How about another pose?
Something schmaltzy.
Thank you.
- Just one more, folks.
- Oh, no, please.
No more now. I'm a little tired.
She's all worn out.
You come back tomorrow.
All right. Thank you, Miss Rennolds.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
- You've been swell.
Better get some rest, Roz.
- Rick, we need you at rehearsal.
- I'll only be a minute.
Darling, how long have you known
this lieutenant?
I met him several years ago
on one of my tours.
- I didn't even remember.
- Evidently, he did.
Well, that's probably because
I picked him out of the crowd...
...to do one of my little routines with me.
Was that the little routine
that wound up with a kiss?
- Yes, that's the one.
- I see.
Rick, I assure you that Larry
was a perfect gentleman all of the...
So now it's Larry, huh?
Well, after all, there were just
the two of us on the island.
It seemed a little ridiculous
to be so formal.
Please believe me, darling.
I've done nothing that need worry you.
I can't say anything more than that, Rick.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's just that American women
are different from the women in my family.
They have more freedom.
They think differently.
Please don't be impatient if sometimes
it's a little difficult for me to accept.
- Am I forgiven?
- Of course, darling.
See you later, darling.
Rosalind,
will you promise me something?
Yes, I'll promise. What is it?
I don't want you ever to see
this lieutenant again.
All right, Rick.
Did my great, big, beautiful Larry...
...really bring little old me out here
for just a teensy dance?
Yes, I did, sweetums,
but I'd like a little kiss too.
Oh, you naughty, naughty boy.
Oh, they spent one whole night
On the island alone
But all they could think of
Was getting back home
If you guys don't get out of here quick,
I'm gonna murder you.
Attention.
- Lieutenant Kingslee?
- Yes, sir.
- Report to Commander Harrisen immediately.
- Aye, sir.
Now, Larry. Larry.
Take it easy, Larry. Larry.
Come in.
Lieutenant Kingslee reporting, sir.
- I believe you know this lady.
- Hello, Larry.
- Sit down, Kingslee.
- If you don't mind, sir, I prefer to stand.
- I said, sit down.
- Yes, sir.
Miss Rennolds has volunteered
some additional information...
...which might help your case
and possibly save you from court-martial.
I take it the lady needs more publicity.
- I'm surprised to see reporters aren't here.
- Your remarks are out of order.
Apparently, you're not aware
of the serious charges against you.
I beg your pardon, sir.
Miss Rennolds claims that she asked you
to fly her to this island.
- Is that true?
- Of course not.
I took her entirely against her own will.
- Miss Rennolds likes her name in print.
- Kingslee.
I'm sorry, sir.
You may go on.
As I told you, commander...
...I encouraged Lieutenant Kingslee
to fly me to the island.
I'd been there before
and I wanted to see it again.
I wanted to refresh old memories.
Is that correct?
With permission, I'd like to leave.
I don't need Miss Rennolds to lie.
If it won't inconvenience you too much,
I should like you to stay.
Won't you please sit down?
Would you please go on, Miss Rennolds?
The lieutenant's conduct on the island
was at all times that of a gentleman...
...although it certainly isn't right now.
And you say you kissed him
of your own free will?
Yes, commander, I really kissed him.
- May I leave now, sir?
- You may not.
What happened after the kiss?
Larry suggested
we leave the island immediately.
He did?
Is that true, lieutenant?
- Well, I...
- Just answer the question, yes or no.
- Yes, sir, I did.
- I see.
Miss Rennolds,
when you arrived, you told me...
...that you were willing to reimburse
the Navy for any damages to the plane.
- Are you still willing to do that?
- Yes, sir, I am.
- I see. That's all, Kingslee. You may go.
- Yes, sir.
Believe me, your performance today was
one of the most magnificent exhibitions...
...of overwhelming generosity
I have ever witnessed.
It's too bad the cameras weren't turning.
Why, you pigheaded,
obstinate, opinionated hothead.
If you had as much sense
as you have pride...
- Go on. You're getting better all the time.
- Obviously, I'm boring you, lieutenant.
Oh, I hope I never see you again,
because if I do...
If I do, I'll drown you.
- Kingslee.
- Yes, sir?
All right, Edward, that's all. You can go.
- Omit those last speeches from the record.
- Yes, sir.
Just between you and me,
if I were 20 years younger...
...l'd plant one healthy punch
right on that stubborn chin of yours.
- That's all, lieutenant. Shove off.
- Thank you, sir.
How about a picture, Miss Rennolds?
Smile, please.
Thank you.
I've been waiting for you, Roz.
- I went to see the lieutenant.
- What about your promise?
It was only right to go down...
...and try to straighten things out
with his commander.
- And did you?
- No, the stubborn idiot didn't want my help.
He insisted on pleading guilty.
- Well, isn't he?
- Well, in a way he is, but...
And just what did you tell the commander
to convince him otherwise?
Well, I tried to take the blame.
I told him that it was my fault,
that I had encouraged Larry.
In other words, you deliberately lied to...?
Or perhaps you were telling the truth.
Of course I wasn't.
I just thought it would help, that's all.
If you don't mind,
I'd rather not talk about it.
But I want to talk about it.
We've known each other
for a long time, Roz.
Let's be honest.
- Are you in love with him?
- In love with him?
I never wanna see him again
as long as I live.
I see. You never want to see him again.
And yet you make a fool
and a liar of yourself...
...over a man who endangered
both your life and reputation.
He didn't endanger my life.
Besides, what difference
does my reputation make...
...when a man's career is at stake?
Why, the Navy's his whole world.
Haven't you any understanding?
I think I have.
Perhaps more than you know.
Yvonne, tell me one thing.
Is it possible for a woman
to love two men at the same time?
Well, I don't know, Ricardo.
It all depends.
On what?
Well, on...
- On the woman.
- Could you?
Of course not.
There's only one way to love:
With your whole heart.
That's the way you would love, isn't it?
Yvonne...
...isn't it your grandmother Spanish?
Why, yes, Rick, she is.
Oh, I knew it.
I could tell by the way
you feel about things.
Somehow I sensed it
from the very first moment.
Come on, Yvonne. Come on, Rick.
We're ready for rehearsal.
Ricardo, this is after you've been
thrown out of the Navy.
You're not a lieutenant now,
you're a bum.
Places, everybody.
Take these out of here.
- Oh, Mr. Buckley...
- I haven't got the time now. Later. Later.
Amigo, my friend.
A million thanks for suggesting Cugat
and his orchestra...
...to be in your magnificent picture.
Oh, it was nothing.
All I said was,
"Why not? There ain't nobody else."
To show my gratitude,
I insist you take this gift.
It's like giving you one of my own family.
Her name is Francisca Jimenes
Maria Gonzales Conchita. Chita for short.
I hope you'll be very happy together.
I don't know about you,
but I'm gonna be miserable.
Besides, it's gonna complicate
my home life.
I've got a very vicious canary.
All right, lights.
I've never seen them dance
so beautifully together before, have you?
No, George, I haven't,
and I don't think that I like it.
Oh, Mr. Buckley.
Not now, honey,
I got business to attend to.
Wait a minute.
Penelope, how would you like a present?
A present? But why, sir?
There's no occasion.
There will be if you accept it.
Look, a bow-wow just for you.
Oh, he's beautiful.
So diminutive.
And he's small too.
I'd love to take him, Mr. Buckley,
but I couldn't.
You couldn't?
No, you see, I have a dog at home,
actually, a very faithful dog.
- I wouldn't dream of hurting his feelings.
- Do you have to tell him?
Oh, I wouldn't have to tell him,
he'd know.
Dogs are much smarter than people.
They sense things.
They're more loyal too.
You see, dogs love you
when no one else loves you.
They don't care if you're rich
or smart or pretty or anything.
Looks like I was designed for dogs.
Dog is man's best friend.
And when you have a problem,
he's always there to help.
I wouldn't dream of taking him
from you, Mr. Buckley.
But thank you kindly just the same.
Come on, friend.
- Anybody home?
- I'll be out in a minute.
Now, there's a girl who's got a problem,
but can I look to you for help?
No. Go ahead. Turn your back on me.
I tried to find a good home
for you, didn't I?
You see? We don't belong together.
You're pedigreed and I ain't.
Besides, I'm not
the proper guardian for you.
Another thing, first thing I know,
you'll be staying out all hours of the night...
...and running around
with the wrong kind of dogs.
And before I know it,
some blond cocker spaniel...
...will come along and take you
for every bone you got.
We gotta be big about this.
You gotta go, so let's just turn our backs
and walk out of each other's lives.
We won't look back.
It'll be easier that way.
Chita.
Chiquita, I'm sorry.
I lost my head.
Hello, Buckley.
- Cugie gave it to me.
- He's very cute.
He's not a he. He's a lady.
You've been crying.
No, I haven't, Buckley.
Oh, yes, you have,
and I think I know why.
But don't let it upset you.
Men are always getting crazy notions.
- It'll all blow over.
- I don't care whether it does or not.
He's a pigheaded mule
and I hope I never see him again.
That's gonna be a little hard to work.
You're doing a swimming scene
with him in the morning.
Scene? Oh, I'm talking about Larry.
You are?
You know, my mother used to say...
...when a woman runs around hollering
how much she can't stand a guy...
...it's a sure tip-off she feels
just the opposite.
What'll I do, Buckley?
Put on your best hat,
powder your nose...
...and run straight down
and tell Larry how you feel about him.
I did go down. I even tried to help him with
the commander and he wouldn't let me.
You just don't know how mean he was.
He didn't care so much after all.
Men are funny people, honey.
Sometimes they want something
till they get it...
...then they don't want it anymore.
The big heels.
Where does that leave me?
Right back where you started,
and that's a pretty good neighborhood.
Now, you just listen to Buckley,
because he's got information for you.
Did you ever stop to think
it puts 10 lines in your face...
...when you frown
and only two when you smile?
When you run into trouble,
there's one thing you gotta do.
You've gotta start off each day
With a song
Even when things go wrong
You'll feel better
You'll even look better
Oh, Roz, everyone has problems.
Why, even Chita and I
had a misunderstanding.
But we made up.
And it's gonna work out to my advantage.
Now when I make out my income tax,
I'm gonna list Chita as a dependent.
That will take me out
of the upper bracket.
That's right, smile.
Now, isn't it better to go through life
With a smile and a song
Than walkin' around with a face
Eleven miles long?
Now, you know that you can't go wrong
If you start off each day with a song
That's right, smile.
Cut it. Print that one, Jane.
That was wonderful.
Couldn't have been nicer.
- Thank you.
- Buckley.
Get the lieutenant and have him check
Rick's uniform before we make this shot.
Okay, lieutenant.
- Everything in order, lieutenant?
- Yes, Mr. Montez.
- Everything's in order. Everything's fine.
- Good.
This is a new experience to me,
working the moving-picture set.
It's a real pleasure.
And anything I can do, please call on me.
Thanks, lieutenant.
Now, Yvonne, when you see Roz
kiss Ricardo in this scene, you're jealous...
...so you finally decide to go back
to the island. Then, Roz...
Roz!
Where's she going?
She's going in to fix her makeup.
She'll be right back.
All right, boys, make the setup
for the close shot.
- Let me know when she's ready.
- Yeah, I'll let you know.
Come in.
I wouldn't do that, Roz.
Better get back to work.
They're waiting for you.
- Tell them that I... Well, that I just...
- Just what?
Well, that I just can't work today.
Oh, come on, Roz. You don't want
someone that don't want you, do you?
You don't understand, Buckley.
You've never been in love.
Maybe I have, honey.
But that's all behind me.
You're just starting your life.
Believe me, Roz, right now
you think you'll never get over this...
...and that you can't live
without him, but you will.
Why, there'll be lots of guys that'll
come into your life, hundreds of them.
And one of these days,
it's gonna be the right one...
...and then you'll be glad you waited.
Are you glad you waited, Buckley?
Oh, I'm a different case.
Come on, Roz. Life's too short for tears.
Besides, honey, you've always got me.
- Tell George I'll be right there.
- That's the girl.
- Please, Mrs. Peabody, I've got problems.
- Go right ahead, Penelope.
Something old, something new
Something borrowed, something blue.
That's what every bride should do.
How do you like that? Plagiarism.
Look, honey, go back to the old way.
This way, nobody'll understand you.
We'll shoot it next Tuesday,
if we're still here.
Okay, everybody, let's get going.
Martha, this is the moment
you've been waiting for.
She's got a curl out of place.
Roz'll be out in a minute.
- How is she?
- She's fine.
Think we ought to stop shooting?
We can get her scenes tomorrow.
- No, I think it's better if you keep her busy.
- Okay.
That'll be all for today.
- Very well. Will you want me tomorrow?
- I don't know yet. I'll get in touch with you.
- Thank you, sir.
- Buckley.
- Is Larry coming back?
- No, honey, he's not.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry. I thought that...
Now, you just go right back to work
and let nature take its course.
Buckley, I think I should talk with Roz.
Don't worry, honey. Roz understands.
Just the same,
I wish Larry were coming back.
I've gotta be gone for a little while
and I want you to take over for me.
All you gotta do is stay out of the way,
keep your eyes open and your mouth shut.
If you have to say anything,
just say, "Yes, sir."
Yes, sir.
Not that I've ever heard him
say anything else.
All right, everybody, on your toes.
Light those arcs, men.
Miss Rennolds, come a-running.
We haven't got all day.
Yvonne, check your makeup.
Martha! Martha, get Roz out here.
Janie, vacation's over. Get out your script.
It's about time we got work done.
You're not gonna get around me
like you do Buckley.
That's my boy.
- Nice to have you back, Miss Rennolds.
- Thank you. It's nice to be back.
I'll bet you won't eat coconuts again.
All right, shorty, forget the sociabilities.
The soup's in the kitchen.
Yes, sir.
Nevertheless, it's nice
to have you back, Miss Rennolds.
Is a Cuban playboy without much dinero
He says, "I wanna be good
And I would if I could
But what can I do?
I'm just a bad boy"
Yeah
- Would you like to dance, George?
- Of course.
Well, maybe the next one
after the next one, Roz.
Well, how about you, Buckley?
Who, me? I can't dance like that.
My feet don't seem to know
what I got in mind.
Besides, it makes me seasick.
But I still loves you.
Well, what do you know?
I wonder what the Navy's doing here.
Good evening, commander.
Are you all here?
Looks like the fleet's in.
Sure a nice-looking bunch of boys.
Buckley, I was supposed
to forget the Navy, remember?
The Navy wouldn't forget you,
Miss Rennolds.
- Good evening, commander.
- Good evening. May I have this dance?
Remember what happened last time
you refused the Navy.
I'd love to dance, commander.
Excuse me. I'll see you later.
Yvonne, do you think your grandmother
will approve of me?
How do you like that?
I turn my back and he grows up.
Maybe he needs an assistant.
- Join us?
- I'd be glad to, if I'm not extruding.
- May I?
- Certainly.
- Do you still wanna drown me?
- Yes, I most certainly do.
Roz.
Miss Rennolds.
You're gonna hate me for this,
but I gotta leave you.
Things don't look so good.
Roz? Please listen me. I'm sorry.
I know I made a mistake...
...but it's so easy to make mistakes
when you love someone so much.
Oh, now who's being pigheaded
and stubborn and obstinate and a hothead?
Don't you think it's time you stopped being
an actress and started being a woman?
Oh, lieutenant.
Lieutenant?
Larry?
Hey!
Something old, something new
Something borrowed, something blue.
That's what every bride should do.
Looks like we're gonna have
a wedding after all, Pineapple.
[ENGLISH]