Hey, buds below
Up is where to grow
Up, with which below
Can't compare with
Hurry
It's lovely up here
Life down a hole
Takes an awful toll
What with not a soul there
To share with
Hurry, it's lovely up here
Wake up
Bestir yourself
It's time that you disinter yourself
You've got a spot to fill
A pot to fill
And what a gift package
Of shower, sun and love
You'll be met above everywhere
With fondled and sniffed
By millions who drift by
Life here is rosy
If you're a posy
Hurry, it's lovely here
Climb up, geranium
It can't be fun subterranean
On the exterior
It's cheerier
R.S. V.P., peonies
Pollinate the breeze
Make the queen of bees
Hot as brandy
Come give at least
A preview of Easter
Come up
And see the hoot we're giving
And see the grounds for living
Come poke your head out
Open up and spread out
Hurry, it's lovely here
On a clear day
You can see forever
Forever and ever and ever and ever
And you'll see who you are
On a clear day
How it will astound you
That the glow of your being
Outshines every star
You'll feel part of
Every mountain, sea and shore
You can hear from far and near
A world you never
Never heard before
And on a clear day
On a clear day
You can see forever and ever
And ever
And evermore
And now the window opens.
It gently, gently opens,
and the night steals softly in.
Your eyelids now are heavy.
Your arms are numb and heavy.
Your legs are dull and heavy
and you give yourself to sleep.
A deep sleep.
He's under. Lights, please.
I'll begin with
posthypnotic suggestion,
and after, if Preston here
is a good subject, regression.
- When does this class meet again?
- On Wednesday, sir.
On Wednesday.
Mr Preston, after I waken you,
the first time I say the word
"Wednesday," you will take off your left
shoe and sock and put them on again.
Remember, the first time
I say the word "Wednesday."
Now for regression.
I will try and take Preston back
through his life to the age of 5.
Stand up and turn around, please.
I want you to go back in time
to your 20th birthday.
- Dr Chabot.
- No questions now.
Now, five years more
to your 15th birthday.
to your 10th.
Now, another five years, and when I
count to three and snap my fingers,
you will be 5 years old.
Five years old,
at your first day of school.
One,
two...
Give me back my chalk, Henry.
Come on, Henry Tillsbury.
You give me back my chalk,
or I'll throw the glue at you
and you'll get all gooey.
- Sit down, Preston.
- Oh, Henry, I am not sitting
- on your turtle. Honest.
- What's her name?
- Miss Hildebrand, you gotta make...
- Doesn't anybody know who she is?
Sleep.
To be hypnotized indirectly
is very common,
but to be regressed indirectly
is not only unusual
but a little nerve-wracking.
Listen to me.
You are no longer 5 years old.
You are as you are today.
And when I count to three
and snap my fingers,
you will awaken feeling fine.
One, two, three.
How do you feel?
Fine.
What happened?
I mean, how did I get over here?
You were hypnotized by mistake.
- Your mistake or mine?
- I suppose it was a bit of both.
I opened the window,
but you fell out.
- What's your name?
- Daisy Gamble.
You're not a medical student,
are you?
No.
Did everybody, I mean,
you know, fall out?
No. No, just you.
Just me?
I'm awfully sorry, doctor.
I didn't mean to butt in, I...
Oh, I'm awfully sorry, everybody.
I mean, I didn't mean to butt in.
Please, go on with your act.
It won't happen to me again.
Boy, you can swing open
that window all you want,
and when the night starts crawling in,
my eyelids won't get heavy
and my arms get numb and heavy
and my legs get dull and heavy and...
When I count to three
and press your forehead,
you will awaken and stay awake.
- One, two, three.
- Oh, God.
Why don't you step outside
and get a little air.
Sure. I mean, sure.
Have you got a cigarette, please?
I'm awfully sorry, doctor. Really.
Do you have a match?
Oh, thank you very...
Doctor, I'm awfully sorry,
kids, really.
Push.
Sorry.
Preston, you are no longer
5, 10, 15 or 20.
You are as you are now.
And when I count to three and snap
my fingers, you will awaken.
One, two, three.
Do you feel all right?
- Yes, sir.
- What is it?
Sir, nothing happened to me.
I didn't go under.
Most people don't believe
they do the first time.
- Well, I know that, sir...
- But that is not your case.
Oh, no, sir. No. Is that all?
On Wednesday, when we
meet again, I want to discuss...
- What are you doing there?
- Taking off my shoe and...
...sock.
- Any particular reason, or just bored?
See you all Wednesday.
Out like a light.
If you don't remember,
he was telling you
to take off your shoes and socks.
Oh, Marc,
did you receive one of these?
Oh, just routine meeting,
nothing important.
Doctor, could I see you
for just one minute, please?
- Don't you feel well?
- Yeah, sure, sure.
But I gotta talk to you
about something important.
If you call my secretary...
I'll see you this afternoon.
- She'll make an appointment.
- But it's just one question, that's all.
Couldn't you ask me
at a Wednesday lecture?
If you come a little early,
I'm sure it's possible...
Oh, my God.
Come in. Come here, hey.
Come, come.
This way, please. This way.
Come in. Here.
Yes. Come in, come in.
This way, this way, please.
Here, come in.
You're doing that
on posthypnotic suggestion.
Oh, no.
Turn around.
I'm terribly sorry.
Is anything else coming off?
- Of course not. Here, your shoe.
- You're sure?
That's quite a weapon
you have got there.
Boy, you fellas must have
one glorious night after another.
I mean...
What's the matter?
- This just isn't my day.
- Come. Come sit down.
You'll feel better in a moment.
Sit down.
- Oh, God.
- Now, what did...?
Oh, rats.
Thank you.
Oh, God.
Don't you hate cigarettes?
Now, what did you
want to ask me?
What I wanted to ask you was this:
Doctor, do you think...?
I mean, can people really be
hypnotized out of something?
I mean, of something like smoking.
It's stuck in the dictionary. I mean, can
you see how yellow my fingers are?
I beg your pardon?
Aren't you looking for a piece
of paper with an address on it?
- Yes.
- Don't you have a dictionary?
Well, yes.
Well, just see if it's in there.
You see, the other night I heard
this discussion going on in the bathtub,
on the radio, and this man said...
It's under X.
He said you could be
hypnotized out of it
without getting something else
instead, you know,
like fat or nervous or acne.
- Miss...
- Gamble.
What about this address?
- Isn't that the one you're looking for?
- Yes, but how did you do it?
I don't know. I just saw you
looking around for something
and wondered what it was and...
You know, I knew.
Very well,
I won't pry into trade secrets.
Yeah.
About this yellow-finger problem...
Can you do any other tricks?
No. You see, I only have until
tomorrow night, and I was desperate.
And that's why I busted on
your lecture, so I could meet you...
What else do you do?
Come on, you can trust me.
Well...
...sometimes...
...I do get the feeling when
the phone's gonna ring.
Or when someone' s
gonna drop in.
So I wait.
And sometimes I can tell
when people
are thinking about me,
so I'll go to see them.
I mean, you know, if I like them.
And
that's about all.
No.
That's all. That's all.
I make flowers grow.
- You make flowers grow?
- Fast. I mean, fast.
And how do you do that?
I don't know.
Doctor, about these cigarettes...
Well, why don't you
just make them disappear.
I don't blame you.
I know it sounds...
It sounds so silly.
Well, never mind, doctor.
I'm really sorry I bothered you.
Thanks anyway.
Oh, answer your phone.
Yes?
Yes, Dr Chabot speaking.
Yes, Conrad. I'm coming.
Order me a...
Double whiskey.
And you thought she saw it
sticking out of the dictionary
on the other side of the room.
Remarkable, isn't it?
- And you think it was a trick?
- She couldn't have guessed it.
Marc, I know as a psychiatrist
I could have my couch taken away
from me for this, but you don't think
by any chance this could be a case
of extrasensory perception, ESP?
All right.
Find the girl, hypnotize her
and prove to yourself
whether or not it was a trick.
You're against scientific research?
How can ESP be called a science
when there is no scientific proof
- that ESP exists?
- What do you mean, exists?
Two people have
the same thought at the same time.
It's happened millions of times.
It exists,
but psychiatry calls it coincidence.
- That's what it is.
- Many people are not so certain,
- and for a very good scientific reason.
- Rubbish.
Pure, unadulterated rubbish.
Violet. Lily. Rose.
Mrs Hatch?
This is my address
for that lunch tomorrow.
- You can type it now.
- Oh, doctor, there's a...
When you've finished, telephone
every student in my 11:00 class
until you find someone who
remembers the name of the girl
I hypnotized by mistake
this morning and...
Oh, you mean Daisy Gamble?
Will you please tell me
how you knew that?
Well, she told me.
She's in the waiting room.
- Miss Gamble?
- Oh, hello, doctor.
Hello. This way, please.
- No calls, Mrs Hatch.
- I'll go to work on your address.
Did you lose another one?
No. Follow me.
- Now, Miss Gamble...
- I'll make it quick.
Do you know the name of a good
hypnotist I can go and talk to
and see if he could help me lay off
these cigarettes
before tomorrow night, or else
Warren won't get that job, see?
Then I won't bother you any more.
Do you understand? Understand.
You don't even know who Warren is.
Oh, he's my fiancé.
Go on.
- Go on?
- Yes.
Well, you see, over here, you know,
in the United States, they have
these big companies that send out
these personnel directors
to these colleges to sign up
the bright students and their wives.
Well, Warren...
Remember? He's my fiancé.
He's graduating in the top 2 percent
of the business school
and Chemical Foods, Inc.,
wanna give him a lifetime contract,
see, and I can ruin it. I mean,
you know, if they don't like me.
I mean, that's that.
And they're not gonna like me.
Because Warren told me, you know,
that they don't like addicts,
and I'm an addict.
And I'm an addicted addict.
I can't stop
unless somebody
like you can make me.
Is that possible?
It's possible, provided it's not
a symptom of neurosis, or...
No, no, I'm normal. I swear.
I'm just an addict, that's all.
Last year I took some of these
vocational-guidance tests, you know,
not for a job, but for Warren
to get to know me better,
and you know the results?
What?
Healthy, adjusted
and no character.
I mean, no character of any kind.
I mean, not even any characteristics.
You see, tomorrow night,
I've gotta have dinner with Warren
and one
of these personnel directors.
So, what do I do about
these rotten, miserable...?
Do you want one?
No, no, thank you.
How old are you, Miss Gamble?
Twenty-two.
And how old were you
when you started smoking?
Twelve. See, I had
this cousin, Harvey,
who came to visit us,
and he was smoking.
You know, he dared me to try.
Well, he was only 9,
what could I do?
Of course.
Miss Gamble,
I will try to help you today.
But from tomorrow on,
you'll have to go to someone else.
And if you call me tomorrow, I'll give
you the name of another doctor.
Sit here, please.
- You mean now?
- Yes, now.
Oh, doctor. I don't know how I can
ever thank you. I mean, really, that is...
- I didn't expect, you know...
- Never mind that, just sit down.
Good.
Please.
That's it.
Just relax now.
Relax.
Now, Miss Gamble, I want you to try,
if you can, to imagine that you see...
I see it.
- What?
- A window.
That's right, a window.
Now, keep staring at that window
until slowly, very slowly,
the window begins...
It's open.
That's right.
And now the dark of night is...
Oh, well, you know the rest, go on.
- Can you hear me, Miss Gamble?
- Yes.
Miss Gamble, if you truly wish
to stop smoking,
I would like you
to raise your left hand.
Drop your hand.
When I awaken you, you will find
that your desire for cigarettes
will grow less and less,
and when you want a cigarette,
your ability to resist it will grow
stronger and stronger.
- Do you understand, Miss Gamble?
- Yes.
Good.
Now, open your eyes.
Miss Gamble, this morning
you were kind enough
to help me find an address I'd lost.
- Do you remember?
- Yes.
It was quite a trick.
Do you know how you did it?
Yes.
I thought so. How?
Well,
I saw you looking around
for something
and I wondered what it was.
And all of a sudden I knew.
- You knew what?
- Where it was.
- That's all?
- That's all.
I see.
- Do you really?
- Of course, a child can understand it.
Who taught it to you?
I don't know. I suppose I got it
from Winnie Wainwhisle.
Who is she?
- Nobody.
- Nobody?
I mean, nobody anymore.
She's dead.
But before she died
she taught it to you.
- No.
- No?
No.
- But you said you got it from her.
- Yeah.
Can you remember an incident
when you saw Winnie Wainwhisle
perform the same trick?
Oh, sure, lots of them.
- Just one.
- Okay.
Where did it happen?
In London.
- You know, in England?
- London?
- What were you doing in London?
- I was with Winnie Wainwhisle.
Was it lately?
Well, was it before you were 15?
Before you were 10?
- Yeah.
- Before you were 5?
- What was it she found?
- A gold locket.
I see.
- It was the one my husband gave me.
- Oh, really.
And how old was your little husband?
Three and a half? Four?
No. He was...
Let's see, 59. Yeah, that's right.
Because he was exactly
35 years older than I.
- What?
- Than me?
Thirty-five years older?
Well, I know it's a lot, but he was rich
and he had a title, so, what the hell.
That would make you 24.
How did you get to be 24?
Well, after 23.
But that makes you two years older
than when you sat down.
Miss Gamble, how can you go back
to a time before you were 5
and say you are 24?
Explain that to me further.
Miss Gamble.
Yes?
What year are you remembering?
1814.
Now, listen carefully. You're saying
that you were alive in 1814.
Very well. I want you to tell me
everything you can about yourself,
beginning with your name.
You do remember your name?
My name?
Gee, I don't know if I can do that.
I mean, boy, that's tough.
- I'm Daisy Gamble.
- Take your time.
Maybe I was called
something else once...
...but the only name I...
I mean, my name has always...
My name is...
My name is Melinda.
Melinda Winifred Waine Tentrees.
And I am appalled and stunned
at this outrageous inquisition.
- Inquisition, Lady Tentrees?
- From the day this trial began,
you have been coiled
like a cobra ready to strike.
Trying to make me crawl
and cower and cringe
and admit to your monstrous lies.
But you shall not succeed.
I shall speak only the truth.
I hope so.
Now you say your name
is Melinda Tentrees?
Would you tell the court
what knowledge you have
of the tragic voyage
of the frigate Westerly.
I know nothing about that unfortunate
vessel except that it sailed.
Yet you advised your husband
not to insure the Westerly.
How did you know
it would never return?
You have asked me that question
again and again.
I have answered it again and again.
The Caroline sailed
two days after the Westerly,
also never to return,
insurance also rejected by
Pelham of London, upon your advice.
How did you know
it would never return?
I do not know.
You don't know if your name is
Melinda Tentrees?
Of course I know my name is
Melinda Tentrees, dunce.
And I also know my husband's name
and how old we are and where we live,
the street,
the number and the city.
- I have a breathtaking grasp of things.
- How long have you been married?
Robert and I have been married
for three
tumultuous, passionate,
Scheherazadian years.
Your husband must be
remarkable for his age.
He's remarkable for any age.
- But still, at 59.
- Fifty-nine? Ass!
That was my first husband.
Robert is 31.
What was your
first husband's name?
Lord Percy Moorepark.
Poor, fumbling, old, rich thing.
But you heard a witness testify to
having seen you on the London docks
on the night of November 14th,
consorting in secret
with a known enemy of the crown.
- He lies!
- Wait, wait, wait.
I'm so glad you interrupted.
I cannot bear this trial another minute.
- What are you on trial for?
- Oh, please.
Very well, never mind.
You were going to tell me
about an incident
when Winnie Wainwhisle
finds something for you.
Yes.
It was the day I first met Robert.
What a glorious day it was.
- Where are you?
- Where we met.
At the Royal Pavilion at Brighton
three years ago.
Percy. Percy, put on
your spectacles at once.
Hurry.
Now look directly across the lawn.
Do you see Diana Smallwood?
- Unmistakably Diana Smallwood.
- Who is that with her?
Robert Tentrees.
- What does he do?
- As little as possible.
Joseph Pelham was complaining
about him the other day.
He knows Tentrees' father
and gave the boy a position.
Maritime insurance.
You know, old ships at sea.
- Is he married?
- No.
But he should have been,
many times.
And he will be soon.
I can't wait to hear
how you arrange that.
My dearest love
Who existed in a dream
Till this evening
When a wave came
And swept me out to sea
None of the loves
That you have known
Could prepare you for the love
Raging everywhere in me
For all the arms
That have covered you
The hands that have touched you
And the lips you have lingered on
Before
Added together would be less
Than an olive
In the banquet of love
I have in store
Love seasoned to entice
Love with all the trimmings
Filled with spice
Love flavoured to your whim
Served piping hot
With all the trimmings
For I'll decode every breath
And every sigh
Till your every lover's wish
Is fulfilled before it's made
Toss in some jealousy and doubt
Should it be required
Not rest till there's
Nothing more desired
Thus loving as I do
Never, never will you ever be untrue
Having love with all the trimmings
Waiting home
For you
Gentlemen. His Highness.
Chef, my good fellow.
Your Royal Highness.
Never in history
have taste buds been
so delectably treated
as they were tonight
with your extraordinary
salmon mousse.
Served with cream
and vin rouge sauce.
Garnished with truffles
and exotic herbs.
You seem to know this woman.
Who is she?
Winnie Wainwhisle.
Do you have a name for this,
if I may be allowed a Gallic pun,
this chef-d'oeuvre?
Yes, with pleasure.
Come this way.
I humbly christen it
Salmon Beurre Brigette.
- To my chef.
- To the chef.
- Melinda.
- Mum.
- Is that your mother?
- Yes.
How are you, Melinda?
Mum, did you ever hear
of Robert Tentrees?
Robert Tentrees?
He's not your kind, Melinda.
Hasn't got a halfpenny to his name.
- Here, I got something for you.
- What?
- Your locket.
- Where'd you find it?
Under the ambassador's night table.
- Well, that's a bit of luck.
- What about this Robert Tentrees?
- Is he here tonight?
- Mum.
Mum, he's here, and I met him. And
I love him and I'm gonna marry him.
- Marry him?
- But you've got a husband.
I'll divorce him.
And don't you worry about
us not having any money.
In two years' time,
I'll make Robert Tentrees
one of the richest men in England.
That good-for-nothing.
How in the world
do you expect to make the likes of...?
No.
No, Melinda. Don't misuse
your talents. Please.
Or God knows in how many
lifetimes you'll be paying for it.
What talents?
What is she talking about?
Well.
- There you are, milady.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
For I'll decode every breath
And every sigh
Till your every lover's wish
Is fulfilled before it's made
Toss in some jealousy and doubt
Should it be required
Not rest till there's
Nothing more desired
Thus loving as I do
Never, never will you ever be untrue
Having love with all the trimmings
Waiting home
For you
And just how do you expect
to get a divorce?
I'm going to be caught
red-handed, dearie. That's how.
Caught red-handed.
- There.
- Where?
Here.
Oh, Percy.
Percy, I knew you'd leave
your spectacles at home. Here.
Here is your other pair.
Oh, thank you very much.
And is it not true, Lady Moorepark,
that in the pursuit of illicit passion,
you and Robert Tentrees
met regularly?
Yes. We met frequently, in secret.
Lady Tentrees, I suggest that you
have committed perjury to this court
and that you have consorted
with those involved
in the treasonous plot
against king and country
to destroy 38 British ships at sea.
No! You are trying
to make a criminal out of me.
What? One moment, now.
You admit to these indiscretions?
I am under oath.
I cannot lie. Yes.
Not one written message.
I am under oath. I cannot lie.
- No!
- Wait a moment, now.
I beg you to consider
that she has cheated her...
- Confess a lie!
- Treason...
- Never...
- Stop.
Oh, thank you. I'm exhausted.
- So am I.
- I can't go on with this.
I can't.
I just can't.
Neither can I.
No more questions.
You may sleep until I count to three.
Then you will awaken
completely refreshed
and you'll remember nothing.
Except to smoke less.
Now, sleep.
- Mrs Hatch.
- Yes, doctor?
I've recorded this session.
After I leave, would you make
three copies of it, please.
And send one
to Dr Conrad Fuller.
One, two, three.
How do you feel?
Fine. How'd I do?
Beyond my wildest expectations.
Do you think I'll smoke less
tomorrow night?
I mean, you know, more normal?
Yes, I think so.
Oh, Dr Chabot,
if there's anything I can ever do
for you,
I mean, really, just,
you know, anything.
Pronounce my name "Chabot."
Isn't it C-H-A-B-O-T?
Yes, Chabot.
Oh, well, anything you say.
Thank you.
Well.
- Goodbye.
The...
Thank you.
Tad.
- Hi.
- Well, well. How are you?
- What are you doing here?
- Well, you know.
Same old thing.
- Looking for myself.
- Yeah, but what are you doing here?
Well, I thought I might
take a course in anatomy.
Maybe I'll find out how you do
all those wonderful things.
No. Oh, for Pete's sake, don't say
anything about that around here.
I mean, will you?
I mean, for Pete's sake.
Why? It's... It's not un-American.
I mean, you've got some kind
of psychic power, that's all.
- I think it's beautiful.
- Yeah, to you, maybe.
That's because you're a nut.
Daisy, a lot of people are psychic.
Fine. I'm sure they're all very nice,
but that is not the group
I'd like to be known as in.
I mean, if Warren ever found out,
he'd never forgive me.
He thinks I'm, you know, normal.
Normal?
Nobody even knows what normal is.
Warren does.
I did write to you
about Warren and me, didn't I?
What are you looking at?
I think you're sexier.
You think sexier? I thought you were
noticing that I'm not smoking.
- Oh, here, excuse me...
- No, no, no! I'm trying to quit.
Where are they? No, no, thanks.
Darn.
Two hours and seven minutes
without a weed.
I gotta tell the doctor.
Doctor? What doctor?
I went to this doctor, you know,
to help me stop smoking.
You went to a doctor for that? Why?
Because five packs a day
is just un-normal.
- Oh, Warren.
- Yeah.
That's him. The one in the chair.
Isn't he dynamic?
Hey, you wanna see the job I'm really
interested in? I mean, this is terrific.
They've got the finest
retirement plan I've ever seen,
and the pension starts
15 years before retirement.
- Fifteen years?
- Can you imagine?
You see, compensation
when you're sick doubles.
They pay for any operation,
including surgery,
and in the event
of mental breakdown,
they pick up the tab
for the sanitarium
for you or your wife,
in the event that she passes.
Boy, when I stop to think I almost
settled for that job in Paris, I could...
What the hell is she growing here,
Yosemite National Park?
I don't know how she does it.
- I planted mine the very same day.
- Where are yours?
There.
Oh, boy, this is embarrassing.
She's gotta cut that out.
I'm so worried
about my nicotine stains.
- Daisy, Daisy, I've gotta talk to you.
- Warren, this is Tad Pringle.
- Hi, fella. Daisy, I've gotta talk to you...
- He used to be my brother.
Really? Your what?
Well, not actually. I mean, his father
was married to my mother once.
Eight years ago. Daisy and I were
very happy. Our parents weren't.
The judge stopped
the fight in the third year.
That's very interesting.
Daisy... You'll... Daisy.
Daisy, I've gotta talk to you
about tomorrow night.
Now, how do you feel?
You nervous?
- Well, l...
- Swell. Just a couple of points
to integrate into the image.
Now, tomorrow night, before dinner,
no whiskey and no martinis.
- Sherry. It's more feminine. Got it?
- Sherry? But I throw up when l...
Swell. Remember about the dress?
Not too low and not too high.
You see, Unkstadder's wife
is coming.
And if she catches him looking
up anything or down anything, that's it.
So tomorrow night, you're a boy.
Oh, and, Daisy, for God's sake,
no opinions.
I mean, talk all you want if you
need anything, but no opinions.
See, they don't like women
to have opinions.
In fact, they don't really like women.
They like wives and mothers.
Let me see your fingers.
Come on, Daisy. Let me see...
Can't you get that nicotine off?
From the knuckles down,
you look like Ho Chi Minh.
Warren, don't worry.
You'll never guess what l...
Come here, Daisy,
I want you to see this.
This is our whole future.
Security unlimited.
Just a few years' work and we
can relax for the rest of our lives.
Yes? Oh, hello, Conrad.
Did you read the transcript?
What you think?
It's amazing, isn't it?
The names? Well, like all these cases,
she must have gotten them
from friends or books or movies.
Look them up?
In what?
Books about England.
Conrad, if you're implying that this
could be a case of reincarnation,
you are sicker than she is.
No, no, I can't see her anymore.
I have no time for all that nonsense.
See you tomorrow.
And from now on, you will find
the third puff of every cigarette
will have a bitter, bitter taste.
Remember, the third puff.
Open your eyes.
Now, Miss Gamble,
yesterday you claimed
to recall a previous life
when your name was
Melinda Waine Moorepark Tentrees.
There's a Winifred in there.
Yes, I know. Now, where
did you get the name Melinda?
From my aunt.
She was the fattest woman in London.
- In London?
- Yeah.
They used to say that
the duke of Westminster
owned everything in London
except one acre, my aunt.
That's very funny.
Then you definitely
have been to London?
Oh, yeah.
How many times?
- Once.
- For how long?
Twenty-eight years.
Twenty-eight years?
How old were you when you left?
Twenty-eight years.
Are you saying
that you left because you...
...died?
Yeah.
What's the matter?
I just hated to die at 28.
I just hope I don't have to do it again.
It's better than 22.
But tell me,
how did you ever climb
from the kitchen maid's daughter
to Lady Moorepark?
How?
Because of a lesson
I learned at the orphanage
where my impoverished mother
placed me as a child.
Where was your father?
Don't be rude.
Our postman, Mr Pimpleton.
And this is Mrs Brickstone himself.
I scrubbed, oh.
And scrubbed, oh.
And I ate.
For recreation, I plotted my escape.
I knew the exact location
of the hitching post
on the other side of the wall.
And I had practiced with this rope
for almost two years.
Up and up I went toward freedom.
My new quarters.
I looked around and thought,
"Oh, dear."
Thirty days in this dungeon
with nothing to do.
I found something to do.
Every night, I heard voices
on the other side of the wall,
which aroused my curiosity.
Cor blimey, a secret room.
Just the sort of place you expect
to find a buried treasure.
And what did I find?
A buried treasure.
Next to the name
of every child in the school
was the name
of the real, unknown father.
Except mine, of course.
It was lord this and the duke
of that and the earl of whatnot.
And as I turned the pages,
suddenly, through the dank
mustiness of the room,
I realized that I had in my hands
the sort of stuff
that sent the flower
of English manhood
out into the world to create
an empire
and might very well
create a little empire for me.
My letters were simple and honest:
"Dear lord so-and-so, if you do not
wish your child to know who you are,
please send 1 pound a month.
Sincerely..."
He sent 1, and he sent 1.
And so did lots of others.
In fact, business was marvellous.
Until one day,
a nasty, dishonest child
stole my letters.
To my joy and happiness,
I was expelled.
When I saw the glow
those pound notes brought
to my dear mother's eyes,
I made a firm resolution.
"Melinda," I said,
"let this be a lesson to you.
Never, never do anything
except for money."
But what about Robert Tentrees?
He had no money
and you married him, didn't you?
True, he had
not a penny to his name.
But love is the exception
to every rule, is it not?
You're crying.
Why?
I should have known
that one day he would desert me.
Desert you?
He was too weak to be faithful.
Why didn't I see that?
Is love so blind?
No.
But mistrust is so exhausting.
It's not easy to be
a strong woman, Melinda.
A man must be strong
for you to respect him,
but weak for you to love him.
And love makes the choice.
That's very clever of you.
Very clever.
Who are you, exactly?
I could ask the same of you.
But you seem to know me
better than I know myself.
That's because
I may have invented you.
Now, what does that mean?
Or don't you know either?
Oh, dear.
I'm suddenly a little...
A little...
Oh, boy, am I beat.
You must be.
What's the matter with me?
There was never Melinda.
Robert never existed.
How could someone who never existed
desert someone who never lived?
And when I heard it,
why did it make me so sad?
No.
None of this is true.
None of it happened.
It's nothing but shadows and
echoes of things that never were.
This is a dream, Melinda
Just a mirage, so they say
This whole affair
They all declare
Was dreamed each step of the way
You're a mere dream, Melinda
Out for a gay little spin
Dealing me lies before my eyes
Of days that never have been
There's no Melinda
They say for sure
But don't go, Melinda
I know and you know
That you're no mere dream, Melinda
Gone when the dawn
Glimmers through
You and I know that long ago
Before the dream there was you
There
Once
Was you
Damn you, Melinda.
If I'm not on guard every moment,
you steal across the border into reality.
There have been thousands
of cases like yours.
And every one, without exception,
has been traced
to something in the person's life.
This life.
Daisy Gamble, somewhere
in some closet of your mind
is the key to all this.
And I intend to find it.
If I have to squeeze out of you every
moment of your whole boring little life.
So en garde.
One, two, three.
Hi.
How do you feel?
Fine. Did I do all right?
I think so.
How was the smoking
last night and today?
Oh, much better. If the phone
hadn't rung this morning,
I wouldn't have smoked
until breakfast.
Do you always smoke
on the telephone?
Well, you've got to.
I mean, you just got to.
I mean, you got this hand
left over doing nothing.
Of course, I usually hear it before
it rings and light up ahead of time.
Of course.
Where are you meeting Warren?
At the Americana.
Can I give you a lift?
- Oh, thanks.
- Good.
You know?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
You sure I'm not gonna
take you out of your way?
No, you're not. Not at all.
I'm going to the Metropolitan Museum.
It's open tonight
and there's an exhibition
of English painters
that I want to see.
Oh, that's nice.
England's had
some very good painters.
I don't know much about it, really.
I mean, anything.
Don't you like painting?
I don't know.
I've gotten so used to wallpaper.
But it's still much easier driving
over here than in England.
In England, they drive on the left.
Boy, those English sure have
a lot of guts.
No, it's the law.
- Haven't you ever been to England?
- Oh, no.
The sea makes me seasick
and I'm afraid of flying.
I mean, not really flying,
I'm afraid of the "no smoking" sign.
- But maybe I can do it now, huh?
- I'm sure.
Wouldn't you like a quick drink?
You have time.
Oh, no, no. Thank you.
I don't think so.
I'm supposed to be
at the Americana at...
- A short one.
- Fine.
And what are you studying?
Well, let's see.
Oh, I'm taking domestic science
at Laura Bates Greeley
and budget-making
at Mary Hope Curtis
and child care at the Sarah Plaut
Gromberg Clinic,
you know, here
at the medical school.
And 20 lectures on planned
parenthood, ten on how to
and ten on how not to.
What size family do you
come from?
Well, my father's pretty fat,
but the rest of us is...
Oh, you mean how many
brothers and sisters.
None.
I had this great stepbrother for a while,
but it didn't last very long.
I mean, there was, you know,
trouble in the front office.
You lived with your mother?
Yeah. In Mahwah, New Jersey.
- Where?
- Mahwah. M-A-H-W-A-H.
That's where...
That's where she lives.
- Fascinating.
- It is?
- Another drink?
- Oh, no, no, no. Thank you, really.
- I've gotta run.
- A short one.
Oh, fine.
- Muriel, have you seen Daisy?
- I thought she was with you.
Oh, I goofed. Chemical Foods called
this afternoon and postponed
and I forgot to call
and tell her.
- Warren.
- Daisy, Daisy, I'm sorry.
It was called off
and I forgot to tell you.
- Did you wait too long?
- Oh, no.
- But you got something to eat?
- Yeah.
- Will you forgive me?
- Sure.
- Thattagirl.
- I forgot too.
- What?
- I didn't go,
you know, to the Americana.
I forgot too.
- You didn't go?
- No.
Isn't that a funny coincidence?
Yes, it certainly is. It's amazing.
You didn't go either.
You... Didn't you really?
No, I didn't. And I'm not just saying
that to make you feel good.
Oh, I believe you. I believe you.
It's just that, well,
Daisy, this was an important night,
and what the hell were you doing?
What's the matter, Warren?
Everything worked out fine.
- Aren't you happy?
- Yeah, I'm very happy.
- Why don't you smile?
- I am.
I like your smile, Warren. Super.
See you tomorrow.
Look...
- Daisy...
- Good night, Warren.
Now, that's what I call a man.
What are you gonna do
about Warren?
That's the first time in my life
I felt like the opposite sex.
What are you gonna do
about Warren?
I wonder if he'll ask me
out tomorrow night.
What are you gonna do
about Warren?
What am I gonna do about Warren?
Oh, Warren doesn't care.
- Warren cares.
But I don't care.
You have to care because
you're engaged to him.
You don't have to care about him
because how do you know
he cares about you?
Then what are you gonna do?
What'd you say?
When you know there's someone
Loving you
And you know there's someone
You love too
And they're not the same
What do you do?
Go to sleep, girl
Go to sleep
Close your eyes
And hide from every care
When you wake up
They may not be there
But tell me, how can I sleep?
Tell me who could
When you see your whole life
Tangled up good?
I could drink
I could weep
Oh, but how can I sleep?
Go to sleep
And when you and someone
Have a date
Which you made
When you were thinking straight
And when you and someone
Stay out late
It was bad to
But I had to
When they're not the same
Who gets the gate?
This is not the way to find a mate
Go to sleep, girl
Go to sleep
Comes the dawn
I may not feel the same
He may not know your name
In the sunlight
Who can see a flame?
But tell me, how can I sleep?
Look what I've done
Mess around with two men
Soon you have none
As you sow, so you reap
Which is why I can't sleep
Go to sleep
Go to...
How do you happen to be in command
of all this useless knowledge?
Because I'm interested
in extrasensory perception, ESP.
What does it have to do
with ESP?
Because if a case such as this
is not the memory of a past life,
then somehow...
...knowledge is being acquired
by a sense
other than the five that we know
about. Ergo, extrasensory.
And, my boy, that's the solution
we'd better root for.
Because if reincarnation is
ever proven,
do you know who will be
the hardest hit?
The sweethearts of Sigmund Freud.
Did you ever look up Pelham and
Company or any of those ships?
This is a fantasy, Conrad.
To 600 million Muhammadans,
so is Christmas.
- Yes?
- Daisy Gamble is here, doctor.
May I meet her?
Ask her to come in.
Did you ever try to hypnotize
her by telepathy?
Oh, for God's sake, Conrad.
Telepathy.
- Hello, doctor.
- Hello.
I brought you these.
Miss Gamble, may I present
Dr Fuller.
Oh, hello.
How do you do, Miss Gamble?
I was just leaving.
They're geraniums.
Any minute now.
Miss Gamble says that she can make
flowers grow faster.
Faster than what, Miss Gamble?
Well, you know, faster.
What I mean, my friend Muriel and I,
we plant our seeds on the same day,
and, I don't know, my flowers come
charging out of the pot
as if the police were after them,
and poor Muriel...
Do you ever talk to your flowers,
Miss Gamble?
Talk to them?
What do you think I am, crazy?
Do you?
- You don't think I should?
- Yes, I do,
and don't let anyone stop you, either.
Well, goodbye, Miss Gamble.
Oh, Marc, I advise you to check
those names.
I brought these for your window.
- You know, sill?
- Thank you.
Let's put them over here.
Doctor,
were you thinking about me
around 4:00 this morning?
I was asleep then, Miss Gamble.
Why?
So was I, but something woke me up.
I could've sworn it was you.
Really?
Those look just great there.
Gotta bring you some more.
Miss Gamble.
I wonder if I could hypnotize
you by...
...telepathy.
What would I have to do?
Just sit here...
...perfectly still, and empty
your mind of all thought.
And I'll stand over here,
and at a certain moment,
I'll begin hypnotizing you
in my mind.
Do you understand?
Sure, I understand.
It's such a ridiculous...
Very good, Miss Gamble.
And very irritating.
About Melinda Tentrees,
you told me
that your husband Robert
deserted you.
Please. Not when I'm about
to make an entrance.
Number four.
Black.
Melinda, my dear.
What a questionable surprise.
Do sit down, if you insist.
Thank you.
It's quite fascinating. I cannot lose.
If I win, I win.
If I lose, you'll be in agony,
and I win.
Number ten. Black.
Well, you have lost.
And I am hardly writhing
on the floor.
Ladies and gentlemen,
place your bets.
And unlike you,
I know what it is to be poor.
All you have ever been
is without funds.
You're so smug about your humble
beginnings, aren't you? You bore me.
Rien ne va plus.
That is not true.
You may resent me, Robert.
But you are not bored.
Number 19.
Red.
Play 24.
I've lost everything, what?
- Everything.
- Splendid.
I don't wish to be rich,
I don't wish to be knighted
and I don't wish to be married.
You lie.
Number 24. Black.
Yes. I lie.
Do you enjoy lying?
To you and with you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
place your bets.
Play 36.
Rien ne va plus.
Must you have everything?
Man cannot live by bed alone.
Number 36. Red.
Good Lord, what does she
see in him?
That gigolo.
What a strange creature woman is.
Does kindness, generosity
and devotion
fill her with kindness, generosity
and devotion?
But give her a good-for-nothing rat
who pinches her money
and every girl in town,
and she'll turn into an angel of love.
Oh, God, why didn't you make
woman first, when you were fresh?
"Robert: Must you have everything?
Melinda: Man cannot live
by bed alone."
"Doctor: Now may we go on?
Patient: I am quite tired.
Doctor: I can see you are.
You may sleep until..."
Et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
This is the case to date.
Now I want to see
by a show of hands
how many of you think it's
a psychological fantasy?
Everybody.
There's no question about it.
No argument.
And no evidence.
Only prejudice.
In my opinion, this case merits
further investigation.
And I intend to go on searching
the patient's life and mind for a clue.
In addition, the information about
England must also be checked.
If any of you have the time or interest,
I would welcome your help.
And the expected high for today
will be 72 degrees.
The time is now 16 minutes past 8.
On the local front,
a nasty case of mysticism
has struck
the Stuyvesant Medical School.
Yesterday Dr Marc Chabot,
professor of psychiatry,
let it be known
that he was investigating
a possible case of reincarnation.
And by dawn, the school
was surrounded.
Countless students, seeking
a fresh cause for rebellion,
congregated in front of the medical
school demanding academic freedom.
An emergency meeting of
the Stuyvesant board of directors
was called for this morning.
I want those junkies out of the yard.
We'll get them out, Brad.
Marc, we were told that yesterday
in your lecture hall,
you read aloud a case history
of one of your current patients,
and in the discussions
that followed,
you indicated that one possible
explanation...
You'll have to forgive me, Marc,
but this is what we heard.
One possible explanation
could be reincarnation.
Now, what actually happened, Marc?
That's what happened.
What the hell did you say that for?
- Because it could be.
- It could be.
But the point is it isn't.
The stink's coming right
through the walls.
We know, Brad.
Get them out of here before they
start setting themselves on fire.
We will, Brad!
This medical school is
a damn sick little guy.
The only way you're gonna be able
to get rid of the poison is surgery.
We've gotta go deep
with that scalpel.
I'm presiding here, Crock.
You might try to remember
how difficult it is
to get good college presidents
these days.
Gentlemen, I think we can cut
through all of this.
Marc, in a privately sponsored school,
such as Stuyvesant,
academic freedom means that if you
disagree with the administration,
you're free to go to
another academy.
That's a choice that you're
going to have to make.
At 10:00 tomorrow morning,
I want you to bring into my office
either a letter denying emphatically
that your remarks had
any mystic implications
or a letter of resignation.
Is that clear?
Mason, I don't see how you could ask
me to do anything else.
We have got to stop this kind
of publicity.
Good day, gentlemen.
And it was never my intention
to suggest reincarnation
as a possible solution
to this case.
I only wanted my students
to learn that all possibilities
must always...
Are you all right, doctor?
Yes, come in, come in.
All those things they said about
you in the paper, I was so worried.
- Come in.
- I mean, how is
- your mental health, doctor?
- It's fine, thank you.
Oh, you're welcome.
Boy, what a layout.
Gee, this is really something.
Who's that?
The woman who lives here.
- Oh, I thought you lived here.
- I do.
Where is she now?
Away with her husband.
- Are they French too?
- No. No.
They gave me their apartment
for the summer.
You sure you're all right?
Yes.
Doctor, how long has this stuff
been going on?
Quite a while.
Does anybody besides you know
who the thing is happening to?
- I mean, you know, who the nut is?
- No.
And no one ever will.
Do most people think it was
a man or a woman?
Yes, most people think it was
a man or a woman.
Daisy, would you mind if we skipped
your session tonight?
That's all right.
But we can still have dinner
if you like.
Oh, great! And will you let me
pick out where?
Of course.
Nobody ever asks me where
I wanna go except you.
I mean, everybody usually,
you know, always tells me.
I'm kind of a...
You know, a go-alonger.
I mean, people say "Come along,"
and I go along.
Downstairs where I live,
they've got
this restaurant called
Enrico and Bernardi's.
But, well, I mean,
does anybody ever say:
"Daisy, do you wanna go
to Enrico and Bernardi's?"
No. No, they say:
"Daisy, we are going
to Enrico and Bernardi's.
You want to come along?"
So I go along.
I don't even like
Enrico and Bernardi's.
They've got absolutely rotten food.
And the pizza, well, I have lost
more temporary fillings...
Hello.
Oh, it's you.
How are you tonight?
I am accused of treason.
And tomorrow I shall be ordered
to stand trial.
Does Robert know?
I sent him a message two hours ago.
Where is he?
He should be home soon.
Could this be the moment
he deserted you?
Deserted me?
Robert has not deserted me,
and he never will.
You ought to know.
Why?
Do you think I can see
into the future?
Yes.
I can about certain things.
But never, never about myself.
Oh, I am pleased you came tonight.
An hour ago I was ready to leap
from the bridge.
What's the matter?
Melinda, I came to say goodbye.
Goodbye?
We shan't be together ever again?
No.
That's dreadful.
I shall miss you.
I shall miss you too.
You have brought something
into my life I never knew existed.
What's that?
Mystery.
How odd.
You have brought clarity
into mine.
What will I ever do without you?
- You have Robert.
- I know.
Whom you love.
I know.
But he isn't you.
How could I be
This at ease with him?
Pour out my heart
As I please with him?
He isn't you
When will I feel
So in bloom again?
When will a voice
Warm the room again?
He isn't you
Memories may fade
In the shadows behind me
But there'll be the dream
That will always remind me
A dream
That I'll be forever
Comparing him to
So love me, he may
Even die for me
Sweep every cloud
From the sky for me
He may be king
But he'll never
Be you
But why must you turn back
into a caterpillar, Melinda?
How did you ever become
this little nothing of a creature?
Oh, sometimes I think
if I hear another "I mean,"
I will tighten my tie until I strangle.
Marc, sit down.
Mason, you asked me yesterday
to prepare a statement.
Forgive me, Marc. Could we
table that for a moment?
- Why?
- Just bear with me.
Marc, you know this building
is called Stratton Hall.
Do you know who
Cleo Stratton is?
The man who owns
that enormous yacht in the river?
He lives on it.
He's now 80.
During the past 25 years he's
had diabetes, tuberculosis,
cataracts, half dozen
assorted tumours,
ulcers, gallstones
and water on the knee,
all of which the doctors here
at Stuyvesant have cured.
Coincidentally,
during this same period,
he has given the school
over $20 million,
including his Social Security
and Medicare checks.
Mr Stratton heard about
our conversation yesterday
and called me early this morning
to inform me
he was definitely in favour
of your being allowed
to continue with your case.
With the four of us against it,
it made the final vote ten for you
and none opposed.
He not only wants you to continue
with your case,
but he wants me to organize
a permanent department
for research into reincarnation.
Good Lord.
Yes, I believe he is.
But Mr Stratton wants proof.
It occurred to him that if it's possible
to identify one's previous incarnations,
it might also be possible to determine
one's future ones,
in which case Mr Stratton
could leave his money to himself.
You mean, if he can't take it with him,
he'll come back and get it?
Yes.
Well, what do you think, Marc?
Well, what do you expect?
It's the chance of a lifetime,
of all my lifetimes.
Thank you.
I will so inform him.
You're...
You're not happy about it,
are you, Mason?
No, I'm not happy.
I think reincarnation is appalling.
It kills ambition,
perpetuates human misery
and propagates false hopes.
And is obviously a pack of lies.
Then how can you accept
his proposition?
I may be wrong.
Dr Chabot's office.
Oh, yes. Yes, doctor, she's here.
One moment, please.
The doctor will be a little late.
Can you wait?
Yes, she can.
Oh, then I can go home now?
Thank you, doctor. Good night.
You don't mind being alone, do you?
He won't be long.
Oh, no, don't worry about me.
I wanna listen to the news, you know,
about him, if there is any.
- Good night.
I'm Daisy Gamble.
Maybe I was called
something else once,
but the only name I...
Take your time.
I mean, my name has always...
My name is...
My name is Melinda.
Melinda Winifred Waine Tentrees.
And I am appalled and stunned
at this outrageous inquisition.
You may sleep until I count to three
and snap my fingers,
and then you will awake
and remember nothing about Melinda.
Now, sleep.
But why must you turn back
into a caterpillar, Melinda?
How did you ever become
this little nothing of a creature?
Oh, sometimes I think if I hear
another "I mean,"
I will tighten my tie until I strangle.
Daisy Gamble,
somewhere in your mind
is the key to all this,
and I intend to find it,
if I have to squeeze out of you every
moment of your whole boring little...
I don't know why
They redesigned me
He likes the way
He used to find me
He likes the girl
I left behind me
I mean, he...
I mean, me...
What did I have
That I don't have?
What did he like
That I lost track of?
What did I do
That I don't do
The way I did before?
What isn't there
That once was there?
What have I got
A great big lack of?
Something in me then
He could see then
Beckons to him no more
I'm just a victim of time
Obsolete in my prime
Out-of-date and outclassed
By my past
What did he love
That there's none of?
What did I lose
The sweet, warm knack of?
Wouldn't I be
The late, great me
If I knew how?
What did I have
I don't
Have now?
I thought he kind of liked me.
And all the time he was thinking
of someone else.
Me.
Those questions.
He wasn't interested in me.
He was interested in me.
Oh, God.
Why did I have to come along?
I mean, what is so special
about an English accent?
Cheerio.
Tallyho, doctor.
Yes, she gave me the jolly message.
Oh, nothing. Nothing is wrong.
After all, what is time?
If you miss me in this life, you can
catch me in the next, can't one?
Eh, what?
Well, kippered herring!
What did I have that I don't have?
What do I need a big supply of?
What was the trick I did
Particularly well before?
What did he see that's gone in me?
What did I use that now I'm shy of?
Why is the sequel never the equal?
Why is there no encore?
Where can I go to repair
All the wear and the tear
Till I'm once again the previous me?
What did he like that I am not like?
What was the charm
That I've run dry of?
What would I give
If my old know-how
Still knew how?
Oh, what did I know?
Tell me, where did it go?
What, oh, what did I have
I don't
Have
Now?
Daisy!
What did you mean, "the next life"?
What were you talking about?
I've been trying to find you
since 6:00.
- Where did you go?
- To Max's Hardware Store.
- Where?
- Max's Hardware Store!
My watering can fell off the roof.
But...? But where have you been
since then?
You knew we were supposed to work.
I had...
Oh, you wanted to do
some researching tonight?
- You know, with me?
- Of course.
Casually glance at some
old English stuff together?
- We might. It's possible.
- And maybe top off the evening
with a little hypnotism?
Sort of one little trance
before nighty-night?
- It's for your good, Daisy.
- Get off my roof!
- What?
- I said, get off my roof!
- What's the matter?
- Get this straight, Chabot.
Your courting days are over.
I am through being a go-between
for you and your dream girl.
You're not gonna go on
using my head for a motel!
Oh, my God. This is disastrous.
Oh, no.
Now that you know who you are,
you can influence every memory.
You're no longer reliable.
How did you find out? Who told you?
- I played a tape, and all I can say...
- Which tape?
- How do I know?! All I can say is...
- What was it about?
It was in a foreign language!
All I can say is...
- Did you tell anyone?
- And get put in a circus? No.
All I can say is... Oh, rats,
I don't even remember anymore.
Oh, yeah, yeah. All I can say is,
if you tell anybody it's me, I'll sue.
Do you hear me? I'll sue!
There may still be a chance.
Daisy...
The first finger that touches me,
I cut off.
Daisy, I insist you stop
this neurotic behaviour at once.
Neurotic?!
You get the hots over somebody
you're not even sure was anybody,
you call me neurotic?!
Physician, heal thyself!
Daisy. Daisy, Daisy, because
I didn't tell you what I was doing,
you may feel betrayed and hurt.
But a case like yours
happens once in a million years.
And, Daisy, we have a breathtaking
adventure in front of us.
By the time we finish, you may find
yourself not only not an abnormal girl,
but one of the few genuinely normal
people on Earth.
Get off my roof!
I will not get off your roof
until I bring you to your senses.
Any other girl would be proud
to be part of this adventure.
Great. If you want to experiment,
go pick on someone else.
I can't, Daisy. I can't.
Daisy, I need you.
You bet your Aunt Susie
you need me.
And not for the noble cause
of science, either.
- You wanna see Melinda.
- Melinda's beside the point.
- You got the hots for Melinda!
- I am not your business!
That's right, doctor.
You're not.
And I'm not yours either.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I got a lot of things to do.
I gotta... I gotta spend more time
with Warren.
I gotta plan my life
with Chemical Foods.
And I need my roof!
So if you don't mind,
one, two, three, beat it!
Your roof?
Very well, keep your roof.
It's as close to heaven
as you'll ever get.
Melinda's soul inside of you?
God, what a housing shortage.
Damn you, Daisy,
I can't let you free. I can't.
Not with all the buried treasure
inside you.
- Help!
- You'll see me again.
You can count on that.
Again and again.
You have an appointment
tomorrow at 6. Be there!
Clip, clip!
Rats.
Oh, no, you don't,
Dr Marc Chabot.
You are not going to hypnotize me
into coming back.
Fourscore and seven years ago,
our forefathers brought forth upon
this continent a new nation
conceived in liberty
and dedicated to the proposition...
Mary had a little lamb,
its fleece was white as snow.
Everywhere that Mary went,
her lamb was sure to...
Hey, what in the name of...?
What the hell do you mean, "shh"?
Jerk.
Fourscore and seven years ago,
our forefathers brought forth upon...
- Daisy!
- A new nation...
- Daisy, what are you doing?
- Liberty and dedicated to...
Daisy, what's happened to you?!
I left you a while ago, you were quiet.
Daisy, pay attention!
What are you doing?!
Daisy, what in heaven...?
That's rude.
That is very rude, and I'm shocked.
That, Daisy, is not necessary.
I like you the way you are.
Daisy! Listen to me!
Oh, Warren!
This is not behaving
in a company way.
Daisy, will you...
For Pete's sake, look out!
Marc!
Yes, Conrad.
Marc, get out the champagne.
Shake out the confetti.
- What's the matter with you?
- I solved your case, that's all.
Will you ever forgive me?
The place to look for spooks,
my dear doctor,
is not in a medical library
or in Burke's Peerage,
but in a spook book.
This is an encyclopaedia
of 19th-century psychics.
- May I read aloud?
- Yes, go on.
"Tentrees, Melinda. Clairvoyant.
Dates, 1787-1815.
Married to Sir Robert Tentrees.
In celebrated case,
Melinda Tentrees found guilty
of conspiring with enemies
of the crown
and was executed one year
after sentencing."
How does that grab you?
What about her husband?
Oh, yeah, well, that's here.
That's here.
"Melinda Tentrees claimed
all her information resulted
from psychic powers, but her husband
failed to appear at her trial.
His evidence might have saved her."
Well,
there it is.
And may I add that I find your gratitude
absolutely underwhelming.
Then she is not an illusion.
She lived.
Conrad, I have the feeling
I've known that girl before.
I've got to find out if it's true.
Hi, fella.
- Hi.
- You seen Daisy?
- No.
- That's good.
Is something the matter?
No, no, no, it's just that we have a date
tonight with the personnel director
of Chemical Foods at 6:00
at the Americana and his wife.
I just wanna make sure
she doesn't forget it again.
I wouldn't worry about that now.
Yeah, well, you wouldn't worry
about it now because it's me.
- Wait till you have to get a job.
- I'm not going to.
Oh, really?
Oh, how you gonna arrange that?
I'm rich.
Oh, boy.
Oh, that's depressing.
You know, it's funny you never know
where Daisy is.
Why?
Well, you're engaged to her.
Don't you ever ask her what she does?
No.
- You're incredible.
- Top 2 percent.
Listen, how come I never see you
with any medical books?
I mean, are you really going to school,
or did you buy the teacher?
I haven't started yet.
Then why are you hanging
around here?
- Actually, I came to see Daisy.
- Why?
She wrote me that she
was gonna be married
and I wanted to see
if she was happy.
Too bad.
Why, you got a better idea?
Yes.
Me.
You?
That's incest!
- We're only related by marriage.
- Well, what other way is there?
- Morning.
Honey, you look kind of tired.
You ought to go back to bed.
I mean, you gotta be
in top form tonight.
Daisy, do you remember
everything we talked about?
- Yeah.
- All right, now, listen, Daisy,
for God's sake, don't let on that
you know that screwball hypnotist.
Sweet mother India,
if they ever found out about that...
Oh, hey, Daisy, I got a great piece
of news for you. You ready?
You don't have to worry
about the cigarettes.
I found out Mrs Unkstadder
is a chain-smoker.
Isn't that a hot one, huh?
Oh, that is...
That... That is really a hot one.
Oh, Warren, that...
That is really a riot.
Isn't that a hot riot, Tad?
Well...
...l've really got a hot one
for you too, Warren.
I'm that patient of Dr Chabot's.
I'm Melinda.
I'm not hearing this.
And do you know why
my flowers get so tall?
Because I talk to them.
Every morning I come up here
and I read them Walter Lippmann.
You talk to them?
And do you know what else?
I can tell when the phone's
gonna ring.
Walter Lippmann?
Watch.
Tell him I'm out!
Hello? She's out.
Now, Warren, what time do we
meet tonight, huh? Six o'clock?
Oh, great. I just can't wait for you
to see my new dress.
Oh, it is not too low,
it is not too short.
It is transparent!
- But, Daisy, what...?
- I can't, Warren!
- I just can't!
- But, Daisy...
Oh, Warren!
Get off my roof.
I've been calling for eight days,
and for eight days
I've been told Miss Gamble is out.
When has she been in?
If she's not been in,
then she's not out. She's away.
Now, which is it?
Is she out or is she away?
And if she's away, when did...?
Hello. Hello!
If you don't mind my saying so,
doctor,
why are you so interested
in coming back?
You don't seem to be having
that good a time.
Thank you, Mrs Hatch.
You've done the impossible.
You've given my depression
a depression.
You're out there somewhere,
Daisy Gamble.
And you can hear me.
So listen!
Hear my voice
Where you are
Take the train
Steal a car
Hop a freight
Grab a star
Come back to me
Catch a plane
Catch a breeze
On your hands
On your knees
Swim or fly
Only, please
Come back to me
On a mule
In a jet
With your hair in a net
In a towel, wringing wet
I don't care
This is where
You should be
From the hills
From the shore
Ride the wind to my door
Turn the highway to dust
Break the law if you must
Move the world, only just
Come back to me
Making a soufflé requires
alertness and cunning
and patience.
And above all, stamina.
Beat, beat, beat.
Blast your hide
Hear me call
Must I fight city hall?
Here and now
Damn it all
Come back to me
What on earth must I do?
Scream and yell till I'm blue?
Curse your soul
When will you come back to me?
Have you gone to the moon?
Or the corner saloon
And to rack and to ruin
Mademoiselle, where in hell
Can you be?
Leave a sign on your door
Out to lunch
Evermore
In a Rolls or a van
Wrapped in mink or saran
Any way that you can
Come back to me
Damn you, Daisy Gamble,
where are you?
Why can't you pick up a phone?
Hear my voice
Through the din
Feel the waves
On your skin
Like a call from within
Come back to me
Leave behind all you own
Tell your flowers you will phone
Let your dog walk alone
Come back to me
Let your tub overflow
If a date waits below
Let him wait for Godot
Ride a rail
Come by mail
COD
Par avion
Par bateau
Dans une vieille
Deux chevaux
Come by steam
Come by gas
Come for free
On a pass
Under drugs
Under glass
Come back to me
Leave your bills all unpaid
Let your bed go unmade
Your soufflé unsouffléd
Come back to me
Come by sail
Come by freight
In a box or a crate
With your head on a plate
I don't care
This is where you should be
Come in pain or in joy
As a girl, as a boy
In a bag or a trunk
Shut up!
On a horse or a drunk
In a Ford or a funk
Come back to me
Come back...
Daisy!
Will you stop bothering me!
- Daisy, l...
- Day after day, night after night,
in the bathtub, on the roof,
awake or asleep.
What is this,
extrasensory torture?
I'd go to the police,
but with a story like this,
they'd have locked me up!
What do you want out of me?
Never mind, I know what you want,
and you can't have it
because I haven't got it.
Even if I did,
you wouldn't get it.
- What are you talking about?
- What you're thinking about, Melinda.
My name never was Melinda Tentrees.
Now, is that clear?
- How do you know?
- Because I know.
- How?
- Well, well, how could it be?
- I'm not like Melinda Tentrees.
- How do you know what she's like?
I don't, but you do,
and you like what she's like.
You don't like what I'm like,
so I know we're not alike.
I know what I'm like,
and I don't like it either.
Because I'm like nothing
and like nobody,
and nothing or nobody can change me.
I'm stuck as I am.
Weak, a go-alonger, no character!
- You have character to stop smoking.
- That's a dirty lie!
I didn't stop smoking,
you made my subconscious
stop wanting to.
And I went along, just like I always do.
Now, will you please leave me alone!
Will you please sit down!
Now, you listen to me!
As little as you know about Melinda,
it's gigantic compared to what
you know about Daisy Gamble.
You think you're nothing
and you walk around looking out
over the world like Jupiter
on Mount Olympus.
Imagine having eyes that can see
the lost article of a friend
or someone about to phone you
or to be filled with a kind of love
that pulls flowers from the ground.
And if that were not enough,
you either have a heart so deep
it spans the ages
or a mind that's filled
with the total memory of life.
Why, Daisy...
...you're a bloody miracle.
Could anyone among us
have an inkling or a clue
what magic feats of wizardry
and voodoo you can do?
And who would ever guess
What powers you possess?
And who would not be stunned
To see you prove
There's more to us
Than surgeons can remove?
So much more than we ever knew
So much more were we born to do
Should you draw back the curtain?
This, I am certain
You'll be impressed
With you
On a clear day
Rise and look around you
And you'll see
Who you are
On a clear day
How it will astound you
That the glow of your being
Outshines every star
You feel a part of
Every mountain, sea and shore
You can hear from far and near
A world you've never heard before
And on a clear day
On that clear day
You can see forever
And ever
And evermore
Gee.
Daisy, I must hypnotize you
- one more time.
- No!
Not to see Melinda, I swear it.
Now that you know,
it would probably be distorted.
It's for another reason.
I ask you as a favour.
One last time.
Just hope I haven't forgotten how...
- Daisy, can you hear me?
- Yes.
Open your eyes.
I want you to concentrate
very, very hard.
You have told me about
your life as Melinda.
Do you remember
any other previous lifetimes?
Oh, sure.
How many?
Let's see.
One, two, three, four.
Five.
Six.
Seven, eight, nine, ten, 11, 12.
Thirteen.
- Fourteen...
- That's enough, Daisy.
In all those lifetimes,
do you ever remember...
...meeting me?
Yes.
Did we know each other well?
We were married.
Happily married?
It was...
...beyond anything.
What were our names?
Laura and John Caswell.
Where did we live?
It's funny.
We lived in Virginia.
I can...
I can see us, but l...
I can't see all around us.
What year was it?
2038.
- I think I see...
- You don't have to go further.
No more questions.
Sleep until I count to three
and snap my fingers.
Then you will awaken and you
won't remember what you told me.
One, two, three.
Fine.
Thank you, Daisy.
When are you getting married?
Warren and I have severed
our relationship.
What are you going to do?
I don't know.
I thought I'd go up on the roof
for a while
and sit around with Tad.
You know, my ex-stepbrother.
I think that's a good idea.
- What about you?
- Well, you know, I'm married.
Oh, really?
Yes, but we're separated.
I spoke to her and somehow
I think it will be all right now.
Oh, really.
She says I've changed.
Have you?
Yes. Thanks to you.
I used to be in love with answers,
but since I have known you,
I'm just as fond of the questions.
I think the answers make you wise,
but the questions make you human.
You got that from me?
Yes, I did.
Well,
I'm glad you got something.
It's only fair.
I don't smoke anymore.
Well...
Goodbye, doctor.
Goodbye, Daisy.
Bye.
Daisy, have you...?
Have you ever been to Virginia?
No.
Have you?
Daisy.
You won't forget what I told you?
On...
...a clear day...
Rise and look around you
And you'll see
Who you are
Well...
So long, doctor.
See you later.
On a clear day
Rise and look around you
And you'll see who you are
On a clear day
How it will astound you
That the glow of your being
Outshines every star
You'll feel part of
Every mountain, sea and shore
You can hear from far and near
A world you never
Never heard before
And on a clear day
On that clear day
You can see forever
And ever and ever
And evermore