Team21@duasatu.com
The kappa are well known creatures
in Japanese folklore.
Dwelling in rivers and swamps
they have beaks turtle shells,
and scams that must be watered
mischievous beings,
they like lo challenge people lo sumo
or to pull them into the water.
Their favourite food is cucumber.
- Next batch.
- Sure.
Still alive.
Let me see.
No.
C'mon, just a peek.
-Lemme see. - No.
-Lemme see. - I said no.
Hey, what”re you doing, old woman?
Put it back!
But it's still alive.
Just put it back.
- What”re you doing? Give it to me.
- No.
- Give it to me. - No.
No, no, I won”t let you.
C'mon, give it to me!
One, two, three, tour.
One, two, three.
The old woman begins to move.
The old woman gets up.
The old woman's stomach growls.
Old woman, old woman.
The old woman thinks.
Thinks on an empty stomach.
Thinks of what to do.
Thinks with her limited mind.
Thinks with her dirty mind.
Old woman, old woman.
Back to work.
Yes, sir.
Do not swim.
Hang in there, little one.
Yikes, almost dropped you.
We”re almost there, okay?
Oh no!
That was close.
Oh, this way.
Hey.
A kappa.
A kappa!
Lt”s a kappa, a kappa!
Hey, I saw a kappa!
I said I saw a kappa!
A kappa, everyone!
I really did.
Over here.
Hurry.
What's happening?
I saw m y first kappa!
This way.
I don't see it.
I swear I saw it.
It was here.
Where is it?
Maybe over here?
Kappa! Come out, kappa!
That”s strange, I know I saw it.
Kappa! Where are you?
-Asuka.
- Yeah?
Can I announce our engagement?
Sure.
Really?
Thanks.
What?
Can I kiss you?
Sure.
There”s no kappa.
Just them kissing.
Tongue and all.
Hey.
What do you want?
Lt”s me, Tetsuya Aoki.
Remember?
Aoki?
Longtime no see.
Why are you a kappa?
I died and became a kappa.
I remember, you died in high school.
You drowned in the swamp.
That was you, right?
That”s me.
Why are you a kappa?
No, wait...
Why”s a dead person alive?
This doesn't make any sense.
Lt”s normal, Chage.
That”s my nickname.
Been a while, Chage.
So you really are a kappa.
Yeah, I need water.
How long ago was it that you drowned?
I don't remember.
We were high school seniors,
so 17 years ago?
Been that long, huh?
Yeah.
You haven”t changed.
I'm an old woman now.
No, you”re not.
What brings you here?
Stuff.
What stuff?
You know, stuff.
Asuka!
It's me.
Hide here, okay?
Uh, sure.
I'm here.
Not today.
Why not?
I have to watch some TV
Let”s watch together.
I have to think alone.
Something happened?
No, nothing.
I'm already here.
Let”s plan the wedding.
Right...
Asuka.
No, not today.
C'mon, why not?
No.
Won 'l lake long.
Think all you want later.
OW.
What was that?
It was nothing.
Take it off.
Wow.
Asuka.
Yes!
You”re amazing.
You're amazing, Asuka.
Here.
Thanks.
I'm taking a bath.
Wait, don't go there.
Hey, what”s wrong?
I'm getting horny again.
Boyfriend?
Yeah, we”re getting married.
Huh, good for you.
Aoki, have you been
a kappa ever since you drowned?
Yeah.
Whats it like?
Not all that different.
I eat fish until I'm full,
go to sleep,
wake up in the morning.
I see.
I manage all right.
I'm glad you”re alive.
Let me stay tonight.
What?
I want to live here a while.
You can't.
Hajime comes here sometimes,
and the villagers might see you.
I know, but c'mon, please?
No, go back to your swamp.
C'mon.
That”s where you live, right?
I just got here.
Let”s have some more fun.
No, I've got stuff to do.
I have to plan the wedding
and start packing too.
That? right, I $11 going to be moving.
im moving in with Hajime, you know.
Let”s play.
No.
Let”s play, Chage.
No. What do you mean, "play"?
Like sing or dance.
Or eat fish or swim, whatever.
I know, let”s do sumo
That”s stupid.
What”s stupid?
I mean, you”re not a kid anymore.
Aoki, why are you here?
C'mon, let”s play.
I said no.
Fine then, stupid Chage.
Just like this.
Forever and ever.
Just by hoping.
As sincere! y as I can.
Just by wishing.
As intensely as I can.
Everything will work out fine.
Even after I die.
Even after you die.
Even after the stars die.
Forever and ever.
Somewhere out there.
In some place we've never been.
This moment will live on.
Just like this.
Forever and ever.
Just by hoping.
As sincere! y as I can.
Just by wishing.
As intensely as I can.
Listen up, everyone.
This is Aoki,
who”ll be joining us part-time.
Hi, I'm Aoki.
He has a condition
that makes him sensitive to sunlight.
But he promises to work hard here.
So please welcome him.
Kawaguchi.
Yes?
Show him the ropes.
Yes, sir.
I appreciate it.
Are you crazy?
What”s the big deal?
Go home to your swamp.
Nope.
You shouldn't have come here.
Oh, be quiet.
Getting smart on me?
Go home, go home!
Cut it out, it”s cold.
Kappa need water, right?
I'll pour some on your head.
Does that feel good?
Hey, cut it out.
You got me wet now!
Take this, you kappa!
You want water, right?
What?
Let”s go home together.
I have a date, so don”t follow me.
Huh.
I'm serious, don't.
Fine, whatever.
Chage.
I'm going to protect you.
Idiot.
Rejected, huh?
Poor thing.
Shall we?
Check this out, and then this,
and then this.
Cool, huh?
I'm getting excited
looking at these brochures.
We're really getting married.
isn't that amazing?
Sure is.
I think I'm gonna cry.
Look, they still have gondolas!
Wanna ride one of these?
Sure.
What”s wrong? Let”s go in.
This is my house.
Liar! it's been abandoned for a while.
I used to live here.
Sure, sure.
My secret hideaway.
Where did everyone go?
The residents?
Tokyo, probably.
I'm saving up to go to Tokyo, too.
Here.
Thank you.
Got any money?
No.
Oh well, first one”s free, then.
What's wrong? Take 'em off.
Yes, ma'am.
Hey, you”re a kappa.
Sorry.
Wow, I haven”t seen
a kappa since I was a kid.
Okay, let”s do it.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Okay, then.
Come here.
Pardon, excuse me.
Where”re you going?
Sorry, I have to go somewhere.
But we have lots to decide.
I'm so sorry! Next time.
I used to play with kappa.
We'd play doctor and stuff.
Wait, is this your first time?
I'm sorry.
Okay, just leave it to me.
Hard to kiss.
Touch me.
This one, too.
Wow, they're amazing.
They”re soft.
Wow, they're so big.
Just like that.
Feels amazing.
Oh my god, it's huge.
Oh, yes.
Feels great.
I'm putting it in.
Yes, please.
Lt”s in.
Oh my god.
Oh my god, you feel good.
Feels good?
Yes, feels great.
Come here.
I'm coming.
You”re amazing.
Kappa are sure something.
Why, thank you.
Are you here?
Aoki.
Aoki, where are you?
Hey!
Where is he?
C'mon, kappa, come on out.
Hey!
Aoki!
Come on out!
Hey!
Boo.
Something good is coming.
If I wait for it.
it'll come.
Something so good
There are now words for it.
Something so fleeting.
it'll disappear it you touch it.
it'll appear before me.
I know it.
I don? understand at all.
I 7/ stay one night.
So let me drink some water.
I $11 hungry now.
So let's eat.
What? good is gluttony.
I 7/ eat anything.
The can itself.
The bottle itself.
Things that taste terrible.
Things that are bad
Things I hate.
Sadness, tears resentment.
Gluttony deliciously consumes it all.
Gluttony happily consumes ll all.
Gluttony gluttony.
Even eats the chipped plate itself.
Now just let the gastric juices
work their course.
Now just let drowsiness
take its course.
And dive deep into a dream.
Deeper and deeper.
I need more time.
How long?
About 30 years.
Idiot, that defeats the point of a life span.
I'm sure there are other lives to take.
What can I do?
it's been decided.
I'm begging you. 20 years, then.
Nope.
Aoki, time to get back to work.
Here.
Hey, please, stop it.
Bukkake, bukkake!
Please, no. bukkake...
Pour it on my head.
Lt”s cold.
Hey, cut it out.
Hey.
It stopped.
Hey there.
What”s going on?
About what?
You and Aoki seem close.
Yeah?
Something”s up.
Not really.
What, do you like him?
Not especially.
Not especially what?
Actually,
I'm getting married to the boss.
To Hajime.
So getting married
means forgetting the past.
That”s not what I said.
Aoki was your classmate, right?
He told me.
He died, became a kappa,
and came all the way here.
Can't you be nicer to him?
You two are friends, aren”t you?
Mmm, yum.
So how”s it been for you?
What?
What”d you do after high school?
I went to Tokyo.
Yeah?
I worked at an office in Shimbashi.
That 's great.
It wasn't great at all.
It was just back and forth
between home and work,
nothing really interesting at all.
Then, ten years had passed.
My parents died so I came back.
I guess you”ve been
toughing it out, too.
Asuka, we have a problem.
I wanted to reserve
the hall today but...
Oh, hi boss.
What”re you doing here?
Uh...
What”s going on?
Aoki was my high school classmate,
and he drowned and became a kappa.
Think I'm stupid?
Lt”s true.
Did you guys... do it?
Lt”s not like that.
Take a good look. He”s a kappa, see?
Looks like one,
but ii”s just a condition.
What're we gonna do?
Are we getting married?
C'mon, answer me.
We are.
Right?
That means you”ve gotta go, now.
Don't come to work, either.
Are you fucking deaf, Aoki?
Shut up, you talk big for a human.
I've died and come back to life.
I'll tell you this.
I'll never lose to you.
Hey, kappa.
You again.
Better not get in my way.
Hey, come with me.
What for?
Let”s get a drink.
Ooh, sounds good.
Dam n, that”s good.
How long?
What?
How long will Chage live?
Sorry, can”t tell you that.
But I gave you sake.
Fine, then.
She has until sunset tomorrow.
When the sun goes down,
poof, she expires.
Cant you do something?
Lt”s been decided.
Damn, I'm drunk.
I'm off.
Don”t get any ideas.
I heard it all.
Asuka's going to die?
Don't worry.
I found this love letter
you wrote in the closet.
So you loved Asuka, huh?
Lt”s not too late.
You should tell her how you feel.
Once we”re married,
we”ll have sex like this everyday.
We”ll make babies, have a family,
our kids will grow up and have kids,
and their kids will have kids...
I know.
Hey, what the hell.
Hey, that”s cold. Stop it.
Got a moment?
Here she is.
Sorry.
What?
You only have until
Sundown today to live.
Huh? What”re you talking about?
Let”s run away.
Quit with the jokes already.
Chage.
What in the world is going on?
For once, just trust me.
I think that”s why I'm here.
I want to save you.
Don't bother,
it's already been decided.
Who”s this?
What the hell”s going on?
Great, look who”s here.
Hurry, go!
Aoki, what do you want?
Chage, let”s go.
If you go, the marriage is off!
Wherever you go, I'll find you.
Chage.
Enough already!
Run!
Almost tripped.
I've decided decided.
I 've made up my mind.
All that 's left.
Is to do it, to move.
wish for it.
And just do it.
Believe in it.
And go with the wind.
The water will carry me.
The water of happiness.
Proof of life.
Like a demon with a club.
It makes me stronger.
Don? trust the tears.
Walk forwards and you won? fall.
I've decided decided.
I 've made up my mind.
All that 's left.
Is to do it, to move.
wish for it.
And just do it.
Believe in it.
And go with the wind.
The water will carry me.
Where”re we going?
Into the mountains.
I see.
Am I going to die?
No.
My time”s up, it's set in stone.
We can change it.
You think so?
I'll change it.
Gotta embrace being human
and live as long as you can.
You”re right, I'll try my best.
Good.
I'm tired. How much further?
A ways to go.
Are you serious?
Hang in there.
I'm so exhausted.
Really exhausted.
Further?
Almost there.
I'm serious, I can't go on.
Watch for Vipers.
Here?
Yeah.
We made it! Yes!
Wow, look at this.
Long time no see, sir.
Been well?
I'm managing okay.
State your purpose.
I need the anal pearl.
To fool the God of Death?
Yes, sir.
Don”t, he”ll curse you.
I'm begging you.
Is she the one who”ll die?
She”s a very dear friend of mine.
Woman, how many years
have you lived?
35 years, sir.
You wish to live still?
Or do you not?
I want to live.
You”ll die eventually.
No matter now much you prolong it,
you only delay the inevitable.
I guess I'll die one day.
Resist all you want,
you”ll still die.
Do you still wish to live?
Yes, I want to live.
Tomorrow, the day after...
I want to live.
I might forget what happened today,
but I'll do my best to remember.
I'll be sure to remember it all.
Please, lend me the anal pearl.
- Woman.
- Yes?
Are you fertile?
Yes, probably.
Good luck.
Music, start!
I've decided decided.
I 've made up my mind.
I've decided.
I've decided decided.
I 've made up my mind.
I've decided.
Nothing good will ever happen.
I was a fool for believing.
I was naive for wishing.
kill, kill, beaf him FO deafh.
Beat that lying kappa to death.
kill, kill, beat him to deafh.
I've decided decided.
I 've made up my mind.
I've decided.
I've decided decided.
I 've made up my mind.
I've decided.
What do we do with this?
Wash it at the river
and shove it up your butt.
What! In my butthole?
Will this thing really lil?
You have to!
it'll ward off the God of Death.
What”s wrong?
My scalp is dry.
I can”t move anymore.
Oh c'mon, pull yourself together!
I'm sorry.
We”re almost there, let”s go.
Go on ahead and wash it.
What, by myself?
Hurry, the sun”s setting.
Fine, then.
Ran all the way here, huh?
What do you want with me?
Your time”s up.
Say goodbye to this world.
No.
You have no choice.
No means no.
I have a lot left to do.
Come.
How dare you!
We”re going.
I'm not going with you.
Now go get my anal pearl!
Do you realize I'm a God of Death?
So what?
Show your ass!
I'll give you a wedgie!
Yes!
There it is.
Don”t look!
Go away!
Water...
What”S with that bitch?
What”s wrong?
Not feeling well?
Take me instead of Chage.
She has the anal pearl now.
She”s that important to you?
Yeah.
She's just a violent old woman.
You must be an idiot.
For a God of Death,
you don”t see anything.
See what?
She”s still young at heart.
That”s why I love her.
Take her when she's actually old.
Now is too soon.
That”s not your call.
Please, I'm begging you.
You really want to lake her place?
Yeah.
You might be reborn as cow shit.
Still willing to do this?
That”s fine.
Blue sky today.
Yeah. Sure hate to lose
a good friend, too.
Sorry.
Aoki.
The anal pearl... it's in.
Ll hurts like hell.
It really hurts, Aoki.
You”ll get used to it.
I convinced the God of Death
to let you live.
Really?
I'm so glad.
What”s wrong? You okay?
I'm glad I got to see you.
What”re you talking about?
I wrote this for you years ago.
What is il?
A love letter, sort of.
You dork.
Well, goodbye, Chage.
Wait, what”s going on?
Hey, Aoki, wake up.
You're joking, right?
Aoki, Aoki!
Hey.
Aoki.
Aoki, wake up.
Why”d you have to die?
I wrote a love letter
to you, too, you know.
This isn't fair! We came this far!
Damn you, God of Death!
I'll kill you!
Aoki.
Come back to life.
Please.
Oh my god.
Aoki, wake up, please
Aoki.
Been a while.
I'm so glad.
Aoki.
Chage.
Chage, I love you.
Ii Love you, too.
I'm going to come.
Me, too.
Aoki.
"Chage, I like you. I like you a lot
Can we walk
to school together next time?"
"This may seem sudden,
but I've fallen for you, Aoki.
When I see your face,
my back gets tingly.
I'm so glad we”re in the same class.
I hope I'll be able
to see you forever and ever.
Maybe I can be your girlfriend?”
Let”s meet again someday, somewhere.
I saw your hand in my dream.
Your cute, white hand.
It was a terrible nightmare.
A nightmare in which
I kill lhe one I love.
its just a dream.
But if it's my dream.
It may come true.
You turn into a kappa.
And play baseball forever.
When morning comes I go home.
And then, and then...
And then, there he is.
its coming it? coming.
I know its coming.
its coming.
Before I know it.
it'll be here.
Something good is coming.
It won? be today
And probably not tomorrow.
Maybe it was yesterday.
Nobody knows.
Oh you gods.
Gods dwelling in the water.
Please wash it all away.
I beg you. Wash if aff away.
its coming it? coming.
I know its coming.
/its coming.
Before I know it.
it'll be here.
Something good is coming.