evey ship does reach the shore.
those who have no oarsman receive god's help.
''oh, you ungodly man!''
radhe krishna.
ls anyone around? can someone help?
Help.
Come quickly.
someone's beating up kunwarji.
beating me up? how dare you?
''but, l'm your servant, sir. - my servant?''
you asked me to massage you.
''oh yes, so l did. odd isn't it? o_ you go, all of you.''
lt isn't the priest's fault. you know him - a bit of a nut.
''but sir, why do you need massage at this age?''
''lf l don't, won't my wife make life tough for me?''
Your wife?
- Yes.
but your wife left you long ago.
'why, yes, that's true. odd, isn't it?''
but l wasn't talking of that wife.
l was thinking of my future wife.
''so, have you found a bride for me?''
''sir, my name is janaki prasad.''
Of the 100 couples in
this town...
...99 have been ruined by me.
'what did you say? - l mean, l brought them together.''
l've brought you an excellent proposal.
not too well o_ but a good family. - how old is she?
she's 1a going on 19.
'well endowed, flashing eyes, and...''
''Softly, softly.''
'You see, my nephew's in the house.
l'll get rid of him.''
wait here. l'll be back.
''up to the age of 25 a man should be a bachelor, celibate.''
from 25 to 50 he should be a householder.
''from 50 to 75... - bhola, it's so hot.''
why are you indoors reading this serious stu_?
you're young. you should be having fun.
got to a park. read a mystey or a detective novel.
''or a romance, or the premshastra. - uncle!''
you keep telling me such naughty things.
''gosh, odd isn't it? l tell you naughty things.''
but what naughty things did l mention?
why did you recommend the premshastra?
but that's a book all young men read.
don't read it if it doesn't appeal to you.
But get out of this stum room.
make use of the river and gardens nearby.
take in some fresh air.
''but l've just had a full meal, uncle.''
''bhola, your name suits you. you're so innocent.''
exercise will improve your health. - it might ruin my health.
No it won't.
all right. l'll go because you insist.
'Vey good, vey good.''
''never mind, pandit. take some more.''
so what were you saying?
1a or 19...flashing eyes...
do you have a photo of her? - photo?
lsn't she fit to be
your queen?
''pandit, you've done vey well this time.''
''from 1 to 25 a man should be a bachelor, a celibate.''
from 25 to 50 he should enjoy family life.
how old am l now?
gosh l'm already 26.
that's 6 months of grihastashram wasted.
a bite! l've caught a fish! seems like a huge fat one!
''oh, my god, a mermaid!''
''oh! you'd cast this line to catch a mermaid, had you?''
l came to catch some fish. - he looks like a shameless guy.
shameless? me?
you're the shameless ones. l'm fully dressed.
but you're practically naked in the water.
''girls, l think he's destined to die in the water.''
''Come on, let's get him.''
''Stop, don't touch me.''
don't you dare. don't think l'm a coward.
''l can hold a girl's hand. l'm 26 years old, you know.''
you sure are proud of it.
why not? look what's written here. it says -
up to the age of 25 a man should be a bachelor.
and from 25 to 50 he should be a family man.
poor thing! a brand new interest in girls.
''so, have you find a girl to start a family with?''
a young man like me won't have a problem.
''oh my! ouite the he-man, isn't he?''
watch it! don't tease me. l might lose my temper.
careful! he might just mary you in his rage.
mary her? no way. even my uncle wouldn't mary her.
But if it were you -
l could consider it.
really? right away.
''Look, look.''
Bye bye. See you.
- Bye.
Yes. This is where we were.
laila said that...
how can he run away? delhi's far away.
those are majnu's dialogues. not prithviraj chauhan's.
you've gone crazy.
can't you speak a single dialogue properly?
''Sory, l forgot!
- Forgot, did you?''
he's wearing laila's costume and speaking jai singh's lines!
''Sory, l forgot!''
you keep quiet! remove that cigarette.
do you remember your dialogues? - absolutely.
let's hear them. - shall l?
laila!
address the audience. continue.
''laila darling, your farhad is having a tough time in mumbai.''
great.
''laila is with farhad, is she?''
''and in mumbai? where's my ''''laila majnu'''' script?''
''calcuttiya, come here. - yes.''
just read this. tell them the correct dialogues.
Here it is.
''see, laila calls out to her beloved manju...''
''no, majnu. in the forest.''
kaiz!
gas!
go back.
quite a miracle.
you're gassing through your lips.
You idiot.
majnu's real name was kaiz. kaiz.
say it : kaiz. - gas.
kaiz. - gas.
kaiz. - kaiz.
got it. he got it finally. - stop laughing. get to work.
''calcuttiya, let's have the tabla.''
''So, where were we?
We were here.''
laila said that - - what?
don't throw stones at my lover.
'what's this, bhola? why are you dressed like this?''
where have you been? - it isn't raining. how're you wet?
did someone pick a fight with you? - did someone beat you?
did someone push you around? - speak up. what happened?
lt wasn't a he. it was a she.
She?
'who was she, bhola? she wasn't a vision, was she?''
she sure was. l was thrown.
but who is this girl who overthrew this bachelor?
A girl.
A girl?
what's her name? - where does she live?
l don't know that.
''but someday...somewhere... - guru, bhola's done for!''
a beautiful face! a picture of loveliness!
Her eyes seemed to smile!
''sir, you've been gazing at this photo since yesterday.''
some faces make such an impact on you.
l've decided to make her my bride.
but if her parents don't agree - - how can they not?
''besides, l'm no less than prithviraj chauhan.''
don't l have a horse?
but.. - but what?
suppose bhola objects?
odd isn't it? l'll send him on his way.
''uncle, you plan to send me o_, do you?''
'Well, l'm o_ on my own.
- Where to, son?''
to my aunt's house. where else? - which aunt do you mean?
The one who's going to come
to this house.
what are you talking about? what aunt?
''don't treat me like a child, uncle.''
l know what's going on. l'm 26 years old now.
you're planning to mary again at this age.
and a young girl at that! you gaze at her picture and sing.
'well, look at this. read what's written here.''
what's written in here?
up to the age of 25 a man should be a bachelor.
from 25 to 50 he should lead a family life.
all right. - you're an old man of 60.
how dare you? l'm only 45.
so you plan to mary for only 5 years.
who's marying again?
you are. l'm neither blind nor deaf.
''l hear eveything, l see eveything that goes on.''
what do you want?
''just one thing, uncle. come to a compromise with my aunt.''
ask her to come back.
you want me to come to an agreement with your aunt?
l haven't seen her for 5 years.
''l'm a rajput. when l leave someone, it's for keeps.''
but l'm a rajput too.
how can l turn my back on the aunt who brought me up?
l'll live with her.
you can mary again if you like. bring a band or whatever.
she'll become a widow the moment she sees your face.
''hey, bhola, is that you? how are you?''
''l'll take that. ma'am, bhola's here.''
''bhola, it's you.''
''l bow to you, aunt. - may you live long.''
'why this luggage? your uncle's well, isn't he?''
him? he's getting younger day by day.
what are you saying?
the truth. that's why l've ieft his house and come here.
but who'll look after him?
someone's on her way there - to look after him. a new aunt.
oh l see. so he's bitten by that bug again.
a young girl at that. how could l stand that?
that my aunt's place be taken by some young witch.
why are you so upset?
your uncle's always been that way. but look at you.
your blood relation is with your uncle.
yet you've always supported me.
don't wory. l have my share of my father's property.
'you and l can manage just fine on that, like a mother and son.''
''but, aunt, what's got into my uncle? at this age -''
forget about him.
''come on. go, wash. l'll make some tea for you.''
All right.
'wow, madho!''
my aunt has kept this room exactly as l left it.
''she always hopes you'll come. let it be, l'll do it.''
madho kaka - yes?
'the house opposite was always vacant, wasn't it?''
yes. but there's a new tenant now. since a month or two ago
a husband and wife. they have a daughter too.
but we haven't much dealing with them.
there's a bucket of water. wash your hands.
All right.
''hmm. a man, a woman and their daughter.''
what's it to me?
''bless you, aunt.''
'what are you listening to, bhola?''
''nothing, aunt. nothing at all.''
that's all she does day and night. she either sings or dances.
''But, Aunt, who is she?''
Some new people.
the parents are simple folk. but the girl is a frisky one.
eternally singing.
did you hear what she was singing?
she's a young thing. shouldn't she be preparing for marriage?
lnstead she's fooling around this way.
why did you cover his face?
let it stay that way. l don't like to see his face any more.
''Once you're upset, th,,ere's no
stopping you.
your tea's getting cold.
''Hey, you monkey!''
'yes, nymph? - you've followed me here, have you?''
lt's you who's following me.
why did you rent the house opposite my aunt's?
tell me first - why was that old woman criticizing me?
she doesn't even know me. how dare she criticize me?
what does she know that the frisky number is you.
Frisky? Me?
''lf you don't like frisky, we could call you fast.''
Listen well.
lf you want to live here you'd better look to your manners.
You needn't peep into my house.
whether l dance or sing - it has nothing to do with you.
as you please.
you can dance or sing. l won't say a thing.
l'll just watch the fun.
''lndeed? so you'll watch the fun, will you?''
okay. then take a look at this too.
what does it look like to you? - a broom.
And this?
- Shoes.
what use can they be put to? - l don't know.
You don't. l'll tell you.
''lf you dare talk about me, l'll flay you with these.''
may god hasten that day. - he will. vey soon.
''gosh, she's quite a fireball. but she is one of a kind!''
Guru!
''speak, girl. what is your problem?''
''guru, this is my husband.''
he married me but since that day...
l haven't been satisfied.
what can l do? my work starts only after sunset.
l understand. you're a thief.
you can read minds. you know eveything.
what doesn't a man do for the sake of his belly?
Who's this troubled child?
l'm a thug from benaras.
but l distribute half my loot among the poor.
l've even built two temples.
gloy to my guru! may he live long!
may you have a long life.
But tell me - why do you
disturb me now?
'what can l say, guru? l had to come and see you.''
l see. Tell me -
have you found out anything about that girl?
l found out. And l met her too
- Found her? Where?
let's go. we'll go and talk to her.
l'll be ruined. what will become of my play?
to hell with your play. - the audience will eat me alive
'Tell me, where did you find
the girl?''
''right next door to my aunt. - gosh, you're made!''
You met her?
l met her and l quarrelled with her too.
she threatened to hit me with a broom and a shoe.
what's so funny about that?
she threatened me but she didn't hit me.
things are getting serious. we have to sort them out.
until we meet this girl you mustn't fall in love with her.
then why the delay? let's go right now.
checkmate. - who says checkmate?
''oh, bindu, you've arrived.''
where did you pick up that piece of wood?
this isn't just a piece of wood.
lt's the college trophy for
the music contests.
your daughter won it!
vey good. whose daughter are you anyway?
good. no one ever defeats your father in chess.
you always win in chess. show me some other victoy too.
'Why? When l won you,
l won the world.''
really?
l've been married to you for 25 years. isn't that something?
Huh. You'll never improve.
how can you talk like this in front of your daughter?
enough fun. you must think of her marriage.
Don't you see how quickly
she's growing up?
you're right. someone has put it so well -
'when a thing is meant to be, it happens.''
bhola? - guru?
When will this window open?
''guru, one has to be patient in love.''
''Guru, there she is.''
''Gosh, how hot it is!''
''radha, open this window.''
what are you doing? can't you look where you're going?
go. make me some tea. l'll pick this up.
no work. just airs.
She's lovely.
a complexion like peaches and cream!
'what do you think, guru?''
what a girl you've chosen!
lf you send her to the battlefield....
the enemy will drop their weapons and surrender.
raven black tresses.
beautiful. - what a girl!
Quiet. Quiet.
you mustn't gaze at your future sister-in-law like that.
from today you must all be like lakshman.
Yes. Done.
Her height suits yours.
''So, we'll look good together,
won't we?''
your master has arrived.
Bring him in.
'who's the master? - how do l know, guru?''
must be a tailor master come for measurements.
Devi!
'this floor is low in places, high in places.''
''lf it were level, l wouldn't have fallen.''
you're early. - early? l'm vey late.
l've been waiting for it to be 5 o'clock.
the minute hand just wouldn't move.
didn't you have any other tuitions today?
how can l take other tuitions? one tuition keeps me busy.
even at home l keep thinking of you.
'When l meet other girls,
l see you in them.''
even in my mother's photo l see only your face.
Even in his mother's photo?
The idiot.
Useless bloke.
- Donkey.
''bhola, he's no tailor master. looks like a blu_ master.''
l'll be a match for him.
l'll play the drums on his bald head.
till l make him a band master.
this is a serious matter. vey serious.
we'll have to proceed with caution.
Don't you see?
how coy bindu is acting with him.
when you bite your finger and iook at the sky...
...l remember the time l first saw you.
Do you remember too?
- Yes.
You do?
l'd invited you home for
dinner once.
you asked me to teach you to dance.
then you sang a song.
l taught you the dance gestures for it.
''sing that song for me, please.''
''Me? Sing for you?
No, no.''
Why don't you sing?
shall l? that song? do you like it?
l like it vey much.
- Oh my!
Bindu.
''Sing, will you?
- Yes. l will''
''oh dear, l went wrong. l ought to sing in hindi.''
How did you like the song?
- l liked it.
'You liked it?
- Yes, l did.''
Go. O_ with you.
let's eat something.
''oh, so he's a dance master.''
lt's going to be the dance of death.
the one you love is already dancing around with someone else.
''lt's a case of ''''house full'' ''already. forget it.''
''guru, won't you say anything? - yes, l surely will.''
then say it.
are we accepting defeat at the hands of a dance master?
so what if the girl is romantic and forward.
but she comes from a good family.
this is the kind of girl one should fall in love with.
''bhola, don't lose heart.''
''no, l won't. l'm 26, by your grace.''
lf you say the word -
l'll even break a bow if l have to.
Good.
o you 5 jewels of the five jewel theatre company -
'we're all united. - yes, we are.''
together we have to defeat this dance master.
we have to - defeat him!
we have to - defeat him.
''devi, allow me to,,recite some verse.
l ask nothing of you. l seek nothing of you.
may your youth be eternal. what don't l feel for you.
'these sorromul looks, this pain tinged smile,''
no one else in your group reflects your beauty.
the verse is beautiful.
but do you understand its meaning?
yes. l do. it's quite a tiger of a poem.
but don't ask the meaning. sit down.
Listen.
you are careful to keep your distance
but l am sure of one thing -
lt is l who reside in your heart.
Nobody but me.
''Devi, listen.''
'where are you o_ to, bindu? listen to me. listen to my verse.''
''master, you're getting too romantic today.''
'you see, the circumstances are such.''
l saw a dream last night. - a dream? me too.
did you see me in your dream?
l'll tell you later. first tell me - what did you see?
''bindu, l saw - - master, keep your hands o_ me.''
''bindu, l saw -''
''far away from the earth, on the horizon...''
A little nest.
A nest? A bird's nest?
- A bird's nest. A little nest.
l was sitting in it.
you were sitting in a small bird's nest?
''master, you'd need a bu_alo's stable.''
who laughed?
the gods laughed at your joke.
''Bindu, do listen.''
''devi, you must hear about my dream.''
l put my head out of the nest and said -
''Bindu, Bindu.''
'then, another bird came and perched on the branch.''
lt spoke too. do you know what it said?
i ''lt said - master pillai master pillai.''
''and l said - l'm here, l'm here.''
'then l called to the bird: come, come here.''
lt stepped into my nest.
and then a little bit of billing and cooing.
beak met with beak.
Like this. Devi -
Ouch!
what a ticklish tree! bindu!
''bindu, l'll catch up with you.''
Why do you run?
bhola. - guru.
''do you understand what you saw? - do you want the truth, guru?''
l only saw bindu's face before me.
l neither heard nor understood anything.
l'll tell you. the master's after bindu with a vengeance.
you stupid man. anyone can see that.
but the point is - what is it about the master...
...that makes her dance to his tune?
Quiet. Quiet.
we've concluded that bindu isn't attracted to his looks.
Then?
''lf at all, she's interested in his art.''
mR_
his music and his dance.
''guru, why don't you teach bhola to sing?''
''certainly. how about it, bhola?''
l'm already 26. l'll learn it in a jim.
why delay a good thing?
'we'll start immediately, in the morning.''
\N__.
Silence. Silence. Silence.
''bhola, the first n,o, te in music is sa.
''guru, wait.''
''bhola, you haven't given your guru any o_ering.''
''Oh, l quite forgot.
- Give it now.''
here you are. - bless you.
''bhola, sing just as l do. get it?''
ready?
Go on.
- Don't be shy.
''no, bhola. not like that. listen.''
wrong at the vey start.
''bhola? - yes, guru?''
there's nothing to it. don't be afraid.
do you hear that? l'll sing. then you can follow me.
Go on. Sing.
''bhola, take it lower down.''
''l told you - lower, lower.''
''Lower down!
- Guru, lower down. Here.''
what are you doing down there?
you asked me to take it lower.
You fool. Sit up here.
Lower your pitch.
come. take it easy.
listen carefully.
Sing it.
Not here. It's over there.
what's so funny about it?
the donkey has a better voice than he does.
why don't you go and teach him?
'Who me?
- Yes, you. Go on.''
go on. move on. what's so funny?
''calcuttiya, o_ with you.''
''lahori, out! - yes.''
ls that better? they've all gone.
'yes, guru. - then, shall we start?''
Yes.
- Vey good.
re. not ra.
bhola. hold that note. ty to get the right note.
again.
''bhola! - no, l can't do it. l can't.''
''benarsi, lahori, come here quickly.''
get some water. get the pot of water.
put the fan on. give him some water.
'wonde_ul, wonde_ul! l have an idea.''
''bhola, l've got it. l've found the way.''
'what, guru? tell us.''
''Silence, silence, silence.''
''caluttiya, give me a betel leaf. good.''
''bhola, do you remember the words of any film song?''
'Yes, l do.
- Go on, sing.''
come on. don't be embarrassed.
''o lover about to leave me. - wonde_ul, wonde_ul.''
o lover about to leave me.
''bhola, l'll sing this song.''
all you have to do is move your lips.
Just your lips. As if you
were singing.
My voice. Your presence.
Do you get it?
'Yes, l get it.''
''o lover about to leave me,''
come back to me.
''are you ready, bhola? - yes. no, just give me a minute.''
Well done.
''bhola, do exactly what l've told you.''
'Yes, guru.
- Don't forget.''
l won't.
- Come on.
but there's no one at the window.
lf there were someone at the window -
would we have to resort to all this?
Get it?
- Yes.
''My Bindu will come, won't she?
- Yes, she will. Definitely.''
''bhola, has she come to the window?''
ls she looking at you?
does she want to talk to you?
Then close the shutters.
Close them.
No.
- Yes.
You idiot!
get back in. come back.
such arrogance!
l only smiled at him - now he's on his high horse.
l can do what l want - laugh or cough.
that doesn't mean that l -
thinks himself a great singer does he?
he's not worth even the dust at my master's shoes.
l'll teach you such a lesson that you'll forget your notes.
''did you hear that? oh gosh, we've messed things up.''
She'd come to the window so sweetly.
''she gazed into my eyes, wanting to talk to me.''
''And you closed the shutters.
Now she's gone o_, sulking.''
''60, 70, a0,...''
''... 90, 100.''
how many did you count? - a round 100.
l can do a 100 push-ups. but l'm still single.
Not single. A widower.
how can you call me a widower? bhola's aunt is still alive.
odd isn't it? l spent 2 years with her.
But there were no children.
''l'm as good as a bachelor, aren't l?''
here he comes. radha krishna.
radha krishna.
you keep uttering god's name
why can't you find a decent proposal for me?
what do you know? wherever l hear of a young girl -
l'm on her track. now after many days l see a ray of hope.
'you are? - in this vey city,...''
... lives the daughter of my old client.
But l need to show them your photo.
My photo?
''hazoori, go and get that photo of mine.''
'which one, sir? - you know, that one.''
have you only got her address so far?
you can take it the wedding's fixed.
But remember this -
lf it doesn't work out
this time -
you'll have to leave this town.
say your goodbyes - ram ram.
''no, l'm better o_ with radha krishna.''
''Odd, isn't it?
All right. Come here.''
bhola. - what is it?
''guru, that day you closed the shutters.''
since then he hasn't seen bindu at all.
you idiot. get up. why are you so upset?
''Look, vey soon you'll see -''
the girl will cary her heart on her sleeve.
she'll sigh and fall at your feet.
do you know what she'll say? - what?
''My innocent lover,''
''my dear lover,''
Without you my life
ls like a lamp without oil.
my life is like a garden
from which the pe_ume has fled.
make me yours.
''bhola, make me yours.''
my love is at your feet. my whole world lies there.
''guru, when she says this... how shall l reply?''
Reply?
'you nut, when you're in love... answers emerge naturally.''
say - anuradha..
''guru, not anuradha. it's bindu! bindu.''
''Oh, yes. l forgot.''
say this - - what?
''my dear bindu, my innocent bindu,''
'the bindu on the forehead, the sindoor bindu,''
''My Bindu,''
the boat of my love is caught in a whirlpool.
help me across.
put your arms around me and sway with me in love.
you are the hope of my life. read the love in my eyes.
''place me in your heart, conceal me in your eyes.''
come quickly. light a lamp in this dark world of mine.
make it bright for me.
Bindu!
bhola! - guru!
You've hit bullseye!
- Guru!
how uneasy she is.
like a fish out of water.
''guru, shall l raise the blinds? - yes, do. let the fresh air in.''
wait. listen to me first.
ready? - ready.
Then whistle. Go on.
what's this? can't you whistle? l'll do it.
namaste.
l addressed you. namaste.
''nevertheless, namaste.''
''master, where have you been?''
l haven't seen you for a week. l've been so upset.
you were upset? on my account?
l'd gone to rameshwar.
''l'm back now. l went to the temple, o_ered some fruit.''
what fruit? what kind of fruit?
why did you have to go there? - l'm sory. l won't do it again.
''lf l ever go again, l'll take you with me.''
come. take up the harmonium. l'm in the mood for a song.
why music? let's talk a while. we can sing later.
hell with your talk. sing first.
can he sing? send him to the temple to ring the bell.
what bell?
my name is bhola.
bhola? namaste.
just a minute. close the window.
why? - this guy keeps staring at you.
let him. let him listen too. let him find out what music is.
thinks he's tansen!
ls that so?
''bhola, come. come and sing.''
No. You go. l sing.
who do you think you are. l'll make mincemeat of you.
don't just make noise. l'll show you what music is.
come on. get ready.
give me the harmonium.
turn that side!
there's something wrong here. his pitch has suddenly changed.
Where's the note?
l won't give up.
this clever woman
l'll hold on.
she insinuates herself into my heart.
l die for her!
this clever woman makes herself beautiful.
a clever horse? what is this?
stick to the lines. either say horse or clever. sing.
a vey good idea to put the radio on.
why are you afraid?
This is our victoy. Our
second victoy.
chess again! when will you think of family matters?
lt is bindu's exam today.
why didn't you call the driver to come early?
Bindu's mother!
'when a thing is meant to be, it happens.''
l'm sick of your
philosophising.
bad boy. why did you let the cat cross her path?
who knows - it might be important work.
''lf a cat crosses, it could bring bad luck.''
why don't you say anything? l'll give you one.
well done. here are two 25 paisa coins.
drink some milk. give some to the cat too.
only 5 minutes left. check your papers.
''bindu, child! how did today's exam go?''
Bindu!
l think bindu will fail this year too.
good. at least it will make you think of her marriage.
Bindu's mother!
l insist we get her married this year. here.
until 25 a man should be bachelor.
from 25 to 50 he should be a family man.
50 to 75: vanaprasthashram.
75 onwards - sanyas.
l can hardly become a sanyasi. l'm only 26.
Listen.
you? did you call me?
Are you studying?
- Yes.
how was your exam? - vey good. it was so easy.
l need to ask a favour of you.
Me?
- Yes.
can you come down for a while?
Down? To your house?
''No. Down - to my door.
You will come, won't you?''
Why not? Of course l will.
shall l come right now? - do come. please.
All right. l'm coming.
''bindu, here l am. what can l do for you?''
Do tell me.
shame on you. go drown yourself.
''Do you see this, Guru?
Look up.''
why are you so low today?
you allowed a girl to slap you. aren't you ashamed?
you may as well wear a dress and sit at home.
you've demeaned the panchratna theatre company.
Quiet. Quiet.
bhola. - guru.
you have to respond in kind.
until you give that girl...
an even harder slap -
you can't hold your head up.
''slap bindu? no, guru. l can't do that.''
'yes, you can.''
lmagine you're arjun. guru is krishna...
... giving you direction.
arjun agreed to take arms against his relations ...
...because krishna told him to.
''ln the same way, you will have to...''
...mark bindu's tender cheeks with a slap.
slap bindu?
with these hands? - yes.
''guru, her fair skin will redden with the slap, won't it?''
certainly.
''lt'll hurt her too, won't it?
- Correct.''
then l won't do it. l can't.
Think it over.
Think well.
you have only 2 alternatives.
either you slap bindu.
or else our friendship is at an end.
'what do you say, friends? - absolutely.''
''but, guru, what shall l do? l love her.''
but l want your friendship too.
she's one. we're 4. will you forsake 4 of us for her?
speak up.
speak. bhola?
''no, guru. l will slap her. - well spoken!''
master! master!
devi! these days l hear your voice in my heart.
ln your heart? l'm here.
How do you come to be here?
l'm not dressed.
l'm dying of embarrassment. - forget that.
come into the garden with me. - garden? why? let's stay in my hut.
l'll tell you later. please come.
all right. turn aside. let me get dressed.
go ahead. l'll be with you in a minute.
''Devi.
- Come on, will you?''
Come on. Quickly.
l'll do whatever you want me to.
my parents in heaven will be so happy to see us together.
to hell with your parents.
You're right. They must be in hell.
they committed a lot of sins. l met an astrologer.
he said today would be good for me.
give me your hand.
but he told me l'd have a bad day.
why's that? - look behind you.
there's only a fountain behind me. - a thug!
A thug? Where?
- Here.
''oh, him. that's not a thug.''
that's bhola. you've forgotten him.
He lives opposite you.
he sings vey well. he quite defeated me that day.
this is the thug who's been stalking me for days.
that's why l've brought you here. do something about him.
But how?
l'm a dance master. not a la_er.
lf l take the law into my own hands...
...l'll be thrown into jail for 6 months.
are you a man or not? - a man? of course.
lf someone dares to look upon the girl you love...
what would you do? - l'd be happy.
lt's a wonde_ul thing to iook at a beauty.
'what a nut you are. you are a hindu, aren't you?''
definitely. l'm a pure hindu. - have you read the ramayana?
'yes, l have.''
'when ravan abducted sita, what did ram do?''
ram took hanuman's army to lanka
''he gave him such a beating, such a guillotine chop.''
can't you do that to this man?
ls that it? why didn't you say so?
ls he like ravan? - yes.
has he been bothering you? - yes.
just watch me. l'll give him good.
ravan! come here.
''bhola, you defeated me in song. - yes.''
can you defeat me in a fight? - l'll break your head.
break my head? - yes.
you'll break my head? - yes.
you'll break it? - yes.
but why do you want to fight?
''lt's not good to fight, you know, bhola.''
You're right.
''look, a boy and girl are walking in a garden.''
Why should you disturb them?
- Shut up. l'll kill you.
don't come any closer. - l will.
Don't come closer.
- l will.
You'll come closer?
- Yes.
You will?
- l will.
''ln that case, l'll move back.''
''how will you move back? l have muscles, you know.''
l'll throw you back.
'what happened, master? - nothing.''
bhola has a muscular body.
''he's tough. l'm delicate. you know, girls are delicate.''
that's how l am. but don't you wory.
l won't leave him alone. - get lost.
his idli diet makes him a weakling.
you need a man who eats parathas.
parathas?
l'll give you a puri. just watch.
'you talk big, don't you? - yes.''
l'll shut you up.
- Get lost.
leave my arm. devi!
devi! come and help me.
serves you right. go drown. you coward.
''bhola, l won't let you go.''
l'll make mincemeat of you. just watch.
'what happened? bindu, don't cy, bindu.''
l won't slap you. l won't.
what can l do to make you believe me?
'what shall l do, bindu?''
'take this, bindu,,, and cut my arm.
you're a strange man.
''sometimes one thing, sometimes another.''
you were bent on slapping me and now -
''Bindu, don't cy.''
''Bindu, the thing is -''
l didn't want to slap you. my friends forced me.
Oh? So you criticized me
to your friends?
''No, Bindu, l didn't.
l told them how l felt.''
you're always so irritable with me.
one has to share my feelings with someone.
name suits you.
really? -yes.
Rs. 50.
you see that man with the girl?
Don't let him go.
Or else l won't let you go.
Go on.
Let me go.
you're hitting him too hard.
Don't kill him.
he's dead.
''bindu. - yes, bhola.''
''Bindu, you're vey cunning.''
you diverted me with your iove talk.
and got me beaten by thugs.
''no, bhola, l had no part in this, l swear.''
Look over there.
Murder. Murder.
- Somebody's killed him.
Pick him up.
Why doesn't my child open his eyes?
he's hurt. but don't wory. he'll be awake soon.
ls his life in danger?
not at all. he's a healthy young man.
A little blood lost won't hurt him
he might get a fever. do let me know of his progress.
and give him some space.
Let him rest.
lsn't it strange? he lives in our neighbourhood.
but we've never even heard him raise his voice.
how can such a decent person make enemies?
nobody respects decency these days.
''bhola, my child!''
bhola's opening his eyes.
''recognize me, son? look at me.''
tell me : who attacked you?
'Tell us, child, tell us.''
tell us his name. we'll call the police.
''No, no. l didn't recognize him.''
l don't know anything.
''daddy, daddy, get up. - what is it?''
''mummy. - what is it, bindu?''
l can hear him groaning next door.
''l think he's all alone. - come on, let's go and have a look.''
You're right.
neighbours must help each other in times of need. let's go.
what can l do? he's a stubborn boy.
l pleaded with him to let me be near him.
but he wouldn't listen. he sent me away.
he has a high fever. is there a thermometer in the house?
''no. - bindu, child, fetch a thermometer.''
get an icebag too.
has he eaten anything at all today?
just a few sips of water.
the poor thing is feverish. you should call the doctor.
All right.
wait here.
Why do you give me the thermometer?
Put it in his mouth.
Go on.
please open your mouth.
l need to put the thermometer in.
the doctor has come. - how is he now? let's see.
nothing to wory about. he was bound to get fever.
l'll leave some medicine for him. give him one tablet evey two hours.
But...
- There's no need to wory.
but he needs nursing. shall l send a nurse?
there's no need. we're all here to help.
our daughter is here. we'll look after him.
Child.
lt's morning. go home and rest.
you've been awake all night.
so what? - bless you.
may god give you a wonde_ul husband.
may he give you prosperity.
''and so many children, you'll have to take a head count.''
the master has arrived.
what did you tell him?
l told him you might not be at home.
''good, l'm glad you said that.''
this is his third visit since yesterday.
''so what? he gets paid, doesn't he?''
tell him l've gone to visit my grandmother for a few days.
all right. l'll tell him to go to his grandmother's too.
''a thousand thanks, krishna.''
the day bhola got hurt he was in a terrible state.
he's better today.
'that's the result of your blessing, aunt.''
''Child, is it you?''
''He's well now, isn't he?''
'yes, by the grace of god. have a look in.''
he talks a bit now.
l don't accept medicine from my enemies.
lndeed? you've improved because you took medicine from me.
false. when did l drink medicine from your hands?
ask your family.
oh. l must have been unconscious.
Yes. You were unconscious.
''l see. tell me, who put the icebag on my head last night?''
l did.
and who massaged my feet?
Who put the thermometer
into my mouth?
me again.
really? l thought it was my aunt.
'Well, now you know.
Now drink your medicine.''
Then l'd be obliged to my enemy.
how can l pay back this debt?
l'll tell you.
By drinking this medicine.
drink it. or else l'll really be angy.
'when a thing is meant to be, it happens.''
now what? - just this -
bindu's exam result has appeared in the papers.
she's failed. - that's good.
l'll distribute sweets.
why are you so upset? l'm glad l failed.
lf l'd passed l'd have to study further.
now l'm free! - really?
l don't want her to study further.
find a suitable boy and get her married.
l agree. l'm as eager as you.
but we must find a good match. - gloy to radha and krishna.
do you recognize me? - you appear to be a priest.
but why don't you close your umbrella?
ls this your wife?
- Yes.
can l sit down here? - do sit down.
you have nothing to wory about.
your brother-in-law is my client.
he told me that you're looking for a groom.
'what? - l mean,...''
... you're looking for a groom for your daughter.
that's why l came to meet you. - l'm so glad you came.
tell us about the boy's family background.
''family? why, he's a thakur.''
and his name is kunwar pratap singh.
what is his age? - he's at the exercise age.
what about his income? - income? it's vast.
even if he spent lavishly he would still have 15-20 lakhs left.
l've brought his photo along.
the photo looks rather old.
''lt's been lying in my bag for days, you see.''
let me have a look.
''panditji, do you approve of him?''
don't wory. l know this family well.
ln that case leave the photo with us.
let me seek my daughter's approval too.
you're right. - as you please.
l'll return in a few days.
''Bindu, child.''
''l wanted to talk to you. - yes, mummy?''
l've brought a photo. tell me how you like it.
photo? - yes. have a look.
l felt like laughing. but l couldn't quite.
you know something? if daddy owned a film company...
...he'd surely cast this guy as a comedian.
lt's come with a marriage proposal for you.
a proposal for me? - yes.
what's wrong with you? how can l mary this character?
why are you cying?
l came to ask what your wishes are. - my wishes are otherwise.
will you stay single all your life?
why stay single? you can start getting my dowy ready.
sure. but what about a boy?
l do like someone.
who is that lucky guy?
''l won't tell you yet.
- Tell me, child.''
l told you - l like him. he's found a place in my heart.
but child - what is his family background?
how old is he? what's his income?
ls he educated or not?
family? he's a prince.
his kingdom is his innocent heart.
his wealth is his simplicity.
his age is similar to mine. as for his income -
Eveyone who comes to know
him loves him.
he has such a good heart.
what does it matter if he's not too well educated?
''even great scholars respect such people, don't they?''
a boy of such a good character? then what else can we want?
''Mother!
- Bindu, child!''
- bindu. - what is it?
did you have a fight with your mother?
''no, not at all.''
she found a match for me and also his photo for me to see.
let me see who the lucky man is.
want to see it? - yes.
what's so funny?
you must mary him. you and l will still have a relationship.
what are you saying?
'yes. if you mary him, l'll be calling you ''''aunt''''.''
ls this your uncle?
You bet he is.
He's my mother's brother.
haven't you noticed his photo over here?
Oh yes.
l kept wondering where l'd
seen him before.
My uncle!
My Bindu invited me to
her house. Bindu!
sit here. l'll be back. - yes. come soon.
come. l want to place you in my heart.
''namaste, master. - bindu, l knew it.''
l knew you would meet me.
l've been longing to meet you for days.
l've been like a fish out of water.
l was concerned. l went to the shrine of a saint.
l went to see an astrologer.
l went to a mosque on friday to o_er prayers.
on sunday morning l went to church.
either a muslim or a hindu or a christian -
some god will hear my prayers.
''he's heard, he's heard. thank you, god.''
''Bindu, how did you
survive so long?''
didn't you remember your master? tell me. why are you silent?
lf only you'd keep quiet. then l could speak.
l'm sory. l got excited.
what are you doing in the evening? - evening? me?
l'm going to a friend's place for snacks.
you can think of snacks in my absence?
that was wrong of me. but l only did it once.
l only ate idlis. without sambar or chutney. see how thin l've become.
bindu! - master!
tell you what - instead of snacks...
...meet me in the park at exactly 5.30pm.
why 5.30? that's half an hour too late.
why not 5 o'clock? - no. exactly 5.30.
not a minute earlier. not a minute later.
don't be annoyed. l'll do what you say.
''l'll come at 5.30. bindu, shall l change my clothes?''
'wear a suit, hat, tie? - no, master.''
You look sweet like this.
- You're right.
'when you're in love, clothes don't matter.''
l'll go then.
go! - namaste.
''Bindu, this is for you.''
This is you.
And this is me.
''bhola, sing a really lovely song for me today.''
Song?
- Yes.
Which song?
- Any song you like.
''quit, move out, you outsiders india belongs to us!''
you call that a song? it's a marching song.
''look, sing a song of love.''
''don't go my love;,come back to me.
don't tease me. l won't talk to you.
''sing, please. a lovely song.''
'what shall l do, guru? - come on, bhola.''
'The thing is, Guru...
- Guru?''
he's told me to only sing at home.
''never in a park, by the river or under a tree.''
he says l'll lose my voice.
really? - yes.
lf you want me to forget his life long teaching...
''All right then, l'll sing.''
''no, bhola.''
l can hear your songs all my life.
bindu. - bhola.
''bindu. - yes, bhola.''
''bindu, your master's coming.''
'yes, l called him here. - is that so?''
do you plan to have me beaten up again?
l have a plan. but something di_erent.
hide behind a bush. watch what happens.
Hury up.
master! come here. quickly.
Devi!
''look, it's exactly 5.30pm.''
look what l've got. the whole world.
around the world. without any dollars.
the astrologer said l'd have a good year.
l'll mary the woman l love.
''From single,
l'll become double.''
an astrologer told me the same thing.
these astrologers are always right.
you should heed their advice. - he always said that...
l wouldn't mary the man who ioves me.
these astrologers are frauds. don't listen to them.
but l took his advice. l've even found a good match.
shall l tell you? - you're joking.
l'm the boy you mean. how will you tell me about me?
l'm your future groom.
''master, l'm the groom, not you.''
''bhola, you got away last time because of luck.''
this time you'll have bad luck. you won't survive.
master. - yes?
but he's the man l plan to mary.
Greet him.
accept my decision and go back to your village.
l'll pay for your ticket.
''devi, you don't have to buy my ticket.''
l've heard you out. l didn't want to stay on here.
l wanted to return to my village
l stayed only for you.
l taught you all l knew - my art.
''Now you tell me to go.
Yes, l will go.''
But remember this -
l will long for you morning and night.
but l won't be the one to call you.
''bindu, you broke his heart.''
He'll mend it elsewhere.
at least our misunderstandings have been cleared. let's go.
walk softly into the garden.
''guru, guru, guru. - bhola, how are you?''
''l'm in a bad state, guru. - now what problem do you have?''
'what can l say, guru? tomorrow is bindu's birthday.''
she's asked me to sing. - so what's to cy about?
l'm the maker of your fate.
'The thing is, Guru -
Bindu loves me now.''
ls it right for me to deceive
her?
l wish l could say to her -
''bindu, l can't sing.''
all l can do is love you.
''don't say that, bhola. or else you're finished.''
love and war cannot succeed without deception.
'what's your advice, guru?''
what l feel is this -
''as long as the act,,works, continue it.
Correct.
''after you're married, tell the truth.''
that's right.
we've wished you a happy birthday.
we've eaten. where's the surprise item?
such impatience! - yes!
''All right, then. Come.''
Listen.
where's the cap?
shawl!
bhola!
''oh, bindu. namaste.''
happy birthday. - thank you.
you promised to sing on my birthday.
'You see, l ... Forget the song.''
''no, no, that won't do.''
'tell him to sing, bindu. - they're impatient.''
l've given them my word
you'd sing.
You must sing.
''bindu, l wanted to tell you something on this happy day.''
not this way. anything you want to say must be in song.
go on. what do you wish to say?
There's something fishy going
on here.
Fishy?
who do you think is singing? - him. my bhola. there he is.
''no, that's vidyapati. - vidyapati? who's that?''
l know him. he's a famous singer.
l don't believe it.
It's impossible.
you have to believe it. come with me.
l have other words of love for you too.
your bindu's dead. don't call me that.
'you liar, cheat, trickster.''
l swear l'll become your aunt. you can call me your aunt.
''Guru, Bindu's gone.
She's gone.''
Mummy!
what is it?
remember the photo you showed me? l agree to mary that man
such a quick decision!
'well, do you expect me to stay single all my life?''
kunwarji!
'why are you yelling? what is it, panditji?''
say radhekrishna! - why should l?
please. say it. - all right. radhekrishna.
you're radha and she's krishna. - l'm radha?
''l mean you're krishna, she's radha.''
god has made the pe_ect match - you mean the girl has agreed?
the girl has agreed. her parents have agreed.
now it's time to organize the wedding music.
absolutely. - we'll have sparklers.
we will! - and noisy firecrackers too!
a beautiful new bride will come to this house.
ln place of my mud house l'll have a cement house.
all right. - find an auspicious date quickly.
''odd, isn't it? that's your job, surely.''
'Yes. You're right. l'll do it.
- Come on, be quick.''
'Tell me, when should the
wedding be?''
findanauspiciousdaythat comes soon.
''namaste, uncle. - namaste.''
l bow to you.
how did l suddenly acquire so many nephews?
you must be bhola's theatre friends.
'yes, that's right.''
come. sit down. l'm vey happy today.
not near the tiger's head. sit near the tail.
only rajputs sit here.
''how did you happen to come? - uncle, we respect you as an elder.''
l seek your opinion. - why call me an elder?
l'm only a few yers older than you.
but you're welcome to ask my opinion.
Uncle.
suppose you have a young son.
i ''lf he'd be born at all he'd grow up too.''
''Suppose he's grown up.
- All right, he is.''
suppose he's fallen in love.
with a vey beautiful girl.
that goes without saying.
''lf the girl is beautiful, cupid is bound to strike.''
suppose he's fixed his wedding date.
he's ready for the wedding. he's even hired his horse.
why are you telling me all this?
The poor boy then found out...
...that his uncle is to mary his girl.
the boy is bhola. the girl is bindu.
and you are the uncle. you are the uncle.
''kunwarji, don't listen to them.''
l've fixed this match with great di_iculty.
''pandit, you're breaking one relationship...''
...to forge another. that's no good.
but he's my patron. l always do what's best for him.
ls this the only girl for bhola? he can get other girls.
Listen to me.
Throw these fellows out.
Before l throw them out...
l just might throw you out.
how could you fix my marriage with this girl?
you knew bhola was interested in her.
l should be the girl's father-in-law.
not make her my wife.
l'd rather die than do that.
bhola's fought with me and left. but he's still like my son.
''Son, you did well to tell me.''
else l would have made a terrible mistake.
tell them l cannot accept this proposal.
''Odd, isn't it?''
''god, l thank you.''
''bhola, eveything is all right. - what happened, guru?''
your uncle heard us out. he was so upset.
''he's decided against marying bindu. - really, guru?''
''oh, that's wonde_ul! - guru, you're terrific!''
But my uncle's terrific too.
don't underestimate him.
''after all, he is a thakur. l'm the only idiot in the family.''
l was entrapped by laughter and smiles.
Now we'll see some fun.
a certain girl is going to be left on the shelf.
you coward! talk to me directly if you're a man.
don't pretend to be talking to others.
wory about your own marriage.
l'll find thousands of guys to run circles around me.
calls himself a thakur.
he asked for my daughter's hand himself.
we didn't go to his door. where will he find a girl like this?
'what is it, mummy? - nothing.''
the thakur changed his mind. maybe it's for the best.
marriages are matters of destiny.
l'll find another groom for your daughter.
his daughter doesn't want a groom of your finding.
go away. - bindu!
''daddy, don't interrupt. didn't l tell you to go?''
Bindu!
master!
namaste.
''bless you, master. l was just thinking about you.''
what could you be thinking about me?
l'm leaving town - for my village.
The city doesn't suit me.
''master, you're so innocent. you're needed here.''
how can you leave town? l won't let you go.
Why do you need me?
- Come on.
Come on.
Sit down here.
''mummy, l had spoken to you about someone.''
this is the man. - child?
''daddy, this is my choice, this is my decision.''
l only need your blessing.
she did speak to me. if this is your choice...
And this is your decision...
then our happiness also lies here.
Mummy!
- All right.
'when a thing is meant to be, it happens.''
what are you talking about? what decision? is it a court case?
''master, come upstairs with me. l'll explain eveything.''
why not explain it here?
''Come with me.
- Yes, let's go.''
''now watch it, pal.''
''come, master, come.''
''devi, l'm holding my luggage. it's vey uncomfortable.''
tell me what you want to say quickly.
''Now wherever we go,
we'll go together.''
you're not only my dance master now.
you're also the master of my fate.
''no, no. l'm not your master. l'm your servant.''
you don't understand.
day after tomorrow you're going to mary me.
''mary you? what did you say, bindu?''
'what l said is right, master. - how come?''
''for so many days it's been apply apply, no reply.''
''now suddenly it's ''''no apply, have reply''''.''
'that's how it is,,in love, master.
speak softly.
''lf the enemy hears, there'll be trouble.''
lf we don't tell the enemy how can we make them envious?
you want them to burn? leave that to me.
Come with me.
not like this. let's take the sangam pose.
like this? - that's right.
bhola. - what is it?
eveything's fixed. - what's fixed?
my marriage has been fixed with bindu.
and you're stuck in your house. - what nonsense!
not nonsense! it's the truth. now you can come over.
we'll get married. you can sing. play music. and cy.
''Bindu, is he telling the truth?
- Yes, he is.''
do come. with your friends and family.
l invite all of you.
bhola!
hury up. it's getting late.
''guru, do something. the groom's party has arrived.''
''bhola, now there's only one path left.''
'what, guru? - you have to die.''
''But, Guru...
- No buts.''
''benarasi, fetch paper and a pen.''
fetch a rope.
A rope?
- A rope.
'we'll enact a hanging. bhola, get up.''
''repeat the name of lord ram. - no, l'll repeat bindu's name.''
give the horse some water. he's tired carying my weight.
Well done.
Give it to me.
''aunt, something terrible has happened. bhola has committed suicide.''
what? -yes. he's hung himself.
o traveller on the road to death
take me with you too.
O my best friend of friends!
lf you're not with me anymore what is this world to me?
'why did you do this, bhola, my child?''
Why were you so upset?
Why didn't you tell me?
O best friend of friends -
lf you're not with me anymore what is this world to me?
''alas, alas, bhola.''
''bhola, you're as inn,,ocent as your name.
you gave up your life for a faithless girl.
there will go the bridal procession.
and here the funeral procession.
your death is a symbol of true love.
'you're dead, my friend, but you've immortalized love.''
what's happened to bhola?
you ask what's happened to bhola?
See the evidence with your
own eyes.
''look, bindu, what's happened.''
''guru, bhola wrote this before he died.''
''Bindu! Bindu, this is for you.''
read it.
''bindu, congratulations on your wedding.''
my heart is full of love for you as l leave this world.
'your poor spurned lover, bhola.''
''bhola, what have you done?''
lf l had known you would die for love...
l would've never done such a thing.
did he hang himself because of you?
God will never forgive you.
Never.
l entered into this marriage out of sheer stubbornness.
''bhola, son, what have you done?''
thakurs give their lives for their county. on the battlefield.
rajputs don't commit suicide for love.
my husband.
what a way to meet you.
now l have seen the light.
but the light has gone out of bhola's eyes.
'why did you leave me, bhola?''
bhola.
''bhola, bhola.''
''bhola, what have you done?''
oh god! what a mess!
''god, give him back his life.''
see how much he loved you. he gave up his life for you.
''guru, what happened? - he still has some life in him.''
''bindu, l have heard that love can breathe life into rocks.''
''and this is, after all, a man.''
lf you have even an ounce of iove in your heart for bhola...
...then express it now.
Just two words of love
from you...
...might bring him back to life.
tell him. tell him that you iove him.
tell bhola.
''bhola. bhola, my heart belongs to you.''
lf you don't come back to life...
...l won't be able to live without you.
Bindu!
''my bhola! bhola, you're alive.''
Gloy be! Gloy be!
''bindu, you are like savitri.''
you've snatched bhola back from the god of death.
the bride's mother! the bride's father!
the groom's uncle! come and bless them. the groom's uncle!