This is Nargis... the younger
sister of Nawab Chand.
Her mesmerising voice...
...and the tinkling of her dancing
bells are a sensation all over.
There are scores of romantics who
yearn for her attention...
and she doesn't bother
in the least.
But yes...
there is this man
whose arrival...
...makes her gloomy in her
unholy surroundings.
Her soul pleads with him...
to take her away from there.
The restless love in Shahab's eyes
convinces her that...
I won't let you wither...
in this infamous place.
I'll come one night and
take you away from this hell.
"Finally, the night arrived."
The night of promise...
...which Nargis had been...
...restlessly looking forward to.
Say something.
I hope you're actually present.
Yes.
And I'm close to you?
Yes. You're close to me.
And you're taking me
to your house.
Your house is built on
a very elevated level.
Completely white...
...and dressed as your bride
in a red ensemble...
...I am alighting from a palanquin...
in your courtyard.
Uncle! Uncle!
- Stop!
How dare you marry a prostitute
and bring her home?
Father! You cannot use such
abusive words against her.
She's my beloved and the
daughter-in-law of your family.
Shut up! You cannot malign my
family with this society girl.
She's not my daughter-in-law.
She's your wrongdoing!
O Allah!
Please stop!
Where do you want to go?
- Take me to a graveyard.
Poor Nargis!
Having alighted from
the palanquin...
...she is standing all alone
in this scary jungle of death.
"There go all her
desires and dreams..."
...leaving her helpless.
Shahab searched for
his oppressed...
bride in every...
...nook and corner.
Shahab's promises to Nargis are
now going against him...
"...and consequently, he is
roaming around in vain."
And here...
"Nargis' sobbing life, having been
drenched in tears..."
...is coming to an end in these...
...deserted days and still nights.
The gold coins are pure.
It must be some minor dirt.
- Whose bangle is this?
- What's the matter?
- It belongs to me.
- To you?
Yes. It belongs to me.
- But it belongs to somebody else!
- Whose is it?
How should I describe her?
God knows who she is.
She's living in our cemetry
since the past l0 months.
She doesn't reveal where she has
come from and what's her misfortune.
Only God knows what is ailing her.
She doesn't even weep.
She is just dying silently.
Is that unfortunate
woman a blonde?
Yes. She is a blonde.
Take me to her. That unlucky
woman is my sister.
Where is she?
O sister!
You're dead?
I wonder how you must
have undergone...
...such a severe punishment
because of your innocence.
I wonder how you must
have tolerated...
...this deserted place
of death.
I wonder how much
you must've wept.
These are some of
her belongings.
You may sell it off.
Sir!
- What is it?
- I've found the book...
...which you were
searching for.
So you got it?
Please show it to me.
- Tell me... what should I pay?
- You may give whatever you like.
"All right. Here, take it."
Whose letter is this which
didn't reach its destination?
Now you'll deliver it
to it's destination?
Why not? It's a noble deed.
I'll surely deliver it.
I was not fortunate enough that...
...I would've breathed my last
at your door-step.
Neither was I fortunate that you'd
take my dead body to the graveyard.
But I'd to leave your home and...
...find a graveyard for myself.
"Today, I'm leaving
your unjust world."
You'll receive this
letter tomorrow.
"The moment you read it,
come over here..."
...and take away this innocent
child from my desolate lap.
She is your child.
Now we will meet on the doomsday.
Goodbye...
Your sick... Nargis.
She had a daughter too.
Yes. But her sister
took her away.
Her sister...?
Get out of this whorehouse.
You may wield your
influence elsewhere.
Don't you know who I am?
"If you ever step here again,
I'll order your limbs to be smashed."
A Mr. Shahbuddin is
calling you downstairs.
Who're you? I didn't
recognise you.
I'm Shahbuddin.
I see. So you're Shahbuddin?
My brother-in-law!
Tell me... what brings you
here again?
Which other culprit are you
searching for this time?
Now which prostitute do you
intend to rescue from hell?
Nargis wrote me a letter
when she was dying.
I received the letter
seventeen years later.
She has mentioned
about my daughter.
I understand that she's here.
- So you've come to see her?
- I've come to take her away.
I see. So you've come
to take her away!
Some graveyard must've made you
a request to bring her dead body.
All right. Take her away.
She's your daughter.
How can I refuse?
But right now... she is busy
with her dance performance.
"Moreover, it's against your pride
to take away your daughter..."
...from this infamous locality.
You may come back
tomorrow morning.
Let's go.
Muscleman... why is it locked?
- They've gone away?
- When did they leave?
They left at dawn.
- Do you know where they went?
They've flown away from this perch.
Who knows where they may
perch themselves?
Let's go.
Give me a paan.
Since you chew paan
free-of-charge everyday...
...you should twist your
moustache downwards.
Disguising ourselves
as beggars...
...we see the spectacle at
every step day after day.
Forgive me... I happened to
come inside your compartment.
I could see your feet.
They're very beautiful.
Do not place them on the ground.
They will become dirty.
Your fellow-traveller.
I could see your feet.
They're very beautiful.
Do not place them on the ground.
They will become dirty.
Your fellow-traveller.
I sent the word that
I'm not a wife...
...that I'd weep in a
corner of the house.
Why would I make my
heart suffer?
"If one is interested,
a person may come here."
"Otherwise, he may
stay with his wife."
You've said it right.
- How wonderful!
Greetings.
Aunty has arrived.
Mother! Aunty has arrived!
- Greetings.
- God bless you.
It would be great fun.
- Greetings.
- Be happy!
Come.
I hope everything is fine.
Can I have some
cold drinking water?
We have cold water.
Bring it over here.
Dibban is not to be seen.
Where is she?
She's sick.
- Is Dibban sick?
- Yes.
- When did you arrive?
- Just a while ago.
I see...
- Have you come alone?
- No.
I've come with my aunt.
What's ailing you?
You're so thoughtless.
I write so many letters...
...and yet you send me a reply
several months later.
Residents of Delhi aren't
believed to be hostile!
How did you become one?
You may scold me later. Rest
comfortably for the time being.
But how come you've
arrived all of a sudden?
No letter... no telegram?
"I don't know. Day-before-yesterday,
somebody summoned aunty..."
"...outside the brothel. When she
returned, she was worried."
I cannot sit with her
in any brothel now.
I'll be traced.
"If I could find some mansion
separately, I would be relieved."
What's so difficult about
finding a mansion?
You could get the pink palace...
...which Nawab Hashmat Shah
had given away to Gauhar Jaan.
I don't have the capacity to be able
to buy the Nawab's pink palace.
The Nawab has passed away now.
And Gauhar Jaan is neck-deep in debt.
The palace is being auctioned now.
The bid may reach upto one lakh
or one and a half lakh rupees.
Don't you have that much money?
That much!?
The train is leaving.
Do you need something?
Take this. You have
the pink palace now.
I've finalised everything.
"From tomorrow, she'll live
in the palace along with him."
And till the danger from
Shahabuddin blows over...
...she'll be recognised as
Gauhar Jaan's niece.
- Who is she?
- She's fire.
Yes. The entire city is
burning with this fire.
But this fire is yet
to affect me.
It already has. You'll not be able
to keep it under control till night.
It has been so wonderful!
Welcome.
Please be seated here.
He's the affluent Nawab Zafar
Ali Khan from Panipat.
My greetings to you.
Please see if it'll be
delayed further.
All right.
Why're you sitting there?
Please sit here.
I'm better off here.
What must be the time now?
- It'll be three o'clock soon.
You may go and sleep now.
Forgive me... I happened to
come inside your compartment.
I could see your feet.
They're very beautiful.
Do not place them on the ground.
They will become dirty.
Your fellow-traveller.
Collect it with both arms.
He's a very romantic
wealthy man.
Whichever brothel
he climbs...
...the stairs of such brothels
get to be made of gold.
Folks! Now our queen
mother'll dance!
- I'll dance?
- Bring the musical instruments.
Come on. You should dance.
You dance so well.
Where do I dance well now?
That was ages ago.
"If the girls are insisting, why don't
you teach them a couple of steps?"
Hurry up! Bring the instrument.
Yes. I'll begin now.
- Greetings.
- Bring it over.
Keep it.
What is this thing?
- Show them.
"The Nawab has sent this carpet
worth 36,000 rupees..."
...as a redressal for
last night's incident.
A blacksmith's one blow is mightier
than a goldsmith's hundred blows.
This is especially for
your amusement.
I'd happened to tell Nawab that
she's very fond of birds.
And pronto! He sent this for her.
It's priceless. It even sings.
- Is it?
- Hear the bird sing.
It's not a bird.
It's our dear sister.
You shameless girl!
How can you embarrass her?
Are you of her age?
- Senseless girl!
"How can you behave like this?
After all, she's her elder sister."
Take it and hang it there.
I don't think I've to
go into details.
"As it is, you're an
experienced person."
Gosh! He has arrived.
- Who has arrived?
- The Nawab.
Please be seated.
What's the matter?
Is there no gathering today?
A gathering is scheduled.
But people didn't come.
Perhaps because of
yesterday's incident.
"Yes, perhaps."
"But why do you worry? If people
didn't come, so be it."
A moonlit night is far brighter
than a star-lit night.
You've made a very
accurate observation.
It's a fact.
Go and call her.
Bring along Shabnam too
to give you company.
"I'd heard that affluent, wealthy
men are very meticulous in conduct."
I hadn't seen it earlier.
I saw it yesterday.
Thanks. I don't chew paan.
I remembered that thing.
That thing? Then let's go.
My greetings to you.
Greetings.
I suppose you're well.
Yes. By your grace.
People do swear by you.
But did anybody...
...remove the effect
of the evil eye?
Ensure that it's removed. I might
caste an evil eye on you.
- Did you get it made?
- Yes.
Give it to me.
Fool! Go and remove
it from inside.
>From inside?
I found it.
I could see your feet.
They're very beautiful.
Do not place them on the ground.
They will become dirty.
O Lord! I'm also your slave.
You're defeated now.
Two and this is seven.
- Where's she?
- She's in the bathroom.
- And this...
- Come and play.
You may play. I don't know
how to play this game.
It's your move now.
Who is it? Saheb Jaan?
- When did you come?
- I just came.
Is it Saaheb Jaan standing?
Tell me... I hope you're fine.
"Well, yes. Morning comes,
evening comes..."
...life is just drifting away.
You should come
over here sometimes.
I'll come some day.
Excuse me... I needed
something from you.
What was it?
I'm going to a dance
performance tomorrow.
I'll need your head
ornament for a day.
I'll return it
day-after-tomorrow.
Of course! You may take it.
"If you like, you may
not return it later."
- Would you like to chew paan?
- No.
Hey! These are the
same old ones.
I thought the Nawab
must've gifted it to you.
"If I'd asked for something else
now, I would've got it too."
Really... I'djust been
remembering you.
I hear you passed the whole
night inside the same blanket?
And that the poor Nawab got
entangled in his own carpet?
I'm tired of hearing the
same thing repeatedly.
Are you tense about something?
Yes. It's something like it.
What is it?
Just pull the curtains.
Yes... what's the matter?
"Since several days, I get the
feeling that I'm changing."
As if I'm undergoing
an unknown journey...
...and that I'm going somewhere.
I'm leaving everything.
Saheb Jaan is slipping away...
...and I'm being distanced
from Saheb Jaan.
- Who is it?
- Who?
The one whom I'm asking?
Tell me!
How should I say who it is?
It's a peculiar incident.
What is it?
"Every night, at 3 o'clock..."
...a train derails from the tracks
and passes through my heart.
And it gives me a message.
What message?
This message is not meant for you.
What?
No. It is meant for me.
I found it kept near my feet.
You're right. But you must not
be wearing the bells at that time.
If you had been
wearing the bells...
...how would anyone have asked you
not to keep your feet on the ground?
My dear one...
It is indeed a message.
But it is misdirected.
"And tonight, he is celebrating."
I'll come in the evening
and take her away.
All right.
- Where from are you returning?
- I'd been to meet Dibban.
Come over here. Look what all
he has brought with him.
I'm coming.
Gosh!
I'm very tired.
Go tell her that I'm very tired.
All right.
This message is not meant for you.
Be seated.
Be comfortable.
What's the matter?
What?
Why do you seem to appear as if...
"...you're not Saheb Jaan,
but somebody else?"
But you've bought me as Saheb Jaan.
Yes. I did buy you.
But I've suffered a loss.
My heart seems to say as if
you're a stolen property.
As if it would be
a crime to buy you.
Why're you looking there?
- I've a request.
- What is that?
- Change the topic.
- All right.
But look towards me.
Do you remember that poem?
- Which one?
Hearing which travellers
forget their route.
I'd happened to meet
somebody enroute.
I remember.
What happened?
What's this?
- Elephants have come.
- What is it?
- Elephants!
"It's a stormy night,
and I'm travelling."
There's nobody in the
compartment besides me.
But on the opposite berth...
...my enchanting memory is
turning over once again.
And the beautiful feet
decorated with henna...
...continue to make me
restless even today.
What is it? What's the
name of this condition?
Love.
O Lord!
He's standing close to me.
And I'm feeling suffocated.
You'll continue to stare
at me in amazement...
...and I'll die without
...even glancing at you once.
"I'll die on your bed,
in front of your eyes."
Turn your face.
Give me some respite...
...so that I can heave
a sigh of relief...
...and glance at you once.
It's such a strange incident.
As if somebody would be
narrating a story.
Greetings.
Not there... this way.
I'm stunned upon
finding you here.
"In this jungle, on this
distant island..."
...who has left you in
the solitude of my tent?
Say something.
Who're you?
What is your name?
Name... my name!
You didn't reply.
Who am I? And how I've come here?
I don't remember anything.
This night will
make me go crazy.
May I try to remind you something?
Perhaps you might remember something
from your lost memories.
It was a rainy night.
You were travelling in a train.
I happened to come inside
your compartment.
You were sleeping.
"You continued to sleep,
but your feet awakened..."
...and they wreaked
havoc on my senses.
You must've received my note near
your feet in which...
...I mentioned about your feet.
You must've read it.
Try to remember.
I could see your feet.
They're very beautiful.
Do not place them on the ground.
They will become dirty.
This message is not meant for you.
What?
No. It is meant for me.
I found it kept near my feet.
You're right. But you must not
be wearing the bells at that time.
Did you remember anything?
Excuse me...
Yes?
I'm going away from you
for some time.
Where?
Not very far. Just across that river.
"But after reaching there,
I'll send my messenger to you."
He'll care for you
till I return.
By when will you return?
- I'll return before dusk.
Make sure that you return
before nightfall.
I'll surely return.
Excuse me.
You were about to say something?
Do return before nightfall.
I will.
"Yes, Sir."
I'm coming.
Go over to my tent immediately.
My guest is staying there.
Take along food-stuff with you.
"Till I don't return,
you remain there."
All right.
Look! Is she the one?
Yes. She's the one.
Thank God!
Sir!
Here I come.
The sun hasn't set yet.
There's nobody here.
There's nobody here?
Greetings.
Yes...!?
You may begin.
You were about to say something?
Do return before nightfall.
I will.
How wonderful!
It's a wonderful beginning.
We poor things have had it today.
You may say that doomsday
will be coming soon.
You're right. But ask Saheb Jaan
when the doomsday will arrive.
Did you see?
Didn't I tell you not to
hold a dance performance...
...till her fever
subsides completely?
Her body is still warm.
How can she dance?
You gentlemen have been
unnecessarily inconvenienced.
I'm leaving.
Her helplessness is a such
a defence that...
...though she made
go away a hundred times...
...yet I returned
as many times.
Here! Take this.
You may ward off the evil eye
from Saheb Jaan on my behalf.
Who is it?
Hey! Didn't you recognise me?
I'm the contractor.
Listen to me.
I've been summoned.
Why're you so worried?
How strange!
What happened?
Perhaps somebody has been
run over by the train.
It's an accident.
"Really, when God protects,
nobody can kill a person."
- Take the train behind.
- It's God's miracle!
You're right. But the engine driver
too has stopped the train rightly.
Where were you lost?
I wonder where I roam around.
I don't remember anything.
You happen to meet me automatically...
...and sometimes you
get distanced again.
"I wonder if it's my dream,
or have I gone mad?"
I don't know when this
dream would be shattered...
...and which desolate place
would I end up in?
I wonder where I'll
regain consciousness.
Wherever you'll regain
consciousness...
...my eyes will be
watching you.
And the key to your dreams
will be found in my eyes.
Yes.
Stop crying. Or you'll get
a severe beating from me.
"Greetings, grandmother."
"Greetings, Mother.
Greetings to everyone."
May you live long.
Please come and be seated.
Everybody is so surprised.
Yes.
We're indeed surprised.
About who this person
accompanying me is?
Yes. Who is she?
I too don't know
who she is.
She's an oppressed girl
who has lost her memory.
Come over here.
She appears to belong
to a decent family.
That's why I've brought her here.
"And till she remembers her identity,
she will stay here."
"Of course, why not?"
- How're you?
- Come on. Take breakfast now.
I'll take breakfast.
Let me refresh myself.
Come on. Help me wash myself.
When are you offering bracelets
to your sweeper woman?
Get married first. Then I'll
offer you several bracelets.
I've already got married. How could
I've waited for you to marry?
You've already selected the girl.
You should get married now.
"Stop, will you?"
Where's grandfather?
He's gone to Hyderabad
to fetch your Uncle?
- Hyderabad?
- Yes.
He's lying sick in the
government hospital.
Why do you've to weep?
He's going to return home.
There should be celebrations
to mark his return.
"Don't weep now. After all, grandpa
will be fetching him back."
- Open the door.
- Who is it?
It's us.
"Greetings, Mother."
My son!
Uncle has arrived!
- Greetings.
- God bless you.
"- Greetings, Uncle.
- God bless you."
She has grown up very fast.
Arrange the food.
"- Greetings, Uncle.
- Oh! So you're here too!"
"When I arrived here, I was told
that you were in Hyderabad."
- Be happy.
- I hope you're fine now.
Who is she?
- Greet him.
- May you live long.
Is she your bride?
- No. She's Arif's bride.
I see. So Arif got married!
We had to marry him.
We searched for you a lot.
But we didn't find you anywhere.
It's nice that he married.
My congratulations.
- You've married too?
- How can he marry?
"Till he doesn't choose a girl
himself, he wouldn't marry."
Then select a girl. I'm very
keen to see you married.
"Moreover, I'm not sure
how long I'll live now."
Why do you say that? You'll live
for many more years now.
It would be better if
you select some girl.
- He has already selected a girl.
- Is it?
- She's sitting there.
- Be seated.
Who is it?
"- Greetings, grandpa.
- When did you come?"
- I too arrived today.
- Be seated.
Who's that girl?
She is with me.
"Girls, you may go."
Yes.
- Who is she?
She's an unknown girl.
- She's with you?
- Yes.
- What do you mean?
Even I don't know who she is.
She's an oppressed girl
who has lost her memory.
"Incidentally, she has
come into my refuge."
But who will believe
what you're saying?
I don't care.
You may not be worried.
But I'm worried about you.
Those who get burnt with milk...
...they even drink
curd-milk with caution.
It's a pity that people
get burnt with milk too.
Do you want to enter into
an argument with me?
You need not argue with me.
A girl who doesn't have a
name or an address...
...why is she in your company?
It's because she is
under my care.
And it's not a crime.
It's not a crime. But it will
bring me disrepute.
No. You cannot lose any reputation.
"If anybody will lose his
reputation, it will be me."
Who're you? Don't I have
any relationship with you?
You've a relationship. But you've no
connection with this matter of mine.
I've no connection?
"If I don't have any connection,
why've you brought her to my home?"
"Undoubtedly, I've made a mistake."
I'd forgotten that people in this
family have to...
...seek permission from you even
before taking every breath.
And your progeny doesn't walk on
the ground which is created by God.
"Rather, your progeny
crawls on your palm."
Let's go away from here.
This mansion is built
with quicksand...
...and it cannot provide
shelter to anybody.
It's a very dangerous place.
Wait!
Perhaps you've forgotten
about yourself for ever.
I'm convinced now that you're
nothing but my destiny.
Look over there.
The entire world is
bowing at your feet.
And they're all saluting you.
O Lord! Please remain quiet.
Don't kill me so lovingly.
I confess that
I remember who I am.
Who are you?
- I'm an innocent woman.
That's what you'd told me.
"You came, you wrote a note..."
...and then you never let me
sleep peacefully thereafter.
"Every night, you have been calling
out and passing through."
"Every single day, you've been
pulling away my soul from my body."
I would have died
aspiring for you.
But you never let me die too.
I would've run away.
But your tent surrounded me.
"You came, and your heartbeats
didn't even let me say..."
...that I'm a prostitute.
Please stop the carriage.
- Make one garland.
- A garland?
All right. Please be seated.
Make an attractive one.
You mean you're not
recognising me?
How wonderful!
But why so much displeasure that
you're not even greeting me?
Who are you?
I see... so she's with you!
Come here.
"- Yes, Sir.
- Who're you?"
- Tell him my name.
- He's Hashim Khan.
"No, Sir."
Now you'll have to reveal
your name too.
I'm a stranger here.
And I'm a decent person.
Come on. Proceed.
Who's he?
How many people's name
will you ask me?
What's your intention?
- I want to ask you your name.
Please stop the carriage.
Let me introduce myself to him.
You were asking me my name?
Get down.
Leave the reins.
- Who's he?
- He's some ruffian.
She's some whore.
She's a heady stuff.
What's your name?
What's your profession?
I asked you your profession.
Is it important
to tell you that?
"- Yes, it is.
- I'm a forest officer."
Constable... you may go.
It doesn't befit an officer
of your rank...
...to have had to come
to a police station.
It's a matter of regret.
"Anyway, you may go."
Bring in Mr. Hashim Khan.
"Wherever you take me, my notoriety
will follow close behind."
This sky is my enemy.
It'll never come to an end.
Where are you taking me
so that you may hide me?
To the place where
your sky ends.
- Greetings.
- What can I do for you?
- I've come to marry her.
All right.
"Gentlemen, please attend
this marriage."
And what's your name?
- She's some whore.
Her name is Pakeezah.
Do you approve of your...
...marriage to Salim Ahmed Khan?
- Say yes.
- You may remain quiet.
Let me ask her.
I'm questioning you
for the final time.
Don't feel shy.
Say yes or no.
Do you approve of your...
...marriage to Salim Ahmed Khan?
No! No!
"Has Saheb Jaan returned?
- Yes, she has returned."
Yes. My vagabond dead body...
...has returned to be buried
in this colourful tomb.
Hush! What dead body?
Yes. Every whore
is a dead body.
I'm a dead body. And you too!
This marketplace
is a graveyard...
...of women whose
souls are dead...
...but the bodies
remain alive.
These mansions are
our tombs...
...in which the living coffins
of we dead women...
...are kept after
being decorated.
Our coffins are left open...
...so that...
Keep quiet. Keep quiet.
I'm a restless dead body
of one such open coffin...
...which is lured by life
again and again.
But now I've got fed up
of my waywardness...
...and this treachery
on the part of life.
I've got tired of it.
What has happened?
Did he reject you?
No. I left him.
I afflicted him with
a serious wound...
...and made my exit
from his heavenly heart.
Why?
I got scared.
The ground of that world
was such that...
"...wherever I set foot, the ground
used to sink at the same spots."
Look over there...
that kite is so much like me.
"It's cut away, like I am."
This gentleman has brought for you
a letter from some Mr. Salim Ahmed.
On the 26th of this month...
...I'm celebrating grandly the
ceremony of forgetting you.
It's also the day
when I'll be married.
You're requested to perform a dance
on this auspicious occasion.
I hear that you're known all over
for your dancing and singing.
Your's Salim...
The feet which remained
hidden in my heart...
...I'll see those feet dancing
in everybody's presence.
Will I be able to see?
Come and see the sight
of you being insulted.
She's your own honour...
...which is dancing amidst people of
your community in your own home.
It's an assassination of
your self-respect.
"It's your daughter's blood,
on which you've put your feet."
My daughter's blood!
My daughter...?!
My father!
Did you see how that oppressed
woman's blood has bloomed...
...whose blood had dried up
on your sleeves?
What nonsense!
You cannot defame me by
making this allegation.
It's not an allegation.
It's the punishment for
your false pride.
- Recognise her.
- Move away!
- Brother!
- What're you doing?
O Lord! My son!
Uncle!
How did this happen?
She's my daughter.
"No, Shahabuddin."
She is still the
daughter of Nargis.
She cannot be called
your daughter until...
...a marriage procession
doesn't come for her marriage...
...and until her marriage palanquin
is lifted by you from my brothel.
I'll take the marriage procession.
My procession will go there.
Take me along with you.
Take me at all cost... alongwith
your marriage procession!
Uncle! You'll go alongwith
the marriage procession.
The palanquin will be lifted
at your hands.
I assure you. You'll surely
go with the procession.
Her palanquin will surely
be lifted at your hands.
Do you approve of this marriage?
Yes.
Silence!
Give your daughter
the permission to leave.
Give her the permission.
"For thousands of years, a flower
withers away without any recognition."
"Only then comes the one,
truly worthy of praise."
Is it Saaheb Jaan standing?