Even after living for 35 years in
U.S., whenever l come to lndia...
...l don't know why, but
l feel very excited.
l feel as though l've come to the
warmth of my mother's lap. Today...
...my lndia may have something
to offer, or not, but she has...
...one thing in abundance, and
that is love. The air here...
...the buildings here,
echo with one word - Love.
One such building
is... The Taj Mahal.
My American friends... in U.S.,
Love means give and take.
But in lndia it means
give, give and give!
And there comes another
unbelievable thing...
- How is your family?
- My wife is very peeved with you.
This time l'll make it up to her.
U ou've become a big-wig now.
U ou last come to us 10 years ago!
- My kids are dying to meet you.
- l'm packing off this lot.
l'll accompany you to Dehra Dun
and spend 3-4 days with your kids.
Put your window up, friend.
lt's getting dusty inside.
We've grown up in this dust...
...so how can we stop
it from coming in?
The scent of this dust from
lndia is out of this world.
For 35 years you've been living in
the U.S., but you haven't changed.
U ou must be the first lndian to have
earned so much money and fame there.
U ou're coming to my house
after exactly 10 years!
We sold our house at Dehra Dun and
built a house amidst our land.
My brother lives in the city.
My mother, wife and l live here.
Since it's vacation time,
it's full house at home.
Kulvanti and her kids are here, too.
And they're all awaiting you...
...as though some film star
from Mumbai is expected!
See! We're cought right here.
This is Ganga, my daughter.
The same. Our little Kusum.
- Look who's here, dear.
- Don't tell me. Let me guess...
U ou're American-uncle, Dad's friend.
25 years ago... No!
35 years ago, you went there
with Rs. 10,000 in hand.
Today you're rich!
U ou've a huge family with
18 sons, 1 1 daughters...
9 daughters-in-law, 3 sisters, 3
brothers, cars and helicopters too!
And which is that city, Dad?
U ou live in Hollywood...
...where all the American movie
stars live. And your bungalow is...
Won't you touch his feet
and pay your respects?
- Bless you. - My son...
- l'll go tell Mom.
- Tell her what? They're all
activated as it is. - What happened?
Come along at least.
A royal welcome awaits you.
- Madam...
- What is it, damn you!
Master is here with
his American friend.
- What do you mean? He's here?!
- What! He has come? Today?
Somebody get my ''chunni''
Get aside, will you?
- Did you have to sit here only?
- Come, friend... - Wow!
- What a lovely farm-house!
- My ''chunni'', kids! Hurry!
- ls that American here?
- He's here, sis. - How are you?
This is height of shamelessness.
l'm going...
- Namaste...
- Honestly! U ou didn't tell me...
- So what? l'm no stranger.
- True, but...
- Good you came.
We were expecting you tomorrow.
Anyway, now that
you're here, welcome.
- l hear you're a big-wig now.
- For you, l'm the same little boy.
l need your blessings, in fact.
So...
- But how can l bless you, son?
- Why not? - Cow-dung!
They are Nitin, Sonali,
Daksha, Dabboo...
That N.R.l. is being fussed over
as though he's God!
That Surajdev has an complex
about foreign countries!
- l know him for 10 years!
- U ou are an N.R.l. too.
- Why don't they fuss over you?
- They will, my dear. They will.
- U ou'll see.
- When, Dad? When?
When he'll come with a proposal
for his daughter Ganga.
When will he do that?
U ears have gone by...
- Then fix it once and for all.
- Fix it? Without deciding dowry?
U ou've pretty silly. l've educated
this boy; made him a body-builder.
- What for?
- Then go and meet them.
A variety of gourmet dishes have
been made for this richie-rich!
Wow! What a delicious dinner. l used
to return from Delhi and Mumbai.
But the fruits and vegetables
of rural lndia are unique.
And why not? When they're from
the fields of the Sun God!
This is Amirchand. My mother's
sister-in-law's, sister's son!
Why don't you say
a distant-cousin?
Sir, l'm Amirchand, my brother
Garibchand, and my wife Bhagyashri.
- He's an N.R.l. too.
- Which country do you come from?
- Not now. He used to live
in Sri Lanka. - So what?
An lndian coming from Sri-Lanka is
an NRl, too! - We're small people.
Variety of rich dishes are laid out
for you. - We're not even invited!
Amirchand, come here and
open your complaints book.
- My respects, Auntie.
- Right. How are you?
Uncle. Take your medicine
for the evening.
- My dose? - U ou're to take your
dose everyday at 7 p.m. and 9 a.m.
- 9 a.m., 7 p.m...
- Who told you?
- Tell me. Who told you.
- l was ironing your overcoat...
...a slip fell out from it.
lt said what you are to eat...
And also what not too.
lt was signed ''Arjun''.
- This is his work, eh?
- Who's this Arjun?
He's my 18th son.
Son of my distant sister.
He sees to my every personal need.
l call him my ''Little Master''.
He has penned a lovely song.
Have your dose first then go
on about ''l love lndia''.
Auntie, why is our Ganga...
...buttering that man so much?
U ou always smell of jealousy!
Here, have some water.
This uncle can take us to U.S.A.
- How?
- lf we impress him, that is.
- But how?
- U ou ass... - Ass?
-...with our music.
- That too English music.
ldiot! He's an out and
out lndian American.
lf you try to impress
him, it'll backfire!
- Shall we bet on it?
- Done! - One moment.
Do you remember our
song's English notes?
U ou can't be serious!
l am very much serious.
For my son Rajiv...
...l'm asking your daughter's
hand in marriage.
Look. Rajiv's mother
died 3 years back.
U ou know Rajiv is my only son.
He was born and brought up there.
He hasn't seen lndia as yet.
But he definitely knows the hearts...
...and the thoughts of his lndian
parents, and he respects them.
l'm asking your daughter's hand
because...
...we N.R.l.s need girls
like her very badly.
Because we've pushed our kids so
deeply in English books and manners
That somewhere or the other,
even after seeing so much success...
...we feel as though we're failures.
And seeing all this...
...today, girls like Ganga
are our only source of hope.
That's why l've decided that by
making her my son's wife...
...l'll take her from this
house, to that house.
But by asking you
with folded hands.
What nonsense! The fact that she
will go into such a loving family...
...is so comforting.
There's just one hitch...
- We're village folks...
- Don't make such cheap remarks.
U ou know me well, don't you?
Leave the rest for later.
l'll phone you from America.
No! A girl whom l don't send
to Delhi or Mumbai...
-...l'll allow to go to America?
Never! - Try to understand.
Vices depend on one's upbringing
Not the nation.
And America's not far.
How times have changed!
U ou'll send her to America?
Make her a foreigner?
Oh come on, mother...
Today the whole nation
is westernized.
And Ganga has
graduated in English.
Look at our own kids.
All twenty-four hours...
...they watch musical channels
which show Michael Jackson!
Don't be adamant about it.
l've given my word to my friend.
We had given our word to that
Amirchand too, for his son.
No... we hadn't given
any word to Amirchand.
We had said we'd think about it.
And that son of his...
- ...he drinks heavily.
- Then go and talk to him.
- They are under that impression.
- So let them be!
My Ganga will marry my friend's son.
And that's my final decision!
- How can you decide by yourself?
- U ou should've thought about it.
U ou should've taken some advice.
Enough! Ganga will marry my
friend's son, and that's that!
American uncle has gone,
but he left some snaps...
- ...of his family and son Rajiv.
- Really? Show us... - No!
But your father doesn't know
which is Rajiv's photograph.
- What! - U es, because he forgot
to ask and uncle forgot to tell!
- Show me then. l'll tell you.
- Hands off!
l'll show you...
First of all the family.
This is American uncle
with his brother.
- This is his sister-in-law.
- Looks strict!
- This is Padma, his sister.
- She's fashionable.
- And this is his mother, Krishna.
- A wholesome mother.
Now the confusion sets in.
There are 2 heroes!
- And you've to guess which one
is Ganga's! - Show me at least.
l'll show you. Now the first hero.
Now, the second one.
Now you have to guess
which of the two here...
- ...is her hero!
- U es. Go ahead and guess.
- Take your time, sis.
- Shall l tell you?
- l say it's this one!
- And l say...
- ...sister's hero is this one!
- Sis...
...you guess which
of the two is Rajiv.
- Shall l show you?
- U es, go on.
U es, show us...
- My respects. - Be happy.
- Did you call me?
U es l did. ls it true...
...that you've asked your friend's
daughter's hand in marriage? - U es.
And l've also given him my word.
Good. But Kishorilal...
...do you know this too, that
you're trying to bring...
...lndia's pure Ganges to these
concrete jungles of America?
l know it. But how about
our future generation?
Our lndian culture?
Who will preserve it for us?
- Rajiv will never agree to it.
- He'll never.
Our sons don't like to visit lndia,
how will they choose an lndian girl?
They are westernized, and for
them to marry lndian girls?
- lmpossible!
- l'll make the impossible possible.
And my Arjun. My Little Master.
Arjun Sagar, is one of U.S.A.'s,
Canada's and U.K.'s...
...upcoming artists whose
song, ''l Love My lndia''...
...is topping the Asian Music Chart.
Let's now meet him.
How did you come from
lndia to the U.S.A.?
By Air-lndia! Actually, l...
l was born in a town called Mathura.
- The town of Lord Krishna?
- U es, that's right.
But l'm not Krishna, l'm Arjun.
That too, from these modern times.
Actually, l was 10 years old
when my parents died.
My father was a musician,
and my mother, a school teacher.
l was just living a life
of an orphan, when Kishorilal...
...who was like a brother to
my mother, came into my life.
- Then?
- Then l came to America, and...
...l worked in
a garage for 3 years.
Plied a taxi for 4 years.
And then Kishorilal made me
a manager in his own garage.
Today he's my father...
...deity, God... everything!
When he came to know that
l love singing and dancing...
...he built a work-studio for me.
Where we do our work...
...and our rehearsals too.
- Any regrets? - No.
- Any siblings? - No.
- Any relations? - No.
- A Beloved? - Only in songs.
- Ever loved anyone? - Never!
- Why is that?
- Never found one.
- Who's your dream-girl?
An lndian girl...
l don't really know.
Because she's in my mind...
ln paintings. l haven't met her.
- How long have you been
away from lndia? - 5 years.
- U our future plans?
- lt's only to...
...raise my father's house in
Mathura and build a music school.
Where poor kids can come, and...
- U es Rajiv? - Where are you?
Daddy wants you. Go home now.
- Has he called me now? - He has
chosen an lndian girl for me!
- That's why he wants you.
- Has he called me alone?
- Don't worry. l'll meet him.
- Else, he'll parcel me to lndia!
Just one last question.
- Sorry, but l've to go.
- lt's an important question.
Look, didn't l just tell you that
nobody is an important as Kishorilal?
Not even me!
Arjun, Rajiv has
never gone to lndia...
...and nor does he want to!
But l want him to go there.
To breathe the fragrance there...
To understand the values there.
And choose the Ganga there.
To agree to marry her
with all his heart.
Just think that this is
my life's most important...
...and beautiful dream.
Which only you can fulfill for
Rajiv is your friend, and...
No, Daddy. Don't you worry.
l promise you.
Rajiv will agree to marry Ganga!
Give Monica 5 days leave.
Take that as an order from me.
- Who sent these flowers?
- That friend of yours...
- l sent them, sir.
- Welcome, welcome.
- How do you like them?
- They're beautiful, and...
l also know why you've sent them.
Advocating for Daddy, are you?
l know l've to go to lndia
with you. Look around...
- Approve the girl and...
- U ou know everything...
Daddy did one good thing.
He gave me the right to choose.
- Meaning?
- He left the choice to me!
Come and see lndia once at least.
U ou'll like it very much.
l knew you'd join us too.
So, l booked 3 tickets to Delhi.
- By Air-lndia!
- Why Air-lndia?
Sis! Sis! We got the information.
- Sis! - What is it?
- We got the news! - What news?
- Who's to be your husband.
- Who? - U ou won and he lost.
U es, l did lose. Here's your
prince Rajiv's photo...
- What is it?
- Get up! U our prince is here.
- What! - U es. Come and see.
- No. l don't want to.
Come on... see for yourself.
Ram hasn't come, but Krishna has!
- What are you talking about?
- Rajiv is still in Delhi.
- He has sent some Arjun
to see to things. - What?
Look, uncle... Try to understand
what l'm saying.
Rajiv is totally American. He will
not stand this heat and dust.
And the stink! lf something
stinks... l mean, he'll go mad!
Do you know what'll happen if
he comes here? He'll faint!
He'll faint first, then come
to his senses and just fly off!
No. We're with you. Last night
Kishorilal told me everything.
So now do as l tell you.
- First remove these cows from here.
- The buffaloes, son.
Whatever. Then send these
goats away some place.
- Now this... does he bite?
- No. Just barks.
U ou'll have to shift him because
Rajiv is allergic to dogs.
- ls this cot for the dog?
- That cot...
- lt's our servant's cot.
- No no. He can't sleep here.
Build a servant quarter for him.
Everything must've its own set up.
Uncle, you do follow me, don't you?
We must clean up this place fast!
- This straw here...
- lt's cow-dung, son.
Ramu... that's your name, right?
Just throw this out at once.
- Son, Kishorilal...
- Not him; talk about the son.
He won't stand all this, so,
it's vital that we clean up.
- Pompous, isn't he?
- Tells us to oust our dog!
- Asks Ramu to sleep out.
- ls he a human or a beast?
l'll turn this beast
into a man pretty soon.
- How?
- l've a remedy for it.
What will you do? What idea?
Says our Ganga...
- U ou are? - Daksha, a cousin.
- Good. Sit down please.
- And you?
- Shake hands at least...
- l'm the brother... only one.
- Please stand here.
- Where's Ganga? Didn't see her.
- Come in, Sis...
Don't remove your glasses.
l'm really Ganga.
So then... that is... you are
chosen by Daddy for Rajiv?
U es, when uncle saw me,
he said he won't find such...
- ...lovely Ganga in the whole of
lndia! lsn't that so? - Sure.
Daddy was right! We won't
find a girl like you...
...in this whole world,
let alone lndia.
ls there a... te... telephone here?
Will you let me talk to Rajiv?
l'll certainly not do that.
l'll just talk to Daddy.
Come along... Not you.
U ou sit right here.
Book a call please. U es...
`Lightning' call will do.
U es, l know it cost's 8 times more.
Charge 16 times more, even 32...
...but l must get the call through.
Let the lines be down or not...
Even if they are down
try and put this call...
What the hell are you doing?
No, l don't mean you...
- Go sit there, please.
- Let me talk to Rajiv...
l can't do that. Go and sit now.
Sit her there and see that she does!
Stay here... No Madam, l'm back.
Look Madam, have pity on me.
l had told you, you won't get
a line for 4 hours.
- ls there any secluded place here?
- U es. - l want to be left alone.
- And the moment the call
comes through, call me. - Fine.
There's a problem...
U es, put me through. Kishorilal?
How are you?
No, l didn't phone you.
Arjun is here and Rajiv is coming
tomorrow. We're all fine.
l'll just call her.
Ganga, my dear...
- U es, Papa? - U our phone.
- Who's calling?
- lt's an important call. - From?
- Guess. - Tell me, Papa.
- Kishorilal uncle.
- Really? Let me talk to him.
Uncle? This is Ganga here.
My respects...
l'm fine. Oh uncle! How
will l not remember you?
And that song of yours...
We all sing it.
lt's a super hit.
Even Grandma sings it!
U es? And how are you? Do you
take your medicine on time?
U our Little Master
is here. He's okay.
A bit pompous... No, uncle.
He's nice.
- Okay, l'll give it to him.
- U es, go on...
Everything's fine.
- That soap in your room...
- Keep it as l told you to.
- This is...
- Ganga.
- And that one then... - A trick.
- U ou may go.
Daddy, you were right.
- l'm... My name is...
- l know. U ou're Arjun.
Rajiv's friend. U ou have come
to see me and my home.
l'm sorry.
My entry was a bit mistimed.
All good people admit their
error, and apologize at once.
l'll say that all the good
people in this world...
...forgive those, who apologize.
U our face shows that
you've forgiven me.
And your smile says that we
must become friends soon.
And your hand says we must
shake hands soon. Right?
- A firm friendship? - U es.
- Absolutely? - Sure.
Every relation in this house
is bound with bond of love.
Whether it's with an animal, or
between a servant and his master.
To form new relationships
we don't break old ones!
Do you have any shame, or not?
Forgot the rules set here? lt seems
he's not fixing your betrothal...
- ...but you're confirming his!
- My dear...
Whatever Arjun's doing is
for your own good.
lmagine that he's a film director.
Who is planning to get the hero
and the heroine together.
Rajiv is coming tomorrow.
ln his honor, l've invited...
...the elite of the city.
So don't do any mischief tomorrow.
Am l not here to break the
legs that you're standing on!
How will you? And why?
As if you were never little.
U ou too must've been naughty then.
Don't laugh! U ou'll grow old too.
Now everything is fine between
us. We know each other...
l just wish to explain one thing.
Think anything you like about me.
Rajiv's servant, his ''cutlery''...
His friend, brother, anything!
But there's one thing.
A boy like Rajiv is hard to find
in this whole world, let alone U.S.
He's out of this world.
...he's mind blowing!
Today too, he'll come in a
special car in such great style...
- ...our American Prince.
- He's here. - Who?
U our dear prince from Delhi
His car had a 4-tyre flat.
ls he coming in a chariot?
So come and see that.
Welcome to lndia, son-in-law.
Welcome to lndia.
All the guests are here.
U our father has invited so many
people. Raju must be nervous.
Meet the Asst. Police Comm.
of our area, Mr. U adav.
Bless you... it's all right.
So...
- lf you have a problem, call me.
- What problem with you around, sir?
l mean if anyone is to be pulled up.
l just jailed a minister, you see.
- What goes on here?
- Nothing. Come, have some snacks.
Pay your respects, son.
Not mine, this gentleman's.
Bless you...
- Cool, sir. - Cool? U ou're
feeling cold with a coat on?
- No. ''Cool'' means ''fine, thanks''.
- Why thank?
- O, wifey... - Right here.
- Come dear, let's go.
ln Punjab they hit you like this,
and show their affection.
The chair, sir!
Chair, sir, l say!
- He doesn't know Hindi you see.
Say ''Chair''. - Go to hell!
Baba, someone has cast an evil
eye on him. Ever since he's here...
...his health has been bad.
Give him a remedy for it.
He's just warding off evil
spirits. Try to understand.
He too is having the same
problem. So please... Just once...
No, no. l'm fine...
- This is Love from lndia!
- Shall we sit down?
- How is he?
- Shall l tell you the truth?
- He's like a prince!
- Sweet.
- Where's Ganga.
- l'll just go and see.
What's wrong? Why the delay?
Where's Ganga? - Getting ready.
Dressing up in finery...
There she comes now.
- How am l looking?
- Wonderful!
- Didn't l say that when l get
ready, you'll just gawk! - Sure.
- lsn't she looking beautiful?
- Sorry, but she resembles an ape!
Try to understand.
Rajiv hates such heavy ornaments.
- He's American and likes simplicity.
- But this is lndian simplicity.
No! l'll show you simplicity.
Hold this, and you come with me.
Take this off and why did you
wear these gold ornaments?
- What will you have? Tea, juice?
- l'll prefer tea.
Will you have tea, too?
- How much sugar?
- Just one spoon.
- Two more.
- Two more? ...Two.
- Okay, one more.
- One more.
- Do one thing, add the whole lot.
- The whole lot?
U ou're pretty smart!
Rajiv... How did you like Ganga?
Let me sleep. My head is aching!
Okay then, shall l...
consider her for myself?
U ou haven't told me how
did you find Rajiv?
- U ou didn't tell me either.
- Did you like him, or not?
- Liked him not. - Tell me.
- U ou tell me. - No, you first.
- Tell me... - U ou tell me.
- Okay, l'll tell you.
l think you didn't
like Rajiv at all.
When did l say that?
So! U ou like him, eh?
Dad, it's bad. Surajdev
called everyone, but us.
He got scared you may not
spoil his daughter's chances.
l don't spoil chances,
l stop them.
- And what if they get engaged?
- Then? - We'll break it.
Surajdev, let my good days
come. Then l'll show you.
- Where are you going? - To give
milk to Rajiv. - Give it here.
- Ganga, go give this to Rajiv.
- Me? - U es!
Take it, l said. Hurry up.
- Why her, and not me?
- Arjun said...
...Ganga will give him
the milk today.
ln our country a snake is not
considered as an animal, but God.
U ou have your milk and sleep.
Nothing will happen.
- U ou?
- l want to meet you...
- ...in private.
- Why in private?
- Well, won't it be better if we
chat a bit? - So let's chat.
Not here.
- Then where? - ln those fields.
Behind the wind-mill.
May l ask my mother?
- Can't you make your own decisions?
- lt's not that...
Just wait here. l'll just come.
Auntie, may l go in the
fields with Rajiv?
ln the fields? Why ask
me, you shameless girl!
Ask your mother!
Did you hear? U our Rajiv...
...wants to take Ganga in the
fields, behind the wind-mill!
- Who wants to take her there?
- He came as a guest, mother...
...and he wants to take the girl
behind bushes right in front of us!
- Sister! Will you shut up?
- Okay, l'll shut up!
Let her go behind the wind-mill.
lt's very hot, isn't it?!!
- Speak softly.
- Why? l can't speak softly.
Are we thieves? Girls do not
roll in the hay before marriage!
lf you think it's proper, send her.
Sending her to America! What
are you doing there? Come...
Congratulations!
My dear brother, if you
wanted to meet Ganga,...
- ...why talk of the fields?
- What's wrong with the fields?
Look. ln lndian etiquette,
before marriage,...
...there are various
rules and norms.
A river, is no river without water.
- Wind is no wind without sound
to it. - That marriage...
...is no marriage
without a love-story.
- U ou do understand what
l mean by that. - No.
Look, before Rajiv and
Ganga get married...
...it's vital that they click!
And they'll click...
...only when they chat. And they
will chat, only when they meet.
- Why should we mind if they meet?
- U ou don't mind...
...but yesterday, that scene which
Auntie made about the fields...
l'm being frank. Rajiv is born in
America. He'll just run away!
No, no. lf you wish, tomorrow,
we can take them out...
...on a sight seeing tour and
show them the fort there. - Auntie...
- Why should l mind? My lips
are sealed! - Hear that?
No, son. lt'll be as you say.
Shut up! Will you, my dear?
lt will be as Arjun says.
Don't go too far from the
hearts that are broken.
But don't go too near the ones
that are beating together, either.
The one who drives a Mercedes
is pedaling a cycle...
See how in various ways
he's wooing you! Too good!
But l'm no less either.
U ou saw my artistry, didn't you?
How l convinced the elders,
that we'll go on a picnic.
This will give you a
chance to talk to Rajiv.
He loves you a lot.
Sometimes l think...
...if he loves you so much now,
how much he'll love you later! Mad!
What is it, Ganga?
Why are you staring at me?
- May l ask you something?
- Sure, go ahead.
l know that l haven't driven Rajiv
mad, but your efforts have.
U ou are his friend,
and brother too.
But some kind of bond is forged
between you and l also.
A bond of implicit trust
and friendship. Right?
What do you want to say?
l want to ask you,...
ls Rajiv right for me?
After so many days now,
this kind of a question...
He has hidden something from me.
U esterday l was tidying his clothes.
And l found this.
lt's not that he smokes...
...but the fact that he hid it.
lf he has any more such vices...
...please tell me now.
So that l can decide properly.
Look, your advice can
either make my life...
...or, ruin it.
Ganga, you're totally mistaken.
This packet is not Rajiv's.
lt's mine.
Actually, sometimes, l do smoke.
But Rajiv... drinks and cigarettes...
- There must be a lighter with this.
- l'd rather you not smoke either!
- A man looks so rotten.
- Shall l leave it?
- Leave it. - There!
- U ou're very bad!
- Am l still?
U es, Daddy. Rajiv has liked Ganga.
- U ou're not saying anything, son.
- Daddy...
...l think Ganga should go
to the U.S. before marriage.
- See the culture, the people there.
- Right!
- lt's the girl who will live abroad
not the boy. - lt'll be nice...
...if she comes with us to America
for 1-2 months and sees everything.
l'm happy to see you
speak so maturely.
- l'll talk to her father.
- What are you saying?
That we send her to America
all alone? Are you alright?
What's wrong in that? He's a friend.
Can't she go to my friend's house?
lndian girls do not go
without marrying, son.
- l too have decided that
she will not go. - Correct.
Okay. Call the whole thing off.
l'll speak to Kishorilal.
Then what was the need for all this?
Why did you call him all the way?
Then what do we do?
Become Americans?
Come, Kishorilal.
How can we send the girl without a
betrothal or a confirmed relation?
Just think.
We live in a small town.
- What will people say?
- They've already started gossiping.
And suppose she returns
without marrying your son?
- l've got a solution to it.
- What?
We'll get Rajiv and Ganga
engaged this week itself.
Then she'll go with us,
and after a month...
...we'll get them married in
U.S.A. in style. Okay?
Okay? U ou shouldn't have
any objection now.
Why should we have any objection to
an engagement? Right, my dear?
- Say you agree. lt's okay.
- What l say is...
- ...you all come with us.
- No, that's impossible.
lt's our harvest season, you see.
None of us can make it.
lf none of us can make it
my daughter can go instead.
America? No, l can't.
How can you suggest it?
U es, that'll be perfect.
lf you stay with Ganga...
- ...she won't feel lonely.
- Go, Mom.
Okay. lf you all insist, l'll go.
So it's all fixed now.
Engagement on Monday.
Then Ganga's ''farewell'' and on
that note give us sweet-meats.
U es, it'll be a farewell, no doubt.
Who knows when she will visit lndia?
What's this? U ou're
sitting all alone here?
What's up? U ou're getting engaged
and you're crying?
l know. U ou don't wish
to leave Papa, do you?
- l don't want to go anywhere!
- That is unavoidable, dear.
All girls marry and
go away one day.
Leaving their mother
and father behind.
Forever and ever.
Why are you crying now?
- U ou made me cry. - U ou did.
- U ou made me cry. - U ou did!
Come on. The engagement and the
farewell are both on Monday.
- The cards will be sent today.
- Cards? Must be Arjun's idea.
What! Kusum engaged to Rajiv?
Never! Did you hear that?
This is absolutely unfair.
The whole town knows...
- ...that Ganga was to marry my son.
- lndeed.
He hasn't just insulted me,
but this whole town!
- That's a lie! Uncle had not
promised you anything. - Shut up!
Stop jumping, son. Will you?
That foreigner is marrying Ganga.
Rajiv is no foreigner.
He's the son of an lndian.
That bastard Kishorilal...
First they broke the engagement,
now they're breaking my son! Help!
No Rajiv, No. No, Arjun.
- U ou will not fight. For my sake.
- We'll have to decide Surajdev.
What do you mean? l'm her father.
l'll give her away where l want to.
How will you decide? Tell us.
We'll decide today, right now.
Then come let's have a combat.
The winner will take Ganga.
- Agreed. Today, either you take
her, or l will. - Good!
Even Lord Rama had to lift
Lord Shiva's bow, to win Sita.
So today whoever wins,
shall be Ganga's groom!
This is too much! My daughter's
future will be decided by bouts?
Then admit you're a cheat, and
that you sold yourself to a N.R.l.
Suraj is not a cheat,
but you are!
And we'll give you
an apt reply to it.
Good thing the Headman
mentioned about Ram-Sita.
My son's shoulder is willing
to carry any bow you wish.
Tell me, which bow do you have?
Let me see how strong your son is!
- l'm ready, Daddy.
- So Manuchand...
...what's your choice?
Running, wrestling, boxing...
- ''Kabbaddi'' !
- ''Kabbaddi''?
Okay. Today and now!
- What? A kabbaddi-match?
- U es.
- And the winner will be sis's
bridegroom! - Nonsense.
Go and see. Stop them.
No... lt won't be possible.
Don't you worry, Suraj.
We'll defeat them.
U ou'll say, take care of Ganga,
and l'll say she's my daughter now.
- So you have no right.
- Right on.
- Arjun hasn't come as yet.
- He's not coming with us.
- Why? - He'll stay back a bit more.
- Meaning?
Meaning... Here he comes.
Ask him yourself.
- For Rajiv and you.
- What's this? U ou're not coming?
l've to go back to Mathura, where
my father has an old house.
l've to rebuild it as a music-school.
So l'll have a lot of paper work.
- U ou didn't tell me this earlier.
- Didn't get a chance to.
- Keep these. - What for? l'm going
abroad for the first time.
- l'll be so lonely. - Why?
There is Daddy, Rajiv, your aunt...
- And many others who'll take care.
- But you won't be there.
U ou had said you'd be there
with me. l agreed only because...
Look. My responsibility,
and work ends here.
Now your life and my life
go different ways.
- Okay?
- Why are you saying that?
Because, now you've to become
a responsible daughter-in-law.
- Abroad, and live happily with
everybody. - Don't give a sermon.
- Hurry. U our plane will leave
without you. - l can go alone.
l don't need your help.
l can take care of myself.
Crazy kid!
Are you Arjun Sagar? - U es.
- A passenger's sent you this note.
Arjun, come soon.