DONKEY SKIN
From Charles Perrault´s fairytale
Once upon a time
there was a great King,
so loved by his people
and respected by others
that he was the happiest of monarchs.
Happy too
in the choice of his beautiful
and virtuous wife.
The couple lived in perfect harmony.
They had a daughter
of such grace and charm
that they never regretted
having but one child.
Their palace was a marvel
of taste and abundance.
The buildings were magnificent.
The vast stables were filled
with handsome steeds.
But what most surprised visitors
was a donkey
in the most prominent place.
This iniquity may surprise you
but when you learn
of his rare ability,
you will agree
that this honor was his due.
However, the vicissitudes of life
fall also on kings,
and the greatest good
is always mixed with bad.
The Queen was stricken
by a cruel malady,
and neither the doctors
who studied Greek
nor the quacks in vogue
could do aught for her.
Allow me, before I die,
to make one request.
If you should wish to remarry...
Never, dearest Queen!
I should rather follow you.
I believe you.
But the State requires heirs.
I gave you only a daughter.
Your advisors
will want you to have a son.
Hush!
Listen...
Swear by your love for me
to marry again
only when you have found
a woman more beautiful than I.
Impossible!
Swear it
so that I may die content.
I swear it.
The Queen is dead.
Come, father.
Leave me, child.
I never wish to see you again.
Ministøi!
Speak.
We think that it is bad for you
- and for the State - to remain alone.
Solitude is unhealthy for kings.
It is time you remarried.
Why do you always request
the impossible?
The State needs a male heir.
The kingdom is at peace
and does not desire war.
Your advisors can but approve
of your policy
but we are supposed to advise you.
I understand your reasons.
I can remarry
but I swore to the Queen
to wed only a princess
more beautiful than she.
- A vain promise!
- How so?
Her beauty matters little
if she is prolific and good.
I do not agree with you
and I will not break my promise.
Search for a princess
who might suit me
in the neighboring kingdoms.
I wish but to please.
The Prime Minister!
That means trouble.
I beg your pardon, Your Majesty.
Well?
Two of our messengers
have brought us
some charming portraits.
If they are like the others,
keep them.
Those were so bad,
you couldn´t tell
whether the girl
was pretty or stupid.
Let me see.
Her father has the largest kingdom...
Come now... Let me see!
She is hideous!
Her father would give you
half his land...
Let him keep it all!
I won´t have an ugly woman
on my arm!
This one is not so young but...
her fortune is greater by far...
than the number of her years.
Sadness!
Boredom!
Pride!
Hypocrisy!
They are all one-eyed or hunchbacks!
And probably deaf!
The fairytale princesses...
have they all disappeared?
There is this one.
Let me see.
God, how lovely she is!
You were hiding her, traitor.
How sweet she is! How pure!
How graceful!
Just look at that shoulder!
Who s she?
Your daughter, Sire.
Love is worn around the neck.
Love is mad.
Four arms entwined...
The soul is glad.
Like a scarf of white woos woven,
love forms a knot.
Love, love
has made me mad.
Love often makes a clamor.
In youth
it cries, it stings,
it swears false oaths.
It makes those lovers suffer
Who refused to turn the page.
Love, love
is never wise.
How beautiful she is!
More than the Queen, Sire...
And much more charming
and intelligent.
When it has lived too long,
content,
Love, at the slightest snag,
frays,
caught on the nail of memory.
Love dies in time.
Love, love,
I love you so!
Your father, the King,
has sent for you.
Love, love, I love you so!
You sent for me, father?
Does that surprise you?
Since my mother is death,
you have avoided me.
Were you hurt?
- Yes, father.
- I am sorry.
Solitude was my sole companion.
I have decided to change.
Stand, dear daughter.
I was listening to you.
Your singing enchanted me.
If you like music,
perhaps you do not dislike poetry.
I know little poetry,
but I like it.
I have some poems of the future.
The ancients wrote well...
but the poets of tomorrow
may delight you more.
Listening to your fairy lute,
trees, stones follow you, Orpheus,
letting you shape them
as you choose.
Clio, the barmaid...
Calliope phoning in a scoop...
Urania turning on the gas lights
which paint the trees from below.
Do you like it?
It is disconcerting.
Your godmother,
the lilac fairy, gave it to me.
Her knowledge
of the future amazes me.
Listen to another
which suits you well.
The ring is slipped on the finger
after the sealing kiss.
What our lips are murmuring
is in the ring on the finger.
Weave roses through your hair.
I love you and want to marry you.
Poetry deranges you, father.
I beg you to stop.
- Do you love me?
- Yes, a lot.
A lot is not enough.
Allow me to go, father.
I feel weary and troubled.
Be that as it may,
I have decided to marry you
and marry you I will.
Don´t ask me for such a crime.
Let me think.
Until tomorrow.
Ty jsi moudrý.
Your advice has never ed me astray.
I love the Princess
and I wish to marry her.
Is mine a sinful love?
Is she fond of your Majesty?
She says she loves me... a lot.
Yet she is confused.
Do you see what I mean?
The Princess is too young
to analyze her feelings.
It is written here
that all little girls who are asked:
"Whom will you wed
when you grow up?"
reply: "I want to marry Daddy."
Have you a daughter?
No, unfortunately.
but if I did,
I should certainly marry her.
You are the wisest of the wise.
I shall marry the Princess.
You! So early!
I hate to be taken unawares.
Excuse me, godmother,
but I have to tell you...
Don´t cry, child.
It will make you ugly.
But it´s dreadful!
Sit down.
Don´t tell me.
I know all about it.
Let me finish dressing.
And dry your tears.
You, go outside and play.
Yellow isn´t becoming to me.
That´s better.
My child, it would be sinful
to marry your father.
You must discourage him.
But I love him.
I know...
But you´re mixing up
different kinds of love.
I must give him an answer tomorrow.
The situation requires attention.
Children do not marry
their parents, my child.
You love your father,
or so I gather.
But whatever their reasons
or feelings may be,
boys do not marry their mothers,
my child.
And it is the tradition
in every condition
for lawmakers to decree
that girls
do not marry their daddies.
A prince with a shepherdess
may find joy.
But a gils with her father
can expect nothing
but tainted offspring.
My child, you must forget
without regret
these depraved phantasms...
And you will encounter
a ragamuffin
or perhaps a beggar prince.
But kindly abjure
this union impure.
Life will offer you gifts,
my child.
But first you must
conform to the plan
which I have concocted for you.
Have no fear of getting lost.
I shall enlighten you at all cost.
I shall protect you
and show you the way
that I have traced without delay.
Be of good cheer...
I´ve fixed it all up, dear.
Don´t worry. Nothing bad
will happen to you
if you follow my advice.
Are you sure?
Fairies are always right.
We must thwart your father.
You must tell him that you have
a whim for... Let s see...
a dress the color of the weather.
It´s very complicated and costly.
He´ll never be able
to give it to you.
A dress the color of the weather!
Is it a condition?
Oh, just a whim.
And you will marry me?
Yes, father.
The devil take me!
But what kind of weather?
Good weather, father.
What kind of weather?
Good weather, of course!
I need it tomorrow.
We haven´t time!
The color of the weather!
He succeeded! How dreadful!
Let me look at you.
It´s gorgeous!
I never saw anything like it.
I didn´t think it was possible.
He must love you very much indeed!
What do we do now?
We must be unreasonable.
Ask him for a dress
that is more sparkling,
less common...
A dress the color of the moon.
Go at once.
The color of the moon?
Yes, father, more sparkling,
less common...
but that one fits you perfectly.
I find it quite ordinary.
I would not displease you.
The co or of the moon?
Yes, father.
The color of the moon?
And even more sparkling
than the nightly orb.
Now he´s asking for the moon!
What a beautiful dress!
My father is so sweet! I am full
of love and ready to marry him.
- You can´t!
- But he´s so nice!
Impossible!
I tore my dress again.
How sad!
That´s life.
There is something wrong...
My magic spell
won´t work anymore. Is it spent?
Can a spell wear out
like a dress?
No, but it can weaken
like a battery.
A battery? What´s that?
Nothing... I´m getting old!
But fairies don´t get old.
You´re right. I had forgotten.
Still my power over men
has weakened.
My spell doesn´t work anymore
on your father.
I must admit
that I am very fond of him.
Oh no!
We shall conquer
this unwholesome passion.
We´ll be simply odious.
Tell him you want dress
the color of the sun.
He´ll give it to me.
We´ll see.
Anyway, I have another idea.
I think he will be surprised
by the request
I advise you to make.
What request?
Listen...
Oh no! Not that!
That´s horrible! I´d never dare...
I´d rather marry him.
You´ll have to do it.
Are you satisfied?
Frankly, I should like
a more dazzling dress...
the color of the sun.
Is this one not dazzling?
It could be made
of gold and diamonds.
Are you vain, my dear?
Not very.
Why are you teasing me?
You may have the dress
if you assure me
it is a sign of love and not a whim.
It is not a whim, father.
Go! Ask him what I told you.
Oh, I can´t.
Go! I command you.
How dazzling!
I have never seen
anything so radiant!
You are beautiful, daughter.
Are you happy?
I am, father.
I am filled with joy.
Is this your last request?
Or, before our marriage, have you
another desire that I can satisfy?
Yes, but I hesitate...
Tell me anyway.
I´d like... the skin
of that old donkey in your stables.
My banker?
Yes, father.
That s a strange request,
and it surprises me.
Who suggested
this monstrous idea to you?
Your fairy godmother?
She has despised me since...
- Since when, father?
- Never mind.
Besides, I don´t care
what the fairies think,
especially that one!
Well, if it is your last request
before our marriage,
it will be granted.
You will have
the donkey skin tonight.
Don´t be childish!
I cannot escape him.
It is cruel to make him suffer.
He is a ready planning the wedding.
That´s just too bad!
Why must I refuse his love?
What have you got against my father?
I need not explain to you.
Your father behaved badly
in an affair
involving only him and me.
Fairies, like women,
hold grudges.
Don´t cry.
If my father loves me,
why not do as he wishes?
Why flee from him?
I owe him my life after all.
Your education
has been sadly lacking.
What do you advise?
You must leave... quickly!
The King will find me
wherever I go.
You will be disguised.
You have the oddest ideas!
Hurry now.
- Wrap this skin around you.
- Oh, horrors!
Do as I say.
Everything is planned.
Where is my wand?
Here is a chest
for your dresses, your mirror,
your diamonds and rubies.
Take my wand too.
- But you...
- I have a spare one.
Strike the floor with the wand,
and your chest will appear.
- Come.
- Why?
Come here.
No one will recognize you.
You enjoy making me ugly!
Don´t be silly.
It´s going to be an ordeal.
Life s not so easy as you think,
even for the daughter of a king.
A coach will await you
at the gate
to take you to a safe place.
Good luck, child.
Lend me my wand to get home.
Come in, Donkey Skin.
I was expecting you.
I need a scullion to wash the rags.
Yes, Madam.
Call me "old woman"
or don´t call me at all.
You can start tomorrow.
Everybody´s asleep today.
You´re even dirtier than I expected.
By definition, a scullion is dirty.
You think too much.
- You can clean the pig trough.
- Yes, old woman.
I am tired from traveling.
Where can I rest?
There is a hut in the forest.
Oh, how wretched!
Where do you start?
The bed.
A chair.
The table.
A looking glass.
Candles.
And my chest.
Love, love, I love you so!
No trace of the Princess.
Search the stables,
the sheepfold, the cellars.
We searched everywhere.
She was sleeping
in her bedroom last night.
The Princess may have eloped
with some Romeo.
Nonsense!
I´m going mad!
Send 100 messengers,
1 000 musketeers.
Search each hamlet, vineyard,
and meadow.
Bring her back to me.
- Dead or alive?
- Alive, stupid!
Oh, it is too hard to bear.
What about the wedding?
Postpone it.
No wedding! No feast!
No decorations! No cake! No bells!
Leave me in peace.
Until you find her.
I can be consoled
only by her presence.
Be gone!
Oh, how disgusting!
Oh, how dirty!
Oh, how filthy!
The poor thing!
She must be sick
Her skin must hide some disease.
Maybe the mange!
Just look at her!
You can´t tell her hands
from her face.
With that hair all over her!
She won´t have a chance
to see the Prince.
Before kissing her,
he´d have to wash her.
Her skin must smell musky.
The old lady said
that you must clean
the stables and the barn.
Do you know why?
How would I know?
Our Prince is coming Sunday.
He insists on cleanliness.
- She doesn´t!
- Oh, how disgusting!
Let´s get away from here!
She infests the air.
They say she´s evil.
You´d better hide.
If the Prince sees you,
he might throw you out.
You won´t be allowed
at the feast.
The King´s soldiers might take you
for a beast and kill you.
I won´t take up much room
nor make any noise.
But I want to see
the Prince go by.
After that, I´ll leave.
She wants to see the Prince!
They´ll all take flight
at such a sight.
What is your name, noble lady?
- They call me Donkey Skin.
- Is it your skin that stinks?
- I think it is her body.
- I´ve never seen anything so ugly.
Am I really guilty?
Of what crime?
I don´t deserve such wretchedness.
Unless a Prince Charming
comes for me,
I vow here and now
to go out and find him.
Are we a most there?
Almost, Sire.
You have eaten nothing.
I am not hungry.
Is something bothering you?
I was thinking
how odd the world is.
They say
it may stop turning.
The fairies won´t let it.
- I don´t believe in them.
- I do.
Fairies are our inner force.
They make us act, for good or evil.
Excuse me.
I need calm.
- I´ll go with you.
- I didn´t say I needed company.
Love hides within the heart,
like a thief.
And secretly plans
its downfall.
Like a worm inside a cherry,
recalling happy days.
Are you bored, Prince?
Never, Rose...
There is so much to be done,
to discover, to understand.
Is it love you seek?
Of course... like everyone else.
Then follow the path.
You can trust me.
Thank you, Rose.
Love, love, I love you so.
Why are you knocking at my door?
I have waited so long
for you to bring me happiness.
Love, love, I love you so.
Tell me, woman,
who is that princess in the forest?
- Not a princess. A scullion, Sire.
- She has the loveliest face.
Little Red Riding Hood, perhaps!
She is a lowly servant.
They call her Donkey Skin.
- Donkey Skin?
- Donkey Skin!
What a pretty name!
Kind sir...
wine and sun have muddled you.
I have not tasted of wine,
and the sun shone
only to lead me to her.
You look mysterious, Sire.
I just saw an angel!
What the devil!
Hang me
if I did not dream it.
I wonder
if I haven´t found
love in my path.
Love that makes wise men go mad...
I seemed to recognize
love´s features.
So young,
so graceful, so lovely,
so tender,
so serene.
My life depends upon her...
I shall live for her alone.
Her love
must belong to me.
I had no hope.
I was desperate.
I went on living joylessly.
Then she appeared,
lovelier than an angel...
come down among us men.
I would give my life for her,
even if I were hanged.
I must see her again.
I do not wish to die
of love.
You tremble, Sire.
- There´s a spell upon him.
- Yes. What joy!
Prepare the horses. We´re leaving.
Were you asleep?
I thought I heard you.
We didn´t expect you
until tomorrow.
I´m not cross
but you know how I worry
when you travel.
Did you have a good trip?
What do you mean by that?
That father should do something
about his kingdom.
There are still scullions
living in huts.
Take it up with your father.
You look upset. Are you ill?
I have ridden 50 leagues.
I am tired.
- You´re burn ng up.
- I´m exhausted.
You gallop like mad.
You have a fever.
Are you ill?
Just my luck!
For your return, I arranged
the ball of the Cats and the Birds.
The Marchioness of Carabas
is coming.
All the Princesses want to see you.
Shall I call the doctor?
No! Thank you.
Leave me. I need to rest.
Where is your son?
Must we beg him to come?
I sent for him three times.
Does he know
the ball is in his honor?
Yes. He says
he doesn´t feel well.
- Where is he?
- He refuses to leave his room.
That isn´t like him.
Has he a secret?
Not that I know of.
- Has he eaten?
- He didn´t touch his food.
- I´ll go get him.
- No... I´ll go.
Madame de Ségur is looking for you.
Madame de Cléves
has traveled four days.
They are all asking for you.
They are all silly wenches.
I want to see that girl.
I want to marry her.
I tell you she is a scullion.
I tell you she´s a beauty.
There is much talk
about your absence.
If you tell them
you want to marry a scullion,
they´ll lock you up.
You are right.
But I must find a way to see her.
Until I do,
I will not leave my room.
I´ll be sick in bed.
I have spoken!
What did you say?
Your Majesty...
Leave us, Godefroy.
- The King is worried about you.
- He needn´t be.
- You don´t eat.
- I don´t feel like it.
You left the hunt,
you wouldn´t see the play,
you refused
to come to the ball.
Everything seems to bore you.
Is there nothing that I can do
to amuse you?
There is only one thing
that would amuse me.
Just name it, and it wil be done.
A cake made by Donkey Skin.
Who?
Donkey Skin. You don´t know her.
But you aren´t hungry.
It´s the only thing I really want.
I know it seems commonplace.
A cake...
Donkey Skin?
Get some rest, child.
Thibaud, I want
to ask you a question.
- A riddle?
- No, a question.
Do you know Donkey Skin?
Yes, Your Majesty. She is
the ugliest beast, except the wolf.
And she stinks!
Who´s she?
A filthy thing that lives
in one of your pigsties...
your farms.
She keeps the pigs.
Filthy or not, go!
The Prince wants her
to make him a cake.
I won´t get there before daybreak.
Then go quickly!
Go... quickly... Right.
She must be a good cook.
We´re here.
- Are you Donkey Skin?
- Yes, sir.
I am the Queen´s overseer.
The Prince, who is ill,
requests a cake... made by you.
- Do you have what you need?
- Yes, sir.
Hurry, scullion... We´ll wait.
I hope she washes her hands.
A cake for the Prince! My cookbook!
An apple savarin...
A rum alaska...
A walnut delight...
King´s cream puffs...
An apricot cobbler...
A plum soufflé...
Strawberry shortcake...
A pineapple charlotte...
A love cake!
My dress the color of the sun!
Prepare your dough...
...in a flat bows.
Light your oven.
Take some flour.
Pour it in the bowl.
Four full handful.
Make a lillle hole in it.
Choose four fresh eggs...
...laid the very morning.
For 20 days later...
...a chick is bound to appear.
A whole bowl of milk...
...nice and creamy if you please.
Sprinkle with sugar.
And mix well.
A handful of sweet butter...
A pinch of baking powder...
A drop of honey...
And a dash of salt.
And now it is time...
...wlise kneading the dough,
to slip in a present...
...for your betrothed.
Make a wish
while the dough is resting.
Butter the dish...
...and bake one hour.
Oh, my skin!
Get up, lazybones.
Don´t keep the Prince waiting.
Hurry up!
- How´s he?
- I can´t tell.
He is delirious but he has no fever.
Aren´t there any fairies around?
They´re all busy.
It´s the full moon.
But you are scientists!
The case s unprecedented.
Here is the cake.
Is it good?
I don´t know. I don´t like cake.
What do you think?
It smells like good butter.
Excellent!
Here, child.
Taste it when you feel like it.
I´m not very hungry.
He shouldn´t eat so fast.
He´ll get air in his blood.
He´s choking!
Do something! He´s been poisoned!
He hasn´t eaten for 3 days.
Give him a glass of water.
Thank you all.
The cake was delicious!
I feel much better.
Now I want to sleep. Leave me.
We must not irritate him.
His illness s characterized
by fluctuations.
The cough is only temporary.
I knew not that you loved me.
Do you know it now?
A golden ring told me so.
There must be a spell on us.
But what will we do
with so much happiness?
Let it be seen
or keep it a secret?
Together we will make our life
as no others have ever done.
Our love will be a legend.
And we will live long in memory.
But what will we do
with so much love?
Let it be seen
or keep it a secret?
We´ll do whatever is forbidden...
We´ll go together to the snack bar.
We´ll smoke a pipe in secret.
We´ll stuff ourselves on cake!
But what will we do
with so much joy?
Life is full of it!
We´ll do whatever is forbidden.
We´ll go together to the snack bar.
We´ll smoke a pipe in secret.
We´ll stuff ourselves on cake!
But what will we do
with so much joy?
Life is full of it!
We´ll have a great many children...
...and live happily ever after.
The doctors!
Have you looked in your books?
Yes, Your Majesty.
We are all in agreement
about the diagnosis.
Tell us!
The Prince is dying of love.
- Love?
- I knew it!
What do you advise?
Marriage, Your Majesty.
Is it urgent?
The sooner the better.
Thank you for your wise counsel.
We´ll think about it.
I can´t handle this.
You take care of it.
As you wish.
Wait! I´ll go with you.
My son... My dear son.
My dear child...
We know everything.
You´re lucky!
You shall have her.
Whether she be stupid or ugly.
Oh, not that!
You promised!
Tell us her name.
I do not wish to distress you
but I can´t give you her name.
Look...
I shall marry
the girl who can wear this ring.
What ring is this?
- Who gave it to you?
- No questions!
- We could...
- No! I know you.
If I tell you this much,
you´ll want that much.
I will command the ladies to come...
...to try the ring on.
Thank you.
By order of the King!
All maidens
are to come to the palace
to try on a ring.
Hear ye!
Maidens only...
The one whom the ring fits perfectly
will marry the Prince,
heir to the throne.
Hear ye!
The ring is very small,
and the finger must be slender.
Come hither, ladies!
This elixir of gazelle milk
will make your finger so slender
that you will wed the Prince.
This way, my beauties!!
I´ll make you a slender finger,
smoother than a plum.
And the Prince
will fall head over heels.
I´ve got a miracle salve
to make fingers slender.
Open the bottle.
Rub it in well.
Push harder, lazybones!
I´m afraid of hurting you.
Are you as stupid as you seem?
Push it down
until I tell you to stop!
Mother, hurry!
The Prince is waiting for us.
My finger is getting thinner!
Mine will fit the golden ring.
My skin is peeling off!
Mine is down to the bone!
It serves you right,
you giddy girls!
The cad! The quack!
Look at my finger.
It sooks terribses
Look at mine. It´s twice as fats
They´re so silly!
He´s jealous.
All that just to marry a prince!
You´re a naughty rogues
Ouch! You´re pinching me!
Help!
What is it, Esther?
I cut it!
Serves her right!
Make him go away!
You must suffer to be beautiful!
First the Princesses.
Then the Duchesses.
Then the Marchionesses.
What a crowd!
What if it fits several of them?
No chance of that!
But if there were?
I hadn´t thought of that.
Calm down! There´s no hurry.
And please don´t push!
The countesses...
The behinds...
I mean, the baronnesses behind.
Sorry.
I have the smallest finger
in the county!
Next...
Come back in a few years.
With pleasure, Your Highness.
Almost, but not quite...
The maids first, then the cooks.
The turkey keepers
and scullions last.
Stop your crackling...
I mean, your cackling!
Miss Gauthier, servant at the castle.
Miss Nicolette, cook.
Miss Saltandpepper, turkey keeper.
Miss Glum, unemployed.
Is it worth trying?
Give me your hand.
No, the other one.
I told you so.
Is there no one else?
No, Your Highness.
There is no one else, Your Majesty.
My dear child...
Every lady of the realm
answered your summons.
None of them could wear the ring.
I am very sorry.
I am surprised.
This ring must belong to someone.
I don´t think I saw Donkey Skin,
the girl who made me a cake.
Did no one inform her?
I don t know, Your Majesty.
Bring her here immediately.
Here she is, Your Majesty.
Do you live
at the third farm down the road?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Show me your hand.
Oh darling!
I´m marrying your father.
Try to look pleased.
My daughter!
My dear daughter!
We´ll never be parted again.
The festivities
lasted almost three months.
Kings came from everywhere.
The King of India with his elephant,
the King of Africa with his camel,
the King of Siam with his cats
and coaches and sedan chairs.
They say that the couple
would still be in sove
if they hadn´t died
a hundred years later.
The tale is perhaps
difficult to believe
but as long as there are children
and mothers and grandmothers,
it will be remembered.
Subtitles: Mary Lou se Gradwoh
Subtitling TVS - TITRA FILM