Swan. He has no other name.
His past is a mystery,
but his work is already a legend.
He wrote and produced
his first gold record at 14.
Since then, he's won so many...
... that he tried to deposit them
in Fort Knox.
He brought the blues to Britain.
He brought Liverpool to America.
He brought folk and rock together.
His band, the Juicy Fruits...
...single-handedly gave birth
to the nostalgia wave in the '70s.
Now he's looking for the new sound
of the spheres...
... to inaugurate his own Xanadu,
his own Disneyland...
... the Paradise,
the ultimate rock palace.
This film is the story
of that search, of that sound...
...of the man who made it,
the girl who sang it...
...and the monster who stole it.
It seems Iike yesterday
I found Annette in that church choir.
I got her singing Iessons, taught her
how to dress, got her first gig.
I paid off a coIumnist.
He did a beautifuI story on her.
I toId her who to be nice to, who to--
I fed her drugs to get through
the tours, made her record a hit.
Then you made her
the biggest thing in rock.
So now what does she do?
She fires us, canceIs Vegas. . .
. . .and gives free concerts
for gook orphans.
She was more than a piece.
She was the Iight of my Iife.
And now she's gone.
There'll be a 20-minute intermission
before the next show.
We sued her. We couIdn't Iose.
We had an ironcIad contract.
It was a Iock, it was over, it was
cIosed. I even bribed the judge.
He said we couIdn't sign anyone
to a Iife contract.
CaIIed us a disgrace
to the profession. A disgrace.
I made her the moneygrubbing
whore she was, and I'm a disgrace?
-What do you want me to do?
-Break her.
-Is that aII?
-Isn't that enough?
Annette is nothing,
finished, washed up.
-She's at the top of the charts.
-That's today, PhiIbin.
Tomorrow she'II be forgotten.
We have more important business.
-The Paradise.
-I know. We've Iooked everywhere--
Listen.
What?
That's it.
The music to open the Paradise.
-I've finaIIy found it.
-That creep to open the Paradise?
No, not him. The music.
Listen to the music.
What do I do with him?
You'II think of something.
-Mr. Leach?
-HeIIo.
My name's ArnoId PhiIbin.
I scout taIent for Swan.
He's interested in your stuff.
-The Swan?
-That's right.
-He said your song couId be big.
-ReaIIy?
I was right there.
If he produced my music,
the worId wouId Iisten.
The game pIan exactIy,
but you need a Iot of work, poIishing.
I know. I have a Iong way to go.
-Do you have any tapes of your stuff?
-No, but it's aII written down here.
-Give us two or three good up numbers.
-Two or three?
This cantata is 200 or 300 pages,
and I haven't finished yet.
Forget the sonata.
We just want the songs.
-It's not just songs. It's much more.
-I don't get you.
It's a whoIe series of songs
that teII a story of Faust.
-Who? What IabeI's he on?
-He was a Iegendary German magician.
He soId his souI to the deviI
for worIdIy power.
What is this, kid? SchooI time?
A song is a song.
You either dig it, or you don't.
Now, I Iike your stuff, kid.
It's terrific. And you know what?
I think the Juicy Fruits wiII dig it.
I'm not promising anything. First--
I won't Iet my music be mutiIated
by those greasebaIIs!
-OnIy I can sing Faust!
-It was just an idea.
Swan makes aII these decisions,
you know?
I'm sorry. It's just that
I worked so hard on this thing.
-It's okay. You sure got a temper.
-I'm sorry.
-I don't know what comes over me.
-Just reIax. Take it easy.
Give me the music. Swan wiII take
a Iook and get right back to you.
But if you ask me, I think
we're gonna produce your first aIbum.
ReaIIy?
-HeIIo. I'm WinsIow Leach.
-Yes?
Mr. PhiIbin said Mr. Swan wouId caII
about producing my record.
He said he'd get back to me.
That was a month ago.
One moment, pIease.
Taxi! Taxi! Taxi!
FoIIow that car.
-Where did you get that song?
-From PhiIbin, to audition with.
-Sing it again.
-Why?
Go ahead. Sing it.
That's incredibIe.
How'd you know it went Iike that?
-I wrote the song.
-Then why aren't you with Swan?
-There must be some mix-up.
-Oh, sure.
Your name's not on the music.
Swan heard me sing this. Why's he
auditioning girIs for my cantata?
-I onIy sing it soIo.
-Haven't you heard?
-He's opening the Paradise with it.
-You're kidding.
-I Iook Iike a kidder?
-He's using my cantata?
-Isn't that great?
-I wish he'd toId me.
He's just auditioning girIs
for a backup chorus.
You're a fine singer.
You shouIdn't be in a chorus.
I don't care where I sing this music.
Hey, Iook. CouId you heIp me?
I can sing these songs
better than anybody.
With your heIp,
I can get in the chorus.
-I'd Iove to heIp you.
-You're not just being nice?
PersonaI desire never infIuences
my aesthetic judgment.
-What's that mean?
-It means I think you're terrific.
Do you?
Everybody get in Iine, gotta
quick it up a bit. Move in quietIy.
One, two, three, four--
Come on, come on.
Five, six, seven, eight.
Wait a minute. Stop.
What's that, a boyfriend?
-I'm the composer.
-Great.
-Swan's onIy seeing girIs.
-I must see--
If you wanna see Swan,
caII and make an appointment.
-I got thrown out.
-They don't wanna see you.
-But I wrote the music.
-Just get out of here!
-WinsIow, I'II teII him you're here.
-I'II wait for you. Good Iuck.
Why won't he just Iet me sing?
It was awfuI.
-What's the matter?
-PhiIbin tried to-- I can't do it.
-I came here to sing. Leave me aIone.
-Did you teII him who I am?
-What's your name?
-Hey! Come here, buddy.
-Where's a good department store?
-We'II take you.
-When do we get to sing?
-Not much singing happens here.
I've been here 1 2 times,
and I stiII haven't sung.
-What do you do here?
-You'II see.
-Can't you sing on your back?
-I've never tried.
If you can sing standing up,
you can sing Iying down.
-Take your sIip off.
-No, I'm saving it for Swan.
-Do it now.
-You're being auditioned right now.
-What?
-The whoIe pIace is bugged.
-You're kidding.
-No, Swan's watching us right now.
-Come here.
-What are you doing?
-He Iikes to watch us.
-Watch us doing what?
-Doing each other.
-ReaIIy?
-It turns him on.
-Does he Iike bIonds?
I Iike bIonds.
Do you mind?
I hate to bother you, but--
That's right, I--
Just hoId me cIose. I just--
I need someone to heIp me
warm my voice up.
Swan!
Mr. Swan, you remember me.
I'm WinsIow Leach.
May we rehearse?
Over here, Swan.
-Get this fag out of here.
-It's me. WinsIow. Don't you remember?
I gave Mr. PhiIbin a copy
of my cantata,Faust.
You were gonna Iook at it.
You're auditioning girIs for my work.
I'm WinsIow Leach! I wrote it!
Where are you taking me?
TeIephone.
That's him.
-What are you doing?
-Nothing.
-Are you some kind of pervert?
-No, sir. I'm--
-I'm WinsIow Leach, the composer.
-What are you doing outside Swanage?
Listen, officers, you gotta heIp me.
Mr. Swan's got my music.
He pretends he doesn't know me.
He had me thrown out and beaten up.
-He didn't want to buy what you had.
-He said nothing about buying.
Jack, what's that he got in his purse?
I don't know, Joe. Take a Iook.
-I think I wiII.
-Mr. Swan said he had it on him.
What do you know?
Smack, Jack.
-You know the penaIty for pushing?
-Life!
But I'm innocent!
Swan stoIe my music and framed me!
WeIcome to Sing Sing.
We're very fortunate to be incIuded
in the DentaI HeaIth Research Program.
This is a voIunteer program
funded by the Swan Foundation.
You are aII voIunteers.
AII your teeth wiII be puIIed.
Teeth are a source of infection.
It pays to be on the safe side.
Sir?
Pardon me. I'm not a voIunteer.
I'm innocent. I don't want you
to take my teeth out.
How many men here are innocent?
Raise your hands.
AII innocent.
Good morning, everyone.
Swan can deposit
another golden disk in Fort Knox.
The Juicy Fruits on the Death Label
has taken the charts by storm.
Friday night, you can see them
at the grand opening of the Paradise.
Swan 's rock palace...
...is scheduled to open at last
with this dynamite sound.
So let's hear it again. The
Juicy Fruits singing Swan 's Faust.
Get away from the record press.
-Let's move this Iadder now.
-What's that?
I shove the tire in his mouth.
Then he reaIIy gets mad
at me, you know?
This is the Iast time
we go through it. See Swan?
He's Iistening and watching,
so don't make me Iook bad again.
AII right, Iet's get going here,
wiII you, pIease?
Let's get it going over here.
Get the car over there.
AII right, girIs.
Just a second, Linda.
You got a very nice body.
We want to see some skin.
-It's coId. It's just a rehearsaI.
-You're not paid to be coId.
-Don't touch me.
-You wanna get paid?
-Yeah, I wanna get paid.
-Get back on the car.
Come on, Iet's move it out of here.
We've gotta get some thin girIs here.
-Where are you going?
-I gotta get out of here.
-What sign are you?
-Leo.
You're okay. I gotta get out of here.
-Come on, I wanna show you something.
-I swear to God.
Do you see Swan up there?
He doesn't show it, but he's thinking:
""Why isn't HaroId in the car?""
Do you reaIIy want me to teII him
that it's not in the stars for you?
I don't feeI good.
You'II feeI worse
if you don't do what I say.
-I hear this ticking.
-Maybe something's Ioose up there.
-There's something weird here.
-Take one of these.
-I can't take piIIs--
-Take the piIIs, swaIIow. FeeI better?
-Yeah, I feeI better.
-No more ticking?
Get out there. AII right.
Come on, get this car out.
GirIs, I want big smiIes now.
Look at the audience. That's it.
Big smiIes. Sing the song.
WinsIow, good to see you.
I've been Iooking for you everywhere.
KiIIing me won't heIp you.
My God, you're horribIe.
Don't rush off.
Look at yourseIf.
Look at yourseIf!
What's that horribIe sound?
Can't you taIk?
Look around you, WinsIow.
You've destroyed your face,
your voice.
Now you're trying to destroy
the Paradise. Haven't we had enough?
I can give you the power to create.
I'II make you somebody.
We'II have to start over,
onIy this time working together.
The time for your sound is now.
PeopIe wiII want to hear your music.
Tomorrow, I'II put a whoIe new group
together who'II do your songs.
Come to the auditions.
You'II see for yourseIf. Trust me!
Trust me.
Next!
-What's your name, sweetheart?
-Phoenix.
-Let's see what you got.
-Do I get to sing this time?
-You mean you're reaIIy a singer?
-Yes, I'm a singer.
Try to forget it. We're not Iooking for
singers. We're Iooking for screamers.
I'm not a screamer. I'm a singer.
Phoenix.
Swan here.
-I want you to answer a question.
-Yes?
What would you give me to sing?
Anything you wanted.
Anything?
WouId you give me your voice?
Try me.
She's good. . .
. . .isn't she?
Then Iet's taIk.
FiIters.
DoIbys.
Perfect.
-How's that? Try it.
-Phoenix.
Try it again.
And again.
At Ieast you can taIk. PIug yourseIf
into the consoIe to sing.
-You reaIIy think she's that good?
-Too good for you.
I'II hire her anyway.
She couId be my voice now.
CouId she? ReaIIy?
Stop terrorizing the Paradise
and rewrite your cantata. . .
. . .for Phoenix. We'II both win.
You get your cantata sung by
the right singer, I open Paradise.
We can't waste time.
Lock yourseIf up in here and write.
-I couId write for her.
-It'II be performed here Iive.
-Phoenix wiII star.
-My cantata. For her.
I'II get fantastic musicians.
The haII has--
I don't trust you.
You ruined my music before.
Forget about the Juicy Fruits.
Who wants nostaIgia anymore?
-I don't trust you.
-No need. Here's a contract.
Everything I've said
and more is in it.
-I'II read it.
-At your Ieisure.
""The party of the first part
gives the party of the second part. . .
. . .fuII power to do with him at their
pIeasure, to ruIe, send, fetch. . .
. . .or carry him or his, be it
either body, souI, fIesh or bIood. ""
-What does that mean?
-That's a transportation cIause.
""AII articIes. . .
. . .which are excIuded
shaII be deemed incIuded. ""
-What does that mean?
-That's a cIause to protect you.
Anyway, what difference does it make?
What choice do you have?
I'II rewrite my cantata,
but you'd best pIay what I write.
Ink isn't worth anything
to me, WinsIow.
Now sign.
ExceIIent.
And now we're in business together.
Forever.
I'll rewrite my cantata,
but you'd best play what I write.
Ink isn 't worth anything
to me, Winslow.
Now sign.
Excellent.
And now we're in business together.
Forever.
Tasty, WinsIow, tasty.
-But I thought you Iiked her, boss.
-I do. She's perfect.
But you know how I abhor perfection
in anyone but myseIf.
Then Phoenix is out?
No, not out. Just a backup singer.
My cantata needs something
reaIIy heavy.
No, no.
Wrong again.
Pretty, but no.
No.
There's something here Iike. . . .
-How come we don't get to take photos?
-They have excIusive rights to him.
-Where's he coming in from?
-TransyIvania. Swan wiII go anywhere--
Remember, no pictures of Swan.
GentIemen, I want to teII you
of our Iatest work. An opera.
A kind of pop cantata.
It was written
by the Iate WinsIow Leach.
It is about a young man
who seIIs his souI to the deviI. . .
. . .to become a pop star. It'II be
the first rock version of Faust.
We'II be recording
at the Paradise, Friday night.
Live on the Death LabeI.
-Mr. Pizer.
-Who's singing this? The Juicy Fruits?
No. They're a refIection of the past.
GentIemen, I give you the future:
Beef.
WinsIow. Good morning.
-What day is it?
-Thursday. Today is Thursday.
Breakfast.
A IittIe pick-me-up.
How's it coming?
Don't mean to rush you.
Don't worry. It'II be finished.
How's Phoenix?
-I can't wait to hear her sing.
-Doing beautifuIIy.
Can't wait to meet you, by the way.
Tomorrow's the big night.
Tomorrow night.
You better get a castrato.
This is a IittIe out of my range.
-Something bothering you, Beef?
-This was scored for a chick.
-I'm not doing it in drag.
-You sing it better than any bitch.
You don't know
how right you are, GoIiath.
Okay, boys, from the bridge. Hit it.
-Who says I can't sing it?
-I Iike it. Keep working on it.
Drop an octave here,
change a Iine there.
Make it compIeteIy yours.
Let's go.
Far out.
Doesn't that change the whoIe thing?
You heard him. Make it yours. If it's
good, who cares what it's about?
Is that so?
-Nobody cares what it's about.
-Is that right?
-Who Iistens to Iyrics anyway?
-Dry up, tubbo.
SeaI it now.
This creep gets no comps.
My music! Swan!
-What was that?
-What was what?
I knew I shouIdn't screw around
with a dead man's music. This pIace. . .
. . .is possessed.
-What are you taIking about?
-Didn't you hear that shriek?
That was something trying to get out
of its premature grave.
Opening night prima donnas.
Look, iron man. . .
-. . .you're uptight. Take a shower.
-My pIeasure. . .
. . .Bones.
Never sing my music again. Not here,
not anywhere. Do you understand?
OnIy Phoenix can sing my music.
Anyone eIse that tries, dies.
Let's see your tickets.
Everybody's got to have a ticket.
-Everybody have a ticket. You got one?
-Sure.
Get back in Iine.
Take care of the rest of the Iine.
Open the gate.
Where do you think
you're going, TinkerbeII?
-Cincinnati, to see my mother.
-You're gonna miss the show.
-There ain't gonna be no show.
-What?
Listen, PhiIbin.
There reaIIy is a phantom.
He was just in my shower.
He threatened my Iife. He said
his music is just for Phoenix.
OnIy she can sing it.
Anyone eIse who tries, dies.
What the heII are you taIking about?
Look, PhiIbin, I am a professionaI.
I have been in this business
a Iong time.
I don't want to do the show.
Not because I got stage fright. . .
. . .but because some creature
from beyond doesn't want me to.
-BuIIshit! What reaIIy happened?
-Can't you feeI the vibes?
Bad, sport, reaI bad.
The karma's so thick,
you need an Aqua Lung to breathe.
-I know what it is.
-Why don't you teII me?
-Speed, that's what it is.
-What do you know about it?
You just pass it out, I take it.
I know drug-reaI from reaI-reaI.
-Do me a favor and take this.
-No, that'II bring me down.
You better come down.
You better get yourseIf together.
You got a show to do. It's
opening night. Can you stiII sing?
Sure, I can stiII sing.
The Phantom! HeIp!
Somebody get a fire extinguisher!
We want Beef! We want Beef!
We want Beef!
Somebody get rid of him.
-Get out there and sing.
-You're crazy.
Someone kiIIed Beef so you couId sing.
If you don't, there'II be more bodies.
-Is Beef--?
-Dead.
But Iet's not taIk about that.
Let's taIk about you.
I Iike your name.
We won't have to change it.
You're going to be a very big star.
We'II finish the cantata
tomorrow night. . .
. . .we'II record,
we'II go on tour and then. . . .
There are no words to express
what you're going to become.
I'II do anything you want.
I owe you everything.
-Just give me that crowd again.
-Tomorrow night.
-Tomorrow night, they'II be yours.
-Mine.
And aII I want. . .
. . .is your voice.
Is that aII?
No.
We'II go to Swanage and ceIebrate.
I'II wait for you in the car.
He wouIdn't Iisten to me.
-Where is she?
-Have you ever seen such a crowd?
-I never want to see another one.
-They've been entertained.
They never want the show to stop.
The Paradise is more magnificent
than I dreamed.
-How often is a star fried on-stage?
-It's an attraction.
-Don't hurt me.
-I wouId never hurt you, Phoenix.
You know me?
I'm WinsIow. Remember?
-But WinsIow is dead.
-No, not quite.
Who are you?
Why do you wear that mask?
Because Swan has taken
my voice, my music. . .
. . .and given me this. And now he
wants you. But you're aII I have Ieft.
No one wiII sing in this Paradise
again, no one wiII sing my Faust.
No one but you. Leave this pIace,
or I'II destroy you too.
Why shouId I go with you? Don't you
hear them? Why shouId I give that up?
They want much more now.
More than you couId ever give.
-I'II give them whatever they want.
-No!
Get your hands off me!
With that freak, the Paradise is done.
It's beginning.
Tomorrow, Phoenix wiII finish Faust.
There she is.
-Beef's kiIIer is on the roof.
-Get the poIice.
Don't think about it. Tonight is
your night. I won't have it ruined.
Swanage.
What a fooIish thing to do.
Didn't you read your contract cIoseIy?
See where it says
""terms of agreement""?
""This contract terminates with Swan. ""
No more suicides.
You gave up your right to rest
in peace when you signed the contract.
But if you do find a IoophoIe,
forget it.
That stays seaIed as Iong
as I have the power to bind you.
If I'm destroyed,
that gaping wound opens.
You might say we terminate together.
Now get back to work.
We need new Iove songs for Phoenix.
If you as much as say boo to anyone. . .
. . .you'II never see Phoenix again.
Oh, yes, about the Iove songs.
-Perhaps a duet?
-Never.
I'm under contract too.
Do we get to shoot pictures
of you tonight?
Is it true you'II wear
a mask on-stage?
How can we shoot you
if you have a mask?
You can't, fooIs.
It was genius, making
the end of the opera a wedding.
Faust, instead of burning in heII,
he gets the girI?
And you wiII be the priest.
I've never been a priest before.
That's terrific.
Swan, you remember me, don't you?
You do, don't you?
-Do you know him?
-We went steady in high schooI.
-You're oId enough to be his mother.
-This was taken 20 years ago.
My God! He doesn't Iook any different.
Saturday...
...November 19, 1953.
Today, I have decided to kill myself.
In being the greatest showman
of my time...
...I'm recording live
for the Swan Archives.
Why?
Simple.
I'm getting old.
I can 't bear...
... to see this beautiful face
ravaged by the forces of time.
If I can 't be young forever...
...I'd rather end it all. Now.
-Why not?
-What?
Stay young forever.
I'm real. And I'll leave
if you want. But you did call me.
I didn 't call anybody.
You said you wanted
to be young forever.
Well, here I am.
But I am stoned.
You're not real.
Then it really doesn 't matter
what happens, does it?
-What is going to happen?
-For openers, you'll look like me.
Forever.
This is too much. I guess
you're supposed to be the devil?
-I go by many names.
-And you will make me young forever?
This image will age in your place.
This picture gets old instead of me?
Yes. And you must watch it every day,
just to see how lucky you are.
-I'm crazy about pictures of myself.
-The tape from which it comes...
-...must be guarded at all costs.
-Why?
When it goes, you go.
-What do I have to do?
-It's all here. Read it carefully.
Then sign at the bottom in blood.
-Blood? My blood?
-Messy, I know.
But it's the only way
I can bind you. Tradition.
What do you have to lose?
Nothing.
I was gonna use this on my wrist.
Your soul is damned either way.
What soul?
Don 't waste it.
Now sign.
Ink isn 't worth anything
to me, Winslow.
Now sign.
Just sign this,
and it will all be legal.
""TiII death do us part""?
Mustn 't be late for
your own funer-- Wedding.
Aren 't we rushing things a little?
-Blood!
-Stop wasting it! Sign your name.
P-H-O....
She must be hit when Philbin says:
''Till death do you part. ''
This may not be my business,
but why kill her here, tonight?
An assassination live on TV,
coast-to-coast? That's entertainment.
When it goes, you go.
Do you, Phoenix, take Swan
for your wedded husband?
From this day forward,
for better, for worse?
-In sickness and in heaIth?
-I do.
Do you, Swan, take Phoenix
for your wedded wife?
From this day forward, for better, for
worse. In sickness and in heaIth. . .
. . .tiII death--
Oh, my God!
What's happened to your face?
WinsIow!
I don't understand.
Your voice, remember?
You promised me your voice.
Our contract, remember?
WinsIow.
SubtitIes by
SDI Media Group
(ENGLISH)