Christmas comes but once a year
For every girl and boy
he laughter and the joy
hey find in each new toy
l'll tell you of a little boy
Who lives across the way
his little fella's Christmas
ls just another day
He's the little boy
hat Santa Claus forgot
And goodness knows
He didn't want a lot
He sent a note to Santa
For some soldiers and a drum
lt broke his little heart
When he found Santa hadn't come
ln the street he envies
All those lucky boys
Easy. Be careful.
- What?
- Will you put me on there?
- Well, where's your mother then?
- She's gone to the shops.
Yes, all right.
How's that then? Enjoying it?
Lovely, lovely.
Now off you go.
Go on.
Now what have l told you about this?
What have l told you?
Go on, go on now. Sling your hook.
Go on. Sling your hook.
Wait for me, Pinky,
you rotten bleeder.
- They're my bullets, ain't they?
- I don't know.
Come on, Tubs.
lt's great down in the tunnel.
Don't you think
it'd be dangerous, Pinky?
No. Don't be daft.
- You all right, Tubs?
- Yeah. Hurt me knee a bit.
- Come on.
- Na. lt's too dangerous.
- We'll wait for the train.
- Give me the torch.
Pinky! Here comes the train!
Get off the line,
you bloody idiot! Here it comes!
Pinky, get off the line!
You!
You! Yes, you!
Stand still, laddie!
What have we here. laddie?
Mysterious scribblings?
A secret code?
No. Poems, no less.
Poems, everybody!
The lad here reckons himself
a poet.
''Money, get back.
l'm all right, Jack.
Keep your hands
off my stack.
New car, caviar,
four-star daydream.
Think l'll buy me
a football team.''
Absolute rubbish, laddie!
Get on with your work.
Repeat after me:
An acre is the area
of a rectangle...
whose length is one furlong...
and whose width is one chain.
Wrong! Do it again!
lf you don't eat your meat,
you can't have any pudding!
How can you have any pudding
if you don't eat your meat?
You! Yes, you, laddie!
Poems, everybody.
The lad here reckons himself a poet.
Again. An acre is the area
of a rectangle...
whose length is one furlong...
and whose width is one chain.
Hello. Hello.
ls there anybody in there?
Do you remember me?
l'm the one
from the Registry Office.
- Hello?
- Yes, a collect call...
for Mrs Floyd from Mr Floyd.
Will you accept the charge
from the United States?
l wonder why he hung up. ls there
supposed to be someone else there...
besides your wife, sir,
to answer?
- Hello?
- This is United States calling.
Are we reaching--
See, he keeps hanging up,
and it's a man answering.
Oh, my God.
What a fabulous room.
- Are all these your guitars?
- God.
This place is bigger
than our whole apartment.
- You like the tube, huh?
Can I get a drink of water?
- Can l get you a drink of water?
- Oh, wow, look at this tub!
Wanna take a bath?
- What are you watching?
- Hello? Hello?
- You feeling okay?
Next time, fuckers!
Wrong! Do it again!
- You feeIing okay?
- Fuck me.
He's gone completely round
the bleedin' twist.
You vicious bastard,
you never did like me, did you?
- The boy's an asthmatic.
- Asthmatic!?
He's an artist!
He's coming around!
There, you see!
How do you feel?
Hammer! Hammer!
Hammer! Hammer! Hammer!
Stop!
Stop.