Lyrics: Eduard Uspensky
Here is a simple fairy tale,
or maybe not a fairy tale,
or maybe not so simple,
that we'd like to tell you.
We know it from our childhood,
or maybe not from childhood,
perhaps we don't remember it,
but will recall it anyway.
Begin!
There once was a crow,
or possibly a dog,
or possibly a cow,
who struck a lucky score.
Someone sent her some cheese
perhaps about 200 grams
or possibly 300
or maybe half-a-kilo.
She flew right up a fur tree,
or maybe didn't fly there
or maybe up a palmtree
she climbed swiftly up
and there for some breakfast,
or maybe for some dinner,
or maybe even for supper,
she quietly made her plans.
And then?
But here a fox was running,
or maybe wasn't running,
or maybe it was a mean ostrich,
or maybe not mean at all.
Or maybe it was a street sweeper
who walked about the countryside,
to find the nearest hazeltree,
to carve himself a new broom!
Oh listen my dear crow,
or maybe you are a dog,
or possibly a cow
the fairest cow of all,
your feathers are so exquisite,
your horns are really something,
your hooves are slim,
and your soul is kind!
And if ever you should sing,
or maybe if you woof
or maybe if you moo
since that's what cows do
then you'll get a big saddle
a carpet and a TV set,
nice presents will be gotten
or maybe will be got.
And so, the silly crow,
or maybe the dog,
or possibly...
the hippo!
began to sing something...
Cock-a-doodle-doo!
And the cheese of our crow,
or maybe of the dog,
or possibly the cow -
of course fell down.
And right atop the fox
Stop throwing things!
or maybe on the ostrich
or possibly on the sweeper
it fell right down.
The moral of this fairy tale,
which may not be a fairy tale,
will understand not just a grownup
but even a toddler:
Don't stand, don't jump,
don't sing or dance
in construction zones
with suspended heavy loads!
That's all!
Written and directed by:
Aleksandr Tatarskiy
Art director: Igor Kovalyov
Music: Grigoriy Gladkov
Camera: Ernst Gaman
Sound operator: Nelli Kudrina
Artists: Yelena Kosareva A. Raspopov
Vocals: Leonid Bronevoy Aleksandr Levenbuk
L. Shimelov Grigoryi Gladkov Alyosha Pavlov
Editor: Lyubov Georgiyeva
Script editor:
Valeriya Konovalova
Executive producer:
L. Varentsova
The End