Progress against crime.
Attempt robbery prevented
ultra-modern system
signaling.
Finally, with the gang Stampa
eliminated forever.
Have you heard? But they are wrong.
And a matter of honor, to prove it.
Alarm?
Yes, I still ringing.
Have you heard about Professor Gromov?
They say he has what you need.
Passkey.
E.
Newest system.
Who dares?
You?
- Gromov? Russian? No.
- You?
What next. No.
You?
Maybe?
Bubba?
Calm down, chief. I have one
guy, he knows everything. Name Hurry.
- Hurry!
- Hurry! Where Hurry?
Hurry!
- Here is Hurry.
- I'm here.
- What can you do?
- All, Mr. Stump.
- I am waiting for the order.
- Then in the path.
Here the transmitter. Good luck,
baby.
"Since my childhood I was an obedient,
Child scrofulous,
I did not like leprosy,
But he adored orders.
Since then, for me the word chef -
law
Next, no arguments!
I have only one deeply convinced
Do not have an opinion!
In the battle of personal clothing
Do not be thinking Hurry,
Boss in favor
I'll go through fire and water.
Always for me the word chef -
law
Next, no arguments!
I have only one deeply convinced
Do not have an opinion!
Sometimes, I'm rebelling
And the chief criticism,
I'm trying to argue with him,
But then I wake up.
No, no, for me, the word chef -
law
Forward! No arguments!
I have only one deeply convinced
Do not have an opinion! "
Hurry, I - Stump. Do not forget
Professor Gromov.
His model is called
"Electronics".
ADVENTURE
ELECTRONICS
The first series
FLIGHT
Arrived. Proceed to
work.
Wonderful.
Give a few more parties.
- I'm tired of chess.
- Well, let's talk seriously.
Do not want to seriously.
Why should I always serious?
Elik, where are you?
Elik?
- Elik, you hear me?
- Of course, I hear.
Elik, you behave badly.
- To fulfill my desire.
- Elik stop.
- Swap. I order.
- You see?
And I do not want you to me
ordered.
Yes.
Elik electronics, I ask
Finally.
I also ask.
Well, that's win,
win, then ask.
You mate, Professor Gromov.
How?
That's incredible.
And if so?
It is absolutely accurate.
So it's wonderful.
It's amazing.
- Here we succeeded.
- So, a victory?
- Holiday?
- And what a.
Congratulations, Elik.
And now you have
fulfill their promise.
- Well, what do you want?
- Be as you are.
I do not understand, put it more precisely.
Always act in their own way.
And do what I please.
In general, be a man.
You know, baby, be a man -
is not quite what you think.
- You created for other purposes.
- To play chess?
- To win!
- No. I do not want.
I want to be like everyone else.
As a boy on TV.
- Who are you? Mosenergo?
- Superkarding.
Sorry.
- Be quiet, Masha, quieter.
- Viktor Ivanovich.
Rather, Masha, at the institute.
What happened?
I barely managed to calm him down.
But the results are startling.
Forgive,
I picked you up so early.
Why? I - your assistant.
And the only person
who knows about electronics.
You should not have made him a boy.
And you know, wanted me
communicated with some drawer?
No, I'm not talking about appearance.
But you have so much invested in him,
that he, excuse me, just
spoiled.
However, the boy failed to
glory.
Volobuev? Where Volobuev?
Volobuev!
Electronics - a brilliant invention.
But what will you do with it?
- I can not imagine.
- Do not you think that he can...
No. I do not think so.
I am very attached to him.
Odd word, I feel sad because
that he will never become a man.
- Are you sure you do not get?
- Electronics! This is his legs.
- Where did he come from?
- From the camel.
Can not be. I have a right
confiscated. Viktor Ivanovich!
Electronics, you act
wrong.
I never expected from you such
illogical behavior.
And you, okay? Who promised
fulfill my wish?
Understand, you're asking the impossible.
I want to become a man, what
is impossible?
Sit, Victor Ivanovich
Sit. I can not drive a car.
Electronics, now we
let's talk seriously.
- Elik, you must understand!
- I understand you do not want to help me.
- And you too?
- Come on down, nasty boy!
Elik what are you going?
Goodbye, I'll come back when
become a real person.
- Back after him! Hurry!
- I'm not a racer. I - scientist!
Electronic!
- Well, lad.
- What guy? What a guy?
- Listen, you're doing what?
- Electronics - a boy
just as real, but doeth
God knows what!
Think, boy.
Do not grab it right away, not enough
it immediately.
Find out first, as he
managed.
Find out how he managed
first.
- I do not understand, repeat.
- Find out where his button!
Where is the button where the button and find
would be where he is.
- Boy, who are you?
- Electronics.
- Who?
- Victor! That's yours.
- Come on, come here. Hold.
You instead Volobuyeva? Sit
rather, starting.
No buts. Rescue team
necessary, we human beings can not.
- Man?
- Well, of course.
Come on, hurry, hurry, hurry.
Go!
- Where is he?
- Do not know.
Yes.
Stop, stop.
- We'll have to wait.
- Well, well, well.
- We lost Electronics.
- Nothing, Viktor Ivanovich.
Wherever Elik not proved, he
necessarily betray himself.
- Yes. Unfortunately, you're right.
- Sorry?
Understand, this is not the usual
boy
which is burst into tears of failure.
If he does not understand, he is satisfied
that failed...
Well, what then?
Electronics can die.
That is why it is urgently necessary to find.
Let us turn to the police?
From left Professor robot.
Can you imagine what will happen?
Why, in fact, a robot, but
Viktor Ivanovich?
Elik Gromov - your nephew.
A? Do you have his photo?
- Yes, here.
- Well?
Oh, that Elik in the magazine?
No, he can not smile
for photo I made appearance.
- And the boy?
- I do not even know his name.
- Sergei! So that was home for supper!
- Yes I will!
There Gusev.
Hello, Syroezhkin.
- Hello, Gusev.
- Well, like, cheese eating or not eating?
- Go you.
- Are you with us today who? Syroushkin?
Or Soronozhkin?
Syropopkin.
- Oh you just Gus.
- What?
Stop!
Well, Seroega!
- I help you?
- Leave me alone. Yes you are Let go!
Nothing, nothing. It is not difficult.
- Go away.
- And yet, it seems hard for you.
I'll support you.
What are you doing? Why?
- How do I know where he disappeared.
- There he is dressed.
Catch Champion!
Boy, wait, we'll
rewards!
- Oh, what is their so much?
- Here! He wrapped up!
Where? Why?
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Hiding, then?
- And you?
So do I.
- From whom?
- Yes there is one. Gusev.
Goose.
Listen, what are you to me
like this?
This is your picture was in
magazine?
- Oh, my.
- I have done on your sample.
The probability of our meeting
is one-thousandth percent.
You and I were lucky.
- Hey, this is not you there yet?
- Me.
- And what are you up to?
- Ran away from the professor.
- Dali bike and said: "Push."
- Well, are you?
I passed. Few bothered
bicycle.
- And so I came early.
- Stop pouring.
- I do not understand.
- I say, I was not cheated.
- Do not obshtopaesh.
- You? Inflates and mend?
- But it is not possible.
- I say, I was not fooled.
I never lie. I can develop
speed of 300 kilometers per hour.
Why are you sitting there? You
same for soccer right.
- All prizes snatch.
- I do not need gifts.
You see, I want to become
man.
- Now who are you? Maker or what?
- I do not kettle, I - Elik,
the passport Electronics.
- What is passport?
- Technical.
I - the machine of new generation.
Yes, yes.
Listen. Listen, you go, and I
'll stay here.
- And then we were again mixed up. Go.
- And can I stay with you?
No, no, no, no, go, go.
And a professor was coming.
Go, go.
Oh, I can not, oh, hold me.
Syroezhkin lost his pants!
You - Gus?
What?
I ask you - Gus?
I'm such a Guster show, a century
'll remember. Ah, well, I repeat,
Makar Ste.
I can not, you're distracting me nose.
And what do you do you?
- Damage!
- Modest. So. Now tell me,
who will remember it all my life?
- I!
- And what will you remember?
- Everything! Mama!
- My mother has nothing to do with it.
- Of all the above must choose.
- I will not!
This is closer to the truth.
- Well, I go?
- Goodbye.
Thank you.
He is no more.
Listen, friend, forgive me, myself
you know, it happens.
- You want to be a friend?
- Ask. Legally.
Of course.
- I'm glad.
- Come on.
- Hello.
- Interesting.
- What is it?
- Gymnastics.
Beautiful work. Exact
movement.
Turns. Just keep your back
and keep an eye on his hands.
- Here's to meet.
- Come on.
So it is closed.
Come.
You know, this is somehow bad
be.
And how well?
And that's it!
Mike, let's go to the movies today?
I'd love to, but I
to three tickets dogs need.
Do you understand? Now everything is in our
hands.
Understood. But you tell me
how to act.
Okay. Right with me.
Well, what are you? Come, come.
Well, how?
- I like it.
- You bet. Township that need.
My father and I wanted out of this barn
garage to do. A car yet.
Like. It is full of all
stuff, take what you want.
Come here.
Understand? There clamshell.
Paperback.
- And what about food...
- I do not need it.
- And sleep?
- And sleep. I can not pretend
what I eat or sleep. And more
all, I do not like to drink water,
She then gurgles.
Yes, they'll be into something to wear.
Here you are.
You're only sorry, here
nothing more, but they are dirty.
It does not matter.
Well, you give.
- Very easy homework.
- Hello. What more do you know how?
Misc. While little, but I quickly
teach
After all, learning - this is the most
nice, right?
How to say.
Hey, Come wait.
Here, wear.
Come here.
Oh, wow.
See? Yes, we now own
mother can not distinguish.
- You think?
- You bet. Yes, you see.
Just look how cool.
- El, we've done in such cases!
- What?
I do not know yet.
Listen, we're sure
to invent something.
- What?
- When've done, then we'll see.
That's all done. "
Never mind. I glued so that no
be noticeable.
Well, that, E, I did it out of you
Rights? Will you say no?
- No.
- So, do it.
- When?
- Yes, even now.
You see, everything is very simple,
want to be a man - be.
- What a strange formula.
- My.
- And what does it mean?
- Well, what?
Rise and shine, in anything myself
do not deny,
try to live in pleasure,
True, it is not at all turns.
- But why?
- Well, as you explain.
And, now represent.
"Above us the sun shines
Not life, and grace,
Those of us in the reply
High time to understand.
We - young children.
We want to walk.
And we are told that cathet
Short hypotenuse
And I say to you: "Enough,
I'm tired of this burden. "
Sum of the hypotenuse.
I'm tired of this burden.
Oh, get up to at dawn,
Remove to a table, notebook
Those of us in the reply
It's time to understand
We - young children.
We want to walk.
And we say: "Athens
The war went to Sparta,
And I say: "Leave
I want to hurry the party! "
The war went to Sparta.
Leaving soon would desk.
Words are stubbornly
I will repeat
Those of us in the reply
It's time to understand
We have small children,
We want to walk.
And we are told that the Volga
It flows into the Caspian Sea,
And I say that long
Do not stand this grief!
To become, say, a man
Stepping need to keep pace with the times,
We do not want to walk,
We want to walk. "
- Well, do you understand my formula.
- No, do not understand.
Well, idiot.
Okay, then you'll understand.
We went to the park or something?
- What is it?
- Dogs, friends of man.
You know, I read in books;
looked at the pictures,
but I never thought that they
such.
Ordinary dogs.
Listen, they are afraid of me. Why?
Look, look.
- I comb it every morning.
- Hey, girl, come to us here,
Give us a dog.
- See?
- Well, do not we eat it. Come on!
Now. Viktor Ivanovich, from
police.
Yes, yes, I listen.
The park has seen the two boys
similar to your nephew.
How?
Do not know. You are asked not
delay. Sort it out themselves.
Yes, yes, now, quickly.
In the park? Two?
- Two?
- Do not, Masha.
Going to the park.
Moving. About the button is not
forget.
- Oh, what a dog.
- Guys, do not touch the dog.
Put your hands. But leave me alone you from
me.
Guys, Leave me alone.
See? Did you see what happens?
Okay, go out, give
those that disappeared,
and say: "Hello, I'm
Syroezhkin.
Yes, but...
- What, but?
- I speak only the truth.
Okay, get out, give them
and ducked out to come here
I'll go.
- And this will be a man?
- What do you think?
Girls must be protected?
Well, come on, come on, well.
Stop, I want you to
leave the girl alone
and left the place.
- And the more you do not want?
- I have one wish.
- But to you it is not relevant.
- What? And in the ear is not it?
- No, spank.
- Boy, Run!
Why?
Shoo! There's more!
Come on, come here!
- Are you cool you do it.
- I was supposed to help you.
Yes. Thank you.
What's the name of my savior?
- Come here. Go.
- Excuse me. One second.
Hush, Martic, well, quieter.
Sergei Syroezhkin.
I am, it looked like they were there.
- Well?
- Procedure. Tide.
Oh, sorry, ran away.
He's here. I can take.
A button found?
- And where did you learn to fight?
- Yes, so somehow.
- Simply amazing.
- It somehow turns.
- Invite?
- Never.
Peace and goodwill,
otherwise he would not compromise.
I wish you good health.
- Are you in a school study?
- In the 42nd.
Hello, I'm in the forty-fourth,
close.
And in what class?
So, Maria, for me, I see it.
- What's your name?
- My name is Maya Svetlova.
Yes.
Go!
Just tell me about you, but then somehow
funny.
- Where is he? A? Where?
- Oh, here he is! Hurry!
Two.
- What happened Hurry?
- Nothing, nothing.
Oh, sorry.
- Viktor Ivanovich.
- What?
Oh, all I do not take it anymore.
Oh, Momma.
- And you did not see the second?
- Do not have time.
Pity. That policeman said
that they are very similar.
- It seemed to him.
- No, I do not think.
- And what if they met?
- Elik and the guy with the photos?
Professor, it's not logical, it is
contrary to any theory.
Elik himself against any
theory.
You'll see, we now
be such a surprise!
- Citizens, can you read?
- Yes. Why?
- Here, Masha, listen...
- Professor, you're an idealist.
If you are sober and realistic
look at these things...
- Well, you see me today and shook.
- Tired?
Yes, okay.
Sergey, what's wrong?
His head does not stay, but still
problems in algebra.
- Give your problem.
- Yes?
84, 85.
- The first response -40, -4 second.
- It's that. I need a solution.
- In the notebook. My handwriting.
- Good. I will copy each letter.
Yes? Really? Well, come on, do it.
Only when you do, wake up,
and then I have to go home.
Well, what about you?
Go on.
And you?
Hey, listen, tell me where
train?
- Well, what you see?
- In general, yes. I did not expect.
Now you'll know. Understand?
Well, tell me where?
The system of yoga. With five years.
- You mean that? A?
- "Wait a minute.
- What you before?
- It was impossible.
Anger accumulated.
Here.
So, so, so, well, well.
Wait a minute.
- Tell me, are you all by himself nareshal?
- Sam.
Originally, very original.
Tell me, dear, what have you got?
Wait a minute, you all now
answer. Warning
Give me a piece of chalk, please.
You can go into place.
S., tell me, please, that
have you got a number?
Well, bolder, S., boldly.
Well. But you have to put this
all solution. Please bolder.
- Serge, we are waiting for you.
- Prompt him.
Integral, integral.
Integral!
Intregal.
S., well, how can you?
What intregal?
Hello, Sergei. I'm sorry,
but I have not had time to finish everything here.
Why are you?
You do not like?
No, thanks, but, you know, if
someone sees you, will be inconvenient.
Maybe remove it?
And I then did, and moped
mended.
Moped?
And the clutch done? Well, you
master! Well, thank you.
This, of course, all is well
Only now...
Why deuce? After the decision
was correct.
Bet! Taratara even jumped.
Very original solution!
- So what's the matter?
- These are your integrals.
I shall never forget. Now, even in
Do not go to school.
Two! At the end of the year!
The mother will eat me now!
- How does it eat?
- Well, to cut will be.
You know what, if I am wrong,
let me and nags.
- Listen, you learn to love?
- Yes.
Exactly. Tomorrow you go to school
instead of me. Twos fix.
But you know, I can not
call myself Syroezhkin.
With you nothing but trouble. What is not
come up with something wrong, it's not some sort.
Well, wait a minute.
Come here.
Help. Dana Electronics is
that it replaces Sergei Syroezhkin.
Well.
And the gates do not need anything.
Come on, after helping. From there, the whole
class seen.
Well, you give. I can not
get used to your tricks.
- Instructions remember?
- Yes.
Well, then, come on, move.
Hello, "Intregal.
- What are you, Syroega?
- Do not bother me.
Understandably. Yoga.
Pose Sphinx.
Come, sit down, sit fast,
sat, who they say. Sat.
A greasy.
And why?
- Hello, hello, boys.
- Hello!
Sit down, sit down.
That gives.
Iron small.
You want to fix a deuce?
I can give 20 evidence
Pythagorean theorem.
Are you joking?
You can start?
- Look, Pythagoras remembered.
- Exactly. You could have Gorapifa blurt.
About Pythagoras, we know little,
He lived in the sixth century BC,
and established a mathematical
school. The proof of the first.
The method of addition.
The method of decomposition.
The method of parquet.
And, finally, the bride's table.
And now let me give you
yesterday's decision problem.
Since the integrals without integrals
and coordinate system.
It's just amazing, just
amazing.
Good luck, academician.
It's amazing.
Well, okay.
Well, that's for you too.
Long enough for you. Well.
Here it is! Freedom!
"Until then came the progress
Before unseen miracles
He dropped to the depths
And he went up to heaven.
Forgotten trouble
Stopped running,
Injected robots
And not a man.
Until then came the progress
Physical labor has disappeared,
Yes, and mental replace
Mechanical process.
Forgotten trouble
Stopped running,
Injected robots
And not a man.
Until then came the progress
It was time to spare,
Now, take a walk through the world
Would you like the song, want not.
Forgotten trouble
Stopped running,
Injected robots
Happy is the man! "
Guys, today we have a free
theme. Draw what everyone wants.
Just quiet. Okay? All
All clear? Yes?
Please, can begin.
Sergei!
Why did you run away then from
park? Offended?
No, I'm not offended. For me
pursued.
- Chase?
- Yes, but do not talk about it.
- And where are you now going?
- At a training session. Competition soon.
And yet, who?
Some other time.
Would you like to meet after school?
Well, okay.
Good, good.
Come on.
What is this?
- Well, why did you, Serge?
- Just that you were well lit.
Thank you, Serge. I put
you four.
- Why four?
- Hush, hush, boys, hush.
And why. Very nice
drawing. Listen, Syroezhkin,
Give it to me, but I'll hang it
the wall.
- The figure is inaccurate.
- What?
I mean, you glossed over life
a true artist
must be truthful.
- I love you why the school sent?
- Over five.
What's this?
- I wanted the best, but it...
- And she, she, it?
A true artist must
be truthful.
Well, okay, so be it,
for the first time I forgive you.
Listen, go and get some home
instead of me.
And then, awaken each morning
without doing anything, ask about school,
In general, replaced me completely.
Want?
I.
Hey, Al, wait.
You're only going to wear me not
forget.
- Why?
- Well, I can not like you.
All right.
- Hello, I came home from school.
- Well, dinner in the kitchen.
Thank you. I just wash my hands
and dressed.
What?
Quiet!
Started.
Well, well.
Let one.
Kukushkin.
Smirnov.
- Lev Leshchenko.
- Korolkov.
Attention.
- Muslim Magomayev.
- Gusev. Come to the instrument.
I? Now. Hold me.
Please.
What's the matter, Gusev?
Deploy and recover.
See? You have the same voice as
pipe. Come on, come on, come on.
I'm hearing no.
- All there is, but hearing no.
- Can I?
Syroezhkin?
- Well, try.
- What is it?
Do not "and".
- Silence.
- Please first.
Well, well.
Silence. Calm down.
"In the month of April, a young
In the old park is melting snow,
And funny swing
They begin their run.
Forgotten everything,
My heart sank in my chest
Only sky, only the wind,
Only joy ahead.
Soaring above the spruce
Unaware barriers
Winged swing
Fly, fly, fly. "
Have you heard? Again yoga.
"Childhood ends when something
After all, it is not forever,
Will the older guys
Scatter in all directions.
And while we are only children,
We grow more, grow,
Only sky, only the wind,
Only joy ahead.
Soaring above the spruce
- Who is singing?
- Do not know.
Unaware barriers
Winged swing
Fly, fly, fly.
Listen!
Done!
- Lucky is this Syroezhkin.
- Skip, skip.
Congratulations, congratulations, now
in our school, this choir.
I declare to you our gratitude.
- Well, what's new?
- Today, only singing.
By singing.
Hey, what is it?
I mean, I sang a voice
Robertino Loreti.
- What are Lobretti?
- Italian.
For this song he came
more than others.
- Well, there are other?
- Caruso, Tito Rocco, Chaliapin.
Chaliapin.
Professor Gromov very
loves music.
What are you doing? Sick or what?
I'm still here Chaliapin not enough.
- Well, I went.
- Wait. Tell me how it all.
- Where?
- Well, how, where, at school, at home?
- I have no time, my guys are waiting.
- What other guys?
Korolkov, Smirnov, Gusev.
Insolence.
Horse!
Smirnov, Gusev.
Clear. Caution.
Caution.
- Ronya!
- Beware!
Where to put?
Over there. No, wait.
No, let's say.
- Are you a long time so you can?
- No, I did recently.
What is it? Cast up!
Attention! Extend the lesson.
A phenomenon Syraezhkin...
... I will explore after
classes.
Hello
- Hello.
- Explore, please.
- Maya Svetlova.
Korolkov.
- Smirnov.
- Very nice.
No, no, well, what you do.
Viktor Ivanovich, you without me
die of hunger.
- Well, that found the double?
- Not yet.
- But the photo was taken in our city.
- Very interesting.
Very interesting. Yes, bad
we are predictors.
Betray himself, it took several
days, and about him not hearing, nor spirit.
- Why are you so happy, eh?
- What do you mean?
Electronic mastered in
our complex world.
And he is not alone, he obviously someone
helps.
He found his comrades
they understand each other.
- Do you understand? I see.
- I understand, let's eat.
You talk as if
conducting an experiment.
I was just worried about the fate
Elika.
I wonder who is with him.
Yes, this guy certainly
knows where his button.
Hurry? What a guy, Hurry?
- Double. I reported to you.
- Find it. Urgently.
We are looking for.
Listen, speak only the truth,
why the stars light up?
You know, this question
short answer is very difficult.
I do not know a lot to explain.
- And I thought, you know everything.
- No. Come on, talk on the road.
Well, electronics, well, friend.
Ah, still did not bring lunch.
Where, then, is what is, eh?
Come on. Now again
compete. In my opinion, good.
I just like it.
In my opinion perfectly. So. Come on.
- Examples. Check. Like it?
- Please.
And the fashionable, and color is good, and
inexpensive. No, really, please?
- It is true that much.
- Scarecrow.
Yes, Serge, has long wanted to ask,
Have you seen a textbook on Latin?
I took him to read.
One of you I have left.
- Is it possible?
- Can. Well, what was interesting?
You bet. You know, it turns
number of words that we say
I have Latin roots. Except
that is a very beautiful language.
- I'm sure he will learn.
- How to learn?
According to your textbook. And you
No other textbooks?
- What?
- Spanish, Greek, Swahili.
- Swahili?
- Of course. It's very interesting.
Hey, you sleepy woodcocks,
open the door of my father.
S., Pope arrived.
- What are you on the chain has closed?
- Someone with a lock dabbled.
Nonsense. Change that.
- As the son doing?
- Do Catkins? All right.
- Before all was lost in the garage.
- And we have a castle will change.
And now, some five, at home
sits, reads books
imagine, Latin carried away.
- Latin? And not buzit?
- Very surprised.
So, you say, some
Five? Listen, there is an idea.
Serega.
You say now an A student?
Do you remember that I promised you?
Come, let's go.
I am going to show you places!
I am in school right.
S., dad one day
come, go, eh?
But it is not pedagogically.
Sorry, I did not come on time,
mother took the store. Fives 6.
He studied English, dulled by
Spanish and Greek.
Grinding!
Daddy!
What are you doing? What are you doing? What are you standing there, as
post, then hung around his neck.
Shake. There.
- How to post? When?
- I was in school should be in school should be.
Also my boyfriend, mood
changes like the weather in autumn,
go, no go.
I do not want to.
What?
- We are ready.
- Please.
- Can I still go to school?
- Well, come on, stay, come on, come on.
- Hey, what happened to him today?
- Unaccustomed.
Sergei, why do not you go? I
also saw how you sat in the car.
Went.
"Rustling much rain
drizzling,
My soul is in trouble and anguish.
I'm a man, in my opinion,
hopeless,
Why am I making plans for the sand?
Thickened over me evil
clouds
And suddenly I was out of work.
Well, why I'm so unlucky?
Well, why suffering - my
inheritance?
Nobody is interested,
To my forever ruined
fate
I got bitten for progress
And this terrible helped itself.
Where to run and where to look for luck?
She hid herself in what region?
I can not sing, I'm afraid now
pay,
And in other matters, sing a song my own. "
Castle changed.
What am I now get lost
what? I am a man or a man?
And here, too.
- Who's there?
- It's me. I, Sergei.
Sergei long home, go home,
boy.
- Who is it?
- A boy of some hooligans.
Yes? Well, now I have his ears Nader.
Right now I catch him,
I'll beat him now.
Sergey, where are you?
Open, I'm the same person.
I have the right to...
- Viktor Ivanovich?
- Yes?
I found a double. This Sergei
Syroezhkin of the forty-fourth school.
- To bring it to you?
- No, no, in any case.
And do not go his eyes,
but then again he would escape.
Viktor Ivanovich, why are you
think that this is electronics?
No, I just do not rule
such a possibility.
That way, you get to know
his class teacher
and learn everything about Syroezhkin. I
sure that the electronics somewhere nearby.
I learned the name of a clone.
Through him, I hope to go to the robot.
- Long fidgeting, Hurry.
- Maybe you would like it?
- I carry out the order, chief.
- Do not be cross. About the button is not forgotten?
She is my dream.
One is.
And here is the second.
Well, what are you staring at?
Syroezhkin - it's me.