Love
Amour
Romance
Amidst rocks...
This autumn...
Oh! For a blossom
Amidst these rocks...
in this autumn...
Oh! For a flower that blossoms...
I have been searching forever...
to find her, if ever
If I find her, ever
If I find...
Use the newspaper.
- Forget newspaper
I saw such a lovely dream.
There she was, back...
The queen of your dreams?
Your dream girl, she?
Talked her into it?
- No
No?
- Missed meeting her, by a hairline
Then sahib, I got to do something.
Next time get her name and address
And tell me
What're today's appointments?
- Board meeting at 11:30
Afterwards, Mr Yamaguchi from Japan...
lunch with him at the club
At four, meeting with
reserve bank governor
Most important, in an hour,
at St Atherton College...
the function where they
give you the scholarship
That's today?
- Yes
Namashkar
(Greetings)
Honourable Minister,
Mr Principal...
guests and students...
at the inauguration of the annual
function of St Atherton College...
I, Pramod Mehra,
in capacity of treasurer...
of Sabharwal Students' Welfare Trust,
request the author of our trust...
Mr Yash Sabharwal, to come on stage
and inaugurate the proceedings
Mr Yash Sabharwal
As you know...
my late father Paramjit Sabharwal
instituted this award 15 years ago...
for able, hardworking graduates
who wish to move up in life...
but those who haven't
the wherewithal
Qualifying candidates will be given
a two-year sponsorship...
for specialisation studies
University of Glasgow in Scotland
alongwith a 300,000 cash prize,
and certificate
I would like to invite on stage
the student who has secured 98%
The presenter of the new project
which has won this scholarship
First class student,
St Atherton College...
Ms Isha Nair
Your certificate...
and cheque
Honourable Mr Minister,
respected Principal Mr Mehra...
staff members and friends...
I wish research in ways of reducing
costs of heart surgeries drastically
To the extent of the cost
of treating a common cold
In our country, no one must die
for lack of money
This scholarship is the stepping stone
to that goal. For which I thank...
the founder of the trust,
the late Mr Sabharwal...
and the present trustee Mr Yash Sabharwal.
Should I succeed, Mr Yash Sabharwal...
and his late father, will share
equal claim to success
At the camera, please
I was sure, our Ishu would bag
the scholarship this year
Mahesh, she's the first from
our family who's going abroad
My friend Inder Bhardwaj wanted
to be her sponsor. But Isha refused
As luck would have it, you're going
to his country, Scotland
My obeisances, Ma.
- Back from office so soon?
Didn't feel like staying on.
- I know why
What?
- You've taken a liking to a girl?
Hassubhai has told me everything
Is she the one?
Yes
Prettier than a barbie doll.
Dream girl
I'm so happy, Yash.
I thought you'd never marry
At last, the Sabharwal lineage
will continue
But why are you so melancholy?
- It's nothing, Ma
Actually, the problem is...
I'm sending away the girl I happen
to like. I gave her a scholarship
Just that? Leave that to me.
I'll make sure you marry Isha Nair
No girl in the world can say
anything but yes to my Yash
She will never find
such a man of honour
Hassubhai, I want Isha's whereabouts.
He must've found out by now, no?
Hassubhai...
- My word
"You've hidden from me..."
"but I've found you"
"Who you are, where you are..."
"I've found in your heart"
"You hear nothing? You speak nothing,
you're as still as a picture"
"My love, you're my life"
"But you don't even know
who I am"
"Is it a stone idol
that I worship?"
"You've hidden from me..."
"but I've found you"
2 "This fair visage,
or is it a Moon?"
"These lovely eyes,
or deep lakes?"
"Oh you don't know,
in those eyes, someone has drowned"
"You've hidden from me..."
"but I've found you"
"Who you are, where you are..."
"I've found in your heart"
"You've hidden from me..."
"but I've found you"
I can't believe this!
You are so rich!
And you come asking for the hand
of a civil servant's daughter?
Who said we're rich?
We're just the groomspeople
And we stand in supplication.
The bridespeople are the rich ones
But I'd like to ask my daughter.
She's planning on going to Scotland...
for two years. For education.
- Education and marriage...
aren't mutually exclusive.
- Mrs Sabharwal is right
We want to give Isha the best.
- But Kanchan, Isha has her opinion
Isha will never disobey us.
We're her parents
What we intend, is for her best.
Just say yes. Don't be stubborn
I didn't have her wrist size
for the bracelets
The design is Italian.
Isha will surely like it
You have sealed my lips.
What can I say?
Address her as a relative,
and try some sweets
For your daughter marriage
is no goal! I want to study
You can continue your education
even after marriage
This is no everyday chance
In this country, can a girl
not write her own destiny?
I'm only proposing to you.
Accepting it or not is upto you
Yes Ishu, you're the one who decides
the future course of your life
How about selecting a wedding invite?
- Yes, I will
Take a look
Who? Isha Nair?
Yes, send her in. To the drawing room.
- Here already? Great tuning!
Go on, Hassubhai...
- Going, going...
Welcome, have a seat
I'd like to discuss something personal.
- Sure. Sit. Would you like something?
I've come to return something
Your mother visited us yesterday...
she left these wedding bracelets.
I don't want to break her heart
So I'm returning them to you
May I know the reason for refusal?
- I don't feel the need to tell you
This is unjust, Isha.
This is not fair
Even the judge cites reasons.
- You cannot use the scholarship...
to force me into a marriage.
- No, you're getting me wrong
For the first time in my life,
I like someone.
Is liking someone a crime?
I told my mother that.
Maybe she acted in haste
I didn't intend hurting you, I promise.
And this proposition...
has nothing to do with the scholarship.
It's your, you've earned it
All I wish to know is why you
negate such a positive approach
So you think marriage is a business
of pluses and minuses?
Can't help it, Isha. I'm a businessman.
I can only talk in pluses and minuses
But the truth of it is, life is
a business. Let me tell you how
But please don't misinterpret me
this time. Isha, as we know...
there's this human bondage that ties
people together
How do man and woman live together?
How do friends go about friendships?
On the basis of what do people in love
build their relationships?
How come, Isha?
And what is this bond?
It's belief, honour. Faith. Trust
Agreement. Contract. Be it on paper
or in hearts, contract is contract
With a contract begins every business.
So tell me, isn't life a business?
For the rich of your ilk,
life might be a business
But for us, life is a struggle.
- You're cross again
Please, just let me go away
I love you truly. Maybe the
way I put it is wrong.
Maybe the timing is wrong
Maybe marriage is farthest from
your mind at this point of time
But if ever, remember.
Yash Sabharwal will await you forever
These bracelets will await you,
and my heart too, Isha
Mr Yash, we differ. Our paths differ.
How can our goals be the same?
Those bracelets will look better
on a businesswoman
Isha made a grave mistake in refusing
you. But you mustn't despair
God might've someone else for you.
Now get ready
He was your father's close friend.
If you aren't present, he might...
stop the engagement altogether.
You know that, don't you?
Yes, Ma.
- Let's go
Yash, my son!
Had you not arrived,
I would've stopped this ceremony
I always wanted you to announce
my daughter's wedding
Sorry for keeping you waiting
Actually, this was my father's
responsibility
But he isn't amongst us anymore.
When I was still a child...
Mr Mehra placed this responsibility
on my shoulders
"Don't leave your memories behind"
"Don't break your promises"
"My darling, I'm crazy about you"
"I was your first love"
"The way you broke my heart..."
"you too will have a heartbreak"
"You too will lose someone"
"Remember this, my traitor"
"Don't leave relationships behind"
"Don't break your promises"
"My darling, I'm crazy about you"
"I was your first love"
"After me..."
"who will you now destroy?"
"Like me, you too will beg someday"
"Remember this, my infidel"
"Don't desert your lover"
"My darling, I'm crazy about you"
"I was your first love"
"Don't leave your memories behind"
"Don't break your promises"
"My darling, I'm crazy about you"
"I was your first love"
What are you doing? Helping me out?
Or taking my Anjali away from me?
Ajay... you?
Didn't have the courage
to face your Daddy
So I had to enlist Gaurav.
He's into modelling. Acting too
No breaks on screen.
So I'm into real-life acts
And you put in a nice act
I don't know how to thank you.
But for you, I'd never have
the girl I have loved
Here's your reward. 100,000.
- No...
Keep it, Gaurav.
I know you need the money
Give your fiancee her ring
Gaurav has become so irresponsible!
Been looking for him all evening
But no news of this hero!
I want to make him India's top model
But he's always missing.
- Maya, maybe I survived the crash...
which killed Gaurav's parents, because
I am to take care of him
But I'm only his uncle,
not his father
Despite all my efforts,
he won't listen to me
Told me, he's off to enact a "role".
- And I've made 100,000 out of it
A hundred thousand?
Cut out these bit roles.
Concentrate on modelling
Be at the studio at ten tomorrow.
I want to take some test shots of you
For a new product from
a multinational
If you're approved,
you get 5 million
5 million?
Tomorrow morning, he isn't going to
the studio. He should be in my office
Consider it done
Your model is here
I know
Tell me, why have you called me here?
What can I do for you?
Lots. If you wish,
you can even change my life
Nice humour. I'm neither manufacturer
nor industrialist, nor an MBA
How may I help you? You have it all.
- All except your finesse
To those whom God has given all,
He has also given certain flaws
You have money, you're sad.
I haven't money, I'm sad
No, I'm not sad. I'm disturbed,
I'm restless
There's a girl.
I'm deeply in love with her
Her name is Isha. Ever since I saw her,
I seem to like nothing else
All this money, this wealth,
is of no use, unless I have Isha
Only one wish remains in life.
To have Isha
Come what may, whatever the price
If you love her so much,
why don't you marry her?
I wanted to
I still want to marry her.
But she has refused
Refused?
But why?
All I know is how to make money
out of money
But in matters of the heart,
I'm a complete imbecile
I want your help
From what I saw in you last night,
uniting the lovers, I was convinced
You are my messiah, you're the one
who can give me the girl I love
I need your help
This isn't my calling.
I'm just a small-time actor
This job isn't tough for you,
believe me
In matters of love and amour,
you are number one
You know what love, amour, romance is?
Most complicated subject
That's why I've called you in.
In this only subject, I'm lacking
Gaurav, make a place for me
in Isha's heart
I'll give you more money
than you will ever make
Go on, sounds nice
You'll forget acting. I'll put you
ahead by 20 years in one stroke
I'm giving you 100 million
What did you say?
100 million?
You're crazy.
- Crazy about Isha
But Gaurav...
Isha mustn't have an inkling
Have nothing to worry.
Six months from now...
she will be in your arms
Call Gaurav again.
Ask his uncle where he is
I'm doing all this for him,
and he doesn't seem to care?
His costume and make-up are ready.
But he's missing
Is this any time to arrive?
You walk in two hours late
on a big assignment like this?
If you want fame and wealth,
learn how to respect time
May I have a say, Maya?
- Sorry? What else have you to say?
You're taking undue advantage
of my friendship
I'm not interested in becoming
a model anymore
I've landed a new assignment.
Here's my resignation letter
Listen...
This one's gone
Yes, gone
But I'll surely get him back
When in Scotland, study hard,
keep calling and don't forget
Inder will receive you
at the airport
Take care. I'll keep calling
Why are you staring at me?
Here for heart research,
University of Glasgow
My name's Tajinder
I'm Lord Bhardwaj's chauffeur
Why were you hassling me?
How did you make me out?
- From your face
From your innocent eyes,
like Ajanta paintings
From your cherry-red lips
When Lord Bhardwaj described you,
I knew Isha would be...
the prettiest girl on this flight.
Only from India comes such beauty
That's why Indian girls always
get crowned Miss world
By the way, I'm Indian too,
though not by birth. By descent
Lord Bhardwaj pays you
for the verbiage too?
Go on. I'll follow you
Now I'm driving you to Lord Bhardwaj's
8000 acre estate
Bless you my child
This is the culture, every
Indian father is so desirous of
Learn something, my son.
This is why I tell you...
when it comes to marriage,
it must be an Indian girl
He's your son?
Have you been pulling her leg?
- He was saying he's your chauffeur
And his mother is Lord Bhardwaj's
personal secretary
The first statement is incorrect.
The second is one hundred percent right
Yes Rohini, my dear?
- Yes. I'm their secretary
Were it not for me,
neither would have stayed at home
His Lordship would've made home
in his financial institutions
And Taj would've stayed at his bank.
Come, let's go home
Right foot in first.
Consider this your home
Proud daughter of a proud father, would
never visit Scotland on my invitation
Thanks to your sponsor, what's his
name? Yash Sabharwal... here you are
Your father Mahesh and I passed
out of Aligarh University together
He wanted to stay on in India.
And I came here
I came here with only 5 pounds in
my pocket. 50 Rupees in those times
. Mahesh says I'm an Englishman. But
you see, after all these years here...
I haven't forgotten my India
Here's the one and only University
of Glasgow. Magnificent, isn't it?
The Gilby-Scott building
is the oldest edifice
And this is Dr Alam.
- Good morning Taj, my son
I've been expecting you
Allow me to commend your fine choice
of a research topic
Students from different countries
are sponsored by the University
You have our full co-operation
in your further studies and research
I'll try my best
The introductory meeting
is in ten minutes. Let's go
Your chauffeur will come
to pick you up in the evening
Lord Bhardwaj called a while ago.
He's quite concerned about you
He was inquiring whether
his ward is feeling lonely
He's a good friend of my father's.
- He said so
Come, let me introduce you
to other Indian students
You won't have any problems here.
Yes Ruby?
No problems
If you don't believe, ask Mini India
The whites have named us that. Used
to sound strange. But now it's cool
Nice. It's an excuse
to maintain ties with India
Consider yourself
a part of Mini India
You're all words!
- Ms Nair, before she was born...
her mother ate crow.
That's why she keeps cawing
I'll fix him in a trice
What are you doing?
Ancient Indian art of healing
Up
Dislocated his shoulder
Daddy's uncle was number one wrestler
in Uttar Pradesh
He taught me this trick.
Always works
Go on
The healing here would've laid him up
in bed for six months
Got to go
Young man, you work here?
Never saw you before
Who are you?
- My name's Gaurav
I'm a handyman here
I've seen you several times.
But why would you notice a janitor?
Nothing like that.
- This is just an accidental meeting
I'll get late for my next job.
If I'm late, I'll lose 5 pounds
Excuse me
Very hard working
Someday he'll reach his goal
Don't you turn her into
one of your Mini Indians
Beware of Mini India gang.
They'll spoil you rotten
You want to finish the year's course
all in day one?
Come on, it's getting late.
Past seven
You're going out to dinner at
Springfield Quay with a prince
Prince of whereabouts, may I ask?
The food was very delicious.
I've had more than my fill
Are you complaining?
Or are you complimenting?
Both
Wait, let me get the car around
You work in the university canteen?
- Yes
You know him?
- Yes, I've seen him at the campus
But what are you doing here?
- Selling flowers. Side business
Working outside the hotel
till I land a job at the hotel
Roses, sir?
Neither it is opportune,
nor is it the occasion
Roses await no occasion
Roses can be given anytime
Round the year, round the clock,
whenever
It delivers a message from the heart.
- Roses? They really say...
what the heart says.
- Choose the right colour
That's all you got to do.
Black rose. It signals hatred, angst
White rose. Peace, patch-up.
To woo the angry one
Ties together
broken heartstrings
Yellow rose. Exchanged between new
friends. The first step in friendship
And the red rose. My favourite.
The colour of the heart
Tells the tale of hearts,
the world over
What does the pink rose say?
I like you a lot
For a special friend
Which rose for you?
Yellow rose
Extra change changes a man.
I only take what I earn
This orange rose to both of you.
From me. It'll bring you good luck
I'm already in luck
This scene reminds me of the old film.
"One Flower, Two Gardeners"
I have a surprise for you
Take this
Keys?
- A small gift for you from the Lord
But I can't accept so expensive a gift.
Taj, you must tell him
The gift, you must accept. Or do you
want me for your permanent chauffeur?
But...
- No buts. How do you like the car?
Go on, you're getting late
for your classes
Clam up
Gaurav, what are you doing?
I don't understand a thing
But tell you what, the choice
of the car is fine
You do exactly as I told you.
I'll run into Isha's car
And you will cause a diversion.
She looks at you
And bang!
You'll die! Your planning is
perfectly dangerous
My boss is crazy about Isha.
And you're crazy about money
Making 100 million isn't easy.
Got to take risks
The car is coming
You?
Is your car all right?
- Forget the car!
You're hurt in the arm!
- I'm fine
No, let me take you
to the hospital. Come on
It was my mistake. You're worrying
for nothing. I'm perfectly all right
Please ask the doctor to let me go.
- You'll be here for a couple of days
You're under observation.
- No, I can't stay in hospital
I have lots of responsibilities.
- Are you married?
Two pre-requisites for a marriage.
First, money to run the household
The other?
- A girl one likes
I'm not as lucky as Taj
It's Taj who's in luck
Please ask the doctor to discharge me.
I have lots to do
Just keep lying. Two days of rest
won't cause harm
You won't understand.
I'm not destined to rest
How will I put together the money
for my cousin's wedding?
My uncle is awaiting surgery
for ulcers
Babli, my aunt's grand-daughter
has to be sent...
to an English medium school
in Gurdaspur
Got to buy two tractors.
- You're providing for so many?
Lord provides
I'm the sole male in my family.
Five daughters
Three cousins on my father's side,
two on my mother's side
Uncle and aunt are aged.
There are household expenses
And so much more to do. I must
see to it that Babli becomes a doctor
Babli?
- Aunt's granddaughter
Very cute. She's ten.
Calls me Ga-Ga
Gaurav! What happened to you?
This is Hassubhai
I'm staying with him
It's time for my practicals. There's
a special seminar on angioplasty
I'll come again
Listen...
you haven't told me your name
My name...
- I know. Gaurav
You're living up to your name
You're a master at acting! How come
you never landed a role in films?
Where are you lost?
How do you save a patient
in this condition?
But weak pulmonary conditions
makes by-pass surgery risky
Gaurav in hospital?
Accident?
How did all this happen?
- It's Gaurav's plan!
No tensions
Make sure my job is done.
- Sure, sure. See you
Taj's friend is Isha. Yesterday, I ran
into her car. It was my mistake
Poor Isha is going through
a lot of trouble for me
Staying in hospital will only
increase my bills
So I've discharged myself
without telling Isha
Will she understand my compulsions?
I don't know
Why won't I understand?
Reading someone's personal diary
isn't a nice habit
First, why did you get discharged?
I'm here in a fighting mood
Fighting in this state will land me
in hospital again
Got to get back to work tomorrow.
- You'll do yourself a favour...
if you rest for a couple of days.
- That's true
Can I tell you something personal?
You and Taj are a cute couple
Taj and I are just friends.
I'm their guest
Then you have another boyfriend?
No
No? There must be someone
who likes you
Nothing like that happening.
- You're lying. I won't accept it
You are so beautiful.
Someone must've come into your life
Can we talk of something else?
- Fine with me...
if you don't want to tell me.
But why these yellow roses, then?
If you take me for a special friend,
you must tell me
There was someone. Yash Sabharwal.
Very rich. He wanted to marry me
But I refused him.
- Why?
Maybe I was expecting someone else
Got to be going. To the library.
Your diary
Not my diary. It's my heart.
And I don't want anyone...
to enter my heart without
as much a knocking
Many secrets hidden in your heart?
If you take me for a special friend...
you got to tell me a few things too.
- As of now, your hands are delicate
Like roses
Does Gaurav ever listen to anyone?
He was talking of a big assignment
in Scotland
Says he'll become a millionaire
in a year
Maybe he's fed up of India,
like the other boys
They think there's lots more money
abroad. But don't you worry
Just give me his address
Memories of motherland
In your company, I still feel
I'm at home
What I tell every fellow countryman...
what I'm telling you Rubina...
and all you Mini Indians. If you marry,
make sure it's a fellow countryman
Who are you telling all this?
They are rotten eggs
Enough! I'm trying
If I find a good Indian, I'll think
about it. Yes Mini India?
Oh I forgot something important
I thought we wouldn't make it alive!
Come inside
Pink rose? For me?
I like you too
Greetings.
- Glory to India
Uncle, this is Gaurav.
This is Hassubhai
Your palace is superb!
I'm very impressed
with your handspun
Is there more to it
than meets the eye?
Where are you from?
- India
And your parents?
- From Punjab
Which city?
- Near Jullunder
District?
Greetings, lady
Come on, tell me. I know every
district in Punjab
District?
Stop interrogating him.
I know him very well
He works at the university canteen.
Very hard-working boy
Come on, Ruby has something important
to tell you. Come
Let's go inside
Isha, I can't. I got to make
a few calls to India
I got to wish folks at home
for Independence Day
I'll see you tomorrow
See you
Got to steer clear of the Lord.
Interrogates like a policeman
Lordship, I wish to make
an important announcement
Mini India and I are going to trek
in Switzerland over the long week-end
I'd like you to allow Isha
to accompany us
She's part of Mini India now
Isha may go
You must accept Taj
as part of Mini India too
What are you getting me into?
- You hear?
He doesn't want to be
part of Mini India.
I'm not interested in going around
with these folks.
Taj, I say you will be part
of Mini India
I'll go to Switzerland with Isha
Stop fiddling with the scooter
and think about your mission
Taj can spoil our party.
In Switzerland...
if he manages to woo Isha,
what will happen to my boss?
Don't teach me my job.
Get me a number ten spanner
Does Gaurav live in this hostel?
- Yes
Can you tell me his room number?
- In my room
Gaurav! Is this any place to live?
What are you into?
What kind of assignment is this?
- My assignment is a solid one
Who's this Gujarati-bhai?
- This is Hassubhai. My agent
Forget him. Let's shake hands
I've got you selected as male model
in a big campaign
The shooting is in Scotland.
And I'm here with my unit
Let me think
If you act in her ad-film,
what happens to my film?
Are you doing a Gujarati film?
I'll do your job, Hassubhai.
Once I'm over with Ms Maya
You're a master when
it comes to girls
I'm willing to do your ad film.
On one condition
No tensions about payment.
It's a two-year contract
You get all of 5 million.
- This isn't about money
Look at this place.
I hate it here
If you want me to shoot,
you must do it in Switzerland
What?
Alongsides the adfilm,
we'll enjoy romancing
In the laps of snowy mountains
in Switzerland...
we'll do official work,
and some things personal too
No! The whole unit is here.
The entire set-up...
will have to be changed.
- Maya, can't you do as much for me?
Then I must go to Switzerland too.
- Why?
My film will stay half-finished
You have your boarding passes?
20 minutes to take off
I think I dropped my boarding pass
at the check-in counter
The flight is about to take off.
But Taj isn't here yet
He'll come
What? I'm on the plane?
What?
Chances like this don't happen
time and again
Mini India is off on
a discovery of Switzerland
The two of you got to discover
your friendship
Coming Sunday at 10:30.
Don't miss the flight to Scotland
Your model Gaurav isn't here yet?
- Relax. Gaurav will be here
This seat is reserved
I don't fancy sitting next to you
I'm taking this flight under duress.
I didn't choose to take it with you
But this seat is ours.
- Yes, ours
Hassubhai, tell him
whose seat this is
Happens to be mine. But our model
has had a stomach upset
So I sold him his ticket
Not to worry! He's taking
the next flight for sure
Taj, where are you? Isha called.
She's with Ruby and Mini India
If she calls again,
give her my number
Maya, where's the model?
- You shifted the location
And your crew is here too.
And your new model...
what's his name? Yes, Gaurav.
There's no sight of him?
If this shoot isn't happening,
we've got ourselves...
a bad name in the ad world.
- You're shooting. Hundred percent
My word. I'm giving you
a far better model. Look
What are you saying? I want
to shoot this ad with Gaurav
Shoot another one with him.
Look. Tall. Handsome
And smooth.
- Smooth?
Meaning, sexy
I'm right, no?
Listen...
right now, I'm very tense.
I want you to model for me
Remember saying that you took
the flight with me under duress?
Will you suffer a little bit more?
For my sake...
Dad always tells me to help damsels
in distress. Specially if she's Indian
But I don't know modelling
I'll teach you all that.
Trouble teaches
Is your name Trouble?
"Love, amour and romance"
"Before you say it..."
"hold your heart"
"Just saying it is
making an epoch"
"Love, amour and romance"
"If I am ever afflicted..."
"what if ever?
But why at all?"
"Anyone who has given his heart,
anyone who has taken this sorrow"
"Ask him not for words,
to describe his long dark nights"
"For he has no sleep in his eyes"
"Love, amour and romance"
"Sweetheart, I'm crazy about you"
"I was your first love"
In this place we meet,
flowers have blossomed in our hearts"
"Who knows?"
"What's happening to us?"
"In the midst of words..."
"between our eyes..."
"somewhere during
this short friendship..."
"sometime during
this brief acquaintance..."
"there's a little mischief'
"Love, amour and romance"
"Before you say it..."
"hold your heart"
"Just saying it is
making an epoch"
My boss is going to be exhilarated
when he sees these photos!
You lost your boarding pass?
Good for Isha that she was
in company of Ruby and Mini India
I sent you to accompany Isha,
and you end up becoming a model?
If you're so careless,
you're going to be left behind
Listen to me.
- Whatever you say...
I'll never forgive this Gaurav!
- My boss will never forgive me
You know, you've lost a big contract!
- Still, you have him
That's if he cares for me!
- Which fool says I don't?
There I lay sick in Scotland
with one name on my lips. Maya
I hope you aren't lying?
- Gaurav lying?
Gaurav is a model of truth!
- Pronounce it right. Model
My word
Isha, today's my birthday.
Today, I'm giving you...
my most precious possession. My diary.
For you to look into my heart...
whenever you wish.
- Gaurav, where are you?
Where can I be
if my heart is with you?
Isha, you are my love,
to me you're everything
So many days we've been together,
yet our hearts aren't sated
Same here
Someone's knocking at the study
Go away. Go
Were you talking to someone?
- Why?
I thought I heard voices.
- I was reading aloud
I forgot to tell you. Your Dad called.
Make sure you call him tomorrow
It was uncle
I should be leaving
I want to give you a birthday gift too
What happened?
I shouldn't be staying any longer
Stealing out of Isha's room like
a thief so late at night? Why?
This silence can't cover up
for your malafide intentions
What brings you here?
I called Gaurav.
He came to return my diary
There's a proper way to enter a house.
Only the bad use the wrong way in
And you better heed my advice.
Stop hovering about Isha
You better find another prey
for your evil intentions
You are getting me wrong.
- And you don't know me either
I don't think it's fair of a man
to hold a gun on another
But if you dare play with
the honour of my family again...
I will have to do the good deed
of putting a bullet in your head
Mr Yash... here in Scotland?
Photographs of your romance with Isha
forced me to come here
Very romantic photos, no?
Must commend Hassubhai's loyalty
But why this childishness?
You should trust me
No on will, after seeing these snaps.
They look real
Are you using the ruse of putting up
an act to have an affair with Isha?
His romance has me all confused
Yes
You speak of trust, but
you don't know what it means
An out-of-job guy like me
is very committed to his job
I'm not in the habit of coveting
what belongs to another
So much about trust.
As far as Isha is concerned...
the game I'm playing with her,
is just an assignment...
a stepping stone
in my life. A job.
Job maybe. For you
For me, it's a matter of
life an death, an obsession
I want to marry Isha.
- Be patient
The fruits of fortitude are sweet.
- Ever since I saw Isha...
I haven't been able to sleep.
Every minute, every second...
every moment, I see her
Anyway, you won't understand
Hey! Look at me, look into my eyes.
Feel what's going on in my heart
Try to understand, listen...
- I'm listening
Till I've taken Isha
for my bride...
this pining, this wait, this obsession
will drive me crazy
Do whatever you have to do, fast!
- As of now, Isha has fallen...
for my act of love.
Now I have to break her heart
After the heartbreak, she will be
in your arms, hundred percent
Don't ask me now, how and when.
Just watch the last act unfold
The last act is always
the most important
Don't forget your 100 million.
- Have nothing to worry
I've told you already.
Love, amour and romance is but a game
If it's a game, come to the endgame
Break Isha's heart
Uncle has told me not to see you.
- Lord Bhardwaj is like a father to you
And every father suspects
his daughter's friends
I want to tell him
everything about you.
Tell no one anything
until I tell you
I'm afraid Gaurav, someone
might take us apart
Everyone thinks, after this ad,
you're going to become a top model
This is going to be
my first and last ad film
Could be my last ad film too.
The entire unit is on location
And Maya is missing.
Gone with that model
Who's that with Maya?
- The unprofessional model
The one whom Maya approved. Gaurav.
- So the flower-boy is into modelling
The client and the agency
have both rejected him
Why did you bring him here?
Whatever happened
was beyond my control
Illness don't knock before coming.
- Gaurav is very upset about the shoot
He's here to apologise to you
Congratulations
Strange turn of coincidences!
You are where I should've been
I'm very happy for you.
- Better if the coincidence...
stays limited to modelling.
I don't fancy taking your place
Do you know each other?
- It's terribly difficult...
forgetting a man like him,
once you've met him
That's why I chose him
Why?
- If the two of you are so close...
why wasn't he in Switzerland with you?
You do have a lot many friends, Gaurav
If it's Isha you're referring to,
she's just a friend
The other night your Dad Lord Bhardwaj
started suspecting me for no reason
The truth my friend, is,
Isha loves only you
She told me herself.
But she's too shy to tell you
What are the two of you whispering?
- Just telling him about you
Well, let me tell everyone
I love her very much, and very soon,
we're getting married
With those words,
you've changed my life
Suddenly, everything starts
looking great
"Before I saw you..."
"I never thought about it"
"There was no one..."
"no one was like you"
"After I saw you, I realised..."
"how beautiful the world is"
"Before I saw you..."
"I never thought about it"
"There was no one..."
"no one was like you"
"After I saw you, I realised..."
"how beautiful the world is"
"What a beautiful world this is"
"The same place"
"The same gardens"
"The same flowers"
"The same seasons"
"So many times I passed by..."
"but where was my heart?"
"After I saw you, I realised..."
"how beautiful the seasons are"
"What a beautiful season this is"
"Life was like a puzzle"
"My path was so lonely"
"I was walking..."
"towards some faraway goal"
"When I saw you, I realised..."
"I don't want to go
anywhere else"
"Now I don't want to go
"Before I saw you..."
"I never thought about it"
"There was no one..."
"No one was like you"
"After I saw you, I realised..."
"How beautiful the world is"
"What a beautiful world this is"
"What a beautiful season this is"
"Now I don't want to go anywhere else"
Stop, wait, listen, Gaurav
Tell me something. Why are you
after both Isha and Maya?
Can't fathom your Casanova act.
- If you could...
you would've been Yash Sabharwal.
Listen, just do what you've been told
This parcel should be in place tomorrow
Rohini darling, here I am.
What gives? It's been years...
since I saw you so excited
Who's the girl?
She's Indian. And someone you like.
- He's talking about Isha
Call up Mr Nair right away.
- You know I'd like to see Isha...
become my daughter-in-law, but...
- Dad, let me clear your doubt
Gaurav and Isha are just friends.
I've found out everything
That maybe so. But it's necessary
to know what lies in Isha's mind
I wish you came into my life,
I wish I could bare my heart to you
But I don't know why I can't express
my personal feelings before you
I'm hesitant. I don't want my words
to hurt you
That's why I keep joking. But behind
this comic facade, there's a heart
And I'm very serious about you
You... here?
I came here to ask you something.
But I saw you sleeping
And I didn't want to wake you.
- What did you want to ask?
Some other time. Now go to bed
What brings you to my bank?
- Good I met you here
I was going to come to your place.
- Anything important?
Yes and no. If you don't mind,
can you pass on this parcel to Isha?
Yes, why not? What's in it?
- Surprise gift from Gaurav
But not for your eyes
You... here?
I didn't know you're at home.
A parcel just arrived for you
From Gaurav. I didn't want to see.
But... sorry
Wait, Taj
Taj, you're my best friend
Will you help me?
You say I'm your best friend
And you still have doubts?
What I'm about to tell you...
I haven't told anyone
If you've seen these photos,
you must've understood
Gaurav and I are very much in love.
You have faith in Gaurav?
I trust him blindly
But he's afraid of Uncle.
He has wrong notions of Gaurav
I want you to dispel your father's
notions. Tell him Gaurav is capable
He's a gentleman. Please Taj.
- Isha I know love is blind. But...
Lord Bhardwaj is never mistaken
when it comes to making out a man
I'm your best friend. I'll help you
always. But bad advice, never
So think before you do anything
Here he comes
Taj... you?
- Where's Gaurav?
Gaurav's address has changed.
He's so amorous of Maya, you will
find him only in Maya's hotel
"Full moon or no moon..."
"it's a moonlit night"
"I'm with you,
you're with me"
"Whatever is or isn't..."
"one thing's for sure"
"So lovely..."
"is our coming together"
"What season is this, my love?"
"No clouds, no monsoons"
"But I feel as if..."
"as if it's raining..."
"when you're with me,
when I'm with you"
"Whatever is or isn't..."
"one thing's for sure"
"So lovely..."
"is our coming together"
"With these fragile bonds of love..."
"let's bind each other"
"Our desires will bear fruit
tonight"
"So lovely..."
"is our coming together"
"Full moon or no moon..."
"it's a moonlit night"
"I'm with you,
you're with me"
"So lovely..."
"is our coming together"
Isha... what are you doing here?
Who's that girl?
- Girl? Which girl?
Who was the girl in bed with you?
- It isn't what you think, Isha
I'm asking you who
you were sleeping with!
She's Maya. An old friend.
She arrived from India yesterday
She was alone. She called me up.
I came over to give her company
She had one too many a drink.
Whatever happened wasn't intended
Shouldn't have happened. Don't know how
I got carried away. Couldn't stop myself
But I have no serious
involvement with her.
I'm in love with you
You're the one I'll marry
How can a modern girl like you
think this way?
Shamelessness, villainy, nudity,
aren't modernisms
Modern is one who is clean at heart.
You turn out to be rotten, Gaurav!
I hate you!
Uncle was right about you.
Your intentions are malafide
I feel like slapping you,
breaking your face
My hatred is enough for you
Out of hatred for me,
you stand to lose, Isha
I took you for a gentleman.
I trusted you. But you deceived me
You're a cheat! A fraud!
Enough of this melodrama Isha!
Enough of playing the loyal woman
You are the one who deceived me.
You gave me that spiel...
about the millionaire Yash Sabharwal
to make me feel jealous, to seduce me?
You took me for what? A naive fool?
You are the fraud
For a multi-millionaire, are you
any match? He wants to marry you?
And listen...
forget all that. Let's shake hands.
Never in your life will you find...
a better partner than me. Come on.
- Right you are
I'll never find a worse scoundrel.
You are the limit of villainy
Good, I found out the truth about you
before introducing you to Daddy
Don't you show me your face again.
For me, you're dead!
I hope you didn't do any mischief
with me last night?
I'll make mischief after marriage.
- That's what I like about you
Maya, I got to go out.
Something urgent. I'll be back soon
You don't cry in here.
In here people find succour
You're right. No point weeping
over such scum
Forget the past. The future
awaits you. Think of that
I'm sure, tomorrow comes
with lots of happiness for you
was feeling so lonely.
Were it not for you...
I don't know what I might've done.
You're so nice, Taj
Will you drop me to the university?
Dr Alam has called me
I happen to be your chauffeur.
- Not chauffeur. My closest friend
You wanted to see me?
- Yes, I've been expecting you
Splendid news for you
The chairman of the largest heart
hospital coming up in India, wishes...
to meet you. He wants you to j5215oin his
hospital after completing your studies
Don't you refuse. Be there at
the Town Hall tomorrow morning
You? The chairman?
Yes
Dr Alam might've told you about
my new hospital project
Yes, you are entrusting me with a huge
responsibility. Do you feel...
you've chosen the right candidate?
- I've only chosen, Isha
The decision is upto you
I want you to succeed
I wish no one dies of heart disease.
Such a dreadful disease
Whatever the disease
it's always dreadful
Yes, but no one ought to get
heart disease. It's fatal
After your research, would you like to
join the Sabharwal Cardiac Hospital?
No conditions, to tags
tied to this offer
I accept
One small request. On your list
of friends, might there be...
a little place for a little man?
- The space isn't there
But I'll try to make place.
I might manage something
Can we begin trying
with a get-together?
Would you like to have dinner
with me tomorrow evening?
I'll pay my bill.
- With all your heart?
What? Bill.
- I was just joking. I'm sorry
But what's this about
splitting bills between friends?
I heard from someone,
life is a business
Isha isn't back yet from the library?
Working for the final exams I guess?
She came back from the library
and she went out somewhere
Went out? Where?
- Off for an important meeting...
with her sponsor Yash Sabharwal.
Dr Alam was saying that...
Mr Sabharwal wants her to get involved
with some important project
Isha is a very mature girl, son.
- I know. But...
You know nothing. You don't know
what lies in a woman's heart
Dad, I'm here to discuss just that
Your suspicions about Gaurav
turned out to be completely true
Isha knows the truth about him.
There's nothing between them now
If Isha has a close friend now,
it's your darling Taj
Then I should be calling Mahesh
right away
Kanchan and I are coming. Certainly
Inder asks for Isha's hand
for his son
He has invited us to Scotland
What's on your mind?
Would you like a drink?
But may I celebrate?
You're right. One must never
jump to conclusions about...
a man's character till such time
that one knows him intimately
I spoke rashly the other day.
But you display no bitterness
Someone else would've
taken it to heart
To tell you the truth,
I did find your words bitter
But after you left, I gave it
another thought
And my regard for you increased.
I thought it was vanity
But it was actually
your self-confidence
Your philosophy...
your confidence...
your principles...
are your wealth
Enough Mr Yash! You're praising me
to the skies!
Isha, you are as pretty as an angel.
And angels belong in the Heavens
What happened?
- Nothing. Maya, let's go elsewhere
Why, what's wrong with this place?
Getting a reservation was tough
Strange is the tale of our friendship.
Others might not even believe it
Why?
- Some people imagine...
it's impossible for rich men
like you...
wanting to marry a simple staid
middle class girl like me
Life is stranger than fiction, Isha.
- I know
But some fools cannot understand that.
Anyway, I think I should accept...
your proposition.
- Which proposition?
Let's make memorable
our first meeting
Yes, but you just said...
Sure, but you just...
But...
Turn around and take a look
They look like such a romantic couple
Jealous?
Let's dance too
You've cut your hand!
You're bleeding
Relax, I'll be back
It's past eleven!
I got to make an urgent call
Be seated. I'll be back
Gaurav, how did you cut your hand?
The girl who wouldn't talk to me
comes straight into my arms
You're really the grandmaster
of love, amour and romance
Do you know Gaurav?
What Gaurav?
The boy who was sitting here with me.
He saw you and your partner
And God knows what came over him
Listen Miss, I don't socialise
with wastrels
Wastrel? What do you mean?
- Bedmates in your parlance...
might be modernistic. But in
my society, they're called wastrels
What are you doing here, Gaurav?
If Isha comes to suspect...
that we know each other,
it will all come to a zero
Collect your money tomorrow,
and return to Bombay immediately
What rot are you talking?
Are you in your senses?
Maya, what happened?
- She's drunk. And she's blabbering
I told you, the ambience here
is no good
What happened?
- I shouldn't have taken the drink.
I just want to go home
Let me give them a check.
I'll be back
Gaurav, here's your grand reward.
A check of 1.45 million pounds
100 million Rupees.
- Tax free. What are you thinking?
Wondering.
- What?
How many zeros in 100 million?
We have a new client. He wants to
deposit a 1.45 million pound cheque
Drawn on the account
of Sabharwal Industries
Sabharwal Industries?
- Yes
Owned by Yash Sabharwal?
Have you cross checked?
Sabharwal Industries has instructed
us to clear the cheque immediately
And today, big businessman
Like other Indians here, you too
have become very successful
Are you being sarcastic?
- Give me a tip. What business
begets an ordinary man millions
of pounds in so short a while?
You must've sold something precious
What did you sell?
Tell me, what did you sell?
My soul
"I want to give you
a birthday gift too"
"I was unfaithful"
"I was uncaring"
"I broke your heart"
"Broke mine too"
"You don't know how..."
"in memories of you..."
"I shall suffer in silence..."
"all my life"
"Every rule of love..."
"I have flouted"
"All my promises I have sold"
"Every vow I compromised"
"What love, amour, romance is..."
"now I know"
"But how will I get back
time that is lost?"
"Time that is lost"
Dad, Gaurav came to our bank today,
with a 1.45 million pound cheque
A 1.45 million pound cheque?
Where did Gaurav land so much money?
Mr Yash Sabharwal gave it to him
The one who gave Isha
that scholarship?
On one hand, he hands out scholarships.
On the other hand...
100 million Rupees
to a wastrel like Gaurav?
But why? I don't get this
Get Isha to invite Mr Yash Sabharwal
over for dinner
Yes, I'm coming over to Lord Bhardwaj's
for dinner. Can I ever refuse you?
See you at eight this evening
On the other hand, we're thankful.
Were it not for your generosity...
Isha might never have been in Scotland.
- Were it not for Isha in Scotland...
you might not have come to our house.
Somewhere or the other
every episode is connected.
In a chain of events,
one follows the other
Right Isha?
- Yes?
Which chain of events leads you here?
- Must be business, Dad. Yesterday...
a new client at the bank was cashing a
1.45 million pound cheque drawn by you
The 100 million Rupees? We transact
millions worth of businesses everyday
Generally I don't discuss business
in public
Well then, let's have
something personal
In the mood of finding out about
my personal and private affairs?
Maybe you don't know.
Alongwith the scholarship...
I gave Isha my heart too
Yash, you are embarrassing me
But I got to say it today
Why have the two of you
fallen silent?
Lord Bhardwaj, you're like
a father to Isha
Allow me to seek from you
Isha's hand in marriage
I did it once before too.
Only Isha can answer that
Isha knows already
that I await her
We'll keep seeing each other
from now on
Isha, you don't know this.
But it was Yash Sabharwal...
who gave Gaurav
a 100 million cheque
Your love story is
ready to roll now!
What are you doing here in Scotland?
I'm here to return your cheque.
- What? You want more money?
No. I was under the impression
that money makes a man. I was wrong
I don't want to step on
someone's heart to climb
Now I see
Now I know why you got so worked up
seeing Isha dancing with me
Have you fallen in love
with Isha for real?
Not to get tense, Mr Yash. I'm not
standing between you and Isha
I'm sure you will make her happy.
- If that is what you think...
then keep this money.
You have earned it
Bravo!
What a trade-off!
Little did I know that there's
a market for love too
A market where men sell and buy
a woman's love
Gaurav! What do you take me for?
A plastic barbie to play with...
till I take your fancy, whereafter
to be sold to someone else?
And Mr Yash! Have you so much money
that you can buy someone's love?
Want to buy a lover for 100 million?
No Isha, no!
Whatever I did was for the sake
of your love. I love you dearly
Before the sacred fires, I want to
take you as my wife, as my bride
Relationship between man and wife
is based on respect
What scant respect I had for you,
you have lost
When I do not respect you, how
can I accept you as my husband?
Isha, I want you with all my heart.
I had no intention of hurting you
In my obsession with you,
I lost my head. That's it
Mr Yash, not money.
It takes a heart to win a heart.
But you won't understand
Because for you,
life is a business.
But love is not a business
But she refused Yash Sabharwal
long ago
What a scene Isha is creating!
- Enough of her whims
Let her come. Let me talk to her.
- Don't force her to marry Taj
Daddy! Mummy! This is so sudden!
No one even told me...
You've been springing surprises
on everyone. So we thought...
why not spring a surprise on you?
What have you done to yourself?
Why do you look depressed?
Have you been crying?
Please take me home with you
I don't want to study anymore.
I just want to go back
Just take me to India
Take me home, Ma!
- Everything's going to work out fine
Have you had your whim now?
And what will you do back in India?
You know why destiny brought you
to Scotland?
For you to meet Taj
You will never find such love again.
We want the 25-year friendship...
between your father and Lord Bhardwaj
to culminate into a relationship
Our surprise for you is
your betrothal to Taj
But the final decision
must be yours, Isha
Isha, ever since you have claimed
your right as our daughter
We gave you your every whim.
Today, may I claim my
right as a father?
Daddy... Uncle...
You've seen more of life
than I have.
Whatever you decide will be
in the best of my interests
Your decision will be mine
What an ad film!
Will someone even praise me?
I'll be all praise for you.
You've made a wonderful ad film
You, here?
When did you come?
- I got to talk to you, Maya
Let's go to the cafe.
- No Maya
I want to tell you something
in front of everyone
Personal matters in public?
I'm returning to India
on important business
What's this sudden business?
Stay back for a day
Day after tomorrow,
we'll travel together
We aren't travelling together, Maya.
My path is different
Different path?
What are you saying.
Don't you rile me
with these fallacies
Falsehood was what I've been
telling you all along
But today, I'll tell the truth
before everyone
And the truth is,
I never loved you
I came to Scotland to woo Isha,
on Yash Sabharwal's behalf
What I did with you the other night
was part of the assignment
In my lust for 100 million,
I betrayed Isha
I betrayed you,
I betrayed myself
I can understand what you
might be going through, Maya
For I'm heartbroken too.
I've lost the one I was in love with
But Maya...
I don't want to lose your friendship.
Forgive me, please
Asking me to forgive you
is making another mistake
You don't ask friends
to forgive you
Friends are forgiving, always
The world over, it's custom that
the engagement is held...
by the bridespeople.
And so it shall be
That will take us to India.
- Dr Alam, you place us in a quandary
And I have a solution. Mr Nair,
Isha is like a daughter to me
Consider my house your home,
and come with me
But...
- But Dr Alam...
No excuse will do. Taj and Isha
are getting engaged at my place
Come on, this brooks no more delay
Congratulations, son. The engagement
has been fixed for the 25th
A lady has come to meet you
We bump in again?
Remember how we bumped into each other
for the first time?
But maybe this is our last meeting.
- Last meeting?
Tomorrow I'm returning to India
Before leaving, I wanted to thank you.
You've helped me a lot
You must attend my engagement
before returning
But...
- Don't refuse
I want to share my happiness
with everyone
Okay, I'll come
Why have you brought her here, Ruby?
- I don't know what, but she has...
something important to tell you
If you don't listen to me today,
you'll cry for the rest of your life
Whatever you say that night
was a sham
There's nothing illicit between
Gaurav and myself
It was for Yash Sabharwal's sake
that he feigned to be in love with us
He wanted to mould you
in favour of Yash
But in the course of the game,
he fell in love with you, for real
I'm just a friend
So much of all this happened,
and you told me not a thing, Isha?
He regrets deeply what he has done.
Forgive him
Now it's too late, Maya.
- No Isha! Let me tell Taj...
all about it. He's a friend of mine.
I'll make him see reason
You'll do nothing of the sort, Ruby!
Will you be able to live
without Gaurav?
Let me be
I've made more than enough
of a spectacle of myself
I don't want to make a spectacle
of my parents and Uncle
Maya, will you do me one more favour?
Gaurav, I just met Isha.
She sends you a message
Gaurav, we dreamt too.
But dreams never come true
Tomorrow, I'm getting engaged to Taj.
The beginning of a new life
A new relationship
Before embarking on
the new relationship...
for one last time, I wish to see you
to my heart's content
Isha's engagement to Taj
is confirmed. Forget Isha
I cannot forget Isha!
And I won't let this engagement happen
No use being adamant anymore
I'm here to invite you to
Taj's engagement with Isha
Happening at my place.
Make sure you come
Lots of important folks are coming.
You get to meet all kinds of folks...
at parties like these. Look at us.
This is how we meet
But I won't be able to attend
this engagement
You must! You've done so much for
Isha. You gave her the scholarship
You're getting her involved
in the new project
You must attend her engagement.
No excuses
If you won't come, I'll barge in here
to pick you up. You'll come, won't you?
Don't badger me. I don't want to attend.
- I know why you don't want to attend
Because you couldn't win Isha's love?
Mr Yash, it was because of you...
that Isha and Gaurav are heartbroken.
Lovers have been torn apart forever
Because of you! In the least,
you can attend Isha's engagement?
Won't make any difference to you,
if you don't attend.
But of you do some
miracle might happen.
You're the one who started
this game, Mr Yash
And you're the one who
can put an end to it.
Sorry if I spoke too much
Of tale's end,
I know nothing.
But this engagement,
I must bring to an end
But he's adamant! He won't listen!
Please come over immediately
Else, everything will go awry.
- Very well, Hassubhai
I'm taking the morning flight
to Scotland
What happened?
You're looking beautiful
except for tears in those eyes
Let me take your tears, Isha
I can't share them with anyone.
I'm tied to my tears
What a thing to say. Today's a day for
celebrations. On a day like this...
you don't talk of these things. I don't
want to see tears in your eyes, ever
I want you to have every happiness
in the world
Let sorrow's shadow stay
miles from you
Gaurav, is this where
our story ends?
Were we to have been together
only for so long?
Silly. The One sitting up there...
takes our lives through
shadow and sunshine
But whatever He writes
is always for the best.
Only, we don't understand
I was just a fellow-traveller, for a
while; not your companion for life
You're lying!
All these are lies!
Look at these pictures!
Tell me, are they not true?
- All this was just a sham, Isha
You can get away lying to me, Gaurav.
But you can't lie to yourself
How long will you deny loving me
as much as I love you?
You must purge your mind,
your heart of me, Isha
Because I was your past.
Taj is your dawning day.
Don't be unjust to him
I won't live if I lose you!
Our story is over, Isha
As of now, we're strangers
I don't want to get engaged, Gaurav!
Please! Please save me!
You have a big
responsibility to save.
Today, you have to save...
your father's prestige,
Lord Bhardwaj's prestige
You must save Taj's prestige.
I have fallen from grace
I couldn't save myself.
How can I save you?
If I instigate you, I will be
the worse off for my ill-repute
And this I'm not going
to let happen. Because...
I brought you and everyone else
to much anguish
But I'm certain that
you will save me
You're right, Gaurav
The moment Taj gives me the ring,
I'll be distanced from you, forever
We will live on,
but never shall meet
I'm going to belong
to someone else
Forever
Now we've really become strangers
Go away now
Else, my resolve will weaken again
Let the pictures be.
- Don't be silly, Isha
I shall never see you again
Gaurav! Have pity on me!
Don't do this!
What are you doing here?
I advised you to stay away
from my daughter-in-law
Isha! What is this man doing here?
He...
What's this gesticulating about?
What are you hiding?
Why are you crying?
Stop
Gaurav! I say stop!
You shall not leave here
before answering Dad
Step out of my way, Taj. Please
What are you hiding?
Tell me what you are hiding!
I beg of you!
Let me go.
For all of us,
it will be more honourable
Honour! A cheapskate talking about
honour! I'm going to expose you today!
Tell me!
What game have you
been playing with Isha?
Please let me leave.
- I'm not sparing you, not today!
Your eyes, your face says,
you are here with evil intent!
He made her cry!
Just tell me straight
what you're hiding
Show me!
What's this?
This is the honour you speak of?
He's in the profession of seducing
innocent girls and blackmailing them
He's a pimp of sorts
You think you can scare Isha
by showing these photos
You think you can blackmail her,
scare her into giving in to you?
Don't you harbour this misconception.
And get this clear
Even if you have these photos
splashed across newspapers...
it won't make any difference
to me and my son
We know what kind of a girl Isha is.
She is the honour of my family
And you want to play with
my family honour?
I'm not sparing you today.
I'll teach you a lesson
Never again will you ruin
an innocent girl's family
100 million isn't enough for you?
How much more do you want? You scum!
What are you doing Lord Bhardwaj?
How much will you give him? How much?
He has refused all my wealth,
in this age of rupees and dollars
The man who refuses so much,
is either a madman
Or else, a true lover.
- He's no lover
He's a blackmailer, Mr Sabharwal.
- No knowing what sin...
He wanted to lead Isha into
using those romantic photos
No, Dr Alam
Not Gaurav, I am the sinner.
His sin is merely...
being a poor, needy, honest boy.
If punishment is what
you want punish me.
If it's someone you want
to shoot, shoot me
I used them
I tried to lure Gaurav with
a hundred million...
into selling Isha's love
I was convinced that money
is the greatest power on earth
I thought Yash Sabharwal could buy
anything for money. But I was mistaken
The two of them have made me realise
that more powerful than money...
is love, amour, romance
That, which they possess
and as long as they have this power,
no one can set them apart. No one can
Lord Bhardwaj, open your eyes,
feel the love between Gaurav and Isha
This isn't an engagement.
This is a compromise, Lord Bhardwaj
No one has compelled Isha.
- She gave her free consent
Ask Isha
My child, break your silence now.
- In front of everyone...
just clarify whether you're
getting engaged of your own volition
Isha, those in love care for none.
Speak your heart. Tell everyone
Don't be afraid.
Isha, my personal experience...
tells me that when you cannot
express your personal feelings...
if you hide things in your heart
you always stand to lose something
Make known what lies in your heart.
- Before you say anything...
heed what I have said
Everyone's waiting.
- Isha, reply him
Isha, this is no day to be silent
What am I to say?
What reply am I to give him?
From all sides, I'm in a fix
I can never live with having broken
your hearts, yours, Daddy's, Taj's
I accept this engagement
No one has coerced me
It's my decision
Isha, my child! Don't cry
Did you hear?
Have you got your reply?
Don't worry, Inder. Isha will enter
your family as a bride
This is the problem with daughters
in our country
Before their parents, they can't
speak their hearts
This confusion must've destroyed
countless homes
Life's most important decision
isn't taken in tears
And don't worry about Taj.
He's like me. Strong at heart
Wait Gaurav
The red rose, the colour of the heart.
Tells tales of hearts, the world over
Go and give it to Isha
Before I accept the red rose,
I have a condition
First, you get engaged.
- For which, a girl is needed
That too, pure Indian.
- If Taj permits me...
I can propose a very nice,
very pretty Indian girl
Are you into the matchmaking business?
I was, from the very beginning
I know this
You'll never find a better bride.
And there was nothing between us
It was just a sham
Say yes, Taj. Else you'll get
left behind
Yash, why are you leaving in a huff?
Nice of you to have accepted
my invitation and come home
Because of you, all hearts
have been united
And now, you're leaving all alone?
Ma... you?
I've come to know everything, son
He has always been a loner. And not
a clue to who he's destined for
Or whom he is waiting for.
- I too am waiting for a lone Indian
I too get a feeling that she's
actually the queen of his dreams
This journey isn't a compulsion.
It should be a journey of heart
Isha, this isn't melodrama.
This is real
What's it?
Pink rose means...
Rohini, get three rings!
Three pairs are waiting
Can someone tell me
which colour of rose...
do you give when you fall in love
after getting married?
After the wedding, the wife
can't be wooed with one rose
You got to give her
a whole bouquet...
of love, amour and romance