Thakur Jaswant Singh Sir,
Greetings
Greetings Mr,Totaram,
What's the news?
I have brought the marriage
invitation of Thakur Ratansingh,-
Son of Thakur Raghuvir Singh,
in the name of god
It's a matter of
great happiness
Greetings Junior Thakur
Greetings, Greetings
Shall I say something
Senior Thakur
Tell me
You sent your younger brother
Mr.Dhanraj to town
You got him educated,
got him married -
He aIso got a chlld
in the name of god
You got your younger sister
parvati aIso married-
She aIso got a chlld in
the name of god
Now, You aIso get married
in the name of god
Mr.Totaram you aIready
know
I have got a younger
Sister Madhumathi
Let her aIso get
married -
Then, I wllI aIso get married
in the name of god
PIease take it
Thanks
Daughter-in-Iaw,
you aIso...
Oh god, Tell me how is
your DeIhi?
It's aIright brother
And how is your cIothes
business?
It's doing very well by
the grace of god
I suggest that you Ieave
this farming,-
And join me in the cIoth business
in DeIhi
There is pIenty of money
there
No, brother. We don't want to
go to DeIhi,
We llke to llve here
Don't worry Madhu, We are not
going anywhere
Tell me, When are you coming
for hunting?
Shall we go tomorrow
DefiniteIy
Brother,Tomorrow we have to
go to the marriage
Tomorrow Raghubir Singh's
younger son -
Ratan Singh is getting
married
Just see what time are
we called?
PIease give me this -
Mother, You onIy decide
Mr.Thakur now you
decide
Yes, Saraswathi, you say
I llke these two goId
ones and-
These, three studded
ones
Randhir, My son,
Isn't it?
Yes, mother, they are fine
What do you say KamaIa?
I llke them but, brother-in-Iaw
shouId aIso...
Sister-in-Iaw, I llke
this onIy
Keep quiet, In our famlly groom
and the bride -
Are not consuIted in
any matter
I see...
These peopIe got you married to me
without consuItation
Then what eIse?
Stop joking...
Once jeweIs are finallzed, We
have to decide about cIothes aIso
Son Ratan
Outside in the jeep bundIes
of cIoth are kept, go and get them
Take them
Madhu!
You...What are you
doing here?
I have come to congratuIate for
the marriage
But, Listen...
I am not going anywhere -
Ratan, I want your repIy
I wllI repIy to you,but you
come this side
Madhu, What is happening here
against my wishes?
Knowing fully well that
I Iove you
My peopIe fixed this marriage
forcibIy
But you wllI have to refuse
this marriage
But Madhu they are not going to
llsten to me at all
Even after knowing, that I am
carrying your baby
I agree that I have put you
in a great fix
But there was no other way
except this
There is onIy one way
I consume poison & die so that
you can get married peacefully
No, madhu, no, I have thought
of a way out
What?
I have heard that your sister
& uncIe have come from DeIhi
Yes -You to go DeIhi
with them
I have a good friend
there -
He wllI take you to
a good doctor
you don't have to
worry at all
Go in the morning and return
in the evening
He wllI do the
abortion
And here is some money
for your expenses
I know you are a
coward -
But you are so mean, I have come
to know onIy today
Keep quiet, keep quiet,
Don't cry
Don't do anything
rash-
So that situation doesn't
worsen further
Brother,What's Ieft
there to worsen
After destroying the llfe of
our Madhu
That rascaI is going to
get married
I wllI stop this
marriage
Listen, I wllI go and meet
Ratan's father,Thakur Raghuvir Singh
I am very sure that when he comes
to know the facts-
He wllI force Ratan
to fuIfll his promise
Answer Ratan
The accusation that Thakur
Jaswant Singh has put on you
Is it true? Or
is it a lle?
Father, all are lles
Look, Ratan
I have come here neither to
quarreI nor to scoId you
Human beings make mistakes,
You have aIso committed etc
But now it is your duty that you
accept your mistake
And keep the promise you
made to Madhumathi...
What's the mistake &
What's the promise?
By concocting these stories
you want to defame me
Concocting stories!?
Then, is it not true that Madhumathi
is pregnant?
She might be
She might be but I am not
responsibIe for it
You are a llar, you are
a crook.
And you are mean & wretched
person of the highest order
Dhanraj
Thakur Jaswant Singh
Ask Dhanraj to shut up otherwise
there wllI be bIoodshed here
There wllI be bIoodshed
Randhir Singh
My sister's honour is ruined
& I remain a sllent spectator -
I wllI exterminate whoIe
of your cIan
Dhanraj keep quiet
Let me taIk
Then you taIk
There is no use striking your
head against a stone
Mr.Randhir Singh
Knowing well, its a question of the
prestige of our famlly -
I Ieave the decision
to you
Thakur Jaswant Singh, I fully
sympathise with you-
More than that I cannot
say anything
Remember Thakur
The end resuIt of this wllI
not be good
Shall I say something?
Go ahead
Whatever Thakur Jaswant Singh
had said
It's all true
What is true?
This evening Madhumathi had come to
meet Ratan here-
Hiding behind the window I
heard their entire conversation-
They used to meet steaIthy,
and she-
Is going to be the mother of
Ratan's chlld
PIease llsten to me. For god's
sake stop this marriage
And make Ratan to agree to
marry Madhumathi
Keep quiet,absoIuteIy
keep quiet-
Before marriage the girI who has
Iost her honour
She is not worthy of becoming the
daughter-in-Iaw of this famlly
And llsten very
carefully-
You have mentioned
this today-
But here after if anybody taIks
even a word about it-
I wllI be very harsh
on him
Randhir, Son you make your
father see to reason
Dhanraj, Nothing wllI go
out of confrontation
There wllI be a
big scandaI
We'll Ioose our prestige in the
entire vllIage-
Then by keeping quiet wllI this
thing lle dormant-
From tomorrow itseIf this news
wllI spread llke wlld fire
That we wllI be constrained even
to step out of this house
That's why I have decided to
Ieave this vllIage
We wllI sell our house, Sell
the entire property -
And go to DeIhi
And what shall we
do there?
Whatever we do,
We may even starve
But we won't be ridicuIed
by peopIe
A respectabIe person can bear all
the hardships of the worId-
But cannot llve
shameIessIy
Dhanraj whatever I am
going to do-
I am very sad about it
I am sure
That kishan wllI give us a good
price for our house & fieIds
Okay, I'll return
by the evening
Brother
Parvati, What happened?
Ratan Singh
Ratan singh this is the corpse of my
sister Madhumathi
According to your promises -
She shouId have become your
bride today-
But today her dead body wllI
be carried-
Dead body wllI be carried
Ratan Singh,but not one
Stop -
But two
Wait Dhanraj
Court awarded llfe imprisonment
to Thakur Dhanraj Singh for murder
Surrounded by the high walls
of the jall
A narrow cell became the abode
of Dhanraj Singh
Jaswant Singh soId his house &
the entire property-
Left the vllIage Dhanakpur for good
& went away to DeIhi
And in the house
of Bhagwandas-
He started a new llfe with
his entire famlly-
In partnership with Bhagwandas
he started cIoth business-
And became a very successfuI trader
in no time
He had onIy one aim
in his llfe-
To give good education to
the son of Dhanraj
And llke this the
time passed
Days became months & months
became years
And then that day came
For your good conducts, Govt. has
decided to reIease you 6 months earIy
My dear father, You wllI be
pIeased to know
That now our exams
are over
On 10th Aprll, in our college
there is a farewell party
In this party, aIong with my
friends I am -
Presenting a musicaI
programme
UncIe amd others in the famlly
are not interested in music
Had you been here
I wouId have definiteIy
invited
But its my bad Iuck that you
are so far away
But that day is not far
when you'll be amongst us-
And I am impatientIy waiting
for that day
Your son, Raj
Friends, first I want to thank
the 2nd year students
Who, for the finaI
year students,
Have given this grand
party today
For us this is our Iast day
in the college
And I know
That for the forthcoming llfe
everyone has thought of something
But I haven't thought of
anything for me
And today
Today I am thinking of onIy one
thing repeatedIy
What?
Today the programme was
very enjoyabIe
What's the programme
in the holldays
We are stuck up badIy
- Why
UncIe has put us
in the office
Very unfortunate
Why don't you come for hunting
with us
What Shyam?
Shall we go?
DefiniteIy
Programme was
very good
UncIe,Iook,who has come
Dhanraj brother
Dhanraj brother, Dhanraj brother
See Dhanraj brother
Daughter-in-Iaw, serve some rice
to Dhanraj
Thank you
But tell me -
How did you come to know that
their function is today
Brother as soon as I got
the Ietter from Raj...
Enough, Enough
You'll make me eat everything in
one day onIy
I have served you very llttIe
eat it
WonderfuI
Brother Jaswant, eating is very
enjoyabIe today
Dhanraj brother
When you were in jall...-
Bhagwandas!
I have a request-
Jall and whatever this famlly
has gone through-
ShouId never be mentioned
in this house-
Brother tell me
How is our business
running?
By the grace of god,
its very good
Now you have come
Raj and Shyam
are with us
We wllI improve it
much more
It's definiteIy the mischief
of that rascaI Randhir Singh
I'll go to Dhanakpur
tomorrow itseIf
Brother, neither you nor brother
Jaswant need go to Dhanakpur
Raj & Shyam can go and
do this job
And aIso nobody recognizes
them there
Yes that shouId be aIright
Raj,llsten son
Tomorrow morning
you and Shyam-
WllI have to go to
Dhanakpur VllIage
Dhanakpur - yes
There meet Iawyer BiharllaI and
give an appllcation in the court
Okay
And llsten
As soon you finish your work
return immediateIy-
Don't roam there
unnecessarlly
Okay
Listen son - yes
I have flled your appllcation in
the court immediateIy
But tell Thakur
Jaswant Singh-
That the case won't
be decided soon
Won't be decided soon?
- No
Appllcation is against
Randhir Singh
He wllI aIso act soon
What wllI he do soon?
It's difficuIt to tell
you immediateIy
Listen. LegaI matters are not
resoIved immediateIy
As the proceeding proceeds,-
I wllI inform Mr.Jaswant Singh
immediateIy about them
ImmediateIy - definiteIy
Listen, Randhir Singh is a very
dangerous person
The news of your arrivaI can
reach him immediateIy - yes
That's why it
wllI be better-
That both of you go away
immediateIy
Okay, We'll go away
I want to go to a pIace...
immediateIy
What a strange man? Come Iet's
go from here
Shall we go?
In my youth I was sitting
on a horse-
And the horse is running
Horse fell down. I am down and
the horse is above me
What happened? Why did you
stop the bike
This is probabIy the mansion of
Thakur Raghuvir Singh isn't it ?
May be
Come Iet's ask that person
come
And then...
UncIe greetings
Greetings
Whose mansion is this?
This is Thakur Raghuvir Singh's
mansion in the name of god
But he is no more allve
His son's are there.
Thakur Randhir Singh
Brother, the entire famlly has
shifted to DeIhi
He comes once in a year to settIe
the accounts of farming-
In the name of god
She is Rashmi, daughter of
Thakur Randhir Singh
The great activity that you are
seeing in the mansion today-
Is because its her
birthday today
Come come
Tell me grandma.
This is the llfe llne
One shouId not read the paIm
on the birthday
But one thing is
certain
Very soon, someone is going
to enter your llfe
ProbabIy tonight
From Haripur, Ietter has come that
Kunwar Pratap Singh wllI not be coming -
But his son, Roop Singh
wllI be coming!
You have seem him
isn't it?
I had seen him, When he
was this much...
Even I had seen him
when he was this much
Now, he must be
a young man
Brother!
Yes
We cannot have a better match
for Rashmi than this
It's true
As soon as Roop Singh comes
bring him to me
BaIwant, come
Come!
Let's go
We'll go inside and have
a Iook around
What? Have you gone mad?
If Randhir Singh comes to know
about it,He'll skin us
In this crowd nobody wllI
bother about us.come
Come, Come, Hey! Mr.Gaurishankar
come,WeIcome
Greetings!.. Greetings!
WonderfuI!..WonderfuI!..WonderfuI!
Great, wonderfuI,
Great,wonderfuI!
This year, did you have
a good harvest?
Hey! Mr.Randhir Singh,I greet
you on your daughter's birthday
Thank you!
Hey! Shyam Iook there! He is
Thakur Randhir Singh
May be, but friend, Iet's
get away from here
Stop, my friend!
Are you coming? Or shall I
go aIone?
Let's go
Where are you sneaking
away, my son?
What?
Where?... Where?
What did you think? Nobody
wllI recognize you?
Why?
We Thakurs, have a arrow
sharp vision-
That can recognize the friends
and aIso the foes
Isn't it? - What?
Confused isn't it?
- Yes
I had seen you when you
were this big
But, I recognized you
as soon as I saw you -
That you are definiteIy Roop Singh
son of Kunwar Pratap Singh
Ask me...how?
How?
After seeing the 'R' symboI
on your coat
'R' means Roop Singh!
Come with me
No, you proceed...I...
Come with me...Come on...
Brother! Here is your
Roop Singh
He was standing in
that corner
Recognized me?
Yes, greetings!
OnIy greetings wllI not do
you have to hug me
Mr.Man Singh, Come here
meet him
He is Roop Singh, Son of
Kunwar Pratap Singh
Greetings!
Is he Roop Singh?!
Yes, he is Roop Singh
I don't know whether
to belleve my eyes or not?
But I feeI something strange
about your appearance
Appearance
Yes
Last year, When I met you in Haripur
You had a great moustache
Moustache?!
Yes, Where has it gone?
That, I have shaved it
Why?
Just llke that!
No, No,... Why?
Just llke that ..
Why?...Why?
Mr.Mansingh!
It's empty!
Your father couIdn't come
I regret very much
Yes!
What happened to him?
He...actually...that...
Again the same Asthma attack?
Yes sir, Asthma!
Yes, my son, Asthma is a very
dangerous disease
Then, Shall I Ieave?
Leave?
How wllI I allow you to go
without attending the feast -
And today, its my
daughter's birthday
Don't you want to
meet her?
greet her?
You wait here, I'll come with
her just now
WonderfuI...WonderfuI, How gracefuI
the butterfIy is?
Roop Singh! Tell me one thing
Why did you shave off your moustache?
Just llke that?
Just llke that!?!...Why?
Just llke that
But, Why?...Why?
Oh! I have shaved my moustache
How does it concern you?
Leave my hand
Okay, granted it was your moustache
but why did you shave it off?
Hey, GentIeman, How many times
have I toId you-
That I am Roop Singh!
Are you really Roop Singh?
Yes sir
Son of Kunwar Pratap Singh?
Yes...Yes
Come I'll introduce you to
one more Roop Singh
Chlld, You wait here, I'll
come just now
DharampaI! What's
happening here?
He fell, I fell on him -
Then all the Thakurs
fell on me
But, Who is he?
How many times, do I have
to tell you that I am Roop Singh
What are you bIabbering?
Catch them...Catch them..
atch them...
Rashmi, and then,
What happened
Then, everyone fell
calling each other
There was a great
uproar
And that boy, who came
impersonating Roop Singh
I never saw him
In the meIee, he
ran away
Randhir Singh, my son!
Yes mother!
Did you find out anything about
that imposter?
Now onIy Mr.CIerk, informed
me that -
To flle an appllcation against
us in the court -
Dhanraj's son had come
And that too, on a red
motor cycIe
If onIy, I knew it before
he ran away
In front of all my cIan I wouId
have Iashed him so much that -
OnIy his corpse wouId have
gone out from here
WonderfuI!...WonderfuI!
Come on, llsten...
Listen...Listen
Received a Ietter from Pandit
Shivnarain of Mt.Abu-
He has invited all of us to
his son's bethrothaI
I think, We didn't have a
hollday for quite a Iong time
So why not take advantage of this
and go to Mt.Abu
Brother, there is a Amba TempIe
near by -
I had taken a vow that if he comes back
I wllI offer fIowers
Yes, Yes definiteIy
go there
AIright, tell me this, Are you coming
to Sitanagar Camp?
It wllI be difficuIt for
me to come
Father is sending me to Mt.Abu
with mother and Aunty
Mt.Abu and Sitanagar
are very near
It's just 3 hours journey
by bus
You just tell your father that you want to
go to Sitanagar and not Mt.Abu
But, I can't open my mouth
infront of my father
Then, take me with you
to him
I wllI open my mouth well
in front of him
UncIe! I was saying that
Mt.Abu is Mt.Abu and
Sitanagar is Sitanagar
Have you ever visited it?
No
UncIe, you shouId visit -
If Mt.Abu is earth, then
Sitanagar is the sky!
Kavitha, how coId the weather
wllI be?
There's so much coId that
You'll aIways be...
Oh god! Then, we wllI
stay in Mt.Abu onIy
Even then, I am very scared
of coId
Hey, are we going there
to enjoy or...
Come on Aunty! It is not
llke that ...actually
One minute, One minute
I wllI decide now
Rashmi!
Where do you want to go? Sitanagar? Or Mt.Abu?
Come on, say it?
Mt.Abu!
It's decided
KamaIa, I am going to
the office
I had toId you, That I'll stagger
infront of my father
Don't worry, Come to Mt.Abu
Iet's see there
Just now, we have reached
all of them have come
Really!
Then, What time has the priest
fixed for the engagement?
Evening 6'o cIock! Yes sir, wllI reach
there by that time
Smlle pIease! StllI broader
StllI broader - yes
I want to take the photograph
the sun going down
You stay here, I'll come
just now
BadIy stuck!
Is it broke?
No
I have taken your photograph
aIong with sun
You are not offended,
are you?
No, if the photos wllI be good then,
I wllI not be offended at all
I don't know much about
photography?
Just trying the Iuck
Yes
For every new thing, its absoIuteIy
necessary to try the Iuck
Yes
By the way, you have done
one thing right
What's that?
You are in the right pIace at
the right time
Really!
I mean that, you have
seIected a good pIace
Yes
But, In the fading sunllght beautifuI
things Iook more beautifuI
Really!
It seems, you know much
about photography
Do one thing, take my photograph
at this pIace
Let's see, how
wllI it be?
Yes definiteIy
Is someone
calling you?
No, not me, I don't know
who is that mad man?
The llght has faded away today,
Iet's meet again tomorrow
Same time, Same pIace
Really!
UncIe, you are too much...
Yes
Tell the reception to send a
qullt to the room
It's very coId here
Yes, okay
How beautifuI she is,
isn't she?
Yes
I want a bride for Raj,
just llke her
Whom were you been
searching?
That,my cousin Shyam...
Yes
I think he has gone
It's very good that, you too
are staying in this hoteI
Why?
Your photograph which I took
I wllI present it to you tomorrow
I don't want those photos
Why?
There's an oId saying that photos taken
with the setting sun
When they are kept,
the person wllI die
Do you belleve in
all that?
I don't belleve, but I aIso don't
wish to die young
Okay, show me your
right hand
What happened?
Your llfe llne is just
llke mine
Look
What does it mean?
You have a very
Iong llfe
Really!
And in this Iong llfe,
What wllI I get?
Fame, Money, Honour and...
...And...
And whatever you wish
you'll get it
Okay, I wllI Ieave now
Tomorrow I'll take few more
of your photographs
What type of a room service
do you have?
Even if you ring the
bell 10 times no one comes
Look, its our friend,
Raj!
Regarding her...
UncIe greetings
Greetings, Greetings,
llve Iong!
They are Raj & Shyam's friend
they go on hunting reguIarIy
It seems you have come here
aIso for hunting
Yes sir
We had pIanned it in DeIhi itseIf
with Raj and Shyam
Yes, definiteIy, definiteIy
go on hunting
We have some important
work
We wllI meet again
IeisureIy
It's aIright!
Come - Greetings
Aunty!
Yes
Today you and mother go for sight seeing
I'll stay back in the hoteI
AIright, if you are not in the mood
We'll aIso not go out
It's very coId,
out there
No, No, No you must go out,
that's because...
We have just now reached here We are
pIanning to Ieave for Sitanagar today
What's so urgent? We'll do one thing
We'll stay for a day and then go
AbsoIuteIy not today we are catching the
3'o' cIock bus and all are Ieaving
You be ready now I am
coming there
AIright
Look, there's no question of
going out!
Raj,in Sitanagar where you
are going for hunting?
Yes
Where wllI you stay?
Daddy, We'll stay in
the HoteI Rocks
AIright, We'll return in 2 days and
together we'll go back to DeIhi
What happened?
Nothing!
Come on Aunty, It's just a
2 - 4 days trip onIy
Kavitha, No
Really Aunty, Sitanagar is
such a good pIace -
Such a beautifuI pIace
It's just out of the worId
What are you seeing out there?
Why don't you expIain to her?
Kavitha, I'll not
come today
What?
As you wish
Why didn't you say that earller? When
you didn't want to come?
I'll come definiteIy, but
tomorrow
I promise
When are we pIanning to start
tomorrow morning?
Eight in the morning
When did these, pigeons
drop into this hoteI?
Yesterday morning
On arrivaI, they fought with CIerk
and then with the hoteI manager
What! PIanning for a
third fight?
WonderfuI!
My friend Hamid, hunting trip
is cancelled
Why?
Hunter himseIf has been
hunted
Who?
Hey, its the same girI
of Dhanakpur!
GirI of Dhanakpur?
GirI of Dhanakpur!
Oh, Yes, isn't she?
I saw her in the dinning hall,
yesterday night
And the funny thing about it is your
parents were fixing alliance with her
How do they know that she is
Randhir Singh's daughter?
Your kerchief? Isn't it?
Wlld pigeons!
What's this Raj? She is coming
here onIy
I want to show your photos which
I took yesterday evening
Photographs!
Look at this
And this
What do you think
about it?
Yes,they are very good,
take them
No, No, I had printed this set
for you onIy
For me?
What wllI I do
with them?
I mean,you are taking
unnecessary troubIe
PIease take them
Sun is going down, I am going
to the same pIace -
Where I had taken
these photographs
Its a very good pIace to
spend time
Oh! Mr.Raj,if you are uncomfortabIe
here you can go
Raj you are very
secretive
Where are you going
brother?
I am going to the market to
get some things -
If you want any thing
I'll get it
Listen Raj!
I know that you are going
to meet Rashmi -
No, my friend!
If she had been any one eIse's daughter
it was aIright
But, She is Randhir Singh's
daughter
Think over it
Come on friends
What a great thing!
I have decided that tomorrow I am
going to Sitanagar
But, first call up
DeIhi
I'll call, but I am
certainIy going
Hey! how much time
wllI it take?
HaIf an hour! Take rest
Stop it, Stop it
for a moment
Hey! What are you
doing?
Friend,isn't she the same girI
who was in the hoteI?
Yes
Yours?
A llttIe further there's a very
beautifuI pIace -
To take photographs!
Why are you troubllng me?
TroubIe?
Did I say anything wrong? I was
just wanting to be friendIy
Hey! Where has this baba
got stuck?
Nothing friend,
Come Iet's go
You?!
How are you here?
What are you doing here?
I...
I wllI tell you
just now
Can I have some water?
Hey! You have got hurt?
Wait here, I'll get
dettoI
Don't know, how I am
Iooking?
But, how did all
this happen?
I was going to Sitanagar and
my bus broke down
I was taking photographs
of the jungIe
I never knew from where this boy
and his friends came
They started misbehaving
with me
I aIso gave him such a kick
that he'll never forget
Any other hurts?
No,nothing that need
dettoI
There are some sandwiches in this
Have some
What are you doing?
Don't you want to sIeep?
SIeep?!
No, No, I'll not
sIeep here
Look, take me to the road there
I am sure of getting a bus
I have forgotten the way
to the road myseIf
What?
Yes
I had come on a hunting trip
with friends
They went on hunting and I got
separated from them
Are you telling the
truth?
Then, What in this dangerous forest am I
spending this night for fun?
Are you going to
sIeep?
Won't you have a small
chat?
Didn't get tired after wandering
in the forest the whoIe day?
I was tired, but after meeting you
I have become fresh
If you permit,I can taIk all the
night with you
Can I come to you?
No, its Iate night,
go to sIeep
You have arranged my bed
so far away
That if I get scared,
I cannot hoId your hand
Scared? Being a Rajput
How do you know that I am
a Rajput?
Your modesty and spIendour
are llke Rajput?
Thank you
These are the first words uttered
in my honour
If you want to say anything in my
honour I am ready to llsten
Can I come to you?
May be, You want to know
something about me
What?
Why don't you ask me
straight away?
Ask what?
Okay, don't ask, I wllI tell
myseIf
That, I am from DeIhi,
Where do you come from?
I am a Rajput and my
name is Rashmi
What is your name?
Raj!
I think its better to tell you that I
have passed my first year exams
I am 18 years oId and I have
not married yet
Look, there is nothing
to hide
Now, that fate has put us together
in this way -
We don't know for how Iong we
wllI be wandering llke this -
It'll be better if we know something
about each other
It wllI be better,
isn't it?
Then, I have toId you
everything cIearIy
You have impressed
me a Iot
I think this reIationship
shouId deveIop -
If you ask me my address
I wllI not refuse
Look, We'll have this taIk
Iater on
First Iet me find the
way to the road
Then, Why don't you
move on? -
Why are you wasting the time
standing here and taIking nonsense?
Was I taIking nonsense?
Then, was I taIking
nonsense?
Look, its not a
matter to Iaugh
If we don't find the way by
this evening, then -
For the entire llfe, we wllI be
going round this pIace
Can this happen?
No
The road is so near and in the night
it seemed so far away, isn't it?
The road, which we were madIy trying
in finding out tllI yesterday
Today, I feeI llke crying
after seeing it
You'll go some where
I'll go some where
WllI you meet me
in DeIhi?
Even if you don't want to meet, atIeast
say yes,to make me happy
AtIeast I wllI wait
for you
Rashmi, Why are you taIking
llke this?
When I came to Mt.Abu, I never thought
I was going to meet someone suddenIy -
Who'll take my feet off
the ground
But, this has happened
Ever since I have met you, I don't know
what has happened to me?
Telling you all this, doesn't mean that
I am asking something in return -
If I had gone mad after someone
it is not necessary that-
That someone eIse shouId aIso be
mad after me
Look, the girI is
the same one
But who is with her?
Raj, they are the
same rogues
Look there, the camera in his
hand is mine
Raj Iets go
What? Where did you spend
the whoIe night?
With this cock
We were staying together
in the hoteI
We share everything in eating
drinking and all other things
Etc...Etc...Etc...
PIease return back
the camera
No, Raj I don't want
She doesn't want
the camera
What do you want?
Come on babe, say it into
the ears of baba
Come on, I'll never reveaI it
to anyone
I swear by him
Look, Mister there is a llmit
for everything -
Its better for you, not to
cross the llmit
Otherwise, What wllI
you do?
What wllI you do?
Me! What can I do...
At the most I can kick
you between the Iegs.
Stop!
Look there, Raj!
Run
Look, didn't I tell you that
I'll come
That too in styIe!
Oh Yes!
Do you know that yesterday,
he saved my llfe
Yesterday my bus had a fIat tyre and
4-5 rowdies surrounded me...
Enough...Enough..
enough..
It seems to be Iong winding taIe
it may need a Iot of time to hear
Anyway are these peopIe going
to stay here onIy?
No, No, We are in the hoteI
on The Rock...
Take out their Iuggage!
Raj, two days have passed aIready
are we going back to HoteI or not?
We'll go friend, tomorrow
we'll go