You can feel in the air
a moisture like in the grave.
Smells like this from six months.
Ciudra!
Why did you left the family?
Gipsies are not like they used to be...
Now they trade their horses for gold.
And their soul...
Who knows more??
The dumb or the wise?
The dumb. The wise
is not suer about anything.
It's better to be dumb.
Too much thinking
brings lots of trouble.
What advice can you give me
if we won't meet again?
Don't love money.
Money dissapoint you.
Don't love women too.
They will trade you.
From all the drinks,
freedom is the sweetest.
Wake up in the morning and don't forget:
life ends when you don't expect.
I wish you a long life.
And die when the right time comes.
THE GIPSY HERD
after MAXIM GORKI
RADA:
SVETLANA TOMA
ZOBAR:
GRIGORE GRIGORIU
Directed & written by
EMIL LOTEANU
Four kings.
Let's drink, gentlemen,
for the new 20th century!
Happy new year!
- Schwob!
- Yes, mr locotnent!
- do you know how to waltz?
- No, mr locotnent.
Put your right hand on my left arm.
Yes sir!
How is going to be the 20th century?
The zodiac signs announce
the end of the world after 16 years.
Look, mr Balint!
Couldn't you
wait until tomorrow?
No. I wanted to try my luck
now, to know how this year will be.
Now I know it will be wonderful!
Look!
You don't find horses like this
on these lands
Make some light!
More!
I don't buy horses
stolen from officers.
- What about the others?
- I said I don't want this kind of horses.
Don't take it! Tomorrow, at the
market, will sell them on gold.
Wait! We have some unfinished
business. What about that?
This is your problem.
You don't let me breathe.
- I want fair trading.
- Fair? With stolen horses?
I want to say to your guests and to
your family a Happy New Year.
Thank you very much.
It's not good to start a
new year with old owes.
Let's go!
Forgive me!
Wait for me here!
- Do you like this?
- Not really.
- I'll give you the rest until Easter.
- Fine.
I left you some good
stallions. Happy New Year!
Get off the horses!
Come on! Come on!
Zobar! Go left!
Surround'em!
Catch them alive!
I want them alive!
Confuse them!
Make them dizzy!
Leave those darn horses!
They will catch us and hang us!
COme on, who is closer!
Take me, come on!
We will hang in ropes.
Leave the horses, Zobar!
Let's cross river Tisa.
Shut up!
Don't kill the horses! You're not
sorry for them either, darn gipsies!
Crows will take away
my blue eyes.
I will hang you!
From your legs!
Confuse them, confuse them!
Let's go!
Dog!
Run!
After them!
Save me, hawk!
Oh! They killed me!
Who are you?
They call me Zobar.
What is that?
Turn around!
Grass of the moon.
I drank water from the grass moon
for the bullett not to touch me.
I can see that!
Leave your left hand down,
so that evil go to the ground!
- Where do you come from?
- From Galitia.
It's snow on Carpatian Mountains,
but here, on Tisa, it's summer.
You will get better.
Where are you?
Zobar!
Wondering the world...
You forgot us!
Welcome, Zobar!
Rusalina, wake up!
Zobar came, with gifts.
Luicu!
- Am I beautiful now?
- More beautiful than the moment of death.
Was our mother beautiful?
So beautiful that other women
from the village were banishing her.
That's what they were doing
when they were seeing her.
Yes, she was the most beautiful
from the gipsy race.
- So I am beautiful too.
- Why do you say this?
People say I look just like my mother.
I will look for an artist
to make your mother's face.
A small one...
Hello father!
People are saying you studied a lot.
You know how to read in
russian, german, polish and romanian.
-You know many things...
- That's right, father. Sto je istina, istina je.
I read people's faces.
Do you think this is easyer?
No father, Your knowledge
is more useful.
I can see the shadow of death on your face.
- Put it away!
- If i could...
- How many horses did they killed on you?
- Three.
I gave up after the second.
You should give up!
I can't, father!
- How come you don't miss a single drop?
- I pour the wine using my ear.
I recognise your horse after its gallop.
- In your honor!
- Yours too!
Please take!
I give you from my heart.
I bow before you!
You throw with money...
Haralambie!
Put your face against the wall!
SIng a love song
for Iliusca to fall asleep!
- You don't have shame!
- Yes, Iliusca!
Lust doesn't know about shame.
I am like grass for you.
You come, you cut it and you leave.
- What's wrong? You're burning. Are you sick?
- No.
I will bring some cold water.
Swiss watches.
Take, mr gipsy!
See how nice it sounds!
It takes your eyes away.
Swiss watches!
For you, lady!
Or for the mister...
Swiss watches!
- Do me too!
- Me too!
How wonderful!
I am good at many things,
but not at this.
- When will you give back what you owe me?
- Don't worry. That time will come!.
Hey, beautiful, i can guess for you!
Tell you everything...
- Good horse!
- Arabian stallion.
I see...
Last year I bought
a hores from you.
From me?
You painted it with ink,
bastard!
I was looking since last year after you!
Come here!
Come!
I will kill you!
Don't kill each other!
We are already a few.
Relax!
Take off your coat!
I can't.
I will feel cold.
Take this bandit away from us! spasite nas!
We will show him.
Please!
Don't touch him!
My dear!
I would like to kick his ass!
Am I right?
Yes, dear!
I don't care about money.
Let him go!
I know my job...
We'll be OK.
He's not better too.
He should be whipped.
- They're all dust in the wind.
- Who wants to whip me? You?
If we don't steal nothing,
how could a gipsy live?
I don't want to catch
you around! Get lost!
I won't forget this all my live.
Thank you very much!
- Where did you come from?
- I am from Galitia.
Why have you done this?
- Stop stealing chickens!
- Steal what?
Virgins and horses.
Learn how to work!
Do I have a face for that?
- What's your name?
- Bucea.
- And the name of your boss?
- Nur.
- Is still Nur?
- I wish he was dead!
And who are you?
I am Zobar.
Never heard of me?
Luicu Zobar?
I wish you live a thousand years,
you fearless hawk!
Zobar? In flesh and bones?
REally, I can't believe this!
Come to us! The family
camped on the shore of Tisa.
You will like our gipsies.
I am the only crazy one.
From my soul!
From my heart!
You should see our girls!
Living icons!
Get away from the road!
Darn you!
Come back!
So that's what you do!
Howdy, young ladies!
You may be smart,
but your driver is a moron.
Forgive us both!
Look at my hand...
Can you guess for me?
- I can guess your name.
- Say it!
Mister! I can see it all...
Antal is your name.
You will have a long life,
but don't get mad because I tell you this...
Your life will be sad...
You are a weak man,
baked from soft mixture.
Anything good to tell me?
Let me drive the horses!
- Mister, I told you! You're soft!
- Apolodor! Give her the whip!
Go to the tavern!
- There you go, young ladies!
- Come up, girls!
Come to my land!
- To be your servant?
- No, no way!
Fly like the wind!
Your heiness! We received
new models from Paris.
Latest fashion hit.
Come! Come and see!
Come, your heiness!
Look what a guest
has arrived!
A fine one!
When we see you
it's celebation for us.
Our family is stronger now.
Ciudra is back.
Danilo returned back!
A soldier who fought many battles
He also brought his daughter, Radu.
The sky enlightened
above our family.
Does your heart tells you
to leave or to stay?
Let it go!
This will destroy you!
Nobody will be able to save you.
Not even me!
Stay away from her!
She's a whitch.
- Do you remember me?
- No.
- It was you! You had four pony-tails.
- No!
You healed me with the grass of the moon.
It's her!
Let go! Come on!
I am made from stone.
- Good!
- What is good?
You speak beautiful,
but you lie ugly.
What an ugly horse!
I will get you a white mare,
crazy like you.
You will die because of me!
I take the mare. You take the rest.
Took away your thinking,
you deviless.
Those women!
Where is Zobar?
We will get them
and we will hang him!
Tomorrow! But today,
you can work for money!
100 gold coins
for whom catches Zobar alive.
Don't lay your hands on
the great emperor Franz Iosef!
Don't touch him!
WHere's Luicu Zobar?
Where's Zobar?
Who knows where he is?
We will kill your bears and horses!
Did you hear that, gipsies?
Where is he?
Give him to us, and get
100 gold coins for him.
- Let go of the wheel!
- I will teach you!