lt's amazing! Your birthday and
your daughter's birthday...
...fall on the same day.
Yes. And we celebrate
our birthdays together...
...on the same day
every year.
Where's Mrs. Sehgal?
There are people
who want to meet you.
This is my brother.
This is my nephew, Jai...
And who's she?
Ah! Aarti...
Looking at your figure,
it doesn't appear...
...that you' re the mother
of such a grown-up girl.
Who told you that
l' m her mother?
l' m only her stepmother.
But my sister loves Aarti more
than her real mother would.
- lsn't Aunt a bit foolish?
- Not a bit. She's very foolish.
- You want to go to Palankhet?
- What's there to laugh about?
People go to see America
and Europe, whereas...
...you want to visit a tiny
hill-station like Palankhet?
Why don't you go to
Switzerland instead?
Because what l can find at Palankhet,
l cannot find elsewhere.
- What's so special at Palankhet?
- My mother's memories.
Father...didn't you meet mother for
the first time at Palankhet?
Look... it is Shalini now
who is your mother.
Forget the one who is dead.
Let her go if she wishes to.
Besides, aren't you visiting
Germany for a few days, too?
Yes....when do you
wish to leave?
When are you leaving
for Germany, Father?
l' m leaving tomorrow itself.
All right. Then l' ll
also leave tomorrow.
But l cannot permit you
to go all alone.
What' ll people say? That l let my
young daughter go all by herself?
She's right.
Gulab and Kamal... you must
accompany Aarti tomorrow.
- To Switzerland?
- Not Switzerland.
What did you say was
the name of that place?
Had you telephoned the Hotel Taj?
Did you ask them to
send a car?
Has the car arrived then?
What can one say? The hotels
here are all useless.
- Had we telephoned London...
- This is not London.
Will you continue to stare at me,
or do something about it?
There's an only taxi
parked there.
lf we miss that one too,
we' ll be stranded here.
She's right... Please stay here.
We' ll go and fetch the taxi.
- Raja Hindustani.
- Raja Hindustani...?
The license number is 420
(as in cheats ).
Anyway, what does it have got
to do with us? Come on...
These people are very lazy.
He's taking a nap. What now?
l' ll wake him up.
- Hey! Wake up!
- Hey! What' re you doing?
- Who' re you?
- l' m the helper on this taxi.
My name is Rajnikant.
Wake your driver. We wish
to go to Palankhet.
We can't go.
- Why can't you?
- The boss sleeps at this hour.
He sleeps at this hour? ls he in
eternal sleep that he can't wake up?
Hold one leg.
l' ll hold the other.
Let's see how he doesn't wake up.
Come on...Get up!
Wake up, O descendent
of the demons!
O descendent of the demons?!
What do you think of yourself?
Who dared wake up the
lndian King of Hearts!?
- Not me, Boss. They did.
- These people?
Who addressed me as a descendant
of the demons?
- Not me, Boss. They did.
- They did?
- Who thumped my cab?
- Not me. They did.
They did?
Aren't you ashamed of raising
your hand on a woman?
Woman? ls she a woman?
- What else? Can't you see?
- And who' re you? Her sister?
l' m male. My name is Gulab Singh.
She's Kamal, a female.
Everything is wrong here. Hot is
cold and cold is hot.
- Don't you know about them?
- About whom?
Shut up, will you? We want a taxi
to take us to Palankhet.
Just tell me if you
will come along.
- No.
- And why not?
l don't feel like it.
l don't want to go.
- Then how' ll we go?
- Put the luggage on your head...
...and walk the distance
of 250 kilometers.
- But just listen...
- Didn't l say no?
- But please listen...
We' re new here. And there's
no other taxi around, too.
Please help us.
You may charge us money.
How much would you charge?
500 rupees?
All right. Take 600 rupees.
All right. Tell me.
How much will you charge?
Boss...
500 rupees will be enough.
- What?
- Yes.
500 rupees is enough. As it is,
our taxi belongs to Palankhet.
amazing! When l asked you, you refused.
But when Madam asked,
you agreed. Why so?
That's my look-out!
- Fetch Madam's luggage.
- Yes, Boss.
Please come, Madam. Be seated.
- Hey! Where are you going?
- To sit with Madam.
No way. Madam will make herself
comfortable in the rear seat!
- Come on. Let's sit in the front.
- No, not in the front.
My cleaner, Rajnikant,
sits up front with me.
As it is, while driving, sometimes
l shake my hands and legs.
- Then where will we sit?
- Yes...where will they sit?
Don't be worried. l've a special
air-conditioned place for them.
- Where's that?
- Above.
Looks like he's
going to kill us!
Hold tightly! l think that
this man is crazy
What' re you doing?
Look ahead, Boss! Or you
might cause an accident.
Shut up!
- Excuse me...
- Yes, Madam?
How far is Palankhet from here?
28 hours in a bullock cart.
5 hours in a ramshackle bus.
And 3 hours flat in
Raja Hindustani's taxi.
Your name is Raja Hindustani?
Yes. Didn't you like it?
No...it's fine. But its
a bit different, isn't it?
Yes, Madam. lt's different.
My name is different from others.
My name is Raja because l' m
the King of my moods.
Nobody can dominate me. And
l' m a Hindustani because...
in this country, you find Hindus,
Sikhs, Christians, Muslims...
but no lndians...
l' m an orphan. When l was a kid,
my father passed away.
Now l' m just the child
of my country.
You' re a very interesting
person.
Am l not?
Thank you, Madam.
- What's this?
- Why? Madam?
lt's an English song. People from
the city really enjoy it.
l don't like it.
Switch it off.
Very well, Madam.
- What's this?
- lt's a hit Hindi film song.
l don't like that either.
Please switch it off.
All right...
Why did you stop it?
That's a nice song.
Let it play.
lt was not a cassette.
lt was me singing.
- You?
- Yes.
- Do you also sing?
- Would you like to hear me?
- Sure.
There's no booking in
your name at this hotel.
How is that possible?
Our booking has been confirmed
at this hotel.
You had telephoned them,
didn't you?
What's this?
Why' re you crying?
l made the booking.
But not for this Taj.
l booked you at the
Taj Mahal in Agra.
What?
Are you out of your mind?
Please book two rooms
for us right now.
There's a conference in
progress right now.
You won't find any accommodation
in the whole of Palanpur.
What should we do now?
- Why' re you worried? Come with me.
- Where?
To a place where there are not
just 5-stars, but countless ones.
To a place where one
serves with feelings.
To a place where the doors are open
even if there's no place.
- Come on...
- But Raja...
Where is such a place?
Come along, Madam. Please come...
Look...what a beautiful
place this is!
After all, you did lie!
Even a blind man wouldn't call
this place as five-star.
ls this a hotel or a rest-house?
How can the young lady live here?
Even a donkey wouldn't like
to be tied to such a place.
ln that case, the donkeys might
return to where they come from.
You called me a donkey!
Why' re you arguing with him?
lt's a good enough place.
lt's better than the
5-star hotel.
ls this somebody's residence?
Yes. lt's the residence of
my Uncle and Aunt.
This taxi too belongs to them.
l only drive it around.
- Are they your blood relatives?
- No.
lt's not blood that ties us
together, but our hearts.
You know how we lndians form
a relationship everywhere.
My relationship with Uncle and
Auntie too is a similar one.
Hurry up! Go and tell Uncle
that Madam has come.
All right.
Also tell them that she has
brought two maidservants along.
Hey! What did you say?
What happened? You cut your
hands, didn't you?
- Hey! What' re you doing?
- Why?
People say that if a tigress
tastes blood...
she doesn't spare
anybody alive.
Really? So l' m a tigress, eh?
And what' re you?
l' m a sheep.
- You've come?
- Yes. Boss too has come.
He has brought
along a madam too.
A Madam...?
A madam with Raja?
Let me go and see which Madam
Raja has brought along.
You' re very beautiful.
What's your name?
- Aarti.
- Ah! What a lovely name!
Yes, it's a lovely name.
You may stay here for
as long as you wish.
You don't have to go
to any hotel.
- Come on.
- Please come, Madam.
Go and get the luggage.
And you, maidservants...
Go and help him.
Please come, Madam.
Just a minute.
l'd forgotten.
She's my wife.
And this poor man is my husband.
He's performing his duties.
Uncle and Auntie are always
pulling each other's leg.
Why' re you standing far away?
Come closer.
- Greetings.
- Bless you.
- What' re you doing?
- Guests stand for good fortune.
How can good fortune enter the
house without a welcome?
Yes, of course.
Hey!
Why did you throw water on me?
l couldn't help it. After all,
it was only a hand. lt shook.
The day my hand shakes, your
brains will start shaking.
lt's your mind which
is wavering, Boss!
- What did you say?
- Whom were you gazing at?
l was admiring the morning....the
Sun that shines so brightly!
But the sun rises
in that direction.
When did it get to rise
in this direction?
You' re getting to be
too smart nowadays.
- Want a beating?
- For your beautiful Sun's sake!
Well...wash the car
properly today.
l must take madam
to the market today.
Please come.
Look at this beautiful
taxi-stand of Palanpur.
She hasn't come here from Mumbai
just to see a taxi-stand.
Hey! This taxi-stand is
our bread-earner.
lf you criticize it, l' ll punch
your ears and nose together!
What's this?
What's going on? Come on...
let's go and see something else.
All right...as you wish.
Wait a minute...you can't leave
without meeting my dearest friend.
Hey there!
Who is it?
Raja! My friend!
My dear friend!
Madam! This is my friend!
My dearest friend.
He's the president
of this taxi-union.
And this is madam!
She's come from Mumbai.
Greetings. Please come in.
Let me serve you refreshments.
l've got some shopping to do.
Yes...l've got to help her
with the shopping.
But please treat the two of
them. l' m going with madam.
Sure. You can sit with me and
enjoy some refreshments!
Meanwhile, l' ll do some shopping.
Don't you worry.
How' re you related to Madam?
l' m her body-guard.
You' re a robust body-guard.
Why don't you embrace me too?
Leave me! Leave me!
- Scoundrel!
- Just a minute.
- Let me go!
- You' re all right.
- Just once more.
- Leave me!
There's something wrong.
Please come inside.
Please come in.
Sit there. Sit here.
Bring two glasses of
some great butter-milk!
lt's so warm. Come on...
Take off your sweater.
- lt's so warm. Take it off.
- Let me go. l won't remove it.
Why not? l' ll remove it for you.
Strange! A brave man takes off
his dress at the drop of a hat!
But he's feeling shy
as if he were a girl!
She is a girl. Wouldn't she
feel shy like a girl then?
Are you a girl?
That's why l was wondered...
why bells rang in my mind
everytime l touched you!
Beware! Don't you
call me a girl!
This is Aarti speaking.
- Yes...?
- Pass on the phone to father.
He hasn't yet returned
from Germany.
- When will he return?
- ln a few days time.
lf he telephones, please
tell him that...
l' m not staying at the Taj, but
with a very nice couple.
- Their address is...
- Fax your address to us.
Whether she lives at the Taj, or
elsewhere, why must l bother?
l disconnected the phone.
You' re an expert in
faking the act, Sister.
l've learnt from none
other than you, Brother.
Well said...if you continue to
follow my directions...
the whole property will be
transferred to our name one day.
And what about Aarti?
Her problem will be
solved by itself.
Just a minute, Madam.
- Take this, Madam.
- What is it?
- Please keep it.
- But what is it?
Shopkeepers here give guides a
commission for bringing customers.
This is my commission.
You may keep it. You' re
entitled to it.
No, Madam. How can l take
commission from your money?
Please keep it.
What did you say?
- Are you sure?
- Yes, l' m sure.
What did you say?
When l say thank you, you
should say ''you' re welcome'' .
What was that?
- What?
- First say you...
Not Gu...say You.
Never mind. You won't be
able to say it. Let's go.
l won't be able to say it?!
Why won't l be able to say it?
- Come on, Raja.
- Let's go, Madam.
What did she say?
Yes...
Boss...
- What is it?
- You' re doing it without reason.
- Nothing's going to happen.
- Just get lost!
lt's your time to get lost.
Madam has been asking for you.
What? Has Madam asked for me?
That's wonderful!
Madam....you asked for me?
l've got such a nice place
to live in, thanks to you.
You've showed me
around the whole town,...
helped me in the shopping...
and you didn't even
collect your commission.
That was only my duty, Madam.
But you didn't even ask for
any money. Why?
here's the hurry?
l' m here. And you' re here too...
You' ll be here for
a few days, won't you?
- Still...take this.
- But this is too much, Madam.
l've asked Rajnikant
for the accounts.
This 800 rupees is for the taxi.
And this 200 rupees
is your tip.
- My tip?
- Yes.
How can l accept
any tips from you?
Why not?
- l can't accept it.
- Why not?
You can accept it from others,
and why not from me?
Are you feeling shy?
ls this less?
Do you want some more?
Take it, l say...
Keep it!
All right. You may go now.
Yes...?
- Fool!
- Don't worry. l' m with you.
Let me speak.
- Hey! Raja!
- What is it?
Come...we want to go
to the market.
l don't want to go
- Why not?
- The boss is in a foul mood.
Foul mood, my foot! There's nothing
wrong with the car, is there?
Didn't l say that l won't
go to the market?
Are you doing us a favor? Haven't
we paid you for the cab?
- You, there!
- Just a minute.
The madam has paid me.
l' m answerable only to her!
not to her servants!
Look at how he uses
his tongue!
You there!
lf the boss gives you a punch,
you' ll begin shaking terribly.
Don't you dare touch him!
lf l go and complain
to madam...
How dare you try to scare me
by using her name!
Go and complain to her!
l' m not scared of her.
- You aren't scared?
- We' re not scared.
Leave them. Let's go.
- Not like this.
- How else?
What? Does Madam
praise me a lot?
l suppose you aren't
playing some mischief.
We swear.
Why would we lie?
- l swear upon this little one.
- Don't you swear upon me.
Just listen to all that
the madam says about you.
Really? What does madam say?
Madam says that Raja is
so handsome!
- ls it?
- Boss...
Just shut up...what else
does madam say?
She praises your singing,
walking and laughing.
- ls it?
- But l regret...
What do you regret?
- Must l tell him?
- Go ahead.
She says that everything about
Raja is nice.
But neither does he have
class, nor style.
What's that?
lt about how one walks, talks,
dresses and conducts himself.
One has to play the hero.
The hero? Really?
- Madam likes all that.
- Yes. She digs that.
All right, then. l' ll do that.
l' ll wear nice dresses.
Behave like a hero.
- Boss...
- Shut up...
But l don't know anything.
How will l do it all?
What' re we for?
- Boss...
- You should help me.
Did you see Raja's style?
lsn't it classy?
Just like a hero!
What's this?
Stop fooling around.
Wait!
But what was the need
to do such foolish things?
Because l am a fool...
a total fool!
But let me tell you something.
Nobody can fool me otherwise.
But they named you,
and l got fooled.
You' re not a fool.
You' re just a simpleton.
You' re a very decent man,
aren't you?
lt's of no use.
Decency and simplicity is
of no use in this world.
People with a clean heart
have no place in this world.
But people with a clean heart
cannot have any worth.
After all, they' re priceless.
How wonderful! You've just
said something so true!
You can't place a price on
clean-hearted people.
- They' re priceless.
- Just like you are.
- Me?
- Yes...you.
Just a minute, Madam.
Give me 200 rupees. Hurry up.
- 200 rupees?
- Keep all of it.
No. Just 200 rupees.
- Here, Madam.
- What is this?
- A tip.
- A tip?
Yes, Madam. That day, you liked
what l said. And you rewarded me.
Today l liked what you said.
So l' m giving you a tip.
The scores are level!
- Please take it, Madam.
- But...
Please take it, Madam.
A tip!?
- Madam!
- What is it?
l like it a lot. Come on,
let's go and tell Baby.
What' re you doing here?
Look at the dress.
lt's so beautiful.
lt's a beautiful dress.
lt' ll look good on you.
- Shall l buy it?
- Yes.
- Yes?
Wait here. l' ll be back.
Baby liked it at first sight.
- Where's Madam?
- She's ours.
Why should you be bothered?
You hit me?
How do you find my dress?
Looks like Raja didn't
like my dress.
- Shall l tell you the truth?
- Yes.
l didn't like this dress at all.
l suggest you change it immediately.
- lt's not nice.
- This boy is naive.
- What'd he know about fashion?
- Don't pay attention to him.
Let's go and do some
shopping instead.
Come on...
You think a lot. My
dress is very nice.
O sweetheart!
lt's so tiny!
Even if you didn't wear it,
you would've looked prettier.
What is it?
Let them say what they want to.
You' re quite a dish!
- Hey!
- Didn't l tell you?
O sweetheart! Are you joining us?
lf you aren't coming,
l' ll come over.
You' re so delicious!
What were you saying?
Scoundrel! How dare you
try to attack Raja!
How dare you confront Boss!
Don't!
Leave him!
Will you kill him?
What does he think of himself?
Let him come. l' ll deal
with him properly.
Yes, Madam...
l see..so you've come?
Why did you have to
create such a scene?
Why did you indulge in
so much of violence?
You made a scene for
such a small thing.
You call it something small.
Those scoundrels were teasing you,
abusing you...
- and you call it a small thing.
- So what?
Barking dogs can't be helped.
You should've ignored them.
This is a common occurrence
in the cities.
lt must be happening in
the cities, not here.
This is Palankhet. Womenfolk
here are treated with respect.
And those who don't know
how to respect...
are kicked several times and
taught how one should respect.
l see...so you've taken it
upon yourself to reform society!
Has the government awarded
you a contract to do this?
How strange! l beat them up
for your sake...
...and you' re scolding me!
Listen to one more thing.
l don't like it at all
when you wear such dresses.
Who' re you to tell me what l should
wear and what l shouldn't?
Who' re you?
l' ll do and wear as
l please. Understand?
Yes...who am l to
tell you anything?
You can do as you please.
And l' ll do whatever
l find appropriate.
Wear whatever you like, and l' ll
keep on bashing up people.
Today l've just broken their limbs.
Tomorrow l' ll break their heads.
l am not scared of anybody.
l' m not even scared of you.
Yes. l' m not scared of you!
You' re searching for Raja?
l know where you can find him.
Where is he?
You' ll find him
in his own house.
His house?
Shall l come in?
- Who told you about this place?
- Auntie did.
Auntie has told me everything.
This is your home, isn't it?
The unfulfilled dream
of your parents...
lt's very pretty.
- Why have you come here?
- To ask for your forgiveness.
l spoke a lot of nonsense yesterday
in a fit of anger.
Please forgive me.
Who am l to forgive you?
What right do l have on you?
You' re very angry, aren't you?
All right. Look...l' m
even holding my ears.
Please forgive me now.
Look...if you don't forgive me
right away, l' ll start crying.
Very well...l forgive you.
Hey! You were so angry at me
just a while ago.
And you pardoned me so quickly.
What does it mean?
l cannot see anybody crying.
lf somebody weeps, l too
start weeping.
What does it mean?
lt means...you' re a darling.
Madam...do you know who is
addressed as a darling?
Yes, of course...one who
is close to the heart.
One who is dear, and one
who is the best friend.
- Am l?
- Yes.
- Me, Madam?
- l' m your best friend?
- Gosh!
Stop talking now,
and let's move.
l've decided to see the
whole of Palankhet today.
- Will you show me around?
- Sure, Madam.
l' ll show you the heavens today.
Please come.
- Shall l open my eyes?
- No, not now. Just a minute.
- Where have you brought me?
- Please keep walking.
Shall l open my eyes?
Yes. Open it now.
lt's such a beautiful place.
lsn't it beautiful? l knew that
you'd like this place a lot.
Come on...be seated here.
lt's such a nice place.
lt must be here that my
parents had first met.
What did you say?
Do you know...my mother and father
first met at Palankhet.
Your mother..? How is your mother?
She isn't alive. She passed away
soon after l was born.
Amazing! You don't have a mother.
l have no mother too.
Both are same.
Pardon me for blabbering like this.
l say anything that comes to my mind.
lt's a problem. l don't
know how to converse.
Who says that you cannot converse?
- You talk very well.
- Really?
Madam...l just talk beautifully.
But you' re beautiful too.
- Me?
- Yes. You' re very beautiful.
You too make a lot of
insincere praises.
l swear...l haven't seen anybody
more beautiful than you are.
Why? What's so
beautiful about me ?
Everything about you is beautiful.
Your hair...
lt's nothing special.
- Your eyes.
- My eyes..?
Come a bit closer.
What's so special
about my eyes?
- Your eyes...
- Yes..my eyes?
- Come on. Tell me...
What's so special
about my eyes?
Your eyes are like the
headlight of a taxi-cab.
What?
You' re an idiot! A clown!
But madam! l don't know
poetry. What could l do?
l' m telling you the truth.
No one is more beautiful than you.
That's enough. lf somebody hears
you, he' ll have a nice laugh.
l' m not scared of anybody.
l' ll tell everybody.
This sky...these clouds...
these mountains...
Madam is very beautiful.
Madam is the most beautiful.
Be careful, Madam. Hurry up...
Hey!
What' re you doing? Why' re you
drenching yourself in the rain?
Come here...under the tree.
No, Madam.
Are you mad? You' ll fall sick.
You' ll catch fever. Come here.
l' m fine here.
Look...if you don't come here
right away, l' ll come out there.
- No, Madam.
- Then come over.
Come...come!
Give me your hand. Come on!
l' m very scared of lightening.
l' m such a fool, aren't l?
No...
No!
Those idiots must've told you
that Daddy has come, did they?
And you...
...came rushing through the storm
and the rains to meet your father?
Yes...
l've come to meet you, my child.
l've come to meet you
straight from Germany.
l haven't even been home.
We' ll go together now.
l' ll take you back.
- Back?
- Yes. Back...
Where had you been?
l was in the storm.
lt's nice that you've come.
Take out the taxi quickly.
Your madam is leaving.
- Madam is leaving.
- Yes.
Her father has come to take her.
She has to leave tonight itself.
They've to board
the morning flight.
What' re you still standing for?
Get the car out quickly.
Come on...keep it.
What' re you saying? After all,
your daughter is our daughter.
You've taken care
of Aarti so well.
Many, many thanks to you!
Always remain just
as you are.
l' m leaving, Auntie.
No. Never say you' re leaving.
Say that you' ll return.
Shall we leave?
Hey! You' re wearing dark
sunglasses in the night?
What's wrong?
Something is hurting my eyes.
lt must be a particle of dust.
lt' ll come out by itself.
Let's leave, Driver.
Come on...
Come on...we've to reach
the airport, after all.
Come on...be seated.
Poor Raja!
What did you do all these days?
Nothing special.
My daughter is not in a mood
to talk to me.
Anyhow, l' ll speak
to somebody else.
What's your name, driver?
Wow! That's a nice name.
Once you hear such a name, it
can't be forgotten for a lifetime.
How much do you manage to earn?
lt depends on the person.
Some give me a lot.
Some give nothing.
You speak well.
You drive quite well too.
By the way, there's a scarcity
of drivers in Mumbai.
Why don't you work with us?
We' ll pay you a good salary.
And give you a room to live in.
What say, Aarti?
No, Sir. l' m fine here.
Why? What's the matter?
Are you married?
- No, Sir.
- Why not?
l haven't yet got
what l desired.
How strange! You people
live in a dream world.
As if some dream girl is
going to come.
Why not, Sir? She' ll come someday.
A dream girl will
surely come for me.
Hey!
What's this traffic jam for?
Hey! Raja! My dear! Tell me...
where are you going?
Where are you going?
O Madam! How' re you, Madam?
- Who's he?
- He's Balwant Singh.
He's my father.
Greetings! How' re you?
Why this traffic jam?
The traffic jam has been
caused because of a landslide.
But we've to reach the
airport by morning!
No problem. lt won't take
longer than a couple of hours.
But why don't you have some food
at the eating joint close-by?
How wonderful!
There's so much feeling
in your voice!
lt's said that when a heart breaks,
it makes no sound.
But when it breaks,
it causes havoc.
There's anguish in your voice.
There's that love in your voice.
But listen...
The people in the world
around you...
...won't do justice to
your pain and your love.
You' ll be left trembling.
You' ll keep singing.
And this world will
just stand and stare.
Listen...you continue to sing.
And today...after a long time...
l' ll dance wholeheartedly.
Hold on!
Our Aarti will never marry
your Raja taxi-driver.
Don't you speak
bad things.
lf l weren't fond of you...
...l would've ensured that
you were dealt with properly.
You'd better hold back
your breath.
You will need it to
extinguish the lamps.
This marriage will never
take place.
- lt' ll take place.
- lt won't take place.
- Why not?
- Let's bet on it.
- All right.
Let's put our arms on trial.
Come on...
l' m asking you once again.
Lovers hold hands firmly.
They don't leave it.
Let's get down to
the confrontation.
- ls it? Here it is.
- Come on...
lt's so warm.
lt's so warm!
- You lost!
- Shut up, will you?
You indulge in cheating?
You show me your Doordarshan
and ruin my Star TV.
Why did you unbutton your dress?
l was feeling hot.
So l unbuttoned it.
7 What if l did unbutton my shirt?
Wouldn't l have felt hot then?
Don't scream. lf that's the
case, let's compete once again.
l' ll win again.
- You' re too confident.
- Yes.
All right. This contest
will be a different one.
What's that?
- Are you willing to wrestle?
- Wrestle?
You got scared, didn't you?
l' m not scared. l' m not
scared of anybody.
- Then how about a bout?
- All right.
Let's go then.
Come on!
Come on, Balwant!
Leave me.
- You have lost, haven't you?
- Yes.
Will you become a girl now?
- All right.
- Will you marry me?
l will. Leave me now.
You' ll get married.
You' ll surely get married.
Aarti has made her decision.
And perhaps you' re waiting
for my decision.
For the sake of my daughter's
happiness, l've agreed to her.
But before this marriage,
l've some conditions.
Aarti will not live here.
And you' ll have to live
with us in Mumbai.
You' ll mould yourself
in our ways.
You' ll learn the etiquette
of our society...
...and you' ll do only that
which you' re asked to.
- Not at all.
- What?
Neither will l come to Mumbai...
...nor will l learn the
etiquette of your society.
And nor will l become
what you want to make me.
l am just like l am now.
And l' ll remain like this.
Did you hear? What l want to make
him, and what he wants to remain?
Yes...are you listening?
And listen carefully...because
l' ll remain just like l am.
l won't change for anybody.
lf you want to accept me
despite all this...
...this is the time
for you to decide.
You' re leaving, Aarti?
You' re leaving your father?
You'd learned to take your first
step with my assistance.
And today, you' re taking away
those very steps away from me?
Don't go...come back.
This is my place from today.
Bless us.
Bless you?
l cannot bless this
mistake of yours.
Your marriage will never succeed.
You' ll never remain happy
by staying away from me.
Gulab and Kamal...let's leave.
Yes?
l too will stay here. My marriage
has been finalized with Balwant.
Marriage with Balwant?
And you, have you fallen in
love with somebody too?
Yes, l've fallen in love too.
l've fallen in love
with all these lovers.
Henceforth, l' ll live in this river
of love. l won't go away from here.
All of you have turned
crazy about love.
You' ll die because of
the illusion of love.
Come on...
No, my daughter...
Father didn't even bless me!
So what?
We' ll bless you.
Perhaps God kept us childless...
...so that we may get you married.
Yes, my child...
l'd never imagined that my only
daughter would revolt against me.
That she would insult me like this.
That too for a tourist guide,
a taxi driver?
No. This marriage can
never take place.
lf she's stubborn,
l' m also no less.
l' ll disinherit her
from my property.
l won't bequeath her anything.