Okay God, let's begin
again. I am Raj Mathur.
Recognise me? I'm your Raju.
I thought you'd forgotten me.
I've brought this trident for you. Take.
Hurry up!
- Wonder when our turn will come.
What's going on here? Is
this a temple or a motel?
Wonder who is inside.
He is not coming out.
You understand?
Raju, what are you doing?
Don't disturb us, we
are discussing something.
Hurry up, there is a huge
crowd waiting outside.
Alright, you go.
You haven't left?
Hurry up.
God, your middleman troubles me a lot.
I forgot what I was saying.
God, you know what I want.
I want to be a renowned engineer.
So in my life there should be
big streets, big buildings...
big houses... This
city is very small, God.
I cannot do anything here, God.
My talent will be
wasted here, you know it.
I feel suffocated here.
Send me to Bombay somehow.
God, if I reach Bombay,
my life will be made.
Make me a rich man, God. Look, my
results are going to be declared
today Please let me score well.
Just a minute.
Please God...Bombay.
''My heart is crazy''
''Friends, I am going''
''My destination is far, but go I must''
''Good bye, friends!''
''My eyes hold dreams for the future''
''My goals are very high''
''Don't stop me, friends''
''My heart is not in my control''
''My destination is
far, but go I must...''
''I have set out with a yearning''
''And a million desires in my heart''
''One day, the star of my luck''
''Will surely shine''
''My destination is
far, but go I must...''
Hey hello! Do you know
where Ram Mohan lives?
I don't have time.
- No one seems to have time in
Bombay. Do you know
where Ram Mohan lives?
Abdul, do you want to work or not?
- Of course sir.
You just disappear.
Go serve tea to Pandey.
Pandey uncle, tea. Want anything else?
- No. Did you find a job?
- Not yet. Let's see... Hello.
- Hello. Is this Azad Nagar?
- Yes. Who are you looking for?
- Do you know where Ram
Mohan lives? Who Ram Mohan?
The one whose wife eloped
with the vegetable vendor.
No, he's not even married. -
Shut-up! You are always raving.
He works in Raj Mills.
- Gulu Dada knows everyone.
Take him to Gulu Dada's den.
Give me those hands, Thakur.
What a dialogue it was, Amjadbhai.
I am a great fan of yours.
Boss, some men have come to meet you.
How many men?
- Only five, Boss.
But in 'Sholay', they were just two.
Why am I afraid? I am not afraid.
Hey guys, leave. It’s 10 pm.
lf Sister comes, it will pour.
Boss, we have laid a bet.
Just let us play one game.
Just one more strike.
- Just one strike and four men.
That's very unfair!
Gulu Dada, listen. This boy
has come from Darjeeling.
He wants to meet some Ram
Mohan. Tell him where he lives.
Gulu Dada, no one can escape your eyes.
I know, but I cannot help him.
- But why, Dada?
I cannot, that's all.
- But why?
He has left this colony. I
only got his house vacated.
Wonder if he is even dead or alive.
What say, Tamba?
Gulu Dada, how many times have
I told you to shut shop at 10 pm?
It’s well past decent people's bed time.
Besides, even the school
exams are going on.
Renu, what have you done? This poor
guy has come from Darjeeling only
today He was asking for someone address.
And you wet him. You didn't do
right. Come, on, leave all of you.
And no Ram Mohan lives here.
I told you it will pour.
Leave, come on. Let's go, Tamba.
Wipe your head.
Hail Bholenath. You gave
me a good bath in Bombay...
Got scared?
- Yes.
Are you new here?
There is no place for
cowards in Bombay. Go back!
lf you stay, you won't
realise when you got sucked.
I have not come here to go back.
I will make something
of myself and show you.
What did you say?
- I am not leaving.
Come here.
- Let me take my bag.
Jaibabu, your dinner.
You?
- Jaibabu, he is new here.
The poor guy was orphaned as
soon as he stepped in Bombay.
This idol inside... People call it God.
I've heard he created the world.
And this creator was
orphaned in his own world.
You are no comparison.
You met Sister?...Take this.
It’s just a comb.
- Comb? I thought it was a knife.
Come, let's eat.
- But...
All these ifs and buts
are meaningless words.
Have a place to stay?
Alright, you can stay with me.
Do you know how to live in Bombay?
- How?
Eat, itch, switch off the light.
Open your eyes, and fool people.
Throw your cigarette and burn the
hut. I mean to say, come here.
Kids, have money in your pocket?
- No.
Then scram!...Hey alright, stay.
I won't wish 'namaskar' to
Hindus, 'salaam' to Muslims...
or 'good morning' to Christians.
Because I have not come here
to create communal problems.
Am I right?
- Yes.
You must be thinking I will woo
you with my talks and sell you kohl.
No, that's not my job,
the doctors do that.
Then you will assume I am
going to sell you tooth powder.
I don't consider you to be such fools.
What will you do with
strong teeth anyway?
No brothers, I won't even
foretell your destiny.
Because a street performer,
and his audience, both have bad
destinies. You must be
wondering what I am going
to sell that you don't get in
Bombay. Look friends, in this magical
city, from fritters to chicken...
and from the most petty to the most
expensive, everything is available.
You only need money to buy it.
And that's what you don't
have. All of you are broke.
Every man standing here desires
to move around in a car...
and dance with a babe
in a five star hotel.
But your pocket is empty.
I'll tell you how to
make money. Want to know?
Yes!
- See! Everyone wants to know.
Everyone wants to grow,
everyone wants to be rich.
But this is Bombay, you don't
get anything for free here.
Everything costs money. You won't
get my advice for free either.
Come on, everyone pay Rs. 1
You'll first have to learn to look up.
Here, only the one
who looks up survives.
Those who...you looked down again!
Those who look down have
no right to live in Bombay.
Only the one who makes his goal
his stepping stone can rise here.
And never give a thought to
who he crushed under his feet.
There is no place for
those who look back.
Just push and make way for yourself.
This is the first lesson... come.
Hello Pandey uncle.
- Bless you.
Come Jaibabu. Took him around Bombay?
Have tea and come home.
Rafiqbhai, I'm very tired.
- Abdul, special tea for Raju.
Why are you beating me?
- You steal cake from the bakery!
No, I just had bread.
Shut-up! Rafiqbhai, you
are always defending him.
He steals cake everyday from my bakery.
His wage is Rs.10 a day, and he
eats cake worth Rs.15 every day.
Then give me a raise.
- I'll give you a tight slap!
Raise indeed! Go and work.
Serve me a hot cup of tea.
- Now stop being angry.
Abdul, give him tea.
One cutting.
- Give him half a cup.
Take.
- Here's the money, Rafiqbhai.
Great! Joseph look,
he is giving me money.
Don't bother. Pay me
when you start earning.
Abdul, serve mince meat and bread there.
Hello Rafiqbhai.
- Hello Sister. Come.
How are you?
- I'm fine, Joseph uncle.
What do you want?
- Four eggs and a loaf of bread.
Get four eggs.
Rafiqbhai, if Raju wants,
he can work in my bakery.
He'll get paid too.
- Good idea.
Raju, work in his bakery for now. You
will at least make some money to live
by No Rafiqbhai, I don't want to ruin my
lf I do odd jobs, I'll
always remain menial.
So you think every man who
does odd jobs is menial?
I didn't say that.
- No, you didn't.
But that's what you meant.
- No, you are mistaken.
What I meant is doing small
jobs, one begins to think small.
Even his ambition in life becomes small.
Even your desires become small.
Do you know there are many
people in the world...
who do ordinary jobs and are yet happy?
Then who are you to decide
who is big and who is small?
Rafiqbhai, I was talking to you. I
didn't ask her to budge in between.
Your statement was such that...
- Look, I don't want to argue with you.
I will one day show you who I am
and what I have come here to be. - Eggs.
She is strange.
lf she is up, she throws water,
and if she's down, she fights.
Does she have a problem?
We have no vacancy to
offer you right now.
You won't get a job like that.
Dreaming of a good job, you
studied from childhood to youth.
Got reprimanded by teachers,
kept writing reams of papers.
And what did you learn? Monday comes
after Sunday. You get 4 eggs for
Rs.1 . You took the beating,
but someone else is
ruling. What did you learn?
1x2 makes 4, 4x2 makes
1? What did you learn?
How will you get a job like that?
Only if you watch the world
standing on your head will you see it
straight. lf you don't
keep weight(bribe) on
your application, it will be
lost. And weights are of different
colours, different types.
The weight of black money,
the weight of a beautiful
body. The weight of bullies.
You won't get a job like that.
What is very dear, what
can be lost very easily.
Look through the torn sole of your
shoe, and you'll see the truth.
Your shoe will seem
big, and the world small.
Your destiny will fall apart.
Did the shoe have to tear today?
I have to go for an interview.
What happened? Why are
you walking like that?
Have you sprained your leg?
- No Pandey uncle.
My shoe sole tore.
- Your shoe tore?
You are laughing? It’s a
question of saving my grace.
I have to go for an interview today.
You will surely get the
job, my heart says so.
Where are you going?
- To get vegetables.
But you have sprained
your foot. I'll get them.
It’s not too bad. I'll be
back soon, you take rest.
Must you do everything yourself?
You are going for an interview,
and look at your gait. Great!
What a gait! Keep limping.
lf they ask who I am,
I'll say, I am a cripple.
Cripple. Keep limping like cripples.
What kind of a joke is this?
You could not argue, so you
have stooped to this now?
What do you mean?
You should feel ashamed
to misbehave like that.
How did I misbehave with you?
imitating girls in the street,
teasing them, is a very decent act?
Look, don't spoil my mood early
morning. You go if you like.
Why should I go? You go.
- You want to go, you go.
Strange man you are. You are
asking me to go, why don't you go?
Alright, I only will go.
You are always fighting.
You are teasing me again? Rogue, loafer!
Why are you calling me names?
I'm helpless, that's why I
am tolerating your nonsense.
Look, my shoe is torn.
Are you satisfied now?
As it is, I am upset, moreover,
you are calling me names.
I am not a loafer, I am an engineer.
Those people who make homes...
Please mend this.
- It will cost you Rs.20.
I have only this much money.
Please make do with it.
Actually, I have to attend an interview.
lf I don't reach in
time, I'll have a problem.
No sir, I won't take
anything less than Rs.20.
Take.
Dagdu, take this, and hurry.
- Dagdu, return her money.
I don't want your money.
I'm sorry I made a mistake.
- I don't want anyone's favour...
I am giving it to you as a
loan, not doing you any favour.
Return it to me when you get a job.
Okay?
We cannot give you any job in this firm.
I wanted this job...
But sir, I badly need
this job. You can...
Father, I'll just be back.
- What is the matter?
I'll just be back.
Look God, whatever you
are doing is not right.
Have you sent me from Darjeeling to
Bombay to run from pillar to post?
Look, my pocket is empty, my time
bad, and even my shoe tore today.
Go and see outside.
I had to take a loan
from a girl...a girl!
I truly feel like crying now.
But I am a man, I cannot even cry.
Enough now God, I cannot
tolerate it anymore.
Do something for me.
You?
- I'd come to ask...
Look don't worry,
I'll return your Rs.20.
I'm not asking for money What
happened at the interview?
What will happen? Even they felt
I am not suitable for their firm.
So what have you thought of doing?
- What is left to think now?
Look Renu, I'm very sorry. In
my zeal, I was talking big that
day. But now I
understand you were right.
What is the harm in
taking up a small job?
Good you changed your mind.
Father is home. Meet him,
maybe he can help you.
No...
- Come on!
I have written a letter for Mr.
Kavas. I hope he can help you.
You have taken the right decision.
Until you don't get a job...
as per your qualification,
take up this job.
Come on, it's time for the library
to close down. Can't you hear the
bell? Close the books. It’s 5:30.
Come at 10 am tomorrow.
Come on, pack up everyday.
Geeta, pack up. Why don't
you eat? You are so skinny.
Come tomorrow.
Didn't you hear the bell?
- Let me finish the last list.
No, I have never done overtime,
nor let anyone else work overtime.
You must come at 10 am,
and leave at 5:30 pm.
You close at 5:30 everyday?
- Sharp 5:30!
That's great.
- You've learnt my language.
Geeta, don't forget that file.
I had not come to meet you. I am
working in the library these days...
so I had come to deliver some
books here to a shopkeeper.
But his shop was closed.
Then I noticed this building.
And I realized it was your
building, so I came to peep in.
You came to deliver
books to a shopkeeper?
Yes, at the corner here.
- So where are the books?
I'm caught.
- Yes, you are.
Actually, I wanted to meet you.
Actually, even I wanted
that you come and meet me.
Really?
Shall we go?
- Yes.
Abdul, serve two halves to Pandit.
- Yes, two special...
Keep one on my table.
Give me a pack of biscuits.
Hey! Do you see what I see?
What are you doing?
- What happened?
Both are coming together?
An air plane in water
and a ship in the air?
5:45.
- Let me see... 5:45.
Leave her hand.
Jai, you deliberately rode between them.
Hey, no messing.
Look there.
We'll have to go now.
They were at war until yesterday,
today they are at peace.
Be at it!
- Why are you behaving like that?
Have you never seen a girl before?
Bye.
- Bye...just a minute.
Going?
He's coming here.
Guys, now the girl's door will open
& she will come out on the pretext
... of drying an already dry towel.
'Dil diya dard liya' running in Roxy
She did it!
Now?
- The hero will act stylish.
Then he will slyly make
a gesture at his beloved.
He will make a gesture now.
Now?
The girl will coyly drum
her fingers on the parapet.
The girl will now drum her fingers.
She did!... Now?
Caring a damn about the world, she
will throw a flying kiss at the boy.
And he will catch it like Azharuddin.
The girl will throw a kiss.
He caught it.
Jai, you are a champion.
Where did you learn it?
Experience!
Even you were in love?
- Very deeply.
What was the name of the girl?
- Madhumati.
But you said Bandhini the other day.
- She came later.
The first one was Madhumati.
I was deeply in love with her.
Why didn't you marry her?
- I forgot.
The girl's father has come.
He's come!
What will happen now?
Nothing, he'll water
the plant and leave.
He's gone.
Listen to this... 'That light pole'
'Those leaves'
The heart will meet the heart.
Bye.
- Bye.
Manoj, give madam grams. I don't
have change. Madam, pay him.
Manoj, I have notes!
- He's become a rich man.
Take.
Renu, we sit and eat
grams here everyday.
Let's go somewhere,
freak around, eat Chinese.
And blow away the whole
month’s salary in a day.
And then ask for loans.
- Yes. You will give me?
Not at all. We are not going anywhere.
Such good breeze is
blowing here. Stay here.
Stay here indeed! We sit here everyday.
Look how much money I
have. 1 , 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
I'll keep the money.
- No, I want to spend it all.
Alright, keep one.
Keep one more.
Enough! We'll spend
the rest of the money.
But why?
- Don't argue.
We'll treat ourselves to Chinese.
No, there is no need.
We are very tired walking.
Let's buy a small car.
You started it again? Let's go home.
No, we won't go home. lf
we do, we'll go by car.
Are you crazy? Have
you seen your pocket?
I have very little
money, but huge desires.
Desires cannot buy you a car.
- Everything is possible with
desires. Come on! For some time.
- No! Don't stop me today. Come on.
- But why go inside?
I want to buy a car.
Why don't you understand?
We want to buy a car.
- Car?...you want to buy a car? Yes.
- Both of you? Yes, both of us.
- Want to buy a car? lf you don't mind,
I want to ask you something. Go ahead.
- Buying a car for the first
time? Isn’t it? Even I am selling
a car for the first time. Oh great!
- It’s my first day in
the show room. Please come.
- I'll have a look at the cars.
Look, we don't want to buy any car.
Raju, let's go. Wait!
Look at his face. The poor
man will be heart broken.
It’s his first day to work.
Sir, don't worry. Tell me
about the car features. Features?
There are so many. Come.
- No, I don't... Look
at its body, its colour,
its size, the model,
its wipers! Look inside.
It has everything. Take a look inside.
I saw it all. Shall we go now?
Can we sit inside?
- Of course! Come.
Not you...madam.
Me?
- Please come.
Renu, get in.
I'll go and sit on the
other side. Renu, I'm coming.
Madam, we'll go for a long drive.
Excuse me, we'll wind up the
glasses to see how it feels.
Renu, those who have such cars
must be having so much fun.
Raju, he is standing
outside, sit properly.
He can't see a thing, I
have wound up the glass.
But he is looking here.
- You look at me, don't look there.
You look so beautiful. Give me a kiss.
Are you in your senses?
- No, not at all.
Where does one get
such a chance in Bombay?
Raju please!
- He cannot see anything.
You have become very brazen.
Sorry...you took very long, so...
Renu, what happened?
We like the car, but
madam is in a bad mood.
Look, it's enough now, let's go.
- See! I told you she's off mood.
You convince her.
- Madam, please don't be in a bad
mood. Actually, you are right.
What a lovely car this
is. And look at this car.
It’s such a lovely colour.
Darling, shall we buy both the cars?
- Both? Yes, both.
We'll take both the cars.
But what will we do with two cars?
I'll take one for shopping,...
and you use the other to drop
Bablu and Pappu to school.
Our kids, Bablu and Pappu.
Nice names. Sir look, madam
has been convinced now.
I'll go and make the bill.
- Just a minute...What is your name?
My name? Lovechand Kukreja.
- Mr. Kukreja, there's a problem.
No problem sir, I'll help
you. What's the problem?
We don't have money.
You don't have money? And
you had come to buy two cars?
Madam wanted...
Let's go, Renu.
Wait.
Lovechand, I will
surely come back one day.
And buy a car for her.
That's a promise.
Come.
Hey!
- Sorry! They were rejection letters.
Didn't get a job?
- Where do you get jobs in your city?
You'll get one.
- Oh yeah?
Sorry...you...
How are you?
Sorry, I got late.
But I have brought a surprise
for you in this envelope.
Want to have grams? Take, eat.
Why are you sitting sullen?
- Then should I laugh like you?
Why not?
- Stop laughing!
Your city is horrible!
It’s got a population of 10 million,
but a man cannot get a job here!
Look, don't blame Bombay.
What has the city done to you?
Damn your Bombay! Damn it!!
Hey! Who is it? Can't you see?
I'm sorry.
- Are you hurt?
Continue.
You'll hurt someone.
- What do I do?
They are popping out of
everywhere. Even earlier...
I know now. I can't do
anything in this city.
Bombay!
I am destined to work
in that damned library.
Poor Raju! Have grams.
But this envelope contains
a bumper lottery,...
opening which, your destiny will shine.
You will have a car,
bungalow, money, everything.
Have a look.
- No, I am not that lucky.
Raju! That was your interview call.
- My interview call?
That too, from our company.
- Chhabria Constructions?
And you tore it.
- Why did you give it to me?
Pick it up!
It’s my interview call! Do
your romance later, help me.
You leave, please.
You didn't tell me...
Take.
- What now?
What? We'll stick it, what else?
The annual report is
lying at home, read it.
I'm Rishi Vaswani, I've
come for an interview.
Please sit there.
Yes.
- You may go in.
The Howrah Bridge suspension.
Mr. Mathur, you have just done
a diploma in civil engineering.
Whereas, even degree holders
have applied for the job.
I don't understand.
He means to ask why
we should appoint you.
Because a degree only gives
you a certificate, not brains.
Which you have?
- Yes.
Can you prove it?
- Of course.
How?
Take Shakti Nagar, your
construction in Delhi.
You take great pride in it.
- Why won't we?
It is one of the posh and
best complexes in Delhi.
That's very true, and you put in
about 300 million rupees in it.
The RCC component would
be 150 million rupees?
That accounts to so
much wastage of money.
Yes, and if you used load
bearing bricks walls...
your budget would be 35 %.
The other expenses including labor
would come to 25 million rupees.
Where you have spent 150 million,
you would only spend 100 million.
Call this a saving of 50 million,
or a profit of 50 million.
What does your computer say?
Modi, who made this complex?
- Sir, not me....
So you made this complex?
That means...
- That means I must get this job.
Meet me later, Mr. Saxena.
''Our colony is celebrating today''
''Everyone is lost in gaiety.
''Our Raju is a hero,
and we are Raju's fans''
''Raju has become a gentleman!''
''Even my stars have shined''
''Water has gushed out of a stone''
''Lost in my own world''
''I hide what's in my heart''
''My heart is now at peace''
''It used to be so restless''
''Raju has become a gentleman!''
''You will have the world
at your feet one day''
''You will be very successful one day''
''God will continually
shower his mercy on you now''
''Raju has become a gentleman!''
''Despite your presence, it is
money that rules your world''
''Money is the God of the world,
what kind of a God are you?''
''It is now I realise
even you are like me''
''Money...money...money...''
''Running after money, the world
has forgotten everything else''
''Raju has become a gentleman!''
''Sing and play the band''
''I am crazy about you, you are my love''
''You have done a great
job, you are Superman''
Gentlemen, this is project Dreamland.
In America, with the help
of a senior architect...
I designed it keeping
the Indian middle class in mind.
There will be 12 multi
storied buildings in it.
And even a swimming pool.
What do you all have to say?
I think, this will be the first
project of its kind in India.
Why not also have a disco?
In fact, I even want a gym, where
there will also be tennis courts.
That will help in selling
our project easily...
You want to say something?
- I... no.
I'm Raj Mathur.
He's Raj Mathur, assistant
engineer, he has joined recently.
lf you want to say something, say
it. lf you want to laugh, go outside.
It’s nothing like that.
- Then what it is?
I was just saying...
- Stand up and talk.
The project you are talking
about is for the common man?
Yes, why?
Then this swimming pool,
jogging park, gymnasium...?
I don't know which world you live in.
Shall I sit?
Why, what's wrong in it?
What are you trying to say?
Sir, I want to say... what is it?
I want to say that those
whose life itself is a jog...
whose children play hockey
with a broken stick...
Madam, hockey is our national game.
and kick a burst ball...
for them, even thinking of
a swimming pool, gymnasium...
and like sir said, a
disco, is a cruel joke.
Madam, these middle income people...
don't want status, they want facilities.
Don't give them a gym,
give them a school.
Give them a bus stop, a hospital.
Give them clean drinking
water, like this.
lf you give them all
this, they will bless you.
And if you don't give them all this,
your Dreamland project will be a
ruin. Because the rich won't
go so far for a flat. And
the middle income class
won't be able to afford it. Am I right?
- Yes... I mean... no. And
if it's no, what's the
sense in making this
building? Believe me, madam.
Who are you to advice us?
Mr. Saxena, teach him how
to speak in a board room.
Saxena, understood what Malhotra said?
- Yes sir. Then hurry up.
Sir...
- You are acting over intelligent.
You spoilt...
- But you said it was alright.
But sir, tell me, what is my fault?
Fault? Call it carelessness.
You challenged the management.
The company from which
you want your salary...
Sapna madam is the only daughter
of it's owner, Mr. Chhabria.
What?
- Yes!
Sir, do you have a revolver,
a knife, a dagger, a blade?
Blade? You think I am a pick pocket?
Sir, listen to me. I was dumb.
I've got this job with great difficulty.
And you'll lose it with equal ease.
Do you know what he did
at the board meeting?
He wants a bus stop for the poor
people, a school, a hospital.
He doesn't want a jogger's park, he
doesn't want a swimming pool, a gym.
Then what does he want? He
said all this in the board
meeting. And do you know to whom?
- Whom? Sapna madam.
Renu, you typed his
appointment letter a week ago.
Now type is dismissal
letter. He's lost his job.
What will happen now? Mr. Saxena
should have told me she is...
What happened, Raj?
- I am ill-fated.
How was I to know Sapna
is the boss' daughter?
I unnecessarily got into an
argument with her in the meeting.
What now?
Raj, Mr. Chhabria has
called you to his room.
I've lost my job! Renu, I
don't want to lose this job.
Don't say that,
everything will be alright.
You go and apologise to her.
Big people often forget small matters.
This is no small matter. She
got angry and left the meeting.
Now that she has called
you, you will have to go.
Yes.
Renu, you also come along with me.
- Me? Raju, I'll stay here.
You'll stay here? Don't go, please.
I'll stay here, and wait for you.
Don't be afraid.
Just a minute.
Sir, before you say anything,
I'd like to say something.
I know I made a mistake,
I should not have argued.
You can see how upset I am. Actually,
I have a problem since childhood.
I cannot sleep. And until I
cannot sleep....I stay awake.
And when I am awake, I keep thinking.
Madam, that's my problem.
I cannot sleep at night...
I stay awake. lf I stay
awake, I don't sleep.
And if I don't sleep, I keep thinking.
And if I don't think, I speak.
You understand my problem, madam?
Look how much I am talking even now,
because I have not slept at night.
I was thinking something last night,
& said something else in the meeting.
And in all the confusion,
I argued with madam.
I had no intention to trouble you.
Drink water.
One feels thirsty too,
when one cannot sleep.
Mr. Mathur, whatever you
said in the board meeting...
the suggestions that you made...
I want you to repeat those
suggestions before us again.
I only wanted to say...
- Then say it.
Yes...Madam, I didn't mean what
I said in the board meeting.
You didn't understand...
- Then explain to me, Mr. Mathur.
Yes.
It’s time to close the office.
Mr. Mathur, Sapna and I
liked your suggestions.
And we have decided to
give you a promotion.
You liked my suggestions? Sir,
I have many more suggestions...
This is enough for today.
Mr. Mathur, we respect
people who work diligently.
But remember one thing.
I understand, sir. I will work hard.
Sapna, you want to say something?
From now on, we will work together.
And am sure we will do good work.
''There is a heart in my chest''
''Heartbeats in my heart''
''And just you in those heartbeats''
''You are my first desire''
''And my last wish!''
''The weather melts into colours...''
''that you come in''
''My mornings and evenings...''
''all come under your lashes''
''Sleep in my eyes, dreams in my
sleep, and only you in my dreams''