Some people live a wretched life!
And some people live by killing!
Babban... was such a man.
No!
You all know what he did with me.
My life has only one aim!
Revenge from Babban!
And for that... fate
send both of them.
Heero and Raj!
Greetings, sir! Let me
carry your luggage!
Give!
Hey! First tell me how
much will you charge?
Sir, don't abuse me!
Money is volatile!
Today here! Tomorrow there!
I don't know where it will
be day after tomorrow!
Come on!
Take both of them!
300 rupees!
- 300 rupees!
- Yes!
But inside you were saying we
are guests. Guest is God.
So God only gives the offering!
Hey! Come on! Give me 300 rupees!
The train is about to arrive!
I don't have much time!
- What if we don't pay?
- What?
What if we don't pay?
I will whistle... and my entire
gang will arrive here!
You both will leave in an ambulance
and not in this cab!
Got it! Come on! Don't talk too much!
- Give me money! Come on!
- Whistle!
Where is your gang?
Scoundrel! We have come to
Mumbai for the first time!
So you think we are fools!
We have seen 3000 samples like you!
Now get lost! Come on!
Listen! Come here!
- Here!
- Let it be, sir!
Keep it! You have earned it!
Now get lost!
I think we will gel well with Mumbai!
Where is Rambha-bhai's address?
You thought that Rambha-bhai
will help you.
You are wrong!
I am the goon of Mumbai!
Not some ordinary man!
What are you doing?
Supplying guns is my side business.
It's just a matter of a few days.
Once I get promoted to
the post of a shooter...
Rambha-bhai, somebody
has come to meet you!
Heero! Darling! You and here?
Yes! I had to come!
And he too has come along with me!
Raj!
Rambha-bhai!
What happened, darling? Is
everything fine in Nasik?
Was? What about the present?
After that Heero-bhai was in trouble.
And he had a fight with some enemies.
I made a mistake. I
thrashed a policeman!
Darling... you were working as Mr.
Sahil, that MLA's bodyguard!
- He went away!
- Where?
- In a scam!
- Scam?
- Get me a nice job!
- Job? Nice?
That too in Mumbai? For you both?
Come on, darling! Leave! Go!
But Heero-bhai... you said this
Rambha... is a useful man.
I am the most useful man!
Job is not a girl of my locality!
That I call her and she will come!
Am I right, darling!
Rambha-bhai! We don't need
a girl! We need a job!
- And the payment too should be good!
- Is that so?
And the job too should be simple!
Anything else? Meals included?
Darlings, I will think of something!
Why did you both come to Mumbai?
If we had thought, then we wouldn't...
have come to Mumbai, sir.
Darling!
Are you both alone?
When we both are together,
how can we be alone?
Bhai, he means to say that
they both together...
will do abundant work for you!
They both are all-rounder!
Driver cum bodyguard cum,
jack of all trades.
They will be your special men
round the clock, darling.
Advance.
Hey! Make arrangement of their stay!
Love you, darling!
He paid us advance handsomely.
We didn't earn so much even
in 6 months in Nasik!
Bowled! Now throw the
ball! It's my turn!
- Hey!
- That's why we have come to Mumbai!
We are concerned just
with earning money!
Whether we get the work from
Mr. Shambhu or Bambu!
What difference does that make?
You are right!
"We will live countless moments
in this short life."
"When Raj and Heero are there,
there is no problem."
"The whole world will take notice."
"We will do such a deed."
"If we can't do anything,
then no problem."
"We will sing."
"Whatever we want."
"No matter how, no problem."
"Friend!"
"We will forget the memories."
"All day, all night we will
forget all the things."
"We will look at beautiful girls."
"And give solace to our eyes."
"I will entice her."
"You can't entice her."
"I will entice another girl."
"No problem, friend."
"There is no problem."
"Hey! What style!"
"We will live now."
"Now smile."
You people think the
police didn't do...
the right thing by nabbing you both.
Yes! Because the police does less
duty... and more mistakes.
Correct!
- You mean... you both are innocent.
- Yes!
I am in the police force
for the past 20 years.
And for the past 20 years...
I have been...
hearing the same thing
from criminals.
It's not about what you say or hear!
It's about the truth!
And we both are telling the truth!
Yes!
I think they both are innocent!
But, sir! If that is the
case then how come...
they both are working
for Mr. Shambhu?
Why are you both working
Because he is a straight man!
And he also pays us handsomely!
You both never thought...
why he pays so much?
Why should we think?
He is giving, fine!
But what do you mean?
Have you heard Bhai Zakar's name?
He is UP's biggest gangster!
In Mumbai Shambhu works for him!
The police are after Shambhu
for the past 5 years!
More than 40 murder cases and...
many kidnappings charges
are against him.
But we never found any
evidence against him!
You just think.
What is unique about you both?
What is your qualification?
What is your experience?
That he is paying
you both handsomely!
He is paying because he
wants to buy you both!
He wants you both to keep mum!
It's not necessary for you
people to believe me!
You people are working for him.
He must have seen something
in you both.
What I am saying...
how far it is true?
You only think!
You talk about the truth!
So try to understand the truth too!
If you understand it...
help the police.
Remember that day Mr.
Shambhu had called.
At Saki Naka.
And after making the call,
he threw the phone.
Yes!
Sir, you can't get better cocaine
than this all over the world.
Seems like I have seen you before.
I think I have never seen you before.
Then everything is fine,
what is the problem.
What is your name?
Gonsalves, Anthony Gonsalves.
- Amar, Amar Akbar.
- And I am Rambha-bhai.
You scoundrel.
- Inspector sir.
- If we try to save him...
then we will be killed.
Tell me clearly, are you
a goon or the police.
Or else I will shoot you.
Just a minute, just a minute,
just a minute...
if you want, you can shoot me.
But before your bullets
can reach me...
brother Heero will shoot Shambhu.
- Where is he?
- Behind those boxes.
Or behind those doors.
Or he can be under the ground too.
Stop confusing me, and tell me
clearly what you want to do.
Let us all sit and think...
we will find someone solution.
What is that noise?
It is not the police.
I am telling you it
is not the police.
And now we will join the police too.
Yes.
Come on.
I am helpless to arrest you both.
Knowingly or unknowingly,
according to the law...
you both worked for Shambhu.
I will try my best that both of you...
are given minimum sentence.
Thanks.
Thanks for everything.
"If you have the courage,
come ahead."
"Move ahead."
"Lock horns with fire."
"If you have the courage,
come ahead."
"Move ahead."
"Look straight in the eye."
"If you have the courage,
come ahead."
"Look straight in the eye."
"This is a fire..."
"This will not stop..."
"This will not extinguish..."
"This is a fire..."
"No one make the mistake
of touching it."
"Smoke is everywhere..."
"How can you breath in this fire?."
"This is a fire..."
What did I tell you?
Brother, that don... do you know him?
He offered me a job.
They asked me to join the gang.
- But I said no.
- But why?
Because Rambha-bhai doesn't
work under anyone...
only gives orders, darling.
That's why I became Mumbai's
biggest goon.
Biggest goon, but I never heard
your name ever before.
Illiterate person, that's
why I am the biggest goon!
Otherwise I would be
locked in the jail.
But you are in jail right now.
I came on my own will darling.
Sometimes in the underworld,
you have to go underground.
By why did you have
to go underground?
This is not the time to help anyone.
That police commissioner
is my friend.
I thought that I should help him.
He wanted to catch two very
dangerous terrorists.
So for doing a good
deed I helped him...
they both were caught but,
the matter reached Delhi.
And after Delhi, America's
C.I.A got involved.
4-5 countries called for
a meeting together...
the presidents.
So helplessly, India
had to surrender me.
Really.
Something terrible happened
after that.
After that America's C.I.A and
the Al-Qaida had a meeting.
America's C.I.A and the Al-Qaida.
Yes. Because I am so wanted darling.
This is a very big quagmire.
- Where was I?
- In the meeting.
After that, both of them forgot
their enmity and came after me.
Who is it, you are ruining my hair.
America's C.I.A, you scoundrel.
And Al-Qaida, here.
You scoundrel, we trusted you
and now we have been arrested.
Darling, I have been arrested too.
Listen to me carefully,
from today for one year...
we will hit you on the
head, and you will...
keep getting shorter inch by inch.
No!
How are you?
- You were not there last time.
- I was right here.
What are you saying?
He was taller then us.
"This is a fire..."
"This will not stop..."
"This will not extinguish..."
"This is a fire..."
"No one make the mistake
of touching it."
"Smoke is everywhere..."
"How can you breath in this fire?."
Inspector sir.
Please don't say that you have
come to arrest us again.
Now I am not in the police.
Congratulations.
How?
- Accident.
- What happened?
There is no need for
you to know that.
Then why did you want to meet us.
There is a work.
Last time we worked for you,
we were jailed for a year.
How many years now.
I told you, I am not
in the police now.
What is the work and what will we get?
8 lakh.
Because that's all I have.
What is the work?
The entire countries
police are confused.
And he asks us, get me Babban.
Yes sir, do you want anything else?
Bring a Babban fry.
That famous gangster.
Go, bring the bill.
We should have laughed at the
inspector like this too.
If you give it a thought,
the money is not bad.
You fool, if we don't catch Babban...
then how will we get the money.
We have just come out of the jail...
and we don't have any work too.
Why don't we try?
What is the harm?
Shall we toss?
Let us go.
Will you take us to Kaliganj?
Brother, Kaliganj.
Rajnikant, is the auto empty.
No, the bedbugs are getting
married in the backseat...
can't you see?
Smarty, where is the driver?
Are you blind or insane?
What do you think,
I am sitting here...
to entertain boys like you.
I am the driver.
But you are a girl.
So, is it written in
the Bhagvad Gita...
that girls cannot drive the rickshaw.
Let's talk business, where
do you want to go?
Kaliganj, you do know
the way don't you?
I know it since I was this small.
- Ask me how?
- Really, how?
Because I was born there.
We have to go to inspector
Narsimha's house.
Don't say that you know him too.
I was so small.
But how?
Because she was born there.
You like to talk nonsense.
Let it be, my friend likes to joke.
Ask your friend to keep
his jokes to himself.
Ghungroo doesn't like jokes.
Did you hear?
What do you like Ghungroo?
Don't act to smart.
Is this meter just for showpiece,
it doesn't work.
On the way to Kaliganj, there
are a lot of potholes.
And you will be completely shaken
while reaching there.
Really.
And if the axel breaks, then
the expenses will be...
Double.
I will have to give the
rickshaw in the garage.
Not by the meter, it
will cost you 200...
fine if you agree, or you can leave.
Okay, then we will take
another rickshaw.
Keep quiet!
My friend is a bit miser,
we want to go.
At the back.
Come on.
Can I help you?
Ghungroo never takes
anyone else's help!
But who is this Ghungroo?
- I already told him that...
- She has been saying it...
for so long, you are acting to smart.
- Sorry Ghungroo, shall we go?
- When did I say no?
Ghungroo, you drive the auto so well.
Even the male drivers
are no match for you.
- Do you know why?
- Why?
Because I have been
driving the auto...
since I had to look after my house.
Quiet, you talk so much.
Why is Laila written on the auto?
Because the name of
the auto is Lalia.
I have kept it according
to the numerology.
If someone castes a
bad eye on the auto...
then it won't be harmed.
Inspector sir's house has come.
And here is your 200 rupees.
- Give me 150.
- But...
But we had decided on 200 rupees.
It was, but you are good people...
and you are the guests
of the inspector.
- So I was thinking...
- Thank you for the discount.
No, no, keep it.
- What happened?
- Don't touch.
Mr. Shyam, this is Heero
and this is Raj.
They have come to meet the inspector.
- This is 1 lakh.
- But you said 8 lakh.
I said 8 lakh for the work,
this is advance.
I am going to the clinic.
Would you like to have something?
- You.
- Coffee.
Being near the sea, this piece
of land in Kaliganj...
have become priceless.
And now Babban has cast
his sight on this land.
The people that live here...
have been living here for
many ages and not years.
That's why they are not ready
to leave this place...
at any cost.
If you can help them in
protecting this land...
First he asks us to catch Babban.
Then he asks us to protect the land.
I am fully assured that the
inspector is completely insane.
Atleast we got advance.
When we are not going
to do the work...
then what is the use of the advance.
Have you lost your mind?
We came here, this money is for that.
That means after taking the money...
Bravo.
Have another drink, it is free too.
As soon as everyone falls
asleep, we will...
It is not your mistake,
inspector sir...
made a mistake by calling you here.
He is living in the
misconception that...
anyone will come and help
him in this battle.
I have only one request to you.
Take the money that inspector
sir has given you.
But find a way so
that he is not hurt.
He has tolerated a lot.
He doesn't have the strength
to tolerate anything else...
nor do I to see it.
Who lives in this house?
Inspector sir and madam.
And the others?
Babban killed everyone else.
Devi, we have decided to stay here!
We had come just to say...
that we will live here!
- Rehmad!
- Yes, father!
Where is the scissors?
Scissors! Scissors!
Did you pay the electricity bill?
Father, I went there twice.
The first time there
was a long queue!
And the second time... it was Sunday!
Very good! Now you can't
even remember the days!
Where is your mind nowadays?
- Shall I tell you?
- You?
- No, no!
- Tell me!
- Shall I tell you?
- Yes, dear!
In looking after you! What else?
Looking after me? Don't joke, dear!
Rehmad wastes his time on all
nonsense things in the world.
Except on himself.
And suddenly he disappears.
Without informing anybody!
- Shall I tell him where you had gone?
- No, no! - What?
He comes to me! For advice!
I give him some wisdom.
What is right in life, what is wrong!
Ahmed, learn! Learn something
from Ghungroo!
What is called responsibility!
Being a girl, she runs
the entire household!
Time for prayers!
You will have to get married!
The entire Kaliganj trembles on
hearing Gangu mummy's name!
And you don't even listen to me!
Mummy! You have asked
me so many times!
And I have told you so many times!
I don't want to marry!
Since when that Tukaram's
family is after us!
He has his own general store!
At the corner of the street!
The guy is nice! Hey!
So you want me to marry
a general store vendor?
Now it's enough! Hey! Explain
to your daughter!
If she behaved like this then not
even a fool will marry Ghungroo!
- You have a gun?
- Then what!
This is great! From
where did you get it?
When I was returning from America...
I stopped over at Iraq
and bought it from there!
It must be difficult to shoot.
It's easy! Really easy!
You see I was in the police
force and army too!
Your shirt is good!
This is enough!
You were in the police
force and army too?
Yes! Do you want to learn?
Me? Will I be able to use the gun?
Ghungroo... when being a girl
you can ride the auto...
then using the gun is nothing!
You are right! Come on!
The first rule in shooting is...
to concentrate on the aim.
You should not concentrate on
what is happening around you.
Why?
What do I know? It's the rule! Yes!
- Wink!
- Wink?
I mean... close your left eye...
and aim with the right eye!
What? Come on!
- You are really too much!
- What happened?
What happened? I know everything!
Where is your attention and your aim!
Hey! Ghungroo!
O Ghungroo!
Ghungroo!
"Stop!"
"Where are you going?."
"Why are you angry?."
"Hey you! Get lost!"
"Why are you after me?."
"Move from my way!"
"Why are you upset?."
"Why are you quarrelling?."
"You don't understand. What to do?."
"What to do?."
"Stop!"
"Where are you going?."
"Why are you angry?."
" Hey you! Get lost!"
"Why are you after me?."
" Move from my way!"
"You are Jhansi Ki Rani."
"You are Hitler's grandma."
" Bruce Lee's student."
"Ghungroo!"
"You are the King of goons."
"You are useless."
"You are a bluff master!"
"Heero!"
"Don't make an issue out of nothing!"
"Do you think I am an idiot?."
"What to think? You are an idiot!"
- "Why are you acting smugly?
- What?."
- "It happens at times!
- Is that so?."
"Just take it easy."
"Ghungroo!"
"I swear."
"I won't spare you!"
"I will drive the auto over you!"
"Heero!"
"I am an innocent and simple man."
"Go and fool somebody else."
"It's just a misunderstanding."
"Stop!"
"Where are you going?."
"Why are you angry?."
"Hey you! Get lost!"
"Why are you after me?."
"Move from my way!"
"Why are you upset?."
"Why are you quarrelling?."
"You don't understand. What to do?."
"What to do?."
Inspector!
Inspector! Tambhe had called!
What did he say?
He is sending Dhania tomorrow.
He is Pradhan.
Everybody respects him.
Babban thinks that...
By pressurizing him, his
work will be done!
Hit the iron when it's hot!
Yes!
Pradhan!
Order tea!
- No!
- What? You don't have tea?
Yes! But I won't give
it to goons like you.
What did you say?
Can't you hear? I called
you a goon! A goon!
Listening to my threats...
has made him lose his mind!
Hey! If Babban found out
about your new ruse...
Sorry!
Come on! Leave!
Now we will have fun!
When Babban will receive
the breaking news!
How many?
- How many?
- Two.
One... two...
Tambhe!
How much money has the government
spend to nab me?
Don't know for sure!
Must be 100 crores!
This expenditure is incurred... so
that every policeman's wife...
doesn't fast for Karvyachaut
but for Babban Singh!
And you three people are
tarnishing my name!
I made a mistake!
It's my mistake! Mine! Not yours!
Low grade people!
Stood against me!
My name!
Tarnishing my name! My name!
- What do you say?
- He should be punished!
Correct! Correct! Correct!
Punishment should be given!
- How many bullets are in this?
- 6!
Remove 2! 4 bullets for 4 people!
No injustice!
Sit!
I have drawn the line!
Now I will spin this!
If the barrel points
at you, you are dead!
If at me...
I... I...
- What?
- I... I...
Did you say something?
- What?
Tambhe! He too fooled death!
Now?
This is... nobody's friend.
If this fires... then you are dead!
Tambhe!
After so many years too... they
still don't understand...
that even Babban himself
doesn't trust his words.
We have launched
the attack on Babban.
Now he must be retaliating
at jet speed!
Pradhan! Tell everybody!
If any unknown man is
seen in our area...
Along with weapon,
you should always...
be prepared for the attack.
I will kill both of them right away!
Along with them 20-25
more Kaliganj people...
I will cause such violence that
forget going against Babban...
people will be scared
to even take his name!
What do you think?
You will go there... and Thakur
along with both of them...
will stand ready for your bullet?
And he will say come on and shoot!
If you don't calm down...
you harm your own self.
I won't make the same mistake
that America did with Iraq.
It's their area.
If you went there without
any preparation...
When is Diwali?
Careful sister.
Who are you calling sister?
Ghungroo, you.
- What are you wearing?
- Why?
Should you have worn it?
No, no you are such
a good looking girl...
you should wear clothes like these.
Like you.
- Don't joke with me.
- Okay.
First you joke with me then you lie.
Hey sparkler!
You are calling me sparkler.
I called a sparkler, sparkler.
Ghungroo, why do you
always think that...
If you dare look at me again
then I will blind you!
And I will put this sparkler
down your throat!
Did you understand?
Listen! I will pour kerosene on you...
- and throw a cigarette on you!
- Enough
No listen, I will sell your
burnt body in the scrap.
You won't find any buyer.
You won't be capable to kick
start too, understood!
You have such a criminal thinking.
You are just too much!
I respect you a lot.
Why?
So much happened, but still
you think about the people...
run the clinic, take care of them.
You do understand what I am saying?
What did you used to do earlier?
I get up in the morning
and sleep in the night...
and the next day, the same thing.
Actually... the meaningless
life that I am living...
I can understand it,
after seeing you.
After seeing Mr. Narsimha.
Even I have learnt a lot
of things from him.
You won't believe, before
losing his job...
he used to live very happily.
He lost his job because of his
fingers, isn't it? - Yes.
- How did it happen?
- It was an accident.
What happened?
I don't know, whenever I
ask him he never says.
Maybe he doesn't like to
think about the accident.
Anyway what is the use
thinking about it?
Naqvi sir! Naqvi sir!
Bhai, we have found one.
One of them has been found.
But... that other one
is still missing.
There is still some risk.
You don't understand feelings.
Like magnet!
Like magnet, he will draw
the other one out!
Hello Narsu.
Hello, hello, hello.
You have grown old, old.
Is everything fine, isn't it?
Have courage, have courage.
So this is one of Narsu's.
Where is the second?
Second!
Come out or I will blow first's head!
- I will count three, only three!
- Wait!
I am coming!
There he comes.
Come on.
Come.
Magnet.
What did I ask you for?
This land at the price of death.
That's not a crime!
And so what if it is a crime.
This is true, that's a lie,
that's injustice.
All of it is a lie.
Babban is the only reality.
Only Babban.
I am telling you one thing,
listen carefully.
Even Babban himself cannot save you...
from Babban's wrath.
What do you say?
Both of them...
Babban sir, I swear on you...
I didn't even know that
you are Babban sir.
- I was influenced by this Narsimha.
- Heero.
Please forgive us.
We didn't know that he was your man.
I am... prepared to fall at your
feet and... beg for mercy.
We don't have any personal enmities.
Please forgive me.
If you say, we will join your gang...
it is fine even if you give 4 lakh.
Sir.
Seems like he ran away.
He ran away.
Atleast he ran away.
After that day, we met today
for the first time.
Which day?
Since the day I joined
the police force...
I had only one motive,
to catch Babban.
The police never saw a
gangster like Babban.
There are some gangsters that
operate from other countries...
and some from within the jail.
Babban used to stay in this
city and operate openly.
I found out that he had
only one weakness.
Younger brother Amber.
Greetings.
I bought a sari and a gold chain.
You have become thin.
I have brought this for Yash.
And this too.
Police force.
Go, please.
Go from here.
Why did you come after all?
You ask me more questions
then I love you.
Because I am tired of giving
answers to people!
The police come every 15
days and interrogate me.
The channel people ask me all
sorts of question about you!
I am tired of it all, I am tired.
Look, if you want to give something...
then give me a promise!
That after today we will
never meet, that's all.
You have grown up.
You have grown up, you
say such big things.
You talk sense.
Stop Babban!
Or else I will kill your brother.
Go.
Keeping in mind all the
evidences and testimony...
the court has come
to the conclusion...
that the accused Babban
has been proven guilty...
for kidnapping and murder.
And so the court finds the
accused Babban guilty...
and life imprisonment under IPC 302.
I will not forget it.
The time you are going
to spend in jail...
you will forget everything.
Take him away.
Okay! Okay! Thank you!
Father! Father!
- Babban has received life sentence!
- Oh!
- Sister-in-law! Sister-in-law!
- Listen...
Father, you don't know how much
people are praising brother!
Sister-in-law!
Sister-in-law, listen!
Your dear husband has got
Babban life sentence!
Babban who?
- Babban who?
- Yes!
Had he been here... he would
have committed suicide!
Forget about Babban, Subbu!
Listen! Did you bring mixed spices
paste that I told you to bring?
What is this? Babban! Nonsense!
Waste of time!
Tell your department...
to give a medal too!
After all you have done
such a great deed!
I will give it to you as soon
as I finish work! - Okay!
Why have you come so late?
Kavita... you know!
But I had told you to come
early at least today!
Again the same thing!
You don't interfere, Subbu!
Not Babban, but you have got
life imprisonment, brother!
What is there to laugh so much?
Hey!
You think our marriage
is life imprisonment?
Subbu! Where are you going
after starting the quarrel!
Brother, quarrel precedes peace!
Narsimha!
What about Devi clinic's assistant?
I have made the arrangement.
Where is Devi?
"The colours clung to the body."
"Hug me like this."
"Why are you laughing?."
"I am in merriment."
"I am crazy. I am not bad."
"Let me go."
"Don't talk like this."
"It's just an excuse."
"Even you know that."
"Your eyes are bad."
"Even I know that."
"Leave me alone."
"It's Holi."
"The language of colours."
"Hear it."
"It's Holi."
"Attack of colours."
"Nobody can escape."
"The colours clung to the body."
"Hug me like this."
"Why are you laughing?."
"I am in merriment."
"I am crazy. I am not bad."
"You don't know me."
"I am multi-hued."
"Touch me and you will be
smeared with colours."
"Look at me covertly."
"Try to escape."
"Otherwise you will regret it."
"Leave! Leave! Leave!"
" Leave! Leave! Leave!"
"What will you do?."
"I am after you."
"Even I am not any less."
"I won't budge."
"Tell me."
"How can I let go of you?."
"It's Holi."
"The colours clung to the body."
"Hug me like this."
"Why are you laughing?."
"I am in merriment."
"I am crazy. I am not bad."
"Don't follow me."
"Listen, loafer."
"What do you think of me?."
"Stop!"
"Don't come after me!"
"Leave otherwise you will regret it."
"Carefully! Carefully! Leave! Leave!"
"Leave! Leave! Leave!"
"Carefully! Carefully!"
"What will you do?."
"I am after you."
"Even I am not any less."
"I won't budge."
"Tell me."
"How can I let go of you?."
"It's Holi."
"You have come."
"Why are you acting smugly?."
"We are carillon. You are bells."
"What saunter!"
"Mind-blowing!"
"Why won't anybody stare at you?."
"Let me see how you stare!"
"Don't talk like this."
"It's just an excuse."
"Even you know that."
"Your eyes are bad."
"Even I know that."
"Leave me alone."
"It's Holi."
"The language of colours."
"Hear it."
"It's Holi."
"Attack of colours."
"Nobody can escape."
- Hello!
- Why don't you answer me?
Why are you going for work today too?
Brother! Please drop us at clinic.
Sister-in-law... again
you have... - Sit quickly!
Okay! All right! Thank you!
Does anybody go for work on Holi?
- Go, go! Brother, go!
- Subbu!
What happened?
They came and...
Kavita!
Where is Kavita?
"This is a fire."
"...that never stops, that
is never quenched."
"This is a fire."
"Whoever touched it has burnt.
And somewhere only smoke is left."
"How can you breathe in this fire?."
"This is a fire."
"What makes it so dangerous?."
"Whoever touches it is burnt."
Untie me! Untie me!
- Untie me!
- Scoundrel!
Untie me! Untie me!
Scream! Scream more!
How is your family?
Don't be afraid!
I won't kill you! I won't kill you!
If I killed you then my
life will lose its fun!
This... finger.
You kill with this!
You like to kill! Point the
gun... press the trigger!
And the person is dead!
The counting begins! Counting!
You note it down!
You have killed countless people!
When I was a kid... I
used to play a lot!
I used to play with my brother!
Do you know what happened one day?
A boy came and slapped
my brother jokingly!
My brother's tooth broke.
I... chopped off his this part!
For my brother... I chopped
off his jaws!
And you killed my brother!
- Hey! Bring the chair!
- Yes!
Not here! There! More!
My brother loved spinning top!
Do you understand it? Like this...
with a nail at the bottom.
Spin the thread and throw it!
It spins! Spins! Spins!
If you took it in your hand,
it spins in your hand!
It tickles you!
It spins! Spins!
Spins!
Once a boy stole it from my brother!
Do you know what I did?
I nailed the top's nail in his skull!
In his skull!
And you killed my brother!
We both brothers used to fly kite!
On the terrace! Terrace!
Kite!
We both loved flying kites!
We used to fly it. Somebody
else used to fly it!
Once a boy tore my brother's kite!
Do you know what I did?
I threw him from the
top of the building!
You shouldn't have killed my brother!
This... you kill others with
these fingers, don't you?
You pull the trigger
and the man dies!
- He was a kid!
- Untie me!
Small... small... a small kid.
Not like you and me! A small
kid! He was a kid!
He considered me as his father!
More than strangers, he hated me!
He hated me! And you
killed my brother!
Tambhe!
If Dhanya's ghost comes and asks me...
you too ran away from there!
What will I tell him?
What has happened, it has happened.
Hey!
What happened... that never happened!
What never happened,
it will happen now!
Celebrate! Celebrate!
Celebrate the victory!
For the moment...
They began the game. I will end it.
Which game?
Why are you working
so slowly! Hurry up!
Calm down, Ghungroo!
How come you know my name?
I even know your mother's name!
- Gangu's mummy!
- Who are you?
Ddaruwala! Ddaruwala with double D!
I am a famous astrologer!
Famous! I am seeing you in Kaliganj
for the first time!
I have come to Kaliganj
So you are bound to see me
here for the first time!
So how come you are famous?
In my village! Safedganj!
How do you know my and
my mother's name?
If an astrologer can't
tell you your name...
then he is not an astrologer!
Laila!
You have named the auto
Laila as per numerology!
Am I right?
This is too much! I think
you are a top astrologer!
What top, what bottom!
I can only say a bit...
I can say that your henna, turmeric
ceremony and engagement...
nothing will happen!
- Then?
- Directly marriage!
With whom?
As per numerology, there
is an O in your name.
So your groom's name
should have two Es!
Kaleem?
If you married Kaleem... then you
will collide with Laila and die!
Then who?
There is somebody! Smart!
Handsome! Hero like!
- Who?
- He even has a gun!
- That Heero!
- Yes!
That goon, ruffian, loafer!
No! No! No!
Don't judge the book by its
cover! He is your lover!
Why? You don't like him?
That is not so!
He is a nice guy! He
speaks good English!
He doesn't speak English! He
only knows how to say yes!
So you too say yes!
Heero, you are right!
That is what I am saying!
- What did you say?
- You are right!
No! Before that!
You are right! Double E! Heero!
You have become mum now!
If you are smart, then Ghungroo
is smarter than you!
What do you think of yourself?
If I lost my temper... then
Laila will be over you!
I will squash you! You fool!
I am giving you last warning!
Laila! I mean... Ghungroo! Ghungroo!
- Listen to me!
- Leave!
I am sorry!
I just want to tell you one thing!
I love you a lot!
And I can't live without you!
Heero!
Mr. Narsimha wants to meet you!
Do you love me?
Yes!
I love you!
I have got information about Babban!
"Yeah! Yeah!"
"Come on!"
"Make way for my man!"
"That's right!"
"Check it out!"
"Come on!"
"Play beyond."
"Fire in the eyes."
"Body is smouldering."
"My sight is the enemy's senses."
"You are my beloved."
"My heart is crazy, beloved."
"My eyes, my breaths."
"My lips, my talks."
"Has stolen the heart of everybody
in this jamboree."
"Beloved, beloved."
"Beloved makes you lose your senses."
"Beloved steals your solace."
"You are my beloved."
"My heart is crazy, beloved."
Beloved! Beloved!
One there! And one here!
Both have killing nature!
Which death is more fun?
That is what is to be seen!
Hey, Tambhe! How will you die?
"Your fear has made
my beauty lethal!"
"Even death desires to
die with my hands."
"My heart is craving."
"My lips are thirsty."
"Don't torment me, beloved."
"Listen, beloved."
"To the words of dream."
"Heartbeats, beloved."
"My eyes do the work of the lips."
"Snatching anxiety,
I provide solace."
"This intoxication never wanes."
"I am that kind of intoxication."
"Love dances after drinking it."
"I am that merriment."
"Companion, beloved."
"Don't be stubborn, beloved."
"Just a glimpse, beloved."
"Over here, beloved."
"The dusks of my tresses."
"The twilight of my dreams."
"Has stolen the heart of everybody
in this jamboree."
"Beloved, beloved."
"Beloved makes you
lose your senses."
"Beloved, beloved."
"Beloved steals your solace."
"You are my beloved."
"My heart is crazy, beloved."
"Beloved, beloved."
At times even I think.
Of immersing myself in you.
What I fear is... what will
happen to you, beloved.
"Fire in the eyes."
"Beloved, beloved."
"Body is smouldering."
Hey! I am leaving!
"Beloved."
- "That's right."
- "Beloved, beloved."
- "Check it out!"
- "Come on!"
- "Beloved, beloved."
"Come on!"
"Check it out!"
What are you looking at?
Still not content, Mr. Babban!
There must have been many
girls in your life.
No! I never gave them the chance!
- Why?
- Love is a weakness.
Babban... is strength!
Delicate! Shall I read it?
What is written?
Babban!
Who is it?
Bhai! Bhai!
Get out of here!
- How did all this happen?
- Raj and Heero!
I don't know how they reached here!
They began firing as
soon as they arrived!
One of them is shot! Maybe...
Shyam! Shyam!
He has been shot!
What... how did this happen?
They had gone to kill Babban!
What did you get by sending them?
What right do you have?
Bring hot water!
You don't understand anything!
How much more...
Ghungroo, why are you standing! Go!
Go and call Jenny!
Its okay! Bring hot water!
Bring hot water! Medicine!
If you had got shot in your chest
then what would you have done?
You survived!
It's a minor thing!
Today seeing your blood...
I couldn't control myself.
After Subhash's death, I...
Subhash?
My husband! Fighting memories...
I was trying to live.
But today... seeing all this...
all the memories...
each thing I remembered it again.
I can't believe it!
That I spoke to him like this.
Knowing... that he has endured a lot.
Why does apple always fall down?
It's because of gravitation.
- What?
- Gravitation.
So how did it go up from below?
This is what has always happened!
That I have...
attacked others!
But today for the first time...
for the first time...
somebody... attacked me.
How did this information leaked?
I will tell you! Your
uncle is the informer!
No! Maternal uncle!
Tambhe!
This blood tie... is really bad!
It's really bad!
I didn't do it deliberately! In
the intoxication of drinks...
- It's really bad!
- I was...
Cat and mouse game... is
really entertaining!
Cat can't enter the hole.
The mouse can't stay in the hole.
So...
So Kaliganj's one mouse... will
surely come out of the hole.
Just wait!
Wait!
- Raj!
- What?
Ghungroo!
- Ghungroo?
- Ghungroo!
Yes! I have fallen in
love with Ghungroo!
What about Nasik's Kajri?
You have proposed to her too!
I was not serious about her!
But I am serious about Ghungroo!
Now I don't want to
do this small job!
I just want to marry Ghungroo!
Heero... that Devi...
What happened to her?
Nothing happened to her! In fact me...
What happened to you?
Let me talk! I like her a lot!
And you are the only person
who can understand me.
I can pour out my soul
to you. I love Devi.
Raj...
you do what you think is right.
Don't ask anybody! Just do it!
Yes!
I wanted to talk to you!
Come! Sit!
I... you see... my friend Heero...
he loves Ghungroo!
And he wants me to go
and meet Gangu mummy...
and talk about his alliance.
I have heard so much
about Gangu mummy...
that I am scared of her.
But if you helped me... then
Heero's work will be done.
And... Heero really loves Ghungroo!
I swear on you.
I swear on myself.
How is your arm now?
If Devi is saying then
the guy must be good.
I forgot! What will you have?
No, no! We won't take dowry!
She is asking for tea or coffee.
Oh! No, no! I am fine!
What is Heero's educational
qualification?
He is educated, isn't he?
- Yes! It will be done!
- Done?
I mean it's done!
How much is Heero's earning?
How much does Heero earn?
Same as mine.
- How much is yours?
- Same as Heero's.
Okay! So you have seen Ghungroo,
haven't you?
She rides the auto! She
looks after the house!
But what does this Heero do?
Heero! Heero uses 'Ghoda' (Means
gun as well as horse)!
- Gun?
- He uses gun?
Not that one! Horse! He rides horses!
I see! You mean to say horse racing!
No, no, papa! Not horse
racing! Running race!
No! I mean... Raj means to say...
that Heero runs like a horse!
- Am I right?
- Yes!
- Exactly!
Heero... is faster than the horse!
I see! I see! I see!
Look, Gangu mummy! Heero
is a nice guy!
Exactly!
And he loves Ghungroo a lot!
Heero loves Ghungroo a lot!
And the most important thing is...
Heero has never loved any girl
as much as he loves Ghungroo!
You mean to say he has
loved other girls too?
Papa, many girls!
I have lost count!
What... what are you saying? -No, no!
I mean... - No! This is not
what he meant, mummy!
What is he saying?
No, no! This is not what he meant!
- What does he mean?
- What do you mean?
I mean to say... Heero used to love
one girl a lot once upon a time!
But now I am 90% sure that this
time it will be fixed for sure!
- Raj!
- Scoundrel!
Raj!
Just a minute. Just a minute.
- What do you think of my Ghungroo!
- Hang on!
- What do you think of yourself?
- Let it be!
- Heero is a nice guy!
- What do you think of yourself?
I will tell Heero to come!
- Heero!
- Scoundrel!
Gangu mummy, let it be!
This is not what he meant,
Gangu mummy! - Leave!
- Gangu, keep quiet!
- Don't come back again!
- And tell that Heero!
- If he came here then...
- You will chop him into pieces!
- I will chop him into pieces!
- Keep quiet!
Heero! Now what will be our fate?
Hey! Move! Move!
Why does this Heero want to die?
Because... they... are not allowing...
me to marry Ghungroo!
Kaliganj's people!
Goodbye forever!
Move! Move!
Bye-bye! Goodnight! Bye!
- Come on!
- Move!
Look!
Okay! Bye-bye!
He is shooting himself! I told you!
He is playing a charade!
Hey! Play your drama somewhere
else! Come on!
He will die! He will die!
Not drama! Now there
will be a sensation!
I am going to kill myself!
Day light murder!
Mummy, he will die!
And Gangu mummy will be
responsible for it!
- What is he saying?
- Me!
Who else?
Heero wants to marry. Ghungroo
wants to marry.
- Yes!
- And you...
Yes!
Ghungroo, I think... your
mummy didn't get...
a handsome husband like me.
That's why she is jealous of you!
You! I am jealous!
- Go and die!
- No, no, no!
- I will light your pyre! Go and die!
- No, no!
Okay!
- No, mummy! No!
- What...
Mummy, stop! Mummy!
- Shut up!
- Gangu!
Priest! Bye-bye! Ghungroo...
I love you!
- Come on! Come on! Die!
- Mummy, he will die!
Shut up! He won't do anything!
Raj! My friend!
Jai Hind!
I am going.
Because of this old lady... a
lover boy is going to die!
Cold blooded murder!
Come on! I have to watch
the serial! Die quickly!
Listen! Listen! This is not
a murder! It's a suicide!
- You shut up!
- Yes!
You... be it suicide or murder...
the result is the same!
Then?
Gangu mummy!
If you didn't go to prison
after my death...
if the police didn't
arrest you... then...
Hey! Help!
Then I will come back! As a ghost!
And he will haunt Kaliganj!
Gangu mummy!
My soul will enter your fish's body!
And she will make
your life miserable!
Say yes! He will die!
You people won't lose anything!
She is my daughter! Keep quiet!
Gangu mummy... you won't find such
a nice guy anywhere else.
Shut up!
- Gangu mummy... the guy is not so bad.
- Yes!
End the matter here!
You won't get stuck
in the police mess!
And Ghungroo will gradually tame him!
- Hurry up!
- Say yes!
My arm is aching!
- Mummy, say yes!
- Come on! Say yes!
Come on! Say yes! Say yes!
Come on! Say it! Say yes!
Yes!
What did you say?
Drunkard! Didn't you hear? Yes!
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes!
- Yes!
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
- Rehmad.
- Yes.
Seems like a cat has entered
in the house...
take care she might spoil the milk.
Yes father, I will take a look.
What happened?
- Ghungroo!
- Ghungroo, what Ghungroo father?
I thought as if I heard
Ghungroo's voice.
No father, it was a
cat I drove it away.
Today is Meena's birthday and
father is not letting me go.
Please talk to father.
- Naqvi sir!
- Ghungroo! Ghungroo!
Where is Rehmad?
You are still here, you know...
a terrible thing has
happened with Laila.
You know dear, I felt as
if I heard your voice.
- My voice.
- What happened to Laila?
It met with an accident.
Are you fine dear?
First class. But Laila is
in a terrible condition.
- She cannot see.
- She cannot see?
Yes, her headlights
have been damaged...
her head, her engine has overheated.
And that's why I have
come to take Rehmad.
Go son go, take him along dear.
But remember one thing, after
you finish your work...
bring him back here.
He was being stubborn about
going to the town.
Don't worry Naqvi sir, I will
bring him back here no tension.
Dear, he is your responsibility.
Of course, he is my responsibility.
Hail Veero.
I found one from there.
The innocent always die.
By the hands of America,
Al-Qaida, and me.
Everyone's motive is something else.
America's is Al-Qaida,
Al-Qaida's is America...
You just got caught up in the middle.
So what if you died, everyone
has to die one day.
You died first, I will die later.
Just don't feel bad.
Don't feel bad.
Hey Tambhe...
Move him he is sitting on my chair.
Narsimha sir, they killed Ahmed.
Gandhi said, if you are
slapped on one cheek...
then show your other too.
I am not Gandhi, I am Babban.
Crazy girl, what are you doing
here, where is your Laila?
Where is your Laila?
Naqmi sir... he used
to love Meena a lot...
and he used to go
to town to meet him.
And Meena... Meena...
It was Meena's birthday and he
wanted to go and meet her...
and I asked him to go to town...
I thought no one will find out and...
And he will come back Naqvi sir.
Rehmad... Rehmad was my
responsibility but...
I made a very big mistake!
Where is Rehmad, is he fine?
I made a mistake Naqvi sir,
I made a mistake.
Where is Rehmad?
It is time for my prayer.
But why did Babban kill an innocent?
There is no one innocent
in this world?
Who makes the government?
The common people.
Who gives money to the
government to catch us?
The common people.
Then who is our enemy?
Whether it is America or Kaliganj...
the common people always die.
That is lid is dead, the rest
of you are still alive...
because Babban has
still not killed you.
But maybe you all wish to die.
If you don't want to, then handover
Raj and Heero to us.
Narsimha, not just
me everyone knows...
that you are right.
But we have to face a
gangster like Babban.
That's why we have been
supporting you till now.
But now he killed Badri's brother.
Bansal's sir's two sons.
Milli he died too.
9 people in the last three days.
If this keeps on continuing,
then what will we do?
Entire Kaliganj will be
eradicated because...
of these Jai and Heero.
What do you all want?
We want you and Raj to
go out of Kaliganj.
No, sending you out of Kaliganj
won't solve anything.
They have clearly said...
that we have to hand them over.
Or else they will keep committing
such murders.
What are you saying,
can you understand?
Aren't you ashamed?
You want to handover Raj
and Heero to Babban.
Those who didn't care for
their own lives for you.
Understand this.
This battle is not with Gabbar,
but with the fear...
that Babban has rooted in us.
So what if we die to
eradicate that fear.
Death is better then leading
a fearful life.
Stop lecturing!
Your husband has died, your brother!
But why are you dragging
us in your fight?
And if you want to fight,
then do it yourselves!
Go and die!
Why should we bear the consequences?
Mr. Narsimha, this is happening
because of you...
because of your enmity!
And we innocent have to die!
Who is talking?
Who is he? Who is he?
Ask him to talk to me!
If you have the courage
then talk to me!
Don't you have some sense?
And if you don't, then
keep your mouth shut!
I am blind but I can see
better than all of you
This battle is against our fear,
and Babban's cruelty...
because he fighting to imprison us.
You should feel ashamed!
If you have the courage, then
point fingers at yourself.
Mr. Narsimha came here to fulfil
his duty and the police duty...
and what's his mistake that
Babban made us his enemies.
Yes, he made one mistake.
He thought for such selfish
people like you.
You don't want to live like this...
you want to go live out
on the sea, then go.
You want to return to
your village, then go!
Anyone can go wherever they want...
but I will not leave
this place and go!
I have lost my son,
I don't regret it.
I would want to request to Allah...
to give me a chance to achieve
martyr in this battle.
So that if I ever meet my son,
then I can tell him...
that Rehmad, your old
father is not a coward.
He died fighting Babban.
Yes Pradhan speaking, I want
to talk to Tambhe sir.
Yes Tambhe sir, we have decided.
To handover Heero and Raj to you.
Pradhan!
Pradhan.
Where are you, buddy?
- Sanam.
- Yes.
They had asked us to come
to this place, isn't it?
They had.
Are they trying to fool us?
You are right?
Heero!
Kill me!
What are you looking at? Kill me!
Come on kill me! End it!
Kill me!
We are not Gandhi too.
Tambhe, understand it.
You are about to die.
I am enjoying it.
I am enjoying it a lot.
I am enjoying seeing you die.
All my life you helped me.
Now that you are dying, you
are giving me a new zest.
Zest.
Now the real fun will begin!
They have fanned the fire. Fanned it.
Babban will now shower fire.
Fire! Fire!
Hey! Tambhe.
What happened?
After Tambhe's death,
Babban will
become dangerous for a while.
How is that?
Before being extinguished
the lamp flickers brightly.
Heero, you go on I am coming.
I want to talk to inspector sir.
Inspector sir...
I wanted to talk to you.
About Devi?
I have told Heero clearly...
if you want to marry me then you
will have to leave all this.
Its not that I can't
live without him.
Laila is enough for me.
I have given him last warning that
locking horns with Ghungroo...
All I want to say is that if you
have lost something in life...
that doesn't mean
that life has ended.
The real motive of life
is to be happy.
All I want to say is that...
I will be very happy
seeing you happy.
And if that happiness is
returning in your life...
then it will not be right
to try to stop it.
You are really too much.
He was talking about Raj.
About Raj.
Whenever you talk to me about Raj...
I can clearly understand
your feelings about him.
But I... - Even Mr. Narsimha
has understood this.
In short, he has no problem.
What are you saying Ghungroo?
I am saying that, except for
you all of us know that you...
- What?
- That you love Raj.
Stop pretending and admit it.
And now I will go and
tell everyone about it.
Ghungroo! Ghungroo, wait!
Heero!
Do you know what has happened?
So this is Ms. Kaliganj.
What do you eat?
Everything's made of pure ghee.
Where is your...
Here he is.
Heero! Heero!
Come.
Look Babban, leave her. Let her go.
I will kill you, I will kill you!
Look, your enmity is with
me, let the girl go.
If you have the courage, then fight
me! Kill me if you want to!
Let the girl go!
Throw down the gun!
Lower it! Throw down the gun!
Don't take tension! I am going!
I am going.
First! First! Come out!
- Come out! Come out!
- Don't come out!
Heero, don't insult your friendship.
Don't listen to him.
If he dies, you will die too.
Heero, run away.
Don't be crazy!
Heero, think about Ghungroo!
Think about Ghungroo!
Don' worry about me.
Where is Ghungroo?
If you come out, then
we all will be killed!
Heero, your friend had come out
Like a brave man on Diwali.
You are a coward.
You scoundrel.
I am giving you a last chance.
I will count till three.
- 3!
- No! No Heero!
Get out of here Heero.
Don't get emotional!
Try to understand the situation.
Run away from here, go get help.
Think about Ghungroo! Go from here!
Run away from here!
That's the only way!
Seems like he ran away.
- Go from here.
- No.
- Go and inform everyone.
There is very little
time left, Ghungroo.
No, Heero.
For Ghungroo, he left you for love.
- Try to understand, go.
- No.
Go, go.
Go.
He betrayed his friendship.
He left you.
Babban's enmity is better than
his friendship, isn't it?
What do you say Tambhe?
Being scared of Babban is right.
Fighting Babban, wrong.
Heero.
The pain that you are feeling now...
I have hidden that pain
in my heart for a year.
With the hope that I will kill
Babban with my own hands.
Consider it my request or plead.
Let me kill him.
I killed myself.