"Let's dance"
"Let's set off
a storm together"
"Dance with me and steal
some color from the world"
"Get colorful"
"Let's dance"
"Let's set off
a storm together"
"Dance with me and steal
some color from the world"
"Get colorful"
"So very colorful"
"There are so many faces...
mine ought to be recognized"
"There are so many big names...
may mine be mentioned too"
"Life would be great"
"The days would be mine,
so would the nights"
"And a joyous tune played
all the time..."
"Dance away"
"Let's kick up a
storm together"
"Dance with me; let's steal
some color from the world"
"Get colorful"
"Come to me, friends;
drive away my problem"
"The goodies fight among themselves;
I'm the sweeter one, they all say"
"They take me for a kid!"
"There's so much
of tension around"
"What would a man do..."
"who doesn't know how to
live it up in the world"
"They look for their
destiny in the parrots..."
"in the stars up above..."
"they hunt for their fortune...
but can't tell what it is"
"Should one believe
in oneself..."
"all obstacles would be
easy to overcome"
"And the world would
be in our hands"
"Dance away"
"Let's kick up a storm together"
"Let's steal some color
from the world"
"Get colorful"
What's up?
You've ruined my dream!
What a dream!
I was dancing and singing
and swaying away...
and the world was
swaying with me.
I'm not going to
forgive you for this!
Oh indeed. As if...
- Where's my file?
It's there on the table!
And where is the table?
Under that heap of files.
- Found it!
"Enjoy yourself, O drunkard..."
Not you too!
- Well?
Who else has been bothering my wife?
- Look at the princess's airs!
She's late for work. And she says
I've ruined her dream!
That's not right, Mili.
She ruined your dream
while you slept.
And she ruined my dreams
while I still live!
Have I ever complained?
- As if you'd be a big shot!
Listen, darling...
- Yes?
I had always dreamed, "that
I'd never be a somebody"
"What have we to be...?"
Aren't you going for your bath?
- "Why must we bathe...?"
What are you doing...?
Have you gone mad?
Stop it!
You must be happy that your daughter
even dreams of what she wants to be.
All right. But dreams are fulfilled
only when man rises from his slumber.
But you dream only when you
go to sleep, understand?
What is it?
What are you doing?
- I'm studying.
Are you really studying?
Or are you asleep?
He's studying... he isn't dreaming.
Here I go...
My word, Motilal! You've taken to
your books so early in the day!
I don't intend to spend 3 years
in Class 10 like you.
My little brother...
I wasn't killing time in Class 10.
I was learning to dance.
Because I'm not going to be
a clerk after those studies.
I want to become an actress.
Sister...
- Well?
Could you give me an autograph?
How about a kick...?
Will that do?
Mili! Aren't you leaving?
- I'll fix you, all right.
The camera isn't rolling.
Whether the camera's
rolling or not...
I'm a director whose mind
is always at work.
I'm not competing with
the directors here.
I'm competing with Hollywood.
So let me see the frame.
It's so very dark...
I can't see anything.
Dark...? It must be
because of this cap.
As I said, "Hum Aapke Hain koun"
is said to be a hit movie.
It has broken all records.
All that is okay. But do you
know the inside story?
No, I don't.
It was my script.
- Yours?!
I was supposed to produce
the film originally.
And all those sequences are
actually part of my marriage!
Really?
- But I said it's okay...
Suraj is my own boy.
Let him direct the film.
And everyone praises the film today.
It's Suraj who is walking
away with all the credit...
but it was my story, after all!
Gulbadan hasn't yet
reported for shooting.
It's a 9 'O clock shift.
And she isn't here at 12!
She's going to make
beggars out of my kids!
I don't think I will
ever see this film.
Don't stand there and grin.
Go and call her!
Here she is...
so very punctual!
Welcome, madam.
Get a chair for mummy!
Set it here.
- Of course, madam.
Do you know the story before
the song sequence?
My baby doesn't know anything.
Our heroine is in the village.
Out there, the cold breeze...
Would you like a cold drink, dear?
- Sure.
Could you send for
some fruit juice?
Get a glass of fruit-juice.
- Two glasses.
As I said, there's a cool breeze
blowing in the village...
I'd like a milk shake
with custard apple... okay?
A milk shake with custard apple.
- Make it two.
Yes. Go on.
- With lots of ice.
This isn't a season for custard apple.
- Get it from somewhere!
It's available only in November.
- So get it in November!
I've been explaining a sequence!
You're screaming!
You have scared my little girl!
Send for the fan...
- Get the fan!
Is this dress okay?
Let's shoot the song first.
I'll narrate the story later.
The shot is ready.
Tickets worth 10 going
for 30...
Want one?
Tickets worth 10
going for 30...
How much?
- 30 Rupees.
Two tickets for me.
- So cough it up.
What?
- 60 bucks.
They're corner seats, I hope?
- Of course. At opposite ends.
Give me some tickets, Munna.
Mine are finished.
How are you doing?
- Great.
I come on foot and hail
a cab to go back home.
Tickets for 10 Rupees
going for 30...
Do you have any tickets?
- Want an advance booking?
You're kidding.
How much is it going for?
Didn't you hear that?
For 30 Rupees.
Could I have it for 15 Rupees?
- You get to watch half the film.
Oh damn it...
- Come back here.
I like your face.
Go and watch the film.
Tickets for 10 Rupees
going for 30...
Come here.
- What is it?
Come here!
- Me...?
You've been selling tickets
in the black-market?
Me? Do I look like
a black-marketer?
What was that about 30 Rupees then?
- I was looking for tickets myself.
I'd happily pay 30 bucks for a ticket.
But there's no one around.
Do you think I'm a fool?
Raise your hand!
Stop kidding sir...
how'd I raise my hand at you?
Raise your hands... go on!
- Hey! You're bullying me!
Look at this, folks!
They let those who instigate
riots, go scot-free.
There was a scandal involving
billions in the stock market.
Did they arrest anyone?
No.
But they will harass a poor guy
like me who wants to watch a film.
Go ahead...
Did you find something?
No?
You have humiliated me
publicly, haven't you?
What's going to happen
to this country...?
Get lost, fellows!
This ain't no drama!
What sleight of hand!
Hey black egg... get lost.
- Scram!
Where's the rest of the gang?
- They've left.
Let's make ourselves scarce...
things are heating up here.
What happened?
What kind of a director are you
to make her do such a dance?
Aren't you ashamed to give her
such difficult steps?
This director is a fool!
He watches MTv and gets us
to do weird steps...
Does anyone ask an actress
to do such difficult steps?
What if something had
happened to my girl?
Don't get excited, mummy.
I'll handle it...
Does it hurt?
- Don't worry...
I'll have the steps changed.
- Like hell you will!
You should've known better than
ask her to do such steps!
You aren't hurt badly...
- Shut up! How isn't it bad?
What do you know?
You don't become a director
by merely wearing a viewfinder.
The poor baby has
sprained her ankle...
It's pack-up for the day...
Pack up!
Hear me out, mummy, please...!
- Didn't you hear me? Pack up!
Come, dear... let's go.
Please, mummy!
I'll have it changed!
I can't figure out of if we have
signed the girl or her mother!
Why do the girls' mothers
ever attend a shoot?!
I'm going to quit this place and
head straight for Hollywood!
What the hell! I'll go bust,
if you go to Hollywood!
I don't care what happens to you!
That old hag...
Calm down, please. I'll somehow make
them see reason and bring them...
Why are you getting worked up?
Sorry, Kamalji.
It's pack up.
Would Julia Roberts' mother ever treat
Spielberg like I've been treated?
Kamalji's leaving.
- What else will he do?
He's such a fine actor.
But the lady always finds
some excuse to throw a fuss.
I think she's just not
interested in her work.
Why must we bother?
We're getting paid.
How can you say such things?
We come here so we can learn
something and become good actors.
It isn't that we just
come here, dance and leave.
Sorry, lady. I have no ambitions.
I'm happy where I am.
Go ahead if you want
to make it big.
How're you doing?
- Fine.
Switch on that fan.
Get us some tea.
Quick.
Read that sign. You pay cash.
If I had the money, wouldn't
I go to a five-star?
I'll settle your account tomorrow.
- Sure?
Of course. Whom else have I paid?
Go on. And get me
some cookies.
Did you get those tickets, Munna?
What're you screaming for?
- Mili! Come here!
Why are you screaming?
- Sit down. Have a soft drink.
No. I'm going home.
Sit for a while. I'll join you.
...get a cold drink for her.
Prakash! You're smoking again?
- I'm kicking the habit tomorrow.
So... how's the shoot going?
Don't even ask me.
The lead-lady made us work so
hard on a simple step today...
that we had it coming out
of our ears.
I've been telling you
to give it up.
You're going to wear out
your shoes in those shoots.
You start lecturing me now...?
- It's true.
I've seen life there on the footpaths.
- Try and think of something better.
You're wasting your time
like a worthless loafer.
Find some job in a nice company.
- To hell with jobs!
Rather than play a rich man's dog,
I'll enjoy my life out on the streets.
I'll be my own boss...
Right, Pakya?
Right!
You're never going to change.
- Where are you going, Mili!
"Listen to what I have
to say, guys..."
"Lead your life like I do"
"It's okay if I don't
own cars and bungalows"
have a bank balance"
"It's okay if I don't own
Tv's and videos"
"It's okay if I can't
flaunt fancy clothes"
"What must I worry
about all that?"
"I'll lead a carefree life"
"Listen to what I have
to say, friends"
"Lead your lives
the way I do"
"lt'd be great to own
cars and bungalows"
"With a bank balance to color
your days and nights"
"Tv's and videos would
be the icing on the cake..."
"to dress up well
would add to your status"
"value the good things in life"
"Mend your ways a bit"
"Listen to the philosophy
I follow, friends"
"And spend your lives
the way I do"
"Look at me..."
"I'm a prince who
acts on his whims"
"Wait for the world
to call you a prince..."
"Don't call yourself
a prince"
"The name is Munna..."
"I do just what pleases me"
"Why should I worry
about how business is"
"Why must I ever keep track
of people coming and going"
"You're ignorant about
the ways of the world..."
"in such a world
you will never make it"
"Listen to this philosophy, friends"
"Lead your lives
as I do"
"Who knows about tomorrow"
"I live for today"
"Only those without
any confidence..."
"talk the way you do"
"Don't you ever say such a thing"
"They think I'm really tough"
"The heart of a lion I possess"
"No matter what,
I hold my head high"
"I wish you could see
beyond your nose"
"But you know nothing"
"Listen to me, guys"
"Lead your lives
like I do"
"It's be great own
cars and bungalows"
"Oh to have a bank balance that
would color your days and nights"
"Tv's and videos would
be such fun"
"Dressing well would
add to your status"
"Why must I worry
about all that?"
"I'd rather lead a carefree life"
"So listen to me, friends..."
"Lead your lives
the way I do"
Kamal was fed up of the
lady's tantrums and left...
What ice cream will you eat?
Vanilla, raspberry, pineapple...?
I don't want an ice cream.
- I'm buying it for you.
Have some.
- I don't want it. Let's go.
Strange! I'm treating you to some
Ice cream, and you don't want it!
So what am I to do?
I didn't like that, Mili.
- What?
I felt like buying you an ice cream.
And you refused it!
Oh come on, Munna. You take
offense for every little thing.
I didn't want an ice-cream
and so I refused it.
I only asked you to have an ice cream!
- There you go again...
Did I say something wrong?
- What's right and what's wrong...?
You start a fight everywhere...
- What are you doing?
One banana. What loss is it to you?
- Pay up quietly!
What will you do if I don't?
Want a bloody punch?
One moment... how much is it?
- You're not going to pay, Mili!
Will you take it away for free?
- You're asking for it!
I've already paid you, so keep quiet.
...c'mon, Munna... c'mon!
You don't know me, punk!
I'm famous around here!
Mess with me and you'd never be
able to sell bananas here again!
What the hell was that, Munna?
- You shouldn't have paid him!
Won't he ask you for money
when you pick up a banana?
It's not about money!
Can't I pay him?
But you didn't pay him.
- He acted as if I'd stolen a fortune!
It was you who started it, Munna.
- But he started the fight!
All right! You're not at fault.
Nor is he. I'm the one to blame!
So why fight with me
if it was your mistake?
What are you doing all alone, Motilal?
- Mili won't play with me.
Not she... go ahead and bat.
I'll bowl an over.
Mom!
- Here I am.
Munna's going to drive me mad someday.
- Why? Did he get into a fight today?
It wasn't just a fight.
It was a scene!
What happened?
- We were walking together...
and there was this banana-seller.
Munna picked up a banana.
know what Munna said when the
poor man asked for his money?
What?
- "What loss will one banana make?"
You're laughing! And I know what I've
been through out there on the streets.
Munna is mischievous, I know.
But he's good-hearted.
Most orphans go berserk
without their parents.
But not him. He's a nice boy.
- Nice, my foot!
Where the hell is it?
For a boy as little as you are,
you play shots like Tendulkar.
know what?
- What?
Anyone can score sixers
off your bowling.
Really?! Let me see.
Score a sixer...
You've had it, my boy!
You're going to get a thrashing!
What's happening out here?
Motilal... who
smashed the pane?
It was Munna.
- What?
Who was batting?
You? Or me?
I'm sure Munna's responsible
for all this, Mom.
Is he innocent only because
he's your brother?
Yes, he's my brother...
so what are you going to do?
Quiet, Mili.
Tell me the truth, Motilal.
Who broke the pane?
Munna did.
- You're lying!
Weren't you the one who was batting?
- But you said you'd score a sixer.
When did I say that?
- You said it, of course!
Will you bully me because
I'm a kid?
A kid, eh...?
You're acting smart with me!
He's blaming me!
- It's all over, okay?
The story's over!
- What's over?
Go and take a look at the kitchen.
- So?
Whoever has done it
will clean the mess.
That's exactly what we don't know.
Who did it?
Munna has done it, I say!
- You're lying again!
Don't you touch me!
- No? I'll give you a slap!
I know you well, fatso.
Go on and clean the mess.
But...
- No arguments... go on.
Very well...
I'll fix you later.
Go ahead and laugh. You're always
waiting for a chance to laugh at me.
My sweet will.
I can laugh at anything
and anyone I wish.
Really...?
- What's this between you now?
I've had enough of
their fights already.
Come on inside and freshen up.
I'll give you something to eat.
That's something!
I'm leaving... I'm going
to the movies.
Which film?
- That Raj Kamal starrer...
Mr. Bond?
- Yes.
D'you have tickets for the film?
- Sure. I have two tickets.
Wait till I get ready...
- Not you.
I'm going with a friend.
- Won't you take me then?
Why must I take you along?
Please, Munna... I've been
dying to see the film.
Will you poke fun at me again?
- No.
Will you be angry with me?
- Never.
All right. Go on and get ready.
I'll change, too.
Kamal! Congratulations!
This film of yours
is a super hit too!
There was this distributor
who called from C.P.C.I.
He said the film would
gross more than 10 million.
The distributor from Delhi
said the same thing.
The film is bit weak
in Rajasthan, no doubt.
But it will pick up
by word of mouth.
In Bengal and Punjab, it's going
to break all box-office records!
This is what I came
to tell you.
Well then, I must leave now.
How about the heroine's call-sheet?
- I've spoken to her mom.
She said she would
confirm tomorrow.
My God! The movie must've begun.
- How are you?
C'mon now... we're already late.
The movie must've already begun.
It's full of songs in
the first half.
Watch the songs on Tv
if you miss them.
No way. I'm going to
watch the whole film.
Tickets for 10 Rupees
going for 30...
Munna! There's your friend. Pakya.
Tickets for 10 Rupees
going for 30...
So?
He's selling tickets
in the black-market!
He's had such a black life...
what else will he do?
What's that about his black life?
- You'd be shaken up...
if you get to know the
story of his life.
Pakya's mother died when
he was just 5 years old.
His father, the alcoholic,
kicked the bucket soon after.
Pakya had just one intention in life.
To get his only sister married.
He lived only so his
sister could be married.
But his bad luck. The suitor's parents
asked for so much of dowry...
that he has been selling tickets
in the black-market ever since.
Tickets for 10 Rupees
going for 30...
No one could know Pakya has
such a sordid story behind him.
The truth about a man is never
obvious from the way he looks.
Let's go.
Show us to our seats, buster...
has the movie started?
This cinema hall is a furnace!
Start that fan!
Will you let us
watch the film, please?
Please let us watch the film.
- Stick to your wife, old man.
Enjoying yourself, lady?
- Shut up, Munna!
You won't even let them
watch the movie in peace!
What a great shot!
- I bought it today. Readymade.
It's him I'm talking about.
Not you.
He wears a hired shirt. I've bought
mine with hard-earned money.
Right?
- Oh yes.
Take that foot off!
Watch the movie... not my foot.
Look ahead.
I've bought a ticket, too.
- So you own the theater, eh?
You're showing off
to the girl, are you?
Really? Wait till I fix you...
Get up! What did you say?
- Don't touch me!
I won't touch...
I'll kick you!
Hey Mili...
At least hear me out!
Why aren't you answering me?
I've been calling out to you...
at least answer me.
Get out of my way!
What have I done...?
Why are you so angry?
Don't talk to me, I say!
What have I done?
- What have you done?
Why did you get into a fight with him?
- Didn't you hear what he said?
I did. And I even saw what you did.
Who asked you to put your foot up?
Great! You find fault only with me!
This isn't right, okay?
I've taken enough, Mili...
Can't you live without
getting into fights?
Now tell me something, uncle.
Why do you go to the movies?
For the fun of it, isn't it?
When I pay for my ticket,
won't I even sit comfortably?
Sure you will.
- Then?
That doesn't mean you will kick
the man sitting in front of you.
Now don't make up stories!
I haven't kicked anyone!
What's wrong if my foot
happened to touch him?
Nothing wrong at all.
He was having a whale of a time!
What's happened, Munna?
- Nothing, aunt!
She takes everything to the limit!
So what if I stretched my feet?
Was that guy more interested
in my foot?
Everyone goes to the movies
to enjoy them.
That doesn't mean you can
kick people around.
Tell me... isn't that
rather cheap?
Isn't it?
- Absolutely.
Talk to me! I'll answer
every accusation!
I don't want to talk to you, I said.
- See?
You decide this, uncle.
She doesn't even listen to me.
And it was such a rotten movie.
It drove me crazy.
Listen... not a word
about the movie, okay?
Why not? Because Raj Kamal,
your favorite, starred in it?
Will a rotten film be good
just because he acts in it?
You're a big shot, aren't you?
- I'm the public!
I have a right to my opinion.
If I don't get value for my money,
he's finished!
Even your favorite, Raj Kamal.
- Really?
Of course!
My finger...!
Are you hurt...?
What happened?
Let me see...
You're always bothering me!
Dad! You're laughing...?
See that?
It looks as if the stars
had descended to the earth.
With a house behind every star...
and a story behind
every household.
They all look similar
from a distance.
Munna... what are
you doing here?
I've been looking for you.
And you're dancing here all alone.
The lead-lady threw a fuss
and walked out again.
I thought I'd rehearse
for a while.
But what brings you here?
I created a scene at the
theater yesterday, didn't I?
I went home and thought
about the whole thing.
I felt very sorry.
I'm a hot-tempered guy, you know.
I flare up when provoked.
So I've brought two more tickets.
I'll show you the film today
without anymore fuss.
Oh, get lost.
Is this the set where you shoot?
The place you're so excited about?
All that blah blah...
what's go great about it?
We have better decorations during
our festivals in the streets.
Really?
"What are you looking for...?
Tell me"
"Tell me..."
"You can have anything you want"
"Such is the magic I work"
"You will have
everything you want"
"What do you want...?
Tell me"
"Take it..."
"You can have my heart
if you wish"
"What else will I wish for
except your heart...?"
"Take a look at the things
you can see from here"
"Everything belongs to you"
"What have I to do with
all these things...?"
"I belong to you;
you belong to me"
"What are you looking for...?
Tell me"
"Ask me... how I feel"
"Let me have your
heart, darling..."
"how about it?"
"Try and understand
what I'm saying"
"Come and take look
at the breath-taking view"
"Let me introduce you
to the spring"
"Forget the views
and the spring..."
"Come closer...
my heart beckons you"
"What do you want...?
Tell me"
"Take anything you wish"
"Such is the magic I weave"
"You will have anything
you wish"
I've got to say something to you.
You won't tell anyone, will you?
Of course not. What is it?
I haven't spoken about it to anyone.
You're the only one.
No sweat.
Mili...
- What has she done now?
Have you had another fight?
- Listen to me!
You start speaking even before
I've said something.
Mili...
her folks likes me a lot.
They love me so very much.
Her Mom and dad...
they're like family to me.
As for Mili...
I like her very much.
You understand what I say?
- Sure.
What?
- You like Mili. Her mom and dad too.
I... I want to marry Mili.
What? Come again, Munna!
I want to marry Mili.
- Marriage?
Munna's getting married!
Hey... forget it.
I'm serious.
And you're joking.
I'm delighted! But why're you
telling me all this?
Go and tell your bride.
I'll only be a guest!
That's the problem.
Mili doesn't take me seriously.
What if I propose to her
and she laughs at me?
Why would she laugh at you?
- You don't know how she is.
Forget all that.
You want to marry her, right?
So you'll have to propose
to her sooner or later.
You're right.
Okay, I'll propose to her.
The moment I find an opportunity.
Help!
She was scared!
You're such a crybaby, Mili.
How're you going to manage?
I'm going to scream even louder!
D'you know how scary it is?
This is nothing. In America
they have better games.
America indeed!
As if you've been there!
He has a railway pass.
He travels there everyday.
That's enough. Why do you keep
bothering her, Munna?
See? And you keep blaming me, mom!
- Enough!
Aren't we going anywhere else?
C'mon...
Where's your daddy?
Did you enjoy the ride, Mili?
Don't ask her, uncle!
- Shut up!
Remember the ride we took on
the beach before we married?
Sure. And you had run out
of breath after the ride.
That was because you were with me!
- Really?
Stop it... not before
the children.
Let's go... are we going to stay here?
- Yes. Let's fight in the car.
No. Look at that ride there.
- Are we to do only what you wish?
Quiet! Are you going
to fight even here?
Go any place you want to go.
And we'll go wherever we wish.
We'll meet at lunch.
Okay?
Talk to her!
Don't be silly...
there are people around.
This is the right time, I say!
Strike when the iron is hot!
You're crazy! This is no place
to talk about love.
This is a fair...
and we need silence.
Silence? So I'll go away.
Why must I spoil the fun?
There she is... Go on!
And pour out your heart.
Where's Pakya?
He's gone to fetch
some ice cream.
There's something I must tell you.
Actually, there's something
I've got to tell you...
Hurry up! I'm getting late!
As I said...
isn't this a great place?
Listen... there's something
I must tell you.
Yes?
As I said...
- Go on.
Actually...
that ride we took, you know?
I was scared too.
Scared, weren't you?
- Terribly scared.
Isn't that true?
I knew it!
Liar! ...c'mon!
No! Don't hit me!
Kamalji?
Who are you?
Me? I'm Mili.
I see you everyday.
At the studio.
I'm a dancer for choreographer
Saroj khan's troupe.
What?! Gulbadan's getting married?
Not just getting married. She's
walking out of our film too!
Walking out? Why?
- We have a lot of love scenes.
And Sudhir doesn't approve!
- Now who is Sudhir?
Her driver.
What has her driver
to do with our film?
He isn't just her driver.
He owns the car!
They're getting married.
You don't mean Gulbadan
is marrying her driver?!
Exactly. I went to meet
her Mom early this morning.
Her mom told me that since they go
from one studio to another...
they fell in love and
are going to get married.
Imagine, Dada! A film heroine
and her driver. In the car.
They romance in the car.
And they marry in the car!
Not even Speilberg
could dream of it!
To hell with Speilberg!
You're obsessed with him!
She's going to settle down
and I'm going to be ruined!
What's going to happen to me?
And to my film?
I'll be lynched by my creditors.
- Just tell me...
what I've got to do?
Take the call, Motilal.
- Haven't I anything else to do?
Yes, Mili here.
What?!
Yes, I'm free...
Okay...
Listen to this!
- Watch out...
know what? You're not
going to believe me!
What happened?
You know Raj Kamal, don't you?
- Which Raj Kamal?
The film star! Raj Kamal!
- So?
He telephoned me, Munna!
I've just spoken to him!
- Why did he call you?
Guess!
- Tell me.
Try and guess!
- Tell me... I'm no astrologer.
He wants me to play the female lead
in his next film!
He has called me over
for a screen test tomorrow!
What are you talking about?
- It's true! I swear!
This is it, Munna!
I'll deliver such a performance,
speak my lines in such a way...
I'm going to shock all of them!
Your eyes are the most important
thing in acting.
Whatever lines you speak...
they must come from your heart.
You must feel them... Okay?
Do you...?
Can you...?
Speak your lines!
Why must you cry?
It happens to all of us.
It happened even to me.
No, it doesn't.
I couldn't speak two lines.
I have no right to be there
in front of the camera.
It's not your mistake.
Let's cancel the shoot today.
Go home and rehearse your lines.
We'll shoot again tomorrow.
You'll do it tomorrow.
Don't worry...
Everything will be all right.
"Come back to me, my love.
I sing for you"
I'm not in!
- It's me, Munna!
Hide the bottle...
Open the door!
- One moment!
Sit down here quickly...
Hold this paper...
- What is it?
You read Rakesh's lines, okay?
- Who's Rakesh?
The hero of the film.
Read the lines after me, okay?
Let's get cracking.
What? Are you in love with me?
My God! I hadn't ever dreamed
you'd talk to me like this.
I've never thought
like that about you.
I don't even know what
to say to you...?
Don't stare at me! Read those lines!
It's your part after mine!
Well, sure...
- One moment.
Now what do I say...
"You mean you don't love me?
And I thought..."
Give it to me.
- What now?
Is that the way to read...
like a parrot?
Can't you read it with some feeling?
Bloody idiot!
Nonsense! You barge into the room
and ask me to read Rakesh's lines.
Now who the hell is Rakesh?
I'm not reading anything!
All right. Don't read it!
- Of course I won't!
You don't need to
do anything.
Do you know what happened
there... at the studio?
I talk so big out here.
And there... I couldn't speak a
single line when it mattered most.
Not a word.
I had forgotten everything!
I looked like a fool!
It was only because
of Mr. Raj Kamal...
that they agreed to give me
a second chance.
They want me there at 9 tomorrow.
And it's already 11.
I wanted to rehearse my lines
with someone.
So I came to you.
Who will help me,
if not you?
Why should you cry
over such a thing?
How would I know it
matters so much to you?
All right. I'll speak
those lines with you.
Once you have practiced with me,
you'll be an expert.
"Are you in love with me?
O God!"
"I've never thought of you
like that"
Idiot! They're my lines.
- Damn! I goofed up!
It's the other lines I speak.
Rakesh's...
Will you show me
how to say it?
"You know my sister
loves you, Rakesh"
"Do you want me to tell my sister
that you love me, and not her?"
"That you want to marry me?"
"Do you realize what she will
go through after hearing that?"
"Let alone saying
such a thing to her..."
"I can't even think
of such a thing"
"My sister is a very
emotional person"
"If she even gets the feeling that
you're in love with me, not her..."
"she could even
commit suicide"
"Don't let that happen, Rakesh.
Save my sister, please"
What's the time, mister?
- 5.30.
What's the time?
- I told you. 5.30.
Why are you asking me again and again?
- So what's wrong?
I only asked you for the time.
I didn't snatch your watch.
Go ahead and read the newspaper.
Mili! Watch out...
what are you doing?
Shut your eyes!
- What happened?
Shut your eyes, I say!
- But what's up?
Shut your eyes...
Go on.