movies subtitles: subtitles.alege.net
Some relationships
are made forever, they say
This one too was
of that kind, perhaps
We met here, in this college,
for the first time
He was...
A class Computer Engineering student
A hot favourite among the girls
During exams, he was
much sought-after
For, everyone wanted
to pass with flying colours
He was my senior in college
In short, the hero
of decent students. Sam
I...
Madhav Shastri?
- Yes, sir
Are you Madhav Shastri?
He is absent even today.
He is incorrigible
A Mechanical Engineering student
ought to have a fire inside him
Yes, what was he asking?
Why I don't attend class regularly?
Ask him if he goes home regularly
Rangeela Beer Bar, every night
Does he know what a spare gear is?
A Mechanical Engineering student
ought to have a fire inside him!
If I get a chance, I'll teach him and
his family fire and backfire as well
Of course you will,
Madhav Shastri
My objective is to enjoy life
as long as I'm in college
Once out of college,
you have to face the music anyway
I was a Mechanical
Engineering student
Hey! Are you a don?
I never said that.
All I'm saying is that...
our college is too congested. Two dons
can't survive in one college, right?
So my advice is... you seniors
be the bully outside the college
Let me open my little shop
inside the college
Acting smart, eh?
- Oh no...
Is that a threat?
- No, sir
You will hit us?
- Damn! How can I hit you guys?
Hit me.
- No, sir
You're a don here, right?
Hit me!
I was the college bully
Now limp all your life.
Wants to be a don!
With my help students passed
with flying colours...
on the condition that
I too must come up trumps
Why the hell do you
come to college?
No question papers for you.
Girls must study and pass. Move
I was a total celibate
Please adjust
I was a hero in college, too
Rats! How dare they talk like that
with the girls in our group?
What did you say about Priya?
- It's already in the newspapers, eh?
Trying saying it before me.
- Nothing, I only said...
that Priya is flat at the front
and from behind...
I don't know why from
the very first day itself...
a special relationship
was formed between me and Samra
I think the jail is the right place
for you, not the college
Why do you do all this?
And Sam, you? Why do you want
to become a gangster?
You are a brilliant
and an intelligent student
My family's not a refugee
Not at all!
The stubble...
the chain around your neck,
unbuttoned shirt...
traits of a decent family indeed!
At least don't misuse the money
that your father sends you
This is the last warning
for the two of you
If I happen to get a complaint again,
I'll suspend both of you
Have some shame
What?
What are you staring at?
Don't think I'm going to spare you
because of the principal's warning
I'm scared
Know what?
I'm a simple and decent guy
However, I don't know why, everytime
I see you and your flunkeys...
I get really pissed off,
and I turn into a beast
You needn't. You were born beast
Don't abuse in English.
Try using your mother tongue
I hated him, he hated me
Please sit down
My friends are getting pretty bored,
growing weaker day by day
What I was thinking is that, if you
could provide them some tonic...
it'd be fun
Don't get it?
I mean...
Just like what you do
with Sam's friends
If you do that with these poor souls,
their lives will be made
Look, they have what Sam has...
except money,
which I'll provide
And you didn't give a thought
to what I will have to offer?
The messiah of the poor,
the big brother...
the guardian of girls, is here.
- He is here!
He is here!
You've got the wholesale agency
of the girls
If you could offer us some share...
The sister says no,
and the brother stops
This is what you call
the relationship of love
The relationship of love!
- Enough, stop
Don't flatter him so much
Let the casanova go with the girls
All he needs is a flute to play
the tunes, so let's buy him one
He tonsured us
Notjust the head...
- The chest too
He's incorrigible
Don't be afraid.
Give me the polythene bag
Turn away.
- Hurry up
It stinks.
- Shut up
The crackers, please
Notjust in the girls' hostel,
the sound of the crackers...
will also echo in Sam's life
Crackers? Urine?
Who was the other boy
with you, Manish?
If you give me his name,
I might spare you
Who was he?
- Samra, sir
Sir, I can't do such a thing.
You know me
I didn't expect this from you, either
I have done the enquiry.
Manish too has revealed your name
I will have to suspend you
for two months
Speak!
On whose bidding
did you frame me?
I...
Speak up!
He did it on my say-so.
Why hit a kid?
You're screwed
Suspended for two months
You cannot attend class
until my friends grow their hair back
How's the timing? Perfect, isn't it?
Enough of idiocy
You want to test
your strength, don't you?
I've been waiting for this!
Just tell me the place,
I'll be there, swear
Same rules?
Not on the face, punk!
Have you forgotten the rules?
See? I'm one up on you
Let me go!
Let go!
- You're saved!
But it's not over yet
The score's not settled yet.
- We're just off the mark
I'll bowl you out!
- Shut up!
Okay seniors,
let's have a group snap
Farewell party of the seniors
Let's mess things up
Yes?
Know what? I've been waiting
for this day
Tonight you are celebrating,
tomorrow, I will
How about finishing off what we
left unfinished the other day?
Tonight I'm sparing you
You're going to America, I hear
What's the job?
Ajanitor's?
You will certainly make it big.
For, you sweep well
Look, I will be doing that
in America
In two years, you will be doing
that right here
At least I'll be earning in dollars
Hey Sam, I have a small wish
Now that we've met here...
don't ever cross my path again
I have a wish too;...
to meet you again,
just once
To finish off what we left undone.
It'll be my turn
I thought it would be
our last meeting, but alas...
I'm Madhav Shastri,
and I'm your instructor
I'm a Mechanical Engineer, and...
I know well
how I completed my engineering
Notwithstanding, today
I'm teaching you software
One minute, Madhav
I don't want to go, sir
My lifeline is my dad, sir
He lives in Mumbai,
and I don't want to leave Mumbai
Sing a song
Wonderful
What the hell?
- Are you singing? Or are you begging?
That wasn't a song
to compliment the mood
What do you know about music?
- Maybe nothing...
but I know much about you.
- What do you know?
Oh really?
How far have you studied?
- A, B, C, D... MSC
Look at him. He passed matriculation
on his fourth attempt
And he forged the certificate,
turned SSC into MSC...
and tries to impress everyone
Notwithstanding, he taught Maths,
free of cost...
to the girl next door
That fatso?
Look at yourself. You are
a case in itself. Most Wanted
Every police station in the city
carries his photographs
Look at your shoes.
One size doesn't match the other
He has never been to a shoe-mart...
yet he gets a new pair of shoes
every week
How come?
- Every Tuesday...
he steals from the temples
And you? What did you do in front of
the Mahalaxmi temple for two years?
You tell us.
- This shameless character...
would throw a 25 paise coin
in some blind beggar's bowl...
and pick up 2 bucks from it.
- Bastard
Moron!
Stop that clapping and laughing
What have I done?
- Sadly, you haven't done anything yet
You are all of 25 now.
Swear by Samanta Fox's eyes...
and tell us about something worthwhile
that have you done
Why should I?
I have my father
You think we are test-tube babies?
Damn you
Fink! You haven't seen enough
of Mumbai and you brag about America
You guys suck. If there's a decent
and handsome guy in our group...
it's me.
- Agreed
If there's someone who spends half of
his salary on your fags and beer...
That's a lie.
- All right, agreed
Agreed, okay? So can't you sing
a lovely song for me?
Now you are trying
to use our talent
Sing, will you?
- Hear, will you?
Mughal-e-Azam! The world's
most beautiful love-story
I have seen the movie 11 times.
Have you seen it?
Dilip Kumar and Madhubala starrer.
You must see it
If you are in love,
you'll get a 20 percent discount
Dad, I'm broke.
Can I get a grand?
A grand? What for?
- To watch a movie
Movie? All right
Here's 1000 bucks. Make sure
you get seats at the corner
Corner seats, Vicky
Why are you telling him?
- He's the one I'm going with
Bloody punk! Two idiots will sit
at the corner and watch a movie?
You ought to be ashamed!
- What for?
If a boy wants to watch a movie,
he should watch it only with a girl
Else, it'd be like embarrassing the
movie, the theatre and the audience
What easy?
C'mon, stand together
Put your hand over
his shoulders... smile
Look at each other, lovingly
You make a nice couple, but it
won't do here. It'll work in America
It's legal there... two boys
going around hugging each other
If you want to stay here in India
with your papa...
go outside, find a nice girl
and tell me that you like her...
that you love her...
and I'll give you 10,000 bucks
10,000 bucks? Sure?
- Sure
Would you go out for a movie with me?
Evening show, corner seats
We'll clap. It'll be fun.
- A movie? With you?
I do, every morning!
Not my fault though.
He asked me to do this
What's your problem?
Shall I take you to some doctor?
Doctor? What for?
- Why aren't there girls in your life?
Because I haven't yet come across
my kind of girl
Dad, pick up the phone
I'm Delhi talking to Mady
Dad...
- Yes?
I have found her
Who?
- My kind of girl
Some meetings
leave behind memories...
and promises
Some meetings...
give you a feeling
of a new beginning
I saw her again
Something surely existed between us
But what was it?
Let's go and meet the groom
You just refused a while ago
I have changed my mind
I have a feeling that
my life is about to change
Who's that girl?
- My wife
Not her. The girl behind me
I see. She's Rina Malhotra
She's a chartered accountant.
Works at Delhi Fort
There was a time when
I was after her
What rubbish!
You're hopeless
Aren't you ashamed?
It's your wedding today
I know
Amazing beauty
Tell you a secret...
- What?
She's so pretty...
nobody is watching you and your wife
Everyone is watching her
Is that what you came here to say?
- Yes
I realised it in the morning itself.
You emptied an entire film roll on her
You saw that?
Now that you know,
why don't you introduce her?
Introduce a girl to you?
- Yes, yes
You are baptized
What do you guys take me for?
Did you guys think I was a?
- Right
C'mon, introduce me to her.
- Let go! It's my wedding
All right, I spare you for your
wedding's sake. Now introduce me
Later.
- Later?
Later, you are not going to listen
even to your father
It's your nuptial-night
You will vanish in thin air.
Don't laugh
If you don't introduce me later...
I'll sneak into your room in the night
and burst crackers. Remember
May I leave now?
Bye sister-in-law
Hey...
- Bye
Hey wait...
Wonderful!
What a babe!
What's her name?
- Rina
Did you talk to her?
- No
Did she talk to you?
Did your eyes meet?
- No, man
She must've seen you at least.
- No
Damn!
For all your flings, you are a
bloody loser! Total waste of time
You'd rather have gone for a girl
at the market. Want me to set it up?
Shut up
Have I ever discussed a girl?
- No, gentleman
There were so many girls in college.
Those sexy girls from Delhi...
Wow!
- Everyone in college were after them
Not once did I cast a glance at them.
- You didn't
Who's that girl staying opposite?
- A good-looking Gujarati girl
Yes.
- Patel
Namita Patel.
- Right, scoundrels
For her, the guys in the neighbourhood
have even altered their schedules
Did I ever say hi to her?
- Never
But this time I'm telling you...
this girl's very different
The small silver bindi
on her forehead!
That cute killing smile!
That stylish sari wrapped around her!
Those beautiful delicate legs!
Her flowing tresses!
- Stop it!
Stop barking! What's your problem?
- Not a word more
Why not?
- Because right here, another man...
will enter your love-story
I'm also beginning to like her
No jokes...
I can't believe it.
- If I say more...
you won't believe it at all.
- Mady...
tonight, even if you say that
Madonna gave you a massage...
I'm gonna believe it.
- Hands off
I'm not Madonna. Lay off
Yes?
- The girl by Rina's side is amazing
She is out of focus.
- Then let's set the focus right
Damn, that's something invisible
Wonderful! It's amazing, Mady.
- Awesome!
I haven't shown you anything yet.
Hold on
I saw something up there
Don't tell me that
your days have turned so bad...
that you've resorted
to stealing cups from bars
Shut up
Look...
the mark of lipstick.
- So what?
Didn't get it?
- No
It's the same cup with which Rina...
- What?
Drank water
Show me
Shut up!
- Oh come on
You should've brought the plate too
with which she had her meals
We'd have made a photoframe
and hung it up the wall
It would've made a nice modern
abstract art, a symbol of love too
Blockhead!
- Come off it
What matters is he finally
found a girl for himself
He hasn't found her yet.
- Hang on...
before this pretty woman
finds herself a beau, we must act
Mady, I can read your face
If you don't have this girl
in your life, your life will be ruined
All right,
but what am I to do?
When it comes to ideas,
you remember D. D
So the idea is, friends;
pack your stuff, book your tickets...
leave for Delhi and find Rina.
- Let's go
No, dad
I hear that
when you fall in love...
only one channel is relayed
from the heart... Love
Great
Only one face lingers
before your eyes... the lover's
It's happening to me,
albeit slowly
Because, I can still see
your rotten faces
In my opinion, I must wait
for a few more days...
to confirm whether it is infatuation
or true love
What say? Until then,
Delhi can wait
See that? Their dads blow up
their ill-gotten wealth in liquor
And these girls blow up their
dads' money in gas
Stop screaming. I'll overtake them.
- Don't be stupid
If they fall off their motorbikes
there will be people to pick them up
If you and I fall...
- We'll have pallbearers to pick us up
What good was all that smoke?
Finally, you are stuck up in traffic
For all the fun and frolic...
you girls have to finally halt
at the wedding signal
Are you tied up?
See? She spoke to me
We only smoke beedis.
- Beedis! It doesn't stink?
It does. A few swills of whiskey
takes care of the stink
It's her!
Mady! The next seven generations
of yours will be born naked and bald
Your children will go begging
for combs and clothes!
Where's my specs?
Found it!
I can see now
Damn! Who hung the
trucker's picture here?
Moron! Did you find
only my truck to die?
Smartass! Take off your glasses
and look around
Did you find only my motorbike
to run over?
Why are you sucking the lemon?
Because my blood pressure dipped
Why the hell did you hang it there?
- For the truck to run properly
I see. How many organs
does your truck carry?
Organs? You mean spare parts?
If your truck cannot run properly
on 750 spare parts...
you think a lemon would help?
Trying to con me, eh? Pandey!
- That's me, sir
Not you... I called him.
Arrest him
One minute. Let go,
I'm not going to flee
Do you have 200 bucks?
- 200!
They won't agree on anything less.
- I gave all I had...
at the previous signal.
- Really? How about...
paying him back in the same coin?
- Stop murmuring, will you?
Hands off. Don't touch me
Prasad! Hands off
I know the Police Commissioner
He doesn't know me though
Is Shruti there? No?
When did she leave?
Okay, bye
What do you think you are doing?
- Mind your own business
I got drubbed because of you
Listen to me...
- Drop dead
You go your way, I go mine.
You are the malefic planet in my life
You are the malefic planet in my life!
What more do I say?
I hate you. I'm off.
- I'll buy you a beer
I love you. You are my best friend.
I go your way
You are a real gentleman.
- Look!
That's the Delhi girl. Rina
And the girl with her...
Your out-of-focus
Let's go and talk to them
Sure, but only I'll talk, okay?
- Sure
I'll have my eyeful.
- Come on...
Where did she go?
All because of you!
You aren't my friend
Drop dead!
You go your way, I go mine
Where did she go?
- Lost the beer!
I saw her again.
- Who?
The Delhi girl.
My kind of girl
Really?
I'm coming
I was with Vicky on the motorbike
when I saw her
Where?
- On the road
Then?
- I got off the bike and followed her
- She went into a shopping complex
Then?
How much for this cassette?
- Free of cost
I too went into the shopping complex.
- Then?
Then she vanished.
- Damn it!
That costs 530 bucks
I let go a golden opportunity.
- Damn
Tell you something... my heart
has been playing only programme
What programme?
- Rina
Only one face lingers before me...
- Whose face?
Rina's
I think I'm in love.
- Gracious! My son is in love
Your cassette is free
I haven't yet found the girl.
- You will, now that you are in love
Don't bathe, just wear a perfume
and take off
Your love's working.
- What!
The girl is in the supermarket.
- Where?
Dumbo! Supermarket.
- I'll be right there
How much for this?
Is she the one?
I'll hit you
She's not the one,
but she is her friend
We can take her help and...
man, you are confusing me
Let me explain. Look boss,
it's simple
If you want to meet the boss,
woo the peon
If you want to enter a bungalow,
woo the watchman
Likewise, if you want
to reach Rina...
you must woo her
out-of-focus friend. Come on
I'm Vicky, I want to have
a word with you
I don't mean to bother you.
Just want a bit of information
Information? What kind?
- Mady is my solid friend
And Rina is your solid friend.
Mady, say something
Your friend, Rina...
we are family friends
Thick friends.
- I'm talking
Actually, for the last few years...
there has hardly been
a contact with them...
there's a bit of...
- A rift
Yes
Yesterday, we saw the two of you
inside the shopping complex
Okay, you do the talking.
- Actually...
I'm talking, aren't I?
- Go ahead
We saw you... and when we thought
of coming over and talking to you...
the two of you just vanished.
- In thin air!
My family is supposed to perform
and important ritual soon...
If we could only get Rina's
phone number in Delhi
Delhi number?
You are telling me that
you are Rina's close friends...
but I'm surprised that you don't know
that Rina has been posted in Mumbai
That's what I was saying
Of late Rina is posted in Mumbai
If I could get the phone number...
- 6223222
Are you really her friends? Or?
- To tell you the truth...
we lied to you, but you know,
my best friend...
wants to be your best friend's
best friend, that's why...
Forget that number right now!
Madam, listen to me.
Ever since my friend has seen her...
he has gone crazy.
- Stop it, stop it
See that? He doesn't eat,
he won't let us eat either
He gets dead drunk, but he won't...
- It's all right
He won't buy us a drop of liquor.
- You are maligning me
Bloody zombie!
- Shut up
If you don't help him, this man will...
- Idiot!
That's your father.
- How dare you?
Try calling her up, try meeting her,
try talking to her...
but she won't talk to you.
- Is she dumb?
Rina's wedding has been fixed
Her parents have found
a match for her
I tell you, stop this farce
and forget Rina
You are neither emptying the stones
nor filling up the sea
Your efforts are going in vain
Vicky...
I never imagined that
a girl would walk into my life
I never ever imagined that
she'd right away walk out of my life
She's gone?
You are raving. It's out of question
since she doesn't belong to you
Why don't you go and meet her?
- Meet her?
And tell her what? Want me
to sing a melancholy before her?
Her parents have fixed her wedding,
she wouldn't talk to a stranger...
what am I supposed to tell her?
You are such a waste.
Look, I bunked college...
lied to my parents, bought
movie tickets in the black market...
What are you getting at?
- And took you to watch Titanic
What do you figure out?
Zero
What happens in Titanic?
Tell me, what happens in the movie?
A slink woos
an already engaged girl...
from right under her fiance's nose,
in just three days
Did anyone find out?
Okay, but what happens in the end?
Who drowned? The slink, right?
Not only Titanic, in real life too,
it is only the boys who drown
You dig?
What?
- Get lost
Tells me Titanic's story
How do I explain?
What?
Listen
It's the new law of the year 2001
Any boy who truly loves a girl...
will certainly find her
All right, give me her phone number
And your birth date?
Gotcha! You remember her phone number
but you don't remember your birth date
If not love, what is it, Mady?
Listen to me
Catch the love-wave signal
Pick up the phone
and dial the number
Her heart's gonna sing, I tell you
I'm calling from the exchange.
Is your line clear?
Yes, clear
Is the telephone working?
- Yes
Would you tell me your address?
So what's he saying?
Nothing.
- What do you mean?
Said, he wants to meet me,
he's coming next week
He'd want to meet me
before our parents fix the wedding
Flirting after the parents have
given their consent is so much fun
But this is more romantic;
you haven't even seen the man...
yet thinking of him and blushing...
But you must've approved of him, no?
When is this hero of yours coming?
I don't know. Before I could even
say something, it got disconnected
At least you should've told him
that you approve of him
Why didn't you say that you do?
Should be him
I'll handle this affair
One moment
Rajiv, this is Shruti.
Rina's best friend
I would like to tell you something
before Rina does
The two of you must meet
In fact, go around together,
get to understand each other
Rajiv, you have seen
Rina's latest photograph
But the last time she saw you was
when you were kids
She has no idea how you look
And all she knows is that you are
her papa's best friend's son...
and you are coming over next week
from Seattle, America
But why next week?
Wrong number, I guess
No good.
I know these type of girls
The father decides
which school she will study in
The mother decides the number
of plaits on her hair
And the entire family decides
on who she will marry
There! He's concluded the story
Moron! The conclusion could be
a new beginning too. Just shut up
Tell me honestly
Do you really love Rina dearly?
You said the she hasn't
seen the boy yet
She hasn't
Not after seven days,
Rajiv is arriving tomorrow
I mean, you will meet Rina
posing as Rajiv
And you'll tell her that you
flew down before schedule
Then, she's going to spend few days
with this Rajiv
And in this duration
you will have to win your game
You will tell her
what you feel about her
You will pour your heart
out to her
lmpress her. It should make her
love you the way you love her
True love never returns empty-handed
And once she
falls in love with you...
tell her that you are
not Rajiv but Mady
This is deceit
No. This is love
And in love, the person is important,
not the name
Now look; call me D. D or daddy...
call me Deen Dayal or Shiv Shankar,
hardly makes a difference
Once the relationship of love is built,
names and numbers cease to exist
One more thing.
You have no other way out
D. D, your brain
is still working. I admit
No wonder you've fixed
the missing link
However, just think...
in the interim,
if the real Rajiv...
calls up Rina from America
even once...
what would happen to the imposter?
That's not going to happen
Now that I have climbed up here,
will I find my way down? I'm scared
Cut the wire!
Else, I'll cut you up
I can't see a thing
Take of your glasses, switch on
the light, and you will see!
Sure. I'll meet you later and box
your ears for landing me in a soup
The phone's ringing
Could be the American.
Cut the line!
Hey...
Now what?
Who's sending these?
At least tell me
who's sending these
Now what?
Don't you guys have a job to do?
Some idiot seems to be sending flowers
and you guys keep delivering it
The idiot is here
Love, romance and amour, eh?
Trying to express your love
by sending flowers, right?
By the way, how much did you spend?
132 dollars
Dollars?
- Yes
Please leave
But you were supposed
to arrive next week?
Right. The flights were
going empty, so I rushed here
May I come in?
Lovely flowers
I chose these flowers
exclusively for you
I like this style
You were to arrive next week, right?
- Yes
Do your parents know
about his surprise?
Yes... actually, Rina...
I wanted the two of us to meet
and get to know each other well...
and tell our parents. So I didn't
inform them about this trip
And, well...
I have five days to spare
And I wish to spend every moment
of it with you
So that we can get to know
each other well
I was wondering if it is possible
for you to take five days off
I'll try. I'll call my boss.
He might agree
Oh, I forgot. The phone's not been
working for two days now
And I haven't yet complained.
- Obviously, it won't work
I mean, phones in India
are always dead
But that's not the case in America.
Over there, people might die...
talking continuously over the phone,
but the lines never get disconnected
How about going out for lunch?
- Sure. Shall I go and change?
I'm a pure Brahmin.
Will I eat chicken? No way
Is that okay?
Any other chicken dish?
Why not order some vegetarian dish?
The vegetarian fare here is fantastic
But your dad said that you
like Chinese chicken...
that's why I ordered chicken
Bloody butcher!
Am I going to defy my faith
for the sake of a girl?
We have met before.
Do you remember?
At a wedding in Delhi
When I was eight years old
You and your friends had locked me up
inside a dark room. Remember?
Your dad then gave you a cool scolding.
- Of course, I remember
You and your friends used to
pull up such stupid pranks
That was long back.
- Lucy was my best friend then
You remember Lucy?
- Yes! Our Lucy...
Lucy was my dog
Exactly! The tall dog...
Sorry, my memory is very weak
I'm famished. Shall we eat?
Absolutely
No! No! Don't!
No! No!
Nice chicken, no?
Okay now! Round two
What took you so long?
Is everything okay?
No problem at all.
I'm fine
Rajiv, how far is
Chicago from Seattle?
How far is Chicago from Seattle?
Couldn't she have asked
an easy question?
You don't know?
You've never been to America?
It's very closeby
It takes me only one and a half hours
when I'm driving
All the cops out there know me.
No one stops me
An airplane reaches even faster
You land before you even take off,
even before you take a seat
Why are you asking?
- My friend is married...
and settled in Chicago.
- We'll go there
I'll take you there.
- No, I don't want to go
Why not?
- I want to stay here in Mumbai
Why? Don't want to go abroad?
Staying there, working there...
I'm not too keen
Nothing like our Mumbai
That's like it.
It opens up avenues for me
Enjoy
I've been waiting for an hour now
Last night we had a party...
I just slept away...
the alarm didn't buzz,
the bike didn't start...
I kept on kicking...
I think I was expecting
too much from you
Don't be so serious.
I'm late, that's it
I have to go. Bye.
- Sure. On my motorbike
It has five gears...
not an autorickshaw!
Rina, come out please.
We'll go on our bike
It's a really good bike.
Soft, and imported
Look, it's so nice
Stop, man!
Don't you have a girlfriend?
Moron
So what's the plan?
Don't touch the meter.
- I know it's made of gold
Don't touch the meter, he says!
Good Lord! It's so hot
I mean, I'm sweating. How do
you guys manage such a hot weather?
You got mineral water, boss?
I drink only mineral water
in America