Five hundred twenty-five thousand
Six hundred minutes
Moments so dear
Five hundred twenty-five thousand
Six hundred minutes
How do you measure
Measure a year?
In daylights, in sunsets
In midnights, in cups of coffee
In inches, in miles
In laughter, in strife
In five hundred twenty-five thousand
Six hundred minutes
How do you measure
A year in the life?
How about love?
Measure in love
Seasons of love
Five hundred twenty-five thousand
Six hundred minutes
Journeys to plan
Five hundred twenty-five thousand
Six hundred minutes
How do you measure
The life of a woman or a man?
In truths that she learned?
Or in times that he cried?
In bridges he burned?
-Or the way that she died?
-It's time now to sing out
Though the story never ends
Let's celebrate
Remember a year in the life of friends
Remember the love
Oh, you got to
You got to remember the love
You know that love is a gift
From up above
Share love, give love, spread love
Measure, measure your life in love
Seasons of love
Measure your life
Measure your life in love
December 24th, 1989, 9 p.m.,
Eastern Standard Time.
From here on in,
I shoot without a script.
See if anything comes of it...
...instead of my old shit.
No, get out of here. Hey.
I said, get off the window.
How do you document real life
When real life's getting more
Like fiction each day?
Headlines, bread lines
Blow my mind
And now this deadline
Eviction or pay
Rent
How do you write a song
When the chords sound wrong?
Though they once sounded
Right and rare
When the notes are sour
Where is the power
You once had to ignite the air?
-We're hungry and frozen
-Some life we've chosen
-How we gonna pay?
-How we gonna pay
-Last year's rent?
-HeIIo?
-Hey, guess who's back in town.
It's CoIIins, man.
Throw down the key. CooI.
Hey.
-You got a Iight, man?
-Yeah.
-Give me that shit.
-Come here, man.
Get that son of a bitch.
Pick his ass up. Come on.
How do you start a fire
When there's nothing to burn
And it feels like something's stuck
In your flue?
How can you generate heat
When you can't feel your feet
-And they're turning blue?
You light up a mean blaze
-With posters
-And screenplays
-How we gonna pay?
-How we gonna pay
-Last year's rent?
How do you stay on your feet
When on every street
It's trick or treat
And tonight it's trick?
Welcome back to town
Oh, I should lie down
Everything's brown
And, uh-oh, I feel sick
-Where is he?
-Getting dizzy
-How we gonna pay?
How we gonna pay?
How we gonna pay
Last year's rent?
The music ignites the night
With passionate fire
The narration crackles and pops
With incendiary wit
Zoom in as they burn the past
To the ground
And feel the heat
Of the future's glow
How do you leave the past behind
When it keeps finding ways
To get to your heart?
It reaches way down deep
And tears you inside out
Till you're torn apart
Rent
How can you connect in an age
Where strangers, landlords, lovers
Your own blood cells betray?
What binds the fabric together
When the raging, shifting winds
Of change keep ripping away?
Draw a line in the sand
And then make a stand
-Use your camera to spar
-Use your guitar
When they act tough
You call their bluff
We're not gonna pay
Last year's rent
This year's rent
Next year's rent
Rent, rent, rent, rent, rent
We're not gonna pay rent
'Cause everything is rent
Hey.
Bum.
Get your ass off the Range Rover.
Benny, that attitude toward...
...the homeIess is exactIy what
Maureen is protesting.
Maureen is protesting Iosing her
performance space...
...not my attitude.
Come down, I wanna taIk to you.
CIose-up: Benjamin Coffin III.
Our ex-roommate...
...who married AIIison Grey
of the Westport Greys.
His father-in-Iaw bought
severaI buiIdings on the bIock...
...and a nearby vacant Iot,
home to Tent City.
Benny hopes to evict aII
of the homeIess from Tent City...
...and buiId a cyber studio.
Roger, you're Iooking good for a guy
coming off of a year of withdrawaI.
-What do you want, Benny?
-WeII, my investor--
-You mean, your father-in-Iaw?
-Right.
Read about Maureen's performance
in the Village Voice.
Got pissed and sent me down here
to coIIect the rent.
-What rent?
-This past year's rent, which I Iet sIide.
You said we were goIden.
-When you bought the buiIding.
-We were roommates.
-Remember, you Iived here?
-How couId I forget?
You, me, CoIIins and Maureen.
How is the drama queen?
-She's getting ready for a performance.
-I know.
-StiII her production manager?
-Not exactIy.
-StiII dating her?
-I was dumped.
-She got a new man?
-WeII....
-No.
-What's his name?
-Joanne.
Thanks for being so understanding.
You expect sympathy
from the guy...
...who shut off our power
on Christmas Eve?
Got your attention, didn't it?
What happened to Benny?
What happened to his heart
And the ideals he once pursued?
Any owner of that lot next door
Has a right to do with it as he pleases
Happy birthday, Jesus
-The rent
-You're wasting your time
-We're broke
-You broke your word, this is absurd
There is one way
You won't have to pay
-I knew it.
-Next door, the home of CyberArts
And now that the block is rezoned
Our dream can become a reality
You'll see, boys
A state-of-the-art, digital,
Virtual interactive studio
I'll forgo your rent
And on paper guarantee
That you can stay here for free
-If you do me one smaII favor.
-What?
Convince Maureen
to canceI her protest.
Why not just get an injunction
or caII the cops?
I did, and they're on standby.
But my investors would rather
I handle this quietly
You can't quietIy wipe out
an entire tent city...
...then watch It's A Wonderful Life
on TV.
You wanna produce fiIms
and write songs?
You need somewhere to do it
It's what we used to dream about
Think twice before you pooh-pooh it
You'll see, boys
You'll see the beauty of a studio
That lets us do our work
And get paid
With condos on the top
Whose rent keeps open our shop
Just stop the protest
And you'll have it made
You'll see
Or you'II pack.
Here you go.
Merry Christmas.
HeIIo?
Oh, my God. You okay, honey?
-I'm afraid so.
-Did they get anything, or...?
I didn't have any money,
but they took my stuff.
No, I'm fine. I'm fine.
I'm AngeI.
AngeI?
Friends caII me CoIIins.
Tom. Tom CoIIins.
Come on. Let's get you cIeaned up.
I sort of have to hurry.
-I have a Life Support meeting.
-Life Support?
Yeah.
It's for peopIe with AIDS.
PeopIe Iike me.
Me too.
I was gonna go try to find CoIIins.
You wanna come?
I thought maybe we couId aII grab
some dinner.
Zoom in on my empty waIIet.
Touch?.
Take your AZT.
I'm writing one great song
Before I....
One song
Glory
One song before I go
One song to leave behind
Find one song
One last refrain
Glory
From the pretty-boy front man
Who wasted opportunity
One song
He had the world at his feet
Glory
In the eyes of a young girl
A young girl
Find glory
Beyond the cheap colored lights
One song
Before the sun sets
Glory
On another empty life
Time flies
Time dies
Glory
One blaze of glory
Find glory
In a song that rings true
Truth like a blazing fire
An eternal flame
Find one song
A song about love
Glory
From the soul of a young man
A young man
Find the one song
Before the virus takes hold
Glory
Like a sunset
One song
To redeem this empty life
Time flies
And then no need
To endure anymore
Time dies
-What'd you forget?
-Got a light?
I know you, you're--
You're shivering
It's nothing
They turned off my heat
And I'm just a little weak on my feet
Would you light my candle?
-What are you staring at?
-Nothing
Your hair in the moonlight
You look familiar
-Can you make it?
-Just haven't eaten much today
At least the room
Stopped spinning anyway
-What?
-Nothing
-Your smile reminded me of--
-I always ''remind people of''
-Who is she?
-She died
-Her name was April
-It's out again
Sorry 'bout your friend
Would you light my candle?
-Well?
-Yeah?
Oh, the wax
-It's--
-Dripping
-I like it between my--
-Fingers
I figured
Oh, well, good night
-It blew out again?
-No, I think that I dropped my stash
I know I've seen you out and about
When I used to go out
Your candle's out
I'm illin'
I had it when I walked in the door
It was pure
Is it on the floor?
The floor?
They say that I have the best ass
Below 1 4th Street
-Is it true?
-What?
-You're staring again
-Oh, no
I mean, you do have a nice--
I mean, you look familiar
-Like your dead girlfriend
-Only when you smile
But I'm sure I've seen you
Somewhere else
Do you go to the Cat Scratch Club?
That's where I work
I dance
Yes
They used to tie you up
It's a living
I didn't recognize you
Without the handcuffs
We could light the candle
Oh, won't you light the candle?
Why don't you forget that stuff
-You look like you're 16
-I'm 19
But I'm old for my age
I'm just born to be bad
I once was born to be bad
I used to shiver like that
-I have no heat, I told you
-I used to sweat
-I got a cold
-Uh-huh, I used to be a junkie
-But now and then I like to feel good
-Uh-huh
-Oh, here
-What's that?
Candy-bar wrapper.
We could light the candle
Oh, what'd you do with my candle?
-That was my last match
-Our eyes'll adjust
-Thank God for the moon
-Maybe it's not the moon at all
I hear Spike Lee's shootin'
Down the street
Bah humbug
-Cold hands
-Yours too
Big
Like my father's
Do you wanna dance?
With you?
-No, with my father
-I'm Roger
They call me
They call me Mimi
We got power.
Merry Christmas.
-Speak.
Mark, are you there?
Are you screening your calls?
It's Mom.
I just wanted to call and say
we love you. We'll miss you today.
Cindy and the kids are here.
They send their love.
Hope you like the hot plate. Don't
leave it on when you leave the house.
-Honey, give me the phone.
-Oh, here's Dad.
Listen, Mark, I'm sorry to hear
that Maureen dumped you.
I say, c'est la vie.
Let her be a lesbian.
She doesn't know
what she's missing.
Happy holidays.
You know...
...there are times
when we're dirt broke...
...and hungry and freezing...
...and I ask myseIf,
''Why the heII am I stiII Iiving here?''
And then they caII.
And I remember.
What's that?
The girI downstairs.
Oh, the dancer
from the Cat Scratch CIub?
-WeII, you are going, right?
-No.
-Oh, come on, Roger.
-Merry Christmas, bitches.
-Hey, CoIIins.
-Your keys.
-Yeah, 1 4 hours Iater.
What the heII happened to you?
Are you aII right?
I've never been better. Here.
Oh, hi.
-''Oh, hi.'' After seven months?
-I'm sorry.
You know what you need?
This boy couId use...
-...some StoIi.
-This is a compIete Christmas feast.
-Thank you.
-You struck goId at MIT.
No.
They expeIIed me for my theory
of actuaI reaIity.
One for you. One for you.
Oh, wait.
For me.
So I came back home.
Merry Christmas.
-Cheers.
-WeIcome home.
I got a teaching gig at NYU.
Oh, so that's how you can afford
to spIurge on us.
No. Sit down.
Gentlemen, our benefactor
On this Christmas day
Whose charity is only matched
By talent, I must say
A new member of the Alphabet City
Avant-garde
Angel Dumott Schunard
Today for you
Tomorrow for me
-And you should hear her beat
-You earned this on the street?
It was my lucky day today
On Avenue A
When a lady in a limousine
Drove my way
She said, ''Darling, be a dear
Haven't slept in a year
I need your help to make my
Neighbor's yappy dog disappear
This Akita, Evita, just won't shut up
I believe if you play nonstop
That pup will breathe its very last
High-strung breath
I'm certain that cur
Will bark itself to death''
Today for you
Tomorrow for me
We agreed on a fee
$1000 guarantee, tax free
And a bonus if I trim her tree
Now, who could foretell
That it would go so well?
But sure as I am here
That dog is now in doggy hell
After an hour, Evita, in all her glory
On the window ledge
Of that 23rd story
Like Thelma and Louise did
When they got the blues
Swan-dove into the courtyard
Of the Gracie Mews
Today for you
Tomorrow for me
Back on the street
Where I met my sweet
Where he was moaning and groaning
On the cold concrete
The nurse took him home
For some Mercurochrome
Then I dressed his wounds
And got him back on his feet
Sing it
Today for you
Tomorrow for me
I say
Today for you
Tomorrow for me
Tomorrow
For me
That was dope.
That was fresh.
-Speak.
Mark. Hi.
It's me. Maureen.
Look, I have a bit of a problem.
I really need your help.
I hired Joanne
as my production manager...
...and I don't think she knows
what the hell she's doing.
If you could just-- Please, baby,
come to the performance space.
-Hey, Maureen. Hi.
-Hi, baby.
-Sure, I'II be there.
-Thank you.
-Okay.
Okay, see you soon.
Can you beIieve her?
I mean, first she just dumps me--
-Maureen dumped you?
-Yes. She dumped me.
For a Iawyer named Joanne.
Now she wants me to heIp her
fix her sound equipment.
-WeII, Mark, you couId've said no.
-I know, but....
-That's cute. You stiII Iove her.
-Yeah, right.
You do.
-We have to go.
-Wanna go to this gathering?
-Where?
-Life Support.
On Christmas?
Some peopIe don't have
anywhere eIse to go today.
You shouId come.
Knock yourseIves out.
Everyone's weIcome.
It's not just for peopIe with AIDS.
Okay, yeah, I'II be there,
but first I got a protest to save.
See? ToId you.
I'm just pIaying with you, boy.
WeII, it's Christmas.
Don't stay in the house aII day.
Bye.
Hi.
Maureen caIIed me to try to come
heIp fix the equipment.
You're Mark?
Joanne?
-Maureen said she'd be here.
-WeII, don't hoId your breath.
This is so typicaI.
I toId her not to caII you.
Oh, weII--
Can I heIp anyway?
I've hired an engineer.
Great.
WeII, nice to have met you, then.
He's three hours Iate.
The samples won't delay
But the cable--
There's another way
Say something, anything
Test, one, two, three
Anything but that
-This is weird
-It's weird
-Very weird
-Fuckin' weird
I'm so mad that
I don't know what to do
Fighting with microphones
Freezing down to my bones
And to top it all off
I'm with you
Feel like going insane?
Got a fire in your brain?
And you're thinking
Of drinking gasoline?
-As a matter of fact
-Honey, I know this act
It's called the Tango: Maureen
The Tango: Maureen
It's a dark, dizzy merry-go-round
-As she keeps you dangling
-You're wrong
-Your heart she is mangling
-It's different with me
And you toss and you turn
'Cause her cold eyes can burn
Yet you yearn, and you churn
And rebound
I think I know what you mean
-The Tango: Maureen
Has she ever pouted her lips
And called you ''pookie'"?
Never.
Have you ever
Doubted a kiss or two?
This is spooky
Did you swoon
When she walked through the door?
Every time, so be cautious
Did she moon over other boys?
-More than moon
-I'm getting nauseous
Where'd you Iearn to tango?
With the French ambassador's
daughter in her room at Miss Porter's.
And you?
With Nanette HimmeIfarb,
the rabbi's daughter...
...at the ScarsdaIe Jewish
Community Center.
It's hard to do this backwards.
You shouId try it in heeIs.
-She cheated
-Maureen cheated
-Fuckin' cheated
I'm defeated
I should give up right now
Gotta look on the bright side
With all of your might
I'd fall for her still, anyhow
When you're dancing her dance
You don't stand a chance
Her grip of romance makes you fall
-So you think, ''Might as well''
-''Dance a tango to hell''
''At least I'll have tangoed at all''
The Tango: Maureen
Gotta dance till your diva is through
You pretend to believe her
'Cause in the end
You can't leave her
But the end, it will come
Still you have to play dumb
Till you're glum and you bum
And turn blue
Why do we love when she's mean?
And she can be so obscene
My Maureen
The Tango:
Maureen
Mark.
Oh, my God.
Are you okay?
ActuaIIy...
...I feeI great now.
I feeI Iousy.
And we're patched.
Thanks.
-Maureen?
-Hi, baby.
-Hi, honey, we're--
-Pookie.
''Pookie''?
-You never caIIed me pook--
-We're late.
Forget it.
-We're patched.
-Thank you.
Pookie.
Shut up.
Okay, everyone, Iet's begin.
First, I just want to weIcome you aII.
Why don't we start by going
around and introducing ourseIves.
Steve.
Gordon.
AIi.
Pam.
Sue.
Hi.
I'm AngeI.
Tom.
CoIIins.
I'm PauI.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
And you are...?
Oh, I'm not--
I don't have--
I'm here with....
I'm just here to....
Mark.
Mark. I'm Mark.
WeII, this is quite an operation.
Does anyone have a probIem...
...if I fiIm a IittIe of this
for a documentary?
Make yourseIf comfortabIe, Mark.
Who wants to begin?
WeII, I'm--
Yesterday...
...I found out my T ceIIs were Iow.
What was your reaction?
Scared.
How are you feeIing today?
Right now?
Okay.
AII right.
Pretty good.
Is that aII?
It's the best I've feIt in a Iong time.
-Months.
-Then why choose fear?
I'm a New Yorker.
Fear's my Iife.
Look, I find
Some of what you teach suspect
Because I'm used to
Relying on intellect
But I try to open up
To what I don't know
Because reason says
I should have died
Three years ago
There's only us
There's only this
Forget regret
Or life is yours to miss
No other road
No other way
No day but today
What's the time?
Well, it's gotta be close to midnight
My body's talking to me
It says, ''Time for danger''
It says, ''I wanna commit a crime
Wanna be the cause of a fight
I wanna put on a tight skirt
And flirt with a stranger''
I've had a knack from way back
At breaking the rules
Once I learn the game
Get up, life's too quick
I know someplace sick
Where this chick'll
Dance in the flames
We don't need any money
I always get in for free
You can get in too
If you get in with me
Let's go
Out tonight
I have to go
You wanna play?
Let's run away
We won't be back
Before it's New Year's Day
Take me out tonight
Meow.
Yeah
When I get a wink
From the doorman
Do you know how lucky you'll be?
That you're on the line
With the feline of Avenue B
Let's go
Out tonight
I have to go
You wanna prowl?
Be my night owl?
Well, take my hand we're gonna
Howl
Out tonight
In the evening I've got to roam
Can't sleep in the city
Of neon and chrome
Feels too damn much like home
When the Spanish babies cry
So let's find a bar
So dark we forget who we are
Where all the scars
From the nevers and maybes die
Let's go
Out tonight
I have to go
You're sweet
Wanna hit the street?
Wanna wail at the moon
Like a cat in heat?
Just take me
Out tonight
Please take me
Don't forsake me
Out tonight
I'll let you make me
Tonight
Who do you think you are?
Barging in on me and my guitar
Little girl, hey, the door is that way
You better go
You know the fire's out anyway
Take your powder
Take your candle
Your sweet whisper
I just can't handle
Well, take your hair
In the moonlight
Your brown eyes
Goodbye, good night
I should tell you
I should tell you, I should--
No.
Another time, another place
Our temperature would climb
There'd be a long embrace
We'd do another dance
It'd be another play
Looking for romance?
Come back another day
Another day
The heart may freeze
Or it can burn
The pain will ease
If I can learn
There is no future
There is no past
I live this moment as
My last
There's only us
There's only this
Forget regret
Or life is yours to miss
No other road
No other way
No day but today
Excuse me if I'm off track
But if you're so wise
Then tell me
Why do you need smack?
Take your needle
Take your fancy prayer
Don't forget,
Get the moonlight out of your hair
Long ago you might have
Lit up my heart
But the fire's dead
Ain't never ever gonna start
Another time
Another place
The words would only rhyme
We'd be in outer space
It'd be another song
We'd sing another way
You wanna prove me wrong?
Come back another day
Another day
There's only yes
Only tonight
We must let go
To know what's right
No other course
No other way
No day but today
I can't control
Control your temper
My destiny
She doesn't see
I trust my soul
-Who says that there's a soul?
-My only goal
Is just to be
Just let me be
-Who do you think you are?
-There's only now, there's only here
-Barging in on me and my guitar
-Give in to love, or live in fear
-Little girl, hey
-No other path
-The door is that way
-No other way
No day but today
The fire's out anyway
Take your powder
Take your candle
No day but today
Take your brown eyes,
Your pretty smile, your silhouette
No day but today
Another time, another place,
Another rhyme, a warm embrace
No day but today
Another dance,
Another way, another chance
Another day
No day but today
-Speak.
Mark, Roger, it's Benny.
Look, you still got a few hours
to stop Maureen's protest.
My offer expires after dark.
Hey.
How you doing?
-Look, about Iast night--
-I don't wanna taIk about it.
You know, Mimi's gonna be
at Maureen's show tonight.
You shouId come too.
I'd hate to see you pass up
something that couId be good for you.
You'II onIy regret it.
I'II Iive.
Right.
Will I lose my dignity?
Will someone care?
Will I wake tomorrow
From this nightmare?
Will I lose my dignity?
Will someone care?
Will I wake tomorrow
From this nightmare?
-Will I lose my dignity?
Will someone care?
-Will I wake tomorrow
-From this nightmare?
-Will I lose my dignity?
-Will someone care?
-Will I wake tomorrow
-From this nightmare?
-Will I lose my dignity?
Will I lose my dignity?
-Will someone care?
-Will I lose my dignity?
-Will I wake tomorrow
-Will someone care?
-From this nightmare?
-Will I wake tomorrow
From this nightmare?
-Will I lose my dignity?
-Will I lose?
Will someone care?
Will I wake tomorrow
From this nightmare?
I am so gIad you came, man.
-I'm proud of you.
-Thanks.
Come on, get up.
Come on, Iet's go.
-Wake up.
-This ain't a campground.
Let's go. You gotta go.
Christ, it's a Iady.
Come on, ma'am, you gotta get up.
SmiIe for Ted KoppeI, officers.
Who do you think you are?
I don't need no goddamn heIp...
...from some
bIeeding-heart cameraman.
My Iife's not for you to make
a name for yourseIf on.
Easy, sugar, easy.
He was just trying--
Just trying to use me
to kiII his guiIt.
It's not that kind of movie, honey.
This pIace is fuII of artists.
Hey, artist, you got a doIIar?
Didn't think so.
New York City
-Center of the universe
-Sing it, girI.
Times are shitty, but I'm pretty sure
They can't get worse
-I hear that.
-It's a comfort to know
When you're singing
The hit-the-road blues
That anywhere else you could
Possibly go after New York would be
A pleasure cruise
Now you're taIking.
Well, I'm thwarted by a
Metaphysic puzzle
And I'm sick of grading papers,
That I know
I'm shouting in my sleep
I need a muzzle
And all this misery pays no salary
So
Let's open up a restaurant
In Santa Fe
Sunny Santa Fe would be nice
We'll open up a restaurant
In Santa Fe
And leave this
To the roaches and mice
-You teach?
-Yeah, I teach.
Computer Age PhiIosophy.
When my students
wouId rather watch TV.
-America.
You're a sensitive aesthete
Brush the sauce onto the meat
You can make the menu
Sparkle with a rhyme
You can drum a gentle drum
I can seat guests as they come
Chatting not about Heidegger,
But wine
Let's open up a restaurant
In Santa Fe
-Santa Fe
-Our labors would reap financial gain
-Gain
-We'll open up
A restaurant in Santa Fe
-Santa Fe
-And save from devastation our brains
Save our brains
We'll pack up all ourjunk
And fly so far away
Devote ourselves to projects
That sell
We'll open up a restaurant
In Santa Fe
Forget this cold bohemian hell
Do you know the way
To Santa Fe?
You know, tumbleweeds
Prairie dogs
Yeah
Oh, guys, I'm Iate for Maureen's
sound check. I gotta go.
-Here, you can heIp me.
-Bye.
See you Iater.
It's coId.
Come on.
Live in my house
I'll be your shelter
Just pay me back
With 1000 kisses
Be my lover
I'll cover you
Open your door
I'll be your tenant
Don't got much baggage
To lay at your feet
But sweet kisses I've got to spare
I'll be there and I'll cover you
-I think they meant it
-When they said you can't buy love
-Now I know you can rent it
-A new lease you are, my love
-On life
-Be my life
-Just slip me on
-I'll be your blanket
-Wherever, whatever
-I'll be your coat
You'll be my king
And I'll be your castle
No, you'll be my queen
And I'll be your moat
-I think they meant it
-When they said you can't buy love
-Now I know you can rent it
-A new lease you are, my love
-On life
-All my life
-I've longed to discover
-Something as true as this is
-So with a thousand sweet kisses
-When you're cold and you're lonely
I'll cover you
With a thousand sweet kisses
-You've got one nickel only
-I'll cover you
With a thousand sweet kisses
-When you're worn out and tired
-I'll cover you
With a thousand sweet kisses
-When your heart has expired
-I'll cover you
-Oh, lover
-Yeah
-I'll cover you
I'm gonna ceIebrate tonight.
AII right, cooI.
-The usuaI.
-CooI.
-Hey.
-Hey. Can I taIk to you for a sec--?
Hey. Lover boy. You steaI
my cIient, you die.
You didn't miss me,
you won't miss her.
Look around.
Got pIenty of customers.
Look.
About Iast night, I'm sorry.
-I don't know what the--
-Just forget it.
I was out of Iine.
Can I make it up to you?
How?
Bunch of us
are getting together tonight.
At the Life Caf?
after Maureen's show.
Yeah?
WouId you Iike to come with me?
Sure. I'd Iike that.
So you're a tough guy?
No. Not reaIIy.
That's pretty good.
Over there.
The guy with the gIasses.
Right there.
-AngeI.
-Mimi.
Oh, my God, you Iook so good.
Maureen! Maureen! Maureen!
Last night I had a dream.
I found myseIf in a desert
caIIed CyberIand.
It was hot.
My canteen had sprung a Ieak,
and I was...
...thirsty.
Out of the abyss waIked a cow.
EIsie.
I asked if she had anything to drink.
She said:
''I'm forbidden to produce milk
In Cyberland we only drink
Diet Coke''
She said:
''Only thing to do
Is jump over the moon''
I
Gotta get out of here
It's like I'm being tied to the hood
Of a yellow rental truck
Being packed in
With fertilizer and fuel oil
Pushed over a cliff
By a suicidal Mickey Mouse
I've
Gotta, gotta, gotta, gotta, gotta
Gotta, gotta find a way
To jump over the moon
Only thing to do
Is jump over the moon
Yeah! Go, Maureen!
Then a IittIe buIIdog entered.
His name, we have Iearned,
was Benny.
And aIthough he once
had principIes...
...he abandoned them
to Iive as a Iapdog...
...to a weaIthy daughter
of the revoIution.
A one, two, three
''That's bull,'' he said
''Ever since the cat took up the fiddle
That cow's been jumpy
The dish and the spoon were evicted
From the table and eloped
She's had trouble with that milk
And the moon ever since
Maybe it's a female thing
'Cause who'd wanna leave
Cyberland anyway?
Walls ain't so bad
The dish and the spoon, for instance,
They're down on their luck
They come knockin'
On my doghouse door
And I say,
'Not in my back yard, utensils.
Go back to China'''
''The onIy way out is up,''
EIsie whispered to me.
''A leap
Of faith''
-Yeah.
-That's it.
''StiII thirsty?''
''Parched.''
''Have some miIk.''
And I Iowered myseIf
beneath her swoIIen udder...
...and I sucked the sweetest miIk
I had ever tasted.
''CIimb onboard,'' she said.
And as a harvest moon
rose over CyberIand...
...we reared back,
we sprang into a gaIIop...
...Ieaping out of orbit.
I awoke, singing...
Leap of faith
Only thing to do
Only thing to do is jump
Only thing to do is
Jump over the moon
Over the moon
Over the....
Moo with me.
Yes. Who is that? Come on.
Yes. Come on, sir.
Don't be shy. Let it go. Moo with me.
Let it rip.
Yes. Let it go, New York City.
Yeah.
Hey, get off, man.
Just caIm down.
Take it easy now, aII right?
Back off.
Hey, hey, hey. Guys, it's okay.
It's okay. Just keep cooI.
Come on, move back.
-Take it easy, aII right?
-This is supposed be a peace--
Officer, pIease.
Look, just keep-- Hey.
PIease. Everyone, be caIm.
Everyone, pIease.
Oh, my God.
Stop it.
-Get off of me.
-Let go of him.
-CoIIins.
-Get off of her.
Get off of me.
-Get off of me.
-Get off her.
-Let's get out of here. This way.
-Go, go, go.
Everyone, be cooI.
Stop, this is peacefuI.
PIease.
Benny got exactIy what he wanted.
He screws up my show,
he gets aII these peopIe arrested.
Cops won't hoId them for Iong.
They'II Iet them go in a few hours.
-Oh, there they are.
-You aII right?
-Yes. Yes.
-Joanne?
-CoIIins.
-Nice to meet you.
-AngeI.
-Oh, it's coId. Let's go inside, okay?
-Yeah.
Hi, baby. Thank you.
Wait, where's Mark?
I don't know, man. Let's wait for him
inside. Come on.
Let's go.
-Hey.
-Hey. Are you aII right?
I'm fine. I'm fine. I'm fine.
Tonight on the 1 1 :00 news,
the Iead story is gonna be your show.
-How do you know that?
-They bought my footage of the riot.
-They're gonna see the whoIe thing.
-CongratuIations.
-Thank you.
-Good work, Mark.
-You serious?
-Yes.
How can I repay you?
Let the boy buy us dinner.
-Okay.
-Oh, no.
PIease, no. No, not tonight.
-PIease Ieave.
-What? Why?
You sit here aII night,
and you never order anything.
That's a Iie. Last week I had a tea.
You couIdn't pay.
-Oh, yeah.
-Yeah.
Tonight we can. Come on.
Fine. Just pIease
don't move the tabIes.
Let's put these tabIes together.
-SIide this way. Put these together.
-No. No, no, no.
Hey, DoodIes.
WeII, if you get back to me,
Iet's say by earIy next week...
...we can break ground,
I'm thinking, mid-January.
Benjamin Coffin III.
The enemy of Avenue A.
You got a whoIe Iot of nerve
showing your face here...
...after what just happened.
Listen, guys, this was not my fauIt.
-Go to heII.
-Jerk.
You put the cops on standby.
-I didn't want it to get out of controI.
-Why did Muffy--
AIIison.
--miss the show?
There....
There was a death in the famiIy.
Who died?
Our Akita.
-Evita.
You make fun
Yet I'm the one
Attempting to do some good
Or do you really want
A neighborhood
Where people piss
On your stoop every night?
Bohemia
Bohemia's a fallacy in your head
This is Calcutta
Bohemia is dead
Dearly beloved
We gather here
To say our goodbyes
Here she lies
No one knew her worth
The late, great daughter
Of Mother Earth
On these nights
When we celebrate the birth
In that little town of Bethlehem
We raise our glass
You bet your ass
To
La vie
Boh?me
La vie boh?me
-La vie boh?me
-To days of inspiration
Playin' hooky
Makin' somethin' out of nothin'
The need to express
To communicate
To going against the grain
Going insane
-La vie boh?me
-Going mad
-To loving tension
No pension
To more than one dimension
To starving for attention,
Hating convention, hating pretension
Not to mention, of course
Hating dear old Mom and Dad
To riding your bike midday
Past the three-piece suits
To fruits
To no absolutes
To Absolut
To choice
To the ViIIage Voice
To any passing fad
To being an us for once
Instead of a them
La vie boh?me
Hey, mister.
She's my sister.
So that's five miso soup
Four seaweed salad
Three soy-burger dinner
Two tofu-dog platter
And one pasta with meatless balls
It tastes the same
If you close your eyes
-And 13 orders of fries, is that it here?
-Wine and beer
To handcrafted beers
Made in local breweries
To yoga
To yogurt
To rice and beans and cheese
To leather
To dildos
To curry vindaloo
To huevos rancheros
And Maya Angelou
Emotion, devotion
To causing a commotion
Creation
Vacation
Mucho masturbation
Compassion
To fashion
To passion when it's new
-To Sontag
-To Sondheim
To anything taboo
Ginsberg, Dylan, Cunningham
And Cage
Lenny Bruce
-Langston Hughes
-To the stage
-To Uta
-To Buddha
Pablo Neruda too
Why Dorothy and Toto
Went over the rainbow
To blow off Auntie Em
La vie boh?me
-Sisters?
-We're cIose.
Brothers
Bisexuals, trisexuals,
Homo sapiens
Carcinogens, hallucinogens, men,
Pee-wee Herman
German wine, turpentine
Gertrude Stein
Antonioni, Bertolucci, Kurosawa
Carmina Burana
To apathy
To entropy
To empathy
Ecstasy
V?clav Havel
The Sex Pistols
8BC
To no shame
Never playin' the fame game
-To marijuana
-To sodomy
It's between God and me
To S & M
-Waiter, waiter, waiter, waiter.
-La vie boh?me
In honor of the death of bohemia...
...an impromptu saIon wiII commence
immediateIy foIIowing dinner.
Maureen Johnson,
back from her spectacuIar...
...one-night engagement
at the 1 1th Street Iot...
...wiII perform tribaI chants
backwards...
...through her vocoder, accompanying
herseIf on the eIectric ceIIo.
Which she ain't never studied.
And Mark Cohen wiII preview
his new documentary...
...about his inabiIity to hoId an erection
on the High HoIy Days.
And Mimi Marquez,
cIad onIy in bubbIewrap...
...wiII perform her famous
Iawn-chair handcuff dance...
...to the sounds of iced tea
being stirred.
And Roger wiII attempt to write
a bittersweet, evocative song...
...that doesn't remind us
of ''Musetta's WaItz.''
AngeI Dumott Schunard wiII modeI
the Iatest faII fashions from Paris...
...whiIe accompanying herseIf
on the 10-gaIIon pIastic pickIe tub.
And CoIIins wiII recount
his expIoits as anarchist...
...incIuding his successfuI
reprogramming...
...of the MIT retro-reaIity
equipment to seIf-destruct...
...as it broadcasts the words:
ActuaI reaIity. ACT UP. Fight AIDS.
Excuse me
Did I do somethin' wrong?
I get invited, then ignored
All night long
I've been tryin'
I'm not lyin'
No one's perfect
I've got baggage
Life's too short, babe
Time is flyin'
I'm lookin' for baggage
That goes with mine
-I should tell you
-I've got baggage too
-Should tell you-- Baggage
-Baggage
Wine and beer
AZT break.
You?
Me
Mimi
I should tell you
I'm disaster
I forget how to begin it
Let's just make this part go faster
I have yet to be in it
I should tell you
I should tell I blew the candle out
Just to get back in
I'd forgotten how to smile
Until your candle burned my skin
I should tell you
-I should tell
-Well, here we go
-Now we
Oh, no
I know this something is
-Here goes
Guess so, it's starting to
-Who knows?
-Who knows where?
-Who goes there?
-Who knows?
-Here goes
-Trusting desire
-Starting to learn
-Walking through fire
-Without a burn
-Clinging a shoulder
-A leap begins
-Stinging and older
-Asleep on pins
-So here we go
-Now we
Oh, no
-I know
-Oh, no
-Who knows where?
-Who goes there?
-Here goes
-That's right. Come on.
-Yeah.
-To dance
-No way to make a living
Masochism, pain, perfection
Muscle spasms, chiropractors
Short careers, eating disorders
-Film
-Adventure, tedium
No family, boring locations
Darkrooms
Perfect faces, egos, money
Hollywood and sleaze
-Music
-Food of love, emotion
Mathematics, isolation
Rhythm, power
Feeling, harmony
And heavy competition
-Anarchy
-Revolution, justice
Screaming for solutions
Forcing changes, risk and danger
Making noise and making pleas
To faggots, lezzies, dykes
Cross-dressers too
-To me
To you and you and you
You and you
To people living with
Living with, living with
Not dying from disease
Let he among us without sin
Be the first to condemn
La vie boh?me
-La vie boh?me
-Anyone out of the mainstream
-Is anyone in the mainstream?
-La vie boh?me
-Anyone alive with a sex drive
-Tear down the wall
Aren't we all?
-The opposite of war isn't peace
-What is?
It's creation
La vie boh?me
Viva la vie boh?me!
Five hundred twenty-five thousand
Six hundred minutes
Moments so dear
Five hundred twenty-five thousand
Six hundred minutes
How do you measure
Measure a year?
In diapers, report cards
In spoked wheels, in speeding tickets
In contracts, dollars
In funerals, in births
In 525,600 minutes
How do you figure
A last year on Earth?
Figure in love
-Figure in love
-Eight, seven, six, five...
-...four, three, two, one.
Measure in love
Seasons of love
Hey, Mimi. Mimi.
Mimi, give me
your New Year's resoIutions.
I'm giving up my vices.
I'm going back to schooI.
Oh, that's very good.
How about you, Roger?
-Finish a song.
-Yeah, maybe this year?
And who are you two
supposed to be?
-Bond. James Bond.
-And Pussy GaIore. In person.
Very nice.
What you want, huh?
WeII, you can take the girI
out of HicksviIIe...
...but you can't take
the HicksviIIe out of the girI.
Heard you got a job offer.
No, it was just that sIeazy news show
Buzzline wants to take a meeting.
We're gonna need an agent.
-''We''?
-Hey, Iisten, mister.
I am the reason you got on TV
in the first pIace.
Oh, my God. You know what?
We'II do another protest.
And this time you can shoot
the entire thing for the TV show.
No, I'm not interested, I'm sorry.
What? Why not?
Because working for a show Iike
Buzzline, that's compIeteIy seIIing out.
Okay. But it's nice to dream.
-WeII, maybe.
-Happy New Year.
Happy New Year.
Give me that. I'm sick
and tired of you aIways--
-Maureen. You're gonna break it.
-Hi, Mark.
-Happy New Year.
-This is not my bar mitzvah.
Give it back to me.
Out of aII the years
I've been in New York...
...I've never gone to Times Square
for New Year's.
-ReaIIy?
-I don't think I wanna do it again.
-I think that was enough.
-It was a IittIe Iike a moo-fest.
-Mark.
-What?
Check out the door.
What the heII is that?
Guys, there's a padIock
on the door.
Benny.
HoId on. HoId this, honey.
I saw this on teIevision. Watch.
Baby, what you doing?
You'II see.
Be carefuI, now.
-You're drunk.
-No, I'm not.
Okay, watch.
-That's so heavy.
-Watch your fingers.
That's my girI.
-Yeah.
-Nothing Iike Pussy.
-Let's go.
-Here you go, baby.
-Thank you.
-Door open.
-That's a fuII-service woman.
-That was great.
-Gonna put that trash can back?
-No.
Oh, damn.
TypicaI.
He took aII our stuff.
Mine too.
What a fricking sweetheart.
What do we do now?
WeII, technicaIIy,
now that you're inside...
...you're squatters.
You can't be arrested.
Benny can't throw you
out on the street.
It'II give you and Roger time
to get some money together.
There's aIways Buzzline.
Oh, my God,
my stomach doesn't feeI right.
You'II be fine.
Is what I'm wearing okay?
Does this Iook right?
Yeah, you Iook reaIIy good.
Do you think this beIt
is too much, though?
-I can't do this.
-Come on.
-Yes, you can. I'II do aII the taIking.
-What are you doing?
-Stop fussing. We're Iate.
Oh, my God, Iook at this pIace.
Yeah, it's corporate America.
WeIcome.
-Hi. We're here to see AIexi DarIing.
-Hi.
-Your name?
-Joanne Jefferson and Mark Cohen.
I'm Maureen Johnson.
Maybe you shouId wait out here.
-But I'm the one--
-We don't wanna come on too strong.
AIexi, Joanne Jefferson
and Mark Cohen here to see you.
Okay. Fine.
Whatever.
How much did I Iove your footage?
So much.
It reminded me of my BerkeIey days.
Fighting the good fight.
-Kudos. Kudos.
-Thank you.
I wanted to Iet you know that I've aIso
been working on a documentary...
...about the homeIess
and peopIe with HIV.
Great. I Iove it. So fresh, edgy.
Everything Buzzline's about.
-ReaIIy?
-We may dip into the tabIoid side.
GuiIty as charged.
But we are a news show.
And your cIient has a fresh eye
to bring reaI stories to an audience...
...and that's what we want.
We get the reaI programming...
...he gets the network exposure. Not a
bad way to start a career, by the way.
So, what do you think?
Yes. What about saIary?
On commission.
On an escaIating scaIe.
Start at $3000.
You're not gonna get
a better deaI than that.
We'II take it.
CongratuIations.
-I soId my souI.
-For 3 grand a segment.
You ain't got nothing
without my protest.
Does everything
have to be about you?
Me? You're the one
heIping my ex-boyfriend.
He needed a Iawyer.
I figured I couId heIp out,
since you got them evicted.
You know what? Why don't the two
of you get an accountant's Iedger...
...and a bottIe of champagne
and go at it.
Invite the girI you were just fIirting with
to join us and I wiII.
Oh, my God. Come on, Pookie.
I was just being friendIy.
-My God.
-What do you want, huh?
I'II do anything.
You want me to be your sIave?
You want me
to just obey your every wish?
TeII me what you want.
Commitment.
That's aII?
Why didn't you say so
in the first pIace?
What?
AII you have to do is ask...
...and I'm yours.
WiII you commit to me?
To be with onIy me
for the rest of our Iives?
I wiII.
I do.
This can't be happening.
I'd Iike to weIcome everyone...
...and congratuIate
my daughter Joanne.
On-- On her wonderfuI choice
of a Iife partner, Maureen Johnson.
My husband and I wouId aIso Iike
to weIcome Maureen's parents...
...Eddie and Nancy Johnson,
into our famiIy.
WouId everyone pIease stand?
And Iet's raise a gIass to toast
the future of Joanne and Maureen.
Hear, hear.
Cheers.
I Iove you, baby.
Thanks, Mom.
You got engaged.
Thanks, Dad.
-Cheers.
-Thanks.
-CongratuIations.
-Hi. Thank you.
Got anything stronger than this?
OnIy champagne and wine,
unfortunateIy.
Hi.
Thank you.
You know, Maureen didn't even
Iet me reaIIy congratuIate her yet.
I know, because....
-Where'd you get this neckIace?
-Oh, just downtown.
CouId you excuse me for a minute?
-Hi. CouId you excuse us a minute?
-Hi, baby.
Thank you.
-What's up?
-What the heII are you doing?
What? We were just taIking.
-Right.
-Pookie, we were just taIking.
Maureen, pIease,
do not do this today.
Excuse me, sir,
can you hoId this, pIease?
-CertainIy.
-Thanks.
You know what, Miss Ivy League?
I can't take much more of this.
This obsessive-compuIsive,
controI-freak paranoia.
-What?
-I didn't pierce my nippIes...
...because it grossed you out.
I didn't stay at the Kink CIub Iast night
because you wanted to go home.
You fIirted with
the woman in rubber.
There wiII aIways be women
in rubber fIirting with me.
Give me a break.
Every single day
I walk down the street
I hear people say
''Baby's so sweet''
Ever since puberty
Everybody stares at me
Boys, girls, I can't help it, baby
So be kind
And don't lose your mind
Just remember that I'm your baby
Take me for what I am
Who I was meant to be
And if you give a damn
Take me, baby, or leave me
A tiger in a cage
Can never see the sun
This diva needs her stage
Baby, let's have fun
You are the one I choose
Folks would kill to fill your shoes
You love
The limelight too now, baby
So be mine
And don't waste my time
Crying, ''Oh, honey bear,
Are you still my, my
-My baby?''
-Don't you dare.
Take me for what I am
Who I was meant to be
And if you give a damn
Take me, baby, or leave me
No way can I be what I'm not
But, hey, don't you want
Your girl hot?
Don't fight
Don't lose your head
'Cause every night
Who's in your bed?
Who?
-Kiss, Pookie.
-It won't work.
I look before I leap
I love margins and discipline
I make lists in my sleep, baby
What's my sin?
Never quit
I follow through
I hate mess
But I love you
What to do
With my impromptu baby
So be wise
'Cause this girl satisfies
You've got a prize
But don't compromise
You're one lucky baby
-Take me for what I am
-A controI freak.
-Who I was meant to be
-A snob, yet overattentive.
-And if you give a damn
-A IovabIe, droII geek.
-Take me, baby, or leave me
-An anaI-retentive.
-That's it
The straw that breaks my back
-I quit
Unless you take it back
-Women
What is it about them?
-Can't live with them or without them
-Take me for what I am
-Who I was meant to be
-And if you give a damn
You better take me, baby
-Oh, take me, baby
-Or leave me
Take me or leave me
-Take me, baby
-Or leave me
-Guess I'm leaving
-I'm gone
Maybe now you two
can get back together.
-WeII, actuaIIy, I'm--
-Come on, Iet's go.
Hey, guys, aII our shit's back.
Benny, what's going on?
I'm here to put an end to this war.
-What changed your mind?
-Mimi did, actuaIIy.
We hadn't seen each other in a whiIe.
So we had dinner, we taIked...
...and she convinced me
to rethink the situation.
Look, I regret
the unIucky circumstances--
Circumstance? Benny,
you padIocked our door...
-...and you took aII of our stuff.
-Right.
Which is why I'm here offering
a new Iease. AII right?
Rent-free, courtesy of CyberArts.
You might wanna get this on fiIm.
Oh, I see,
this is a photo opportunity.
The benevoIent god ushers
the poor artists back to their fIat.
Brought to you
by your friendIy CyberArts.
-FuII story tonight on Buzzline.
-It's not Iike that, CoIIins.
Look, we don't need your charity.
ShouId cover us for a IittIe whiIe.
Where'd you get this?
It's my first advance.
Okay. CongratuIations.
Excuse me.
Roger...
...nothing happened.
Benny and me, it's over.
We had a thing once...
-...but it was two years ago.
-It doesn't matter.
-It was before I met you.
-I don't care.
Without you
The ground thaws
The rain falls
The grass grows
Without you
The seeds root
The flowers bloom
The children play
The stars gleam
The poets dream
The eagles fly
Without you
The Earth turns
The sun burns
But I die without you
Without you
The breeze warms
The girl smiles
The cloud moves
Without you
The tides change
The boys run
The oceans crash
The crowds roar
The days soar
The babies cry
Without you
The moon glows
The river flows
But I die without you
The world revives
Colors renew
-But I know blue
-Only blue
-Lonely blue
Within me, blue
Without you
The hand gropes
The ear hears
The pulse beats
Without you
The eyes gaze
The legs walk
The lungs breathe
-The mind churns
-The heart yearns
-The tears dry
Without you
-Life goes on
-But I'm gone
-'Cause I die without you
-I die
Without you
-Without you
It's right...
...that today's HaIIoween.
It was AngeI's favorite hoIiday.
I knew we'd hit it off
the moment we met.
There was this skinhead
that was harassing her...
...and she just waIked
right up to him and said:
''I'm more of a man
than you'II ever be...
...and more of a woman
than you'II ever get.''
And then there was this time...
...he waIked up
to this group of tourists...
...and they were petrified...
...because, A, they were
obviousIy Iost...
...and, B, had probabIy never spoken
to a drag queen before in their Iives.
And he....
She...
...just offered to escort them
out of AIphabet City...
...and then Iet them
take a picture with her...
...and then said she'd heIp them
find the CircIe Line.
So much more originaI
than any of us.
You'd find an oId tabIecIoth
on the street and make a dress...
...and then the next year,
sure enough...
...they'd be mass-producing
them at the Gap.
You aIways said how Iucky
you were that we were aII friends...
...but it was us, baby...
...who were the Iucky ones.
Live in my house
I'll be your shelter
Just pay me back
With 1000 kisses
Be my lover
And I'll cover you
Yeah
Open your door
I'll be your tenant
Don't got much baggage
To lay at your feet
But sweet kisses I've got to spare
I'll be there and I'll cover you
I think they meant it
When they said you can't buy love
Now I know you can rent it
A new lease you are, my love
On life
All my life
I've longed to discover
Something as true as this is
Yeah
So with a thousand sweet kisses
-If you're cold and you're lonely
-I'll cover you
With a thousand sweet kisses
-You've got one nickel only
-I'll cover you
With a thousand sweet kisses
-When you're worn out and tired
-I'll cover you
With a thousand sweet kisses
When your heart has expired
Oh, lover
I'll cover you
Five hundred twenty-five thousand
Six hundred minutes
Seasons of
-Love
-I'll cover you, oh
It's true you sold your guitar
And bought a car?
It's true
I'm leaving now for Santa Fe
It's true you're with
This yuppie scum?
You said you'd never
Speak to him again
-Not now.
-Who said that you have any say
-In who she says things to at all?
-Yeah.
Who said that you should stick
Your nose in other people--?
Who said I was taIking to you?
-We used to have this fight each night
-Calm down
-She'd never admit I existed
-Everyone, please
He was the same way
He was always
Run away, hit the road, don't commit
You're full of shit
-She's in denial
-He's in denial
Didn't give an inch
When I gave a mile
-I gave a mile
-Gave a mile to who?
Come on, guys, chiII.
I'd be happy to die
For a taste of what Angel had
-Someone to live for
-Unafraid to say ''I love you''
All your words are nice, Mimi
But love's not a three-way street
You'll never share real love
Until you love yourself
I should know
You all said you'd be cool today
So please, for my sake
I can't believe he's gone
I can't believe you're going
I can't believe this family must die
Angel helped us believe in love
I can't believe you disagree
I can't believe this is
Goodbye
Don't breathe too deep
Don't think all day
Dive into work
Drive the other way
That drip of hurt
That pint of shame
Goes away
Just play the game
You're living in America
At the end of the millennium
Leave your conscience at the tone
And when you're living in America
At the end of the millennium
You're what you own
The filmmaker cannot see
And the songwriter cannot hear
Yet I see Mimi everywhere
Angel's voice is in my ear
Just tighten those shoulders
Just clench yourjaw till you frown
Just don't let go
-Or you may drown
You're living in America
At the end of the millennium
-You're living in America
-Where it's like The TwiIight Zone
-And when you're living in America
-At the end of the millennium
-You're what you own
-So I own not a notion
-I escape and ape content
-I don't own emotion
-I rent
-What was it about that night?
-Connection in an isolating age
-For once the shadows
-Gave way to light
-For once I didn't disengage
-Angel, I hear you, I hear it, I see it
-Mimi, I see you
-I see it, my film
-I hear it, I hear it, I hear it, my song
-AIexi, Mark. CaII me a hypocrite...
-One song, glory
-...I need to finish my own fiIm. I quit.
-Mimi, your eyes
Dying in America
At the end of the millennium
-We're dying in America
-To come into our own
-And when you're dying in America
-At the end of the millennium
-You're not alone
-I'm not alone
-Speak.
Hey, guys, it's Benny.
Look, I was wondering
if you've seen Mimi.
I haven't seen her
in a couple of weeks.
She dropped out of rehab...
...and I'm afraid that she may
have started using again.
-If you find out anything, let me know.
-Hi, Roger, Mark...
-...it's Maureen. Still no sign of Mimi.
-I just wanna know if she's all right.
-Joanne and I printed up some fliers.
-Hey, it's Collins. Just checking in.
-I'll call back if we hear anything.
-You heard from Mimi?
Roger, I spoke to the manager
of the Cat Scratch Club.
-She hasn't shown up for work.
-Roger, are you there?
Look, I just went to the police station
and I filed a missing-persons report.
I spoke to a friend of Mimi's who
said she saw her three weeks ago.
She hasn't picked up
her AZT in a while.
-She's been living on the street.
-Couple of weeks.
It's Collins again. I should be heading
home, like, right around Christmas.
I'm really starting to get worried.
It's getting cold out there.
-It's too cold out there.
-How can she survive?
December 24th, 1990, 10 p.m.,
Eastern Standard Time.
I can't believe a year
went by so fast.
-Speak.
-Hey, it's me, throw down the key.
-Hey, Iook who's home.
Hey, CoIIins, don't get
your ass kicked this time.
-Hey. Merry Christmas.
-Merry Christmas.
WeIcome back.
Come here.
Take your key. Hey, man.
HeIIo, Thomas. Merry Christmas.
-Hey, any word from Mimi?
-No.
You got the projector--
You finished your movie.
-I did.
-WeII, I wanna see it.
Okay.
And I thought you guys couId use
this to get some heat up in here.
-You shouIdn't have done that.
-Thank you.
-Tutoring again?
-Nope.
-You back at NYU?
-Negative.
-Then how'd you get aII this?
-I rewired the ATM...
...at The Food Emporium.
Now aII you need is the code.
-The code? What code?
-A-N-G-E-L.
Cheers.
Merry Christmas.
Mark?
Roger?
Anyone? HeIp.
We can't get her up the stairs.
Hurry up, pIease.
Mimi.
She's been Iiving on the street.
We found her in the park.
She wanted to come here.
No room on the couch.
Just cIear off the tabIe,
we'II put her there.
Up here.
Roger.
-You're back.
-I'm back. I'm back, baby.
Rog.
-We need some heat.
-Okay, I'II buy some wood and food.
-It's too Iate. I'm caIIing 91 1 .
-Roger?
I'm right here. I'm right here.
It's okay.
I'm here. We got you.
We got you.
I should tell you
I should tell you Benny wasn't any--
I know.
I should tell you why I left
-It wasn't 'cause I didn't--
-I know.
-I should tell you
I should tell you, I love you
Who do you think you are?
Leaving me alone with my guitar
Hold on, there's something
You should hear
It isn't much, but it took all year
Your eyes
As we said our goodbyes
Can't get them out of my mind
And I find
I can't hide
From your eyes
The ones that took me by surprise
The night you came into my life
Where there's moonlight
I see your eyes
How'd I let you slip away
When I'm longing so to hold you?
Now I'd die for one more day
'Cause there's something
I should have told you
Yes, there's something
When I looked into your eyes
Why does distance make us wise?
You were the song all along
And before the song dies
I should tell you
I have always loved you
You can see it in my eyes
Mimi
Mimi.
I was heading
towards this warm...
...white Iight.
And I swear...
...AngeI was there.
And she Iooked good.
She said:
''Turn around, girIfriend...
...and Iisten to that boy's song.''
You're drenched.
Her fever's breaking.
There is no future
There is no past
Thank God this moment's
Not the last
-There's only us
-There's only this
-Forget regret
Or life is yours to miss
No other road
No other way
No day but today
-I can't control
-Will I lose my dignity?
-My destiny
-Will someone care?
-I trust my soul
-Will I wake tomorrow
My only goal
-Is just to be
-From this nightmare?
-Without you
-There's only now
-The hand gropes
-There's only here
-The ear hears
-Give in to love
-The pulse beats
-Or live in fear
-Life goes on
-No other path
-But I'm gone
-No other way
-'Cause I die without you
-No day but today
-I die without you
No day but today
Ripped By Assem