[ Timmy: ]
rig...Rigoletto?
[ Bonnie: ]
Rigoletto!
Now hush and pay attention,
Or you'll miss something
really important.
Once upon a time,
in a land far away--
So far away you'd
never know it existed--
There lived
an Elfin prince.
To his people,
he was called Rigoletto.
He was a master of song,
And he used the art
of music to heal his people,
And they lived in peace
and prosperity
Unknown to
the race of men.
And on these distant shores
lived the Princess Gorfindel.
She was lovely to behold
And her voice was cherished
by all who heard her sing.
She loved Rigoletto,
and he her,
But cold winds
blew them ill will--
Mortal men who came to destroy
the Elfin kingdom
On the night before
Rigoletto and Gorfindel
Were to be wed
in eternal bliss.
Yuck.
What do you
mean "yuck"?
Go ahead,
Bonnie.
And Rigoletto would
not yet know happiness,
For he was struck
in battle by an evil sword,
Which left half
of his face pale,
Deathlike
and hideous to behold.
In his pride, Rigoletto allowed
the ugliness of his face
To poison his heart,
making it ugly as well.
And none could heal him.
So Rigoletto left his kingdom
and went into the world of men,
Accompanied only
by his betrothed
And his faithful servant,
Never to return until he found
one from the world of men
Of pure heart, whose love
would break the evil spell.
I wish I could sing
like the Princess.
Then I would win
the competition.
Good night, Timmy.
%% I love the part
in fairy tales %%
%% that's very near the end, %%
%% when all the kingdom
cheers for their new Queen. %%
%% and all is well
and all is good %%
%% and everyone belongs, %%
%% and happily
they're ever-after-ing. %%
%% but when I enter
the kingdom of dreams %%
%% and face the promise
of all I can be. %%
%% will they see me
as a heroine? %%
%% tell me,
will they let me in? %%
%% won't someone
let me in? %%
[ applause ]
You were wonderful.
Thanks, mom.
You was g-g-g-ood.
It was beautiful.
[ mc: ]
our next contestant
will be Kathleen Hamilton.
[ applause ]
Hi, Kathleen.
You've improved
since last year.
Thanks.
Nice shoes, Georgie.
What a perfect match
for the dress.
[ porter: ]
why you...
Porter...
Not here.
S-she ought n-not
have s-said that.
I know, but returning
hurt for hurt
Never helped anybody.
Shhhhh!
%% the glory of the morning
is in my love adorning. %%
%% my every hour with radiant
light as splendid as the sun. %%
%% and up until the evening,
until my love is leaving %%
%% he fills my
day with pure delight %%
%% and tells me I'm the one. %%
%% fa ah ah ah ah ah... %%
%% ah ah ah ah
ah ah ah ah ah... %%
%% the glory of the morning
is in my love adorning %%
%% my every hour with radiant
light as splendid as the sun! %%
[ applause ]
Well, we're ready
to find who the winner
Of this year's talent
showcase is going to be.
Bonnie, would you
please come up.
[ applause ]
Well, here we have
our two finalists--
Kathleen Hamilton...
[ mild applause ]
...And Bonnie Nelson.
[ very loud applause ]
Do the judges
have a winner?
Splendid.
I wonder who
it's going to be?
Let's take a look...
Well, by a vote
of two to one,
Once again, this year's
winner is Kathleen Hamilton.
[ sparse applause ]
Thank you!
Thank you.
Kathleen, on behalf
of Mayor Murphy
And the citizens
of castle gate,
I'm please to award you
this certificate.
That completes our talent
showcase for this year.
We hope to see you
out next year.
I'm sorry, Bonnie.
I thought you did
quite well tonight.
You w-w-was robbed,
b-Bonnie.
No.
Kathleen was good.
[ Georgie: ]
she's an awful person!
But being bitter won't
make me a better singer.
[ Bonnie: ]
congratulations.
Thanks.
[ giggling ]
Come on,
we need to go home.
Bonnie!
You kids get away
from there!
We'd better go.
That old dam is going
to kill somebody someday.
I don't know why they
don't block it off.
Hey! Lookit!
Ain't t-that the
silit-t-toe p-p-lace?
Yeah, it is.
Looks like someone's
moved in and fixed it up.
[ porter: ]
a lot.
Yester-day it was
like frankenst-st-st...
Frankenstein's
castle.
Maybe ghosts
moved in.
Georgie! Porter!
Gotta go.
Porter!
Didn't you
hear me, boy?
Port, are you
gonna be okay?
My d-dad...
He hasn't had w-w-w-work
for almost t-two years is all.
He ain't really m-mean.
Poor porter
and Georgie.
[ Bonnie: ]
Mr. Baker ought not to be
so mean to his own children.
[ Bonnie's mom: ]
don't be so quick
to judge Mr. Baker.
Bein' poor can make
a person do things
They might
not otherwise do.
Come on, we're gonna
make those porkers squeal!
Wait up, you guys!
You fat pigs!
Hey, you hogs!
You big fat hogs!
Pig face!
Fat pigs!
Hogs!
Fat faces!
Big fat hogs!
I smell bacon...
Bacon...
Piggy...
Hi, Tommy...
Boys, them pigs
is like family to me.
They got feelins' just
exactly like you and me got.
Just exactly like you and me!
Now how do ya
think them pigs
Might be feelin' right
now this very minute
Knowin' you been out there
callin' 'em names
Just cuz they're different
than other people?
Them pigs
ain't people.
They pigs!
They got no feelin's!
They got feelin's
all right!
They just can't express 'em
like you and me do.
Why not?
What do ya mean,
why not?
Cuz they can't talk--
that's why not!
If they could, they would!
Wait just a minute.
You know, I suppose them pigs--
maybe they can talk,
'cept that we can't
understand 'em, that's all.
So is pigs
people too, pa?
Just look different
cuz you can't understand 'em?
Yeah...No!
Them pigs is better behaved
than some people I met.
Them pigs ain't people--
they're pigs!
My paps--
he's a butcher--
He cuts 'em up
and we eat 'em!
My mom bought a pig
from you last year
And we ate 'em
for Christmas!
His name was blue.
[ gagging ]
Blue...
You ate blue?
[ gagging ]
Tommy, get your
friends outta here!
Don't you
let me catch you
Callin' them pigs
names any more!
I don't care
if ya ate 'em!
They got feelin's!
No more!
Nooooo more!
Dang kids these days!
I don't know where
they get some of their ideas.
Emelda...
I got bad news for ya.
[ clears throat ]
Ol' blue's dead.
Some nasty little boy down
the road ate 'em for Christmas.
What's for breakfast?
Bacon.
Have you gotten one
of them to holler yet?
No, not yet.
You should think
they had legs
The way they disappear
now-a-days.
This is the contract
to the Silitoe house,
Including that old place
the Nelson's live in.
I'll need your signature
right here on this bottom line.
Someone's bought
the old Silitoe place.
It's been fixed up
So as it looks just like
a castle from a story book.
Some dang quick fix-up.
That place looked like
a heap a junk a week ago.
Probably a banker.
You know, it's funny getting
a buyer for this place,
Especially during
times like these.
The inanes lost
their farm yesterday.
Ingans too.
Couldn't make mortgage.
How much do you know
about this man?
His name's Ribaldi.
Other than that, nobody seems
to know a thing about him,
Except that he has access
to large amounts of money.
This world has gone crazy
when a good man like Alf
Can lose his home
of 20 years just like that
To some newcomer banker!
We don't know who it was
that took his farm, Dallin--
Just a bank!
Bankers run banks.
Ribaldi...
Why would
a man like that
Come to castle gate?
Who knows...Odd.
Have a good day.
Thanks.
Dad?
Yes, son.
You sold
Bonnie Nelson's house?
Well, it wasn't
their home,
But, yes,
I sold it, why?
Will the Nelson's
still live in their house.
Son, like I said,
it wasn't their house.
It never was...
It was mine,
And I don't know where
they're gonna live.
People like the nelsons
and the Ingans--
They'll survive somehow.
Hi kids.
Hi
hi.
Hi, Margie.
I'm afraid I have
some bad news for you.
I'm sorry.
Evicted?
I would like to speak
with a, uh, a Mr. ...
...Ribaldi, please.
Come in.
Madame, the master
will see you now.
You may enter and go as far
as the carpet, and no further.
The carpet...
Why?
To the carpet
and no further!
If you cross the carpet
or step onto it
Or go any further,
Your interview will come
to an abrupt end!
Do you understand?
Yes.
[ footsteps ]
Hello?
You may approach.
Your servant
said that I...
Just three feet
towards the piano,
Then stop in the light.
I want to look at you.
May I come closer?
I like to see who
I'm talking to.
No.
State your business.
You bought the old house
on Patton street--
The one that belonged
to James McBride.
It's our home and you--
you evicted us today.
What concern
is it of yours
What I do
with my property?
If I lose my home,
I could lose my job,
And without a job, my family
would be in the street
We have nowhere to go.
Tell me,
Mrs. Nelson,
How valuable is
your home to you?
Well, I was paying Mr. McBride
10 dollars a month,
And I am prepared
to pay you 12.
[ chuckling ]
is your home
of no more value to you
Than 10 or 12 dollars
a month?
Well, certainly it is!
What is this house
worth to you?
Very little.
You see, to me
this is a "house."
Yours is a "home."
One is physical,
the other...Spiritual.
You, Mrs. Nelson,
of all people
In this tiny little town
should know of such things.
I should?
Yes.
Now, I ask you again--
What value do you
place in your home?
I don't understand!
I don't have
anymore than--than that!
Think--
think for a moment--
What is of greater value
to you than money?
Than even your home?
My family.
Yes,
your family.
More specifically,
your daughter--
The one who sings.
Yes,
that's Bonnie.
If you want something
of great value from me,
You must provide
something
That is of great
value yourself.
I am a poor woman.
I have nothing else
to offer you.
You may have your home
free on one condition--
Bonnie will work here
Each afternoon
as my servant.
As long as she
works for me,
You will never want
for a place to live.
She's so young--
why not me?
Her tasks
will be simple.
No harm
will befall her.
No.
No? No!
And why not?
Because you're--
you're too cold...
And you're
too unfeeling!
Too cold?
What--you think me
without feeling
Like a common beast?
Too cold?!
Get out!
I'm sorry...
Leave! Be gone!
Never come back!
Get out!
Hans! Hans!
I think
he wants you.
Hans, come
to me now!
You told me
it would work!
what to do!
It didn't work!
How long
must I wait?
How long must
I keep looking?
Aaauuuuggghhhh!
Patience
is a virtue.
is a virtue?
Get your sniveling,
pasty face out of here--now!
I don't know.
You told him no?
Bonnie, you are not
working for that man.
Why not?
Cuz there's something about
him that frightens me.
Like what?
It's like he's
hiding something--
This dark secret.
He wouldn't even
let me see him.
As we talked, he just
kept in the shadows,
And then, when
he got angry,
It was as if
he were this beast.
So...Either
we're homeless...
Or I go to work
for a person
That's more like
a beast than a man?
Sweetheart,
this is not worth it.
It's okay.
I don't mind.
Could it be worse
than being homeless?
Maybe.
Let me at least
try it for one day.
He is different.
But, being different
doesn't make you bad...Does it?
Most of the time, no.
But sometimes it does.
Well, there's only
one way to find out.
Bonnie, do you
see this door?
Yes.
This door, here.
I see it.
You must never,
never enter this room.
Do you understand?
I can't hear you.
I understand.
Good.
Follow me.
[ Hans: ]
Bonnie...
What will happen
if I go in there?
Have you ever
heard the expression,
"curiosity
killed the cat?"
Yes.
Good.
Now follow me.
So what will happen
if I go into the room?
The master resides
in that room.
The master
desires his privacy
More than anything
else in life.
Should you invade
that privacy,
You risk his anger.
His anger can
be terrible.
Do you
understand now?
So what will he do?
If you promise me
That you will never
go into that room,
Then I'll see to it
that you receive
Whatever dessert
you want
Every night
you are here.
Banana split?
Certainly.
Deal.
Good.
Now, follow me.
[ Hans: ]
Bonnie!
[ Dallin: ]
somebody bought my note,
demanding payment in full.
I gotta sell
my hogs to pay.
You know I'd rather
see them pigs e't
Than sold
like animals.
Them pigs is animals,
ain't they?
It's that newcomer
banker sittin' up there
On his high horse
buyin' and selling
On other people's
misery and hard times.
Ain't no better
than your hogs, is he, pa?
Boy, there's only
two differences
Between my hogs
and a banker--
A banker wears
expensive britches,
And my hogs ain't
never stole nuthin'.
One of these days
somebody's gonna pull
That rich newcomer
down off his high horse
And teach him
a thing or two.
I hear
he's a monster.
He's got teeth four inches
sticking out of his mouth
To suck
the blood from.
Monster, huh?
Where are you goin'?
Business.
Hey, watch it!
Hey!
Look at this!
Look at this
what I got today!
Look at it!
It's a notice on my butchers
place of employment!
Your note's
being called in.
Note?
Your place is
being taken away.
You betcha!
If they say I don't pay
by the end of next week!
[ Dallin: ]
see, and it ain't
just us two--
There's lots of people
is bein' put out.
Times are hard now.
Things are happening
all over the country.
Ain't never happened
t' me till now!
And if it can happen to us,
ain't nobody safe
From losin'
everything they got!
Not even you!
I suppose
you're right.
Who's doin' this
to us?
That's hard to say...
It ain't t' me.
How's that?
All started when
that Ribaldi fella
Moved in up to the
old Silitoe place.
My money says,
it's him.
You can't be
sure it's him.
Anybody could have
bought those notes.
Who's got money
to buy pig farm notes
In castle gate?
Dad?
Ain't you two
supposed to be home?
Mom says to come
and get you for supper.
Go on home.
Tell your mother
I'll be along soon.
Go on now.
C-c-come on home.
It ain't right you
b-bein' alone like this.
Go home, son...Now!
B-b-but...
Didn't ya hear
what I said?
Can't ya hear any better
than ya can talk?
Now get!
Georgie! Porter!
Hey, mister...
That ain't right
what you did.
I don't need you to tell me
what is and ain't right.
I noticed this new fella
was up to no good.
Why don't he go back
t' where he come from?
Why's he
gotta burden us?
You talkin'
about fancy pants
Up on the hill there?
I hear he's got
the little Nelson girl
Up there workin' for him.
Ain't it enough
that our kids
Have to eat
sugar and lard
And wear rags
all the time?
Why's he gotta have
'em cleaning for him?
It ain't right...
That's all I'm sayin'.
That fella's
danged strange.
Never comes out
'cept at night.
My boy said he
saw him one night.
Saw him?
Saw somethin'...
Looked like a man,
but...Different.
Different?
Only comes out not
in the sun...At night?
Makes you think,
don't it?
Listen,
Bonnie's seen him.
Mrs. Nelson doesn't
think there's a problem.
Maybe so,
but any man
That would steal another man's
land 'n' home is a monster!
I don't care
how he looks!
[ Gabriella singing ]
%% un soffio mi rimane %%
%% un giorno da passaro %%
%% ancora do toto
a te morendo %%
%% un' altra alb' presiosa %%
[ Ribaldi: ]
no! No! No!
It's all the same!
You must take the music
out of your throat
And put it
into your head!
But what would you know?
You can't think
beyond your own face!
[ Gabriella: ]
it is you who cannot see
beyond your own face!
Ever since
you were wounded,
You've let the
ugliness of your face
Make your heart ugly!
[ Gabriella: ]
how long must I wait?!
Will you drive
this one away
Like you've driven
all the others away?!
[ Ribaldi: ]
enough, I said!
[ Gabriella: ]
like you try
and drive me away?
Ari,
I love you!
[ Ribaldi: ]
no, enough!
I said enough!
You came to sing,
not lecture.
[ piano ]
[ Gabriella singing: ]
%% un soffio mi rimane %%
%% un giorno da passaro %%
%% ancora do toto
a te morendo %%
%% un' altra alb' presiosa %%
%% un' altra or' risveglia %%
%% momento caru nei
bracci tuio mi risposo. %%
Ari, stop!
Can't you see you've
frightened her?
This is my...House.
[ Gabriella: ]
I don't care
whose house it is.
If you cannot speak to this
beautiful young woman,
Then go away and pout.
I said go!
Come with me Bonnie.
You know my name.
[ Gabriella: ]
you're famous in this house.
You must not let
the master frighten you.
He speaks
of you often.
Often?
Often.
You're a special girl.
But then all little
girls are special.
Aren't they, Ari?
Is that Ari?
Yes.
Ari and I have been
friends for an eternity.
I suppose you could say
that our road together
Has been long
and hard.
Your lessons are refreshing,
as well as frustrating.
Then why do you
keep coming back?
Why don't you stay
in your world of princes
With dainty faces,
and white knights
Full of Grace
and pleasantries?
Gabriella...
I will always come back,
Even though
we're worlds apart.
Good-bye, Bonnie.
It was a pleasure
to meet you.
Be brave.
She's beautiful.
You were told not
to enter this room.
I heard the music.
That woman--
who is she?
Her name is Gabriella.
Gabriella is a Princess.
A real Princess?
I never lie.
A lie is a black hole that
grows deeper and deeper,
Getting blacker
and blacker,
Swallowing everyone who
happens to stumble into it.
Then when all
are consumed by it--
Friends, loved ones,
family, all--
Do you know
what happens?
What?
It turns into
a great black beast.
It turns on its creator
and devours him or her.
I never lie,
either.
That is good to know.
Trust is the best way
to begin a relationship.
Now, tell me the truth--
Did you like what you
heard from Gabriella?
It was beautiful.
Yes, it was.
In fact, you have
never heard anything
Quite so beautiful
before, have you?
No, never!
And do you know why
Gabriella is the best?
She was born that way?
Born that way?
No...And yes.
You see, many are born
with what Gabriella has,
But few ever become
what Gabriella is.
No, Gabriella is the best
because I made her so.
She is the product
of my genius.
You're not very
humble, are you?
Humble? Humble.
No,
should I be?
Humility is a virtue,
Mr. Ribaldi.
I should think
you should have
A lot to be
humble about.
My, you are an honest
little brute, aren't you?
So, what are you saying?
Nothing.
That I am...Ugly?
You're not...
"ugly", ugly.
Do not insult me.
What--you think
that I'm not ugly?
Where is honesty now?
No...I mean yes...
I-I mean...
That I am ugly!
You think that I am ugly!
Say it! Say it!
Yes, sir!
You have
an ugly heart!
That's worse than
having an ugly face!
You can't control
the way you look,
But you can control
the way you treat others!
[ piano ]
Yes, I am mean
and I am ugly.
Now you may go.
Did you really teach her
to sing like that?
I did...Now go.
A beast?
[ Bonnie: ]
yes, just like you said.
And he acted
like one, too.
Then we're gonna have to
find another way to get by
Because you're not gonna
go back to that place.
But...There was something
even more strange
Than the way
he looked.
Like what?
Well, he had a woman
with him today,
And she looked
just like a Princess
And sang like an Angel.
And he said that
he taught her to sing.
And mom,
she loves him!
How could he do
something so wonderful
If he's supposed
to be so bad?
And how could
someone so beautiful
Love someone so ugly?
I don't know,
But maybe there's something
more to Mr. Ribaldi
Than meets the eye.
I wonder if...
What?
I wonder if he could
teach me to sing like that?
I'm afraid this
is not a fairy tale.
Wait for me!
Shhhhh!
I told you
not to bring her!
She said she'd tell
my pap if I didn't
And he'd
woop me good!
Look!
Hey, look,
he's gone to bed.
Or going to work.
You mean
sucking blood?
Yes.
We don't know
if he's a blood sucker yet...
...Do we?
Ooga ba goo-ga!
[ screaming ]
Someone's gone 'n' chopped
porter's head clean off!
[ laughing ]
Hey, what are you
guys doin' here?
Come to peep on
the blood sucker.
[ Elaina:]
the blood sucker who got you
captured up on the hill!
They say
he's a monster,
And we've got
to get a look at him.
[ Bonnie: ]
Mr. Ribaldi?
Yup.
There isn't
any blood sucker,
And there certainly
isn't any monster.
Mr. Ribaldi is just...
...A monster?
No.
He's just different,
that's all.
C-can ya p-prove it?
Porter, you too?
You don't
believe me?
Everyb-body
in t-town says it.
Look,
come back tomorrow
And I'll take you
to meet him.
It's too late now.
Tomorrow he'll
be a man again.
We want to see
him tonight
Before he--he...
You know whats.
No,
I don't know.
Have you
ever heard
That "curiosity
kills the cat?"
I ain't a cat.
Let's go.
Ain't you comin'?
Nope.
I don't peeper!
See anything?
Nothin'.
[ door creaking ]
T-t-ommy...
Ni-ni-Nick...
Hey, guys,
There's somebody
in here.
Elaina!
She's going
into the house!
Elaina! Elaina!
Listen!
The blood sucker's
got her!
Aaaaaaaahhhhhhhhhh!
Oh, my goodness me!
Me poor little girl!
Hurry, everybody hurry!
He gots me baby!
He was huge
with big teeth.
He doesn't have
big teeth!
And red eyes
with a red tongue.
And horns
on his head!
Why don't you be quiet
and let the the boys talk!
Don't you talk
to my girl that way--
Not when I'm around!
Don't you know
any better?
I'll take a bar
of soap to your mouth!
Let's go!
[ crowd shouting ]
What's the matter?
Why is everybody shouting?
She's still alive.
[ laughing ]
Everybody,
come into my house!
Come, come!
[ crowd chattering ]
[ Bonnie: ]
I know you said
I couldn't go back...
...But, mom, I saw her
go into Mr. Ribaldi's house.
And you saw her--
she wasn't hurt!
How'd she get back anyway?
[ mom: ]
maybe that's something
you should ask Mr. Ribaldi.
[ Bonnie: ]
you mean you'll
let me go back?
All that I've ever seen
come from Mr. Ribaldi is good.
I think that you guys
should get to know him.
Why?
Hey, Nick, how'd your sister
get home last night?
And how d-d-did
your sister's leg
Get b-b-better
all of a s-sudden?
[ indistinct chatter ]
My pap said I can't
talk to you anymore.
Oh, Bonnie,
are you going
To the state
solo finals?
I haven't heard
anything about it.
What is it?
Oh, I'm sorry.
You weren't invited,
were you?
Well, you have to
be one of the best.
Sorry.
Some day I'm gonna
teach that Kathleen
A lesson
in good manners!
Nick,
how are you today?
You been noticing things
that might be strange?
No, I don't
think so, why?
See my girl--
look at her.
Hey,
her leg's better!
Mr. Ribaldi,
how did you do it?
[ sighing ]
I didn't expect
you back.
I mean Elaina.
How did you do it?
I know she was here.
Now she can walk
without limping.
How did you do it?
Is that why
you came back?
Am I like a
side show freak
That you can come back and peek
at for your own entertainment?
I'm not tolerant of
pernicious little persons
Snooping about my house trying
to take a peek at my snout.
If your friends come again,
I'll eat them
with cabbage and rye bread.
[ snickering ]
I don't think you'll
have to worry about that.
You've scared them
to death already.
Good!
Why would you want
anyone to be afraid of you?
Are you afraid of me?
I don't think so.
Good.
Then go back to work.
[ piano ]
Can you teach anyone to sing
like you did Gabriella?
No, I can't.
The beauty must
already be there.
I simply unlock it
and set it free.
I can sing.
I said,
I can sing!
You--no!
I'm good to boot!
You don't say?
We'll see.
Well, what is it you
would you like to sing?
Do you know...
"I'll be loving you always?"
"I'll be loving you always..."
[ piano ]
Well...
Go ahead,
I'm just warming up.
[ clearing throat ]
You never warm up
by clearing your throat!
Oh, sorry.
%% I'll be loving you always. %%
[ laughing ]
What's the matter?
You sing like a goat.
You didn't even
let me finish!
I get better
as I go along.
Better? I can't wait
for you to get better!
Your singing
is physically painful!
My ears are too delicate for
your bellowing and screetchings.
You know nothing.
Yes, I do!
And I don't sing
like a goat!
What would
you know anyway?
You're just
making fun of me!
I'm a good singer!
You wouldn't know a singer
if it sang you to sleep!
You have no heart,
do you?
No feelings!
You're ugly
inside and out!
Ugly? Ah, that is a word
I know the meaning of well.
Hans!
Hans, come here!
Hans,
come to me now!
Sorry.
Thank you, sir.
"the curse"...
Now.
%% we heard the tales
since we were young. %%
%% heard the words-- %%
Not sing!
Just play.
Oh, I see.
Now?
Now.
%% we've heard the tales
since we were young, %%
%% heard the songs
that have been sung %%
%% about an evil spell. %%
%% someone beautiful
is cursed, %%
%% we feel sad through
every verse %%
%% 'til a kiss and all is well. %%
%% the message that
no one can see %%
%% is clearer
to someone like me. %%
%% there is no curse
or evil spell %%
%% that's worse than one
we give ourselves. %%
%% there is no sorcerer as cruel
as the proud, angry fool. %%
%% and yet, we cry,
"life isn't fair." %%
%% beneath our cries
the truth is there. %%
%% the power that
will break the spell %%
%% we should know
very well %%
%% is locked within ourselves. %%
%% yet we'd rather blame and
curse our fate than change. %%
%% we run from everyone
to hide from the pain... %%
%% and all the shame. %%
%% the story's old,
we know it well. %%
%% about a wretched,
evil spell. %%
%% the power that
will break this curse-- %%
%% oh, I know all too well %%
%% is locked within myself. %%
I was wrong.
I'm sorry.
You're beautiful.
No one can sing like that
and not be beautiful.
Bravo!
Wonderful!
Get out!
What?
Your excellency,
didn't you hear her?
She's the one,
I know it.
Get out!
I said get out!
Leave! Go!
Are you all right,
your excell...
Get ouuuuuut!
[ Dallin: ]
%% I love these pigs, %%
%% I love these
pigs so much. %%
%% we love them swine. %%
[ snorting ]
%% they is divine. %%
%% we love them pigs. %%
%% it makes me want
to dance a jig. %%
%% la-la, la-la... %%
%% la-la-la-la-la-la. %%
%% I love them pigs. %%
[ snorting ]
How do you
get 'em to sing?
Well, it starts
in your mouth
And moves
down your arm,
And comes out
their lips.
You hear about
Rufus Ellington?
No, just he's havin' some kind
of money trouble or somethin'.
Yeah, he lost his farm,
but that ain't the trick.
You know
his little boy?
Yeah, he's, uh,
he can't see very well.
He's near sighted
or somethin'.
Yeah, well, he ain't
near sighted anymore.
It's got old Rufus
going back to church.
Figure that out.
Somethin' unnatural
is happenin' here
In castle gate.
Hey, guys,
come on outside.
I got somethin'
I wanna tell ya.
You know, we gotta
warn the town
About this
Ribaldi fella.
I know exactly
what you mean...
Let's split up...
[ indistinct chatter ]
Hey, mister,
there's a monster up there
In them there hills...
Mr. Ribaldi!
Bonnie.
You did this
for me, didn't you?
We've work to do.
Come, come!
Stop gawking.
But you said
I sounded like a goat.
You do.
If I sound like a goat,
Then why did you recommend
that I be included
In the state
solo finals?
Because when I am
through with you...
You'll be angelic.
[ Angel choir: ]
%% ahhh...  Ahhh... %%
[ indistinct chatter ]
[ Bonnie: ]
%% ...Won't someone let me in? %%
Well, how was it?
Excellent.
Well, I never...
No,
you should never...
Never!
You shouldn't be
so rude to Hans.
Perhaps.
That is not the point.
The point is, you are
not allowing the sound
To exit uninhibited
from your vocal cords
Through your
frontal resonators.
The tip of the tongue
must be drawn towards
The lower part
of the bottom teeth
So that it
cannot drop back,
Trapping and
obstructing the sound.
[ %% piano note %% ]
%% ah-h-h-h-h.... %%
Yes!
[ piano ]
I'll try to be
better with Hans.
[ porter's dad: ]
why do we gotta have
beans every single night?
I'm sick and tired of this!
We could have a little meat
sometimes, couldn't we?
What--what are you doing
with all the money?
I know it isn't much!
You're taking it and using it
on them kids all the time!
What are you using
it for anyway?
Of course,
she needs a new pair of shoes?
We could all
use a new pair...
Is dad mad again?
Yeah.
Whatcha doin'?
I'm g-going out.
Out where?
I d-dunno.
Just out.
Don't t-tell mom
and d-dad.
[ yelling continues ]
[ Dallin: ]
bills, bills, bills!
I figure if I sell all my hogs,
we can keep the place.
My goodness, Emelda,
Who'd a knowd
a man would be forced
To sell his family
just to keep his home.
We'll get through.
We've still got
the farm.
We can start again.
Telegram from Denver...
Who do you know
in Denver?
I don't know.
Well, here.
It's from the Winchester
clinic in Denver.
Winchester clinic?
It says my condition
can be reversed.
I'm to go to Denver
as soon as possible.
Here,
let me see that.
We never seen nobody
in Denver about no condition.
Besides, we ain't got the money
for that sort of thing.
[ giggling ]
[ Dallin: ]
well, Emelda Avery--
You's a
ten "thousandaire"...Ha!
Who are you?
Perhaps, I should be
asking you that.
I'm p-porter.
I'm a friend
of b-Bonnie's.
Yes, Bonnie speaks
highly of you.
Really?
She tells me
you've got a problem.
Sit down.
There is nothing more mean
and ugly in this world
Than to have a beautiful gift,
a loving spirit,
And a desire to give
and share these things
When there is nobody
to share them with.
You know what I mean,
don't you, porter?
Is it your father?
[ crying: ]
I hate it.
I hate my d-d-dad.
Do you know
what I think?
W-w-what?
I think that you
love your father
And you hate
the way you feel.
Change the way
you feel.
He doesn't
deserve love!
He's mean and selfish!
He doesn't care about us!
He only cares
about himself.
I hate him!
He should love us!
He should take us
hiking and fishing
And teach us
how to play ball...
Sometimes it takes hard times
to make us gentle and strong.
How can it do both?
It just makes my dad mean.
Meanness isn't strength.
Your father
is not a strong man...
Not yet anyway.
But who knows what
tomorrow brings.
You mustn't
give up on him.
He needs the love
of his family now,
Just as you need
his love.
And someday you will
both get what you need.
Do you
see this mirror?
Yeah.
It's a magic mirror.
Like in snow white?
Now that you mention it,
I think it was snow white
Who gave this mirror
to me as a gift.
If you look deeply
into the mirror
And tell yourself what
you've learned tonight,
The mirror will show you how
you've been made a better man.
I don't understand.
You d-d-d-don't?
Wow!
So, you have Cyrano who has
a nose about a foot long
Afraid to tell Roxanne
he loves her.
She's too beautiful,
And he's afraid
that she'll laugh at him.
Can you imagine it?
A guy who just
the night before
Successfully dueled 100
assailants scared of a woman!
So what does
he do about it?
He hires the handsomest man
he can, named Christian,
To "woo" the beautiful Roxanne
By saying the things
that Cyrano writes for him.
Well,
it just so happens
That Roxanne falls in love
with Christian,
But not because he's handsome,
But because he expresses
a beautiful soul
By the things
he says and writes.
Problem is that Christian
also loves Roxanne,
But can't tell her
because he has a hard time
Expressing his feelings...
So who get's the girl?
You have to read
the play.
This is
very strange.
%% memimamo memimamo
memimamo memimamo mou. %%
[ Bonnie and Hans: ]
%% memimano memimamo
memimamo memimamo mou. %%
Hans...
How many times
have I told you
That it hurts my ears
to hear you sing?
Perhaps I could give
you a lesson or two.
Really!
Did you hear that?
The master is going
to give me a lesson!
Do you think I'll
ever be any good?
No.
Play.
Now, Georgie, I have
something for you.
%% dolce amor %%
%% figlietta divan %%
%% sei un fiore in gemma %%
%% sbocciando vicin. %%
%% aprile sei tu %%
%% ma sogni di giun. %%
%% eogni giorno passando, %%
%% t'inbel lezza di piu. %%
%% dear April child, %%
%% are you dreaming of June? %%
%% like a tender young flower %%
%% awaiting Summer's bloom. %%
%% sweet April child,
in the springtime of youth, %%
%% what a glorious season, %%
%% it is yours,
let it shine through %%
%% ti sveglia Cara figlia %%
%% of what begins to to wake. %%
%% in fondo sieigia Bella. %%
%% let it grow inside of you. %%
There's something strange
goin' on around here.
I used to think papanickolas
was superstitious,
But there is something
strange goin' on.
%% ti sveglia Cara figlia %%
%% of what begins to to wake. %%
%% in fondo seigia Bella %%
%% let it grow inside of you %%
%% sweet April child, %%
%% it's the spring
of your youth. %%
%% cherish these Precious days, %%
%% Summer comes all too soon %%
%% dear April child,
still dreaming of June. %%
Yeah, there's some strange,
strange things happening,
That's for sure.
Makes me wonder
what's wrong?
what's right.
Mom, I'm home.
Bonnie, I'm afraid that they
have some some bad news.
I'm sorry, honey.
I know
how much singing
In the contest
meant to you.
Listen, Mr. McBride
left me a message.
He said that if you stop
working for Mr. Ribaldi,
They'd allow you to sing
in the contest.
[ Ribaldi, shouting: ]
I don't know why
I allowed myself
To be talked into listening
to your croaking!
A frog has better cords!
I've heard yaks in the
high Andes belch in Harmony
Compared to your bellowings!
I take umbrage
at the insinuation.
Insinuation?
Who's insinuation?
I might have charges
brought against you
For polluting the air!
He thinks
I'm getting better.
Bonnie!
A Ray of sunshine
on this...Irksome day.
Now,
come soothe my soul.
I think you are finally ready,
so I want you to have this.
It's a song.
I wrote it a long time ago
when times were better.
Better?
Happier...
At least for myself.
You've been awakened.
What?
Awakened...
To the truth.
You see, you bear
the blush of a young girl
Who has come
face-to-face with reality.
Reality and all it's ugliness.
[ piano ]
They won't let me
go to the competition
Unless I stop
working for you.
Mom says they think
you're taking their homes.
You're not, are you?
Does it matter?
It does to me.
No, I haven't taken anything
from these people.
I didn't think
you could.
Why don't you
tell them.
Because people hear and see only
what they want to hear and see.
What I say can't
get past their eyes,
Let alone
into their ears.
Now go.
I understand.
Where were we?
What?
My lesson.
Lesson?
You're the most beautiful person
that I've ever known.
You don't mean that.
You don't think I'd let
those people tell me what to do!
I won't leave you!
No.
You must go now...
Quickly.
Why?
Because neither you
or I want to waste
All that we've accomplished
this last little while.
When you go
to that competition,
You and I will
have triumphed.
If you don't,
we will have failed.
You will go
to that competition,
And you will win!
You will be everything that you
ever dreamed of being and more!
Not for yourself,
But for what you
give to others.
But I...
No buts!
Our time together
is fulfilled.
Now you must go
and never come back
Or all that we have
accomplished will be wasted!
Now go.
Go now and sing!
Sing!
I'll be with you.
Is she...Gone?
She chose not to stay?
She chose to stay.
She chose to stay?
I practically had
to chase her away!
She chose to stay?
Ha, ha, ha...
She chose me!
She chose to stay?
[ piano ]
%% heir, heir meistro... %%
Do you wish to wound
this moment of happiness?
...You listen
to what he has to say.
I love you,
sweetheart.
I love you.
Hans,
take care of her.
I wish I could go,
but I've gotta work.
She will be just fine.
Okay...
Bye, Bonnie!
I hope you win!
Good luck, Bonnie.
Hello, Georgie.
Hello.
What can I do for you?
Can you teach me to sing...
Like you taught Bonnie?
Do your parents
know where you are?
Someday I may teach you
how to sing, Georgie.
But, today
is not that day.
Now come, I'll take you
part of the way home.
Aren't you coming?
[ Ribaldi: ]
is there no other way?
This is a short cut.
Perhaps the long way
would be preferable this time.
Come on, we play here
all the time.
Georgie, wait!
This place
looks dangerous!
Georgie!
[ Georgie screams ]
Gee, it's like
a church...
Only bigger.
In many ways
it is a church.
For that reason,
It will not frighten you--
it will inspire you.
Thanks.
Two more lost
their homes--today!
That Don Duncan
and Kevin welsh.
Well, you know
those fellas...
I know they wasn't much
in the way of being men,
But nobody should lose
their houses like that!
Hi, son.
Georgie hasn't come home
from school yet.
Well, where is she?
I don't know.
We've been looking
all over.
Mom's out lookin'
right now.
Come on.
Uh, Gordon, your girl,
Georgie, she's a missing?
Yeah.
That's no good.
Hey,
we gotta help him!
Come on, let's go!
%% the birds in June, %%
%% they sing their cheery
fa la la la la. %%
%% the birds they swoon
and laugh so dearly, %%
%% fa la la la la. %%
%% all who sing along
join in springtime song, %%
%% fa la la la la la la la. %%
[ applause ]
She's good.
So are you.
Put the map down.
Let's look at the map.
Where are we
on this map?
Where are we not?
[ indistinct chatter ]
%% in the mountain still
while my love sleeps, %%
%% I climb to yonder hill. %%
[ woman screams ]
[ indistinct chatter ]
[ bell on door rings ]
[ woman screams ]
Georgie!
Georgie, honey!
She fell!
It's true...
He is a monster.
What was she
doing with you?
Is she going
to be all right?
Georgie!
The monster...
He must a done something to her.
Get him!
[ yelling and screaming ]
[ applause ]
Thank you, Kathleen Hamilton
of castle gate.
Next, Bonnie Nelson singing an
original composition by Ribaldi.
%% music boxes have within %%
%% melodies they
carry with them. %%
%% once they're opened,
music fills the air. %%
%% every person you have known
has a song of their own. %%
%% once they open up
you'll hear what's there. %%
%% it's not easy, %%
%% you must listen
with your heart %%
%% for what lies hidden. %%
%% there was a melody
locked deep inside of me, %%
%% but now it's free. %%
%% it found a place
embraced by Harmony, %%
%% sweet Harmony. %%
%% love more than anything
teaches our hearts to sing. %%
%% only love
could break the shell, %%
%% now I know very well
the love within myself. %%
[ gunshot ]
Stop it!
You don't know
what you're doing.
So just leave
this man alone!
Somebody help me.
Somebody please help me!
I say we go up to that
castle in the Sky
And see what the monster's
done to us all!
[ cheering ]
[ screaming ]
will nobody help me?!
Get his feet!
Take his feet!
%% there was a melody
locked deep inside of me, %%
%% but now it's free. %%
%% it found a place
embraced by Harmony,
%% sweet Harmony. %%
%% love more than anything
teaches our hearts to sing. %%
%% only love
could break the shell, %%
%% now, I know very well
the love within myself. %%
[ applause ]
[ indistinct shouting ]
[ glass breaking,
crashing ]
[ applause ]
I got it!
I got the book!
[ glass breaking ]
[ shouting ]
I got the proof!
I got the book
to show 'em
What the monster has
been doin' to us all!
Read it!
[ Dallin: ]
yeah, here we go!
Rufus Ellington!
Yeah!
Andre Ellington!
Andre?
Near sighted,
$ 450.00...He sees.
[ woman: ]
let's hear about the land!
Julie Johnson,
broken femur--
$700.00...
Walks.
Julie?
He did that
for my Julie?
[ quietly ]
Steve sorter...
Steve sorter,
son of Mitch Sorter,
Club foot,
$ 1,300.00--he walks.
Emelda Avery.
Emelda Avery,
tumor at base of spine,
Crippled, $ 10,000.00--
will walk soon.
I don't get it.
Who's been takin'
our homes?!
Me!
It was me.
I'm the one
that took your land.
So if you want to hurt
somebody, then hurt me.
But please leave
this man alone.
Let's go.
There's been enough harm
done tonight already.
Son...
[ crying ]
Come on, we'd better get
this man to a hospital.
Good man.
Will you come
back tomorrow?
Hey, I was told two bucks
for a day's work.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
I know that.
What happened?
They t-t-took him.
Where is he?
What happened?
He pulled Georgie
from the culvert.
He saved her.
Where is he?
He died
this morning.
%% ah, ah, ah, ah, ah... %%
Well, I suppose it's
off to the east for me.
What will you do?
I'm...Going home.
Where's that?
Oh,
a far off land.
So distant you'd
never know it existed.
I've been re-employed
by an old patron.
Well then,
you're happy.
Definitely.
Well,
good-bye.
It has been wonderful.
I wish I could
say as much.
We need
to get on home.
Timmy...Timmy...
Timmy.
C'mere.
S-s-ure c-c-cleaned
things up in a hurry.
[ music playing ]
Listen!
What is it?
That's my song!
Mr. Ribaldi
gave it to me.
May I help you?
No, I thought you
were somebody else.
I'm sorry, my daughter
has had a bad experience.
I'm sorry.
What was it?
May I help?
[ Bonnie: ]
no, it wasn't bad.
In fact,
it was wonderful.
I'm sorry
to bother you.
No problem.
[ Bonnie's mom: ]
we need to go.
Who are you?
Why are you here?
Bonnie...
No,
it's okay.
I used to live here
a long time ago.
I was just passing through
And thought
I'd take one last look
Before I left
for home.
Where's home?
Far away.
So far away I'd never
thought it existed?
Some might put it
that way, yes.
Well, I've people
waiting for me.
I'd better go.
I found something
that might belong to you.
B-b-but this...
Porter...
This was
Mr. Ribaldi's.
Hey!
Who are you?
What's your name?
My name?
Some people
call me Rigoletto.
But then, you don't
believe that, do you?
Rigoletto...
Do you believe it?
No, do you?
[ Bonnie: ]
...Restored to his kingdom,
Rigoletto took
his beautiful bride
And left the world of men
to dwell happily ever after.
Do you believe
that, Bonnie?
I do.
%% I love the part
in fairy tales %%
%% that's very near the end. %%
%% when all the kingdom
cheers for their new Queen. %%
%% and all is well
and all is good %%
%% and everyone belongs,
%% and happily
they're ever-after-ing. %%
%% but when I enter
the kingdom of dreams %%
%% and face the promise
of all I can be. %%
%% will they see me
as a heroine? %%
%% tell me,
will they let me in? %%
%% I love the hour
the seasons change %%
%% and winter turns to spring %%
%% and empty branches
welcome newborn leaves. %%
%% the earth makes room
for every flower %%
%% and reaches for the sun %%
%% "I'm glad you've come"
is whispered on the breeze. %%
%% but when I enter
the spring of my dreams %%
%% just like a wild flower
that burst on the scene. %%
%% will I find my place
with the gentle wind? %%
%% tell me,
will they let me in. %%
%% and if a heart's breaking,
a part of me's aching %%
%% to show them
how much that I care. %%
%% but if no one lets me
or turns and forgets me... %%
%% then how, how can I share? %%
%% there is a part,
of fairy tales %%
%% that's very near the end, %%
%% the Princess and the Prince
proclaim their love. %%
%% and hearts that heal
and souls are changed %%
%% and two blend into one, %%
%% all orchestrated
by the stars above. %%
%% but when I stand at
the door of my dreams %%
%% and face a lonely heart
calling for me. %%
%% I could fill
that emptiness within %%
%% if that heart
would let me in. %%
%% won't someone let me in? %%
}}