Do you know?
So far away from here,
Across the wrong and right...
there is a ground,
I will meet you over there,
Amazing!
You wanted to become a hero,
You are showing cinema here,
What's the matter?
Come to police station,
I will shoot your song,
Sean Morrison!
What?
He was a great singer,
Girls used to tear up their clothes
to see him,
He went to the crowd,
On the stage,
Showed up his middle finger,
Like this...
And crowd were happy,
People were applauding to him that
he did such a greatjob,
And I am singing a song
here respectfully.
So the people of bus stand could
pass their time,
And they are slapping on my face,
It was really bad,
It means I have no level.
There are so many criminals
in Delhi,
Catch them first,
You are right.
Why only this poor fellow,
It's a dead piece.
And it's a Jumna part of fashion,
Have some style.
You are on stage,
Like this...
Like you are going to screw them all.
What happen?
My days are not going well.
Only your days are bad,
If you didn't stop your music,
then how your entire life
is going to screw up.
You are such a negative person,
Like if he will join his father
business so he will be successful.
I will neverjoin transport line,
So finish your studies and be
a lawyer here for Rs. 30,000.
You can't fly so high,
You mean nobody should even try.
Then he doesn't have any chance,
He already have no chance,
Nobody has become a Rock star like this
But he is playing guitar since childhood.
So why he didn't made it yet,
You mean...
Because he have no abilities.
He is not that damn good.
And what kind of friends you are?
You just want to spend his money
for snacks,
As soon he will understand it
will be good for him,
Take my number,
Give me a call if I will be selected,
Feed it,
You have a visiting card,
If I work more hard then...
Even a donkey works hard,
Then what's missing in me?
Look!
An artist have a heart,
He have a personality,
And I don't have it,
It's not like that,
Your life is not like that,
There is another kind of life who
turned a man into artist,
Which kind of?
You check everyone's life...
Like all artists, musician, writer
and painters...
Look at them,
You will find a common thing
amongst them,
What?
You just check by yourself.
Pain! Tears...
Till you don't have pain in your life.
Nobody will become a famous
in life,
And reform your friends,
If you will stay with them so
they will put rubbish in your mind,
They have suffered lot of pain,
They got many wounds...
They trembled with pain,
Lot of pain,
They have suffered tragedy,
And me...
I didn't suffered from anything,
I don't have single pain,
I never felt shortage of food,
I didn't face any problem for house,
My parents are still alive,
Nor I got beaten up in childhood,
Nor somebody molest my
in my life.
I am not even adopted,
I never met a serious accident,
Nor I have deadly disease,
Music comes from only broken heart,
When you heart breaks...
then the tunes comes...
What happened with you?
Did you heart ever broken,
Did you ever felt in love?
If you have to think then
it's not a love,
Love...
and...
Where will the music come from?
You tell me,
J. J!
You should come along,
No! I am leaving,
And I don't like dance,
Who is going to watch dance,
We are going to see girls.
You better watch,
What to see?
Till she is here she will
be number 1.
People are right about Kashmir,
If heaven is somewhere in the world,
So it's here...
Creator has used such great material.
Material is same,
but engineering is mind blowing,
Car or Girl?
Both!
It's her last dance,
Why she was in hurry for marriage?
Look at her from distance so
you will be happy.
I must have to try once,
Many people have tried,
but all of them were failed,
It's a heart breaking machine,
Hi!
Janardhan!
J.J. For short.
I want to talk to you,
About what?
Actually you...
Iooks so cute to me,
that's what I wanted to say,
And you are really hot,
Amazing combo,
Hot and cute at same time,
I love you,
Be my girlfriend,
Can you see that they are
laughing on you,
I can see you only,
You can see me...
So look at me very carefully
that what I am saying,
We will rock together,
Think about it,
Hey! Are you stupid?
No!
Only crazy for you baby,
One second!
Let me think,
Yes, I am sure you idiot,
Get off from here,
You are breaking my heart,
Don't show me your face again,
Shall I eat 2 samosa in this chatni,
Bring more,
It's funny for you,
I really love her,
What should I tell you?
How did I feel when she said
Burger off!
I don't even know it's meaning,
You are such a cheap person,
If your heart would be broken so you
would having samosa's here,
You would be fighting for Chatni,
You couldn't even pass the bite
from your throat,
You should have desperation
in your love,
You should have pain,
It's not love.
It's a drama,
What should I do?
What's the way?
How do I...
He must have forgotten,
Really!
But we never forget,
Where you have lost?
Look at him!
He is not listening to his brother,
I am in stress,
Don't yell at me right now,
So when should I scold you?
Give me the appointment,
Tuesday at 11 will be fine,
I have to propose Heer,
It's a true love,
She have no right to leave me and
get marry with someone else
because he is rich,
Give me one chance,
I will work really hard,
I will become rich,
If you will come to me again then
you will see what will I do with you,
What will you do?
I will break your legs.
I will restrict your entry in campus,
I will get you finish,
I think you never felt in true love,
It is different,
Pratab! Take him out...
Sooner or later you will understand,
Just spend some quality time
with me,
It's enough!
Now watch how I will fix you.
You can take any action,
Report in police,
True love...
never afraid from the world,
It's not even scared from police,
Ghalib has also said allot,
I don't know at the time but
I will and tell you,
If you won't give me a chance then
how would you find out,
We must have to talk,
Let's talk right now,
What happen?
You wanted to talk to me,
Yes! I...
What?
We should give it a chance,
Let's give it a chance,
Give a chance,
What are you thinking?
Tell me,
I want to know how it is?
I was...
Coming!
What happen?
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Coming!
You don't have to be nervous
to see me every time,
I am not angry with you anymore,
I am really sorry,
I don't love you,
Entire campus have a rumor,
that Heer is so cool,
All of my friends,
But personally I don't think that
you are damn hot,
Like I said...
I didn't mean that you so ugly,
You are beautiful.
But I...
So why you following me?
I can't tell you it's such
a madness,
Everyone does madness,
But it will be madness for you
to bunk your class,
Or having some snacks,
You must be thinking after that...
Oh my God!
Today I have done crazy enough,
But I am not like that,
What do you think about me?
I didn't meant so wrong
So what you were meant to be?
Nice family,
There is a cinema theatre,
Amar Talkies in old Delhi,
A movie is showing there,
Junglee Jawani,
I am going to watch that movie,
Do you know what kind of movie
you are talking about?
I have seen the posters,
And you will watch that movie,
I have find out the way of hall.
I have made excuses too.
You can't go over there,
I am going,
With who?
Alone!
You are crazy,
Run! Run!
Happy!
We should stay more,
If light would be on so you
would be raped over there,
Let's do one more thing today,
By God!
I am scared to hear about that,
Can we get some local beer?
Are you Heer?
Show me your face,
I want to drink it,
Then who is that Stephen Heer?
Don't talk rubbish.
Buy me a beer,
How is that?
It's too bad,
Why you are not drinking?
I am drinking,
Show me,
It's so bitter,
How do people drink it?
You don't drink it,
I just rub some beer on my face,
and I act like I am drunk,
But you are the first person
who caught me,
So you can't act with me,
You will have to actually drink
with me,
I am getting married,
Entire university knew it,
Only two months are left,
I have heard you got a rich husband,
And once if I get married,
So you are fulfilling your bad habits
before marriage,
You are not that stupid like you
looks like,
You don't looks rascal like you are,
Now will you go home or you want
create more mess,
I want to make lot of mess,
I have to do amazing things,
But I don't have time,
We have tomorrow,
You are Genius,
Why did you fail in B.A.
It's a demand of time,
You make the list,
Make a list of all of your insects,
before marriage,
We will kill all of them,
Really?
Yes!
And my image is already ruined
up on your front,
So, I will make a list,
He is such a unique friend of yours,
You shouldn't have complain,
I will bring disprine in 2 minutes,
He is not so poor,
He also enjoy the life,
Why are you cheating?
And what about your shortcut?
You should have invite him in wedding,
He came for wedding shopping so he
will must attend the wedding,
Put it on to your husband,
Remove your hand,
Make it lower and show me,
Make it lower,
Fine?
Mind blowing,
He will be seduced from you,
Listen!
I can't come right now,
Khatara Bro has stopped Platinum Music
people in canteen,
You tell him that you didn't meet me,
And don't come here for few days,
I am going out and I have made
some excuses at home,
I was feeling so bore here,
People doesn't have anything to do
in their own wedding,
I have done all the arrangements,
I can't go like this,
I am a bride,
Can you come out?
Who can stop me?
Nobody knows here who actually
you are?
Only you know,
Jordan!
Can you hug me?
Now?
You are in hurry?
No!
Hug me properly,
Tight!
Is it ok?
I should leave now,
They must be looking for me,
Why you are getting so sentimental?
I am getting married,
If you don't like then don't
get married, So what?
Back door is open,
Run!
Let's go,
Tell me one thing,
Don't ask me anything,
Otherwise I will tell the truth,
So tell the truth,
Who is scared?
Yes!
How am I looks like?
College guys were right,
You are looking hot,
Bride is on wedding level or not,
Those guests came to wedding,
They all does bride's fantasy
at night,
You will also do my fantasy,
You are not falling in love with me,
When will you come to meet me?
Parag!
I never went to Nepal.
But you will have to come Parag,
So! I am going first,
then you should come,
We will meet in Parag and
create a mess,
This plan is perfect or shall
we escape now,
Tell me one thing,
This media is so stupid that he can
make anything news,
You can take anyone to sky,
Who is this Jordan?
What he has done?
He is just an artist of Platinum Music,
He is not from Platinum Music,
He just shared few songs in album,
You are making him star,
Believe me I am not his fan,
It's my job that...
But it's not my job
that I should make false praise
for him
That's why find out anything about him,
and print it...
He doesn't live here,
It's been 2 years but still phone
calls are coming,
But can I talk to his family members?
He have no family,
Please don't call here again,
I can't do it,
We need 4 of that kind for
the rising star,
every month,
Bury your ego being shameless
and find it and print it,
Actually he is not in anyone's touch,
What happened with J. J
after the college
Any lead?
Jordan always liked the music,
and I always appreciated the
artist inside him,
Art was deeply inside him,
He was notjust a good artist but
a nice person as well.
Kids were asking me
that when this show will come on TV,
It will not come on TV,
Why?
Because I don't have any material
about this Jordan,
But I have said allot,
But you lied everything,
I am asking you straight questions,
You knew Jordan those days,
Why don't you tell me about him,
You are getting angry,
No! I want to know,
Now no camera is here,
Tell me,
After all what is this Jordan?
Few people...
have their mind somewhere else.
Do you understand?
I don't understand,
Earlier he could give his life to meet
there peon of Platinum Music,
One day I told him by myself,
Musician!
Where are you?
Platinum Music people were
asking about you,
Dilip Menand! Remember?
I will call you later,
I will meet you tomorrow,
After 2 weeks Platinum Music people
came to canteen,
in search of him,
I offered them few samosa's and
kept them stopped,
I sent a person on my bike,
Why Kashmir?
I don't know,
But when he came back so
he has been caught.
Brothers beaten him up allot,
Mom started crying,
We work all day long and he
is playing guitar,
Who is this Heer?
What's your affair with her?
Nothing,
Get his guitar,
If you have nothing to do with her
then why did you attend her marriage,
How are you?
Where are you?
You quit the college.
And you know it's not so bad here,
A. C is here and not to do anything,
I have set the video game on TV,
There is a world inside the game,
But he was saying he will never
join his family business,
And music?
He quit.
Then?
Then one day same thing occurred,
Same brother, same mom and
same social drama,
Leave my collar,
You accept it that you steal the money
and I will leave your collar,
I said I didn't steal the money,
You just wanted to beat me,
Someone else must have stolen
the money,
Keys are always in drawer and
everyone knew it,
You ask to your staff,
Money has been stolen before
I joined,
Can I stay here for few days,
So did he stood at your home,
He still lives at my house,
Which night he has been removed
from his house,
He came to your house,
Not that night after two months,
Where you have been?
I went to house thrice,
They didn't take me back,
So what did you do in tomb
all these days,
You must have done something,
You are losing the tune,
Can you hear the pilot?
Yes!
Take a break,
Want some tea?
Are you playing on music or
you are screwing the music,
You are not listening,
I can't do it,
Don't know why you were searching
for me I can't sing,
It's not inside me,
You are right,
You were singing wrong intentionally,
Why would I do that?
Even I can understand the tune,
And you didn't understand,
It was a miracle.
I have seen you earlier,
You know where?
At Hazrat Nizamuddin's Tomb,
I have also seen you,
You came on TV.
He is Ustad Jameel Khan,
I know you are such a big...
But I don't understand this
classical music,
I feel bore.
Why do you play the same thing
over and over again,
Now move on and play
something new,
He is a monster,
He won't be locked up in
your small cage,
He will make his own world,
You mean this guy...
He is another thing...
He have a God's blessings,
Put your money on him,
You will earn allot,
Khadala Bro told me for interview,
Tell me one thing,
Why dhinga have a problem with you?
You have some secret,
You are newly born,
From today you are my asset,
Now you will perform your own album,
Now you will have to learn how
to become a star,
Many people can play the music.
But you remember one thing,
From today you are not a musician,
You don't know they are going Europe,
Dhinga is taking 5 Indian Musicians
over there,
I want to make a phone call.
Sure!
Take me Europe!
How did you get in?
I am ready to sign your contract,
I will do whatever you will say.
You are not laughing today,
No!
Not at all...
I have to go.
Why?
I am ready to sign everything today.
Just take me along.
You will sign a special
contract with me,
Whatever you say?
You are taking something,
Why don't you buy something
for yourself?
I should like something,
Why don't you like something?
Come here.
Nice scarf's arrived here,
I have an appointment,
You really enjoy to visit the doctor,
Why you are going now?
Your all tests are negative,
You need something to do.
He also said the same,
You have nothing to do here that's
why you keep down.
I have embarrassed everyone here.
And I know it.
I am gone to Parag,
Let's create the mess.
I have an appointment
with psychiatrist
You are gone mad,
I can't come right now,
I have to go,
I am not feeling well.
But we will meet later,
tomorrow!
I will take you for lunch,
Some nice place,
Where do you stay?
When did you come?
And what are you doing here?
I shouldn't drink by the way,
When did you start drinking?
Right now,
Let's make a list,
These cheap pubs,
Some cheap kind of discos where
they have dirty lights,
Dirty people came there,
And you will dance on front
of them,
I think we should kiss now,
Really?
Why do you feel like that?
That's the next step.
You can watch any movie,
That's good we are discussing
about this issue,
These things are made for
discussion,
Not like you are gone emotional
and got kiss,
Precautions can make life easy,
So let's have a detail discussion,
All matter should be discuss,
So we should have a proper plan,
How would be the kiss?
What kind of kiss it would be?
If the matter won't finish on kiss,
If we will get more emotional so
where to stop,
How we will find out that point
has come,
We both are item,
If someone will hear us that
what we talk about,
We should stop here,
What are you doing?
Get off!
You don't know why?
Because it's wrong,
Then why I don't feel it wrong,
What do you think?
How could you imagine that you
can do it with me?
I really enjoyed,
It's not a joke.
I have kissed earlier,
but what's this?
Look! From this point
we could ruin everything,
and we shouldn't do it,
So we won't do it,
Now you drop me home and we
will never meet again,
It's too late Heer.
It's impossible.
But it will happen,
So you are friend,
I am sister in law,
Meena!
So dinner tomorrow,
You didn't tell him,
He is very busy,
But he must have meal sometimes,
Or he don't have it...
No! You must have to come tomorrow,
We all are really excited to meet you,
And we will take good care of you,
You are not in hurry,
No!
I have heard allot about you,
What?
Good things from Heer,
Do you know for which program
you have invited here,
few of my friends are involved in
it's organizing committee.
It would be fun but I was busy
all this month,
So I have to drop it,
And Jordan I should tell you since
you have come Parag,
And Heer is meeting you,
She is feeling very well.
In fact Doctor was so happy
and surprised,
You should have join this program,
I have to hug you,
I will wait back side,
You have lost your mind,
Shut up and go from here,
I will wait.
You don't come,
What do you want?
How is it?
I don't know,
You admire me,
Increase the amount 300 percent of
that contract what I have signed
with you,
Miser man like me is talking about
to increase the amount,
And he is really famous in India,
Many things are publishing about him,
You have kept my respect
in front of white people,
Now perform like this in Paris
and Barcelona,
Say bye and let me go,
They are waiting for me,
It will be a problem,
Let it be,
That won't be your problem,
You are going,
After that you don't want me to
live happy in my house,
No!
I don't want you to stay
happy at home,
You have no feelings,
What do you feel about me?
I feel that you have to stay here,
Now!
That's what I feel.
Go to hell!
You are just worried about yourself.
You want what you want,
Come here!
And you are uncivilized,
We can't live together for 6 months,
Thank God you are leaving,
You are forcing me to fight,
I can't tolerate you anymore,
So what did you think?
We will be happily separated,
So you would meet me again and
have fun with me,
You are gone mad,
I was but now I am fine,
Come here! Say bye properly.
Get lost!
All of you...
Get off from me,
Come fast otherwise I will
have nervous breakdown,
What have you done?
Jai! He won't do anything,
Go! Your plan is accomplished,
Now I will never be fine
in my house,
I came to say bye,
Don't show me your face again,
I never want to see you again,
Really?
Today this media has come to cover a
criminal not an artist,
In your world...
On every step human is wrong,
Whatever I do to think it's right...
You says it's wrong,
I am wrong,
I just want to tell the media that
No comments,
You call the press and says
no comments,
But isn't it true that you are
releasing Jordan's next album,
which songs he recorded in
Europe for you,
Album will be release in market and
artist is in jail.
Only Negative works in Media,
To live from my own wish
Shall I give you the application.
It means you have right on me
more than me,
Bring our right here...
Jordan probably can't handle
the fresh fame,
Lucknow people still don't believe
that he didn't come to show,
besides the matter is clear,
that he has been seen coming out
from the Lucknow Airport,
He lost his mind,
Shall I put him in the jail again,
This day has come,
I have to take you out from
that place,
You will be over before the start,
Your reputation is getting
more worse,
And you will never find out that when
people will start hating you,
What happen to you?
What are you up to?
What's your problem?
Look at yourself,
What do you want that people
should ran away from you,
I shouldn't be happy,
That's all I ever wanted,
But I am not happy at all.
Now you believe he is J.J.
We must need an evidence,
You don't want more pictures,
Have you done?
Shall I go now?
Contract of 5 albums and he
can't work outside,
Don't you think it's enough,
So don't sign it,
It has decide,
Sit back home,
Sir! You are right but...
You have screwed up with Dhinga,
Now what will you do?
They want to sign you,
They will handle all of
your cases,
Why they are talking to you?
They are scared from you,
Your image is like that,
So they thought I am closer
to you and...
Are you?
What?
You can't forget her.
He is burning inside for
someone's love.
I am not Heer,
We have to talk,
Not in this condition,
I will never be fine,
My condition will go more bad,
What do you want to do?
That's what you have to say,
I betrayed you,
I have crossed the line,
I knew that time that I am
doing wrong,
I knew every second,
I was trying that I should stop
myself but...
don't know why?
Don't know what happened to me,
Now what do you feel about him,
This feeling will be gone,
Everything will be fine
in few days,
then we will talk after few days,
Get up!
I am feeling bore,
how long will sleep,
Can you come for a second?
Close the door,
What happened in night,
After that how dare you to enter
in this house,
You didn't ashamed,
Now only dad will talk to you,
You won't come back here,
Go!
I can't go,
I know myself,
I will stay with Heer,
Heer is not in this condition that
she could tolerate more drama,
Nothing will happen to Heer,
Don't worry,
She is already dying.
They are going to throw me out,
but you don't worry,
I will be back,
And let's have a kiss before
they come,
They will come.
Stop it! You stay there,
I am kissing you,
You do whatever you want,
Jordan! I am telling you I
will kill you,
Have you lost your mind,
It would be done yet,
How did you get up?
She didn't get up from the bed
since 3 weeks,
It's good,
But how?
You want to talk to him,
What should I do?
You don't want to talk?
She don't want to talk,
Listen!
When will you die?
Doctor said that you are dying,
So when will you die?
Is this a joke?
No!
It's really serious,
Your body is not building blood anymore,
What do you want?
I want to ask you,
You don't have security alarm
in this house,
Why?
What you going to do?
Parag house alarm was so loud,
Within a second all lights
were switched on,
Scene was totally changed,
You shouldn't came out,
Now I will have to come to you,
Don't do it,
I can't tolerate it,
Am I doing it?
You said you don't want
to see my face,
Did I came to you?
Did I call you in 2 years,
I even tried that I shouldn't
think about you,
But what happened?
It's you...
Standing next to me,
Don't you understand?
It's something else.
What is taking us together,
We couldn't live apart,
I am such a great personality,
I am a star,
I have lot of money,
I am famous,
But I have a fire inside me,
I am only set with you,
and that's the matter,
When you are not with me so you
have some deadly disease,
I am dying,
May be few months,
After that I will die,
And if you didn't die then...
Nothing will happen to you then...
So you will be mine,
Can you hug me?
You are in hurry?
Hold me tight!
You are like Guitar,
You know what kind of man he is?
2 weeks back Heer didn't have
strength to talk properly,
After all the efforts she was sinking,
and today she walks in the park,
She came downstairs for breakfast,
However it's happening?
Do you think I will stop her,
However she looks cheerful from outside
but she is weak from inside,
We think we know the life,
But life always giving us surprises,
That's what I was thinking that
he is such a big star,
He can't work,
But whenever I ask him he
says he is free,
12 recordings, 6 shows and one
product launch has cancelled,
I have got 2 legal notices,
I am hiding my face from everyone,
What should I tell them that
I don't know where he is,
Since one month...
His phone is switched off,
He is using another number,
Where does he stay?
Either he is alive or dead,
These foreign companies...
they have their entire law army,
and theirjob is to screw people
like us,
This time you are not going to survive.
This time you will go to jail.
You tell me what immediately
he have to do.
After that he have many shows
on different places,
Live shows ticket didn't stop.
I am not going anywhere,
But I am going,
I have to go,
I want to go to cliffs,
I want to see Himalaya again,
You guys don't report about her,
Is she your girlfriend?
Since when you both are together?
Say bye and let me go,
You won't listen to me,
I am listening,
You are not listening to me,
I should leave now,
I won't have my bye,
Bye!
Finish your shows and come to me,
Call Jordan and tell
him to come right now.
Everything depends on you,
Look!
At this time I can't come,
Operation is under process,
Somebody is inside,
We have our official orders,
I don't need it all.
I don't to be famous,
My heart shouldn't be broken,
Please do something,
I have nothing else.
It's all because of you,
You have send her to Coma,
Everyone is gone,
It's our world.
Nobody else is here,
Not any journalist,
Not any photographer,
Not any society,
Not any rules.
Not any hospital.
Not any doctor.
Not any contract,
Not any court case,
Not your marriage,
Did you like our world.
I couldn't come outside,
You don't have to live outside
You have to stay here,
Now...
Forever!