Hallo,Airport
Yes, please
Today by 11 O'clock flight
There is a man going -
Whose name is Jugran,
Jagmohan lal Jugran -
There is a plaster
on his left hand-
Which has no fracture,
but Diamonds in it.
Mr. Jagmohan lal Jugran
Sir, there is nothing in it
I'll file a case on you all
You all have no rights
to keep bothering a decent man
I am sorry, but we were......
By your sorry,
my plane won't come back -
Which I have left
Do you know, how improtant
was it for me to go?
We regret for the
preplexity caused to you-
We will get your plaster
tied again-
After which, the first flight
that takes off-
We will get you a seat in it.
Is Dr. Ashok soni there?
Yes.
D'souza, you have come again -
I told you today I'll not go
anywhere with you
I have to make a palace of dolls
for my daughter-
Today itself
did you understand or....?
Doctor, I have to get the plaster
tied on my hand
Doctor, Make it fast
Mr. Jugran, the flight is at 3 O'clock
And this man is.....
Shut up
You talk too much, Keshav.
Doctor, your fees
Airport, look today by 3 O'clock
flight, a man, Jugran.....
Daddy I have come
Daddy, what happened?
Daughter, Seema daughter that man,
diamonds, diamonds smuggler....
I regret, to remove
your plaster again
But now, this plaster will be
removed only after my Lawyer comes
Sir, again, but only today
in the morning
What ever I say, only do that
I am Jagmohan Lal Jugran speaking
What, Mr.Jugran?
Yes, Jagmohan Lal Jugran speaking
I need to speak with
Advocate Mehta
Go and call those two officers
who were present here in the morning
Mr. S.P I am not
Jagmohan Lal Jugran -
I am his twin brother
Manmohan Lal
Sir, this man is speaking shit
He is the same man, Jugran
I have told you
several times that -
Okay, find it out from
Bangalore, where we used to stay-
Where we spent our childhood
From the school, college,
from our relatives
From our neighbours residing
over there ask them, that I am
Jugran's twin brother
Manmohan Lal
Sir, This man is telling right
The information we asked from
the Bangalore police about him -
Here is the report
They told you,
told you, that l....-
One minute, one minute,
Sir, they have also confirmed on this-
That, there is a twin brother of his
who is just like him-
And whose records hold, no good
Did you see?
We are sorry Mr. Manmohan Lal
you got troubled -
But,regarding your brother-
Even, if you get a slightest
of information, then....
How are you my brother?
Get lost from here, get lost
What happened, brother?
I feel ashamed
calling you my brother
Actually calling an ldiot
man like you, to be my brother-
Even I don't feel very happy
Be afraid of God, Jagmohan
You be afraid of God
because you are his devotee
I am the worshipper of devil
I swear by the devil
If I knew that I would
meet you like this,-
I wouldn't have come at all
But, now that I have come
be Hospitable
Can you make arrangements
for some food
I'll bring
Inspector Pathak, I am
Manmohan Lal
You immediately come
to my house
Manmohan Lal now, I am
going to kill you
By killing me,
you cannot eacape-
The police will come here
any moment
You cannot escape
I have no intentions
of escaping either-
But here, the police will not
find me -
Instead they'll find
only you, you
To refer, Manmohan Lal will not
be you, It will be myself
Rascal
Manmohan this was the only Resort
for me to escape from the police
I swear by the Devil, from today
I am only-
Manmohan, and
I am only Jugran
So, the police believed me,
to be Manmohan Lal
Sir, this work was
perfectly alright
But, that customs officer was
clever, more than he required to be
I swear by the Devil,
such a clever man-
Should not be alive
for a long time
Very good my son
You are grown up-
You have started travelling
even without mother and father
Daddy, there mother made me to sit,
here you have taken me down
But Daddy, when will
Mummy, Ravi and Kusum come?
After two days
Stop the Car there,
where he would be able to see me-
I want that he should
come behind me
Son, you sit down here, I'll
just come, don't go away from here
Mrs. Verma, at that time of the
untoward event-
When the police reached
Mr. Verma was alive,-
He only told us that the killer
is none other than Jugran
Who ever it is,
my life has got ruined
Now, I should only
get my son, Ramesh back
I don't know where he would be?
When a string brokes
its pearls get scattered where all-
"BAL BHAVAN" an Orphanage
Uninformed of his father's death
seperated from his family
Life had brought Ramesh here-
And here he got those remembrances
which he could never forget
He met Simi, the same girl
whose father Dr. Ashok soni's murder-
Was done by Jugran
Father's death, and after her
mother loosing her senses-
Yesterday's darling daughter
was today in an Orphanage
Simi was dejected
Ramesh was alone
In the times of their sorrow
Their friendship started growing
like creeper's of flowers
Will you eat this?
I don't like
Do you know, what will I do
when I grow up?
Along with you, the man who
killed your father, I'll kill him
Why?
Because you are my friend but you
never laugh, why don't you laugh?
Because, I don't like anything
I find everything bad
Okay, I'll tell you a tale,-
You tell me whether
it happened good or bad?
One day, A robber entered
a man's house, good or bad
Bad
But there was nothing in
the house that could be robbed
Good
After this the robber
got furious,-
Taking a big stick
he went to his bed
He hit him one hard
Bad
But the man was not
sleeping on the bead
Good
And, further what happened,
I forgot
Bad
But you got a laugh
Good
Look Simi, they are your
new aunty & uncle
And from now you'll not
stay in this Orphanage
You'll stay with them
I am leaving
So what, we'll meet again
Do you remeber,
you made a promise to me-
That the man who killed my father
you will.....
Do you remember?
I remember
After Simi had left, Ramesh was
not happy at the Orphanage
And with the desire
of meeting Simi-
One night he ran away
from "Bal Bhavan"
Are you in a hurry. My dear son
what's the story?
I..... I.... Iost my way
No problem, my dear son
I'll show you the right way
Wicked Girdharilal took innocent
Ramesh to a path of robbery-
And the changing times made
Ramesh a safe breaker thief
Girdhari Boss, take care of this
My dear son,
everything is ready inside
Have you kept the diamonds safe?
Its perfectly safe, you don't worry
Still 10 minutes are more
Mr. Katiklal
Ay what are you doing?
But instead, it was good.
Once more
No It's my mistake
No it's our mistake
No, No our mistake
No, it is only my mistake,-
I was walking somewhere,
and seeing somewhere
Madam, you may be seeing anywhere
But, we should have looked at you
She looks like a loose character
should we take her Tel:No
Is this your brief-case?
Don't know how it fell down?
Should I tell how it fell?
Like this
You are joking
Should we go back of her?
Sir, Mr. Narang..... come....
Then come
Oh! I stopped there because of you
otherwise...
Sorry, Narang
we got late
Have you brought
the diamonds?
See this, such diamonds
you will not get anywhere
They are of a very good quality
Yes, look, how they are glittering
Tonny, put the crown of
diamonds on their head
Okay, Seema, after these diamonds
are sold, you'll get your money
And, you'll get your commission
Okay, Pinto, call me up if there is
some other similar work
Seema, tell me one thing,
a beautiful girl like you-
In such a dangerous profession
why?
Pinto, If you are in search
of a drunkard -
Where will you find him?
In a Tavern
And a gambler
In a gambling house
I am, in search of a
diamonds smuggler
Who is he?
This is what I want to know
So, you are searching him,
whom you even don't know, why?
Why?
The answer for this "Why?" one day
I'll only give it to him
Greetings Mr. Manmohan Lal
Tell me, how can I help you?
Sir, he is Dr. Mishra
Mr. Manmohan Lal, we are running
a hospital for children
We thought, If another
ward could be set up then....
Enough, enough, you don't have to
take pains of saying anything more
Bihari, whatever amount of cheque
Mr. Mishra wants, give it to him
Great, how much do you do
for the afflicted people
May be, because of these
afflicted people
God has give me so much
Otherwise, where am l?
and where this wealth
Sir, phone, lts an
important call
Sir, Mr. Donze wants to
meet you in the evening
Okay, Okay.
Sir, one more thing, Kirti who had
taken our diamonds, has come back
Now, he is here
Okay, I'll come
Okay, I'll leave,
It's time for my worship, Greetings
Thank you.
When did you come?
Mr. Jugran, I returned,
from Europe only today
I have handed over your
diamonds to your man Victor
If an improbity is commited with
hard work, devotion and intelligence-
The world's entire honest
people can do nothing-
To such a dis-honest person
Balwant, This man Kirti is of
great importance to us-
He took with him diamonds worth
crores, and went out of country-
But, the police
could not catch him
I swear by the Devil
I cheat people
people don't cheat me
Rascal, you went there and kept
glass pieces instead of diamonds
Take him away
No, Mr. Jugran
forgive me, forgive me
I'll not commit
such a mistake again
Come, Mr. Donze, we were only
waiting for you
Come
Mr. Donze
Till today I have done many
transactions of diamonds with you-
But today, today I am going
to give you such an offer-
Which will be the biggest
offer of your life time
5 crores
10 crores
50 crores
100 crores
100 crores.......
But, where will we get diamonds
worth 100 crores at a time?
Have you heard of the name
"Kohinoor Diamond Corporation"
Every month, a train takes
diamonds worth 100 crores
From there to the airport -
And this train, for 15 minutes
passes through a desolated area
But, the diamonds in that safe
cannot be robbed even in 15 hours
Mr. Donze, you don't
know about this country
If searched, I swear by the devil -
There are experts
scattered all over
My dear son
Oh! Mr. Girdhari Lal
what's the news?
Where are you, what's the story?
Girdhari Boss, come to the point
Have you heard of the name
queen Yashodhra Devi
But, what will I do going to
queen Yashodhra Devi's party
Try to understand,
my beautiful
The Necklace that queen
Yashodhra Devi would be wearing-
It's every diamond
would be priceless
Are you sure she would be
wearing that necklace
Definitely my dear son
definitely
Then, think that necklace
has become ours
Girdhari Boss flicking Yashodhra Devi's
necklace will be my victory-
Apart from this nothing else
can be done, who'll stop me?
Come, Ravi come
You know, that I consider you
the best officer of my department
This file is of the robbers
pertaining with diamonds
From today, this case
is of your responsibility
Sir, I promise one day it would be
robbers hands and my manacles
Brother, do you know this Holy
thread is also a kind of manacle
The manacle of love
Well, this is also fine
Through out the year we make
the accused wear the manacles
Today, you make me wear
Son, after wearing this
fine has also to be paid
Yes, fine, ofcourse I have to pay,
have I ever forgotten, Kusum?
Ay, what happened?
Again, like every year
Every year, she deposits one Holy
thread in the name of Ramesh
You are such a big officer,
you can come to know of anybody-
Can't you search your brother?
Don't cry Kusum, don't cry
Brother
Our blessings will definitely
bear fruit
We'll get our Ramesh
we'll definitely get him
Ay brother, where have you come from?
Son Jango, It's clearly stated
on the card
"Entry for one person only"
You do onething,
you go, understood
I'll go and clear the neck
of Mrs. Yashodhra Devi
Hallo Mr. Batliwala, how are you?
you are alone -
Yes
Where is your best friend
Mr. Topiwala?
I heard the responsibility of
catching that famous Jewel thief -
Is on your head
You Press people
are simply great
One should not hear
any one's talk-
But this talk walked itself
into my ears -
That you are a police officer
And, I have also heard Mr. Ravi,
that now-a-day's the diamond robber-
Who has created an uproar
you are intended to catch him
Absolutely right
One day, it would be robbers
hands, and my manacles
My necklace till now, it was
in my neck, where is my necklace
My necklace
Keshav, the necklace is stolen
In this party, a precious
diamond necklace of Yashodhra Devi-
Is missing
Who ever is present here
will not be permitted to leave
Oh, I am sorry, my leg....
You, sing very good
I regret for it, but this is the
question of our hotel's reputation
I feel ticklish
You may go
This way please, ladies that side
Friend, you helped me
at the right time
Otherwise, today these diamonds
and this Hero -
Both, would have been
in the police station
His name was Jango and yours?
The name is something else
with love, people call me Romeo
Even, you can call me Romeo
but, with love
Romeo, this necklace was brought
out of the hall by you -
But, I had removed it
from the neck
No, Not at all
Look, if you don't want that,-
I should be at the back of you
like a shadow-
Make your living difficult
I spoil all your work
So, 50 - 50, Okay
Madam, this is very strange
actually its called a thumb
But, if it is shown like this
its called Balls
Great, great, great
Here, strike it
My dear son, tell me one thing
you'll give me the necklace-
After selling it
I'll give you, your share-
And, like everytime, you'll give
your share to the Orphanage-
After so much, of hard work
what did you have for yourself?
Girdhari Boss, in life,
I have lost so much-
That to gain something,
has never interested me
One day in the same city,
amidst the croud-
A child's hand was separated
from his father
Then, everything got lost-
Mother, father,
brother, sister everything-
Even, If I get them today,-
I'll immediately abandon the,
world of crime, at this moment
Girdhari Boss, people loose
their keys, of their lock-
And I am one, who has lost
the lock, of the key
Who called me?
You remembered me, sir
Yes
You remembered me, and
Sub-inspector Rangbirangey lal Chauhan-
Is at your service
So today, Rajkumar, you are having
the fever of filmstar Rajkumar
What to do Sir, -
When ever I watch a movie
of a particular filmstar-
Then, 24 hours, I am
intoxicated about him-
Now, 12 hours of it
are passed my dear-
Sir, still 12 hours of it
are remaining, 12 hours
Have you seen the
Nihal Singh murder case file?
Nihal sing's file
File.....
The condition of the file
tells that this case is-
Very much dangerous
amd very complicated
Very complicated
Do one thing, take the file
from my table -
And give it to S.P's office
One more file, alright
My dear, by looks you
look like a star-
But, you do the work
of a paper-weight -
By the way, who are you?
Sir, lock
This is that lock,
The key of which has got lost
Daddy, daddy you were telling
that you have such a lock-
That no one else in
the world has it
Daddy, show it to us
Do you want to see the lock
this is the lock-
This lock is for Ravi,
and the key is for Ramesh
But, remember one thing
both this lock and key
Without one another
is totally useless-
If you have to use it,-
Then, forever you'll both
have to stay together
Ay, Is your name Romeo?
Why, It shouldn't have been
You give the answer
only in "Yes" or "No"
Is your name Romeo?
"Yes"
You will work for us
"No"
Do you know, we can give you a
good price for this work
"Yes"
Tell, what do you say?
"No"
Very funny
talk in a straight way
Well, you only told me to
give an answer in "Yes or No"
Then, we also know other
methods, of asking questions?
If the appereance is like this
Then one shouldn't have a
Gun in his hand
Instead, one should
have a begging bowl
No.., No I'll not listen
for any explanation-
You all were present there
you, you, you-
Balwant and Kashav
were also present there-
And that Romeo was
in front of you
It's a shame,
Shame on you all,-
He has made you all
bite the dust for ever
Jugran Sir, what happened was.....
You shut up, you use to brag
that you would bring him here-
Useless
Balwant, listen for the last time
I want Romeo
Because, a safe breaker like him-
I swear by the devil
he is very important to me
Hallo, any new Drama, Today?
Yes, absolutely new.
And, if you want that I don't
do this drama-
Then, that necklace which is
In your pocket-
Without doing any drama,
give it to me
My answer for the necklace is
same even today Madam,
As it was yesterday
Ball's
Alright, then I'll present
the drama,
"A tale of a sorrowful woman"
Ay! what happened?
I am robbed, I am ruined.
My dear, how did you get
the heart of leaving a Girl-
Whose face is so innocent
my dear
My dear
Ay what are you doing?
My dear, My dear, My dear
Don't leave me and go like this
I beg of you
What happened sister
what happened?
Mother.....
You called me sister, Then also
listen to your sister's sad story
This Romeo, a lad of Bombay,
and me Shanta a girl from Madras.
He told me a story of a movie,
entraped me, married me-
Made me a wife,
and now, he is befooling me
She is not my wife.
Oh! My God, you say there is nothing,
There is nothing
If I am not your wife,
then the auspicious thread-
Which I am wearing, is it for me
to die by hanging with it-
And, the locket with your photo,
Did your father give it to me?
Ay brothers', mothers, he tells
me, that I am not his wife
Aren't you ashamed of troubling
your wife, son of a Gun.
He sells my Jewellery
and gambles, drinks liquor,-
Goes to brothels, watches girls
dancing, sings songs
This, this is false,
all this is false
And today, he is selling
my last, last diamond necklace
It's in his pocket
Sister's, catch hold of
his body tightly
What are you all doing?,
I don't have necklace
I don't have any......
What is this? you are a liar,
cheat and a betrayer-
Son of a Gun
Thank you, thank you
give me my necklace back
Take it
Wait, sister, you have
heard her story
But now, listen to my
sorrowful story also
It is true that
she is my wife
Mother, he told, he told......
But, she is my wife only for
the necklace, not for the love
What does that mean?
Father, if I lie,
I see your dead body
What?
It's two years since
we are married
But, she has not given me
a kiss till date
Yes, kiss, which means
meeting of the lips
Ask her? Has she ever
given it to me
My God, it's two years since the
marriage is over,-
And, still a kiss
has not been taken
Oye, what kind of a wife are you?
She is different, father she is different
She is not of the "KlSS" type
if she was,-
Then there wouldn't
have been any problem
Do one thing, you give
her the necklace
You give him the love
and you both become one
From my side it's done
Ay, what non-sense
are you people talking?
Oye, he will now give you a kiss
Is it his, father's property?
Daughter, spit out your anger
Where do I spit?
on your face
Look Shanta forgive him
And now he'll hug me and
kiss me in front of everybody
I, l, l....mean, to you-
And with his own hands, he'll
make you wear the necklace
Yes, Yes, Yes, Yes.......
Confusion, a lot of confusion
Go, take a kiss,
put on the necklace go, go.
Okay, first I'll
finish this work
I am coming shanta
I don't know you
Don't know, don't worry,
I'll tell you now who I am
Ay, you got a chance
don't let it go
Sinner, wicked
You have started getting a
complex with that Romeo-
Now, he has started coming
in your dreams-
And is giving you nightmares
Now listen to what I say-
Search the man who
gives you nightmares,-
And make him your
slave, slave
Girdhari Boss, why was l
asked to come here?
My dear son,
Are you seeing this?-
This statue is identical to the
2000 years old statue of Egypt
Its cost is only Rs.300
But, there is no approximation
for the cost of the original statue
Then, What's the story?
The story is that my dear son
the original statue
Is with Egypt's millionare
Abu Aslam Ghanvi-
Who is now-a-days in this city
and this evening he is going to-
Display the original statue
to a few people
I'll make you reach there
Take this along with you
That means
Keeping the duplicate,
I take away the original one
Correct, my dear son
I have made
all the arrangements
Exactly by 8 O' clock, for 1 minute
lights will get switched off
Understood.....
You are, Mr. Abu Aslam Ghanavi
Ghanvi
Dhongri Batala, Dhongri Batala
Dhongri Batala
This is the salute
of Matunga Country
Prince you will not believe
that Matunga is a country-
Only today I came
to know of it
Come prince, I'll introduce
you to other guests
Even she, understood......
Your highness, meet him, he is
prince Singh Batada of Matunga-
And she is
princes China Chini of of......
Chinch pokli......
This country is pasted between
China, Chilly & Cherapunji-
Only today I came
to know of it
Silver spoon, silver spoon
Silver spoon, this is the
statue of Chinch pokli
Thenga, Thenga, Thenga
Thenga
Prince says, great, great, great
he liked the salute
Mr. Abu Aslam Ghanvi's
party, is at which floor
At the 20th floor
Princes, this statue of our
country is famous world wide-
But, what is famous
of your Chinch pokli?
Magic
Magic, what magic?
This statue will be Chikmanglu
Chikmanglu
"Missing"
Can I take away this statue?
Oh sure, But why?
For the magic
You, have thrown down my
world famous statue
Not thrown, only magic
But, in the magic the thing
which gets disappeared-
It also comes back
but, you have thrown it away
Not thrown
Not thrown, then where is it?
Here it is
Did you see, not thrown away
only magic
Great, great, great.
Magic is also done like this,
only today I came to know of it
Donghribadala, Donghribadala
Silver spoon, Silver spoon
Silver spoon.......
I was so much engrossed in the
work for the last few days-
That I couldn't come
When you come, It feels good
keep coming
What's the use of coming?
Your daughter didn't even
offer me a cup of tea
Seema, I'll just bring
Mummy, Mummy even I'll have
tea along with Seema Aunty
Seema, did you come
to know anything
If I come to know anything
or if I doubt anybody-
I'll only come
to you "D" uncle-
You are the only one, who can
recognize the killer
Is Doctor Ashok Soni there?
Yes, How can l
forget that face
Mr. Manmohan Lal has come....
Come Mr. Manmohan Lal
Why all this? This is
necessary only for big people
For us, you are
the biggest person
This library is established
only because of your help
The inauguration should also
be done by you
Come
Please come....
What I mean is, that
in this business -
There is no harm
in investing money
If we wouldn't have
met that Girlie....
Profits were in diamonds too
did you understand-
But, what did we get?
she befooled us and went away
Seema, here is the
Price for the statue
You
You Girlie....
Catch her, catch her, catch her......
We are all thankful to you
Thank you, Thank you, Greetings
Driver, stop the Car
Who are you?
Sir please, my life is in danger
Those people are following me
Have you seen any girl?
Sir, we haven't seen
Seema, who were those people
who were following you?
Who ever they were,
they were not good
Then they..., daughter, are you
into something, that you...
Remember one thing, the end result
for a bad work, is always bad
Forget it, Mr. Manmohan Lal
All these philosphies sound
good, only in the books
Why is so much of
bitterness in you?
Sir, my father was a very
decent man
The man who killed him,
did a very bad thing-
But, the killer hasn't
yet reached to his end result-
Then how can I believe -
That the end result for a
bad work is always bad
So your father.....
Yes, Dr. Ashok soni
Dr. Ashok Soni, who killed him?
do you know?
I don't know, but one day
I'll definitely know-
And, I am alive,
only for that day-
My every moment, every bit of me
is in search of that killer
Mr. Manmohan lal,
the day I get him
Sir, he is lnspector Ravi Verma
Greetings
Greetings, please come
Mr. S.P had called me up,
that you wanted to meet me
I need to get some
information about Jugran
Definitely
Who would be more
pleased than me, if he is caught
Seema, there is a brother
of mine somewhere in this world-
Jugran, twin, ldentical face.
Identical face
Mr. Manmohan Lal, Mr.S.P says
who ever has seen you both -
They say there is not a pinch
of difference between you both
Mr. Ravi, the only difference
is that -
He has lost in the
darkness of crime
This girl, where ever she
wants to go, drop her
Go daughter
Mr. Manmohan Lal,
who is this girl?
If I am not worng, I have
seen her somewhere
She is the daughter
of my late friend
In her childhood itself,
she lost her father
It's straight-
What ever my daughter says in
this house only that will happen
That is why I say, my father
is the best among the world
"D" uncle,"D" uncle, do you know
what my father tells me
My daughter Simi is the best
daughter in the world, best....
In this palace of Dolls,
your doll will stay-
Like the way
you stay in this house
Come, sit into the car
Come
I regret, I certainly regret-
That I had to call you
here in such a manner-
But, by coming here
you are only benefitted
Don't get surprised
by seeing me-
I know that you have
met my stupid brother-
Who has the cancer of decency
So, you are only
that Jugran
I know, Manmohan Lal spoke
about me, infornt of the lnspector-
And rest, whatever was told
there, I know it
So, You are in search of
your father, Dr. Ashok Soni's killer
I know, who he is?
Who is he?
I swear by the devil,
If I want, I can tell you
But, If I ever want to,
for that Miss. Seema Soni-
Even, you have to do
something for me
I swear by the devil
Mr. Jugran
You are not so clever,
as you think you are
Just now you told, what ever
happens at your brother's house-
You come to know
everything of it
I am in search of
my father's killer-
Even this was told there
which you came to know-
Apart from this. You are
totally oblivious about it
When your father was killed,-
He was making
a "Palace of Dolls," for you
This was not told
there by you
Am I worng?
You, You, all this.....
All this I listened
from the killer himself-
I know him, and I can
hand him over to you
For this, for this, what is it
that I have to do?
You need a man,
that responsibility is mine-
And, I need a man
that responisbility is yours
I need this man, there's a safe
which only he can open
You make him prepare
to work for me
Why do you think that I can
make him prepare for this work?
If a clever and beautiful girl,
like you asks such questions-
I swear by the devil,
It doesn't sound good
And, My father's killers
name and address
The day he breaks open that
important safe for me
You'll get to know the name,
address of your father's killer
Okay, Okay, I'll give it a try
Come on sweet hearts,
eat properly, don't drop it down
I think he must have gone in
search for some female pigeon
Today let me see, how good
a post man are you?
Oh, so finally you have come-
Can I ask where were you
missing all the day?
Jango, I have told
you so many times-
That stop behaving
like pigeons
What is it that is hanging
on your neck
Romeo, your rememberance
very often comes to me-
Even you must be remembering me,
don't you?
What ever has
happened till date,
Let's forget it
and become friends
I know, that you consider me both
beautiful as well as dangerous
If you feel that, I am more
dangerous, then don't come-
And, If you feel that
I am more beautiful-
Then, My address is
written below
Jango, whatever is true
is true
The girl, no doubt
is more beautiful
Madam,
Madam
So, you have come
Madam, I have come only to know
that why did you call me here?
Romeo, don't be so ignorant-
When a beautiful girl, calls
a young boy alone to the house then-
Then, there is a definite
reason behind it
Intelligent, really intelligent
Madam, the intelligence of mine
will be known to me-
Only when, you come out
from the curtain
Here, I am out from
all the curtains
But, the secret is still
behind the curtain-
That what exactly
do you want?
A friendship with you
But why?
That's because, now-a-days I am
working for a very big man
So,
So, he requires you for a
very special assignment
Okay, Okay, Okay
so this is the matter
The matter would be,
that you look into my eyes-
And say that, you can do
anything for my friendship
Madam, these beautiful eyes
this moon face, and these rosy lips-
Cannot lure a man like me
I don't need your friendship
In my life, I have always been
a loner and will remain a loner
And, If my beauty
stops your way, then
Would you be able to
stop my way?
leave me and go?
Would you be able to
seduce me?
sign me off?
Madam, it is impossible that you
cast the magic of your eyes on me
It possible that I melt your
heart with my seductive looks
Madam, I'll not let
my heart to get melted
I am going, and this heart
is also going along with me
In a very short span of time
we have come so close to each other
Very close
So, should I understand that,
you will do that work for me
No, No I'll not do it
What? you'll not do it
I'll not do it
I spent a nice evening with you
thank you so much
But,...
Don't forget that,
I know your reallity
If I want, I can tell
it to the police
Alright, what is the work
that you have with me
Whatever the work is
it will not be difficult for you
Okay, so this is it
Madam, difficulty is only in
forcing me, to do a work-
You tried to tempt me
with your beauty-
With displaying the viles
of beauty and charm-
You had tried to scare me
with the police and the gun-
If you have any other cheap idea
then, try using that and see
Madam, your repeated attempts
make me understand, only one thing
That how much gready
are you for money?
Who hates money?-
But, I haven't seen any other big
worshipper of money, than you
I am confident, fully confidemt
that a wretched woman like you-
Would see nothing in her dreams
except for gold, silver & diamonds
Stop it Romeo, stop it
How much ever you
wanted to say, you said-
How much ever I had to
listen, I listened-
And now, if you utter
a word more then I'll.....
I don't deny against
the opinion, that you hold for me
But, before you go away
after calling me wretched and cheap-
Listen to one thing, that I am not
doing all this for money-
I am not doing this for money
Then, for what are you
doing all this?
Do you want to know?
Yes, I want to know
You want to know?
then look there
The lost lifeless woman who is
sitting like a stone statue-
Is my mother
17 years ago my father was
lying on the ground
Drowned in his own blood
17 years ago I heard the voice
of my mother for the last time
It was not a voice but shriek
a painful shriek
I laugh when people talk about
principles and justice
The person who killed my father
did he get any punishment?
No.
The person who made my mother
a living dead body
Did he get any punishment?
No
The person who ruined my home
my life
Did he get any punishment?
No, No
What ever I am doing is an
effort to reach that murderer
Whether you help me or not
or anybody helps me or not
But the one who ruined
The happy home of the
darling daughter of her parents
And sent her to the orphanage
I will never forgive him
I will never forgive him.
Never forgive him
Atleast now did you come to know
Diamonds and jewels
don't come in my dreams
But the lifeless face of my father
And the painful shrieks of
my mother comes in them
A robber entered a man's house
good or bad?
Bad
But there was nothing in the
house that could be robbed
Good
After this the robber
got furious
Taking a big stick
he went to his bed
He hit him one hard blow
Bad
But the man was
not sleeping on the bed
Good
Seema has told Romeo whom
she is searching for?
But, before leaving Simi didn't ask
her childhood friend
Ramesh that after recognizing her
Is he prepared to help her or not?
I am here only, Seema if you
like you can ask even now
Jugran Sir,
I have brought the person
whom you wanted to meet
So you are that magician
With one flick of whose
hands safes open
I swear by the Devil
You have a great reputation in
this game.
People like coloured fish
but I like Tortoise
And I like, Pigeons
But Mr. Jugran
I don't think you have not
called me here-
To talk about fish, tortoise
and Pigeons
Shall we talk business
This is that safe
You have to open a safe
like this for me
Your work will be done
But this job is not so easy
Because, if you can open this
safe in 15 minutes-
Then you are useful to me
But, if you take 16 minutes
then you are no good for me
In 15 minutes I can open
the safe 3 times
He is talking non-sense
Mr. Jugran
A person who is carrying a
pigeon on his shoulder-
How can he open this safe
You are very proud of
your talent, let me also see
Jango one minute
Keep on looking at your watch
see how much time do I take
How much time did I take?
5 minutes
That's why I said that I can
open the safe 3 times in 15 minutes
what's your name?
Keshav
Keshav, Pigeons are of
two types
Some have the face of a pigeon-
And some have the
intellect of pigeons
Jango has only a face of a
pigeon and you are-
A pigeon with an intellect
Jugran Sir, why have you kept
this pigeon as a pet-
Jugran Sir, this man
may be useful to you
But, make this Rascal
understand that he shouldn't.....
You talk too much Keshav
In front of so many people
you have... I am going
Come Romeo and see.
Every month a train
from Chandipur station
Brings a safe to Bombay
In this safe Kohinoor diamond Co's.,
diamonds are kept
This train passes through
a lonely stretch for 15 minutes
You will have only 15 minutes
Withing 15 minutes you have to
open the wagon and the safe
And come out with the diamonds
When has the job to be pulled
When exactly the safe
will come in the train
Nobody knows till the last moment
except Co's., G.M., D.K.Malhotra
D.K. Malhotra in a sealed envelope-
Informs the owners of
the diamonds
But he has a copy of the
letter in his safe also
To know that, this train will
start when and on what date
We will have to open
D.K. Malhotra's safe
I swear by the Devil,-
It is easy to converse with
intelligent people
To reach the safe of
D.K. Malhotra we have to plan
D.K. Malhotra has made it
easy for us himself.
He is throwing a big party on
Tuesday in the Co's., banquet hall-
And the entire arrangement for
the party is with our hotel
D.K. Malhotra's flat is on
the top floor of that building
Every body will be watching
Seema's dance in the party-
And you will open the safe in
D.K. Malhotra's study
From which you will know
the day and time of train's departure
Once you give me those
diamonds, I swear by the Devil-
I will guide you to reach
the murderer of Seema's father
Remember Seema we
used to come here often
Probably you love for the pigeons
started from here only.
Yes, My love for the pigeons
also started from here
And one day both of us there....
Seema you wait here
I will come
My dear Son, you are here
with such sweet Company.
What is the story?
Girdhari Sir, it is no more
business relation with her-
It's something else
Oh it is something else!
I have wasted all my life
in earning money
I never did anything else
Okay, atleast you do
something else.
But first do one thing for me.
What is it?
In Mayfair hotel,tomorrow
there is a big exibition of jewellry
And in this exhibition
beautiful models-
Will come on the stage
wearing jewels
There will be
countless on lookers-
And many secuirty guards.
Sorry Girdhari Sir, I can open the
lock of a safe but.
I cannot close the eyes of
so many on lookers
My dear Son.
I was thinking of making a
hostel of your Bal-Bhavan
But Girdhari Sir, how will l
reach the stage
I can make you reach there
Perhaps you don't know
That in the world of fashion
and modelling
I am known as the queen
of beauty
I can make you reach to the stage
where the jewellery will be
My dear daughter
I like your suggestion so much-
That I did not feel offended
after knowing
That you were listening
to us stealthily
What ever we did till today
we did it as opponents
Let us work as parteners now
and see
After all what ever you would
do for the Bal-Bhavan
Even I have stayed in it
If the queen of beauty
paves the way to reach there
Then, the king of thieves will
find a way to escape from there
Beware
If anyone acts smart. I will
Shoot the girl. Shut up
Ay, throw the gun down.
Bend down
Hey mister, Clear the way
show must have started
There is problem every where.
Run
Darling this car is going
backwards
It is going backwards like you
Oh! on top of the Car
Hey donkey, haven't you paid the
Road Tax to the Municipality-
You are driving over our car
What are you thinking
of my car
Stop laughing. Put the
jewellery in the brief-case
Why am I not looking beautiful?-
You are looking very beautiful-
But we won't be looking
beautiful in the Jail
Take out the Jewellery Seema
and have the brief-case with you
Hey, what's all this-
Why are you laughing?
My husband is suffering -
Come down.
I have only one husband
Stop
Darling, who is exploding the
crackers-
I say stop
Darling, one has got down and
the other has climbed up.
Give me the brief-case and do
as I had told you. - Look out
Oh! it has become 50-50
Go, come fast
Oh lnspector Sir,! come soon
you have become very late-
He is hiding some where here.
Hey, where are you? I will
kill you, my jewels are missing.
Hey, where is he?
where has he gone?
He has run away
Where will he run & go? He will
definately be caught, well...
He pointed the revolver and took
you outside. Then what happened?
Then he said that if you
want to remain alive-
Then quietly sit in the Car
As I wanted to remain alive,
so I sat in the Car quietly
Then
Then, the car started, But you
can say it flew away
The Car was going very fast.
very fast
That cruel robber was laughing
like a villion in a movie
Behind there were police cars....
Revolver was stuck in my head
Then
Then he said
Mona darling remove all the
jewels put them in my bag
Bad cheat
And you removed all the jewels
and put them in the bag
Just think inspector Sir,
If you were in my place
And you have had ear-rings
in the ear, bangles on the hand-
Necklace in the neck
Pendant on the forehead
You would have looked funny
You.. You...
what do you want to say?
If someone had put the
revolver on your head
What would you have done?
You also would have
Removed the jewels isn't it
Yes
Then.... then what happened?
He stopped his car, picked up
his bag and told me -
Hey, girl if you try to follow me
then I will fry you
Fry you?
Yes.... No, No No No it was
something about cooking
Yes, if you try to follow me
then I will roast you
He said that and disappeared
Why didn't you try to stop him
I want to say something sir
after hearing this girl
I don't know why, but this girl
is telling the truth
And under those circumstances -
In front of the Rascal,
what else this girl could do
She,she was under compulsion
She was helpless
Okay, You go with him, give your
statement and give your address
And then you can go
Then, Shall we go?
Yes let's go
Great, great, great
My dear son, you have formed
a nice pair
Thank you very much Girdhari Sir,
You are gold, and she
is its glitter
But, for some you'll have to
forget this gold
I will forget.
But remember one thing-
If you work for someone else,
Then, I am very emotional,
I will get offended
Don't worry.
This is not your department's work
Then what's the story?
The story is, that to
reach a particular person-
I need the help of Romeo
Who is he?
I don't know
I will tell Seema that her
father's murderer is none else,
But, Jugran himself.
I will tell her
Have you gone mad?
Yes, I have gone mad
in front of everybody...
I have flattered him enough
Now I will reveal
his true character
Yes speaking.
Who are you?
Never mind who I am-
But, I can tell you this much that
who is your father's murderer?
And where he is
Where will I find him?
In the same party where
you are going tomorrow
The name of your
father's murderer is......
D' Uncle, that murderer is
going to come in that party.
You had said one day that
you can recognize him.
Seema, to help you, I will come
where ever you want me to
Tiwari, had you told Balwant
to wait for me
I am going to
D.K. Malhotra's party
18th of November
They are still children
They thought that with the
help of that old man D'silva
They will locate that murderer
But, I swear by Devil
Neither Romeo knows
nor does that poor Seema
That I can to both of them
for the rest of their lives-
Make them dance to my tunes
But Jugran Sir, how did
all this happen?
The moment you told me that-
Keshav was talking to
Seema over phone
I thought till
this party is over-
Seema should be kept
under surveilliance
When she went to meet D'silva
my men were following her
They heard her conversation
with D'silva-
And after Seema had left-
D'silva's daughter and her
child were kidnapped -
And D'silva was told
that if he opens his mouth-
Both of them will be killed
Then the same thing happened
that I wanted
Now Sir, what will you do with
D'silva's daughter and her child
What will I do?
I will release them
If after that D'silva talks to
Romeo and Seema then?
You didn't understand Balwant
I will leave them but,
I will kill D'silva
Understood
Understood Sir,
Come on get down
Come
No....
Don't take it as an
obligation Rosy
What ever I am doing
is my duty
Only, because of me he
did that to Mr. D'Silva...
I am hardly doing
anything for you
No, Seema both of you have done
everything for me and for my child
You have made provision
for my entire life
Is nothing in proportion
to Mr. D'silva's life
What happened Rosy?
What are you looking at
That Car Seema, Romeo that Car
that car only hit my Daddy
Rangbirangey. Any news
about D'silva's case
Which D'silva, what D'silva,
where from D'silva Sir
That D'silva who was crushed
by a car on the road-
Whose daughter had reported that
it wasn't an accident case
Oh! I see, that case
Sir, I think we'll have to close
down that case because
Statement of deceased's daughter
and her child has been taken-
Rosy what ever we have
done for you-
They only said that the black
car was an old model Ford-
But, nobody has noted its number
That's all sir
There may be many old Fords
in the city -
But and till you get the
number of the car....
You can get the number
May I come in
Ravi Sir, the car which
killed Mr. D'silva
You can get its number
So, What have you brought,
The Car's No. or the Car's No. plate
Neither the car's No. nor
the car's No. plate
I have brought this pigeon
Pigeon
Though he is a pigeon but he is
my friend, his name Jango
The Car which hit Mr. D'silva
His daughter
recognized that Car today
This Pigeon Jango was present there
Jango flew and follwed the Car.
Jango recognizes the No.
and can tell you too
This is Bullshit
this is all frivolous talk
The job that this Rangbirangey
couldn't do. Can this pigeon do it
If that is possible the Govt.
will close the police stations
And open pigeon houses
Please continue Mr. Romeo
If you permit me then should l....
What was the No. of that
Car Jango? tell them
Seven
Three
Nine
Six
7396 is the No. of that Car
If this pigeon can recognize
and tell the No. of the Car
Then why not make him the
traffic constable Sir.
Constable pigeon
Very good, like you, your pigeon
is also marvellous
Jango considers his duty
to help the law
Yes, I am sure
And now, can I go
No No, people like you don't come
to the police station often
Have tea and go
Okay, Mr. Ravi, Jango you go
I will come later
Jango doesn't take tea.
Really
Sir, your phone
Yes sir, I am working
on that Case
Your, your lock?
Yes Sir, it's quiet unique
And its key?
I lost it in my childhood.
How long the thief will be lucky
Afterall I am a police officer
I have neither sympathy for such
law breaker nor mercy
I assure you Sir, one day it will
be robbers hand and my Manacles
Sorry you had to wait
Sir, your mother and
sister have come
Oh God! I have to take
mother to the doctor
Sorry Mr. Romeo if you don't
mind I have to go
No it doesn't matter
Romeo, if you want to go back to them
then there is only one way.
You will have to
change your life
You will have to swear
that after today
You will not commit any crime nor rob- never....
Tomorrow
Tomorrow Romeo will bring the
diamonds from that train
And I will know the name of
your murderer daddy
Tomorrow Romeo will reach me
to my destination
So tomorrow it's your
examination
Come, I will tell you how you
will reach the running train-
And how we will take you out
I will not commit this theft
Mr.Jugran
I swear by the devil
you will commit it
You think that you can force me
to do any job like this?
And you think you can refuse
to do any job that I ask you
I am not accustomed
of hearing a no
So Mr. Jugran if you are not
accustomed to hear no
Then you will have to change
this habit of yours
The claws of the pigeons
are not usually so sharp
Come Seema, come on, What an
opportune time you have come.
What, what is this?
This is revolver. revolver
Without firing it,
Romeo -
The deal that was struck
between both of us-
He has fired it
Isn't it Romeo?
Is this the fact?
No
Romeo is not like this
He can't do this.
Give an answer Romeo
Sweet heart is asking
something
Sweet heart wants to know
To find out about her father's murderer
Can you do something or not
Do you know what will
I do when I grow up?
Along with you, I will kill the
man who killed your father
Today for the last time I will
do this job for you
But tomorrow if you
don't tell Seema-
The name and address
of that murderer
Or if the name and address
is not correct
Then all your loyal dogs can't
protect you from me
I swear by the devil
Love can force a person
to do any thing
3 Guards will be inside the
compartment and one in guards room
And this compartment will be
sealed from outside. Okay
Okay Seema you remember
what you have to do
Yes, I remember
Romeo I know-
That you are doing this
dangerous job only for me-
No Seema
Not only for you only,
but for me too
Besides I and you there is
another word in the world
I had cautioned
That apart from me don't work
for anyone else my son
But he is working
Now see I am offendend
Connect the phone to the
Police Head Quaters
Take the bag first.
after that...
Don't forget to take the bag
Sir, he has fallen
into the water
Sir, he is running. He should
not remain alive shoot him
Let's go, that's why I asked you
to wait there Seema-
Because, I knew their
intentions well
Bravo Romeo, how
clever you are.....
Oh! this character is also there
in the story
Get down from the Jeep
my dear Son. Come
And my dear daughter
you also come down
My dear son, what is the story
You forgot your old partner, give
give those diamonds to me
Till I am alive I won't give
Girdhari Boss
Alright. I'll take them
after your death
Do one thing,
shoot both of them
Sorry Girdhari Boss,
These bullets were
meant for me-
But by mistake they came to
your address
Now we will phone Jugran
and call him to the place of our choice
And if he wants the diamonds
Then he will have to tell the
name of the murderer first. Right
Romeo, where are you?
I am here Jugran
I have a gun in my hand
you are on its target
And I don't miss my aim
like your men
Romeo, my people didn't act
under my orders
They had evil intentions
But I swear by the devil
I'll abide by the deal
Deal will be settled from
here only Mr. Jugran
You tell the name of the murderer
I'll tell you where the
diamonds are
Okay, you may not
have faith in me
But, I have full faith in you
Seema's father, late Dr. Ashok Soni
was murder-
The man who did it-
That man.......
It's Me
Here I have fulfilled my promise
Come, come
You people were unnecessarily
hiding from me
Jugran, if you have killed
my father, then I'll....
I swear by the devil.
I did.
But, now how to ask you people,
that where the diamonds are?
Before coming here I found out
that this closed factory-
Was a chemical factory
Even now there are so many tanks
in this factory in which -
Contains Acid
Where are the diamonds Romeo?
Where are the diamonds?
Where are the diamonds?-
Stop
Diamonds, diamonds are
in that big box
Jugran Sir, he is telling the truth
diamonds are there in the bag
I swear by the devil. Love can
make a person do anything
Listen
Now tie this lover near his
sweet heart
If I wish, I can get you thrown
in this tank. But no
I swear by the devil
I won't let both of
you die so easily
Open very slightly
Acid must fall in drops
Slowly this acid
will gnaw the rope
And till then both of you will
wait for your death
I swear by the devil
Waiting for death is more
dreadful than the actual death
Don't look there Seema
Romeo, this had to be the end of us
Don't look there, look at me
There was a queen of beauty and
there was a king of thieves
They met each other after years
Good
But after meeting the distance
remained between them
Bad
Then they started loving each
other secretly
Good
But, they could not tell their
feelings to each other
Bad
And one day the queen of beauty
So what were you saying?
I was saying that
I love you very much Seema
Me too
Will you?
Will you
will you marry me
I will
Look there our marriage
party has come
Romeo, Romeo I am very much afraid
Nothing has happened.... till now.
Romeo, Romeo that rope Romeo
Don't look Seema,
don't look that side
Don't look at the
impending death
It is better we look at each othe
till last moment
Yes Romeo, I will see your face
in my eyes and die
Seema, Seema you wait here
here at the gate
May be any Jugran's
man is outside
I will bring the car and come
I had told you that one day
It will be the robbers hands-
And my manacles
Today that day has come Romeo
I am ready to remain behind bars
for the whole of my life
But not today, today.....
No
Don't throw this key brother
Ramesh!
Yes brother
You will meet here
Meet this way.
I couldn't think brother,
I couldn't think
You knew it?
You knew it
Even then... naughty boy
why didn't you tell me
How could I brother?
The world of crime in which
I am........
If you have committed a sin, there
is an atonment for it too. fool
Come, first come home, touch
mother's feet and embrace sister
This punishment will be
your atonement
And... where are those
diamonds?
Those diamonds are
not with me.
Then who has them?
They are with the person
for whom I worked. Jugran
Jugran,
Yes
This sin can't be atoned
even if you go to jail
Idiot, fool.
You work for your
father's murderer
Jugran....Jugran
Yes Jugran is the murderer
of our father
I didn't know.... I didn't know
Brother, I will touch the feet
of mother and also go to Jail
But.... after teaching a
lesson to Jugran
No Romeo, I can't let you
I will come back brother
Sir, I want the arrest warrent
for Ramesh and Seema
They have committed this theft
But, now Jugran has the diamonds.
He should be in this city only
Alright
I am ready to extend any help
to you for this job
We want to put you on the TV
Mr. Manmohan Lal
Me on the TV
Yes Sir, so that the
public would know that-
The police is searching for
a person with the similar face
Strange.... strange
Police is searching
you every where
And you are roaming here,
very bad, very bad
Come I will tie you in
the bondage of love
Take you to the
police station
Don't ditch me... don't ditch me
We are residents of that country
where there are police stations
Run
Where there are police stations
What are you waiting for? catch them
catch them, don't leave them
I touch your feet sir.
By God I won't leave them
I will catch every one
I will catch every one. Dog's
I am not talking to you rascal
Dacoit.. I am coming, Dacoit
I am coming
Sir, now where to
look for them?
Now, where to look for them
I don't know where have they run away
Has the earth concealed them or
the sky has swallowed them
Seema we have escaped
I am sure that you will help
the police in locating him
Thank you
Seema he is
No Romeo, whom you are
thinking to be Jugran
He is his twin brother
Manmohan Lal
If he was Manmohan Lal then
Manmohan Lal is only Jugran
Why?
I will tell you
First you find out,
Where Manmohan Lal will be
at this moment
How have you suddenly decided
to go to Europe
I am not going for good
Mr. Gulshan has unnecessarily
thrown such a big farewell party
What are you talking
Mr. Manmohan Lal
This is hardly a big party in
your honour. Isn't it S.P. Sir
Arrest them
Leave me, leave me
Leave me
Romeo and Seema, we have
recognized both of you
S.P. Sir you have recognised us
But you couldn't recognize
Manmohan Lal
If you want to arrest,
arrest him first
You are saying this
for Mr. Manmohan Lal
The man whom you are thinking
to be Manmohan Lal-
Is actually Jugran
Yes, he is Jugran
I am Jugran! I am Jugran!
You are laughing Jugran, but
your laugh is hollow
Your accusations are hollow my
child because, you have no proof
Proof is there
Mark of pigeon's claws
on your wrist
Jango had clawed, Jugran's wrist
how did marks come on your wrist?
The mark of the claws, is the
last blow on your fate
Thorns scratched my wrist while
I was watering the garden
S.P sir plenty of vulgarity
has been exhibited about me
Wait
You will not clamp the manacle
on his hands
I will clamp them
Sir, I had told you, one
day it will be robbers hands-
And my manacles
Brother
Brother he is the murderer
of our father. He is Jugran
Brother?
Yes sir
he is my brother
But, at this moment he is
only a criminal
You are a theif, robber
a fugitive from law
You think that if you accuse the
honest and decent-
Man Mr. Manmohan Lal
We will concur?
No,
I think it's time for you to
go to the airport
Brother why don't you agree
he is the murderer of our father
Shut up
Why should I agree?
Why should I agree? what proof do
you have that he is Jugran
And what proof do you have that
he is not Jugran
Proof..... you will get it now
Mr. Khurana
2 persons may look identical
But their finger prints will
never be the same
You remember, that once
Police arrested you thinking
that you were Jugran
They had taken your
finger prints also
I have them.... excuse me
I got them from police records
I have also brought the finger
print expert, Mr. Khurana with me
He will take your finger prints
And confirm here itself
That both the finger prints
belong to the same person
And then
Then I will ask you people
That if he is Jugran then why
the finger prints are similar
Sir your finger prints your
finger prints, your finger prints.
Get away
What's this?
This is the proof sir,
that he is Jugran
It's empty
I gave you intentionally
These are also not Manmohan lal's
finger prints
The fact is that police never
took Manmohan Lal's finger print
Romeo you told me over the phone
that Manmohan Lal is Jugran
And I have proved that
he is Jugran
You people did half the job,
I did the other half
And Jugran... you are defeated
You are an examplary brother
Before congratulating each other
look there also
Leave me- shut up. Come
No....
Brother
It is not a joke to
defeat Jugran
Inspector this not empty
Mr. S.P. girl's life
is in danger
That is why I tell your people
to clear the way for me to go
I swear by the devil
This should be the last
seene of this drama
My dear if you worship the devil
then I am dealer of death.
My dear give me this Gun, it is
not a play thing for childern
It can wound the hand
Tables have turned Jugran
Come - your end awaits you
Look around you
Come on driver, go fast
Romeo, Romeo there is Balwant
Jugran Sir, save me Jugran Sir
What is this?
Save me Jugran Sir
Take it up
Throw it throw that
container in the Sea
I swear by the devil. I will
do this job myself
Seema you don't worry
sit in the Car quickly
Kill both of them
Jugran. I have confiscated
these diamonds. Jugran
No Jugran you can't escape
today it's the day of justice
Remember every crime of yours and
every sin that you comitted
Remember then
Get up Jugran,
your game is up
After killing my father you have
not only snatched him-
But you have snatched the entire
family from me
Dr. Ashok Soni, do you remember him
do you remember, do you
Didn't you feel pity before
killing my father
Tell me, tell me didn't you get
mercy give me an answer, give me
This is the only way
What ever you wanted to do
you have done
Now it is my turn.
Now it is my turn
I want to see the three of you
dying from close quaters
You all stay there.
I will come
By the devil.