Life is like a film
Each of us is the lead in our own film
Some might assume he is also
the co-lead in someone else's film
But in fact, his role is merely supporting
Or just a bit part
Or worse...
his scenes could have been edited out
He just doesn't know it
Like the mother and child here
The girl will certainly be the lead
in her mother's film
Yet, in ten years
How important would the role of the mother
be in her daughter's film?
I'm responsible for keeping track
of these deleted footages
I make sure they are intact
Because people do make mistakes
in editing all the time
When they realize they made the wrong cut...
I'd deliver the footages back to them
The destination of my next delivery is here
The time is now
The set is done
The studio is lit
The door is open
Costumes' been chosen
Vocals' been sweetened
Rhythm' been enlivened
All ready and waiting
Shoot-the past and present
Shoot-love and pain
Shoot-tangled rivalries
All are nothing, but an illusion
No less than a blink
No more than an eternity
It's heaven nevertheless
How close is the present
how distant are the memories?
How stressful is the past
how tiring is the present?
"In a world where love's forgotten
can a memory be born to last?"
What kind of a love story can pay
for your living?
Who would allow this story the highest glory?
Perhaps all love stories do not come easy
But they're just words on a blackboard
such is the irony
Wipe away the past and present
Wipe away love and pain
Wipe away the rivalries
All are nothing, but an illusion
No less than a blink
No more than an eternity
What kind of heaven is that?
Oh, this love story
Forget this love story
Hold onto this love story
Oh this love story
Forget this love story
Hold onto this love story
How close is the present
how distant are the memories?
How stressful is the past
how tiring is the present?
"In a world where love's forgotten
can a memory be born to last?"
How close is the present
how distant are the memories?
How stressful is the past
how tiring is the present?
"In a world where love's forgotten
can a memory be born to last?"
Or fade like a picture on a silver screen
Cut
Cut!
Slate... Clap-board!
Do we have a take?
Is lunch ready?
Let's break now
Meal break!
Mr. Nie!
Wanna be an actress? Meet the director!
How's it going?
The love amongst the leads is way too artificial
What do you mean?
She read your script yesterday
and cried so many times
- Didn't you?
- Oh yes... It was so moving!
You hear that? So moving!
Xiao-yu is not exactly in love with Zhang Yang
Zhang neither... he reunites with her
for other reasons
As for the circus master and Xiao-yu...
what they have is hardly love
If so...
This is not a love story then!
Xiao-yu and Zhang have to be in love
with each other
The circus master has to love Xiao-yu
and vice versa
There, we have a love story
which is exactly what I've promised to deliver
- You must make me a love story!
- Love story is silly
Love story is... that's not the point!
The point is, women dig love stories
The audience digs love stories!
Do you like love stories?
- Oh, yes...
- Good girl!
You see?!
No kisses, no nudity and no love scene!
Where am I?
- All in the contract...
Shanghai, on the way to the hotel
press conference
Hey! I must get the cheque
before the conference starts
Otherwise, we're not getting out of the limo
Okay, bye
How long did I sleep?
15 minutes
That's all?
You called and woke me up again last night
And said something about revenge
and getting even
I said that?!
Next time you take sleeping pills
go straight to bed!
Whenever you don't, you go crazy!
Why are we taking this film?
You're missing all the offers in Hong Kong!
I'm out of here as soon as the press
conference ends! You'll be on your own
Just don't ring me up every other night
Look, your actress
Don't you dare fall for her during the shoot
She's an opportunist
But she won't go for someone like you
She only digs directors
What "memoir"?
I only agree to do a photo book
But Miss Sun
Your success story can inspire our youth
If they were as poor as I was as a child...
They don't need to be inspired to succeed
Oh, that's good!
"If they were as poor as I was..."
What are you doing? You heard me
"No memoir"
Time to go, Miss Sun
The only value of my past is to remind me
to stay away from it
Is that clear?
What if one day you really forget it all?
Wouldn't it be a pity?!
That'd be perfect
What about love?
There is no such thing as love!
Miss Sun...
Hey Chief!
The contract should be fine with just
a couple of changes
Such as this word, you know
no one is comfortable with it
And this clause...
Never mind! I'll just rewrite the cheque
One more thing! Why is it written in past tense?
Never mind! I'll just take a zero off the cheque
But it's not something from the past
We'll talk later
The press conference is starting
- But the present tense suits the artist better...
- Later...
- The artist needs that...
- Get lost!
Rumors say that this time
the finance drives the project
And it's your Hong Kong investor...
...who insists on a musical and casting a star
from Hong Kong
Does it mark the end of Nie Wen as an auteur?
How do you think of...
I've never had more than one option
which is to make good movies
Finance, cast, genre
whatever are simply means towards my end
Sun Na
This is your first collaboration
with Lin Jian-dong
What's your favorite movie of his?
You won't believe it
I've not seen any of his films
- I seldom watch Hong Kong films
- Are there love scenes?
Wouldn't Mr. Nie be jealous?
Sun Na, have you closed the deal
on the Hollywood picture yet?
Not yet
Will you be using a dance-double?
If you don't start to ask
more intelligent questions
I suppose
I can end my Q & A session right here!
You've been avoiding making films in China
What makes you change your mind?
Good paycheck, a great director
And a gorgeous leading lady!
Well said, indeed!
And a great movie in the making
will eventually answer it all
Let's learn more about its plot
from the director now
This is a story about a love triangle
Sun Na stars as Xiao-yu
She had lost her memory
She'd forgotten her lover
She became homeless
And then... one day
She met a circus master
He took her in and made up
a beautiful memory for her
Good evening, mister
Mister?
Hurry, Xiao-yu!
But at this time, her former lover shows up
He's Zhang Yang
It was you, no doubt... your voice, your back
The distant look in your eyes puts me to silence
Are you testing me because you doubt me?
Perhaps my memory is flawed
You aren't you after all
Who are you then?
Someone who has forgotten her love for me?
My heart is enthralled by you, broken by you
I regret nothing even if I should
Love that once existed, or perhaps
it was only my illusion
How could you forget it all...
Forget all about me?
Who are you?
Who's this person gazing at me?
Is it deja vu, or is it a dream?
I seem to have known you before
The love in your eyes is a feeling
I don't understand
Why do you have to ask me...
...ask me who I am?
Have I really forgotten...
...who I really am?
I did know you, didn't I?
Look
The camera loves him
But who are you?
Sun Na
The pressure is on you now!
You lost your focus here
Your performance was unstable
You're just picking on me!
Take it easy
It's only a rehearsal shoot
We've been through this every time
After editing
you'll always give us a pleasant surprise
Does it mean I should get you to edit
my next Hollywood film?
Practice your English first
Your deal is not even signed
Remember
Mr. Gu's party is the day after tomorrow
He has promised to invest in my next film
I have to study the script and stay "focused"
Where do I find time to entertain your investors?
Jian-dong's gaze is good
but there is too much anger
Got to tone him down...
Mention this when you meet Mr. Gu
Our musical deserves a bigger budget
for promotion
Who's going to be your PR
once I'm gone to Hollywood?
Good evening, Mr. Nie, Miss Sun
Nie
Zhang's agent called me just now
He read the script and...
He realized the circus master is not the lead
So he's not interested
He'll change his mind in a couple of days!
But he's already negotiating
another picture deal!
He won't turn me down
If he does, I can do it! I was an actor once
It was Nie who made Zhang a star
Get real, you guys!
No one needs to repay a favor
with the rest of his life!
Who are you then?
Someone who has forgotten her love for me?
"I hate you..."
The check, please!
Hey!
Can I take a shower at your place?
...spectacular
The world out there is so forlorn
While you're enjoying the world out there
I'll be here wishing you the best
Sorry, I took your carton of instant noodles... -
Monkey
Miss Sun
It's been a long time!
Oh, you are...?
Don't you remember?
Back then when you were a showgirl in Sanlitun
I saw your performance!
Your troupe leader Song was my buddy
You're mistaken
I've never been to Sanlitun
Hsian Ping, you're an assistant director now!
You gonna be a director next
You make it sound like a curse!
Jian-dong, my handsome man
Hsian Ping can make you a star!
Damn right!
Let's make a toast to our future
big shot director!
Stop jinxing me! Just drink up!
I could hardly recognize you
You come here often?
No
A classmate of mine got hired
as an assistant director
We came here to celebrate
So you're in film school
Yep
Is it fun to make movies?
Hey, what's your real name?
Call me Monkey!
My last name is Sun
same as the mythical Monkey King
- And you've come to Beijing to...
- Sing!
Who's going to be my audience in the village?
And you? An aspiring actor?
An aspiring director!
So "Hongkonger", I still owe you noodles
We'll meet again for sure!
Embarrassing, wasn't it?
You don't recognize the guy
but you do know the song, right?
I'd like to take a rest if you don't mind
You were so cute in those days
We've never met
Never
Knock it off!
You're driving too slow!
I'm sorry, ma'am!
So who was this girl I met ten years ago?
A ghost?
Whatever
Who you thought you met never existed
Ghost or not...
You know what scares me most?
...is that she never loved me
Then I've been a fool for ten years
Stop the car!
Miss Sun!
Lin Jian-dong!
I looked for you in the dorm
But they said you've moved out
When did you come back?!
Just now! And I came for you right away!
I'm going back to Hong Kong next week
You've graduated?
Nah... I...
I'm dropping out
What about directing?
I don't have the talent... I can't pretend
How do you know you don't have talent?
Do you have to raise your voice?
I mean, it's not like
you've made a few films already
How do you know you aren't talented?
Didn't you quit already?
What are the books for?
For the library! And I'll submit my resignation!
Hey!
Monkey, I'm not like you... invincible!
I do fall apart sometimes, you just don't see it!
There's no fun if everything comes easy
I blew all my money on the shoot...
even next term's tuition fee
Just come stay with me!
I'm getting by! I can take care of you!
It's your turn to owe me something
The troupe is disbanded
No way!
Such is life!
Nothing is certain! I might be a movie star
the next time you bump into me!
You want to be an actress?
A pub, at most, can only fit 100 people
But a single theatre can fit a few hundred!
Who would not want to be a movie star?
C'mon in!
Watch your head!
This ceiling is fine for me as long as
I don't grow taller
I'm stocked up with goods here
and that means extra income
If you tidy up the place sometimes
that would pay your rent
An art director is still a director, I suppose
Still, I'm a bit disappointed
I was counting on you to make me a star
once you become "the director"
I was kidding!
If you're determined to be a star
You can make it
You think so?
Because you're invincible
Quite true
Let's drink to that!
Good!
We'll drink to that!
A long, long time ago
You belonged to me; I belonged to you
You left me to explore the world out there
The world out there is so spectacular
The world out there is so forlorn
While you're enjoying the world out there
I'll be here wishing you the best
A long, long time ago
You left me to explore the world out there
The world out there is so spectacular
Zhang Yang reunites with Xiao-yu in the circus
Bad news: She's become amnesiac!
And worse...
The circus master has already won her over...
...by providing her beautiful stories of her past
Once upon a time, he had a love story
Days of romance and youth
A sweet story to tell
Xiao-yu... that was your name!
We grew up together
Once upon a time
they were childhood sweethearts
His charm, her affection...
...inspiring envy
Then one day the girl lost her memory
A beginning hard to forget
An ending hard to remember
Enough! I'm happy as I am!
A loss so tragic, where truth lies
Not knowing, a blessing in disguise
The boy with a beautiful memory
The girl without a past, a mystery
Monkey
Are you happy?
What's your trick?
How can you always remain happy?
Do you remember?
I used to hold you just like this
Once upon a time, he had a sad story
Without a happy ending he won't surrender
Passion burns to shine, a brief history
Irony of fate, why hold onto misery?
Forget this love story come what may
Why not drink and dream your sorrows away?
Remembering changes nothing anyway
Will knowing the past begin a new day?
Once upon a time, I had a love story
I wonder, was it real...
...or fantasy?
Cut
Cut!
That's it for today!
- Mr. Nie...
- We'll continue tomorrow
We still haven't got the circus master...
who do we shoot with tomorrow?
I'll be the circus master!
Mr. Nie
Hot and sour noodles
Thanks
Remember your first movie?
It was shot right here!
You came here for my noodles everyday!
You gulped it down fast every time
Yes!
I was always hungry in those days
What happens to my appetite now?
You used to say, the sooner you finish a film...
...the faster you prove yourself a good director
Am I still a good director?
Stay asleep, in the dream within a dream
From this day on, no more doubts
All I'm asking is a word from your heart
Say you loved me... all along
That will be all, just say no more
Because... you do love me
Perhaps... you do love me
I'm enjoying this more and more!
I had a long chat with Zhang Ji this afternoon
For old times' sake
He promised to ditch the other deal
to do the role of the circus master
It's too tiring for you to direct and act as well!
What is it?
Am I not big enough?
With Zhang, you can recoup a couple
more millions in European sales
Why bother being an actor?
Zhang taught you that?
You taught me that
Would you care so much about me
if I hadn't made you a star?
If my film sucks...
- Will anyone care about me?
- Nie Wen!
Enough!
I'm not your child!
"Nie Wen", "Nie Wen"...Iong before you
became Sun Na, I'd already made Nie Wen!
When is the shoot? Can I visit?
Deal! It's the day after tomorrow!
Is the film going to be shown in America?
Yes, of course!
The American producer also said...
...don't know if he's serious though...
...that he'll marry me
A paper marriage! Otherwise
who would marry a fifty-year-old?!
He's probably teasing me
He knows I want to go to America
Is that what you want?
Of course! All film people dream
of going to Hollywood!
Who's going to watch the films made here?
He also said that I'm petite...
only a head shorter than average...
But in America, I'd be three heads shorter!
That would make me very special!
And much easier to visit you in Hong Kong
with an American passport!
Don't look...
It's a wonderful world out there
If I go out, how will I fare?
The world out there has so much to share
I can be free if only I dare
I can't see the present in my despair
Out there I'll see what my future will bear
The choice is not easy, I just can't compare
Blow out a candle
make a wish with this breath of air
It's a wonderful world out there
I'll find love and someone to care
Out there where there're chances to spare
I'll learn who I am, in the world so rare
Neither of us is going anywhere...
You aren't going to America
I'm not returning to Hong Kong
Where's the director?
Nobody's coming; just you and me