Hey, Frosty!
Hey, Rudolph!
What a great June day!
Positively balmy.
Only 10 below.
Rudolph, can the kids watch
your jumping practice?
Sure.
Millie. Chilly.
- Okay. Daddy.
- Here we come.
Would you light up your nose for us.
Uncle Rudolph?
Just once. Please?
Okay. Just once.
- Rudolph.
- What's the matter with your nose?
I-- I don't know.
It-- it's going out.
Yes, sir. Believe it or not,
Rudolph's nose went out.
And all because of something
that started years and years ago.
And I mean years.
Long before I came to the North Pole,
all this territory was ruled over...
...by a powerful magic king
of the North Pole named...
...Winterbolt.
And this terrible tyrant's powers
came from a scepter of solid ice.
All the good creatures
who dared defy his wickedness...
...were destroyed or driven away
from their Northland homes.
Old Winterbolt's tyranny lasted for ages.
But one day...
...there came a being
who was more than his match.
Lady Boreal, the queen
of the northern lights...
...who took on human form
in order to defy Winterbolt...
...and defend the oppressed and innocent.
King Winterbolt.
For years I have seen
your malevolent cruelty.
And now I take human form
to command thee...
...stop this tyranny at once!
You've caused enough pain
and unhappiness.
You don't frighten me. Begone.
You had your chance,
cruel monarch of the North...
...and now I must silence you.
- Forever?
- Alas, nothing is forever.
But you will fall into a deep, deep, sleep.
And so you shall remain,
so long as my magic burns bright.
Too powerful for me.
Your force overwhelms me.
And he fell into a profound sleep...
...of many, many winters.
And eventually, Winterbolt
and all his evil were forgotten.
The good and gentle creatures
returned to the North.
First, the animals...
...and then the little ones,
the Kringle elves.
And I suppose it was
Lady Boreal's good grace...
...which led me and my young bride
to these Northlands.
The perfect place for me
to build my toy factory...
...and carry out my life's mission,
far away from all who would stop me.
The passing years were good to all of us.
But Lady Boreal's monumental efforts
had drained her of most of her magic...
...and all of her strength.
She knew her days as a human
were numbered.
Alas, nothing is forever.
But in Santa, the Northlands
have a kind and true leader.
And I may rest with ease.
And she became again the magic glow
of the aurora borealis.
I am awake, I live again!
Winterbolt lives!
I can't wait to see what's been going on
while I've been resting.
Who is this my magic eye of snow shows?
He looks to be a king.
But there can be no king
of the North, save me.
I must rid my Northlands
of this ho-ho-ho'ing creature...
...and his flock of Christmas interlopers.
But how?
Tell me, O Genie of the Ice Scepter.
His power comes from
the love he receives...
...from children all over the world.
Is he as powerful as me?
At the moment, far more powerful.
Then I shall make the world's children
love me instead of him.
Tell me, how does he please
these children?
Each Christmas Eve,
he sets forth in his sleigh...
...and leaves every child a toy
before dawn.
Is that all?
Genie, tell me how I might stop him
from going forth.
Next Christmas Eve...
...have the snow dragons
create a storm of ice and fog...
...the likes of which
the North has never seen.
Santa will become hopelessly lost...
...and the toys will never be delivered.
Bravo. Excellent!
Then I shall set forth
with my own supply of toys...
...in my own sleigh.
Why. I could be greater than Santa!
I'd give the little brats
twice as many toys...
...and they would love me more.
They'd become lazy
and dependent on me...
...and I would rule them all.
And when they grew up,
why, the whole world...
...would be my own personal snowball!
How little Winterbolt knows
of the ways of Santa and children.
There's more than just getting toys.
There is kindness...
...and the loving warmth
of a family on Christmas morn.
These things cannot die.
I will not let them.
But I am so old and weak.
Ice and fog on Christmas Eve
to hinder Santa's sleigh.
I must leave him something...
...small. I fear, to guide him on his way.
And a little later that day...
...a tiny reindeer was born.
Have no fear, my little one.
Soon your father will be home.
And I must rest for the moment.
Little one...
...I have so little magic left
to leave thee.
Use it wisely and well.
On this small hoof, a magic mark I make.
The Christmas star, cradled by a snowflake.
And with this secret mark...
...the magic of the northern lights
lives in thee.
How, you ask?
Think good thoughts and you will see.
Will the magic last forever, you wonder?
Nothing is forever,
as I have often said.
But this magic is strong...
...and your nose will glow,
so long as you use it for good.
If you are tempted, even once,
to use it for an evil purpose...
...it will be extinguished forever.
Do you understand?
And will you never use it for evil?
And now I leave you, little babe,
to your mother's love.
Use your secret magic well.
What was that? Was someone here?
Can't you make up your mind,
my little one?
Hey! Where's my boy?
Here, my darling.
Flew 300 miles in only 15 leaps
when I heard the news and...
Will you just look at him.
My little buck.
We'll name him...
...Rudolph!
O eye of snow, what's this you show?
A red-nosed reindeer?
So that's how Santa defeated
my snow dragons.
It will be a different story
next Christmas Eve.
A red-nosed reindeer is no match
for King Winterbolt!
Hey, it's really going out.
What's happening. Uncle Rudolph?
What's wrong with your nose?
Dimmer, darker, darker, dimmer
Rudolph's magic shall not glimmer
Dark and dim
Dim and dark
Now extinguish magic spark!
Rudolph!
It's all over. Frosty.
My nose is going.
I feel awful.
Rudolph, your nose just can't go out.
Santa depends on it.
Yeah, but--
There's kids all over the world...
...who'd never get any Christmas presents
if you didn't light the way.
You're right, Frosty.
I can't lose my nose.
Unless... Unless...
What are you trying to say?
Can't remember exactly.
Something a pretty lady
once whispered to me.
I-- I don't know.
But my nose just can't go out!
Don't worry.
I'm okay now.
Good old Uncle Rudolph.
It's impossible that his power
is greater than mine.
There must be a reason.
He has the wonder of the aurora borealis
within him.
A power far greater than thine.
So long as he uses the nose for good...
...it can never go out.
Then I shall see that he uses it for evil.
Not in these northern lands, O master.
The memory of Lady Boreal
still glows here...
...and protects him.
He must be made to leave the North Pole.
He sets forth but once a year.
Christmas Eve.
I cannot wait! There must be a way
to make him leave now!
Help me, O Genie of the Ice Scepter.
Look into thy magic eye of snow.
There you will find the answer.
What's this? A balloon?
How can a hot-air balloon
help me lure Rudolph away?
I wonder...
Rudolph! Hey, Rudolph!
- Hey, it's Milton!
- Who?
The flying ice cream man.
He keeps his stock up here,
where it won't melt.
And this time every year, he picks up
a load to take to the seashore...
...for the Fourth of July weekend.
Wait till you meet him. A million laughs!
Come on.
Frosty! Millie! Chilly!
Dinner's ready, sweethearts.
Sorry. Crystal. I gotta meet somebody.
Rudolph says he's a million laughs.
But I've got dinner on the table.
It'll get all warm.
You can always cool it up
in the ice stove.
Come on. A million laughs!
- Come on, come on!
- How you doing. Milton?
- Awful!
- What's wrong. Milton?
- I'm in love.
With who?
You're in love with a whole circus?
I'd call a guy like that fickle.
No.
Just with her.
Laine Loraine.
Her mother owns the circus.
We were gonna be married,
right on the high wire.
Hired a preacher and a net
and everything.
Well, what happened?
Oh, the circus is going broke.
And another showman,
a crook named Sam Spangles...
...is ready to pay off the back taxes
and take over the show.
Okay, tack it up over here.
So you see...
...Laine can't even think about romance.
And if her mom's show doesn't
get a big audience on the Fourth...
...it'll be sold to Sam Spangles on July 6th.
Laine will have to go on the road.
And we'll never get together.
What luck!
Thank you, eye of snow.
Rudolph will never suspect a thing.
First, however...
...I shall put a little idea
into Milton's empty head.
I don't know what to do.
Hey! I just got a great idea!
There's only one guy who could draw
the kind of crowds...
...the Circus by the Sea needs.
- And that's you, Rudolph!
- Me?
Why, the kids would just pack that tent
to see you and your nose in person.
Uncle Rudolph in the circus?
Hey, wait a minute.
Rudolph, you just gotta go.
Well, if you say so, pal.
Okay.
It would be wonderful
if we could go with him. Frosty.
I sure would like the twins
to see a real circus.
If you'd appear too, Frosty,
we'd have to get a bigger tent!
- Oh, Daddy.
- Can we?
- Please?
- We'd be good!
No way!
The seashore on the Fourth of July?
We'd be real misfits.
We'd melt in 10 seconds flat!
Being snowpeople has its drawbacks.
Sometimes I feel like a real misfit.
Oh, Frosty, I just forgot for a minute.
I'm sorry. Why. I wouldn't have us
any other way.
That melting business is a nuisance,
but it doesn't make you all misfits. Frosty.
Take it from another misfit.
If only there was some way
to make you unmeltable.
Like a fairy godfather.
Just say I'm an old, old, magical friend...
...who wishes to help.
Children should see a circus
at least once in their lives.
So I will help.
But what can you do, sir, to stop
Frosty and his family from melting?
Observe.
Magic amulets.
If Frosty. Crystal. Millie and Chilly...
...wear them about their necks.,
they cannot melt.
Even though the temperature
be hot enough to melt steel...
...still they will remain cool and icy.
Our troubles are over forever!
No, not forever.
See? On each is a design.
The letter F four times entwined.
Yeah. “F, F, F, F.“
What's that stand for?
That means the amulet's magic only lasts...
...until the final firework fades
on the Fourth.
You must return here
before the fireworks finish...
...or you will melt in the heat
of the summer eve.
But until then?
Why, you will be safe.
- The circus!
He certainly does blow in and blow out.
Well, I'm delighted you're all going
for a summer holiday...
...but I never heard of any
icy fairy godfather.
You should have seen him, sir.
I wish I had.
Who could he be?
Well, I guess I'm just being
over-cautious.
You all go on and have a wonderful time.
- Just one thing.
- What's wrong. Frosty?
It's too bad the kids have to miss
the Fourth of July fireworks.
But half a vacation's better
than none. I guess.
No, you're right.
Children should see fireworks.
Let me think.
And now to entwine them
just a bit more...
...into a morass from which
they will never escape.
Hey, I just got a wonderful idea!
Mama and I will fly my sleigh down
for the Fourth.
We'll pick up Frosty and family
just before the fireworks finish...
...and whisk back up to the North Pole...
...by the time the last one fades.
- Wonderful.
- What a neat idea.
I can't believe it!
Rudolph. Frosty and now Santa.
Why, this-- This really will be the greatest
show in the-- In the universe!
It will!
???
Oh, Frosty, it's lovely.
- Oh, look over there.
- It's the circus!
Yep. They're starting to set up
their tents.
Come on, you guys,
let's get this tent up!
Oh, Mama, look, it's Milton.
Hi, Laine. Hi, Ms. Loraine.
Oh, Mama, isn't he wonderful?
He's the greatest ice cream man
in the world.
Oh, forget him, honey.
There's one thing life's taught me:
You can't live on banana splits.
Laine, look who I've got for the show!
Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer
and Frosty the Snowman!
- In person.
Well, I'll be...
Oh, Mama, we'll be a hit!
- What do you think of Milton now?
- Maybe I was wrong.
Milton's like the butter pecan he sells:
A little nuts but mighty yummy!
Oh, Milton.
Oh, Laine. Now everything
will turn out all right.
Rudolph and Frosty? I can't believe it.
And Santa Claus too.
Santa too? What an idea for a closing act.
Print more tickets!
Why, it's just like Christmas
is coming early this year.
Oh, Milton.
Everything is just perfect now.
Now we got something to work for.
Come on with that tent.
Heave ho-ho-ho! Heave ho-ho-ho!
What's with the “ho-ho-ho“?
Well, it is Christmas, isn't it?
And I suppose they believe...
...everyone will live happily ever after.
Never!
And now for the snow dragons.
Make yourselves ready, my pretties.
Build fury in your hearts.
Soon I will have
a very special job for you.
What is thy will, O master?
Genie of the Ice Scepter...
...find me a reindeer as mean
as Rudolph is kind.
As cunning as Rudolph is guileless.
As selfish as Rudolph is giving.
A corrupt, cunning knave of a creature...
...with ambition to equal my own.
But why, O master?
All part of my plan, good genie.
All part of my plan.
Find me such a reindeer!
Beyond the Forest
of the Burned Christmas Trees...
...and the Hill of the Broken Baubles...
...there you will find
the Caves of Lost Rejections.
Ask the keeper for...
He's in cave number 13.
I wish to see him.
You ain't the only one.
I've been trying to throw him out
all week.
Behind in his rent, he is.
But he's mean
and I don't fancy risking my neck.
Thirteen, you say?
That's right this way.
Scratcher!
- What do you want?
- Come forth.
- Make me.
- Very well.
Hey! What's happening?
All right, all right.
For crying out loud.
I'll pay the rent.
I don't want the rent.
I want Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer.
And you will help me.
Rudolph? Don't mention that name.
I was all set to be one of Santa's reindeer,
when he came along.
Indeed. Santa fired you
to make room for Rudolph?
Well, I also stole some toys and ate
a whole new batch of candy canes.
Candy? Excellent!
It was all downhill from there.
Till I finally ended up in this joint.
Good.
- How would you like to work for me?
- Doing what?
Destroying Rudolph
the Red-Nosed Reindeer.
Sounds like a good job to me.
What do I gotta do?
Oh, nothing much.
Spend a few luxurious days at the seashore.
Get to know Rudolph.
Lead him astray, as it were.
Gee, it sounds like a pretty good idea.
Now, go at once.
And find a man named Sam Spangles.
And then...
Well, Ms. Loraine,
we're finally ready to open.
We worked night and day, kid,
but we made it.
Boy, running a circus is no easy job.
Well, I tell you, Blinky,
it's got its ups and its downs.
Life with the circus is like
life with a guy.
Sometimes you're low
and sometimes you're high.
Now, have you memorized
your instructions?
Don't worry. Me and Sam Spangles
will take care of everything.
Good. Here, nibble on these.
These are Santa's magic feed corn.
Hey, that means I'll be able to fly,
like Donner and Blitzen...
...and all those other goody-goods.
Now, fly forth and do my bidding.
What's the hurry?
Soon my pets here will blow up
the worst snowstorm of the century.
Well, what if I get lost?
I mean, I don't have a red nose,
you know.
You'll be well out of these parts
before the storm hits.
- I think--
- Will you go forth forthwith?
Oh, soon. Soon., my little pets.
We mustn't be hasty.
Timing is everything
if my intricate plan is to succeed.
You really are looking forward to this trip,
aren't you?
Papa. I haven't had
a summer vacation since...
Can't remember when.
We work too hard, Mama.
Oh, though I guess I'm not the easiest man
in the world to live with, though.
Well, only when it gets close
to Christmas Eve.
We have had lots and lots
of Christmas Eves. Mama.
- They were good times. Papa.
- And I still love you...
...just as much
as the first day I saw you.
Instead of talking, you gave me
a lovely china doll.
Well...
...giving toys is my way
of saying hello.
And showing my love.
I know that. Papa.
Mama.
Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
11:00, Papa.
The circus parade's at 12.
Hurry or we'll miss it.
Yes, hurry.
Go on, laugh, you old fools...
...while you may.
Thank you, little Kringles.
We'll be back, late tonight.
Don't wait up.
Away!
And away, ho!
Use fog to blind and snow to bury
Wind to tear the heart that's merry
Ice and gale and sleet and hale
Santa must, in his mission, fail
Oh, that's an angry wind
for this time of year.
Yes, I don't like it at all.
Papa! Look!
My goodness, no!
We've got to get back!
Back. Dasher!
Dancer! Comet!
It's too late, Papa, it's got us.
Hold on. Mama!
If only Rudolph were here!
Well, we're safe here
in the storm's eye, Mama.
But I'm afraid it's only for a little while.
Papa, do you think we'll ever get out?
Well, storms are strange things, dear.
- I mean...
- Are you frightened...
...of what may happen?
No., my dear, not at all.
Even with this storm.
Papa.
We've gotten out of worse
situations than this.
Yes.
I say the best thing to do...
...would be to get down from these
stormy skies and continue on the ground.
All right, Mama, we'll try it.
Hang on.
Smile. Frosty.
Lilly says that in show business.,
you've gotta keep smiling.
But I'm kind of worried
that Santa won't be here on time.
- Daddy, the show must go on.
- That's what Aunt Lilly says.
Okay. But I got a feeling tonight
there's gonna be a real wet act.
And it won't be the seals.
Are you Sam Spangles, the circus man?
How can I be a circus man
without a circus?
I think I might have
an interesting proposition.
Just do your act like you did in rehearsal,
Blinky, and we're bound to be a hit.
I'll try. Ms. Loraine. I sure will try.
Well, I gotta give a pep talk
to the clowns.
Hang in there, Blinky.
Hey, Rudolph.
- Scratcher?
- Oh, the big star remembers his old buddy.
- We were never buddies.
- Let bygones be bygones.
- What's the matter?
- Boy. I am really down and out.
Haven't had a bite to eat in three days.
Think you could get me a job
with the show?
I guess we could use another roustabout
to help with the tents.
You're a prince, Rudolph, a prince.
I'll speak to Ms. Loraine.
Yeah, you do that, Rudolph.
You just do that.
Sucker.
Perfect. Perfect.
Everything going according to schedule.
Now to tighten the net.
What a magnificent sleigh and team
the snow genie has created for me.
Instead of reindeer...
...I have rein-snakes.
To the top of the porch
To the top of the wall
Now slink away, slink away
Slink away, all
Onward! Onward!
Ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to the new edition
of Lilly Loraine's Circus by the Sea.
Bring on the clowns.
Boy, this is a great job
you got me. Rudolph.
Well, just do it well and I'm sure
you'll get a promotion.
I ain't complaining, old buddy.
Oh, you know, Mrs. Loraine wants me
to get something out of the office wagon...
...but it's all dark in there.
I think a fuse blew.
Will you come with me
and give me some light?
But I've gotta do my act.
Oh, it won't take a minute.
Let me finish hauling this thing
and I'll meet you over by the wagon.
Well, okay.
Oh, you really are a buddy, old buddy.
This is hard.
Oh, it...
It's so late. Mama.
Poor Frosty.
We're doing everything we can. Papa.
Look up there, Mama.
Black as pitch.
Not a star in the sky.
Onward! Onward! We don't want
to miss the fireworks, do we?
I forgot my parasol.
How many times I gotta tell you?
Make notes for yourself.
Yes, Mama.
And now...
...presenting one of our star attractions...
...Frosty the Snowman and family...
...in a sensational, spellbinding exhibition...
...of world championship belly-whopping.
Now meet the folks.
Like I always say:
The family that slides together,
abides together.
You don't always say that. Frosty.
Stick to the script, Daddy.
If Santa don't get here soon,
we'll be sticking to everything.
Come on!
Hey, I've been waiting for you
over by the office wagon.
Come on. Rudolph.
That's my warning cue.
Look, as soon as I'm done,
I'll meet you by the wagon, I promise.
That's my buddy.
Lights, please.
Bring out the fog machine, boys.
- Are you ready. Rudolph?
- I am ready.
Then lights on. Rudolph.
Lights on.
He's burned off the fog.
Let's hear it for Rudolph!
He'll be back, folks.
He'll be back.
His act is over. Quick!
Here's the rest of the disguise.
Just think.
Me., Sam Spangles, a policeman.
Here he comes. Hide.
Good old buddy. Now, turn it on.
She said it's under the table here.
- What are you looking for?
- She said it was a little leather suitcase.
Oh, there it is.
Gee, thanks, old buddy.
I hurt myself.
Just taking a little fall like that?
I twisted my nose...
My neck or something.
Now I can't pick up that suitcase.
Buddy, would you do it for me?
Well, sure.
All this fuss over a little suitcase.
- What's inside?
- Well, she didn't say.
Just pick it up and give it to the cop
waiting on the corner.
Okay, but...
Hey, this bag is filled with money.
The night's receipts.
That's why she wants
to give it to the cop.
So he can take it to the bank
and make a night deposit.
Well, okay.
And now for our grand
Christmas in July finale.
Whether July or December.
Christmas lives in our hearts.
But it's up at the North Pole, remember,
where Christmas always starts.
Where are my elves?
Oh, hark!
Here they come now.
Elephants? I thought the midgets
were gonna play the elves.
No, they wanna play the polar bears.
Actors.
Very good, elves.
But I have an idea...
...of what will bring all of us
lots of cheer.
So just to please all the girls
and the boys...
...why don't we have a parade
of the toys.
And now, to make us all feel jolly,
my very best toy:
A dancing dolly.
Thank you, me fine lad.
Well, off to the bank.
- Where were you, Rudolph?
- Frosty, something funny is going on.
I don't think it's so funny.
I'm just about ready to give up hope.
Oh, I don't mean that.
Here's your star.
Frosty. Santa gave his word.
He'll be here before the fireworks are over.
I don't know.
You ever see a policeman
wearing a helmet?
No. But then. I never looked for one either.
Sure I'm not too heavy?
No, but you're kind of chilly.
Well, that's the show, folks.
A little corny, but expensive.
Be sure and hang around outside
for a free Fourth of July fireworks display.
And come back again next year!
You hear that. Rudolph?
Time for the fireworks.
I heard. Frosty.
I just don't understand.
And all that business with Scratcher.
Something's real wrong here.
- Come on. Daddy. Uncle Rudolph.
- Don't wanna miss the fireworks.
Miss them? I'd like to stop them.
Why do you want to stop them. Daddy?
Aren't you patriotic?
Sure. I'm patriotic.
My only regret is I only have
but one life to melt for my country.
Wait a minute, Frosty.
What you just said--
Maybe we can stop the fireworks.
Yeah. Let's find out
who's setting them off.
You go this way. I'll go that.
Mrs. Loraine, you've gotta help me.
Anything. Frosty. You just name it.
- Stop the fireworks.
- You named the wrong one.
I can't stop them.
Once the main fuse is lit,
they keep going.
Even if a cloudburst poured down
on top of them.
- Why do you want them stopped?
- Well, I got a funny kind of feeling.
- About fireworks?
- No, about melting.
- How many are there?
- Exactly 100.
That's number three.
I'm counting. I'm counting!
- Which one's number 100?
- Right over there.
That's my number, all right.
And when my number goes up,
my number is up.
And where's Santa?
Still no sign of it letting up. Mama.
I'm afraid we're gonna be too late
to save Frosty.
It's not your fault. Papa.
All we can do is keep going.
Faster!
That's number 72.
Daddy, why are you so worried
about the pretty fireworks?
Children, you must be very brave.
Gee, why'd I get everybody
into this mess?
Seventy-four.
We promise to be brave, Mommy.
I'm very proud of you.
Seventy-five.
Oh, Frosty.
There, there., honey.
I just want you to know
that I'm sure glad I married you.
I am too, love.
Seventy-six.
Boy. I remember when I could
only count to four.
The good old days.
Now to go down and put out
Rudolph's light for good.
Hey! We've been robbed!
I went to get the money to give
to Officer Kelly here and it's gone!
He's the policeman
it was supposed to go to?
Well, yeah. Why?
Didn't you send Scratcher to fetch it?
Me? Let a roustabout reindeer
handle the loot?
I ain't that daffy!
Hey! What do you know
about this. Blinky?
Ninety-one.
Daddy, Mommy, look! It's Santa!
Frosty, it's a sleigh!
Oh, boy!
Wait a minute.
It's a sleigh, all right...
...but it's not Santa.
Oh, how I've waited for this moment.
Ninety-three.
Sir? Sir?
My name is Winterbolt.
King Winterbolt.
A king? Gee!
Your-- Your Majesty.
Santa never showed up.
Yes, I know.
- Frosty's time is almost over.
- Just seven more fireworks.
Correction: Six.
That was number 94.
You've just got to make those amulets
last a little longer.
Maybe even a lot longer.
Of course. Of course, my dear friends.
You hear that. Frosty?
Wait till I tell the wife and the kids!
One moment!
Ninety-five.
We don't have to bother
keeping count anymore.
- Oh, yes, you do.
- What do you mean?
I will make the amulets' power last.
Rudolph...
...only so long as your nose
remains extinguished.
My nose is not extinguished.
Really? Try to light it.
Ninety-six.
Go ahead. Rudolph.
I'm trying.
I'm trying real hard.
Rudolph! What's wrong?
It-- It won't light up.
What did you do to it, Winterbolt?
I didn't do a thing.
You did it to yourself.
You used your nose for an evil purpose.
You robbed the money
from the box office wagon...
...and gave it to one Sam Spangles.
Sorry, sucker.
- I don't understand.
- They tricked me. Frosty.
Well, I'm gonna set things straight.
I'll tell everybody what really happened.
No, you won't.
I warn you, if you clear your name
to save your nose...
...the Frostys all will melt.
Admit your guilt and I will allow them
to remain frozen.
Ninety-seven.
Ninety-eight. Only two more.
What do you say. Rudolph?
Okay. I won't tell anybody the truth.
I'll take the blame
and let my nose go out.
Ninety-nine.
But you just can't let your nose
go out forever. Rudolph.
I don't have any choice. Frosty.
Come on.
We only have one firework left.
Only one more. Where is Frosty?
Hey, what's going on here?
Ms. Loraine. I--
I stole that money.
- What?!
- Uncle Rudolph?
I don't believe it.
No, he-- I mean, I can explain.
No, Frosty, don't!
I stole the money, ma'am,
and I gave it to Sam Spangles.
Spangles? That means
he takes over the show.
Rudolph, what got into you?
I can't explain.
One hundred!
Oh, Frosty!
Relax. Crystal.
We aren't gonna melt. See?
Why-- Why, you're right.
Mommy, we're saved!
Oh, Daddy, we're not gonna melt.
Congratulations.
Now you don't have to worry.
I'm sorry, Rudolph,
but I don't want the twins...
“associating with a dishonest reindeer.
- Uncle Rudolph...
- Why'd you do it?
No, wait. You don't understand.
Frosty, you must never tell them
that I didn't do it.
- But. Rudolph--
- Never!
What's more important?
A silly old red nose...
...or the lives of my best friend
and his family?
Rudolph, what can I say?
You sure are a friend.
Hey. That funny little mark
on your hoof...
...the star inside the snowflake.
It's gone!
Yes, I know.
Thanks to Winterbolt, we've done it!
Come. You're the number one reindeer
of the North now.
You bet.
Away! Away!
So long.
Okay, creeps. There's gonna be
some changes around here.
- You don't own the show yet.
- Wanna bet?
Who's gonna pay to see:
Rudolph the unlit reindeer
With the very nothing nose
I can't wait till tomorrow night!
I'm sorry.
But I can still do my jumps.
We want our money back!
Rudolph?
How can you even speak to him,
after what he did to my mother?
But there must be some reason.
We're old friends.
You can tell me. Rudolph.
There's nothing to tell.
I stole the money and gave it
to Sam Spangles.
- But. Rudolph--
- Just-- Just let me be. Milton.
You heard him. Let's go, Milton.
Goodbye. Rudolph.
Goodbye...
...for good.
There must be something I can do alone
that wouldn't hurt the family.
Maybe I could give Winterbolt
something in exchange.
But what do I have that he'd want?
What, indeed? His corncob pipe?
He does have something.
I don't know.
He might have something.
Why not ask the genie.
Frosty the Snowman
has his own magic...
...which could prove quite valuable.
Really? Tell me, what is it?
His hat.
Let me show you, O master.
Just think...
...if you had that hat and could
find the secret of its magic...
...you could duplicate it over
and over again, O master.
Why, you could bring an army
of snowmen to life.
And Frosty, the only one who knows...
...the true secret of Rudolph's nose...
...would be lifeless.
Yes, and I would be safe.
But what could I give Frosty for his hat?
Lie to him, my master.
Deceive him.
Tell him you have the power to restore...
...the borealis light to Rudolph's nose.
The light.
Of course, of course!
Gee, I'd do anything,
anything to help Rudolph.
I know what to do.
Faster! Faster! Back to the circus lot!
More fireworks?
Rudolph.
That voice. I remember.
I am no more.
But my love, in the form
of the northern lights...
...watches over thee.
What am I gonna do?
Have no fear,
when you defend the helpless.
I don't understand.
Be brave.
Be very brave...
...and the starin the snowflake
will return.
You mean there's a chance
my nose will light up again?
Be brave.
Be very brave.
No! Don't go!
Alone again.
Rudolph, is that you up there
on the beach?
- What now?
- Out here, in the water.
Big Ben, the clockwork whale.
Remember me? I work for Father Time.
Sure, I remember.
What are you doing here?
Strangest thing. Like I was led to you.
I was under the water, following
the glow of the northern lights.
Came up to get a good look
and there you were.
Oh, Ben, I've got problems.
Well, little fella, you tell them to me.
I got a big shoulder to rest your head on.
And it's wet already,
so a few tears won't hurt.
So you want to give me your hat?
Only if you can turn Rudolph's
nose back on.
Why, of course I can.
- What did you say?
- It's hardly worth it.
It is to me.
This hat is what keeps me all living.
- Without it--
- Oh, very well.
I'll make the trade.
Would you say goodbye to
Crystal., Millie and Chilly for me?
Especially Crystal.
Oh, Crystal. If only we could
be together one more time.
But that's impossible.
So I hope you'll remember
all the good times.
And that's the whole story, Big Ben.
Oh, that's terrible.
Rudolph, you gotta get your nose back.
I can't. If I tell the truth,
that means Frosty has to melt.
Not necessarily. No time to explain.
I gotta swim like thunder.
Where are you going?
To South America!
South America?
Now. Give me your hat!
What's going on here?
The poor frozen fool gave me his hat...
...when I promised to return your nose.
You know you can't do that.
Yes, I know. But he didn't.
Okay, Winterbolt. You asked for it.
You've got to catch me first!
Frosty?
Frosty? Frosty, where are you?
Oh, no!
No.
Don't look, children.
Come on out from there.
I know where you're hiding.
Come and get me.
Okay, I will!
Surprise!
You don't frighten me.
The hat is mine!
Try and get it.
Hey!
Oh, no. No! It's impossible!
It's like Lady Boreal said.
It's back for good.
I warn you! I warn you!
I will not be defeated!
Oh, Daddy.
But-- But can't he get
another hat, Mommy?
Children, remember him as he was.
Poor roly-poly little son of a gun.
All right, all you jerks. Clear out of here!
Show's mine now.
Not so fast!
Hey, you got your beak back.
That's not all we've got back.
Go ahead, officer.
Here's your money. Mrs. Loraine.
Rudolph was tricked into taking it.
He's innocent as a newborn babe.
Well, I'll be blasted.
One other thing.
Rudolph risked his life to get this back.
For you, sir.
Happy birthday.
- What are we celebrating?
- You!
Oh, good idea.
Here's your dough.
The circus is still mine.
- I'll be taking that.
- Why?
You won't be needing it in jail.
Oh, Rudolph, we're so sorry
for the way we acted.
What can we do to make it up?
It wasn't your fault.
Gee. Thanks. Rudolph.
Thank you, You gave everything
you had for me.
Well, didn't you give everything for me?
I mean, us misfits gotta stick together.
Put it there, pal.
Not so fast. I still have my scepter.
Destruction to you all!
This one looks like my job.
But, Mama, there are only blanks
in those guns.
Yeah, but the guns are made of iron.
No. No!
My-- My powers are gone!
When the scepter dies. I go too.
I turn, I turn, turn...
I turn...
...into a...
...tree.
What an exit!
Mama, the storm's gone!
Like a miracle.
Now we can be to the shore
in a few minutes.
Up! Up!
Dash away, all!
Well, our troubles are over.
Kind of dull, huh?
Well, I'm glad old Winterbolt's
powers are gone.
Me too.
- Hey, wait a minute!
- What is it, Blinky?
If all his powers are gone, that means
those amulets are no good either.
Frosty! Crystal!
Laine, what happened?
Well, the sun came out and they just--
Look!
Gee whiz!
After all we went through.
I should have realized, it's too late now.
When Frosty melts, nothing can help...
...except a magic December wind
to unmelt him.
And this is July!
Yeah. Well, where we gonna find
a Christmas wind in July?
Right here!
And I brought Jack Frost with me.
Hey, Rudolph!
How'd you do it, Ben?
Had to go all the way to South America.
That's where winter goes in July.
Jack Frost...
...do your stuff!
I've got to aim real carefully...
...or I'll give colds to all the kids
on the beach.
Well, here goes.
- Happy birthday!
Come on, gang. Let's dig them out.
Keep that cold breath on them. Jack.
Look!
Great jumping geraniums!
Santa Claus is finally coming to town!
Papa, we'd better get going
before Jack runs out of breath.
I'll stick with the show, sir,
until they're out of debt.
They should be out of debt real soon.
I gave Lilly some of my magic corn feed.
The kind that makes animals fly.
A circus by the sea is one thing,
but a flying circus by the sea...
- Daddy. Daddy! Can we stay and see it?
Oh, Frosty, could they?
No deal. Enough's enough.
Then let's get going!
Away!
Gee. I kind of miss not being with Santa.
Blinky, you wanna lead something
through the sky, you got it!
- What?
- Forget the sleigh!
It's time for the flying circus parade.
With you right up front.
Okay!
[ENGLISH]