Don't stop moving
To the funky, funky beat
To the S Club beat
Oh, good
Welcome to Eagle Peak!
S Club S Club S Club
S Club S Club
We got the record company first
We're gonna pick up some gold discs
Then we've got radio-station
interviews for the album promotion
press conference, then a photo
session for tomorrow's front page
And then finally, we have the gig
Last day of the tour
Thank you, Barcelona
Good night
Thank you very much
We'll see you next year!
You were brilliant tonight Brilliant
You, you, you All of you
Barcelona loves you
You are the real tortillas
You're right
We were pretty good
Water won't cut it now,
I'm gonna need plasma
Well done, guys
That was it, the last gig of our tour
So, Alistair, what are you
gonna do during our month off?
Because I'm going to the beach,
get a little tan
I'm gonna go back to London,
see my family
- go in the studio and chill out...
- Hold it Your what?
Our month off,
now that the tour's finished
A month, a week, a day
They all sound so similar, don't they?
- Alistair, you promised us
- You can't keep doing this to us
You promised us that month
Okay, okay Time off starts with a week
in LA, right after this press conference
- That's ridiculous
- What?
For the album It's a great album,
but you've got to promote it
Natalie, protein bars?
What are we gonna do?
- Why don't we fire him
- Who's gonna manage us, then?
Well, we could manage ourselves,
I suppose
And do loads of solo projects
that no one's gonna buy
And then you can marry
a footballer, Rach
And have loads of babies
with silly names
No, come on, guys
We've gotta stand up to him
Can't we do this in the morning?
No time Flight for Los Angeles leaves
at 7 am You can sleep on the plane
Come on Reporters are outside
Big smiles, energy,
eyes and teeth
Guys, look, I know it's tough, but
I promise you, it won't always be like this
One day, your records won't sell
The label will drop you
and even I won't return your calls
Ladies and gentlemen of the press,
S Club
S Club, do you feel that your exposure
to the West Coast hip-hop scene
will be felt musically
on your next album?
- Yes
- No
- What she said
How many of you girls
have had implants?
Me I had a cactus once,
but I watered it too much and it died
Do you see yourselves
as a manufactured band?
Do you see yourself
as a war correspondent?
What do you miss most
about being on the road?
- My dog
- Sunday roast
Tea with the queen Yeah
Bradley
Sorry, sorry, sorry What did you say?
I missed the question Sorry
Well, that wasn't so bad, now, was it?
We're having fun, aren't we?
A lot of people would love
to be in your shoes
Not in Jo's Her feet stink
- You all right?
- You said we was gonna have a holiday
Give me that
Get some sleep Up in three hours
" Up in three hours"
Alistair Beresford?
- That's me Have we met?
- Susan Sealove Enchantée
Enchanté
Bloody hell!
Right, that's it Nobody move
I've got a gun
Guys, why is it so dark in here?
What are you lot doing down there?
Am I dreaming?
What's this big, hard thing?
- Jon
- Get off!
- Oh, sorry
- What is going on?
Look at the time!
We've missed our flight!
Alistair's gonna kill us!
- He checked out?
- We have a dress code
- Okay, did he leave a message?
- No message No pijamas in the lobby
A forwarding address? Anything?
This
It's the bill
I don't understand this
It's really not like Alistair
Can you believe the bill
was 2000 Euros?
- Why didn't he wake us?
- We upset him He's paying us back
We gave him a hard time
We always give him a hard time
He knows it's in fun
Maybe it's his idea of a joke to leave us
here stranded with no money or tickets
Well, what's funny about that?
Oh, yeah, that is funny,
on some level
I mean, 10 years on from now
when we look back, I'll be saying:
"Jo, do you remember the time
when Alistair abandoned us
and we went down to the lobby
in our pijamas?"
It'll be hilarious Really funny
If this is a joke, then it's on him
because we just got what we wanted
A day off
Guys?
- Guess what I found
- Well done, you, Rach
- Yes!
- Come on
High-five
This has been one
of the best days of my life
- Paradise Heaven on earth
- I'm creamed and steamed
Go ahead, feel my skin
No charge
- lf only we had just one more day
- Well, we haven't heard from Alistair yet
I mean, why can't we just stay here
until we do?
Well, don't look at me
Bradley gave the room-service girl
a 60 percent tip
It's all right
I can stick it back together
with my nail glue
Hannah, it's at its limit
Come on, guys, cough up
All right, what have we got?
What have we got?
After all that, we've got 2 Euros left
I think we're in trouble
Well, we're gonna
have to go back on tour
Right, what we'll do is, exchange
our tickets and book a flight Okay?
So who's got the tickets to LA?
Oh, well, that's Natalie
Natalie takes care of the tickets
Okay, so who's got her number?
So we're stranded
- I'm starting to panic
- No, you're not
I can't quite breathe properly
I'm not getting oxygen to my brain
I tell you, I'm hallucinating
I can see us on TV
It's Happening Now live from
Los Angeles, California S Club
When did we tape this?
Hang on a minute,
does my bum really look that big?
Well it's not taped, it's live Look
But that's impossible Where it says,
" live," that can't mean it's live
It can't mean it's happening now
- Excuse me, what show is this?
- It's called It's Happening Now
S Club
- Jo, my favourite
- That is not Jo I'm Jo
Hey, guys Look, there's Alistair
Don't you see?
He's got fed up with us whining
and moaning all the time
so he hired look-alikes in LA
He's trying to teach us a lesson
Well, we're gonna teach him a lesson
because he's fired, and that is it
How could he do this to us?
Especially as I lent him
my fluffy monkey slippers
- That's it He's fired
- Can we fire him?
I mean, we signed a contract
Yeah, but has anyone
ever read the contract?
Apparently, Alistair can make us
weed his yard
If he needs a kidney transplant,
one of us has to be the donor
I said we should have got a proper
lawyer instead of your uncle Peter
He knows the legal system
better than any other lawyer
Your uncle's an ex- Con
Oh, come on, you lot This is serious
We've gotta find Alistair
before this thing gets out of hand
Come on, Jon, quick
Lower, lower, lower
Lower That's it
Come on, come on
That's it That's it
All right, all right, I got it
Ready
Hannah?
Well, I'm not taking a suitcase
I'll look far too suspicious
Let me handle this, yeah
Please, my hombre,
prepare our bill for checkout
- You pay the bill now?
- Yeah, just after we go for our short walk
- Walk?
- Cardiovascular
You know, she's gotta lose a few stone
Doctor's orders Right
- Better go
- See you Bye
Hello, can I help?
- Yes! I think we handled that pretty well
- It was a piece of cake
S Club, you don't pay the bill
- First the pijamas, now this
- We haven't done anything
Yeah, we're just walking
You know, for exercise
With those?
Weight-training Come on, guys,
pick it up Let's go
Feel the burn Oh, yeah
Yeah, do some squats
for me, please, Hannah
Arrest them
I'm really tired of this
I've had enough
We were gonna wire the money
to the hotel as soon as we got to America
- That's what Columbus said
- We haven't done anything wrong
- Been there, heard it
- Yeah, but we can explain
- Older than the oldest profession
- You're making a big mistake
Tell me something new
You can't arrest us
We're a famous band
If you let us go, I'll sign an autograph
and give you a copy of our new CD
That's what I was waiting to hear
You're the S Club? All of you?
- Yes
- Impersonating the S Club Fraud
- Impersonating?
- Anything else?
- We're not impersonators
- I've got the complaint right here
Signed by their manager,
Mr Beresford
Alistair?
Alistair? Alistair?
Open your eyes
- Alistair?
- You hit him too hard, Miss Sealove
Nonsense, doctor
Look, he's awake
Mr Beresford?
Don't try to move
There's someone
I'd like you to meet
Hello, handsome
Can I have a club sandwich
with no pickle?
I don't believe this
I can't get any reception in here
Hey! We know our rights
Attention Anyone caught sucking feet
will get two days in solitary
- Oh, my God, it's the Spanish Inquisition
- Blood I'm gonna faint
No, no, my dear, it's not blood
They've been crushing grapes
in the warden's vineyard
If you give me 2 Euros,
I'll let you lick Armando's feet
He's got the biggest
My little Chianti, aren't you, Armando?
Private reserve
I'll give you 2 Euros,
hold the toe- Suck Please help us escape
Escape? My dear
this is the only prison in Barcelona
where people are trying to break in
But I can tell you,
the desk sergeant does like to dance
Don't stop moving
To the funky, funky beat
Yeah, come on
DJ got the party started
There's no end in sight
Everybody's moving
To the rhythm that's inside
It's a crazy world
But tonight's the right situation
Don't get left behind
I can feel the music
Moving through me everywhere
Ain't no destination, baby
We don't even care
There's a place to be
If you need the right education
Let it tak e you there
And just go with the magic, baby
I can see it there in your eyes
Let it flow
Stop the waiting
Right here on the dance floor
Is where you gotta let it go
Don't stop moving
Can you feel the music?
DJ's got us going around
Round
Don't stop moving
Find your own way to it
Listen to the music
Taking you to places
That you've never been before
Baby, now
Yeah, yeah, yeah
You can touch the moment
Almost feel it in the air
Don't know where we're going, baby
We don't even care
Ain't no mystery
Just use your imagination
Let it tak e you there
And just go with the magic, baby
- I can see it there in your eyes
Let it flow
Stop the waiting
Right here on the dance floor
Is where you gotta let it go
Don't stop moving
Can you feel the music?
DJ's got us going around
Round
Don't stop moving
Find your own way to it
Listen to the music
Taking you to places
That you've never been before
Baby, now
Yeah, come on
Don't stop moving
Forget about your fears tonight
Listen to your heart
Let's just touch the sky
- Listen to your heart
- No need to reason why
Just listen to the sound
Let it mak e you come alive
Don't stop moving
Can you feel the music?
DJ's got us going around
Round
Don't stop moving
Find your own way to it
- Listen to the music
- Yeah, yeah, yeah
Don't stop moving
Can you feel the music?
DJ's got us going around
Round
Don't stop moving
Find your own way to it
Listen to the music
Taking you to places
That you've never been before
Baby, now
Don't stop moving
To the funky, funky beat
Bye
Don't stop moving
To that S Club beat
- I feel like an escaped convict
- Let's go to Natalie's
Okay, try around the other side
Guys, what took you so long?
The prison is right there
The scenic route was better
Guys, guys, guys
Natalie, please help us, all right?
We're fugitives
We don't know what to do
But you can't be here
You're in California
Look, you're booked to play
at the Fuller Center
Guys, we've got to get to LA
Tickets, passports
gum, earplugs, protein bars
neck rest, Game Boy and vibrating...
No, no! My last dollars and the address
of the place I rent when I'm in LA
- Bye Good luck Bye Bye, guys
- Bye
England!
Bradley, stop it!
Wait for me Come back!
Well, according to Natalie,
112 Whalecove View
is an attractive, sea- View property
with an alfresco dining area
This must be the place
Well, she said the keys
were under the flowerpot
Oh, great
Tina, you start on that side
I found it
We should go there
and kick those look-alikes right off-stage
What? And get arrested again?
According to Alistair,
we are the impostors
Maybe he's right
You know in that movie where
the robots are programmed to think
that they're people, but they weren't?
Well, maybe we're not actually us
Maybe they're us and we're them,
and we actually don't realise it
- You lost me at " hello"
- Okay, we'll just stick to the plan
Yes
We're gonna go in there, find Alistair
We're gonna have
a civilised conversation
And then we fire his butt,
and we kick it down the stairs
- Yeah
- Let's go
You lot stay here,
and we'll meet you after the show
- How much for the tickets?
- A hundred bucks from a scalper
- Each?
- I knew them when they were nobodies
Thank you
Thanks
- Screw you!
- Tina, wait Come back!
Can you give me
my microphone back, please?!
- Don't do that!
- Oy, give me my microphone!
It's my microphone!
Thank you
I'm sorry, but that girl was awful,
and everyone's gonna think she's me
That was no reason to jump on-stage,
grab her microphone and scream:
" Hello, Hollywood, it's great to be back"
It was like looking into a mirror
Maybe I had a twin, and we were
separated at birth
- I've actually always wanted a twin
- Yeah, or maybe they were robots
Or popbots
- Let's just stick with the twin thing
- Yeah
Let's go through this one more time
We find Alistair, and we have
a civilised conversation
- Wow, they really are identical
- No way, she's at least a size 14
I can't believe they walked
through without giving one autograph
Our fans are really gonna hate us now
- Bradley, I love you! No, wait! Bradley!
- Look, there's Alistair
Not now We're never gonna get
past those security guards
Come on, guys Let's just
follow the bus, all right?
- They're staying in a private estate
- Something's fishy
Yeah, that must have been
when we got thrown in that garbage
What I mean is, we never stay anywhere
this posh on tour
Well, why don't we just have a look
We could probably jump over
that wall or something
Who let the dogs out?
No, for real Look
I've got an idea
Bird Dog to Essex Terrier Come in
Oh, Jo, that's you
- I don't want to be Essex Terrier now
- Well, you pick ed it
I've gone off it,
and I want to be something else
- Fine What?
- Tough Sirloin
Jo, you can't just change
your code name It will get too confusing
Go on, let her be Tough Sirloin
if she wants to be
Bird Dog to Tough Sirloin Come in
Tough Sirloin here
Speak to me, Bird Dog Over
Okay, the roads all clear Over
- Tough Sirloin to Hedge Pig Come in
- This is Hedge Pig Who's Tough Sirloin?
I changed it from Essex Terrier
Well, then, I want to change mine
I want to be Mr Black
Well, that name's tak en
Yeah, yeah
Yeah, Big Pants ready to go Yeah
And on my order
- Not yet, a car's coming
- All units, hold We have a hostile
Operation Rogue Manager
is on hold
until my further command
Repeat, wait for my command
Okay, the eagle has landed
- The eagle has landed
- Where? I love eagles
- Hannah, just go
- Oh, sorry
This is Tough Sirloin
Meet me at the wall
Now, settle down Be quiet
I've got two friends I'd like you to meet
This is Mr Walker He's a naughty dog
And this is Rafferty He's a nice dog
Now, one day, Mr Walker
decided he wanted to go to the beach
So he got on his little spotty trunks,
and off he went Bye- Bye
Right, who's gonna go first, then?
Rach, you go
If I don't make it, will you tell my mum
I wanna be buried in my violet dress
Not the one I wore for my sweet 16,
but the one with the sandals
Now, Rachel
Okay, I can do this
Mr Walker's swimming trunks
were too small
because Mr Walker
had a big, fat tummy
- We can't make our way through that
- It's the only way of getting past the dogs
Stop, stop
Okay, Tina, come here
Okay, go, go, go!
Don't pay any attention to that
Do you wanna listen to my story or not?
That's better
Come on Quick, this way
Down here
- Jo, stop pushing
- You're going the wrong way
- It's this way
- Wait for us
I'm trying my best
- Come on, Teen
- Jo, get off my back
- Take the next left
- No, it's this way
I've never seen so much hedge in my life
Listen I can hear music
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven
One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven Boom
Head
One, two, four, six, eight
Jo, you're getting it wrong
Four, five, six
Concentrate, Jo
Keep it on Two, three, four
You're not getting it, Jo
Six, seven, eight
Come watch it from the front
Five, six, seven, eight
One, two, three and four
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight
And pull Two, four, six, eight
One, two, four, five and six
and down, down
One, two, three, four, five, six, eight
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven
- Keep down
- Quiet
- Okay, okay
- Look, they're in there
- By that yellow bush
- Keep your heads down
Take your time and down
Six and lift
Step and four, five, six
You're gonna have to try
harder than that, Jo Hold it there
Boy, they really are identical
Two, three, four, six, drop
Two and four, five, six, seven, eight
One and two, three, four
- Do we have to stand in this bush?
- Yes
- Why?
- Because I'm allergic to it
Don't worry about that
That's just the atchoo bird
Will you sit down?
Come back here Come back!
- Dogs! Run!
- Tina, this way
Follow the string!
Dance
Thank you
Two, three, four, six, eight
- Oh, look, there's some string
- Keep moving, guys
- There's two of them
- They've got massive teeth!
Four, five, six
- They're right behind us!
- Follow me
Faster!
Quick, keep moving
Come on!
- Come on, you lot!
- Over the wall
Faster They're getting closer
- It's right behind you
- Help me up
- Come on
- Help me up!
Come on, Bradley,
he's only a puppy
Puppy? Puppy, my...
- Oh, nice buns, Brad
- I'm just glad they're still there
Where's Jo?
Hang on a minute
Has anyone seen my sweater?
No?
- Maybe we should have rung the doorbell
- Then I could have finished my story
Now I'll never know
what happened in the end
I don't understand Alistair
Why is he doing this to us?
Well, we asked for time off
I guess we got it
Wait, he's replaced us with them,
so why don't we replace them with us
How?
We'll kidnap three of them
and switch places
Good luck, Rach
Operation Squeegee is a go
Morning
- Hello
I've come to clean your windows
- Wait just a minute
- Oh, no I've had orders
Security guards cannot have
dirty windows It restricts your vision
Could you shut the windows
so I can clean them?
- All right
- Thank you
There you go That's better
Yeah
- That was the best soaping I ever had
- Oh, thank you very much
Anyway, better be off
Plenty more windows to clean, so
- All right
- Take care
- Thank you
- No problem
- So long
- Bye
Tina, I'm in the loo
- Okay, wait there
- Okay
Hi, Teen
I've got a nice bucket
I've always wanted to do that
Never mind that Just start stripping
What?
Hannah, there you are
Perhaps you could come over here
How nice of you to join us
Perhaps we could rehearse verse two
while we're still in our 20s
Good Playback
Lately you've been searching
For the other side, side
There's a feeling to discover, baby
You can feel it in the air tonight
Let the groove just tak e you forward
- Grab him
- Hey, hey!
Let's mak e it tonight
Don't fak e it
There's no need to analyse
Now's the time to recognise
- Are you ready?
- Yeah
Now, find out what you can
Meet us tomorrow
on Mulholland Outlook about, say, 1300
- Got it
- All right, I'll look after you I mean, him
- Okay
- Go Go, go, go, go
Everybody
Dance
Let the music tak e you over
Let the beat become your lover
Dance
You can't stop it, baby
And cut
Excellent work, everybody
I'll see you on set in five minutes
Final touches Thank you
Are you hungry?
I've got some toast and jam
If you give them toast and jam,
they'll want milk to wash it down
then they'll be asking
to use the loo
So we'll have no toast and no jam
We'll just talk
- So, what's your name?
- Rachel
What's your real name? Don't lie to me!
I'm Rachel
- Is this part of our training programme?
- Look, I'm asking the questions, all right?
What training programme?
This is a test
It's a good test
Do I tie you up now, Bradley?
We'll talk about it later
Come here, you guys
Either she's jerking my chain,
or they're all two slices short of a loaf
We might as well untie them
They're too dumb to escape
So, what's after dinner?
- Rehearse, of course
- What, every night?
- Performing is what we do
- Don't you ever just relax and hang?
Relax?
- Hang?
- No, no, no
I think what Hannah means is,
you know
we could just sit here
and talk and stuff
Exchange life stories and
we could discuss how we,
and by "we," I mean you
how you got here
and where "we," again that's you,
where we come from
And what "we" hope to achieve
We are S Club We formed a band
We make records
We release records, and we tour
Great hang!
What do we do now?
Are you gonna eat that?
No
I've made tea
- Oh, thanks
- Enjoy
Did she just get you tea?
What? Biscuits as well
Tina, Tina
We gotta keep her
She's housebroken
You're a sick boy
What's all this?
SBB: Shower before bed
Shower before breakfast
SBB You must shower
No, no, no It's all right, honestly
I had one this morning
Just a " BB" Before breakfast
Fresh as a daisy, me
But go right ahead
You knock yourself out
Jon, I think the natives
are getting a bit suspicious
I don't care, Rach
These don't come off for anyone
unless they've bought me dinner first
For heaven's sake! Come on
Pretend you're in a JLo video
We're adults, aren't we?
We can handle this in a mature way
No time to be a shy guy, Jon
SBB Shower
Just a shower of little droplets
Falling from the sky
Bradley, don't use all the hot water
The rest of us want a shower too
Scrub, scrub, scrub
Wash off all the stains
Going down the drain
- Shower time
- Hang on a minute
You can't...
You can't do that
Wait, what are you doing?
Well, it's a small shower,
but we can all fit
Oh, right Well, then, you wash my back
and then, Rachel, I'll wash your back
and after that, we can turn around
and do the same again
Great
Now pass me the loofa
What are you doing? Get out
What are you doing in here?
That's sick, man!
SBB SBB
Where's Jon?
We are required to shower together
to save on water
Well, who made that rule?
Alistair makes all the rules
Any breach of protocol
must be reported to Alistair
- Jon didn't breach any protocol
- Where is he, then?
He's right behind you
- Jon
- Hello, love
Watch out for that shirt
Yeah, it might get all wrinkly
in the shower
Jon, is it just me, or did you notice
something in the showers?
No, I did I'll admit it, Rach,
I looked
but hey, I still respect you
Jon, shut up, I'm being serious!
I'm talking about them!
They haven't got any bellybuttons
Jon, she's right
Look
Today was a good day
Keep this up and we shall
be ahead of schedule
Tomorrow, we have six hours
of rehearsals
- seven hours of interviews
- Thank you, Alistair
- a long video shoot
- Thank you
and an appearance
on Totally Live Requests
So it's a light day
Good night, S Club
Hannah Spearritt,
your colour is yellow
You lik e Sunday roasts, parties, clubbing,
macaroni and Leonardo DiCaprio
Your fav ourite subjects
are geography and PE
Rachel Stevens,
you are a three-times winner
of the coveted Harvey Nichols
Shopper of the Year award
Your nicknames are Rach, Rats
Tina Barrett, your colour is red
You lik e lie-ins, watching television
and crazy nights out
Your personality is loud, silly
Jon Lee, your colour is green
You love your dog, Molly,
and your budgie, Harry Boy
You prefer vegetables to meat
- Your fav ourite hair product is
- Rach
This thing, it's like a crash course
on how to be us
They're not look-alikes,
they're replacements
Guys, we have to get out of here
We've gotta warn the others
Look at them They're really quite sweet
Maybe we should take them clubbing
I bet they've never been
Maybe they're robots
Or popbots
Well, personally, I think they're clones
It's not science fiction anymore, is it?
They've cloned sheep and goats
before, so why not a band?
You can't just clone someone
unless you've got a piece of them
like hair or fingernails or skin cells
The Internet!
Okay, here it is
One guy's been buying
all the S Club stuff
Victor Gaghan He bids on everything
Props, costumes, underwear
They've got our underwear
on the Internet?
Well, do a search on him
A genetics professor
at Golden State University
" Fired for illegal cloning experiments"
That's the guy!
Hello How are you?
- What's your name?
- Andrea
Hello
I like your top It's really nice
Help
Being held prisoner by aliens
or possibly popbots
Please call police
Best wishes, Rachel
What's your name?
Nice to meet you Bye
- Hello What's your name?
- Thanks very much Bye
Hello, little one
Could I take a look
at Rachel's autograph?
Thank you
- Victor Gaghan, please
- Hold on one second
It's Alistair for you
S Club have infiltrated the clones
S Club have done what?
Do it like that
This is the Rolf Harris technique,
and it'll come back
They're late
They are not late, and will you stop
pacing? You're making me nervous
Well, I've shown them
the Tasmanian swing
And Jon's got the hang of it
Look at them They're just so content
That's because they're bores
and boomerangs are boring
It's a perfect match
If I'd have known you could
make that from my underwear
I would never have worn any
But they're not bores, are they?
They just don't want anything
They don't have to worry
about anything
They just exist
Kind of creepy, though, ain't it?
I don't know, it's like they're not human
Oh, it's up in the tree
- Boomerang
- I don't think it's coming back anymore
- But Tina said it would
Can you see Alistair?
We've gotta be at Mulholland Lookout
He must have left
Excuse me I just need to visit
the little pop star's room
- So do I
- Yeah, me too
Lost?
Put them on the bus
- Get off me!
- Get off!
You're making it harder on yourself
Come with me now!
- I have them
- Good
Bring them to the facility
Hi, this is Jon Please leave
a message after the tone
Yo, Bird Dog This is Big Pants
What's happening with you,
Hedge Pig and the Shopper?
Call me back
Something's happening
This is not right Something's wrong
Maybe Jon thought I said, " Malibu
Overlook," not " Mulholland Outlook"
- I'm gonna check the beach
- Oh, I've never been to the ocean
All right, well, come with me
Everybody's got something
They had to leave behind
One regret from yesterday
That just seems to grow with time
There's no use looking back
Or wondering
How it could be now
Or might have been
All this I know
But still I can't find ways to let you go
I never had a dream come true
Till the day that I found you
Even though I pretend that I've moved on
You'll always be my baby
I never found the words to say
You're the one I think about each day
And I know no matter where
Life tak es me to
A part of me will always be
With you, yeah
Somewhere in my memory
I've lost all sense of time
And tomorrow can never be
Because yesterday is all that fills my mind
There's no use looking back
Or wondering
How it should be now
Or might have been
All this I know
But still I can't find ways to let you go
I never had a dream come true
Till the day that I found you
Even though I pretend
that I've moved on
You'll always be my baby
I never found the words to say
You're the one I think about each day
And I know no matter where
Life tak es me to
A part of me will always be
You'll always be the dream
That fills my head
Yes you will, say you will
You know you will, oh, baby
You'll always be the one
I know I'll never forget
There's no use looking back
Or wondering
Because love is a strange
And funny thing
No matter how I try and try
I just can't say goodbye
No, no, no, no
I never had a dream come true
Till the day that I found you
Even though I pretend that I've moved on
You'll always be my baby
I never found the words to say
You're the one I think about each day
And I know no matter where
Life tak es me to
A part of me will always be
With you
- What are we gonna do?
- Well, they're not coming
Why don't we go and meet Bradley
They must know something
They think they're S Club
What could they know?
Well, supposing we told them the truth?
The shock might jog their memory
Truth?
Truth about what?
The truth, the whole truth
and nothing but the...
I can't do this
Oh, for God's sake
Oy, you lot You're not real
You've been made- Up
- You're clones Get over it All right?
- What?
You mean we're fake?
You've been grown
Manufactured in a lab
- Like penicillin
- Or cheerleaders
- Fake boobs
- Yeah, I just said, cheerleaders
We're the real S Club
You've been brainwashed
with a personal history
- That would explain the gaps
- Gaps?
Well, yeah Whenever I pass
a shoe store, I get really excited
- But I don't know why
- Oh, for pity's sake
- Where's Victor Gaghan?
- Who?
We have to find him
if we wanna save our friends
So either you tell us where they are
or goodbye to your heads
Look, just try and remember
Where did you first meet?
- I met Jon at an audition
- That's what you was programmed to say
Come on, think about it Think
Jon
do you remember the lights?
We were in a cave
A big, colourful cave
And we were all there
- Papa
- Where are you?
I can't remember
Peak
It was called " Eagle Peak"
Get off me! Let me go!
This, my little pop chums,
is the end of the line
This isn't just Alistair's way
of getting back at us
This is bigger than that
Okay, so we've been captured by a man
who's built a dungeon in his basement
Now, that's not good
Sit down
All right
Now, let's not have any trouble here
- Give me your hand
- Who are you?
Oh, no, please don't cut my fingers off
I need those...
Oh, right, a fingernail
Oh, okay, you can have one of those
Actually, could you cut that one?
Because that one's really snagging
on my jumpers
- I'll give you a tip
- Not necessary
But I have a tip for you,
Miss Smarty Pants
Say your prayers
What did that mean?
Don't you see? Gaghan's gonna
clone us again from our fingernails
Yeah, he's got what he wants now
He doesn't need us here anymore
He's gonna kill us!
We can't just go on our own
We need backup
Okay, go and call the LAPD
Tell them an evil scientist cloned us
and had them do gigs
I'll come and visit you in the loony bin
Eagle Peak Let's rock 'n' roll, baby
We'll come with you
- We can't trust you
- Yes, you can
Alistair lied to us We're feeling really
- Angry
- Yes!
- We want
- Revenge
Yes!
- I'm sorry, it's too dangerous
- We're not afraid
To sum up, we're angry, we want revenge,
we're not afraid and can kill if necessary
Wait
- We're still on the same team, right?
- Yeah
All right Let's go
All right
First, we'll short-circuit
the electrical current
then bypass the video input
Then freeze the computer- Identification
system, and if that don't work
then we'll just chuck Hannah
over the gate
- It's a retinal scanner
- Rectal scanner?
Well, every castle has one
of those, don't they?
No, Hannah, a retinal scanner
Look, this is gonna take forever
Why don't we split up into two groups
You go and find Jo,
Bradley and Tina
and we'll try and find Rachel,
Hannah and Jon
We're here
You found us
And we found you
That was so easy
Jo, this is your idea
- No! It was Bradley
- My back
You guys okay?
Wait a minute
Where's Bradley?
He's there
- What happened?
- You got hit by a pillow Come on
Nice try
but we can't let you escape
Grab them
There you are
Admiring my collection of genetic matter
from the dearly departed?
- But Tom Green isn't dead
- A man can dream, can't he?
So you're the guy who bought
the knickers off the Internet?
Yes I wanted to meet you all in person
before I tied up the loose ends
You must be wondering
why I brought you here
I used to have heroes
stars who I'd write to
but who never replied,
because I didn't count
I was beneath them
Then I realised
I can grow my own stars
Programme them to obey me,
do whatever I say
- So I started collecting their DNA
- But it doesn't make any sense, though
If you want power, then why not clone
people like Bill Gates or President Bush?
You can take over the world
with clones of that calibre
Tell me
who would you rather see stepping
naked out of an accelerated growth pod
Bill Gates or Britney Spears?
- Britney
- Britney Definitely
Thank you
As for controlling the world,
do you really think
people are interested
in politicians or corporate moguls?
The subtle influence
that captures the minds
and hearts
of the young is music
The future lies
in music
And I own that future
Of course, I'm only telling you this
because you'll be dead in five minutes
- Do you wanna know how?
- I'd actually rather be surprised
The floor will fall away,
dumping you into a pit
full of lethally poisonous
snakes and spiders
You don't scare us
What are you talking about?
Yes, it does
Actually it's more the
spiders than the snakes
No, no, no
It's definitely the snakes
Shut up
There is nothing more powerful than
an idea whose time has come
Your time, however, is gone
Goodbye, S Club
Look, I don't understand
We're S Club
No, we're fake boobs
The real S Club are in there
This looks familiar
It's just like I remember it
It's no use struggling
The doctor is a genius
He's calculated all the odds, run all the
scenarios, envisioned every outcome
There's absolutely nothing
that can save you now
Stop that!
- There you are
- Stop that right now Obey me!
- We're rebelling If that's all right
- It's not all right
Get back to the castle!
It's rehearsal time
- No way
- That's my girl
- You lied to us, Alistair
- Yeah, we're just fakes Copies Clones
Is that what they told you?
Don't you see?
They're jealous
They want to replace you
- You mustn't trust them
- Don't listen to him
You must trust me
I wouldn't lie to you
- Maybe he's right
- No, he isn't
Come on, follow me
Wait
Alistair!
He's a clone
What? Wow
Look at that, a built-in M&M holder
By the way,
can I have my clothes back now?
For lunch today there is meat loaf,
broccoli spears, followed by
humble pie, limp biscuit
and vanilla fudge
Vanilla ice cream
and cream for dessert
Lights out at 10:30 tonight, apart
from Marilyn Manson
who wants
to sleep with the lights on
The bedtime story
will be read by P Diddy
It will be Little Red Riding
in the Hood
Tina There's hundreds of them
Would Madonna please report to the
music room for extra singing lessons?
Holy cloned cow
Is that Posh Spice over there
eating a steak and kidney pie?
Well, that proves
she's not the real thing
And look, there's Robbie Williams
having a food fight with Eminem
And Ozzy Osbourne I can't believe
they cloned Ozzy Osbourne
No
That's the real Ozzy Osbourne
Victor never cloned him
He's a mad scientist, but he's not insane
All you, look
We've got something to show you
Spit it out, boy
What about the clones?
They're rebelling, Dr Gaghan
Damn!
- Lf we leave here, how will we survive?
- Form tribute bands
- You can go on Pop Idol
- The point is
there's a whole life out there
beyond those gates A whole world
A whole world where you can do
what you want, not what you're told
A whole world of fun and freedom
You can throw a plastic boomerang
whenever you want
And there's potatoes cooked
in hot grease and sugar Good, right?
Look, all you need
to say is, " I'm tired..."
Not so fast
So go back to your rooms
Anyone who disobeys me will be killed
We'll have to make an example
of someone, I suppose
Get that one
No, get off me
If you kill her,
you have to kill me first
- And me
- We may need extra backup
- It's over
Plan Q
Isn't that " nuke Fort Knox
and ruin the world's economy"?
No
Plan Q:
Destroy the evidence
Blow this entire building to oblivion
Pull the switch
Three minutes to destruction
All clones remain calm
In three minutes, all of you
will be destroyed
along with this facility!
- Two minutes, 52 to destruction
- What are we gonna do?
Don't panic, all right
I've seen this bit a zillion times
The hero always saves the day
- Okay, so where are the heroes?
- We're the heroes, you mook
We've got three minutes
Hold up
Time- Out, time- Out
Why do we always get three minutes?
Why can't we get an hour? Why?
We've been living a lie
We're not what we seem to be
And we've had enough of being fooled
And now we wanna be free
Yeah, we've been living a dream
Somebody else's
And now we wanna live ours
But we got to leave this game behind
To know who we really are
Don't let anyone tak e over your life
No, no, no
Don't give up your dreams
And you'll be all right, no, no
They think they can control you
But they should have told you
When you're a clone
You know you're never alone
Who
Who do you think you are?
Do you know for sure?
Now tell me
Who
Who do you think you are?
Do you know for sure?
Now tell me
Two minutes, six to destruction
We're ready for change
And we just want to come out
And it's up to you and me now, boy
Why are we waiting around?
Feels lik e we're caught in a trap
Somebody else's
Maybe it's all in the mind
But we've gotta find a way to leave
All of this trouble behind
Don't let anyone tak e over your life
No, no, no
Don't give up your dreams
And you'll be all right, no, no
They think they can control you
But they should have told you
When you're a clone
You know you're never alone
Who
Who do you think you are?
Do you know for sure?
Now tell me
Who
Who do you think you are?
Do you know for sure?
Now tell me
Who
Who do you think you are?
Do you know for sure?
Now tell me
Who
Who do you think you are?
Do you know for sure?
Now tell me
Quick
To the helicopter!
One minute, six to destruction
Just gotta get, just gotta get back
38 seconds to destruction
Who
Who do you think you are?
Do you know for sure?
Now tell me
- Go! Go!
- Victor, no!
Who do you think you are?
Do you know for sure?
Now tell me
Who
We're free!
Do you know for sure?
Now tell me
Who
Who do you think you are?
Four, three
two, one
- Plan Q aborted
- I think we've done it, guys
We've freed the clones
We've just released
a whole new set of Britneys
*NSYNCs and Nelly Furtados
into the world
Maybe we should be quiet about that
Nobody move!
I want my S clones back
They obeyed my every command
They were always on time, and they
only needed one toilet break a week
They were the perfect band
Alistair!
Okay, put me down, S Club
I'm sorry!
- Natalie
- Hey, welcome to Hollywood
You are not gonna believe
what's been going on
Bye
Bye, Rach
Come here
I'm gonna miss you, you know
I've never met anyone
like you before
Well, not anyone with a bellybutton
Where are you gonna go?
What are you gonna do?
I'll get along
What the...?
Bradley, that is disgusting
- What are you doing? She's me
- No, it's not
She's all right
I mean, she made me tea
It doesn't mean I fancy you
I don't fancy you at all
- That goes for me too
- Come on, you lots, stop bickering
We'd better get going
We've got a big tour ahead of us
- Natalie
- All right
Now, we've got radio interviews
at 8 sharp tomorrow
- Tuesday, San Diego Wednesday, Detroit
- Oh, no
Thursday, New York
Friday, Washington
Saturday, Kansas City
- Wait!
- Hey!
- Come back! We need you!
- We need to talk!
They're doing fine You know, they're
almost as good as the real thing!
Cool
All right, take care
Guys, Alistair says the S Club
are doing better than ever
I think he's right as well
I mean, Jon, for me,
really is the star of the show
- I feel a bit guilty about this
- Well, don't
They'll get time off when we go on
It's so perfectly fair
Well, I think everyone
should have a clone
People would just be
so much better off
I just meant that they're
getting paid in boomerangs
You've got to admit, the clones are
all right, though, aren't they?
Aren't they, Rach?
They're all right
- You know that already, right?
- Go on, Rachel
This is ridiculous
I want you to mean it,
"This is ridiculous"
This is ridiculous
Bradley
- We can't trust you
- Yes, you can
Alistair lied to us
We're feeling really
- And we're feeling...
- Cut
- Help!
- Louder " Help!"
- What is your name?
- Hannah
Ready
Hannah?
Yeah, but
- Sorry
- Cut
Well, my name's actually Jonathan,
but everyone calls me Jon
That's just J-O-N, no H
One more time, Jon
Guys, Alistair says the S Club
are doing better than ever
I think he's right
Sorry, I can't remember the line if I don't
do "you know, you know, you know"
- I've got to get out of jail!
- Action
Jo from Essex
And cut
Look, this is gonna take forever
Why don't we split into two groups
You three...
Look, this is gonna take forever
Why don't we split up into...
One more time
Cut!
I want my dinner!
- " I want my dinner!"
- I want my dinner!
And action!
- What is your name?
- Tina
We can't just go up there on our own
We need backup
Go and phone the LAPD
Tell them that a mad scientist has...
I want my life back!
Rachel
R-A-C-H-E-L
Try Try
I don't like that
Where's Jon? We are required
to shower together to save on water
- Well, who made that rule?
- Alistair makes all the...
- I'm loving it
- Oh, yeah Yeah, bring it on
Cut!
- Did you slip her the tongue?
- Well, you know
- Pose
- What's up?
Come on
And another pose
Cut!
That's a wrap
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group
Ripped by
..::McLane::..