wWw.KoTuWa.Tk
wWw.BuGGeRs.Tk
»   ජය වේවා!   «
I think U need Subtitles  :)
Man has to face many storms in life.
But this orphan has
to face another storm.
And that is his
helplessness, his weakness.
And sense of loneliness.
What are you doing here by yourself?
Somebody definitely comes
to meet or take home all the kids.
But nobody comes to meet me
or to take me home.
Don't l have anyone in this world?
Yes, my son. Those who have nobody...
He belongs to them.
- Pass the ball.
- He's lame. He can't.
You cripple! Can't you hear?
Pass the ball!
Not only deaf is he lame,
he's also deaf!
- He won't understand like this.
- Then how will he?
Now let us see you walk.
l'll show you! Calling him lame?
Thank you pal. You helped me
a lot. What's your name?
Akash Verma. And yours?
From today Akash and
Aman are friends.
See what l have for you.
This looks imported.
Must be expensive.
That's not your concern. You eat it.
- What's in your hand?
- A 10 paise sweet.
- Give it to me. l like it.
- What are you doing?
That was for me, l ate it.
This is for you so you eat it.
Let go! What are you doing?
You're always up to something!
What if somebody sees you?
So what? l'll ask them for permission
Mister Viewer, can l romance my wife?
l've got used to asking for permission
First ask you if l could romance
you then your parents to marry you.
Then the priest to get us married.
A year later take permission from
our son, put him in the cradle...
And ask can l go to her?
When we first met, it felt
as if you didn't have a tongue!
l still don't.
- Now it's 100 parrots on one side
and you on the other! - Parrots?
Who will believe that you are Rajiv
Verma, the owner of Verma Estates?
The father of a 12 year old boy.
That reminds me where is our son?
Gone to meet his friend.
Since he found this new friend
he has forgotten his old pal.
Dad this is my best friend Aman.
Where do you live son?
What do your parents do?
l have nobody.
l live with Father D'mello.
No Dad, he's lying!
In this world l am his!
lf you love him so do we!
Never say that you have nobody.
Didn't you bring Aman?
- He refused to come.
- Refused?
Where are you going?
Let him go.
What we adults couldn't do,
Akash's love will do.
- Will you come or not?
- l will.
- What's going on?
- l'm looking for a coin l lost.
- Acting smart with me?
- Honest. But what are you doing?
He's asking me! l'm looking
for a 50 paise coin l dropped.
What is going on?
He lost 25 paise and l lost 50.
We were looking for them.
Come out. l'll find the coins.
- Let go my ear.
- First get up.
Someday he'll get me thrashed!
The kid is bad enough but
the Dad takes the cake!
By god! l'm terrible.
l'm getting fired thanks to you!
No, l got fired because of you!
Did you alone win all
these cups and shields?
What's terrific about it?
It's thanks to your blessings.
He is always terrific but ask
your useless son what he has brought.
What did l say? l knew
Mummy would ask this question.
But l haven't come empty-handed.
lf Aman has brought a cup,
l have brought a plate.
- Now answer me!
- See how cheeky you son is!
Aman has brought a cup and he a plate!
Tell her l'm 24 years old!
Forgive him this time. Next time
he does something, beat him not me.
Here's the plate.
Please get some tea.
- You'll never change.
- You'll get me thrashed!
- You've spoilt him thoroughly!
- Daddy, your dialogue.
Does love spoil anyone?
l love you too. Are you spoilt?
The kids are watching. Have shame!
The loyal and eflicient workers
of Verma Constructions.
Today l introduce you to my sons.
This is Aman.
- And this is...
- l am Akash,
- Okay carry on.
- What's left to say?
l forgot what l had to say.
You have encourage me so far.
To strengthen our foundation.
After today...
Help these boys in the same manner.
This is the oflice of
Varma Constructions.
- How is it?
- Very nice but what will l do here?
Here's a telephone.
You have fingers.
There are girls in town.
Call them up and have fun.
Can l really?
What are you doing?
l had heard about angels.
Never seen them but today l can say
confidently they're just like you.
What have we done?
The honor you've given me
by giving me your name...
That's a debt that l can never repay.
You call our love a debt?
Why do you talk of debt,
Ioan, obligations?
l've never considered you
any diflerent from Akash.
Of course. You think he's
intelligent while l'm a fool!
And that's right. No.
We have to attend a party.
But you won't go anywhere.
- Where are you going?
- To meet these.
- What's this?
- List of girls.
Rita at 12, Sita at 2.
Meeta at 4, and somebody at 6.
And when l return home at $,
my Dad gives me a spanking!
Your list is driving me mad.
Okay, should l move?
- Today is the first day of oflice.
- That is true.
- Okay, should l move?
- If Dad calls?
Then l'll be in trouble.
Okay, should l move?
What if you're needed in the oflice?
- Please go ahead.
- Okay, l'm ofl.
The heart is at peace
by a glimpse of you.
The enemy of my peace is back!
What is it?
Come on.
Finally found time?
l had so many business appointments
since morning that l'm tired.
Only now l've found time
for Menaka darling.
Let's go out. We'll freak out.
No, l'm exhausted.
l'm feeling sleepy.
Go to bed. This isn't your cup of tea!
That's a funny friend you have.
Why didn't he come with us?
Said he's tired and sleepy.
- Neither is he tired not sleepy.
- Meaning?
l know him very well.
He must be reading something.
- You mean it was an excuse.
- To get rid of us.
Because he's not
interested in anything.
Not even in pretty girls?
Girls? He runs miles away from them.
He's a modern Viswamitra.
lf l disturb his penance...?
l'll throw a grand party
for you and your friends!
- What's this?
- A picture and this for real.
- l'm busy and Akash isn't here.
- l know that.
But what do l do? Since l set
eyes on you, l see only you!
You misunderstand me.
l'm not interested in these things.
l know that you're the
modern Viswamitra.
But my name is Menaka.
And l've become to
disrupt your penance.
Considering that you're Akash'
friend, l'm asking you to leave.
And if l don't go?
l'll have you thrown out of here.
You can't do that.
What do you think of me?
There's no place in my heart
for society girls like you!
Don't ever try to come here again!
My foot won't come to you!
Have you ever seen your face?
l got talked into a bet.
Othe_ise a man like you
only deserves pity not love!
You snubbed a pretty girl like me!
That is why God has rendered
one of your legs useless!
lf l had my way,
l'd break the other leg too!
You're a beggar living ofl others
in addition to being a cripple!
l'd bet you to win
his heart not break it!
You've insulted my friend! l'll...
What are you doing? Are you mad?
- Take her out of my sight!
- Let's go before something happens.
Forgive me. Menaka has
been punished for her deeds.
lt's not your fault.
lt's that bitter truth of my life...
...that l'm used to living with.
Time will tell whether
l'm an ember or a dew drop.
At the moment l'm a tear
glistening on the lashes of time.
Exquisite, l swear by poetry.
At this tender age,
such thoughts, such depths.
This upliftment. l swear...
Every word of your poems...
... stings the heart like a dagger.
But l don't understand in spite of
being the loved poet of thousands..
Why are you a stranger to them?
Why don't you let people know that...
The one rising like the tide in
their hearts is none other than you!
No, l can't do this.
Let it remain a secret.
- But why? - l'd like my feelings
to reach every corner of the world.
But l'm scared to
come before the world.
lf mother, Dad or Akash
feel my pain in my songs...
They will be very hurt.
They might feel there was
something lacking in my upbringing.
l can give up my life for them.
But l can't hurt them.
l live for them not myself.
Great! Not only are you a good
poet but also a good human being.
You embarrass me.
Let's get down to business.
According to your instructions...
l send all the royalty
earned by your books to...
Father D'mello's orphanage.
These are some letters and fan mail.
The rest is ordinary but...
This is very special.
She seems a devoted fan.
She is always requesting me
for your songs, your poems.
And her name is Miss Pooja.
l will fulfill her request.
l swear by poetry.
The name that l have earned
by singing your songs...
...is truly yours because the
words were from your treasury.
l'm sending you a cutting of the
picture of me receiving the prize.
And a gift for you.
Received your letter.
Was happy to read its' contents.
l've kept my word and
sent you my new poem.
Hope you like it.
If you don't, don't hesitate.
Let me know so l can write even better
The blank frame hanging in my house
and l await for your photograph.
You snubbed a pretty girl like me!
That is why God has rendered
one of your legs useless.
lf l could, l'd break your other leg!
Not only are you a cripple,
you're a beggar who lives ofl others!
The Sagar (ocean) of my joy.
The Sagar of my imagination.
Every word written by you
sends my heart racing.
Your words woven with
pearls are my very life
l pray to God that you keep writing.
Today your face is extra bright.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
Looks like you're a victim of love.
With you around
anything can happen to me.
- Why? - Because you have
the world rights for love.
You're talking to me but
your eyes are on that girl.
She looks as smooth as a duck!
l'll enjoy it when the mountain
sitting next to her falls on you.
You're talking of the mountain?
l'm thinking of cuddling up!
That mountain?
No, the girl. The little hillock.
Son then you're in for a lashing.
And if l hug her, you'll pay the bill.
Or l'll pay. Fine?
What are you doing?
- l'm blind.
- Take him to the toilet.
Poor boy. He's blind.
He's had it.
Get dinner fast.
Or l'll have to eat a punch.
What a lively boy.
Seeing them together l'm
reminded of the film, -Dosti'
One chap is lame and the other blind.
- Who is blind?
- That boy on that table.
He's Akash Verma. He'll become
anything to flirt with girls.
He fooled me!
See how l'll teach him a lesson.
Forget business. Talk about home.
- About children.
- My children are great.
lf one of my sons is a diamond,
the other is the Kohinoor diamond!
How do you diflerentiate between them?
How do l tell them apart?
Hear and decide for yourself.
Take Aman for example.
A turbulent mind
becomes calm at seeing him.
When he speaks it feels as if
rose petals fall from his lips.
Great! Then why don't
you open a flower shop?
l also want to start a shoe shop.
No place. Shall l use your head?
Don't be angry. The other son?
Akash will write the name
of Varmas in the sky with light.
He will add light to our family name.
He's a dark horse.
l mean he'll run ahead of everybody.
He'll keep running with
the world behind him.
He'll keep running so will people.
Stop the car.
He's really running
like a horse in a race.
He's ahead with people behind him!
Tomatoes instead of flowers.
Stones instead of love!
Sticks instead of reward!
What about our family name?
- What happened to your family name?
- Nothing. Get ofl the car.
- He's getting beating and l have
to alight? - Get ofl quickly!
How will l go home?
- Take a cab.
- Cabs don't go there.
- Then take a rickshaw.
- How will that go if cabs don't?
Take your legs and go!
- l hold your legs.
- Not on hire, out!
What's wrong with him? He's getting
beaten and l have to get ofl!
Use your legs!
l'm ashamed of your condition.
Feel like drowning myself!
Why are you sounding link a man?
- What is it? - You're on the
phone when l'm scolding you!
There's no respect!
How did this tear?
Why did you get beaten up?
You won't understand.
l'd gone for a fancy dress party.
And those fools
thought l was a beggar!
Do l really look that foolish?
- Not that much.
- What? - Why?
Beggars are given charity, not
beaten by tomatoes, eggs, stones!
- How do you know?
- l was passing by. l saw you chased.
Long live fathers of today!
- Didn't try to rescue me!
- Me rescue you?
So that people leave you
and beat me up instead?
- Should have iced him there!
- l'm not ice cream to be frozen!
- l'll give you one!
- The father within awakens!
The one outside not within!
Forgive him now. l promise you
he'll never repeat it again.
l swear by my Dad l won't do it.
- Sure?
- Sure.
Must be Julie.
This telephone is the reason
he's getting spoilt!
You're right. If l get this
line cut all his lines will be cut!
Ass! Donkey!
Whatever l am, however l am,
l am only your son.
My business partner.
My son Aman. We're building
a big hotel in Ooty with him.
The entire construction
responsibility is yours.
- Me? - The cold climate
of Ooty has aflected him.
lt's not that.
l'm not sure whether
l can handle it well...
l am confident you will.
- When do l have to leave?
- When does the flight leave?
- Tomorrow.
- Is it your Pop's flight?
lt leaves on Monday.
When will you reach?
ln 4 days.
My other son. Listen to me..
- Why are you looking there?
- l've seen him somewhere.
ln some party or restaurant.
l'm the life of every party.
l'm always followed by thousands.
One in front followed by thousands!
A dark...
- Let me say horse.
- Doesn't sound nice from an ass.
- Go home! - First you say come
to oflice, then you say go home!
Are you making fun of my son?
Let your son do anything,
l'll have it printed in the papers!
- l don't have a son.
- Then who was in your house?
- The neighbor's son.
- And that woman in your house?
She is my wife.
Any problems? Go do your work.
Laxmi will come to pick
you up from the airport.
He'll tell you the rest.
Since when are you here?
- And before this?
- l was in Vellore.
- How did you come here?
- What happened...
l once had a picture taken.
The positive appeared negative.
The photographer told me...
You'll become an ape in Vellore.
- Can you cook well?
- Yes sir.
My parents were good cooks.
Once you eat good cooked by me
you'll lick your fingers.
You cook very well.
You should join a 5 star hotel.
You're pulling my leg.
Here, wash your hands.
- Is there any good market nearby?
- Sure.
Just 5 minutes away.
- What do you get there?
- Shoes.
- What nonsense!
- Listen to the rest.
Shoes, clothes, fruits, everything.
What do you want?
l want some books.
- Is there any book stall?
- Book and stall too.
- The owner is incomparable.
- What do you mean?
Her name is Pooja but deeds othe_ise.
Are you responsible for everybody?
Then why did you pay the rent
for Asha's shop?
That gangster was troubling her.
l thought you'd be happy
we could help somebody.
But l get scared when you
start preaching to a hoodlum.
You make a mountain out of a molehill.
Pass me the books. l'll put them away
Do you have the latest Newsweek?
Sure. Come in.
Mother! Pass the books.
A little more space.
She's much more
beautiful than l imagined!
- Did you say something?
- No.
l want some editions of poets.
lf you won't feel hurt may l say
something? Everyone has his choice.
But have you ever read Sagar's work?
Who the hell is he?
Haven't you heard of him?
He's a famous poet of these times.
l'm sure you'll like his work.
What can these poets of today write!
They steal drops from the works of
famous poets and become oceans!
No knowledge of the sound of
anklets yet write about it!
l won't take it lightly if
you speak one word against Sagar!
- What will you do?
- l won't give these books.
Looks like you...
what's the poet's name?
Looks like you like him too much.
Yes l do! None of your business!
l mean you are flying ofl
the handle for no reason.
l take back my words.
Now give me the books.
lf Sagar's new edition
is included in this...?
Then you'll even get a discount!
How much is the bill
after deducting the discount?
Rupees 40 for the books,
10 as discount. That's 30.
Seems new to our city.
- Looks like a stranger.
- An interesting stranger.
You don't know Sagar?
He's a famous poet of these times.
l'm sure you will like his work.
But why are you laughing?
l'm laughing because you're laughing.
lt's great fun!
The phone is ringing.
lt's the door.
- Who is it?
- Somebody from Bombay for you.
- When did you come?
- This morning.
- How are mother, Dad, Akash?
- Fine. They miss you.
- l too miss them.
- Hope you have no problems here.
lf he has any problems,
l'll sort it out.
l have a very long name.
- Get some tea for him.
- In a minute.
Now who has come!
There are some maps and papers in this
See them and try to understand.
Good day sir. Come in and sit.
How can l serve you?
- Get me first class tea.
- We don't serve it.
Then do you serve third class tea?
We serve no class of tea.
We only have...
Does every tea here carry Ram's name?
Yes. What is that sir?
l'm Bajrangbali's devotee.
You tell me whose devotee he was.
- Ram's. - Yes.
That's why tea carries his name!
So get me one Rampyari.
Get one Rampyari for sir.
Can l get a paper and pen?
Here you are.
- One tea.
- Get a tea for sir.
So back on the same path?
To the same destination?
Who are you?
l'm your reflection, your conscience.
l want to bring what's in
your heart to your tongue.
That you love Pooja intensely.
And that love for her has
created a storm in your heart.
And your heart has accepted her.
You worshipped her and now
she's the purpose of your life.
You are right.
l love her too much.
Then why don't you tell her?
Some day l will.
l'll tell her l'm her Sagar!
Have some sweets dear.
- What for?
- Because my shop is doing very well.
Really? How come?
- Thanks to you.
- Thanks to me?
A stranger comes to my shop everyday.
And drinks 30-40 cups
of tea by evening.
How am l involved?
Actually his eyes are on your shop.
Eyes here, tea there.
And the total rupees 30.25
So this is the matter!
Let that 30.25 come.
l'll teach him such a lesson
that he'll forget to drink tea!
Then what about my business?
Don't worry. Call me when he comes.
That l'll do but keep
the honor of these sweets.
Lord! What difliculty
have you gotten me into!
What have l done!
Ruined my own business!
Lord! Save this foolish man!
- How are you?
- The Lord is kind.
The stranger has come!
So what's the latest news?
l've heard the weather
outside is terrible!
Dark clouds are gathering.
Clouds are going to burst.
Lightning is going to strike.
There are chances of terrible rain!
Great! Exceptional!
Listen to what Sagar says.
A picture is painted
in my heart since ages.
My destiny sits in
the shade of your tresses.
That book stall girl was right.
Listen to what else he has written.
As far as my vision..
l see only you, just you.
l see you every moment.
lt's only the jeweler who
knows the value of the diamond.
l'm reciting Sagar's poems to you
and you're not concentrating.
l meant to ask which
era did he write in?
- And where does he live?
- in my own city.
And because of that l do meet him.
lt's after coming here
that l learnt he writes well.
Didn't you know before that?
That's a sign of greatness.
They never proclaim their greatness.
Sagar, you turned out to
be deeper than the ocean!
Now when l meet you,
l'll kiss your hand and say..
What will you say?
You are great!
One fantastic Rampyari for him from me
- Why the formality?
- Because you know Sagar.
You belong to the same city,
you move in the same circles.
And l'm his fan.
lf you know Sagar, why did you
abuse him in my shop?
l wanted to test the
limits of your love.
By the way how do you know him?
Through letters and his poems.
Tell me something else about him.
Ask me something else about him.
- How does he look?
- He's smart and young.
Really? Can't you
introduce me to him?
Definitely but on one condition.
That you'll show me
this beautiful place.
Because l'm new to this area.
ls that all?
So it's a promise?
Mother, this is Aman.
Have you come here for sight seeing?
My Dad is constructing a hotel
here. l'm here in that regard.
What a fool l am! l forgot to
tell you he knows Sagar very well.
Now you're in deep trouble!
- l don't understand.
- Neither do l.
God knows why she is crazy for him!
Now she'll drive you mad
talking about Sagar all the time!
You've started ofl again!
l'll show you our house.
This is Billu's room.
That's mother's room.
And there's our prayer room.
And that's the guest room.
And this is my room.
See the view from here.
Everything looks so beautiful.
Yes, it's truly beautiful.
lf Kashmir is heaven on earth,
this place is our heaven!
This place has made me
forget heaven on earth!
You're wondering why
the frame is blank.
This frame is waiting
for Sagar's photograph.
Your wait is over.
Sagar has come in person.
Pooja here.
How did you think of me
so early in the morning?
- To remind you of this evening.
- Anything special?
That's why l called. There's a grand
show at Nehru Stadium this evening.
l'm also taking part in it.
- Then l will definitely come.
- Don't be late. l'll be waiting.
l didn't know you dance so well.
Forget it. l'm very happy today.
The show went of better than...
Veera....?
l'm a poet and you're my poetry.
That day you escaped my clutches.
But who will rescue you today?
- Come on. - Let go!
- Get lost!
Don't beat him!
Police! Run!
Catch them all!
Don't let anyone escape!
What were you doing here?
You know how helpless you are.
Man protects woman. You can't
Iook after yourself forget any girl!
Had anything untoward happened
you wouldn't ever forgive yourself!
Excellent God!
What justice you mete out!
You snatched my parents
as soon as l took birth.
l said nothing.
When l was able to walk,
you gave me these crutches.
l kept mum.
From childhood to youth
l had to cross many dark alleys.
l had to bear loneliness.
l bore everything. Do you know why?
Because l'm accustomed to
drinking this bitter truth!
But when you made me realize this
bitter truth in front of Pooja...
l couldn't tolerate it.
Today l realize it, dear God...
l am truly an incomplete man!
A cripple! Is this my fault?
ls this my crime?
Who made this incomplete man?
Who has made me a joke
in the eyes of the world?
Answer me! Who brought me
to this juncture of life?
You! You are the culprit not me!
You are at fault not me!
For what crime are you punishing me?
Answer me!
Let's go.
l've found the answer
to every question, my Lord.
Forgive me.
Good your plane didn't get derailed.
Once l was going to America, the
plane was delayed. Both stayed here.
Ouiet. Hope you didn't
tell Aman l'm coming.
How could l say when
you told me not to tell him?
You said so l didn't tell him.
But why the suspense?
Anything that occurs suddenly
has its' own pleasure.
Aman and l will meet
each other suddenly.
What happened suddenly, mamma mia!
l think the tire is punctured.
How did this happen suddenly?
Did you call me beautiful?
You look after the tire.
l'll look after them.
What is it?
Do you mind getting up?
Walking like a blind bat!
Tire ready sir.
He's got a flat!
wWw.BuGGeRs.Tk
What a girl she was!