A City of Dreams,
you can't find this on any world map,
because this only is in my dreams,
and this is the wonderful bar of my city,
RK bar,
I used to drink English whisky
whenever I have money.
It makes me feel good,
by the way, I am Gulab
you have never seen a woman like me,
anywhere,
who sells false love each night,
but narrates a true love story
this story which I'm about to tell you,
is not of any normal man,
It's a story of an Angel!
dirty jeans,
A guitar in his hand,
wearing a cap,
A Rock Star Angel!
I met him here first time,
at this bar,
like everyday, I was the
last customer of the bar,
give me one more glass of whisky
give me one glass of  milk, please!
who is this guy asking for milk in the bar!
I'm the lead singer of this bar,
tomorrow is my first show,
so I'm here to practice,
but you can't sing lullaby here,
Here, only songs that
touch your body will work
a song is that which touches your soul,
not your body!
Soul!
a thing what you can't see?
like this matchstick, which has fire
but can't be lit until scratched,
or like whisky, contains intoxication,
but can't be seen,
wow, your words are indeed powerful!
Will I become a star?
- You'll become a super star!!
then you must listen to my song,
I'll just hear two lines,
come on sing!
what a guy he was,
like one in every girls dream!
that night, his song became
his identity for me,
Saawariya!
his voice was running all over my body,
the whole night,
when I think about him,
he makes me happy!
one night I was sitting in my area,
and was counting my earnings!
Hey, get your ball!
this is my ball!
Good evening!
you know what
I don't' have a pillow,
So, I sleep on it as a pillow.
But it doesn't stay put for long.
Sorry, I'll just pick it up!
you're the singer at the RK bar,
yes,
that's why I was thinking,
I have seen you somewhere,
but why are you sleeping
here on the street?
you tell me what should I do?
First, this city is new to me,
also my job,
and I don't know anybody here,
so no reason to be in anyone's home,
or trust a stranger,
the world is not like that,
In short, you don't
have place to live
correct!
You have come to the right place.
look up there...
that's my house!
What you say, partner?
Shall we try it tonight?
Thank you, but maybe some other time,
I like you,
you are the first one,
who refused to Gulab ji!
you are so gorgeous,
and the gorgeous like you,
don't sleep in street.
Lillian lives there.
An arrogant old woman!
If she likes you,
she'll make you a tenant,
if not, then Chicken Tandoori...
you can try you luck,
tomorrow morning!
Thank you!
Are you able to live here?
this is our area,
of Prostitutes,
why won't I be able to live here?
Gulab ji, they are someone's sister,
mother, or daughter,
but not anyone's wife,
but can be someone's friend,
what do you say?
can you be my friend?
you want to make me friend!
ok, we are friends.
I feel very sad, whenever
I heard Razia's baby cry,
I don't like it,
she cries this much every day,
her mother went to business,
she won't be here all night,
our business is quite tough,
and life is the same,
Our all childhood went this way,
crying without mother,
whole night,
or else waiting whole night
for the fairy to come,
not a single fairy came,
and no one make us quiet,
you go to sleep!
Lillian Ji!
Who is it?
Me!
Who are you?
actually, I've heard that you have
a vacant room,
but who are you?
Ranbheer Raj!
but you can call me Raj!
what's your father's name?
Did you lose him in gambling while drunk?
no, I don't gamble,
and I swear I don't drink!
you have any reference?
no reference,
actually, I'm new to this city!
sorry, I can't give it anyone
without reference,
get out!
I have one reference!
what you say?
I have one reference.
Who?
You.
me?
Whatever anyone says about me,
good or bad,
you are the one to decide,
my reference is your heart,
is it ok?
do you do something
or do you just talk?
nothing but music,
piano is quite out of tune,
how many keys are there in a piano?
eighty eight (88)
and how many strings in violin,
four,
If you add the string of your heart,
then it's five,
what will you give as a deposit,
I'll give myself!
And rent?
Until I can't give,
I'll do everything you say,
you know anything else
besides music?
yes,
I see dreams, I write thoughts!
and I try to spread happiness all over,
and sometimes, I need to sleep,
and have bread and water,
If you say, I can even repair this piano.
- No.
What about the room?
If I'll give you room, then I too sleep
after eating bread and water!
Can I ask you one thing?
What?
when did you smile last time?
- It's none of your business.
When did the last time
you called someone yours?
When did you love
anyone last the time?
When did you hug someone last time?
I hugged him,
Vincent
I told him
please don't go in Army!
but he went there,
37 years, he's been away!
you are alone for last 37 years,
you don't smile, don't love anyone,
don't hug anyone,
It's ok if you don't give me room,
but I want to give you something,
What you want to give me?
I want to hug you, Lollipop!
Oh Rascal,
he uses to call me Lollipop!
you want to be hugged Lilly?
that night Lillian
found her lost son,
unmelodious piano, got melody,
and women like me got
a good friend,
He was everything to us but
there was no one for him.
The only thing he had was fate...
which finally came to my Saawariya one night,
Hello!
It's not raining, then
why this umbrella...?
are you crying?
Please Madam, just don't cry,
I feel sad if I see anybody crying...,
you can have umbrella,
no problem,
I'm just so stupid,
Hello,
Hello!
where'd she go?
Madam!
you need any help?
no thank you,
please just don't follow me,
I don't follow you, Madam,
I was trying to help you,
If you need any help, do call me.
I'm seated in that cafe. Okay?
Ok!
excuse me!
can I drop you home?
no thanks,
I don't know you,
I don't know you either,
but it has become my responsibility to
drop you to your home,
Madam, who knows,
that trouble may come once again,
you don't have to trouble for me,
I'll go myself,
what trouble?
It would be my honor
to drop you,
no thank you very much,
hey listen!
hope you aren't thinking me
as that drunk man,
yes, I thought you were,
when you stopped at
bridge looking to me,
no Madam,
you are totally wrong!
when I saw you alone
at the bridge I thought,
what?
what'd you think of me?
that I was also a prostitute?
no Madam, you are wrong again,
I didn't think of you,
in that manner,
you were crying,
and it looked to me
like you needed help
and you do...
come on,
I'll drop you to your home,
but still one thing remaining,
you didn't tell me,
why were you crying!
I live nearby!
that's why you were crying,
I also live nearby,
but I don't cry,
I must admit,
you are too funny!
look, there's no path
without potholes,
and no life without grief,
Why are you lying at my feet?
oh, you dropped your anklets!
your anklet is too much,
you look so pretty,
when you smile,
then why you were crying,
by the way, sadness
also suits you,
you know what,
grief, it's quite dangerous,
I know,
It's comes in everyone's life,
but don't worry, I have a remedy
to fight it with,
it's a secret,
suppose, life is like boxing,
and grief is your opponent,
it's got a thousand hands,
but you have only two!
don't be afraid,
whenever it comes in your way!
look deep into it's eye
recognize it's strength,
and then,
Ladies and Gentlemen,
welcome to the fight of the century!
in one corner is a beautiful
young lady,
and in the other is unhappiness,
and the crowd goes mad,
but don't forget one thing,
that grief is a very strong opponent,
let's fight
it will first attack your face,
it'll hurt you,
no worries,
keep fighting,
it'll attack once more,
and you'll fall down,
but you got to stand up,
and fix it,
because if you lose
in the third round,
then every punch, grief will
fill tears in your eyes,
and every jab, it can
snatch your smile,
and in the fifth round,
it'll get into your house,
and then snatch
your family's' happiness,
and in the sixth round,
everything,
everything what you want most,
it'll finish it up,
it's going to knock you out!
and the winner is unhappiness,
yeah,
yes!
there's still remaining sadness
in your smile,
by the way, happiness
suits you too,
this is my home!
you home is quite beautiful,
don't you think that your home
came quite early,
I wish your home
should be a little farther,
I wish we can be together,
for a while more,
I wish this rain wouldn't stop,
and I wish we keep standing together,
under this umbrella while it's not raining,
Ranbheer Raj!
you can call me Raj!
and what's your name?
one second,
just wait there!
what is your problem?
we are friends now,
still you don't want to tell me
your name!
no!
you rejected this hand five times,
in today's meeting,
If I tell you your name in next five seconds,
you must shake this hand,
or else you won't find this Raj anymore
One!
Two!
Sakina!
it's midnight, come on, get in,
you are Sakina!
you'll be beaten, besides sweets on Eid day,
if your grandmother wakes up,
come inside hurry!
yes, I'm just coming,
we'll meet tomorrow,
tomorrow!
who knows what will happen tomorrow,
what will happen!
It'll be Eid day,
if the moon appears,
or else you wait.
Goodbye!
Sakina!
I was waiting for you the whole night, and
you drop in by window and sleep on the piano.
you idiot, you are in love.
what?
so finally God has mercy on you.
full with mercy.
what is her name?
Sakina..
Sakina!
how does she look?
She is Beautiful.
she is girl or orchestra party?
when I am going to meet her?
I will meet her today, and will tell her
how I feel and tomorrow you can meet
you don't have any issue?
if it were Vincent, would I have
any issue?
you won't leave me after getting married?
if it were Vincent, would he leave?
he has left!
but this Raj will never leave you.
what is this?
- Leave application.
tonight I won't be able to sing.
why?
you won't sing?
Sir, someone is waiting for me,
and I must meet her.
And what about all those people who
are waiting for you to sing?
don't worry, I will apologize
to them personally.
but today my heart is not in
control.
that's why I am leaving.
tonight you will sing 'til these
people want to hear you.
So the magic has climbed upon your head!!
if tonight you won't sing, you are out.
you are in a hurry Saawariya,
Sakina is lucky to have a lover like you
you know her Gulab ji?
I am street queen, take one step and
I can tell the whole journey.
this is the path of love,
beware.
and listen, don't fall too much,
or someday you'll hate yourself
wow, Gulab ji...
fool.
so you want to leave this job?
I want something else, and I can
leave life for her.
but you won't get this chance again.
Sakina...!
what's the problem?
ok bye, I am going!
how...!
I have seen you after long time,
so where were you going that late?
Badi Ammi will get worried,
it's not good.
it was raining in the morning, and
because of Eid preparation I have to.
see everything come together this year,
Friday, Eid and rain.
and our friendship too.
you know him?
no. Khala Jaan, he seems a stranger.
stranger?
Oh God, two ladies can't even talk
in person.
you're stupid, listening our conversation.
see I told you it's not good,
lets go, we will go somewhere else
listen,
will you listen to me Raj?
Ranbheer Raj ok? my name is stranger
and also known as stupid.
forgive me Ranbheer Raj,
you take me wrong.
if you didn't like me, you should have
told me, I would forget about you
if I talked to you, Khala Jan would inform
at home and I won't be allowed to go out.
and our friendship would end
in one night.
friendship... you don't even know the
meaning of friendship.
and I called you by your name too.
and I heard...
yeah still left.
I though what would you think,
in only one night this girl stopped.
madam, for you its easy to forget last
night, not for me.
you have changed in one night, last
night we were friends and now strangers?
it would better if I would wait for
the moon, not you.
oh. God, you speak so sweet.
listen Raj,
shop is closed come in the morning.
I am telling,
I am a very dangerous man,
ok.. ok..
forgive me.
not like this.
you didn't forgive me but I did.
hey listen...!
shop has closed.
what?
now don't start laughing...
what are you doing, leave me...
I am stupid...
see I don't like this, leave me.
I am a wanderer!
and wild too..
forgive me.
And a fool as well.
where are you taking me?
what is this place?
When I am happy, I come here...
And even when I'm sad, I come here!!
"Subhanallah"
How beautiful the world appears from here.
- But, not more than you!
what are you doing?
leave me.
I was just kidding.
you scared me..
don't do this again.
last night I was thinking about you.
you were also thinking about me?
why would I think about you,
I don't even know you.
you know my name! I work as lead
singer in RK bar
Lillian is my only family, I am her paying
guest, come with me, I will show you my place
I have told you everything
about me, now it's your turn.
name and address you know already. work,
making carpet, Badi Ammi is only family.
and Chunri Aapa is for taking care
of.
what about parents?
Badi Ammi says Dad left, no one knows
where.
and mom was waiting for him
her whole life.
that's it.
you know, when God takes everything
from us, he must send someone for us.
just like Lollipop..
and Badi Ammi for me.
no.. Raj!
crazy...!
tell me one thing,
does Badi Ammi love you?
yeah.. but she is strict, even ties
me with safety pin.
safety pin, who ties with a safety pin,
you are telling me story.
Badi Ammi can't see well, she is
afraid I will leave her like my parents
that's why she ties me.
if she ties you then what are
you doing here this late?
you fool, I came here and ties
someone else instead of me.
that means Badi Ammi is not strict,
but you are mischievous
lets have coffee.
no...
what happened?
Raj I can't go with you.
Why?
I have to go to the bridge.
Bridge?
I am waiting for someone.
who Sakina?
someone special.
special!
Who?
The one whom I love dearly!
whats happening, why you are silent?
nothing...
Can I know his name?
no... calling a lover's name
lessen the years of his life.
But, you could tell me by writing
Raj!
no Raj, its Iman. oh God, forget his
name.. you are so stupid.
we were so poor, even our
house was put for rent.
I remember that night everybody was
sleeping, and there was knock.
Badi Ammi someone is at the door,
must be paying guest.
Greetings...
Iman, you can watch me whole life.
lets move.
Sakina, how this guest looks like?
ugly, as wet cat.
is he from out of the city?
no..
Badi Ammi he came from outside.
how old is he?
very young only 60 years.
paying for us.
Jhoomri, yeah.. go find new paying
guest, he is already dying.
don't know how long he will stay
Badi Ammi... you just leave him..
Sakina, give him receipt and take
rent.
no. I won't go, send Jhoomri aapa,
he knows him.
no, you go and tell him he will get
breakfast only one time a day.
and without tea.. should I tell him?
Yeah go..!
ok, I am going...
You are here or gone?
Move.
you don't do anything right,
you do everything wrong.
rent!
and I drink milk not tea!
why you were talking about me?
you are pure, but not child.
have you ever noticed me?
then notice now am not that bad.
greeting...!
they kind has already taking over
queen, and his attractive voice.
now queen has lost her peace
day and night.
where did king come from in this
story?
he wasn't in there?
yeah, that's what I was thinking.
Who she is talking to?
I was dreaming with open eyes,
falling in love like hell.
I hadn't see him since many days.
and then one night.
across all limits.
I went to his room.
Good Morning.
come, come, Mr. Iman
Who?
He is our tenant Mr. Iman.
Good morning, Nabeela Bi.
Good morning.
Have a seat, Mr. Iman.
How are.
Fine?
God Blessing us.
Sakina.
come here, My child.
Yes, Grandma
Did he tell you his age?
Yes.
What did he tell you?
Just I get grow in
some days Grandma
Masha Allah
(so nice of gods creation)
You voice is so
strong for his age.
Just see it by touch my
body its strong 'til now.
How you telling like this.
Tell how you come here.
Just to meet you.
Tell me what you
think about it?
For what?
Sakina child.
You won't tell her.
Now what you forget.
Nothing much its a
little story Mrs. Nabbo.
Which function made at lake side.
There is a premier of Mughl-e-Azam.
I think that will you
come with us.
Will you come?
We don't go anywhere, but if you
force us then we shall come.
You must go but how
you see there?
Naughty.
What we need to see.
I just listen.
How fear when you fall in love.
Falling in love is not a
wrong thing.
Then why live like this.
For God Sake, your owner.
Don't make her alone.
God being started to make
story of our love but.
The words are end.
Second day Jhoomri sister tells me.
That he leave our house forever.
Stop crying.
Lets clean your tears.
I would take you with me.
Here.
But I can't take you with me.
I am doing work for death.
and where I am going,
There's danger every moment.
And every relation is weakness.
I want to make you my power.
But you want to be my weakness.
Sakina...
O Sakina..
I miss you so much.
When I read any book.
I miss you.
When anyone is crying
And when anyone will stop
laughing.
And laughing in crying.
I miss you.
O Sakina.
Where are you?
And that night he promised me.
Next year on night of Eid.
He will meet me before
moon's dawn.
Just I am waiting for him.
And for Eid's moon.
What is this?
My face showing gift.
He was given me that night.
This is a useless coin.
And your story is false.
Its not a story.
Its truth, Raj.
I can't trust Sakina.
You want to tell me that.
You love's a man like this who
comes like a rain one night.
And then lost in clouds.
Do you know what he does?
Where he lives?
I don't know.
House, home he have anything?
I don't know anything.
You won't know where he goes?
How these questions
belong to my love?
Sakina, its related.
Because if he is homeless then
how he will make your home?
Does he write any letter to you?
Make home.
And this coin have one side, wait.
And one side, alone life.
Your face showing is false.
How's my luck today without
crack body coin comes.
Listen, its my coin.
But I got it in the way.
Please, my coin.
But your name is not written on it.
Look, I don't want to speak
like you women.
Give me my coin.
Why are people like you scared
to speak our name?
Ok, What's your name?
Don't ask for name to Mrs. Gulab,
ask about price.
Mrs. Gulab give back her coin.
Do you know her.
We are neighbors.
Am I right, Beloved?
Stop joking give the coin back.
I will give back the soul to God.
What is this coin.
Take.
Why you do this?
Let her go. He have to see
that how you love her.
Its just a little meeting
of last night.
And you wrote her name
on stones and walls.
She has to know these stones are
costly in love between money.
Raj.
come here, Raj.
What's up Sakina?
you tell me that he won't come.
Look, he wrote my
name on stones.
That means he comes back.
If he comes, then why
shouldn't he meet you?
He wants to check our love.
Its possible he is hiding here.
And watching us.
How I love him.
How I love.
Look at it carefully.
It has one side Promise
and second side Trust.
And look Raj.
He will do his promise.
Look, I was right
he will come.
And take me away from here.
Sakina go from
here while you can.
I am already a
heart patient.
You gone mad.
can I say something?
Tell.
I am very.
It's raining, I swear
hard to go home.
Why lady.
Brother, do you think
that rain will stop?
Raj, are you my best friend?
Yes.
Then you tell me what I
have to do?
Do for what?
About Iman.
You can't speak her name nor
ask also but you can write.
You mean letter?
Why write a letter.
There is no side effect?
He don't think that I want
to show him my love.
Waiting all night and
crying to every word.
Its better then that you
take the first step.
I will try if you say.
Yes.
Ok, tell me if you were,
what you wrote?
Damn.
I too.
You.
Yes, me.
Lets begin.
I will write that you fool Iman
It's no need to come back now.
I am falling in love with
a boy who is named Raj.
Seen you stop me
at first time.
We can begin it like this.
Since when I see you
just like hope.
I want to write it.
Ok then I have write
that you want too.
Now write some bad words.
Did he mind it?
If you give him inside
your heart then not.
With trust.
I have told you just one word.
But you can't do this.
You call yourself a friend.
Why you worry Sakina?
I have the whole letter in my mind.
yesterday I will give you in
written a good hand writing.
And then you will post it.
Liar, you are a liar.
If that is a last night of our
friendship Raj.
And when I go back with him.
Then you'll get too much sorrow.
Thank you,
think about my pain.
I was listening to your story
from last 2 nights.
Why Raj.
Do you have some pain inside.
Nothing any problem like this.
Yes, but it will be from
tomorrow.
Raj, may I give you one problem?
What.
This letter?
I wrote it for him.
Sakina if you have a letter
then why you tell to me?
Just to know that
what I wrote is true.
But which you think
exactly like this.
Will you send it to Iman.
I know that you
can't tell me no.
And yes Jhoomri sister tells me
that he lives in old town.
I know it's so far.
Bring it.
Ok Raj, I have to go now.
If Grandma is awake then
its really a big problem
Goodbye.
Stop, Sakina.
I will leave you there.
I can go.
Just send the letter there.
Ok.
Sakina should we
meet tomorrow?
If you get an answer then.
Listen if I can't get the
answer then?
Then I give you more problems.
And yes don't forget to send it.
And Raj.
What?
Nothing.
I'll wait for you.
Ok bye.
That bloody love is
thing like this.
Which converts God in a stone
And an angel to a devil.
that night I look a beloved
dies in his eyes.
Its just in two nights make it all.
But I don't know what's
in the next two nights.