Lunch time
Overseer, the workmen are going to lunch
Come over here. Come here
Sit down
The ruins of the mansion...
I am demolishing it today
How splendid it once was
Years ago, I came to Calcutta from my village...
...and saw this mansion
How magnificent it was
Brother
- Brother-in-law!
Just arrived?
Your last letter didn't say you were coming
If only you had let me know...
If you'd sent me a postcard,
I'd have met you at the station
No purdah?
I live upstairs. Come along
Why stare at them?
Never do that!
That was Majhaley Babu.
He's head of the mansion now
Where are they going?
- What is it to you?
Don't pry. In this mansion
you'll hear and see nothing
They are important people
Since I am diligent, they are kind to me
At the beginning, I came here
to teach the children
Their studies ended long ago...
... but I am still paid and lodged here
I always will be
Stay with me and see Calcutta
I've seen it, brother-in-law.
So many big buildings
So tall, that my neck...
Everything is big here
Buildings, people, names.
Prices are big, too
At home, milk costs 1.20 for
20 liters and here you get...
... 1 1 liters
- Only?
Here everything is big,
and all the weight is borne...
... by us small people
We are obliged to submit
I have found a job for you
At a bridal-mark...
Mohini Sindoor?
What shall I do in a women's concern?
It's not women's work, though
It's good pay, seven rupees a month
Plus lunch
Lunch, too?
Can I eat as much as I like?
Certainly!
But come and sit here
This bed is meant for you
Mr. Suvinay, the proprietor, is a
Brahmo Samaji, a noble man.
But Brahmo Samajis are not of our caste
How can I eat at his place?
Don't worry, he has employed a Maharaj to cook
Nibaran, it's you?
Is all well?
Hurry! The British have been shooting
in the Bazaar again
Rest a while. I'll be back soon
Hurry!
Chotte Babu is coming out
I know
I know who you are
You're Teacher's brother-in-law, aren't you?
You're a wonder
- A wonder?
Why sit in the dark?
Can't you light that English lamp?
No, you definitely can't
I was afraid I'd break the glass
True. When I first...
...came here, l, too, was afraid of that
But that wicked girl Chinta has
broken thousands of lamp-glasses
Why are you standing? Sit
It's a curious mansion. No one
asks about the cost of breakage
Curious?
Did you see the young master?
No? He left in the carriage
Do you know where he has gone?
She's the cause of all evils.
I'll tell you about it later
I'm run off my feet here.
I never have time to talk
"My eyes..."
"are weary and tired"
"O beloved, where are you?"
"Come home, so gently, so softly"
"A voice calls from afar"
"Come home, my beloved"
"The long night is filled with waiting"
"My restless heart aches"
" Beloved, do not taunt me so"
"Come home, so gently, so softly"
"A voice calls from afar"
"Come home, my beloved"
Teacher, for the nation's uplift
and freedom, the principles...
...of Brahmo Samaj are good
Only those principles can shed
a new light on the nation
Throwing bombs will not suffice
Yesterday's bomb incident
proves the foolishness of that
Yes... but didn't you want
a new clerk for your concern?
I've the right boy for the job.
- What kind of boy?
He's a villager, but he's educated
Hard-working and honest.
He is standing outside
Why did you not tell me at once?
Call him upstairs
Brother-in-law, come upstairs
Now what was I saying?
So people threw bombs.
First remove the faults in society
Remove false values, old
customs in the name of religion...
You were saying something about old customs
Society's customs. This...
My late wife regarded him as her brother
He's just arrived
Will you drink tea?
- I drink milk, but not now
Where is he from?
Village Fatehpur. Post Gajna.
District Nadia
Fatehpur...
... in Nadia district
Do you knowthat village?
What is his name?
- Bhoothnath
The fact is, I was born on Shivratri...
...so my aunt named me Bhoothnath
Jabba, such laughter is not suitable...
...for girls of our society
Let her laugh. I'm not offended
All laugh at my name: it can mean Ghost Man
Teacher,
your brother-in-law seems to be a simple man
Bhoothnath,
if you wish you may begin work today
I'll explain the job
They're new
Your meal is ready
So little rice?
- You will not get more
The young mistress herself issues the rice
I've cooked all there was,
so how can I give you more?
This is a crime! Return my land!
My children are starving!
I will stir till you return my land
Another word and your tongue
will be pulled out
No! You people have taken
the land of my forefathers
Tell your master...
...that if the curse of this poor man...
A splendid son-in-law!
There's none like him in all Calcutta
Are you drunk?
There's none like him in all lndia!
See how his eyes gleam
You have outdone that Cheni
Dutt who tries to compete with us
Cheni Dutt married his cat to an lndian cat
When I told him our son-in-law came from Persia...
... he was dumbstruck
What nonsense you always talk
When I told Cheni Dutt you spent
1 0,000 on your cat's marriage...
... he was so surprised, his eyes went like this
Fan properly. See the drop of
perspiration on master's neck?
Not a moment to spare.
I'm run off my feet here
I have to do everything.
That Chinta does nothing
My sister.
Do you know whose maidservant she is?
Chotti Bahu's servant. But I am
Chotte Babu's special servant
The man I saw you carry
into the mansion the other night?
The other night?
I have to bring him home every night
What can I say?
My Chotte Babu drinks
He returns at five in the morning...
...and falls asleep downstairs
He never gets upstairs
Where is he all night?
- What do you think?
With the courtesan
He's lost in her spell
If only I could...
... I'd cut her hair off
That Chunni has bewitched my
master. His wife Chotti Bahu...
... never sees his face
The Chotti Bahu who sings
such sad songs at night?
Should she sing songs of joy?
If a husband turns from a wife,
what can she do but lament?
Chotti Bahu is very unhappy
You haven't seen her
She is fairer than the moon
"This much harassment is not good"
"My love, sweet love, do not torment me so"
"My love, do not torment me"
"I'd give my life and soul for you"
"This much torment is not good"
"These eyes are to intoxicate you"
"ln their depths lie tales of love and passion"
"Let us lose ourselves in this sweet stupor"
"Drink not from the glass.
Come, drink from my eyes"
"Let us fill our hearts with this magic passion"
"Too much torment is not good, my love"
"You are lost in carefree intoxication"
"l am lost in a fever of love"
"You lie senseless
while I quiver with love for you"
"l know not where I am,
you know not what you are"
"This consuming passion will not be denied"
"This much harassment is not good"
"My love, sweet love, do not torment me so"
"My love, do not torment me"
"I'd give my life and soul for you"
"This much torment is not good"
Is your father at home?
No, he has gone to a meeting
This is terrible
The proof of the advertisement
must be corrected at once
I'll do it
I remember the text.
Read it aloud
"The wonderful miracles of Mohini Sindoor"
"The lover...
"... and the loved one... "
"...troubled by separation... "
Why stop? Go on
"... or whose union is hindered..."
Go on
"...or the beloved who is near... "
"... but does not air... "
What?
"... or the beloved
who is near but does not air... "
Make this correction
"...who is near but does not care... "
What vegetable should I buy?
I'll tell you shortly
Go on
May I ask you something?
What?
Who gives rice to the cook?
Why?
- Nothing. I just asked
But why?
"...or lovers who have quarreled...
"All may use Mohini Sindoor"
"Money back if not satisfied"
I'm off
Why did you speak against me
to Miss Jabba? It means trouble
But l...
Cross my path
and you'll soon lose your job
Lots of boys like you
have come and gone here
Bhoothnath, come here
Stand here before me
What has this Maharaj told you?
Nothing
- You're lying
Then have I lied to father?
I heard everything.
Tell father plainly what he said
Just that if I crossed his path
I would lost my job
You accepted it in silence?
Get out of this house!
You're a coward.
Why didn't you complain?
I didn't want to bring it up...
Excuses! You asked me
who gives rice to the cook
You thought I was giving you less food?
Why should I do that?
What could I have against you?
We've no ties.
All I have to do is see you're fed
Haven't you gone home?
I wanted to talk to your father
He is upstairs
I wanted to talk to you, too
Well?
Well, I've thought it over
So you think!
And what have you thought?
I am entirely at fault. I should
have complained about the cook
Forgive me
Why stare?
Because of me, the man was sacked
Now look at the trouble you've been put to
Don't worry, I know how to cook...
...although it must frighten you
Why should I be frightened?
From tomorrow you must eat
food cooked by me
Will you eat food
prepared by a low-caste?
Why are you always taunting
when you talk to me?
How else should I talk?
Don't hesitate. Go on, tell me
I'm going
Going?
Weren't you intending to apologize
to my father, too?
I'll do that tomorrow morning
You could apologize to me
tomorrow morning, also
Was it necessary now?
Listen
What is it?
The night is so dark and still
Shall the watchman see you home?
A man isn't afraid of the dark
What are you carrying like that?
Destiny. Chotte Babu did not return home
Come with me and you will understand
Do people of the mansion deign to come here?
To reap barley for a cure...
...one must tread in mud
Where is your mistress?
Your master's alone.
My mistress is making herself up
Wait here for me
Why are you here, you fool?
Yesterday Bahurani observed the
feast of Astami, but you were out
Go away
Please let the water touch your toe
Unless Bahurani drinks this water...
...she cannot eat
She hasn't eaten at all
So? If she wants to prove she's
a devoted wife, why bother me?
No bother, sir. Just let your toe touch the water
Now get out of here!
The glass, sir
Let's slip away
A miracle
What's that?
- That?
She is Bari Bahu, mother of Chottan Babu
She is going to the Ganges
To bathe? In that mosquito net?
Not only will she bathe,
she'll bathe the mosquito net, too
Such purdah?
She also has untouchability sickness.
She is a widow
It's a very delicate matter
Don't tell anyone
Chotti Bahu summons you to her room
She summons me?
Yes. Tonight
Tonight? But I am a man
Only men of the family may go
to the women's quarters
True, but don't worry
Tonight I shall take you there secretly.
Understand?
Now I must go. I'm run off my feet here
"The bee is so naive"
"How he flits about the garden"
"Yet why do the flowers smile for him?"
"The bee is so naive"
"How he flits about the garden"
"Yet why do the flowers smile for him?"
"The bee is so naive"
"He flits from flower to flower..."
"never betraying his heart's desire"
"He flits from flower to flower... "
"He hovers before me, exchanging glances"
"He gazes at me, yet remains silent"
"The bee is so naive"
"Secretly, he drinks nectar from the flowers"
"lntoxicated, he sways as he walks"
"He is near the heart, yet always far away"
"Far away, like one unknown"
"The bee is so naive"
"lf you surprise him at play..."
"... he is quick to fly away"
"lf you surprise him at play... "
"He never wants to learn"
"What an innocent creature he is"
"The bee is so naive"
"How he flits about the garden"
"Yet why do the flowers smile for him?"
"The bee is so naive"
Can't you cough?
How dare you sneak up and hear my poetry!
Why stare me? Go to work
Come along
What if anything goes wrong?
Don't go back on your word
Who goes there?
- It's Bansi
Wait. Bari Bahu is washing her hands
It's the mosquito net lady.
She'll wash her hands all night
Bari Bahu
Are you counting how many times I've washed?
Sixty-two times.
Wash once more
Now it's 63
Bansi, you can come now
Bahurani, here is Teacher's brother-in-law
Bansi, leave now
Come over here, come on
Sit down
You seem to be very shy
They call you Teacher's brother-in-law.
What do I say?
My father named me
Atulya Chakravarty
But since he died all call me
by the name my aunt gave me
Why not?
Bhoothnath is a lovely name
What is wrong?
I shall call you Bhoothnath. It is
one of the many names of God
Won't you call me Chotti Bahu?
Chinta, serve the offering
It is blessed by Shrijadi
Do not be shy to eat.
Otherwise, I shall feel bad
Bansi tells me you work
at the Mohini Sindoor factory
Do you?
Yes, but...
There...
I don't get on with Jabba
Jabba? Who is she?
A girl
I mean, the owner of the company...
She is his daughter
She is very nice,
but she speaks so harshly
What has she said?
We have to ties - all she has
to do is to see I'm properly fed
That's very harsh
She also said...
I'm talking to you as if
we've known each other a long time
I'm sorry. It's very late
Haven't you learnt
the customs of this house yet?
Days are for sleeping and nights
for waking and waking others
I have summoned you to relieve the torment
Torment?
You can't understand,
but you can help me to remove it
Why give me money?
It's for the bridal mark of
Mohini Sindoor. Bring me a box
For you?
- Yes, for me
Tell me, is it effective or not?
I don't know
Ask them
Discreetly. Do not tell anyone about me
If you forbid me, I shall not tell anyone
Would you have done,
if I had not forbidden you?
Why so perplexed? Don't you know
such things are not talked of?
Do not even tell Jabba. She is
unmarried, she won't understand
What won't she understand?
It cannot be explained to a man,
or to some women, either
It can only be understood
by unfortunate women
It is a great disgrace
and a great shame for a woman
I'll await you tomorrow
He's Chottan Babu, Bari Bahu's
son. He's very fond of women
Be careful.
Here's the timekeeper
He winds the mansion clocks
Who are you?
Where do you live?
Speak up! Are you mute?
What's your name?
Father's name?
Village? District?
How many houses?
How many mansions?
Any mansions?
Run back there
Stay away from mansions.
I, the timekeeper, tell you this
Have you seen a clock? Time?
It overcomes all illusions.
It cures all misconceptions
It has reduced Time into pieces
of hours, minutes, seconds
Listen to the sound of time and
recognize the misconceptions
Kingdoms do not last.
Palaces do not endure
Mansions will not endure
I speak the truth, young man.
Time does likewise
"l shall not feel sleep heavy upon my eyes"
"The glittering night is vibrant"
"Throughout the long night
we shall unblinking gaze"
"The glittering night is vibrant"
"l shall not feel sleep heavy upon my eyes"
"Throughout the long night
we shall unblinking gaze"
"The glittering night is vibrant"
"Wine, the night..."
"and the spell of love"
"How fortunate is he who profits
from this magic"
"The enchantment will endure
the whole night long"
"Why should we worry
about the coming dawn?"
"The enchantment will endure
the whole night long"
"Why should we worry
about the coming dawn?"
"lf I can behold your gentle face..."
"what more could I desire?"
"Your soul and spirit will be revealed to me"
"The glittering night is vibrant"
"l shall not feel sleep heavy upon my eyes"
"Those consumed by the fire of love..."
"have lost control of their destiny"
"This is the passion..."
"which enters all hearts"
"Who is not lost in love?"
"Who does not sigh with longing?"
" Beauty will enthrall you"
"There can be no escape"
"Your life will be lost in your unblinking gaze"
"The glittering night is vibrant"
"l shall not feel sleep heavy upon my eyes"
"Throughout the long night
we shall unblinking gaze"
"The glittering night is vibrant"
Don't worry, you won't lose
your high caste
Now you can eat without fear
I have employed a new cook
That wasn't what was worrying me
I know we villagers eat a lot of rice,
but still...
You must eat it
If you're even a bit hungry,
you'll be cross with me again
Tell me...
If used properly, is Mohini
Sindoor really effective?
I'm sorry, but I have had no call to use it yet
Do you want to use it?
Who will you try it on?
It's not for me, is it?
If so, you'll be the loser
Please don't joke about it
I must buy it for someone else
She is a very unhappy, very tormented
Who is she?
My Chotti Bahu
- "Yours"?
What torment?
It is a great disgrace
and a great shame for a woman
What sort of torment?
It is very great trouble.
But you will not understand
Explain it
How? You are still unmarried
Who is she, "your" Chotti Bahu?
I will not tell you, she has forbidden it
She seems to have command over you
I promised not to tell anyone,
not even Jabba
Me? Does she know me?
I told her everything
- What did you tell her?
Did you complain?
Not even your enemies
would complain against you
I said...
You said? Go on, say it.
Why do you stop?
You won't like it
Even so, I won't reduce your rations
I knowthat
We have no ties - all you have to do
is see I'm properly fed
Did you tell Chotti Bahu all that?
I told her everything
You don't tell me what she says,
but you tell her what I say
Go on. Tell me what you told her
It's very hot; it's a chili
I used to think you're naive.
Now I know you're wicked, too
Elder sister!
It's time to eat.
What are you doing?
Her hands are unclean
A crow perched on her clothes
so her hands are unclean
Majli Bahu, do not laugh
One day you may be afflicted
with this sickness
Do not laugh
Should I seal my lips?
Your antics make people laugh
Chotti Bahu, come and see
Why tease her?
The poor widow does no one any harm
Don't stand up for her. Do I say
anything when you lie in your...
... husband's arms?
When am I ever near your brother-in-law?
When do I have the opportunity
When does he ever stay at home?
Stop lamenting shamelessly
My brother-in-law is a man of a rich family
He enjoys song and dance all night
I come from a poor family
All know is that a woman
lives for her husband
If the husband stays away...
What are these ornaments for?
What is this life for?
Have some shame. You ruin the
prestige of the Chaudhary family
I've never seen a woman
who pines for her husband
I want to ask you something
What is that?
Do your advertisements
for Mohini Sindoor speak true?
My father started the business
He was an orthodox Hindu
not a Brahmo Samaji like me
I became Brahmo Samaji after my marriage
I asked about Mohini Sindoor
- I'm coming to it
Goddess Bhawani revealed Mohini
Sindoor to my father in a dream
He believed in this boon
He began the business which I continue
But do you believe in it?
Here's Dharamdasji, head of the Samaj
My nephew, Supavitar
He has passed his M. A.
Come in
I was waiting for you.
The offering is on the table
Have you brought it?
Yes, Chotti Bahu
Show me the Sindoor
Is Chotte Babu in?
- No, he has gone out
Tell the kitchen I shall not eat today
Do not bring me food.
Go and fetch Bansi
Why won't you eat today?
There is no other way to fulfill my desire
I was very young when I was
married. My mother said to me:
"Daughter, serve your husband..."
"The husband is a god"
When I come here I found that
my husband was never at home
Tell me, whom shall I serve?
This is a curious house
I married into a grand house
Plenty of wealth, servants, ornaments
I have every comfort
But all these comforts are meaningless
The greatest comfort a woman can have...
You sent for me?
By some means,
bring Chotte Babu to my room tomorrow
How? Chotte Babu sleeps all afternoon
As soon as he gets up
Tell him I am very ill
and I have eaten nothing
Ask him to see me once.
Understand?
Yes, Bahurani
You were surprised
You think your Chotti Bahu is a liar
But, believe me, my Lord knows
I have never told a lie
But today I lie for my husband's benefit,
isn't that so?
Your husband's benefit?
Yes, Bhoothnath.
His daily outings, his drinking
How long will his health last?
May it be effective
Don't worry, the Sindoor
will definitely be effective
It will, won't it?
My heart say's so
Until the day I die, I shall not forget
your kindness
If you ever have any troubles,
inform me through Bansi
Do not forget Chotti Bahu
I won't forget
The British are coming!
Run!
" Beloved, you have cast such a spell on me"
"l have lost my tranquility, my very self"
"Every step I hear, I think it is you"
"l hide my face beneath the finest veil"
" Beloved, you have cast such a spell on me"
"When you enter the courtyard of my world..."
"all doors open to you"
"When you enter the courtyard of my world... "
"l sense that my beloved is near"
"Showers of petals fill the air"
" Beloved, you have cast such a spell on me"
"l have lost my tranquility, my very self"
"l anoint my brow with bridal vermilion,
with Sindoor"
"l make myself beautiful for my beloved"
"l anoint my brow with bridal vermilion,
with Sindoor"
"l make myself beautiful for my beloved"
"Fearing my beloved may cast an evil eye..."
"l darken my eyes with kohl"
" Beloved, you have cast such a spell on me"
"l have lost my tranquility, my very self"
"Every step I hear, I think it is you"
"l hide my face beneath the finest veil"
" Beloved, you have cast such a spell on me"
Why have you called me here?
Why so silent?
Look at me, just this once
You see nothing?
What nonsense, I have no time
to stare at your face
Please, even if you don't like to look at me...
... please don't go there today, I beg you
Do you think
all the males in this house are impotent?
Living close to a wife
does not make a husband impotent
We wed according to the rites of Hinduism
Have you no duty towards me?
He who learns from a wife...
... has no shame
How are you?
At least it's as well the bullet
struck you in the leg
What if it were?
Who is there to weep over me?
No one?
- I don't see anyone
I've heard of someone.
Who?
You murmured her name in delirium
I murmured?
All the time. Tell me...
What are you to her?
You hear the name and you are lost
Is she very beautiful?
You would understand if you were to see her
That's enough. I can imagine how she looks
One can imagine beauties...
... but my Chotti Bahu is beyond imagination
Don't you think of anything but her?
You're angry. Very well,
I will never mention her again
What if you do?
Who am I to stop you?
You are quite right
We have no ties - all you have to do
is see I'm properly fed
Will you never forget?
I've looked everywhere for you
How are you? Does it hurt?
Chotti Bahu?
Why did she run away?
She had ordered me to find you;
the palanquin is outside
Does Chotte Babu stay at home now?
Don't talk of such things
A leopard cannot change his
spots. He slips away every day
Didn't the Mohini Sindoor work?
Does Chotti Bahu use it?
Yes. On her forehead and in her hair parting
A mark as large as a rupee coin
But it's no use
It's all my fault, Bansi
If I hadn't given the Sindoor to Chotti Bahu...
Are you worse? We have been
so worried about you
Suvinay Babu, I must go.
I cannot stay any longer
Why? Do you lack anything?
No, you have cared for me well
- Then why leave?
I cannot stay. In giving
Sindoor to someone, I have...
...done her injustice
Why didn't you tell me?
Bansi, how is Bhoothnath?
The doctor says he'll be
skipping about in a few days
See that he lacks nothing.
I shall pay for every medicine
Was that Chotti Bahu?
Yes, that door leads
to the room of Chotti Bahu
Then this room must be
in the women's quarters
It is and it isn't
It is a secret room
But the mansion has many
rooms; why put me in this one?
Perhaps Chotti Bahu ordered
it, to keep you under her care
I'm run off my feet here
Bansi
I'm fortunate you're here
Where is that fool?
Sit here for a while, I'll call Bansi
I'll find him
- Listen to me
Something to say?
Only that I haven't seen you for many days
Well, take a good look now.
Satisfied?
A look. To see you all my life
would not be enough for me
What nonsense you talk. I'll be late
You go there every day.
Stay with me just once
I am a man,
not a bunch of keys tied to your sari
Just for today.
Give me a chance to serve you
Why do you laugh?
Do you know how to serve?
Give me a chance, then you will know
I am a Chaudhary. I have hot blood in my veins
The women of this mansion cannot serve us
I'm not like the other wives;
I come from a poor family
I can do everything to please my husband
Can you sing to please me?
Will you like my songs?
Not devotional songs - romantic
songs, such as Cunni Dasi sings
Will you sing, dance and drink wine?
Wine?
Will you drink wine all night with me?
You wanted to serve me
How can you serve me?
Bhoothnath, come here
Come over here
I am here
It's so dark
It is better not to see my face today
Today I have summoned you to do something...
...that should make a woman die of shame
Die of shame?
Yes, Bhoothnath
Who else but you could I tell?
There is no one but you
to understand my torment
Why summon me?
No one should know
Bring me wine
You will drink?
I shall have to drink
I shall do whatever he wishes
He wants me to drink wine
So I shall drink
If you become addicted, you will be ruined
What if I am ruined?
If a man does not love his wife,
she has no place in this world
I shall not bring wine for you
You must. This is my last hope.
- I will not
You must, or I shall never win my husband
No, I cannot bear to see you destroyed
You are fond of me, aren't you?
If you really want me to be happy,
do this for me
Bring wine for me
For my sake
My dear Lord
Where were you?
- Fetching dried fruit for you
The dried fruit is here.
Now more excuses
Drink
Go on. I shall drink later
I have drunk alone too long.
Now you take some
Go on. Drink
No courage?
No, it's not that
Will I get very drunk?
No matter how drunk,
you will look just as beautiful
Look away
Are you shy of me?
Start
It's bitter
I'll show you
Kingdoms do not last.
Palaces do not endure
These mansions will not endure
May I come in?
We were just thinking of you
Did you get my message?
You're ill?
I have been unwell since the day you left
I have given up the Sindoor business
Given it up? Why?
You ask why?
Bhoothnath, I have much to say to you
Jabba, go and bring that letter
For many days I have felt a certain apprehension
Apprehension?
You were born in Fatehpur,
Nadia district?
Yes. Why?
Your parents died when you were a child?
When I was four
In his old age, father lived in Fatehpur
Was your father's name...
Five hundred rupees for you
- For me?
Keep them
I promised Master to care for you;
now I cannot give work
Do not refuse the money,
or I shall have no peace
Why distress father, when he is so unwell?
Take this letter of introduction to Mr. Rupchand
He is a big contractor;
he will give you a good job
Thank you
There is something else
Jabba is my only daughter.
Now she is of age to marry
Father, the doctor told you not to talk much
Should I stand on ceremony with him?
You can see how my health is
That's why I want Jabba
to marry next month
I cannot do that
without your help, Bhoothnath
I am unworthy
I have utmost faith in you. I am an ill man
Tend to the marriage formalities
I have found a good husband for her
He is Supavitar
Come in, Mr. Dharamdas
I'll come again
"My unspoken words lie sealed in my heart"
"l was so confused, I could not utter a word"
"My dreams remain unfulfilled..."
"as the fire spreads in my life"
"My unspoken words lie sealed in my heart"
"l was so confused, I could not utter a word"
"O beloved, my sweet love"
"You have entered my very soul"
"My eyes plead with you..."
"but you do not hear my cry of pain"
"Although the rain fell,
my heart remained parched"
"My unspoken words lie sealed in my heart"
"l was so confused, I could not utter a word"
"We could have talked,
we could have listened"
"Why did you leave me with a broken heart?"
"My life is plunged into darkness"
"The light of hope is extinguished"
"My life is cloaked in darkness"
"My unspoken words lie sealed in my heart"
"l was so confused, I could not utter a word"
"Wherever you are, my love..."
"you will always be near me"
"How can I live without you?"
"How can I love again?"
"There has never been another for me"
"My unspoken words lie sealed in my heart"
"l was so confused, I could not utter a word"
"My dreams remain unfulfilled..."
"as the fire spreads in my life"
"My unspoken words lie sealed in my heart"
"l was so confused, I could not utter a word"
Bhoothnath? Come over here
Chotti Bahu, are you unwell?
Why should I be?
These days, it's like spring again
I have some money. May I leave
it with you? I have no strong-box
No? We'll give you a thousand
Fetch Bansi
No, you keep it.
How can I keep it safe?
Silly fellow, your Chotti Bahu isn't dead
Come nearer to me. Come closer
Are you afraid of me?
I cannot do it.
Take this key...
...and put your rupees in the safe
Give me that glass
I ache all over
Your troubles are caused by the wine
You don't know
As soon as I drink, I feel alive again
Give it to me
You're addicted
I'm not addicted, but...
But what?
I am lost in intoxication with my husband
He wants me to drink, so I drink
Do you know,
he stays at home every night now
I am very happy
Don't you see that I am putting on weight?
Give me the glass
No, you can hardly move.
Don't drink any more
Should I obey you,
rather than my husband?
Give me the glass, I shall drink
Empty the glass then,
give peace to your soul
Yes, who are you to interfere?
Shame on you
Shame?
What's that to do with it?
No other member of the
Chaudhary family has done...
...what Chotte Babu has done for me
Now he is mine alone
I am not ashamed. I am proud
Will you drink more?
- What if I do?
No, you shall not
Have you any command over me?
Yes, you may drink before
Chotte Babu, but not before me
You dare to touch me?
The wife of another?
Go away!
You're learning the overseer's work quickly
Do you study at home?
I've been learning from
M r. Banerji at night
Every night?
So you've been too busy to call
at Mr. Suvinay's house?
Go there today; he is seriously ill
How is your father?
Is Supavitar asleep? Wake him
He must be exhausted
Tell him to go home
How can he go?
Your father is seriously ill
Supavitar has responsibilities as
his future son-in-law
No, he has no responsibilities towards me
Even if he doesn't want to go, he has to
How is father?
Why didn't you wake me?
Go home, Supavitar
Go home? Why?
Never return. Try to forget me, if you can
What are you saying?
Do as I say. Go
Bhoothnath, come into the other room
Father has died
There's talk...
...that they're going to buy a motor-car
We will lose our jobs
When was my job ever safe?
They'll give up smoking hookahs...
...and smoke foreign cigarettes instead
They plan to sell the land and buy coal mines
How stupid! Who incited them?
Sethji, I have persuaded my masters
to buy your mines
And you give me only 50,000 rupees
Very well, take 1 0,000 more
Mr. Robertson, a cheque for 20,000
Have you made the necessary enquiries?
M r. Robertson, mining expert,
says the mines are excellent
The mine is very good
Chotte Babu, read this agreement
Where do I sign?
Where is the elder brother?
His signature...
It will be done
Cheni Dutt's pigeons have flown
Cheni Dutt has lost
The Chaudhary's do not dare
to challenge me
Release my pigeons
Sir, these are his pigeons
Let's showthese Chaudharys
We've beaten them, Master
Master, the coal mines
agreement for signature
Our valiant pigeons have brought
four rival pigeons home
Take a 1,000 to the Chaudharys.
Ask them to return my pigeons
Did you call me?
I need a reliable man
to supervise my work in Munghair
If you go there I'll have no worries
When do I leave?
Tonight. You'll have to stay many months
Go and collect money for your expenses
Eat something. How much
longer will you torment yourself?
Not only yourself, but Supavitar, too
Supavitar?
- Yes
He met me outside. Why did you
stop him coming here?
How can I let him?
Why not? Your father
arranged your marriage
What is the hindrance?
You are both Brahmo Samaji
Yes, but how can I break other ties?
Ties that go back generations.
How can l?
Jabba, please speak plainly
You remember the day when father died
You two were in the other room
Something happened on that day.
It seems like a dream
It changed me completely
What do you mean?
Father told me that day
When I was one year old
my grandfather took me away...
...and in accordance with
Sanata family rites...
... he had me married
Married!
Yes, when I was 1 year old
What is happening now, Yasin?
Chotte Babu's going out again
- Yes!
Long live Chotte Babu.
May the round of pleasure go on!
The carriage is ready
Will you go out again?
I've been at home so long that I'm stifling
Let me have a change of air
You've stayed so many days.
Did you get comfort from me?
A wife can give comfort,
but it's not the same thing
"lf you will not stay, what will become of me?"
"Beloved, do not leave
the gentle embrace of my arms"
"My eyes will fill with tears"
"This cascade of hair,
these kohl-darkened eyes..."
"this glittering veil, the desire in my heart"
"This cascade of hair,
these kohl-darkened eyes..."
"this glittering veil, the desire in my heart"
"All this is for you alone"
"Today I shall not let you go"
" Beloved, do not leave
the gentle embrace of my arms"
"My eyes will fill with tears"
"l am devoted to you, I thirst for you"
"You are my love, the light of my life"
"l shall take the dust
from beneath your feet..."
"and powder my brow with it,
now and for ever"
"Beloved, do not leave
the gentle embrace of my arms"
"My eyes will fill with tears"
"You who elude me..."
"l implore you to heed me"
"I implore you to heed me"
"I am all yours,
I am at your feet"
"Here shall I live,
here shall I die"
What surprising about that?
It is every wife's duty to live
and die in her husband's house
Then do something
Just forget I am your wife
What?
Keep me like those women
in Badan Bari
I shall live there happily
At least I'll be able to see you
They change their names,
don't they?
If you like, give me a new name,
any name you like
Are you in your right mind?
If you did that, our family
would be dishonoured
Then what should I do?
Do what the elder
sister-in-law does
Refurbish old ornaments,
play kauris, sleep with ease
You laugh?
You are comparing me
with them?
Refurbish old ornaments?
Play kauris?
Where are you going?
Answer me
Do you think I'm like
the other daughters-in-law?
Aren't you? Have you descended
from heaven?
If I am not different, why am I
fated to this torment?
Has any other wife made
such a great sacrifice?
Being good Hindu women,
have they drunk wine?
Why so silent? Speak
Answer me
How could you compare me
to the others?
Do I have what they have?
What have you given me?
I have no one to call me mother
What do you want to say?
I drink, but I don't
become mad, like you
You say I'm mad?
Is that what you say?
Get the carriage.
Chotti Bahu is going out
She's going out? Really?
It's a disaster, Master
Cheni Dutt and
Chotte Babu fought
Dare he do such a thing?
What's going on, Chotte Babu?
He's unconscious,
drenched in blood
You're back!
What has happened?
You haven't seen the worst.
Look there
Everything has been sold off
How is Chotti Bahu?
The day that Chotte Babu
come home wounded, she fell ill
They say that Chotte Babu
is paralysed
Now he has stopped drinking
But what about Chotti Bahu?
- Better not ask
Look at the mansion
I haven't been paid
for seven months
How did it all happen?
The coal mines
ruined everything
My masters
did not check properly
They were cheated.
There's no coal, only rock
Just look at what is happening
I want my money. 1500 rupees
My five thousand
- My three thousand
Just wait a few more days;
the money is on the way
When did you return?
- Today
Good. Do something for me.
Bring some wine
Haven't you given it up?
I shall, from tomorrow
Take this
I have nothing else left
And you want me to sell it
to buy such stuff?
You think you will give it up
tomorrow, but you never will
Look at the mansion
Chotte Babu is ill and you
won't come to your senses
You speak to me in this way?
Drinking has robbed you
of house, family and husband
Who are you to lecture me?
If I don't serve my husband,
then who does?
For his sake,
I've sacrificed everything
I have even sacrificed my God
You say it is my fault?
How can you say such a thing?
Who is there?
Who was he?
- Teacher's brother-in-law
Do you want to speak?
Do you want to see me happy?
Yes, completely
Then stop drinking wine,
Chotti Bahu
Leave it
Drinking has
a devastating effect
What can I do? I can't stop
A man can stop drinking,
but a woman...
I am not like other women,
I'm not
I can do everything for you
I began drinking for you,
I can stop drinking for you
You'll see. From tomorrow
I'll not touch another drop
You won't drink?
- Not at all
I won't drink even a little drop
I returned a while ago; I came
to see you as soon as I could
I've thought of you very much
Really?
You're from Nadia District?
I was married there
If the family wanted to accept
you, why have they kept silent?
Who can tell why?
My father
took the secret with him
Your husband
may have remarried
I'm still his wife
Maybe he is bad
and won't make you happy
That is my misfortune.
- He may think you are bad
Will he accept you?
That's what I want to know
Why do you stop me
from finding out?
Jabba, I want to help you.
I'll do whatever you want
Get me his address
I found a letter
in father's papers
Grandmother wrote secretly
without telling my grandfather
She named my husband
Atulya Chakravarty?
Why look at me like that?
Do you know him?
Perhaps
I'll make enquiries
about the marriage
Master, there has been
no work for us lately
Master, our weapons are rusting
Hurry, you must go
to the city with Chotti Bahu
The city? At this hour?
To see a great saint.
I have hired a carriage
We've waited for you
since this morning
Don't worry. I won't be long
I've heard that the saint
of Barey Nagar is a true saint
He will certainly cure you
I'll be back soon
Did you call me?
I'll be back very soon
Let's hurry, Bhoothnath
Tell the driver to drive fast
Who went there?
- Teacher's brother-in-law
How is Chhote Babu?
I worry about him ceaselessly
His condition is worsening
May God give him my life
My life...
When I die, make sure
that I am adorned in splendour
Did you hear?
Adorned in splendour
Adorn my brow with Sindoor
the bridal vermilion...
so everyone will know...
...I was a devoted wife
Don't talk like this
In this
lies the peace of my soul
May God bless him
with my lifespan
No one else understood me...
besides you
Tell me... why don't you marry?
Marry?
How I longed
for a happy family life
How happy I would be
to welcome a daughter-in-law
Bring a wife to me;
I shall adorn her
I am married
When?
What has happened?
What about Chhoti Bahu?
There is no trace of her. The
day you left in the carriage...
I was turned out
of the mansion
Now I am working as a coolie
Don't the servants know
where Chhoti Bahu is?
I asked everyone
There is no trace
of Chotti Bahu
The mansion is now a ruin
The master is living
with his in-laws
And is Chotte Babu
still in the mansion?
Chotte Babu has passed away
Overseer, we have found a grave
A grave, in this mansion?
Chotti Bahu
Make sure that I am adorned
in splendour
Adorn my brow with Sindoor,
the bridal vermilion
So everyone will know
I was a devoted wife
A devoted wife