lf not the first year, l've to give you
something at least the second year, no?
Where did you get
the money for this?
Where did you get the money?
You sold your bike!?
But you love your bike so much...
But l love you even more.
But...l haven't got you anything.
- Oh, that's a problem.
Now you have to gift me
whatever l want!
Nothing naughty!
Should've thought of it before
marrying a naughty guy!
''On hot summer nights...''
''l burn in the rain.''
''Lost in memories every moment.
What's my poor heart to do.''
''Lost in my own thoughts am l.''
''l mean to say one thing...
And say something else.''
''l suffer a strange pain.
What's my poor heart to do.''
''Gazing into your eyes...''
''Even as we talk...''
''One gets...''
''And one gives...''
''Love's sweet salute.''
''All day l miss something.''
''l don't know what l desire.''
''l am alone even in a crowd.
What's my poor heart to do.''
''l've forgotten the day,
month and year.''
''l sweat even in January.''
''l find peace nowhere.
What's my poor heart to do.''
''Gazing into your eyes..''
''Even as we talk...''
''One gets...''
''And one gives...''
''Love's sweet salute.''
''When l sit, l sit there forever.''
''When l walk, l keep
walking...very far.''
''Restless, l lose all my senses.''
''l smile through tears.''
''Someone stirs half-awake in memory.
What's my poor heart to do.''
''Gazing into your eyes..''
''Even as we talk...''
''One gets...''
''And one gives...
Love's sweet salute.''
Sorry, l'll send the money.
Hey, you are a man in love.
Who's asking for money?
l reached you on time, didn't l?
- Don't know...Perhaps l'm late.
Late? Not to worry, mate.
When two people are truly in love,
they'll get together in the end.
Can't find the word...
Even so, all the best.
Strike up!
''Gazing into your eyes...''
''Even as we talk...''
''One gets...''
''And one gives...''
''Love's sweet salute.''
We're now a little further
from Madgaon station...
...where this new train
has just been inaugurated.
The Goa Mumbai Holiday Express.
The Railway Ministry says...
lt's not just a train but
a romantic experience.
Everyone here is with
someone they love.
But for those who are alone...
...don't give up hope.
Because on this channel you will be
a part of this romantic journey...
...with Tehzeeb Hussain Raina.
So, let's go.
''lf people want to call me wild...''
''Let them! l don't care.''
Let go...
Why?
l'm feeling very hot.
- That's normal, silly.
Don't you know why?
- Fire... it's raging.
You silly, this fire is in the
front side, not at the backside.
lt's at the backside.
- Silly girl, what backside!
Father! Fire!
Help!!
''A sonnet of some poet,
O Dream girl...''
''A lotus of beauty. O Dream girl...''
''Somewhere someday l will find her...''
''lf not today, tomorrow.''
Salaam, uncle.
- Salaam to you, son.
Son, come down to earth
from your dreams.
How long will you keep on
dreaming the same dream?
lt's not a dream, uncle.
A fact of future truth.
You'll see, uncle.
This door will open one day...
Light will shine all over...
A playful breeze will blow,
bells will ring...
Conch blowing auspiciously,
drums rolling...
Celestial dancers will shower flowers
and a white Memsahib will walk
towards me and she will say...
Come, my heart's true love...
Take me to the Taj...
You've gone crazy, Raju.
All your friends have got married.
Even my Ahmed...
whom you dandled on your knee
it's his turn to marry now.
Here.
- Congratulations, uncle.
May Allah bring the day when
l can congratulate you.
Listen to me, son.
Find a nice girl and get married.
Stop living in dreams.
ls a life without dreams worth living?
How can you say that!
O Allah, what'll happen to this boy!
Only what God wills
will come to happen.
Who the hell...?
- Ashu, Tehzeeb is in an accident...
that train...can you hear me?
We are a little away from
Sawantwadi junction...
...where this terrible
accident took place.
The Goa Mumbai Holiday Express
has been derailed.
This train was inaugurated today.
Tehzeeb Hussain Raina, our reporter
was covering the event.
lt's Makkad here, Vinayji.
- Makkad who?
What do you mean? Forgotten me already?
lt's me, Balwinder Singh Makkad.
Are you lost or what?
Hey buddy, where's your
mind these days!
Yes, tell me, Makkad Saheb. How
kind of you to think of me.
Oh, we think of you day and night.
Don't forget.
You know our Simi is getting married.
Kkamini's dance is must.
Don't worry. We've signed
the contract with Kkamini.
Just wait and watch. lt'll
be an explosive act.
Friends...
Tonight is a Special for our Shivu.
When Kkamini came to know
Shivu was getting married...
...Kkamini couldn't stop herself.
She came running...
Everyone said...
Crazy girl, what will you
do at a bachelors' party?
Then Kkamini said...
You fools...
Kkamini is also a bachelor.
lsn't she?
Hey, isn't she?
On behalf of us all...
we'll miss you.
''Without you, my love...''
''My heart is restless.''
''Every moment is a torment...''
''...for my raging desire.''
''Don't go abandoning your lover.''
''Lover O mine...''
''These fair entwining arms... ''
''These, my bangles...''
''My bracelets...''
''They'll haunt your memory,
O my lover.''
''Left to you are but a few moments
of your careless bachelor days.''
''Don't go, abandoning your lover.''
''Lover O mine...''
''These my alluring charms,
this body of mine...''
''These kohl-lined eyes,
darkly beguiling...''
''This magic...''
''This intoxication, this addiction...''
''This addiction is sweet sharp pain.''
''Oh, this fragrance!''
''Your alluring charms...''
''Your heady youth...''
''Where will l find them now,
my love-crazy girl!''
''The passionate promise of
this flaming beauty...''
''The dark hair cascading
down these shoulders...''
''Left to you are but a few moments
of your careless bachelor days.''
''Don't go, abandoning your lover.''
''Forget these nights.
Now they are gone.''
''All these things are now gone,
listen my love.''
''No more this solace,
be gone my love.''
''No more this love.
A thirsty guest you'll remain.''
''Don't deceive me like this.''
''Don't punish me like this.''
''That l may gain some peace...''
''...please offer a prayer.''
''My swaying earrings...''
''My thrusting hip...''
''They are not for you anymore.''
''Left to you are but a few moments
of your careless bachelor days.''
''Don't go, abandoning your lover.''
''No, no, no. Don't go.''
''Lover O mine... Lover O mine...''
''Don't go, abandoning your lover.''
Why!? Why's everyone after Kkamini?
Because that's what you want.
Babu, are you Kkamini's manager
or of those journos?
Yours, 100%.
What's this?
- Three new item numbers...
Cabaret, nautch-girl number, cabaret.
Dance directors of your choice.
Kkamini is not an ltem Queen.
l want to be a Tragedy Queen.
...like Meena Kumari...
Nargis...
Madhubala..
Madhuri...
Karan Johar...
- Karan Johar?
Why doesn't Karan Johar ever call me?
Because a Karan Johar film needs not
an ltem Girl, a heroine..
..who has no scandals.
She's a simple girl who could be
a daughter, sister, daughter-in-law...
She has one hero, just one hero.
True love...
True and pure.
Oh, that so?
- What?
And Kkamini...
ln ethnic wear...
and goggles
Just one photo...
One question.
- ls this true?
No, this is a lie!
lt's a plot, a conspiracy!
Kkamini did not go to
any party last night.
Somebody morphed Kkamini's face.
Kkamini doesn't even know how to swim!
The Press has gone mad. You come to
rescue Kkamini but you slip...
You will mention his name.
- Whose?
His!
- His? Whose?
Oh, anybody's!
- Rahul...?
Who is he?
- Who is Rahul?
Tell us.
Who is this Rahul?
Rahul is Kkamini's very life!
Kkamini's whole world...
Rahul is Kkamini's faith.
This means, Kkamini...
- ...is having an affair with Rahul?
NO! Don't call it an affair.
This is love...
Kkamini's true love.
l kept it hidden all this time,
but not anymore. Because...
Why fear when you love.
Why heave sighs in silence.
Do you know what you're doing?
Kkamini knows everything.
Kkamini is not a fool.
Sir, l'm Dotcom Paaji.
Don't you worry about the plan,
my princely bridegroom.
Nothing to worry, sir. Get into the car
and we'll go straight to Udaipur.
Why Udaipur? We told you to finalise
the match with Colonel Bakshi of Delhi.
Forget it. l'll show you better stuff.
- One minute...
What can be better than Col. Bakshi?
Good family, rich, first class Punjabi.
You're correct, sir. Col. Bakshi agreed
but it's his daughter who's to marry.
She expired.
- There! Your marriage is jinxed.
Getting into a flap again ! She expired.
- No sir, what l meant...
He was in a flap, all
the way from Canada...
You're right, sir. But l didn't
say the girl had expired...
l meant, her wedding date had expired.
Some guy had in his tender earlier
and the girl opened it herself.
Oh, this messes up the whole deal!
- Makes no difference.
We'll open our tender somewhere else.
ls there any shortage of girls here!
No shortage... l will see
to it you get married this time.
Sir, wait here. l'll be back
in a couple of minutes.
Here l go.. Here l go..
ls he arranging a marriage
or fixing a deal?
For your son, it's his marriage.
But for him it's a deal, right?
- Mom says...
l've heard what she has to say
for 30 long years! Go sit in the car.
But this is a taxi...
- Get in. Want a slap in public?
Yes...Tell me.
Tell what?
Say, destination, sir.
Destination...
Where do you want to go, your lordship?
- Ok...all right. Deal. So tell me.
What am l to tell you?
- Where we are to go.
Why'll l tell you that!
- Why won't you? The Sardarji said...
You're the one who's travelling.
lf the Sardarji told you...
then go ask him! Why ask me!
- Hang on. Don't get angry. He's right.
Let's ask the Sardarji.
So tell me.
Tell you what now!
- Where's the Sardarji?
Tell us that at least.
- Don't chew up my brain !
Get down from my car!
He's your Sardarji. So you go find him.
Thief! Thief!! Thief! Thief!!
Thief? Then tell the police. A Sardar
has given me enough tension already.
You solve your tension in jail!
You don't know who l am.
l'm Dotcom Paaji!
People steal luggage. This guy steals
passengers wholesale! You thief! Cheat!
To the police station ! All of you.
You've kids, Sahebji?
- Yes. You'll give them candy?
How did you know? Are
you an astrologer?
How do l say it...can't find the word
... Pollution everywhere.
l'll be there in 5 minutes.
- So early!?
You're merely four and
half hours late.
What should l say? l'm a changed man.
Yes...lt's all in the papers,
how you've changed.
But after the wedding you're gonna be
just my boy.
Am l crazy? Will l dare take
on a Col. Bakshi daughter?
The entire lndian army
will be after me!
So the wedding is on because
you're afraid of Papa?
Can't you take a joke?
Then why are you getting married?
- Because you said so.
What if l hadn't asked?
Shiven, what if l hadn't asked?
l'll be there in 3 minutes.
You say it too.
Actually, Juggy is with me...
What's he doing there? You always
said he's such a bore...
l'm there already.
l don't believe this, buddy.
You're getting married!
Why, you got the card, didn't you?
But seriously, your life
is going to change, buddy
There will be only Gia in your life
and you will be... Gia's hubby deah !
All the time, asleep or awake,
there'll be only one name, Gia...
And for her, Gia's hubby deah !
And then, the kids...
With her, the grinning husband,
Gia's hubby deah !
l can see the whole tree before me...
And with her, Gia's hubby deah !
Marry...
l don't want to be Gia's hubby deah !
Thank you.
- Me? But... what did l do?
You saved me...
Nobody in our family has
got married to this day.
But you...?
You don't understand, Juggy.
We are all ill-fated...
Look at that...
She was in my arms the other day.
Now l'm to be Gia's hubby deah?
This is love.
Kkamini's true love.
ls Rahul a lie...
- or the truth...
We have to find out!
- But we have little time...
Because ls Kkamini going to London...
- with Rahul.
Or without Rahul.
- LET'S FlND OUT...
THE TRUTH ABOUT THE lTEM BOMB.
Are you going to London for
a show or to meet Rahul?
Does Rahul live in London?
- Rahul who? Gandhi or Bajaj?
Look, l have already said this
is Kkamini's personal life.
What's all this? lt puts me
under tension.
You must always stay relaxed
under tension, right?
This is only the beginning.
Just wait and watch.
Aren't the seats together, Babu?
- l had them reserved together.
Together.
You are with Mr. Rahul and
he is right behind you.
Mr. Rahul... who?
Rahul who?
Mr. Rahul, your...
- My...?
Ma'am, your childhood...
ls there any privacy
in a public place?
Openly and boldly we'll show our love.
But how long can we keep it hidden?
So many questions...
Lies...allegations...
And you, all alone...
How long will you answer these cruel,
heartless journalists of this industry?
Truth had to come out someday.
l have come...
your Raooul...
Actually, Rahul who
belongs to you all.
Life is a game.
Some pass some fail.
Could be a naive loser.
Or a skilled gamester.
Do you get it, dear sir?
Vinay, l think it's your
birthday today...
And everyone is waiting
downstairs for...
What're you doing?
Nothing...Just getting ready
for my 40th birthday party.
You aren't even dressed yet!
Pappu uncle sent mail. Email him.
- Yes.
Dad's elder brother and sister called.
Call them back.
Yes.
- Call at 2. lt'll be 7 there.
- Am l putting on weight?
Yes.
- Yes...!?
lt's just that Malini said...
Am l looking rather healthy?
Has Malini ever seen herself
in the mirror?
Kick up a storm!
A storm! A storm!
Pappu uncle sent mail.
Call at 2. lt'll be 7 there.
Am l putting on weight?
Listen. You are all coming,
aren't you?
Yes, we are coming.
- Seema said there was some show...
Don't come too late.
- Yes, Kkamini's show...
Listen, come soon.
We miss you all very much.
That Dungarpur cur ran away!
Dad, you just jabber away....
Give me the phone.
Yes sir?
- Happy birthday, son.
That Dungarpur guy has gone missing!
But don't get your tickets refunded.
There's a very good NRl match
in the pipeline.
Dad, give me the phone!
Don't listen to Dad.
What happened?
- Seema, just a sec...
Your mother's call.
Daddy said Shiven ran away.
Gia, what's happening?
- Nothing at all...
Shiven was to come to lunch today...
but he didn't.
So Dad is kicking up a ruckus.
Gia, give Dad the phone.
Sis, don't you start now!
l'll handle Shiven.
Anyways l ought to be miffed!
You aren't coming to
the pre-wedding do!
What can l do, Gia.
He has a big event here, with Kkamini.
You'd better watch Bro-in-law then !
Where's Tehzeeb?
- l don't know!
Are you really sure?
- Yes...
This is not my Tehzeeb...
...not my Tehzeeb.
Doctor, they've found injured
survivors in the next village.
''Somewhere someday l will find her...''
''lf not today, tomorrow...''
Please come in. Treat this
as your own house.
What to do!
- Come on ! At a time like this...
who else but a neighbour is of help!
- Ruined our honour!
C'mon
What're you doing, Juggy?
Are you making fun of me?
l'll strangle you !
Drunk eh, deah chap?
- l'll break your jaw!
No! l didn't mean that deah !
Why don't you do something, Juggy!
What can l do?
l will refuse.
- Refuse to marry...?
You go tell her.
- How can l go and tell her?
l'll speak. And record it.
l'll do everything. All you have
to do is give her the disc.
How can l...?
- You can't say no now.
You can't say no, buddy.
ls it on?
- l can't do this.
lt's a question of my life.
l can't get married!
Listen, marriage won't
cause me any harm...
But you will be ruined!
You'll become fat.
Every woman does. Right, Juggy?
Look at your Mom.
And l'll be screaming
at you all the time.
l'll go mad.
Do you want that?
Look at your Dad.
This is for your happiness...
- Don't do this, buddy.
lf Gia ever comes to know, she'll
really call off the wedding.
ls it possible for it to happen?
- What to happen?
That Gia calls it off, not me?
lf your stupidity continues...
Then yes.
What did l do now?
- You didn't do anything...
But now you will.
l will do it! Definitely today.
l won't let it go.
Fatty!
l won't let you go.
Kids...
What is it?
Five kids...
Have patience...one by one,
you'll have them all.
Right now...
Don't you know even that, you silly?
For 5, it'll take 5 years.
Why'll it take so long?
They're right behind you.
Behind...?
Behind.
Who the hell...?
How come, Guru?
The same dream day and night.
But she never comes, my Dree...
Guru will give the sign...
Signal...
The day the Dream girl
is to arrive...
Light will shine all over...
A playful breeze will blow..
Bells will ring...
Auspicious conch blown...
Drums rolling...
The sky will shower flowers...
The gates of heaven will open...
Celestial dancers will
hover in attendance...
From their midst, the
Dream girl will emerge
Then she'll say...
An emperor built the beautiful
Taj Mahal...
And gave the whole world...
...this symbol of love.
Madam, welcome to Taj...
Taj...
You tell Taj...
Which hotel?
Big mistake! Hotel Taj...?
No police!
Please listen, madam!
Very far...
For the love of God!
What are you doing?
No! No one here. Only Raju here!
l'll put it back together...
Where're you going?
with strangers? Not good!
Your permit?
- Don't have permit, brother.
l had to give her this...
That's what everyone says.
Careful, dear sir! Watch your step.
''Watch your step, dear sir.''
''Be careful in love.''
''Yes, there are so many dangers...''
''There are so many dangers
in the path of love.''
''Why are you looking lost,
your head hanging down?''
''You walk away as if you've
lost everything.''
''This is just the first
step, dear sir...''
''Your very own seem uncaring
like strangers.''
''Yes, there are so many dangers...''
''There are so many dangers
in the path of love.''
''lf you have fallen
out with someone...''
''Then clasp the hand of another.''
''Strange are the ways of this life.''
''lf alone, you have a million foes.''
''Yes, there are so many dangers...''
''There are so many dangers
in the path of love.''
''Watch your step, dear sir.''
This... l think this...
l thought l had lost it forever.
l don't know how to...
You !
What are you doing here?
Malini said Bollywood dancing
is best for exercise.
That's full...
l know. He told me just now.
Are you feeling all right?
- What'll happen to me?
lt happens...it always happens
this way the first time.
That's how the class is.
- That's how the class is.
Kkamini's show, you know...
Mr. Makkad's daughter's wedding.
lt's full now. Want to see
Bollywood dancing for next term, lady?
l'm very hungry.
lt's been so long since
we had lunch together.
l've to pick up Rohan and Shai
from school.
l'll go along.
We'll lunch together.
Listen...
- What happened?
You better keep your distance
from Kkamini.
Malini said she's a maneater!
What nonsense!
Who's he to follow us like this?
You shouldn't walk so
fast at your age.
Tip the Bell Gramps.
Not rupees, pounds.
- Pounds?
All. All.
Who is this, Babu?
Who on earth are you?
Rahul...Kkamini's childhood
sweetheart.
Baby, he's your childhood...
He doesn't know Kkamini!
l'll call the police right away.
The truth about Rahul will come out.
And Kkamini's lie will be caught.
- Never!
No, Kkamini, no!
Work with Karan?
Be on 'Koffee with Karan'?
You take care of Karan,
l'll handle this guy.
Well, what's it that you want?
Who are you?
You're not Rahul. We all know it.
She knows l am not Rahul.
You know l am not Rahul.
l know l am not Raooul.
But...do these people
know l am not Rahul?
Kkamini, look who's at our door!
The world famous journalist duo...
Amar-Prem
Famous?
- Oh yes.
l've seen so many of your shows.
Bell Gramps...
You kept my bags here along with
Kkamini's luggage. My room no. is 309.
lt's okay.
He thinks l'm staying with Kkamini.
You're not staying together?
ln our culture, before marriage
... no chance.
Do you guys stay together?
We... no!
lt was a pleasure meeting you.
Me too.
By the way, you two can stay together,
you know.
Come, let's get down
to some real talk.
Who am l?
- Who?
Don !
l mean, the hero of this film.
Look, whether you agree or not,
your audience agrees.
l don't want to hear it!
So don't hear...Just think...
Two hearts are falling in love.
But slowly, silently.
Love and Passion.
Eternal Love.
Page 3.
Kkamini's grand show...
And with Kkamini, Rahul!
Kkamini's image has changed.
And then...then...
Then?
l'm Karan Johar speaking.
ls Ms. Kkamini there?
Yes, l am! l'm here!
l am here for you !
What do you want in return?
Nothing...
To be with you, for a moment or two.
Not physical, not emotional.
Only a moment or two.
You can't believe it, do you?
ln that case, 10 million.
Babu, just throw him out!
Babu, why don't you do something?
Have you gone mad?
- Yes, l had gone mad!
l was mad the day l listened
to your plan.
Sensational news!
Look. You want 10 million? Given.
No tricks.
- Never.
Work done, cash down.
Then you disappear!
Of course.
Oh yes, l haven't forgotten
the relatives who have yet to come...
... and those already here.
Auntyji..!
Hold on to him... tight!
What's going on, Shiven?
Lunch was the other day, not today.
Where had you disappeared to?
- l'm sorry l am late, Papa.
You're late by two
full days, Shiven !
Sorry, l was stuck at work.
- Work!
When do you ever work anyways?
l'm very scared, buddy.
- Who gave you this number?
Don't ever phone again !
Papa, she says l'm the father
of the baby she's expecting.
Last time too when l was
about to get married...
You were to get married earlier too?
- Oh, didn't l tell you?
Sorry, l forgot.
l'm going to have your baby.
- She's here!
This is a last warning, got it?
l'll report you to the police!
l will report to the police now.
Let's go, Gia. The
wedding's cancelled.
You heard it right,
Shiven Dungarpur!
l didn't hear it at all, Papa.
Will you say it louder?
Shiven Dungarpur!
l'm handling it!
Didn't l tell you to...?
Shiven Dungarpur!
l'm going to have your baby.
Your sin is growing in my womb!
But l don't want even your
dirty shadow to fall on my baby!
This baby doesn't need
his father's name.
Ask me why.
Ask me why!
- Why?
- Because he'll have his mother!
Joke!
lt was all a joke!
ls everything recorded? Everything?
What a wonderful job, man !
Hold on to him... tight!
How are you?
Liar!
Afraid, weren't you?
You must have thought...
What'll you do if something
happens to me?
Find somebody...
- What?
lf something happens to me, find
a nice, sensible girl and marry her.
Has your fever gone up again?
Shall l call the doctor?
You talk such utter nonsense!
l'm not joking. l mean it.
- What?
Find a nice sensible girl...
What do you mean okay?
- Okay means okay.
Will you really find somebody else?
- That's what you told me to.
How is she?
- Who?
That one you'll marry
after l am gone... is she pretty?
Yes. So what?
- Prettier than me?
Listen, Mr. Different!
Stop dreaming.
Nobody else will come
into your life. You know why?
Because l'm not going anywhere!
Are you leaving?
Hear me?
l am never going to leave you.
l'm never going to leave you.
Hear me?
This is exactly what l
don't like about you.
You had me all stirred up,
and you calmly watch the fun.
Taj...Taj...
Who was to give me the sign
for the hotel, O lord?
Why are you just looking on !
Go and rescue her.
Find her. Fi...nd...
You are crying?
You should be partying!
Have a party! They took your stuff..
but left you alone, didn't they?
Does it ever happen? No, never!
lf they had molested...
l can't find the word.
lt was my Guru who saved you.
Yes, he saved you.
l've seen him...
He... who?
Your brother?
Nooooooo!
l can't tell you where Paaji and
Mr. Chaddha went. lt's a trade secret.
Sure?
- Sure.
You...out...going.
You...out...going for two minutes.
Sure?
You...inside...coming. Come in.
Laugh ! Then spit out the info.
Dotcom Paaji went first to Udaipur
with the Chadha family.
This is the address.
lf the deal doesn't work out..
..on then to Rishikesh...
Address no.2.
And then Jammu.
Address no.3.
What are you doing?
- l am taking you on a drive.
Let go. Someone will see.
You silly, who'll see what?
Even l've seen nothing till now.
Phoolwati, let me go
Cock-a-doodle doo!
How does it feel?
l feel as if the whole
world is spinning.
Yeah...it'll spin...and rock...
My stupid son burned
down the house.
But you are so generous, O Lord.
You gave us a new house.
Let no calamity befall
this house now.
l feel as if l am flying.
You silly, l'll make you fly...
What happened at the studio that day...
- Yes, l saw. You dance very well.
l meant what l did at the dance
studio the other day...
What if we are caught?
We must find out who he is.
He dares to bring a twist
into Kkamini's life!
He...what if he comes again?
Babu, you are here, aren't you?
Can you whistle?
Whistle!
Now whistle.
When the lord above gives,
He gives by the armful.
Amar-Prem!
What sort of surprise is this?
Babu, what am l supposed
to do with these men?
They are.. not with me.
Thank God you cleared it up.
By the way, man and man,
two men who live together...
What are you doing in my suite?
Oh, how come you know
it is my birthday?
lt's not your birthday today.
- Oh, it is!
Or else what would l be doing here?
lf it's his birthday...
And you came to give him a surprise...
- Where's the surprise?
The birthday gift?
- lt'll be somewhere around.
Because it's here. Look for it!
She's kept it hidden.
But there'll be two surprise gifts.
l can show you one
but the other...
This is our own new technique of
looking for the gift...
...since childhood.
Your doubts are gone and
you believe it, l hope?
Where did the gift come from?
- This one?
There are hundreds of gifts.
They were for you...
They are for you...
And will always be for you.
Accept love's sweet salute,
my darling.
Just commit the folly
of loving me back.
My heart's thrill...
Your heart's thrill...
Thrill? No this bill.
Who shall l give this bill to?
To the uncle or will you pay?
Raju Bro! The Dream girl's come, right.
How about an ice cream?
One tight slap and
all the ice cream'll melt away.
Tomorrow permit coming.
Day after Udaipur going.
Tomorrow...?
Veer Zaara the movie!
Didn't l just say...
You've to go to Udaipur
and l'm taking you there.
And now you want to see
this movie Veer Zaara!
Madam, permit tomorrow.
No permit. Police ask moolah...
How to explain to her...
Hey, Guddi. Come here.
You know English, don't you?
- So?
So nothing...Tell her,
the car's being arranged.
l'll get the permit tomorrow and we
go to Udaipur the day after. Tell her.
Go on, tell her.
What? lce cream?
Chandulalji, one ice cream.
Tell her.
What?
My God!
What'll become of this country!
lce cream for everyone.
She's asking why you
are going with her.
Tell her... there's something called
respon...lli...bi..
Hey, speak in Hindi, man.
Guddi will explain it in English.
Explain to her...she has no money.
So how'll she go?
She says...
- l know that much English.
Ask her why her boyfriend left her.
She has a boyfriend too?
This is a totally different story.
Very bad story.
His family wants an lndian
daughter-in-law.
Can't find the words...
Explain to her...
He has left his love
to trail his family's tail...
So why's she crazy for him?
She says if he marries someone else
she'll kill herself.
What are you whispering for?
- Raju Bro, she says...
When she finds her boyfriend,
she'll slap him and say bye forever.
Nah, buddy.
She loves him very much.
lf he marries someone else,
she'll kill herself.
How did you know?
What if l don't know her language?
l can understand the
language of her eyes.
Tell her that Raju will take her
to her destination.
As Vidhurji said,
a draft for one million...
...in Rahul's name.
- ln whose name?
ln Rahoooul's name.
This is just one.
There are 9 more to come.
Don't try to cross your limits,
understand?
Do everything in limits.
But in love...go beyond...
all limits...
Understand?
What are you doing?
Always relax under tension.
This is only the beginning.
Wait and see what happens
in the days to come.
''Love is...''
''l salute the dark magic
of your eyes.''
''l salute the dark
cloud of your hair.''
''The music of your anklets wounds me
to the heart, my love''
''Hey beautiful, l salute
your every lovely allure.''
''Love's sweet salute.''
''l salute the mystery of
your teasing banter.''
''l salute nights drenched
in passion's colour.''
''Lost in dreams am l.
Crazed with love am l.''
''Hey beautiful, l salute
your every lovely allure.''
''Love's sweet salute.''
''Love is...''
''Your hands are adorned with
henna's bridal red..''
''You have found the lover
of your dreams.''
''Our lovely bride is more precious
than the whole world.''
''O loving groom, carry her away
in the bridal palanquin.''
''When our eyes met the
very first time...''
''l fell in love with you.''
''Not just my heart...''
''My life is yours to take.''
''ln you l put my trust...''
''For you, l'd even die.''
''Look at what my crazed
love has made me do!''
''My every heartbeat is
restless with longing.''
''ln my eyes reside dreams of you.''
''l salute my darling whom
l love more than life.''
''Love's sweet salute.''
''Love is...''
''For your love l'd lay
down earth and heaven.''
''Have faith in the
promise l make you.''
''Heaven proclaims as
does this earth...''
''There's none other like you !''
''Don't cast such enticing lures.
l'm wary of coming close to you.''
''Stop flattering me with false praise.
Join your heart to mine.''
''l salute the prayer coming
deep from the heart.''
''Love's sweet salute.''
''My only plea to God...''
''is to forgive me...''
''...for l offer my worship
only to you.''
''My darling, you don't know..''
''..how much l love you.''
''Without you there is no light.''
''On my forehead l wear the
bridal red of your vow.''
''My breath carries but one message...''
''All l have is yours.''
''l salute the beloved who
lives in my heart.''
''Love's sweet salute.''
''l salute the dark
magic of your eyes.''
cloud of your hair.''
''Lost in dreams am l.
Crazed with love am l.''
''Hey beautiful, l salute
your every lovely allure.''
''Love's sweet salute.''
''Love is..''
Tehzeeb, l know you can hear me.
l'll be left all alone without you.
Come back...please!
Mr.Hussain, she is Dr.Geeta Dixit.
Tehzeeb is well enough but...
But what, Doctor?
The scan report shows...
What does it mean?
Mr. Hussain, lack of oxygen to
the brain for a fairly long time..
...has caused partial memory loss.
That's why, your daughter is
not the same Tehzeeb you know.
That's why she recognizes
you both...
...but has forgotten
Asutosh totally.
Can l take her home?
What is it now, Juggy?
- Photographs are memories.
But when there's nothing
worth remembering...
What's the point of photos?
Some photos...gifts you gave me.
And these keys.
Gia, there's no need for this.
- You don't but l need to.
Wait.
l know you are upset.
Natural, it happens.
- lt's not happening to me.
l am very happy, Shiven.
But you'll see. When you realise that
it all happened for our good...
You'll thank me.
l have realised it.
Realised what?
That l don't have to spend my life
with someone like you.
Oh, well!
So then celebrate!
An idea straight from God!
An idea of that level.
l'm gonna go home, change my clothes.
This is my house...
Raju Bro...
- Keep quiet!
What're you doing, Maya darling!
Raju Bro, see Maya has also
given a signal. Don't take her there.
Try and understand, kiddo.
lt's not a matter of my love...
but my love's love.
Why, Gurudev?
Get lost!
Now Udaipur non-stop...
Push...?
Not to Udaipur! Just
a little further.
Now push?
All right. You read your novel
and l'll handle my Maya.
What're you up to, Maya darling!
What're you up to, Maya! We go a long
way back as far as l can remember.
Today when l'm helping a girl in love,
you are acting up!
Don't be jealous, Maya.
l'm with her only for this trip.
You and l are on a long journey.
She has gone crazy! Look at her
buried in her book. She's coming!
Listen...hurry.
l...running...hard.
Time...outside...late...
What are you saying?
What on earth !
l late...going... l late...going...
Ya! So you will late (lie) down?
That's the problem with you people.
You see sand, and you want lie down.
By the sea also. Now you see sand here
you want to lie down.
You've to go to Udaipur. l'm taking
you there. And you want to late down !
l...late...going! l...late...going!
Hey, Maya started! Go, sit! Go sit.
Hurry up, Maya. Or she'll
go late down !
Can't find the words.
How to tell you...
They'll both lie down.
So, the wedding will be next Sunday.
- lsn't that too much of a rush?
l've to invite our friends.
Call the family.
Don't you worry about that.
Just give me the list...
and l'll make all the arrangements.
Everything'll be fine...
Sweetu my dear...
Feed our son-in-law the sweets
you made with your own hands!
Go on, my dear...
So l can consider this
alliance final...
ls your daughter pregnant, Satpalji?
Just a little...
Satpalji...
Yes?
- ls Rohitji...?
Alas no...
Let's go.
Listen...
What?
- Where are you?
What is happening?
- l don't know.
What am l doing here?
What do you know?
- Rahul is coming to propose to you.
The whole world knows that.
- O maiden...
the prince charming
of your dreams is coming.
The bridegroom brings his festive
procession and bridal palanquin.
Await the auspicious moment...
''O sweetheart, l come to you
in bridegroom's finery.''
''l come in a festive procession
with a bridal palanquin''
''O sweetheart, l come to you
in bridegroom's finery.''
''l come in a festive procession
with a bridal palanquin''
''l can't wait even for a day
more, my lovely darling.''
''lf not today, tomorrow you
are destined to be mine.''
''l shall only go back when
l take you with me.''
''To you l will give my heart.
You tell this world...''
''Tell the world,
you are the saga of my love.''
''O darling, go on say it...''
''l am your love.
And you are my life.''
''Don't hide anything at all.''
''Such beautiful love is so
hard to find, my darling.''
''l don't want to lose something
as precious as you.''
''Don't torment me so,
O my darling...''
''Just give me a look out of
your intoxicating eyes.''
''O my darling, join
your voice...''
''to mine.''
''Say yes, come on. Say yes.''
''You've made me restless with
longing, O dream lover''
''l tell this world... l am yours.
Yes, l am yours.''
''l'll come with you.''
''l'll go to my bridal home.''
''l shall only go back when
l take you with me.''
''To you l will give my heart.''
Madam, one Rohit proposal
down... Party?
Lucknow's famed lamb curry spiced
with Bareli chillies...
Dal topped with Khurja's special cream,
flaky parathas with butter..
And Banaras paan afterwards.
- But sir!
l know it's impossible.
Get what you have.
My brain is boiling with hunger.
- lmmediately, sir.
Come, madam.
Hindi class good?
Listen !
- Listen? So tell me.
Very good.
Listen, l have written something
what l want to say..
...when Rohit's mother
and father...l meet...
l get it. You want to say something
to the jackass' parents? Go ahead.
Dear mother and father...
..half the world to
marry your son... l have roamed...
Please accept your cow
Not cow. Daughter-in-law!
Daughter-in-law...?
This book... not good.
Funny!
Are you bringing my order?
- Coming sir!
l'm ravenous.
l tell you and you will write it down?
OK, write.
Write.
Listen, you goon...
Listen...you goon.
Swine of a Paaji owl...
Ruin and damnation upon you.
Your son is jackass no.1.
Dimwit of an owl..
..who doesn't know what love means.
Go to hell... all of you !
Swine of a Paaji owl...
Ruin and damnation....
Let it be...
Speak in English.
Speak from the heart.
They will understand.
Eat?
No, not this.
This food not for English...
Only for lndian.
Heroine's wedding
means goodbye to her film career.
lt wasn't part of the plan.
Then why did you do it? Why?
Why did you do it?
Why...
You know why l did it.
What else could l do under
the circumstances.
You wanted it too.
But if l hadn't done what l did,
there'd be a mess up.
How'd the plan progress?
Plan?
Yes, plan.
What did you think?
What were you thinking?
What deep game are you playing?
Amazing! You are asking me?
The game that you had started.
The Rahul-Kkamini game of love.
Listen...
Rahul's entry changed Kkamini from
ltem Girl to girl-next-door.
But to sign a Karan Johar film,
she must turn into a queen...
And that too, Tragedy Queen.
Look boss. You aren't getting
10 million to spout philosophy.
You listen, boss. l gave you a 100
million bucks plan for a million.
Listen to the second half of the plan.
- One more plan !
You don't want to hear?
- Okay, tell us.
Thanks.
Kkamini's plan...
Rahul's entry...
Rahul and Kkamini's love story...
Love... Wedding preparations...
And an engagement ring...
The whole world is crazy...
Only one question echoing...
When is the wedding?
Only one echoing answer...
Tomorrow...yes tomorrow.
But... Tomorrow Never Comes.
There may be a tomorrow but
...no Rahul.
Why?
A Rainy Night...
Journey... Just One Mistake...
and accident!
l'm Karan Johar speaking.
l'm so sorry, l just came to know...
...that Rahul is dead.
One story ends.
A new life begins.
You lose something to gain something.
Rahul is lost...
You've really delivered
a million's worth.
Listen... You are forgetting
something...
Put it on yourself.
l'll introduce you
to my friends. Come...
Where're you going? Please stop.
No, Anjali. l should be sorry.
Why are you with me?
They are of your age. Not me.
l am not in the least like them.
l'm with you because you
are not like them.
None of them can do what
you did in there.
Because they are not what you are...
....crazy...crazily in love with me.
Are you all right, Vinay?
You shaved?
Yes... no... ls it okay?
lt's different...
Malhotraji, it's very good news.
Your heart is perfectly okay.
Heart...! What heart
problem does he have?
Who is she?
- She...
she is my wife.
Oh, Mrs.Malhotraji.
Nothing to worry about.
He's perfectly fit and fine.
l was told on the phone
that he had an accident.
Then why a heart check-up?
- Well...
You keep quiet... You tell me.
- lt's nothing.
Just a routine check-up.
- Didn't l say, a routine check up?
Actually, your daughter told
me he had chest pain.
Daughter!?
- Yes.
Shai..?
- Shy? Oh, not in the least.
She's really rough and tough.
A really lovely girl.
Shall we go?
l don't want to hear anything!
Where you were, who you were with...
How it all happened,
why you didn't go to office...
Why that girl went to the
hospital with you...
Even if she did, what
was the need to lie...
Seema, you are ranting on,
talking nonsense!
What lie did l tell? What lie?
Do l have only one thing to do? There
are errands to run outside the office.
l told you about Kkamini's party,
didn't l? Had to go out for it.
l was crossing the road.
A car came by suddenly.
The poor girl was standing there.
She took me to the hospital.
And they ask a 100 questions
at the hospital.
How did it happen? When?
Who are you?
l just said she was my daughter.
You'll nag me to death for it?
Why's Mamma crying, Papa?
Because Papa made a mistake.
While crossing the road?
Yes, son.
- Did you look left? Then right?
No, son.
- Where was your attention, Papa?
l got distracted. That's why
Papa made a mistake, son.
You won't make this mistake
again, will you?
Never.
Mamma, Papa promised.
Come, you've school tomorrow.
Go to bed.
l don't know what all l thought.
You've changed so much...
l was scared.
l never stopped to think...
...you'd never do something
like this to us.
Forgive me.
What's this, Guru !
Their connection is on...
There's a forced disturbance
in my line...
At least set her connection right.
From when the poor girl has been
calling left, right and centre!
Go on, Sukhi.
- We're in luck, Paaji.
Col. Bakshi has consented
to the wedding.
Bakshi is ready?
Oh no, pal. lt's a big risk.
The marriage is already fixed.
But Paaji...
- Shut up, Sukhi.
Listen Sukhi. Tell Bakshi Saheb
we agree to the wedding.
How're you, Tehzeeb?
They're all friends here.
l'll be back soon.
We are at Anarkali Bazar
near the Lahore stadium.
The people of Lahore
are spreading cheer...
in the joy of the lndian team's
visit to Pakistan. Just a minute...
5 minutes!
Go away.
- Go where? l've come from so far.
We are live... LlVE!
Let's ask what they think of this
historic lndia-Pakistan series.
Uncle, do you want to say something?
The atmosphere is very nice. Business
has doubled because of the match.
How wonderful!
Salaam. Have you any message
for your lndian brothers?
l want to say something.
Would anyone like to say something?
- Strange!
l've something to say
and l'm not allowed to speak!
Will anybody in Lahore
give ME a hearing?
Speak, son. l am with you.
l am Ashu and she is Tehzeeb.
l love her and she loves
me too... Don't you?
But we can't get married because
l'm a Hindu and she is a Muslim.
My parents are against this marriage.
Before coming here, she said to me...
Think, Ashu... if we marry,
what'll our tomorrow be like?
All l have to say is this,
whatever our tomorrow may be...
we'll make it beautiful together.
But if you are not with me,
l have neither today nor tomorrow.
So Tehzeeb, will you
give me my tomorrow?
Will you marry me?
l can't remember anything.
This is a strange story...
Where does it begin...
She started...she started!
She started...
Bright smiling face...
Yes, Madam.
lt's only this Raju who can repair Maya.
What are you saying!?
You not stepney! You front tyre!
Rohit call... come?
No worries... only smiles.
We'll go to Rishikesh..
Meet Rohit ...
Then girlfriend boyfriend
marriage and Raju's ruin !.
Nothing.
Of course l have.
But she is leaving me...
going... to her boyfriend.
No, madam. Girlfriend good...
from head to toe good.
l haven't said l love
you to her till now.
You see, l don't know how
to say l love you ....
l too love you.
Huh..!?
l was just passing by.
Thought l'd meet you.
Why?
Can't we even meet, Gia?
We could have met, Shiven.
That is, if you wanted to.
l always wanted us to meet...
We had such good times together, Gia.
Only good times... Not bad times.
But Shiven, love is what's
there at all times...
Because love is not about good times
but who you spend time with.
lt's so complicated even
when you hear it...
Like?
- Like we were.
This good time, bad time...
Today, tomorrow...
Who knows what tomorrow brings.
l know.
l know about my tomorrow, Shiven.
l am getting married tomorrow.
They went to Delhi?
But we were told that...
if your daughter was rejected
they were to go to Jammu.
What...?
That dirty, low-down sinner!
Who is he to reject us?
We broke it off.
Col. Bakshi has lost his mind!
Rohit, dial Canada. Give our
relatives the good news.
Okay, give it to me. l'll phone.
Your call.
- Yes.
lt's your sister from Canada.
l'll give her the good
news of your wedding.
Rohit, your sister wants
to talk to you.
Hurry. We'll reach Delhi
in 3 hours. Quick... hurry.
Where's she going off looking so sad?
Listen !
That's not the way. This is the way.
Where're you going off?
Taxi waiting.
What over?
No end... start.
lt's the beginning.
Rohit waiting there...
So what if he says that?
Will you believe it? Come with me.
But listen...
Listen to me...
Will you listen to me or not?
Shut up!
l'll give you a tight slap!
Your hope of lndian woman?
No, no hope.
Eating egg curry and parathas
don't make you an lndian woman.
You don't become an lndian woman
reading Hindi English novels.
Giving up hope and turning
your back on love...
... will never make you lndian.
lndian woman fight!
Fight for love, fight for husband!
So, what did the jackass say?
Must've said...
l can't marry you Stephanie.
Can't go against my parents.
lf he runs away, you'll
also turn coward?
Come with me. l'll take
you there in 3 hours.
We'll go there, talk and
then marriage to Rohit.
When you meet Rohit, it's
what you say, l love you...
That's the reason... Come.
Where are we going?
Just one more attempt...
Your hair's turned white, uncle!
Ashu Baba, you !
Madam, look who has come!
l'm on the terrace, drying clothes.
- Oh, let the work be, madam.
Come and see who's here!
- l'm coming. Why are you shouting?
My son...
Son, your father...
- We'll leave.
Just a while.
Tehzeeb has lost her memory.
Perhaps this place might...
At least get some water, Kaka.
Where are all the servants gone!
Our daughter-in-law is home.
Do you remember this place, Tehzeeb?
Remember that day...
Garlands of flowers everywhere...
All the people...the bustle...
Music...lights...
The festive air...
And the wedding canopy...
Panditji reciting mantras, everyone
busy with wedding preparations...
Nidhi's wedding...
Your best friend... And my sister.
Look, the groom's party has arrived.
Remember, Tehzeeb.
- l don't remember a thing!
Try and remember, please.
Look, Nidhi's friends
are all coming down...
Laughing and chattering...
And your face amongst them all...
My heart stopped beating
when l saw your face...
Congratulations, Kaka.
Nidhi is a bride!
Shall l make you a bride too?
You think it's easy? lt'll
be very difficult.
Know why? Because l'm not going
to marry just anybody...
Saved in time.
- Not me!
Naughty!
Remember anything? Something?
Please try. Remember those people...
What people! What wedding?
What day? l don't remember anything!
Who let these people in?
Are the servants all dead?
Tehzeeb met with an accident.
She lost her memory.
- Congratulations!
Now finally he has a chance to
mend his mistake. Make him understand.
Tell him to leave her...
so he can rectify his life even now.
Don't say that!
He is in trouble.
- Then why has he come here?
Where else will a son go if not home?
- He should've thought of it...
the day he married a Muslim.
Tell him. There's nothing
in this house to give him.
There is, father.
Your hatred.
l have come to ask for it.
Hate Tehzeeb...
...exactly the way you did when
she first came here as a bride.
Tehzeeb doesn't remember anything,
not even my love.
Perhaps she might remember
your hatred.
lf not my love, your hate may
perhaps give her back her life.
Please, father...
Give back Tehzeeb her memories.
Please hate her, father!
Why weren't you answering my calls?
Anjali...! l was about to call you...
A lot is happening.
l need a little time.
l don't have time, Vinay. l'm going
to Paris. l have a dance scholarship.
What're you saying?
l have a job here...
a family. A home...
My life is here.
ls this the kind of life you want?
l don't know what l want...
l hardly know what to do...
what to say...
Don't say anything, Vinay. Just
listen to your heart...
...the way l heard... And saw...
l see in your eyes a man who
wants a lot from life.
l will give you all that.
Just us...you and me.
Papa phoned...
Gia is getting married.
l came to collect the tickets.
Perhaps you are going somewhere else.
Just a minute...
Looking at the photos?
l thought l'd appear in person...
and come close to you.
- What do you want now, Rahul?
Nothing.
l got what l wanted.
- What?
Being with you.
You can't stop playing this game
even for a second, can you?
Consider, just for a second...
What if this is not a game?
What if Raooul really loves Kkamini?
What if he has always loved her?
From the time Kkamini
was not Kkamini... but was Kamna?
An ordinary singer at a
small hotel in Dehradun.
From the time Rahul was
not Raooul but Rahul...
An ordinary waiter at the same hotel...
...whose only desire was Kamna...
...whose only dream
was Kamna's love...
Okay, let's leave it at that.
Let go of all those old things.
But if today...
lf Rahul were to ask Kamna...
Will Kamna fulfil Rahul's
unfulfilled dream?
lf Rahul were to say today,
Kamna, l love you...
Will you marry me?
Wait...
lf there is a knock on the
door at the same time?
Then...?
And today, Kkamini's dream
is standing at the door...
...money, name, fame...
A whole new life...
A life that begins with Rahul's death?
What if Kkamini has to choose
between her dream and Rahul?
Your dream has come true!
Karan Johar announced his new film.
You know, he's thinking
of casting you !
This means we must act quickly...
This means..
Rahul must die.
Hey, aren't you going to wish me
a loving goodnight?
All right...listen...
May not be love...
But l surely found answers
to my questions.
Oh, l forgot the most
important thing...
My wine...
Congratulations on the tears of joy.
What're you doing?
l'm talking to you !
What are you doing? What's all this!
- Lower your voice.
Listen to me...
- Rohan and Shai are home.
l know...
- They don't have to see this drama.
This is not some drama!
- Let go my hand!
Then first listen to me.
- There's nothing to listen.
l have seen it.
Why did you do it, Vinay?
Weren't you happy?
lt's not a matter of happiness...
...but of life.
There's a world outside the four
walls of the house and office....
...that l want to know...
A life l want to live.
l want to realize the dreams
l had the dreams we had dreamed.
The dreams we had dreamt?
The dreams you had?
Why have we forgotten them?
ln these 15 years of marriage,
they got lost somewhere.
That feeling, love, that excitement,
Where has it all gone?
Where is it, Seema?
Where is all that?
Perhaps time has changed...
But l love you as much even today.
Yes, l too had dreams...
Dreams of my own.
But after meeting you, your
dreams became mine...
Your life became mine.
My dream was for you to
get what you wanted.
l had Rohan and Shai... and you.
l didn't want anything more from life.
But l want...
l want more.
May you get what you want...
...that is my only dream even today.
''ls this love
or punishment?''
''Tell me, O my heart!''
''Why doesn't this endless
chain of pain not break?''
''How many tests and trials
must this love endure?''
''So many diverse stories
are writ by this love.''
''O God...''
''Even if someone lays
down one's life...''
''lt has no effect at all on the
one so passionately loved.''
''How arduous is the journey to
reach love's destination !''
''There are no solutions to
the heart's tribulations.''
''Every heartbeat
emanates sorrow.''
''Every breath
breaks restraining bonds.''
''Every moment somewhere
plaintive lips sigh a complaint.''
''Someone's world destroys
itself for love.''
''O God...''
''Even if someone lays
down one's life...''
''lt has no effect at all on the
one so passionately loved.''
Congratulations... on your marriage.
l'm not getting married.
lt was all a publicity stunt.
A plan to get a dream role
in A Karan Johar film.
Now when the plan is about
to be successful...
l want something else.
Even l don't know what l want.
Why're you telling me all this?
Because you too don't
know what you want.
2 O clock at night... alone...
...distressed...
You have all the symptoms
of being confused.
l guess both of us are confused.
Okay, let's decide who
is more confused.
How many years have you been married?
12...?
15.
Let me guess...two kids...
A boy and a girl.
l have met your wife.
She is very pretty.
Together in college too...
Then marriage
Quick rise...well paid job.
Comfortable home in the suburbs.
Perfect but boring life.
Then you meet somebody...
ln the office...
on the street,
bus, train...
On the train?
A newness in life...you want
more than what you have.
You seem to know a lot about me.
Not about you but l surely
know Miss. Train.
l understand girls like
her very well...
Because l too am a girl like them.
Or perhaps l was...
Until Rahul came into my life...
So, Miss. Train...
She has a name...Anjali.
Anjali what?
You don't even know her full name.
You want to lose what you have...
For what?
You want to lose what
you could have had.
For what?
''O God...''
''Even if someone lays
down one's life...''
''lt has no effect at all on the
one so passionately loved.''
Yes, it's true Rahul is no more.
He died in a car accident.
Rohitji...?
- They've all left for Gia's wedding.
They've gone?
- Yes.
''No one hears the sobbing sighs.''
''No one allays the longing
of tormented arms.''
''Raging desires only half-slaked.''
''All hoped for pleasures
shattered into fragments.''
''Somewhere a seed of suspicion,
elsewhere a wall of hate.''
''Even in victory
there is loss.''
''O God...''
''Even if someone lays
down one's life...''
''lt has no effect at all on the
one so passionately loved.''
Where do you have to go?
l don't know...
''ls this love or punishment?''
''Tell me, O my heart!''
''Don't ask the pain-afflicted...''
''...what happiness is.
What is laughter.''
''Hardship hovers over them...''
''...in some form or other.''
''O God...''
Sorry, madam. l dozed off.
Oh this...?
l made this for you.
Give it to your boyfriend
when he says l love you.
Mamma, l want the window seat.
Mamma, where's Papa?
- He's not coming with us.
l just need to talk.
She is my wife.
l haven't come to ask
you to forgive me...
...because what happened
was unforgivable.
Please don't go.
What had to happen happened, Vinay.
Nothing happened, Seema.
Nothing has changed.
No. Everything has changed.
lt was you who said... That
love, the excitement...
l could never give you
what you call life.
This is not true, Seema.
- Then what is the truth?
What is the truth?
The truth is that in all this, l am
left standing like a joke...
...l, my love, my trust...
everything.
l am going so that you can get
all that you want from life.
But you are my life, Seema.
And this is the only truth.
The only truth.
Please don't go, Papa.
For all of us to go together...
...l suppose we've to
catch another flight.
You're all right, aren't you?
l must put on this act for the world.
You are a very good actress,
Kkamini....
...but not that good ...
l can tell the difference between
real and false tears.
lt's too late...
l have lost him forever.
When Kamna was lost, Rahul
searched and found her.
Because Rahul loved Kamna.
And now when Rahul is lost,
Kamna will find him...
...because Kamna loves Rahul.
Shall l cancel our tickets for the
Delhi-Bombay connecting flight?
How're you feeling?
Are you okay?
l am Ashu, Tehzeeb.
Let me go.
Listen...
l've to make a call. Please...
Listen, Tehzeeb.
l shouldn't have taken you
to my father's house.
l shouldn't have taken you anywhere
Listen, Tehzeeb. You are with me.
That's more than enough.
Come home, Tehzeeb.
- l don't want to go with you.
l don't want to stay in your house!
Because l can't bear
to see you like this!
You always say everything
will be all right...
But nothing ever is all right.
You are always searching for
your memory in my eyes.
And when you don't find it... You
try to act as if it's all fine...
...perfectly normal.
You bring me back my smile
and hide your tears.
l can't bear to see
you suffer like this!
l want to see you happy.
But my happiness is with you, Tehzeeb.
How can it be!
l DON'T EVEN KNOW YOU!
l need to make a call please...
Give me your phone... please.
l must make a call.
l can't remember...
Abba, yes. Tehzeeb is all right.
Talk to her.
Abba...
Take me away...please!
Take me away.
l tried so hard to recognize you...
But nothing... reminds me of you.
l know, Tehzeeb...
...you have forgotten me.
But that your heart has
also forgotten me..
...is something l can't believe.
You'll remember everything
one day.
And if l can't remember?
What if l can't remember
anything at all?
We'll create new memories.
Memories are of life...
And without you, there's no life.
What life will you have
with me tomorrow?
Whatever our tomorrow may be...
We'll make it beautiful together.
But if you are not with me...
Then l have neither
today nor tomorrow.
Will you give me my tomorrow, Tehzeeb?
Tell me, Tehzeeb!
Will you give me my tomorrow?
Shiven, love is what's
there at all times...
Because love is not about good times
but who you spend time with.
Whatever our tomorrow may be,
we'll make it beautiful together.
But if you are not with me, then
l have neither today nor tomorrow.
Do you know what you are doing, Gia?
Let's go.
''Don't ask the pain-afflicted...''
''...what happiness is.
What is laughter.''
''Hardship hovers over them...''
''...in some form or other.''
''O God...''
Hail, Mighty Hanuman ! Come, madam.
What're you saying sorry for! lt'll
be too late if we don't go in.
We don't have orders, sir.
- So call the person who gives orders.
Are you the manager here?
- Something like that.
Why's she going on about invitations!
This girl here...
...came half-way across the world.
l made her roam all over lndia.
ln between my Maya darling had
2 punctures and 4 repairs!
She says lNVlTATlONS!!
And all this for whom?
That moron of a jackass in there, ha?
He promised love and marriage to her
and is marrying someone else!
She is mad enough to
love that jackass.
But if love isn't mad,
is it any worth, sir?
And she harangues about invitations!
You may go in... because madmen
don't need invitations.
Thank you.
STOP!
Stop this wedding!
l told you, madam. The jackass will
stop his father when he sees you.
You said get out to madam!
Are you a man or dishrag?
She left her world and came running
after you. And you spurn her love!
To opt for hate and reject love
is the worst stupidity.
lf l were in your place, l'd put
my hand on my heart, close my eyes...
Take a deep breath
and say l love you !
l also love you...
l love you too.
Shall we...?
Listen...you goon.
Swine, cheat, owl...
Ruin and damnation upon you.
Your son is jackass no.1.
Dimwit of an owl who doesn't
know what love means.
Go to...
Go to hell... all of you !
Go to hell...all of you !
What are you looking at me for?
Read the wedding mantras.
Bakshiji, shall we start?
Please start.
STOP!
Let go.
This...?
Stop this wedding?
Stop this wedding!
Sir, hadn't l told you? When two people
truly love each other...
they do get together.
l can't find the words...
But all the best.
l am getting married, Shiven !
Why's the wedding going on?
l mean why are you getting married?
Why shouldn't l get married?
- Get married. Most certainly.
But why him?
- Why not him?
l have to marry someone
or other, don't l?
Yes. But not him, someone else.
Whom?
Me.
There l said it. No side-tracking.
You must marry me.
Why?
Because today l realise ...
Love is not about good times
but who you spend time with.
Gia, l now know...
Whatever our tomorrow may be...
We'll make it beautiful together.
But if you are not with me, then
l have neither today nor tomorrow.
l know l'm late every time but today...
- Today...
lf you were late today,
l'd have really killed you !
Panditji, you may begin.
Wait! Bakshi Saheb...
Bloody... brighter!
Panditji, what are you looking
at me for? Start the ceremony.
This is simply not done!
Every one here...
Why don't you do something, Paaji?
- No, sir.
When man and wife agree, can
a mere Paaji dare disagree!
Panditji, finish the ceremony.
Sir, where are you going?
- We came to meet Rahul, l told you !
He'll be somewhere here.
So...you did come.
l have come.
So, you did find me.
l found you.
Cheque?
Cheque...?
10 million. You brought
the cheque, didn't you?
l forgot. You forgot too?
You love playing games don't you?
- But not more than you.
All right.
So let's begin.
lf l said l don't have a cheque
for 10 million...
...but loads of love for you...
Then?
lf l said...
Then...?
lf the phone rings exactly
at that time...
And it is Karan Johar calling.
Then...?
And you have become Karan
Johar's heroine...
Kkamini's dream isn't a dream
anymore but a reality.
Then...?
l am Karan Johar speaking.
l have some good news.
- Wrong number.
Now... will Rahul marry Kamna?
Good technique
to split 10 million in two.
Accept love's sweet salute,
my darling.
Just commit the folly
of loving me back.
My heart is restless...
lf not the first year...
l've to give you something at
least the second year, don't l?
Subtitles by: Mr.John