Captioning made possible by
U.S. department of education
and Turner entertainment group
happy new year!
[Cheering]
[Band playing hail! Hail!
The gang's all here]
[Playing a hot time
in the old town tonight]
* should auld acquaintance
be forgot *
* and days of auld Lang syne? **
hey, there's wine
in lotta's fountain!
Free wine!
Hey, Duane!
Duane!
You want any more?
Sure! All of it.
Empty the warehouse.
You bet.
I'll take a dozen
at the same price.
Hello, Blackie.
Happy new year.
Hello, Duane.
Happy new year
to you.
Some sight, huh?
Yeah. Some advertising.
Hello there, Blackie!
Happy new year and many of them.
Happy new year, Della!
Happy new year, girls!
You know everybody, don't you?
Well,
everybody that's
worth knowing.
Hello? Fire!
[Fire alarm ringing]
Where's the fire?
On the Barbary coast.
Maybe it's my joint.
[Man]
Stand back.
Keep clear.
[Different man]
Clear out
for the hose!
It ain't your joint, Mr. Norton.
No. It isn't hot enough
for my joint.
[Yelling]
Save us!
Jump! Jump!
Hurry! Hurry!
Aah!
Is everybody out of there?
O.K., they're all out,
Mr. Norton.
Well, happy new year.
Hello, Blackie.
Happy new year.
Thank you.
Herr Norton--
hello. Happy new year to you.
Happy new year, Blackie.
[Cabaret singing]
* and now we're gonna change it
for another one... *
Blackie, happy new year!
Hello.
Happy new year.
* and it's slightly corn
like a fad that's out of style *
* everybody,
raise your glasses high *
* 19-6 is saying, "here am I" *
* happy new year *
* here comes 19-6 *
* and it doesn't
seem to matter... **
where's the fire, boss?
Dupont street--
the old Bristol
house.
Happy new year, Blackie!
Happy new year, honey.
I want it to be happy.
The fire was at the Bristol.
Oh, that trap.
Blackie, your shoes
are all muddy.
That makes the third fire
we've had in one week.
We'll have to
get ourselves
asbestos suits.
Yeah.
I'll say so.
I thought I told you
not to wear that thing.
Gee, honey, I think it's nice.
Yeah?
Well, I think
it makes you look cheap.
Now, don't wear it anymore.
Blackie doesn't like it.
Oh, say, Blackie,
Mrs. forrestal's here
with a party of swells.
She's been asking
especially for you.
That so?
Yeah.
Happy new year.
Happy new year, Blackie.
Oh, ho!
Oh, I want you
to meet my husband.
How do you do?
Happy new year.
Happy new year to you.
Mark this on the house.
Happy new year.
Thanks.
* noontime means luncheon
for someone *
* nighttime means sleep
for the same *
* daytime means brightness
for someone *
what are you doing?
* easily... **
throw him out!
Let's go.
I don't like his singing.
But you mustn't hurt
the artist's feelings.
His feelings?
Who is he to get so many?
Where are you from?
Los Angeles.
I thought so.
I beg your pardon.
Are you the manager here?
Well, I kind of run the joint.
What do you want, sister?
I'm looking for work.
Oh, just get to town?
Oh, no. The place
I've been living at
was just burned down.
Oh, yeah. That trap
on dupont street.
Yes.
Well, that's tough.
Yes. I've been
looking for work
uptown,
but there doesn't
seem to be anything,
so I thought I'd try
the Barbary coast.
I've been to several places,
but there's--
how about a little drink?
Well, thank you,
but if you don't mind,
I'd like to see the proprietor.
Oh, you would?
Yes.
All right.
This is the paradise?
I'll say it is--
the hottest spot
on the Barbary coast.
Hello, chica!
Watch yourself, brother.
Ha ha ha!
Wait here a minute, honey.
Blackie, there's a little lady
out here looking for a job.
She was burned out
in that fire
at the Bristol.
Yeah?
She's not bad.
All right.
Bring her in.
This is Mr. Norton.
He owns the joint.
How do you do?
Well, sister,
what's your racket?
I'm a singer.
Let's see your legs.
I said I'm a singer.
All right.
Let's see your legs.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Let's see them.
Thin for down here.
You know that number?
Yes.
All right.
Let's hear you sing it.
* I care not
for the stars that shine *
* I dare not hope
to e'er be thine *
* I only know I love you *
* love me, and the world *
* is mine **
well, you got
a pretty fair set
of pipes, kid.
What do you say to 75 a week?
I guess she fainted.
Yeah. Give me 75 bucks a week,
and I'll drop dead.
Hello, kiddo.
Did you get
some rest?
Yes. Thank you.
Good. Joe, get rid
of this, will you?
Yes, sir.
I want to thank you, Mr. Norton,
for your kindness.
Never mind the etiquette.
It's so stupid of me--fainting,
but I haven't eaten much today,
and I...
It's true, isn't it?
You did offer me a job?
What's the matter?
You want it in writing?
Well, no, but...
You're all right, honey.
What's your name?
Mary Blake.
Mary Blake?
Well, that's catchy.
Make yourself at home.
I'll be right with you.
Where do you hail from?
Benson, Colorado.
That's near Denver.
I see.
Been here long?
No. Just a few weeks.
Where have you been working?
The Benson public library.
Singing?
No. I sang
in the church
on Sunday.
Oh, so you sang
in the church choir?
Yes.
You see, it was
my father's old church.
And your father is a preacher?
Yes. He was.
Was? Oh. He got
onto himself, huh?
He died four years ago.
I get it--
the orphan child
of a country parson.
Well, after all, Mr. Norton,
there are such men
as country Parsons.
Sometimes they do
have daughters.
Well, now, that sort of
puts me in my place,
don't it?
Well, who brought you
to San Francisco?
No one. My mother
helped me get here.
Oh, I see.
You don't believe me, do you?
Why, sure, sure.
I believe you.
You're all right, Mary.
Tomorrow we're going to get rid
of those Benson glad rags
and dig you up
some swell, new scenery.
You got all the makings, kid.
Why, you're going to do great.
What's the matter?
Where are you going?
I don't know.
Wait a minute.
You don't have to
stall me, honey.
Well, you know,
I wrote that old spiel
you just pulled--
parson father,
sacrificing mother--
the whole thing years ago.
I guess you got
some John on the string.
Is that it?
Please let me go.
I see.
Well, how much
is the railroad fare
here from Benson?
I paid $16.80.
Tomorrow morning, I'll have babe
give you an advance
in salary--$20.
You can send for
that mug you're stuck on.
You know, I admire a woman
you can trust out of town.
Getting late.
You can bunk here,
if you want to.
Try the sofa.
Good night, sucker.
Hey, Blackie,
the professor's
waiting for
that new girl
to show up for rehearsal.
She hasn't shown up.
No good, huh?
I'll say she's good.
Her father was a preacher.
Are you falling for
that old preacher
gag?
Maybe her father wasa preacher.
Oh, so you
still believe
in Santa clause?
Trouble with you is you don't
believe in anything.
Oh, that's where I'm smart.
Did you say smart?
That's what I said.
I'm a sucker if I'll
ever learn anything.
For 20 years that mug
has mauled me around
making a chump out of me,
and I always come back for more.
He got to bed
earlier than you
last night.
Come on.
Get up.
I'm not going to move
from this spot
till you're out of the building.
Ha ha ha!
All right, kid.
So long, mug.
Hey, that guy packs
an awful wallop,
don't he?
Yeah.
Is he gone?
Uh-huh.
Look at the parade.
Hello, Blackie.
Hello, mat.
Hello, boys.
Blackie, would you like to...
Yeah. Thanks.
Someone just
showed me to a seat.
Mat, get me my robe, will you?
Blackie, we've looked you up
to complain about that fire
last night on dupont street.
Complain? I thought
it was perfect.
What do you boys want
in the way of a fire?
You talk better at the meeting--
sitting down.
Jim Sullivan's kids got trapped
in that fire last night.
They had to jump for it.
Yeah. I know.
I saw.
They pulled it off
like circus performers.
Mr. Norton,
you ain't got no kids.
I got plenty kids--
Luigi, Pedro, Maria,
and little Tony,
and maybe more when I get home.
[Man]
Don't go home.
Well, look, boys,
put me down for 100 bucks
for Jim and the kids.
That isn't what
we came for,
Blackie.
We want to run you
for supervisor.
What?
That's right, Blackie.
The only way
to get decent
fire regulations
on the coast is to force them
through the board
of supervisors.
You're the only man on the coast
with the, uh...
Authority...
To do it.
There's nobody else
crazy enough--
ixnay.
Shut up!
Yeah, and maybe I'm not either.
I think it's a great idea.
Well, hello, father.
Why, certainly.
It's dynamite.
Supervisor Norton--
you'll get the joint
a million dollars'
worth of publicity.
Well, what do you say?
Where will you get the dough?
We'll back you, Blackie.
Up to the limit.
Father Mullin, you speak to him.
You like a fight,
Blackie. Go on.
Have you all gone crazy?
I can't do anything with him.
I've been trying for 20 years.
Maybe you fellas can.
So long. Good luck.
Bye, Tim.
Well, Blackie, what about it?
Come on over to the bar.
Let's have a drink.
Can you
imagine what
that Nob Hill guy
is going to say--
there won't be any competition.
Mr. Norton, I tell you what.
The next boy
my Maria give to me,
I name him Blackie
after you. Ha ha ha!
Oh, name the next
half-dozen after him.
You think it won't be a battle?
He'll have all Nob Hill
flooding around him like bees.
I think you fellas
have all gone crazy.
Oh, Mr. Norton.
Yes? What is it?
May I have that job?
Didn't I say so?
Yes.
How many times do you
want me to say it?
Come on around here.
Come around here.
[Piano playing]
What will you have, boys?
Make mine a little whiskey.
Whiskey.
That's good.
* open your golden gate *
* you let no stranger wait *
* outside your door... *
what will you
have to drink, mat?
[Mary]
* San Francisco... *
a little chloroform.
Water for me.
Here's looking at you, Blackie.
Gentlemen.
Thank you.
* more *
* other places only *
* make me love you best... *
ain't she singing
kind of slow, Blackie?
Yeah.
Hope you ain't gone
and signed her up.
Why? So you
can grab her
for your joint?
* west... *
do you think I'm running
a funeral parlor?
But, Blackie,
with a voice
like hers,
it ain't so easy to--
go on. Go on.
Get out.
Give it this.
[Plays San Francisco rapidly]
Put something into it.
That's what
it's about--
San Francisco.
But I can't
sing like that,
Mr. Norton.
That's the way
you're going
to sing,
or you're not
going to sing it
for Blackie.
Hey, mat...
Go tell babe
to dig up a contract.
A contract?
Yeah. I'd better
sign that girl up
before I change my mind.
Changeyour mind?
You've lost it.
I'd like to see Burley's face
when he hears about it.
[Mary]
* open your golden gate *
* you let no stranger wait
outside your door... *
well, here's to
supervisor Norton.
* here is your wandering one *
* saying,
"I'll wander no more" *
* other places
only make me love you best *
* tell me you're the heart *
* of all the golden west *
* San Francisco *
* welcome me home again *
* I'm coming home to go *
* roaming *
* no... *
[applause]
* San Francisco *
* open your golden gate *
* you let no stranger wait
outside your door *
* San Francisco *
* here is your wandering one *
* saying,
"I'll wander no more" *
* other places
only make me... *
good evening, Mr. Burley.
Show Mr. Burley
and signor baldini
to a box.
Just a minute.
Is Blackie Norton around?
Yeah.
Tell him I'd like to see him.
Come with me.
* I'm coming home
to go roaming... *
boss, there's a couple
of gentlemen to see you.
All right.
[Mary] * more **
[applause]
Hello, Blackie.
Oh, hello, Burley.
Mr. Norton, signor baldini.
[Baldini]
Very pleased
to meet you.
Gentlemen,
what'll you have
to drink?
Maestro, my name is Harrison.
I played under your direction
one night in Dresden.
Really?
I haven't been
in Dresden
in 20 years.
Yes. That's right.
Oh, I'm happy--
very happy--
to see you again.
Thank you.
Me, I'm nothing, but, maestro,
we have down here a voice--
a voice that would
delight your soul,
maestro.
Professor, how about
going on with the show?
Yes. Yes. Excuse me, Mr. Norton.
If you could only hear it
in something good.
[Blackie] Professor!
We're trying to
give a show tonight.
Yes. Yes. Excuse me, Mr. Norton.
Maestro, this voice--
I would like
to have you
hear it.
Well, how about it?
Yes. Yes.
I'm going.
Well, I guess you know
why I'm down here.
Nope.
I heard this afternoon
you're going to run
for supervisor.
Yeah.
That's right.
I wouldn't do it,
if I were you,
Norton.
Why not?
I don't think you'll like it.
I'll love it.
Have you ever
stopped to consider--
just a minute, Burley.
Waiter.
Yes, sir?
Tell babe to go backstage
and see what's the matter.
[Mary singing]
Jack. Jack,
that girl got
a voice.
She had some training, too.
Hey, boss.
Boss, you going to
let that crazy dame
boss the show around?
Pipe down.
Beat it! Beat it!
* free *
* ah, then, let music ring *
* la, while three voices sing *
* la, pleasure is mine *
* echoes repeating,
measures retreating *
* song of a heart
light and free *
* not a thought, not a care *
* with a heart debonair *
* I am free as the sea *
* like the lark who at dawn
bid the darkness be gone *
* so I sing merrily *
* with a laugh and a dance,
my design--to entrance *
* for I know not what will be *
* and the things that I bring
and the words that I sing *
* is the song of a heart *
* that's free **
[baldini] Bravo. Bravo.
Brava. Brava.
How long has
that girl been
down here?
Just started.
What's her name?
Mary Blake.
What did I tell you, maestro?
Will you get back to that piano?
Yes. I'm going,
and I don't care if you fire me.
At least I've had
the opportunity
to help a girl.
Well, who said I was firing you?
Now, come on.
Get going.
Yes. Thank you,
Mr. Norton.
Thank you.
I'd like to meet that girl.
Oh, waiter.
[Waiter]
Yes, Mr. Burley?
See if miss Blake will meet
a respectful admirer.
I haven't
had her working
at the boxers yet.
I'm glad of that.
One never knows
where one's going to
find talent.
No. No.
One never does,
does one?
Yes, and I quote from Plautus.
[Speaking Latin]
Yeah. You took the words
right out of my mouth.
Mr. Burley?
It's very gracious of you
to allow us
this privilege,
miss Blake.
Thank you.
May I present signor baldini?
How do you do, signor?
Good evening, my dear.
Won't you sit down?
Waiter, a bottle
of cordon Rouge '94.
You bet, sir.
And the usual for you?
Yes.
A little water.
Hearing a voice like yours
in the variety theater
has been for me
a great experience.
Thank you, signor,
but you might have heard me
under more favorable
circumstances.
I sat in
the outer office
of the tivoli
for six days once.
So you want to sing in opera?
That's why I came
to San Francisco.
You have the training, too?
Yes, with the best
teacher in Denver.
I led the Bach choral society,
I won first prize
at the Schubert festival,
and I've done
violetta, Marguerite,
puccini's Mimi, and Tosca.
I love Puccini.
Oh, Puccini.
[Speaking Italian]
Did you ever hear
of Puccini, Norton?
Yeah. Didn't he run a joint
down on dupont street?
Ha ha ha!
Well, there's no law
against an opera singer
being slender and young
and beautiful.
What do you think
about giving miss Blake
an audition?
Yes, by all means.
Say, that's darn sweet
of you, Burley--
to take an interest
in the little lady,
and you, too, signor,
but she's under
a two-year contract.
To whom?
To me.
Two years?
Yes, but I'll have
her notify you
when it runs out.
Surely you wouldn't let that
stand in her way
to sing in
the tivoli.
Why? She's doing all right here.
I'm sorry, miss Blake.
Mr. Norton's quite right.
After all, paradise is
just as important to him
as the tivoli is to you.
What would happen to the tivoli
if its artists were
allowed to walk out
anytime they pleased?
You are a very
loyal girl, miss Blake.
No. I'm very grateful
to Mr. Norton.
Well...
Well, I'll be going.
We don't have much time
between numbers.
Thank you, signor.
This has been the happiest night
of my life.
Bye.
I haven't given up yet
about the tivoli.
You don't know Mr. Norton.
You don't know me.
Good-bye.
Just a minute.
I want to see you.
Who told you to sing
that highbrow number?
No one.
Well, now that you've
made your impression,
don't do it again.
Blackie doesn't like it.
Friend of mine runs a joint
around on kearney street.
I want you to hurry around there
and tear up
a little number for him.
All right.
Where is it?
St. Anne's mission--
just around the corner.
St. Anne's?
Yes. Ask for father Mullin.
You know
the hokey-pokey
they sing there.
You've got a number
to do back here
at 10:30.
We won't need that now.
Burley, you don't
want me to run
for supervisor?
You know as well as I
it's not practical
to rebuild the coast.
The coast is picturesque.
People come down here slumming.
They don't want to feel
like they're in a spotless town.
But that isn't your real reason.
The main one is
you don't want to
spend your dough
to make your property
down here safe.
If I did what you wanted me to,
it would be
a calamity
for the coast.
The Burley estate has to make
certain interest
on its investment.
I'd have to raise rents.
You boys couldn't live.
You'd have to
charge 10 cents
for a glass of beer.
I don't get him, Mr. baldini.
He tosses a fortune every year
to the tivoli opera house.
But that's not business.
That's for San Francisco.
The coast is San Francisco, too.
That's why I wouldn't change it.
These little mugs down here
are my people.
I'll see
that they get
a square deal,
so I'm not pulling
out of this fight.
I don't want
to fight you, Norton,
but you're asking for it.
I'm not ducking anything.
Good night.
You're wanted
on the phone, boss.
O.K.
Hello.
Oh, hello, Tim.
Why don't you come on over?
What for?
The organ recital
and to hear
the young lady.
She'll be coming back here
to sing the things I like.
All right. Have it your own way.
I was just sort of hoping
you'd make my evening complete.
If I had you here now,
I'd hug you,
and then I'd knock
your block off.
Ha ha ha!
I don't have to
tell you how I feel
about the organ.
Ah, forget it.
All right, Blackie.
Good-bye.
[Organ playing]
[Mary]
* last night I lay
a-sleeping *
* there came a dream so fair *
* I stood in old Jerusalem *
* beside the temple there *
* I heard the children singing *
* and ever on, they sang *
* before the voice of angels *
* from heaven in answer rang *
* Jerusalem, Jerusalem *
* sing for the mighty lord *
* hosanna in the highest *
* hosanna forevermore *
* hosanna forevermore **
oh, father, that was
simply marvelous.
And that little boy.
Wasn't he sweet?
Can you get home all right?
Yes, thank you.
Good night.
Hey, Mike.
Yes, father?
Got any money?
Sure, father.
Me wife's got a job.
Good night.
Good night. Good night.
Good night, father Mullin.
It was very nice
of you to leave work
and rescue us.
It made me feel good being here.
You're not the girl
whose father was
a preacher, are you?
Well, yes.
How did you know?
Blackie told me.
I'd like to talk to you.
But I'm afraid I'll be late.
That's O.K. I'll fix it
with Blackie.
Will you join me
in a cup of coffee?
Yes. I'd like to.
Thank you.
I make good coffee.
How are you making out
at the paradise?
Well, I've only just started.
I see. Sit down there,
won't you?
Thank you.
How do you like Blackie?
I'm afraid of him.
Ah. And he's someone
to be afraid of.
He's as unscrupulous with women
as he is ruthless with men.
But why did he
send me down here?
I don't understand him.
You don't, huh?
No.
Ha ha ha!
What's the matter?
You probably understand Blackie
a whole lot better
than he understands you.
You see, I don't think
Blackie ever knew
your type of woman before.
But there's nothing
to be afraid of,
unless you're afraid
of yourself.
Are you?
No.
No, I guess I'm a little dazed.
You see, I've been
in San Francisco
for over six weeks,
and nothing ever happened,
and then, within
the last 24 hours,
the whole world's
gone Topsy-turvy.
Makes me feel like running home.
Well, if you are afraid,
you'd better run home.
How about it?
I'm going to stay.
That's right.
You're in probably
the wickedest,
most corrupt,
most godless city in America.
Sometimes it frightens me.
I wonder what the end
is going to be.
But nothing can
harm you if you
don't allow it to,
because nothing in the world,
no one in the world, is all bad.
Do you know who gave the chapel
that organ we've been
dedicating tonight?
The most godless, scoffing,
and unbelieving soul
in all San Francisco--
Blackie Norton.
Blackie heard
one night that I was
saving for an organ.
The very next morning,
men arrived to plan
the installation.
Cost him $4,000.
If that monkey
would save his money
for a few weeks,
he'd be rich.
He's a tremendous force,
Blackie is.
If he were only
a force for good
instead of evil.
I've tried to do
something with him
for years,
but I haven't had any luck.
Maybe I'm not the right one.
You've known each
other a long time,
haven't you?
Oh, sure, sure.
Blackie and I
were kids together.
Born and brought up
on the coast.
We used to sell newspapers
in the joints
along pacific street.
Blackie was
the leader of
the neighborhood kids,
and I was his pal.
Our families used to
try to get us to go
to mass on Sunday,
but we generally ducked.
That reminds me,
that Rooney kid
ducked mass.
And then I got
so I wanted to go.
Blackie thought I was crazy.
And when I decided
I was going to study
for the priesthood,
I wanted to talk to Blackie.
I wanted to see
if I couldn't get him
to understand,
to feel a little bit as I felt,
but he just said, "well,
good luck, sucker,"
and that was all.
We never were able
to have that talk.
I came back from college
and found Blackie
deeper than ever
in the life of the coast.
But he has a code.
He's always had,
ever since
we were kids.
He never lied, he never cheated,
and he never
took an underhanded
advantage of anyone.
There's a picture
of us together
when we were kids.
Hmm.
Oh, don't let him
know I told you
about the organ.
He'd never forgive me.
Oh, no. Oh, no, I won't.
He's that way, Blackie is.
Ashamed of his good deeds
as other people
are ashamed of their sins.
And nobody will ever
make me believe
there isn't
more good than bad
in Blackie Norton.
[Hissing]
Holy smoke!
The coffee!
[Crowd]
* San Francisco *
* here is your wandering one *
* saying,
"I'll wander no more" *
* other places only
make me love you best *
* tell me you're the heart
of all the golden west *
* San Francisco,
welcome me home again *
* I'm coming home
to go roaming no more *
* San Francisco,
open your golden gate *
* you let no stranger wait
outside your door *
* San Francisco,
here is your wandering one *
* saying,
"I'll wander no more" *
* other places
only make me love you best *
* tell me you're the heart
of all the golden west *
* San Francisco,
welcome me home again *
* I'm coming home
to go roaming no more **
[cheering]
Ladies and gentlemen,
introducing the president
of the ladies
Blackie Norton club,
miss Della Bailey!
[Cheering]
Girls and boys,
I just want to tell you
that the ladies of the coast
wish to go on record
as endorsing Blackie Norton
right up to the limit!
Ladies and gentlemen, I will now
introduce that great guy,
our candidate.
Born on the coast,
raised on the coast,
lives on the coast,
a-vying for the coast,
our champion, Blackie Norton!
[Cheering]
Thanks. I'm no politician.
I didn't ask for this,
but now that I'm in it,
I won't stop until I get
some decent fire laws
for our people
down on the coast.
[Cheering]
[Man]
Wait a minute, Norton.
What I want to know is,
what construction company
is paying you
for trying to
rebuild the coast?
Yeah. That's right.
How about it, Blackie?
Why are you going into politics?
Tell us, Norton.
Here's the answer you can take
to your boss Jack Burley.
Oh! Oh!
We've tried long enough
to get a square deal
from those potbellied
landowners up on Nob Hill.
Now we're going to
go after it on our own!
Wait a minute.
Tommy, come here.
This is Jim Sullivan's kid.
Last new year's Eve,
he and his sister
had to jump three floors
out of a burning building.
Are we going to go on
letting these Nob Hill stiffs
make fire dancers
out of our women and kids?
Not if I can help it!
Yeah! Yeah!
And now, free beer on me!
You were swell!
I'm so proud
of you, I--
thanks. Run along
and get yourself
some beer.
Aren't we going to be together?
I told you I'd be busy
when I brought you here.
Well, I'll wait for you.
You get yourself
a drink. That's a girl.
Professor, will you
do me a favor?
Sure.
Go and get Trixie
and take her back
to town.
To town?
Yeah. She's
hanging around
getting stiff.
Then what about miss Blake?
Oh. How do you do?
How do you do?
I brought her out here.
I'll see that she
gets home all right.
[Waltz playing]
That's awful pretty.
Know the name of it?
Would you?
Would I what?
Glad you came?
Yes.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Do you mind
going a little
faster, please?
I promised father Mullin
I'd stop by if I had time.
Yeah, sure.
Go on. Get up there!
You and Tim seem
to be hitting it off
pretty well.
Oh, yes.
What do you talk about?
Lots of things.
His work, mostly.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
You believe in that hocus-pocus.
Yes.
Even if I hadn't believed,
the faith of a man
like father Mullin
would make me.
Yeah, that's the trouble.
It gets hold of people
that are all right
and makes monkeys out of them.
It lost me Tim Mullin.
He'd have made
the greatest gambler
on the coast.
I wanted to hang on to him.
He loves you more
than anyone else
in the world.
Yeah? Well, he
blew me for a lot
of plaster saints.
You know, I don't
go for that sucker
competition, Mary.
Blackie's got to be
number-one boy.
But it isn't competition.
I think people who
believe in something
can love each other more.
Well, honey, if that's
what you believe,
it's all right with me.
I don't hold it against you.
Say, who's that mug
you're stuck on?
No one.
Well, didn't there used to be?
No.
Never?
Never, no.
Whoa.
Are you kidding?
No.
Well, I'm a sucker if I ever
knew a girl like you before.
Come on. Get along there, Dan.
You must have had to do
some fast footwork
to side-step those dudes
out there in Benson,
Colorado, huh?
It wasn't
so difficult,
Mr. Norton.
Blackie.
That's better.
* he holds her in his arms *
* would you? Would you? *
* he tells her of her charms *
* they met as you and I *
* and they were only friends *
* but before the story ends *
* he'll kiss her with a sigh *
* would you? Would you? *
* if the girl were I,
would you? Would you? *
* and would you dare to say *
* let's do the same as they? *
* I would, would you... *
well, that lets me out.
That all your dough?
Every dime.
Here's 100 bucks.
Go get yourself a cup of coffee.
Gee, thanks, Blackie.
I guess I'll get some sleep.
Hey, chick. Put this
stuff away, will you?
Good morning.
Good morning, Burley.
Anything I can do for you?
I want to buy that
contract you have
with miss Blake.
You think it's for sale?
I don't see why
you're so stubborn
about it, Norton.
You might be needing money.
I'm doing all right.
You may be in for
a few difficulties
down here.
What do you mean?
Ever hear of
the Johnson-addi
gambling ordinance?
Yep.
You're operating
against the law.
So's every other joint here.
Well, I'm just
telling you, that's all.
You've taken quite an interest
in the little lady, haven't you?
I'm only interested
in making her
a useful member
of the tivoli
opera company.
Yeah. Now, isn't that
sweet of you?
Well, I'll tell you
what I'll do, Burley.
If the little lady
wants to leave me,
you can have
her contract
for nothing.
[Mary] * would you? *
* and would you dare to say *
* let's do the same as they? **
Mary?
Yes?
Come here a minute, will you?
You're taking
a long chance,
Blackie.
Yep. Maybe I got an Ace
or two in the hole, too.
Oh, Mr. Burley.
Good morning, miss Blake.
Thank you for the lovely roses.
I'm so glad you liked them.
Sit down, kid.
Mr. Burley wants to
buy your contract from me.
I told you I wasn't giving up.
You really
think I'm ready
for the tivoli?
Yes, but what's more important,
baldini thinks so.
Oh!
What do you say, kid?
Would you like to
sell my contract,
Mr. Norton?
No.
I'm very sorry.
I can't accept.
Too bad, Burley. I hope
I can do you a favor sometime.
Thanks, Norton.
Would you thank
signor Baldini
for me?
You've both been more than kind.
It's been a pleasure,
and I hope to show you
another side of
San Francisco, if I may.
Thank you.
Good-bye, Norton.
So long.
You wouldn't take 5,000
to tear up that contract,
would you?
Nope.
10,000?
Are you trying to
make an impression?
I said he could have
your contract for nothing
if you wanted to leave.
I'm afraid the tivoli will
have to struggle along, Burley.
Did you do that, Blackie?
Sure. You made
your own choice, kid.
And I hope you'll never
be sorry, miss Blake.
Good-bye.
Oh, that was awfully
generous of you--
about the contract, I mean.
Oh, forget it.
Say, look, kid.
You've heard a lot about
the tivoli opera house
from mugs that never
get anywhere.
Now I'm going to tip you off
to a few facts about
the paradise.
Come on.
Ever been here?
No.
Well, I don't do
much office work,
but here's where
I keep my records.
Take a hinge at those cups.
Every year,
the wine agents in town,
Freddie Duane and all the rest,
pull off an event called
the chicken's ball.
Ever hear of it?
No.
You know what happens there?
They have a competition
and give a prize
of $10,000 in gold
to the proprietor
of the joint who puts on
the most artistic show,
and you know who's won it
three times running?
The paradise.
Oh, that's fine.
For artistic achievement.
That's what they said
when they slipped me
the trophy.
Artistic achievement.
That's wonderful.
Ain't I telling you?
I'm going to win it
the next time, too,
and the dough goes
to the campaign fund
for those little mugs
down here on the coast.
Hey. You know,
I like to look into
those big lamps of yours.
If you ever cut this,
I'll put some in my watch.
I'm crazy about you, kid.
You know it, don't you?
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Well, you look kind of scared.
I guess maybe I am.
Of what?
You.
Are you sure it's me
you're afraid of?
Well, what do you think
we should do about it?
Nothing.
Nothing? Oh, because you
don't want to, maybe.
If that's it, don't
be afraid to spill it,
and we'll call it a day.
Oh, but it isn't right.
What isn't right?
For a man and a woman
to be stuck on each other?
Have you anything
better than that
in Colorado?
If you have, I'd like
to take a whirl at it.
It must be immense.
How does it feel
to feel like a woman
and be afraid of it?
Oh, Blackie, listen.
If you're going to
preach, please sing.
That's what I believe in.
Your voice.
The way you move.
The way you stand
on those pretty
little feet of yours.
That's what I believe in.
Don't you believe
in anything more
than that?
What more is there?
God.
God? Ha ha ha!
Isn't he supposed to be
taking care of the suckers
that come down to the missions
looking for help?
I've seen them
on their knees
asking for things
they should stand up
and fight for.
I don't see god
coming down and giving
them a shortcut.
That's not what I want.
I want to push over
the mugs in my way
before they push me over.
What I believe in
is not up in the air.
It's in here and in here.
But maybe that's not right.
Maybe it's not right
to feel alive,
like you and I feel
this minute...
But I think it's right.
Mary, I want to
get a kick out of
things I can see,
like lights on the harbor
or a good fight
or a woman worth looking at.
Did you ever taste
a fog in your mouth,
like it was salt,
or take hold of someone
and feel your blood
rushing like a river?
What more does a man need,
or a woman, either?
You know, I never tried
to kid you, Mary.
You take me as I am,
or you don't take me.
Tim doesn't try
to change me because
he knows he can't,
and you can't, either.
Nothing can.
You know what
I've been waiting for?
I've been waiting
to hear you say
I'm all right with you
the way I am.
Maybe you're ready
to say it now.
Are you?
I don't know.
Well, it's about time.
Oh, it's going to
be swell, baby.
I'll make you
queen of the coast.
You'll ride
in your own carriage,
and everybody will know
who you are.
I'll plaster your
name and face clear
to the golden gate.
You and I together
are going to find out
that we don't need
anything else but us.
Hey, look.
How about going upstairs
and having some chop suey, huh?
Come on.
[Man]
Watch me
and keep your mind on my feet.
Watch this wing.
See? That's it.
Then you do a sort of a--
what's the matter?
Come on, let's--
that's right, Trixie.
You can knock off.
Everybody's going to
have champagne on me!
Dig up some pommery
for the boys and girls.
All we got is semillon.
That champagne.
It's enough to
make me dizzy.
A guy gets killed.
Can I order you some breakfast?
No, thanks. Mary and I
will have chop suey upstairs.
Mary, I have
another new number
I'd like you to try.
Oh, no, no.
Not this morning.
Mat! Tell Charlie--
never mind. I'll
tell him myself.
Stay right here, honey.
I won't be a minute.
[Girl]
Gee, I haven't had
any champagne since--
nice going, sister.
You done all right.
[Humming]
Knock off, Maggie.
You're going to have
champagne.
Me, too?
Well, I'd like to know why not.
Oh, Mr. Blackie,
I haven't had any
of that for a long time!
Here's to Blackie!
Blackie! Blackie!
Where's Mary?
Oh, I guess
she went upstairs
to set the table.
Here's to you, darlin'.
I wish I had me youth.
I wish I'd never had mine.
Why, Trixie.
That's not nice, baby.
[Man] Tell Mary here's to her!
Babe, when
that runs out,
open up some more.
You bet I will.
Tell Mary
here's to her, Blackie.
Sure. "Everyone to
his own taste,"
the old lady said
as she kissed
the cow.
Ha ha! Ain't that--
what's the matter,
no sense of humor?
Oh, Blackie!
Oh, hello, Tim!
I just came
to talk about
the campaign.
Oh. Look,
Tim, do you mind
coming back later?
Sure. Sure.
Oh, by the way, Blackie,
I just saw Mary.
Yeah. I put her in a cab.
She said to tell you good-bye
and that she was taking you up
on your offer to let her
out of that contract.
What? What's that?
Well, you said she
could go, didn't you?
Well, yes, but--
she's gone to the tivoli,
and I'm glad
you did it, Blackie.
This was no place for her.
Oh, you think not, eh?
Of course not.
Neither did you, did you?
You think
she's better off
at the tivoli
under the management
of Jack Burley, huh?
She'll be safe
with Burley, Blackie.
You see, uh...
She doesn't love him.
Huh!
Now look, Tim. You like
chop suey, don't you?
Chop--sure.
Come upstairs.
We'll have some.
Good evening, ladies.
Good evening and get out.
The child has
a performance to give.
Oh, no. We've got to thank him.
Do let him stay.
Alone, I suppose.
That's right.
Come on, Louise.
In my day, the opera came first.
My mother's out there
tonight, Mary.
Is she?
Yes. She came
all the way from New York.
I guess she got tired
of reading about you
in my letters.
Well, in a few hours,
you'll be famous.
Before the whole town
is at your feet,
I want to put in my bid.
I love you, Mary,
and I want you to marry me.
I've always wanted you,
from the moment I first
set eyes on you,
but I didn't realize then
howi wanted you.
Well, I--
please don't try to
answer me now.
I just wanted you
to know how I felt.
Good luck, darling.
How do you do, Mr. Burley?
Good evening.
How do you do?
Fine, thank you.
How are you?
Fine, thanks.
Thank you.
I'll be right with you.
Want to take a look out front.
Hello there, Mr. Burley.
Hello there.
Jonathan.
What a thrilling first night.
I hope so.
Mr. Burley, we can't wait
to hear the new star.
Hello, Jack.
Have you seen signor Baldini?
Not yet.
Hello, Jack.
Big night, eh?
I hope so, senator.
Hi.
Good evening.
Hello, Norton.
I didn't
know you were
a first-nighter.
I am tonight.
I came to close you up.
To what?
Close you up. You've got
a girl appearing here
that's under contract to me.
No, you're wrong.
You abrogated
that contract.
You gave her
permission to leave.
I gave her a choice,
and she said she'd stay,
so the contract stands.
Look. See that man over there?
The one with
the big black mustache?
Well, that big, stupid-looking
man represents the law,
and he's got a paper
that's going to stop
your prima Donna
right in the middle
of her first cantata.
Isn't that awful?
You wouldn't do that.
I'm sorry, Burley,
but I thoughtlessly
got the man started,
and I can't do a thing with him.
Well, I guess I'll get my star.
Wait a minute. She
doesn't go on till
the second act.
That's not very good
showmanship.
We'll wait. I don't want
to listen to those others.
While you're waiting,
would you have a cigar?
Yeah, thanks.
Pardon me.
I'll get them.
Excuse me. I want to
speak to Mr. Baldini.
Excuse me.
Sure.
What is it?
Hello? Hello, central.
Filmore 2871.
Norton's outside
with the sheriff
to stop Mary Blake.
Stop her?
Yes.
He can't do that!
Is Mr. Davis there?
Maybe he can.
Oh, hello, Davis?
This is Jack Burley.
I want you to hurry
over to the opera house
with a restraining order
to hold up a process.
I don't care if
the office closed
10 hours ago!
Find him! But I've
got to have it.
But what is it?
You go backstage.
I'll see what I can do.
[Woman singing opera in french]
Well, here you are, Norton.
Oh, thanks.
Thank you.
Have a peanut?
No, thanks.
Hmm. Cameo here, eh?
I didn't think
you knew that brand
at the paradise.
Yeah, that's right.
You needn't have bothered
to call up Davis, Burley.
I could have told you his deputy
was away on a deep-sea
fishing trip.
He's crazy about fishing,
so I chartered him a boat.
How about you and I make a deal?
I'll give you 15,000
for that contract.
I'd like to oblige you,
but the thing is
out of my hands.
That process server
is the meanest man
west of the Rockies.
He'd push his mother
off a boat for half a dollar.
He'd turn the air off
in a baby's Incubator
just to watch the little
sucker squirm.
Well, Jim, what do you say?
The quicker I stop her,
the quicker we get home.
Remind me not to order these
for the paradise.
Right.
[Singing opera in french]
That's kind of pretty, ain't it?
Yeah.
Sit down.
Hey, what's the idea?
I didn't come
to this opera
to hear the opera.
Sit down.
[Men singing Faust]
[Man singing]
Blackie, I think she's great.
Yeah, not bad.
Seems a kind of
shame to choke
her off, huh?
Oh, yes.
He's gone around back.
It's all right.
There's nothing to worry about.
[Speaking Italian]
[Orchestra playing]
Darling!
Blackie.
Hello, kid.
Oh...
Madame Albani--
oh, I understand.
It looks like
Burley's getting
a little careless--
putting things down on paper.
Oh, yes. He asked me
to marry him.
No. On the level?
You know, you were
all right tonight, kid.
Did you really
think so, Blackie?
Yes. Say, who am I
to hold out against
these 3,000 mugs
that went goofy over you?
I never caught
this opera racket
up to now.
How long has that been going on?
Oh, only about 150 years.
No fooling?
Well, it's all right.
You know, I was proud
of you tonight.
Is that all?
All?
Don't you love me?
Oh, sure, sure.
Well, you haven't said so.
Oh, well, I love you, kid.
You know, I never
sprang that line
but once,
25 years ago.
Who was she?
Oh, just a girl I knew.
I haven't seen her lately.
She's up in San Quentin.
Oh, so I'm the second, hmm?
No, you're the first.
Will you marry me, Blackie?
Marry you?
Mm-hmm.
Well, I'm a sucker.
If you ain't the most
domestic woman...
I suppose, if that's
the only thing that
would make you happy.
You know, the gang
always said I'd be
a sucker.
Oh, Blackie!
[Knock on door]
Wait a minute.
Come in.
Hello, Blackie.
How are you, boy?
Feeling pretty fit.
Oh, Mary, you were great.
Oh, thank you.
I had to battle my way
through half
of San Francisco
to get here.
Father Tim, Blackie and I--
we're going to be married.
Yup. That's right.
The little girl
harpooned me.
Well, I guess you know
how I feel
about it, don't you, Mary?
Mm-hmm.
So she harpooned you, huh?
A girl that any man
in San Francisco
would give his right arm for,
but she had to harpoon you.
Blackie, I'm not
going to wish you
the best of everything
because you've got it already.
Thanks, Tim.
Now, I know you folks
would like me to stay,
but I really have to go.
Really. I'm sorry.
Of course,
if you insist,
I could stay.
Will you get out?
[Tim]
Oh, I'm sorry.
Sorry, father.
Mary, you haven't changed yet.
Well, Norton.
Oh, I just thought I'd come back
and congratulate my fiancee.
Your--
oh, I'm sorry, Jack.
You better get out
of that rig, baby.
The gang is
waiting to celebrate
your homecoming.
Where?
Down home in the paradise.
They're waiting
to hear you sing
San Francisco.
At the paradise?
Yeah.
Wait a minute.
You don't mean to say
that you're
going to send her
back there now?
Sure.
What kind of a chump
do you think I am?
I'm going to marry her, ain't I?
Well,
what do you want, kid?
Me or this?
[Band playing
ta-Ra-Ra boom-der-e]
Good evening, father.
Great business tonight.
Tell Mr. Norton
I'd like to see him.
O.K.
Is Blackie back here?
Yeah.
Where?
Where do you think?
In there.
Come in.
Gee, she looks
pretty sharp,
huh?
She's all right.
Say, uh, Blackie,
father Tim's out there.
He--he wants to see you.
Well, all right.
Bring him back.
O.K.
You know, you're a funny kid.
Why?
Why, the way you act,
anyone would think
that wasn't becoming.
Are you happy?
Yes. Yes.
Yes, I'm happy.
That's good.
Blackie, Blackie,
let's set the date
for our wedding now
so we can
tell father Tim
when he comes in.
Yeah, sure. Anytime.
Oh, but look,
it's got to be after election.
Oh, really?
The mob down here
know how I've always
kidded that sort of thing.
I can't back down now
and make a fool of myself
just before election.
It would lose me too many votes.
It means a lot to me
to win this fight,
not just for putting it
over on Burley,
but for the coast.
You understand?
Yes. Yes, I do.
I do understand.
We'll sneak off to Sacramento,
and I'll let you
slip the halter on me.
Say, I never thought
I'd be so goofy
about anyone.
[Knock on door]
Come in.
Hello, Tim.
Good evening, father.
What's wrong?
Are you out of your mind?
Why?
Showing Mary
like this to that
mob out there.
Like this?
What's wrong with her?
Yeah, sure.
What's wrong with
my being proud
to show her off?
Blackie, don't you
understand what I'm
trying to tell you?
Wait a minute.
I'm making her
queen of the coast.
You see those posters there?
5,000 of them
will be plastered
all over San Francisco
and 10,000 for ashcans
and the front
of trolley cars.
I'm not going to
let you do this,
Blackie.
I don't get you, Tim.
You never butted in
on me before.
Well, I am now.
You're not going to
exploit this girl.
Come here, Mary.
Will you tell his holiness
that you made up
your own mind
to come back?
I love him, father.
That isn't love, Mary.
Is that so?
Well, it happens
to suit me.
It isn't love
to let him drag you
down to his level.
Say, wait a minute, Tim.
I'm going to marry her.
Not if I can stop you.
You can't take
a woman in marriage
and then sell her immortal soul.
Immortal soul?
Now, look, I don't go
for that kind of talk.
Don't believe
in that nonsense
and never have!
You better get back
to the half-wits
that do!
[Man]
Blake's on next.
Mary, come with me.
I'm running this joint.
You take care
of your suckers.
I'll take care of mine.
She's not going out there.
I've listened to your
psalm-singing blather
and never squawked.
You can't bring it in here.
This is my joint!
Miss Mary Blake!
She's not going out there.
The place is crazy without you.
Get out there, kid.
Wait a minute.
You leave now,
and you're never coming back!
[Crowd yelling]
[Pounding]
[Women screaming]
Hey, Blackie!
Hey, Blackie,
it's Burley!
He's giving the joint the works!
You can't buck a guy like that.
Shut up.
Look at it. Come on.
Hey, Blackie!
Blackie, look!
Look at what
they're doing
to our joint!
You see what they're doing?
Is Mrs. Burley in?
She's in the small cellar.
What do you think
of our little shack?
Oh, but it's magnificent.
We only have one real treasure.
She's waiting to meet you.
Ha ha ha!
You needn't
sneak up on me.
I know you're there.
[Kiss]
Mary...
This is my mother.
How do you do, my dear?
How do you do, Mrs. Burley?
Maisie, have you been
in the house all day?
I just got back from the races.
You're even prettier
close to than you were
from me box at the tivoli.
Oh, so are you, Mrs. Burley.
Oh, go on with you.
Get out.
Get out? Me?
Certainly you.
If I have to sell
this amazing,
beautiful creature
the idea of joining
the Burley family,
sure, I got to tell
her lies about us
that, heaven help me,
no son should hear
his mother speak.
Call me as soon
as you've made
the sale.
Get out! Get out!
Sit down, my dear.
Take off your coat.
Thank you.
Now tell me,
why won't you marry my boy?
Mrs. Burley, you belong
to the aristocracy
of San Francisco.
I'm just
the daughter
of a country parson.
I haven't had
the advantage Jack
deserves in a wife.
Wait a minute, darling.
I didn't mean
what I said just now
about telling lies.
We'll speak the truth
to each other.
I think I know
what it's all about.
It's that rapscallion
Blackie Norton
you were working for
down on pacific street.
Listen, Mary.
I'm an old lady,
and I've been through
a lot in my life.
I came to San Francisco
in the winter of '51
in a sailing vessel
around the horn.
When I got here,
there were 150 males
to one female,
and if I do say it--
I shouldn't--
I wasn't so hard to look at.
I started business in a shack
near Portsmouth square
doing washing.
Do you know how long
me business lasted?
No.
About 45 minutes. Ha ha!
They busted me tub
to smithereens,
and there was
a free-for-all fight
between five of
the big swells in the town
to see which one
would take me to lunch,
so, you see, I got to know men.
I knew all kinds
in them early days,
and among them was a man
like Blackie Norton.
He was a selfish and sinful...
And adorable scoundrel.
So, you see, I've had
my Blackie Norton, too.
And you gave him up?
Yes, yes, I--I gave him up
because he was killing me soul.
Killing your soul?
And I pulled myself together,
and one day, I married Burley.
Burley was a good, solid man.
He never got used to
wearing his coat
till the day he died,
but he built me this mansion,
and every cuspidor
of the place
was 18-carat gold.
And there came a time
when I was glad I married him
because he loved me.
After a while,
Jack was born,
and I had me peace.
Look, Mary, you say
we're the aristocracy
of San Francisco.
We are.
Listen.
[People laughing]
Come here, Mary.
Listen to that.
That's the mcdonough mansion--
aristocrats--
and that party's been going on
for two days and nights
straight running.
There isn't
a rougher joint on
the whole Barbary coast
than that home
right here on Nob Hill.
They call this
the wickedest city
in the world,
and it's a bitter shame, it is,
for deep down,
underneath all our evil and sin,
we've got right here
the finest set of human beings
that was ever
rounded up
on one spot.
Sure, they had to have
wild adventure in their hearts
and dynamite in their blood
to come here in the first place.
That's why they're
so full of untamed deviltry now,
but we can't go on like this--
sinful and blasphemous,
with no fear for god
in our hearts.
That's the reason
why I want my boy
to have a good woman near him
and to raise
fine, beautiful kids
for the glory of our heritage.
You can make a fine man of him,
and maybe, one day,
you'll be proud
that you met up
with the family
of old
Maisie Burley,
the washerwoman.
I'm glad I know you
now, Mrs. Burley.
Maisie to you, darling.
Maisie.
[Bell ringing]
[Customers screaming]
Jiggers! Jiggers!
The joint's pinched!
[Women screaming]
Wait a minute.
Where are you going?
You're going to be caught,
so where you going?
Hey, what's the big idea?
Get back on the stage!
Get out!
No rough stuff, now.
Nobody gets hurt.
Good evening, Charlie.
I'm sorry.
What's the charge?
Serving
liquor without
a license.
We've got a license!
It's been revoked.
What will the rap be?
Probably 5,000 fine
and a year in jail.
You know judge cardigan.
Yeah, I know him,
but Burley knows him better.
I'd like to help you,
but I have me wife
and me kids
to care for.
I've been counting
on winning that
prize money
from the chicken's ball.
Give me a couple hours
to rustle up bail
and get my entertainers out.
Well, how about
being at the station
before 6:00 in the morning?
I'll be there.
Thanks.
It's an outrage!
Burley's timed this
so that you can't cop
that prize money tonight.
Babe, let's take a ride.
Will you bring me back?
That's up to him.
I'll have you all out.
Well, Blackie, had enough?
Oh, hello.
What's eating you?
We can't fight Burley, Blackie.
He's got you buffaloed, eh?
If we trail along with you,
we'll get what you're getting.
We can't afford to be raided.
The boys sent me.
The district's mugs
are counting on me
to go through for them.
You haven't done any business
since they started raiding you.
Where are you going
to get the money
to carry on your campaign?
Whoever wins that 10,000
tonight could carry us
through the campaign.
Not if I win it.
We'll build a new coast
that'll top anything
San Francisco's ever known.
The old coast
has been good to me
and to you, too,
up to now.
I won't quit.
Are you fighting for the coast,
or are you
fighting for
a personal reason?
We think it's personal.
We've had
a bellyful of
this boudoir battle.
So long.
[Women screaming]
[Woman]
Get away! Don't you
dare take my purse!
[Man]
Want anything from
inside, Blackie?
What? Oh.
[Bell ringing]
Well, I guess
I might as well
turn out the lights.
By golly, that's right.
There's no use
running up
your light bill.
[Woman]
You can't do that!
Well, that's the first time
the joint's ever been locked.
I threw the key away
the night it opened.
See you before 6:00, Blackie.
Come on! Let's get
going here now!
Come on!
[Bell ringing]
Break it up!
[Boy]
Paper!
Get your early morning paper!
Hiya, Blackie.
Hello, bill.
Have a paper.
Yeah, thanks.
Oh, that's all right.
It's on me tonight.
Paper!
Get your paper!
Early morning edition!
[Singing opera in Italian]
[Man singing]
[Speaking Italian]
Hey, hey, hey, wait a minute.
Oh, you're jealous.
That's the matter with you, eh?
Mary, I love you.
I'm glad.
Mr. Burley,
the caterers are here.
Have them put
the tables on the stage.
Yes, sir.
You'd better
look after things, dear.
Right, as usual.
Wait. You forgot
to ask the stagehand
to the banquet.
Did I?
I asked him.
Father Mullin.
Mary.
Oh, were you out front tonight?
Your last night?
Oh, I'm glad someone
of the old crowd
remember me.
I got my invitation
to your wedding, Mary.
Are you coming?
Of course.
Mary, are you happy?
Oh, yes.
Yes, I'm happy.
Then everything's all right.
Good night, my dear.
Oh, won't you stay
and join our party?
No. I'm sorry.
I must run along.
Well, good night.
God bless you.
Is madame tired?
Oh, no, no.
I'm quite all right.
Thank you.
[Knock on door]
Oh, come in.
They're calling for you, dear.
Oh, but I've got to change.
Don't bother now.
Change before we go
to the ball.
The ball?
Why, sure. We're
going to wind up
at the chicken's ball.
Oh, no, Jack.
Well, why not?
Well, I...
That's all right, dear.
I happen to know
that Blackie Norton
won't be there.
Eat, drink, and be merry,
for tomorrow you die.
Dead men don't have any fun.
Alice, look what I found
in one of the dressing rooms.
Well, I can
recommend him,
honey.
He's my husband.
[Cymbals crash]
Good evening.
Step this way, please.
Good evening, folks.
Do you mind if I sit down?
Oh, hello, Della.
I'm glad to
see you again.
You won't be for long.
I just dropped over
to tell you what
I think of you.
I haven't seen this woman
since she walked out
on the best man
in San Francisco
to marry the town's
number-one rodent.
Well, I think
you'd better go,
Della.
Oh, no. I've got
a few things I want
to tell you, too.
Now, in case you folks
don't follow me,
I'll tell you
that this mouse here
has just had a padlock
put on the paradise
and thrown all of
Blackie Norton's
performers in jail.
That's what Blackie got
for picking this phony
up out of the gutter
and giving her a chance.
Hold still.
Don't think
I want to breathe
the air near you
any longer than I have to.
You ought to
make that mouse
awfully happy.
Here's a five-spot, brother.
I'm buying back
me introduction
to you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
now, that distinguished
proprietor,
that illustrious showman,
Alaska Joe Kelso,
presents the golden gate trio.
* there's a big sensation
going around the town *
* called the Philippine dance *
* Philippine dance *
* there's a big sensation
going around town *
* you ought to see it
with all your friends... **
[Della]
Oh, Blackie!
Beat it, will you?
Oh, all right, Della.
Well, how about it, kid?
Did you get them out?
Well, what's the matter?
Aren't there any hockshops open?
No. It wasn't any use.
My troupe's being held
without bail.
Without bail?
There they are now, celebrating.
Who?
Oh, Burley and your
ex-nightingale.
Are they?
He won't be satisfied
until you're under a wet rock.
Why don't you go
curl that dude's
mustache,
and I'll
kiss the lady
with a bottle?
Ah, forget it, doll.
Thanks just the same.
You're a sweetheart
if there ever was one.
You know,
didn't I give you
this one?
Yeah. You were just a kid.
Yeah, that's right.
* 'cause that's that new tune
called the Philippine dance *
* oh, get him, Swanee *
* and the first thing
you do, babe *
* is move both shoulders... **
where you going, Blackie?
Over to my place.
Well, I've got to
pack up a few things.
I may be taking a little trip.
I'll go help you.
No, no, no.
You stay here
and see the show.
You come over later
and tell me who won.
Oh, Blackie,
they say you'll
go up for a year!
No, no.
I can handle it,
but I'm worried
about the others.
Gee, Blackie.
Your're kind to all
that you know.
[Applause]
Ladies and gentlemen,
the last entry of the evening
was supposed to have been
from Mr. Blackie
Norton's paradise.
But as it is now 4:30
and the performers
have failed to
arrive,
why, we'll
close the show
without them.
Mr. Duane.
I'm representing
the paradise
for Mr. Norton.
Mary,
I forbid you
to go up there.
[Applause]
Oh, Dave. Know
where Blackie
Norton lives?
Sure.
Well, go get him.
Ladies and gentlemen,
representing the paradise cafe,
miss Mary Blake.
[Applause]
Play San Francisco.
[Orchestra playing]
* it only takes
a tiny corner of *
* this great big world
to make the place we love *
* my home upon the hill,
I find I love you still *
* I've been away,
but now I'm back *
* to tell you *
* San Francisco *
* open your golden gate *
* you let no stranger wait *
* who's a-knockin',
who's a-knockin' *
* outside of your door *
* San Francisco *
* here comes your
wandering one *
* and I'm saying,
and I'm saying *
* that I'm gonna
wander no more *
* other places, other places *
* only make me love you best *
* tell me, tell me *
* you're the heart
of the golden west *
* the golden west *
* San Francisco *
* welcome me home again *
* I'm coming home
to go a-roamin' *
* no more *
come on, everybody!
Join in the chorus with me!
* hoo Dee hoo, la la la *
* San Francisco *
* welcome me home again *
come on!
Everybody sing!
Sing, everybody!
* no more *
* other places only make me
love you best *
* tell me, tell me you're
the heart of the west *
* San Francisco *
* welcome me home again *
* I'm coming home
to go a-roamin' no more *
* San Francisco,
open your golden gate *
* you let no stranger wait
outside your door *
* San Francisco,
here is your wandering one *
* saying I'll wander no more *
* other places make me
love you best *
* tell me you're the heart
of all the golden west *
* San Francisco *
* welcome me home again *
* I'm coming home
to go roamin' *
* no more **
no, kid.
Wait here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you are the jury who shall
judge these criminals,
and by your applause
shall ye know them,
beginning at this end!
[Cheering]
Ladies and gentlemen,
the appearance
of miss Blake
for the paradise
was as much
a surprise to me
as it is to you,
but, however,
I congratulate you
upon your choice
and present
the award
to miss Blake
for Mr. Blackie Norton
with my congratulations.
[Blackie]
Wait a minute.
There's been
a mistake here,
Mr. Duane.
I never told
this woman she could
appear for me.
You got me all wrong, sister.
I don't need this kind of dough.
[Crash]
[Muttering]
Shall I take you home, dear?
Thank you.
Everybody stew!
All right, professor,
give a little music there.
[Orchestra playing]
[Low rumbling]
What was that?
[Crashing]
[Screaming]
Mary!
Blackie! Blackie!
Blackie!
[Muttering indistinctly]
[Groaning]
[Man]
You can't go in there!
You're crazy!
Ethel, come back!
[Ethel]
You let me alone!
Jim! Jim!
Jim!
Hey, you better get out of here
before this place falls--
Jim! Jim!
Where are you, Jim?
Jim, where are you?
Jim!
[Man]
Mr. Norton.
There. Thanks a lot.
Gee, that was a whopper, huh?
Yeah. Think you can
walk all right?
Yeah, I can make it.
You know
if Mary Blake
got out all right?
I didn't see her.
Well, we certainly
don't do things
halfway
in San Francisco, do we?
Yeah, that's right.
[Woman]
Eddie! Eddie!
Mildred! Mildred!
Oh! Ha ha!
You're hurt!
No, I'm all right.
Where are the kids?
They're safe.
You're hurt!
Where are the kids?
They're safe in a vacant lot.
The roof fell in.
The baby laughed!
He laughed? Ha ha!
[Eddie]
Ain't that just
like him? My kid.
[Bell ringing]
Mr. Norton!
Please. We're pinned under.
Please.
Connie's still alive.
I can hear her
breathing.
Hey, hey! Give me
a hand here, will you?
Come on. They're caught in here.
[Low rumbling]
Here it comes again.
Wait a minute.
You'll get killed.
Come on! Get out!
[Screaming]
Kelly! Have you seen Mary Blake?
I'm innocent, o lord--
stop that drivel!
Have you seen
Mary Blake?
Leave me alone!
Have you seen Mary Blake?
Or Jack Burley?
Oh, I saw
Mr. Burley.
He's over there.
Oh, dick!
[Woman] I thought I'd lost you!
[Man]
There, there, honey.
It's all right.
You're not hurt, are you?
There. Don't cry.
Don't cry, dear.
Irene!
Hey, hey.
Give me a hand
here, will you?
Irene!
Give me a hand, will you?
Irene! Irene!
Irene.
Irene!
No! No!
Oh!
Oh, no!
Chick! Have you seen Mary Blake?
I've lost my old lady, Blackie.
Maybe she went home.
I can't find her.
My house is
in the street.
Look out for live wires!
[Bell ringing]
Can you tell me
where they've taken
the injured?
Couldn't tell you, partner.
My house is on fire!
Four blocks down
on Fulton street!
No use, boss.
Sorry, brother.
The water main's broken.
There's no water.
Anybody here?
Is Mary Blake here?
She lived here
but hasn't been back
since the quake.
We're getting
everyone out of here.
The flames are picking up.
Mommy! Mommy!
Oh, Jimmy, how are you?
Let's get out of here!
[Bells ringing]
[Man]
You'll all get
something to eat.
You people will
all get something
to eat
down at Sacramento
and Octavia street.
Push on, push on.
Push it down, push it down.
[Music playing]
I'm sorry, friend.
Good luck to you.
Thanks.
Why can't you save what's left
of my building
instead of destroying it?
I can't help it, mister.
That's my building
you're going to dynamite.
I've worked half my life for it.
We're doing it
to save other
buildings.
We haven't any water.
It's the only way
of stopping
the fire.
We're dynamiting all the way
from here to Nob Hill.
All right, let her go.
Fire!
Mrs. Burley!
Mrs. Burley,
have you seen
Mary Blake?
She was with my son.
He's dead, isn't he?
Well, it's god's will.
[Sobbing]
You have to move on,
Mrs. Burley.
We're dynamiting.
Can't you wait a minute?
Oh, it doesn't matter.
Are the wires all set?
All set.
Everybody clear!
All ready.
Fire!
My son was born there.
Never mind, Blackie Norton.
It's god's help
we both need now.
Good-bye.
Hey! You can't go through there!
Hurry up!
Fire!
[Piano playing oh! Susanna]
Mary! Mary, my darling!
Thank god!
My prayers have
been answered!
I've found you at last!
Want a lift, brother?
Thanks. Where are you going?
Daly city to get some
milk for the kiddies.
If you see
a red-headed girl
in a white dress,
tell her Blackie's
looking for her.
Glad to, and god help you
to find her, brother.
[Carriage passing]
Better stand back
from that wreckage.
I'm looking for the priest.
I think he's doing rescue work
at the stable next
to the carbarns.
Thanks. Have you
seen anything
of a girl--
sorry.
I've just come down
from the presidio.
All right.
[Man praying in Latin]
Mamma Mia!
Oh, mamma Mia!
[Groan]
Hiya, Blackie.
Hello, mat.
The cops couldn't hold on to me.
I got away from them.
Did you?
That's great.
Yeah. It took
an earthquake
to get me.
How are you making it?
Oh, I'll
pull through.
I'll be all right.
Yeah, sure.
Sure, you will.
Hey, Blackie,
I hear that Mary went on for you
at the chicken's ball.
I was
wrong about her.
She's a great kid.
She's all right.
Don't leave him.
There you are.
[Tim]
Now, you're
going to try to get
some sleep, aren't you?
[Girl] Yes.
With your eyes open?
That's right.
Hello, Blackie.
Thanks, Tim.
That map
of yours needs
some attention.
Come on.
No, no, no.
I'm all right.
You haven't found
Mary yet, have you?
No.
Well, you can't want her
for the paradise, Blackie.
That's gone.
I wasn't thinking
of the paradise, Tim.
Wait a minute.
Come on, mug.
I'm going to
take you to Mary.
You--
is she all right?
Yeah, she's all right.
You folks will have
to be vaccinated.
It's for your own good.
Joe, take these people
to the hospital tent.
[Choir]
* my god, to thee *
* nearer to thee *
* nearer, my god, to thee *
* even though it be a cross *
* that raiseth me *
* still all my song would be *
* nearer, my god, to thee *
* nearer to thee... *
Tim.
I want to thank god.
What do I say?
Just say what's
in your heart,
Blackie.
* my god, to thee *
* nearer to thee... *
thanks, god. Thanks.
* even though it be... *
I really mean it.
* that raiseth me *
* still all my song shall be *
* nearer, my god, to thee *
* nearer, my god, to thee **
fire's out! The fire's out!
The fire's out!
[Cheering]
Come on, come on!
The fire's out!
Hooray!
We'll build a new San Francisco!
Hallelujah!
* of the coming of the lord *
* he has trampled
out the vintage *
* where the grapes
of wrath are stored *
* he has loosed
the fateful lightning *
* of his terrible, swift sword *
* his truth is marching on *
* he has sounded forth
his trumpet *
* that shall never
call retreat *
* he is sifting out
the souls of men *
* before his judgment-seat *
* oh, be swift, my soul,
to answer him *
* be jubilant, my feet *
* our god is marching on *
* glory, glory, hallelujah *
* his truth is marching on *
* glory, glory, hallelujah **
[humming San Francisco]
Captioning made possible by
U.S. department of education
and Turner entertainment group
captioning performed by
the national captioning
institute, inc.
Captions copyright 1995
Turner entertainment co.
All rights reserved
public performance of captions
prohibited without permission of
national captioning institute