we were returning from Shirdi and
our car broke down on the way...
she is in labour,
can we come in for sometime?
Call them in!
- Please come in!
Thank you very much,
will I find a doctor here?
So a baby is expected?
-Yes.
Yourwife is expecting?
-Yes, doctor.
Please hurry up!
-Yes, I am!
Congratulations sir, God has given
you a very pretty daughter!
How is Rama?
- She is perfectly alright.
She has just fallen asleep.
Here you are!
Great! She was born even before
I could get here.
Doctor, please don't get upset
at my daughter's haste.
Thanks for the trouble
you took to come here.
Here is your fees.
-What is the need for this?
Actually I need it!
Aunt Leela, the medicine you gave
me for a cold, really worked.
Doctor, you've taken fees to come
here.
Do you also collect to leave?
Okay, I am leaving!
Please take this money.
Sir, we may be poor but we can't
accept this. Please keep it back.
Then you tell me,
what can I do for you?
Sir, we don't have a child...
please pray that
we also get a child...
actually, a child was born
in our house last night...
what I mean is that
even my wife should...
He has understood!
-Yes, I will surely pray for you.
You'll have done us a big favor,
if we would get twin daughters...
then I would surely give you
one of my daughters.
Okay, good bye!
- Good bye, sir.
Listen, come here...
Why did you do this?
- They really did get twin daughters.
So you hid one of them?
- So what?
What would they do with
two identical daughters?
Didn't he say that if they would
get twins, he'd give us one!
He said it that doesn't mean he'd
do it, even I say a lot of things!
Why didn't you think how we'll
raise a child from a rich family?
We'll give her the love that is
rarely found in the rich families!
Grandmother, your
cough has increased.
Yes child but yet, I don't die!
Grandmother, have this medicine.
I am losing my eyesight too!
But I don't mind because,
I cannot see...
the torture that is meted
out on you.
Wretched girl!
Even the servants are not
called like this!
You go, child.
- But grandmother...
Are you dead?
- Go child, don't bother about me.
Yes, aunty.
I've been calling you since past
two hours. Couldn't you hear me?
Aunty, grandmother...
- Damn that old woman!
We'll be relieved if she dies!
I feel like conducting her
final rites when she is alive!
Stop staring! Will you get me hot
water or will your ancestors get it?
I'll get it.
Will your legs break
if you walk faster?
I've not seen
a bigger idiot than you!
It's time for my college and
you've not yet ironed my sari?
I'll do it, Sheila.
- Hurry up, stupid!
Did you get the soap?
- I'll get it.
Wonderwhy she is with us!
She will never do anything
unless you don't tell her.
Why don't you tell her anything?
Wait a minute!
And what are you doing there?
I was just polishing my shoes!
Have you worked all your life
that today you are doing this?
Hey, wretched girl!
Polish these shoes.
But...
- Give it to her.
Giving!
Here, child.
- Polish them quickly.
Why did you ask her to do it, the
poor girl does many other things.
Do you ever see how much
she eats the whole day?
If she does some exercise,
her fat will burn out!
She gets hot water for you everyday,
why don't you repair the geyser?
I'll do that only when the lawyer
will get this month's allowance.
Didn't Seeta's father trust
you even a bit...
why did he entrust the entire
property to the lawyers before dying?
This bungalow is also in Seeta's
name and what do we get?
All we get is
Rs. 5,000/- per month.
That too we'll get only till
Seeta gets married.
Her marriage!
It's a chiffon sari,
do you know how expensive it is?
Be careful while ironing it.
What is it?
- Sir, your tea.
Old man, who asked you
to get tea for me?
Where is that pretty girl?
You mean Seeta, she is
attending to Madam's chores.
ldiot, anybody can attend
to sister's chores...
ask her to attend to me,
give me a match!
Listen, I don't want to see
your mug from tomorrow morning.
Get out now!
Sister, can l
polish father's shoes?
No Babloo, I will do it,
give it here!
No, while you iron this sari,
I'll polish these shoes.
Both the jobs will be done soon!
-And what if your mother sees?
She'll scold me.
And if you are late,
she will yet scold you!
Alright, do it but
don't dirty your hands.
Seeta, are you going to get the
soap or shall I come and hit you?
Oh my, I forgot!
I'll get it, aunty!
What took you so long
to get a bar of soap?
Get out from here!
Yes.
- Please come here.
I have a lot of work.
-Will you stand there and talk to me?
I won't eat you up, why don't you
do things for me too?
Will you do it?
-What do you want me to do?
You are very simple! Okay,
can you stitch up this button?
You keep it aside,
I'll do it in the afternoon.
It will take two minutes, do it now.
Here is the needle and
thread and the button too!
I mean it, Seeta. I feel very sorry
to see you in this state.
But you are to be blamed for this,
just trust me once...
nobody will tell you a word but
you think that I am your enemy!
Look what she has done!
-What happened?
Coming!
- Sheila, please forgive me.
What happened, child?
Aunty, I am extremely sorry, there
were too many things at a time...
Liar! Mother, she burnt my sari!
You louse! How dare you?
It happened by mistake.
- It was by mistake...
or you did it purposely?
You are jealous of my daughter!
Why would I be jealous ofher?
- How dare you argue?
I will skin your hide!
-Aunty!
Don't beat her!
- Forgive me, aunty.
I will kill you today!
Stop interfering, move away!
Get inside! Only when you'll be
locked in here, will you realize.
Only when you'll not be fed for
4-5 days you'll value things.
You keep quiet, you've spoilt her!
Mother, father,
why did you'll leave me?
Nobody loves me here!
Mother, I would like to come to you!
Listen to me, for how long
will you order food from outside?
Please let Seeta out.
- Stop siding her!
I just suggested.
She has become too big for her
boots.
Two days if she is inside,
she'll get back into her senses!
That's okay but...
- But what?
Nothing!
Mother, the laundry man hasn't
got my blue sari yet.
I've to go to college.
- Do you have dearth of saris?
I promised my friends that
I would wear a blue sari today.
That laundry man is very mean!
- I am a little surprised, child.
Do you go to college to study or
display your sari to your friends?
Shut up, you are
always taunting her!
This is the age to flaunt things.
Child, you sit at home today.
I've to pay my college fees today.
- Fees??
Is it the 1st today?
- I think so!
Then the lawyer will come today.
- If it's the 1st, he'll surely come.
Please come in, Mr. Gupta.
What is the matter,
you don't look alright.
Nothing much, I've got cold,
you please sit!
You should have called a doctor.
- Ramu, get tea and snacks quickly!
Hello!
- Hello!
There is no need to call for
anything. I am in a hurry, please call Seeta.
You come here as ifit's a duty.
-Well, it is a duty.
Your brother made me the trustee
ofhis entire wealth.
But the responsibility of such
a vast wealth is not at all easy.
Mr. Gupta, you have not
seen our responsibility.
We have raised this orphan girl
as our own child.
We always have the fear that people
may criticize our upbringing.
You do take care ofher!
- But yet, I live under that fear.
I don't want to lack anything
in my responsibility.
I suggest that you get her married.
Your responsibility will end
and so will mine!
As per brother's will, our
responsibly is till her marriage.
Have you'll seen
any suitable boy for her?
We've seen dozens of them!
But I feel that not a single one
is suitable for our Seeta.
Mr. Gupta, why don't you
suggest some good proposal?
Isn't it, Kaushalya?
-Yes, even we will keep looking!
Yes, I will look out.
Come, child!
Why did you get it, you should have
asked the servant to get it.
I'll make the tea. She loves
doing household chores.
Even if I stop her, she keeps
doing something or the other!
That's very nice, girls must be
well versed with domestic chores.
How are you, child?
-Yes, thank you.
Child, this is your
monthly allowance.
Take it!
- Count it!
What is the need for that,
it must be exact!
I will be convinced.
- Child, give the money to your uncle.
Here, take your tea.
- Thank you.
It's exact, Mr. Gupta.
- It had to be!
He was just joking about it!
Don't give me, give it
to the person it belongs to.
Alright Mr. Badrinath,
permit me to leave.
Have some more tea.
- Let him leave, he is a busy man!
She's right, I am in a hurry.
Good bye!
What are you doing here?
Come on, take this tray inside.
You seem to be in a great hurry
to get your niece married.
Don't you know the day she gets
married, you'll be out on the street!
That's right but...
- Damn you and your buts!!
That too is right!
Yes, grandmother.
- Come here, child.
Sit close to me.
You are looking very beautiful.
You look like a princess!
You mark my words, one day a
prince in a shining armor will come...
and will sweep away my princess
and take her to his kingdom!
These are mere fairy tales,
no prince will ever come!
He will, my child. I have
a strong feeling that he will come!
Grandmother, you are very nice!
Grandmother, I am going!
Aunty, you called.
Yes, why are you yet
dressed like this?
Remove the jewellery and this sari!
Don't you feel like taking them out?
Give it soon and
what about this sari?
I'll go in my room and take it out.
-Why there? Take it out here!
Stop this act of a chastity,
shameless girl!!
Take it out and
go and cook the food!
Aunty, how can l...
-What do you mean?
Are you going or shall I hit you?
Oh! So my sister did manage
to take out your clothes?
Why have you left the rest,
do they belong to you?
What is it, old man?
-You had asked for cigarettes.
Throw them for all I care!
Grandmother!!
- Stop crying, my child!!
Why can't I die?
- Don't say that, my child!
Grandmother...
- Don't say a word, child.
I understand your tears!
God, isn't there anybody in this
world who can save her from them?
''Life's a game,
some win, some lose...''
''there are experts,
and there are novices''
''Do you get it, mister...?
Or perhaps you, fatso?''
''There are experts
and there are novices''
''Life's a game.
Some win, some lose...''
''there are experts,
and there are novices''
''Do you get it mister...?
Or maybe you have?
''Cut the nonsense.
Get to work, Raka''
''Oh yes, it's work that
will bring you fame''
''You're like a bird in flight,
I swear by you''
''Don't you fall...
watch your step''
''Get that, mister...?
Or perhaps you, sister?''
''Step back, children...
- Sit down''
''Turn around, snobbish one''
''And people will give you
a round of applause''
''Applause!''
''A true spectacle
I will show them...''
''every heart, I will send pounding''
''Get that, sardarji?
Get it, lady?''
''There are experts
and there are novices''
''Life's a game.
Some win, some lose.
''There are experts
and there are novices''
''Got it, mister?
- Or you, Pathan?''
Damn it!
-What is the matter, chief?.
Nothing Cheena,
it's just my bad luck.
I bet on the wrong number.
- But you were given a right tip!
I saw number six last night
in my dream and I bet on that number.
And now I've lost the money!
What do you think will be the
number today?
Ace!
Are you sure?
-Yes, I am!
I've neverwon the way you do!
Come on, take your share.
- Geeta, you've made an equal share.
Raka, you can play five times today.
What about the notes
that are under yourfeet?
What do you mean?
Move your leg and
give me that money!
Oh, these? Don't shout,
I did not hide them purposely.
You do it everyday but when I get
angry, you'll realise it!
Just try doing that,
don't forget my name is Geeta!
Even my name is Raka,
I'll break your legs!
What did you say?
Do you think you are a don?
How dare you show me that knife?
- Leave her, chief!
You steal and then you show
this knife? Apologize to him!
I don't want to work with her, does
she think we cannot do without her?
No, the public throws money when
you show your juggling tricks!
Such things happen chief,
why make it a big issue?
Nonsense! How could she
threaten me?
It was just a knife!
Go to your room and rest.
-You don't side her!
You are back, Geeta.
- Mother, I am very hungry.
You will drop the tray,
come with me to the temple.
You go there, I'll go home
and eat something.
I haven't cooked,
I'll come back and make something.
I'll be famished by then!
- It doesn't take long to cook.
I'll be back soon.
- I'll knead the dough meanwhile.
No, you please don't touch
anything in the kitchen.
I'll come back soon.
Geeta, why are you straining
your eyes in the night?
Cheena told me that today,
you fought with Raka again.
We do it everyday but actually,
it was my fault.
Stop fighting with the poor boy,
think of your future.
I may not live long,
I suggest you hold his hand.
But why should I hold Raka's hand?
You fool, I am talking
about your marriage!
You mean with Raka?
-Why, what does he lack?
He may be a little hot tempered
but he has a clear heart!
Mother, you are getting senile!
Yes, I have!
It's a sin to talk to you.
What is it?
- The bride groom is coming!
Did you see, he is a drunkard,
can I marry such a man?
No, a prince will come here
to marry you.
Yes, a prince in a shining armor
will come to marry me.
Have you seen this stick,
how light it!
Along with a medical degree from
London, I've got this golf stick too!
I've seen that men often get a
foreign wife when they go abroad.
That is their problem!
I don't say that women
out there are not good...
there's a big difference in our
culture & marriage is impossible!
What is your image of an ideal wife?
A sari clad girl, who cooks well...
a very simple, Indian woman!
He'll surely like her, Seeta is the
kind of girl Dr. Ravi is looking for!
What kind of girl does
that damn doctorwant?
A very simple Indian girl,
just like our Seeta.
Is that so?
Come, child.
God bless you! Is she the one?
- No, she is my daughter, Sheila.
She is doing her B.A.
Mother, can I get some tea or
coffee? -No child, Ramu will get it.
She is very fond of
doing domestic chores.
She doesn't have any habits
of a modern girl.
Child, why didn't you
get Seeta along?
She's in her room...
- I'll go and get her.
You talk to aunty,
I'll be right back!
Ramu, how does the boy look?
You must have seen him.
- He looks very decent.
He'll make a good husband for
Seeta. - Listen, what is his name?
Ravi, why are you so quiet?
-What should I say?
Talk as much as you want, after
your marriage, you won't get that chance!
Isn't it, Mr. Badrinath?
Walk down or I will...
-Aunty!!
Sit here, child!
Sit down!
Is she Seeta?
-Yes!
Mr. Gupta told us something else!
He speaks about the 18 century...
if these girls will not be
fashionable then will we be?
Besides, this is the age
of progress, isn't it Ravi?
Right, I think our country has
progressed more than the west!
They would like to have tea
made by you, go get it.
Go!!
Ramu, give the tray to Seeta.
How did you fall,
what is the matter?
Did you hurt yourself?. I am sorry,
your clothes are stained.
Let's leave, son!
Please don't leave.
- No, it's quite late.
We'll come some other time,
let's go Ravi.
But Mr. Chaudhary...
- Let's go!
Please wait Mr. Chaudhary,
please listen to me...
Please don't insult us and go.
I assure you that you what you are
seeing is absolutely wrong!
My Seeta is not like that, she
will serve you whole heartedly.
For God's sake, please stop.
-What can I do?
Ravi, please accept this proposal.
Well, l...
- I plead to you, son.
No grandmother, please stop it!
Kaushalya, whatever you are doing
is not right!
You?!
-Who else could it be?
I am the only one who writhes
in pain when I see your sorrows!
But don't worry, if not Ravi,
I am still there!
You can find better boys!
Ranjit, you please go from here.
You are great! You want to
mourn for a stranger...
and the ones who are crazy about
you, you don't even look at them!
You please go or else...
- Or else what?
I will scream.
- If you scream you will be defamed.
Please go away!
- Scream, I will not go!!
Grandmother!
Uncle!
What happened?
Tell me, where is my wallet, thief?.
Where is the thief?.
- In front of you!
Aunty, he is lying.
Shut up! Talk when I ask you to talk!
What is the matter, Ranjit?
- She cleaned my room today.
After that my wallet was missing,
who else could have taken it?
You wretched, horrible girl,
you've started stealing too?
Uncle, I have not stolen anything.
You can search my room.
-Yes, you can check her room.
Yes sister, let's both
search her room.
Here it is!
Detestable girl! You steal and
then you make false promises!
Sister, you move away, your
thrashing will not affect her.
You thief! I will skin your hide!
Someone please save her!
Please don't hit her!
For God's sake, please stop!
Stop, Ranjit!!
Grandmother, please save me!
This old woman will save you?
- Ranjit, let her go, I plead to you.
Then tell her to stay
within her limits...
or else I will skin her hide!
Grandmother!
- Stop crying, child!
Where are you?
Oh! You are here!
What happened?
-Ask what did not happen?
Do you know what your niece has
done?
What did she do now?
-What can she do, she has run away!
Seeta has run away?!
- Oh God, what will we do now?
What will we tell people,
we have been defamed!
You are more concerned
about the allowance.
The way you'll were behaving
with her, she had to run away!
Will you just lecture me
or even do something?
We should do something
but what should I do?
Look for her, report
the matter to the police.
That's right!
- Leave this now!
I did not like her
behaviour these days.
She was acting too big
for her shoes!
Why Ranjit had to go to Delhi this
morning? Did you get the number?
I am Badrinath speaking.
Actually, my niece...
Seeta, has left the house!
And we are very worried about her.
What, why did she go away?
Actually, her mental state is...
You come to the police station,
I'll write down your report.
And yes, do get her photograph.
What will we do if we don't find her?
That wretched Gupta will not
give us a penny!
O God, please have mercy on us!
Aunty, what have you cooked
today?
The stove has become cold but
I wonder where Geeta is!
I wonder if she has gone to buy
vegetables or grow them!
She has gone to buy vegetables! In
that case you observe a fast today.
She is playing marbles
with the children of the area.
What, I have been waiting for her
and she's playing marbles?
Are you saying the truth?
- I've seen it with my own eyes!
Don't mind but it doesn't look good
if a young girl plays with marbles.
I will go and break her bones!
Aunty!
- Give it to me!
Her marbles are very lucky,
she always wins!
Are your marbles over?
Here, play with them.
- Give it to me!
Now tell me which one should I aim?
- The green one!
You are cheating,
you're crossing the line!
What did you say?
Don't waste time, hurry up!
- I get angry if someone provokes me!
Shall I aim the green one?
-Yes.
What are you doing here?
- I was just playing!
You've been missing
since past 2 hours.
Why are you hitting me?
Do you want me to love you
because, you've made me happy?
Good that Raka told me you were
here! - Oh! So he told you?
I will not spare you, you creep!
-Wild cat!!
You are wild cat!!
What do you think of yourself?.
You Keep beating me every now and then
I'll run away from home.
I will not look for you!
Raka, go get her!
Aunty, she has gone, what will
we do about ourwork now?
Why you had to hit her,
she was just playing with marbles!
Should you hit with a stick,
look at her!
You are so big and
yet you are crying?
What is the matter,
did someone hit you?
Why don't you say?
- That man took my school fees!
Oh! You have lost
your school fees in gambling?
Why did you play?
Alright, come with me!
Come on, bet your money!
Bet on your cards!
Talk to me, aren't you
ashamed to dupe a child?
I've not duped him, he has
lost that money in gambling.
It's as good as duping,
come on, give his money back!
What if I don't?
- I'll drag you to the police station.
I am not scared, let me see who
has the guts to take me there!
I can take your father there too!
I can deal very well with
people like you.
Stop pushing me!
- Confess in front ofhim.
Sir, he has a gambling
den in our area.
He even looted this poor boy's
school fees.
What nonsense are you talking?
- Raghu, you've started again?
I was broke, sir.
- How much money did you play for?
Put him in the cell and take out
Rs. 20/- and give it to this child.
If you gamble next time then
I will lock you up too!
Out you go now and you...
you come with me,
I want your statement!
My statement!
- Tukaram, get me a glass of water.
I'll give my statement but I won't
get involved in court matters.
After all, I am
a service class girl.
It's strange that you've come here.
I am a very bold person.
I can go anywhere.
Hello, is that Mr. Badrinath?
We have found her, she is here.
You come here quickly
within 5 minutes.
Sir, my statement?
- I'll just have it typed.
But tell me, why did
you go away from home?
Actually sir, I don't like
this everyday hassle!
That is why I left home,
now let them look for me!
Never mind, I've called them up,
they must be on theirway.
Who they?
-Your uncle and aunt!
Who did you say?
I don't have an uncle nor an aunt!
That's bad, such small fights
cannot sever relationships!
Don't say that, Seeta!
- Seeta?! What confusion is this?
My name is Geeta and
I am leaving, good bye!
Catch her, don't let her run!!
Open the door quickly!
What is this?
Inspector, where is
our niece, Seeta?
Tell us soon, where is she?
Oh, my!
- See it for yourself!
Come down, child!
-You come up, fatso!
I think she has
actually become mad!
Seeta my child, we are
your uncle and aunt!
You look like a pair of
cartoons to me!
We've come to take you home.
-Am I your father's property?
Look, if you don't come down
then I'll put on the fan!
Don't do that, I will come down!
Uncle!...Aunty!!...
Which oil do you use?
-What?
Can we take her home?
- Please do that!
Let's go now!
- Stop screaming.
Thank you very much, inspector.
Thank you very much!
-Will you come along now?
Sit down!
This car is really very good!
Uncle, where are we going?
We are going home.
- Home?! Whose house?
You'll know it in sometime, I'll
thrash you on reaching home!
Why do you keep nudging me, fatso?
-What?
I lovingly told you, fatso!
Did you hear that?
- Forget it, she's a child.
I'll cut off your tongue,
did you understand?
What nonsense is this, at the police
station you were calling me child...
and here you are...
- Shut up!
Oh! She's there, stop the car!!
Go after her and catch her!
She's is our daughter and she's mad,
we were taking her to the asylum...
and now she has run away,
please help us to catch her!
Please help us, hurry up!!
What are you doing, run after her!
-You also come along!
Oh! She jumped on the
other side, get her!
Hey! What are you doing?
You've damaged my car!
Come out and see what you've
done!
Do you have a problem with your
eyes, can't you see properly?
How could you use your brakes
suddenly? Who gave you a licence?
Forget it, let's go!
-You keep quiet!
He's my youngest son but what
about this bumper that you've broken?
What do you think you were driving,
you've broken my headlights too!
Why don't you wear glasses?
How can you drive like this, without
giving a signal, you use the brakes?
Hey! Talk to me!
- I can talk to anyone I feel like!
Why did you use the brake?
- Did he use the brake of your car?
How can you use brakes of my car,
it's not for public!
We put brakes on our car.
- So what?
Tell me now.
-You should've seen that I was behind
There's nothing worth
seeing in you!
Don't act smart!
Don't argue with me.
We don't have eyes at the back
of our heads!
You were behind,
you could have seen us!
What is she saying? If there are
2-4 drivers more like you then...
Please listen...
- Don't interrupt and annoy me!
With people like you, we must have
2 drivers, one ahead and one behind!
Don't talk too much
or I will slap you!
Don't act tough with me, I'll file
a police complaint against you!
Shirin, note down their number!
He went away!!
It was our fault and you
started lecturing him!
If you get involved in a squabble,
this is the way you should talk!
Is it so? Okay, tell me one thing...
how did you get into this car?
- From the door, where else?
No, I mean, where did
you sit in this car?
On the seat, where else?
I mean...
-What do you mean?
Forget it.
- No, ask me!
Okay, where are you going?
-Where are you going?
I am going to Mahableshwar
to meet my parents.
Does that mean half the car
will go somewhere else?
Not at all!
Then don't ask me, even I am
going to the same place.
You are too much!
That I am but you ask
too many questions!
Great! Looks like
you are a very rich man!
I may look but looks can be
deceptive! Even you looked different on that day!
Which day?
That day!
- Oh, that day! How was I looking?
A stupid girl, trying to
pursue western fashion...
with excessive make up on your
face!
Me?!
-Yes, you!
And look at you today. Do you know
how you look in these clothes?
How?
- Like a gypsy girl!
That I am!
- I don't know what you are!
But I would surely
like to know you better!
Forget all this, before my parents
come, go and change into a sari.
Come.
But what is wrong
with these clothes?
They are not bad,
they are very good!
But is it necessary that whenever
my parents see you...
you should always be
in a fancy dress?
It's not necessary.
- Then let's go!
Alright!
This is my sister, Nirmala's room.
She is married and lives in Germany.
There are few saris in this, you
can choose anyone from them!
I'll wear it right away!
You are supposed to tie them on
your feet and then walk with them!
Oh, I see!
I think my parents have come,
you get dressed quickly...
I'll go down.
Son, the gardener said that
some girl has come with you.
Girl?! Oh, I met Seeta on the way
and I got her...
You got her here, what was the
need?
Seeta is very different from
what we thought about her!
What about the scene
we saw the other day?
It was just a drama.
Yes mother, I was shocked
to see her today.
Mother, she is a very smart
and a nice girl!
Unless you don't see her,
you will not believe me!
You wait here, I'll just get her.
Are you ready?...
You tie it on your feet
and then walk!
And then you slip and fall?
- Sometimes.
Won't you meet my parents?
-Yes, I will.
Then let's go.
- Come on.
Just a minute!
Shall we go?
- Oh, yes!
Aren't you an Indian girl?
-Yes, I am!
Then you are supposed to act
coy in front of my parents.
I understand.
- So come on, act coy!
Let's go there then I'll act coy.
-Alright.
That's a bit too much!
That's fine, let's go.
What will I have to do there?
- Nothing, shake hands with them.
What?
- I am sorry...
I said it wrong, just seek blessings.
-Your blessings?!
No, my parent's blessings.
And then yours?
-We'll see that later.
You already know her!
- Come children, sit down.
You'll sit.
-Yes, please sit.
Seek their blessings!
Is everyone fine?
- Oh, yes!
I liked everyone, you all!
I am not talking about us,
how are your uncle and aunt?
Oh, my! This aunt has come here
too! Well they...
Child, don't they behave
properly with you?
In front of everyone she dotes on
me and puts up an act of love...
but when we are alone,
she acts like a demon!
Mother, I had a doubt
on that day itself.
I had seen it myself that
the other girl Sheila, kicked her!
Didn't she kick you?
Don't lie now!
Why should I lie?
Yes, she did kick me.
That means the other day
what we saw was just an act!
I have to put up an act everyday,
tell me what else can I do?
I have to do all these things
to satiate my hunger.
Why do you need to do that?
You don't live on their mercy!
I have started
detesting those people!
That day they presented her in such
a weird manner and look at her today!
I always look good
in borrowed clothes!
We like her frankness!
Child, where are your bags?
- Bags?!
Oh yes, her bags! Well actually,
her bags were left behind.
And she came with me!
Child, you must have
informed at home, isn't it?
Oh, my! In this chaos I forgot
that I do have a family!
God, I have nobody in
this world who loves me...
it's said that you love the people
who are not loved by anyone!
I am coming to seek your refuge.
Wow! That was a brilliant jump!
Chief, that person is drowning!
Aunty!!
What happened to Geeta?
- Raka is getting her.
She jumped in the river
to commit suicide.
Geeta, my child, please get up!
Why isn't she talking?
Where...
- Don't worry, child!
You are perfectly alright!
-Why did you save me?
Don't say that, child. Nobody ends
life over such a petty fight.
I did not know that a small joke
would lead to such a serious thing.
She's alright now.
What is all this? Who are you?
What is the matterwith you?
I am your mother, Geeta!
Geeta? I am Seeta!
Oh God, what is wrong
with my daughter?
My child, don't worry, nobody
will scream at you anymore!
I will always love you, come close!
Will you ever leave your mother
now?
Mother!
- Stop crying, child!
Mother!!
Oh, my God!
If you hurry up then you'll
surely break your bones.
Let it break, you are
a doctor, you can fix it!
You can tie that white cloth
on it, what is that called?
White cloth?!
Oh, you mean a plaster?
No, it's called a plaster!
Never mind, forget it! If you
really want to learn skating...
then listen to me carefully, keep
yourweight on the front wheels...
like this, do you understand.
What you do is keep yourweight on
the rearwheels and that is why...
Doctor, if you want to learn skating
then remember one thing...
don't keep yourweight on rear
wheels, keep it on the front wheels!
Like this!!...
''With the winds...''
''along the clouds...''
''With the winds and the clouds...''
''let's move, O companion''
''Walk with me...
all day and night''
''Watch it... let's go hand in hand''
''Let's move, O companion...''
''Walk with me...
all day and night, like this''
''With your hand in mine...
let's steady ourselves and go along''
''The weather's so lovely,
as it is...''
''The weather's so lovely
''and we're also crazy at heart''
''Mind the mountains.
Don't collide with them...''
''like a cloud...
let's move, my love''
''Let the world laugh,
ifit wilI''
''Let the kick of
the weather get to us''
''Let me live in your eyes...''
''like kohI''
''Like your silken tresses flow''
''Let me get into your arms''
''I'm so tired today...
let me go''
''Let's meet tomorrow''
Please stop me!
Hey! Stop.
Hey! She's the same girl.
Come on, get down!
- Hey! Which police station is this?
Don't you recognize your own
house?
My house?! Well actually,
inspector...
when I left my house, it was
very small, just one room...
it has really grown huge
in a couple of days!
I am not acting, you are making
a mistake, this is not my house!
Take her inside!
I am saying the truth,
this is not my house!
Why can't you understand,
Didn't you understand?
You found her!
Are you Mr. Badrinath?
- Me, l...
What are you thinking,
you are Badrinath, tell him!
Is she your niece, Seeta?
- Of course not!
Where did you go, my child?
- I went to Mahableshwar, fat aunty!
Why don't you treat her?
-We'll do it and she'll be fine!
Okay, we'll leave now.
- Okay, let's go!
Where are you going, my child?
Look, enough ofjoking,
I am going...
You wretched girl!!
Seeta, my child!!
My child, where did you go?
Sister, where did you go?
- Sure, go ahead and hug her!
Stop shedding tears and ask her
where she went to defame herself?.
Stop it, Kaushalya. I mean, why
do you want to argue so much?
You keep quiet, you are the one
who has spoilt her!
Listen to me, if you step out of
the house, I will break your legs.
Come, child! And what are you
doing there, come with me!
What happened to her?
- I think she has fainted.
Grandmother, please get up!
Child, let's take her to her room.
Child, she is burning with fever
since past 3 days.
Nobody is bothered about her.
Look at this!
Forget getting medicines
but since you left...
she did not even get
her meals on time!
Sister, one day when grandmother
asked mother for medicine...
she abused grandmother a lot!
You know your aunt's nature...
she vents out your anger on her!
My child!
Where are you, my child?
Grandmother, I am here!
I am close to you!
Child, where did you
leave me and go?
Child, will you leave me
and go again?
If you go away again
then I will die!
Will you leave me, child?
No grandmother, I will not go!
Until there are tears in your
eyes and pain in your heart...
and till injustice prevails in
this house, I will not go anywhere!
Chief!
-What is it?
There is a great news, American
people have driven car on the moon!
Don't fib, how can
anyone drive on the moon?
There is a picture in
the newspaper, have a look!
Oh, yes! The Americans
can drive a car anywhere!
But our car has stopped!
Cheena, what is the matter
with this girl?
The fire within her is dead!
- That's what even I was thinking.
That jump in the water
has reformed her completely!
And she speaks
very formally these days.
It really annoys me, our business
has closed down because ofher!
Let her not come,
we'll go forwork today!
I am bored of sitting here!
-Ask her once, let her come along.
I'll not ask her, if you
want, you can go and ask!
Alright!
It will be good if she agrees!
For how many days do you
intend being on strike?
What?
Don't you want to work, we've been
home for a long time now.
Yes, I do want to work.
Then let's go.
- Let me ask mother's permission.
Child!
- There she is!
You have washed all the clothes?!
-Ask her now!
Mother, can I go forwork?
- Do as you please, child!
What will she do at home, just see
how sick and pale she looks!
She'll feel better if she steps out!
You'll decide amongst yourselves.
-Alright, let's go!
Let's go.
-Will you come in this dress?
Let her come the way she wants!
But in this outfit?! Alright,
let her try it out in this outfit.
My dear friends, what trick
would you all like to see?
My friends, this is not
an ordinary act.
To walk on this tight rope
which is tied on these sticks...
you need to be swift,
agile and alert!
One slip could maim you for life!
But for the sake of money, this
girl will endanger her life!
Go a little behind, anyone who
would like to offer some money...
can put it out on this cloth below!
- Here is my advance!
Here is my advance but
the show should be good!
Thank you very much,
everyone please clap!
Friends, now we present the girl
who'll walk on this rope...
like a train,
come on, play the drums!
Here comes that girl....
Friends, before starting the show,
I'd like to say one more thing...
there are decent people here, but
there may also be thieves here...
that is why, be alert of
pickpocketers...
while watching the show,
you wallet may get stolen.
That is why my friends, watch out!!
It's not easy to walk on this rope,
this girl here...
once she climbs up, she'll get
stuck to the rope like a bat.
Come on, climb up
and start the show!
You've put me in trouble!
He said that this girl
would walk on the rope.
I think he is a cheat, he has
picked up this girl from somewhere!
He has cheated us, let's bash him
up! - Sardarji, please listen to me!!
Stop it! Let's hit him!
Aunty, enough ofit, from now on,
my partnership ends with your daughter!
Why are you getting so angry
over such a small matter?
Small matter?! Good I was saved
or she would have me killed today!
Who could kill you?
You don't know the
people of this city.
It's fine if they are happy but if
they are angry, they can deform you!
She should have told me if she
was not interested in working...
we would not get into this mess!
Give me a needle and a thread.
My shirt tore and
I lost all my money!
How will we eat now?
-You can eat here!
You have started pampering her
a lot after her suicide attempt!
Come on, go in!!
Give me, I'll sew it up!
You'll do it? Get lost!
Give it to me!
- Take it.
Give me your shirt,
I'll stitch it up.
Cheena, when did
she learn tailoring?
Chief, can I tell you something?
When a girl learns stitching...
you should understand that she'll
not do anything that is unfeminine!
Raka, come and have lunch!
Wow! Green vegetables
and lentils, I love it!
I am starting, chief!
Aunty, it's delicious, I can
kiss your hand for this!
I've not made it, she's
the one who has cooked today.
She?!
In few days she has learnt
all the domestic chores!
Chief, you wanted to kiss aunty's
hand for the vegetables...
what will you do now?
- Shut up and eat your food!
You talk more than your age!
What is the matter?
Mother, I'm calling her but
she's not listening.
I hope she has not run away again,
go down and check.
You are yet sleeping?
Seeta, wake up!
Are you getting up or
shall I ask mother to thrash you?
You will not listen to me!
What happened, my child?
Why are you crying?
What did that witch do to you?
She hit me!
- I'll break her hands!
She kicked me!
-What? I'll break her legs!
You witch! How dare you
touch my fragile daughter?
Stop chewing my brains!
- How dare you!
You've been exposed to the outside
world and lost your senses!
Just get up so that I can
get you back into senses!
What is wrong with you?
Have you gone mad?
How dare you? Shameless!...
Am I shameless?
- Oh! My hand!!
I'll thrash you, get out!
Why are you screaming like this?
My hand, hurry up!!
-What is the matter?
What happened?
That wretched girl twisted my arm!
And you are asking what is the matter!
She's back!
-Who is back?
If you ever disturb my sleep,
I will deform you!
I understand, child!
- Oh, you are calling me child!
From now on, who will cook
in this house?...Tell me!
I'll cook!
-And the morning tea?
I'll make it, I used to do it
in your absence.
Oh! So you used to make
tea in the morning?
And this buffalo used to
sleep comfortably?
Listen fatso, you'll make the tea!
-Alright!
Very good! Now go quickly and
make a special cup of tea for me!
I'll get it!
Mother, make it for me too.
- Shut up!
Silence! If you raise
your voice, I'll slap you!
Go quickly and make for him too!
- I'll get it!
Kaushalya, shall I direct you
to the kitchen?
Come here!
- Me?!
Yes, you!
Why is this table so dirty?
From tomorrow, you'll wake up early
and dust the entire furniture!
Take this, sister!
- Come on, start!
I had heard that a dog's tail
can never be straightened.
But how did you manage this?
If you apply force then not only the
tail even the dog become straight!
It was a great film,
worth the money!
The hero tells his father, I don't
want the position nor the wealth...
I just want to marry the heroine!
That's great, where is
this film running?
At Taj Talkies.
- I will also see it!
The emperor is a mean guy,
he puts the heroine in the cell...
Hey, aunt Leela's daughter! Where
are you going dressed like this?
Temple.
-You are going to the temple?!
Hey! She's going to the temple.
-Why don't you come along with me?
I don't need to go there, I don't
need anything from God...
you carry on,
I don't have the time!
You have the time to put up an act
in front of this world...
and the Almighty, forwhom
this world is an act...
you don't have
even little time for him?
Look, don't talk to me like this!
I am an ordinary juggler.
Even God is a juggler,
an ace juggler!
You throw three balls
in the air at one go...
but there are millions of balls made
by him which are in the universe.
You hide a quarter in your fist and
when you open it becomes half cent...
but when God hides
the moon in his fist...
he brightens this world
with the sunlight, isn't it?
Wow! That was good. I suggest you
should contest for elections!
Okay, I am going.
You and here?!
-Yes, I have come here!
Why are you surprised?
-You came here suddenly!
The way you disappear suddenly,
I appear suddenly!
People have different habits!
Can we sit?
May we sit?
- Sure, sit down!
What will you have?
A sensible man will have
nothing else but water!
Don't be formal, okay tell me,
is anyone at home?
Why, am I not enough?
Of course you are!
Actually, I would like to
meet your uncle too!
Why, what work do you
have with him?
I have some work.
- But what is it?
I cannot tell you!
Oh, yes! Take this.
What is in this?
- It is...
Hello, uncle!
- Hello, how are you, my child?
I am fine!
- I'll be back in a moment!
Sit down, Ravi!
Uncle, actually I have been
sent here by my parents.
Oh, I see!
Uncle, all I have to say is that we
give our consent for this proposal.
And if you give your consent then
I'll consider myself very fortunate.
Ravi, we'll be fortunate
to accept this proposal...
and Seeta would get
a husband like you!
I'll write a letter to your father
and fix the marriage date.
Are you happy?
Hey! Why are you crying?
It's nothing!
Aren't you happy?
I am very happy, so happy
that it scares me!
Why should you get scared?
Ravi, you have no idea who I am!
I am...
- I know one thing for sure!
Whoeveryou are, you surely
are a little crazy!
Not much but little!
Okay madam, I am free on Sunday
and you are going out with me!
But Ravi...
-Yes or no?
Ravi, you...
- No?
Coming!
Have you cooked the lentils?
- Long back, mother!
Give this, I'll clean it.
- No, I'll do it!
No mother, I'll do it!
- Let me also do something.
Why are you screaming,
what is the matter?
Are you coming to PascaI's den?
- No, I am broke!
Nobody gives me a loan.
- Forget your state!
I am loaded today,
look I have 15 rupees.
Speak softly, someone
may pick your pocket!
If anyone tries to do that
I will kill that person!
Aren't you my friend?
Walk quietly!
Yes, aunty!
- So, you are going?
I'm not going to have alcohol,
this Raghu lives down the street...
he has a wife and four children...
so how can a family man
go and have alcohol?
I'm going to tell Pascal to stop
giving him credit or liquor.
Stop making such noises,
shameless man!
Everyone seems to be drinking,
I'll go and fix everyone right!
This is the only flaw he has,
he has to drink everyday!
There is nobody who will stop him!
He has no family.
If he gives up on alcohol,
he'd be a very good person!
''With a drink in my hands...''
''goodness! There's so much to do''
''When I have the time,
let's see what happens...''
''I'll think about the world too''
''Why think of death,
when I haven't even lived enough?''
''Why must I worry
about tomorrow?''
''Who's scared of a night
of sorrow...?''
''the evening's so lovely''
''The evening's so lovely''
''I have so much to do''
''When I have the time for it,
I'll see what happens''
''As for the world... aah!
I'll think about it''
''Right now, I have a drink''
''I was a bit tired...''
''I added a bit of falsehood
to the truth''
''From the bottle,
I took a swig...''
''and I really find
a bit of peace now''
''Though I feel better...''
''goodness! There's so much to do''
''When I have the time,
I'll see how things go''
''About the world... aah!
I'll think''
Listen.
-Who is it?
It's you, at this hour?!
Why aren't you sleeping?
Go on, go to sleep!
You come home first.
Whose home should I go to?
Your home!
- I don't know where my home is!
You know where my home is?
-Yes, I know it!
You know it?!
-Yes, come with me!
Okay, take me home!!
Are you harassing me, do you
really know where my house is?
You are a very nice girl,
you know where my house is!
It's a problem finding it,
where is it?
Here is your house!
Is this my house?
Do you call this a house?
Come inside with me
and see my house!
Do you call these fourwalls
and a roof, a house?
Is this bed, chair or
this window my house?
A home is made with a family and
I don't have anyone in this world!
No parents nor siblings,
I don't have anyone!
I was born on the footpath and
raised up on the streets...
then someday, I will
die in this closed room!
And then, the municipality van
will come here...
and will take me away! That will
be the end of the story!
What are you doing?
-Who says that you have nobody?
Raka, can't you ever
give up on alcohol?
If I don't drink then
how will I live?
But what difference
does it make to you?
What ifit does make a difference?
Chief, I have come to you!
I know I've come late but l
couldn't help it, I was side tracked!
Last night, Geeta told me that
I should stop drinking...
and I should start working. When l
heard her, I had tears in my eyes!
At that moment I decided that l
would come to you in the morning...
and say that I am sorry forwhatever
wrong that I've done till date!
From today, I will
never touch alcohol!
Even if Pascal gives it to me
free, I will not have it!
Chief, you are the supreme being...
please forgive me!
God, give Raka the strength
to fulfill his promise!
No child, this medicine
is very bitter.
Stop it, grandmother!
- It's little.
Hold your nose and drink it,
the doctor said...
if you have this medicine,
you'll become perfectly alright!
One..two..three...five!!
When you were small,
I was your grandmother...
but now I feel that
you've become my grandmother!
No grandmother,
she has become a don!
You imp! You've
started talking a lot!
Okay listen, Mr. Gupta has come!
Oh, the lawyer! That poor man
is not aware of anything.
The money he gives you, is taken
away from you, after he leaves!
Mr. Badrinath, I am glad that
this alliance has been fixed.
Even we are very happy!
- But where is Seeta?
Here I am!
Come, dear.
Come child, we were
talking about you!
Oh, I see!
- Child, how are you?
I am fine, how are you?
I am fine.
Mr. Badrinath, I can
see a change in her.
She's got self confidence!
She's changed a lot!
-Yes!
It's not only me, by the grace of
God, something has happened...
due to which all the family members
have changed quite a bit!
Isn't it, aunty?
Yes, you are right!
-Wow! She has started talking a lot!
Formerly, she used to sit quietly.
Now I feel that you aunt is
taking care of you!
No, first she took care of me
and now I take care ofher!
After all, even I have certain
duties, isn't it, aunty?
That's right!
Alright then let me also
fulfill my duty.
This is your monthly allowance.
- Thank you very much!
Please count them.
- Mr. Gupta, why do you always insist?
Give your uncle..
Why, is his counting more superior
than Mr. Gupta's honesty?
Mr. Gupta, there is
no need to count them.
But yet if...
- No...
I don't want to insult you
by counting this money!
Child, since the past 20 years
I have been coming in this house...
for the first time,
without counting...
Many things are happening for the
first time in this house these days!
Isn't it, aunty?
-Yes!
Okay Mr. Badrinath,
I'll take your leave now.
You are leaving?
-Yes, I'll leave now. Good bye!
Good bye!
- Good bye!
May God bless you.
- Let me drop you to the door.
Aunty!
- Child, I was suggesting that you...
What were you suggesting?
- May I keep this money in the safe?
You'll keep it in the safe?
Here, keep it!
I'll be back in a moment!
It's very heavy, your delicate waist
cannot take the burden of these keys.
Never mind, I'll keep them with me!
Yes, you can keep it!
Seeta, my child...
Get away! Is the food ready?
- Not yet...
It should be ready
by 1 p.m., get that?
Go now!!
Kaushalya, I can smell
something burning.
My heart it burning.
That means you are cooking
non vegetarian food.
You like to rub salt over
my wounds, move away!
That terrible girl made me a cook
and you could not say a word!
It's the law of nature, the
powerful one rules the roost!
Let her do as she pleases,
let my brother come back...
he'll fix her right!
I hope your brother does not
get thrashed in bargain!
Nonsense! Ranjit is my brother!
That means now he'll show
his true colors?
He will...
-Aunty!
Coming, child!
I've made all your favorite
dishes today.
I have made ladyfingers,
green vegetables...
and you'll be very pleased
to eat fried bitter gourd!
Please sit and eat!
Kaushalya, the kid
played a prank on you!
She is very naughty, she keeps
fooling around!
Just like you!
- Naughty girl!
You will not sit here, sit there!
- But I always sit here.
Now, the mistress of this house
will sit here!
Did you get that? Come on, move!
You can sit here if you wish,
I can sit anywhere...
the idea is to eat...
-Wait! I'll be back right away!
Where has this stupid gone?
-Wait, I'll set her right!
They all are waiting foryou!
Child, how can I eat with them?
No, they will eat with you!
From today, grandmother
will sit in this place.
Did you understand?
-Yes, child!
And from today, she'll have
all the keys to this house!
Did you understand this too?
-Yes!
Hold these keys, you are
the mistress of this house!
Hold these keys!
What are you watching,
come on, start eating!
Then what happened?
That fatso acted as if it
didn't effect her!
She said that I am
a very naughty girl!
That you are! How much sugar?
Is this sugar?
Why do they make blocks of sugar?
They are not blocks of sugar,
they are called sugar cubes!
What?
Forget it, keep it aside!
-Why are you getting annoyed?
How are you?
- Fine, thank you!
How is your knee now?
- It had become fine but...
Has it started hurting again?
-Yes!
Let me check.
Do you apply the ointment
everyday? -Yes, I do!
Do one thing, come to the clinic
tomorrow, we'll take a X-ray.
Hey! Listen.
''There's this girl I saw
in my dreams last night...''
''she had a beautiful face
and a lovely name''
''And I met this boy
in my dream last night''
''He was so handsome to look at
and he had a nice name too''
''Had I seen the woman
who was my bloody rival...''
''I'd have killed her,
I swear''
''Had I seen the lover
you dreamed about...''
''I'd have ended my life,
I swear''
''Why're you sulking again?
- Because you're sulking!''
''You are the one
I met in my dreams last night''
''And you are the one
I met in my dreams too''
''You and I needed
to see each other very badly''
''You and I sure needed to
see each other very badly''
''So many times we met
on moonlit nights...''
''we said so many loving things
to each other''
''All night, we were awake.
I gazed into his eyes...''
''we promised so much love
to each other''
''You're a liar!
-You're the liar!''
''There was this boy...
- There was this girl...''
''a lovely meeting I had with
the beloved in my dreams last night''
''What a face..
what a nice name''
Hello!
- May God bless you, son!
How are you?
- Fine, thank you!
Do you know my brother?
-Yes. Seeing you after long, Ranjit.
Yes, I had been to Delhi
for business purpose.
He has a vast
import export business!
By God's grace he has everything,
all that he lacks is a house!
That is why the poor man
lives with his sister!
You've started talking a lot.
Ravi, what is father's
brother called?
Uncle.
-And uncle's wife?
Aunty!
-And aunty's brother?
He's called a'chuchu'. Ravi, you
talk to 'chuchu', I'll be back!
Listen, I am going.
-Why are you going so soon?
Yes, I have some work. Good bye!
Aunty, you talk to him, I'm going!
Did you see that?
-You keep quiet, sister!
It's your fault, you must
have left her loose.
I went out for few days and this
girl has forgotten her limits?
You don't know what
all she did after you left.
She also doesn't know
what I can do!
You don't interfere, I will go and
skin her hide! You wait here!
You have lost your mind!
You need a lot of overhauling!
By threatening Sheila and sister
you think you are very smart?
Don't you recognize this? This has
given you many injuries even before!
Have you forgotten the thrashing?
You'll do only as I say!
From now on, you will behave
as you used to!
You will cook and
wash the vessels...
you will clean the house, get it?
And you will sit and rule on me?
No, Seeta!
- Stop chanting my name!
I will skin your hide
and stuff you up!
Grandmother, please save me!!
Coward, you're pleading to the one
whom you never sympathized with!
No Seeta, won't you listen to me?
Grandmother?!
- Go up to your room!
If you have some shame left in you
then wear my bangles!
What are you doing,
this is not an ox's back!
But she whipped you thinking
you are an ox!
Damn that girl, she has
whipped you up like cream!
Mother, take this.
- Got it, have you heated it well?
I'll put this turmeric paste on you
& very soon you'll become fine!
Grandmother, what are you doing?
What?
- I am reading the Bhagvad Gita.
Come and listen to what
Lord Krishna tells his devotees.
What does he say?
He says whenever there will be
a rise of evil in this world...
he will come to slay the evil!
- Has he ever come to fight the evil?
My child, every human being who
fights evil and injustice...
is a reincarnation of God!
Grandmother, what if one has to
resort to a lie to fight injustice...
then is that too a sin?
Lord Krishna says...
that if one has to resort to a lie
for a good cause...
then that one lie is equivalent
to many truths!
Sir!
-Where were you, you old man?
Why does it take you two hours
to buy a pack of cigarettes?
What are you seeing now,
give me a light!
You oaf! Can't you
even light one cigarette?
Get lost!
Ramu is very much older than you...
almost like your father!
Apologize to him!
Ranjit, apologize to him.
Ramukaka, wait here.
Didn't you hear me Ranjit,
apologize to Ramukaka!
Come on!
Forgive me.
- Not like this!
Bow down before him!
Come on, do it!
Ramukaka, please forgive me!
Wait!
Which brand of cigarettes
do you smoke? Oh, it's 555!
And what do you contribute
towards this house?
Nothing!
If you eat in this house without
working then I'll whip you 555 times!
Ramukaka, Ranjit will go to
the market to get the groceries!
Sir, everything is fresh!
- How much is this spinach for?
You're only asking the price,
are you buying forthe first time?
Why are you getting annoyed,
are you giving it for free?
What is this?
-Aubergine!
Do aubergines look like this?
Okay, what is the price?
Rs. 2 per kilo.
- Okay, give me a kilo.
Where had you been?
- Oh, it's you?
What is the matter,
why do you look so scared?
Nothing!
- Tell me clearly, what is the matter?
I am scared!
-About what?
I am scared that someone
may separate you from me!
Who can dare to do that?
Don't you trust me?
I do but I don't trust my fate!
You fool, one can change
the fate in a jiffy!
You wait here,
I'll be back in a moment.
Where are you going?
- To go and join your and my destiny!
Can I go?
Sister, it's a very auspicious date.
You should fix up the marriage
on the 18th of this month!
Alright!
- Priest, 18th is very far.
Can't you make it earlier?
- No son, it has to be on the 18th!
Alright then!
18th?!
Yes, Ravi's parents
have decided the date.
And I gave my consent.
- But, uncle...
Child, don't forget that we are
from the bride's side...
if we dillydally then
they may misunderstand us!
Besides, it's very rare to find
boys like Ravi in this age!
Okay, I will go to the jewellers
and get your ornaments.
Uncle...
-Yes, child.
Nothing!
- May you always be happy!
I have no right to
call you my parents...
I have hidden the fact that I am
not your daughter and the only...
reason for it was, to wipe
the injustice prevailing here!
But what shall I do now?
These people, who consider me
as your daughter, Seeta...
want me to marry Ravi!
They don't know that I'm not Seeta,
who belongs to an affluent family.
I am just an ordinary gypsy girl
Geeta, who performs on the streets!
Please tell me what I should do?
Whose picture is this?
This is Mr. Badrinath's niece, Seeta!
- That's what even I thought...
but she's Seeta's look alike,
a gypsy girl called Geeta!
Then where is Seeta?
You have to find her, wherever she
may be, you have to get her here!
But before the 18th of this month!
Watch out, uncle.
If I could watch then
why would I fall?
I am sorry, here is your stick!
Child, my car must be somewhere
around, please take me there...
Come on, I'll take you there.
Sit down quietly or else...
Child, you aren't yet ready?
The wedding procession
must be on it's way.
Uncle, I...
- I understand, child.
If your parent's were alive, your
motherwould dress you up as a bride!
And brotherwould send you away
to your husband's house!
But what can I do child,
I am feeling very lonely!
Okay child, I am going,
you get dressed.
I am very lucky
to have you in my life!
I have a wife who is beautiful,
cultured & from a decent family.
Marrying you...
What is the matter?
- Ravi, I...
We are starting a new
life from today.
I don't want to hide
anything from you!
I am not what you've been thinking!
-What do you mean?
I don't belong to any
affluent family.
I am just an ordinary gypsy girl...
whom these people have mistook
as Seeta and got home!
What are you saying?
-Yes Ravi, I am Geeta!
My work is to perform
dances on the street.
This cannot be true! If it is then
why didn't you tell me before?
I tried to tell you
many times but you...
You have deceived me!
- Ravi, please listen to me!
You think that I will accept
a street performer...
who has no idea about her
lineage, as my wife?
But we are married!
- Shut up!
Aunty, I went to the temple,
she is not there!
She told me she's going to the
temple. -What happened, Cheena?
Geeta had gone to the temple 2
hours back but she's not traceable now!
It's ourwedding today
and where did she go?
I'll tell you!
''Oh yes...''
''I'm drunk''
''Not a little... I've had
more than I can remember''
''Please do forgive my misdemeanor''
''I can't help it...
my crazy heart isn't in my control''
''Stay away from me...
do not come closer''
''Oh yes, undoubtedly...''
''what I've had is surely evil''
''See the liquor in my hands?''
''But no one will notice
my shattered heart''
''Did anyone ask me
what poison I've had?''
''Oh yes, undoubtedly...''
''I say it cheerfully...
I'm quite drunk''
''Yes, I'm drunk on liquor''
''Not a bit, I've had more
than I can remember''
Why did you do this, Seeta?
Grandmother, I cannot get married!
Mr. Badrinath, did you call us
here to humiliate us?
If she did not want to get married
then why did you put up this act?
I'll tell you
why she put up this act?
She did it because, she is
a very greedy person!
She did it because, she was eying
the wealth of this family!
She eyed the property
of this family!
What nonsense are you saying?
- I am stating the facts!
This girl, whom you'll
consider as Seeta...
she is a look alike of Seeta
and a street performer, Geeta!
This is a lie!
- This is the truth!
And this is a bitter truth!
For you as well as me!
-Who are you?
Ask her who am I!
Tell them who I am or is it
that you don't recognize me?
I never imagined that the greed of
wealth could make you stoop so low!
You pretended to be in love with me
and cheated this gentleman here!
You promised to marry me and...
- No, this is not true!
I did not make any promise!
Ravi, don't believe his words,
this is a lie!
Is it a lie that
your name is Geeta?
Is it a lie that you a girl
who performs on the streets?
Is it a lie that we were
supposed to get married today?
And is it a lie that
this woman is your mother?
Child, where did you go away?
I was very worried about you,
why did you go away from home?
Tell me, Geeta.
She's not your daughter,
she's our child, Seeta!
You think I am blind that I will
not recognize my own daughter?
I think you have misunderstood!
- No, I have not!
Child, tell them all
that I am your mother!
Hey! Why are you quiet?
Why don't you speak?
Oh, my! I hope they have not done
some black magic on you!
Geeta, tell them
that I am your mother!
Have you forgotten me?
Geeta, speak up!!
Mother!
Mother, please don't cry!
I am your Geeta!
Then where is my Seeta?
Perhaps, she has abducted Seeta
and has hidden her somewhere.
Or perhaps, she must have
killed Seeta.
You rogue, scoundrel!!
Wait!
Is it true that your name is Geeta?
-Yes!
And even this is true that you've
been staying here as Seeta?
Yes!
In that case I will have to arrest
you for committing deceit and fraud!
Come on!
Grandmother, if possible,
please forgive me!
Don't touch me!
If a lie is spoken
for a good cause...
then that one lie is equivalent
to many truths...
remember, you told me that!
Let's go, inspector!
-Wait!
Please don't take her,
she is not as you think!
Please leave her!
Someone please...
So the person whom we thought was
Geeta, was actually Seeta?
The person who loved me was
Seeta?!
Yes and that is why,
everyone misunderstood Geeta!
Now the police has taken her!
You don't worry,
wherever Geeta is...
i will surely get her back!
Sir, Seeta is throwing a tantrum!
-What happened?
She has broken her head
against the wall!
Alright, you go and call
some doctor.
Did you see properly? Are you sure
It is the 2nd room on the 1st floor?
I am sure, I've just been released
from there this evening!
Alright, you go!
Raka, you?!
Doctor, without asking questions,
bandage this girl!
Alright!...Oh, you?!
How come you are here?
- These people have imprisoned me!
You?!
Idiots, didn't you find
any other doctor besides him?
Ranjit, I have understood
all your moves!
I will...
There is no need
to get angry, doctor.
Just do yourwork or my friends
will take you to task!
Wear this bridal attire
and come down quickly!
And as soon as finishes his work,
lock him up in the next room!
Raka, I don't understand why you...
- Geeta, please forgive me!
I did not know the truth infact,
even you are not aware of the truth!
What do you mean?
- Seeta is your twin sister!
My twin sister?! Who told you this?
Aunty told me that...
- But where is Seeta?
I know it!
-Where is she?
Ranjit has locked her up
in Plaza Cottage!
Come on!
- There are Ranjit's men all around.
So what, I can fight any
monster to save my sister!
How long will it take?
- Few minutes more!
Damodar, where did you get
this old hag from?
O God, what shall I do now?
Don't worry Seeta, God has
sent me here to protect you!
Who are you?
Don't look so surprised Seeta,
I am not a stranger...
I am your twin sister, Geeta!
My twin sister?! But...
- I will explain everything to you.
But before that, I need to explain
few things to the scoundrels...
who have put you in this state!
Ranjit wants to forcibly marry me!
- He cannot even touch you!
Seeta, trust me and
quietly do as I say!
Why are you delaying so much,
how long will it take?
Everything is ready,
you call for the bride.
Go and get Seeta, you start!
Come down quickly!
- Please have mercy on me!
I can't have mercy on anyone,
come on!
Where are you taking me?
- Come on!
How did you come here?
Let's go!
What joke is this?
- Idiot!
A lioness cannot marry a wolf!
What did you say?
I'll fix you right away!
You?!
-Yes, it's me!
Then where is Seeta?
- Seeta is here!
Hey! You are here?!
-Yes, I am here!
Get them!!
Wait a minute! Give that to me!
Let me check you! Breathe heavily!
You blockhead! You have asthma
and you want to fight, sit down!
Hey, shorty! What's your problem?
- I am constipated, doctor!
Lift your shirt...now you can go!
Don't you'll have any problem?
- Shut up! Come along with us!
Go, get her!
Take them all and tie them up!
Take them quickly!
Very good, my brave men!
Now you'll know who is a lion
and who is a wolf!
Hey! Tell your men that
the king of lions has come!
What are you seeing, go get him!
Come, let me bash you up!!
Take this now!
You are back again?
Are you fine now?
Yes, sir! - Did you go?
- Twice.
Go once again, where is the
bathroom? - This side!
Don't worry Ranjit, I don't
attack unarmed people.
Take this!
What are you seeing? If you have
the guts then pick up the sword!
Come on, pick it up!
Doctor, I've never been scared
of anything in till date.
But I wonder why,
I am very scared today!
There is nothing to fear!
Doctor, what does one do
on the nuptial night?
How would I know,
it's my first marriage too!
Oh, I see!
-Why are you so surprised?
It's really my first marriage!
-You go, don't worry!
Alright, as God wills!
-Just a minute!