[ Gunfire ]
[ Explosion ]
[ Man Narrating ] The war to end all wars
did not end soon enough.
So, Heartland, U.S.A.
sent the allies...
its most effective secret weapon.
[ Explosion ]
- Sergeant Pepper...
- [ Bell Dings ]
and his Lonely Hearts Club Band.
[ Drums ]
[ Continues ]
For music above and beyond
the call of duty...
Sergeant Pepper was awarded
the coveted Golden Eagle.
Heartland was proud
of its famous sergeant.
But more than that, they delighted
in knowing that he remained...
a good, simple, small-town boy.
Every time Sergeant Pepper played,
the world danced.
They danced through
the Roaring Twenties,
the Depression,
[ Moos ]
economic recovery...
and yet... another great war.
And for some 50-odd years,
Heartland's feet tapped to the beat...
of Sergeant Pepper's magical music.
How do you honor someone
who had done so much...
to make so many people so happy?
Heartland decided to erect
a Sergeant Pepper weather vane...
on top of our city hall.
It would always point
the way to happiness.
And as mayor,
I presided over the ceremony.
At the end, Sergeant Pepper assured us
that he would play us one more tune.
[ Crowd Applauding ]
[ Loud Cheer ]
[ Crowd Groans ]
Oh, well.
August 10, 1958.
A day none of us
will ever forget.
To the town of Heartland,
he left his musical instruments.
These instruments have the power
to make dreams come true.
And as long as they remained
in Heartland's care,
humanity would live
happily forever after.
Sergeant Pepper left
his wholesome grandson, Billy Shears,
his cherished Golden Eagle.
This made Billy's stepbrother, the greedy
Dougie Shears, veryjealous indeed.
Sergeant Pepper then asked Billy
to form a new Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band.
This band would feature
Billy's three best friends.
Mark, Dave and Bob Henderson.
We wondered if there would ever be a new
Sergeant Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band.
And we wondered what
the new band would sound like.
Dougie appointed himself
their business manager...
and introduced the band
in his own unique way.
It was 20 years ago today
Sergeant Pepper
taught the band to play
They've been going
in and out of style
But they're guaranteed
to raise a smile
So may I introduce to you
The act you've known
for all these years
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
We're Sergeant Pepper's
We hope you will enjoy the show
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
Sit back and let the evening go
Sergeant Pepper's Lonely
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
It's wonderful to be here
It's certainly a thrill
You're such a lovely audience
We'd like to take you home with us
We'd love to take you home
I don't really want to
stop the show
But I thought you
might like to know
That the singer's gonna
sing a song
And he wants you all
to sing along
So let me introduce to you
The one and only Billy Shears
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
Billy
Shears
What would you think
if I sang out of tune
Would you stand up
and walk out on me
Lend me your ears
and I'll sing you a song
And I'll try not to
sing out of key
I get by with a little help
from my friends
Mmm, I get high with a little help
Yeah, gonna try with a little help
from my friends
What do I do
when my love is away
Does it worry you to be alone
How do I feel
by the end of the day
Are you sad because
you're on your own
No, I get by with a little help
from my friends
Yeah, I get high with a little help
Gonna try with a little help
from my friends
Do you need anybody
I need somebody to love
Could it be anybody
I just want somebody to love
Would you believe
in a love at first sight
Yes, I'm certain that
it happens all the time
What do you see
when you turn out the light
I can't tell you
but I know it's mine
Oh, I get by with a little help
from my friends
Yeah, I get high with a little help
Oooh, I'm gonna try with
a little help from my friends
I get high with a little help
from my friends
With a little help
[ Mr. Kite ] Heartland loved the boys,
and the boys loved music.
Billy and Strawberry loved each other.
And Dougie loved making money.
But on that memorable day
a telegram arrived...
that was destined
to change their lives.
It came from B.D. Hoffler,
the president of Big Deal Records,
the world's largest,
most successful record company.
''We hear your music is great. Stop.
''We need a tape of your songs,
and we need it now. Stop.
''If we like your music, we'll make you
superstars and the money will never stop.
Stop.
Signed, B.D. Hoffler, Hollywood. ''
A long, long way from Heartland.
How about that?
Superstars from Heartland.
Who could be more deserving?
Wouldn't Sergeant Pepper be proud?
Just think. Superstars.
Who could be more deserving?
Hmm.
I'm fixing a hole
where the rain gets in
And stops my mind
from wandering
Where it will go
I'm filling the cracks
that ran through the door
That kept my mind
from wandering
Where it will go
And it really doesn't matter
If I'm wrong I'm right
Where I belong I'm right
Where I belong
See the people standing there
who disagree and never win
And wonder why
they don't get in my door
I'm painting my room
in a colorful way
And when my mind
is wandering
There I will go
La, la, la, la, la
I'm fixing a hole
where the rain gets in
And stops my mind
from wandering
-  Where
-  It
-  Will
-  Go
Oh, one and a two
One, two, three
Da-da, bah, bah
Bah, bah, bah, bah
Bah, bah bah, bah, bah-bah
Dee-dee, dee-doo, dee-doo
dee-diddledy diddledy diddledy
And one
Two
One, two
One, two, three, four
It's getting better
all the time
-  Used to get mad at my school
-  But I can't complain
The teachers that taught me
weren't cool
No, I can't complain
-  You're holding me down
- [ Acoustical Feedback ]
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
It's getting better
all the time
- I used to get mad at my school
- But I can't complain
The teachers that taught me
weren't cool
No, I can't complain
You're holding me down
You're turning me round
Ahhh
Filling me up
with your rules
I got to admit it's getting better
Better
A little better all the time
Can't get no worse
I have to admit
it's getting better
Better
It's getting better
Since you've been mine
Me used to be
angry young man
Me hiding me head
in the sand
[ Deep Computerized Voice ]
Keep your mind on business.
- Take over Heartland.
- I've got to admit it's getting better
- Better
- A little better all the time
It can't get no worse
I have to admit
It's getting better
[ Computerized Voice ] Why?
[ Buzzing ]
[ Computerized Voice ]
We hate love.
We hate joy.
We love money.
[ Beeping ]
Money. Money.
It's getting better
all the time
Better, better, better
I used to be cruel
to my woman
I beat her
and kept her apart
From the things
that she loved
Man, I was mean
but I'm changing my scene
And I'm doing
the best that I can
Oooh-ooh
I admit it's getting better
Better
A little better all the time
It can't get no worse
Yes, I admit
it's getting better
Better
It's getting better
Since you've been mine
Getting so much better
all the time
It's getting better all the time
Better, better, better
Getting so much better
all the time
[ Whistling, Cheering ]
[ Mayor Narrating ]
Big Deal lost no time in responding.
The telegram read,
''B.D. loves your music.
B.D. loves you. Expect you
in Hollywood tomorrow. Signed, B.D. ''
[ All Cheering ]
Everybody was happy.
But Strawberry realized that
she and Billy would be separated...
for the first time
in their young lives.
There was barely time
for tender farewells.
[ Rooster Crows ]
Here comes the sun
Here comes the sun and I say
It's all right
Little darlin'
It's been a long
cold, lonely winter
Little darlin'
It feels like years
since it's been here
Here comes the sun
Here comes the sun and I say
It's all right
Little darlin'
The smiles returning
to their faces
Little darlin'
It feels like years
since it's been here
Well, here comes the sun
Here comes the sun and I say
It's all right
Sun, sun, sun
Here it comes
Little darlin'
I feel that ice is
slowly melting
Little darlin'
It seems like years
since it's been here
Here comes the sun
Here comes the sun and I say
It's all right
Oh, it's all right
[''I Want You (She's So Heavy)'']
[ Continues ]
I want you
I want you so badly
I want you so bad
It's driving me mad
I want you
I want you so bad, babe
I want you so bad
It's driving me mad
I want you
I want you so bad, babe
I want you so bad
It's driving me mad
She's so
Heavy
[ Continues, Instrumental ]
[ Continues ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
She's so
Heavy
I want you
I want you so bad, babe
I want you so bad
It's drivin'me mad
I want you
You know
I want you so bad, babe
I want you
You know
I want you so bad
It's drivin' me mad
[ Continues, Instrumental ]
[ Shutter Clicking ]
[ Continues ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
She's so
Heavy
[ Continues, Instrumental ]
[ Continues ]
[ Ends ]
[ Horns Honking ]
Good morning
Somebody needs
to know the time
Glad that I'm here
Watching the skirts
you start to flirt
Now you're in gear
Go to a show
You hope she goes
I've got nothing to say
but it's okay
Good morning
Nothing to do
to save his life
Call his wife in
Nothing to say
but what a day
How's your boy been
Nothing to do
It's up to you
I've got nothing to say
but it's okay
Good morning
Going to work
Don't wanna go
Feelin'low down
Heading for home
you start to roam
Then you're in town
Everybody knows
there's nothing doing
Everything is closed
It's like a ruin
Everyone you see
is half asleep
And you're on your own
You're in the street
After a while
you start to smile
Now you feel cool
Then you decide
to take a walk
By the old school
Nothing has changed
It's still the same
I've got nothing to say
but it's okay
Good morning
People running round
It's 5.00
Everywhere in town
it's getting dark
Everyone you see is full oflife
It's time for tea
and Meet the Wife
Somebody needs
to know the time
Glad that I'm here
Watching the skirts
you start to flirt
Now you're in gear
Go to a show
You hope she goes
I've got nothing to say
but it's okay
Good morning
Good morning, Good
Good morning, Good morning
Good
Good morning
Good morning, Good
Good morning, Good morning
Good
Good morning
Good morning, Good
Good morning, Good morning
Good
Good morning
Good morning, Good
[ Man Announcing ]
And now, to cool the pace,
the B.D.-- Big Disco Show--
brings you Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band.
He's a real nowhere man
Sitting in his nowhere land
Making all his nowhere plans
for nobody
Doesn't have a point of view
Knows not where he's going to
Isn't he a bit like you and me
Nowhere man, please listen
You don't know
what you're missing
Nowhere man
The world is
at your command
He's a real nowhere man
Sitting in his nowhere land
Making all his nowhere plans
for nobody
[ Applause ]
Well, you should see
Polythene Pam
She's so good-looking
but she looks like a man
You should see her in drag
dressed in a polythene bag
Yeah, you should see
Polythene Pam
Yeah, yeah, yeah
[ Girls Screaming ]
Get a dose of her
in jackboots and kilt
She's killer-diller when
she's dressed to the hilt
She's the kind of a girl that
makes the News of the World
Yeah,you could say
she was attractively built
Yeah,yeah,yeah
She came in through
the bathroom window
Protected by a silver spoon
But now she sucks her thumb
and wonders
By the banks
of her own lagoon
Didn't anybody tell her
Didn't anybody see
Sunday's on the phone to Monday
Tuesday's on the phone to me
She said she'd
always been a dancer
[ Audience Cheers ]
She worked at 15 clubs a day
And though she thought
I knew the answer
Well, I knew
but I could not say
And so I quit
the police department
And got myself a steady job
And though she tried her best
to help me
She could steal
but she could not rob
Didn't anybody tell her
Didn't anybody see
Sunday's on the phone to Monday
Tuesday's on the phone to me
Oh, yeah
[ Man Announcing ] BDTVproudly
presents The Sergeant Pepper Special.
[ Audience Cheering ]
We're Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
We hope you have enjoyed
the show
Sergeant Pepper's Lonely
Hearts Club Band
We're sorry
but it's time to go
Sergeant Pepper's Lonely
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
We'd like to thank you once again
Sergeant Pepper's one and only
Lonely Hearts Club Band
It's getting very near the end
Sergeant Pepper's Lonely
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts
Club
Band
Hearts Club Band
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
[ Audience Cheering ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
You left me standing here
Lead me to your door
[ Continues, Instrumental ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Ends ]
[ Crickets Chirping ]
[ Computerized Voices ]
Mean Mr. Mustard sleeps in the park
Shaves in the dark
trying to save paper
Sleeps in a hole in the road
Saving up to buy up some clothes
Keeps a 10-bob note up his nose
Such a mean old man
Yes, a mean old man.
I agree. A mean old man.
[ Computer Beeping ]
[ Deep Computerized Voice ]
Steal the instruments.
Such a mean old man
[ Continues ]
[ Computerized Voice ]
Take the cornet to Dr. Maxwell.
Take the tuba to Father Sun.
Bring the saxophone to me. F.V.B.
Keep the drum for yourself.
Such a mean old man
His sister Pam works in a shop
She never stops
She's a go-getter
Takes him out
to look at the queen
Only place that he's ever been
Always shouts out
something obscene
Such a dirty old man
[ Cash Register Bell Dings ]
[ Continues, Instrumental ]
Such a mean old man
Such a dirty old man
''A dirty old man''?
Yes, a dirty old man!
Such a dirty old man
[ Snoring ]
[ Both Beeping ]
[ Both ]  Wednesday morning at 5:00
As the day begins
Silently closing
her bedroom door
Leaving the note that
she hoped would say more
She goes down the stairs
to the kitchen
Clutching her handkerchief
Quietly turning
the back door key
Stepping outside she is free
She
We gave her
most of our lives
Is leaving
Sacrificed most of our lives
Home
We gave her
everything money could buy
[ Robots ]
She's leaving home after living alone
For so many years
Bye-bye
Father snores
As his wife gets into
her dressing gown
Picks up the letter
that's lying there
Standing alone
at the top of the stairs
She breaks down
and cries to her husband
Daddy, our baby's gone
Why would she treat us
so thoughtlessly
How could she do this to me
She
[Jingling ]
We never thought of ourselves
- Is leaving
- Never a thought for ourselves
Home
We struggled hard
all our lives to get by
[ Robots ]
She's leaving home after living alone
For so many years
Bye-bye
She's leaving home
Wake up, Mr. Mustard.
[ Alarm Blaring ]
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up.
Wake up. Wake up.
[ Yelling ]
[ Alarm Continues ]
Look. Strawberry is leaving.
[ Alarm Stops ]
[ Melodic Beeping ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Synthesizer ]
[ Continues ]
Picture yourself
in a boat on a river
With tangerine trees
and marmalade skies
Somebody calls you
You answer quite slowly
A girl with
kaleidoscope eyes
Cellophane flowers
of yellow and green
Towering over your head
Look for the girl
with the sun in her eyes
And she's gone
Lucy in the sky
with diamonds
Ahhh
Follow her down
to a bridge by a fountain
Where rocking horse people
Eat marshmallow pies
Everyone smiles as
you drift past the flowers
That grow so incredibly high
Newspaper taxis
appear on the shore
Waiting to take you away
Climb in the back
with your head in the clouds
And you're gone
Lucy in the sky
with diamonds
Ahhh
Picture yourself
on a train in a station
With plasticine porters
With looking glass ties
Suddenly someone is
there at the turnstile
The girl with kaleidoscope eyes
Lucy in the sky
with diamonds
Talkin' about Lucy
Lucy in the sky
with diamonds
Talkin' about Lucy
Lucy in the sky
with diamonds
Ahhh
Lucy in the sky
with diamonds
Talkin' about Lucy
Lucy in the sky
with diamonds
Ohhh, Lucy
Lucy in the sky
with diamonds
Talkin' about Lucy
Lucy in the sky
with diamonds
Ohhh, Lucy
Lucy in the sky
with diamonds
Oh, darling
Please believe me
I'll never do you no harm
Believe me when I tell you
Oh, darling
If you leave me
I'll
I'll never make it alone
So believe me
when I beg you
Don't you ever
leave me alone
Leave me alone
When you told me
You didn't need me anymore
Well,you know
I nearly broke down and cried
When you told me
You didn't need me anymore
Well, you know
I nearly broke down and died
Oh, darling
If you leave me
I'll never make it alone
So believe me
when I tell you
- [ Tires Screech ]
- I'll never do you no harm
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
When you told me
You didn't need me anymore
Well, you know
You know
I nearly broke down
And cried
When you told me
You didn't need me anymore
Well, you know
You know
I nearly broke down
And died
Oh, darling
Please believe me
[ Thud ]
[ Audio Cassette Rewinding ]
Well, while Mustard roamed through
the building looking for Strawberry,
she and her Heartland friends
dashed to the van and captured it.
Now, the question is
could the boys discover...
how to use this computerized
link to F. V.B....
to help recover
the lost instruments.
[ Melodic Beeping ]
[ Beeping Continues ]
[ Computerized Voice ]
Turn on the big screen.
[ Low Hum ]
[ Deep Computerized Voice ]
Take the cornet to Dr. Maxwell.
[ Mr. Kite ] Dr. Maxwell, a small-time
quack who became a big-time specialist...
turning ugly, old corrupt people
into handsome,young corrupt people.
Joan was quizzical
Studied pataphysical
Science in the home
Late nights all alone
with a test tube
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Maxwell Edison
majoring in medicine
Calls her on the phone
Can I take you
out to the pictures
Jo-o-o-oan
But as she's
getting ready to go
A knock comes on the door
Bang, bang
Maxwell's silver hammer
Came down upon her head
Bang, bang
Maxwell's silver hammer
Made sure that she was dead
Back in school again
Maxwell plays the fool again
Teacher gets annoyed
Wishing to avoid
an unpleasant sce-e-e-ene
She tells Max to stay
when the class has gone away
So he waits behind
Writing 50 times
I must not be so-o-o-o
But when she turns
her back on the boy
He creeps up from behind
Bang, bang
Maxwell's silver hammer
Came down upon her head
Bang, bang
Maxwell's silver hammer
Made sure she was dead
Ho, ho, ohh
P.C. 31 said
we caught a dirty one
Maxwell stands alone
Painting testimonial pictures
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Rose and Valerie
screaming from the gallery
Say he must go free
The judge does not agree
And he tells them so
Oh, oh, oh
But as the words
are leaving his lips
A noise comes from behind
Bang, bang
Maxwell's silver hammer
Came down upon his head
Bang, bang
Maxwell's silver hammer
Made sure
he was dead, whoa
Bang, bang
Maxwell's silver hammer
Came down upon his head
Bang, bang
Maxwell's silver hammer
Made sure he was dead
Wh-wh-wh-whoa
Whoa
Whoa-o-whoa
Wha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Mr. Kite ] Well, they had
Sergeant Pepper's silver cornet.
One down, three to go.
Jubilant, they returned to the
Computerettes for additional guidance.
[ Computerized Voice ]
One down, three to go.
[ Mr. Kite ]
The bass drum was easy.
Mustard left it,
Billy found it.
[ Bang ]
Shh!
[ Mr. Kite ]
Just like that.
[ Computerized Voice ]
Congratulations. Two down, two to go.
[ Mr. Kite ] They hugged each other
andjumped forjoy, some of them.
Let's go back to work.
There's still two instruments missing.
[ Loud Humming ]
[ Computerize Voice ]
Take the tuba to Father Sun.
[ Mr. Kite ] Marvin Sunk,
now known as Father Sun,
was an unemployed school-crossing
guard at the bottom ofhis life...
when he suddenly got the idea
to drop the ''K''from his last name.
Well, that move lit up his life
and it's been uphill ever since.
He decided to go
into the media business...
and help destroy the minds
of those young people...
who teased him
on their way to school.
Now he was busy brainwashing
them for F. V.B. to build an army
to take over the world.
[ Chanting ]
We hate love!
We hate joy!
We love money!
We hate love!
We hate joy!
We love money!
We hate love!
We hate joy!
We love money!
We hate love!
We hate joy!
We love money!
Ahh ahh
Because the world is round
It turns me on
Because
The world
Is round
Ahh
Because the wind is high
It blows my mind
Because
The wind
Is high
Ahh ahh
Love is old
Love is new
Love is all
Love is you, sweetie
Because
The sky is blue
It makes me cry
Because
The sky
Is blue
[ Chuckling ]
Ahh ahh ahh ahh
Ahh ahh ahh
ahh ahh ahh
Ahh ahh ahh ahh
Ahh ahh ahh
ahh ahh ahh
ahh ahh ahh--
[ Acoustical Feedback ]
- [ High-pitched Feedback ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Mr. Kite ] Could Billy survive
10,000 volts?
It was a lot more than normally
came through his guitar.
Frankly, he was shocked.
Stunned and unconscious, only the power
of true love could revive the injured Billy.
Let me take you down
'Cause I'm going to
Strawberry Fields
Nothing is real
And nothing
to get hung about
Strawberry Fields forever
Living is easy
with eyes closed
Misunderstanding all you see
It's getting hard to be
someone but it all works out
It doesn't matter much to me
Let me take you down
'Cause I'm going to
Strawberry Fields
Nothing is real
And nothing to get hung about
Strawberry Fields forever
No one, I think
is in my tree
I mean, it must be high or low
That is,you know you can't tune in
but it's all right
That is I think
it's not too bad
Let me take you down
'Cause I'm going to
Strawberry Fields
Nothing is real
And nothing to get hung about
Strawberry Fields forever
Always know
sometimes think it's me
But you know I know
when it's a dream
I think I know I mean
Ah yes, but it's all wrong
That is I think I disagree
Let me take you down
'Cause I'm going to
Strawberry Fields
Nothing is real
And nothing
to get hung about
Strawberry Fields forever
[ Computerized Voice ]
Let's not play.
Stop.! Stop.! Stop.! Stop.!
Stop! Stop!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
[ Machinery Winding Down ]
[ Mr. Kite ]
The boys were really desperate.
There was one instrument
still missing...
and now there
was no way to find it.
Heartland was in
desperate condition,
seething with corruption.
B.D. was desperately
canceling concerts everywhere.
He was losing his cool,
his profits...
and his hair.
Things were really desperate.
But Dougie came up
with a great idea--a giant benefit.
Musical artists from all over
would come to Heartland...
for a concert
that would save the town.
And Sergeant Pepper's Lonely Hearts
Club Band wouldjoin them.
That was bound to get
the boys back on the road.
[''Being For the Benefit of Mr. Kite'']
For the benefit of Mr. Kite
There will be a show tonight
on trampoline
The Hendersons will all be there
Late of Pablo Fanque's Fair
What a scene
Over men and horses
hoops and garters
Lastly through
a hogshead of real fire
In this way Mr. K
will challenge the world
The celebrated Mr. K
Performs his feat on Saturday
at Bishop's Gate
The Hendersons
will dance and sing
As Mr. Kite flies through
the ring, don't be late
Messrs. K and H assure the public
Their production
will be second to none
And of course Henry the Horse
dances the waltz
[ Cheering ]
The band begins at 10 to 6.00
When Mr. Kperforms his tricks
without a sound
And Mr. H
will demonstrate
Ten somersets
he'll undertake
On solid ground
Having been some days
in preparation
A splendid time
is guaranteed for all
And tonight, Mr. Kite is
topping the bill
[ Whooping, Cheering ]
[ Cheering ]
[ Man On P.A.]
Testing.!
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
You never give me
your money
You only give me
your funny paper
And in the middle
of negotiations
You break down
I never give you my number
I only give you my situation
And in the middle
of investigation
I break down
Out of college, money spent
See no future, pay no rent
All the money's gone
Nowhere to go
And a job
I got the sack
Monday morning
turning back
Yellow lorry slow
Nowhere to go
Oh, that magic feeling
One sweet dream
Pick up the bags
Get in a limousine
Soon we'll be
away from here
Step on the gas
and wipe that tear away
One sweet dream
Came true today
One, two, three, four
five, six, seven
All good children
go to heaven
One, two, three, four
five, six, seven
All good children
go to heaven
One, two, three, four
five, six, seven
All good children
go to heaven
One, two, three, four
five, six, seven
All good children
go to heaven
One, two, three, four
five, six, seven
All good children
go to heaven
One, two, three, four
five, six, seven
All good children
go to heaven
[ Cheering, Applause ]
[ Announcer ] Introducing
the mighty elements of the universe--
Earth,
- wind...
- [ Explosion ]
- and fire.!
- [ Explosions ]
[ Cheering, Applause ]
[ Thunderclap ]
[''Got To Get You
Into My Life'']
Got to get you into my life
Into my life
Do do do do do do do do
do do do
I was alone
I took a ride
I didn't know what
I would find there
Another road where maybe I
Could see another sign there
Ooh, and then
I suddenly see you
Ooh, and then I tell you
that I need you
Every single day of my life
You didn't run
You didn't lie
You knew I want to hold you
And had you gone
you knew in time
We'd meet again
for I had told you
Ooh, you were meant
to be near me
Ooh, and I want you
to hear me
Say we'll be together
every day
Got to get you into my life
Got to get you
into my life
Got to get you in
In--into my life,yeah
Got to get you
into my life
Ahh
Got to get you into my
Got to get you into my life
Got to get you
into my life
Oh,yeah,yeah
Ooh, then I suddenly see you
Ooh, did I tell you
that I need you
Every single day of my life
- Got to get you into my life
Got to get you in
Got to get you into my life
Into my life
Got to get you
into my life
Yeah
[ Screaming ]
- Got to get you into my life
Into my life
Got to get you in
Got to get you into my life
Yeah
Yeah, gotta get you
into my life
Got to get you in
In-- Into my life
[ Cheering, Applause ]
[ Ends ]
[ Explosion ]
[ Mr. Kite ] Mustard
was on his way to F. V.B. Central...
where the evil genius would
suppress the magical instruments...
and make the world safe
for his corrupt legions.
[ Computerized Voice ]
Bring the instruments!
Our army is ready!
[ Mr. Kite ]
It was the end of decency,
unless the band could get there
in time to stop him.
[''When I'm 64'']
Now when I get older
losing my hair
Many years from now
Will you still be
sending me a valentine
Birthday greeting
Bottle of wine
If I'd been out
till quarter to 3.00
Would you lock the door
Oh, will you still need me
Will you still feed me
when I'm 64
You'll
Be older too
Jealous?
[ Computerettes ]
And if you say the word
I will stay with you
[ Computerized Voice ]
Stupid. Stupid.
Send me a postcard
Drop me a line
- All right.
-  Stating point of view
Mm-hmm.
Indicate precisely
what you mean to say
You don't know?
You're sincerely
wasting away
Give me your answer
Fill in a form
Mine forever more
Will you still need me
Will you still feed me
When I'm 64
[ Both ]
Ohh.
[ Horn Honks ]
- [ Horn Honks ]
- [ Mustard Groaning ]
[ Mr. Kite ]
The boys were traveling like the wind,
and that was the problem.
Heartland's fastest pursuit could not
keep up with Mustard's evil engines.
[ Beeping ]
[ Computerette ]
Mr. Mustard, look what I found.
Now you're gonna get it!
[ Cackles ]
[ Mr. Kite ] They were about
to confront the villain in his lair.
F. V.B., the evil force
that would poison young minds,
pollute the environment,
and subvert the democratic process...
and worst of all, change Strawberry
into a mindless groupie--
this was the enemy-- F. V.B.
Future Villain Band.
Here comes ol' flattop
He come groovin' up slowly
He gotJooJoo eyeball
He one holy roller
He got hair down
to his knee
Got to be a joker
He just do what he please
He wear no shoeshine
He got toe jam football
He got monkey finger
He shoots Coca-Cola
He say, I know you
You know me
One thing I can tell you is
you got to be free
Come together
Right now
Over me
He bag production
He got walrus gum-boot
He got Ono sideboard
He one spinal cracker
He got feet down
below his knee
Hold you in his armchair
You can feel his disease
Come together
Right now
Over me
Ow
He roller coaster
He got early warning
He got Muddy Water
He one mojo filter
He say, One and one
and one is three
Got to be good-lookin'
'cause he's so hard to see
Come together
Right now
Over me
Come together
[ Stops ]
[ Gongs ]
Once there was a way
To get back homeward
To get back home
Sleep, pretty darling
do not cry
And I will sing a lullaby
Golden slumbers
Fill your eyes
Smiles
Awake you when you rise
Sleep, pretty darling
do not cry
And I will sing a lullaby
Once there was a way
To get back homeward
To get back home
Sleep, pretty darling
do not cry
And I will sing a lullaby
Boy,you're gonna
carry that weight
Carry that weight
a long time
Boy,you're gonna
carry that weight
Carry that weight
a long time
[ Continues ]
Boy,you're gonna
carry that weight
Carry that weight
a long time
Boy,you're gonna
carry that weight
Carry that weight
a long time
Boy,you're gonna
carry that weight
Carry that weight
a long time
[ Mr. Kite ] The instruments
were safely back in Heartland,
but at what a cost.
Was it worth it?
Could anything or anyone make
everything all right again in Heartland?
The wild and windy night
That the rain
Washed away
Has left a pool of tears
Crying for the day
Why leave me standing here
Let me know the way
Many times I've been alone
And many times I've cried
Anyway you'll never know
the many ways I've tried
But still they lead me back
To the long
and winding road
You left me standing here
A long, long time ago, ohh
Don't leave me waiting here
Lead me to your door
You left me standing here
A long, long time ago, ohh
Don't leave me waiting here
Lead me to your door
I read the news today
Oh, boy
About a lucky man
who made the grade
And though the news
was rather sad
Well, I just had to laugh
I saw the photograph
He blew his mind out in a car
He hadn't noticed that
the lights had changed
A crowd of people
stood and stared
They'd seen his face before
Nobody was really sure if he
was from the House of Lords
I saw a film today
Oh, boy
The English Army
had just won the war
A crowd of people turned away
But I just had to look
Having read the book
I'd love to
Turn you
On
Woke up
Fell out ofbed
Dragged a comb
across my head
Found my way downstairs
and drank a cup
Looking up
I noticed I was late
Found my coat
I grabbed my hat
Made the bus in seconds flat
Found my way upstairs
and had a smoke
Somebody spoke
and I went into a dream
Ahh ahh ahh
Ahh
I read the news today
Oh, boy
Four thousand holes
in Blackburn, Lancashire
And though the holes
were rather small
They had to count them all
Now they know how many holes
it takes to fill the Albert Hall
I'd love to
Turn you on
[ Thud ]
Get back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back,yeah
Get back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back,JoJo
JoJo was a man
who thought he was a loner
But he knew
it wouldn't last
JoJo left his home
in Tucson, Arizona
For some California grass
Get back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back
Get back,yeah
Get back to where
you once belonged
Sweet Loretta Martin
thought she was a woman
But she was another man
All the girls around
said she's got it coming
But she gets it
while she can
Get back
Get back, yeah
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back,yeah, whoo
Get back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back, yeah
Get on back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back, yeah
Get on back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back, yeah, whoo
Get back
Get back to where
you once belonged, now, now
Get back, yeah
Get on back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back, yeah, whoo
Get back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back, yeah, whoo
Get back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Whoo
Get back, Loretta
Your mama's
waiting for you
With her high-heel shoes
And a low-neck sweater
Get back, Loretta
Get back,yeah
Get on back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back,yeah
Get on back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back,yeah
Get on back
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back,yeah, whoo
Get back to where
you once belonged
Get back,yeah, whoo
Get back,yeah
Get back to where
you once belonged
Whoo
We're Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
We hope you have
enjoyed the show
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
We're sorry
but it's time to go
Sergeant Pepper's Lonely
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
It's wonderful to be here
It's certainly a thrill
You're such
a lovely audience
We'd like to
take you home with us
We'd love
to take you home
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
We'd like to thank you
once again
Once again
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
It's getting
very near the end
Sergeant Pepper's Lonely
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
We'd like to thank you
once again
Sergeant Pepper's one and only
Lonely Hearts Club Band
It's getting
very near the end
Sergeant Pepper's Lonely
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts
Club
Band
Hearts Club Band
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
Hearts Club Band
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
Hearts Club Band
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
Hearts Club Band
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
Ahh ahh ahh
Ahh
I'd love to
Turn
You
On
Yeah,yeah,yeah
[ Girls Screaming ]
Get a dose ofher
in jackboots and kilt
She's killer-diller when
she's dressed to the hilt
She's the kind of a girl that
makes the News of the World
Yeah,you could say
she was attractively built
Yeah,yeah,yeah
She came in through
the bathroom window
Protected by a silver spoon
But now she sucks her thumb
and wonders
By the banks
ofher own lagoon
Didn't anybody tell her
Didn't anybody see
Sunday's on the phone to Monday
Tuesday's on the phone to me
She said she'd
always been a dancer
[ Audience Cheers ]
She worked at 15 clubs a day
And though she thought
I knew the answer
Well, I knew
but I could not say
And so I quit
the police department
And got myself a steadyjob
And though she tried her best
to help me
She could steal
but she could not rob
Didn't anybody tell her
Didn't anybody see
Sunday's on the phone to Monday
Tuesday's on the phone to me
Oh,yeah
[ Applause, Screaming ]
We're Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
We hope you have
enjoyed the show
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
We're sorry but it's time to go
Sergeant Pepper's Lonely
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
We'd like to thank you
once again
Sergeant Pepper's one and only
Lonely Hearts Club Band
It's getting very near the end
Sergeant Pepper's Lonely
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts
Club
Band
Hearts Club Band
Sergeant Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
[ Applause, Screaming ]