Stop that. Why, the idea.
Voulez-vous me to call the police?
-What does that mean in English?
-The same as it does in French, monsieur,
All right.
Comme ca, a little brook.
Comme ca, a little river.
Where is Petrov?
Please, can you not see
l am busy being a wave?
Comme ca, a little river,
comme ca, a little brook.
Where is Petrov?
Look here, l don't want to be bourgeois
and remind anybody...
that l'm the owner of this company...
but if somebody doesn't tell me
where Petrov is...
there'll be trouble for everybody.
He's in his private room,
practicing his grand leap.
Thank you.
-But he does not want to be disturbed.
-Thank you.
-What is this?
-Hi, Jeff.
Stop it. Stop that.
-What on earth are you doing?
-l'm just having fun.
Fun? The great Petrov
doesn't dance for fun.
The great Petrov doesn't, but l do.
-Pete Peters, remember me?
-Oh, that awful name of yours.
l was born with it. lt isn't bad.
Pete Peters, Philadelphia, PA.
How do you make
that exasperating noise?
What have you got on those shoes?
-Taps.
-Taps?
-On your ballet shoes?
-Sure.
Sacrilege. At last l'm beginning
to understand...
why you wanted a private room
to dance in.
All this time l thought you were practicing
your grand leap.
But, Jeff, l haven't neglected anything.
Look, the entre chat trois.
Lovely, beautiful.
But how much more effective
it is this way.
Lovely.... l forbid that.
-That's not art.
-Maybe it isn't.
Perhaps it's just the Philadelphia in me.
Jeff, l wish we could combine
the technique of the ballet...
with the warmth and passion
of this other mood.
Mood, what other mood?
You mean this jazz business?
Jazz went out with the flapper.
That isn't jazz.
After 15 years of the hardest work...
you want to dwindle
into a shimmy dancer.
Well, forget all that nonsense.
Here, look at this, do you realize
we ought to be sailing?
Do you realize the Metropolitan
in New York City is getting nervous?
l'm sorry, but l have to stay in Paris
a while yet.
Stay in Paris? What for? Why?
That's grace, that's rhythm.
What is that? What have you got there?
lsn't she lovely?
So that's it.
Who is that girl? Who is she?
Where did you meet her?
That's it, l haven't been able
to meet her yet.
But l hope to dance with her someday.
-Dance? With her?
-Sure.
Are you mad?
Are you sure that she hasn't tried
to persuade you to stay on here?
l told you, l haven't even met her,
but l'd kind of like to marry her.
l think l will.
Thanks, Jeff.
You are so beautiful when you are angry.
Pardon, mademoiselle,
l cannot help what l cannot help.
Neither can l.
You cannot let us up like this.
-lt not up she let us, it is down.
-Up or down, she lets us.
-lt is all your fault, you kissed her.
-But it is in the play.
You kissed her out of the play, too.
Go home, all of you.
Go home!
Well, hello, my little darling.
What have you got there?
lt's Mr. Miller, miss.
He just arrived from New York.
-Hello, Arthur.
-Hello, Lynn.
You better go.
lf l ever walk on a stage again....
-How did you get here?
-By rail.
l hung over every inch of it.
A new experience for you,
you usually have your foot on one.
Yes, Lynn.
Of all the humiliating experiences.
Did you ever dance with a man
you didn't care about...
-and who's in love with you?
-No, Lynn.
Why do actors have to take
the author's lines literally?
And why must there always be a kiss
at the second-act curtain?
As long as l live, l hope l never see
another hand-kissing, heel-clicker.
Careful, Lynn.
You know, l come from a long line
of heels myself...
but we've never clicked.
And it's all your fault, too.
l was a happy, peaceful girl
until you discovered me.
Fame, name in lights.
l never should have listened to you.
l'll quit.
-l'll retire from the stage forever.
-Again?
lt does you good to break an engagement.
Engagement?
Engagement. That's what l'll do, Tai.
Send a cable to Jim Montgomery.
Tell him l want to see him desperately...
and l'm coming back
on the Queen Anne tomorrow.
-Yes, miss.
-Now, Lynn, don't lose your head.
-You have to stay in the theatre.
-Never.
l refuse to be a bowl in a gold of fish.
You mean a fish in a bowl of gold.
That's what l said, a bowl in a goldfish.
-Just a moment, please.
-Thank you.
Petrov? What's a Petrov?
Just the Russian ballet's greatest dancer.
Fine, tell him to go back to Moscow.
The gentleman seems very anxious
to see you, miss.
l've got enough troubles
without adding a dizzy Russian to them.
Just another dancer to swoon in my arms.
That's all l need to make things perfect.
A simpering toe dancer.
Get rid of him.
He probably only wants to say
he's seen a picture of me...
and can't live without me.
l am Petrov.
Charmed. l'm Linda....
-Linda....
-Linda Keene.
-Yes.
-How do you do?
So glad you came, Mr. Petrov.
Not mister, Petrov, alone.
-Just Petrov.
-And why not?
Just Caesar, just Napoleon,
and only Garbo...
so Petrov, too, she's enough.
Just about enough.
And you, l understand
you want to dance with me.
Of course, l cannot blame you...
but l will not permit it.
Who told you that?
A little bird she tell me so.
Not in the least.
What, you do not want to dance
with the great Petrov?
Don't be a silly horse.
Maybe you could twist for me once...
like so.
No, l don't....
-Twist.
-Better twist.
Get up, l hate these discords.
She is horrible, nyet?
Well, that kind of settles it.
With me, nothing is settled.
Well, l must go now. l must go to Moscow.
-Funny, nyet?
-Very.
lt kills me.
That lunatic's dangerous,
they ought to lock him up.
Am l glad l'm sailing
on the Queen Anne tomorrow.
No, Denise, no.
l can't take you back as ballerina.
Why, you've done absolutely nothing
for four years.
And everything's been so peaceful
since you left.
lt wasn't my fault.
Peter just refused to fall in love with me.
Peter, darling.
Why, Denise...
-or should l say Lady Tarrington?
-No, it is Denise again.
Denise wants to come back to the ballet.
She does?
Well, that sounds like fun.
l didn't know you felt that way.
Why, of course, Denise, you're engaged.
-You go downstairs and get your contract.
-Thank you, Jeffrey.
Jeffrey, may l speak to you
a moment, please?
-You'll excuse us?
-Of course.
And l'll let you know about the rehearsals
the first thing in the morning.
Of course, we can't give her
anything important to do at first.
-You want me to stay, don't you?
-Why, what a question.
-Well, then get rid of her.
-Get rid of her?
Remember all the trouble
she caused the last time?
-But you just told her, l heard you myself.
-l was only being polite.
Oh dear, and l've given her my word.
Look, Jeff, l'll make a deal with you.
You want me to go to New York,
don't you?
Why, naturally.
l'll sail on the Queen Anne tomorrow
providing you get rid of her.
Tomorrow, oh dear, that's so sudden.
l wouldn't know what to do.
l wouldn't know what to say.
-All right, l stay here in Paris.
-But l'll think of something.
l'll connive, l'll connive something good.
Good.
Peter.
Hello, Denise.
l feel very bad
because l'm not going with you.
-So do l.
-ls your wife going with you?
My wife, l haven't any wife.
Jeffrey told me it was a secret
for professional reasons.
Oh, Jeffrey.
Did he mention how long l'd been married?
Yes, he did.
lmmediately after dear Tarrington
took me away from you.
Dear Tarrington.
-ls she sailing with you?
-Who?
Oh, my wife, yes, of course.
l'd love to meet her.
Well, you couldn't.
She's busy with the children now.
Children? But Jeffrey didn't tell me.
Jeffrey doesn't know everything.
lmagine, married four years.
lmagine.
-And how many little ones are there?
-Five.
-Five?
-Well, twins.
-How wonderful.
-lsn't it?
-All visitors ashore,
-Well, goodbye, Denise.
-Sweet of you to see me off.
-Goodbye, Peter.
Bon voyage,
Miss Keene, l know,
wants me to tell you...
how much she hates
leaving her dear Paris.
She's enjoyed everything about it,
and everybody in it.
All visitors ashore,
Monsieur Petrov, a picture, please.
Thank you.
-One more, please.
-All right.
l certainly do envy you, Pete,
going home at last.
l kind of like the idea myself.
All right, so long, fellows,
thanks for everything.
Bye-bye.
Miss Keene.
Why, just Petrov.
You come to see me go, nyet?
Yes, isn't it sweet of me?
l know you come.
Petrov, l have been looking all over for....
-l beg your pardon.
-Miss Keene, my friend, Jeffrey Baird.
-How do you do?
-Really, Miss Keene....
What did you say?
Me? Nothing.
What's the matter with you,
you got a cold?
No, l feel like you say, good.
Well, you don't sound so good.
What's the matter with you?
Doesn't Mr. Baird understand Russian?
-Not a--
-Yes.
What?
What sort of a game is this?
lt's just a game little American boys play.
l beg your pardon, sir.
-We can't find Mr. Petrov.
-Well, you've got to find him.
He's probably practicing
that jiggling somewhere.
l've looked everywhere, sir.
Splendid service, that's all l can say.
Bring the world's leading ballet
dancer aboard this ship...
and he disappears from his stateroom
under your very nose.
Well, he might be
in someone's else's stateroom, sir.
What would he be doing
in someone else's stateroom?
That would be entirely up to him, sir.
You aren't really serious
about that marriage idea, Lynn?
No, Arthur?
What about me?
l'm sorry, but l'm facing real happiness
for the first time in my life.
Yes, and l'm facing bankruptcy...
for the third time in my life.
-Steward, miss.
-Come in.
l ordered lunch for us.
You can put the table right here.
l guess we won't be having
many more of these together.
Lynn, l still think you're a sap
to walk out on me just to get married.
No, l'm tired of living the kind of life
l've been leading.
Look, Lynn, l'll give you $10,000 more
than l gave you last year.
You don't understand,
your kind never does.
Money, isn't everything.
But, Lynn, after all these years together.
Arthur, l'm tired of being pawed.
l beg your pardon.
My compliments, miss...
and as for you, sir, shame.
You misled me, you tricked me.
You knew that she was going
to take this boat.
l'll admit the charge and plead
in extenuation my extreme youth.
And where have you been all day?
With that woman?
Not that woman, Jeff. The woman.
But l wasn't with her, and furthermore,
she hasn't left her room all day, darn it.
Probably one of those night prowlers.
But she's not going to prowl
too near you...
because l intend to accompany you
all evening.
-Good, maybe she's got a friend.
-Really?
What's the matter, what are you doing?
What are you weaving about like that for?
-Weaving?
-Yes.
l'm not weaving.
lt's the boat.
You mean this boat's doing that?
Of course, it must be getting choppy out.
Of course.
-Why, Jeff, what's the matter?
-Nothing, l'm all right, l think.
l guess.
-You look terrible.
-Do l?
Why, yes, you're all white,
sort of green, kind of yellowish.
-Maybe you ought to go to bed.
-Maybe.
No, maybe l better get some air.
-Do you mind?
-Not at all.
-What's the matter, old man?
-lt's the boat.
The whole boat is weaving.
There, is that better?
l don't know, really, l don't know.
-Straight lemon juice, please.
-l wouldn't drink that.
-No?
-lt'll make you seasick.
What this gentleman needs is champagne.
Champagne? No, l've never touched
champagne in all my life.
-l refuse to touch it.
-You can watch me, then.
-Keep them coming.
-Yes, sir.
Nothing.
Tell me the truth, do l look bad to you?
To tell you the truth,
l don't know you well to tell you the truth.
Miss Keene, you remember the night
we met in Paris?
Yes, l remember.
Wait a minute, please.
l want to explain.
You see, l once saw a photograph of you...
and l decided right then and there
that l simply had to meet you.
And l tried every way but...
nobody in Paris
seemed to know you and....
Everybody in Paris knows Linda Keene...
everybody worth knowing.
Of course, but l just don't seem
to know the right people yet.
Couldn't you do something about that
right now...
as one Yankee to another?
l'm from the South.
Maybe you all's from the North.
lt's funny, dogs have an instinct
for the right people.
How do you like that?
lt's marvelous how you can do it
with so many at one time.
-Let's drink to that.
-Steward.
Another bottle of this lemon.
He's gone to bed, must be late.
What time is it?
What does your watch say?
lt says tick-tick-tick.
Hey, Jeffrey.
Hello, good morning.
What's the matter, you lose something?
l got great news for you, old man,
you're not going to be seasick.
The captain just told me this will continue
to be the smoothest trip in 10 years.
l don't see why you should
have such a big head.
-You only had one glass.
-Yes, but you kept filling it.
Your breakfast, sir.
What'll l do?
Before you do anything,
you'd better put that breakfast away.
That'll save me an extra trip.
Come here, darling.
What has happened?
You ruined your sweater,
now l'll have to fix it.
lsn't it wonderful
being here tonight like this?
Still on the same boat together.
l seldom change boats in mid-ocean.
l mean, look how lucky l am.
The first time l find myself on a boat
with somebody like you...
it turns out to be you.
Fellows, listen to this.
''Lady Tarrington left this morning
on the S,S, Marseilles,,,
''for a trip to America to visit her friends
Mr. and Mrs. Petrov...
''who are aboard the S,S, Queen Anne,
''Upon further questioning...
''it was learned that the Petrovs
have been married for some time...
''their marriage not having heretofore
been disclosed for professional reasons.''
That is news for your morning bulletin.
That must be the musical comedy star
he's with so much, Linda Keene.
By George, you're right.
Sparks just told me that ballet dancer,
Petrov, is secretly married.
-l'll wager it's to that American dancer.
-Righto.
-Will that be all, Miss Linda?
-Yes, thank you, Tai.
And he's been secretly married
to Linda Keene for some time.
They're a lovely-looking couple,
don't you think?
My dear, l knew it.
-How do you do?
-Good evening.
That's what l like about boats,
everyone's so friendly.
A toast.
Wake up, Petrov.
We're going to have a baby?
-What?
-Why did you keep this a secret from me?
-What are you talking about?
-lt's all here in the ship's bulletin.
lt says you've been married for years
to Linda Keene.
And the editor announces:
''lt is rumored that a blessed event
is imminent.''
Why did this have to happen to me?
To you? lt hasn't even happened to me.
Lady Tarrington.
Do you realize
that you're the father of my child?
Of course, that's ridiculous,
that's impossible.
lt's very simple.
You told Denise l was married...
somebody selected a wife,
and now l'm going to be a father.
-lsn't that cute?
-Cute? lt's a miracle.
l warned you association with that
Keene woman would get you into trouble.
l warned you l was gonna fall in love
with her. l have.
-lt's your fault, go and explain it to her.
-l'll do nothing of the kind.
lf you want me to dance
at the Metropolitan...
you go to Linda and clear this thing up.
ln that case perhaps l had better.
l'll take care of this.
Operator, get me Mr. Petrov.
What? Don't you dare congratulate me.
Come in.
l've come to tell you, Miss Keene,
that we will not tolerate your insinuations.
Stay where you are...
while l compose myself.
l suppose you and that toe dancer think
this whole thing's a good joke.
lt was not altogether the toe dancer,
Mr. Petrov's fault.
lt wasn't?
A man in Petrov's position is besieged
by women.
Naturally.
And there was one
persistent wretch who....
Well, to get rid of her,
he said he was married to you.
-To get rid of her?
-Exactly.
He had to choose somebody, and he felt
that a person like you wouldn't mind.
-So he used me to....
-Exactly.
You see, it wasn't altogether a joke.
Good morning, little mother.
Good morning.
l want to book passage on that mail plane.
l'm sorry, but that's against
government regulations.
But l must leave the ship.
lt's absolutely urgent that l leave.
Well, l understand,
but it's just a little irregular.
l'm quite sure the government
would understand.
Well, perhaps under the existing
circumstances, madam--
Not madam, miss!
Where's Linda?
Pardon me.
Take a good look.
Gosh, and l could have
explained everything.
You couldn't have explained her
embarrassment and humiliation.
Thanks.
Now she's going to get married.
-Married?
-Yes.
Married to a Park Avenue cluck...
with the longest yacht
and the shortest chin ever christened.
-You've driven her to that.
-Me? l didn't do anything.
Only told somebody
you were married to her...
just to get rid of another dame,
only used her, that's all.
-Who said l did?
-Your impresario, Mr. Baird.
Oh, he did?
Excuse me, gentlemen...
in a few moments the fire bell will ring,
but don't pay any attention to it.
-A fire drill for the ship's crew.
-Right.
He's probably in here.
Did you tell Miss Keene that l used her
to get rid of a woman?
My very words, dear boy.
One of these days
you'll thank me for doing it.
Thank you?
lf l didn't need you to explain to her--
What is the matter with you?
Haven't you any feeling of responsibility
for your art, your company?
Do you realize because of your lies...
the best musical comedy star
is quitting show business?
ls that so? That's no loss.
lt'd be if Petrov were mixed up
with that cheap vaudeville.
However, l've scotched all that,
and l'm proud of it.
You scotched it all right.
This boat is getting terrible.
What is that noise?
-lt's a fire, the boat's on fire.
-ls it?
This boat?
Of course, yes! What are we going to do?
-Nothing.
-Nothing?
-Stay where you are.
-Don't move.
-Don't move, but hurry. My word, yes!
-You'd better get into this.
-l'm going to sue the company.
-lf we get out alive.
-l'll sue them anyway.
Take the Thermos,
you may get stranded on an island.
We'll need this for cold nights.
l feel the flames, they're getting nearer.
Now let's keep our heads.
What else do we need?
-Hats.
-Of course, hats.
-We don't want head colds.
-No.
Gentlemen always dress,
even on a tropical island.
-And this basket of fruit to eat.
-Of course.
l'll pick up a few blankets. No, wait.
The clock, so l'll know when it's bedtime.
Petrov, l know they've lowered our boat.
Take this. We may be stranded for a while.
Time will hang heavy on our hands.
-We will vary it with a little golf.
-A little golf, yes.
-Go ahead, Boat Station 4.
-Station 4. We got everything?
-Everything.
-Come on, don't forget the blanket.
-l'll get the blankets.
-And don't get excited, just follow me.
Come on, follow me.
Come on, Petrov, hurry up.
l'm all right. Don't get excited, anybody.
Everybody keep calm.
My boat's Number 4.
My boat's Number 4, where? Four?
All right, l'm here. Let it down.
What are you waiting for?
Miss Keene? She's back already?
Goody. Miss Keene's back.
Give me her key, will you, please?
Thank you, very much.
-Welcome home, l'm so happy to see you.
-Thank you, Cecil.
You're in sooner than we expected.
Are you alone?
Certainly, and who else
would be with me?
You are the one, miss,
keeping it a secret so long.
-There is no secret.
-No, not now but--
There never was.
Very well, miss.
l know professional people.
You'll find me the very soul of discretion.
Yes, indeed.
Just one moment, please.
l've got a surprise for you.
Voila!
-Jim, l'm so glad to see you.
-l received your cable, Linda.
You're looking very well, considering.
-You look grand, too, Jim.
-Thanks, l'm lucky that way.
Nothing shows in my face.
But why didn't you tell me, Linda?
Tell you? There's nothing to tell.
-Then somebody's wrong.
-Oh, that.
Lot of false malicious gossip.
Petrov? On his way up? Splendid.
-Cecil Flintridge.
-No, Jeffrey Baird.
l beg your pardon, Cecil Flintridge.
l beg your pardon, Jeffrey Baird.
No, Cecil Flintridge.
l don't like to disillusion you, old man,
but l am Jeffrey Baird, Petrov's manager.
And l am Cecil Flintridge.
You mean you are Cecil Flintridge?
-Yes, that's what l mean.
-Well, what of it?
What?
-Cecil of the hotel?
-Yes, of the hotel.
Of course. Well, how are you?
How are you? How do you do, indeed?
l've been at great pains
to make you and Mr. Petrov comfortable.
-Have you really? That's very kind.
-l thought it was kind of me.
Your suite is right next to
Mrs., or shall l say, Miss Keene?
Miss Keene? What!
You blundering blunderer!
Petrov.
-Do you know where we are?
-Wait a minute, don't tell me.
New York.
Yes. No, we're right next to Linda Keene.
-Good.
-That's what l thought.
Nobody's interested in what you think,
if you do.
l'm only trying to do my best, sir.
Do your next best and move us
to another part of this hotel.
Why shouldn't married people
have adjoining suites?
-Because they're not married.
-Not married?
Arthur.
Linda, l've only kept the roof open
in the hope you'd come back.
Since you left,
l haven't had one revue there.
l couldn't find a big enough name.
Arthur, l'm not that good.
You're right, Linda, you're not.
Seriously, the crowds who haven't been
on the roof since you left think you are.
-Arthur, l forgot to tell you something.
-What, Lynn?
l'm going to be married
to Jim Montgomery.
Well, l guess l'm licked.
lf you have your mind made up
that definitely...
there's nothing more l can say
to influence you.
No, l'm afraid there's not.
Except to wish me luck.
Well, you know l do, Lynn.
All the best, the very best.
Thank you, Arthur.
There's just one thing l insist
on doing for you.
What's that?
Give you and Jim a farewell dinner,
tonight, on the roof.
We'd love it.
So nice of you to think of Jim.
l think of him constantly.
We've had our dinner.
What are we doing up here?
You'll find out when l do.
Yes, Mr. Petrov,
Mr. Miller's expecting you.
This way, please.
-Take this to Evans.
-Yes, sir.
Thank you, Arthur.