Greetings to Lovers of Music!
...So told the Aryans!
The sweetness of Music is....
....Enjoyed by Babies,Cows
and also by Snakes!
Traditional Music is a never
ending flow of Nectar!
We are inviting you wholeheartedly
for a dip in that River of Music
The sweetness and soothing effect of
our Tradtional Living Art Form!....
..With a hope that you'll support
us in this small endeavour!
So many starlwarts! this is our
humble greetings
Today's Music programme passed
off exceptionally well
Now the important programme
after this interval is....
...'Raga SankaraBharanam'
Maestro of Rhythm,Sir
Sankara Shastri!
...Who gave a new life
to the'Raga'
...One who mesmerised the world all
over by his rendering of the tune!
He'll sing that Raga
SankaraBharanam!
...He stopped suddenly in the middle
of the Recital and walked out!
That's all,isn't it,madam Sarada?
When he starts singing,audience
sit like Sages in penance!
Gopalam! do you know what
happened at Sarada's birth?
Labour pains started
for madam....
...When Doctor said that
situation is worsening!
...l ran to the Music programme
to inform him!
As soon as l saw him singing
with single minded devotion...
...l stood there standstill!
Atlast,after finishing the programme
when he came home....
...Everything was over!
He didn't even have a
last glimpse also!
Seems to be like our carriage
Did you hear? Oh God!,l find
anger even in that hoots also
What's this Gopalam? ls there
any justice in it?
...l am asking you
is it there?
l am carrying my persucussion
why are you asking about justice?
That's not the matter,Man!
When this man met you for
the programme!
lt seems you had asked
him to cancel it!
...You sit here! l'll tell him
-No problem!
Look! our Telugu people praising our
own Telugu man is quite different!
People from a very far away
Karnataka state
Coming here on behalf of
a Kannada Association
..After arranging a Music programme
by our man!
..Want to Honour him? lavishly
..Will be taken procession
on an Elephant!
..Will be honoured by the
Minister with a Garter!
They've arranged everything
in a very big way
Yes sir!
We have arranged everything
to Honour Mr.Sankara Shastry!
On his name,we have even
sold tickets heavily!
Now,lf you say no the
programme....
...They'll finish off me
with it!
Gentleman! that's what l'v
been speaking to him?
You keep quiet!..keep quiet
Did you hear this man?
How sad he's feeling
in Kannada,poor chap?
Whatever it may be,this
programme should go on!
That's all sir!....that's all!
lf Sankara Shastri's programme
is cancelled....
...A lot of...
...Didn't l tell you not
to interfere in my talk!
Didn't l tell you?
Yes sir,you've told!
Leave it to me! you
please sit down!
Sit down...please...
sit down!
-okay!
What? ls your intention to deny
people hearing his music?
What?!
Sir,why are you asking me?
You both are bosom pals,isn't it?
Why don't you ask that
with my boss?
l'll ask him only!
...Not only ask him!l'll give
him a good shedding too!
Even a killer who has
murdered 10 people...
..l can look straight into his
eyes and make him accept the crime!
What?....do you think am
l afraid of him?
ls he there inside?
He's there in the next
room only!
You idiot! why don't you
tell that first?
Do you think,would he have
heard my talk?
What's it Madhava?
What you were talking about beating
and shredding some one?
Oh! lt's about your sister-in-law!
As lf there are no vegetables
in the market....
She took Rs 3 and brought
1 Kg of Brinjals....Brinjals!
l was telling this to Gopalam
isn't it Gopalam?
Sir,without talking about
musical programme!....
...You're talking about
some brinjals
You don't know about him!
lf we talk about musical
programme!lt'll be disastrous
...That crazy woman did
bring brinjals!
Will she have to bring
only brinjals?
ls it good?
Poorthing! he's secretary of
Kannada Association!
She did bring brinjals!
shouldn't they be good?
...All were worm infected!
..He wants to arrange your
music programme and....
Even though worm infected l've
ordered her to make curry!
Did she prepare it? she
made it very ordinarily!
..He's...Honour with..Garter!
My child! Sarada!
...Keep this inside!
Hey! will you listen to my
talk properly or not?
What are you saying?
Sometimes you're saying this and
then,for sometime that!
..Talking about brinjals!...
...What do exactly want
to tell me?
Do you want me to tell?
Sir,please tell him!...
tell him...tell him...
He's secretary of Kannada
Association
He wants to honour you by Elephent
procession with a Garter!
lf you accept it,l'll be
very happy!
lf you don't accept
then,it's a swear on me!
..l am going!
Oh! Lord Raghavendra! everything
is your mercy!
Hey! Rathna! what is
Tulasi saying?
What will she say,sir?
Believe me! lf l say she's ready
to die for you!
She's always immersed in your
thoughts only,poor mad girl!
Sometime back it seems she had
seen you on the road!
That night,she got up from sleep
half way & sleeping on my bed
Do you know what
did she do?
Yuck! how am l to say it?
Even then,l told you her that l am
her mother,not the LandLord!
But...still....
...l am feeling very shy!
l can't tell it anymore
Even at this age you're
making me sweat!
l don't know how tantalising
you would've been in your youth!
That days were quite different!
When l was at Tulasi's age....
No married man lived happily with
their wives in the village!
That was a great time!
...Even my daughter has got
all my traits!
Sir,you're everything to her!
What was that?..what was that?
Ah! Diamond Necklace!
How can l come bare neck
infront of the Land Lord!
...How am l to come?
...My child is feeling very
much like this!
Sister,lf land Lord decides
what's Diamond necklace?
..He can get even a Diamond
waist belt also!
..lsn't it sir?
Leave side those jewel's talk!
This time l've come to this
place only for Tulasi
lsn't it possible atleast
today or not....
Oh! why isn't possible sir?
Last time,it wasn't possible
because it was her menses period!
Today,you come as soon as
night falls!
We'll arrange everything
for you here only!
You'll come definitely,isn't it?
lf you don't come
it's a swear on me!
Nice my child!...
lt's very nice...
There,l've been trying hard
to attract that LandLord
Here,you're sitting prettily to
repair strings of your instruments
lf we believe,ldols of Gods
and ordinary mortals!...
..We'll be left with only Ash!
Fool,l've spent money to teach
you song & dance...
...Only to mesmerise and keep these
rich men under your thumbs
Actually,a priest mustn't have stammer
and we mustn't have devotion
Understood my child?
Look,that LandLord will come
her at dusk!
lf you refuse,Goddess of wealth
will go away from our door step!
l always wanted that eyes of such
rich men only must fall on you,so
..l've been keeping you behind a curtain
even though so many desired you!
Look,if you come after having
a nice head bath with oil
..l'll plait your hairs with flowers
and make you wear a silk saree!
What my child? you must
listen to me
You're my Goddess,isn't it?
go,my child!
Sister,why are you requesting her?
Tonight,if she accepts that
Land Lord,it's okay!
lf she acts madly,l'll tear her
apart into pieces and throw away
Hey! she may be in this train?
This train? ldiot,she has
already left in that train!
Come with me,let me see!
Gentelman! we've come!
Get down!
Fine?
-fine!
Don't know!
Shastri is in this coach
..this coach!?
Oh! my child,there's no place where
l haven't searched for you!
Without having food and sleep,l've
been searching you,my child!
My child!
What's this,sir?
The girl who should've got
married and settled!
Have you made her to
elope with you?
Look madam,do you know whom
you are speaking with?
l know it sir!
l know very well about him!
My daughter Tulasi is mad
about Music!
Taking advantage of her weakness
This music Teacher trapped her and
made her to elope with him!
You come my child!
Look gentlemen!
For Holy places like this bring
some Holy man! they'll become purified
But,not womanizers
like this man!
l am getting late to the court!
Please,quickly tell details
about your case!
My father! he had..
two wives!
l am first wife's son
...My mother is no more!
Extremely sorry!
Now,my father wants to bequeth all
property to second wife's son
Excuse me!
-yes madam!
Will you come here for
a moment?
Coming madam!
Not you!....it's me!
l am very busy there
what's it?
ls it true?
-what?
l couldn't believe it!
lt seems that brother is roaming
all over with that Tulasi
Till that,what you said
is true!
Beyond that whatever you may hear
is totally false!-is it okay?!
That isn't like that
The whole village is gossipping
about it by biting ears!
Let them bite their ears!
Why only ears? let them bite and
eat their noses,eyes,hands,mouth!
Not like....
l am discussing with the party
there,don't disturb me!
Ah!...what were you
saying man?
...And your father had died!
No
My father has two wives
my mother has died!
Excuse me!
Oh God! what's your problem?
lt's not a problem,why don't you
listen properly what l am saying?
What's it?
How orthodox is my brother?
How traditional is his family?
Without praying God,he wouldn't
even take a drop of water?
Now,did he get over drunk and
fell on any streets?
He gave shelter to an orphan
that's all,isn't it?
Don't twist the point like
your parting of hair!
That isn't it....
Oh God!..outside a party...
Oh! what were you saying?
You have two wives and
your first wife's dead!
No sir! l am dead....
Greetings! l'll take leave
of you!
Hey! man! wait.....no one's dead
come back!
No sir....l don't want!
Brother and his ancestors are
very orthodox,isn't it?
Then,if he does....
Gone...my party has gone away!
What's your point?
He gave shelter to Tulasi
that's all,isn't it?
Both Love Music! so only he
did like that!
ls it wrong?
Tomorrow,if any lady customer comes
and talks with me here!
Do you take it as that,l'll leave
you and go away with that lady?
Whatever caste she may belong but
she's as Holy as the Oscimum sanctum
No one gets that Modesty,Obedience
Humbleness and Devotion!
Till now,you are tantalising me
like a hiding gauva behind the leaves!
My desire on you is over!
Now,you go with that music
teacher or go to the hell
ls he God to you?
Mad girl,what can this man be to
you who knows nothing except music?
lf you want go with him
..go with him!
That's all isn't it?
Yes,Madhava!
Somehow Tulasi must get out
of this case!
l'll bear whatever it
may cost me
Understood!
lf there's any crime in this case
everything's of mother,not Tulasi!
Somehow l'll argue and
win this case....
Excuse me!
What?
Butter milk?!
Which one is with lesser salt?!
This one!
Now,my point is that l know the
relationship between you both
But,there's a world at large
Even if a father goes out
with his grown up daughter!
This world talks something
bad about them!
Madhava,l am not afraid of
this world,except God!
The relationship l've with Tulasi
only l & God know about it!
You think about the case!?
You mean to say,you've
accepted this case?
l mean you're going to
argue Tulasi's case!
lsn't it to argue? that l've
taken up this case!
Will you argue and win it also?
lsn't it to win that l
am going to argue?
Then,break that mirror first!
Why?
l want a broken glass piece!
Why? do you want to
stab and kill me?
No,l'll stab and kill myself
You've tottooed conch & discus
on your shoulders!
Are you going to argue for
a prostitute?
Oh! my God!
Whatever you may say,l'll argue
her case that's for definite!
What?...what's the problem
in it?
You're born wrongly to me!
The good advices given me have
become loathsome,isn't it?
Will you bring your own
mother to the streets?
You'll pay for all this!
Sister,you don't feel sad!
Before you come back,l'll
put her into the right track!
l begot a very bad progeny
so only l am going through this
Where are you going off?
l'll deskin you & dry you up
be careful!
Come to the house!
lf we request humbly
you'll not listen!
lf l lash all over your body!
You'll go to any man quietly
as and when l order you!
Come to the house!
Child Sarada,l am going
away from here!
lf we allow anyone into the house
all the sins will besiege you!
They'll go to the hell!
This was a orthodox house so only
l could stay for so many days
Now,with new ideas and if they
allow new people into the house
...l feel like l am in the
middle of a great fire!
Hereafter l can't stay here! l'll
retire in some temple
Are you listening my child?
Till now,lf they had mentioned
the name of this house!
..They used to think it as
pure as the fire!
Now the same people are
abusing this house
Hereafter l can't stay here
my child Sarada!
Father,that cooking aunty!...
My child,go and get my
prayer room ready!
Oh Mother!
Father,the vessel fell!
While,l was coming quickly to
prepare food for the God's offering....
What? don't you know to cook?
When a small girl was trying
to cook with great difficulty
Those who know it can go and
help her,isn't it?
Rituals & traditions are for keeping
a man's heart in right path only
They're not to create barriers
between men by caste,Tulasi!
Next you came in!
Madam,do you need the cart?
Sir,A bad man's sin is taking
a human form in me
l may have expected much more
than my luck!
My wish of serving you remained
an unfulfilled wish!
So,l'll name my forthcoming
child on your name
Have you got any objections sir?
You've only told that Sankarabharanam
means poisonous snake!
The poisonous snake became
a jewel to Lord Shiva!
The poisonous seed growing
inside me!
lf it can reach your lotus feet
that's more than enough for me!
Madam,get in!
Mother,why are you praying
to the foot prints?
Didn't l tell you that,there's one
who's Mother,Father,Teacher & God to us!
These are his foot prints! son!
Oh! ls it of Mr.Sankara Shastri's!
Where's he?
Son,what are you going to
tell him?
Sir,my parents are dead!
Sir,l am an orphan!
lf you feed me l'll serve you
& be at your feet only!
For so many years l had looked
after you so well!
Only to present you
at his feet!
The luck which didn't favour me
if it favours you!
Only to see it happily and die!
Don't worry mother,some how l'll
enter his house!
...l'll learn music from him and
become as great as himself
Greetings madam!
You're a small kid why are
you singing that song?
You're singing of wide oceans do
you know the meaning of it?
....Means....
Oceans means....
When elders in the family've great
difficulties like marriage,ills..etc!
When they're not able to
withstand these difficulties....
They'll say that we are not able to
swim through this family of ocean!
That's the meaning of it!
Oh! ls it the meaning?
Oceans means difficulties!
Look! without knowing the meaning of it
l was singing about myself only
l too have many difficulties
l don't have parents
l am an orphan!
Even that is also an ocean of
difficulty,isn't it?
lf you had a small kid
brother like me!
How nicely you would've dressed
him up and sent him to school
l don't have anyone to send me
to school or good clothes!
Even that is also an ocean of
difficulty,isn't it?
Sometimes,even lf l roam few streets
l don't get even a fistful of rice!
Then,feeling very hungry,l'll drink
water to my stomach
That's all!
For every gulp,l'll imagine it
as some food item and drink it
When it rains or gets very cold
l'll sleep in a corner in some temple!
Like this l've got lot
of oceans of difficulties!
Sometimes,l'll sing this song
sitting in some temple
Then,why did you come
here today?
Only yesterday,l came to know that
this is Sankara Shastri's house!
You're his daughter,isn't it?
...l am new to this place!
Just because you're his daughter
you may not know about it!
Right from useless singers like
me to Great Musicians!
Sankara Shastri is God
to everyone of them!
We don't have any other God!
So only l am sitting at his door
step and singing like this
That God's heart may melt....
And shower mercy on me and
give me a job & shelter!
Expecting this l've been
singing at his door step!
Poor Boy! are you feeling hungry?
Yes!
l didn't eat anything
since yesterday!
ls it so?!
Come,brother!
Thank God! l've got the
priest's Boon
..Now,lt's enough it l get
the God's boon
Can l call you as sister?
You can,what's wrong in it?
Then,sister you don't have to worry
about anything from now!
...Now that your brother
has come to you!
l may look very small
but l can do all the work
Without cutting my fingers
l can cut vegetables!
Without tearing l can
wash clothes!
Then,without spoiling the broom
l can sweep home clean!
Oh God! do you know how many
jobs l can do?
Come and show me!
Will you do the cooking
traditionaly or....
Even that also you want
me to do!
You don't have to do anything
you just sit here!
l'll call you as soon as
l finish my cooking!
Son,lf you touch their door you'll
hear the music of Tanbura
Wherever you place you feet in that
house,you'll hear the basic 7 notes
That house itself is a Temple
for Goddess of Learning!
Greetings sir!
Sarada,why did you allow this
boy into the house?
Father it seems he's
an orphan!
Sir,l am not boy
l am Sankaram
l am an.....
sister,you tell him!
..l can't say anything further
regarding this matter!
lf we feed him,he said he'll stay
with us only doing odd jobs for us!
So feeling pity on him l only
allowed him to stay here!
Sir,even yesterday,l had come
to ask you about this only!
As soon as you opened the door
Aren't there those poltergiests!
hearing their cries & shrieks
Making fun of them,l shook
my hips like this...
You opened the door and
slapped me!
Sir,even if you scold or beat me
l've come to be at your feet only!
My stomach is very small
isn't it,sir?
l'll not eat much...
only this much!
l'll do everything for you sir!
l'll wash your clothes!
Your..and sir,l know the prayer
Hymn also!
While you're doing the prayer
l'll recite it!
Sir,when you take bath,you'll not be
able to reach you back,isn't it?
...l'll clean it for you!
Have you written it? yes sir
l've written it!
Now,the intro will come
here again
That's it!
You have many records and other
things in your home,isn't it?
Yes!
Did you hear this song
at any time?
l've heard it,Master!
Sing it as you've heard it!
Stop it...stop it!
That's the difference between
you and me!
Long back this song was tuned in
this Raga while travelling in a boat!
Now,Buses,Trains,Planes,Rockets
Jackets,Jets everything have come,isn't it?
Speed!...the whole world is
nothing but speed!
How speed has come into our
daily life?
Just like that,it must come
into our Music also!
Regarding this,l've done so
many new experiments!...
...l've found new Ragas
and tuned them!
lf l say truthfully,learning music
from a Maestro like me...
..lt is your luck!
Do you know how to sing
this song really?
How to sing it sir?
Oh! is it you Mr.Sankara Bharanam?!
...Come...come..come
lt's very important that orthodox
people like you
..Should compulsarily hear the
experiments by Maestro's like me!
Breaking up the word into
letters as you wish...
And changing the meaning,is that
what you call as experiment?
Das! A hungry child calls its
mother in a different way
A child got hurt calls it mother
in a different way
A child getting up in the middle of
sleep calls its mother in an another way
Every experience has a definite
Note,Rhythm & Tune!
Das,behind every word of that Hymn
there's heart felt experience!
This song came out of the heart of
a Great Saint in a Trance!
..And this Raga!
With insufficient knowledge and
in the name of experimenting...
Don't desecrete the
Nectar of Music!
The music,on which this Nation
holds it's head high!
..Don't vulgarise it!
Don't know,what's all this fuss?
l don't understand,not only his
song's even his talk also!
Andalu! Did you understand
anything?
Master,l understood it
very well!
Wipe it off! wipe off the
cob webs from your brain!
..Now,learn the song child!
You don't know anything
l'll not learn from you!
Sir,l understood everything you
said to that master!
But,sir l couldn't understand
the meaning of 'Experience' only!
Sir,what do you mean
by'Experence'?
An idea,that a Language
can't fathom
An idea that'll melt
your heart!
Oh! is it? then,isn't there that
'Experience'in that master's song?
There's no 'Experence'in it!
There's Derision in it!
there's Ridicule it!
When we sing that Raga even
stones should melt!
Music in a Boon!
A God given power! Ridiculing
it is a great sin!
Then,shouldn't we sing
like this,isn't it?
You shouldn't!
That isn't the style to sing
that devotional song!
Uncle! come!
lsn't you father at home?
He has gone out uncle,he'll come
back please be seated!
There's no time to sit! do one thing
pack your clothes quickly!
Why uncle?
l and your Aunty are going
to Annavaram!
She's has to fulfill a wish!
lf you also come will us and
have a glimpse of the Lord!
l feel that your marriage time
will arrive at the earliest!
Come on,get ready!
get ready
After asking father's permission!...
Father! what father?!
He never takes you out
no entertainment or fun!
What a father he is?
completely abstruce father!
Uncle,that isn't it!l think it'll be
better if you inform him & take me
Why? Am l afraid of
your father?
Why? will be chop of my head?
You were very young,you may
not remember it!
..Your father used to shiver
even at my thought!
He never used to talk to me
looking straight into my eyes!
He used to go away after talking
looking at threshold,doors,etc..
Fearing that you'll be afraid if
he sees your straight
Shut up,you impertinent boy
l'll tear you apart!
Sir!
l'll turn and pluck out your ears!
Be careful!
...Look,sir has come!
Let him come,today,l'll
wash him clean!
lf l ask him to send Sarada
with us to the pilgrim centre
ls he so brave enough
to refuse me?
Which place?
l and your sister-in-law are
going to Annavaram!
lf you don't send Sarada with
us it's a swear on me!
Sarada pack your bags!
l can't anymore!God l can't
go up this steps!
Hey! Kamudu! l am feeling
breathlessness!
Good! as if the mortar for pounding
grains,complaining to the drum!
..You're complaining to me
about breathlessness!
..Already l am feeling
giddiness
Telling that going to temple
fasting would do good!
You brought me here without
allowing me to have coffee also!
Come on!..move on!
Lord Sathyanarayana!
Hey! You?!
Me? l thought you were
calling the Lord!
Oh! God! it's a sin!
What?
Open that water jug and give me
some water,l'll quench my thirst!
Oh! God! My Golden Glass!
Thanks madam!
Okay! come let's go!
Grandma,we'll sit here for
some time! it's very fine here!
Up there,it'll be better
than this!come!
Hey! l am feeling again
very tired
Feeling it? thank God! please sit here
for sometime and quench your throat
Grandma,for every second step
take rest & have some water
That is my wish!
Here!
Why are you so irresponsible?
That was given by my parents as
a dowry,when l got married!
l was looking after that glass
like my own life!
l don't know,how many dents
it may have got?
Hey! hey! wait
-what happened sir?
What's there in the bag,show me?
there's nothing sir!
Hey! take it out..take it out
l'll give it..give it you
First take it out
here take it sir!
So,small boy,yet....
Grandma!
Have you seen my grandma?
How do l know,who's
your grandmother?
Already she's little crazy,l don't
know where she might have gone?
Grandma!
Stand properly in the queue
turn back sir!
Grandma! Grandma
Please,wait my grandma
is missing!
Grandma!
Hey! Kamudu!
Why did you come without
informing me?
Do you know,l was searching
you all over futily!
Enough of your cleverness! before
that security sees you,join the queue!
lf he sees you he'll throw
you out of the line!
May be this is ladies queue!
No problem! come in!
Did you bring the glass?
Brought it!
Yes move on...move on!
Move on...move on
Come on sir,quickly!..
move on...
Move on..move on!
Sir,you please wait!
Why are you stopping us?
There's no space inside
go after some time!
Look,allow us to go!
lf you want,stop the
people behind us!
That is not possible madam
eveyone is equal here!
Buying a bus ticket for Rs 2 and
coming from a far away place!
When we have come for a glimpse of
God!who are you to stop us?
Look! do you think am l an
ordinary woman?
ln Kakinada isn't there a son
of Gundu family
Do you know,whos'it? he's Head Constable
Don't you know him?
son of Gundu family
...He's my nephew!
Hey! you come in...
come in!
Madam,you wait...wait!
l had a very nice glimpse of God
because of your good deeds!
Even,l too have the some
satisfaction!
My child,how was yours?
Uncle,l too had
nicely!
Okay,you both sit here,l'll
go & get God's offerings!
Alright!
Uncle,why do you take trouble
l'll go and get it!
Will you get it? my child
my great child!
Here take this and get it
get it....
..We'll be sitting here
and get it!
May be we are getting late
for the bus down the hill!
Go quickly and get one packet
of God's offerings!
l can't go!
You must go and get it & then if
you feed me with your hands!
..Till then,l am not in a position
to move an inch also!
Alright,l'll go myself!
Wait! you're old! why do you
take trouble?
Give it to me,l'll go
and get it!
One packet
-4 packets please
Here take this Aunty!
....Uncle
Seems to have given
excess change?!
Uncle,give it to me,l'll
find out and come!
lts God's property! give and
then only come,my child!
Take it!
What's this?
What?
You took Rs 10 but brought
only one packet!
..The balance should be Rs 9.50
but you've brought only Rs 3.00!!
Wait here!
You've given less change,you've
given more change to me!
Settle it between yourselves
why to distub me?
Grandma,take it your Rs 9.50
tie it safely in your saree corner!
Give me some water Please!
Where's the water jug?
You were only carrying
it in your hands!
Yes!
You've missed it some where?
was it any ordinary water jug?
When,l was married....
lt isn't here also!
Excuse me sir! did you see
my water jug?...water jug?!
How do l know,if you ask me?
Go and search,where you
had lost it?
What happened to it?
Look,Sankarabharanam has
come here rolling?
Poor soul,may be interested
in learning pop music!
What do you say,master?
l am saying howling & making noise
at midnight is wrong
Noise and shrieks at midnight?!
Learning for 24 hours a day also you
can't learn even 10% of the pop music!
Have you taken it to be
your 'Prologing Music'?
Learning the 7 Notes by heart
lt isn't like for hours stretching
& pulling one single note!
Your style of Music can be
learnt just like that!
..But our music isn't
like that!
..lt's an ocean..
in that..
Hey! it's useless telling all
this to an illiterate!
Mr.Shastri,please sing your
music go...go please go!
ls it so difficult,that music?
Difficult? its great difficult!
For you to sing 3 words
you've to toil hard for it!
ls it? alright sing
a few lines!
You called our music as
very silly & easy
l'll hum a Raga
please try it!
Music doesn't have differences
of Language & Regions!
lt's an Eternal Flow
of Nectar!
Man from any Caste from
any Religion or any Country!
...Can quench his musical
thirst in that Eternal Flow!
Who are we to decide about
one music as high and other as low!
Without ever trying to learn our
music and traditions!
Your Ridiculing it is
sheer stupidity!
When many foreigners have
accepted the greatness of our music!
..And have been trying to learn
our Traditional Music!
Children fo this country
ridiculing our own music!
..ls like the crime of
abusing one's own mother!
..And a sin like hating
one's own mother!
Pack one kg!
Cost of a biscuit packet sir?
Rs 1 .25 paise!
Give me one!
Subbaiah! l've come to you
for a small obligation!
What? do you need
money again?
Yes!
Sir,how many times can l give
you money on your mortgaged house
Till now,you've given me a lot
l don't deny it!
l am keeping account of
everything!
Some day l'll settle your account
and only then l'll go!
Sir,lts not that,you'll cheat me?
How can you repay it?
All you have is expenses and
not a pie as income!
Alright,lf you don't want to
give it,l'll not force you
l'll go!
Wait sir!
l can understand under what
circumstances,you had asked for it
Keep this Rs 300!
Take it madam
What's this,Gopalam?
...You're missing the beat!
Missing the beat was because of
the mistake l committed sir!
l ditched you & came off!
Sir,for 12 years these hands
never had any work!
Before l die,atleast for once l
must play perscussion to your music!
...l've been praying to all God's
for that oppurtunity sir!
lt's not the question of you
getting an oppurtunity!
People are not fortunate enough
to hear Good music
But,Gopalam this will not
continue forever!
Again,the Traditional music
will get back its glory!
Gopalam,and that day
is not too far!
You've a rock like confidence
so you feel like that
Sir,but after seeing you live
like a king & seeing you now
..My heart is being overwhelmed
by deep sorrow!
Madman! though the property l
had earned vanished away!
..The God given voice
hasn't diminished!
l don't regret on the day l
don't have food!
..l'll regret only the day
l don't sing!
Take this money Gopalam
Sir,are you giving me charity
after taking loan?
Gopalam,we had shared good times
let's share bad times also
Take it...come on
take it!
Though when she was alive
she was hated as a street woman!
l felt really sorry for your
mother before her death!
She died after being
bedridden poor thing!
Once your mother fell ill
your uncle disappeared!
After that she had an unwept
and unsung death!
She had great desire of seeing
you once before her death
But,what was the use of it?she
died without her wish fulfilled
Before dying she bequethed
all her property to you!
Here! take these papers!
Sir,l don't know have any need
for this property now?
Till now,l had laboured
to earn my living!
l've sent Sankaram to the place
where he deserves to be!
Sir,l don't have desire
on anything now!
May be it is true!
But,if you don't want,you can
use it for some good cause,isn't it?
..You're interested in fine tuning
your instruments....
..But you're not at all concerned
about your daughter's life
This is in fine tune
..l've seen a very good match
for your daughter!
Seen it,isn't it? till now you
had seen may good matches?
Look,look l am warning you first
to stop ridiculing me
Like the match's before that
grooms father was cook!
..And this groom's mothers
background isn't good!
Citing such silly reasons,if you
refuse this match!
..l'll not keep quiet!
Now,this boy is multilingual
and handsome too!
Good & cultured
Except a grandmother he doesn't
have parents! poor boy!
He joined the school in our town
and as my neighbour very recently!
Look,hey! Sankaram!
l & my wife both have
liked him very much!
l thought of arranging the
marriage myself....but..
This generation children if they don't
see each other it may not be good!
What sir? is it my
sister's marriage?
Yes! this time it'll be
settled definitely!
Arrange everything!
So,it may not be that good,since
you're father of the bride!
lf l don't show you the boy
you may be feel bad,so only...
Even though being a bosom pal taking
undue advantage may not be good so!
Without giving you a hint,proceeding
myself not be that good,so..
l have told my wife to
bring them here!
They'll be arriving here at
any moment!
This ceremony of bride seeing
is just a namesake!
Look,hey! l am now giving
you a second warning!
lf you refuse it citing silly
reasons,it won't be good!
Crazy man,who are we to stop
marriage,if it is destined?
Won't l be happy if my
daughter gets married?
l'll not speak anything!
do as you please!
Stop..man!..stop!
Come in Aunty,this is
the house!
Come....get down!
Look! you've brought me
here forcibly!
l am warning you,l'll never
marry this girl!
Keep quiet boy!
Fool,consider it as your luck to
become son-in-law of Mr.Shastri!
Get down
Yes,get down
What's he saying Aunty?
Nothing! he was saying that the
house is very beautiful
Look! they've arrived!....
Come..come...come
Kamakshi! you go and look
after the girl-alright!
Come...come...Hey...come on!
Hey! Sankaram! he's groom
Mr.Kameshwara Rao
Your father-in-law
Sankara Shastri!
Did you see him at anytime?
Sir,he's a kid,where would
he have seen him?
l used to dream of hearing
this sir's music in my young age
My husband never used
to take me out!
With that,my wish has
left unfulfilled!
They used say in our times that he's
a heir to Goddess ofLearning
After so many years of life
atlast l could meet him!
what meeting him? now you're going
to become his relative!
Sit down
That is definitely a boon of our
past life's goods deeds!
Sir,l am not telling this just
because he's my grandson
...My Kamudu is....
What?
Why are you calling me as Kamudu?
can't you call me as Kameshwara!
You keep quiet!
My Kamudu has great
respect for elders!
Did you hear? he has
great respect for elders!
Sir,he doesn't have any
bad habits
Did you hear? it seems he
doesn't have any bad habits!
Except that he eats a left over
porridge in the morning!
..He doesn't have any habit
of taking coffee or tea!
How lucky it is now a days to get a
porridge eating son-in-law
My child! come
come sit down!
Hey! the girl has come....
Aunty tell him to lift his head
and look at the girl
Sarada,you too look at him!
Look at her,why are you feeling
shy like a bride?
Look!
My child,what is your name?
ls it?
So,you've been named after
Goddess of Learning
You said it right our girl is
re-incarnate of Goddess of learning
She sings very well,she has
education to write letters to her husband
Master! if you like my sister
then,take the glass-glass!
Sister,if you like him,take
the steel glass!
Did you see her nicely?
did you like the girl?
What's there in his liking or
disliking?
He's a young boy!
what does he know?
Sir,Even if she doesn't know
to cook also,l've no objection!
She has a great property of
music accrued hereditorily
That's enough for me sir!
l don't have the capacity to
ask that great man to sing!
lf his daughter sings a song
l'll think that he has sung it!
What my child? will you
sing a song?
Sister....
What is the Raga
you were singing?
..And what is the note
your singing?
How did Rishabam come
into pure Hindolam Raga?
Come on tell me,what is
Ascent of Raga Hindolam?
Descent?
Then,how did that Rishabam
come into it?
Don't you have any senses to
adulterate Ragas?
Really,if Vrishabam
comes into it then....
What's that?
Vrishabam or Rishabam?
lt's Rishabam sir,Rishabam!
A tongue slip!
lf a rishabam comes then
it'll not be a Hindolam
..lt may be Charukesi!
Charukesi?!
No..how can it be
Charukesi!
Coffee!....lt may be Kafi
First,you get up from there!
Get up!
When you can't pronance a
word Rishabam?
What right do you have to
talk about music?
lf you know it then talk
otherwise keep shut!
That's not...
Sir,we'll meet you
sometime later!
Not necessary!
You don't have the necessity!
But,Sarada needs a marriage!
She needs a companion
she needs a home of her own
Why do you want to marry her to
a Musician & spoil her life?
Aren't you satified with
your happiness?
ln music you're a Genius
an expert in Sankarabharanam
You've got yourself the fame
of wearing a Garter!
ls there anyone to call you for
a programme & pay you a Re 1 ?
How many years have passed
since you wore clean clothes?
How many years've passed since you
ate 2 square meals contentfully?
Are you able to buy atleast a
blouse for your daughter?
Why are you still proud
about yourself?
Kalidas cried that fate doesn't make
him to write poetry to uninterested!
When people don't want
your music?
When that music can't earn
you a decent living?
You've it! okay!
But,who has given you the right to
spoil her life with your desire?
Getting dejected she'll
commit suicide!
And taking her body into your
arms,you can then sing!
Even God can't save you
my friend!
What is the Raga you're singing
what is that note?
l don't know,what's
that Kamu?
Without keeping quiet,l had only
insisted on the girl to sing?
...And put her in a fix!
You put that girl in a fix
that's okay!
Unnecessarily l am in
a fix
Fool!
Without keeping shut,why did
you talk unnecessarily?
l had spent a fortune to
teach you music!
Couldn't you pronounce
a simple Rishabam?
lf it hasn't been your fate?!
You don't grumble!not that
l wasn't able to!
lf you want,test me now,l'll tell
everything Raga,Ascents & Descents!
Suddenly when he become angry
l got shivers!
..ln that l blabbered
something in haste
..That's all!
Even lf we penance for 10 lifes
we'll never get a match like that?
We spoiled with our
own hands!
Poor Boy!
l am more sad than you in this
how do you know it?
He told me to get out because
l didn't know music,isn't it?
Let me see it!
Rs 5000! your account is settled
isn't it?
Settled madam,wait here,l'll
get the receipt!
Mr.Subbaiah! l don't
want receipt
lt's enough if you say once that
Shastri's account is settled!
What's that madam?
Look! ln future,whenever Mr.Shastri
asks for money,give him
..l'll settle all his dues!
As you say,madam
l'll go now!
Mr.Shastri is coming here
don't tell him anything about me
Come sir...please come!
Please sit down
l've already taken a lot of
loans from you!
l thought l should never come
to you on that pretext!
But,l couldn't avoid it!
Sir,why are you saying
like that?
Do you need money sir?
l am arranging my daughters
marriage!
This time,you don't have to
lend me an just word!
Have you seen this?
l never considered this
as an ornament!
This is also a part of
my body...
And thought that lt'll go
with my body!
..l never imagined that such
a necessity will arise!
l don't know the value of
this in money!
Mortagage this and lend
me money
The people presented this ornament
for the Goddess of Learning in you!
Sir,l don't have the capacity or
worth to valuate this!
l'll give money happily whatever
is your requirement
Up to which have you
written boys!?
Master!...master!...
Wrote upto to Udayan?
Udayan's....
Evening at 5 PM come to
the Temple-what?
Why?
Very urgent!
Sister...sister..sister
sister...sister...
Evening at 5 PM come to
the Temple!
Why?
-very urgent!
Hey! what's this?
what's all this?
Everything for your good only!
Please,lift me!
Sir,has accepted for your
marriage!
l thought you both will have glimpse
of God happily,so l called you both
Rest is your will & wish
Sir,l felt very sad for
losing this proposal!
Now,you've come by yourself to
give your daughter in marriage!
My friend is always like that!
He's like dry ginger!
lf you put into eyes it'll
burn severly!
After that lt'll cool you
down you like snow!
ls it Sundaram Bhagavathar?
Look,the tune will be
like this!
...Harsh!
..But heart is...like butter!
..Hey! stop it man!
So,with this,invitation
work is completed!
l've promised someone with a
confidence that you'll not refuse me!
What's it?
Our....
..Sheshachalam's Hall has been
brought by someone
..lt has been remodelled
and refurbished!
lt's induguration is scheduled on
the day our daughter's marriage!
ls it?
They want to reopen it with
your musical performance!
They came and asked me
l've said 'yes'to them!
Sir's musical performance!?
l thought l'll die without
ever hearing him even for once!
So after many years atlast
my wish is going to be fulfilled!
That depends on his
acceptance
Hey! man! what do you say?
As you wish!
'Sankara Bharanam' Sankara Shastri
Temple of Arts!
Greetings to elders!
l don't have the capacity to talk about
the Art of this Great Exponent!
..Considering it as stage
But,still as his companion..
...l'll tell about the distinction
about this man!
ln past people eagerly awaited
to hear Mr.Shastri's music
..They used get thrilled
by hearing it!
l still remember him living
like an Emperor! Majestically!
l can still visualise that
Pomp and Grandeour
But with time,many changes
had crept into music!
For example,shall l embrace you
shall l cut you?
Shall l bite you or chew you
such Lyrics!
Music that resumbles the shivers
of a Malarial patient
...Have come to the fore!
Many sounds,shrieks!...
cries,shouts..deep sighs!
Have crept into music!
At this juncture,when there was no
support for his music!
..Mr Shastri inside the 4 walls
of his house!
Considering all living creatures as
Music Loving Audience!
Has been practising his
music uninterruptedly!
The traditional music which
is his life!
..Seeing such a stupendous
reception for his music
...A new brightness is seen on the
face this Great Sage!
That Mr.Shastri be blessed with power to
mesmerise us with his music
l pray God to bless him
with that power!
Thank you!
Greetings to everyone
The Lamp of Traditional Music which is
flickering with he storm of western music
l don't know who's that benefactor
trying to protect it!
..l am bowing to him
a million times
The lndian culture which is
getting weakened!
..And traditions...
..The Great Soul who's working for
its resurrection
..l am bowing my head and greeting
him by bowing at his feet
This Art from is a Living Art!
lt has no begining!
..There's no end to it!
The music which is being
disregarded!
To support it,even if one
in a crore is there!
..This Nector will Flow Eternally!
Even,when a man earns
money upto his height!
Long live with health
prosperity,fame!
Mother...mother...mother...
Father..father...father...
Sir,my mother?..