"You exist in the blue sky"
"You exist in soft buds"
"You exist in the
movement of the earth"
"You exist in
every moment of life"
"O God, wonder what
each one's zenith is here"
"You are the strength of the heart,
everyone's hope"
"You are everyone's companion"
"You are the strength of the heart,
everyone's hope"
"You are everyone's companion"
"You exist in the heat of the sun"
"You exist in the
softness of winds"
"You exist in running streams"
"You exist in the flight of birds"
"Everyone looks for
his zenith here"
"O God, wonder what
each one zenith is here"
"O God, you are the true summit
of everyone's path"
"Zenith!"
The facility GG Builder gives, no
other builder in Mumbai can give.
You are intelligent.
You can verify everything.
See for yourself. You have
invested in the right place.
Your money will bring you
rich dividends in the future.
Only if this government survives.
The political situation is in chaos.
The moment the government falls,
property prices will crash.
How can we invest more
in such a situation?
The interest rate GG gives,
no one else in the market does
And GG is no ordinary man.
No one had even heard of
him six years ago.
Today, he is the
top builder of the city.
Mr. GG has come.
Who among you wants
his money back?
What to do, sir?
Political crisis is on.
The government can fall any time.
The moment the CM falls,
even property prices will fall.
Neither will the CM fall,
nor property rates.
My offer still stands.
Want back your money,
I'll return it.
But remember, I will never
take money from you again.
Mr. GG, you are getting angry.
It's simple.
One can either sulk, or smile.
You can't do both together.
But GG,
think about the investors too.
One, the government won't fall.
And two, either fly in
the sky with me...
or crawl on ground like worms.
Glory to Amrit Patil.
This is great!
All good ministries, you will take.
And you expect me to show the
thumb to my party workers?
Sorry. Jaihind!
Patil, I'll give you
Labour, Water...
How will that help?
Tell me... how?
Agriculture, Health, Transport will
all stay with you. Even Garments.
You think I am a fool?
Stop being immature, Patil.
I'm giving you more
than you can digest.
Look CM, if I don't get
Rural Development ministry...
I'm not joining the government.
Great! You have learnt to bargain.
Good.
But remember, in the next
two years...
you will not make any more demands.
And if this condition
is acceptable to you...
congratulations for
the new government.
To you too.
Glory to Amrit Patil!
Silence please!
Look I only want to say...
for the progress of the state, and
for the welfare of the people...
our Party will
support this government.
But you were against the ruling
government during the election.
Isn't this cheating the people?
No, in politics, there is no
cheating, only decisions.
Sir, is it true that you
are getting Land...
and Rural Development ministry,
that is why...
Look, who gets what is
a matter of destiny.
It's day somewhere,
and night somewhere.
Glory to Amrit Patil!
Amrit Patil took the oath...
of Land and Rural
Development Minister today.
I, Amrit Patil...
"Why are you smiling so much?"
My love, life is
such a beautiful gamble.
I had thrown a fib to my investors,
that the government won't fall.
And it didn't.
Amrit Patil became king.
He became the
Rural Development Minister.
- Did you congratulate him?
- I'll give it to him personally.
400 years ago, Mumbai was
a group of seven islands...
where a few fishermen lived.
Which the Portuguese
gifted to the English.
Who had imagined such a
big city will come up here...
where business in billions
will be done.
Just think, who must have dared to
dream of building such a big city?
One man does not see the dream of
building a city.
Only one man sees a dream, Natasha.
Dreams cannot be seen in a group.
Last night, even I saw a dream.
Come to the bedroom,
I'll tell you about it.
Natasha, when I am thinking,
let me think.
City? Must say GG, you still
have the dream of building a city?
GG, you need thousands of acres
of land for it.
And this entire region
belongs to tribals.
It is not easy to buy tribal land.
There are a hundred laws,
thousand hurdles.
And you are not talking of
building a colony, but a city.
To build a city,
roads, hospitals, schools...
Shopping malls, multiplexes,
business centers...
amusement parks, hotels, clubs.
Yes, I am talking of a city.
Have you ever been to Las Vegas?
That's a place for players
like you.
I'll go if you take me.
Las Vegas; there was nothing there,
except a desert.
Not as many people come to
see the Taj Mahal in a year...
as many people go to gamble there
everyday.
Why?
Because just one man saw the dream
of building a city in a desert.
Just think, our own city, where we
will have monopoly over everything.
Security, electricity, water,
business, transport, everything!
And if we get permission for
casinos...
just think what can be done.
The investment
is of 8-9 hundred million.
And it can become a business of
30-50 thousand millions.
I'm not convinced, GG,
Mr. Patil, the region is yours,
the government is yours.
The financier is ready,
then what is your problem?
We will decide
your share beforehand.
'Let those who are looking
for God, find Him'
- Mukadam.
- Yes sir?
GG, he's Mukadam.
He handles all my business here.
Take Mr. GG
around the whole of Songarh.
GG, the dream is wonderful.
I've come across a man who dreams
with open eyes for the first time.
But until the dream materializes,
keep your eyes open.
They will stay open.
Mr. Patil... good night.
Mukadam, tell me,
what do these tribals do?
They do some farming now.
Earlier, there used to be
a drought here every year.
It's barren all around here.
I haven't see a single tree.
Show me some place where there
is greenery, there is water.
This area won't do.
This area is dry.
There is no water here.
Go towards the east,
there is water over there.
I heard some Guru has done
water harvesting there.
Even a huge lake
has been formed there.
What is that?
- That is Rishi-Van Ashram (Home).
- Ashram? It's heaven.
Know why King Jahangir
called Kashmir heaven?
Because he had
not seen this place.
Sir, who is King Jahangir?
The world's greatest builder,
Shahjahan, who made the Taj Mahal...
- his father.
- Oh!
Let's go there.
- Greetings Swamiji.
- Shubham (good wishes).
Vehicles are not allowed
inside the Ashram.
Sir, we will have
to walk from here.
Sir, about 50 years ago,
this Sage Vaidyanath...
started this Ashram.
If he is available,
we'll meet him.
No sir, he died 5-6 years ago.
They are into medicine business?
Not business, they distribute
Ayurvedic medicines...
since his times to people
for free.
There is a new Guru
who runs the Ashram now.
Their medicines are very effective.
Some years ago,
he even started an orphanage here.
He takes care of orphans,
distributes medicines for free.
What's his income?
I mean, where does he
get so much money from?
I don't know that, sir.
Come.
He is Mr. GG,
he wants to meet Guruji.
Guruji? Not possible today.
Today is Guruji's inspection day.
Wonder where he will be now.
It is better you
come some other day.
Is this Guru the sort who prays
and gives religious discourses?
No sir, this Ashram has no
connection with any religion.
It is said the doors of Rishi-Van
are open to people of all religions.
I'm sorry,
but smoking is prohibited here.
Hey Guruji!
Guruji, not me... he...
Because of the mistake of these
two, Guruji is fasting since 3 days.
He has not eaten anything.
You two will go to Guruji now
and apologise to him.
We will never smoke again.
We will not even fight again.
We made a mistake, Guruji.
Please eat, Guruji.
- You won't do it again?
- No.
Guruji, there is bad news.
I've heard Minister Patil's men
are buying land from the villagers.
- Ramnath, drink.
- Enough!
Drink free liquor and die!
Guruji is coming!
They are giving them free liquor
all day and night.
What will you talk to them,
Guruji?
Forget the Guruji. Drink!
Guruji cannot do anything to you.
Guruji will suppress you.
He won't let you progress.
Don't worry. The Minister has said
everyone will get a room...
and a ration card in Mumbai.
What is wrong with you people?
I fought for so many years with
the government...
and got you this land, and
you are selling it and leaving?
You don't know what you are doing.
Listen, tell Minister Patil
what he is doing is not right.
And I will not keep quiet.
- What did Talati say? All done?
- Yes.
Mukadam, this is Rs.1500000,
for petty expenses.
Give me an account
for this separately.
Khhote, whatever land
you are buying...
ensure the papers are in order.
And all the money should be given
through the Assembly's office.
Leave it to me, sir. Everything
will be done in a legal manner.
It was surprising.
I thought we'll have to use force.
GG, you are very lucky.
People are queuing up to sell land.
I am not teaching a minister...
but there is no place in the world
where money doesn't talk.
- Hello sir.
- Hello.
15 acres land. Pandurang Jadhav.
Rs.2000 for one acre,
Rs.30000 for 15 acres.
Witness, chief of Usla village.
Take. One, two three. 30000.
Put your thumb impression.
...The left hand.
People of other states are
coming and taking over Mumbai.
When our government is giving
houses for free...
then you have the first right
to take advantage of it.
It is my responsibility
to give you electricity and water.
A building will come up here
in two years...
and you all will get a home in it.
Sell hope,
and remain the winning candidate.
I've given you a permanent
vote bank for free.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Sir, I took Rs.10000 from each
person for a 10x10 room.
That's called killing
three birds with one stone.
Only if the work is done
on a war footing...
will we be able to give
infrastructure for a city...
at the earliest.
Time is money applies most
to construction business.
GG city will be such a city...
which the people of India
must not even have dreamt of.
This is Phase I.
Amusement park, five star club,
along with a golf course.
The moment it is ready,
people will start coming here.
Then with that money,
and money from the club...
we will start Phase II.
Housing.
The plan is very good.
But for that, Patil,
I want this Ashram land.
Have patience, GG, When all
the surrounding land is ours...
then even the tribals will leave.
Then what will the Guruji
sit here alone and do?
Even he will leave.
Every green leaf here,
every branch, tree...
is the result of Guruji's
hard work and effort.
This land was barren before.
We have to stop Minister Patil.
He will turn this beautiful
jungle to a concrete jungle.
Lawyer, what do we do about Patil?
Have you given it a thought?
Just one straight solution.
We will have to take a
stay order from court...
and stop this construction.
- Who is your Supervisor?
- What is it?
You will have to stop
construction immediately.
Why?
This is a copy of
the writ petition.
What's in it?
Ask your boss to ask his lawyer.
The court case will go on.
I own this place.
Have faith in me.
If construction
stops, I will be ruined
Millions have gone
into the project.
Can't you do anything about
this old Guru?
If you like,
I can get him killed any time.
I can make him
disappear like smoke.
But before that,
we must check his background.
Who he is, what is his goal,
we must know this.
- Wait until then.
- Wait?
Yes.
You want me to stop
construction until then?
Keep the construction going,
I'll see what is to be done.
Do you consider a writ petition
notice to be a joke?
What happened?
Now the Bailiff and government
officers are our witness.
Give him the stay order.
You got the notice to stop
construction two weeks ago.
And you are still working?
Take this stay order seriously.
If you continue with the
construction work still...
there'll be a
contempt of court case.
Lawyer, we are making a park, then
where is the contempt of court?
The stay order is on
entire construction.
Now you cannot do any work
anywhere in this area.
We will settle this between us.
Sure we'll settle it.
Stop all work!
You can wait for the stay order
to be canceled, we cannot.
Tell us when you are
returning our money.
What is the current situation?
Look, you have supported me so
much, just a little more.
If the work does not
start in three months...
you will get back your money.
- What will you do now, GG?
- I'll do something.
- Can I do anything for you?
- What will you do?
GG, this Guru turned out to
be a big shot. Know who he is?
He's Srinath Vardhan, the owner
of Vardhan Industries.
Crossing swords with him
will cost us dear.
We have got a stay order.
And moreover...
you and me are nothing
compared to Vardhan Industries.
You said it today, Mr. Patil,
don't say it again.
10 years ago,
I didn't have Rs.3000...
and in the next three years, I'll
gift wrap Vardhan Industries...
and gift it to you.
First hear the good news.
The Ashram land was given to this
Guru's Guru, Sage Vaidyanath...
on a 50 year lease.
That lease is expiring next year.
So what?
He will ask for lease again.
He has. 50 years. He has even
made an application to the CM.
The CM has not accepted it,
nor will he.
Why?
Because I saved this government
from falling.
And I only will
save it in the future.
GG, just one year. You'll have
to wait until the lease gets over.
One year? Are you crazy?
If everything stays like
this for a year...
my machinery worth millions
will rot away.
What do I do with it?
Sell it as scrap?
I'm paying interest
on millions of rupees.
What can we do now, GG?
We'll have to do something.
That mad old man must be having
some weakness.
Just let me get one loose end and
I'll pull the wool and strip him.
Just one weakness!
"My heart... my heart..."
"These bright rays"
"Shined in the mirror of life"
"This fight between sun and shade"
"The heart and body dances
with abandon"
"Everything seems new"
"My heart... my heart..."
"These bright rays"
"Shined in the mirror of life"
"In the lap of earth
is that dream valley"
"Where I had left
my childhood friend"
"Wonder what will happen next"
"The winds feel different"
"What I have felt is lovely"
"Sometimes I think I'll say this"
"Sometimes I think I'll say that"
"He sometimes seems my very own,
and sometimes a dream"
"Everything seems new"
"My heart... my heart..."
"The peace of day is lost"
"The sleep of night is lost"
"Someone seems to be
in my memory these days"
"If I meet him alone"
"I'll tell him"
"How crazy I am
about this dream lover"
"These bright rays"
"Shined in the mirror of life"
"This fight between sun and shade"
"The heart and body dances
with abandon"
"Everything seems new"
"My heart... my heart..."
Take.
Homi Wadia, careful, it's hot.
Forget it.
If you cared so much for me...
you would not come here
and become a recluse.
I knew you will take care of
Vardhan Industries well.
Which you have.
Now stop buttering me
and listen to me.
You withdrew your son from
a good school...
and gave him an education here.
Did I say anything? No.
What will the poor guy do learning
horticulture and tissue culture?
Who will run the mill
and industries?
I'll take your son, Jaidev to
Mumbai and teach him business.
Homi, even I want that he joins
you...
so that you teach him
the ways of business.
- Even Jaidev is like your son.
- Come, sit.
We have come to take you to Mumbai.
Whatever Baba(father) wishes.
He will surely come. Let him
stay with me for a few days.
- He has just come.
- Yes, stay.
But come to Mumbai soon
and manage your father's company.
Thank you.
Jaidev will have to go to Mumbai
and learn business management.
Punditji, Madhavi has
completed graduation.
I have told you many times
to find a suitable groom for her.
There is no need.
I won't leave you and go anywhere.
Even I won't leave
you and go anywhere.
Let's go, Manasi.
You spoke of taking
three people to Singapore.
Yes Baba.
Then take Kusum, Bajanlal,
and Madhavi.
How many days will you have to go?
The training will take 1-2 weeks.
I am going to Singapore for taking
equipment for the tissue lab.
I thought the three will also get
training on how to operate it.
Good idea. Then even if you are in
Mumbai, work will go on here.
Yes Baba.
This laboratory, technology,
how will we learn all this?
Jaidev is such an idiot!
Just keep listening to that
guy who talks in circles.
Mr. Bhajanlal, MA. LLb Allahabad.
Are you coming to Singapore?
- Ofcourse.
- Very good.
But only if Guruji wishes
and the government permits.
Because as per law,
every Indian...
has a right to live within India
without a passport or visa...
but if you wish to go abroad,
you have to have a passport and...
Enough! Stop your lecture.
I understood.
Jaidev was telling me he will make
20 bigger green houses than this.
He will grow 500000 plants,
that too, only in eight months...
and before the rains.
He also said you, me and Bhajanlal
will have to go to Singapore...
for training.
He told you, then you go.
He didn't tell me, I won't go.
The one who doesn't want to go,
go and talk to Guruji.
Kusum, tell me, what do you
know about plants and trees?
- That trees & plants are green...
- Wow!
Trees and plants are green. And
they are red, yellow and blue too.
Trees? Do you know the different
names of trees? Count.
- How many?
- 16. - There are more.
Bhajanlal, the lecture is over.
Your going to Mumbai and learning
business is important.
Homi has to retire too.
But Baba, what about your dream?
- So you remember my dream?
- You have just one dream.
To see this barren land
green and bountiful.
Baba, I will plants millions of
trees and fulfil your dream.
That's the day I am waiting for.
Today, I want to teach you
my principle of business.
Look son, the power to give
something to the world...
exists only in goodness.
Whereas evil only knows to
snatch and loot.
Thieves, bandits, fiends
can only snatch from others.
They cannot give anything,
except sorrow.
Whenever you meet someone,
weigh him on this scale.
Test whether he is out
to give something to the world...
or to snatch.
But Baba, if we only give,
how will we earn?
How will business prosper?
Earn... earn lots. But spend
a big part of your money...
for the betterment of society.
Then you will get the real motive
for your earning...
and the love of society.
And this love from society
will be your true earning.
Your true wealth.
Understood, son?
Son, I am your father's
greatest critic...
but actually respect him a lot.
Which man will leave so much money
today and serve poor tribals?
30 years ago, when your
father started this industry...
I owned 25% shares of this company.
This is a different world, son.
This is the world of business.
I'll show you how we turn
cotton into money here.
Your basic principle of business
should be...
that the quality of your goods
should be the best in the market.
And its pricing should
also be the best.
This is your father's philosophy.
And to achieve this, we have put
up the most modern machinery here.
So that we can have maximum
cost effective production.
Ultimately, the success of
a business depends on...
how you handle your manpower.
To take this company ahead
is your responsibility.
Now this is the annual report.
Please study it.
Excellent Mr. Prem. I knew
you were into many businesses.
And the dealership of
Vardhan Industries, that's great.
I have a business proposal
with which both of us can benefit.
Can you fix my meeting
with Jaidev Vardhan?
I have been selling the cloth
of their mill in my showroom...
since the last 20 years...
and you are asking for a meeting?
Assume the meeting is fixed.
By the way, does this Jaidev
have any friend in Mumbai?
He has just come to Mumbai.
He has no friends here.
If I had his phone number,
I would fix the meeting now.
- Mr. Prem, treat this as urgent.
- It will be done, GG,
- Some more coffee, Mr. Prem?
- No, I'll be going.
GG's idea is great.
It's between you two, you decide.
- All the best to you.
- Thanks Mr. Prem.
Don't mention it. See you.
Jaidev, Vardhan Industries
makes the best cloth in the world.
But who knows this?
You don't advertise.
You are right.
But whatever cloth we produce...
it gets sold without advertising.
Then why spend on advertising?
That's what I am telling you.
How much do you sell your
best quality cloth for?
Suppose Rs.1000/mtr.
If the same cloth is given
a fashion label...
like Armani, YSL...
a pant of the same material
will get sold for Rs.10000.
Our profit will be ten times more.
Mr. GG!
This is Ashwin Raga,
India's topmost designer.
- Nice to meet you.
- Thank you. Call me Raga.
Jaidev Vardhan.
I was telling him...
What is there to say? Whatever
GG lays his hands on turns to gold.
Construction, travel,
exports you name it.
That's why I want to give
Vardhan textiles a fashion label.
All the finance will be mine,
the designs of Raga...
and the cloth of Vardhan.
What say?
If you don't mind,
shall I ask you a question?
There are other mills who
don't advertise.
Then why did you come to me only?
Every big textile company
has its own fashion label.
And if I join hands with any
company, it won't be news.
GG is stepping into fashion
business for the first time. News!
With top designer Raga,
bigger news.
With Vardhan textiles.
Front page headlines!
Jaidev, I only want your material,
that too on credit.
I'm giving you one third
partnership...
that too, only in profits.
Losses will be mine. Only mine.
Your offer is indeed very good.
I'll speak to Uncle Wadia
and let you know.
Look Jaidev,
fashion is for young people.
Today's generation,
young minds, you see.
People like Wadia
won't understand it.
That is why he didn't advertise
until today.
I'd heard your praises,
that is why I contacted you.
I will deal only with you.
And Vardhan Industries belongs
to you people...
- then this Uncle Wadia...?
- He is my father's partner.
And your father, Mr. Vardhan?
My father?
- He doesn't manage business now.
- Oh.
Okay, let's have lunch.
The steaks here are good.
Sorry, I don't eat non-vegetarian.
Even the vegetarian must be good.
Hello!
- The super model is here!
- Hi Raga.
- Jaidev Vardhan.
- Industrialist.
But you look like a model.
- Hi Jaidev.
- Hi.
- Shall I call you Jai?
- Yes, sure.
Nats, GG's fashionable idea.
Fantastic!
Great? So when are you starting?
- Whenever Jaidev says.
- Not Jaidev, Jai.
Sorry, what is this wella?
- Wella means... it means...
- Wella waiter, menu.
- Only in profit.
- Yes, I understood.
Just think uncle, every textile
company has its own fashion label.
I know.
Because of this fashion label,
they sell the same cloth...
at double-triple rates,
and make more profits.
- I have checked everything.
- Are the people good?
- What did Mr. Prem say?
- He said the people are good.
Infact, he himself invests
in his construction company.
Son, I have never done
any advertising.
You have to
manage this company now.
If you think it is right,
go ahead.
We'll have to decide
on a brand name first.
Heed me, Manali is a great name.
Is this a fashion label
or a drug den?
Manali works.
Got it! Va for Vardhan and
Ga for Gaurav, and Raga. Vaga!
GG, that's brilliant.
Vaga by Raga!
It almost sounds
like Viagra in French.
There is just one promise
of fashion, quality.
When there is Raga,
there is quality.
And when there is Vardhan Textiles,
there has to be quality.
I think we should sell
something different, don't you?
I think we should sell sex.
Vaga fashions should make you
feel sexy and macho, and...
Come on, Raga.
In advertisement,
only one thing is said.
Okay, you're right,
we'll say only one thing.
- Let's sell sexy.
- No, not sexy, it's very vulgar.
Sexy means beautiful,
attractive, hip.
Whatever, but I think we
should target middle class people.
The middle class doesn't
care for a brand name...
only the first of every month,
my Qutub Minar.
Yes...
Excuse me Raga,
why did he call me Qutub Minar?
Whoever GG likes, he gives him the
name of a great construction.
- What does he call you?
- Guess.
Eiffel Tower?
We have to hype Vaga Fashions.
Not just with advertising. Parties,
press conferences, ramp shows...
- women, wine and money.
- Why GG?
News gets hot only with that.
I'll teach you how
to deal with the media.
Right now, you should
have only two goals.
Work hard, party harder.
And these two things are done
to the fullest only in youth.
But youth is meant for working.
And the real fun of parties
and discos lies in old age?
When I was 16 years old,
Camps Fire Club, Delhi...
My father gave me a beer in hand,
and said...
'Son, never do anything in
hiding from now on'
- Hi guys!
- Hello.
- Hi Jai.
- Hi!
- You always wear such clothes?
- Yes, why?
Nothing.
Look, we must quickly start
the entire advertising campaign.
It will be an investment
of atleast 15-20 million.
But that's too much.
Nothing of Vaga Fashions
will be sold less then Rs.1000.
Whether it is a handkerchief,
or socks. Nothing.
I don't want repetition.
- But a campaign of 15-20 million?
- People think cheap is passe.
It's my money that is being spent
and you are taking tension.
Exactly.
Natasha, which ad film maker
will be good?
If you want the whole ad campaign,
take Thakkar.
That's it, guys. Baywatch!
The concept should
be clear to everyone.
We have to shoot Baywatch.
Lots of girls are
dancing on the beach.
061810:46:5:1210:46:54:00
Costing. What will be the cost?
7-8 models, one male model,
we'll take John Abraham.
Shooting, Bali or Thailand,
one of those exciting places.
I think, it should not
cost more than 7-8 million.
Why abroad?
We have beaches even in India.
My friend, good advertising
is done like that.
Or you can take two pictures of a
shirt & stick it in the newspaper.
Advertising done.
Look brother,
the film has to be sexy.
Won't you give me company?
Not in this.
You give company in measures?
What are you doing in the evening?
Come on!
- Stupid!
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
Know to dance on your hands?
Learn.
Because you won't
have your legs tomorrow.
I'm sorry GG,
I didn't know they were with you.
- I'm really sorry.
- Tell them.
I'm sorry guys, really sorry.
GG, Jai is not coming to Thailand.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
What will I come and do there?
The ad campaign is going to begin,
and you are my partner.
Yes, but I told you, I have to go
on urgent work to Singapore.
I found out. Your lab training
is given in Thailand too.
I'll get the lab equipment
imported. Chill.
Leave your programme to me.
Okay. But 2-3 more
people will come with me.
They are not the uncle-aunty types,
are they?
No.
- Lift the glass, let's toast.
- Why?
Jai, you've made news.
You are on Page 3.
We have to celebrate today!
Come on!
- Take.
- I don't drink.
It's just champagne, not whiskey.
No one refuses champagne.
Come on.
He simply feels shy.
- Jaidev! Shubham.
- Bhajanlal. Get in.
So this is Patil's
construction work.
Not just this,
there is more behind the hill.
- Where? Behind?
- But everything is stalled for now
By the way,
what are you doing here?
I just needed shoes for the trip.
I bought those too today.
- Like them?
- They are very good.
- What's news on Mumbai?
- Everything is fine.
Business is good.
For that green house, we have put
up 8 tanks of 10000 ltrs each.
Greetings Baba.
Son, remembering your elders
is a good tradition.
With time,
man sometimes goes astray.
At such a time,
the blessings of his elders...
and his values save him.
Jaidev, wherever your mother
will be...
she must be blessing
you every moment.
This is a nice way to draw
someone's attention to yourself.
Keep teasing him,
but don't talk to him.
Stay away from him,
but be seen too.
What else will you do?
Hey bobpin. You are still
the same, like a bobpin.
Slim, trim, you'll never change.
Stretch, yet you get
back to the same shape.
Top! Even you have not changed.
You are always spinning.
You do your work, let me do mine.
Why do you have so much attitude?
What is your problem?
- Tell me.
- Go away!
Move aside.
So Bhajanlal, as I was saying...
Have you lost it going to Mumbai?
Why do you two always
keep fighting.
Atleast patch up before
leaving for the trip abroad.
- According to law, cease fire.
- Correct.
One who is a coward
may call for cease fire.
Move!
Know what your problem is?
You are not a girl,
you are quarrelsome.
I have decided
I am not taking her to Thailand.
Then don't take me,
and tell Guruji too.
You mean we are not
going to Singapore?
No, Thailand.
I've heard.
England, Poland, Holland...
But when are we leaving.
Assume the flight
is ready to take off.
I don't believe this!
Three other Minars
with your friend, Qutub Minar?
That makes them a foursome.
Looks like they are out
on some rights procession.
Why does Qutub Minar look
so worried.
I'll talk to him.
There's one problem.
They haven't got their baggage.
- Even my baggage has not arrived.
- Lucky girl.
Indulge in your favourite
hobby, shopping.
The ground staff said we will
get the baggage in 1-2 days.
1-2 days!
What will we do until then?
We have only what we are wearing.
We lost everything.
- What?
- Everything.
Two pairs of clothes, a bottle
of oil, and under garments.
- What?
- Underwear.
- Shall we go?
- Yeah.
- Has everyone got their room?
- Yes, they have.
- Wow! Lobsters!
- Hey, tiger prawns.
Eeks! We won't eat this dirty food.
- Don't worry, I'll...
- I cannot even see this. Let's go.
What happened?
Full on just seeing the food?
- No, actually...
- We won't eat this.
We cannot even touch it.
It is impure, and unholy.
Unholy?
We cannot eat what moves, crawls,
swims, flies.
Okay, there are fruits over there,
we'll eat fruits.
Fruits?
We are tired of eating fruits.
Please give us something to eat.
Some lentil and bread.
Okay, I'll arrange something.
- Some vegetable too...
- Yes, I understood.
Bhajanlal, call your friends.
Kusum, Madhavi, come.
- Yes madam?
- You get good clothes here.
Clothes? They are tatters.
You get clothes here,
buy them.
These clothes?
How can we wear such clothes?
Won't we get a saree here?
You won't get a saree, blouse,
dhoti, kurta here.
In Rome, do as Romans do.
Wear what the others are wearing.
- It's just a matter of 3-4 days.
- We don't wear such clothes.
You will have to wear the
clothes available here.
And anyway, who knows you here.
- But dhoti is the best garment.
- How is that?
I'll explain with an example.
Like you have a window at home
for light and air to enter...
likewise, you wear a dhoti for
entry of light and air in the body.
Vegetarian food is ready for you.
Come.
- But Bhajanlal, such clothes?
- That's their culture, nudity.
You must have eaten already.
- Who cares whether I have or not.
- I do.
Even I have not eaten.
What we'll do is...
I'll show them the table and come.
Come.
Jaidev, everyone's luggage arrived
How come ours didn't arrive?
- According to law...
- Stop your accordion.
Even Natasha's luggage has not
come. She is helping you.
Jai, everyone is making
fun of us here.
- Who?
- And you too.
Me? Fun...
Don't take us to be
weak and helpless.
You have got them, that is why
you are treating us like this.
- Me?
- I understand everything.
They laugh behind our back,
and he is supporting them.
Sister, let's go from here.
When you get food,
it should be respected.
I've never seen such a drama
for food till today.
- Forget it.
- What is her name? Madhavi.
Explain to her. Man has always been
eating what he found around him.
Will those living in the dessert
eat vegetables everyday?
Why do we Bengalis
eat fish and rice?
Because it is available in Bengal.
Some people have the habit
to make an issue of everything.
Do one thing.
Please explain this to them.
You will have to explain to them.
They will have to wear
whatever clothes I buy them.
"The heart slowly grew young"
"New desires awoke slowly"
"Slowly, every no, became a yes!"
"The heart slowly grew young"
"New desires awoke slowly"
"Slowly, every no, became a yes!"
"The heart slowly grew young"
"New desires awoke slowly"
"Slowly, every no, became a yes!"
"New paths, new destinations"
"New sights, new people"
"Everything is new"
"And look, the heart also
beats in a new way"
"New paths, new destinations"
"New sights, new people"
"Everything is new"
"And look, the heart also
beats in a new way"
"Slowly, the world changed"
"Slowly, every moment changed"
"Slowly, every no, became a yes!"
"The heart slowly grew young"
"New desires awoke slowly"
"Slowly, every no, became a yes!"
"It's a colourful party"
"And with me is my crazy beau"
"And in this unknown journey"
"The heart is lonely"
"It's a colourful party"
"And with me is my crazy beau"
"And in this unknown journey"
"The heart is lonely"
"Slowly, I began to lose my heart"
"Slowly, someone began to sing"
"Slowly, every no, became a yes!"
"The heart slowly grew young"
"New desires awoke slowly"
"Slowly, every no, became a yes!"
Jai, don't you think
Bhajanlal intends to do modeling?
Kusum, it is not a sin
to enjoy life.
- When did Guruji say that?
- Not Guruji, Jaidev.
So your new Guru is Jaidev.
- Liar!
- What happened?
Why did you lie that
you don't get a saree here?
What do I know?
Even I am new here.
That Indian woman said there is
a shop close by.
Atleast we wouldn't have
had to wear such clothes.
Why are you fighting with him?
How is he at fault?
How many clothes can we buy?
And then, are your hands made
of camphor that they'll melt...
the moment they are exposed?
Now relax! Come on!
How much you have changed.
You are smoking, drinking...
gambling, roaming with those girls.
Whatever I do, what
difference does it make to you.
You are spoiling Jaidev,
and you expect me to keep quiet?
If I spoil,
won't it make a difference to you?
If I smoke and drink,
how will you feel?
- Won't you stop me?
- Have you come to reform me?
- I am leaving.
- What if Guruji comes to know?
Threatening me? That you'll
tell Guruji? Take, tell him. Take.
Betting today on cricket?
Ofcourse. Only two matches are
left of India and Pakistan.
I won Rs.100000 yesterday
and Qutub Minar lost Rs.50000.
Have to make him win today.
Hey guys, hear the visuals.
John Abraham, babes.
John and Natasha, dancing.
John and Ria, sensuous.
Last two seconds,
Vaga Fashions, irresistible!
The rest is just oomph... oomph...
We are almost set, ready to roll.
Where is John Abraham?
There's a problem.
Production said John has
not come out of the airport.
- Damn! You didn't talk to him?
- I did in the evening.
He was even going to
leave for the airport.
But I don't know. Have a phone?
I'll call up his manager.
Hello Bhasker, Natasha here.
Where is John.
What!! Bhasker,
you've got to do something.
- What happened?
- John's suffered food poisoning.
He's in hospital. It will
take him 3-4 days to recover.
We have spent so much money on this
trip. What do we do, Thakkar?
It will take atleast 2-3 days for
any model to come from India.
Raga, have you seen any
Indian looking model here?
We have a diamond in hand,
and we are searching the bazaar.
Will you model, Qutub Minar?
Jai? That's a brilliant idea.
You're good, you must try.
Yeah, he's very good.
- Me... no... Me, modeling? No.
- Come on.
- Give it a shot.
Finished laughing? Now get serious.
Will you do it?
GG... l... l... cannot do modeling.
I mean...
For business, I can do anything.
Then what's in modeling?
Yeah, but... seriously GG,
not me...
- Come on!
- Alright, pack up.
Book tickets to go back.
Sorry, we suffered a loss
before starting business.
Anyways, the loss is only mine.
"The heart slowly grew young"
"New desires awoke slowly"
"Slowly, every no, became a yes!"
"Slowly, the heart sways"
"It cannot control itself"
"It counts stars at night,
and makes dream mansions"
"Days are new, nights are new"
"New incidents,
new things happening"
"All relationships are new"
"All meetings are new"
"Slowly, the world changed"
"Slowly, every moment changed"
"Slowly, every no, became a yes!"
"Someone put sense into this heart"
"Bring it under control"
"It has won the heart's game"
"So it plays stakes everyday"
"Someone put sense into this heart"
"Bring it under control"
"It has won the heart's game"
"So it plays stakes everyday"
"Slowly, new eras began"
"Slowly, even ways emerged"
"Slowly, every no, became a yes!"
"The heart slowly grew young"
"New desires awoke slowly"
"Slowly, every no, became a yes!"
How should I explain about acting?
Acting is like betting.
Jai, who do you think will win?
Don't know, can't say.
Take a guess.
I think India will win.
Raga, what do you think?
I'll tell you at the right time.
This is the right time.
Irfanbhai, what's the rate?
One million.
GG, don't play today,
you lost only yesterday.
What's the fun in life
without winning and losing?
Oh God!
- What do you think now?
- Now I think India will win.
Okay, I'll stake yours on India.
GG, I won't gamble any more.
Damn! You disgrace
my prestige every time.
You say no to everything.
- Chill!
- Cool it, GG,
Okay GG, even I'll gamble.
- How much do I stake?
- Ten... thousand?
Ten thousand?
Are you gambling or joking?
- GG again. Another one million.
- GG, not so much.
Come on, you are the owner of
Vardhan Industries.
Play that much stakes atleast.
I have not even seen
a million rupees.
I'll take guarantee.
We'll recover from profits.
Come on, Jai.
- Okay, I'll play.
- That's the spirit!
One million. Jai Vardhan.
He's my partner. I take guarantee.
Yes... yes Irfanbhai.
It's so peaceful here, isn't it?
Sometimes, even in solitude,
you find peace.
You are so far away from worldly
troubles, yet you are worried?
I look worried to you?
You are either thinking about
someone, or are worried.
And if you are not worried,
you are thinking of someone.
I am neither worried now,
nor ever will be.
Those who do wrong worry.
It's something to ponder over.
Let's sleep with
that thought tonight.
Golden gate City.
The estimated cost of this
project is two lakh million.
Their own home in India for NRI's.
The whole area only for NRI's.
2/3 bedroom beautiful bungalows.
A totally planned,
fully self sufficient...
technologically advanced city,
with five-star facilities.
And the cost of each bungalow
from five million to 25 million.
All details are in the brochure.
Mr. GG, on what
stage is your project?
The first phase of construction
has begun...
with the amusement park,
club, and golf course.
At a distance of
three hours from Mumbai...
we are giving you a dream city
with all comforts and facilities.
Because the name of
this place is Songarh...
we have named this city,
Golden Gate City.
Now if there are no more questions,
that's it. Thank you, gentlemen.
What are you saying?
You are Guruji's son?
Yes.
The Guruji of
Rishi-Van is your father?
- And Vardhan Industries?
- I'll explain.
My father's name is
Srinath Vardhan.
He started Vardhan Industries.
Then, a few years ago,
he went to Rishi-Van Ashram...
and Homi Wadia, who is his partner,
he handles his business.
I wanted to make you my partner
even in this project.
So how could I have asked?
I would not ruin you along with me.
But God is strange.
Look at the coincidence,
he brought us together.
Now this entire project
is in your hands.
If you wish, you can save
this project and me.
Tell Guruji to cancel the stay
and become my partner.
We both will benefit from this.
Only benefit.
Say something.
It's not the question
of benefit, GG,
If I can help you, I will love it.
- But I have a condition.
- What?
While leaving the Ashram,
I had made a promise to Baba...
that I will plant millions
of trees there.
I will surely help you.
Every tree I cut,
I will plant two in it's place.
That's my promise.
Thanks.
- What are friends for?
Surprising! I never thought
I will see such a miracle in life.
One plant will give us 100 plants?
Was everything okay in
the foreign land?
Yes.
Then where is the effervescence now
that existed while leaving?
Purohitji, I have a dilemma.
Tell me,
is it a sin to enjoy life?
Enjoy? What enjoyment?
If your enjoyment is hurting
someone else...
then where is the joy in it?
- Now what is the dilemma?
- No, now there is no dilemma.
Did you hear,
the dilemma has been solved.
Bhajan, even I have a dilemma.
Who has Jaidev brought
to meet Guruji?
That's not a dilemma,
he's big trouble.
He is Jaidev's new partner.
And we came to know abroad
that he is that Patil's builder...
against whom Guruji
has taken a stay order.
Okay.
I have heard you out.
But the matter has become serious.
Even I want this region to progress
and people to get employment.
That there is
progress and development.
But the thousands of tribals
who have left from here...
it's a question of the lives
of those tribals...
is connected with this project.
What is their future?
Baba, GG wants to open
an IT centre here.
He has promised that all the
tribals who have left...
will be brought back,
and even employment given to them.
You only have to
cancel the stay order.
Son, I understand his problem.
But...
Guruji, I am telling you
all this because you understand.
I want to make such a city here,
which we don't have in this country
Where there is not a single hut,
no beggar.
Where there is no filth anywhere,
no spitting.
Is there any such city
in this country?
How much I tried to tell you this.
It is my good fortune
that I met Jai.
You just let me do my work,
and I will do everything you say.
I have understood your plans.
Just give me time to think.
Let's see what we do then.
Son, drop your friend.
Yes Baba... come GG,
Sage, my testing time has arrived.
The monster has come as a saint and
my son is unable to recognise him.
He is supporting injustice.
O God, give me strength.
Give me strength.
"Fickle... fickle... fickle"
"Take it or leave it, this heart"
"Why lose your heart to someone?"
"Why win someone's heart?"
"Why unite your
heart with someone?"
"Why break someone's heart?"
"Don't fall in love"
"I'm sorry, O fickle heart"
"Why lose your heart to someone?"
"Why win someone's heart?"
"Why unite your
heart with someone?"
"Why break someone's heart?"
"Don't fall in love"
"I'm sorry, O fickle heart"
"Take it or leave it, this heart"
"Beating heart, excited heart,
tormented heart, yearning heart"
"Why unite your
heart with someone?"
"Why break someone's heart?"
"Don't fall in love"
"I'm sorry, O fickle heart"
"Take it or leave it, this heart"
"Beating heart, excited heart,
tormented heart, yearning heart"
"Pumping heart, convinced heart,
slipping heart, careful heart"
"Take it or leave it, this heart"
"Beating heart, excited heart,
tormented heart, yearning heart"
"Pumping heart, convinced heart,
slipping heart, careful heart"
"Why is the heart..."
"Why is the heart such an impostor?"
"I'm sorry, O fickle heart"
"The heart must be having a heart"
"Which heart thought of the heart?"
"This heart, within,
has suppressed sorrow"
"Take it or leave it, this heart"
"The heart must be having a heart"
"Which heart thought of the heart?"
"This heart, within,
has suppressed sorrow"
"No one torments so much"
"As much as the fickle heart"n
"O fickle heart"
"O fickle heart"t
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
- Tell me, how do I look?
- Lovely.
- Only lovely?
- Very lovely.
- Only very lovely?
- Okay, very very lovely!
- What did your Baba say?
- He hasn't given a reply yet.
That means it will take time.
It took two kings to make
Qutub Mlnar.
It won't take that long, will it?
Cheers!
Homi, one who is greedy is tricked.
Before getting into
a partnership with GG...
didn't you find out
about him first?
Our old dealer, Premji,
he introduced Jaidev to GG,
He is GG's investor.
And he was offering a good deal.
Deal.t
In the greed for a deal,
you got trapped into the net...
of the conspirator.
Homi, this deal, partnership,
and friendship is all an act of GG,
He did all this to reach me.
And this was his game to
get the stay order canceled.
But he has invested millions
in GG Fashions.
And his billions are stuck here.
We must do something
about this GG,
- What will you do about Jaidev?
- I don't know what to do about him.
But I have faith Homi, whatever
my son does, he will do right.
So this is your Rishi-Van Ashram.
I never thought there will be
such a beautiful place...
so close to Mumbai city. But
why are you not taking me there?
You? Like this?y
Has anyone told you
that you are mad?
Yes, mad.
GG always calls me mad.
But he himself is mad, about me.
- Like this?
- It's nice.e
It's GG's birthday gift.
Now tell me, who is mad?
You.
That I am.
But can you tell me about who?
Know what a girl's
biggest problem is?
What?
To know who will be mad
for her for life.
Who will never cheat her.
And that is very difficult to know.
But I know that you
will never cheat anyone.
You will always help everyone.
Jai, GG is in trouble. He owes
lots of money in the market.
He is very sad.
I know. I will
try my best to help him.
- Really? You will help GG?
- GG means more to me than a friend.
He has shown me the world.
I will surely help him.
Jai, you are so nice.
If he treats me more than a friend,
why doesn't his father...
cancel the stay order?
You must not have tried hard, or...
What do I try?
What do you want me to do?
I have taken 1000 million
from the market.
If this job doesn't get done,
you'll lose everything...
the necklace,
the lipstick, the earring.
We will be on the streets.
If you have dreams, hopes,
then even I have them.
I am waiting to marry you
since two years.
Every girl dreams to get married
and settle down. That she has kids.
How long will I wait? How long?
Hear the last time! I've
begun to hate the word marriage.
If you cannot do this job for me,
don't. Keep crying.
I'll assume
I am alone in this fight.
Excellent.
The saplings have grown big.
You have done a good job.
Jaidev, plants are ready to be
planted in green house six.
Very good.t
My life has found a goal,
a direction...
- Where is Baba?
- In the factory.
Kusum, don't you think this job
gives immense mental satisfaction.
Yes... yes.
Hey bobpin!
Listen! Where are you going?
You have become the same again
on coming back.
The same clothes,
the same fear.
Wait! Why do you
always run so much?
What happened?
Jaidev, you must
tell Guruji everything.
What?t
- About whatever happened.
- But what happened?
- All that happened in Thailand.
- Meaning?
Guruji is very worried.
I fear even to pass close to him.
Then fear, and live like that only.
And anyway, what sin have I
committed for which...
I should fear to go before Baba?
I only smoked and drank.
And what Baba is doing with GG,
is that right?
Do you know,
his whole life can be ruined.
- I will speak to Baba today.
- No Jai.
Jaidev, you won't tell
all this to Guruji.
Madhavi, why are
you always so afraid?
Guruji has not taught
us to live like that.
Since I have met GG,
I feel everyone here...
has locked himself in a cage.
Come here.y
Look at me. Don't you feel
I have caged myself?
Even you have become
just like that.
You always keep yourself caged.r
And when you leave the Ashram,
you take the cage along.
I don't understand why
you are always so scared.
You will understand.
I hope you will understand one day.
It is so easy
for you to say all this.
You say anything, do anything.
You are not an orphan.
And don't even know
what it is to be an orphan.
Enough Bhajanlal,
don't put more juice in this.
These medicines are unique.
Add one ingredient,
and their character changes.
If added in a little more measure,
the same medicine becomes poison.
But it's different with humans.
They can take care of themselves.
- Son, how is your work going?
- Very well.
Baba, I wanted to talk to you
about GG,
Bhajanlal, keep it on slow flame,
it will take time to get ready.
Tell me.y
Did you give a
thought to GG's land?
Do you know why I
have stalled his work?
No, but I do know his
project will develop this region.
Our region will change.
Yes, like Mahableshwar
(hill station) has changed.
Where it rains less than half
it used to before.
Like Shimla has changed,
where it has stopped snowing.
Look son,
I am not against progress.
If he wants to make a city, he
has the whole Shahyadri mountains.
Let him go and make his city.
Why is he insisting on
making it here?
Because without doing anything, he
is getting water and a green area.
For his selfish motive,
he wants to ruin my world.
Baba, you misunderstand GG,
He is not like that.
Nothing will happen to Rishi- Van.
He has promised me.
Promise? You trust a
builder's promise so much?
He is bent on destroying my world
and you are defending him?
I am not defending him.T
Baba, listen to me. He is my
friend, he has invested money.
He will be ruined.
The tribals have been
ruined because of him.
He grabbed their land and threw
them in dirty huts of Mumbai.
Go to Tilak Nagar and see.
They are the same people
who grew up with you.
The decision the tribals took, they
themselves are responsible for it.
The tribals are responsible?
You and me standing alive
here...
the tribals are responsible
even for that.
You don't know anything.
You were four years old...
when after a holiday...
we were returning from
Mahableshwar to Mumbai.
We were very happy.
You were your mother's pet.
We didn't know there has
been a landslide ahead.
The driver could not control the
car, and it fell into the valley.
The driver had died on the spot.
When I opened my eyes,
a sage, who looked like God...
stood before me.
He tried his best
to save your mother.
But she did not survive.n
Our world changed in minutes.
I lost everything.
The cremation fire destroyed
everything in minutes.
All my wealth was of no use.s
You are my real wealth,
and I have to live for you.
That sage worked hard
and gave you a new life.
Living in the Ashram,
I saw a new life.
There had been a drought,
and the sage was serving everyone.
People were craving for
every drop of water.
The heat of the sun had
fissured the earth.
Men and animals were dying.
I felt God sent me here
to see all this.
The people who had saved me,
I could not leave them to die.
I had to eliminate
hunger and drought.
Then I reached the decision
that to fight drought and hunger...
I started planting trees.
Where it didn't rain for years,
it started raining every year.
And then, there was
never a drought here.
And now, you want to change
our victory to defeat?
You want to call Rishi-Van
GG City?
What are you doing?
Do you know, a small spark
can destroy the whole Ashram?
Why has God given you brains?
Guruji save us. I made a
mistake in leaving the city.
I lost my wife.
Now it is very difficult
to leave them and find work.
I don't know what to do.r
Keep these two in your Ashram.
I had told you many times that
you need money to live in a city.
How long will you survive on the
money you got...
from the sale of land?v
You have left this
heavenly place...
and are living in dirty huts
of Mumbai is that life?
What is the point in crying now?
You lost everything.
Bhajanlal, take the kids.
You mean to say the tribals
lived in palaces in Songarh?
They live in huts now
because of me?
- I am not saying that.
- Forget it.
It is so many days, and instead
of talking about my case...
you are talking about tribals.c
What are they?
Just a burden on our country.
They only know to sire kids.
We earn money, we pay taxes,
and they...
Look, if you don't
want to do my work...
I'm trying my best, GG,
And... I won't do modeling
in this fashion show.
If you don't mind,
shall I speak to your father?
But, what will you
speak with Baba?
Leave that to me.
Are you with me?
Guys, this is not working.
Come on, it's a fashion show.
What're you looking at?a
I want you to do it with elegance,
finesse. Do it again please.
Try it together.
Roll the music.
- Who is Jaidev Vardhan?
- Me. Yes?
When are you giving money?
- What happened?
- We are Irfanbhai's men.
- We have come to take money.
- Money...
Wait. You have to pay one million.
Irfanbhai... your men... you
got my money, you'll get his too.
I have taken guarantee..
Yes, 45 million is big money,
but you will get it.
- Yes... you'll talk to him?
- Yes.
I've spoken to him.
You go, you'll get the money.
GG, 45 million?
One million dollars
is 45 million rupees.
But we didn't play in dollars.
Tell him whether we played
in dollars or not.
We will have to pay him.
You pay, or I, it's the same thing.
But right now,
all my money is stuck in GG City.
You'll have to do something.
Okay, that's it.
Now turn around, hold it.
Very good.
What are you doing? Get down.
When did you play in dollars?
What dollars, I'll play every game.
GG, you are doing wrong to Jaidev.
And he is doing right with me?
- You all are alike.
- What are you doing!
- What is wrong with you?
- Go away from here.
Before I say something, go.
Are you mad? Get down!
What are you doing!
And what are you doing with me?
Shut-up!
I am trapped,
and you are supporting him.
You all are alike.
You find one rich man,
and you go with him.
- Go! I don't need you.
- First get down.
If I get down,
everyone will go down.
You, that Guru, your
industrialist friend, all of them.
Go inside and cry,
don't do your act here. Go!
How do I convince you that I
won't let you build a city here?
You understand,
I will make huge profits.
And even you can.
If I only wanted to make money, why
would I start an orphanage here?
I would start an expensive
boarding school here...
and educate children of rich men.
In Mumbai, there are many cigarette
sellers and barbers...
who earn more money than
renowned doctors.
It's not the question of money.
It is how you earn money,
and how society benefits from it.
You have very good ideals, which
are nice to hear over here...
away from the real world.
But perhaps you are not
away that I am a builder...
and know how to get my work done.
I know... I know very well.
That is why you builders
get the maximum number...
of threatening call for extortion
from goons.
Have you given a thought why?
How much is a builder worth?
People are ready to kill
someone for Rs.10000.
And if I had let those orphans
in the street...
even Rs.10000 is too much.
One builder's life would
be worth Rs.500.
What do I tell you? My millions
are invested. I will make the city.
Your son is ready to join me.
You have lived your life.
Just bless that my job is done
when you are alive.
My son will never support you.
Your son has supported me
at every step. Want to see?
He is a gambler. He has to
pay 45 million in the market.
Look... look... look!
Hey look!
Jaidev is smoking.
Dwellers of the Ashram,
when you get this letter...
I will have left the Ashram.
I regret that the Ashram which we
all build together...
that Ashram is in trouble today.
Jaidev is supporting those
who want to destroy the Ashram.
If this is the
state when I am alive...
what will become of this Ashram
after I die?
I cannot live a suffocating
life with this dilemma.
If this Ashram
has to get destroyed...
it is better this is done
before I die...
so that I die in peace.
I request you not to tell
my son about this letter.
Nor try to find me.i
If I have ever unknowingly made
any mistake, forgive me.
Your well wisher... Good wishes.
What are you thinking, Mr. Patil?.
Wish some of my MLA's were like
that, I would stay in the Assembly.
Why would I come here?
Come Qutub Minar.a
Mr. Patil, he's Jai Vardhan.
Minister Amrit Patil.
- How is Guruji?
- He's fine.
- Spoke to Baba, GG?
- Yes, but he did not relent.
Now everything is on you.
- Where are you going?
- Coming.
This design is great.
- Shall I make one for you?
- What's the rate?
- Rs.35000.
- Rs.35000!g
Only for you.
Is this a rate, or a rage?
Excuse me.
John... John Abraham, right?
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
- Are you the medical rep?
- No, Jai, Jai Vardhan.
You had suffered
from food poisoning.
Food poisoning?
Perhaps you are mistaken.
You were going to model
for Vaga Fashions.
Vaga? What is that?o
Do you know GG, Gaurav Gupta?
GG, Natasha's boyfriend?
Looks like he made a fool of you.
Sorry, if you don't mind,
can I ask you for something?
- What?
- Just your five minutes.
- Okay.
- Thanks. Follow me.
What is your motive behind
Vaga Collections?
Vaga Collection has
only one aim.
To fulfil the desire
of fashion conscious people.
Vardhan is our partner...
and they have made special
fabric for Vaga Collections.
But what is so unique
about Vaga Collections?
That answer will be given by
our designer, Ashwin Raga.
- Thank you.
- All the best.
Vara Collections has the latest
international design range.
It is a new style statement
for the new generation.
What more do you want?
Let's make today's evening
entertaining.
Please join us
for cocktails and dinner.
Where were you?
- GG, John was telling me...
- What will John tell you? I will.
I wanted to make my
friend a model...
I took your excuse
and made him one.
- He was saying that you...
- I am saying it even now.
If he agrees, I can make
him a super model like you.
- I don't model anymore.
- Then?
Don't you read
the paper these days?
Anyway, all the best.
You all are liars. All of you.
Only scare him, don't touch him.
Jai, just wait.
Don't say anything.
What had you said?
That the most difficult thing for
a girl to decide...
is who will not cheat her.
The man who is cheating the whole
world, will he not cheat you?
You are right, Jai.
He has cheated me too.
Influenced by his talks...
I was playing with your feelings.
Forgive me.
If you have understood this,
I'll only say...
take care.
Yes sir.
He has come to Tilak Nagar.
In the tribal colony.
He must have come to meet someone.
Why is he not getting off the car?
He got off.s
Hey listen. Only threaten him,
don't beat him. Okay?
- Yes.
- Go!
When will you give
Irfanbhai's money?
Turn back..
- Tell us!
- Don't touch me.
Don't stare.
When will you give the money?
Don't stare at us.n
I told you, don't touch me.
- Ramnath, Shambhu! Come quickly
- What have you done!
They are beating up Guruji's son!
Come quickly!
Let's run!s
They beat up Guruji's son.
They are mad! Catch them!
You dogs!
Okay, I have understood.
Don't tell anyone anything.
I won't.m
What happened?
Madhavi, what happened?n
Ashram dwellers...
Madhavi, this is
not the time to cry.
Go with Chandu,
I'll manage things here.
Go Madhavi.b
Are you mad? You will leave me?
Yes, I was mad,
to be with you for two years.
Leave my hand. Leave!
This is the first and last time
you are using force on me.
- Enough now!
- Enough for me too.
Good.v
If you step out of here,
don't ever come back.
Alright. I'm taking only my things.
I've left everything you gave me.
In a few days anyway,
it's all going to go.
You will never be
able to win with Jai...
because you are not
honest with anybody.
Not even yourself.
Will you live in the Ashram,
or in Vardhan's bungalow?
He will fulfil your dreams now?
Forget my dreams, GG,
Think of your dream GG City.
A man who could not make one home,
he will make a city?
Have you come to fight again?
"Since I treat you as my life"
"Life seems to be like life now"
"Life seems to be like life now".
"Since I have come into your arms"
"I feel I have
found my destination"
"There are many desires in the
heart, but also the dilemma..."
"that this love is killing"a
"There are many desires in the
heart, but also the dilemma..."
"that this love is killing"
"We have come at that turning
point in life"
"Where I cannot live without
your love"
"What do I call
this love of yours?"
"What do I do with
my love for you?"
"Until yesterday, our life
was a beautiful dream"
"I saw real life only today"
"Until yesterday, our life
was a beautiful dream"
"I saw real life only today"
"How it fights with
darkness for light"
"At every moment,
every life is fighting"
"Now I realise what is true,
what is false"
"I will live life my own way now"
Look, heed me. Come back to
Rishi-Van. Is this life?
What is over here? You will
not get anything in this hell.
Don't believe ministers talks.
They are not going
to give you homes.
- How will we get back our land?
- I will get it back for you.
But I want a promise
from you all too.
When I call you, you all
will come together with me.
If you are with me,
raise your hand and say yes.
Yes!
I'm sorry, uncle.
I made a grave mistake.
How many times
will you apologise?
Now go to the Ashram,
you are needed there.
I'll go, uncle. But I have
to meet Irfanbhai first.
I have spoken to the Commissioner.
It will be done.
- Excuse me. Irfanbhai.
- DCP Deshmukh has sent us.
- Go.
- Thank you. You wait here.
I'll call you later.
- What is it?
- I'm Jaidev Vardhan.
Yes, DCP Deshmukh had called.
What do you want?
How much betting had GG
done with you in my name?
- GG? Who GG?
- Gaurav Gupta.
That builder?
What happened to him?
He did betting with you, right?
He used to play before,
he hasn't since many days.
But I don't understand.
What is the matter?
Tell me something, Irfanbhai.
Did GG bet with you on my behalf?
I told you, when he himself did not
play, how will he bet in your name?
Can't believe this!n
GG, Jai here. How much money
do I have to give Irfanbhai?
Where are you, Jai?
Are you alright?
Irfanbhai's men made
a small mistake.
A big mistake. And the mistake
was not of Irfanbhai's men.
It was your men.
- Jai, Irfanbhai is mad.
- Is it?
Take, talk to Irfanbhai.
- What's going on?
- Irfanbhai, how are you?
I was just teasing my friend.
Tease, but in your own name.
I do business here.
DCP Deshmukh called here.
And who are you playing
this game with?
Why are you getting angry? Give
the phone to Jai, I'll explain.
Hello Jai.e
Thank you.e
Why trouble the DCP or police? If
ever you need me, here's my number.
Call me directly.g
I won't need your number.
This area is very good.
How far is the Ashram from here?
- About 40 kms. Want to go?
- Some other time.
What do we do about Guruji? He is
asking for a 50 year lease again.
Please don't extend
the lease of the Ashram.
Because of that Ashram...
the development of this
entire region is stalled.
Until that Ashram exists,
Guruji won't allow development.
Give him some place
outside Songarh.
Give the land to GG
for development.
That's okay, but how will
we remove the Ashram?
What is there to remove?
Just 8-10 sheds, and some huts.
Against this Ashram,
GG will make a new Ashram for them.
With all facilities.
I'll make a modern Ashram.
I take the guarantee.
If he's ready to make a new Ashram,
what problem does Guruji have?
That is what I am saying, sir.
CM, it is in our interest.
- Okay, I'll look into it.
- Thank you.
I know you are
somewhere here, Baba.
I know you can hear me, Baba.
I made a grave mistake, Baba.
Forgive me.
I have become alone, Baba. I have
realized what it is to be an orphan
Baba, forgive me.
Forgive me.
GG ruined my life.
I will not spare him!
Premji, our relationship
dates 20 years.
Then why did you introduce
my son to such a man?
I myself didn't know
he would turn out like this.
And I introduced them
in the interest of both.
What can be done now?t
- I'll think, Guruji.
- Think.
Calm down.
This notice says...
the government is not extending
the lease of the Ashram.
- But sir...
- Let me finish.
I spoke to their lawyer,
Mr. Khote.
They are talking of giving us
a new Ashram outside Songarh.
You have to decide what
we have to do next.
No sir, if we listen to them,
even we will face the same fate...
the tribals did.
Just think, where will we
take all these people and go?
Tell them we will
not leave the Ashram.
We will not leave
this land and go anywhere.
And this year...
we will surely celebrate
our Ashram's golden jubilee.
Over here.r
One seed is broken
and put in a different medium...
and in a few days,
from one, many plants are grown.
After keeping them
separate for some time...
in about 4-5 months, they are
ready to be planted in the ground.
And this year, the Ashram children
will plant 500000 plants.
And the man doing this massive
task is Jaidev Vardhan.
Why are you doing this?
As per my father's desire, and
with the Collector's permission...
I want to make the whole
of Songarh green.
Then what is your hurdle
in this task?
Just one, builder Gaurav Gupta.
He wants to grab land
and make a city here.
And the minister and MLA
here Mr. Amrit Patil...
is supporting him.
A big scam has surfaced,
the Rishi-Van scam.
Where on one hand, the government
is busy demolishing huts...
Minister Patil has created
a new colony, Tilak Nagar.
A huge scene was created in
the Assembly over the matter.
Mr. Patil, you say there
is no scam in the Rishi-Van case.
Look, this is a propaganda
of these people only.
You'll even say there
was no deluge in Mumbai.
The truth is you want a deluge,
so that you can take money...
from the central government
and fill your coffers.
People like you pray
deluge, drought, earthquakes.
Look, you are the son of
the very respected Guruji.
So think, understand,
weigh your words...
and then speak.
Every year, before rains, you
proclaim there will be a drought.
Then beg for 4000-5000 million
from the central government.
That's what you have been doing
every year for the last 10 years.
What can anyone do
against natural calamities?
If you won't, who else will?
The speed with which trees are
being cut because of you...
we will either have deluges,
or droughts every year.
You have sent all the people
of your region to Mumbai.
But have you see in what
state they are living there?
Your Qutub Minar turned
out to be smart.
He learnt to manage the media
from you, and is teaching you.
Even hens are not taken
to slaughter houses...
the way people travel in
trains in Mumbai.
Now you think, weigh, and speak.
Part from begging from the
central government for your area...
what else have you done?p
Speak... give an answer, Mr. Patil.
Your time is coming to an end.
Down with the CM!
The police arrested people who were
protesting the demolition of huts.
The tribals living in Tilak Nagar
decided to go back to Songarh.
Our reporters say...c
like they had found life again.
The return of these tribals has
been possible due to Jaidev Vardhan.
Now what decision
the CM takes on this issue...
the future of the tribals
depends on it.
In Songarh,
the return of the tribals...
has put the government in a fix.
A tense atmosphere has been
created regarding tribal land.
It is the first time that people
living in huts in any city...
have returned to their village.
The Chief Minister spoke to the
media on this explosive issue.
One by one.
What are you going to do with the
tribals returning to Songarh?
I cannot say anything now.
The land on which millions of
saplings have been planted...
you are selling it to GG builders
under pressure from Mr. Patil?
You all know I never work
under pressure.
Due to fear of the
government falling...
won't you extend the lease
of Rishi-Van Ashram?
You will let the Ashram and
the 500000 plants be destroyed...
and not extend the 50 year
lease of the Ashram?
Look, I am going for the golden
jubilee celebrations of the Ashram.
I will myself go and check...
that if really 500000 saplings
have been planted...
I will decide right
there what I should do.
Reporters tried to talk to GG, the
builder connected to Rishi-van.
But annoyed with their questions,
he misbehaved with them.
He left without replying.s
A man who can behave like this
with the media...
how he must have behaved with the
poor tribals can be guessed.
The GG City that I, CM and Patil
could not complete...
you will complete it.
- Who is behind the 500 million?
- What will you know that and do?
And how much do you know the CM?
Heed me, in politics,
nobody can be trusted.
And the CM who says he will
decide at the place itself...
has decide something already.
How did you see a golden brick
in this broken home?
Are you talking business,
or politics?
If you have understood,
what do you say about my offer?
Take 500 million and the land and
machinery standing there is mine!
Or you will be ruined.
Keep the 500 million
offer with you, Mr. Prem.
Forget land and machinery,
for 500 million...
I won't even sell
you GG City's soil.
If the CM is going to Rishi-Van,
even I will.
We were standing here
when you asked me to wait a year.
A year is almost over,
what do you say now?
The situation was different then,
it is different now.
That means, you change stance
according to situation.
GG, even I suffered a loss.
Only if there are profits.
All the loss is mine.
Let me remind you,
all the money invested is mine.
I'll be ruined, Patil.
I'll be ruined!
GG, Patil is still alive.
We'll do something.
People have reached here
in thousands.
The function is about to begin.
The CM is coming, but
industrialist Homi Wadia right now...
is welcoming high court
Justice, the honorable Mr. Ahmed.
"O cloud of the sky,
you bring water from the sea"
"And fall on earth"
"O cloud of the sky,
you bring water from the sea"
"And fall on earth"
"On the green earth..."
"On the green earth
flash colours of love"
"Happiness is dancing
with spring today"
"O cloud of the sky,
you bring water from the sea"
"And fall on earth"
"On the green earth..."
"On the green earth
flash colours of love"
"Happiness is dancing
with spring today"
"If there are jungles,
there will be life"
"And the cycle of
life will continue"
"If there are jungles,
there will be life"
"And the cycle of
life will continue"
"We get oxygen for breathing
from trees and plants"
"Their branches are paths of life"
"In time..."n
"Weather changes in the world
in time due to them"
"Happiness is dancing
with spring today"
"On the green earth
flash colours of love"
"Happiness is dancing
with spring today"
Go up and drink liquor!
Pick him!e
Let's leave, hurry!
Over there!
Catch them! Don't spare them!
My God! There is a fire!
The Ayurvedic factory of
the Ashram has caught fire.
There is chaos all around.
What is worth noting is that
the CM has yet to reach here.
Police, don't let anyone go
across the bridge.
Sit down everybody!
Calm down!
The fire is spreading.
We have to see...
whether the tanks put up to water
these plants, can save them today.
This fire was started to destroy
the saplings planted in the Ashram...
so that when the CM comes,
there are no plants.
The CM is going to decide
to extend the lease...
based on the planting of saplings.
The good news is that
the fire has been doused...
and even the CM has reached here.
- Are you involved in this fire?
- Should you always suspect me?
The whole incident has happened
before Justice Ahmed.
The main witness in the case has
been saved...
and he has given his statement.
Jaidev Vardhan is
taking him to the stage.
Sir, whatever happened today,
you have witnessed it yourself.
These people tried to burn the
500000 saplings...
along with the Ashram. And threw
this man in the burning fire.
I only request you,
please do something.
Everyone present here, listen.
Realizing the seriousness of
the act, I order...
that those involved in
this act, the Minister, Patil...
and Gaurav Gupta, the builder...
and their men who were caught
at the place of incident...
be immediately arrested.
And they be kept in police
custody until the case is heard.
I order the police to take
immediate action.
For the first time, I see a Justice
give verdict on the spot.
CM, do something.n
We had decided you won't
ask for anything for two years,
- You can save me.
- How?
What do you mean, how?
I cannot go against
the Justice order.
And anyway, you always talk
of pulling down the government.
CM...e
I'll announce elections
on this issue.
I had told you,
eat only how much you can digest.
- Look CM...
- Go!
I told you, in politics,
nobody is your friend.
Accept my offer
and settle this deal.
Sign these papers and you will
have 500 million...
in your account tomorrow.
Sell the land to us.
Maybe we have the GG tomorrow.
Or you will lose everything.
Everything!
I trusted you for so many years.
I invested in your company.
Trust me once. Maybe you are
released from this case too.
It was a conspiracy! In which, he
was made to drink...
so that he would
be blamed for the fire.
But he is fine now. I also fought.
Now the perpetrators will be
behind bars for six months...
under a non-bailable warrant.
If need be, I will myself fight
this case. Bhajalal, MA, LLb.
Won't you like to know
who is behind this?
Mr. Prem, GG always plays blind.
I know.
- What a move, Qutub Minar!
- I learnt it from you...
leaning tower of Giza.
You have won this game. Keep
the money too in your account...
until the next move.
I have stopped playing, GG,
Perhaps you won't understand.
But despite losing,
you won this move.
Because now the land will
go to those who have a right to it.
You have a right
to say anything today.
Yet I'll say this.
Neither was getting
you beaten my aim.
Nor was this sabotage at my behest.
You made friends
only for benefit, GG,
And such friendship
only gives losses.
If you extend your hand
only for friendship...
my hand is always available.
Okay, but only till the next move.
Thank you Premji. Come.i
Now the people here are waiting
for the CM's decision.
The future of thousands of kids
of the Ashram is in his hands.
I regret all the incidents
that happened in the Ashram.
And I hold the government
responsible for it...
and apologise to you for it.
The work the government
should have done...
Guruji has fulfilled
that responsibility.
I am proud that such a man,
such an Ashram...
is in my state.
So I extend the lease of the
Ashram, not for 50 years...
but 99 years.
"You are the strength of the heart,
everyone's hope"
"You are everyone's companion"
"You are man's every breath"
"You are the hope of every moment"
"Everyone is distant,
you are close"
"When there is sun,
you are shade"
"How do you recognise your
intangible form?"
"Everyone here looks
for his own zenith"
Forgive me, Baba.
I made a mistake, Baba.
"O God you are the true
zenith of everyone's path.
Son, I notice today that
you have understood everything.
Now I know you
can manage everything.
Baba, we got the
papers of the land.
I will fulfil your dream, Baba.
Son, everyone has dreams.g
But those who achieve their dreams
with others tears...
even their dreams turn to tears.
Only those people's
dreams come true...
who, along with their welfare,