while the white man play
loadin' up boats
with the bales of cotton
gettin' no rest
till the judgment day
get yourself
a brand-new gal
on saturday they're cozy
along your arm
those black rules
are hard down south
they always look discouraged
round the cheek and mouth
darkies all work
on the mississippi
while the white folks play
loadin' those boats
with the bales of cotton
gettin' no rest
till the judgment day
cotton blossom,
cotton blossom
love to see you
growin' free
when they pack you
on the levee
you're a heavy load to me
cotton blossom,
cotton blossom
love to see you
there's the show boat!
growin' free
on the levee,
you're too heavy
for this poor black child
[Woman]
Andy!
Gosh almighty, woman,
what's eating you?
Did you tell the band
to wear their new uniforms?
Of course i did.
What did we
get them for?
You'll have them
all ruined!
Gosh almighty.
Look at them there
waiting for us.
That's our public.
Hi, public!
And now, folks,
as soon as we tie up,
i'm going to bring
the entire troupe ashore,
and we'll give you
our monster parade!
[Band playing]
Don't frown, steve.
Smile for your public.
If i catch pete
talking to you again,
i'll break him in two.
Oh, don't do anything
foolish, steve.
What could
a man like pete
mean to me?
Smile, darling.
Ain't he handsome?
That's julia laverne,
his leading lady.
Do you suppose
he's in love with her?
I suppose so.
Get those pictures
out front fast.
[Man]
That's what
i'm doing.
Out of my way,
eightball.
Who wants to
get in your way?
Hey, you,
wait a minute.
What you want?
Where did you get
that gold brooch?
You mean this scrumptious
piece of jewelry?
Yeah. Where
did you get it?
It was give to me.
By who?
Ask me no questions,
and i'll tell you no lies.
Ha ha ha!
I know who
give it to you,
and she's going to
be sorry, too.
All right,
miss julia laverne.
If that's how you
feel about me...
ladies and gentlemen,
i want you to meet
some of the greatest artists
playing the river town.
Miss elly may shipley,
the toast of cairo, illinois.
Come on, elly.
[Cheering]
Now i want you to meet
mr. Frank schultz.
To show you
what we have
in the way of comic talent,
i want to call your attention
to rubber face smith,
the funniest man in the world.
Give them the smile,
rubber face.
[Laughter]
Ain't that good?
Tell them more,
and they won't have to
see the show.
Ha ha ha!
And now, folks, right over here.
Right over here.
I want you to meet the little
sweetheart of the south,
miss julia laverne,
our leading lady!
[Applause]
You all know and love her.
What more can i say?
And over here, we have another
famous ornament of the stage,
mr. Stephen baker,
the handsomest
leading man on the river.
[Applause]
Smile, darn you, smile!
[Loud applause]
So here we are, folks,
just one big, happy family.
Get out of here.
All right, boys, let her rip.
look what we got,
look what we got
how can we fail?
How can we fail?
you never seen
a show like this before
we'll try and make
your evening bright
and if you come around
tonight
tomorrow night
you'll come around for more
captain andy,
you know how to make
a show sound dandy.
Frank and elly,
let's show them
just a sample of the dance.
My land, he gives away
his show for nothing.
Just a sample
of the dance. Diddly-dum.
Looking out to sea.
[Laughter]
That was a fine
thing to do,
giving my present
to a colored cook.
Pete, if steve
knew you sent me
that brooch,
i declare he'd about
beat you to death.
You'd better be
nice to me,
or you'll
be sorry.
I said, stay away
from my wife.
I reckon i won't do
any more talking
about it!
[Crowd screaming]
Steve! Please!
Steve!
Aah!
Steve, get up there.
Get up there!
Let go of me.
We had you fooled,
didn't we? Ha ha!
That was just a sample,
just a sample.
The boys were showing you
a scene from one of our plays.
That's the way they are...
always skylarking,
always playing pranks.
Just one big, happy family.
[Laughter]
I'll be having lunch
at mrs. Benson's.
All right,
parthy.
Well, miss laverne.
That was nice
goings on this morning.
It wasn't
julie's fault.
And you protecting her!
One thing
i'm thankful for...
magnolia wasn't there.
I don't want my daughter
mixed up with you
or anybody like you.
Mrs. Hawks,
please don't say that.
Nola... nola's just like
a little sister to me.
Mr. Hawks, if i've
got to stop seeing her,
i just can't
stay on the show boat.
I just can't!
Now you done it.
Now you done it!
The best
leading lady
on the river.
Oh, captain andy,
if julie goes,
could i try
for the lead?
Why, elly... ha ha ha!
There ain't a funnier
gal on the river
than you are.
Oh, captain andy,
don't!
Don't stamp your foot down
on real acting ability!
Leave go
my husband's knee!
And you! You think more
of your show boat crew
than you do of your own
daughter's upbringing.
Where i come from,
no decent body
would touch
this show boat riffraff
with a 10-foot pole,
let alone
having their daughters
mixed up with them.
I'll have more
to say to you later.
Ha ha ha!
Just one big,
happy family.
[Man]
who cares if my boat
goes upstream
or if the gale bids me go
with the river's flow?
i drift along with my fancy
sometimes i thank
my lucky stars
my heart is free
what are you
looking at?
I bet he's
an aristocrat.
Look at the cracks
in his shoes.
... wonder, "where's
the mate for me?"
hello.
How do you do?
Do you live here?
Oh, no.
I'm just a wayfarer
along the river.
So am i. Which way
are you going?
Either way.
Where are you going?
Anywhere papa
gives shows.
Oh, are you
a player?
Like on the piano?
Yes, i play a little.
Was that you
i heard?
Yes, that was me.
What a pity.
What did you say, mister?
When i asked if you
were a player,
i meant,
are you an actress?
Oh! Oh, no.
But i'd give anything
if i could be.
Why?
Because you can
make believe so many
wonderful things
that never happen
in real life.
Oh, but wonderful things
do happen.
Why, this very day,
i was walking
upon the levee,
feeling blue,
and suddenly,
i looked up, and...
i must go now.
Oh, why?
You're talking to me,
and i don't know you.
Does that
really matter?
No. Not to me.
If you like to
make believe things,
make believe
we know each other.
Yes! We haven't
seen each other
for 75 years,
and you're
my long-lost nephew.
There's a scene like that
in the village drunkard.
Oh, no. 75 years
is too long.
Besides, you know,
i don't think
i'd like the idea of
being your nephew.
Let's suppose
we've just met.
Well, we really have.
Well... let's suppose
we've fallen in love
at first sight.
only make believe
i love you
that you love me
others find peace of mind
in pretending
wouldn't you? Wouldn't i?
Wouldn't we?
make believe
our lips are blending
or two or three
might as well
make believe i love you
for to tell the truth,
i do
the game
of just supposing
is the sweetest
game i know
our dreams
are more romantic
than the world
we see
and if the things
we dream about
don't happen
to be so
that's just
an unimportant
technicality
though the cold
and brutal fact is
you and i
have never met
we need not
mind conventions,
ps and qs
if we
put our thoughts
in practice
we can banish
all regret
imagining most
anything we choose
we could
make believe
i love you
we could make believe
that you love me
might as well make believe
i love you
for to tell the truth,
i do
[hoofbeats]
[Man]
Ravenal!
You will
excuse me, ma'am.
The judge would like
to see you.
What for?
Nothing serious,
but you'd better
come along
and have a talk
with him.
You'll
excuse me, ma'am.
I hope
to see you again.
[Dogs barking]
[Woman]
Joe!
Joe! Where you been,
slowpoke?
Why are you always
dragging them big feet
like they was
chunks of lead?
Take your time,
queenie.
Take my time?
I got to have that flour
to bake the bread.
It won't run away
from you, queenie.
And if it do,
there will always
be tomorrow.
Give me that flour.
Give me it!
Queenie.
You got anything else
for me to do?
'Cause why?
'Cause if you ain't,
i got some whittling
left over.
I'd like to
get it finished.
Joe, i believe you're
the laziest man
that ever
lived on this river.
On this river,
queenie, that's
saying a whole lot.
Yeah, that's saying
a whole lot.
There will be
some taters to peel later,
and when i yell
for you,
you come in
and make it quick!
Lazy, good-for-nothing...
ha ha ha!
[Woman]
Joe.
Hello, miss nola.
I didn't know
you was up there.
Did you see that young man
in the sheriff's buggy?
Yep, i seen him.
I seen lots like him
along the river.
Oh, but, joe, he was
such a gentlemen.
Have you seen miss julie?
I got to tell her.
I got to ask her
what she thinks.
Julie. Julie!
Ask miss julie
what she thinks.
Better ask the ol' river
what he thinks.
He knows all about
them boys.
He knows all about everything.
there's an old man
called the mississippi
that's the old man
that i'd like to be
what does he care
if the world's got troubles?
if the land ain't free?
old man river,
that old man river
he must know somethin'
but don't say nothin'
he just keeps rollin',
he keeps on rollin' along
he don't plant taters,
he don't plant cotton
and them that plants 'em
is soon forgotten
but old man river,
he just keeps rollin' along
you and me,
we sweat and strain
body all achin'
and wracked with pain
"tote that barge,"
"lift that bale"
you gets a little drunk,
and you lands in jail
i gets weary
and sick of tryin'
i'm tired of livin'
and scared of dyin'
but old man river,
he just keeps rollin' along
darkies all work
on the mississippi
while the white folks play
pulling those boats
from the dawn till sunset
gettin' no rest
till the judgment day
don't look up
and don't look down
you don't dast make
the white boss frown
bend your knee
and bow your head
and pull that rope
until you're dead
let me go 'way
from the mississippi
from the white man boss
show me that stream
called the river jordan
dat's the old stream
that i longs to cross
old man river,
that old river
he must know somethin'
but don't say nothin'
he just keeps rollin',
he keeps on rollin' along
old river forever
keeps rollin' on
he don't plant taters,
he don't plant cotton
and them that plants 'em
is soon forgotten
but old man river,
he just keeps rollin'
along, old river,
keeps hearing that song
you and me,
we sweat and strain
body all achin'
and wracked with pain
"tote that barge,"
"lift that bale"
you gets a little drunk,
and you lands in jail
i gets weary
and sick of tryin'
i'm tired of livin'
and scared of dyin'
but old man river,
he just keeps rollin' along
[julie]
Don't tell your mother
i met you here.
Why?
Never mind. Tell me
about this man.
Who is he?
Well, i don't know.
He was standing
on the wharf,
and i was standing
on the top deck,
and he looked
so different from
everybody else
and so beautiful.
Julie, he said
he liked me.
You think
he meant it?
I don't know
as i like you
falling in love
with some man
no one's heard of.
Suppose he turned out
to be a no-account
river fellow?
If he was
no-account,
i'd stop loving him.
Oh, no, you wouldn't.
Once a girl like you
starts to love a man,
she don't stop so easy.
Well, couldn't you
stop loving steve
if he treated you mean?
No, honey.
No matter what he did.
Why do you
love steve?
Oh, i don't know.
He's such a bad actor
on the stage,
and he thinks
he's so good.
Maybe that's
why i love him.
You see, nola,
love is such
a funny thing.
There's no sense
to it.
That's why you've
got to be careful
when it creeps up
on you.
It's like the thing
you always sing about
on our walks.
fish gotta swim,
birds gotta fly
i gotta love one man
till i die
can't help lovin'
that man of mine
that's it.
tell me he's lazy,
tell me he's slow
tell me i'm crazy,
maybe i know
can't help lovin'
that man of mine
how come you all
know that song?
Why? Do you
know it, queenie?
Sure, i does,
but i only heard
colored folks
sing it.
Sounds funny
for miss julie
to know it.
Julie sings it
all the time.
Can you sing
the whole thing?
Course i can.
What's so funny about that?
oh, listen, sister,
i love my mister man
and i can't
tell you why
there ain't no reason
why i should love that man
it must be somethin'
that the angels
done plan
fish gotta swim,
birds gotta fly
i gotta love
one man till i die
can't help lovin'
that man of mine
tell me he's lazy,
tell me he's slow
tell me i'm crazy,
maybe i know
can't help lovin'
that man of mine
when he goes away,
that's a rainy day
but when he comes back,
the day is fine
the sun will shine
he can come home
as late as can be
home without him
ain't no home to me
can't help lovin'
that man of mine
that's beautiful,
miss julie.
Why, that's
my favorite song.
[Queenie]
my man is shiftless
and good-for-nothin',
too
he's my man
just the same
he's never near me
when there's work to do
he's never round you
when there's workin' to do
the chimney's smokin',
the roof is leakin' in
but he don't
seem to care
he can be happy
with just a sip of gin
why are you all
talking about gin?
i even loves him
when his kisses
got gin
fish gotta swim,
birds gotta fly
i gotta love
one man till i die
can't help lovin'
that man of mine
or else
she ain't my gal
tell me he's lazy,
tell me he's slow
tell me i'm crazy,
maybe i know
can't help lovin'
that man of mine
she's just as crazy
'bout me
when he goes away
that's a rainy day
and when he comes back,
that day is fine
look at that gal, sugar.
he can come home
as late as can be
home without him
ain't no home to me
can't help lovin'
that man of mine
magnolia!
Say, dealer,
what was the turn?
Ace won,
and king lost.
Raise you
30 more.
50 more
on the king.
Who's that
sporting gambler
over there?
Name's gaylord ravenal.
Sounds familiar.
Yeah. Got in
a little fuss here
about a year ago.
Proved self-defense
and got out.
The judge just told him
he'd better clear out of here
by nightfall.
Waiter!
We'll be late
for rehearsal.
One more.
Can i talk
to you, sir?
Yeah, if you got
anything to say.
See that?
Why, that's
miss julie laverne,
ain't it?
Yeah. That's what
she calls herself
since she got married
to a white man.
What?
Frank, i want you
to hear this.
You, too, elly.
Sit down
and explain yourself.
And you'll make sure
you know what you're
talking about.
[Captain andy]
Let's go on with rehearsal.
Good evening,
miss lucy.
I was absorbed
in meditation
and did not realize
night had fallen.
The days are growing
shorter, hamilton,
but they're long
when one is waiting.
As i came
across the field,
i saw the cattle
being driven home
by your faithful dog.
You got that,
rubber face?
Yep. I got
a cowbell.
[Clang]
It ain't a cowbell.
It says here,
"cows moo
offstage."
Have you got
a moo affect?
Oh, i can
do that myself.
Moo!
Try that again
a little deeper.
Moo!
No, i guess
you better
ring the bell.
May i make
a suggestion,
captain?
Huh?
I thought it would
be good if,
while i was
talking over there,
for frank
to pass the window
and peek through,
like this.
You can't. Room's
on the second floor.
Frank couldn't
look through the window
if it was on
the second floor.
It wouldn't be
any good anyway.
Julie let me
study her part.
I know every line
and all the business.
If you forget anything,
ask me.
You stick to the piano,
young lady.
No playacting for you.
[Captain andy]
All right, now try it.
Oh, there you are!
You're late.
I'll explain later.
Steve, i got something
to tell you.
Where's frank?
He's coming.
Is thall you're
going to say to them?
She said she'd
explain later,
didn't she?
Humph!
Fine disciplining
this troupe's got.
Humph!
He'll be here
any second.
[Captain andy]
As we're waiting
for frank,
we'll cut
right down
to his entrance.
All right,
steve.
Oh. All right.
Miss lucy, although
i wear the clothes...
garb.
Garb of a parson,
beneath these
somber vestments,
there is the heart
of a man that ats
for you alone.
Hamilton.
[Elly]
They'll be here
any second.
Embrace over.
Then what?
Then... then
i say, uh...
prompt her,
noli.
[Magnolia]
Hamilton,
my own, my...
papa, look
at julie!
What's
the matter?
Julie's
sick.
What's
the matter, julie?
Land's sakes!
Sure you won't be
feeling better
by tonight?
No, no. Let me alone.
Can't you leave me alone?
[Captain andy]
Hello, windy.
What are you doing here?
Just come over
to warn you.
Seen pete
coming along the levee
with the sheriff.
Be along any minute.
Well, let him
come on board.
Our license is paid.
Seems that skunk pete's
up to something.
Seen him yank
a picture of julie
out of a frame
on the levee.
I seen him.
What are we
going to do?
Stay right here.
You know what
i told you.
Steve!
What are you doing
with that knife?
I'm not going to
hurt her, you fool.
Leave me be.
I know what i'm doing.
It won't
hurt much, darling.
Aah!
Steve!
Hello,
windy.
Captain
hawks,
do you
acknowledge
to be owner of
the show boat?
Why, of course i do.
What do you want?
I have
an unpleasant duty.
I understand that you
have a miscegenation
case on board.
What's that?
[Captain andy]
How's that?
A case of a negro woman
married to a white man...
a criminal offense
in this state.
No. No such thing
on board this boat.
The name
of the white man
is steve baker.
The name
of the negress...
the name
of the negress
is julie dosher.
Which one's
them?
I am steve baker.
This is my wife.
Julie dosher,
my information says
you were born
in mississippi.
Your pop was white,
your mammy black.
Is that right?
Yes, that's right.
You two better
get your things
and come along
with me.
You wouldn't
call a man a white man
that had negro blood
in him, would you?
No, i wouldn't,
not in mississippi.
One drop
of negro blood
makes you a negro
in these parts.
Well, i got more than a drop
of negro blood in me,
and that's a fact.
Are you ready
to swear that
in a court of law?
I'll swear to it
anyplace.
I'll do more
than that.
Look at all
these folks here.
Every one of them
can swear
that i got negro blood
in me this minute.
That's how white i am.
Well, i've seen
fairer men than you
that were negroes.
Still,
you better tell that
to the judge.
Ahem! Ike vallon,
you've known me
the better part
of 25 years.
I was keelboating
when you was running barefoot
around the landing.
Now, i'm telling you...
me, windy mcclain...
that white man's
got negro blood in him.
But this fellow
told me...
i don't care
what anybody told you.
I'm taking my oath
on what i just said.
Steve's got
negro blood in him.
Do you all stand by
what windy just said?
Of course we do.
You look like
a respectable woman.
I am.
Windy wouldn't tell a lie
to save his own life.
You know that, sheriff.
Yes, i know.
I reckon i'll have to take
windy's word for it,
but from now on,
it's your business and not mine.
I warn you...
if these folks around here
ever got wind
that you've got negroes
acting with whites,
they'll ride you
out of town
on something that won't
set so easy as a boat.
Get away from that window!
Go on about your business.
Break it up!
Now you go!
Both of you!
You needn't look at us
like that.
We're not going to
hurt you.
We're going right away.
Come on, honey.
Julie! Julie!
Nola, where are
you going?
I'm going to julie!
Come back here
this instant.
No daughter of mine
will talk to that...
let me go, mother!
I think my show boat's
made a darn fine gal
out of my daughter.
But where
do we go from here?
Hanged if i know.
We can't give
no more shows
without a leading man.
Or a leading lady.
I can play
the lead, can't i?
No. You're
a comedienne.
I was thinking
maybe we'd let
noli jump in.
She knows
all the parts.
Over my dead body.
There never was
an actress in my family,
and there ain't
going to be.
Now if only there
was anybody to play
steve's part.
What about frank?
[Parthy]
Hmm!
Fine leading man
he'd make
with that face
and those flat feet.
I never asked
to play leads, did i?
I never set up
to be a beauty.
Just a minute,
captain!
Mercy! Something
must be on fire,
the way
queenie's running.
Now what's
the trouble,
queenie?
There's a powerful
fine-looking fellow out here.
Wants to know if you-all
could accommodate him
by taking him down the river
far as the next town.
We don't carry
no passengers...
fine-looking,
did you say?
Is he an actor?
Might be, but he seems more
like the kind of a gentleman
it's a pleasure to wait on.
There he is.
I thought, sir,
if i could have
a bed on your boat
tonight,
i could pay my way
as far as fort adams.
You ain't
an actor,
are you?
An actor, sir?
No, captain.
I'm a ravenal.
Gaylord ravenal is my name,
of the tennessee ravenals.
I knew it. He looked
like an aristocrat to me.
Aristocrat? Huh!
Looks more like
a river gambler.
Well, i'm going to
take a chance.
Look here, sir.
I'm looking for a juvenile
leading man.
Am i to understand
you're offering me
the position, sir?
Andy hawks will wind up
in a lunatic asylum yet.
If you can
play the parts
to my satisfaction,
i'll give you
$15 a week
and a chance
to see the world.
I've seen it.
We don't usually pick up actors
off the wharves,
but we can't be choosy
just now.
Madam, your courtesy
is only exceeded
by your charm.
Ha ha ha!
Mother! Father!
Don't let them go,
please, papa!
Don't send julie and steve
away like this.
Nobody will know about them
in the next town.
Julie's my friend.
That's a nice thing
to say.
Well, she is! She is!
She's been my friend ever since
she's been on this boat,
and if you're going to
send her away
for something she can't help,
i'll go, too!
Nola!
Nola, don't talk nonsense.
You've got to stay here
with your mother,
no matter what.
And another thing...
i'm depending on you
to play the leads
till we can get somebody.
See, nola?
What a chance for you.
I just know
you can act.
And if this young man
wants to play the leads
and play opposite you,
i can get you both ready
by tomorrow night.
Are you a quick study?
Lightning.
[Steve]
Ready, julie?
I didn't have time
to get everything
together, captain.
If you'll bundle up
our trash
and leave it
at the post office
in new orleans,
we'll pick it up.
Do you need
any money, steve?
No. I guess we'll
make out all right.
Thanks. Good-bye.
Good-bye, steve.
Forget it.
Good-bye, nola.
I'll write to you,
and you write to me,
julie! Julie!
Don't look back,
darling.
Bye, master steve.
Good-bye, miss julie.
Bye, joe.
Good-bye, joe.
Good-bye.
We ain't got much time.
Mr. Ravenal, i want to see
how you handle dialogue.
Will you read
that speech right there?
Now, the idea
of this character is
you're in love with her.
Now, come on.
Just a sample.
What do i do,
papa?
Oh, you just smile.
That'll get them.
Miss lucy,
will you be mine?
Hmm!
Ha ha ha! Gosh, no.
Nothing like it.
More feeling.
More like you meant it.
You love her. Gosh almighty,
man, you love her!
Go on and tell her.
Oh, i understand.
Miss lucy,
will you be mine?
Ha ha ha!
[Applause]
Did you like it,
mrs. Ewing?
I've seen it
four times.
I liked it
better than ever.
Don't you think
the leading man
is gorgeous?
Yes. He took his part
off quite good.
I liked the leading lady
the best, though.
Did you understand the moral
of the play, my dear?
Oh, sure, mom.
Did you see
how he kissed her?
Yes. I hardly thought
that was in the best of taste.
Well, that's
show business.
What's show business?
I've been trouping
up and down this river
for 12 years.
Nobody ever heard of me.
This ravenal has been
acting exactly three weeks.
They make a star
out of him.
I feel the same way,
frank.
Look at magnolia.
Her picture with ravenal
is on all the posters.
We're not in town
an hour
before captain andy
has their faces
on every ashcan.
You want to know the secret
of their quick success?
They're falling in love
with each other.
What's that got
to do with it?
Well, they make love
on the stage,
and it rings true.
That's why they're a hit.
Well, i've been
playing opposite you
for five years,
and i love you.
Yeah, but maybe
i don't love you.
So you're responsible
for our failure!
We'll never be stars
on this show boat.
You talk
as if you expected
to live on this barge
the rest
of your life.
Ain't you got
no ambition?
Sure,
i got ambition.
I want to marry you.
You know our rules,
mr. Schultz.
No gentleman
allowed in no lady's
dressing room.
He was only waiting
while l...
you know the rules,
too, miss shipley.
Out, mr. Schultz!
Hello, frank.
Hello, ravenal.
Huh!
Uh...
the show, uh...
uh...
the show seemed
to go well tonight.
Yes. Didn't it?
Yes, it did.
Hasn't the weather
been fine?
Yes, hasn't
the weather been fine?
Well, good night.
Good night.
It seems to me i've seen
that stocking someplace.
Where could it have been?
Don't you belong
to a miss magnolia hawks?
I thought so.
Next time you see he
will you give her
a message for me?
I can talk to you
better than i can to her.
I always get flustered
when i try to say
anything to her.
Tell her...
tell her you saw
the young man
who lives upstairs,
and... well,
that's just the point.
I have the room
above her.
she doesn't know
i love her
how could she
know i love her?
sitting in her room
below
how could she dream
how far a dream could go?
sometimes we meet
she smiles, and, oh,
her smile's divine
it's such a treat
to hear her say
"hasn't the weather
been fine?"
i blush
and stammer badly
my heart
is beating madly
then she goes
into her room
and i go sadly
up to mine
a lover
more impetuous than i
would say his say
or know the reason why
but when i get
my chance
i let my chance go by
i have the room
above her
she doesn't know
i love her
how could she
know i love her?
sitting in her room
below
how could she dream
how far a dream could go?
sometimes we meet
he smiles, and, oh,
his smile's divine
it's such a treat
to hear him say
"hasn't the weather
been fine?"
i blush
and stammer badly
my heart
is beating madly
then he goes up
to his room
and i go sadly
into mine
hmm hmm hmm
[continue to hum
in harmony]
Ha ha ha!
Isn't it
a beautiful night?
Yes. It's so light.
Where's the moon?
We could see it better
if we went up on top deck.
Oh, no, i couldn't.
I'll wait up there
for you.
Oh, you came.
I was afraid
you wouldn't.
I can't stay.
Oh, but you can
a little while.
Not a minute.
Mother saw me.
I said i was coming up
to the water barrel.
Good.
Then she said
she was thirsty, too,
so i'll have to hurry
and take it down to her,
or she'll get suspicious.
Will you...
will you come up
again tomorrow night?
And every night?
Nola!
Shut up and come
to bed, you old...
oh.
Oh, i'm sorry.
I'll fill it
for you.
Will you forgive me,
magnolia?
Yes... gay.
then she goes
down to her room
and i go sadly
back to mine
come outside.
I can't leave
the box office.
Frank will take it
for you.
There are
some things
more important
than selling
tickets.
I'd like to know
what they are.
I'll tell you.
Come out!
Oh, come on, frank.
Oh, all right.
What do you want?
What is it now?
Listen to this.
"Dear mrs. Hawks,
i know captain andy
don't like me."
Who is it?
Pete.
I don't like him.
"But i got something
of interest to tell him
about gaylord ravenal."
That's the man
your daughter's
gallivanting with.
Bah!
"I hear
tcotton palace
"comes back to natchez
next thursday.
"I can be reached
at the above address
in fayette.
Faithfully,
pete gavin."
Well, what have you
got to say now?
I say forget it.
Forget it?
Yes, forget it!
And when i say
forget it, forget it!
Soon as we arrive
in natchez tomorrow,
i'm going over
to fayette.
It's two hours away,
but i'll make the trip.
Are you coming
along with me?
I ain't.
All right. It's good
someone has a sense
of duty.
I like ravenal.
He's a right smart young man.
He's the best
leading man we ever had.
Shifty,
that's what he is.
Mark my words...
if you asked around
about him,
you'd find
something queer,
for all he says
he's a ravenal
of tennessee.
He is a ravenal!
He says he is.
Didn't he show me
the tombstone of his folks?
Hawks,
you're a zany.
I could tell you
my name is bonaparte
and show you
napoleon's tomb.
That wouldn't make
him my grandfather,
would it?
Oh!
This the boat where
they have the playacting?
Yes, sir.
Two seats?
Seeing's how this is
the first show we ever seed,
you better give me
and my friend zebe here
the best two seats
in the theater.
I got two left
in the stage box.
35 cents apiece.
There you are.
There, zebe.
Hey,
come back here.
What's the matter?
Excuse me, sir,
but this is
confederate money.
That's the kind
we use in the hills.
It's as good
as yours, ain't it?
Better.
But... but...
but what?
Look at this quarter.
It don't ring.
It don't...
it don't ring! Ha ha ha!
What do you want
for two bits?
Sleigh bells?
Eh, come on, zebe.
[Band playing]
I want my mamma!
[Crying]
Remember, lucy,
i'm telling you this
because i'm your sister.
This is a man's world,
as i know to my sorrow,
heaven help us.
Young girls like us
are like flowers.
We bloom in the sunshine
till plucked
by a passing mule.
Male.
What?
Male. What are we?
Ornaments.
Bright nosegays to be
worn in boutonnieres,
then cast aside
to float along
on the tide of eternity
like floatsam
and joatsam on the sea.
Shh!
That's pretty talk, gal.
And remember,
i'm your sister.
Huh?
And remember,
i'm your sister.
Yes, i know.
Don't tell me.
And remember,
i'm your sister,
and if any harm
should come to you,
i'd never
forgive myself.
[Applause]
I wonder what can be
keeping parson brown.
He promised to be here
before dark,
and the twilight is
fast fading into night.
[Whispering]
Fading into night.
Yes, the twilight is
fast fading into night!
Hamilton brown,
noble soul.
Dare i hope that
that look in your eye
bespeaks the love
which in my heart
of hearts i long for
with every fiber
of my being?
Oh, love.
Noli.
Wait a minute, noli.
Excuse me, folks.
Is seth purdy in the house?
Yes, sir.
Your missis just sent
a message over.
Her sister is took sick
with the fever,
and you got to drive her over
to centerville.
[Band tuning up]
All right, noli.
Oh, love, love.
5:00. can it be he will not
keep his tryst with me?
Moo!
Ah, there is the bell.
It must be
parson brown at last.
[Playing pop goes the weasel]
[Applause]
Good evening,
miss lucy.
I was absorbed
in meditation
and did not realize
night had fallen.
[Cough cough]
The days are growing
shorter, hamilton,
but they are long
when one is waiting.
As i came
across the field,
i saw the cattle
being driven home
by your faithful dog.
Ha ha ha!
Moo!
Moo! Moo!
Shut up!
Miss lucy, although
i wear the garb
of a parson,
beneath these
somber vestments
is the heart
of a man that beats
for you alone.
Oh, hamilton,
my own, my own.
Will you be
my cherished bride?
Oh, hamilton.
Will you?
Yes.
[Parthy coughing]
[Applause]
[Cough cough]
Eh...
[coughing]
Oh, magnolia.
[Cough cough]
Oh, miss lucy, l
you have made me
the happiest man
in the world.
Little did i think
i could ever be
so happy again.
10 minutes past 5:00.
I must go now
to the ladies aid
society meeting.
Will you come with me
and let me announce
our betrothal?
We must not forget our work
in our newfound happiness.
I will stay here
and correct
the examination papers
of my little pupils.
Very well, then.
Good-bye until
tomorrow, beloved.
Good-bye,
my own dear hamilton.
Meet me up
near the water barrel.
I have something
important to tell you.
[Applause]
Ohh... to think that
after my first marriage
with that drunken beast,
i could ever be loved
by such a man as hamilton brown.
[Knock on door]
[Man laughing]
My husband!
[Hissing]
I reckon you thought
i was dead, gal.
I'm about
the liveliest corpse
you ever saw.
Too bad you won't
be able to marry
hamilton brown.
Ha ha ha!
Hamilton brown!
Why don't
he let her alone?
Don't spoil my one
chance for happiness.
Is there no mercy
in your evil soul?
Please, please, go away.
Don't wreck my life again.
I'll give you
a chance, gal.
$1,000 and quick,
or you don't
walk down no aisle
to no wedding march.
But i haven't got it!
[Hissing]
Where's the money
you've been saving
all these years?
Let that gal alone!
I haven't got $1,000.
I swear it!
Oh, you haven't,
ain't you?
For years, i've waited
for this chance.
At last, i have you
in my power.
Heh heh heh!
I warned you!
Ha ha ha!
[Gunshot]
Schultz!
That's right.
Git!
Schultz! Schultz!
Let go of her,
you swine.
Where is he?
Let her down,
rubber face! Curtain!
[Cheering and whistling]
Quiet, folks. Quiet.
I'm sorry i had to ring
down the curtain
before the act was over,
but the fact is,
our heavy man, mr. Schultz,
was suddenly took sick.
He gets a spell like that
every once in a while.
Yeah.
Take it up, rubber face.
Take it up. Take it up.
Go on. Take it up!
Now, folks,
just before mr. Schultz
was tooken
with that attack,
he and the parson
were on the verge
of going into one
of the most sensational
hand-to-hand struggles
to the death
ever seen on any stage.
Now, when egbert sees the parson
coming in through this door,
he should have said...
"ha ha ha!
I'm glad you come
when you did."
And with that,
he hauls off
and hits the parson.
But the parson knows
a thing or two,
and he gives egbert
something he ain't looking for.
"Take that, you cur!"
And down goes egbert.
Egbert, realizing that he ain't
going to win the fight
by fair means,
resorts to foul.
He grabs the parson
round the waist
and backheels him.
"Let go of me, i say.
Let go of me!"
Ow. In the meantime,
lucy is over here
praying for her beloved.
Now comes the big
dramatic moment.
Egbert, the dirty skunk,
reaches in his pocket,
pulls out a monkey wrench
with which he hits the parson.
"Uh!" the parson groans...
"wooo!"...
reels and falls.
Egbert is about to beat
the parson's brains out
when lucy says,
"do with me what you will
but spare my hamilton!"
Now, as though providence
had heard her prayer,
the door swings open,
and through that door there
in walks emmy,
the errant foster sister
of lucy,
ready to right the wrong
she'd done poor lucy.
"Oh!"
Quick as lightning,
emmy, looking at the prostrate
form of the parson
and the weeping figure
of her heartbroken sister
begging egbert
to spare the parson,
grabs the water pitcher...
where's
the water pitcher?...
the water pitcher,
sneaks up on egbert and says,
"the wages of sin
is death!"
[Audience screams]
And she kills the dirty rascal
deader than a doornail.
Now that's what you
would have seen
if it hadn't been
for mr. Schultz
being tooken sick
when he was.
Hurry up,
miss nola.
Captain andy
said he'll
keep talking
till you're
ready.
All right.
Let her down, rubber face.
Let her down.
And now, folks, folks,
i want you to know...
i want you to know i always
put on strong moral plays.
I've been 20 years
on this here river,
and i ain't never
put on a show yet
where virtue
ain't won out.
Of course, i had some
tight squeezes sometimes.
Now we'll go right on
with the olio.
The first number
on the program
will be a little
southern song
solo with banjo
by miss magnolia hawks.
Take it away, rubber.
Take it away.
Give them
a smile, noli.
a smile.
liza matilda hill
visited friends
in louisville
then came back home
her man was waiting
at her front door
jealous and sore
asking questions
"liza matilda hill"
"what did you do
in louisville"
"so far from home?"
"hon, i had fun"
"here's
that i done done"
been gallivantin' around
just gallivantin' around
my feet been off
of the ground
been gallivantin' around
been dancing
all night long
getting home to bed
i don't know when
there's no tellin'
all the times i fell in
love and out again
been gallivantin' around
but now i reckon
i'm through
'cause now i reckon
i've found
it's more fun loving you
rubber face.
How are you,
captain andy?
Almost time
for the moon effect.
Is everything set?
Are you ready?
I'm ready's brother.
Looks kind of
complicated.
I'd better
do this myself.
been gallivantin' around
just gallivantin' around
my feet been
off of the ground
been gallivantin' around
been dancing
all night long
getting home to bed
i don't know when
[audience oohs and ahs]
[Applause]
That always gets them.
been gallivantin' around
but now i reckon
i'm through
'cause now i reckon
i've found...
[laughter]
[Humming ol' man river]
Oh, i can't stand
these stolen seconds
any longer,
these secret
meetings.
I want you
all to myself,
forever.
Nola, dearest,
i want to take you
away with me.
I want to show you
a world you've
never dreamed of...
cities, theaters,
restaurants, people,
and you and i,
together,
enjoying
all those things.
Gay, don't be angry,
but can you afford...
magnolia,
it's not the place
of a gentlewoman
to share in
business worries.
Now, i will
provide for you.
You must
trust me, dear.
Oh, i do. I do.
Nola, i want you
to marry me
here in natchez
tomorrow.
My mother.
We won't tell her
till after
we've done it.
But father.
I spoke to him
tonight.
He gave me
the idea himself.
Father gave you
the idea of marrying me?
No, goose. Doing it
after the parade
at that lovely
little church
at the other end
of town
without your mother
knowing.
You say father
thought of that?
[Thump]
Did you hear anything?
Sounded like someone
on the stairs.
Suppose it's mother.
What will we say
we're doing up here?
Rehearsing.
Rehearsing here?
To get the right
atmosphere...
moonlight and all.
Come. Put your arm
around me.
Gay.
Remember
how your father
directed us?
He said,
"look up in his eyes
like you loved him."
That's it.
you are love
here in my arms
where you belong
and here
you will stay
i'll not
let you away
i want
day after day
with you
you are love
bud of romance
unfurled
you taught me
to see
one truth
forever true
you are love
wonder of all the world
where you go with me
heaven will always be
[band playing]
Andy! Andy!
Gosh almighty,
it's parthy.
He's a murderer.
Mamma!
You're letting
my daughter
marry a murderer.
Who?
That ravenal.
He killed a man!
Gay!
Then why ain't he
in jail or hanged?
The jury figured
the gentleman
he killed
ought to have
went anyhow.
Andy hawks, are you
going to stand there
and let
your only child
marry a murderer?
Oh, don't be so
narrow-minded,
mrs. Hawks.
I killed a man
meself once.
You killed?
Yes, me. Now, are you
coming with us,
or ain't you?
They're going to
be married.
Married to
a murderer. Oh!
She's fainted!
Are you sure?
She's out.
Good! Now we'll go on
with the wedding.
I now pronounce you
man and wife.
[Joe humming ol' man river]
he just keeps rollin'
[thunder]
he keeps on rollin' along
Ooh! Woo!
Woo.
There you go again.
Look at them peas
all over the floor.
The river done it.
The river done it?
That ol' river can do
most anything, queenie.
Look out there
what it's doing now.
Won't let us give
no show tonight.
Show? That don't
worry me none.
There's something else
on this old boat
worries me more.
Miss nola?
That's what.
She'll be all right.
That's what you say
about everything.
You don't get excited.
Why? 'cause you don't
do nothing.
You don't cook like me,
you don't act like
the show folks,
you don't work
on the towboat.
What do you do?
Well, i just
shelled them peas.
You ain't
picking them up.
No. I could have
if you didn't do it.
I could do
a lot of things
if it was necessary.
Why don't you?
'Cause it ain't
necessary.
keep on naggin'
and bullyraggin'
and criticizin'
and call me poison,
i ain't apologizin'
no, sirree
ah still suits me
the rag you're chewin'
must be a ruin
keep right on
knockin'
mockin'
my rockin' chair
ain't rockin'
no, sirree
no matter
what you say
ah still suits me
does you ever
wash the dishes?
does you do
the things i wishes?
does you do 'em?
No, you don't
will you do 'em?
No, you won't
when there's
any workin' to it
i'm the one
that's got to do it
when it's rainin',
who's the fella
uses up
the whole umbrella?
selfish
as a man can be
no matter
what you say
ah still suits me
you don't make money
i know that, honey
i never seen none
ain't going to
be none
but that don't
worry me none
no, sirree
shiftless, lifeless,
no good!
no matter
what you say
ah still suits me
i may be no good,
no good for your good
i may be lifeless,
but with one wife less
my life would be
more strifeless
yes, sirree
no matter
what you say
ah still suits me
"does you ever
wash the dishes?"
"does you do
the things i wishes?"
"does you do them?
No, you don't"
"will you do them?
No, you won't"
always imitatin' me
and always
aggravatin' me
then, in spite of
everything
in spite of
all the grief
you bring
expectin' me
to love you, too
no matter what you say,
i thinks you do
queenie? Queenie!
Mrs. Hawks wants you
to bring some hot water
up to miss nola's room.
My goodness!
You and me
and mrs. Hawks
will have to do
all we can.
There's no way
to get a doctor
tonight.
I'll get a doctor.
You'll get a doctor?
Well, i've never
seen joe
move that fast before.
Where's gay?
Where's my gay?
Suppose
he's drowned?
He ain't drowned.
Gay and frank
probably
couldn't get back
to the boat.
Most likely,
they're staying
at a hotel
till the morning.
And his baby
being born.
Gay didn't know it.
We didn't
think that...
it's much sooner.
How could gay
know it?
Of course he couldn't.
Now, now, don't get
excited, deary.
Oh, lie back.
That's a girl.
Three jacks.
He wins again.
Beats 10s
and 2s.
By george,
it's 2:30.
Aw, come on.
You've got
nothing else
to do.
No. I'm
clean out.
Cut.
[Snoring]
[Thunder]
Captain andy!
Any news?
Not yet.
keep on
goin'
don't let
that river
get the better
of you
come on,
you, joe
you good old joe
fine time to sing.
Dragging me out of bed
in the middle of the night,
telling me the river
had calmed down.
Lying son of satan.
no matter
what you say
ah still
suits me
cootchy cootchy
cootchy.
Hee hee hee!
Cootchy
cootchy cootchy!
Go away, hawks.
You're making
a nuisance
of yourself.
I got an idea
what to call her.
I don't care
to hear it.
Kim.
Kim? That ain't
no name.
I made it up.
"K" for kentucky,
"l" for illinois,
and "m" for missouri,
since she was
born on the river
inside three states.
Humph. Kim!
[Fussing]
Cootchy cootchy
cootchy cootchy!
Hello. You're up early,
mrs. Hawks.
Good morning,
madam.
I knew
this was coming.
I knew from the first minute
i set eyes on you
that you was the kind
to bring trouble
to them that
loved you.
I knew you'd go carousing
the first chance you got
and break
my girl's heart,
and i wish
the lord had kept you
from ever setting foot
on this boat.
Indeed? Then you'll
be glad to know
that i'm leaving it
forever,
and i'm taking
my wife with me.
Humph. When?
The minute the river
goes down enough
for us to take
our things ashore.
You will not go today,
gaylord ravenal.
Why not?
What have you to say
about it, anyway?
She'll not
leave her home
till you've money
to care for her proper,
and you know how long
before that will be.
And suppose
i was to tell you
that i had money,
and plenty of it?
I still say
you can't take a girl
that's been laying
close to death all night
and a 5-hour baby
off this boat today.
A baby?
A baby!
Nola.
Shh!
Gay! We surprised you.
Who? Who
surprised me? You?
No. She did.
She's sleeping.
That's what her mother
should be doing.
Try to sleep, darling.
Humph.
Cootchy cootchy...
now, i want you
to get well quickly
so i can take you
to chicago with me,
just we three together.
You'd like that,
wouldn't you?
Good morning.
Darling, is my hat
on straight?
You look enchanting.
[Shouting]
Ha ha ha!
Gay, you're
wonderful.
Gay just
can't lose.
What's good
in the next race?
[Honk honk]
[Bang]
Ha ha ha!
There isn't anything
i haven't got...
nothing left
to wish for.
We've been through
some pretty hard times.
Might just as well
enjoy the good times.
[Bang]
Something must
be wrong, darling.
Ha ha ha!
"We may move
to a large apartment.
We need more room,"
and so and so and so.
What was all that?
Nothing. Just that
they don't like it
at the palmer house
anymore.
Ain't you going to
read it to me?
Oh, yes.
"We're placing kim
in a convent school."
It will
cost them a fortune.
Why did they do that?
"Gay thinks kim
will have a chance
to form better
social connections."
Public school is the best,
but not for gay and nola.
Nothing's any good for them
unless it costs a lot.
Did he buy her any
new diamond bracelets
or automobiles?
She don't say.
Well, what
does she say?
"I hope
you and mother
are well,"
and so and so
and so.
"Give my regards
to joe and queenie,
and don't forget"...
so and so and so.
"Hasn't the weather
been fine?"
So and so
and so and so.
"Your loving
daughter, noli."
Very inter
you know what i'd
like to do, parthy?
No.
After we put up
the show boat
for the winter,
how about you and me
making a trip
up there?
Chicago?
You must be crazy.
Well, i've got
a kind of a feeling
i'd like to see
noli and gay.
I don't care
to see gay again
as long as i live.
He's a wastrel,
an adventurer,
a cheap river gambler
with a high and mighty air,
and mark my words...
shh shh shh!
We ain't seen kim
in a long while.
She must be getting
kind of big.
Smart as a whip,
too, i guess.
Did i show you
those crayon pictures
she sent me last week?
Teddy roosevelt
and the one
of the battleship?
Hee hee hee!
I seen them.
Oh, she's smart,
all right.
Yes.
Come on.
Let's you and me
make the trip.
You can bake a cake
and bring it to her
up to the school.
Huh?
Well... maybe.
You won't find
another room like this
at the price.
Well, anyway,
it's chicago, kiddo.
Looks like somebody's
living in it.
Well, they won't be
after this morning.
12 solid weeks
gone by
and not
a penny paid.
No, ma'am,
i have me own bills.
Is that you,
nola?
Elly.
That's right.
Elly! Oh!
Hello, nola.
And frank!
Oh, noli.
How did you find me?
Well...
they came to look
for rooms,
and i told them
you were leaving.
Oh, yes.
Yes, of course.
You see, these were
only temporary quarters
until we move
into our new home
on the lake shore.
Meanwhile,
we stopped here.
It's near gay's
business, and then...
we like to help out
mrs. O'brien.
Huh! Great help.
I'll be going
downstairs.
You can let me know
about the room.
Huh! Helping out
mrs. O'brien!
[Mrs. O'brien grumbling]
Oh, she's
a dear old thing.
Why, nola, is this
your little girl's picture?
Yes, that's kim.
Isn't she a darling?
She's
at the convent...
saint agatha's.
Gay insisted
on giving her
every possible
advantage.
Gay doing well,
noli?
Oh, yes, yes.
He's a big success.
Well, sit down.
Tell me something
about yourselves.
Oh, we're doing
pretty good.
Ooh!
We're kind of
breaking in
a new act.
We open
new year's eve
at the trocadero.
I was thinking,
if you needed money,
i could
fix you up a job.
Maybe a little act...
singing,
playing the banjo,
like you used to.
Oh, that would
be fine, nola.
Gay would never
hear of it.
Of course, i'd like to...
just as a lark, i mean.
I don't need the money.
No,
of course not.
[Knock on door]
Come in.
A boy left
this for you,
mrs. Ravenal.
Thank you, ethel.
Oh, yes. G must have
stopped at the bank.
I've got to see
what gay says.
He may want me
to meet him somewhere.
Tell me, dear,
what's the matter?
Is gay hurt?
No.
Elly, you read it.
I may believe it
if i hear
somebody else say it.
"Dearest,
"by the time
this letter
reaches you,
"i shall be
on a train
"bound heaven knows
where.
"There's nothing
left to pawn
"and no more friends
to borrow from.
"I am enclosing
$200.
"This will let kim
finish her term
at the convent.
"Then you can both
go to your parents.
"I am doing this
because i love you.
"Please believe
i will always
love you,
"my dear
little wife.
"Good-bye.
Your own, gay."
Oh, nola.
Is there anything
we can do, nola?
I don't think so, elly.
I don't know. I never thought
of living without gay,
no matter what happened.
I can't imagine it now.
He seems to think
you and kim will be
better off.
Better off?
I never complained.
I've lived like this
half the time.
One room, one bed,
washing clothes in a basin,
cooking food
over a gas jet,
but i loved him,
and if all that went with him,
i was willing to take it.
I thought he knew that.
Look, deary,
you and kim
can have a good home
on the show boat.
Good home?
Living on charity
and having my mother tell me
she always knew
it would be like this,
the whole show boat troupe
whispering about me
in their dressing rooms...
no. I'll do anything
but that.
Won't it cost you
something
to keep the kid
at the convent?
This money will help me
for a month or so.
Meanwhile,
i'll look for work.
Well, don't forget
what i said
about the trocadero.
The troca...
oh, yes. I might
try that, frank.
I'll think it over.
You'd like us to go,
wouldn't you, dear?
Sure. Sure, noli.
Elly and i 23.
We skiddoo.
You can get us
over at forbes hotel
if you want us.
All right, dear.
Oh!
[Crying]
[Singing]
Your daughter's
class
will be coming
through next.
Kim.
Daddy!
Where's mom?
Mother couldn't
come today, dear.
Now listen,
kim, dear.
Daddy's in
a great hurry.
He must
catch a train.
Where are you going?
Away for a little while
on business.
I just had a few minutes
to rush in and see you.
Can i go with you?
No, darling...
not this trip.
And when i'm gone,
i want you
to think of me
once in a while.
Will you?
Yes. I think of you
all the time,
and when i miss you,
i always do
what you told me.
What was that?
Don't you remember?
Make believe.
Oh, yes.
That's right.
I gave you a system
for having
everything you want.
only make believe
i'm near you
that you're with me
girls and boys
find it fun
just pretending
couldn't you?
Couldn't i?
couldn't we?
and if i'm
a little late
in coming back,
you just
remember
and pretend
that i've never
been away.
Will you,
sweetheart?
best of all,
make believe
i love you
for to tell
the truth
l...
ahem. Her class
has gone in.
Good-bye, darling.
Good-bye, daddy.
Kim.
Be sure to tell
your mother
that i came
to see you.
Will you,
sweetheart?
All right, daddy.
I'll tell her.
Say, where
are you going?
I want to see
mr. Green.
Can't see him now.
Rehearsal.
He told me not to
let anybody in.
Can we wait
out here?
Sure, but don't walk
on the wet floor.
Oh. Come on, noli.
Sit down over here.
All right, jake.
Call them at 12:00.
[Man]
O.k., girls,
12:00 tomorrow.
Come on, julie.
Let's hear the new song.
I don't feel like
singing.
Oh, don't you?
What do you
feel like doing,
duchess?
I feel like
going off on a tear.
Come on, julie.
Let mr. Green hear the song.
It's a good one,
mr. Green.
i used to dream
that i would
discover
the perfect
lover someday
i knew
i'd recognize him
if ever
he came round
my way
and i always
used to fancy then
he'd be one
of the godlike
kind of men
with a giant brain
and a noble head
like the heroes
bold
in the books
i've read
but along came bill
who's not
that type at all
you'd meet him
on the street
and never notice him
his form and face
his manly grace
are not
the kind that you
would find
in a statue
oh, i can't explain
it's surely not
his brain
that makes me thrill
i love him
because he's
wonderful
just my bill
he can't play golf
or tennis or polo
or sing a solo
or row
he isn't
half as handsome
as dozens of men
that i know
he isn't tall
or straight or slim
and he dresses far worse
than ted or jim
i can't explain
why he should be
just the one, one man
in the world for me
he's just my bill
an ordinary man
he hasn't got a thing
that i can brag about
and yet to be
upon his knee
so comfy and roomy,
seems natural to me
oh, i can't explain
it's surely not
his brain
that makes me thrill
i love him
because he's,
i don't know
because he's
just my bill
use it tomorrow night,
and listen...
be sober.
I'll be sober.
If you want me,
i'll be in my
dressing room.
Queer how a woman
goes all to pieces
over a man.
She was the best bet
in chicago
till that big,
curly-haired tramp
threw her down.
Want to go
to radley's
for a drink?
Yeah. Thanks, boss.
O.k., kids!
See you tomorrow!
Mr. Green,
can i see you a minute?
I'm frank schultz
of schultz and schultz,
the well-known
comedy team.
The new act, huh?
I'll see you later.
I want to see you...
what do you want?
I got a girl
i want you
to hear sing.
I ain't seeing
no more people today.
I thought...
you thought wrong!
You thought wrong!
Who do you
want to see?
Well, l...
that's the girl
i mean, mr. Green.
I'd like to sing
for you, mr. Green.
Yeah? What kind
of singing?
I do negro songs.
Oh, coon-shouter, huh?
All right, let's see
what you can do.
Oh, come on, noli.
Hold that!
Couple of chairs.
Take off
your hat.
fish gotta swim
and birds gotta fly
i gotta love one man
till i die
here you are,
miss julie.
You got 15 cents
coming to you.
Keep it.
Thank you.
Wait, sam. Who is
that girl singing?
Don't know. Must need
a job awful bad.
Been sitting
on those steps
most of the morning.
tell me he's lazy,
tell me he's slow
tell me i'm crazy,
maybe i know
nola.
Do you know her?
I used to.
She's singing
one of the songs
i taught her.
when he goes away
she was the sweetest kid
i ever knew.
That her?
Shall i tell her
you're here?
No, no, no,
sam, no.
Well,
if she gets
the job...
she can't!
Green only uses
one singer in the show,
and that's me.
that day is fine
i wonder...
i wonder how bad
she needs a job.
he can come home
as late as can be
home without him
ain't no home to me
can't help lovin'
that man of mine
what do you say,
boss?
Rotten.
Why, that song is the most
beautiful song i know,
and if you don't like it,
i'm sorry for you!
Mr. Green.
Well, what do you want?
Got a message
for you from your
prima donna.
She said to tell you
she's leaving
your show flat.
Where is she?
Just went off
in a cab.
She's gone off
on one of her
sprees.
She won't be fit
for anything
for a week,
let alone tomorrow night.
Oh, why didn't you
stop her?
Say, i'm a doorman,
not a nursemaid.
It's enough
to drive a man crazy.
That settles it.
She's through!
Said to tell you,
if you want a girl
to fill her place,
you better
grab the one
that just sung.
Can't you use her?
I can't afford
to take chances
with amateurs
on a $2,000 production.
Now, wait a minute,
will you?
Let me think.
Her personality
is all right.
If we could
only teach her
some up-to-date
numbers.
That song she sang
ain't bad, boss,
but we could
trick that like this.
wot dot da,
da dot dot da
da dot dot da,
you mean rag it?
Yeah. We got to change
the words, too, see,
and at the finish, put in
a couple of gags like this.
bot dot da,
da dot dot da
catch line.
bot dot da,
da dot dot da
another catch line.
See what i mean?
Say, that's
all right.
Noli, try it this way.
Follow jake.
fish gotta swim,
birds gotta fly
no, no!
Rag it, he means.
Rag it, honey. Look.
fh gotta swim,
birds gotta fly
fish gotta swim,
i know. All right,
go ahead.
fish gotta swim,
birds gotta fly
i gotta love
one man till i die
can't help lovin'
that man of mine
tell me he's lazy,
tell me he's slow
tell me i'm crazy,
maybe i know
can't help lovin'
that man of mine
when he goes away,
that's a rainy day
what do you
say, boss?
Does she get
the job?
Sure.
home without him
ain't no home to me
nice new year's,
i must say.
They ain't here. Nobody
knows where they went.
You and your surprises.
You're a nitwit, hawks,
and always will be.
Well, haven't you
a word to say?
Will you listen?
No, i won't.
I thought you won't.
Are you going to
stand here all night?
Give me the key.
I'm going to my room.
I'm all tuckered out.
Oh, parthy, always...
parthy.
Parthy!
Parthenia!
It's new year's eve.
Let's go out.
I'll bet you
noli and gay
are celebrating
in some restaurant.
Come on. Let's go out
and find them.
Huh! Like looking
for a needle
in a haystack.
You go out
and look for them
if you want to.
Give me that key.
Oh, yes, here's
the key, parthy.
Now, you go up
and have some sleep
while i have
a look around
for the children.
Sleep! A lot
of sleeping
i'll do
wondering where that
good-for-nothing
has dragged nola.
Hawks, it's 8:00.
You be back by 9:00.
You understand?
One hour.
All right, parthy.
[Elevator starts]
[Chuckling]
Hello, pop.
Ladies.
Who was that you were
just talking to?
That was
parthenia,
my wife.
Oh, my mistake.
No, mine.
Ha ha ha!
Well, it's
new year's eve.
It certainly is.
Ha ha ha!
4 quarts
of mumm's extra,
and while you're
drawing that,
i'll be looking
at the menu.
By crackey, i ain't
done that in years!
[Honk]
Say, pop,
what's mistletoe?
Ha ha ha!
By crackey, i ain't
done that in years!
[Honk]
[Squeak]
so you're
going away
because my heart
has gone astray
and you
promised me
that someday
you'll come back
to me
good-bye, my lady love,
farewell, my turtledove
you are the idol
and darling of my heart
and someday you will
come back to me
and love me tenderly
good-bye,
my lady love, good-bye
[honk]
[Squeak]
Captain andy!
Frankie schultz!
Andy hawks!
Ha ha ha!
Happy new year!
Ha ha! Girls,
i want you to meet
an old friend of mine
mr. Frank schultz.
This is miss so-and-so.
Miss thingamabob,
and this little
devil is lottie.
Hello.
Captain andy, how did you
happen to come here?
Oh, just dropped in.
Parthy and me came up
to surprise noli and gay,
but they ain't stopping
at the palmer house
no more.
But i'll find them.
I left parthy
at the hotel at 8:00.
Ha ha! Told her i was
going to take a walk.
Ever since 10:00,
i've been trying to think
of an excuse for not
being back by 9:00!
Captain andy,
noli's here.
Where? Where?
She's acting.
Acting? What
do you mean, acting?
Gay wouldn't let her.
Gay is gone.
He went broke
and quit.
I'm telling you this
because noli opens
here tonight,
and we want
everything
to go smooth.
It will be tough
if she don't
make a hit.
What do you mean,
don't make a hit?
My noli will stand
this crowd on their ears!
Didn't she always do it?
My daughter is
singing here tonight.
Are you old enough
to have a daughter?
No, but i got one!
Ha ha ha!
Ladies and gentlemen!
I regret to announce
that miss julie wendel
is indisposed
and unable to appear
this evening.
Ohh. Ohh.
Now, wait,
please, please!
We are fortunate
in obtaining the services
of miss magnolia ravenal,
who will sing you
an old favorite.
Magnolia ravenal!
Who's she?
I'll show you
who she is!
[Orchestra playing]
[Applause]
a little maiden
climbed
an old man's knee
[talking and shouting]
Shh. Quiet.
why are you single,
why live alone?
quiet!
Get the hook!
have you no babies?
Have...
[shouting]
i had a sweetheart
nola!
years, years ago
where she is now, pet
noli!
you will soon know
list' to my story
smile, noli.
i'll tell it all
smile!
i believed her
faithless
after
smile.
the ball
after the ball is over
after the break of morn
after the dancers leaving
after the stars
are gone
many a heart is aching
if you could
read them all
many the hopes
that have vanished
after the ball
everybody!
after the ball is over
[captain andy]
Everybody sing!
after the break of morn
smile!
Smile, noli!
after the dancers leaving
sing, everybody!
after the stars are gone
many a heart is aching
if you could read them all
many the hopes
that have vanished
after the ball
[cheering]
[Clock chiming]
Happy new year!
[Band playing a hot time
in the old town tonight]
Hawks, i think
your daughter
is the finest
artist i've seen
on the new york stage.
I must have her
in my new play
in london next spring.
I'll give her
200 a week.
You'll have to do
better than that.
They don't
know her in london.
But they will.
How much?
400.
Out of the question.
[Bell rings]
[Ring]
[Gay]
best of all,
make believe i love you
for to tell the truth,
l...
[playing piano]
i want to be
a good little wife
in a good
old-fashioned way
kim, darling,
don't you think
you're pressing
just a little bit
too hard?
How do you mean,
mother?
Don't throw it at them.
Let the audience feel
the sentiment
of the song
for themselves.
Remember the folks
in the gallery.
So many things
to learn.
All right.
Rest a minute.
This newspaperwoman
has been waiting
all day
for an interview.
Better grab her quick.
They'll be
calling her back
any minute.
My paper's interested
in the family angle.
Your folks all started
on a show boat,
didn't they?
Yes.
Did they help you?
Taught me
everything i know.
Do they still
help you much?
Ha ha! Too much.
This time i packed them
all off to europe.
That's marvelous.
Miss ravenal! Sorry.
We've got to have you now.
I'm so sorry.
[Clapping]
Aren't you
the new stage doorman?
Every time
i come in here,
i see you watching
the rehearsal.
Watch the stage door.
That's what you're
paid for.
Yes, sir.
Night, pop.
Pop, i'm
from the office.
What's your name?
I believe it's pop.
Isn't that what
all stage doorman
are called?
Yeah, but i want
to list you
on the payroll.
What's
your real name?
Oh, uh...
brown.
Hamilton brown.
Night, pop.
Good night.
[Humming]
No mail for me?
No, miss ravenal.
If a wire comes
for me,
will you send it
to my hotel?
Yes, miss ravenal.
Thanks.
Good night, pop.
Good night.
Good night, kim.
Don't worry. The boat
will dock on time.
It's
such awful luck.
They were supposed
to be here early
this afternoon.
Oh, why did that fog
have to come up
just at this time?
I know.
The curtain will
be going up
any minute.
Don't fret, parthy.
It won't take long
to get uptown.
We'll be
in time for most
of the show, mother.
We won't see
kim's entrance.
Well, i didn't
put this fog on.
Who said
you did?
Mother.
[Orchestra playing]
[Humming]
[Siren]
Oh! We shall never
get there alive!
I thought we'd
never get here!
It was
such dreadful fog,
but not as bad
as it is in europe.
You know...
thank you.
Oh, my.
There's kim.
Go on, go on.
Ch-ch-ch-ch!
Come this way.
What are you
doing here?
I just wanted to see
the one number, sir.
Why, that's the most
outrageous thing
i ever heard.
Go back
to the stage door.
Come to the office
in the morning
to get your pay.
You're fired.
Here, sir.
Right in here.
This is your box.
Gay.
Don't you
recognize me?
You haven't
changed much, nola.
Oh...
wouldn't you like
to come in here with us?
I think we...
well...
this is our
daughter's big night.
Sure,
why don't you?
I didn't mean
to come back
into your life.
I don't want you
to forgive me,
because i don't
deserve it.
Just let me...
slip out.
Gay.
There's another ravenal
in the house tonight...
magnolia.
Noli.
Maybe she'll take
my encore for me.
How about it, mother?
Please play
you are love.
[Orchestra playing]
Give them
the smile, noli.
Give them the smile.
I think
she likes this better
than any song
she knows.
you are love
here in my arms
where you belong
and here you will stay
i'll not let you away
i want day after day
with you
you are spring
bud of romance unfurled
there's another
ravenal here tonight...
gaylord ravenal,
my first leading man.
[Applause]
where you go with me
heaven will always be
[joe]
that ol' man river
he just keeps rollin' along