The accident last month of the
truck carrying arms to the border.
And the fire in the jeep.
The task of their inquiry...
l've prepared its' report.
- And?
- lt was a plan not an accident.
The aim being stealing of arms.
Meaning our people are involved.
Must hand the case to intelligence.
l have a request. The truck
that is to leave tomorrow..
Give me the responsibility of taking
it to the border security force.
lf this happens again, the arms
looters will be uncontrollable.
Why doesn't this plane fly?
What are you saying, son?
Do toys ever fly?
Buy me a flying plane.
First grow up. Then you'll see...
You'll have more planes
than people have cars.
For the time being,
make do with this.
lf you fill A, B, C... in
his mind instead of this...
He'd learn to write his name.
He will learn. The alphabets
are not leaving lndia.
But his age is flying past.
He's grown so big. You neither showed
him a book, nor did he see a school.
Aren't you at all worried?
Buy a couple of buffaloes with
the money you'll spend on books.
The boy will drink milk
and become as tough as us!
He'll become as clever as
brother. You won't believe it.
- What is it? - Sir has
called for an urgent meeting.
- What meeting? - The usual
but he has called everybody.
That's fine but what about the
cash for the arms we gave last time?
He's given this bag full!
- How much is it?
- l can't count much.
l'll weigh it if you say.
Must be 7 or 8 kilos with the bag.
No need. You wait at the
corner, l'll change and come.
Are you doing the duty for which
the government gave you this uniform?
Of course! That's what l'm doing!
You were but no more!
Earlier 3000 rupees came
on the first of every month.
Now millions come at any date!
l ask, why? What do we lack?
What an illiterate woman!
l want to live, enjoy!
By selling your country?
Do you want me to spend
all my life carrying a gun?
And die at the
enemy's hand someday?
You want to be a widow?
That widow is better than a woman..
Whose husband is a
martyr for the nation.
l can bear to see you
dying by a bullet.
But l can't bear the
stigma of a traitor on you!
l say for the last time..
Don't be loyal to me.
But if you're disloyal to your
country, l won't forgive you!
- Mother!
- Don't teach me!
l can leave my wife for money!
Subhedar Pratap Singh has come.
What's the matter? DK always
meets after delivery of arms.
What meeting is this beforehand?
l've called this meeting...
Because the truck of arms to go
to the border with you tomorrow..
You can't loot it easily.
- Why? - Because..
another in charge is coming.
How did you find out?
From our fourth partner,
Jaswant Dalal, Major's driver.
He is a very strict man.
With him around, forget trucks
we can't steal a nail!
Opportunity never strikes again.
The truck carries latest arms worth
10 crores that sell like hot cakes.
Each of us 4 partners
can earn 2.5 crores.
Come what may, we will
have those weapons.
The soldiers who play
with guns and cannons...
... do not fear
the police's revolver.
l came stealthily yet
you found me out.
We soldiers have 4 not 2 eyes.
- You...
- Hello.
Sudden trip?
l've come from Delhi to
give you some good news.
- What is that?
- Not now.
First some good piping hot
breakfast, then the news.
The good news is
l've been promoted.
l have to join duty
in Bombay in a week.
And to celebrate we're going
to Simla by the evening flight.
Here are the tickets.
We won't be able to go.
l'd promised Raju we'll go to
a hill station if he stands first.
Trucks with arms are
going to the border.
- l'm in charge of it.
- Hand it to somebody else.
lf it was given by an officer
l would have done this.
But l've asked for this assignment.
You've ruined my plan.
Doesn't matter. l'll go
to Bombay today itself.
- The jeep is ready sir.
- Wait for me.
Stop the jeep.
Reverse.
Why have you stopped the truck?
There's an oil leak.
So the wheel is jammed.
l'll try to contact headquarters.
What's wrong with the wireless?
Some soldiers will remain here
with you for security.
The rest will go with me.
l'll get help from
the nearby station.
Any doubts?
Pile it in.
Bastards!
These weapons are not bought from
the gold in a king's treasury!
But by the sweat and blood
of 90 crore lndians!
You swore to protect the
country but you loot it!
lt's a shame for this uniform
to be draped on your body!
You'll get only some copper or
bronze medals by arresting us.
Become our partner.
We'll give you one half!
You want to buy me off!
Who can't be bought? Everybody
is for sale. At their own price.
What will we soldiers do in
this environment by being honest?
Our nation is safe
because of our honesty!
Or it would lose its' identity!
People don't sleep
because the sun sets.
lt's because we guard the border
that the country sleeps in peace!
lf we sell our honesty...
Another color will fly
in place of our tricolor!
A fax from lnterpol, Australia.
Send a message to
ACP Dinesh Kapoor.
For an urgent meeting.
This is Jaswant Dalal. We've
got a message from Australia.
He deals in illegal arms smuggling.
He's coming to Bombay
by a cargo ship today.
lf we arrest him, we can find out
about illegal arms smuggling here.
l've called for a secret meeting
so nobody outside hears about it.
Otherwise people attached to him,
who'll suffer by his arrest...
...will have him killed.
You'll be in charge of the
operation to nab Jaswant.
And l want him alive
under any circumstance!
- Got the fax?
- Yes.
The police want him alive.
You know what you have to do.
Remember he must not get into
the police's hands alive.
- l cannot help you in this.
- All right.
He can't escape. There are more
policemen than workers here.
Jaswant has come.
Shall we begin movement?
Who are you? What do you want?
- To save your life.
- Whom do l fear?
Whom every criminal fears.
The ones outside are
the police not workers.
The police can be recognized
by their shoes not clothes.
lf you want to get out of here...
Do as l say.
Jaswant is not to be seen.
Nobody here.
Jaswant is in the container
that is being off loaded!
There's another man with him!
Should we surround the container?
Surround the container
being off loaded.
- Stop the container!
Bring the container down.
Nobody will fire.
We want him alive.
So far l did what you said.
Now you'll do what l say.
Stop the car.
Hands up.
You're a useful man but
my principle is...
Job finished, man finished.
And my principle is
man finished, job finished.
l want the killer not your sorry!
Seal all the ways of going out.
And remember he must
not leave this city!
- Are you an lndian?
- You know me?
- No.
- No?
- Now?
- No.
No, l don't recognize you.
- Why are you crying?
- lt's a sad story.
Once there was a fair of Kumbh.
- ln Australia?
- No, lndia.
l have a twin called
Sohan. l'm Mohan.
- He was left and l right and
in the center was... - Your mom.
My father. We were happily
going when all of a sudden..
- He ran.
- Who, your Dad?
No, a thief. l screamed, Dad!
He's running away with the bag!
- He ran after him.
- Who, your Dad?
My brother was behind the thief.
They were running and l screamed
and he fell with a thud!
- Thief?
- My Dad!
He was drunk and the
police caught him
- The thief?
- My Dad!
- And started beating him.
- But why?
They thought he was the thief.
in the meantime he ran away!
- The thief?
- My brother!
Since then l'm looking for him.
- The thief?
- No! My brother!
But if he was lost in lndia
why are you looking for him here?
That was different. He ran away.
He had two hobbies, to see
kangaroos and pick pockets.
Tell me, is any place better
than trams to pick pockets?
That's why l took this job.
Someday he'll come here to
pick pocket and l'll see him.
- lt's come! - Your brother?
- No, your station!
lf you ever see that rascal
whom l'm looking for..
- Give him my card.
- Whom? The thief?
To my brother, Sohan!
Turned my head round!
Who will be Miss Valentine
in today's function at the club?
Me.
Why are you laughing?
This was my new car!
You damaged my car!
Why do you drive abroad
when you don't know driving!
Why don't you drive bullock
carts in your own country?
These days lndians pilot planes,
jet rockets and space shuttles!
You braked and the car stopped.
l braked and my car didn't.
- lt's a little thing.
- Little thing?
So it may be big. But not so big
that Vicky can't compensate for it!
How much? 50, 100, 300?
You'll remember you
met a wealthy lndian!
How dare you touch me!
Dress like a modern girl
and talk like an old woman!
Madam this is Australia not lndia
You can't stop and talk midway...
Go and talk of love in a garden
Sing, dance, makes no difference.
We're not talking of love.
He crashed into my car.
Both of you will have to
come to the police station.
Why are you wasting time?
We take back our complaint.
This is understanding.
You lose some to gain some.
When and where?
- You?
- Yes, me.
You have a twin?
Who was lost in the fair?
- l saw him. - Where?
- He's a tram conductor.
That is me.
You're talking of Sohan.
l thought...
He must have graduated
from picking pockets.
And he'll steal somebody's car
and break the signal to escape.
And l'll catch him.
So l became a traffic policeman.
Why did you make fairs, Lord?
A day for lovers.
You all know, we in lndia Club
choose a Miss and Mr. Valentine.
And this years'
Miss Valentine is...
Friends, amongst you whoever
answers 3 of Preeti's questions..
He will be chosen Mister Valentine!
He gets an opportunity to dance...
And kiss Miss Valentine's hand!
She sets one small condition.
lf you can't answer her questions..
You'll have her pretty
sandal not her hands to kiss!
What's the matter? Can none
among you answer her questions?
l'll answer her.
Think again. lf you lose
you'll have to kiss her shoe.
Don't worry. One who is
kissable from head to toe..
Her head and toe are the same.
Ask the question.
First question. What is
her favorite fruit?
The sweetest fruit is of labor.
But Miss Valentine is
miles away from hard work.
So her favorite fruit can't be
mango, sweet lime or orange.
Because you have to
peel it to eat it.
Her favorite fruit is one that can
be popped in the mouth and swallowed.
That is grape.
Next question. What's
her favorite sport?
Man likes games
according to his nature.
And her nature...
fight, fight and fight!
So she likes WWF wrestling.
Tell him to answer simply.
Why is he beating round the bush?
So what? He's answering right!
Now the last question.
Which of the 7 wonders
is her favorite?
l'll have to answer this
in a roundabout manner.
Will do!
The wonder she likes is very
different from her nature.
She hates the word love.
But likes the wonder
that is a symbol of love.
This year's Mister
Valentine is Vicky!
She asked three ordinary questions.
lf she had to ask anything today
it should have been of heart and love.
l would even answer that.
What's in her heart.
The heart in you is lndian.
And lndian heart is not a loafer.
lt likes the whole world.
But belongs to an lndian.
All of you can participate
in today's Valentine Day.
You'll see, l won't leave him!
Don't ever leave him!
He's so handsome, intelligent.
Shut up! Just because
he answered my questions..
You think that fool is intelligent!
He's great. He even said
what l hadn't told him.
- You told him all this?
- Yes!
l won't spare you!
- Which is table 7?
- That one.
But don't sit there.
Here's your best drink.
- You?
- Yes.
- You have a twin?
- He's searching for you all over.
- Where is he?
He's become a traffic policeman.
- That was me.
- You were in the police.
l tried that job too but
Mohan didn't meet Sohan.
So l became a waiter.
He loved one thing...
Of seeing dances. And English
dances are shown here.
So l joined here. Someday
he will come here, l think.
Please don't sit at this table.
Please sit at any other table.
He's come here! Did you
tell him we're coming here?
l swear this time l didn't tell him.
You can't sit here because
this is Jojo's table.
- Who is he? - The son of
the most dangerous man here.
He always keeps smiling.
- Something like this.
- lt's good for health.
l know that but when he stops
laughing other's health suffers.
When somebody else sits on
his table, he stops laughing.
So what happens?
This. Their only fault
was sitting at this table.
Geigy saw it and thrashed them.
No better chance to get him beaten.
Hope nothing goes wrong.
- lf l get him beaten?
- Bet 100 bucks!
l don't want a nice man like
yourself's picture be stuck here.
Get up my Pop!
Or he'll throw you out.
Great!
Did the sun rise in the west?
- Sure, sit.
- No!
Don't join on this table
or your joints will be disjointed.
Please join at another table.
What's going on? Don't you
know how to talk to customers?
- That's Jojo's table.
- So what?
Why are you standing here? lt's
time for Jojo. Get his order.
l'm the hotel manager.
Please get up from here.
- This table is reserved.
- You should have kept the plate.
You don't know.
Jojo is very dangerous!
What do you think?
Vicky is double dangerous!
- lsn't it?
- Yes, triple dangerous!
Now l won't move from here.
Whether Jojo comes or bow wow!
Please be seated.
l think she didn't like your face.
l've trapped him so that
he goes straight to the hospital!
Swallowed the cap?
Are you so hungry?
l am finished!
Let go of me!
l went to the loo and
you showed your colors!
l know she wanted to
get me into trouble
But that doesn't mean you carry
her off as if she belongs to you!
The damage they have
suffered because of you..
Pay for it.
Now onwards when you laugh
people will laugh at you.
l got the money for the damages.
But in return Jojo's Dad
will damage you a lot.
That's what l want.
Let's go meet him.
Does it hurt a lot?
Here are 50 dollars for treatment.
These are days of inflation.
Doesn't matter. Keep 500.
Consult a good doctor.
l saved you from a gangster like
Jojo, risked my life for you!
l fought with his henchmen,
shed so much of my blood...
And you are insulting me
instead of thanking me!
Deeds of a loafer and
talks like a soldier!
Look in the mirror!
Soldier! Let's go.
Don't forget to wipe the sauce.
Very sour.
- Who? - The one who knows
everything in your heart.
How dare you call me!
With great difficulty l've
mustered courage for my finger.
So they could dial your number.
Don't disconnect without talking.
- What is it?
- l'm going away to lndia.
l want to meet you one last time.
- You're going back forever?
- Yes.
So you want to meet me
for the last time?
All right. Come over.
- What the blazes is this?
- Time is limited.
- Why do you want to meet me?
- Card.
- l'm getting married.
- Which poor girl is jacked?
Will you marry her?
l won't do anything.
She'll do all that has to be done.
But how did you agree to marry her?
What can l do? l'm helpless.
- What's the problem?
- Twist in story.
Shall l sit and tell you?
My father and her father
were friends
And her grandfather and
mine too were friends.
And her grandfather made my
grandfather promise on deathbed...
They would marry us to continue
their friendship for 4 generations.
Tell me, what can l do?
l can't put off my Dad,
this marriage can't be put off!
This marriage is firm!
What can l do?
- Give me a present.
- What preset?
Give me one of your
sweet smiling evenings.
Which will spread light in
the darkness of my life.
Will you meet me?
A drunken man never lies.
He can't lie.
Your car banged into
mine at the signal...
lt didn't crash.
l banged it on purpose.
Banged it on purpose?
What could l do?
Had to make friends with you.
For that l had to meet you.
l needed an excuse for it.
And my tail light down.
But this method of
friendship was wrong.
And the method of giving money?
Absolutely wrong!
No experience ...
Then it's all right.
l'll tell you something.
l goaded you into fighting Jojo
at Little lndia Restaurant.
Very bad.
No experience...
Did l say sorry for
troubling you so much?
- Did l say sorry?
- No.
Let's apologise to one another.
One minute. ln your country
that's not how you say sorry.
How else?
Like this.
What are they doing?
Saying sorry to each other.
Good you told me.
l thought something else.
Let's say sorry to each other.
Wait.
When two people say
sorry to each other...
Why don't their noses clash?
What a wrong time for the nose!
You don't know? Doesn't mater.
Let's ask somebody.
Brother!
Tell us something.
When a girl and a boy
say sorry to each other...
Why don't their noses clash?
Say something.
Sorry, l'm new to this place.
No problem.
We'll ask somebody clever
Where do you want to go?
We're not going anywhere.
Just want to ask one thing.
- Ask as many questions.
- When a boy and a girl...
...say sorry to each other,
why don't their noses clash?
What are you thinking of?
We don't have all night.
l'm not thinking of that. lt's
been 20 years since my marriage..
l never said sorry to my wife.
How will l know why
the nose doesn't clash?
Both of you say sorry
to each other and see.
You'll find out why
the nose doesn't clash.
l'll go home and say sorry to the
wife to see where the nose clashes!
And the car goes there!
So clever.
We'll say sorry and see.
Wait! How can you say sorry to me?
- Why? - Because
sorry is only said to...
- The one you will marry.
- That's what l'm doing.
See the card if you don't believe.
Where is he?
The one who has eyes only for you...
How can he marry another?
Yet if you don't accept my love,
tear this card and leave.
l'll go away from you forever.
lf not, shut your eyes
and say in your heart...
l'll appear again.
And if not, shut your eyes
and say in your heart...
l'll reappear.
Are you thinking what l am?
Let's go in and get married.
You'll have to talk
to my Papa for this.
l'll talk to him. Where is he?
l want you to meet somebody.
- The young man who is with you.
- Strange. How did you know?
l even know what
clothes he's wearing.
l keep track of you
like any good father.
Where you go, with whom
and who is meeting you.
But when are you coming?
Come Pratap. How are you?
Absolutely fit. And you?
l'm fit if my brother is fit.
Why did you want to meet?
- Bad news.
- l know.
You want to say Jaswant is dead.
No, even worse.
l've got reports that
DK had him killed.
Absolutely wrong.
Sir can never kill his
partner of 25 years!
He can do anything for money.
Even if he did, it's good.
Had he escaped alive, the police
would've beaten everything out of him
And handcuffed us and
taken us back to lndia!
Try to understand.
Someday he might even
finish us off.
lf he kills us who will supply
him American arms in lndia?
Listen to me. Right from beginning
his intentions were not true.
That's why he never
told us his address.
He can contact us anytime
but we can never reach him.
What do you want?
What should we do?
Before he attacks us,
we should finish him!
The idea is not bad.
We were 4 partners.
Jaswant died and three remain.
We kill DK and 2 remain.
You kill me and only you are left.
Do you think l'm a village idiot?
You want to grab the
entire organization?
l find your intentions
dishonorable not DK's.
- Shut up or...!
- Control yourself.
You'll be finding your fingers
if they touch the trigger.
l'm not Jaswant.
Firstly l won't die so easily.
Even if l do die, l won't become
a police file or news in paper.
lf you have a file on me,
l have a file of your deeds.
That file will go to
the police soon as l die.
What's the matter?
Changed tune seeing the gun?
Laughing instead of crying.
Hats off to you friend!
l talked of killing DK...
Because l wanted to know if you
had a hand in killing Jaswant.
lf you were responsible..
You would agree with me.
So what have you decided?
That you haven't changed.
You're still a friend of friends.
As you were 20 years ago.
Nobody can divide us 3 partners.
Except for death!
Do you see that island?
Papa bought it for my last birthday.
And that one? That was
for my first birthday.
So your Papa buys you a new
island for every birthday?
Yes, in my name.
Don't tell this to anybody else.
- Why?
- lt will let out your age.
Look there. That's my papa.
This is...
You know his name
without my telling you?
When he knows the color
of my clothes from miles away..
- He can know my name too.
- While giving a daughter...
Work is seen in addition to name.
Whatever he does, is great!
We'll see. You go in
We have business to talk.
First tell me who gave you
the contract to kill Jaswant?
So you know abut my work?
Anyway hear my principles too.
l see the cash while accepting
a contract, not the payer.
You haven't seen the man who gave
you a contract to love my daughter?
l accept contracts for killing
not to play games of love!
Preeti's love and mine is no game.
Maybe but a father won't
give his daughter to a man...
Whose hands are tainted with blood.
lf mine are tainted,
are yours milky white?
Even l know about you.
We belong to the same community.
Community but not position.
You are a paid ass in this
business while l'm a lion!
You've reached here because
you came with my child.
Otherwise my security dogs wouldn't
have let your bones come near me.
For the first time, l've
seen dogs guarding a lion!
Listen to 2 things l have to say.
ln today's world, lions
can be safe in only 2 places.
ln the circus and the zoo!
Secondly regarding position.
l can take you to that place..
That you're dreaming of for 20 years.
But can never reach it.
Meaning?
Saw what l broke in place
of two teeth of mine?
Pomeranian Puppy!
Give the line to your Pop,
the bulldog.
- What is it?
- He called me a puppy!
And me?
He called me a bulldog?
Give me the line!
Are we a family of dogs?
l didn't find you or
l'd have broken you too!
You act smart with me!
l'm very bad!
You won't believe how rotten l am!
We're a family of tigers not dogs!
We bite not bark!
Are you frightened?
Can you hear?
l'm talking to you not myself!
l've been yelling for ages!
l'm not mad!
Total 8500.
- Plus 100% tax.
- What?
Total 17000.
Round figure 20000.
Which figure are you
rounding and squaring?
This is the damage
your son did to my house.
- You'll take money from me?
- Not rupees, in dollars.
My bill will reach you at 3.55
l'll come at 4 to take the cash.
And leave at 4.05.
10 minutes for giving and taking.
Take those 10 minutes seriously.
- What happened?
- Nothing, he talks rot!
Says he'll send the bill at 3.55
And will leave at 4:05.
As if we're here to pay cash!
The arms buyers would have come
Bring them in. Let me do some work.
We have machine guns.
Even those not yet in the market.
We have 2 lakh pieces of each.
We'll send you the guns you need.
This is a pipe gun.
With every pipe gun, you get
a dozen Hamam soaps free.
Now show them our bomb section.
- 3:55
- 3:55?
lt's the phone.
Don't be scared.
lt's the bill not a bomb.
Do you think l'm scared?
l play with such bombs day and night.
l deal in them. Where are you?
- What?
- He's come downstairs.
Tell him l'm taking the lift up.
Well done.
You did very well!
l thought you were good for nothing.
But you proved to be very smart!
You deserve all the praise!
And you called me a bulldog!
Whether a dog bites or licks,
both are dangerous!
His pistol is empty.
Don't move or the bullet
will go off in your ear.
But some other place will bleed.
Cash.
Pomeranian puppy!
lt's a very big deal.
- Call George.
- He's in hospital.
- Then call Kalia or Rahim.
- They both are also in the hospital.
ls the gorilla also
in the hospital?
Unfortunately he too
is in the hospital.
Have they gone to get a corpse
or have they all got aids?
This is all because of that lndian.
First he burnt my teeth
then he bashed up my men.
He called me a pomeranian
puppy and him...
Then he did a miracle!
- What?
- He thrashed Dad.
He took money from him for all
the damage l did to his house.
Rascal! Recounting the tale of his
bashing as if he's won a medal!
He's not an ordinary boy.
Then is he King Kong? lf the
tale of my shame spreads,...
l won't have the face
to return to Patna!
Take my marksman with you.
Go, shoot him! lf you come without
shooting him, l'll shoot all of you!
The rascal's mother is coming.
He will go to the
airport to receive her.
l'll kill him.
Shoot.
Shoot him!
Now!
Where's that rascal come from?
- Mother has come.
- Now!
Shoot Jojo!
Sister-in-law?
- Stop!
- What's wrong?
This is my sister-in-law!
That means this is my
elder brother's son!
This is our own blood!
lf brother hears this good news,
he'll will me all his Patna property!
Uncle will be happy to hear it!
- ln Australia?
- Yes!
The boy we went to kill
is actually your son!
My son! My wife!
l can't believe it!
Are you telling the truth?
Yes. Jojo, you tell him
what you have seen.
Dad is right. We ourselves saw
brother Vicky touching her feet.
My son!
You've come to the wrong address.
Vicky's mother stays
here not your wife.
Think why fate has brought
us together in a foreign land?
Just so that we live together.
An child who pretends to be
an orphan will get his father.
Orphans are kids who have
neither father nor mother.
And Vicky's mother is alive.
Don't be adamant. Today l have
so much wealth l can buy anything.
Then go and buy yourself
a wife and a son.
People who sell themselves for
money don't live in this house.
Please forget everything.
l apologise on brother's behalf.
The man who sells his motherland...
Who is responsible for
the death of innocents...
They deserve punishment
not forgiveness.
You may leave.
Listen to me.
Brother, this is your son!
- You don't know me, son...
- l know.
l heard everything.
Son! My son!
Don't be angry with me.
l'm pining for you since 20 years!
Even l've been pining for
my father for 20 years!
Blood is thicker than water.
- Now if Shanti agrees...
- Leave her to me.
l'll convince her.
Organize a great party now!
l'll announce to the world
that l'm not childless!
His son who will work with him
shoulder to shoulder has come!
- You?
- Yes?
- You have a brother? - Yes.
- Twin? - Yes.
- Lost in the fair?
- Yes.
- He's come to look for you
from lndia! - Where is he?
- He becomes a policeman, waiter..
- And sometimes band master!
You always find me only!
l'm Mohan!
l thought my brother would
have become a smuggler.
They keep having parties.
Someday l'll find him
singing and dancing.
Lord! Why did you make fairs?
Welcome Pratap!
- How are you?
- Very well.
She's my daughter.
You've grown so big!
Where do you live?
- l haven't seen you for ages.
- l stay separately as l'm studying.
Congrats for finding your
wife and son after 20 years!
- Where are they?
- My wife hasn't come.
l'll introduce you to my son.
Come here son.
ls this your son?
Yes. Got a start seeing him?
And why not? Till yesterday
Pratap was our equal every way.
But after son's arrival our
strength has grown 4 times!
The enemy gets startled.
Not our friends. And he is our pal.
ln lndia, elders give blessings
not congratulations.
Do you know each other?
Now it's your turn to get startled.
He's your son later. First he
became my to-be son-in-law!
Meaning your son and my
daughter are in love.
- What? - Yes, uncle. For her
Vicky brother burnt my teeth.
So my son hasn't come alone!
He's brought his bride alone!
What are you looking at?
Open up champagne immediately!
lt's a joyous occasion!
Where are we going, Dad?
You are my heir so it's essential
you know what l've earned in my life.
And where l've hidden it.
This path leads to that
secret place of mine...
That nobody including my
brother knows nothing about.
l've brought you here so that l can
tell you the secrets of my business.
Finally you have to take over.
Come my son.
l'm very happy today.
ln one day you fulfilled
my dreams of years!
A father's dream is to
get his son married.
Not for that but because
you trapped that rascal's girl...
And brought him to my feet!
What are you saying?
Pratap is your friend.
What friend? lf he gets the
chance, he'll gobble up his friend!
But l'm no less. You must
have heard the magician's story?
His life was in a parrot.
Pratap's life is in my hands.
- l don't follow.
- That's why l brought you here.
This is that parrot in which
the proof of Pratap's evil deeds...
...is written with dates.
This is our third partner Jaswant.
He is no more. And this is
our fourth partner, D. K.
He stays in lndia.
You are right. Pratap's life
is really in your hands.
But the problem is that
my life is in his hands.
Pratap has a similar file on me.
That is why l've agreed
to have relations with him.
So that as his son-in-law
you can get my file from him.
Then you'll see how l
give him a rat's death!
And then l'll put all
my burden on your shoulders.
l'll sleep in peace.
What use is the son who
can't put his father to sleep?
l haven't seen Dad since yesterday.
You won't believe the calls
that have come since morning.
So many inquiries. But they
will speak only if they know.
What are you saying?
Yes, he's here.
Where will he go?
Come here.
Now you can't escape!
Your secret is out!
- What secret?
- Hear it yourself.
lt's you?
Got you scared!
Do you remember it's a
girl's birthday today?
- Which girl's?
- One innocent girl.
Who is trapped in a foolish,
absent minded boy's love.
lf he's absent minded
he will obviously forget.
The girl should have thought
of this before falling in love.
She had no experience of love.
That's how she made a mistake.
Now what is she to do?
She must trust the boy.
l'll catch that fool and bring him.
How will that foolish boy
recognize that girl?
That won't be necessary.
That boy is so special..
That the girl will
come running to him
lt's also possible that
the boy will be left watching
And the girl goes away
with another!
Fine, so let's see.
Looks like somebody's
heart is burning
Looks like there's a fire somewhere.
Should l call the fire brigade?
God! What have you done?
Taken my brother away!
Uncle, why are you crying?
Why are the police here?
You won't believe this son.
Somebody killed your father!
- What? - Killed him and
fed the body to sharks.
lf he was fed to dogs,
we could have found his bones!
- To cremate him.
- Now how will we do the rites?
l can't understand what he's saying.
He's asking whose lighter this is.
l don't know. My brother never...
Why did you say the
lighter belongs to brother?
He hadn't touched a
cigarette for 20 years!
l knew Dad didn't smoke. This belongs
to the man who killed him
l lied because the
police cannot harm him.
Tell me who he is!
He fed brother to the fish!
lf l don't feed him to the
maggots, shame on my name!
Tell me who he is!
Think of where you saw this lighter.
This belongs to Pratap.
The scoundrel extended
his hand for relations...
And cheated us!
l'll kill that bastard!
No! Those who work in excitement
are either under the earth...
Or over the pyre. So we must
work with our senses not anger.
Collect all your men.
We'll attack Pratap together!
Now what do we do?
- Hide the weapons.
- Call up.
Where is everybody?
l'll check.
Well done.
l kept my promise of killing
all of Virendra's group.
Just half.
Where's my file Virendra had?
You'll get it. First you keep
your word of giving Preeti to me.
Tell me, when?
Whenever the bride and groom wish.
l can't believe somebody
can love some one so much!
As much as you love Preeti.
You killed your own father
just because l asked you to!
He wasn't my father!
- What? - A bastard like
him cannot be my father!
l made him my father
so that l can reach him.
lf he wasn't your father,
how did he accept you as his son?
Because of his wife.
His son was lost years ago.
l went to him as his lost son.
And it was not difficult convincing
a mother mad for her lost son.
What a trick!
Hunted so many with one arrow!
Virendra's wealth,
my daughter and my trust.
You turned out to be
smarter than l thought.
Today you killed Virendra
making him your father.
Tomorrow you might kill me
after l become your father-in-law.
l'm no fool like Virendra!
The file has come to me. Hence..
You're more foolish than Virendra.
You should check the bullets
before pressing the trigger.
The man who can remove your
file from Virendra's vault...
lt's not tough for him to remove
the bullets from your revolver.
l was joking, son!
Brothers-in-law joke.
Not father-in-law with son-in-law.
That is why listen
to something serious.
l killed Virendra for
DK not your daughter!
He gave me a contract
to kill three people.
One was Jaswant.
The other Virendra.
And you're the third.
Bless your daughter thanks
to whom you are still alive.
l used her as a step to reach you.
But l really love her so much...
That l can't fill her eyes with tears.
You won Preeti's heart earlier
Today you've won mine too.
Forget the heart and
think with the head.
DK wants you dead to own 100%
But l can kill him and
make you the complete owner.
- But his whereabouts..?
- l know that.
Prepare to leave for lndia.
To kill that rascal,
why just lndia..
l'm willing to go anywhere.
So far l thought l was the
luckiest girl in the world.
But today after listening
to my father and Vicky...
l've lost faith in all relations!
lf you hear, you'll die!
The one you think is
your son, is not your son!
He became your son so that
he could kill your husband.
Vicky killed your husband!
He made you a widow!
He is a cheat!
l know it.
He is not my son.
He has not cheated me.
ln fact, to lighten mother
earth of her sinful burden...
l supported him by
becoming his mother
And he didn't kill my husband!
He punished a traitor for his sins!
Those who die for their
nation are called martyrs.
Those who kill for their country
are called soldiers not killers!
And this soldier's story
started not on foreign soil...
But in the desert sands of lndia.
Where my husband and your father..
And their third partner,
Jaswant worked in the military.
They stole arms from there and
sold it to a fourth called DK.
Once Vicky's father, Major
Malhotra caught them red handed
To hide their crime,
these traitors killed him!
And blamed him for the arms theft!
We were going towards the
border with the truck of arms.
The truck had a problem so Major
Malhotra sent us to camp to get help
On the way we saw a
civilian driving the truck.
We smelled a rat and
returned to see...
All the guards were dead and Major
Malhotra and his men were ...
...loading the arms into their truck.
We challenged him and
he fired upon us in return.
We had to fire back to answer him.
On the evidence of the eye witness
account of Subhedar Pratap Singh...
Lance Corporal Virendra Sinha
and driver Jaswant Dalal...
Maj. Malhotra is charged with loot of
arms meant for the nation's defense
He is guilty of killing the
guards defending the country.
So the army terminates
his entire service.
We take back all the titles, medals
given to him and declare him a traitor
No! No!
He is not a traitor!
- Mother!
- Don't take his medals!
Sir, you know how much
he loved his country!
Then why are they snatching
away the medals in front of you?
He is a martyr not a traitor!
He has sacrificed
himself for his country!
We won't let the body be burnt!
We won't let a traitor be
cremated on our holy land!
Don't touch it!
Throw the body away!
Mother!
Mother earth took that
martyr into her lap.
Yet these traitors
had evil intentions
They put the stigma of
shame on his mother's head.
And threw her out of the village!
Sister, l've come to
take you and Raju.
We'll go and stay faraway.
No. lf l leave this place,
his soul will tell me...
That like others l too
think he's a traitor.
Take Raju away if you can.
But how will he live without you?
His welfare lies in
staying without me.
Son can forget his mother.
But the people here will remind
him of his father and kill him!
Take him away!
Will you live without me, mother?
No, my son!
You are not separating from me.
l'll be with you every
moment in every breath.
l'll go if you want me to.
And from that day to this,
neither did she see her son...
Nor did the son see his mother.
For 20 years that goddess
is still in the desert...
Tolerating the barbs of the villagers
Sitting in that same temple.
What's the matter?
l hope you don't feel you're
guilty of making me a widow?
l considered myself a widow the day..
When my own son died along with
other kids because of arms he sold!
The man who can kill the
husband's of hundreds of women..
And is responsible for
the death of innocent kids...
No lndian woman not just me...
...will adorn her hair with
the vermilion of his name!
l'm proud of you son!
The day that was lowered in shame
because of my husband's deeds...
lt is held high once
again thanks to you.
lt is said, of all God's gifts..
The most precious is mother.
l am so lucky that l have 2 of them!
What you did was out of ignorance.
But after knowing what l'm going
to do, you'll hate not love me.
Your father's name is top most
in my list of enemies.
lf a wife can support you against
her husband in your fight ...
Then a daughter can go against
her father for mankind!
Raj here.
Why did you call?
Keep contact only by fax.
No need for that now.
l'm bringing Pratap tomorrow.
My work here is done.
Now l have to come
there and do one job.
Unmask DK.
- Yes sir?
- The drama my man enacted..
Of killing you with fake bullets..
That has made my plan succeed.
How long do l have to stay here?
There's no need for you to stay.
With the information you gave me
my partner killed Virendra and his men
He's bringing Pratap here tomorrow.
So now you're free.
lt's so strange...
The story will end where it began.
Looks like you know this place.
What's the use in hiding from you?
Our business started from here.
And this is the place where
death touched us and left.
There was a scoundrel Major Malhotra.
He thought he was the
protector of the nation!
He caught us.
lf DK hadn't reached in time,
he would have killed all of us.
That dog was very strong!
But fate was with us.
We gave that scoundrel such a death!
That it's quoted as an example.
We proved the martyr a traitor.
We didn't let him be cremated!
Some will die today too.
But won't be cremated.
Of DK and his men!
Why did you stop the car?
A goddess is sitting in
this temple for 20 years.
They say anyone who sees her
gets his wishes fulfilled.
Let's go see her.
l will see her.
So that l can see
DK's corpse very soon.
For 20 years these eyes have only
seen hatred and been shunned.
l have seen them everyday.
But for the first time,
l'm seeing eyes filled with tears.
Mother!
l kept you away for 20 years!
Despite being a mother,
l didn't give you that love.
Forgive me!
No, you were not away from me.
The dust of your feet was
always with me like a blessing.
Now it's time for your wait
and my pledge to be fulfilled.
See whom l've brought here!
You mother and son can't stay here!
She won't leave like this. We'll
put such a stigma on her forehead..
That she won't be able
to face anyone!
Leave my child!
l'm the son of this goddess!
This is that goddess...
Of whose forehead you wrote
the stigma of shame, not pride!
l'm the son of Vijay Malhotra!
Who was called a traitor
despite being a martyr!
Do you know why l brought you here?
So that the soul where the
greatest injustice was done...
Justice too should be given there!
And my mother who has been
doing penance in this wilderness..
Can see justice being done!
People die but their voices don't!
Listen! Listen to the voice
of my father's torture in this sand!
Listen to a child cry
and weep for his father!
Hear the scream of a mother looking
for her husband's body in a storm!
Hear my mother's screams!
Not DK but Jaswant.
l recognized you mush earlier.
You haven't come here
but been brought here.
According to Raju's plan
l informed you of Pratap's arrival.
Because we know you would come
here to save him for your business.
And since Jaswant has been
forgiven by the law...
You'll be tried as DK not Jaswant!
You cheated your partners
for their shares.
Did you think l'd come
alone to save my man?
Wanted me to hear screams?
Now you hear the screams!
Mother!
This rascal is Vijay Malhotra's son
His father was buried here
after his death.
Bury him alive!
Let's go or he'll kill us!
Don't kill us!
l'm your father-in-law.
Will you kill me, son?
l won't kill you.
He's so merciful!
After all he's my son-in-law.
Look up.
These vultures will eat our flesh!
- Shoot us!
- Yes, kill us!
- For God's sake!
- l had pledged...
That you will neither get
the flames of a cremation...
Nor the lap of mother earth!
No!
l gave false evidence
against your father!
l had whipped him to death!
We are butchers! Remove
your revolver and kill me!
You are educated, sensible.
Why don't you kill us?
Villagers! We accept all our crimes
Save us from the vultures.
We can't even walk!
Kill us! Wait!
On your goddess like mother's
forehead, l had written...
Your husband is a traitor! You
write on my forehead with bullets.
That l'm a dog, a pig, a swine!
- Stop!
- Don't leave us and go!
Gun salute!