Subtitles: Luís Filipe Bernardes
I've something to sing about now
and I want the world to know
just why the moon's aglow
...why stars are winking up above.
I'm in love.
I've something to sing about now.
My heart is so full of song,
just couldn't hold it long
I want to brag a little love.
I'm in love.
I never knew why the robin spent hours
singing sweet little ditties to the flowers.
I thought he sang just because it was spring
la di da...
but now I know it was love
for I have felt the same thing.
I've something to sing about love.
And someday I'm gonna try singing a lullaby
Who said that heaven's up above?
I'm in love.
And that was Tina Wyatt, featured vocalist
with Terry Rooney and his orchestra.
And now it's time to say goodbye
to our old friend Terry.
In a few hours Terry will be
on his way to Hollywood to make a picture.
Good luck, Terry,
and success to you as a movie star.
Goodbye, Terry.
Goodbye, Charlie.
Goodbye, Terry. Gee, I'm sorry to see you go.
What's the use of my sticking around here
when he won't give you a night off?
I'm glad to see you go.
But I'll be back.
Bye, Terry and all kinds of good luck to you.
Goodbye, Joe.
Are we off the air, Mac?
Yep, it's all yours, Terry.
Thanks, friends, for a wonderful send-off.
As you probably know, Hollywood calls.
And I'm about to trade close-ups
with Montgomery and Taylor...
and uh...
that other big good-looking fellow,
you know, er... I mean...
uh, Gable.
and, uh, may the best profile win.
And now, by way of saying goodbye...
Hit it, you cats!
All I know is Terry told us to wait for him.
Any of you guys see the cover to this doodad?
You'd think that I might have been playing a fiddle.
What are you squawking about, Happy?
Suppose you had to carry a dog house
around all your life?
Here we are, boys, here we go!
Gather around, gentlemen, and why!
Here we are.
Champagne, champagne and more champagne.
Let's get some chairs, and the trays
and some glasses down there.
Come on, wrap yourselves around
some of this champagne.
Champagne
Wow, what is all this?
One last drink before I go, boys.
Ah, success, success, success.
Let's get all our goodbyes done here.
Boy, this is goodbye in anybody's language.
We'll call it auf wiedersehen.
Now, look.
I don't want anybody to come to the train with me.
Oh, now, wait a minute, Terry.
No, no, no. I get embarrassed.
Standing around saying goodbye, goodbye, goodbye
for a half hour.
Makes me self-conscious.
Anyway, I'll be back in a couple of weeks.
I don't know, if they get you out there in Hollywood
and make one of those movie heroes out of you.
You mean I'm a cinch, can't miss?
I ain't kidding.
You wouldn't toy with me?
Hm-hmm.
Don't worry, I'll be back.
And meanwhile you're all set.
I've seen to that.
Anyway, I'm leaving Rita with you.
Where is Rita?
Rita! Rita!
I'll call her.
Call her, will you?
Hey, Rita.
Rita, Terry wants to see you.
Come on, canary, get your nose wet.
And, uh... You don't think I'm gonna leave
my baby for long, do you?
Yeah, sweet, all for you.
For now, auf wieder all.
Good night all.
Here we go.
Hal, I've got a job for you.
Yeah?
Yeah, dig out the Wedding March in Lohengrin.
The Wedding March?
Still a good tune.
We'll give it a shot in New York.
You make a nice arrangement,
something sweet and hot.
What do you wanna do with that old tomato?
Come on, geek.
What do you need, a blueprint?
Oh, I know what you mean.
You mean something like this.
That must be Rooney.
Come on, kids.
Terry Rooney?
Yeah.
I'm Hank Meyers, Publicity Department,
Galor Studio.
Glad to meet you.
How are you, Terry? Come on, kids, okay.
This is Jan, Joan, Eleanor and Dora.
How do you do?
Out of your clothes, kids.
Come on, we got work to do here.
Straight up, that's better.
We shoot from right down there, Eddie.
There you go, girls. Light it up.
Give me that smile now.
Hold it!
That's good.
Next.
Hold that.
That's good. Next.
That's the one. Hold that now.
Good!
There we are, That's enough, kids.
Into the coats.
I'm sorry.
All right. The cars are outside.
Okay, Terry.
A car for you, too. Come on.
Hi, Toots.
How do you do?
Good morning, honey.
The name's Rooney.
Mr. Regan?
Oh, Mr. Regan...
Yes?
Mr. Regan, Mr. Hank
and Mr. Rooney are here.
Yes, sir.
Go right in.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
How do you do, Mr. Regan, I'm happy to see you.
No, that's not Regan. That's his secretary, Eddie Burns.
Well, hello, anyway.
Hi, Mr. Burns. How are you?
Mr. Regan is expecting you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Hi, B.O. Here's your new leading man
for any old for "Any Old Love".
Name's Terry Rooney.
Hi, Mr. Regan. I'm very happy to be here.
Oh, so you're happy to be here, are you?
You're happy to be here.
Of course you are.
Hollywood is the natural goal
of any actor's ambition.
You're wrong, B.O.,
he's not an actor.
He's a hoofer.
Hollywood is the natural goal of any hoofer.
And Bennett O. Regan will try
to make you an actor.
Thanks, Mr. Regan, thanks very much.
Come over here.
Yes, Mr. Regan... Oh, I'm sorry.
Come over here at once.
Come to my office immediately.
In Hollywood, Mr. er...
Rooney, Rooney.
Yes, thank you...
In Hollywood, Mr. Rooney, we create.
We create not only pictures
but actors and actresses as well.
We create and mold them.
We even try to mold hoofers.
Soon you'll find that out, Rooney.
Please, please don't turn away.
I'm speaking.
I'm so sorry.
The hair.
Do you always comb it that way?
I er...
Yes, yes I do, but er...
I can change it if it's important.
Important? Imp...
Important...
Here they are. Grief, trouble and worry.
Gentlemen.
Good evening, Mr. Regan.
This is Mr. Terry Rooney,
who's to play the male lead in "Any Old Love!
Mr. Eastman, from the makeup department.
The hairline!
Gracious!
It belongs on an entirely different face, Mr. Regan.
Well, fix it!
So easily said.
Mr. Daviani, our wardrobe expert.
The clothes. Gentlemen don't wear clothes like that.
Of course, of course.
That's why I brought you in here.
Mr. Farney, our dialogue director.
Speak to me.
Why, it's er...
It's rather hard to think of anything to say.
Would you mind to repeat this once more?
I said it was rather hard to think
of anything to say.
Once more, please.
I just said it was rather hard to think
of anything to say.
Thank you.
Impossible. The diction. Those "rs".
It will take months.
And the voice is not in the mask.
I place him in your hands.
Gentlemen!
Yes, Mr. Regan.
You have work to do.
I want to shoot him in two weeks.
Yes, Mr. Regan.
You see what I mean?
In breathing you must remember the diaphragm.
Very important. Like this.
Why, I thought I knew how to breathe.
I've been doing it a long time, you know?
Please. Now once more for the diction.
See?
The duke blew on the hunting horn
and he laughed, ha-ha,
when the hounds came running.
Like that?
Yes, exactly.
Here we go.
The duke blew on the hunting horn
and laughed, ha-ha,
when the hounds came running.
Please, don't do as I say.
Say as I do.
A bit lower, lower.
Yes.
The duke blew on his hunting horn
and laughed when the hounds came running.
Please, not, "dook", "duke".
I said "duke".
Not "laft", "laughed".
I said "laughed".
"Laughed"!
I want to hear those pear-shaped vowels.
Pear-shaped.
Which end of the pear?
The duke blew on his hunting horn
and laughed when the hounds came running.
The duke blew on his hunting horn... Lower.
The duke blew his hunting horn... A little higher, please.
The duke on blew the hunting horn
and laughed when the hounds came running.
The duke blew on the hunting horn
and laughed ahhh!
Mr. Rooney, please!
Now, look. I'm a quiet, peaceful kind of a fellow
and I'm willing to stand here all day
and let you stick pins in me.
But one more tickle
and I'm gonna break off a leg
and wrap it around your neck for a scarf.
I'm sorry, but the coat must be perfect.
Hm-hmm.
The duke blew on his hunting horn
and laughed when the...
Would you mind pulling your coat
down just a trifle?
You pull it down.
Thank you.
The duke blew on his hunting horn...
and laughed when the hounds came running.
Mr. Rooney, if you don't mind.
You distract me.
The duke blew on his hunting horn...
Was that pear-shaped enough?
You're just aggravating me.
Oh, who said?
I'm just whipping up a batch
of pear-shaped vowels.
When I look at that hairline I could almost cry.
Wait a minute.
Just a minute. I want you to see this.
Now, it will help,
you can take my word for it.
It'll help.
Now there.
The Robert Taylor...
Now look.
I've heard all I want to hear
about Robert Taylor.
This pan of mine may not be anything
to boast about
but I'm not going to wear a widow's peak.
But I...
I've worn this face of mine a long time.
I've washed it, I've shaved it...
I've sung with it, and more than once
I've fallen on it.
And if Regan doesn't like it, I'm gonna take it
right back where it came from.
But I will not wear a widow's peak.
Savvy?
Oh, Academy Award, eh?
Yes, the Academy Award.
Ah, how nice.
For which picture did you win it?
Well, we haven't won it for a picture yet
but I thought it'd be nice
to have it around to get used to it.
One gets used to so much in Hollywood.
Yes.
Never mind.
Steffie, did you see the rushes
of Terry Rooney today?
Oh, yes, I saw the rushes of him.
He's all right, I suppose.
But, um...
All right!
But I am not interested in your baby stars.
No?
No, no, no, no.
For my leading man I must have an actor.
Well, of course, Steffie, I know that you have
the privilege of choosing your leading men
for your pictures, but in this case
I think you're making a mistake.
But I am not running a school for acting.
No, Steffie, you certainly are not.
I demand a supporting cast at least
worthy of my talents.
Well, Steffie, we'll think about it.
Goodbye, dear.
Au revoir.
Hm? Oh...
The egotistical little mink coat!
What does she think she's doing.
Who does she think she is?
Take a letter.
Yes, sir.
Miss Stephanie Hajos, Galor Studios.
Dear Madam.
Where's Blaine?
On the set rehearsing Terry Rooney.
I gotta see him.
That sound ready?
Ready.
All right.
How about you, Terry?
Have you got the lines or do you want
to run through them again?
I think I know them now.
We can make a shot if you like.
All right. Let's make a take.
Come on, come on, boys.
Hurry up.
Oh, that's all right...
Remember, pear-shaped.
Pear-shaped.
Come on, come on, let's go.
Very important.
Okay.
Oh, now, go away and let me alone.
Come on, let's go.
Will you get this thing out of the way, please?
Come on, now.
Quiet, please! Roll 'em.
Speed!
Action.
Oh, Holly. Miss Emily was supposed to be here
at 8 o'clock, wasn't she?
Blaine. Mr. Blaine...
Cut!
All right, relax, everybody.
I saw the rushes this morning
and the boy is great.
He's got it, Blaine.
He certainly surprised me.
But I don't want him to know it.
You've all spoiled Stephanie Hajos
by telling her how good she was.
Now tell him he's no good.
How can you expect me to get
a performance out of him
if I continually tell him he's no good?
Well, tell him it'll take him five years
to make an actor out of him.
But don't let him see the rushes.
And I'll fire anybody who tells him
he's any good.
If I'm bad as they say in this picture as I am
I'm gonna do the sensational nose dive of the century.
It makes honorable master very happy
to joke with humble servant.
It's no joke, Ito.
At least the director doesn't think so.
Yes, please.
Honorable master would like
humble servant bring dinner?
No, thanks.
I'm sick and tired of eating in this joint.
Yes, please.
You know, Ito....
you're the only one around this studio
who'll even deign to talk to me.
And all you can say is "Yes, please".
Would you rather that I spoke ordinary English, sir?
Was that you?
Yes, sir.
My former employers felt that the accent
lent a certain dignity.
Now look here.
You're not gonna stand there in all this heat
and tell me this Japanese lingo is an act.
Oh, very much so.
Pull up a chair.
Sit down.
I want to hear about this.
Tell me about yourself.
I came here aspiring to be an actor.
And they couldn't mold you, huh?
They didn't even try.
Tell me,
how do you like being a gentleman's gentleman?
Oh, very much.
As an actor, it was a long time between meals.
What are you doing for dinner?
I know a place on Hollywood Boulevard
where they serve wonderful wiener schnitzel.
Swell. May I come along?
It's rather embarrassing, but...
there was a young lady that I had to...
Oh, I'm sorry. I shouldn't even have mentioned it.
Forgive me, will you?
Well, uh... You're probably late for your date now.
You better go on.
Oh, thank you, please.
Come on, Ito. Stop kidding me, will you?
Thank you. Thank you, please.
Will you go on. Go home.
The topper and the payoff.
A Japanese who speaks English better than I do...
with a weakness for wiener schnitzel.
It's too much for me in my weakened condition.
Hello? I want to put in a person-to-person call
to New York City.
Yes, please.
The phone's ringing! Hold it!
Rita! Hollywood's calling!
Hey, shut up, will you?
Let her talk on the phone.
Oh, hello, darling.
How are you, canary?
Darling! How are you?
Oh, lower than a whale's foot.
Silly. A whale doesn't have feet.
Did you ever see a whale's foot?
You'd be amazed.
Hm?
Oh, it was funny when I first got in.
I thought I could handle it but...
Kinda getting under my skin now.
Let's not talk about that...
I wanna forget it.
How are things with you?
We've written a new song.
You have?
Come on, sweetheart, sing it to me.
I don't care if it costs a million.
Go on. Shoot.
Wait a minute.
Wait till I get comfortable.
Okay, darling. Go on, render your song down.
Tear me apart. Go on.
It's costing him money. Hurry.
Ready?
Stop to ask the why or wherefore.
Wouldn't help me any if I would.
Only know that you're the one I care for.
Trying to reason wouldn't do no good.
Right or wrong.
This I know.
Love is just like a strong undertow
that takes me wherever you go.
Marvelous, marvelous.
Right or wrong.
Your commands
are all that my heart understands.
I'm only a slave in your hands.
Right or wrong
When you're near
All my fears,
every doubt that I have disappears.
But sweetheart
when we part
the thoughts of my longing you start
Right or wrong.
Who can tell?
When each beat of my heart knows so well.
For life may be heaven or hell
I'll string along
Right or wrong.
Hang up, will you?
Listen, you're breaking my heart.
Any more of this and I'll cut my throat.
I'm that homesick now.
Will you please hang up?
No, don't make me hang up.
You do it.
All right. Boys!
Boys on this camera,
listen to me just a minute.
I want you to take this boom up
as far as it'll go
and give me a shot of the complete set.
Got that?
All right, take your boom up
whenever you're ready.
Hold the lights. Are we all set?
All set, Mr. Blaine.
Now listen, boys.
Everybody, please.
Hey, Rooney, don't play with the props,
will you?
Andy, Andy!
Yes, Mr. Blaine.
Let's get to work. This is the last shot
in the picture and let's get it right.
I don't want much of a fight here,
but I do want it to be good.
You understand?
All right. Everybody on your toes now.
By the way, Terry, come here.
You've never staged a fight before, have you?
No, never have.
No fight, eh?
No.
Well, don't let it worry you.
It's perfectly simple.
Hm-hmm.
It's all a matter of camera angles.
You see, we'll get in an angle so that
when he makes a pass at you
it'll be like this...
Take it, let your head go back with it.
Do it again, huh?
All right.
Ready? Here we go.
That's it!
Simple as that, huh?
Simple as that.
Well, uh...
Tell me, do those other boys
know how to do it just as well as you do?
Oh, yes, don't worry about that.
They've been doing it for years.
By the way, you're not afraid,
are you, Terry?
Oh, no, no.
I don't care how hard they sock him.
I didn't make a thing he has on.
I hope somebody at last will knock
a pear-shaped vowel out of him.
I hope so.
I haven't socked a green horn actor
in months.
Get a load of this.
I heard you remark, son.
You're not afraid of us, are you?
Hey, would you do that again?
Sure.
It's all right.
You try one.
You want me to try it?
Yeah.
Close?
That's right.
Yeah, you'll do it.
Good enough?
You're okay.
Thanks.
Thanks very much.
Oh, too bad, too bad, too bad.
All right, come on, everybody. On your toes.
Let's quite down now.
Make this scene right.
Come on, boys, I want to explain this scene
once more to you before we start to shoot.
Now, Terry, on camera
you're coming down the stairway, you understand?
Joe and Eddy are hiding back there.
Oh, no like this.
I just itch to take a poke at that chin.
You should land, well, I should say about here.
Right about there?
Right about here.
Fine.
Okay? Fine, let's make a take.
Cameras ready?
Sound ready?
All right. Quiet, please.
Johnny, got your number?
I land right about there.
That's it.
That's fine, thanks.
Take your places now.
On camera.
Turn them over.
Speed!
Camera.
Cut!
Fine! Great!
Cut my foot.
Keep that traveler running.
Close that up.
Keep it going.
Up on high there. Get all this.
OK! Kill 'em!
Sock 'em!
Good for honorable master.
Get this in your camera!
Hey, what's going on here?
I'll see you later.
One, two...
three, four...
five, six.
That does it.
Yeah, please.
Hello?
Hello, darling.
Well, I'm through.
Terry! Are you all right?
Now look, sweets, pop yourself
on the first plane from San Francisco.
I'll meet you at the airport.
Oh, I'd love it.
Where are we going?
I don't know where we're going
but it'll be far away
from where they make motion pictures.
All right.
I love you, darling.
I'll be waiting.
Bye-bye, darling.
Bye.
I've something to sing about now
And someday I'm gonna try singing a lullaby
Who said that heaven's up above?
I'm in love!
I didn't know anyone can be as happy as I am.
Where are we going now?
To the City Hall for a license.
Oh, sweet, I've got a  confession to make.
Well, if it's about another girl,
I don't want to hear...
No, no, it isn't that.
I've got to tell you that my name
is not Terry Rooney.
I'll break the real one to you very, very gently.
It's uh... It's McGillicuddy.
What?
McGillicuddy.
McGillicuddy?
Hm-hmm.
But that isn't the worst.
The first name is Thaddeus.
Mrs. Thaddeus McGillicuddy.
Can you stand it?
I've always wanted to be Mrs. Thaddeus McGillicuddy.
And where are the McGillicuddies going
on their honeymoon?
South Seas, we sail this afternoon.
And what's more?
We're going on a very exclusive,
a very exclusive...
tramp steamer.
Tramp steamer?
We're the only passengers.
That's wonderful.
There it is. How do you like it?
It's the most beautiful boat I ever saw.
How are you, lad?
Mrs. McGillicuddy.
How do you do?
Come this way.
Now listen Blaine, I want that Terry Rooney picture
ready for preview and I want it immediately
But Mr. Regan, we're doing all we can.
We're working 24 hours a day.
Well, work 25 hours a day if necessary.
Now when do I get the picture?
In about three weeks.
Well make it two.
Cutting room.
When will the Rooney picture be ready for preview?
It'll take us at least two weeks, Mr. Regan.
One?
Hey, Harry, where's that close-up
with Rooney in the fight sequence?
Look in the tin can.
Any old love,
any hugs today...
Any old kisses
that you want your way, say
I'm just the fellow to see.
A bona fide collector of anything to do with love
and if you should find
a moon up in the sky
and love on your mind
babies, don't you cry.
Just say this till I come your way.
Hm?
Any old love today?
Oh, mister...
how about tonight?
Good, marvelous... I predicted that boy
would be a star the minute I saw him.
Do you still want me to go on telling him
he's no good?
By the way, Rooney ought to be here
right now to sign his contract.
Is Terry Rooney up there?
He's not here, Mr. Regan.
Well, find him.
I'm waiting for him.
Good, good...
I'm getting tired of saying "good".
Oh, Hank, a terrible thing has happened.
We can't find him.
Terry Rooney.
He's disappeared.
He's gone.
We can't find him.
He's vanished.
Oh, I see.
And you're all afraid to tell Regan.
Now don't quarrel, boys.
Let me tell him.
Disappeared?
I hope the poor boy didn't commit suicide.
That's ridiculous!
Yeah? He got some pretty rough treatment
around here.
I make a star out of him
and you call it rough treatment.
Get on the telephone. Call his orchestra.
Call New York.
Hank, we've got to find that boy.
First, I'll have the harbor dragged.
Hank...
Hank, please, stop!
Hank, dear old boy, dear old pal...
I'm depending on you now
more than I've ever depended on you before.
Hire detectives. Do anything.
But find Rooney and bring him here...
before he knows he's a success.
Now hurry, hurry!
Maybe we best start with the morgue.
Good, good, excellent.
Good, good...
Hello! Hello!
Any news?
Oh.
Not a thing.
Hours of working, waiting, wondering.
And for what?
Nothing.
We're no nearer to finding Terry Rooney now
than we were when we started.
Why do I have to be crucified like this?
Any news?
Plenty of news.
But it's all bad.
Nothing but mystery.
But I can't get the idea of suicide out of my mind.
Torture me with that word once more
and you're through with Galor Pictures.
Oh, I'm just as anxious to find him as you are.
He borrowed 5 bucks from me the other day
in the lunch room.
Five bucks.
Yeah.
Five dollars and I'm talking in millions.
Five dollars means a lot to me on my salary.
Hank, find him and I'll double your salary.
Agreed. He's found.
I mean, I'll find him.
Just a minute.
Is this some foul scheme of yours?
Are you holding out on me?
Oh, B.O. ...
I wouldn't do that.
Terry Rooney, where are you?
My Terry!
...change of bites, he bites left...
brown boy against the ropes...
right white boy...
Come on, white boy, that's it.
Oh, right...
Right, left, right and left...
Brown boy's down!
Eight, nine, ten, he's out!
Ladies and gentlemen,
you've missed the most terrific fight in years.
Pandemonium, we're facing an uproar!
Man overboard!
Goodbye, McGillicuddy.
When you get to Chicago look us up, will you?
You bet!
Take good care of our little sweetheart.
I will.
See you in the next trip, Mac.
Isn't this a terribly expensive suite?
Yep.
Can we afford it?
No.
Do you care?
Wait a minute, leave that on.
We're going out take a nice long walk
so we can get our land legs.
Good?
Oh, you have such lovely ideas, Thaddeus.
Oh, Mrs. McGillicuddy. I strive to please.
In fact, I strive to please Mrs. McGillicuddy.
How do you feel now?
Oh, I feel much better.
Got your land legs yet?
Yes.
That's Terry Rooney.
Both of them?
Yes.
Hey, is there something strange about me?
People seem to be staring at me.
What is it?
Oh, it's because you're so beautiful, darling.
You think that's it?
Yes.
Well, it has been said.
Look what we have here.
One of those movie palaces.
Do you know that in places like these people
actually earn a living making faces?
Really?
Absolutely. I know a man who did it.
For example, they do things like this, uh...
the double take,
And then there would be the triple take
which was, uh...
And the triple take with a slow burn...
with a one-eye fade away, which was this.
And uh..
Do another one.
Another one? Well, there was the Charlie Murray,
who always did this.
Now you see what a motion picture
career can do for you?
That woman thinks I'm crazy.
Come on, make some more faces.
Not on your life. I'm through for the evening.
Is it my imagination or...
or am I hearing my voice?
There's nothing strange at that.
You're talking.
That isn't what I mean.
I'm singing someplace.
Now, Terry.
No...
It's "Any Old Love" from the picture.
Ahhh, Mr. Terry Rooney.
Please, take this flower
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
It's coming from over there.
Why, look. They have pictures of you
plastered all over the place.
Yes, darling. Things have been happening
while we've been away.
But you didn't tell me they made
any records of you.
They didn't. They probably took them
from the soundtrack.
Hello, Mr. Rooney.
Your performance was lovely.
Thank you.
Very fine performance, Mr. Rooney.
Very glad you're back again.
Please, Mr. Rooney, may I have your autograph?
Yes.
May I have your autograph, Mr. Rooney, please?
Rita! Rita, where are you?
What's going on out there?
A fire, a riot or what?
Terry Rooney's out there.
Terry Rooney?
Yeah. Come on,
let's get him and bring him in.
Mr. Rooney said that he'd meet you at the hotel.
Thank you.
Guess you know what that means.
Terry Rooney!
Get them out of the lobby.
Get me the Galor Studios in Hollywood right away.
Say, what is this all about?
It's about you.
Can you tell me where on earth you've been?
Yes, certainly, the South Seas. Why?
Why, he asks me why.
Give me that phone quick.
Hello?
Hello, this is the manager of the Belvedere Theater
in San Francisco.
I've got Terry Rooney here in my office.
What... who...Hold the phone!
Rooney! Found him.
San Francisco.
Telephone.
What?
Yes.
Mr. Regan! Mr. Regan!
They found Terry Rooney. San Francisco.
Telephone.
Hello! Hello!
Give me that call for Mr. Regan.
Call the airport and have the fastest plane
standing by for San Francisco.
Give me the phone, boss.
Nr Regan wants to talk to you.
Regan?
Yeah.
Hello, B.O.
Huh? What are you saying...
Oh, hello, Hank.
Where are you staying?
Have you talked to any reporters?
No, I haven't talked to anybody.
Nobody.
Well, nobody but a crazy manager,
if that means anything.
Swell, don't talk to him. Don't talk to anyone.
Don't even talk to yourself.
All right, but...
you ought to see what they did to my hat.
B.O. and I are leaving right away by plane.
Yeah, right away.
Just as soon as we can get to the airport.
Now for the love of Mike
don't talk to anybody, will you?
Hide in the closet till we get there.
Here we come. Goodbye, kid.
Come on, B.O., let's get out of here.
The contract!
Thanks a lot!
Thanks for what?
For all the publicity I'll get out of this.
Gosh, Mr. Rooney, you don't realize...
I guess they must have liked the picture, huh?
Liked it? Liked it?
Hey, canary!
Yes?
Can you see it from there?
Yes, I can see it from here.
You can see from both of these.
Oh, darling. I'm so proud of you
I don't know what to do.
To think I married a celebrity
and didn't even know it.
Oh, 'twas nothing at all.
Anybody in my place would have done the same.
You're not having a slight attack of swell head, are you?
Yes, darling, I'm afraid so.
I've got that good old feeling coming over me now.
You now owe me 129 million dollars.
Hm-hmm. Give me a bag-o-tail.
I'll settle for a box of candies.
You'll take chewing gum and like it.
Probably Hank and the National Guard.
I have to fix my hair. It's a mess.
You go get yourself fixed up...
I won't say anything about you.
You stage a surprise entrance.
Fix the door so I can hear a bit.
All right. Don't miss a word.
Who's there?
Mr. Regan to see you.
Regan?
Step right this way, sir.
Terry, my boy!
Hey, kid.
Hi, Terry.
Hank, I'm glad to see you.
Baby, when I say I'm glad to see
I'm just beginning to talk.
Say, Hank, I want you to forgive me for putting
the slug on you the last time I saw you, but you know...
Forget that. I had it coming to me.
Where have you been?
I've been running myself bald looking for you.
Terry, here's the contract all ready for you to sign.
Now look, B.O., let's get our hellos over with
have a little drink or something
and then we talk about the contract later, huh?
While you're talking you just take a look
at that money.
Better take a peek, Terry.
Did you read this?
Every word of it.
See those figures?
And you're worth every penny.
Do you know what that picture's doing across the street?
It's doing very well.
Very well? It's terrific!
Wait a minute, wait a minute...
I can't sign this.
What's wrong?
I just can't sign it.
Why?
Pardon me, I...
Oh, this is Mrs. McGillicuddy.
This is Hank.
Nobody knows his last name anymore.
And this is Mr. Regan,
How do you do?
But why can't you sign the contract?
The reason herself.
What has Mrs. McGillicuddy got to do
with the contract?
Of course we don't know what arrangements
you have with her, Terry
but this is a...
Now, look, pulp head, you don't understand.
Rita is my wife.
My real name is McGillicuddy.
And it says in the contract
that I must remain single.
Your wife? But you can't.
You can't have a wife.
But I have and I'm going to keep her.
Look at that thing, darling,
that top clause there... it's silly!
Well, darling, if this is for just one picture
we could go on keeping it a secret.
One picture, it's for seven years.
And look at the dough.
But I have an idea.
This is for so much money,
why couldn't we take less and still be married?
Hang on to yourself, sweetheart.
Now listen, tell me.
What is this all about anyway?
Don't they have married people in Hollywood?
Why a silly clause like that?
Don't you understand? You're the potential
heart interest of every woman in America.
It's your stock-in-trade.
Yes.
Isn't that charming.
You think I can handle it?
Oh, Terry.
Look.
If you think I'm gonna give up this gal
for any movie contract, you are crazy.
You two are very nice and I thank you.
But we are going back where we belong
with the band.
That's very sweet of you, darling.
But this is too important to decide that bet.
Why couldn't I go to Hollywood as just a visitor?
As Mrs. Thaddeus McGillicuddy.
What a moniker. Thaddeus McGillicuddy.
We like it.
Are you kidding, Terry?
No, absolutely on the level.
I'm sorry, Hank,
but it was given to me while I was asleep.
Well, I'm glad you woke up in time to change it.
Well, couldn't I?
Couldn't you what?
Wait a minute.
I think I got it. Come here, B.O. Listen to this.
Come here, Terry.
Would you be willing to go down to Hollywood
and go to work?
I mean, take a job, a cover-up job?
Why, certainly.
That's swell.
Now we have nothing to worry about.
Here's what you do.
You come down to Hollywood as Terry's
confidential secretary.
Take care of all his personal affairs,
fan mail and all that stuff, huh?
Hank...
Would you do that?
Of course, darling.
I think it's marvelous.
You're a genius sometimes.
Sometimes I think I deserve more dough.
All right, come on. Give me the contract.
Here you are, Terry.
Amateur! That nobody!
Hi, Daisy.
How do you do, Mr. Hank?
Glad to see you.
Well, good morning.
How's everything, Snooks?
Don't Snooks me.
What, I ask you, what is that?
What? Why, it's a bungalow.
Yes, I know. But whose?
Whose, why, I don't know. Let me see.
Don't stall with me. You know.
Do I?
It's Terry Rooney's.
Is it?
You know darned well it is.
Five rooms and three baths.
What, I ask you, is he going to do
with three baths?
He's not running a laundry.
Although he should be.
Who lives here?
Mrs. McGillicuddy.
And this is her hideaway.
You remember Mrs. McGillicuddy?
Yes, I have a vague recollection.
And you come to see her.
Oh, do I?
Every night?
No, not every night.
The neighbors might talk.
Who?
The neighbors.
Hm-hmm.
Who cares for the neighbors?
Shhh!
That'll take care of them.
Why don't you get some lights on in here?
Well, why don't you take off your glasses?
Oh, never thought of that.
You look silly in them anyway.
I suppose I gotta go on wearing these.
Well, Hank thinks it's a good idea.
I see.
Oh, and here's the stairway.
It leads to two of the cutest bedrooms
you ever saw.
How many?
Two.
We can rule out the other one.
So you think I should carry him along, eh?
Help build him up?
Now listen, darling.
You come in with me on this...
and I'll team you with Rooney for more publicity
than you've seen in a year.
Get this. Hollywood's newest  love interest!
Do you like it?
Hm-hmm.
Why, they'll eat it up.
I adore it.
Good!
For Galor.
Good again. I'll get started with the story.
Leave it to me, honey.
Lots of publicity and a good story.
Just leave the whole thing to me.
All for me!
Cut! Cut! Cut!
Steffie, darling, what is the matter?
You're not giving me anything.
Can I make a love scene with a icicle?
He doesn't give me anything. Nothing!
Terry...
Oh, I know, I know it's bad.
Listen, I can give you the scene
if you just get these people off the set.
Imagine that guy getting to have a medal.
Doesn't take long for their heads to start swelling.
That's not so.
Oh, you too, eh?
Listen, don't you go going gaga over that guy.
You're not in his class.
He only goes for stars.
Like Stephanie.
Oh, is that so?
Yes, that's so.
That was no tempering, Blaine.
Something upset me on the set.
I think I can give you the scene now.
All right, Terry, but look.
Warm up to Steffi a little bit.
She needs it.
All right, sure.
Uh, Steffie.
Yes?
Please forgive me for blowing up.
You see, you're such a very great actress
and I'm actually no actor at all.
I never even expected to be on the same set with you.
I guess I'm a little bit scared.
It's so sweet of you to say
those things to me.
Will you go through it once again with me?
I will.
All right. Let's do it once again now.
Come on.
Action!
But I can't give you up like this, darling.
But it is so difficult with things as they are now.
I can't give up hope. It's all I have.
Maybe someday in some faraway place.
No, no. No faraway place, darling.
No faraway place.
Here and now.
Here and now!
Is that what you mean?
Perfect!
The boy has talent.
Sorry, canary, I had to do that to you.
But I had to.
But the only reason I came on the set
is because I haven't seen you for two or three days.
Yeah, I know.
I couldn't play that love scene when I knew
you were there standing watching me.
I had an impulse to drop her
and rush over to you.
Now I want to play a love scene with you.
Now, Terry...
You're not gonna try and run away from me,
are you?
No, but I...
It won't do any good, all the doors are locked.
Someone may look in the window.
The windows can take care of themselves.
But Ito...
Ito's too smart.
Hi, Terry.
Don't you ever knock, chump.
I see you're rehearsing the little scene
you told me about. Looks good too.
A critic, huh?
Well, I'm glad you like it.
Thanks, it certainly does look good.
I'd like to have you know Miss Robbins.
How do you do, Mr. Rooney?
Oh, how do you do, Miss Robbins?
How do you do, I'm very happy to meet you.
We were just going over the fan mail situation.
Oh, I thought it was a rehearsing.
Well, yes and no, you see.
Sometimes they rehearse
while they're running through the fan mail.
Oh, I see.
Yes, I'm glad you do.
Mrs. McGillicuddy, will you run and see if the mail
is ready to sign, please.
Right away. Pardon me.
Thanks.
She's my confidential secretary.
Very confidential, I expect.
You'd be surprised.
And very pretty too.
Yeah, we think so, don't we, Terry?
Well, for a secretary.
But then again the...
average run of girls around here
have very high standards of looks, you know.
If you'll excuse me, I'll run inside
and get out of this collar...
before it cuts my throat.
Go right ahead. Take your time, Terry.
Wait a minute. What are you up to now?
Just a little blind item for my column.
What rising young star was caught
making love to his pretty secretary?
Now listen. If you print that story,
you're going to ruin two lives.
What lives?
Yours and mine.
Oh...
First of all, if you print it,
I'm gonna sock you on the nose.
Oh...
And if I sock you on the nose,
I'm gonna lose my job so figure it out.
But it's a story.
Yeah? Well there's a bigger story
than that around here...
if somebody was bright enough to spot it.
What?
Listen...
do you think Terry Rooney would be fooling around
with a funny little secretary
with a glamorous dame like Stephanie Hajos
here in the studio?
Oh, Hank!
Yeah, you better sharpen your pencil.
That's very interesting.
Now. There's one thing I'm sure
all our readers will want to know.
What is your ideal of feminine beauty?
Well, I er...
That's a funny thing you should ask him
a question like that.
You know, Terry was saying to me only this morning
that his idea of feminine beauty is Stephanie Hajos.
A little less statuesque then Venus de Milo, perhaps.
More delicate, possibly. More flaming.
Am I right, Terrence?
Exactly my words.
In fact, practically verbatim.
How lovely!
Now, Mr. Rooney...
won't you tell me what was your first,
your childhood love?
Well, you see, what Terry...
Oh, Hank, may I handle this one, please?
Well, my first, my childhood love...
That goes way back, way back...
In fact, she was the dog catcher's daughter
in my home town.
And every time my pooch was snatched...
Your what?
Every time they snatched my pooch...
Oh...
She'd get it back to me by hook or by crook.
In fact it happened so often that her old man
began to think my dog was quintuplets.
One of the characteristic things about Terry
is his love for animals.
Particularly dogs.
Please, honorable master,
excuse humble servant.
Oh, they want me on the set?
Thank you, please.
Well, I'm awfully sorry to break up
this luncheon this way
It's was awfully pleasant.
It's been delightful.
You will come again, will you?
Oh, yes, thank you so much.
I've enjoyed it. And anything you want
just call Ito, he's here.
Hank, thanks so much.
What a quaint servant. What's his name?
Uh, Ito.
Ito.
Oh, he adores Terry.
Why, when Terry disappeared we had trouble
restraining Ito from committing Charlie Cary.
Or a Harry Carryl.
Nice interview, huh?
Did you get everything you wanted?
Plenty.
Having Hog's tea?
Hi, Terry boy, how are you feeling?
Oh, fine.
Good. Here's your tickets.
Tickets for what?
Tickets for the opening of part you're playing tonight.
You're taking Stephanie.
Oh, yes?
I'm not going to any opening tonight.
What do you mean you're not going
to any opening?
I am not going to any opening tonight.
I've been working for a week on this.
The reporters, the photographers,
they're all gonna be there. It's important to me!
Now look, you can save yourself all that.
I am not going to any opening.
Oh, stay and let me talk to you,
why do you want to act like this for?
Wait a minute, what about Stephanie?
You can take her and put her
back in the woodwork.
Don't be so unreasonable.
When I say a thing is important it's important.
I can't just stand...
Now look!
I've got a wife and I like her.
And I'm gonna see her once in a while.
Cut out that wife stuff, will you?
I am not going to any opening!
Come here and listen to me, will you?
What do you want to be such a bull head?
Billy, call Mr. Regan on the phone
and tell him to go right over to Rooney's bungalow.
Yes, sir.
That boy's going nuts again.
Get me Mr. Regan's office.
Quick! Certainly it's important.
Now, Terry, why don't you do this for me?
You know what I do for you.
Why, I've worked my head to the bone
to put you on top.
And I'd cut my arm off to...
off to here to keep you there.
Having me run around every night with
Stephanie Hajos is keeping me on top, huh?
Say, what am I, an actor or a stooge?
I'm supposed to be an actor.
Well, at least that's the rumor.
Well, if I'm not good enough,
I can always go back with the band.
And something tells me
I'd be a whole lot happier if I did.
But Terry, you've got a duty to the...
I've got a duty to myself and my wife.
And that fine elaborate scheme you worked up
in San Francisco isn't gonna work either.
It's got me and Rita absolutely insane.
While I'm out to previews, and openings
and cocktail parties and testimonial dinners,
all for the glory of your dear old Galor,
she sits up in the hill swirling her thumbs.
She isn't yelling, is she?
No, she's too good a sport for that,
But I know how she feels and I don't blame her.
He's right, B.O.
Of course he is.
We've been entirely unfair to Rita.
I can see now the whole situation
has been a terrific strain on her.
Terry, will you let me do something?
With your permission, may I?
Hank, get a drawing room to New York.
Wire the office there and get a reservation
to the best hotel
and get tickets for every theater in town.
Right.
For Rita.
Now what kind of a solution is that?
Wait a minute.
That's only half the plan.
Terry, when you finish this picture
I'm going to a four weeks' vacation.
To go to New York and be with Rita.
That's great, B.O.
There you are, Terry.
That solves the problem.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Let me understand this.
You promise me four weeks off
after I finish this picture?
Yes.
Four weeks?
Successively?
Successively and positively.
If you go to the opening tonight.
All right.
That's great.
Fine, Terry.
That's swell of you, B.O.
See what a grand time those two kids
are gonna have on those four weeks.
What four weeks?
Every time I put this vest on I think of Regan.
All front and no back.
What time do you think you'll be home?
Oh, I don't know, darling.
You know how these things are.
I may have to stay in town if I expect
to be on the set at nine in the morning.
Do you have to go?
Well, you know, practically a command performance.
Darling, listen to me.
This isn't going to work out trying to live this way.
I know that.
It's a dog's life for you and...
I don't mind telling you
that it's getting the best of me.
It's driving me crazy.
Look, darling. We've got an idea.
How would you like to go East and visit your mother
and see the boys while I finish the picture?
I could join you in, say, three or four weeks
and then we could go someplace together
where nobody ever heard of pictures.
All right, if you want me to.
No, wait...
I didn't say I wanted you to.
I just thought it might be a good idea.
That's what I mean.
What are you doing?
I'm not going.
Oh, yes, you've got to go.
I am not going!
But you made a promise...
and you mustn't break it.
Here, get into this.
Sure you understand?
Perfectly.
I've hurt you, haven't I?
No.
Well, you don't like the idea of going East.
I really haven't given it much thought.
You said you wanted me to go...
I did not say I wanted you to go.
Oh, I must have misunderstood.
All I meant to say was that Regan promised
if I went to the opening tonight,
you could go East and I could possibly
join you later. That's all!
Well, then, by all means go!
What is the matter with us?
Here we are standing here arguing
like a couple of children over nothing at all.
No, nothing. You've arranged
for me to go East, that's all.
And I'm going.
I did not arrange for you to go East!
Oh, put on your coat and go to your opening.
I have a lot of packing to do anyway,
and you'd only be in the way if you stayed.
I probably would.
Hi, canary.
Well, Rita, hello, how have you been?
Where have you been?
Oh, just a little trip to California.
I see the boys are still here.
Yes, they're still here.
Why I don't know. Look at this business.
Do you mind if I go up and say hello to them?
No, no, go right ahead.
Rita, stop in my office and see me
before you go, will you?
Thank you.
Who's doing that?
Somebody's singing.
Sounds like Rita's voice.
I want to croon
???
Then I found you
it was love from the start
and I traded my heart
for an angel
from out of the blue.
Rita, when did you get back?
So glad to see you!
Mr. Richards, can we have five minutes, please?
Can you have five minutes?
You're taking it, aren't you?
Go on back and get your hellos over.
Baby, when I heard that voice
I knew who it was right away.
Boy, am I happy.
Is she coming back to sing with the band?
We ought to ask her to.
Yes, I saw Terry in Hollywood.
Everything is coming along beautifully for him
and he's coming East in about four weeks.
Is there any truth to the stories the paper
about him and that Hajos dame?
Just a lot of press agent drool.
You're sure?
Well, I know the press agent.
Boy, I'm sure glad to hear that. We were all
beginning to get worried, weren't we?
Yeah, we thought... well, you know what he said
when he left the band.
About you being on the West Coast and everything...
Stop kicking me, will you?
Well, I guess I'd better go in
and get the piano warmed up...
Telling her isn't going to be easy, you know.
But you must.
I can't stand the idea of hurting her.
We have reached the point where you and I
are the only things that matter.
That's the way I feel, you know that, don't you?
Hm?
Cut!
That's swell.
Print that!
Can that pair play a love scene?
Why not?
Terry, I'm proud of you.
Those pear-shaped vowels were perfect.
Bless your hearts, children,
I could kiss you both.
Don't you kiss me.
I'll let Steffi do it for me.
Why, gladly.
I think we are wonderful.
No doubt about it.
Come on, let's go in and say hello to Terry.
Hello, Mr. Rooney.
Hello.
Amy, darling!
Hello, Steffi.
That last scene was a knockout.
You liked it?
Terry, you know Miss Robbins, of course.
Yes, sure.
We'll book for an interview Sunday.
Sunday?
Oh, yes, that's right. Sunday it is.
We'll have a good long gab this time.
Very happy to see you.
If you'll excuse me, I gotta go change my tie.
Bye-bye.
Miss Robbins, wouldn't you like to sit down?
How's the play coming?
Excuse me, Mr. Blaine,
I'm going to steal Amy from you.
Oh, yes, of course.
Amy, will you come with me
while I fix my makeup?
You have an interview with me today.
I have something most exciting to tell you.
Why, Steffi!
Something about Terry and me.
Where does it go from here?
Fine bunch of musicians.
Have a girl run your band.
Oh, I guess we missed her.
We miss Terry too, of course, but...
Terry? You can kiss him goodbye.
He's cooked.
What do you mean?
Haven't you seen the paper?
No.
What's the matter? Is he hurt?
Stephanie Hajos reveals engagement to Rooney.
Sensational dancing star and exotic actress
plan to make their real romance real...
when their current picture ends.
I thought something terrible had happened.
This is just more silly stuff.
Doesn't look like silly stuff there.
Don't be ridiculous. Besides, it's impossible
for him to be engaged to Steffi.
Why is it impossible?
Because we...
Well, we hadn't intended telling you
until he came East but...
we're married.
Married? Why didn't you tell us?
We thought you were working out there.
Hey, wait a minute. How can they print
about him being engaged to her...
when all the time he's married to you?
That's what I've been trying to tell you.
Give me that!
All right, take your places, girls, please.
Come on.
Oh, come on, girls, please.
Blaine.
Just a minute, Hank, please.
I wanna talk to you, Blaine.
All right, what is it?
Relax, girls.
You've seen this, haven't you?
What?
Well, she certainly laid it on thick.
Yeah, but you can read that later.
Now, listen.
Nobody has got to Terry with this yet
and nobody's gonna get to him.
I've got both doors guarded.
That boy'll kill me if he sees this story.
Why should he kill you?
As a publicity gag it's all right.
Yeah, but there's a lot more than you can see,
you can take my word for that.
Murder is the least he'll do to me.
Where's Stephanie?
I don't know. she's not working today.
I know that.
Did she happen to say where she's gone?
No.
Well, she's not home and I've paged
every beauty shop in Hollywood.
The girls already in waiting?
Oh, yes, please.
Well, well.
Very cute.
Oh, do you like it?
Oh, Mr. Blaine.
Hm?
Is this the one I'm supposed to marry?
Oh, no!
My luck.
Hi, kid, how goes it?
Well, what dirty press agent trick
are you up to now?
No, you're wrong.
I'm working on a high spiritual plane.
I'm praying, my boy.
Praying, huh?
You'll never know how hard I'm praying.
How nice for you.
Well, what's doing?
Who's murdering who today?
Oh, nobody murdered anybody. Gimme that.
I'm doing a crossword puzzle.
I'll get you another one.
You ain't mad, are you?
No.
All right.
I'm ready whenever you are.
All right, Terry.
My dear Terry, I want to be the first
to congratulate you.
On what?
On what?!
Get out of here!
What is this?
It's B.O.'s orders that you're not
to be disturbed while you're working.
He oughta know better than that.
Congratulations, Terry, my boy!
Say, what is the matter with you?
There's nothing the matter with me.
It's an old superstition...
that an actor can't be congratulated
until his picture is finished.
He oughta know that.
Mr. Rooney...
He's out?
Yeah, he's out cold.
Take him outside and give him a little air.
That's all he needs.
I brought it for your scrap book...
Wait a...
So this is what you've been doing.
You're trying to keep this from me.
I'm not trying to keep anything from you, Terry.
My word of honor.
I've nothing to do with this.
Your idea of publicity.
My idea of nothing.
Take my word for it, Terry.
I have nothing to do with it.
Nothing to do with it.
And I thought you were my friend.
I am your friend.
Let me explain a thing to you.
I haven't anything to do with that,
you gotta believe me.
Let me explain it to you!
Will you go away?
Where's Ito?
Ito!
Ito...
Follow Mr. Rooney to his bungalow
and beg him to stay there till I come, will you?
Yes, sir.
What a day and what a life!
Mr. Hank, Mr. Hank!
Miss Hajos just drove up to her bungalow.
Miss Hajos?
That lets me out.
Hold everything!
See you later, Daisy, you're excused.
I don't know whether to kill you for that story or...
kiss you for showing up.
How dare you!
Oh, don't give me that
how dare you stuff today, Steffie.
You got me in a jam.
I only did what you told me to do.
I got Galor Studio a million dollars' worth of publicity.
I certainly didn't tell you to say
you were engaged.
Do you mean to tell me that he objects
to being engaged to me for a few weeks?
Objects? He does nothing but object!
I, Stephanie Hajos, the great star,
condescends to link my name with this hoofer?
And he objects? He objects?
I won't speak to him again.
I won't even finish the picture.
Tell him in public I am through.
Oh, you're through all right.
Unless you go with me to Terry Rooney's house
and tell him you're responsible for this.
You'll go if I have to drag you by the hair of the head.
You can't talk to me like this.
I never wanted to smack a woman, but...
I'm awful close to it right now.
Go ahead and strike me, you woman striker.
Oh, Steffie, I didn't want to have to tell you this,
but I suppose I'll have to.
The boy is married.
But why don't you tell me things like this?
Because we were trying to keep it a secret.
Trying? It seems to me you have succeeded.
Now, you don't want to hurt
Terry and his wife, do you?
I don't want to hurt anyone.
I've been hurt so many many times.
I know what it is to be hurt.
I will go with you.
But please...
Please don't scold me anymore.
Oh, darling, you're a haywire dame.
But I love you.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Come on, Steffie.
We want Mr. Rooney.
Terry!
Terry Rooney!
Where is he?
Honorable master, he no home.
Cut off the honorable master stuff.
He's no home, huh?
Any idea where he went?
No, sir, please.
Did you phone the studio?
What good are you around here?
No, sir, please.
No, sir...
Hello, give me the gate.
Why didn't you follow him
when he left the stage?
No, sir, please.
No, sir...
Has Terry Rooney come back to the lot?
What don't you do something?
No, sir, please.
Why don't you beat it?
I resent your tone.
I came out to Hollywood to be an actor,
not a servant.
I shall go. In your own vulgarism,
I shall beat it and I shall not come back.
I bid you good day.
Did you....
Oh, grand pappy's cracking up under the strain.
I fear poor old grand pappy's going nuts.
Get on the wire, Rita, will you?
Rita, will you please call him?
All right. If it'll make you fellas any happier.
You'd think he was your husband instead of mine.
Am I worried?
No, I'm not worried, but you're...
Hello, I want to put in a person-to-person call
to Terry Rooney at the Galor Studios in Hollywood.
Yes.
You're going to see how ridiculous all this is.
Imagine doubting Terry.
I thought he was gonna get us in his second picture.
Oh, but Candy, it wasn't that kind of a picture.
There wasn't a band in it.
Every picture's got a band in it.
A least a fiddle.
No?
Well then, try Hollywood 12521.
Yes.
That's our hideaway.
It's the cutest little house.
Hello?
Hello? Is Mr. Terry Rooney there?
Who is this speaking?
This is a friend of his.
Hello?
What's the matter, Rita?
You win.
That was Stephanie Hajos at the house.
Gee, I'm sorry, chicken.
Don't be.
I can't stand people being sorry for me.
At our hideaway.
He took her to our house.
Our house.
It's like the old saying.
As you sow...
So what?
I'll get it.
Hello, Mr. Richards.
Well, how are you boys?
Would you really like to know?
Yes, and how's the little lady?
Oh, swell, she's fine.
Well, hello there. I'm glad to see you.
We finally got the break at last.
It's on the front page of every newspaper in town
that Mrs. Terry Rooney is singing at the Palomino Roof.
How did you know I was Mrs. Terry Rooney?
Well, I overheard you telling the boys
on the stage and uh...
while I was standing in the bar a newspaper man,
a friend of mine, overheard me mention it.
Well, Mrs. Terry Rooney is not singing
at the Palomino Roof.
Oh, now listen, girlie...
And don't call me girlie.
If you think you can use us just because
you overheard what I was telling the boys,
you're wrong.
Now listen.
For one night only. Just for tonight.
I'll give you a thousand dollars.
Every table has been reserved by telephone.
We sold out before we opened.
There'll be a riot if Mrs. Terry Rooney doesn't appear.
Get out.
Oh, now, listen...
She said out.
And, brother, she don't mean in.
Oh, so that's the way it is, huh?
Well, now let me tell you fellows something.
You get down there and get those instruments
before they hit the ash can.
Boys, you'd better go with him.
Will you be all right?
Just sit tight, chicken. Everything's gonna be all right.
I'm gonna get my flute...
Mr. Rooney, may I congratulate you?
I hope you'll have a lot of happiness.
Is something the matter?
Is there anything I can do for you?
No, thank you.
I can't think of anything that would help.
Oh.
Well, do you still want us?
Do I still...
It'll cost you 2 thousand bucks for the night
and we knock off at 12:30.
Oh, listen to reason.
Give us a quick yes or no.
Yes.
And in advance.
Boys, you can trust me.
And in advance too.
Okay, Maurice!
Maurice, hurry up.
Get those waiters ready.
Get some more tables and the flowers.
Let's see. You want eight uppers,
eight lowers and a compartment, right?
No compartment. I'll take a lower.
All right. Go on, boys. Get ready.
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I have your attention, please?
I take great pleasure in personally introducing to you
Mrs. Terry Rooney.
Right or wrong
this I know.
love is just like a strong undertow
that takes me wherever you go.
right or wrong.
I've never seen the moon
out shining in the sky.
But why do I want to cry?
I guess it's just 'cause I
can't convince...
All these are going to car 43 down at the station.
The trunks are down there already.
All right. I'll get a couple of men to help me.
that's what loving you is for me.
I love you, I do.
My whole life is yours.
The reason for my smile,
for loving all the while.
All right.
Hello, Holly. Who's doing all the travelling?
We all are. We're getting out of here.
Where's Rita?
She's on, doing her number.
She's going along with us.
Wait a minute, Terry, I wouldn't interfere.
She's made up her mind.
Made her mind on what?
About getting out of here.
Now look, you go in there
and tell the boys to start my music.
I can't do that, Terry. She told me...
Get in there and tell the boys to star my music!
Come on!
I've learned it from your own lips.
Though life may be heaven or hell
I'll string along
right or wrong.
Hit it, you cats.
Come on, canary, get into your cage.
Subtitles: Luís Filipe Bernardes.