Thanks.
Can I have a room?
Yes, but it won't be that comfortable.
It doesn't matter,
as long as I can sleep.
Do you want a meal?
Just a drink.
I heard this hill
is called Pansori Hill,
and this inn is called Pansori Inn.
Is it because of your Pansori?
Then someone sang
Pansori before you did?
Yes.
They were named after him.
Then did you learn Pansori from him?
No, but I learned it
from his daughter.
Why don't you sing some of it?
I'll play the drum.
I shall go.
I shall go after my love.
Even where the winds and clouds rest.
Along with the wild geese in flocks.
Over the Dongseolryung Hill,
I shall follow my love.
Although the galaxy is blocked...
The Altair and the Vega meet once a year.
Why has my love not come yet?
I shall die now and become a swallow.
Make a nest under the roof.
Meet my love at night.
And reminisce my love.
Who caused this eternal separation?
What shall I do without my love?
I cry in secret.
That's nice.
Who's that?
A Pansori singer invited by Yoon.
Since Yoon's fortunes were on the wane,
he just invited a vagabond Pansori singer.
I'm going to Gangjin tomorrow.
I heard Chosun will perform during
the ceremony at the rice mill./Yes.
You're going to stay here longer, huh?
Yes, I'm going to.
I have no other place to go.
After a secret royal inspector appeared,
they gathered.
With a wooden club, the royal seal
which is like the moon.
From all directions, they're gathering.
-The secret royal inspector has come!
-He has come!
The secret royal inspector has come!
The sky has fallen,
and the earth has collapsed.
Hundreds of sightseers are
scattered like waves.
What a frightening sight!
What a surprise!
Everyone trembles with fear.
The local governors are running away,
and the servants are scattering.
Food is stepped on, and dishes are broken.
Janggus are broken, drums are kicked.
Noegos are played.
Jegeums and flutes are stepped on,
and kisaengs lose their hairpins.
trumpeters lose their instruments.
Artillery makes a 'bang'
sound with its mouth.
Their foreheads and noses are broken.
They are bleeding and knocked down.
"Ouch, ouch," some are crying.
Some are running away.
Our town is in trouble.
More messengers...
There's a rumor about us in the village.
What's wrong
with a widower and widow's love?
I'm scared that I'll encounter a mishap.
Mishap?
My family doesn't like it.
How come?
They say it dishonors the family.
Because I'm a man of lowly status?
Do you think so, too?
If I did, would I be like this?
Let's leave this place.
Though I'm a poor Pansori singer,
I won't let you starve.
Will Song-hwa like me?
I mean your daughter.
It doesn't matter.
She's not my real daughter.
She's an orphan. I'm with her
to make her a Pansori singer.
Push, push...
Push harder.
Harder.
Isn't his name Yu-bong?
That's right.
He sang Pansori here
and passed away.
I learned
Pansori from Song-hwa, his daughter.
What happened to Song-hwa?
After mourning for three years,
she went somewhere.
Do you know where?
No, but I wonder
what a blind woman can do by herself.
You mean...
You mean, she's blind?
Yes.
How did she lose her sight?
Well...
Rumor says he made her blind
to make her a good singer,
or to prevent her from running away.
Someone said he couldn't have
made her blind
to keep her by his side.
He made her
blind to put anguish in her heart
so that she'd be a good Pansori singer.
But...
that's not trustworthy either.
Ari-arirang, Suri-surirang.
Arariga natne.
Try it, Dong-ho.
It's not that.
It's not like that.
Go away!
Song-hwa, try it.
Your feet here,
and place your hand on it.
Sit up straight, hold the stick properly.
-Now, we're going to try Jungmori again.
-OK.
Louder.
I miss my love,
I miss my love...
Is there something on the floor?
why are you looking at the floor?
Again.
I miss my love...
I miss my love, I miss my love...
I miss my love in Hanyang.
After separating with him,
I've never received a letter from him.
Is it because
he's busy studying?
"Lee" stands for plum.
It's a "son" under a "tree" in characters.
Even if the son is over 60,
he'll be below his parents.
Excellent!
He's really good.
What a calligrapher.
I need to ask him for one, too.
"Min" stands for the people.
For the people's courteous treatment,
I added a phoenix.
Sure. Absolutely.
Be quiet.
Stop making noise.
"Ju" stands for pillar.
We all need a good pillar.
So I drew
a pine tree pillar and a crane.
Lee Min-ju.
Nice name.
Can I have one, too?
I've met my buddy.
and I'm going to have a drink with him.
How do you do?
Song-hwa's become a woman.
When are you going to be my daughter?
Don't you dare want my daughter.
Aren't you going to greet your big father?
-Give us a drink and some tofu please.
-OK.
What brings you here, anyway?
I heard
a good Pansori singer will perform.
So I brought them to hear him.
-I was there yesterday.
-Oh.
But he was sick,
so another man performed instead.
Really?
Anyway, why don't you let me take them?
What do you mean?
Japanese songs were popular. But after
the liberation, western songs got popular.
Learning old songs is meaningless.
If they learn how to draw from me,
they won't starve.
Shut up, man.
Japanese
and western songs can't beat Pansori.
You'll see.
Pansori will conquer all.
The moon, the bright moon.
No matter how busy you are,
please hang high in the sky.
So tomorrow won't come,
and 100 years will be like tonight.
Please don't let us get old.
Love, my love.
She refused my order
to serve me.
One.
Since you hit me once,
I'll answer with "one."
I've decided on one mindset.
It won't change in one second.
It's hopeless to think I'll change.
Yu-bong!
Are you running away?
-Welcome.
-Do you have a room?
Here comes the hero.
Take him to a room.
Why do you have a big nose?
I wonder if your thing is big as well.
If it gets mad, you'll die.
We'll have to see who's going to die.
She's totally crazy about him.
Girls are crazy about the hero.
Who's crazy?
I prefer this oyster.
I wonder if he's deaf?
Yu-bong,
You're going to cut all ties with Seoul?
The master
said this before he passed away.
He told us to cancel your expulsion when
5 years have passed since Chu-wol died.
He's too much.
He blocked his student's future.
Hey, let's stop talking about that.
Who is Chu-wol?
She was our master's concubine.
Something happened between him and her?
Did she die, too?
She killed herself more than 5 years ago.
Ohmo
She took advantage of you.
Not the other way around...
I said, stop talking about that.
Your talent is a terrible thing to waste.
You couldn't finish learning
and have been wandering.
I can take care of myself
without a teacher. So shut up.
Come on, you still have a temper.
I was thinking of you.
Who asked you to worry about me?
Mind your own business.
You think your Pansori
skill deserves a stage?
What?
You think you're the best?
-What's going on?
-You, jerk!
Guys, easy. Yu-bong's drunk.
As a dog...
Friends? Yeah, right.
I know you're enjoying teasing me.
Drunk as a dog?
Right, you can say that again.
Though I've been wandering like a dog,
I'm not scared of you guys at all.
You'll see.
-That's not scary at all.
-What?
What's wrong with you guys?
Guys, it's late. Go back to the inn.
I'll continue drinking with Yu-bong.
We were drinking pleasantly. What's this?
Let's go.
Have a seat.
You and your pride.
Without it, I would have gone crazy.
Here, cheers.
I think he'd better stop drinking.
Are you thinking of me, too?
I'll take care of myself. Shut up.
After he opened his mouth,
he's become hot.
-Shut up and give me a drink!
-OK.
Yu-bong, let's go back to the city.
If I go, you guys
will be dead.
Let's see if that's true.
You arrogant man.
You think too much of yourself.
You shouldn't talk thoughtlessly.
You were the best pupil then,
but it's me now.
Is that so?
Sorry I didn't recognize you.
-Hey, give this virtuoso a drink.
-OK
-Come on.
Hey
Stop being cocky
and perform Pansori well.
What?
Are you...
You want to leave?
Go ahead.
Hey, Do-sang.
Let's go to my inn and drink some more.
Good-bye.
Love, love, love, my love.
You missed one beat.
Come here and play with me.
Love, love, love, my love.
It's love, my love
Again. Add some Chuimsae, too.
Love, love, love, my love.
It's love, my love.
It's my love. My love.
What are you going to eat?
Sour wild apricots.
You'll have small Lee Doryung...
Sis.
What's small Lee Doryung?
It means having Lee Doryung's baby.
What are you going to eat?
Sour wild apricots.
You'll have small Lee Doryung...
No, I don't want that either.
Then, what are you going to eat?
Are you going to eat sweet melons?
I don't want that either. My love.
You want grapes or cherries?
You want some candy?
My love.
Go that way. Let me see your back.
Come here. Let me see your front.
Walk on. Let me see you walk.
Smile.
Let me see your tonsils. My love.
Great.
You sing so well.
Your voice
is wonderful and you're pretty.
Should I take your virginity?
Will I sell my field?
Will I sell a part of the mountain?
-Hey, fill up my glass.
-Right. Pour him a drink.
She's too young
to know how to do that.
Shut up. Just do as I say.
Baby, go ahead.
Do it.
-You're light-headed.
-It's OK.
For punishment, you take a glass.
I can't drink.
If you don't drink it,
you can't go home tonight.
It's from your elder. Take it.
Hey, at least pretend to drink.
Come on!
Good, good.
Hey!
That's too much for a little one.
What?
If you had taught her properly,
this wouldn't have happened.
I teach Pansori,
not how to pour drinks.
How can a lowly man talk back to me?
Times have changed!
How could you talk back to me?
Yu-bong, ask them to forgive you.
I didn't do anything wrong!
Although times have changed,
a lowly man is still a lowly man!
Don't ever think of working here again!
You, boor!
Hey, why did you get a man like him?
What low-level dirt!
Bad girl!
You actually poured them drinks?
How could she not?
How dare you talk back to me?
You have no discretion!
What kind of father is he?
What do you mean?
How could a father hit you like that?
Because I did something wrong.
He must've been really angry.
What did you do wrong?
How long are you going to live like this?
With Pansori, your future is dark.
Till when are you going to follow him?
I still like Pansori.
When I sing it, I'm happy.
He spends all you make on drinks.
He must be hurting deeply inside.
I feel sorry for Father, too.
Father? He's nothing.
Dong-ho, you shouldn't say that.
He suffered while raising us.
Dear, are you really going to leave?
What about me?
When are you coming back?
Tell me when.
Will you be back...
when the high peaks flatten?
Will you return in March,
when flowers bloom?
Will you be back
when a small stone becomes an ore?
Is he playing a drum or what?
Unjongryong Pungjongho.
Clouds go where dragons go.
Winds go where tigers go.
Where you have gone,
I will follow.
He's also taken aback...
Move aside. Move aside.
Are you playing the drum?
Because I said so,
you may think this is a panacea.
But it's absolutely not.
It works well on only one disease.
So what is that disease?
Come on in.
Eat these.
Listen...
A drum has to
harmonize with the voice.
If you bang it,
that's not playing a drum,
but beating leather.
For a car to run,
the road has to be smooth.
Likewise,
the drum and Chuimsae have
to make a smooth way for Pansori.
Like we have four seasons,
there are
four ways to play a drum.
How many times have I told you?
If you play Jungmori...
Here's number one
two
three
four
Got it?
I'm sleeping. Be quiet
And...
when you say the Chuimsae...
When the sound starts fading,
you have to encourage it
by saying "Ulsigu."
And when the sound becomes sad,
you have to dampen the drum beat,
and add a sad Chuimsae.
When the sound becomes strong,
you have to play the drum strongly,
and say the Chuimsae strongly, too!
If there are 1,000 beats in Chunhyangga,
you have to practice a million times
to make the drum sound
soak into your body.
Got it?
We want to get some sleep!
I'm sick of your drunken frenzies!
Me too.
I'm also sick and tired of following you
around to sell Pansori.
You and your damn Pansori skills.
-What?
-lf you're tired of it, quit!
OK, I'm going to quit!
I'm not going to have your dirty meals!
That's good.
We wanted violin players anyway.
Pack your things!
Pay back what you owe me!
How long can we live?
Let's live smoothly.
What kind of a hill is Mungyungseje?
I cry along the way.
A vagabond life following Pansori.
Let's relieve our anguish.
There are many small stars in the sky.
There are many worries in our hearts.
Ariarirang. Surisurirang. Arariga natne.
Arirang. Arariga nate.
My dear love is gone.
Gone forever, following the wild geese.
Let's ask that wild goose.
Where are we supposed to go?
Golden baby or jade baby. Oh, my baby.
Learn Pansori
diligently and be a virtuoso.
I'll add
excitement to brother's drum beat,
and follow the long road to Pansori.
Let's play.
Let's play until the moon rises and falls.
Cold or hot? Come into my arms.
Lay your head on my arm.
The sun sets at the western hill.
It didn't want to set.
My dear who left me.
My love didn't want to leave me.