Twelve minutes to race time.
I didn't realize it was so...
- Just relax.
- Let go!
- What are you doing with my date?
- Your date?
I thought she was my date.
No wonder you were so uncooperative.
- Out!
- I like your taste.
Out!
Bye.
I have to change.
It'll only take a few seconds.
- Who was he?
- That was Kenny, my manager.
Some manager!
The minute I walked in here,
he grabbed me and started kissing me.
Don't worry about Kenny. He's harmless.
Yes, if you're 6'4" and a karate expert.
How can a guy like that be your manager?
I go back a long way with Kenny,
ever since we were kids.
Neither one of us ever had very much.
Whatever he had, we split.
Now he works for me,
handles my business...
takes care of all my endorsements
and all my money.
You mean,
you let him take care of your money?
Why not? I like to live dangerously.
- Does that go for girls, too?
- That goes for everything.
Honey, I'm gonna leave the driving to you.
- I wanted to see if it was the same girl.
- It's the same girl.
There's a drivers' meeting
in eight minutes.
- You're gonna be late.
- Eight minutes. Oh, no!
- She really had 10.
- Good move.
A new track, a new girl.
You certainly get the goodies, don't you?
It was a chance meeting. I followed her.
Good afternoon, race fans...
and welcome
to Charlotte Motor Speedway...
where we'll soon be underway
with the Charlotte 100...
first place paying $7,500.
The pits are buzzing with
the last-minute checks of everything...
Back to the car wash.
- How you doing, Birdie?
- Hi, Stevie.
- Want a chip?
- No, thanks.
She's purring like a fat cat.
She'll run like a lean one,
because I'm going flat-out today.
- Want to wish you luck.
- All bad? At least you're consistent.
- Good luck.
- Yeah, same to you.
Clear the midway.
Remember, everyone must remain
behind the pit wall...
except the regular crew.
- Run over 'em, Paul.
- Sic 'em, tiger.
The weather is perfect,
and the track is fast.
You can feel the excitement in the air.
Gentlemen, start your engines.
You ain't got a chance.
Fans, here we go.
And here's your leader at the moment...
Miss Mary Ann Ashman,
Miss Charlotte Speedway 100.
All cars in their proper position,
as we travel around on the pace lap.
...traveling around
at about 75 miles per hour...
giving all the cars a chance to warm up...
and for drivers to check any bugs
before we get underway.
A final wave from Miss Charlotte 100.
The pace car heading down
under the apron.
Here they come out of the far turn,
down the main straightaway.
There's the green flag and they're racing!
Number 42 has moved into third.
/t's still a race for first and second.
Here's the rundown.
Number 21 your leader, Cale Yarborough.
Running second,
Car Number 42, Tiny Lund.
/n third place, the 17 car.
Moving into fourth spot,
Steve Grayson in Car Number 6.
Right on his tail for fifth spot,
Paul Dado in Car Number 43.
/t's still a three-way go for first place.
The 17 car is starting to slow down.
And here comes Grayson
to take over third.
Paul Dado rises to take the fourth spot.
The 21 car into the pit
with a blown engine.
Grayson in the second spot,
and Paul Dado running third.
Look at this. The leader, Tiny Lund,
heading for the fifth.
Now it's a race for first spot
between Grayson and Dado.
Through the far turn they go,
right together.
Steve Grayson holding down the lead.
Come on!
Paul Dado in Car Number 43...
starting to move on the leader,
Car Number 6, Steve Grayson.
Side by side they go!
This has been going on for the last 36 laps.
Dado pulling away to take over the lead!
Down into the infield, the 76 car,
taking the 80 car with it.
Both drivers are okay.
Paul Dado, holding down the first spot.
Grayson holding on for second.
Grayson's staying right with him.
Here they come,
down in front of the grandstand.
Grayson's pouring it on.
Down on the inside.
They're right together.
You could throw a blanket
over both of them.
The heat is on.
Grayson pulling ahead in the 6 car.
Here's Paul Dado trying to make up time.
Paul Dado in Car Number 43.
And here comes Dado.
Look at this boy go!
Closing fast on the leader.
Out of the turn,
Paul Dado has closed the gap.
He's right on the bumper of the leader.
Come on, Stevie.
Now they're side by side.
The duel is on for first spot.
How long can they keep this up?
It's been going on lap after lap.
Dado the hard way, around the outside.
Grayson pulling right back up again.
A beautiful job of driving
by both of these drivers.
Out of the far turn they go,
Grayson the leader.
The 19 car has lost it in Turn Number 4.
Here's the leader,
down the main straightaway.
The white flag is going out.
One more lap to go!
Paul Dado takes the flag
and chases it all the way around.
They're going to race for it,
right to the flag.
Birdie, look at his tires!
There's smoke pouring out
of the wheels of the 6 car.
This could be the end for Steve Grayson.
His tires.
He's chunking rubber
all over the racetrack.
Car Number 43 is right on top of him.
There's smoke pouring out of the 6 car!
In front of the grandstand,
the checkered flag coming out!
And Steve Grayson earns the victory!
Man, looked like
he was really gonna bend his racer.
That was hairy.
Thought he'd be smoked out for good!
I prayed to every patron saint in the book.
I made some up, too.
And from here, race fans,
he looks all right.
What a great race!
You'll never see any better than this.
Here's the first three positions
as they came across the line:
Grayson, the winner, in Car Number 6.
Second to Paul Dado in the 43 car.
Finishing in third spot, Car Number 3.
- You had me scared.
- What happened? You all right?
I'm still taking an inventory.
I think everything's still here.
You had as much right winning
as the man in the moon.
You were way over your head,
chunking tires all over the place.
You should've been black-flagged off.
Don't tell the officials till I get my check.
They might disqualify me.
Now, in the winner's circle...
waiting for Steve Grayson,
Miss Charlotte 100...
Mary Ann Ashman...
along with Hunter McCabe,
making the presentation.
It's my pleasure to welcome the winner
of the Charlotte 100, Mr. Steve Grayson.
This is Mary Ann Ashman...
our beautiful
Miss Charlotte Speedway 100.
- How do you do?
- Mr. Grayson.
Mary Ann will present you
with the winner's trophy.
Thank you.
I hope you don't mind kissing each other,
just for the newspapers.
Not at all, if it's all right with you.
Well, if it's for the newspapers.
Just in case the newspapers
didn't get a good picture.
Come in.
Hello?
Oh, brother!
Is anybody home?
- Hello?
- This is Susan. He won again.
$7,700, including lap money.
My, how interesting!
- It's certainly all adding up, isn't it?
- Yes. First place again.
- He's a real hot dog.
- "Hot dog"? What does that mean?
Just a little race talk I picked up.
You're not there to pick up
whatever it is you're picking up.
Yes, sir.
Give me the number where you are,
in case I need to call.
I can't do that.
I'm calling from their trailer.
Their trailer? What if they find you there?
I think they'd love it.
Stevie, I've got an idea.
- Is it good or bad?
- I'll call you again tomorrow.
Really, what you ought to do
is lie down and get yourself a good rest.
I do feel a little beat.
On second thought...
you really ought to stay outside.
Get yourself a lot of fresh air.
That's just what I need, a lot of fresh air.
- Hello!
- Hello.
- Goodbye.
- Wait, I saw her first.
- Bye-bye.
- Why can't I stay? I'm over 21.
Sometimes I doubt it.
- Where did you come from?
- I rang the bell.
A voice said, "Come in," so here I am.
- That was quite a race you won today.
- Thank you.
You've been in the money now 20 races.
More or less. A pretty girl like you
didn't come here just to talk about racing.
He didn't.
- Oh, no.
- Surprised?
Wait a minute. I know what you think.
But I didn't suggest it. It was his own idea.
- Of course.
- You've got to believe me.
Obviously, I do.
- Sometimes I think he's five years old.
- Open the door.
Sure, I'll open it, and you're free to go.
I've got a key right...
I got a key somewhere.
It's in my other pants.
You wait right here. I'll be right back.
See? I knew I'd find it.
I'll unlock the door,
and you're perfectly free to...
Gone.
Okay, everybody. Regroup.
It's entertainment time
here at The Hangout...
and you all know the rules.
When I hit you with the light,
you gotta get up and do something.
If you don't, we do something to you.
I'm gonna go last...
because nobody can follow me.
Okay with the horns. I can take a hint.
- You're on!
- No, wait a minute. Hold it.
I don't want to... Wait a minute.
Okay, all right.
- I see a man coming into your life.
- Do you see him leaving, too?
No, there's no window to sneak through,
like some people do.
No, he doesn't leave.
He peers into the crystal ball
and tries to think what to say next.
How about "goodbye"?
That's too old-fashioned.
Don't you have any imagination, Miss...
Now concentrate.
Keep your eyes on the watch.
Watch the watch.
Your eyes are getting very heavy.
They weigh about 3 pounds each.
You want to tell me your name.
- What is your name?
- This is getting ridiculous.
You're fighting me.
Let's get back to the watch.
Watch the watch.
- Bottoms up.
- Wait a minute.
- When will I see you again?
- Ask your crystal helmet.
Kenny, how about assisting me
with one of my tricks.
- No, thanks. I have a little trick of my own.
- You're cute.
It will only take a minute.
So will mine.
Trying to get away
with the mustard, too, fella?
- "Too"?
- Ain't it enough you ate six hot dogs?
Six hot dogs?
I really enjoyed them, too, pal.
There you go.
Come and get it.
That smells good.
I'm hungry. I'm starving.
I'm more starving than you are.
Where'd you get this stuff?
I borrowed it from the cook
when he wasn't looking.
Six hot dogs...
potato chips...
coleslaw, three colas...
one diet.
Six hot dogs is $1.50.
Pop, they're the giant size.
Six giant hot dogs.
That's $1.90.
- We don't wanna cheat anybody.
- No, Pop.
- I'll just add these up now.
- You forgot the mustard.
- Hi there, Mr. Grayson.
- Hi, Abel.
So I did.
It looks a little less than half-full.
I'd calculate about 13 and a half cents.
I saw you run today, Mr. Grayson.
You looked like Jack the Bear.
It kind of reminds me
of when I was driving.
I'll be out there again
as soon as my leg comes around.
You stay off the track.
I got enough competition as it is.
Go on, now.
Ellie, I want you
to take this over to the cook, honey.
That's okay. It's been taken care of.
Mr. Grayson,
you shouldn't have paid for it.
But, as long as you did,
I'll just sign this over to you.
What is that?
This here is a promissory note for $4.32...
plus 6% interest.
That's for the food we took, including
the half bottle of mustard and a diet cola.
- Yeah, well, okay.
- All right, we can eat now.
Excuse me.
You got a bunch of hungry kids, Abel.
Well, things have been a little slow, lately.
I try to keep them fed
and a roof over their head.
Let's sit down.
The car won't start, so we're living in it.
- "Make the best of life," is our motto.
- You're doing a fine job.
They may even vote you
Mother of the Year.
- You think so?
- Sure.
Mr. Grayson.
Gee, you shouldn't have done that...
but I'm glad you did,
on account of the girls.
Tell you what.
I'm going to write you an IOU for the $60.
Let's see...
"IOU $60," plus 8% interest.
- 8%?
- When it's cash, we raise the rates.
- Mr. Grayson?
- Steve.
- Mr. Steve?
- Ellie wants to talk to you.
Will you stay for supper?
There you go.
I'll give you the biggest part
of my hot dog.
Don't bend it. I'll just take a bite.
We'll have a lollipop for dessert.
I've got a half one hidden.
We'll all take a lick.
That's the best hot dog I ever tasted.
I hate to eat and run,
but I don't eat dessert.
So you can have my lick, okay?
- Bye.
Bye, everybody.
- What's your name?
- Come on. Not me.
- Yeah, you.
- Oh, no.
Come on, rules are rules.
Go out there and wail.
Marvelous, just marvelous.
See what you can do if you try?
Okay, everybody, let's dance.
Choose your partners and then forget 'em.
Hit it.
- You're good.
- Thank you.
While we're dancing,
maybe we can think up a duet.
No, I'm sorry. Someone's waiting.
Who?
- Excuse me.
- Him!
- Paul?
- Yes, Paul.
Bye.
That's the first time
Dado's beat your time all year.
He hasn't got the checkered flag, yet.
There's an old station wagon outside.
Esterlake's? I worked on it
for two hours this afternoon.
They should make a floor lamp out of it.
- That bad?
- The worst.
Where's Kenny?
He trapped somebody in the trailer.
Real nice.
That tickles, silly.
Yes, but everything is perfect:
The night, the mood, and the girl.
And, oh, what a girl.
Gee.
Especially the girl.
She's moonlight...
she's quicksilver...
she's radiant and lovely,
and most of all, she's desirable.
I think I better go. It's getting late.
But it's only 10:30.
Look.
I better go. You don't mind?
Of course I don't mind.
Why, I wouldn't even want you
to stay here...
unless you wanted to.
It must be a decision
of your own free will and accord.
You're really very nice.
Most fellows wouldn't be so considerate.
They generally fight me.
I never thought you'd be so...
What's that?
I don't know. We'll just have to
turn on the radio and find out.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is an emergency broadcast.
Attention! All the wild animals in the zoo
have broken loose.
They are roaming the streets of our city.
Stay where you are!
Well, good night.
- Good night?
- Yes, I thought you were going.
- I couldn't go out there.
- Don't you have to go home?
Couldn't I stay here, please?
- Is that your decision?
- Oh, yes.
- Of your own free will?
- Yes.
Look!
Save me!
You're so strong. Please save me.
- Don't let them in.
- I'm not going to let them in.
Save me. I know you will.
- Don't let them in here.
- I'm not going to let them in here.
Close the door! Don't let the animals in.
- What animals?
- The animals that escaped from the zoo.
- Animals that escaped from what zoo?
- The wild ones. The mean ones.
- Didn't you hear the radio?
- What radio?
- You know, the radio.
- You mean your tape recorder.
Of all the dirty, rotten tricks,
this one really takes the cake.
- This is one of his better ones.
- You're ruining me.
I know.
- Where's my wrap? I'm leaving.
- Sit down and I'll help you look.
- You're leaving, aren't you?
- No.
- Well, I must have misplaced it.
- No, you didn't. It's in here.
- What's it doing in there?
- He always puts them in there.
- I'll get you. You wait!
- I'll wait.
Look, at least let me walk you home.
It's dark outside.
- A lady unescorted...
- I'd rather be alone.
- Good morning, Ellie.
- Good morning.
I have a present for you.
You don't have to give me presents.
I like you because you're just you.
But this is a present you can share.
- Is it a doll?
- No.
- Is it a puppy?
- It's bigger than a puppy.
- That's smaller than a puppy.
- What it belongs to is bigger.
It's all yours.
- That belongs to me?
- Yep. You got to get somebody to drive it.
It's beautiful. Can I give it to my Pop?
He can drive.
Say, that's a good idea.
Pop, Annie, Debbie! Everybody!
Look what Mr. Steve bought for us.
There you go, honey. Come on, girls.
And there's enough groceries in here
to last you a month.
Aren't you going to give him a note
for the car, Pop?
Sure, Ellie.
To tell you the truth,
I'm so shook up, I don't think I could write.
Girls, won't you say thank you
to Mr. Grayson and Mr. Donford?
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Annie, say thank you to Mr. Grayson, now.
Thank you.
Okay, girls, let's go around
and look at the car now.
I just don't know what to say.
- You know something, Mr. Steve?
- What's that?
I wish I were big enough to marry you.
We're nearly at the end of
one of the finest races I've ever seen...
here at Charlotte Motor Speedway...
with a winner's purse of $8,500
plus accessory money.
Here's Steve Grayson, Car Number 6,
into Turn 1.
Right with him, in Car Number 43,
Paul Dado.
These two have been cleaning up
on all the tracks this year.
Out of Turn 4 they come, side by side.
Grayson's the leader by inches...
Out of the turn,
into the main straightaway.
This will be the white flag.
One more to go!
Into the wall! And he's upside-down.
And the checkered flag!
Steve Grayson the winner!
The total purse close to $9,500!
Paul Dado second in the 43 car.
And in for third, Car Number 14.
Mr. Hepworth, he won again. Over $9,000.
He did?
So far, he's the top money winner
on the circuit.
Well, money's what we're interested in.
He's sure making a lot of it.
Good.
I love to hear good news.
I'll keep in touch. Bye.
Now down to the winner's circle.
Mr. Steve Grayson,
may I congratulate you...
on winning the Charlotte Speedway 250.
Thank you.
Isn't there something else
that goes with it?
Of course.
Have you made up your minds yet?
The lady and I will have a steak sandwich,
medium-rare, please.
Steak sandwich, medium-rare.
Hold the onions, please.
"Hold the onions." How thoughtful.
Baked or French fried potatoes?
Tomatoes.
- Tomatoes.
- No dressing.
- Tomato-wise, I mean.
- No dressing, tomato...
Oh, that's cute.
What dressing
would you like on your salad, please?
- What do you have?
- We have French, Thousand Island...
Roquefort, oil and...
- Vinegar?
- Vinegar, yeah.
Thank you.
I'll have Roquefort.
That will be 35 cents extra.
It's okay. She can have
all the Roquefort she wants.
That's wonderful.
He doesn't care if it costs extra.
My poor boyfriend, he's so poor
he can't afford anything extra.
He needs all his money for school.
He's still got four more years to go...
before he becomes a registered nurse.
Nurse?
Male, that is.
I'll get your order
with the extra Roquefort.
Thank you.
Problems.
I think she really loves the guy.
I wonder what I can do to help.
The ceremony is really a rocker.
Bye! Thank you!
Have a happy, happy!
Don't forget to take the You Drive back.
- Your bouquet.
- No, you caught it.
And you know what they say
about catching the bridal bouquet.
- That's when it's thrown by the bride.
- I was just giving it a little assist.
Hey, wait a minute.
We can't let this happen.
I'm sure we can't,
whatever we're talking about.
The bouquet. Look at the way
the petals are drooping. They're in a coma.
- What do you suggest, Doctor?
- We got to get it in some water.
- Where should we go?
- I know you'll think of something.
My place is too far, so let's go to yours.
- See? I knew you'd think of a place.
- But we gotta hurry before it's too late.
There he goes with
that put-the-flowers-in-the-vase bit.
I'll break the vase over your silly head.
If I were a girl,
I'd let the measles in before letting him in.
- Don't stop now. You're killing me.
- You know what else she should do?
She should pile her furniture
against the door.
Now, miss, if you want someone
who's mucho charming...
who's a champion furniture pusher, I'll...
She's gone.
- Why did they call me in?
- You've been making it big recently.
They call in everyone
over a certain income. It's just routine.
Yeah? Well, I'm worried.
You've got nothing to norry...
Nothing to worry about, Mac.
It's like your friend says.
It's just routine.
Thanks.
You had my income tax made out
by a reliable man, right?
- Well, of course.
- Of course what?
I had your income tax made out
by a reliable man.
You're looking me straight in the eye.
That means you're lying.
- Boy, I'm in trouble.
- No, you're not.
- Then why am I here?
- Maybe they just want to get acquainted.
- Knock it off.
- You know something?
- You're scared.
- You better believe it.
Just like everybody else in this room.
These tax people are nice, warm,
friendly people.
Thank you, Mr. Hepworth.
See how relaxed he is?
All right, sir. It's all right.
You'll be just fine.
You'll be all right, sir.
We'll get you a drink of water.
Mr. Steven Grayson, please.
I'm Mr. Grayson. This is Mr. Donford.
I'm Mr. Hepworth.
Well, you don't need me.
Come with me, please.
Please be seated, gentlemen.
Would you care for anything:
Cigarettes, cigars, soft drink?
A straight scotch with a gin chaser.
No, thank you, sir.
We won't have anything.
Quite an interesting tax return
you made out, Mr. Grayson.
I made out.
- You made out the form, Mr. Donford?
- All by myself.
Well, congratulations, Mr. Donford.
I'd like to shake your hand.
It is the most ridiculous...
impossible, jumbled, disorganized return...
I have ever seen in all my 30 years.
- I ought to break you in half.
- You'd then have two very short friends.
Funny.
You have a great many deductions
I would like to have explained.
Under "business entertainment":
Rental of a powerboat
listed at $100 a day...
and $200 a day...
- for bait?
- Bait?
- We had to buy presents for the girls.
- Presents?
That's what you classify as bait.
Yes, we didn't do much fishing.
But, boy, did it work out!
Disallowed.
"Depreciation on stock car.
"Salaries for the mechanics.
Bonuses and percentages."
That's all right.
"Gas, tires, maintenance."
$4,000 for air?
Now, that I don't understand.
I'm with you. Explain that one, will you?
We stopped in this gas station...
to check the tires.
But Steve...
he got to talking
to the owner of the station...
and he told us how tough things were.
So we invested $4,000
just to help him out...
and he blew the money. So I figured...
The air cost $4,000.
- Disallowed.
- Right.
"Station wagon, furniture,
You Drive trailer...
"flowers," etc...
all listed under "charities."
- Very commendable.
- Thank you.
Watch out for the zinger.
Unless these are registered,
recognized, licensed charities...
these deductions cannot be allowed.
- Now, just one minute.
- Skip it, Kenny.
- We spent that money!
- I said, skip it. Tie your tie.
Now, under "business deductions"...
you have listed a $22,000 trailer...
with various mechanical
and electronic devices...
perfumed record albums...
and pages and pages...
Stop right there, Mr. Hepworth.
There is no sense in going on.
There's been a lot of mistakes made.
- We'll do something about it.
- That's about the size of it.
How much does "about the size of it"
amount to?
About $145,000.
$145,000?
That's an awful lot of money.
Now, if you agree to an arrangement
we have in mind...
one of our staff
will collect all of your earnings.
You will be put on a strict budget
until you repay the government...
every penny you owe.
All of a sudden,
he decides to test the car at 6:00 a.m.
And I got home at 5:00.
- He's really giving it a beating!
- I bet nothing's wrong with it.
You know Steve.
When he's mad and he wants to find...
- $5 he don't.
- You're on!
Run her up, Birdie.
- Any problems?
- Not a one, man. She's really honking.
See you guys later.
"Honking" means
she's running exceptionally well.
Scratch.
Thank you.
Steve, I've got it!
- You got what?
- The check from the last race.
- What do you mean?
- Right here in my sneaky hand.
Mr. Hepworth is sending someone
to collect the money.
Yeah, I know,
but I thought we could hold onto it.
- No.
- On a permanent basis.
We made a deal, and we'll keep it.
Steve, $7,500 in case
we need a few essential luxuries.
You aren't an honest person.
- That's part of my charm.
- Give me the check.
It doesn't belong to us. Get in the car.
You're making a mistake.
A guy's got to live.
You can't...
Hello, Mr. Hepworth, I went
to collect the check, but it was gone.
We had an agreement, and I trusted him.
This is very discouraging.
I'll get the check back. Don't you worry.
It shows you how much
Mr. Grayson's word means.
I hear music. Where are you calling from?
Your expense account
doesn't include going to dances.
I know, sir. I'm in his trailer.
It sounds like wild animals.
Are you being attacked?
Not yet. Mr. Grayson isn't here.
He's got all kinds of gimmicks
in this trailer.
Gimmicks? You be careful.
Oh, yes. I'll be careful.
And I'll get that check back, too. Goodbye.
That figures.
Relax.
Let every muscle in your body go limp.
You never felt so good.
You don't want to go home.
You're beginning to get tired. Tired.
Hi there. No, don't move.
I want to remember you
exactly as you are.
The check, please.
- What did you say?
- She said, "The check, please."
I speak her language.
If she said "The check, please,"
that means...
- Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
- My name is Susan Jacks.
I work for the Internal Revenue Service.
Beautiful. Just beautiful.
According to Mr. Hepworth,
you made a certain agreement.
Remind me to write him
a nasty letter of thanks.
- Let me handle this.
- You've done enough already.
But you're too honest to deal with her.
I'll be back. I have to wash his car.
Here's the check.
Thank you.
You must understand...
that you owe the government
a great deal of money.
Unless you pay it promptly,
your indebtedness will pyramid...
and you'll never be solvent again.
I don't think you realize
the gravity of the situation.
- Let's sit down and discuss it.
- Yes.
First, there's the amount
of your allowance.
You understand
it must be a minimum figure.
In order to pay back $145,000...
we must be as efficient as we possibly...
can.
Interest compounds.
Therefore, the quicker
you make restitution, the better.
Now, I know it's going to be...
- a pong lull.
- Long pull.
This situation demands drastic measures.
- As to your allowance, Mr. Grayson...
- Anything you say.
As to your...
Allowance.
Your allowance.
Mr. Hepworth thought
that $100 would be sufficient.
I can make out fine on $100 a day.
No. Your allowance will be $100 a week.
$100 a week?
I spend more than that on Band-Aids.
- I'm afraid that's it, Mr. Grayson.
- What are you trying to do to me?
Nothing.
I only work for Mr. Hepworth.
I don't make any rules.
- Sure, sure.
- But it's true. There's nothing personal.
- I'm just carrying out orders.
- And loving every minute of it.
If you don't believe me,
call Mr. Hepworth. There's the phone.
I know where the phone is. I live here.
Well, I'm afraid we have nothing more
to say to each other.
- I'm not through with you yet.
- Goodbye, Mr. Grayson.
Is everything all right, Miss Jacks?
Did you and Steve
reach a nice, fair, liberal allowance?
Somewhere in there
there's room for an answer.
Your allowance will be $50 a week.
That's the wrong answer!
$50.
Boy, did you ever fix it!
Do you know
what my allowance is gonna be?
No, but mine is $100 a week.
We can't live on $150 a week.
You've gotta talk to her.
I wouldn't ask that iceberg for anything
even if...
- If we were dead broke?
- Yeah.
We're dead broke.
What happened to the money
you were supposed to be holding?
We should have a few thousand.
- There were expenses.
- What else?
- Presents.
- Go on.
Phone calls! Lots of phone calls.
Hello?
- Is this Donford?
- No, I'm not in right now.
I know it's you. This is Tillman.
I'm glad you called.
No, you're not.
Your horse didn't come in again.
You better pay the bread. I'm getting tired
of carrying you on the books.
I'll see if I can't try
and squeeze you in on Saturday.
Saturday's as far as we go.
Goodbye, baby.
Baby?
What room did you say Miss Jacks was in?
- 1210.
- You're right!
- Yes?
- Hi, remember me? I'm Kenny.
May I come in, please?
American Beauty roses
for an American beauty.
All right, give me the pitch.
No. The roses are yours,
to have and to hold. No strings attached.
No, thank you very much. You have them
and keep them. Good night.
There is one thing we might discuss.
You see, it concerns...
You tell Mr. Grayson...
that I'm not empowered
to make any changes...
in his arrangements with the government.
- And even if I were, I wouldn't.
- Mr. Grayson did not send me.
He doesn't send me, either.
He doesn't even know that I came here.
I'm here on an errand of mercy
on his behalf.
- How much?
- Well, I'm embarrassed for him.
Embarrassed for how much?
About $7,500 worth.
If you could just give me back
the check he gave you...
- Out.
- Please.
Don't blame him. Blame me.
Some men are weaker than others.
- Out!
- Don't bother showing me out the door.
I'll use the window.
- May I open it for you?
- You're very polite.
I don't jump out of windows
unless they're in the basement.
Chicken.
Bye.
Come in.
- Mr. Grayson.
- Yes?
- Here are your flowers.
- Well, thank you.
Your allowance check will be $64.50.
Wait a minute.
I thought it was supposed to be $100.
I called the florist.
What has he got to do with my allowance?
The flowers were charged
to your account. $35.50.
Now, $35.50 from $100...
leaves $64.50.
I wouldn't send you flowers...
- if you were the last person on earth.
- I have some advice for you.
- Lf you're trying to trick me...
- What do you mean, trick you?
- You know what I mean.
- No, I don't know.
Furthermore, I've had just about enough.
My dinner!
No, Steve won't make a move
without first asking for my advice.
I leave nothing to chance.
First, I analyze the wind...
then the time of day...
and then the angle of the track.
Then I sit down with Steve,
and we have a nice long talk.
I tell him exactly the way
I want him to drive.
No, we don't win by chance.
The whole thing is psychological.
Listen...
what do you say we go someplace
just a little more private?
- I want to talk to you, Donford.
- Donford? There must be some mistake.
- That's not my name!
- Yes, it is!
If you don't get the bread before Saturday,
I'll beat your brains out.
- You understand that?
- Yes.
I understand. Saturday.
Ellie, what are you doing here?
I know you didn't want us
thrown out of our station wagon.
Who threw you out of your station wagon?
Sorry to break in on you this way,
Mr. Grayson.
- What's this about being thrown out?
- They repossessed it, Mr. Grayson.
Terrible shock.
Repossessed it? That's impossible.
They had a paper. All legal and everything.
Yes, Pop?
Would you put the other girls
to bed, honey?
- Put them on the couch.
- That will be fine.
This whole thing is ridiculous.
I gave Kenny the money to pay cash for it.
I'm sure you did.
I guess it's not so ridiculous after all.
I hope you don't mind,
but it's way past the girls' bedtime.
What?
- The bedroom is right back there.
- Good. Thank you.
I'll get you some milk later, honey.
- Pardon me.
- Sure.
I see we have visitors.
- You'll excuse me if I go to bed.
- Hold it. It's occupied.
Why didn't you pay cash
for that station wagon?
- Oh, that.
- Yeah, that.
Hello?
Lori, what's the matter?
They repossessed our furniture.
What did you do with the money
I gave you for Lori's furniture?
I'm still working on the station wagon.
This is no time to be funny.
I wanna know... Lori, hush.
I want some straight answers.
What did you do with all that money?
What happened to the money?
I was held up!
You're looking me straight in the eye
again, and that means you're lying.
I'll be with you in a minute, Lori.
Now out with it!
Not you, Lori. You!
I've always liked the horses,
but I could never pick them.
The more I tried to get even,
the deeper I got with your money.
I'm sorry, Steve.
Where are you now, Lori?
We're spending
the rest of our honeymoon...
at his mother's house.
I'll get back to you. Don't worry, honey.
I don't deserve to be called "honey."
- Good night, Mr. Grayson.
- Good night.
Hello.
Susan, Paul. I'm down in the lobby.
Yes, Paul, I'm ready.
I'll be down in a minute.
I don't recall inviting you here.
I hate being here
as much as you hate seeing me.
- That finishes our visit, doesn't it?
- I've got to talk to you.
- I have an appointment.
- And I need $7,500.
Good night, Mr. Grayson. There's the door.
Look, everything I bought
for the Esterlakes, Lori, and the others...
has been repossessed.
- You should have paid cash.
- I thought I did. I got to have the money.
That's against the rules
of the Internal Revenue Service.
Good night, Mr. Grayson, and goodbye.
Don't "goodnight and goodbye" me,
Miss Internal Revenue Service.
- Get your hands off me!
- You'll listen to me first.
It was a fist. I saw it.
It's a game.
- I'm not finished with you yet.
- Watch where you're going!
Please, there's a man after me. Stop him.
Hey, you. Come back here.
- Please don't let him get me. There he is!
- Excuse me.
I'm sorry. I have to catch that plane.
I mean, that girl.
- Excuse me.
- Excuse me. Pardon me.
- No, you don't.
- Somebody call the police.
I know you're in here somewhere.
You'll listen to me.
No, I'm not.
I will talk sense to you,
if it's the last thing I ever do.
That will be the last thing you ever do.
If I could get near you,
I'd knock that stubbornness out of you.
I want to see the manager.
They ought to condemn that elevator.
- George, I want you to sue this hotel.
- Yes, dear.
- We're checking out right now.
- We're not even staying here.
- I've got you. You listen to me, will you?
- Let her go.
- Make me.
- Gladly.
What floor, buddy?
No, you don't.
You're gonna listen to what I have to say.
- No, I'm not.
- Yes, you are.
- Let go of me!
- What's everybody looking at?
You sit here and listen to me.
You are the most obstinate, stubborn,
ornery, impossible girl I ever met.
You just won't admit there's another side.
My side.
You know why?
Because you're unreasonable.
Sit still. You're argumentative, mulish...
uncooperative...
and unbelievable.
No. It could never work.
We're complete opposites.
You're wild, extravagant, and unreliable.
You're not the kind of man
that I should fall in love with.
And besides,
we don't even like each other.
- Hi, Steve.
- Hey, it's late.
- Why aren't you in the car, sleeping?
- I couldn't close my eyes.
- How'd you do with Miss Iceberg?
- Great. Just wonderful.
- You got the money.
- Not exactly, but we can get it.
- You're kidding!
- No, not at all.
You're supposed to be the smart guy.
Why didn't you think of it?
- What's "it"?
- The trailer trap, man.
- We can sell it.
- Sell it? The trailer trap?
Sure, we can get at least $12,000 for it.
We can pay everybody we owe,
and all our problems are solved.
How can you think of selling
the trailer trap for a measly $12,000?
It's worth a lot more! It's worth at least...
Oh, boy.
What are they doing here?
The company repossessed the trailer trap.
They're adorable.
Good night!
Oh, boy.
- I've got to get some money somewhere.
- Yes.
My stock car. I could sell it
for at least $10,000 or $15,000.
No, you can't.
You'd be giving up your future.
What future?
Wait a minute.
Operator.
- Hello?
- Hello, Mr. Hepworth.
Hello. Susan?
Yes. The Charlotte 600
is on Sunday, and...
Let him keep some of the money
to pay his personal obligations?
We can't do that. It's against the rules.
Well, then he won't race.
And he'll sell his stock car.
But he can't do that.
But he will,
unless you agree to his proposition.
If he wins the 600 on Sunday...
we could collect a lot of money
for the government...
plus all the winnings from future races.
Plus?
Well, in that case, all right.
And in the future, Susan,
don't call me at 4 a. M...
unless it's as important as this call.
Bye.
You're the greatest.
You'd better be the greatest
on that track tomorrow.
- And qualify, right?
- Right.
It was nice of you to call Mr. Hepworth.
We're in qualifying for the World 600.
Come on!
Down to the flag.
There's the white flag.
If he puts his hands out,
he'll fly like a bird.
Paul Dado on his first time at 35. 15.
35 seconds and 15 one-hundredths.
- Come on!
- Go!
The checkered flag.
And the time...
It's a beauty! 35.10.
Well?
He qualified. Man, did he ever qualify!
35.10 seconds.
That would be 153.484 miles per hour.
I'll have to stand on it.
That means push the accelerator
to the floor.
I know.
Grayson, always a tough qualifier,
will have to really go.
He's got some real good times to beat.
Right out of Turn 2.
There's the green flag.
Boy, he is really honking.
Time to beat. 35. 10...
to make it into the first four positions.
Out of Turn Number 4.
The white flag. Coming up, the finallap.
The first time around.
The time at 35.05.
That puts Steve Grayson
in the first six cars.
Wide out of the turn...
You're home free.
The checkered flag.
Grab hands, girls. Come on. Let's go.
Steve Grayson climbing out of the 6 car.
He looks all right.
Grayson was really on it
when he came down to the flag.
He made it, even with the spin,
into the first four positions...
with a time of 35.03.
I feel fine. Birdie, did I qualify?
Yeah, you qualified, but you sure
made a clunker out of that car.
Clunker means that...
Well, it's no problem.
Birdie will have it fixed in no time, I hope.
Well, you might as well get started now.
Come on, kids.
I've seen blown engines before, but, boy...
Never mind the details.
Just put another engine in here.
- Speak to Kenny.
- Repossessed.
- All of them?
- I tried to hide one, but I couldn't lift it.
- Can this be fixed by tomorrow?
- We can't fix this in two tomorrows.
They took all our spare parts, too.
We don't even have one spark plug.
What are we gonna do now?
- Why don't you go and buy some?
- With what?
All right, then. Borrow some.
Even if we could borrow the parts,
we couldn't fix it that fast.
How do you know unless you try?
She's right. I think you can do it.
You drive 'em, Steve. We fix 'em.
I tell you this clunker
can't be ready for the race tomorrow.
- What's the first thing to be done?
- Get new engine parts.
I could be a mite helpful
in the parts department.
- Good. I'm glad somebody can help.
- What are we waiting for?
All right, come on.
- Come on.
- Okay.
- Hi.
- Is it all finished?
- All finished.
From the Charlotte Motor Speedway,
the World 600.
The green flag is out, and we're racing!
Into the first turn,
it's a scramble for the first spot.
The 14 car takes over the lead.
It's Paul Dado in car 43 around the outside.
Something's wrong with Steve Grayson...
This is a new one for me.
He's dragging.
Come on, stand on it, Steve.
Grayson can't get up to speed.
We'll keep an eye on him while the rest
of the track is jockeying for position.
The 43 car, Paul Dado,
he's still riding the outside...
picking off car after car.
Still the leader, Car Number 14.
Paul Dado now running second.
Steve Grayson has dropped back
to 12th position and running low.
From here, it looks like Steve Grayson
is having handling problems...
or something is wrong
with the weight distribution.
Come on. You're no feather-foot.
Any of you guys
leave a tool kit in that car?
Paul Dado driving a perfect race...
still picking off cars
and coming up on Grayson.
When he does come around,
he will have lapped the 6 car.
And here he comes on the outside.
There he goes,
and Grayson's now one lap down.
Tough break for Grayson,
the fourth fastest qualifier.
What are you doing here?
After we finished working,
I guess I fell asleep in the car.
Lay down and hang on.
The weight's killing me.
I'll just hang on.
The 6 car heading for the pits.
Still having trouble.
- What's slowing you down?
- Get him out of here.
Holy smoke!
Come on! Let's get him out of there.
- Can you make up the time?
- I've got to. Where am I?
You're way back.
- Get off the track.
- I'm not on the track.
Get him off the track!
You all right?
Am I out of the car?
Steve Grayson in Car Number 6
comes back into the race, one lap down.
The leader in Car Number 4,
Paul Dado in Car Number 43.
Dado holding the first spot
for the last 192 laps.
And here comes the 6 car, Steve Grayson.
Man, is he moving!
Already, he's picked up four cars.
He'll have to pass the leader,
Paul Dado in Car Number 43...
to be on the same lap.
Look at this boy go!
He's going to try it on the outside.
There it is.
He's on the same lap with the leader
and pulls away.
Car Number 6 is passing cars
at almost record speed.
We've got him on the last lap...
at 149.06 miles per hour.
That should be a great credit to his crew.
Already, he's made up three-quarters
of a lap, and he's looking for the leader.
Here he is behind Car Number 43...
hitting the wall, trying to get by...
and he made it.
Steve Grayson in Car Number 6.
That's your new leader.
Grayson has been holding the lead now
for the last hour-and-one-half...
riding the high groove and pulling away
as we come to the last five laps.
Steve Grayson,
after all kinds of problems...
has made a fantastic recovery.
He's coming onto the track
one fulllap down. Made up for one lap...
turning this track at almost record speed...
to take over the lead
with only three more laps to go.
The battle is still on.
Paul Dado in the 43 car
is trying to recover that lead.
The yellow flag comes down.
The car losing it in the turn,
Number 88, is okay.
We're down to the last two laps.
Please. Come on, Steve.
One more lap to go.
It's Grayson and Dado,
they'll race for it right to the wire.
Both drivers coming out okay.
Steve Grayson's real steady
with only a half lap to go.
And the 9 car loses a wheel.
And this will be your winner.
Paul Dado wins!
Car Number 43.
Here comes Grayson out of the car.
And he seems to be all right.
The fire crew is there.
Well, race fans, we've seen a beauty.
Darling...
you were wonderful.
- Flat-out all the way.
- A lot of good it did me.
You tried.
Steve, I figured it out.
Counting lap money,
you get $7,670 for third place.
- How about that?
- That's marvelous!
That's enough to get you out of trouble.
We can pay off the furniture,
we can get the station wagon back...
and we've got $170 to celebrate with.
$170 goes to Uncle Sam on account.
On account of what?
On account of you still owe him $137,000,
plus interest.
She's right.
It's back to The Hangout for
the victory dinner. Beans and hot dogs.