Oh, the rang, tang, tang.
Yeah, the rang, tang, tang.
Uncle Bill!
Uncle Bill! Uncle Bill!
- Here's your picture.
- That's it, Uncle Bill.
- Well, what do you know?
- Read us about it, Uncle Bill.
- Well, look at this.
- Read it, Uncle Bill.
What does it say, Uncle Bill?
Why, it say, " Dear Bill:
Jim Europe would have been
proud of you."
Signed, " Ex-Drum Major,
Noble Sissle."
Who's Jim Europe, Uncle Bill?
Jim Europe? Why he had
the greatest band in the world-
Attached to the 15th Regiment.
Didn't I never tell you that?
No, Uncle Bill!
Why, we was under fire
for 191 days straight.
Yes, sir! And our regiment was decorated
with the Croix de Guerre.
You don't say, Uncle Bill.
Why, children, I remember when
we come back from France in 1918...
the flags was flying,
people were cheering.
- Boy, I'm looking out for us.
- What you got there?
Book of telephone numbers
I won from Joe.
Boy, I'm gonna promote us
a couple of gals...
- for the ball tonight.
- How do you spell "us"?
- "U.S."
- You leave off the "S" and worry about you.
Every time you start to promoting,
that spells trouble.
Here we go again.
- Did you go to the ball that night?
- We sure did.
- And did Gabe promote you a girl, Uncle Bill?
- No, he didn't...
but he promoted everything else-
a girl for himself,
a big limousine and a chauffeur.
We sure went there in style.
This must be General Pershing coming.
Can't be, because
General Pershing's a blond.
Well, boy, here we are,
and I'm gonna Lindy Hop down.
Boy, I'm gonna carry on. Come on, honey.
Come back at 12:00, my man.
Come on, honey.
Yes, you.
Cousin Jake,
what you want this time?
What you keep on calling me for?
I'm sorry, Gabe.
I can't come back and get you.
- Why?
- The boss wants to use the car at 7:00.
But, Cousin Jake,
how we gonna get home?
How'd you get uptown
from the ship this morning?
- Walked.
- Right there's your answer.
- I'm going to the powder room.
- All right.
- Daddy, can I have a dollar for the maid?
- Huh? Oh, sure.
Sure, sure, honey.
Here you are. Here you are.
Right here.
Go ahead.
Man, you gonna brag yourself
into the poor house yet.
Well, I ain't got far to go.
That just leaves $4.30
twixt me and it.
I should have called one of them
numbers in Joe's book for you.
You see, the trouble with you is-
What I mean is-
when it comes to women,
you just don't know, or else-
Man, you're ramblin'.
What hit you?
Look at that gal
standing over there.
There's nothing like that
in that book you was talking about.
Better not be.
Lieutenant Europe?
Well, well. Selina Rogers.
Hello, Jim.
It's nice to see you back.
I'm mighty happy to see you, honey.
And how you've grown up.
Say, Jim, I'm looking for Clem's buddy,
Bill Williamson.
- Can you point him out to me?
- I'm sure I can.
He's bound to be around here somewhere.
Come on. We'll find him.
- Okay.
- I hear that you're a big star now.
Yes, I'm doing nicely, thank you.
I used to tell you you'd
get there someday. Remember?
You taught me my first song.
I'm still singing it too.
There's Bill Williamson now.
Private Williamson!
- Attention!
- Who, me?
My ears hear something,
but my feet don't believe it.
Bill, this is Selina Rogers...
- Clem's little sister.
- Who's sister?
- Clem's.
- You don't mean Clem Rogers?
- Yes.
- My!
- I didn't expect Clem's
little sister to be so big.
You two get together.
I've got to get on back to work.
- Okay, Jim.
- I'll see you kids later.
I'm glad to meet you, Bill.
Clem wrote me a lot about you.
He told me a lot about you too.
You know,
I was gonna look you up.
Here's something
that he wanted you to have.
It's the Croix de Guerre for bravery.
Here I am, Daddy.
My, what a big cigar.
Yes, and a big man
is smoking it too, honey.
Honey, I does everything
in a big way.
It must have cost you
a lot of money to keep...
that car and chauffeur
while you were at war.
Chicken feed, honey,
just chicken feed.
- You must be powerful rich.
- Oh, I got a little. I got a little.
- Gardenias. Twenty-five cents.
- Yes, indeed.
Nothing too good for the little lady.
Yes. My daddy does
everything in a big way.
- Give me all of them.
- All of them?
I sure go for a guy
that's free with his money.
Do you, honey?
- That'll be $3.00.
- Huh?
It was very nice of you
to tell me all this about Clem.
Oh, that's all right.
- You want to dance, Selina?
- I'd love to, soldier.
Ooh, I never expected to have
so many flowers till I was dead.
Let's dance, Daddy.
No, come on, let's sit down.
Waiter, table for two.
I've been marching all day.
Anyway, there ain't
no point in dancing.
- What are you gonna drink?
- What you got?
- Just ginger ale and root beer.
- What?
You positive you ain't got nothing
but ginger ale and root beer?
- That's all we got.
- This is gonna spoil my whole evening...
'cause back in Paris, I didn't
drink nothin' but champagne-
the best of champagne.
Well, now, maybe I'd be able
to fix you up with a bottle of that.
I got a friend on the outside.
- But it'll cost you plenty of money.
- Oh, that's all right.
- Money's no object to us. Is it, Daddy?
- Well, no.
- I'll see what I can do.
- Uh, yeah, here, boy. Come here. Come here.
- Don't knock yourself out. It ain't that important.
- Oh, he don't mind.
I always wanted to taste that stuff.
Well, honey, if you never tasted it,
it might make you dizzy.
- That's what it's for, ain't it?
- I'll do my best.
But-
I sure hope I'll be able to walk
out of here without any trouble.
Me too.
- Aw, that was swell.
- I want you to meet Gabe.
- Who's Gabe?
- Why, he was Clem's other buddy.
There he is, right there.
Come on over.
You know, they called us
the Three Musketeers of the A.E.F.
Meet Selina Rogers, Clem's sister.
I'm mighty proud.
This is Miss Cynthenetta Webb.
Say, this buddy of yours
is a sharp dancer.
He ought to be on the stage.
Ought to be on the stage?
Oh, by the way, Bill. I had the booking
office on the phone this afternoon.
Looks like you gonna play the Palace
week after next, boy.
- Then you are on the stage.
- Why-
Yes, and he's his manager.
He's gonna put me on the stage too.
- Really?
- Well, I don't usually bother with amateurs...
- but in this case-
- Oh, Gabe, why don't you come up for air?
Now listen to him, the most
modest man in the whole world.
Oh, let him go on, Bill.
I'd like to hear more about you.
You only got to ask
anybody in show business.
Take Bud Williams-
He's crazy about Bill and me.
Oh! Then you must know
Chick Bailey.
Chick Bailey!
Do we know Chick Bailey?
Why, we put him in show business.
We're just like brothers,
ain't we, Bill?
Sure.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Presenting Miss Selina Rogers...
one of our newest stars.
- Well, here's where we break in the new song, Selina.
- Okay.
Miss Webb, Bill Williamson...
- this is my partner, Chick Bailey.
- How do you do?
- You know Gabe, of course.
- Gabe?
- Come on.
- Who'd she say?
He heard her- Chick Bailey.
The guy he put in show business-
his brother.
- But, honey, I can explain everything.
- Don't explain nothing to me.
- I can see through it. The nerve.
- But, baby-
- Trying to pull a trick like that.
- Well, honey, I was only-
And after all you've done for him.
Why, the ingratitude.
Trying to make out like
he didn't even recognize you.
Hmph!
I may not be so very smart
As far as books are concerned
Where I leave off most people start
But here's what I've just learned
There's no two ways about love
It's true what they say about love
Come what may, it's just that way
There's no two ways about love
When fate appears on the scene
There's no betwixt and between
There's no doubt
You're in or out
There's no two ways about love
It comes right out of the blue
Like a cyclone
Sweeps you right off your feet
Don't try to cut any corners
You're heaven bound
on a one-way street
The schemes that you're dreamin' of
Fit into your world like a glove
Once you're hooked
your goose is cooked
There's no two ways about love
It comes right out of the blue
Like a cyclone
Sweeps you right off your feet
Don't try to cut any corners
You're heaven bound
on a one-way street
The schemes you're dreamin' of
Fit into your world like a glove
Once you're hooked
your goose is cooked
There's no two ways about love
What's the matter, sister?
Don't you like music?
Sure.
But I like this better.
Hmph. Here comes
that Mr. Chick Bailey again.
- Gee, Selina, you were swell.
- Thank you.
Say, waiter.
Same thing all around.
- And the party's on me, so see that I get the check.
- Oh, yes, sir.
Oh, I wouldn't want you to do that.
Oh, that's nothing.
It's a pleasure.
Well, I wouldn't argue over trivialities.
How long you gonna stay
in New York, Bill?
- I gotta leave town tonight.
- That's an excellent idea.
You see, I've got my old job
waiting for me down in Memphis.
Oh, but with the talent you've got,
you should be a dancer.
Oh, I only know a few steps
I picked up myself.
Yes, but you could work at it and learn.
Couldn't he, Chick?
Sure. They even teach elephants to dance.
Ladies and gentlemen.
The Cake Walk.
Everybody join in!
Come on, Selina.
Let's try and win this cake.
- But this is our dance.
- Tonight's the army's night, Chick.
Wait a minute, waiter.
Come on, let's dance, honey.
- But you said there was no point in dancing.
- But there is now, baby.
Why, you big blow-off.
Trying to show my daddy up!
But you ain't foolin' nobody.
Hmph!
- We got your number.
- Your check, sir.
Clem never told me
you could sing like that, Selina.
I couldn't when Clem went away...
but I practiced, and I studied.
I've always been ambitious.
Haven't you, Bill?
Never have been, except to get
three square meals a day, regular.
But I'm beginning
to see things different now.
Sorry you're going away, Bill.
- Oh, I'll be back.
- When?
Oh, when I get to be somebody.
Man, there ain't nobody
in the world...
can get me on my feet again
until we hit Memphis-
- unless this boat sinks.
- I'm tired too.
And if I never see
a bale of cotton no more in life...
that'll be too soon.
What's that?
Must be them traveling
minstrel boys got on in New Orleans.
Hee, hee!
Oh, has you seen Miss Linda Brown
She's the finest gal in town
Turns all Memphis upside down
- Yeah, man, yeah, man
- She's a dark-eyed Dixie queen
Boy, she got it and she got it mean
- "Struttingest" gal I ever seen
- Yeah, man, yeah, man
Now you should see her
when she gets goin'
- Reminds you of the Mississippi flowin'
- Aw, you dog!
- Think you boys is hot enough
- Yes, us boys is hot enough
- Well, come on boys, let's play the stuff
- Yeah, man, yeah, man
- I do a
- You can't do no
- Yes I can
- Yeah, man, yeah, man
- I can take a chorus too
- You can't take no chorus too
- Yes I can take a chorus too
- Yeah, man, yeah, man
- I can do some shufflin' too
- Look out man, what you gonna do?
- Look out, boys, he's comin' through
- Yeah, man, yeah, man
Boy, he got educated feet.
Boy, I practice all the time.
Here's what I sit up
all night trying to do.
Get this.
When the boat docks in Memphis, you should
get yourself a job in one of them Beale St. cafés.
Boy, you been readin' my mind.
Watch me go to Beale St.
Hee, hee!
Oh, sand, oh, sand
Yeah, sand
Ada, the boys want another round.
Give 'em the joint.
It's on its last leg anyway.
Two up, boy.
Baby, baby
What is the matter with you
Ain't nothin' wrong
with me, babes. Nothin' at all.
Baby, baby
What is the matter with you
One never knows, do one?
You got the world in a jar
Yeah, but where's the stopper?
And you've got nothin' to do
Do you hear that mess?
She's always layin' it on me.
- You know I always told ya
- Mmm.
- You'd be the death of me
- Mm.
And when I'm always with you
I get the third degree
- That ain't right
- Aw, tell these fools anything, but tell me the truth.
Oh, that ain't right at all
What's wrong with it?
Yes, you're takin' all my money
And goin' out havin' yourself a ball
Baby, I was born ballin',
and I'm gonna ball the rest of my life.
I took you to a nightclub
- I bought you pink champagne
- That's right.
You rode home in a taxi
While I caught that subway train
Hey, hey!
- That ain't right
- Oh, that's all right, baby.
- That's just a slight-
- Oh, that ain't right at all
Oh, that's all right, baby.
That's all right with me, in fact.
That you're takin' all my money
And goin' out havin' yourself a ball
Aw, beef to me, mama, beef to me.
I don't like pork no how.
- I went to a fortune-teller
- Yeah?
- And had my fortune told
- What'd she say?
She said you didn't love me
- All you wanted was my gold
- She was right.
- How'd she know?
- That ain't right
Oh, oh, oh, ain't right at all
Everybody wants some gold, baby.
Yes, you're takin' all my money
And goin' out havin' yourself a ball
Suffer, excess baggage, suffer.
Yeah.
- Just saw Chick Bailey.
- Chick Bailey from Chicago?
Yes. Been playin' in New Orleans.
Just stopped on his way through.
Comin' down Beale St. with a big party.
Says he wants to put Fats
for his new show at the Pickens Theater.
Fats, you's now on your way
to fame and fortune.
Boys, smarten up.
Let's put the best-lookin' one in front.
- That's me.
- All right.
So we can see the lighting effect
in the drum.
Hey, Ada, do I look better
with the hat on or with it off?
With or without, man,
you leave me cold.
- Bill!
- Yeah?
Those tables- push them together.
Here they come.
I wish somebody would
book me someplace.
- Hey, Chick Bailey.
- Hello, Ada.
Nice table right here for you.
Round of drinks,
and the best in the house.
Well, Ada, let's
hear that band of yours.
All right, Fats, go to work.
Well, all right then, boys,
latch on! Come on.
No one to talk with
All by myself
No one to walk with
But I might be on the shelf
Ain't misbehavin'
Savin' my love for you
For you, for you, for you
I know for certain
The one I love
I'm through with flirtin'
It's you that I'm thinkin' of
Ain't misbehavin'
Savin' my love for you
Like Jack Horner in the corner
Don't go nowhere
What do I care
Your kisses
A re worth waiting for
Believe me
- I don't stay out late
- Well, uh-
- Thank you.
- No place to go
I'm home about 8:00
just me and my radio
Ain't misbehavin'
Savin' all my love for you
- Hey! Whoo!
- Come back here.
I don't stay out late
Got no place to go
I'm home about 8:00
just me and my radio
Ain't misbehavin'
Savin' my love for you
Ada, I sure hate
to steal your band away.
Oh, that's all right.
You're taking a liability off my hands.
Why don't you fold up this joint?
You know, I could use you
in the show too.
- You could?
- Sure could.
Oh, boy! This joint is folding
as of Saturday night.
- What?
- Guess you're out of employment again.
You're high and outside.
- I'm going to tell Fats.
- Aren't you Bill Williamson?
- Huh?
- Sure you are.
- Hello, Selina.
- Gee, I'm glad to see you.
- What are you doing down here?
- Dancing.
But on account
of the bartender being sick...
the cook had to take
the bartender's place...
the waiter took the cook's place...
and I had to take the waiter's place.
- Gee, I'd love to see your act, Bill.
- Oh, waiter.
Bring me another pack
of cigarettes, will ya?
- Yes, sir, boss.
- Say, Chick.
I want you to do me a favor.
I want you to put Bill in the show.
- Doing what?
- He's a terrific dancer.
But, Selina,
dancers are a nickel a dozen.
Maybe so, but he was Clem's buddy.
I want to help him if I can.
- All right, Selina. He's in.
- Aw, thanks, Chick.
Bill, how soon can you leave for Chicago?
I'm on the outskirts of Peoria right now.
- Chick's gonna put you in the show.
- Sure enough?
Yep. I've got just the spot for you.
I'm gonna put you right on top.
And did he put you on top,
Uncle Bill, like he said?
Mm-hmm.
He put me on top, all right.
Hey, you, get your wig on.
There's a spot
I know a place they call Samoa by the Sea
Talkin' there's not the most
They palaver on the coast
They command each other
understand each other perfectly
If you're feeling fancy-free
If you don't give 'em repartee
To win a tropical maiden
Doesn't need topical talk
You maneuver
and if you approve her
You can win her love in a walk
Zulu man is feelin' blue
Hear his heart beat a little tattoo
Diga diga doo, diga doo doo
Diga diga doo, diga doo
You love me and I love you
The idea's old but the method is new
Diga diga doo, diga doo doo
Diga diga doo, diga doo
I'm so very diga diga doo by nature
If you don't say diga diga to your mate
you're gonna lose a papa
So if you want to be in style
way down on that tropical isle
Say diga diga doo diga doo doo
Diga diga doo, diga doo
Gee, Selina,
you were wonderful.
- How about a sandwich after the show?
- That sounds swell to me, Bill.
- I'd love to.
- Okay. I'll see you later.
- It's a date.
- But you can't, Selina.
I don't want her seen
around those cheap lunchrooms.
- Don't be like that, Chick.
- But it isn't good for the show...
and I'm running the show.
Yes, but after the show is over,
I do as I please.
We'll see about that.
If you're thinking
what's good for the show...
why don't you let me
go out and do my dance?
What? Let you do your cheap hoofing
in a classy show like this?
Why, they'd walk out on you.
Listen, Mr. Big Shot.
The only reason they ain't
walking out on you...
is because it's raining out.
Yeah? Well, if you want
to stay in this show...
just do your stuff
on the drums, that's all.
Just do your stuff on the drums.
That's just what I'm gonna do.
Fire
The low beating of the tom-toms
The slow beating of the tom-toms
Low, slow
Slow, low
Stirs your
Blood
Dance
A night-veiled girl
Whirls softly
Into a circle
Of light
Whirls softly
Slowly
Like a wisp of smoke
A round the fire
And the tom-toms beat
- What's he doing?
He's fixin' to tie
the show up in knots.
Look at 'em out there.
They love it.
Bill, you's out
of employment again.
And look at Chick.
He's thinks he's wowing them.
Stirs
Your
Blood
The tom-toms beat
And the tom-toms beat
And the low beating
of the tom-toms
Stirs your
Blood
Boy, I've never known
that number to go better.
That's right.
You were terrific.
Come in.
- Well, he fired me.
- Yes, I know.
But I don't care.
You know, I just had to do it, Selina.
Well, I don't blame you, Bill.
If it wasn't for making
trouble for you...
I'd hang a sign on that guy's eye-
"closed for the season."
Well, don't let me stop you.
Does that invitation to a sandwich still go?
It sure does. The lunchroom?
Ah, that sounds like a great place to me.
Come in.
Say, didn't I tell you
to get out of my theater?
And didn't I tell you I'd get out
when I get good and ready?
- Well, you're ready now.
- That's right.
Ready, willing and able.
Come on, Selina.
One never knows, do one?
That's just like Chick.
He ain't changed a bit.
What happened after
you socked him, Uncle Bill?
Oh, we had our ups and downs-
more downs than ups at first.
- Did you keep on dancing?
- Sure. That's when I invented that Bill Williamson step.
- You remember that, don't you, honey?
- Yes.
Come on, let me see
if you can do it. You ready? Go.
Why, you haven't forgotten it.
You did that fine.
- What's this?
- Well, well. Look at this.
It looks like Gabe
is still out of money.
Just like my old man.
What happened to Gabe,
Uncle Bill?
Oh, we kind of lost track
of him for a few years.
- Did he quit promotin'?
- Well, he did and he didn't.
You see, I was trying
to open a show in New York...
and having a peck of a lot
of trouble about money.
I was walking down the street
in Harlem that day.
- No, it ain't.
- Yes, it is.
- Well, I'll be doggone.
- How you doin'?
Ain't doin' so bad.
Thank you.
Imagine me comin'
here for a shine and finding you.
Get right on up there,
'cause this one's on the house.
- Lord, I been reading about you.
- Yeah?
Yeah. Funny thing, I was coming down
to catch the show tonight...
and comin' back and ask for you.
- Oh, man, it don't look like there's gonna be no show.
- How come?
All the chorus girls
ganged up and refused to work...
- unless they get paid for last week's rehearsal.
- What?
But if I could get open tonight,
I'd be out in front.
- Well, how much money do you need?
- I need exactly $560.
Ain't you got that much
in the box office?
No, that's been attached
for the costumes and scenery.
Well, buddy, if that's all that's
worrying you, your worries is over.
You got yourself a new agent.
You mean to tell me you got $560?
No, I ain't got 560 cents,
but I got an idea.
I got ideas too,
but what I need is money.
Now, you listen to me.
If you look prosperous
and sweet-talk them gals...
they'll be so busy figuring out how to
make you spend what they think you got...
that they ain't got no time to worry
about how much money you ain't got.
Look here, Gabe,
what are you driving at?
Just leave that to me.
Leave it to me.
You just go on back down
to that theater...
and tell them gals
that Gabriel the angel is coming.
You ain't gonna have no trouble
stalling them gals, is you?
- Oh, no. I'll see you.
- All right, buddy. I'll be out-
- My rent is due!
- I need cash money.
All you keep doing
is flapping your big mouth.
- You say too much and you do too little.
- Girls, girls, girls.
Listen. The angel is on his way,
and he'll be here any minute.
Oh, we've heard that before.
I guess that's old Gabriel
blowing his horn now.
Might be.
- Gabe!
- Evening, William!
- Shake hands with Mr. Miller.
- Mr. Miller.
Girls, this is your new boss,
Mr. Gabriel Tucker.
- He's even got an angel's name.
- But he doesn't look the part.
- All right, everybody, inside. This way, Gabe.
- Okay, Willie.
- Wait a minute.
- Where's the money?
Ladies, after all. Let's do this
in a businesslike manner.
- Let's proceed, William.
- How do you like that?
- He looks like ready money.
- Well, let's take a chance. We ain't got nothin' to lose.
Okay.
Come on, girls.
I've seen that guy
somewhere before.
Yeah?
Come on, girls. Mr. Tucker
has something to say to you.
Ladies, I understand that there's
a little matter of back salaries...
which I am here to clear up.
- That's right.
- Providing, of course-
If I can see a little sample
of what I'm putting my money into.
Maybe I could give you an idea.
Vamp me, Professor. Vamp me.
All right.
Salt Lake City haunts me
How that city taunts me
Night and day I pine
Salt Lake City on my mind
Oh, I lost my sugar
in Salt Lake City
Oh, why did I go there
I should have stayed
down in New Orleans
Never, never gone nowhere
A gal with sweet talk
From Kansas City
Her words were sweet like wine
She bought him diamonds
and limousines
Stole that man of mine
When night comes creepin'
For me, there's no sleepin'
What he sows he'll be reapin'
For he done me wrong
Oh, how I cried my heart out
in Salt Lake City
The day I heard the news
He left me deep in my solitude
With the Salt Lake
The Salt Lake City blues
Ladies of the ensemble...
I have decided to personally guarantee
the money that's coming to you all.
You will find your pay envelope
at the stage door as you pass out tonight.
And henceforth, you will
all receive a five-dollar raise.
Why, it's Gabe, isn't it?
Hello, Gabe.
- Oh, Selina, oh.
- Selina, come here a minute, honey.
I got something
to tell you confidentially.
Just a minute, Bill. I hardly
recognized you in those clothes.
- Yeah, it's been a long time.
- Oh, I should say it has.
Not since the night of the ball in New York,
when you pretended you knew Chick Bailey!
Yeah, that was funny,
but don't let me detain you.
Come on, honey.
You got to get dressed.
Oh, and that
big limousine, remember?
Bill and I've laughed about it
a hundred times.
- Haven't we, Bill?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Boy, call a half-hour.
- But Mr. Williamson, we've got an hour yet.
Listen, call a half-hour now,
and call it loud.
All right.
Bill always said if you didn't have
a nickel to your name, you'd still-
- Half-hour! Half-hour.
- Come on, Selina. It's half-hour.
- But my watch must be slow!
- It sure is!
- I know I've "seed" that guy someplace before.
- Yeah? Where?
I don't know.
The face is familiar...
but I can't recollect
the surroundings I "seed" it in.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Was it a pool room?
- No, no.
- I thought it might give you a cue.
A barber shop?
No, no.
- Say, Cousin Jake. Do me a favor, please.
- Well, what?
- Run outside and get me a box of candy.
- Candy?
- You know, somethin' big and fancy.
- Well, how big and how fancy?
Well, do the best you can
with three bucks, hear?
Uh, okay, okay, okay.
Clear outta here!
- What's wrong with it?
- I d-
- Where'd you have it fixed?
- I just had it worked on!
- Who worked on it?
- The man that's got the garage-
Well, he ain't no good.
The man you want is the man-
I had him!
He's the one that ruined it!
Well, I see you got plenty water,
but is you outta gas?
No, t'ain't that. I think maybe it's-
- Oh, it couldn't be that.
- Well, there ain't much wrong with it.
What you need is some
of them new gadgets.
You know,
the kind that you buy-
- I just bought some.
- Oh, not them.
I mean the kind what fastens
where they fits.
- A whole dozen'll cost about-
- That's too much money.
I can't afford it. I got to get
some that don't cost no more-
You can't get 'em that cheap.
Well, we can get the car
fixed up good maybe for around-
No, what you need...
- is a new car.
- Yeah.
- The kind like my uncle had. He made a trip out-
- Did he go out there?
- Sure!
- I thought all the time he was gonna go-
- He did, but not that time.
- Well, what's he doin' now?
Since he been back, he's been very busy
gettin' ready for what he thinks-
- Is that so?
- Sure.
- Well, I guess like all bachelors, he's-
- No, no. Not him.
- He gonna get married.
- He is?
Yeah, he's gonna marry the widow
whose husband used to be-
- She's a fine lady!
- Mm-hmm.
But listen-
- I heard that one time she-
- That was her daughter!
- Oh.
- You see, I'm keeping company with her.
- You is?
- Yeah, I been engaged to her ever since the time-
- I didn't know you knowed her that long.
- Sure!
I worked with her brother. And one day
on the job, the first thing I know-
That was your fault.
Now, what you should have done was-
- I did!
- You see that?
- Now that why I like talk to you.
- Yeah.
'Cause me and you can
agree with one another.
Sure!
You know one thing.
When I get the car fixed up...
I'm gonna take you and your girl
out for a ride sometime.
- That'll be great! Can you make it-
- I'll be busy then.
- When can you make it?
- Let's see. The best day for me will-
That'll suits me.
What hour?
- Anytime between-
- That's a little early, but we'll be there.
- All right, I'll be seein' ya.
- Later, bye-bye.
Bon voy-
That was awful nice of you,
honey, to promise us a raise in salary.
Oh, that's trivial, honey, trivial.
- I might even split my profits with you.
- Oh, really?
Wonderful.
Oh, that's my man.
Now, don't go away.
I'll be right back in a second.
Oh, that's swell. What-
All of this for three bucks?
Uh, the candy may be
a little stale, but it's a nice box.
Thank you.
Thank you, Cousin Jake.
- Isn't he wonderful?
- Edna Mae, I believe you've taken a shine to that angel.
- Shine? Did you say shine?
- Yes.
Doggone it.
I know I saw him somewhere.
- He's a bootblack.
- Who?
That angel. He ain't no angel.
He's got a shinin' stand in Harlem.
- He shined my shoes a thousand times.
- What? A bootblack?
- Come on, kids.
- I'm so mad, I don't know what to do.
Listen, girls!
This is me, kiddies, Gabe.
I've got a surprise for you.
Come in, deary.
We've got a surprise for you too.
All right, honey.
Now, here is somethin' for you.
Now, this is-
- What's the matter? What's wrong?
- I don't know.
Girls! Girls! Just a minute!
What are you all trying to do?
What's the trouble in here?
They can hear you out front.
There's plenty of trouble.
We're not going on till we get our money!
But, girls, you've got to finish the show.
If I have to give the people their
money back tonight, I will be ruined.
- I'm ruined now.
- He reminds me of-
No. He looks worse than that.
If it's money you all are worried about,
I think I have the solution to your problem.
Cousin Jake, where did you get
all that money?
Uh, I drove my boss
to Belmont Park today.
- You mean, there was a coincident?
- What you mean?
That the right horse
came in at the right time...
and on the right track
at the right odds?
- Uh, yeah!
- As we live and breathe!
I can't give you anything but love
Baby
That's the only thing I've plenty of
Dream awhile, scheme awhile
We're sure to find
Happiness and I guess
All those things you've always pined for
Gee, I like to see you looking swell
Baby
Diamond bracelets
Woolworth doesn't sell
Baby
Till that lucky day you know darn well
I can't give you anything but love
- Can't give you anything but love
- Love
I left you love, baby
That's the only thing I've plenty of, baby
Dream awhile, scheme awhile
You're sure to find
- Happiness and I guess
- And we guess
All those things
you've always pined for
- Baby, you're lookin' swell
- Do, do, do-do-do
Baby
Diamond and rings and jivin' things
Woolworth doesn't sell them, baby
Till that lucky day you know darn well
Baby
I can't give you anything but love
I can't give you
Anything but love
When did you go
to Hollywood, Uncle Bill?
Honey, the first time
I went to Hollywood was 1936.
- Did Miss Selina go with you?
- No, she didn't go.
- How come?
- When two people can't seem the same thing the same way...
life just gets powerful complicated.
You see, honey,
this is the living room...
here's your room,
and this is the nursery.
Oh, that's swell, Bill. That's about
the prettiest little house I ever saw.
- But not for us.
- Why not for us?
You know why not for us. We're show
people, on the road day in and day out.
We don't have time
to live in a house like that.
Sure, that's the way it's been
up until now, honey. But-
Oh, but Bill, we've been
over this a thousand times.
I know, but since I've got that Hollywood
contract, we'll have plenty of money.
- You won't have to go on workin'. You can quit.
- Quit?
Sure. You worked long enough.
It's time that you settled down.
And we have a home and-
But, Bill, I don't wanna quit.
I wouldn't be happy unless
I went on with my work, just like you.
Singing's in my blood.
I'm sorry, Selina. I just thought
maybe you'd see it different now.
Bill, I'm afraid I'll never
see it differently.
Never.
I'm sorry too.
Selina, then she went to Paris
and got to be a big star over there.
Didn't Miss Selina ever
come back, Uncle Bill?
Not yet.
- Cab Calloway!
- Hi-de-hi-de-ho
Hi-de-hi-de-ho
- Ho-de-ho
Hello, Cab!
Hello, Pops. What's all of this?
You never told me 'bout this jive.
I wish they were mine. The neighbor's
kids, just trying to show 'em a few steps.
Run along, kids. See you later.
- Come over and sit down.
- Bill, I guess you ain't as lonesome out here as I thought.
Yes, it's lonesome all right.
But I hate to give up the place in case Selina
ever change her mind and wanna come back.
- But what are you doin' out here?
- Oh!
Tonight we givin' a big party
at the Downtown Club for the soldiers.
- For the soldiers?
- Sure! A big blow-out before they go overseas.
- Bill, I want you to be there.
- You bet I'll be there. Anything for the soldiers.
Way down in Charleston
lives old Geechy Joe
Going way down to Charleston
To dig old Geechy Joe
Got a good old geechy urge
Can't do nothin' else but go
Got misery
Misery I can't lose
Nothin' but bad news
Then I dig old Geechy Joe
So he can voodoo
those lonesome blues
Gotta get back to Charleston
If I have to walk down
that railroad track
Rub a hand on a lodestone
Blue is black
If old Geechy Joe can get it
I'm never, never, never,
never, never, never, never
Coming back
Whoa
Yeah
Comin' home
Geechy Joe
Coming home
Be like old times.
- Why, t'ain't Gabe.
- Well, if this ain't a solid send out.
What do you know, Pop?
Gimme some skin.
Mellow. Now lay your racket, jack.
Say, this cat ain't hep to the jive.
Stop beatin' up your chops to him.
Now, ain't that a bring-down.
That's a wrong riff, jack.
Say, what the devil
you two fools talkin' about?
We're talkin' jive. He says he's glad
to see you, and he wants to shake your hand.
- Solid. -
Righteous. - Crazy.
- Go along, Cab.
- Okay.
Say, Bill. Come on. I want you to come
out front and catch this next number.
- I'm quite sure that you'll get a great big kick out of it.
- Really?
- Go ahead.
- I'll see you.
Don't know why
There's no sun up in the sky
Stormy weather
Since my man and I ain't together
Keeps rainin' all the time
Life is bare
Gloom and misery everywhere
Stormy weather
Just can't get my poor self together
I'm weary all the time
The time
So weary all the time
Since he went away
The blues walked in and met me
If he stays away
Old rockin' chair will get me
All I do is pray
the lord above will let me
Walk in the sun once more
Can't go on
Everything I had is gone
Stormy weather
Since my man and I ain't together
Keeps rainin' all the time
I'll walk around heavyhearted and sad
Night comes around
and I'm still feeling bad
Rain pourin' down
Blindin' every hope I had
This pitterin', patterin'
beatin' and scatterin'
Drives me mad
Love, love, love, love
This misery
Is just too much for me
Can't go on
Everything I had is gone
Stormy weather
Since my man and I ain't together
Keeps rainin' all the time
Keeps rainin' all
The time
Ooh
Keeps rainin' all the time
- Keeps rainin' all the time
- Stormy weather
Keeps rainin all the time
Can't go on
Everything I had is gone
Stormy weather
Since my man and I ain't together
Keeps rainin' all the time
- So you're goin' over, huh?
- Yes, sir!
- And I hope to be with him soon.
- Oh, I envy your dad. I wished I had a boy like you.
And so do I.
Hello, Bill.
Why, hello, Selina.
Did I hear you say something?
- Yes, and I meant it too.
- But you always-
But a woman can change her mind.
You hear that?
"We want Williamson."
- Honey, you got him!
- We want Williamson.
And Williamson is the guy.
Where you goin' there, Mr. Bill
I've got a date up on the hill
You don't mean that pretty chick
That's the one
I got to get there quick
What's the matter, Bill
Go ahead
I'm a fool who fears to tread
Looks to me like you're in love
Come on, Cab, gimme a shove
It comes right out of the blue
Like a cyclone
Sweeps you right off your feet
Right off
Don't try to cut any corners
You're heaven bound
on a one-way street
The schemes you're dreamin' of
Fit into your world like a glove
Once you're hooked
your goose is cooked
There's no two ways about love
There's no two ways
About love
Mmm
My, my. Ain't that somethin'?
You ain't seen nothin' yet.
Talk about a treat.
You should see that chick and me-
Struttin' down the street
My, my
Ain't that something
Hear me shout
Mm-mm
Ain't that something
to shout about
- Boy
- Whatcha gonna say there, gate
- Oh, boy
Palomar, shalomar, Swanee shore
Let me dig that jive once more
- Boy
- Lay it right on down to the gator
- Oh, boy
- Lay it flat as a gator
Now can't you hear
those hepcats call
Come on, boys
Let's have a ball
The jim, jam, jump
if you jump and jive
Makes you dig your jive
on the mellow side
Hep, hep
Hip, hip
The jim, jam, jump is the solid jive
Makes you nine foot tall
when you're four foot five
Hep, hep
Now, don't you be that ickeroo
Get hep, come on
and then you follow through
You get your steady, fool
You make the joint jump
like the gators do
The jim, jam, jump
is the jumpin' jive
Makes you like your eggs
on the Jersey side
Hep, hep
The jim, jam, jumpin jive
Makes you hep, hep
on the mellow side
Now, I've told you 'bout
the jumpin jive
The jim, jam, jump
jumpin jive
You got to dig this mellow jive
Yes, yes, you dig it
on the mellow side
Everybody dance!
My, my, my
Ain't that somethin'
Where's my hat
My, my, my
Heart's a-thumpin'
I ain't seen nothin'
that looks like that
My, my, my
I'm thumpin'
Just like that
My, my, my, my jumpin'
Well, I'm jumpin' to the rumba
and I'm jumpin' to the side
It really walks, it really talks
It really moves around
Lucky me who thought I'd be
We're gonna figure it out
Oi, oi, oi
My, my
Ain't that somethin'
Hear me shout
My, my
Ain't that somethin'
Ain't that somethin' to shout about
My, my, my, my
My, my
Ain't that somethin'
Ain't that somethin' to shout about