It's a red light!
Hang on to your seat!
Charlie! I can't believe
you did that.
You scared me half to death!
I can't open my door.
How am I supposed to get out?
You said you wanted
to go to this dance.
I do want to go to the dance.
I just didn't think...
Hi, Charlie. Nice parking job.
This is gonna cost me $2.00.
Hi. Hello.
You're looking pretty. Thank you.
You look nice yourself.
Look who's here!
Your favorite from the Rainbow
Road, Miss Patsy Cline.
Howdy. You all havin'
a good time? Yeah!
This is a Bob Wills' tune
that I picked special
just to sing to you.
Deep within my
heart lies a melody
A song of old San Antone
Where in dreams I
live with a memory
Beneath the stars all alone
Well, it was there I found
Beside the Alamo
Enchantment strange
as the blue up above
On that moonlit pass
that only he would know
Still hears my
broken song of love
That's Cline?
Patsy Cline. Right.
Why don't I know her?
Damned if I know.
She sings at the Rainbow Road?
On weekends, yeah.
Lips so sweet and tender
like petals fallin' apart
Thanks for bringing me,
Charlie. Speak once again
Of my love, my own
Broken song Empty words I know
Shall live in my heart all alone
For that moonlit pass
She went to school
with my brother.
They used to say,
" Don't dare Patsy if
you don't want it done."
And Rose, my Rose of San Antone
She's got real nice tits.
And she's married,
Bozo. You lose.
Thank you.
Stop it! You're such a geek!
Hi. Hi.
I want you to get your coat.
I wanna drive you someplace
for a drink. I want us to
dance a while.
Then I want us to get to know
each other a lot better.
You want a lot, don't you?
Yeah, I do, baby.
Well, people in hell want
ice water. That don't
mean they get it.
Patsy, you never did.
I did so. I looked him right
in the eye and said...
"People in hell want ice water.
That don't mean they get it."
Who was he? Some clown
with hot britches.
Lord, I do get tired of men
sometimes, always pawin'
and snortin' around.
They after you all the
time when you were my age?
I don't know.
Were they, Mama?
Tell me. Stop it.
Quit, Patsy.
Back when I was in high school
and had a better shape...
there was this boy
named Teddy Welloff.
Had gray eyes with
coal black eyelashes.
This is way before
I met your daddy.
May he rot in hell. Don't speak
like that about Daddy.
Anyway, at lunch we'd all
go in the cloakroom to
get our dinner buckets.
Every day this Teddy
Welloff used to brush his
front up against me...
when I was bent over.
That's the truth.
Wait, there's more.
One day, I took my
ink pen with me.
That thing had a real
sharp point on it.
I never looked at him
the rest of the day...
but there was egg salad sandwich
all over that cloakroom.
That boy walked funny for a week.
I'm gonna pee my pants.
You gonna come in for a while?
Is Gerald still up?
It looks like it.
No, honey, I better go
on home. You chicken!
I'll be over for Sunday dinner.
Bye.
Nightynight.
Good night, baby.
I'm home.
How'd it go?
Well, I only made $25.
I did real good I
think. That's nice.
I sang "San Antonio Rose."
I've been gone all evening.
Don't you want to talk to me?
Say "Kiss my ass" or something?
Sorry, honey.
How'd it go tonight?
You already asked me that.
Ask me something else?
Come on, let's have
a conversation.
Notice anything different?
I finished the riggin'.
Patsy, why are you always
pushing at me so hard?
I don't know.
Just hoping for a fight,
or a laugh or something.
I don't want to fight
with you. I'm not mad.
I can't stand it. Makes me want
to scream and claw my face.
What should I do?
You didn't ask me how to
get into this marriage.
I don't think you ought to
ask me how to get out of it.
Is he mean to you? No.
Does he drink? Gamble?
Does he chase the women?
Then what?
Come on, girl. Speak the
truth and shame the devil.
God as my witness, I don't know!
I laid in bed and thought,
" Shit! What if I was blind
or didn't have my legs?"
You watch that mouth.
Mom, I'm home.
I'm starvin'.
There's lunch made,
but don't spoil your dinner.
Say hello to your sister before
you worry about your belly.
I don't know, Mama.
My life ain't so bad.
I got a decent house,
a man who loves me.
I've even sung on
television four times.
Tell me. Why do I have to
force myself to get out
of bed every mornin'?
You always was hard to
keep satisfied, even when
you was little.
I'm not talking about
when I was three.
I'm asking you what
I should do now.
Maybe you should scream and claw
your face. See if that'll help.
I said blue moon of
Kentucky keep on ashinin'
Shine on the one that's
gone and left me blue
Blue moon of Kentucky
keep on ashinin'
Shine on the one that's
gone and left me blue
It was on one moonlit night
Stars shining bright
Whispered on high
Love said goodbye
I said blue moon of
Kentucky keep on ashinin'
Shine on the one that's
gone and left me blue
Thank you. Goddamn
woman, you're good!
That bitch can sing!
I don't know if you
remember me. Take a walk.
I really like the way you sing.
What were you doing while I sang?
You think that's funny?
I was listening.
I don't like the way you
listen. Take a walk.
Hi.
Oh, merciful God.
I want to explain.
It's the creature
that wouldn't die.
I came over here to
explain. He won't go away.
To apologize for messin' you up.
I was just enjoying your singin'.
Now that I get a good
look at Patsy Cline,
she don't look so hot.
I don't care if you have
sung on some halfassed
television program.
You don't sing that good.
You ever listen to a Kitty
Wells record real close?
You'd go home and slit
your goddamn throat.
I've grown so used
to that man somehow
And I'm nobody's sugar baby now
'Cause I'm lonesome
I got the lovesick blues
We're gonna take a
break. Thank you.
Seven and seven.
Last week at the high
school you said you
wanted to buy me a drink.
I want a seven and seven.
A seventyseven.
Well, you've got the
advantage on me.
You know my name,
but I don't know yours.
Charlie.
Charlie Dick.
Dick?
Charlie Dick?
That's right.
What do you want
out of me, Charlie?
You didn't follow me out
to Rainbow Road because
you're a fool for music.
Hell no. I want to get
to know you better.
Okay. What does that mean?
It means I want to get
to know you better.
I figure when you say you want
to get to know me better...
what you mean is you want
a tenminute screw in the
backseat of your car.
Son of a bitch.
You must think that thing
you got between your legs
is lined with gold.
I can get tail anytime.
I don't have to crawl
after a mean woman who's
got a cob crossways.
If I just want to bump uglies
with somebody, I got plenty
of places to go.
"Bump uglies"? That's right.
My Lord, what a charming
expression.
I just grew up.
My daddy dumped us
when I was about 16.
I haven't seen him since.
But Mom and I did okay.
She couldn't work too much,
so I've worked pretty
steady since I was 15.
You made a livin' for
the whole family?
No. Mama sewed for people.
But basically I did.
I want to ask you something.
What?
You know all those things
you said you want?
Yeah.
Answer me quick.
Which you want most?
All of it. I want it all.
And I want to make it right.
I do.
Since I've been 11 or 12 years
old, I've had my life mapped out.
I haven't pushed hard these
last years, but I'm gonna
start next year.
I'm starting next year,
too, by God. That's the
time to start for me.
I'm serious. I'm gonna
be a singer.
I'm gonna make some
money, have some kids...
and then I'm gonna stop singing
and raise those kids right.
Have a big house with
yellow roses all around it.
You think that's silly? No.
I figure somebody
ought to be happy.
Hell. It might as
well be me. Right?
Right.
I've never met a woman like you.
I can talk to you.
You know what that
means to a man?
Do you?
I don't know.
Let's go dancin'.
Where? Right out here. Come on.
In the parking lot? Yep.
Are you kiddin'?
I don't do this. You don't?
No. But I'm doin' it.
No, Charlie, don't leave me.
I was starving,
and I didn't even know.
Hey, Mama!
Mama, come here.
What are you doing here
on Sunday morning?
Mama, I feel so good!
Don't give me that dark
look. I feel so damn good!
What's them suitcases?
I left him.
I don't care!
There's a man. No,
I'm doing this for me.
There's a man. Mama! Honey baby!
Come on, honey.
Be happy for me.
Does Gerald know?
I stopped by on my way
over here and told him.
You know what he said? What?
"Patsy, if your considered
opinion is that you really
want a divorce...
I'll not stand in your way."
There's a man. You're too happy.
Yes, there is.
I don't know. There might be.
I don't know, but oh,
sweet Jesus, I just feel so good.
Oh, my darling, you're crying
Boohoohoohoo
There's no use in denying
I've cried for you
It was your favorite pastime
Making me blue
Last week was the last time
I cried for you
Seven hankies blue
I filled with my tears
Seven letters too
I filled with my fears
Guess it never pays
To make your lover blue
Seven lonely days
I cried and I cried for you
Oh, my darling, you're crying
Boohoohoohoo
Your cheating heart
Will make you weep
You'll cry and cry
And try to sleep
But sleep won't come
The whole night through
Your cheating heart
Will tell on you
When tears come down
Like falling rain
You'll toss around
Nice day.
Great day.
Do you want to top me
all the time? Just say,
"Yes, it's a nice day."
Yes, it's a nice day.
This water is cold.
We used to come swimmin'
here up till November.
I'm telling you, this water's
got ice cubes in it.
A guy in my class says he saw an
8foot water moccasin in here...
with his mouth open,
showing white.
I ain't afraid of snakes.
Take a swim, big talk. Go ahead.
I'll pay you. How much will
it take for you to jump in?
What? I'm serious. How much?
Three hundred.
You'd really do it?
You got the cash? I love it!
Man, I wish I had $300.
You don't have it?
I ain't jumping in for nothin'.
I'll save you.
You want to have other
nice days like today?
Sure.
I mean lots of them. Sure.
No, I mean lots of them.
Good times all the
time, Sunday to Sunday.
What?
Charlie?
Wanna get married?
I dare you!
Yes!
You telling me yes? Yes!
Beautiful. Doesn't
she look beautiful?
Are you ready?
We're ready.
Byebye.
If you find yourself
wondering what to do in
the dark, give me a call.
I think I can manage.
I'll see you at work.
On Monday morning.
Byebye, Mama.
I love you, sugar.
You take care of yourself.
You look so pretty today. Bye.
What the hell you been
doing in there? Come here.
It's kind of scary,
isn't it? What do you mean?
You go out and buy a new dress...
stand in front of a
preacher, say a few words...
suddenly everything's changed.
I just want it to work out,
Charlie. I want everything
to be right.
Well, come here.
Wait.
This is my wedding night.
I want the words.
Say the words.
I love you.
Say it again.
I love you, goddamn it!
That's so nice.
I want this to work out, too.
I'm sure as hell gonna try.
Yeah? Yeah.
Here. You look like you
need this more than me.
God bless you, mister.
Big night, huh?
Real big.
Tell me. How was the
honeymoon? Nice?
Hell, yeah. It was wonderful.
Two days at a cutrate
motel. It was great.
Real uptown stuff.
Pasty didn't like it?
Patsy didn't say a word.
She wouldn't. I didn't like it.
I didn't like it. Jesus,
you're in a mood.
I've got $12 to my name.
Twelve dollars until payday.
The money ain't so bad here.
Or so good.
What do you want?
Want to be like that old
fart, Lawrence?
Wear a suit, run the place?
Hell, no.
I'd just like somethin'
different maybe. Do something
a little better.
I'd like to get my
own place maybe.
I don't care,
I ain't gonna do it.
The idea of you asking me to
go on television and lie.
I am not asking you to lie.
All you've got to do is say,
"Mr. Godfrey, I'm Hilda Hensley.
I brought my friend Patsy
Cline. I'm her talent scout."
That's not a lie.
You are my friend.
I ain't gonna do it,
so stop flapping your jaws at me.
That man from the show told
you that talent scouts
can't be a relative.
Is that why you give me
that housecoat of yours
with the puff sleeves?
I give you that housecoat
'cause you said you liked it.
Well, I won't lie on television.
Goddamn it! I'm not
asking you to lie.
Just don't spill your
guts is all I'm askin'.
Stop that dirty talk now.
Mama, think of what it could mean
to sing on national television.
All you gotta do is just say...
"Mr. Godfrey, I'm Hilda Hensley.
I've brought my friend Patsy
Cline. I'm her talent scout."
Come on, Mama.
Do I have to get on my
knees and beg you? I will.
Please! Help me to be a
singer, have my house with
the yellow roses. Please!
That house with the yellow roses!
I'm sick of hearing about it.
What does Charlie
say about all this?
He thinks it's a terrific idea.
Well, I ain't gonna do it.
The idea of me on television.
Thirty seconds.
They're from
Winchester, Virginia.
Patsy, I can't do it.
You can, too. Don't be
an old chicken.
You look beautiful.
A little color in your cheeks.
Mrs. Hensley? You're on.
Follow me. Just say what
we practiced.
Say what we practiced and
smile. You look real pretty.
You're better looking
than her, Woodhouse.
Get her off of there.
Let's see Patsy.
Marla Kleinman. Remember, folks.
Your applause is on
the applause meter.
Get lost! Stop it.
Hello and welcome.
There's your mama!
That is a pretty dress.
What color is that exactly?
Mr. Godfrey, I'm Hilda Hensley.
And I brought my
friend Patsy Cline.
And I'm her talent scout. Good.
Miss Cline, let's go.
Hurry please, around the back.
Where are you from?
Winchester, Virginia.
That's lovely country. So,
what's Patsy's talent?
She sings.
Does she sing better than I do?
Oh. Well, she's...
She's wonderful.
She made a record.
Why don't we bring her out?
Ladies and gentlemen...
let's welcome Patsy Cline.
Come on, Patsy! Come on, baby!
I go out walkin' after midnight
Out in the moonlight
just like we used to do
I'm always walkin' after midnight
Searchin' for you
She looks great, don't she?
I walk for miles
along the highway
Well, that's just my way
of sayin' I love you
I'm always walkin' after midnight
Searchin' for you
That's beautiful.
I stopped to see a weepin'
willow cryin' on his pillow
Maybe he's cryin' for me
You lucky boy.
She could make it big.
Night winds whisper to me
I'm lonesome as I can be
She's singing good.
I go out walkin' after midnight
Out in the moonlight
just hopin' you may be
Somewhere out walkin'
after midnight
Searchin' for me
Patsy Cline!
This Virginia gal can sing.
Let us hear from you
through the applause meter.
Watch the meter. Come on,
people, clap louder.
Go, go!
Patsy Cline is the winner!
She won!
Bull's eye!
A little draggy to me that
time. Patsy, that's all right.
This is gonna make us all a
whole lot of money, little girl.
Listen, boys, you don't
mind if we try it one...
Come on. One more time.
Thanks a lot, boys.
I'm home, baby.
Where've you been?
I stopped and had a drink.
Yeah. Five or seven.
I worked my hump off
making you baked chicken,
you come home this late.
I'll eat it.
You got a finger? Then put it
in a telephone and dial when
you'll be late.
I said I'd eat the thing.
Lady, I've got a message
for you. Screw your baked
chicken and screw you.
Yeah? That's the last time I'm
gonna make you something nice.
Oh, poor Patsy.
You dumb son of a bitch!
You want your dinner?
Why don't you eat it now?
Gonna throw a plate?
You wanna start on
the living room?
Charlie, look what you've done!
Goddamn it!
Sip it slow and the
world stays sweet.
My daddy used to say
that same thing.
Do my back, baby,
would you please?
He was something, my old man.
He used to eat cold navy
bean sandwiches for
breakfast every morning.
I hope he rots in hell.
What do you mean?
He's crazy.
He tried some stuff with me once.
You telling me he tried
to mess with you?
I don't want to talk about
that now. How come you
never told me about that?
How come you never say
anything about your family?
Not when I'm in such a good mood.
Hello? Patsy Cline?
That's me. What? Who is it?
Is it Woodhouse? Hush up.
I'm sorry. I didn't hear
you. Tell him he made me
late for dinner.
For the love of God,
put a lid on it. Yes, ma'am.
I'm sorry, my husband's
a little nuts.
This is Decca Records. What?
That's Decca Records.
" Walkin' after Midnight"
jumped to number 16!
I am on the son of
a bitchin' charts!
Goddamn it, baby!
Let's go spend some money.
I got a letter from Washington.
Probably from Eisenhower,
wanting to know why I
didn't vote for him.
Shit! I've been drafted.
What? They want me to
show up next week.
I can't be drafted.
I'm in the National Guard.
You said they never miss
you at those meetings.
Well, I ain't goin',
I'll tell you that much.
I'll shoot my toe off.
I'll tell 'em I'm a
homo. I ain't goin'!
I love you. Take care
of yourself.
Bye, baby.
Well, now, it ain't
the end of the world.
Fort Bragg's not exactly
a million miles away.
You've got that tour coming up.
Shit! Why don't you tell me every
cloud's got a silver linin'?
Why don't you move
in with me, honey?
No sense in paying
rent on your place.
Well, good mornin'.
Says who?
For heaven's sake.
Sit up and take some nourishment.
Charlie'll have his first
leave in three weeks...
and you walk around with your
lower lip draggin' the floor.
Big bawlin' baby.
I oughta fix you a sugar tit.
You're still not too big
for me to smack your jaws
for you. You know that?
You make that sign again,
I'll leave the print of
my hand across your face.
I'll make your teeth rattle.
For those of you who've
got to get to work,
it's 8:30 in the morning.
Let's continue listening
to everybody's favorites.
I got a check today.
Why don't you go out and
spend some money?
It'll make you feel better.
Says who?
You're just too mean
to live lately.
Well, what do you think?
I think it's beautiful.
I think I hate it.
You sour, mean thing.
But I know how to
get sweet again.
I'm lookin' for Charlie
Dick of the 20th Battalion.
Go down here and turn left.
Can you tell me where
"C" Company is?
Right over there. There?
Thank you. You're welcome.
Charlie!
Hey, baby. How are ya?
What'd they do to your
hair? They cut it.
Eat your hearts out!
Come on, honey. Hurry up,
get the key in there.
I was waitin' to see you.
Wait, Charlie.
I gotta close the window.
Hurry up.
You know something, Charlie?
You can't go to your grave
saying you weren't ever loved.
'Cause no matter what happens to
you for the rest of your life...
right now, by God,
somebody loves you.
Totally.
Come on home and
fool around with me
So, honey, fool around You'll
know right where I'm at
And don't worry if I'm lonesome
'cause I'm used to that
And when you're tired of foolin'
'round with two or three
Then come on home and
fool around with me
Won't you come home,
Bill Bailey Won't you come home
I'm home the whole day long
I'll do the cookin',
honey I'll pay the rent
I know I've done you wrong
Remember that rainy
evenin' I drove you out
With nothin' but a fine tooth
comb Take it home.
I know that I'm to blame
And ain't that a shame
Bill Bailey, won't you please
come home Come home, Bill Bailey
Bill Bailey, won't you
please come home
Lord, I'm give out.
I'm so tired, my ass is draggin'
the floor behind me.
I'm so tired,
I wished I was dead.
I'm so tired, I wished
I'd never been born.
I'm so tired, I wished my
daddy'd had his thing cut
off so he never...
God Almighty! Will you
boys let it be?
Rollin' in my sweet baby's arms
Gonna lay around this shack
Till the milk train comes back
Rollin' in my sweet baby's arms
I ain't gonna work
on the railroad
I ain't gonna work on the farm
Gonna lay around this shack
till the milk train comes back
Rollin' in my sweet baby's arms
Patsy?
Are you okay?
Darling, tell those boys
they'll have to wait.
I can't get up.
How about it? You gonna live?
Oh, Lord, I've been better.
Let me have a sip of this.
You have to do that in
the mornin'? It puts hair
on your head.
Oh, my God in heaven!
I bet I'm pregnant.
Lord, I can't be pregnant.
I just had a hit record.
My husband's in the army.
I mean, oh, Lord.
How the hell am I gonna
tour if I'm pregnant?
Oh, God. You talk
about your bad timin'.
Please, Fred, don't eat that.
Hi, honey.
Charlie.
Look at me, honey.
You think I look just awful?
Hell, no. You look great, baby.
You always do.
Thanks.
I'm crazy 'bout you, baby.
I love you all the time.
Come here.
You sure you want to?
Look out. I'm comin' to get you.
Ah, baby.
You still like me, Charlie?
Yeah. You do?
Lord, bitch. You don't
sing. You whine. Whine.
Hi, darlin'.
What are you doin'?
Havin' a glass of champagne
with Kirk Douglas.
What's it look like I'm doin'?
You don't have to iron
me a shirt every day.
I thought you told me Sergeant
Wilson wanted you lookin' sharp.
I'll tell you a secret.
I don't give a goddamn
what Sergeant Wilson says.
That tight assed bastard's been on
my back ever since I got here.
God, I hate this army.
I hate this state.
I hate this miserable
little apartment.
I've been places I
like better, too.
I could still be making
records if I'd stayed home.
Nobody asked you to come here.
The hell you didn't.
You begged me. I didn't mean it.
Come on, Charlie. Don't fuss now.
I'm makin' chili for
dinner. You like that.
Let's just be nice. Oh, my.
"I'm makin' chili,
and I try to be nice...
but my husband's just
so rude and nasty."
Shut up. Poor Patsy!
Why don't you just shut
your mouth? Why don't
you try and make me?
Don't push me,
Charlie. I dare you.
Patsy. Patsy!
Leave me alone!
You know the part I remember?
I remember the part when you
told me over and over...
how you're gonna protect me.
Keep anybody from hurtin' me.
You remember all those
times you told me that?
Patsy, wait!
Patsy, I'm sorry.
Open the door up.
I'll bring the rest.
Will you get the
baby things, John?
I'm gonna start singin' again
right after the baby's born.
I was hopin' you'd
stay home for a while.
I'm gonna start singin' the
same week the baby's born.
I can make it, Mama.
Damn it, I know I can.
All I need is one good song
to put me over the top.
Then when I've made enough,
I can retire, raise the baby.
I just wanna make it right.
You forgot the part
about the yellow roses.
What the livin' hell?
They told me...
It's a false alarm.
Why don't you put a star
in your crown, and get old
Charlie a beer?
Can I have a kiss?
Can I have a decent kiss?
Miss me?
Nope.
I didn't know it till I
saw you, but, yes, I did.
Look at you.
I got ten days' leave.
I got two good lookin' women,
and a baby on the way!
Hog heaven!
Mama, look at these sweet little
things Betty just gave me.
Aren't they darlin'? Look
at that one. It's got a
little bit of embroidery.
Damn it! Get your feet
off the baby's clothes.
Charlie, for the love of God!
Why don't you get out
from under our feet?
Go buy yourself a beer
or something. Lord.
All right, if that's what
you think I should do.
Dinner's at 6:00. All right.
Charlie here says he loves
the army. Hell, yes.
Says he's gonna reenlist
when his time's up.
You know, Woodhouse,
I never saw so many
teeth in a horse's ass.
I gotta go.
You butthole. Come on.
I didn't know they made
apron strings this long.
I gotta get home.
Let's stop and have one.
It's on the way.
Just a quick one.
Hey, bartender, let us have
a shot for everybody.
No, not for me.
Nothing but the best for
Charlie. Yes, one more.
One more. Just one before you go.
No, I gotta get goin'.
Y'all have a good night.
It's been real nice.
I'll see you before I go.
Hey, Charlie. What?
Nothin'. What?
Well, your hair is all.
You look so different
with short hair. So?
So, I think it's kind of cute.
I like it.
Remember?
All those good times we had.
Yeah, I remember.
Of course I remember.
Well, why do you have to
go home so early then?
Talk to me, Charlie.
You know I've always liked you.
We're goin' to Carol's
house. Come on, Charlie.
Let's get outta here.
Is the father around so I
can get the rest of this
information from him?
Well, what's his name?
Charles Dick.
Son of a bitch!
Stop that dirty talk
now. He'll be here soon.
The son of a bitch!
Oh, Mama.
Somebody answer the phone.
Hello. Charlie?
Where are you?
Charlie, we're at the
hospital. She's had her baby.
I'll be right down. No,
you won't be right down.
You keep your miserable
self away. She had a hard
time. She's finally asleep.
She asked for you 14 times
tonight, and you weren't there.
Damn your soul, Charlie
Dick. Where were you?
There's your dad.
Hi, honey.
She's beautiful.
You want to hold her? Yeah.
Come here, you little thing.
I got her.
I got ya.
She's so pretty.
Look at her hair. I know.
It's curlin' already.
You still think Julie's
a good name for her?
I wish to God I'd been with you.
Yeah. Where were you?
I'd tell you a hundred
lies, but I ain't goin' to.
Got drunk.
That's whiskey under the bridge.
Fifty cents, please. Yes, ma'am.
Hello? Hi, baby, it's me.
Hi, Charlie. Guess what?
I found us a new apartment.
It's got room for the baby...
and it's still cheaper than that
other one we had down here.
Got a big kitchen, too.
So, what do you say?
Why don't you come on down?
No, Charlie, I can't.
I want to start singin' again,
and Mama helps me with Julie.
Come on, baby. I really miss
ya. I wanna see my kid.
Don't you get another leave
in a couple of months?
You can see her then.
Goddamn. Why are you
so polite anymore?
Can't you just talk normal?
I feel like I'm talkin' to
Eleanor Roosevelt.
I gotta go, Charlie.
The baby's cryin'.
I'll talk to you, okay? Yeah,
okay, if Julie's cryin'.
Patsy.
You awake?
Wake up, baby.
Shh. Put something on.
I want to take you someplace.
What's the matter?
What are you doing here?
It's important. You crazy?
It's the middle of night!
I can't leave the baby.
We'll put her with Hilda.
Why won't you tell me
what this is about?
Just wait.
At least tell me
where we're going.
I need something from you.
I need you to look me
in the face and say...
"You screw up a lot,
but I still love you,
Charlie. I always will."
I told you before you left,
I'm not holding any grudges.
I need something from you.
I need you to look me
in the face and say...
"You screw up a lot,
but I still love you,
Charlie. I always will."
You screw up a lot,
Charlie, but I still love
you and I always will.
Say it again.
You screw up a lot,
but I still love you,
Charlie. I always will.
I'll have a blue Christmas
Without you
I'll be so blue
Thinking about you
Decorations of red
On a green Christmas tree
Start the movie!
Won't mean a thing, dear, if...
What are they doin'?
What the hell's goin' on?
I cannot believe this!
Honey, your mama's life is not
workin' out. Trust me. It's not.
I'm goin' to Nashville tomorrow.
See if I can do something.
Aren't you Patsy Cline?
Yeah.
I'm Randy Hughes.
I was just coming to
see you. Is that right?
You wrote me a letter
about a year ago.
But I had a baby and haven't
been doin' much singing.
You don't have to sell me.
I think you're maybe the best
country singer in the world.
Come in here.
Let's you and I talk.
I always did like a man who knew
how to start a conversation good.
I swear, I can make us
both a lot of money.
You won't be sorry.
You know why not? Why?
Because when the song is
right and I feel it...
I can tell from looking
at people's faces that
I've reached inside them.
You got any idea what
that feels like?
You want to be Kitty Wells?
Hell no! I want to
be Hank Williams.
All right. Sit down,
listen to me.
I got a story to tell you.
I heard you sing one night
in a dump in Virginia.
Twelve tables,
watereddown drinks...
dance floor the size
of that coffee table.
You were good.
The crowd liked ya.
Ate up that yodelin'
and growlin' stuff.
Then you let go on "Walkin'
the Floor Over You."
But you did it slow
like a ballad.
I'm tellin' you, the hair on
the back of my neck stood up.
There I was in this
dive in Virginia...
and I was listening to
something real special.
Yeah.
You get my drift?
I'll make it simple.
You got a voice that was
made to sing love songs.
If I work with you,
we take advantage of that fact.
I don't wanna talk about
it anymore. I got starving
kids waiting in the car.
It's too late. It's all set up.
I don't give a damn!
I don't want four big male
singers drowning me out.
They're booked and
will be there at 2:00.
If they're there,
I'm not showing up.
Musicians are booked.
Owen Bradley's gonna be
there. I'm gonna be there.
You can show up or not.
Just suit your damn self.
I will.
2:00.
Grab hold of Randy, Madrine.
They got four singers backing
me up today. Big ones.
They're just gonna drown
me out. Hell's bells!
Let's have the next bit.
One, two.
Hello. Did you tell
'em what I said?
Mr. Bradley's the
producer, darling.
Hello, Patsy. Hi, Mr. Bradley.
What's the frown for?
You've been worryin' again.
Don't frown. You'll make
yourself old before your time.
I wanted to talk to
you... Listen to me.
Everything's all right.
The song's a good one.
The arrangement's a good one.
The backup singers are
good. Even the glazed
doughnuts are good.
Everything's good today,
so relax and be happy and sing!
Just make sure they hear me.
Sing!
Take seven coming up.
I can see you all recognize
that song. That's great.
We happen to have the little girl
backstage that made that famous.
We're proud of her at the Grand
Old Opry. Miss Patsy Cline!
I fall
To pieces
Each time I see you again
I fall
To pieces
How can I be just your friend
You want me to act
Like we've never kissed
You want me to forget
Pretend we've never met
And I've tried
But I haven't yet
You walk by
And I fall to pieces
I like everything you
sing. You just open your
mouth and I fall down.
But when you sing
those slow ones...
I just love it.
Randy told me it's number
nine on the pop charts.
I'm a crossover.
Money, money, money!
I wanna buy Mama a
pure silk dress.
Give Sylvia that graduation
party she never had.
I want to spend
some of that money.
I'll tell you what.
I'll help you do it.
I'm home. Had to crawl
part way, but I made it.
That's pretty.
Bake that all by your Ionesome?
I sure did.
How come you didn't bake
me a cake for my birthday?
Goddamn it! That's not funny.
Been working on that all day.
Didn't this pie turn out nice?
Did it with tapioca
just like Mama does.
I can't wait to see her and
John and Sylvie tomorrow.
Why don't you go easy on that
drinkin' tomorrow at the party?
Why don't you kiss my furry butt?
You think I wouldn't?
Come on, Charlie.
I'm cooking chicken.
Stop it. Everything's gonna burn.
Where are the kids
at? They're upstairs
in their bedroom.
Come on. Oh, Lord!
On the linoleum floor...
with my dress up around my ears?
Charlie!
Red hots. Get your red hots here.
Here's a taker for you.
Come on now. Like New York City.
Come on!
Hey, everybody. Listen a minute.
We have a high school
graduate in our family
for the very first time.
Charlie and I finally
got enough money...
Finally!
To give her a party
and buy her a present.
Here it is. Happy graduation.
It's a new toothbrush.
Don't Sylvia looks sweet today?
I love her new hairdo.
I'm gonna put him
down. He's so crabby.
Good night, honey.
Give Grandma a kiss.
Here, sweetheart. Put him down.
Give Mama a kiss.
Oh. It just kills me
I don't see him more.
I know it. I wrote that book.
How's things with
you and Charlie?
Up and down?
There's lots of up and down.
Oh, Patsy!
Geez, Mama.
You know Charlie. He drinks a
little, but I knew that when
I married him.
Other than that,
things are silky smooth.
When he drinks,
he's got a temper.
Does he hit you?
Just that one time.
They say if a man hits you once,
there's always another time.
Sis, you have some money?
We want some more beer.
I wanna go with you.
See you in a minute.
You don't remember
Barbara Simmons?
You had crush on her all
through the fifth grade.
You're a damn liar.
I don't know why, though,
with that frizzy brown hair.
What about you and
old Homer Atkinson?
I never liked Homer Atkinson!
You loved Homer
Atkinson. I did not!
You called him every
night and hang up...
when he answered.
Look out!
Somebody help me!
The babies.
Where are the babies?
Patsy, they're fine.
John's all right, too.
You had us scared a little bit.
Tell me. Are the babies alive?
Honey, little Randy and
Julie weren't with you.
John was with you, and he's okay.
The kids are sleeping.
Good night.
Relax. Just a moment.
Forceps, please.
Very good.
That's fine.
That's very good. Fine, fine.
Just as we expected.
It's healing nicely.
Is it that bad?
It's not that bad...
I wanna look.
When the stitches come out,
the scars will heal very quickly.
This is what I got to deal with?
You cut your suit
to fit your cloth.
Later you can have plastic
surgery if you want.
Hell yes, I want plastic
surgery. I want all I can get.
Maybe you can make me
look like Grace Kelly.
Cut it. Cut it, please.
Mr. Bradley...
I don't care how many times
you play that, I can't sing
this man's songs.
I don't know how
to sing like that.
Nobody wants you to.
You can take it away from him.
Yeah. The hell with the demo.
Steal the son of a bitch.
I don't understand why
everything has to be so
hard. How am I to do this?
Just like you always
do. Your way.
Let the song tell the story.
Crazy
I'm crazy for feelin'
So lonely
I'm crazy
I think that's a good tempo.
Let's try it that way.
Somebody bring me a beer.
Will somebody bring the lady a
beer? Then we'll go for a take.
Wonderin'
What in the world did I do
Oh, crazy
For thinkin' that my love
Could hold you
I'm crazy for tryin'
And crazy for cryin'
And I'm crazy for lovin' you
Oh, God, honey,
I hope you like it!
It's so pretty.
There. There it is.
See that white one
with the columns?
Ain't it the truth?
I fell in love with it
the minute I saw it.
I'd like a pale,
pale blue carpet.
Maybe a couple divans,
make a conversation area.
Honey?
Look at this.
We got a dishwasher.
And an oven built
right into the wall.
I want to check a roast,
all I have to do is open
the door like this.
No more bending over.
The Queen of Sheba.
Say you already bought
it? I paid down on it.
Why didn't you tell me?
I wanted to surprise you.
You surprised me.
The best thing we can do
with our money is put it
in bricks and mortar.
That show went on
forever last night...
and every minute of it
shows in my face today.
I'm glad we saved "Crazy"
till the end. I think it
made a great encore.
You love Charlie?
What?
You love him?
Oh, come on. I couldn't
get along without Charlie.
How's that song go?
" He may have been a headache,
but he never was a bore."
That's Charlie.
Is that an answer?
I think Charlie and I
deserve each other.
Looks like Charlie might be
throwing you a little party.
Sure does. Take care.
I'll see you at the
session. All right.
Try and get a little sleep
between now and Friday.
Nightynight. Good night.
Miss Patsy Cline! In person!
My baby's home!
We're having a party.
I see.
Did you see my new car?
I bought an old clunker to
drive in the demo derby.
How are you?
You know most everybody.
This is Cindy.
John and Sarah from work.
That there's...
I don't know who that is.
This is Skip. He sold me that
car. I'm glad to meet you.
Nice to meet you. Think I'll
get myself a beer.
How'd it go tonight? All right.
This your date, Otis?
Lucky man. Yeah, goddamn it.
Help yourself to food in there.
Bought a bunch of Chinese.
Let's us dance one.
Come on. Don't be such
an old wet blanket.
Oh! No fair. We gotta
wait for the next one.
I'm going to bed. I'm so tired.
That girl I was dancing with goes
with that guy from the derby.
Obviously you got me mixed up
with someone who gives a shit.
Come on. There you go.
That's Goldilocks and the
Three Bears. Take your book.
Oh, how's my big boy?
You are the most
beautiful little boy.
Here we go.
Fell right on your
butt. Take your bottle.
Hey, kiddo.
Hope you're rested.
Otis wants us to go out after
the demo derby tonight.
Darling, I'm so tired,
I feel like I'm
walking on stumps.
I gotta sing there tonight.
I don't feel like walking
off the stage and taking
a busman's holiday.
What's a busman's holiday?
A guy drives a bus,
he doesn't want to take a
bus ride for his vacation.
Hell. It's too hard to explain.
I understood it.
You getting awful goddamn
fancy all of a sudden.
Yeah?
Here comes another
paycheck for Charlie.
Crazy
Crazy for feelin'
So lonely
I'm crazy
Crazy for feelin' so blue
You didn't finish that.
"And the cow jumped...
Over the moon.
Three little bears
sittin' in their chairs."
Better start gettin' ready.
We got time. Not that much.
"And a pair of mittens."
You're not dressed yet.
I get dressed faster than you.
No, you don't. White?
What? White.
What are you talking about?
Want to see if you say "black."
"A quiet old lady who
was whispering 'Hush."'
Blue moon of Kentucky
Keep on ashinin'
Shine on the one that's
gone and left me blue
Love said goodbye I said
Blue moon of Kentucky
Keep on ashinin'
Shinin' bright
Whisperin' on high till
lovers said goodbye
I said blue moon
Come on, baby, treat me right.
I'm gonna get you!
Baby, baby. Be good to me.
What happened? That's not
supposed to happen.
I was lookin' for you.
I ain't been hidin' nowhere.
Wanna dance? Yeah, later.
You should've seen Charlie.
His clunker is still burnin'.
Why don't you take a busman's
holiday? Go sing another song.
Sit down.
Baby, let's dance.
I'm gettin' thirsty.
I don't know about you, Otis.
I'll be right back.
You want to leave?
Hey, you.
Bitch!
What the hell you think you're
doing? Same question back to you.
I was just talkin' to her. Me,
too. I'm just talkin' to them.
How old is she anyhow?
She said she's 24.
Ask her how old she is
counting the years she
went barefoot on the farm.
You got a mean mouth.
I'd like to pull your tongue
with a pair of pliers.
I'm takin' a pee.
I'm warnin' you. You set your
ass down at my table. You hear?
Don't you warn me!
You spend the evening rubbing
up against some tramp,
I'll do whatever I please.
You will, will you? I'll walk out
with the first guy.
I'd like to see you
try. You just watch me.
This is it right over here.
I get Patsy Cline on my
cycle, all she wants is
coffee and a ride home.
You're a real gent. Just my luck.
Thanks a lot. No problem.
Well, the slut's home.
Came home to see the pig.
Where's that guy?
Had him let me off
about a block away.
We just talked. You're a whore.
Let's not call each other
names. It don't do no good.
We still gotta wake up tomorrow,
and look each other in the face.
I ain't having no more
nights when my wife goes
off with another man.
Don't tell me what you
will or will not have.
I looked at you tonight and
thought, "God help you, Patsy.
No matter how hard you try
to make things right...
goodtime Charlie keeps
dragging you back down!"
Don't whine about me!
Where are you when the kids
want oatmeal in the morning?
Where are you when Julie pukes
in bed? You sure ain't here!
You lie!
You never changed a shitty
diaper in your life...
between Mama, Madrine and me!
That's right, I'm not here!
I'm singing in every shit house
between here and Kansas City...
so you can wear $30 silk shirts!
Yeah? Take the goddamn thing!
Take it!
You lay down for that
guy tonight? Don't ask.
I'm askin', slut.
Yes, I did! I did!
It was great. It was wonderful.
It was better than it's been
with you.
We're gonna get married,
Mr. Motorcycle man and me.
Come here. Stand up!
Stop it! Stop!
Goddamn it!
Shut up!
Mama?
Oh, God, baby, go back to bed.
Regarding that family
disturbance, unit 17 has
that in hand.
Trade me an eye for one
of them cigarettes?
What are you in here for?
Had an argument with my wife.
I fell asleep in a doorway.
Put them there. You can have
one whenever you want it.
Thank you. I appreciate it.
You look like you got the
whole world on your shoulders.
You give me a cigarette,
these questions go with
it, you can have it back.
I just thought we'd
pass the time.
Go ahead and take it.
You only got one.
It's all right.
I smoke too much anyway.
Thank you.
Sleep light, don't you?
Just like my old man.
He smoked Camels, too.
He started when he
was nine years old.
There he was, nine years
old, in the fourth grade...
still wearing knickers.
Get up in the morning,
he'd have a cup of coffee
and a cigarette...
right at the breakfast
table, big as you please.
He was a pisscutter,
my old man was.
He always could make me laugh.
I never knew who my daddy was.
I don't think Mama did either.
My daddy's six feet tall...
when six feet tall was big.
Had this real high voice.
Could walk halfway around
the block on his hands.
One morning I was getting
ready for school.
My daddy stayed home from
work, he was at the kitchen
table smoking Camels...
one right after the other,
he was eatin' them.
I went to get corn flakes
out of the cupboard...
and heard this noise.
I thought the whole
house was falling down.
I turned around, he'd shot
hisself in the head.
Sweet Jesus!
I sat on my bed for five days.
Wouldn't talk to nobody.
Wouldn't go to his funeral.
On the fifth day, I got up,
went out the door.
And I never looked back.
Just keep on movin'.
Know what I mean?
I can't seem to find anything in
my life to hold on to anymore.
It's like everything is
falling down around me.
I say to myself, " I don't have
to lead that trashy dog's life...
that my daddy led my mama.
I can make things different.
I can make it right."
And look at me. Here I am,
my face busted up.
Calling the cops in the
middle of the night.
And my kid saw it all!
Mama, I don't know
what to do anymore.
I don't know whether
to divorce him or not.
All I know is I can't
keep him outta the house
like this forever.
This is your baby.
You have to rock it.
Hell! I'm not asking for your
goddamn eyeteeth! I was asking
for your opinion.
You're talking to your
mama. You keep a civil
tongue in your head.
Yeah?
Oh, no, Randy, not a big show!
All right.
Christ on the cross!
I don't believe it.
I got recording sessions Friday.
Now I gotta do a benefit for that
disc jockey that died last month.
Tell him you're wore out.
I'm sorry I snapped at you.
If that's the worst thing
that ever happens to me.
You still like me?
Now and then.
You love me?
Sometimes.
Tell me what to do with my life.
I've got your picture
That you gave to me
And it's signed "With love"
Just like it used to be
Hey! Whoa! Charlie.
Where are you goin'?
I'm gonna talk to my
wife. Hold on a second.
What do you want, Charlie?
I want to talk to you.
It's all right.
Everybody, take five.
Kill Patsy's mike.
God, Charlie, don't.
I'm sorry.
I did wrong.
I will never raise a hand
to you again. I swear it.
I know you're thinkin'
of leavin' me.
I swear to God, I don't think
I could take it.
I don't know.
Can't we try and
make it right again?
If you want a definite
answer right this minute,
the answer is no.
I don't know if I can
live with you anymore.
Sweet dreams
Of you
Every night
I go through
Why can't I forget you
And start my life anew
Instead of having sweet dreams
About you
You don't love me
It's plain
I should know
I'll never wear your ring
I should hate you
The whole night through
Instead of having sweet dreams
About you
Sweet dreams
Of you
Things I know
Can't come true
Why can't I forget the past
Start loving someone new
Instead of having
Sweet dreams
About you
Thank you.
Tony, I gotta take a pee!
Pretty Boy Floyd!
Get this boy one.
He's been on bread and water.
Give me a drink.
I've been in the jail.
You drink any more, you'll wish
you was dead when you wake up.
Where was it you left
your ball and chain?
In my private room in
prison. Take a walk.
Charlie, finish this and
let's get outta here,
find us a couple of girlies.
That's one thing I do not
need. I got that already.
Can everybody hear me?
I got me a wife.
She is hard to handle and as
contrary as a hog on ice.
That ain't half of it.
You guys ain't got no
idea what it's like...
to be rubbing up against
something that dangerous.
That's what I like
about the South
Mama, hi!
We're still at the
airport. The weather bad?
Yeah. We've spent the
whole damn night here...
but the first spot of good
weather we'll take off.
How are my babies?
Just fine. Charlie came
by the house with two
quarts of ice cream.
He did? He said he
missed seeing them.
I knew he couldn't stay away.
He hadn't had a thing
to drink. Good as gold.
Hell, Charlie's always
good. Except when he isn't.
You just hurry home.
Give those babies sugar
for me. Of course.
Let's go! Hot dog! This beats
the hell out of drivin'!
Let's get this show on the road.
Looks like we might be
in for a little fun.
A little turbulence.
Right tank's empty.
Switching over.
Oh, boy! What the
hell's goin' on?
What's the matter with this?
Gotta drop the nose. Hold on.
Kick it over.
Come on, baby. Come on!
Catch on!
Come on, baby.
It started. Oh, Lord, thank you!
Attaboy, Randy.
I almost peed my pants.
I did pee in mine.
My God!
You can't work and take
care of two babies.
Look at me.
I'll take the kids
with me for a while.
I'll be good to them.
I know it.
Subtitles And Translation By
Captions, Inc. Los Angeles