Go on, take a card, any card at all.
Now look at it.
Put it back.
Ace of spades.
- When did you change the act, Pop?
- I didn't. He did.
He did?
Yes, he said straight magic
is too old-fashioned.
Wait a minute, take a bow.
No, you take it. I got to get married.
Come here, they're applauding you.
They like it.
Lucky.
Now what?
- I want to reason with you, if I can.
- But you already did.
Have you really made up your mind
to leave me...
just to marry some girl
you happen to know?
It's kind of customary
to know the bride, isn't it?
I hate to see you leave show business.
A man with your talents...
My talent is gambling, Pop.
Hoofing is all right,
but there's no future in it.
I want to spread out.
I think I'm going to miss you, Lucky.
I know I'm going to miss you, Pop.
Is he staying with us, Pop?
No, he's made up his mind to get married.
How do you like that?
Letting his marriage interfere
with our career?
We shouldn't have played his hometown.
It was a bad move.
Bad for us and bad for him.
Local boy makes bad.
- Father, has he come yet?
- No, and it's all very much as I expected.
Hi, fellows.
- How do I look?
- Marvelous, colossal, splendid.
Wait a minute. You're not going like that.
Of course. Big church wedding,
girl's family very social...
whole town there.
I guess it doesn't really matter,
just a hick town.
What doesn't matter?
- Last year's trousers.
- Last year's trousers?
No cuffs.
- No cuffs?
- No cuffs.
Whoever heard of cuffs on these?
Are you serious?
Don't be ridiculous.
- Maybe he's wrong.
- Wait a minute. Let's see that.
- What do you think of that?
- You know, you're in a hurry and...
Garnett, you're wanted on the telephone.
Just a minute. I'll answer it for you.
It will only take about five minutes.
Let us have your pants.
- Hello.
- Hello, John. Will you hurry?
Tell him the minister is here.
Margaret's been ready for an hour.
We're all waiting for him.
All right, I'll tell him.
- Who was it?
- It was the minister.
He said to take it easy.
He'll be about a half-hour late.
- Good.
- You see, there's plenty of material.
- I'll take them down and have them fixed.
- No, you don't.
Pop, take them to Schmidt's
and have them back in five minutes.
- You want two cuffs on them?
- Yeah, one on each leg.
And hurry up. Tell him
I got to have them back right away.
While we're waiting,
we'll indulge in the famous indoor sport.
I'll get seven.
- The next man.
- That's it.
- Any word?
- They say he'll be here any minute.
You know, I told Margaret
this would happen.
I always say, marry in haste,
repent at leisure.
The young man is now
one hour and 25 minutes late.
That isn't exactly marrying in haste.
As long as I am living, and longer...
I have never seen cuffs on pants like these.
What's the matter, can't you make them?
I can make anything...
but I would rather not be wrong
than right.
I'm paying for cuffs and I want cuffs.
No. 10 times...
20 times, no.
Can't you understand?
Look, here, let me show you.
Do you see any cuffs there? Not one cuff.
Thousands of no cuffs.
Here, look these over. You see? No cuffs.
Millions of no cuffs.
No cuffs.
More than that, positively not one cuff.
Why not?
- I want to speak to Mr. Garnett.
- Speaking.
- Here he is, sir.
- Let me talk to him.
Say, listen, you,
the guests are all going home and...
I'm the happiest man in the world
because the wedding is off.
And furthermore,
if you ever come to this house again...
I'll break every bone in your body.
Do you understand that?
- Red, is that call for me?
- No, it's my dame.
Okay, sweetheart,
and a great big juicy kiss for you.
Wait a minute.
Give me a chance to get my dough back.
- Give us a roll.
- Here it comes...
You ought to marry those dice.
Marry? Holy cats! What time is it?
- Pop, my pants!
- You've got them on.
Oh, yeah.
Wait a minute!
You're not going with all our dough.
I got to get married.
I'll bet you the bankroll
you don't get married.
That's a bet.
No cuffs.
The tailor says those kind of pants
shouldn't have cuffs.
What?
Nice fellows!
Hello.
Where's everybody?
Why, the guests have all gone, sir.
Did you wish to be announced?
Just let me get my hands
on that young man and I'll strangle him!
You leave him to me. I'll take care of him.
No, maybe I'd better surprise them.
He can't do a thing like this
to a daughter of mine.
This is my affair, you keep out of it.
I'm your father
and I'll settle this as I see fit.
We'll be the laughingstock
of this whole town!
So...
Here I am.
Young man,
why didn't you appear for your wedding?
I thought you'd ask me that.
Don't stand there like a statue.
You said you were gonna do something.
Well, do it.
What are you gonna do?
Don't you dare touch him.
- Why don't you do something?
- I will.
I will, but...
Pardon me, I think I'm in the way.
- Perhaps you two would like to be alone.
- You stay right where you are.
- I'm not finished with you yet.
- I had a feeling you weren't.
I wouldn't let you marry her for $10,000.
- How about twenty?
- Not for $20,000.
- Twenty-five.
- Not for...
Say, young man,
where could you get $25,000?
By dancing?
And there's another thing...
coming back to your own hometown
in a dancing act.
I'm going into a new business.
Only this afternoon I made $200.
$200?
Yes, that's why I was late for the wedding.
That makes it a little different.
I'm not consenting to your wedding...
but I always admire
any young man that can make money.
It shows character.
- That's too kind of you, sir.
- Not at all.
Then Margaret and I can get married?
If you go to New York
and work hard at your business...
and if you are successful...
you can come back here
and ask me for my Margaret.
Oh, Daddy.
And in all probability
I'll be very happy to give her to you.
Right, sir. Thank you, sir.
John, dear.
You'll come back soon, won't you?
That all depends upon the stakes,
the stocks...
Goodbye, my son.
Thank you, father-in-law.
I'll say goodbye again
because we'll both be waiting for you.
Hurry back, dear.
I feel that I'm a little to blame in this.
You know, I didn't realize what a bright,
upstanding young man you were.
And I don't care how big the city,
I feel confident...
you're going to be successful.
Thank you, sir.
Lucky, couldn't I go with you?
I'm afraid you'd try to be
a good influence on me.
No, honest I wouldn't.
I'm terrible bad when you get to know me.
Then I wouldn't want you
to come with me.
One to New York, please.
- Whose money are you using?
- Yours, thank you very much.
But our money belongs to us again.
What's the idea?
Remember our bet?
You see, you didn't get married.
- I'll pay you later.
- No.
All aboard!
- But I've got to get that train.
- You mean you had to get it.
You know,
you didn't win that lucky quarter.
I'll flip you for a ticket to New York.
I don't want to go to New York.
He doesn't want to go to New York.
Goodbye, Lucky, old boy. So long.
- Goodbye, Lucky.
- See you later.
Give my regards to the folks, will you?
Say hello to Aunt Lucy.
So long. Goodbye, Lucky.
Lucky, here's your suitcase.
Here's your toothbrush.
Boy, I'd give my life for a smoke.
- Well, take the quarter.
- No, sir, not the lucky one.
Wait a minute. I'll get a smoke.
I beg your pardon,
have you got a match, please?
Thank you.
How careless of me.
I left my cigarettes at home.
Then you won't need the matches.
I'm afraid that won't work,
unless you have a needle and thread.
Excuse me, have you change for a quarter?
Thank you very much.
You shouldn't have done that just for me.
I could've gotten along without them.
- You hold it.
- All right.
Looks like a jackpot.
Go and get your lucky quarter back, quick.
I beg your pardon.
You probably think I'm silly.
Yes, I'm afraid I do.
Just a moment. That quarter,
I wonder if I could have it back?
This isn't getting you anywhere.
You don't understand.
I'm not trying to get acquainted.
All I want to know is...
It's all my fault, too.
I'm awfully sorry.
Yes, I know.
You've been trying so hard to avoid me.
All right, give it back.
- Give what back?
- The quarter you stole from my purse.
Come on, will you?
Hand it over or I'll call a policeman.
I haven't got it.
I gave it to you at the cigarette machine.
- Officer.
- Come on. Let's go, will you?
No, wait a minute.
What seems to be the trouble?
Good morning, sir.
Officer, this man stole a quarter
from my purse. Make him give it back.
Now, miss, does he look like a man
who would steal quarters?
- That's just what I said to the lady.
- Imagine...
I don't care what you think he looks like.
I know he stole my quarter.
Now you run along, sister...
before I run you in
for disturbing the peace.
But, Officer, he took my...
That'll be enough.
Run along now, you're obstructing traffic.
Why, you Cossack.
Officer, you had no right
to speak to that little girl that way.
I suppose you're going to tell me
what my duty is.
Not at all, but...
Listen, guys like you pay me
to protect them from screwy dames.
That's fine, but in this instance
I'm sure you were wrong.
So now I'm wrong.
You ought to thank me for what I've done.
- All right, thank you.
- All right.
What did you say?
I said, look out for the great big ditch.
Pop, why didn't you tell me you had it?
In front of the cop?
I would've been accused of stealing it.
Give me that.
Wait for me.
Miss Carrol!
Hello, kids.
No wonder this school is losing money.
Everybody late every morning.
Any more dilly-dallying and
some of you will lose your jobs.
Yes, and that goes for you girls, too.
Anybody would think
I had nothing else to do, but nothing.
One would.
Miss Anderson, good morning.
If you're late again, you'll be fired, too.
That's final. I have nothing more to say.
That's good.
- Is that you, Mabel?
- I don't know. Tell me, is it?
- Kind of sounds like you.
- That's a load off my mind.
I'm never sure these days.
- Did you see a young...
- Visitors make the pupils self-conscious.
Would you mind waiting a second, please?
Thank you very much.
Miss Anderson, come quickly.
Please.
He's hissing at me again, the swan.
And good morning to you, too.
- Are you interested in the dance?
- I came here to see if I...
All the world loves a dancer.
To know how to dance...
Is to know how to control oneself.
Thanks. You saved me a lot of breath.
Our course is $45.
But the first lesson is given free...
to see if the prospective student
has any real aptitude.
That's why our school is so successful.
We never refuse the $45.
- I mean...
- You never let a pupil get away.
I understand.
We don't fool anybody.
Have you any preference as to the type
of instructress you'd like?
Yes, I have.
I'd like one that comes to about here.
And if she had red hair,
that would be a great help.
And a cute little nose.
She might be able to teach you
to move your feet.
Miss Anderson, my dear. Good morning.
Me, too.
- Mr. Gordon, this is Mr...
- Garnett.
How do you do, Mr. Garnett?
I'm delighted, I assure you.
- The young man would like a trial lesson.
- Of course.
I think Miss Carrol might please him.
Of course, Miss Carrol.
Come this way, will you?
She's one of our best instructresses.
You're a very fortunate young man
to learn to dance...
- to move...
- To flirt with Terpsichore.
Yes. What?
How do you do?
Do you mind if I wait here?
- No, help yourself.
- Thanks.
I mean to the chair.
Miss Carrol, this is Mr. Garnett.
This is Miss Penelope Carrol.
We're all so fond of her here,
we just call her Penny.
Penny, dear.
- This is Mr. Garnett.
- Penny.
Miss Carrol.
Mr. Garnett is very anxious
to learn how to dance.
So you won't always be stepping
on other people's toes.
- That's very good, isn't it?
- Yes, that's very good.
What kind of dancing
would you like to learn?
What kind have you got?
- Sap.
- Sap dancing?
- No, she means tap dancing.
- Tap dancing, of course.
You see, we have tap dancing...
and ballroom dancing
and aesthetic dancing.
If it's all the same to you,
I'll take a little of each.
A little of each, yes.
Miss Carrol wants to know
what kind you'd like to learn first?
Whichever takes the longest.
Go on, begin the lesson.
You must learn to walk first.
Now start with your right foot, please.
- No, your right foot.
- Sorry, I'm left-handed.
Right, left.
Miss Carrol, I'm sorry about your quarter.
But you see, Penny...
If you're trying to annoy me,
you're succeeding.
I know you don't care about dancing.
But I do. All the world loves a dancer.
Don't you?
Right, left.
- This is fun.
- Now you turn.
Start again. Right, left.
If you don't get out of here,
I'm going to lose my temper.
If you talk like that, I'll call a policeman.
- Why, you...
- Officer...
"Our young ladies are sweet-tempered,
patient and understanding. "
You're doing splendidly.
I don't think you need me here any longer.
I know I'm leaving you in good hands.
Lovely hands.
You know, that's the most marvelous trick
I've ever seen a magician do.
You mean the one with the four aces?
No, the way you made
my club sandwich disappear.
Who, me?
My dear young lady...
You'd better take a club sandwich
out of this hat.
Are you accusing me
of eating your sandwich?
You might begin by taking that piece
of lettuce off your necktie.
One, two, three. Turn.
Let's try it again from the beginning.
- I'm getting it, aren't I?
- Yes.
Again.
One, two, three. Turn.
Now you've got it.
I can't teach you anything.
All right, I'll show you again.
Remember, three steps to the left...
three steps to the right and turn.
One, two, three.
Listen, no one could teach you
to dance in a million years.
- Take my advice and save your money.
- Miss Carrol.
How do you think this school can exist
if you turn away applicants?
- You're discharged.
- But, Mr...
Get your things and go.
- But I...
- Get out.
That's quite all right, don't you worry.
I'll find you another instructress.
You stay right there.
So this is the way you treat
your customers?
I certainly don't treat them to sandwiches.
Get out of here.
Miss Anderson,
what is the meaning of this?
What's gotten
into everybody this morning?
My sandwich got into him.
You're fired.
Okay, swivel puss.
It might interest you to know
that I've also discharged Miss Carrol.
You've discharged Penny? Why?
Why, for no reason at all. Please see her.
But she said
she couldn't teach you anything.
She was trying to flatter me.
She's the most wonderful
little teacher I've ever heard of.
Miss Carrol, I want to show Mr. Gordon
how much you just taught me.
No, never mind.
Thank you. That's very sweet of you.
I'm anxious for Mr. Gordon to see this.
It's an interesting experiment.
How did you say that last step went?
Shall we try it right through?
Won't you sit down, Mr. Gordon?
Wait!
Sheer heaven, my dears, sheer heaven!
- Is she still fired?
- Fired?
You took me too seriously, both of you.
Just you wait there for one moment.
Hey, he got her job back for her.
Wasn't that swell?
What one man can do, another man can.
All right, Al. Thank you.
Now listen, I've just made
an appointment for you for a tryout...
with Mr. Simpson,
the owner of the Silver Sandal.
The Silver Sandal!
That's wonderful, isn't it?
It certainly is.
Penny, you wear your white lamé gown.
That's how I see you. You in white,
and Mr. Garnett here in dinner clothes.
- Dinner clothes?
- Yes, certainly.
You'll do it? You'll be there?
Now do you think I could disappoint you?
I'll be there.
You are still fired!
Pop, you can pay the cab.
- Have you got change for $10?
- I have.
Thanks.
Here you are, buddy. You keep that.
Now I don't want you to worry
about losing your job.
I'll take care of you.
Yes, but I'll take care of my own $10.
Wouldn't you like to double it?
Sure, I love to gamble
if I'm sure I'm going to win.
- The trouble is, you lose sometimes.
- No. We always win.
Why didn't you say that in the first place?
That's fine then.
I'll telephone you when I'm ready.
- All right.
- Where do you live?
- Right here.
- Since when?
Since from now on.
How am I going to get a dinner jacket
for tonight?
Don't worry about that.
Look, I borrowed this from Mabel.
You're marvelous.
- How do you do?
I want to get suite for myself
and Mr. Cardetti, please.
- Something at about...
- Just about...
Yes, that's about enough.
Doctor, would you mind rushing down
to the docks...
to see if our trunks
have passed through the customs yet?
Just a moment.
You may need my verification.
- What size chest?
- Chest?
You mean that little chest.
The one in the hold?
Yeah.
- That chest is 36 inches.
- 36.
How long do you intend to stay with us?
That'll be entirely up to you.
Did you get a dinner jacket?
No, I went broke trying to win enough
to buy you one.
- What am I going to do?
- Now don't worry.
I got you the swellest looking outfit
you ever saw in your life.
Where is it?
It looks like a perfect 36.
I want you to meet my old friend, Eric...
What's your name again?
My name is Eric Lacanistram.
I met Eric in the gambling house.
He lost all his money, too.
I lost all my money, too.
- Eric just loves to gamble.
- Really?
It's in the Lacanistrams' blood.
Yeah, he'll play you for his necktie
or his shirt or anything he's got on.
Well, I'll toss you for the whole outfit.
No, I'm off pitch and toss.
The Lacanistrams' game is piquet.
Has been for years and years and years...
before the conquest
and then after the conquest...
for years and years and years.
In fact, we've been playing piquet
for years...
and years...
- But I don't know piquet.
- Don't worry, I do.
Yes, Al. All right, goodbye.
If we're not at the Silver Sandal
in 10 minutes, the tryout's off.
But 20 minutes ago,
Lucky said he'd be here in five minutes.
He's said that for the past hour.
I'm gonna go get him.
I wish you would. I feel like a fool.
But you are.
Twenty-four, twenty-five,
twenty-six and twenty-seven.
And that's piquet, Mr. Garnett.
Pop, you certainly did show me
how to play piquet.
You're doing fine.
Fine? This fellow will have my skin
in a minute.
Come in.
Penny!
Listen, Penny. Look, Penny.
Listen, let me explain.
The clothes that I had before...
When you're talking to a lady,
you should take your hat off.
Your petticoat's showing.
Keep up the good work, boys.
The public is with you.
Mabel, will you get down from there
and stop being ridiculous?
Maybe you're the one
that's being ridiculous.
For a whole week you've been sulking
at him for something that wasn't his fault.
I suppose it was my fault.
It's your fault that you're missing
the tryout that Lucky arranged tonight.
He's only doing it for you.
You're not so smart,
letting your stubbornness...
interfere with the very thing you want.
I like being stubborn
where he's concerned.
It must be love.
How could I fall in love
with a common gambler?
When a man takes a little quarter...
and builds it into a bankroll
that would choke a horse...
and makes my little $10
grow into hundreds...
I'd call him an uncommon gambler.
Come in, comrade.
You, outside.
My card.
You're a big success.
She's willing to arbitrate.
I told you it would work.
Mabel, will you tell that fellow to get out
of the hall and stop annoying me?
No, you sit down.
You just hold your ground.
Yes?
Hello.
- Penny.
- You'd better get out of here.
All right, I will.
However, before I go, I want to tell you
that maybe I was wrong the other night.
But I didn't know it at the time.
- So now you know.
- Yes, I do.
Goodbye.
Wait a minute.
Maybe, in a way, I might have been wrong.
No, this one is on me.
Listen, Lucky Garnett,
there's no use arguing.
- I'm not.
- Yes, you are.
All right, goodbye.
Lucky, wait a minute.
This concludes the Ricardo Romero
Romantic Melody Hour.
You know, I don't like that fellow.
- He's very nice.
- That?
You have no reason to dislike him.
You don't even know him.
It's true, but when I dislike someone
for no reason...
I always find it more enjoyable.
As a matter of fact,
he's asked me to marry him several times.
Of course you laughed.
Or does he make you lose
your sense of humor?
- Ricardo.
- Hello.
I want you to meet Mr. Garnett.
He's going to dance with me tonight.
How do you do? I played that last number
especially for you.
Thank you.
Now I know him and I still don't like him.
Beautiful, isn't it?
- What is?
- The music.
What music?
- The music they're playing.
- Yes.
What made you think of it?
- Think of what?
- The music.
I don't know.
My mind was wandering, I guess.
You as scared as I am?
Don't be nervous. It's only a dance.
It's nothing to worry about.
That's right. Don't worry at all, my dear...
because you're not going to dance.
Because there isn't going to be any music.
But, Ricky, you promised.
I promised you could dance
anytime you want, alone.
I'll dance with Lucky or not at all.
That's what I said, too, not at all.
Good night.
Come on, we'll see about that.
- Mr. Simpson?
- Hello, Garnett.
Will you please tell Romero
that he has to play for our dance?
I'm sorry, but I can't.
Romero's played his last tune for me.
- But you said that...
- I know I did.
But I lost his contract last night
playing cards.
He's now the property of Dice Raymond.
Orchestras usually play for somebody.
This is the first I've heard
of anybody playing for an orchestra.
- I guess there's nothing we can do.
- Wait a minute.
Do you think we could interest Raymond
in another game for that contract?
I doubt it.
He's always wanted Romero's band
for his club...
but he's a gambler.
Where is this Raymond's place?
Thirty-sixth floor, Club Raymond.
Thirty-six.
- Hello, Raymond.
- Hello, Ricardo. Looks like a big night.
Because where Ricardo Romero goes,
the others come.
Here goes everything on the red.
Will you excuse me for a second?
I think I need a bit of fresh air.
- I can't stand the strain.
- Wait a second.
Twenty-seven, red, and third dozen.
This is no strain.
Please, don't be angry.
I want to talk to you.
I don't want to talk to you.
I'm awfully sorry if I hurt you...
but I didn't want to see anyone else
dance with you.
It makes me jealous.
Jealous?
Because...
I love you.
You have a very funny way of showing it.
On the red.
I want you to look at this new fellow.
He's taking me, and fast.
Say, if that hits for you,
you'll have just exactly enough.
Enough for what?
Why, enough to go back
and marry Margaret.
What? Wait a minute. No bet.
Seven. The red wins, and the first dozen.
Pop, you're a pal.
In fact, you're more than a pal...
you're a partner. I'm going to cash in.
So you won enough,
you're going to leave us.
Yes, winning more money
doesn't interest me.
Boy, you like to gamble.
I'll cut you once, double or nothing.
- No, thanks.
- Scared?
You have a contract with Romero,
haven't you?
I'll tell you what I will do.
All my winnings against his contract.
No, I win the orchestra...
I keep the orchestra.
Scared?
You're on. I'll high-card you.
Tony, bring a fresh deck.
Keeps them on the ice.
You're covered.
Shuffle.
- Cut.
- After you.
King of spades.
Wait a minute.
Let me, will you?
Sure, let the old boy cut.
Ace of spades.
Excuse me, boys,
I got to go and get a double sundae.
Maybe we play
for this orchestra again someday.
Thank you, Mr. Raymond.
Pop, cash in for me, will you?
Okay, give us dough for these, will you?
Maybe we can have that dance after all.
- How?
- Look, I just won Romero's contract.
- That's a nice orchestra you have there.
- Just about the best.
- The leader's the same as the orchestra.
- It's awfully nice of you to say that.
I wonder if you'd be kind enough
to play something for us...
- if you don't mind.
- But I do.
I'm afraid you'll have to because, you see,
I now own you.
What do you mean, you own me?
He just won you at the gambling tables.
I see.
Congratulations on winning
such a valuable piece of property.
Thank you.
Now will you play your waltz for us?
No. If you read the contract carefully...
you will see I don't have to play
after this hour unless I want to.
So you won't play?
You're right. I won't play for you.
I see.
That's all, boys.
Ladies and gentlemen,
my favorite maestro, Ricardo Romero...
has very kindly requested that Ms. Carrol
and I dance to his newest composition...
the lovely Waltz in Swing Time.
- Wait a minute. I didn't say...
- Look, he wants to be coaxed.
What's the matter, Ricky, old boy,
you bashful?
My pal.
This is the moment I've been waiting for.
- Wait a minute. Where are you going?
- I'm going to get Pop.
I'll get him. I mean, I'll do it for you.
Sit still.
What's the matter with Lucky?
He seems to have something on his mind.
You mean something else besides you?
I don't know. I only get to see him
at the rehearsals or with you and Pop...
or when somebody else is around.
Don't worry, darling. I'm going to see
that you get a break this afternoon.
Say, whose idea was this, anyway?
Going to the country on a day like this.
It was Mabel's, but she's made it mine.
Listen, you got to do me a favor.
No matter where we go or what we do,
don't leave me alone with Penny.
What's the matter,
ain't you in love with her?
You wouldn't pin me down
with a question like that, would you?
I see. Why, that's fine.
Why don't you tell her?
She's too sweet a kid, and besides that...
I can't go on like this without her knowing
something about Margaret...
and I haven't got the nerve
to come out and tell her, that's all.
You don't have to go back to Margaret
unless you get $25,000.
Yeah, I know.
So you haven't got it.
So you don't have to go back.
Yes, but it's more than money.
I'm in a fine spot.
- I'm going to take care of this.
- Pop, no.
- You better lay off gambling for a while.
- But I don't want to lay off.
- Hello, Lucky.
- Hello, Mr. Simpson.
I was looking for you.
Have you seen the improvements?
The decorators are working day and night,
and when we're through...
the Silver Sandal
should be the finest place in town.
And with you and Penny
dancing to Romero's music...
we're going to clean up.
Yes, but I'm not sure I can stick around.
Yes, you can.
But you must. Look, if you're not satisfied
with the terms...
I'll make you a half partner.
I'll give you 50%. That should make you
about $30,000 for the season.
My advice is to take 25%
and be on the safe side.
Let me see.
25%, that would give me $15,000.
You're right. Not over 25%.
- Is it a deal?
- Sure.
Right.
Remember what I told you about
not leaving me alone with, you know...
Would you say he was crazy, or am I?
I wouldn't say.