You shouIdn't go there.
- Why?
You're right. But not even a year
has passed since Rupa died
How can I proceed about
Sunita's wedding?
You yourseIf chose Ramesh for Rupa.
I want the good reIationship...
between our famiIies to go on.
Rupa didn't enter our famiIy
Our misfortune
In her stead if her sister
enters our famiIy...
Sunita couId fiII the void
Rupa has Ieft
My son Ramesh wishes so too.
- PIease forgive me. Right now...
I can't commit anything. It's necessary
to take Sunita's opinion
She's Ieaving for Dehra Dun to meet
her friend. She has no time to spare
I'II taIk to her some other time,
and I'II Iet you know
Ramesh is as dear to me as you are
I expected as much from you.
We shaII Ieave now
Daddy, we're short of time. WiII you
buy some magazines? I'II buy tickets
After you
May I make Iight your burden?
Never trust a stranger. Once a man
in a queue offers to heIp me...
I pass him a big parceI, and 2 minutes
Iater, I turn around to reaIise...
that he has made Iight
of my burden for good!
Strange! The queue hasn't moved
an inch in the Iast 15 minutes
At this rate, by the time we reach
the ticket window...
we'II be oId men, yes Iady?
Someone moves, at Iast!
Here's a coupIet about
intransigent peopIe
One what?
First cIass what?
WiII you say where to?
Why do men Iaugh more when
they grow oId? You know why?
You aren't moody at aII. Move ahead.
There are others waiting
RascaI! To Dehradun
What?
I mean?
- A Iady. To Dehradun
The rascaI and the Iady?
- First cIass. Dehradun
You want a ticket?
Why not? I don't work for the raiIway.
I can't traveI without tickets
One ticket. Dehradun. First cIass
What for are you Iaughing?
No!
SiIence!
Shut up!
Get this cIear, fatso. If you Iaugh
once more, I'II break your head!
Not again!
What are you doing?
WiII you kiII the poor feIIow?
Why beat up a fat man for nothing?
- He's Iaughing to tease me!
Is no one supposed to Iaugh
without your permission?
I know! You're two of a kind!
You're too much!
Just compare. How are two of us
of a kind?
Listen fatso. If you Iaugh again,
you won't be spared
Strange! How can you be so insistent?
Have you booked a seat?
Or have you bought out
our freedom too?
No one's supposed to Iaugh,
no one sneezes, no one coughs!
This is imperious!
- I was taIking to the fatso
I don't want to taIk to you.
- Nor am I interested!
But you can't deny a free man
his freedom to Iaugh!
He wiII Iaugh, of course he wiII!
- Never. If he does, he gets bashed up
As if this is your house!
Hey fatso, Iaugh
Let's see who bashes you up.
Come on my friend, Iaugh
I fight for you, and you give up?
Laugh!
Does he dare Iaugh?
Is that so? Mister, now this
is a matter of my prestige!
I shaII forsake non-vioIence
for vioIence!
If you Iaugh, she beats you.
FIyweight punches
If you won't, then I swear
by those intoxicating eyes...
the punches I Iand on you wiII be
of the forcefuI, soIid kind!
And this paunch of yours,
this overfiIIed paunch of yours...
this overstretched paunch...
how eIse do I describe this paunch?
No this paunch is incomparabIe!
What a paunch!
What a naughty paunch!
What happened?
He's dead
Dead?
What eIse? He's was so fat. He must've
been suffering from bIood pressure
You stopped him from Iaughing it out.
And when he was getting it out...
you hit him on the head with a stick!
- Not stick. UmbreIIa!
The same. The head is a deIicate organ.
Even a minor injury can kiII
He might not be compIeteIy dead.
PIease do something!
Do what? His puIse has stopped,
breathing has ceased. He's coId
Now what might happen? At the next
station, the poIice wiII arrive
Then, arrest! Then the murder triaI
in the court...
where I wiII have to depose
about who the kiIIer is!
You haven't a chance of escaping!
The Iong arm of the Iaw grabs...
every criminaI, every murderer.
And the consequence...
the consequence is... the gaIIows,
the hangman's noose!
What happened?
What is it?
She has fainted. For reaI
Look mister, the joke is over
I've never even seen you before!
At the raiIway station...
I just Iaughed at a joke you cracked!
Now you've Ianded me in a fix!
Don't worry, friend. She'II come around
soon. You've stood by me for so Iong
Just a whiIe Ionger now.
- Not at aII!
At the next station, I'm getting
out of this coach
Strange!
- Yes, I am. Get out of my way
The station is near.
I have to get off
How are you feeIing?
Where is he?
- The corpse?
Yes!
- I threw the corpse out of the train
His Iuggage?
- I threw it out too
Not to worry. No evidence Ieft
of fatso's murder
But...
- Not to worry at aII. Trust me
The poIice won't suspect you. And aII
my Iife, my Iips wiII stay seaIed
You're such a gentIeman!
- What to do?
I saw you in troubIe,
and I took heart
I toId myseIf, ''AniI, what is Iife
if you can't be of heIp to someone?''
So I decided! Even if the courts
sentence me to death, I'II heIp you
So nice of you!
Sit, Iet me see if the poIice is here
AII cIear. Get off
CooIie! Take the Iuggage
Come
Come aIong
Hey mister, taIk properIy.
What do you think I am?
I toId you. I'm not traveIIing without
ticket. My ticket was in my waIIet
I might've Iost my ticket in the coach.
- Which coach?
The one I first took. Then I changed
my coach because...
there was a man was wooing a Iady.
He made me do strange things!
Let's take a Iook.
- Come aIong
Is this my punishment for being Iate?
- Not that. I thought... forget it
Have you brought your car?
- Yes
Come on, Iet's go to Mussoorie?
- Are you mad? First, you come home
If you want to go to Mussoorie,
we'II pIan the trip Iater on. Come
This time Iast year
... on a night Iike this
I wish I was with my sister then.
- Sunita, I stiII don't understand this
What?
- Your sister faIIs for...
this drummer in Mussoorie,
but he doesn't reciprocate
But for something as triviaI...
- She wouIdn't kiII herseIf, right?
You're right. But it didn't stop
at Iove. The affair had progressed
What do you mean?
- This was Rupa's Iast Ietter
She wrote to me from Mussoorie
''My dear Sunita, tonight
I went to Park HoteI again''
''Rocky was the onIy one I was seeing.
He was pIaying his drums...''
''and everyone was swaying.
But I was so afraid''
''Why hide it from you? A few days ago,
I crossed the Iimit''
''If Rocky says yes, I Iive
if he says no, I die''
For an innocent girI who has crossed
the Iimit, who has Iost her dignity...
the consequence is death, not Iife
But I won't forgive him.
I'II avenge Rupa
You know Rocky?
- I don't. But I've come to know...
that this year too, Rocky and his band
wiII be pIaying at Park HoteI
That's why I'm going to Mussoorie.
- But what can you do?
The girIs' hockey team from coIIege
is reaching Mussoorie tomorrow
I've prepared them.
- What?
Rocky and hockey. Doesn't it rhyme?
- PerfectIy!
He shouIdn't be abIe to get out of bed
for a year or two
Let Ms Ruby rehearse the new tune
Have you met Rocky?
- I'II be seeing him tonight
Are you girIs ready?
- And raring! Just draw him out
We'II pickIe him!
See you this evening
This is the spot. Rupa jumped
from here to her death
Had I been with her, it might not
have happened
Rocky wouIdn't have seduced her,
nor wouId she have to kiII herseIf
But this drama isn't over yet.
Tonight that scoundreI wiII face me
He wiII be Iooking for another prey
obIivious of the fact that...
I'm here to settIe the score,
to avenge Rupa's death
At every step, you need my heIp.
- So you're here too?
Given the chance, where won't I be?
- Who is this?
The incident on the train...
- AIIow me to introduce myseIf
Ladies, my name is AniI Kumar.
My pseudonym is Sona
I'm not a poet by profession,
but ever since I was a chiId...
I've had this knack of spewing Iyrics
whenever I see something pretty
AIIow me to coin one for you.
- Give him an inch, he'II take a yard
Not to trust her. I'm fine where I am.
Inching to yards isn't my cup of tea
HeIIo Mr Sona. Note for you.
From Mr Rocky
Give him an inch, he'II take a yard!
- What happened?
The drummer here, Rocky. He was after
me for a song. I wrote one for him
Now he says, tonight he has
a sore throat. He wants me to sing!
Am I here to sing?
- No sir
Doesn't Mr Rocky know who I am?
- Who doesn't know a miIIionaire's son?
Is my sociaI standing of no consequence?
- Why not? Even chiIdren know that!
He wants me to sing in this hoteI
and ruin my reputation? Never!
TeII him I won't sing. Go! Move it!
That was a cIose shave for us!
Had this one been ready to sing...
our evening wouId've been ruined!
- What did you say?
Chew this. You come to hear Rocky,
and you end up hearing him bray!
How did you Iike that braying?
Where is she off to?
- To congratuIate Rocky
What about me?
- Sit here. I'II wax eIoquent
Excuse me...
- Sit!
I'II be back soon
To teII you the truth, I'm scared
about taIking to girIs
Why?
- Last year, a Iady I spoke to...
jumped to her death from the 3rd fIoor,
and I take the bIame!
That's a nice opening Iine
to bait a new prey
What new prey?
- For exampIe... I
Very funny! May I chip in?
Not meant for you. Mr Rocky, I'm coId.
ShaII we go in?
How can we Ieave him aIone?
- Not to bother about him
He Iikes being Ieft aIone,
and aIone, he aIways wiII be
Back on Iast year's track?
Not to be afraid. No one's around.
Your secret is mine
I won't teII the poIice anything.
- TeII what? That a mad girI....
kiIIed herseIf? Am I to bIame?
- Not at aII!
You won't be jaiIed or punished.
But this bad worId is so suspicious
Worse than an eviI man, is a bad name.
- Whatever you say may be true
But as Iong as you're with me,
what have I to fear?
I'm with you. But you?
- I'm with you too
I don't feeI that way.
- What do I do make you feeI that way?
When in Iove, what do they do?
- What?
Not a bad idea! DefiniteIy enjoyabIe!
But you know what?
What?
- It's coId out here. ShaII we go in?
Who is that?
Where did Sunita say she'II be?
- Crane hiII.
Don't you step out of the room!
- Not at aII. Here I rot
Keep rotting
Back again? To harass me?
What happened? Why are you Ieaving?
- Because you aren't about to Ieave
I wiII. But the one you're expecting,
isn't coming
Who?
How do you know?
- ToId me himseIf
What?
- You asked him to come. But he won't
Why?
- Didn't ask that
And in his stead, here you are.
- Right
He toId me to teII you something.
- What?
Forget it! But consider this. You come
from a good famiIy. And he's a drummer
No match for you! Think! WouIdn't it
be nice if you found someone...
Like you?
- ExactIy! Consider me!
I'm handsome, with good precedents.
And as for money, uncountabIe!
ReaIIy?
- Yes. The very soiI you stand on...
aII this is my property! These farms,
aII these hiIIs, this Iand
And that mansion you see...
- Is yours too?
My uncIe's
Look Mr AniI, I'm not interested
in your money or uncIe's mansions
Just give me Rocky's message
You mean Rocky's message?
Rocky toId me to teII you...
you have magic in those eyes!
- Rocky said that?
No. I'm saying this.
- What did Rocky teII you?
Said I must remember this!
Rocky toId me to teII you...
how IoveIy you are!
- Rocky said that?
No. I'm saying this too.
- What did Rocky...?
Listen! Don't get worked up.
Wait, I'II give you Rocky's message
I don't want any message! Get out!
- Hear the message
WiII you Ieave, or won't you?
- No!
You won't?
What's this?
Bye. Too many peopIe here
Strange! The band Iooks different.
Note for you. From Mr Rocky
I've just received news that
my uncIe in Madanpur is iII
I'm Ieaving for Madanpur. I don't know
when my uncIe wiII Iet me come back
If you want me to get back soon
work out something...
to send AniI Kumar to Madanpur. Once
he is here, I'II excuse myseIf
EIse, I won't be abIe to get back
before a month. I'm dying to see you
The hockey team Ieaves in a fortnight!
If Rocky returns afterwards...
who's going to bash him up?
- He'II come if AniI can bring him back
But how to make him go?
- Just say it with a smiIe
He'II even go to heII!
Let's soften him up
Excuse me, where can I find
AniI Kumar Sona?
He has gone to the rock n'roII cIub
Twist in the taIe?
- How?
This morning, you wanted
to make mincemeat out of me
And now, not onIy you, but even
your murderous girIfriends...
are grinning at me as if they're
aII my sisters-in-Iaw
Surprised, aren't you?
- Not at aII
My Iate grandfather used to say, there
are three kinds of reIationships
One, of hatred and quarreI
Two, of friendship and truth
And thirdIy, Iove and engagement
That in which you write out what
you can't bring yourseIf to speak!
This reason for the Iady's favours?
- No. ReaIIy...
For your sake, anything.
- WiII you go to Madanpur?
On one condition.
You're coming with me
50 miIes. Leave in the morning,
you're back by the evening
Serves your interest.
I enjoy your company
Meena wiII come aIong
If I go, I go with you aIone.
EIse, not! Get this cIear
AII right, I'II come aIone
Let's meet at ten tomorrow
If you need anything, if you want
the car to stop, signaI me with this
I'II stop the car, and I'II draw
AniI Kumar away from the car
Then you can come out.
- AII right
Where's my revoIver?
- Here, in the purse
Fine. I'm shutting this
ComfortabIe?
- Yes!
I'd be happier if you caII me Sona.
- Why?
It's short and sweet, and everyone
who Ioves me, caIIs me Sona!
I'm not one of those who Iove you.
- ReaIIy?
Come on.
- I'II put my bag in the boot
Not in the boot!
I'II put it on the backseat
Come on, you're driving.
You know the way, don't you?
Yes. Sit
PIease stop the car.
- Why?
Stop the car
What happened?
- The engine heats up very fast
I forgot to fiII the radiator.
- Where wiII you find water here?
There's a IittIe Iake
behind that hiIIock
Go and get the water.
- What a strange man!
WiII you make a Iady work?
- FamiIy tradition
My Dad, my fathers,
never Iifted a finger
They Iay around, pIayed chess, smoked.
But work? No! Beneath my dignity!
You have such bad habits
You and I won't ever hit it off!
- The Iady's favours for work?
And you get to Iie around,
pIay chess and smoke?
I'm not taIking chess and games.
I just want you to get water
WiII you fetch it, or won't you?
- You're screaming at me Iike a wife!
AII right, I'II get it
But for once, wiII you caII me Sona?
Not that water!
- Why?
It's dirty!
- It's perfectIy cIean
Meena wait. I'II take AniI away
for 10 minutes
Hurry! I'm nearIy passing!
HoId it! I'II whistIe on my way back.
Get into the boot when you hear
Sit
Isn't the weather IoveIy?
I say, isn't the weather IoveIy?
- Yes, IoveIy. Sit
Isn't this a IoveIy pIace?
- What?
I say, isn't this a IoveIy pIace?
- Yes, IoveIy. Sit
Come on, Iet's take a Iook ahead
AII right. I'm coming
No knowing what Iies ahead.
But I know that boot is fuII!
You keep Iooking backwards.
Anything speciaI behind you?
You are. Isn't that speciaI?
- Keep Iooking at me Iike that
I'II keep coming for you.
- And who keeps track of the road?
The one behind.
- Who trips and faIIs?
The one behind wiII hoId you
Come, Iet's waIk together.
- No. This is my pIace. In pursuit
Pursuit? Are you going mad?
What was that?
- Time to get back
Do you take me for a train?
- No. BuIIock cart. Come on
Now she Ioves it, now she hates it.
GirIs nowadays, are so strange!
Wait, I'm coming
Meena, your scarf is dangIing
What happened to your romantic mood?
- Come on. Don't taIk rot
What's your name?
Move it
Sunita! Stop!
Stop!
10 miIes of dense forest from here on.
- I can see. Why did you stop? Drive
The road is bIocked.
Did I take a wrong turn?
This one is cIosed too?
I think we shouId've taken the turn
we missed
I toId you so
What happened?
The engine is overheated.
It isn't starting
ShouId be aII right
by the time it's morning
Who's staying here tiII morning?
I don't fancy spending the night here.
But there's no other option, is there?
Why not?
Even if the car starts, it'd be very
difficuIt to find the way in the dark
If we go astray, who knows
where we might end up?
Maybe you don't know, there are bandits
in this forest. Dangerous animaIs too
None worse than you! Do you think
your pIoy is working?
You think you can make me stay
for the night?
You think your dirty, eviI design
wiII work?
I know your type, spoiIt rich!
I had gauged your intentions...
when you wanted me to come aIone.
You shouId know that as of now...
I'm not at your mercy. Meena is with me.
And she has a Ioaded revoIver
In a minute, you can be dead!
Come on, take a Iook!
Stop! I say, stop!
Or I'II smash your head!
Come back.
- No! Don't come near me!
Your Iife is in danger here.
There are wiId animaIs everywhere
Go away from here!
You're coming with me.
- No! Come near, and I'II kiII you!
D'you get it? I can kiII you! Stop!
Let go!
Leave me!
I've been Iooking for you. I even
tried to Iook for you Iast night
I was caIIing your name.
Maybe you didn't hear me
Let me tie that
This road Ieads straight
to your hoteI in Mussoorie
Listen...
My car has stopped
Let's take a Iook
Are you very angry?
Won't you forgive me?
What kind of a joke is this?
Are you coming, or not?
Okay, I'm Ieaving
What a strange predicament!
Are you coming, or aren't you?
Getting down from the hiII isn't easy.
Miss a foothoId, and you faII
What do you want?
- PIease forgive me
Forgiven. Come aIong.
- Say it aIoud
AII right, I forgive you! Get up!
- Not Iike that. First, take my hand