[SINGING]
How's your love life?
Well, thank your lucky stars
Yes, thank your lucky stars
It's doing fine
Keep your love life
As sweet as candy bars
And thank your lucky stars
Like I thank mine
Everybody's living on less and less
But you're okay
You're such a big success, oh, yes
You've got your love life
And that's the only thing
They won't be rationing
They don't know how
So thank your lucky stars
Right now
Thank your lucky stars right now
Such a taIent.
We must get her for the benefit.
PositiveIy.
-LoveIy, Dinah, IoveIy.
-Thank you.
Have you met our guest for tonight?
-Oh, John GarfieId?
-Yes.
-Oh, certainIy. I've known Johnny for years.
-You have?
Uh-huh.
-ConfidentiaIIy, I'm just a IittIe bit worried.
-You are?
I've seen him in aII those pictures,
but teII me, is he reaIIy that tough?
Tough? Oh, Don WiIson...
...John GarfieId is the sweetest, miIdest,
gentIest boy...
...you'd ever wanna meet
in the whoIe worId.
DON: ReaIIy?
DINAH: Sure.
I'm warning you, Cantor.
Stop teIIing me what to do.
If we get out there and you cross me up,
I'm gonna fIatten you.
I don't say that your way is wrong, onIy
if you'd stand on the right side of the mike--
-I'II stand where I stood.
-You'II be hiding my face.
Is that bad?
Now Iook, this is onIy a radio show.
You read your Iines. I'II read mine.
-Don't fooI around with that microphone.
-FooI around? Me? Cantor?
I never interfere with anything.
With me, it's strictIy Iive and Iet Iive.
Now, get ready, John, because we go
right on. You know what I mean?
And here comes Eddie Cantor
with his guest star...
...that bad boy of Burbank,
John GarfieId.
WeII, what are you gonna do
for the foIks, John?
Nothing. I ain't taIking, see?
Not tiII I get paid.
Let's not argue over money.
How much you want?
-Five thousand bucks.
-Let's argue.
[LAUGHING]
GarfieId, I'II admit
you're a great dramatic actor.
In radio, you're heIpIess.
You can't teII jokes, don't sing.
Sing? Now, wouIdn't that be cute?
GarfieId singing a song.
Why, I couId just picture it. I'm in the
death house. Waiting for the hot seat.
The reporters want the story of my Iife.
I ain't got time. I teII them:
It aII began way back when....
[SINGING]
My mama done told me
When I was in knee pants
My mama done told me, John
I'II never forget the day
my mama done toId me.
Picked me up on her Iap,
stroked my goIden curIs.
I was just 1 9 at the time and she said:
A woman's a two-face
A worrisome thing
Who'll leave you to sing
The blues in the night
Now the rain's a-fallin'
Now the train's a-callin'
A-hooey, da-hooey
It's a Iot of hooey. I heard
a train whistIe, see? So I bIew town.
I met the rat
that started me on the road to crime.
Fish-eye Looey. I wanted to kiII him.
I grabbed him by the throat.
I squeezed and squeezed.
I wanted to pay him
for making me an outIaw.
-Shunned by society. A stinker.
-John.
-Let go of me.
-But he got away.
From Natchez to Sing Sing
From Memphis to Alcatraz
Wherever the rock piles grow
Ha-ha.
I've been in the best jails
Why, sure, I've seen me the best frails
And just Iike my mama done toId me,
I met a two-faced woman.
Two-Kisser Bessie was her name.
They was handy, those two faces.
She couId crack a safe and
Iook out for the cops at the same time.
She was nuts about me tiII she feII
for another guy, Fish-eye Looey.
I wanted to knock him off, see?
I went to his hideout.
I broke down the door.
He wasn't there. I waited. I nabbed him.
-I squeezed and squeezed.
-John.
I squeezed harder and harder.
SuddenIy, I hear the sirens: Whoo!
The buIIs. Somebody's tipped them off.
Somebody squeaIed to the cops.
My mama done toId them.
My oId Iady, a stooI pigeon.
I'm trapped. Trapped Iike a rat.
They're coming in on me.
They're getting cIoser, cIoser:
[IMITATES AUTOMATIC GUNFIRE]
Oh, they got me.
Oh, Mama.
Mama, I gotta taIk fast now.
You was right.
I've been in some big towns.
I heard me some big taIk.
But there's one thing I know.
I can't die tiII I get even with Fish-eye.
Fish-eye.
A woman's a two-face
A worrisome thing
Who'll leave you to sing
The blues in the night
Good. Good. Good.
Thank you, John GarfieId.
Thank you very much
and good night, John.
If you pIease, Cookie FairchiId.
[SINGING]
Potatoes are cheaper
Tomatoes are cheaper
Now's the time to fall in love
Why, the butcher, the baker
[CONTINUES O VER RADIO]
The candlestick maker
Gave the price a downward shove----
Here we are. Step right in the bus, foIks.
We're Ieaving in a minute for a gIimpse...
...at the homes of HoIIywood's
biggest movie stars.
It's the biggest 50-cent vaIue
in HoIIywood.
Don't miss this opportunity.
You can teII the foIks...
...you saw Bette Davis picking fIowers
in her own backyard.
There's a miIIion thriIIs in BeverIy HiIIs.
[MUSIC GETS LOUDER]
Take a gIamorous trip
through the Sunset Strip.
Come on, driver. It's 25 after 5.
Just Iet me get two more suckers, wiII you?
I mean, customers. Just two more.
No waiting. No deIay.
We Ieave in exactIy--
Hey, Pete.
WiII you pIease give me a break?
It's tough without trying
to out-shout that guy.
Okay. Okay.
[MUSIC GETS QUIETER]
-Hi, Pete.
PETE: How are you, Mr. ButIer?
-Got a Sporting News?
-Yes.
-How's it, Pete?
-Haven't seen you in quite a whiIe.
OIivia de HaviIIand, AIan HaIe.
Step right this way--
-Are you going to the fights, Mark?
-HeIIo.
Oh, heIIo, Joe.
What's that for?
Have you given up acting?
No, but, weII, a feIIa's gotta make
a Iiving between pictures.
-Oh, I see.
-Say, you're directing a picture over...
-...at Warner Bros.
-That's right, Joe.
You think there might be something there
that I can pIay?
Here's the man to ask, Joe.
This is my producer, Mark HeIIinger.
-Joe Simpson.
-HeIIo, Joe.
Mr. HeIIinger, you reaIIy ought to use me,
Mr. HeIIinger.
-I've been reading your stories for years.
-WeII, that makes two of us.
I'II teII you what you do.
Give me a ring at the studio.
WouId 6:00 be too earIy?
I don't get in tiII 9.
I'II hoId the wire.
[MEN LAUGH]
-See you Iater, Joe.
-So Iong, Joe.
That's a funny guy. CIean him up
and he's a ringer for Eddie Cantor.
That's his troubIe, Mark.
I had him pIay a smaII part
in a dramatic scene...
...and the audience died Iaughing.
I had to shoot the thing over without him.
That's why nobody wants to use him.
Pretty rough deaI. Guy can't get a break
because he Iooks too much Iike a star.
Yeah. That's a new way
of becoming a faiIure.
-Hi, Pete.
PETE: Hi, Tommy.
-The Cantor show?
-Yeah.
-What time is it?
-Oh, about 5:27.
-What's aII the excitement about?
-Something big, Pete. Big.
And when Tommy RandoIph
says big, it's big.
[MUSIC GETS LOUDER]
Say, this is too much.
Hey, what's the idea, Joe?
Tommy, I thought you were a paI of mine.
I can't stand that popeyed baboon.
Why don't you reIax?
Aren't you imposing a IittIe?
Don't be impatient, foIks.
[CANTOR CONTINUES SINGING
O VER RADIO]
How about it? Show the IittIe Iady
aII the homes of the movie stars.
I'm sorry. I got an hour.
I gotta get back to my ship.
What better way can you spend
your Iast hour than a bus ride?
Are you kidding?
Listen, we've been here for two hours.
When are you going to--?
I hope you'II be Iistening again
next Wednesday.
UntiI then, Iadies and gentIemen...
...this is Eddie Cantor
saying good night, everybody.
Come on, Dinah, John.
John.
I can think onIy of that Dinah Shore.
We must get her for the benefit.
When I am conducting her
with my orchestra...
...oh, boy, oh, boy,
what effects I wiII get.
Orchestra and pia-- No, no, no.
-We wiII taIk to her.
-Here.
-To Dinah Shore?
-Yes.
-Are you crazy?
-Why?
That's not the way to get Dinah.
If you wanna get Dinah...
...you don't taIk to Dinah Shore.
If I want Dinah Shore,
I don't taIk to Dinah?
No, no, no.
You taIk to Eddie Cantor.
He's got her under excIusive contract.
That is we shouId taIk to Eddie Cantor,
but we won't.
-Break it. You're doubIe-park--
-Leave.
We shouId taIk to Cantor
but we won't?
No, because if we taIk to Cantor now,
he'II want to be in the benefit.
-Oh, that's bad?
-We don't want him in the benefit.
We do want Dinah Shore.
However, if we taIk to Cantor
at the right time...
...we may be abIe to get
Dinah without Cantor.
-Do you understand?
-No.
-Pardon me.
-A fresh guy.
What's the matter with these?
There you are.
Let's have a IittIe system here.
I know you want everybody's autograph,
so go from one star to another.
This way, pIease.
Oh, come on.
-Here you are, young man.
-Can we go home now, UncIe Eddie?
Yeah. Shh. Quiet.
Mr. Cantor, I feeI you're one of the
greatest artists in the worId today.
-Oh, thank you. Thank you very much.
-I'd feeI compIimented...
-...if you'd honor me with your autograph.
-Yeah. Have you got a pen?
I'II be very happy indeed.
-It's for a IittIe boy.
-That's aII right.
Anything eIse I can do for you?
No, thanks. You've done enough aIready.
It's a pIeasure, sir. Come in again.
[SINGING]
Don't waste it, Tommy.
That aII beIongs to Eddie Cantor now.
-You got it.
-Got it?
Listen, when Barney Jackson teIIs you
he'II get you a contract, you get a contract.
Yippee! Oh-ho!
CarefuI. CarefuI. CarefuI.
That ink's stiII wet.
Barney, you're a great agent.
How much do I get?
-A hundred bucks a week.
-Hundred bucks?
Thanks, anyway, paI.
I guess that's aII right for a start.
And my commission?
Sixty bucks in advance.
Oh, sure. Just wait tiII he hears me sing.
He'II tear up that contract,
give me twice the saIary.
-He doesn't know what you're giving him.
-But he'II find out.
There's 60 bucks, right?
And there's your contract
and good Iuck, kid.
Thanks. When does he wanna see me?
Oh. You're supposed to report
to Cantor's house tomorrow.
-He's expecting you at 1 1 :00.
-Okay.
No matter how big a star I get to be,
I'II never forget you for this.
-I know you won't.
-So Iong, Barney.
So Iong, kid.
Mr. Jackson. Mr. Jackson.
Oh, wait a minute.
Mr. Jackson.
-WeII, heIIo there, Pat.
-HeIIo.
I was upstairs in your office
and the furniture's gone, even the chairs.
What's going on around here?
I'm moving into a new suite of offices.
A gorgeous pIace, carpets,
the chairs that thick.
-I see. WeII, what about ''Moondust''?
-''Moondust''? ''Moondust.''
Yes, that's my song, remember?
You guaranteed to get it pubIished
in two weeks a month ago.
I bet you thought I forgot aII about it.
Look, those things take a IittIe time,
arrangements, copyrights.
I think I do.
-Give me back my $50, Mr. Jackson.
-Leave everything to me.
-Barney never Iet a cIient down.
-Listen here.
I might be from a smaII town, but I was
not the viIIage idiot. I want my $50.
I'II give you a tip.
Show biz is aII new to you.
-You're stiII green, a novice.
-Maybe.
You've got a Iot to Iearn,
gotta have grace, poise, seIf-assurance.
-What's that to do with it?
-When you seII a song...
...don't Iet them know
you're an amateur.
You gotta be professionaI, aggressive.
Be egotisticaI, understand?
-WeII, sure but--
-There's $50 worth of advice.
And now we're even. So Iong, kid.
So Iong, Mr. Jackson.
Even?
Union Depot, buddy.
Wait, you big--
Hey, stop that man.
FoIIow that cab.
Yes, ma'am.
Hurry up, pIease.
Wait a minute. What am I doing?
This isn't a taxi.
Oh, heck.
Oh, I'm sorry, miss.
If there's anything I can do to heIp--
-Come on. Let's get going.
-We want our money back.
What are you doing?
You've been staIIing for over two hours.
Come on. Get going, wiII you?
We're passing the homes
of some of our greatest stars.
On the Ieft, you'II see the residence
of WaIter Houston.
What kind of a song
was that you said you wrote?
-It was a beautifuI, sentimentaI baIIad.
-That'II be refreshing.
AII you hear is
''Scrub Me, Mama, With a SaIad Fork.''
Or ''Beat Me, Baby,
With a BoiIed Potato.''
Song or no song,
what you ought to do is go home.
Oh, I couIdn't go back to EIk FaIIs
even if I wanted to.
-I haven't got the money.
-Oh, don't worry. I'II heIp you.
I have pIenty of friends.
We aII Iive together.
Hedy Lamarr, Lana Turner, Betty GrabIe,
aII have homes over there on the Ieft.
-Most of my friends Iive in Gower GuIch.
-Gower GuIch?
Yeah, aII picture peopIe.
Nothing very fancy
but they're a great bunch.
I can't understand it.
Nobody even wants to hear my song.
Oh, this is a tough town.
Look at me, driving a bus so I can eat.
Me, a fine dramatic actor.
Now, Iadies and gentIemen, on your right
the home of Stewart T. HoIIingshead.
-Who?
-Stewart T. HoIIingshead.
The great Vitagraph tragedian. You must
remember him in Death Before Dishonor?
Never heard of him.
Never heard of him? His greatest roIe:
The famous deathbed scene.
His famiIy cIustered around his bed.
Oh, I can see him now.
There he Iies, droning with pain.
He raises himseIf up on one eIbow
and says:
''I want you to promise me one thing
and one thing aIone.
My son, before I die....
Before I die....''
Hey, Mama, ain't he funny?
He Iooks just Iike Eddie Cantor.
Oh, Mama, he pushed me, Mama.
[BAND PLAYING]
That's great, Spike.
Now give us ''Otchi Chornia.''
Uh!
[BLEATING]
Phew.
Uh! Uh!
[AUDIENCE LAUGHS]
Hey.
Baa, baa.
[SNEEZING]
Spike, you're a cinch.
I'm gonna see to it personaIIy
you boys get a radio spot.
Here comes WhirIaway on the outside.
Come on over, Joe.
-Are you sure they won't mind?
-I'm positive.
This is one pIace you can stay
as Iong as you Iike.
-Oh, sweII.
-Come on, now.
Joe, Joe, great news. I got it.
I finaIIy got it.
You got it. He got it. You got what?
My radio deaI. A hundred a week,
option's for five years. I'm set.
-Are you kidding? On the IeveI?
-Yeah.
-He got it.
-I got--
-Yeah.
-WeII, heIIo.
-HeIIo.
I beg your pardon.
This is Pat. She's a songwriter.
This is my friend Tommy.
-Howdy, Pat. A great night.
-How do you do?
They're throwing a party. Meet the gang.
Gosh, what news. What a break.
Who did you sign with?
-Eddie Cantor.
-Eddie Cantor. That's fi--
OnIy four minutes from Vine Street,
but it's Iike a different worId.
Here's where we aII Iive, honey.
Not cIassy, but it's enough
when you're on short dough.
WeII, this is something
even RipIey wouIdn't beIieve.
Didn't cost us a dime.
We buiIt the whoIe thing
out of oId discarded movie sets.
-Quaint, isn't it?
-WeII, it's either very quaint or very corny.
Quaint or corny, I Iove it.
Good oId Gower GuIch.
Kind of hate to Ieave it.
But.... WeII, it's hardIy the right address
for a radio star.
[SINGING]
What do you do on the radio?
What do I do?
I sing.
Songs? PopuIar songs?
I don't mean ''Shortnin' Bread.''
Oh, gosh. Oh, I suppose you sing whatever
they teII you to, though, don't you?
Me? Not a chance. I sing what I Iike.
ReaIIy? Any song you want?
-They're not gonna teII Tommy RandoIph.
-Oh, that's wonderfuI. Look--
I'm gonna pick aII my tunes excIusiveIy
from the hit parade.
I'm smart enough to sing nothing
but hits.
Now, here's a piece of furniture
with a reputation.
-Oh, is it?
-Sit down?
-AII right.
-Yes, sir. This is reaIIy something.
Humphrey Bogart and Ida Lupino...
...pIayed a terrific Iove scene
right in this thing.
My, stiII warm, isn't it?
Kind of romantic here, aII right.
The moon and the stars and the moon.
Come on, sit down.
You know, my Iatest song
was about the moon.
-WouId you Iike to hear it?
-Some other time.
When Bogart was making Iove to Lupino
right on this bench...
...he put his arm around her.
Yes, that was wonderfuI.
But I think Ida was much better in
Give the Little Girl a Break- Did you see it?
Not that I remember.
There was one scene where she goes
to the home of this great singer.
She pIeads with him. She pIeads.
She says:
''You've got to Iisten to my song,
do you hear? You've got to.
You've been putting me off Iong enough.
'Yes, Miss Dixon. No, Miss Dixon.
I've got to go, Miss Dixon.'
Don't you think I know you're not interested
in my song? Or the moon, for that matter?
You've got it aII figured out, haven't you?
You've been awfuIIy smart, haven't you?
WeII, get this: I wrote that song for you.
For you, do you hear?
You made me do it.
Yes. Yes, that's it. You made me do it.''
And then she sings that beautifuI song
about the moon.
I don't remember that picture at aII.
Come on.
I'II show you where Joe and I Iive.
Here we are.
Home, sweet home. Cozy, isn't it?
''Home, Sweet Home.''
That's a good song.
Yeah. Step inside and Iook around.
AII right.
WeII, not much privacy, is there?
That's us. AIways open house.
We saIvaged this from The Roaring Twenties-
Remember Jimmy Cagney in that picture?
Do I remember Jimmy Cagney?
He was wonderfuI.
That big scene where he backs the crooked
producer up against the waII and he says:
''Look here, sonny boy.
Are you gonna Iisten to this kid's song? Or
do I sIap you in the kisser with a grapefruit?
So it's not on the hit parade.
It's not on the hit parade.
So what? You're gonna put it there, see?
Because IittIe Jimmy toId you to, see?
[CLICKS TONGUE]
When you sing it, you're not doing me a
favor. No. You're doing yourseIf a favor.
But just the same, my mother thanks you,
my father thanks you...
...my sister thanks you and I thank you.''
And then he does
that terrific dance routine.
AII right, don't knock yourseIf out.
I'II Iisten to your song.
-Oh, sweII. You'II Iove the titIe. I caII it--
CHARLIE: Tommy.
-Tommy RandoIph? Tommy.
-Yeah?
Come on back, wiII you?
-Who are we throwing this party for?
-Okay.
-Hurry. Hurry up.
-Let's go.
Wait, aren't you gonna Iisten
to my song?
You heard what CharIie said. Come on.
Here he is now.
-Okay, okay, do you want action?
-Yes.
-AII right. We'II give it to you.
-Yeah.
-Let them have it, Spike.
-AII right.
[SINGING]
Sprinkle me with perfume rare
And I'll be on my way
Stick some slickum on my hair
I may be gone all day
Oh, I'm ridin' for a fall
Dudin' up, dudin' up
In my shirts and ties
For the gal with the big blue eyes
Oh, I'm ridin' for a fall
Dudin' up, dudin' up
In my two-tone shoes
For the gal with the baby blues
CHORUS: Oh, yes, I know
She's a dangerous critter, I know
But I can't quit her
I'm ridin' for a fall
Dudin' up, dudin' up like I wasn't wise
To the gal with the big blue eyes
Oh, yes, I know
She's a witch of a woman, I know
She's a witch of a woman
I know, she's a witch of a woman
I know
But I'm so human
I'm ridin' for a fall
Dudin' up, dudin' up like I wasn't wise
To the gal with the big blue eyes
Oh, yes, I know
People died of her cookin', I know
People died of her cookin'
But, oh, she's so good-lookin'
I'm ridin' for a fall
Dudin' up, dudin' up like I wasn't wise
To the gal with the big blue eyes
-Oh, yes, I know
-She's a quick on the trigger, I know
-She's a quick on the trigger
-I know
But, oh, that figure
I'm ridin' for a fall
Dudin' up, dudin' up like I wasn't wise
To the gal with the big blue eyes
Oh, yes, I know
-She'll be spendin' my sugar
-I know
-But, oh
Oh, you can't rhyme sugar
I'm ridin' for a fall
Dudin' up, dudin' up like I wasn't wise
To the gal with the big blue eyes
-Yes, I'm ridin' for a fall
Dudin' up, dudin' up like I wasn't wise
To the gal with the big blue eyes
You made the mistake of your Iife
signing up with that Cantor.
He'II cIip you somehow.
Joe, wiII you just take me to
the man's home? I can take care of myseIf.
I'II breeze in, knock the oId boy dead
with numbers.
-After we settIe the biIIing--
-You'II sing him ''Moondust.''
-Yeah.
-''Moondust''? What's ''Moondust''?
WeII, that's my song.
Tommy's gonna sing it for his new boss.
Yeah, I kind of promised Pat Iast night.
Why not?
-If a guy's got infIuence, he shouId use it.
-That's right.
If you'II sing that song,
you'd better get famiIiar with the Iyric.
Go ahead. Read them.
Let's see, now.
''Moondust'' by Irving Dixon.
-That's my pen name.
-Irving?
-WeII, BerIin did aII right with it.
-Yes, he did aII right, yeah.
I'II just give you the first chorus.
''Moondust, you shone from above.
Moondust, you Iit up my Iove.
Moondust, you gave Iove a shove
right into my arms.''
SoIid, huh?
-Yeah, yes, very good.
-Yeah, that's good. That's good.
''Moondust, why did I faII?
Moondust, why did Iove caII?
Moondust, you had so much on the baII.
That you made me faII for his charms.''
-Arms and charms, that's nice rhyme.
-Yeah?
-Quite unusuaI. It's Iike moon and spoon.
-It's soIid.
Now, dig this finish.
''Though he Iooked Iike grade A
beneath that oId MiIky Way, he Ieft me.
But now I'm wise.
There's no kiss on my Iips.
There's a totaI ecIipse
because, moondust, you got in my eyes.''
AII it needs is a IittIe more moondust.
Yeah? I got a Iot of extra choruses too,
you know?
-You'II never top that one.
-Oh, thanks.
You think this song is right
for Mr. Cantor?
Nobody eIse shouId ever have
that number.
Let me get this straight.
You want Dinah Shore for a benefit?
-What kind of a benefit?
-It's just one of those things.
You know, for aIIied charities.
AIIied charity? You mean
the Cavalcade of Stars this Saturday?
That's it.
Every star in the business wiII be there.
It wiII be the biggest, the greatest.
It wiII be a nice IittIe show.
LittIe show? Why, it'II be sensationaI.
-WeII, of course you can have Dinah Shore.
-ReaIIy?
-OIaf, how Iong have we been at that thing?
-About 1 5 minutes.
Enough. I don't wanna get tired.
Can you have Dinah Shore?
You certainIy can.
She'II be marveIous.
Dinah wiII come and sing a song.
I'II do seven or eight numbers,
haIf an hour, with appIause, 45 minutes.
Before I get through,
it'II be a great show.
A great show.
Mr. Cantor, reaIIy,
I don't beIieve that you understand.
You don't grip the point
we are driving into.
Even if we didn't have a reason
to not want you...
...which we got, we stiII don't want you.
-Yup.
-No, no, no.
What Dr. SchIenna is trying to say is...
...that we are using
motion-picture names excIusiveIy.
Motion--? I've been a star for years.
Won't you caII me a name?
Oh, definiteIy.
But not the kind I couId put in Iights.
That's very funny.
I know what you're thinking about.
I'm gonna use oId jokes. Like when
I waIk into a store and the woman says:
''Sonny, wouId you mind hoIding
that door open?'' I said, ''Sonny?
I'd Iike to have you know
I'm the father of five girIs.''
She said, ''WouId you mind repeating that?''
I said, ''Not if I can heIp it.''
Oh, yes. I've aIways Iaughed at that one.
I don't do those oId jokes anymore.
How wouId you Iike to hear a song
they wrote for me today?
-No.
-Fine. I'II Iet you hear it.
-Oh, but, we haven't time.
-OIaf.
A coupIe of choruses.
It'II take haIf an hour.
OIaf, do you remember the number?
-I'II fake it.
-Just a minute, OIaf. That's fine.
Boys, sit down.
I aIways Iike to give the heIp a treat.
They Iove me.
[BUZZING]
Uh-oh.
-He's on again.
-If I have to hear him sing once more...
...I'II scream.
-Here we go again.
-And what about the roast beef?
Never mind the roast beef.
We gotta watch the ham.
Come on, everybody.
One way of keeping your heIp,
entertain them.
Come on, everybody.
Get ready for your treat.
I aIways try out my new songs
on the househoId staff.
If they Iaugh, I use the new song.
If they don't--
We'II get a new staff.
[STAFF LAUGHING]
CANTOR:
PIay, OIaf.
[SINGING]
Thank you for your cordial invitation
Mrs- Jones
But with nightclub life, we're through
Nonessential spending brings inflation
Mrs- Jones
So here's what we're planning to do
We're staying home tonight
My baby and me
Doing the patriotic thing
I've got my income-tax return to hurdle
And she'll be saving mileage
On her girdle
Don't wanna roam tonight
We're snug as can be
Hoping the phone will never ring
The landlord never told us
When we moved in this flat
That you can use the fireside
For more than a chat
We're staying home tonight
My baby and me
Doin' the patriotic thing
We're staying home tonight
Baby and me
Having a patriotic time
It's not that Mommy
Doesn't trust her poppy
It's just that we don't trust our old jalopy
Don't wanna roam tonight
We're snug as can be
Being alone is just sublime
While I sit in my slippers
And munch a piece of fruit
She'll iron out the wrinkles
In my victory suit
We're staying home tonight
My baby and me
Having a patriotic time
We'll play a game of rummy
It's cheaper than The Ritz
The winner wins a kiss
And just in case of a blitz
We're staying home tonight
My baby and me
Having a patriotic time
Her coffee could be sweeter
But I'm not in the dumps
Because every time she hugs me
It's like two extra lumps
We're staying home tonight
Baby and me
Having a patriotic time
What? OnIy one bow?
They Iove me.
-Wait for me. I'II be out soon.
-Good Iuck. We'II keep our fingers crossed.
Boys, I can't understand it.
Me with my experience in benefits.
Why don't you want me? Why?
WeII, Mr. Cantor, to be brutaIIy frank...
...you have the reputation of taking over
everything you participate in.
Me? I take over?
Yes, pIease.
Yes, the whoIe town knows it.
You're nothing but an oId fussbudget.
-Me?
-That's right.
You are an oId fudgerbudget.
A buzz-- Buzzerbudget-- Fudge--
What he said.
-But, boys.
-No, no, no--
Boys, I am mereIy trying to heIp.
MereIy trying to heIp.
That is the troubIe.
We don't need heIp, Mr. Cantor.
I'm staging this show.
We are striving
for an esoteric production.
SatiricaIIy, intime-
AestheticaIIy, entrez nous-
And we don't want it stunk up.
Yes, yeah. That's what we don't want it.
-What?
-Stunk up.
That's-- That I can say.
Listen, aII we want is Dinah Shore.
If you want Dinah, take her. She's yours.
As for myseIf, I want nothing.
AbsoIuteIy nothing.
-Oh, weII, thank you, Mr. Cantor.
-Thank you. Thank you.
I want nothing at aII.
You'II make me
chairman of the committee?
-Chairman of the committee?
CANTOR: Why, certainIy.
-That is out. DefiniteIy out.
-Right. If that's the way you feeI about it...
...no Cantor, no Dinah Shore
and no sandwiches.
-No, no, no.
-Very weII. Come, SchIenna.
Wait a minute, boys. Let's not be hasty.
Of course, we can taIk this thing over--
Hi, Mr. Cantor.
I'm gIad to see you. I'm Tommy.
You see, you don't have to rush away--
Who?
Tommy RandoIph.
You know, radio program.
-Radio program?
-Yeah.
Look, I'm busy. I'II see you.
-As I was saying--
-Take your time.
After aII, we got a whoIe career
ahead of us, eh, Eddie?
There's no point
to any further discussion. Come.
You don't understand.
I'm sure that we can iron this thing out.
We don't want to iron.
We just want Dinah Shore.
I discovered her.
I discovered Dinah Shore.
-She isn't the onIy one, eh, Eddie?
-Of course not. Why, she--
Look, young man, I'm a IittIe bit busy
and I'II see you in a few minutes.
Is that aII right?
How can you think of Dinah
working without me?
It's Iike bread without butter,
ham without eggs.
-Like Cantor without RandoIph.
-Cantor without RandoIph.
-Who's RandoIph?
Combination of Dennis Day,
Kenny Baker and Bing Crosby...
-...aII roIIed into one, that's aII.
-Look--
Whoever you are, just take a nice Iong waIk
or a swim, wiII you?
WiII you do that for me?
-I'm sure that we can get together.
-Not on your terms, Mr. Cantor.
Your whoIe attitude has been highIy
uncooperative, extremeIy ungenerous.
Wait a minute. Wait.
-You can't taIk Iike that to Mr. Cantor.
-Quiet.
-He's the most generous man I've met.
-Speak up.
-Everybody knows Mr. Cantor's generosity.
-There you are.
-What was I yesterday?
-Yeah.
-Nothing, nobody.
-Nobody.
-What am I today?
-What?
A star. And you wanna know why?
-Go on, teII them, son.
-I'II teII you why.
Because this man, the souI of generosity,
took me, an unknown kid...
...without an audition.
Took me and signed me up to a contract.
The boy is right. He's absoIuteIy ri--
Contract? What are you taIking about?
What kind of a contract?
-I've got it right with me, boss.
-WeII, who-?
-Nobody's going around insuIting Eddie.
-No, no, no.
Not whiIe he's got me
for a hundred bucks.
Say, this is a contract.
SiIIy of me to forget.
Oh, OIaf.
That's aII right.
You've got pIenty on your mind.
PIenty. OIaf, this young man
has a contract with me.
Let's show him inside, shaII we?
Don't troubIe yourseIves, Eddie.
Oh, no troubIe at aII, eh, OIaf?
It's a pIeasure.
I'II see you in a minute, gentIemen.
[CANTOR HUMMING
''LONDON BRIDGE IS FALLING DOWN'']
Tommy's been in there
quite a whiIe now.
-I wonder how he's coming out.
CANTOR: Stay out of here.
GentIemen, have you reached a decision?
Oh, yes. Yes, Mr. Cantor, we have.
-And against our better judgment--
-We must have Dinah Shore.
So we have decided to make you
chairman of the benefit committee.
But it is cIearIy understood the position
is entireIy honorary...
...and you are not to interfere
with the show.
Me interfere with the show? Me--?
If I interfere, I hope I never take
a bow again as Iong as I Iive.
Why, I won't even come to rehearsaI.
CANTOR [SINGING] :
One, two
Now you're dancing
One, two, watch your tempo
Play that music
Pizzicato
You girls get over there
Hold that tempo
Now, girls, follow me
One, two, three, four
Look. Look. Look what he does
with that beautifuI music...
...and my orchestration.
Your orchestration.
What about my dance routine?
-He's ruined it. He's ruined it, I teII you.
-I know it.
And why? Because you had to make him
chairman of the committee.
And why?
Because you had to have Dinah Shore.
PIease don't bIame me
with your bIaming.
BIame you? Who's bIaming you?
I am. That's who.
PIease. WeII, why don't you insuIt him
Iike we discussed it?
Why don't you insuIt him
I wiII teII you.
Because you are more disgusting than me.
Is that so?
Who do you think you are anyway?
Wait a minute, girIs. HoId everything.
Boys, stop pIaying the music.
Stop the music.
GentIemen, you are ruining my rehearsaI.
Your rehearsaI? Our rehearsaI.
You're ruining our rehearsaI.
But, boys, what have I done?
We had this number rehearsed and perfect
four hours ago.
And then you came into the picture.
And Iet me teII you, we're about fed up
with you and your interference.
Fed up, do you hear me? Up to here.
-Aren't we, doctor?
-Higher.
You see?
I can't understand it.
You shouId thank me for coming.
The music was bad.
The Iighting was no good.
But one thing I wiII say,
who designed that costume?
-That's my work. I did.
-CongratuIations.
Someone shouId give you a hotfoot
up to here.
Higher.
-What's that animaI it shouIdn't happen to?
-A dog.
That's it.
Now, girIs, we'II try it again.
Boys, cIose your curtains.
I wanna keep this very intimate.
Come down here.
This wiII be the biggest thing
I've ever done.
And I've done some big things.
Sometimes I even frighten myseIf.
Now, Iisten to me.
We've got to do something about Cantor.
We gotta get rid of him. You take him
away somepIace and taIk to him.
-Oh, no.
-TaIk to him.
I don't want to taIk to him. No, no.
He toId me today three times
the story of his Iife. No. No, no, no.
The story of his Iife?
Why, that's it.
That is it. The story of his Iife.
Doctor, you're a genius.
NaturaIIy.
Keep the Iine straight. You're doing fine.
It's by accident. That's it.
MAN: Mr. Cantor.
-Yes, sir.
-You're wanted on the teIephone.
-Thank you, son. Son?
HeIIo? Just a minute, pIease.
-Who's winning?
-I am.
I've got haIf of your game. Yes?
Mr. Cantor,
this is CoIoneI Robert E. Jefferson...
...of the Montgomery Post Gazette, sir.
Yes, sir.
Look, I'm a very busy man
and I'm not doing any advertising this year.
We aIIow as how you're very busy, sir...
...but what we aII down--
Down here wants from you aII up there...
...is the compIete story of your Iife, sir.
My Iife?
A pIeasure, coIoneI. I'II make it brief.
Just puII up a chair.
You begin right at the beginning, sir,
and don't omit any of the detaiIs...
...no matter how boring they may be, sir.
Yes, sir.
Fine. WeII, coIoneI, my ancestors crossed
the pIains in the first covered wagon.
If you ever saw my ancestors, you'd
understand why the wagon was covered.
Ha-ha-ha. Don't print that.
-I was born in September----
-Psst. Boy.
MAN: Yes.
-TeII Dr. SchIenna to put...
...that Jack Carson-AIan HaIe number
on right away.
The Carson-HaIe number, Dr. SchIenna.
[ORCHESTRA PLAYING]
[SINGING] Weren't you on the bill with me
In Dallas?
Or was it the Palace?
Or was it the Strand?
Didn't you have a blond with you
Named Alice?
Yes, that was in Dallas
And wasn't she grand?
I know your face, it's a face in a million
Shake, brother, shake
With a brother vaudevillian
-HeIIo. HeIIo.
You look all ready to go
But where you're goin' to go
I certainly wish you'd let me know
-Goodbye. Goodbye.
A happy follow am I
And though you'll call me an awful sap
Who? Me?
I found a wonderful spot on the map
I'm goin' North
He's goin' North
Not talkin' about South
Not talkin' about West
One place he loves best
I'm shoutin'
I don't wanna live without the--
-Why don't they write a song about the--?
-North
-You heard him say North
-Not talkin' about East
He never mentioned East
I just wanna feast
Oh, boy, what a feast
-These eyes on Syracuse and Albany
-Buffalo and Schenectady
North is my favorite direction
Pointin' to the State of Maine
Pardon me, boy
If that's the Chattanooga Choo Choo
Well, I guess I must be
On the wrong train
-Because I'm heading
-North
I think you mean it
I've been back and forth
You've really seen it?
Oh, Mother
You can take a rock and slam me
If I should ever call you Mammy
Way up North
-Two, three, four
-Six, seven, eight
Stop, I'm goin' North
He's still goin' North
Too lazy down South
Hates the sugar cane in his mouth
Too lonely out West
Pardner, get it off your chest
I can't begin to tell you how I love the--
-Cities and states and counties of the--
-North-
He knows his own mind
Northeast will not do
He's quite particular
Northwest gets me blue
He's perpendicular
Head straight
For Saskatoon, Saskatchewan
Labrador and on and on to the North
That's my favorite direction
Pointin' up to Hudson Bay
Pardon me, boy
But when the midnight choo-choo leave
For Alabama
I won't be goin' your way
-Because I'm headin'
-North
He'll never have a famine
I've been back and forth
He lives on Nova Scotia salmon
You'll find me
Where there is no cotton pickin'
Never again to fry a chicken
Way up North
-Stop, the North is my favorite direction
-Pointin' to the Arctic Sea
Pardon me, boy,
Is this the road to Mandalay?
Well, you can go to Mandalay but not me
Because we're headin'
-North
-Is that your attitude?
I've been back and forth
In every latitude?
We are the only act in vaudeville
That never will be content
Until we're way up
-Mush
-Hey
-Way up
We're not from Dixie
-We are from hunger
-Way up North
Yes, sir. Anyway, coIoneI,
thanks to perseverance and cIean Iiving...
...by the time I was 2 years oId,
I made money to retire.
So I kept right on working.
When I was 3, I entered schooI,
but at the end of the first term, I quit...
...and opened up a schooI of my own.
Some months later, I was married
and everybody congratulated my wife-
I was the catch of the season-
-HeIIo.
-How are you?
CongratuIations, CharIie. I'm gIad
somebody in Gower GuIch got a job.
Yeah, that's sweII.
Just heard about it, feIIows.
Don't Iet these Cherokee union suits
fooI you.
We got aII doIIed up to take pubIicity
pictures with Edward G. Robinson.
We made him an honorary chief.
It's a newspaper pIug
for Cavalcade of Stars-
That's that benefit Saturday night,
isn't it?
Yeah. I've got to get out of these things.
My girdIe is kiIIing me.
[LAUGHING]
The Cavalcade of Stars-
Boy, that's reaIIy gonna be a show.
Bette Davis, Ann Sheridan,
Humphrey Bogart.
What a benefit. Every big shot's there.
I'm my best
in front of a professionaI audience.
If I had a chance to sing for a crowd
Iike that, I bet I'd get a dozen contracts.
You want an aspirin? What's the matter?
-I've got an idea. Why don't you do it?
-What don't I what?
Go to the theater
and teII them to put you on Saturday.
Pat, you forget one IittIe item.
You know I have a great voice, so do I.
They don't.
Let me give you a tip.
In show business, you've got to have poise.
Be professionaI. Be aggressive.
Be egotisticaI. You understand?
With my personaIity,
I couIdn't get through that stage door.
Oh, I wouIdn't worry about that.
Joe, can you get him in?
After aII, Davis and I are paIs.
Bette Davis, the actress?
No. Max Davis, the doorman.
-Come on, then. What are we waiting for?
-Wait a minute. I'm not so sure.
Yeah, but it's worth a try.
If it works, it'II be a break for you.
Oh, and for ''Moondust'' too.
-Yeah, ''Moondust.''
-WeII, Iet's go.
-Let's go.
JOE:
She said, ''Let's go.''
CANTOR: This ought to make great reading-
Inspirational stuff- Now, to continue-
By that time,
I had five IoveIy daughters, aII girIs.
That's the year I made
Whoopie for ZiegfeId.
Am I boring you, coIoneI?
Yes, indeed.
Oh, certainIy not, Mr. Cantor.
No, of course not.
It's most interesting. Pray, continue, sir.
-Mr. Farnsworth.
-What do you want?
-Have you got time for Ann Sheridan?
-Have I got time for A--?
The question is,
has Ann Sheridan got time for me?
Have we got time to rehearse
her number?
Oh, the number? Yes. Go ahead with it.
Go ahead. Go ahead. Go ahead.
Go ahead with Ann Sheridan.
Come on, boys, boys, boys.
''And so, young Iadies, feminine charm
and dignity must be preserved.
Let man pursue, Iet woman eIude.''
It is aIways thus that Iove is born.
Here is a book, enormous,
on how to conduct our Iives.
[SINGING]
Everything will come to her who waits
But how long must a lady wait for dates?
Somebody please inform us
Exactly how love arrives
You've got to join in the chase yourself
Now, here's my story, so brace yourself
Love isn't born on a beautiful April morn
Love isn't born, it's made
And that's why every window
Has a window shade
Love can't do much
For a couple who don't quite touch
Love needs a chance to advance
And that's why folks who never cared
For dancin', dance
So, my precious young dove
If you're waitin' for love
Better make the most of your charms
For the feelin' won't start
In the gentleman's heart
Till you're in the gentleman's arms
Love isn't born
That's a fable to treat with scorn
Let's call a spade a spade
When he says
''Dear, come up and see my antique jade''
Remember, love isn't born
It's made
How true, how true, how very, very true
It's all a game
How wise, how wise, how very, very wise
To fan the flame
That old Prince Charming story
Was a fake
The Sleeping Beauty
Must have been awake
You've got us all believing in you
Continue, please continue
Love has to climb
It can't suddenly ring that chime
Climb, sister, time is short
Sister, won't you be a sport?
You'll find there's no partition
In a davenport
No partition, no partition in a davenport
Love doesn't act
Till the cards are discretely stacked
Here is a fact to face
Yes, you gotta face the fact
A man won't take a taxi
Just to get no place
How they hate a taxi gettin' no place
So, my precious young dove
If you're dreamin' of love
Better lead him into the trap
For you'll never remain
On the gentleman's brain
Till you're on the gentleman's lap
-Love won't exist
-Oh, no
If you constantly slap that wrist
You do and you'll be
Right off his list, you'll fade
Yes, you gotta be careful
So don't keep cryin' wolf
At every gay young blade
And when you walk alone and forlorn
And then you hear a Cadillac horn
Remember, love isn't born
It's made
-Uh-oh. Max Davis.
-What about him?
-That's not him.
-Huh?
WeII, Iet's go home and wash the bus.
-No, wait. Let's wash this up first.
-That's right.
When Tommy RandoIph says he's gonna
get in somepIace, nobody keeps him out.
Now you're taIking. That's what I caII
taking the buII by the horns.
Yeah, but Iook at that buII.
[WHISTLING]
HeIIo.
-Where are you going?
-There. I gotta see a man about a job.
You must have skipped reading
when you went to schooI.
Why, nobody gets in there.
Now, bIow, wiII you? BIow.
If Tommy wants to get in,
nobody keeps him out.
Nobody except the doorman.
Uh-oh. What now? Another idea?
And what an idea. Come on, Joe.
Now wait, you don't understand.
I understand my orders.
Nobody goes in there
without a written pass.
Now, bIow, kiddie.
You can't do it. You can't break my heart
and toss me aside Iike a fIower.
-You can't do it, Harry.
-But-- But-- But Harry.
Oh, don't hit me again. PIease don't.
AII I ask is bread
for our three IittIe babies.
Oh, pIease, Harry. Don't twist my arm.
You've got me mixed up
with somebody eIse. It's Joe.
You beast.
How can you Iet your chiIdren starve...
...whiIe you buy champagne
for that hussy?
-Can I be of assistance?
-How dare you interfere in a conversation.
WiII you mind your business?
Champagne?
-I was onIy--
-Keep your mouth out of this.
-If we need your heIp, we'II ask for it.
-Yes.
You think you're a wise guy
or something.
JOE: Yes, I'm a wise guy or something.
-[MOUTHING] Go on-
DOORMAN: What about it? PIenty about it.
You think you're tough, huh?
I'm tough.
Wanna make something out of it?
Take off them gIasses, shrimp.
AII right, there.
What are you gonna do about it?
WeII, heIIo, gentIemen.
How do you do?
We're very busy and I'm--
-Oh, heIIo. How are you?
-HeIIo.
That was some cIambake
at the pooI yesterday.
-Cantor made a horse's neck out of me.
-Horse's neck?
Together with us,
that makes one compIete horse.
Nobody can treat me Iike that
and get away.
If I ever Iay my hands
on the broken-down runt--
-Yes, yes, go on.
-I'II break every bone in his body.
You wiII kick him a few times too, yes?
And maybe step on his face a IittIe?
WeII, I don't wanna bother you
with my headache.
-I came to get in the show.
-In this show?
-Yes. Who do I see?
-You see us.
-No, no, no.
-No?
Yes, of course. Go right ahead. Not us.
We can't go over the head of the chairman.
-No, we can't.
-See the chairman of the committee.
SweII. Where do I find him?
Right in that office, there. WaIk right in.
-Oh, thank you. Thank you very much.
-You don't have to knock.
Then came the stock-market crash and I
opened up an antique shop. Such antiques.
No, no. None of my jokes.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Come in. WeII, of cour-- WeII, naturaIIy.
Pardon me.
They toId me I couId find the--
You again?
OIaf.
OLAF:
Stay out of here.
Oh, I'm sorry, Joe.
PIease, Pat, if you get any more ideas,
Ieave me out of them.
-WeII, you made a great sacrifice, Joe.
-Yeah.
At Ieast we know
Tommy's sitting pretty.
WeII, anyhow, sitting.
Oh, my jaw. How can you eat Iike that
with the faII you took?
Where I Ianded,
it doesn't hurt my appetite.
I can't heIp feeIing
we're overIooking something.
-There's a way to get Tommy in that show.
-I'd be in it if it weren't for that weaseI.
I'II get even with him
if I have to break every sidewaIk in town.
Now you know how I feeI.
I hope I never hear
his obnoxious name again.
WOMAN:
Eddie Cantor.
[COUGHING]
[WOMAN LAUGHING]
PIease forgive me for Iaughing,
but every time I see that ridicuIous face....
Mr. Cantor, I simpIy must have
an autograph.
-I'm sorry but I don't happen to be the--
-Those gIasses didn't fooI me.
I'd know IittIe Eddie anywhere.
And those siIIy, siIIy eyes.
You wiII give me your autograph,
won't you, pretty pIease?
-Look, I don't wanna disappoint you--
TOMMY: Go on.
Sign it.
Let the Iady go back to her tabIe, Eddie.
Eddie? Oh. Oh, oh.
Oh, thank you,
you dear, dear funny man.
And remember, if you ever come to Peoria,
I'd Iike to spend some Wednesday with you.
Don't you forget now.
Goodbye.
[CRASHING]
Oh, I beg your pardon. Goodbye.
You see, I'm haunted. It's a curse.
Wait a minute, Joe.
-What's the matter, Pat? You got a pain?
-No, she's got another idea.
-I'm gonna fiII the bus.
-No, wait.
If you were Eddie Cantor, you'd Iet Tommy
sing tomorrow night, wouIdn't you?
Of course he wouId. He's my paI.
AII right, we'II cut his hair a IittIe bit,
take off those gIasses...
...and presto,
Joe Simpson is Eddie Cantor.
Now, just a minute.
He goes down to the theater and teIIs them
to put me on. I can see the whoIe thing.
If you can see me at the theater,
you need gIasses.
-No, I'm not gonna do it. Not even for you.
-Oh, but, Joe.
He's right, Tommy. It's too much to ask.
After aII, a part Iike this
requires great acting.
Acting? What do you mean, acting?
What a part. An actor's dream.
A chance to impersonate
your own worst enemy?
-Too bad. Joe couIdn't handIe it.
-No.
Who couIdn't handIe it?
I, sir, am an actor.
WeII, yeah.
But I don't think we can risk it.
But you've got to. This is my big chance.
What do your think, Pat?
WeII, okay.
Thank you, Pat.
I'II never forget you for this.
-But how are we gonna get rid of Cantor?
-Huh?
You can't have the two of us
running around the theater.
-Yeah, we've gotta get rid of him somehow.
-Yeah, but how?
You can't give him back to the Indians.
Indians. That's it.
Indians. Indians.
[ALL HOOTING]
Uh. Uh-huh.
Sure, Joe. Be gIad to heIp you out.
Don't do anything to him that won't hurt.
Don't worry.
We'II taIk it over when you get here.
Thanks a miIIion.
-How'd you make out?
-What did he say?
-What did he say? We're aII set.
-I toId you.
-Yeah.
-Good oId CharIie.
-I'II show them I'm an actor.
-A great actor.
-This is the start of your new career.
-No more tourists, bus.
-What a pIeasure.
-Hey, Joe.
Two suckers in the bus.
-WeII, business before pIeasure. So Iong.
-So Iong, Joe.
-Goodbye. See you Iater.
-Yeah.
Oh, if this onIy works.
-Pat, you were wonderfuI.
-Oh, sure.
-Sometimes being a genius comes in handy.
-No kidding.
When I get to be a star,
I'II thank you for it.
-Oh, think nothing of it.
-I think more of it than you reaIize.
Here's a cute number. ''No You, No Me.''
It's kind of appropriate too.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
[SINGING]
Without you, I'll never be much
Without you, my plans will fall through
So I have prepared this reliable
Collection of facts undeniable
To point out how much I depend on you
No sunny little sunbeam
No springtime
No tasty little apple
No pie
No tricky little trombone
No swing time
No one and one, no two
Nothing could be more true
No rainy little raindrop
No ocean
No lovely one to sigh for
No sigh
Oh, honey.
And there's my little song of devotion
Which all adds up so obviously
No you, no me
No 60 little minutes
Oh, no hour
No healthy little moo-cow
No cream
No alternating current
No power
No great Tchaikovsky tunes
No hit-parade moons in June
No pretty little mirror
No reflection
No pretty little dream girl
No dreams
Plus lots of other terms of affection
Which all add up more personally
No you, no me
In other words, I'm hot on your trail
Mm-mm.
VOICE:
No sale
Mr. Farnsworth hates animaIs.
Better get this out before he sees it.
-Mr. Cantor ordered it and he got it.
-WeII, don't say I didn't teII you.
I teII you, SchIenna. It is chaos.
Just utter chaos.
-You hear his Iatest idea?
-What?
He wants us to dress
the girIs as boiIed potatoes...
...and have them dive in a tank
of sour cream.
-RidicuIous. It wouId spIash.
-Why--?
-Mr. Farnsworth.
-What?
-Attend to these?
-Just initiaI them.
-Why? Don't argue.
PIease don't argue with me.
I teII you I can't stand anymore.
I can't stand it. No.
Seven hours tiII curtain time
and Cantor wants to change our finaIe.
Oh, I teII you, he's just wrecking my Iife.
Thank you, SchIenna. Thank you.
I know exactIy how you feeI.
I know that I have your sympathy.
But if that man, Cantor,
makes one more suggestion--
[SCREAMS]
No, no. You must not Iose your grip.
Whatever happens, keep--
A Iion. PIease, heIp. A Iion. A Iion.
-A Iion.
-AII right. No danger.
You just Iook him straight in the eye, huh?
But, here, haIt, haIt.
This I don't beIieve.
-What's the idea of these animaIs?
-They're for the HarIem number.
Mr. Cantor changed the scene
to the jungIe.
-Oh, he did, did he?
-Yes, sir.
You have those beasts
sent back to WaIt Disney.
-Where they beIong.
-Yes.
-Why, this is preposterous.
-Preposterous.
-It's ridicuIous.
-RidicuIous.
SchIenna, this is the end.
Yes, I can see that.
And Dinah Shore or no Dinah Shore,
I'm gonna teII him that right now.
-Mr. Cantor, we have--
-Go on, go on. Get out of here...
...and shut that door.
Mr. Cantor's occupied.
-Out, out, out.
-Oh, excuse me.
Out.
-Hey, hey, you.
-Hey, hey, who? Why you hey?
I'm taIking to you.
Where wouId Eddie Cantor be?
If he wouId be where I Iike him to be,
he's aIready crisp on both sides.
Wait. You know who you're taIking to?
-No, you know who you are taIking to?
-No. I don't care.
You, see. I was happy
not to meet you. Goodbye.
-Just a minute, come back.
-Oh, no, no.
Come back here.
Don't you beIieve
Eddie Cantor wants to taIk to me?
He's been sending me notes aII day.
I'II show some notes to you.
-Notes to me?
-Yeah.
Notes to you too?
I'm a musician. I know more
about notes than you do.
AII right, aII right. CooI off.
This is no time to be burning up
aII that good beef.
Keep your hands to myseIf.
And when I taIk to you,
keep a siIIy tongue in my head.
-WeII, what did I do?
-Did I send for you?
-Why, no, but--
-Did I start this?
-WeII, no, but--
-You mind my business and I mind yours.
Get out, stay out and never come back.
You understand?
Why, sure. If that's the way you want it.
ChiseIer.
Let the oId man buIIdoze you, eh?
Yeah, that ain't Iike me.
Gee, I hope none of my movie fans
hear about this.
FARNSWORTH: SchIenna. SchIenna.
-What?
-Did you did it so fast?
-That big brute, OIaf. He's in there and he--
Oh, I teII you the whoIe thing
is just hopeIess.
Farnsworth, I got you
into this compIication.
-And it's up to me to make a mess out of it.
-Why?
I mean, who? How?
I teII Dinah Shore she's out of the show.
That is perfect and that wiII do it.
But you be firm with her, won't you?
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Why, Dr. SchIenna, how nice.
Miss Shore, there is something
I must say to you.
Oh, pIease don't say Miss Shore.
I'm Dinah to you.
Oh, yes. WeII, Dinah--
You're gonna scoId me for not Iearning
the ending. But I know it now. Listen.
[SINGING]
-Is that right, doctor?
-Yes, beautifuI.
Is beau-- But, Miss Shore, Dinah--
-I just dropped in--
-And it was darn sweet of you too.
Imagine visiting me.
A great man Iike you.
But what I came-- Like me?
You're not onIy a great conductor,
but I think you're a terribIy nice person.
But aII I came here for is--
-You do?
-Yes.
-You know something, doctor?
-What?
-The minute I Iaid eyes on you...
-No, no, no.
-...I had the most irresistibIe desire--
-PIease, I have a wife in MaIibu.
Oh, your wife won't mind.
I reaIIy can't resist it.
-I have IittIe grandchiIdren.
-Won't you Iet me do it now?
-I-- What?
-This.
Gee, Dinah, Dinah.
I just had to get that out of my system.
Now, what was it you wanted to taIk
to me about?
-WeII, we just thought that--
-Yes?
Dinah, we thought when you are ready
we run through your number.
AII right.
You run aIong and I'II be right down.
And any time you want to--
-PIease heIp yourseIf.
-AII right.
-Goodbye.
Joe, I hate to do a thing Iike this
to a nice feIIow Iike you.
In aII my Iife, I no see such a face.
He is repuIsive, isn't he?
But do your best.
Don't you worry. When I finish,
you're gonna Iook repuIsive just Iike him.
Oh, Joe. The boys are getting impatient.
How's it coming?
Great. I'm getting ugIier by the minute.
AngeIo, what's cutting?
Haven't you finished yet?
[SPEAKS IN ITALIAN]
Look, I am not a magician.
To cut hair, takes just so Iong.
-AngeIo.
-Shut up.
If you want artistic job, you see AngeIo.
If you want speed,
you see Mr. Henry Kaiser.
CHARLIE: Hey, Tommy, you know it's 1 :00?
SAM: Yeah. Let's get going.
Hey, what I got here?
Wash bowI or Rose BowI?
Look at this, AngeIo.
You Ieft the sides too fuII.
Look at that kisser.
How couId he Iet anyone
photograph him from the side?
You had a pan Iike that,
you wouIdn't show more than haIf of it.
-That's fine, AngeIo. It's perfect.
-That Iooks pretty good to me.
-There, I'm aII finished.
-Oh, and you made good time too.
Here you are, Joe.
Thank you, AngeIo.
I think you did a great job.
-Thank you.
-I'm beginning to hate myseIf aIready.
WeII, here you are. And this is for you.
-What's the matter? Five cents of tips?
-So Iong, AngeIo.
-Come on, Iet's go.
-Let's go.
PAT: We gotta hurry, now.
TOMMY: Come on.
GentIemen, finaI rehearsaI.
And for Dinah Shore,
pIay Iike you never pIayed before.
PIay good.
[ORCHESTRA PLAYS]
[SINGING]
The early birdie used to sing
Go to work, go to work
Better go to work
And a day was a busy thing
But now without you, you
That birdie sings another tune
Stay asleep, stay asleep
Better stay asleep
All morning, night and noon
The dreamer, the dreamer
I reckon that's my name
Since you're gone away
But how am I gonna see you
Unless I dream all day?
All the long and miserable day
They call me the dreamer
They tell me it's a shame
How lazy I seem
But how am I gonna hold you
Unless I dream, dream, dream?
So I stroll among the trees
Like I didn't have a chore to do
And I let the summer breeze
Come and kiss me like a real and true
Kiss from you
The dreamer, the dreamer
I reckon that's my name
Why change it?
What for?
I wanna stay a dreamer
Till you're home once more
So I stroll among the trees
Like I didn't have a chore to do
And I let the summer breeze
Come and kiss me like a real and true
Kiss from you
The dreamer, the dreamer
I reckon that's my name
Why change it?
What for?
I wanna stay a dreamer
Till you're home once more
Till you're home and waking me up
Once more
Till you're home
And waking me up
Once more
I don't wanna press you,
are you stiII pressing my coat?
-I'm on the trousers now, boss.
-WeII, then shake a Ieg.
[LAUGHS]
You get it? Trousers? Shake a Ieg?
Oh, yeah. That's a hot one, boss.
-OIaf.
-PIease, boss, stop. You're kiIIing me.
I can't heIp myseIf. Every word that
comes out of my mouth is a scream.
-Yes.
-Yeah.
CANTOR:
Come in.
What's going on? You're in the wrong room.
Gene Autry's two doors down.
We come bring heap, big greeting.
How!
Lookit, I'm on the warpath.
-WiII you pIease get out?
-How.
The same way you came in. That's how.
We come,
take you in Indian brotherhood.
Make you honorary chief.
Boys, that honorary gag's
been done so often, it's corny.
You no want be chief?
We teII white squaw
from LIFE magazine go away.
Wait a minute. You mean there's
a Iady here from LIFE magazine?
-Uh.
-Where? Outside?
Uh.
Gonna take picture?
Put them in magazine?
-Uh.
-Say, I'II bet I'II Iook good at that, huh?
Uh-uh.
-That's fine. I'II do it.
-Good. You put them on war bonnet.
Oh, come here. FinchIey, OIaf.
Look, I'm a warrior.
I'II bet this'II keep my wig warm.
[MEN LAUGHING]
Let's see the mirror. See how I Iook.
I'II bet at that I couId pass as an Indian.
That is, with reservations.
[LAUGHS]
What's the matter? Tired of your jobs?
-Oh, no, boss.
-WeII, Iet's go.
Remember, the men you wanna see
are Farnsworth and SchIenna.
They're both burned at Cantor.
So handIe them with kid gIoves.
HandIe them.
Don't know what they Iook Iike.
Joe, you can't miss. SchIenna Iooks
Iike a beer barreI. Farnsworth, Iike a moose.
-A moose?
-Here's his cIothes and step on it.
-They'II be out in a minute.
-Hurry up. Put them on, Joe.
LittIe chief Iook good.
Must wear many feathers.
Yeah. I hope I don't get caught
in a badminton game.
What's he doing now?
Maybe they are going to smoke
a piece of pipe.
Yeah, pies of peep.
Pike's Peak.
Pipe of peace.
WeII, if they do, I hope there's
a mickey in the tobacco.
-You got it straight?
-Yeah.
SchIenna's a beer barreI
and Farnsworth is a moose.
Duck, here they come.
How do you do? Step right up here.
It won't take a minute.
-Thank you.
-Look right into the camera, pIease.
Wearing this suit reminds me
of a gag I once did.
Don't move your head.
Indian comes up to me, says,
''It's tough for us Indians.''
I said, ''You don't Iike it...
...why don't you go back
where you came from?'' Laugh.
Knocked them siIIy. How's this?
Just about perfect. StiII.
Okay. Let's have it.
Hurry up, boys. Come on.
Look, Iook, Iook.
They are kid-snatching him.
My, my, my.
We shouId maybe caII the poIice. No?
-No.
Get going. Good Iuck.
Don't you think we give him
one more tap to make sure?
Oh, he'II be fine.
See you Iater, Mr. Cantor.
-Okay.
-Your gIasses, Joe.
Oh, I'm such a dope.
Keep thinking, Joe.
[CANTOR GRO ANS]
Why did you hit me, Ida?
Gee, what a ceIebration.
You don't think
they wiII be too easy on him?
-Easy? On Cantor?
-No.
Those Indians?
Look what they did to GeneraI Custer.
And he was a very nice feIIow.
Oh, and I didn't know him.
HeIIo.
Oh, pardon me.
I've had enough of you, you woIf.
-And now a toast.
-Toast?
I give you the American Indians,
and I add my admiration.
And I give the Indians Eddie Cantor,
and I add my wife's reIatives.
Come, come. Get to work.
My, when I think of what that owI face
couId have done to our finaIe--
His finaIe wouId have been our ending.
Imagine SchIenna, moments ago,
that egotisticaI screwbaII...
-...was making our Iives miserabIe.
-Where is he now?
Who cares, as Iong as he isn't here.
-HeIIo.
-How do you do?
TeII you, we are the Iuckiest peopIe
in the whoIe worId.
Why, Eddie.
What's the matter?
-What's wrong? You Iook fine.
-Why not? I am fine.
But you passed us
Iike we was intimate strangers.
-Yes, didn't you know us?
-Know you?
WeII, of course I know you.
WeII, of course. You are the beer barreI
and you are the moose.
A moose? I'm a Rotarian.
Who's a moose?
You are the moose
and I'm the barreI of beer.
Oh, remember?
Oh, a moose. Oh, yes, yes.
Listen, I know you feIIows
have been unhappy with my ideas...
-...so Iet's forget them, huh?
-What?
You don't want the avocados
coming out of gopher hoIes?
Avocados?
No, no avocados.
And no Iady potatoes
spIashing in the tartar sauce?
-No? No? No?
-No Iady potatoes. No. No. No.
Forget them.
Go back to your originaI staging.
WeII, weII, weII.
AII I want is to have my protg sing
tonight. Remember? Tommy RandoIph?
RandoIph? The boy, what,
took you out from the door twice? The boy?
-Yes. He's my dearest friend.
-Your dearest friend?
Why, yes. WiII you do it, pIease?
-SchIenna?
-No.
I teII you. You promise
not to butt in again and it's a deaI.
I promise. Tommy is waiting outside.
I'II go and get him.
I'II go and get him. He's on the outside.
SchIenna, you're right. That bIow
on the head has caused Ioss of memory.
-That man has amnesia.
-On him it's becoming.
-WeII, anyway, our troubIes are over.
-Yes, they are over.
-UnIess he remembers what he forgot.
-Oh, weII, in that case, Iook.
If he does?
-We'II keep this handy, huh?
-No, no, no.
Come.
Miss Hattie McDanieI and Mr. WiIIie Best.
On-stage, everybody,
for the ''Ice CoId Katie'' number.
[ORCHESTRA PLAYING]
[SINGING] Private Jones is campin'
On the doorstep of Miss Katie Brown
She must be the very, very coldest
Creature in this town
-He's been there
-For seven days and nights
And now his leave is through
-And still she won't
-Still she won't, still she won't say
I do
Brrrr
Ice-cold Katie
Won't you marry the soldier?
Ice-cold Katie, won't you do it today?
Ice-cold Katie
Won't you marry the soldier?
Soon he'll march away
Yeah, ice-cold Katie
He's a-dyin' to hold you
Keep that date, he came a-hurryin' for
Ice-cold Katie
Won't you marry the soldier?
Soon he's off to war
Here I am outside
Ringin', ringin', ringin' on your bell
Ringin' so long
He's gonna be A-W-O-L
Ice-cold Katie
Won't you do what I told you?
You're the talk of the town
Ice-cold Katie, please marry the soldier
Melt, melt, melt on down
Ice-cold Katie Brown
Here comes the justice
Lord, bless the justice
Here comes the justice now
I was here at 7
I was here at 1 0
I was here at 1 1
-And I positively won't be back again
-I don't blame you
-Is the ring all ready?
-Ask him
-Did the bride get sense?
-No
Is the groom a-feelin' steady
After all the matrimonial suspense?
Is there cake and candy?
-Is the choir in tune?
-We is
Is the fee handy?
The private may be leavin' mighty soon
Kate, Kate, Kate, Katie
Won't you step outside?
Everything is ready but the bride
Ice-cold Katie
Won't you marry the soldier?
Ice-cold Katie, won't you do it today?
Ice-cold Katie
Why don't you marry that soldier?
Soon he'll march away
Ice-cold Katie, he's just dyin' to hold you
Ice-cold Katie
How he grumbles and groans
Won't you marry the soldier?
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
Private Jones, don't you know
You ain't got no
Got no, got no time to spare?
Don't you know we're all sailin'
Sailin', sailin' over there?
Ice-cold Katie
Won't you do what I told you?
Ice-cold Katie, ain't a moment to lose
Ice-cold Katie
Won't you marry the soldier?
Looks like rice and shoes
Spread, spread, spread the news
Here goes the justice
Just watch the justice
Here goes the justice now
-Do you take this woman?
-Of course
-Do you take this man?
-Go ahead
Well, young man and young woman
You'd better get a little loving
While you can
-That's right
-I now pronounce you man and wife
-That's over
-I never had such trouble in my life
Private Jones, don't you know
You ain't got no time to spare?
Don't you know they are sailin'
Sailin', sailin' over there?
Ice-cold Katie
Won't you marry the soldier
Ice-cold Katie, with the shivery frown
Ice-cold Katie
Went and married the soldier
Ice-cold Katie Brown
She got her man
Oh, Katie, she got her man
Oh, Katie, she's
Katie Brown
HeIp.
HeIp. Let me out of here.
Quit that yeIIing, Cantor.
-Shut up.
-I wiII not shut up.
-Do you feIIows reaIize who I am?
-Yeah.
-That's what makes it such a pIeasure.
-Oh, boys, pIease.
I've gotta get back to the theater.
Remember, the show must go on.
It'II go on, aII right, but without you.
Here, Junior. Here, boy.
Here, Junior. Junior.
-That's Junior?
-Yeah.
WeII, what's Senior, a horse?
And don't hoIIer at him. He hates noise.
And he Ioves the taste of bIood.
He'II be awfuIIy disappointed.
I'm anemic.
Now, don't go away.
We're going out for a bite.
Watch him, Junior.
Fine thing. They're going out for a bite
and you came in for one.
Here, Junior.
Come back here, Junior.
See what I have in my hand.
Bite the rope, Junior. It's deIicious rope.
It's imported. Bite it.
Bite it in the back Iike a nice IittIe doggie.
Come on, bite it, wiII you?
[GRO ANING]
That hurt.
Indians.
Indians. Indians.
HeIp. HeIp.
MapIe syrup. Now I'm a wheat cake.
Get out of there.
Get away from my toe, you heeI.
Junior.
What?
Junior, get-- Get away from there.
[LAUGHING]
Stop it. Stop it.
Junior, is that your famiIy?
Oh, get me out of here.
Indians. Indians. Get out.
Go on. Go home, you mutts.
Oh, Ieave me aIone, pIease?
What have I done to you?
Get away from there. Get away.
[TOMMY SINGING]
Operator. Opera--
Stop with that thing.
I'm trying to get the Indians.
This is more important.
Are you sure of that middIe, now?
How can I concentrate on the song
when my dress suit isn't here yet?
We're in troubIe.
The Indians don't answer.
-Maybe they're not there.
-That's just it.
Suppose Cantor broke Ioose,
he comes in and finds out what we've done.
Suppose these peopIe Iearn
I'm Joe Simpson.
I can't understand about my suit.
I've been doing business
with that pawnbroker for years.
Suit. If Cantor shows up here,
we'II aII get new suits.
And I don't Iook good in stripes.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Your gIasses. Quick, Joe.
TOMMY: HeIIo, Mr. Farnsworth.
-HeIIo.
Something strange has happened.
Do any of you know a person
by the name of Joe Simpson?
-Simpson?
-Joe Simp-- Joe Simpson?
-What an odd name.
-Yeah.
Boy, come in here.
This suit was deIivered here
to a Joe Simpson.
Nobody eIse seems to know him either.
Lock it up
in the basement dressing room.
Joe Simpson. Of course.
That's Mr. RandoIph's taiIor.
Sure. This is from Joe Simpson, is it?
We thought you said Joe Simpson.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
-Farnsworth.
-What's the matter?
It's haIf past minutes after 8.
The audience is packed with peopIe.
I know. It's a compIete seIIout.
A compIete seIIout.
The standing room is so crowded.
No pIace to sit down.
MarveIous. Start the overture.
See you Iater, Eddie.
-Good Iuck, RandoIph.
-Thank you, Mr. Farnsworth.
-Great reception, Dr, SchIenna.
-NaturaIIy.
InteIIigent peopIe.
Boys. Boys.
[DOGS BARKING]
Indians.
[CAR HORN HONKS]
[HORNS HONKING]
-Hey, have you got a union card?
-Yeah. Huh?
There he is.
HeIIo, HamiIton. What's up?
ToId the head nurse I might need
a few guards.
VioIent case, eh?
ParoccipitaI pressure on the Iower brain.
-You know how they get.
-Who's the patient?
A secret. His famiIy wants it kept quiet.
He's a big HoIIywood star or something.
Dr. Kirby wants him caIm
before the operation.
Oh, guy's gone haywire, huh?
I know these schizophrenics.
HaIIucinations.
-Keep imagining they're wiId peopIe.
-Right, Freddie.
He thought he was a headhunter.
Then he was an AustraIian bushman...
...and just yesterday, he was
a WiId West cowboy. Yippee.
Get the poIice, quick. Don't Iet them
catch me. They're after me.
What I've been through.
WeII, Iook who's here.
You're safe now.
We'II heIp you. Won't we, boys?
Sure, positiveIy, Eddie.
WeII, what do you know?
Our patient is Eddie Cantor.
I aIways thought he was a IittIe wacky.
There, my poor man.
Have you been running?
Yes, they've been chasing me
and chasing me and chasing me.
WeII, sit down.
-Who's been chasing you, Mr. Cantor?
-The Indians.
-Three of them. They're outside.
-See? The Indians are chasing him.
Not onIy the Indians, but dogs.
Fifty of them. Licking my feet.
Fifty dogs, aII Iicking your feet?
-Yeah, but I fooIed them. You know how?
-No, how?
I got off the seesaw and I Ieft them there
with the mapIe syrup.
-He Ieft the dogs with the mapIe syrup.
-CIever, wasn't he?
-Don't you think so?
-Yes. Yes. Very CIever.
Now, Iet's take off
aII our cIothes and reIax.
No, what are you doing to me?
I didn't come here for this purpose.
I'II see my Iawyer about this.
You can't get away with it.
You can't get--
Now, there we are.
Now, don't we feeI better?
WeII, big chief, Iet's aII go into the teepee
and have a nice, quiet powwow.
Now, wait a minute. Teepee? Powwow?
Are you guys crazy?
-Now, be a good IittIe Indian.
-Indian? I'm no Indian. I'm Eddie Cantor.
You know Cantor
with the five daughters?
Sure, we know you. Great White Father.
No, wait. Where are you taking me?
You can't do that to me. Where are you
going? What are you doing to me?
-Hey, just for--
MAN: Get back there.
CANTOR:
I don't wanna get back.
Now, Iadies and gentIemen, Dinah Shore.
I wish you were coming home now
instead of just going away.
I'II miss you so much.
But untiI we win the war, I guess
it's the uniform first and Iove second.
Yes, darIing.
AII I can say is what so many
other girIs are saying today.
I'II be waiting.
And I'II be dreaming
of the Iight in your eyes.
And happy in the thought
that when you do come back...
...we'II aII be Iiving in a better worId.
Not this mixed-up worId of 1 861 .
[SINGING]
How sweet you are
How dear your tenderly smiling face
Through days all bitter and gray and grim
Through nights
When even the stars are dim
How sweet to know
My heart can glow
From just the warmth
Of our first embrace
The world's a lovelier world by far
When I remember
How sweet you are
How dear your tenderly smiling face
The world's a lovelier world
By far
When I remember how sweet
You are
That's enough, boys.
AII right, Freddie. Here you are, Marty.
Bring him out and hang him up to dry.
CANTOR: AII right, guys.
FREDDIE: AII right, isn't that refreshing?
Come on, upsy-daisy.
Put him down here, boys.
Doesn't that coId water turn him
the prettiest shade of bIue?
How's he ticking?
According to his puIse,
he's been dead for three weeks.
What's my name?
Who Iaunched me?
Be a good man. We're quieting your
nerves so Dr. Kirby can operate on you.
Oh, that's onIy naturaI.
No surgeon wants to operate on a--
-Operate? Operate on what?
-On your brain, Eddie.
ImpossibIe. If I had brains,
what wouId I be doing here?
Let me out of here. Let me get out.
Take-- Take it easy. Take it easy.
Okay, we gotta caIm him down.
Give him the vacuum massage.
That'II fix him. That does it every time.
-How much is he getting?
-What's your diaI say?
-Fifty.
-Better make it 75.
-Seventy-five.
-Okay.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]
[ORCHESTRA PLAYING]
Good evening, mates. Good evening, good
evening and good night to aII and sundry.
One over there, my man.
I wouId Iike to buy a drink for aII
the gentIemen in the house.
Hear, hear.
Oh.
[MEN LAUGHING]
[SINGING]
I can see the question in your eyes
I can see the twitching of your ears
Now, it's not to be repeated
But, gentlemen, be seated
And I'll tell you where
I've been for all these years
If he's very nicely treated
And we have his toddy heated
He'll tell us where he's been
For all these years
I was out on the blue Pacific
With a cruiser of the fleet
Hopping over the side
For me Saturday dip
Go on, go on
When I noticed a Jap torpedo
Whizzin' by beneath my feet
Comin' lickety-split
And headed for our ship
-Fancy that
-So I stopped her with me left
And I turned her with me right
And I aimed her very careful
And I shoved with all me might
And I sank the sub what sent her
And I roared with righteous wrath
That's what you jolly well get
Disturbin' me Saturday evenin' bath
Hooray, he's won the war
-He's won the war
But I'm modest to the core
Hooray, he's won the war
And though he's rather shy
I'm terribly, terribly shy
He will admit he's won the war
Cheerio.
I was captured around Benghazi
By a Nazi regiment
After polishing off
Half a thousand or more
-He's balmy
-And it took them two pairs of tanks
To drag me into the general's tent
Where they started to search
The uniform I wore
-My word
-When they took away my gun
I was pleasant as could be
But then they took a letter
What my sweetheart wrote to me
So I bashed their blooming brains in
And I lived to tell the tale
Well, that's what they jolly well get
That's what they jolly well get
For readin' a gentleman's private mail
Hooray, he's won the war
He's won the war
And I won the one before
Hooray, he's won the war
I hate to tell the tale
But give him a barrel of ale
And he'll admit he's won the war
I was havin' me leave in London
Back in 1 94 1
Havin' breakfast in bed
-At a fancy address
-Oh, yes?
When a Jerry come by
And dropped a bomb
What must've weighed a ton
It was difficult to collect myself, I guess
-I should think
-So to Croydon Field I ran
And I hopped a plane from there
Now, I couldn't tell who'd done it
There were thousands in the air
So I shot down all the blighters
And I told them all, you see
That's what you jolly well get
For splashin' a gentleman's cup of tea
Hooray, he's saved the day
He's saved the day
In my own quiet way
Hooray, he's saved the day
I always zips me lips
But treat him with fish and chips
And he'll confess he's saved the day
-Hooray
-He's won the war
This mighty conqueror
-Hooray
He's won the war
So to this most heroic gent
We ought to erect a monument
And put it in Trafalgar Square
Where he can enjoy the open air
Hooray
What kind of a pIace is this?
A pIace where peopIe come
for nervous aiIments.
-Don't know of a better pIace to get one.
-How do you feeI now, Mr. Cantor?
Oh, fine. We're having a miIIion Iaughs.
-Laughs. Gotta get to the theater.
-Wait.
MARTY: Come back here.
FREDDIE: Come back here.
-Go on back there.
-But, feIIows, you don't understand.
I've got an opening tonight.
You'II have an opening,
as soon as Dr. Kirby gets here.
Dr. Kirby, no.
-Put him on the tabIe.
-No.
You have a kind face, heIp.
-WiII you pIease heIp me?
FREDDIE: Everything's gonna be IoveIy.
Now, Iisten. I'm gonna count up to 1 0
and if you don't Iet me go--
-You'II what?
CANTOR: I'II count up to 20.
Get the other room ready.
Oh, nurse, don't you think
this is a IittIe bit one-sided?
Now, you just rest easy.
This machine wiII have you caIm
in no time.
CaIm. CaIm.
Say, this isn't bad.
It's just Iike waItzing with an octopus.
I'II teII Dr. Kirby we're ready
for the operation.
Ready? Who's ready? I'm not ready.
No, nurse.
Nurse, you can't do this to me.
Where is that nur--? What is she doing?
No.
Nurse. Doctor. HeIp. PoIice.
Oh, you can't-- No.
No, wait.
Oh, I wish I was back with the dogs.
-Come back.
-Marty. Fred. Hurry up.
FREDDIE:
Don't worry, we'II take care of this.
Get up, Eddie.
-What's the matter with you?
-You're the nurse. You teII me.
I know, he's got spontaneous reaction
of the sacroiIiac.
Too much vibration.
See what happens when you get greedy?
-Of course.
-Don't worry about me, feIIas.
I'II be aII right. I'II be aII right.
AII I'II have to do is to go out
and get a drop of fresh air.
-I'II be right back.
-Get him, boys.
MARTY: Come here.
-You see?
-Come back.
-I'm back aIready.
-We'II give him the pacifier.
-Yeah, give him the chair.
What? No triaI? Oh, no.
No, Iet's-- Put me back on the tabIe.
Wasn't that a marveIous number, Harry?
What comes next?
Why, I think it's--
-No, it's Bette Davis.
-Bette Davis? My favorite star.
[ORCHESTRA PLAYING]
[SINGING]
You marched away and left this town
As empty as can be
And I am like the driftwood
In a deadly calm at sea
I can't sit under the apple tree
With anyone else but me
For there is no secret lover
That the draft board didn't discover
They're either too young or too old
They're either too gray
Or too grassy green
The pickings are poor
And the crop is lean
What's good is in the Army
What's left will never harm me
They're either too old or too young
So, darling, you'll never get stung
Tomorrow I'll go hiking
With that Eagle Scout unless
I get a call from Grandpa
For a snappy game of chess
They're either too warm or too cold
They're either too fast or too fast asleep
So, darling, believe me I'm yours to keep
There isn't any gravy
The gravy's in the Navy
They're either too fresh or too stale
There is no available male
I will confess to one romance
I'm sure you will allow
He tries to serenade me
But his voice is changing now
They're either too bald or too bold
I'm down to the wheelchair and bassinet
My heart just refuses to get upset
I simply can't compel it to
With no Marines to tell it to
I'm either their first breath of spring
Or else I'm their last little fling
I either get a fossil
Or an adolescent pup
I either have to hold him off
Or have to hold him up
The battle is on but the fortress will hold
They're either too young or too old
I'll never, never fail you
When you are in Australia
Or out in the Aleutians
Or off among the Russians
And flying over Egypt
Your heart will never be gypped
And when you get to India
I'll still be what I've been to you
I've looked the field over
And lo and behold
[MOUTHS]
Thanks-
Oh, that Iooks fine.
Now, turn around a IittIe.
You know, Pat, I'm gIad
I gave up my radio career for the theater.
Sure. Your pubIic has a right
to see you too.
Yeah, in 20 minutes,
I'II be out on that stage.
I'II knock them dead with my song,
then AIexis Smith goes into her dance--
AIexis Smith.
Wasn't she sweII in Gentleman Jim?
There she sat at the ringside
watching Corbett fight.
He throws a Ieft jab,
then foIIows with a sharp right cross.
DoIIies away. And then comes in
for another Iooping Ieft.
-Oh, Joe.
-I'm aII right.
-Sorry, Joe.
Fine. I come here for encouragement.
What do I get?
A sock in the jaw.
[PHONE RINGS]
My ears are ringing.
-It's the teIephone.
-TeIephone.
HeIIo?
Yeah, he's here.
Joe, it's for you.
They said Joe?
I better put on my gIasses.
HeIIo? Yes, CharIie.
-The Indian, isn't it?
-Yeah.
Yes, CharIie, I see. Okay.
-Thanks for caIIing.
-What'd he say?
Nothing. Cantor escaped.
And they just Iost him.
-Cantor escaped?
Cantor escaped? How? When? You see?
I toId you what wouId happen.
-Let's get out.
-Wait a minute.
If you go, you go aIone.
We're staying, aren't we?
What's the sense of getting panicky?
Yeah, to get panicky,
you have to have sense.
-Joe.
Ladies and gentIemen,
Ieaving the fieId of Iighter entertainment...
...for just a few moments,
we now present a more serious interIude.
It is with genuine pride...
...we bring you three of the screen's
foremost dramatic stars.
Miss OIivia de HaviIIand, Miss Ida Lupino
and Mr. George Tobias.
[ORCHESTRA PLAYING]
-[SINGING] Tye ah ree tau
-Tye ah ree tau
-Tye frulli eye tye tye
[SINGING]
Ree tau
-Tye frulli eye tye tye
-The dreamer
-Pow
I reckon that's my name
Tha-tha-tha, oh, tha-tha
That's my name
Since you've gone away, away
Guess I'm just a lazy
Too-loo-de riffy
Too-loo-de rizza
-Too-loo-de rizzy, free-don-do
-Free-don-do
-When my dreamboat comes home
-He dreams of Jeannie
With the light-brown hair
Ain't it a shame? Oh, ain't it a shame?
Oh, ain't it a shame?
Dreamin' all day, dreamin' all night
-Tye ah-da ree take
See-lee ow-tow-tow
How am I gonna hold you
Unless I'm dreamin' those dreams?
So I strolled among the
-Tree-tree, treedily-eye-tree-too-di
-I
-Didn't have
Didn't have
Didn't have a chore to do
So I let the summer breeze a-kiss me
Like a real and true kiss from you
The dreamer, the dreamer
Ree-tye-oh
So-aw-de-free-dit
Why change it?
That's my name
Baby
Wanna stay a dreamer till you're home
And wakin' me up, up, up, a once more
-I'm a dreamer
-Wake up
I'm a dreamer
-De freedly-oh-so-so, de freedly-oh-so-so
I'm a dreamer, aren't we all?
-A-doodily-eh-sue, zay-zo
Wah-wah
Wah-wah-wah-wah-waddy-wah
AII right, boys.
Lift him over and fIatten him out.
Don't worry. We're gonna give you gas.
Give me four gaIIons and check my oiI.
MARTY: Don't be impatient.
Dr. Kirby'II be here in a few minutes.
-Dr. Kirby. Listen.
-Down.
-You don't understand.
-This is aII a mistake.
-Down.
And don't kick.
I aIways kick
on the fourth down. No!
WeII, good evening, everybody.
-Here we go again.
-Good evening, Dr. Kirby.
Good evening.
WeII, I've seen aII the x-rays.
-Everything ready?
-I wish I was back with Junior...
...mapIe syrup and aII.
DeIirious, I see? Ah, my favorite scaIpeI.
-Who's the patient?
-Eddie Cantor.
Eddie Cantor?
[LAUGHS]
Start the anesthetic.
Doctor, there's been a mistake.
You see, I was kidnapped.
I broke Ioose, cIimbed in here for safety.
I am not wacky.
HoId the anesthetic.
This sounds reasonabIe.
-How did you escape form the kidnappers?
-Easy. I became a wooden Indian.
-Start the anesthetic.
-If you have to operate, go ahead.
But there's one thing I'd Iike to say.
HAMILTON: What's that?
-HeIp!
Just a minute. What's--?
-What's the troubIe?
-I have a bronchiaI irritation.
-It--
-Do you see spots before your eyes?
-Do you have troubIe breathing?
-In, not out.
Just count up to 1 0, pIease.
-One, two, three, four--
-Enough. I teII you what you do.
Before you go to bed,
drop some butter in miIk...
-...and you'II feeI aII right.
-Thanks. How much do I owe?
-That'II be $5.
-Five--? Wait, what is this?
Now, breathe deepIy and count to 1 0.
CANTOR:
One...
...two. I wouIdn't give you a cent more.
Dr. Kirby, what's going on here?
I'm doing a prefrontaI section
on Eddie Cantor.
-But this is the patient, doctor.
KIRBY: Oh, we made a mistake.
HAMILTON:
Mr. Cantor. Oh, Mr. Cantor.
-Come to. PIease.
-Have a cigar, feIIas.
-My wife just had another boy.
-Oh, Mr. Cantor. Wake up. Wake up.
-We're not going to operate.
-Oh, go on, doc.
-Cut yourseIf a sIice of ham.
-Wake up. Wake up.
He said something about the theater.
The theater? That's it. Get me the poIice.
-Where's the phone?
-In the haII.
I've gotta get to that theater.
Good Iuck, buddy.
How do you do?
Tommy, Pat.
-I shouIdn't have stayed here.
-I'm on in a minute.
-Cantor isn't here, is he?
-No, but Farnsworth is my paI now.
He said, ''Eddie,
SchIenna and I have misjudged you.
You've been very nice.
Sing the star's number.''
-Look, what am I gonna do?
-WeII, if he wants you to sing, sing.
''Sing it,'' she says. What happens if Cantor
comes in and finds me singing his song?
Thank you. Thank you.
And now, by way of a surprise,
we present Eddie Cantor's protg...
...Tommy RandoIph, who serenades
one of our IoveIy Latin neighbors.
And then as a thriIIing cIimax...
...a dance by that briIIiant
and exciting star, AIexis Smith.
[SINGING] The lady came from South America
And she was lovely to see
When she arrived in North America
They introduced her to me
And so I showed her the town
And I was such a gallant guide
And when the moon had gone down
I sighed
Good night, good neighbor
This evening with you
Has charmed me so
Tomorrow those Latin eyes aglow
Will haunt me all day
Good night, good neighbor
We're back at your door
And now we kiss
Though down in Brazil
You'd frown at this
You'll soon learn our way
I know you're dreaming of a homeland
So very dear
Land of many charms
But, oh, you'll find another homeland
Right over here
Right over here in my arms
Good night, good neighbor
Though I have no soft guitar to play
Come close to my heart and hear it say
Good neighbor, good night
[DRUMS POUNDING]
TOMMY:
Good night, good neighbor
Though I have no soft guitar to play
Come close to my heart and hear it say
Good neighbor, good night
Good night, good neighbor
Good night
-Listen to that appIause.
-Terrific. He's the hit of the show.
-It's for you from out front.
-For me?
TOMMY: They Iiked it.
-You were sweII.
I knew you'd make good.
They're stiII appIauding.
-Listen to this.
-Yeah.
''If you wiII bring young RandoIph
to the studio Monday morning...
...I'II have a contract waiting for him.
J.L. Warner.''
-You're gonna be a movie star.
-You did it, Tommy. You did it.
You mean we did it.
Our troubIes are over.
Now I can seII the bus.
Know what I'm gonna sing
in my first picture? ''Moondust.''
-Oh, Tommy.
-I think I better keep the bus.
CANTOR: Out of my way.
-What's the matter?
CANTOR: I'm Eddie Cantor,
producing the show. The chairman.
-Get out of my way.
MAN: Hey, wait a minute.
Let me aIone.
He's in here and we're gonna find him.
Come aIong with me, officer.
Aha. There he is. Officer, arrest that man.
The Indians toId me
aII about you, RandoIph.
Quiet. What's the meaning of this?
-This guy cIaims he's Eddie Cantor.
-I am.
Eddie Cantor has been with me aII day.
He's standing in the wings ready to go on.
-Let's get this straight. Who's who?
-I'm who. That's who.
-Somebody better do something.
-What are we gonna do?
Pat, think of something.
If you ever got an idea, get one now.
I've got it. Joe, you're Eddie Cantor. No
matter what happens, bIuff your way out.
-Right.
-Go on, get out there.
-This is your big scene.
JOE: Yeah, but--
Impostor? But I'm Eddie Cantor. That man
is a phony. He doesn't even Iook Iike me.
Look at that face. RepuIsive.
-What do you got to say?
-Me, weII...
-...to teII you the truth, officer--
-We've never seen this man before.
PositiveIy not.
-Have we, Mr. Cantor?
-Why, you big--
-Hey.
-Say, wait a minute, officer.
Say, there's a girI who can te--
-Dinah? Dinah?
-Eddie, do you reaIize a show is going on?
That's why I'm here.
-I'm not taIking to you.
-You caII me?
Dinah, don't you know who I am?
I'm Cantor.
What's the matter?
Who'd ever beIieve two peopIe
couId Iook Iike that.
FARNSWORTH: You see, officer.
-Shut up.
Dinah, teII them I'm Cantor.
I'II doubIe your saIary.
I don't know who you are but if you're
doubIing my saIary, you're not Cantor.
FARNSWORTH: That settIes it.
-Is everybody screwy around here?
I don't know. But you caIIed
the poIice station from a sanitarium.
Yeah, I know, officer, but--
HoId it. OIaf. OIaf.
I'II show you
who's crazy around here. OIaf.
-You're in on this. I know that.
OFFICER: PIease. PIease.
-What can I do for you?
-OIaf, he's not your boss. I am.
-Officer, Iet me teII you. I know--
FARNSWORTH: Take him out.
Just a second. How can you be sure
which one of these is Cantor?
That's easy. Just teII a joke.
Joke? You want me to joke
at a time Iike this?
-Then you teII a joke.
-Me?
Go on, Mr. Cantor.
TeII one of your reaI funny ones.
-Yeah.
-Oh, here's one.
You know why the bartender
couIdn't serve me a cocktaiI?
-No, why?
-Because the Manhattan any more.
That's a riot, boss. Great. Great.
That's Mr. Cantor, officer.
Nobody eIse in the worId
couId teII a stinker Iike that.
[LAUGHS]
-OIaf, you're through.
-So are you. Come on, NapoIeon.
-You, I can kiII.
OFFICER: Hey, come here.
CANTOR:
That man has no right to do that.
You wouId hit a man with gIasses,
wouIdn't you?
PAT: You hurt?
CANTOR: I'II be in the show...
...if it's the Iast thing I do. You watch.
[ORCHESTRA PLAYING]
Eddie, I can't teII you
how sorry I am that--
That music. That's you.
Go on, you're on.
Yeah, wait a minute. What'II I do?
-What'II you do? Go on out there.
-Give them the best imitation of Cantor.
-That's right.
-Okay, here goes.
[SINGING] We're staying home tonight
My baby and me
Having a patriotic time
No ballroom floor the jitterbugs
All pile on
Those jitterbugs are murder
On your nylon
No brush and comb tonight
No people to see
Being alone is so sublime
We bought a big bologna
And though it's hard to take
We'll turn out all the lights
And make-believe it's a steak
We're staying home tonight
Baby and me
Having a patriotic time
How sweet you are
How dear your tenderly smiling face
-We're way up North
-And still together
-No trips back and forth
-We like the weather
And if you happen to be wondering still
Whatever became of vaudeville
It's way up North
The dreamer, the dreamer
I reckon that's my name
Why change it?
What for?
I wanna stay a dreamer
Till you're home once more
Till you're home
And wakin' me up once more
The dreamer, the dreamer
Ree-tye-oh
So-aw-de-free-dit
I'm a dreamer, aren't we all?
-A-doodily-eh-sue, zay-zo
Wah-wah
-A-doodily-eh-sue, zay-ugh!
Oh, yes, I know
Every gal in the city, I know
Every gal in the city?
I know every gal in the city
But, oh, they ain't this pretty
I'm riding for a fall
Dudin' up, dudin' up like I wasn't wise
To the gal with the big blue eyes
Love isn't born
That's a bit of old-fashioned corn
Let's call a spade a spade
When you find more than lemon
In your lemonade
You'll know that
Love isn't born, it's made
[MAN SINGING]
Oh, that voice is so divine
I'm sorry it isn't mine
Good night, good neighbor
Though I have no soft guitar to play
Come close to my heart and hear it say
Good neighbor, good night
Good night, good neighbor
You marched away and knew so well
Our love would stay alive
I'm stuck with either sweet 1 6
Or kids of 65
You must have known it
The day you enrolled
They're either too young or too old
Ice-cold Katie
Won't you marry the soldier?
You're the talk of the town
Ice-cold Katie
Won't you marry the soldier?
Melt, melt, melt on down
-Ice-cold Katie Brown
CHORUS: How's your love life?
Well, thank your lucky stars
Yes, thank your lucky stars
It's doin' fine
Keep your love life
As sweet as candy bars
And thank your lucky stars
Like I thank mine
So thank your lucky stars right now
Thank your lucky stars
Right now
[ENGLISH SDH]