Lady in Ermine,
lady in white
This is the moment,
tonight is the night!
THAT LADY IN ERMINE
This is the castle of Bergamo,
and the principality of Bergamo,
in south eastern Europe.
The year is 1861.
This is the castle's ancestral gallery.
Every night, old Luigi bids
goodnight to his dead masters
who, through the centuries,
ruled from this castle
in peace and war.
Mostly in war,
for small Bergamo
holds a strategically important
position on the road to Rome.
There in the background is Count Giovanni,
a famous poet in his time.
Next, Countess Isabella.
This is Count Dominic.
This is Orlando...
And this is Count Alberto,
the great-great-great-great grandfather
of the presently ruling
Countess Angelina.
His wife, Francesca,
called the Lady in Ermine,
saved the castle 300 years ago,
from a mighty conqueror
in a moment of danger.
But tonight Francesca is happy,
for her great-great-great-great granddaughter
Angelina, will be married tomorrow.
And this is Angelina,
ruling Countess of Bergamo,
great-great-great-great granddaughter,
of the Lady in Ermine.
It was a beautiful ceremony, wasn't it?
Yes, very.
And the devotion of the people,
it was touching.
They all seemed so happy.
They were taking to you, I could feel it.
Strange.
One can be prepared,
and yet when it happens...
Well, I've known all these years
than when a simple baron
marries into a family of
sovereign lineage it...
Darling, it was just a formality.
Yes, I know it, and yet when I had
to kneel before you
and you crossed the sword over my head,
and you raised me to the rank of
the Count of Bergamo,
it was a feeling of...
Well, I'm sure I will get over it.
I'll tell you how I felt
at the same moment,
Just as I was about to
make you a Bergamo...
Do you realise how heavy
that big ancestral sword is?
I was so frightened,
if that sword had fallen on your head,
you would have never found out
that you had become a Bergamo.
And I would have been a widow
before I became a wife.
But darling, the sword didn't fall.
And here we are.
One Bergamo and another Bergamo.
Darling, try to understand...
When you put the ring on my finger,
it suddenly dawned on me that
you were going to be the count, and frankly,
I don't think I'll be very happy as a countess.
But, darling...
Oh and when he asked me to
promise to obey, I...
... I could have killed that man.
Do you remember when we were children?
You were nine years old,
and our parents pledged us in marriage,
and after we had promised
to obey that pledge,
I stuck out my tongue at you,
and you pushed me into the flowerbed?
Well, I...
Darling, if you ever doubt that you are
the master, take me in the garden.
The flowerbed is still there.
Thank you, Angelina.
Oh Mario, I want this
to be a glorious marriage,
With quarrels and making up, with tears
and kisses. Always something happening!
I want to be a good wife,
not only because it's right, but because
I once read a book, or maybe I heard it,
that when you fall in love,
somewhere, or somehow, you hear the
sound of a flute, way off in the distance.
Well we can do much better.
I'll get a whole orchestra, by your window.
How does that sound, eh?
I ask for so little,
yet you offer me so much...
That's my nature.
What's that?
- I didn't order a salute.
And I gave strict orders against it.
With a firing line so close
It might cause a turmoil.
- What is it?
- The enemy, they've broken through our lines.
The Hungarian hussars
are on their way to the castle.
Oh my dear countess!
I carried you in my arms
when you were a baby.
Those soldiers are ours!
Our troops, retreating from Hungarians!
I gave everybody downstairs
instructions on how to behave.
I told them not to call those Hungarians
'Hungarian'! Why should one provoke people?
- Tell them to have the horses ready.
- Yes sir.
The thought that you would be at the
mercy of that Hungarian colonel...
That dreadful man strutting into this
castle and ordering you around.
No! No, no. No no no no.
No!
I'm not going.
I'll stay here and protect you.
They will take you prisoner.
I'll disguise myself.
I'll hide you, darling.
I'll do everything in my power.
Of course if they catch me
they will shoot me.
Shoot you!?
Ha! Let them shoot me, I'm not afraid,
I'm a good target.
Mario, do whatever you think is best
and forget about me.
You don't want me to stay do you?
I'd love you to stay. It would only
be too wonderful if you could.
Of course I realise that I have
to go, and immediately.
What a wedding night.
What an unfortunate wedding night.
But you'll come back.
And then it will be at the head of your
troops, taking the castle by storm.
Yes, you'll come back,
not only as a Bergamo,
but as the conqueror of Bergamo!
And I'll be in the entrance hall,
waiting for you.
Your prized captive.
The threat on the castle of Bergamo,
was also heard in the ancestor's gallery.
What a crisis.
What a crisis!
It calls for clever devices.
It calls for strategy.
- Calls for trickery!
- Calls for cruelty!
Yes, brutality.
- It calls for a woman!
- Francesca!
Francesca! Where is she?
Where is she? Where is she?
Somebody find her.
- Somebody get her.
- Maybe she's here.
- Maybe she's there.
- Stop! Look.
A letter!
- A letter?
- What does it say? What does it say!?
Right away, don't delay.
What does it say!?
"We'll be back in an hour.
Have gone to the tower."
We can't wait an hour!
The tower, the tower!
Let's go to the tower, the tower!
Francesca, Francesca, at last!
Save the castle, as you did in the past.
You heroes.
What do you see?
Nothing.
She sees nothing.
Simply nothing.
Wait, I see something.
Something!
And is he something.
He looks like he'd stop at nothing.
She sees something,
that would stop at nothing!
- He is a captain!
- A captain!
- No, a colonel!
- A colonel!
And he is so young
to rank so high.
He must be a great fighter.
But so... am I!
Oh what I'll do
to that wild Hungarian.
to that wild barbarian.
I'll handle, that vandal,
with weapons of my own.
I'll haunt him, I'll taunt him,
and when I get him where I want him...
Oh what I'll do
to that wild Hungarian.
to those eyes.
He'll get a little surprise!
I'll trip him, I'll trap him
I'll pinch him, I'll slap him!
I'll teach him
manoeuvres that are new!
So, let him come.
And I'll do what I'll do.
It's wonderful, it's glorious,
again she will be victorious!
- Bravo, Francesca.
- Bravo! Bravo!
Oh what she'll do
to that wild Hungarian.
to that wild barbarian.
I'll let him have a rhapsody,
and not the one by Liszt!
She will use her fist!
I'll keep him jumping with my thumping.
Oh what she'll do
to that wild Hungarian.
And what I'll do, to that man
Hooray!
No other enemy can.
I'll rip off his medals.
She'll bite off his buttons.
This battle will be his Waterloo.
- So, let him come.
- Let him come!
- Yes, let him come!
And do what she will do.
What she will do.
What I will do.
Attention!
May I report sir, all your
orders have been carried out.
That is the countess Francesca,
1537 to 1578.
I like her best of all the ancestors.
She even smiles at me.
Naturally I can't see it,
but one can feel when one is liked.
Horvath!
Yes sir.
I want you to make it clear to the men
that this is not a vacation from war.
- Yes sir!
- If I find the slightest...
... What is the matter with her!?
She has her coat on and her shoes off
This woman doesn't make sense.
- She certainly doesn't sir.
What woman does?
Do we want them to make sense?
Believe me, sir, there is a reason
for everything in that picture.
- Horvath!
- Yes sir.
If I find the slightest lack of discipline
I'll throw them out of their soft beds,
And they will sleep in the mud again.
- Yes sir.
- Horvath!
What are these women dressed up for?
To welcome you sir, that's the way
we do things in Bergamo.
- What is your name?
- Luigi sir.
Luigi?
Yes, I was born in this castle.
My father was born here too.
- And your grandfather too?
- Yes that's right.
- Watch him Horvath, keep your eye on him.
- Yes sir.
- Who is the master of this house?
- Angelina, countess of Bergamo.
Where is she? Why isn't she here?
I think the countess probably didn't expect you...
- Be quiet.
- Thank you, sir.
I don't want this countess to throw
roses at my feet, but I
Want her to know there is somebody
new in command of this castle.
Bring her down immediately.
- Yes sir.
Now see here you charming
ladies of Bergamo.
I think we should have a heart
to heart talk.
I saw you looking at my hussars,
and I know what you're thinking,
But if I catch any of you with my men I...
Attention!
Now listen, you stupid sons of
the wind swept Hungarian steppes!
You are so stupid, that if you don't
watch out, these women will
steal your horses right out from
under your saddles!
Don't give them any information.
Dismissed.
Dismissed!
- Good night.
Novak!
- Yes sir.
- Looks like we lost Horvath.
- I want them down here in one minute.
And I don't care if Horvath carries the
countess, or the countess carries Horvath.
Yes sir.
- And Novak...
- Yes sir?
- Don't forget to come back yourself.
- No, sir.
The composition isn't right.
But you play it beautifully sir.
No, no, no.
The composition of the painting.
The painting in the hall.
What was the painter thinking?
Why did he cover her shoulders
and reveal her feet?
It strikes me as very peculiar.
Where is she?
Well I spoke with her personal maid.
Where is she!?
Unfortunately, the countess had already
retired and did not wish to be disturbed.
I see that I'll have to handle this countess
myself, and I'm going to.
As for you, how dare you bring me
such a ridiculous message!
And not even from the countess herself!
You half-witted hussar!
You've been sitting on a horse so long that
even your brains have become bow-legged.
Yes sir.
I beg your pardon sir.
What do you want?
I'm sorry sir, but the countess has
asked me to explain to you
that there are strange echoes
in this castle
and by the time the echoes
have carried you to the second floor
your voice, which by itself
may not be offensive...
- She moved!
- Who moved?
The Lady in Ermine.
I saw it with my own eyes.
What is the matter with you?
Go back where you belong, go to bed.
Yes colonel.
Horvath!
Yes sir.
Everybody is crazy around here!
That's all.
Thank you sir.
Horvath!
Yes sir.
Good night.
Night sir.
What I'll do.
Let's look at the horses.
Good morning, gentlemen.
I see you're looking at my ancestor.
A very interesting woman.
Some people think we look alike.
Perhaps we do.
I'm so happy to meet you, colonel.
Oh I'm afraid there's a...
Well, may I introduce the colonel?
Oh, so you're the colonel.
How do you do?
- How do you do.
I'm sorry I was unable to greet you
last night, but your arrival was a bit late.
By the way, there is one person I
simply must meet: Horvath.
- Horvath.
- Yes!
May I present Major Horvath.
The countess of Bergamo.
So you're Horvath. Major Horvath.
How do you do?
You seem to be quite popular.
Apparently very much in demand.
Isn't he, colonel?
Uh, countess there are several matters
I'd like to discuss as soon as possible
Well Tuesday is always such a busy day.
This is Wednesday.
Wednesday is even worse.
I'm sorry, I have to see you.
Well perhaps that can be arranged.
Let me think. I'll see you right now.
I'll join you later.
If you please.
Now countess...
Please sit down, colonel.
Countess unfortunately this is war.
Please colonel, there is nothing to be
embarassed about.
I realise that you didn't come here
of your own volition [will]
You were just sent here by a higher authority
and there is nothing you can do about it
So please, no apologies colonel.
I want you to feel completely at ease.
I've already told my people to make
everything as comfortable as possible.
And if you have any complaints, don't hesitate.
Just talk to Luigi, and I'm quite sure...
Countess, may I make a suggestion?
Why don't you keep quiet.
Thank you.
Well...
It may take me a little while to get
accustomed to the way
one talks to a prisoner of war.
Prisoner of war?
No, no, it has nothing to do with that.
That's just the way I talk to a woman
who talks too much.
Have you ever been slapped in the face?
Many times. And I take it very well.
Once in Madagascar, I asked for more.
Sit down.
As I was trying to say, this is war. Grim war.
Men are shooting and other
men are shooting back.
- Yes sir.
- Technically you are an enemy.
I'll have to restrict your freedom of movement.
Thank you sir.
May I go now?
There are just a few more questions
I'd like to ask for security reasons.
You are the ruling countess.
- Yes sir.
- Born here?
By the way, are you married?
Is this also for security reasons?
Might be.
I am married, I love my husband,
I'm a good wife and always will be.
I hope that makes you feel secure.
- How long have you been married?
- Since last night.
- Last night!?
- Yes last night.
- Well well well! Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Where's the happy bridegroom?
I'd like to see him.
So would I. Very much.
This is not very easy to grasp, but
nevertheless I would like to grasp it.
When I stood in front of your door
last night, did he...
He had already gone back to his regiment.
Oh I'm so sorry.
Did I spoil your honeymoon?
- I'd rather not discuss it.
- Well I'm sure I didn't help it.
Countess, if only I had known
I would have postponed this attack
a few days, or at least a few hours.
I hardly think there could be any
more questions colonel.
By the way, what made your husband leave?
- Not a fear of you.
- Oh no, I'm sure not.
When he made his decision,
I'm sure he was guided by
a passionate love, for his country,
and nothing else.
You're quite right.
And yet countess, sometimes,
love and war
go beautifully together,
very beautifully.
I always thought it so romantic
that Napoleon wrote
his greatest love letters to Josephine
in the heat of battle.
"I love you, Josephine".
And the bullets flying around and around.
Yes, and when Marc Anthony learnt that
Caesar was approaching
did he free himself from the arms of Cleopatra?
He not only remained in the same palace,
he stayed in the same embrace.
Historically, you are speaking
complete nonsense.
- The fact remains that he ran away.
- He left.
Countess, people in love don't leave each
other just because a few shots are fired.
If two lovers are caught in the rain,
do they part just because of a few drops?
If one is in love, one doesn't need an umbrella.
No, countess. No umbrella.
Why you impudent, conceited,
impertinent creature!
Why do I tolerate all this?
I love your great-great grandmother.
I loved her from the moment I saw her.
What's that?
Just target practice.
No one was shot.
No spy, no husband.
Thank you.
Countess, I don't know anything about
your husband.
But when those shots were fired
and I saw that look on your face...
Is he really that wonderful?
Yes, he is.
I can see him in front of me: Very strong,
very brave, very brilliant...
and very lucky.
I congratulate you again.
Countess...
If I had lived in your grandmother's day,
you think she would have dined with me?
She might have. She was rather daring.
Yes, she is wonderful, magnificent, inspiring!
I never thought a painting could make
such a deep impression on me.
Yes, it's a very fine portrait.
Oh, it's much more.
You know countess,
sometimes I feel she smiles at me.
That she's taken a liking to me.
But I don't imagine that's hereditary, is it?
I wouldn't know.
They say I inherited her looks,
and that's all.
Congratulations anyway.
More coffee, sir?
A fresh glass of wine?
- No.
Don't go, Luigi.
You seem sad, sir.
And I think I know the reason.
I don't blame you. She's the loveliest
girl in the world.
Tell me about her Luigi.
Tell me everything.
Well sir, she was born more
than 300 years ago.
It was on the 22nd of June that she
made her gallant decision.
The castle was doomed, surrounded
by the troops of the duke of Ravena.
Just as you sir, are gentle and
kind at heart,
he was severe and terrifying.
A brute, sir, a tyrant.
His own men trembled
at the sound of his voice.
And he was even more dangerous in silence,
when he paced back and forth in his tent.
Benvenuto!
Yes, your grace.
I'm getting bored.
Yes.
How long have I been looking
at that castle of Bergamo.
Almost three weeks, your grace.
Spoiling my view.
I want it destroyed at dawn.
Yes, your grace.
I vowed to myself that everything would
be wiped out! Except that little dog.
I know, your grace. The one that comes
out of the gate every evening.
I love that little dog.
Yes, your grace.
Why are my men laughing!?
Did I say something amusing today?
No, your grace.
Then why do they laugh!?
I offer my sword to my conqueror.
What I ask, your grace, is to spare
Bergamo and its people.
If this doesn't move you, take me.
I offer myself for what I'm worth.
Let me be your slave.
Let me be your court jester.
Permit me to make you laugh.
I can be very funny.
- Benvenuto!
- Yes, your grace.
- Tell him to be funny.
Be funny.
Well I usually sing a song at the round table.
My knights think it's hilarious.
Oh, the donkey kicked the king, ha ha...
the donkey kicked the king
I was there, and I know where
the donkey kicked the king.
Did he kick him in the palace?
No, no, no.
Did he kick him in the garden?
No, no, no
He kicked him, he kick...
This is where my knights always
scream with laughter.
As a matter of fact, they laugh so much
that I never get any further...
Benvenuto!
Yes, your grace.
After we have destroyed the castle
I want my portrait painted,
with me standing on its ruins.
That's all.
Where did he kick him?
He kicked him in the courtyard.
Get out of here!
Mt poor Francesca...
Francesca!
Where are you going?
I only want to try where you failed.
It's no use. He will only sneer at your
noble efforts as he sneered at mine.
He's not our kind, Francesca.
I know it, Alberto, and yet where you
awaken the warrior in him
I might be able to get under his armour,
and touch his heart.
Alberto, I don't want you to die,
I really don't.
You must live by all means.
You devoted good woman.
I know I shouldn't let you go, I...
... Why the ermine coat?
To uphold the dignity of the Bergamo's.
I wish my father could have heard that.
You splendid woman. Splendid, splendid...
But...
But Francesca, your feet are bare.
To show my humility.
You came with a sword.
I come with my feet.
It's a deep thought.
It's deep, Francesca, very deep.
I shouldn't let you go.
I shouldn't.
Goodbye, Alberto.
Goodbye, Francesca.
Benvenuto!
He's going to kill her.
No, no, no, no.
No you don't know him,
and you don't know her.
If she talks to him the way she sometimes
talks to me, he's going to kill her.
Benvenuto...
Yes, your grace.
The seige is lifted.
The people of Bergamo are free.
Escort the countess back to the castle.
Yes...
She killed him...
with his own dagger.
Killed the man who had fallen in
love with her.
Some say she did it because he was
the enemy.
Some say she was afraid of herself,
for she too, was falling in love.
Still, others claimed that she killed him
because she couldn't bare the thought
of any other woman putting
her arms around him.
But that's a lie, sir. A malicious lie.
Don't you believe it
- I won't, Luigi.
Don't worry, it's a beautiful legend.
It's not a legend, sir, it's true.
Every word.
I'm sure it is, Luigi.
What great days those were.
Filled with excitement, love, death...
Luigi, the duke was a very lucky man.
At least he wasn't ignored.
Good night, Luigi.
Good night, sir.
Mario!
My bride.
How did you get here?
I couldn't stand it anymore.
I had to see you.
A gypsy caravan came along, and instantly
I realised that this was my chance.
So I went to the general, you know what he
thinks of me,
He gave me permission right away.
- I'm so glad the general did!
My bride!
Now, tell me everything, every detail,
everything about that colonel.
Mario, I wish he would leave.
How I hate that man!
What has he done?
Well, nothing in particular.
Nothing I can put my finger on.
But his mere presence is unendurable.
Well what did he do?
What did he say?
He is the most irritating, annoying person.
You know I simply couldn't fall asleep tonight.
I'll settle with him someday.
Please, Mario, talk to the general again.
Come back with your whole army,
and soon, Mario, soon!
Throw that man out of the castle, please.
I will Angelina.
I...
I just wanted to say goodnight.
Good night, coronel.
Good night, countess.
Mario.
Who was it?
Oh, the colonel.
The colonel? What did he want?
Just to say goodnight.
Why should he say goodnight?
I don't know.
In the middle of the night, suddeny a man
knocks at the door and says goodnight...
What exactly did he say?
"Good night".
I don't like it.
No, I don't like it at all!
Please darling, you didn't come here
to argue, did you?
- What made him come upstairs?
- He's probably going to bed.
He's going to bed!?
Well yes, everybody goes to bed
sooner or later.
Don't tell me he sleeps in my room!
Yes Mario, he does.
In my bed?
Yes.
In my...
How do you know?
I don't know. Maybe he doesn't,
maybe he is sleeping on the floor.
I'm gonna drag that Hungarian
out of my room!
I'll break every bone in his body!
I'm gonna kill him with my own two hands!
I beg your pardon countess,
we heard a man's voice in here.
You must be mistaken.
I'm sorry, countess.
Search the room.
Just a moment.
What is it, lieutenant?
We distinctly heard a man's voice
in here, sir.
- Is there someone here?
- No.
- Was someone here?
All three of us heard it, sir.
There are strange echoes in this castle,
and it's easy to be mistaken.
Anyway I don't think we should question
the countess' word, that's all.
I'm glad there was nobody here.
And I take it for granted that nobody will be.
Naturally.
- Good night, countess.
- Good night, colonel.
Mario.
It is the east, and Juliet is the Sun.
Arise, fair Sun, and kill the envious Moon
who is already sick and pale with grief
that thou, her maid, art far more fair than she.
Tis my lady, oh, tis my love!
I thought I'd forgotten what Shakespeare I knew.
I wonder what could have brought it back.
Italy? This night in june? The balcony?
Or perhaps you, countess.
I'm afraid I'm no Juliet.
One has to be very very young,
to be so foolish.
I might not be young enough to be foolish,
but I'm foolish enough.
And I'm certainly not too old to climb a balcony.
Not this one, colonel.
If you're in a climbing mood, may I recommend
that very steep mountain to the left?
It's been climbed before.
I mean your balcony.
And by someone who has no respect
for your beautiful roses.
Good night, countess.
Good night, colonel.
If you should hear, a magic flute,
and someday dear, you might...
Just remember this.
You must remember this.
The melody has to be right.
If someone cute, should play that flute,
the touch may be too light.
Just remember that.
You must remember that.
The melody has to be right.
So wait, for a great persuader...
who isn't only a serenader.
He'll play something gay and lilting [lively].
And you positively will start wilting [melting].
He might be tall, he might be small.
Forget about his height.
If you get a kiss, and want another kiss,
then the melody is right.
The tune should be entertaining
if there is a snowstorm, or if it's raining.
If you like the music faster,
you'll discover he's a music master.
He might be shy, and only sigh.
But when he holds you tight...
Only say "I do", if he convinces you...
that the melody is right.
Good night.
Gypsy, eh?
Got separated from your caravan.
Sounds very plausible.
So you're a gypsy.
- Yes, my colonel.
- Where were you born?
- In wagon.
Naturally, you don't know which country.
No, don't know.
Of course, gypsies are always travelling,
from there to here, from here to there.
"All world home of gypsy".
Yes, my colonel.
Now tell me, my wonderful gypsy,
are you married?
Yes, to wife.
Where is wife?
Wife in wagon.
In wagon with other gypsies?
Yes, everything in wagon.
- Quite a wagon.
- Yes.
Play it, gypsy.
Not have violin for long time.
Hand little stiff?
Hand very stiff.
But gypsies can always play,
stiff or not stiff.
Yes, my colonel.
I didn't ask you to sing, my friend.
No, no, my colonel.
Just play a few notes.
Wonderful.
Wonderful!
You really are a gypsy.
Did my colonel doubt?
Forgive me, my friend. I'm sorry.
Thank you, thank you, my colonel.
You know, I haven't seen a gypsy
since I left Budapest.
You make me so homesick.
What is life without a gypsy?
You must stay with me.
But, colonel, I must look for wagon.
You stay with me!
Yes, my colonel.
Thank you, thank you, my colonel.
Thank you.
From now on, you will be my personal gypsy.
When I'm sad, you will play
something gay [cheerful].
When I'm gay, you will play
something very, very sad.
And when I'm angry and I break
the violin over your head!...
Don't worry...
You'll get a new violin.
Thank you.
I heard the music. Someone told me
there was a gypsy.
Oh, please. Don't apologise.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
You looked so lovely in the moonlight
last night. I hated to leave.
Get out, gypsy.
Would colonel like me to play
other gypsy songs?
- Not now. Get out.
- Maybe colonel would...
like me to tell fortune.
- Out!
Please sit down, countess.
I want to tell you something.
Something that is so easy to say
if one doesn't mean it.
And by not saying it, you make it
unnecessary for me to protest. Thank you.
But, countess I...
You forget I'm the enemy.
And even worse, a married enemy.
Countess, I believe in marriage,
I believe in married men,
and just as much in married women.
But I also believe in fate, and I'm
sure that you and I...
That we, are two people destined by
mysterious fate
to have dinner together tonight.
Shall we say 9 o'clock?
I'm sure it's written on our hands.
Colonel, it's definetely out of the question.
Tonight or any other night.
Well let me call the gypsy and have him...
Yes, my colonel.
Your gypsy always near you.
You have good ears, gypsy.
Anyhow, come here, my friend.
If you see anything about this beautiful
lady in my hand, don't be afraid.
Speak up.
Gypsy won't be afraid.
Good.
Oh, colonel fine man.
Very kind heart.
I see colonel winning battle.
And another battle...
See many more battles
and colonel always winning.
Come on, read the civilian part
of my life.
Oh, yes.
Here private line.
Very private.
But oh, it's not good.
It's very bad.
- Bad, eh?
- Here is dangerous line.
Saying colonel should leave castle soon.
And here is very little line saying
much sooner.
I'm sorry, colonel.
That's alright, gypsy.
You're honest and I'm grateful.
Thank you, my colonel.
Now just one little look at the
ladies hand.
Please, I'd rather not.
Now countess, I really think you
can trust this gypsy.
Oh yes, yes.
I see man in ladies hand.
- Really?
- But not colonel.
Please go on.
I see husband. Very nice husband.
Wonderful husband.
Husband love lady,
lady love husband.
And here I see colonel winning
another big battle.
Congratulations colonel!
- Thank you, my gypsy.
- Thank you, my colonel.
- Guard!
- Yes, sir.
- Take good care of our friend here.
Give him a good meal, anything he wants.
And keep your eye on him:
I don't want to lose him.
Thank you, my colonel, thank you.
Well countess, our lifelines seem
to go in different directions.
I'm afraid they do.
And yet, we are going to have dinner together.
You know, this situation reminds me of 1561.
- I don't understand.
- Oh yes you do.
There was a moment when I was
completely fooled...
but when this gypsy became ecstatic
about your husband,
something in me rebelled.
Something in my pocket that I picked
up under your balcony last night...
Here, countess.
If he weren't your husband, what duets
we could've played together. It's too bad.
You've got to save him.
You're right. We simply must
save him, you and I.
It's true, neither of us love him, but
we can't have him shot can we?
Colonel, there must be a way.
Let him escape.
To let a disguised officer escape, I'd be shot.
You're going to lose one of us. Make up your mind.
Which one will you miss more?
Shall I die for you?
Now there's a tempting idea...
Your horrible.
Just horrible.
I'm a beast and you know it.
Listen, tonight my tent will be right here...
Take off your shoes.
Put on an ermine coat.
It's 1561 again.
Alright, wear your shoes.
But you must come.
Make history repeat itself.
There will be a buffet with every
delicacy you can think of.
And in the middle of the table,
a long sharp knife.
If you want to kill me before dinner,
or after dinner, it's entirely upto you.
If I come, my husband will be free?
If I should survive the dessert,
I'll take you to that window
and you and I will watch your husband
climb that very steep mountain to the left.
My word of honour.
What can I do? I'm defeated.
I have to help my husband.
I'm at your mercy.
Colonel, you've won another battle.
Congratulations.
What time is it, Luigi?
Just a little bit later, sir.
Not very much.
She won't come, Luigi.
If you knew where she is,
would you tell me?
No, sir.
Do you know where she is?
Any better?
Worse.
Go to bed, Luigi.
Thank you, sir.
Wouldn't you rather go upstairs, sir.
I can't.
I'm expecting someone who is just
a little late, that's all.
Good night.
Good night, sir.
Don't look so unhappy, colonel.
It's time you had a little dream.
It would make you feel so much better.
Yes colonel, dream. You will have you're
evening. I'll give it to you.
It'll be 9 o'clock all over again,
and I wil be Angelina.
I will wear her prettiest dress,
and her prettiest smile.
This is the moment,
this is the time.
Why don't we take it
and make it sublime.
On this grand night,
we could whisper in the shadows
until dawn,
As skies grow bright, I'll be sorry
that the shadows, are gone.
This is the moment.
Love has begun.
Maybe there is danger,
but that might be fun.
I used to say, if the right one
came my way,
I would know it, in a moment.
This is the moment.
You are the one.
I must tell you, countess, that I...
Angelina.
Angelina!
Do you realise it's four minutes after nine
and you haven't kissed me yet?
Angelina!
Kiss me!
Tell me, before you became a colonel,
were you by any chance a shepherd?
Shepherd? I don't remember.
I can't remember anything.
Angelina, there are so many things
I have to tell you.
But time is so precious,
why waste it on words?
Angelina...
Chatter, chatter, chatter,
nothing but chatter.
I want you to know that I'm going
to keep my promise.
Your husband will not be shot.
Nothing will happen to him.
Who cares? It doesn't matter.
He's just a boy I met when I was
nine years old.
I don't care whether he gets shot,
or you get shot,
or I get slightly wounded. What's
the difference? I want champagne.
Yes, countess.
And you better see to it that it bubbles.
Would you mind if I propose a toast?
Let's drink to what's going to happen next.
Kiss me!
I loved you from the moment I saw you
riding to the castle.
I was mad about you
even before I saw you.
When I walked into the hall,
and took one look at that painting.
The Lady in Ermine?
She was a fool.
She killed him and for 300 years
she wish she hadn't.
But Angelina won't make that mistake.
You're going to live.
Oh yes, indeed, you're going to be alive.
Horvath!
Yes, countess.
Isn't this wonderful.
That is all, Horvath.
Thank you, countess.
Oh what she'll do
to that young Hungarian.
to that poor barbarian.
She'll taze him.
Amaze him.
She'll drive him simply mad.
Salom was milder.
He may be wild, but he'll be wilder.
Dance with me.
But I don't dance. I can't.
With me you can do anything.
Dance!
I can't believe it! I'm dancing!
I'm dancing beautifully!
I'm the best dancer in the world!
Why shouldn't you be?
Angelina, something's happening to me!
This is nothing. Just the beginning.
But I want to shout and sing!
- Alright, then sing.
- Oh but I can't. I never could.
With me you can.
Sing!
I'm singing!
I'm singing magnificently!
With me, anything.
This is the moment,
this is the time.
Why don't we take it
and make it sublime!
On this grand night we could
whisper in the shadows
until dawn,
as skies grow bright, I'll be sorry
that the shadows, are gone...
This is the moment.
Love has begun.
Maybe there is danger,
but that might be fun.
At last you're here,
and your lips are very near.
And your eyes are full of kisses...
This is the moment.
You are the one.
I could conquer the whole earth!
I could be Alexander in the morning,
and Caesar in the afternoon!
I could pick up the whole world with
one hand.
I don't want it.
I'd rather have you.
Thank you.
Kiss me!
Thank you!
They went through the roof.
- Good night.
Well, good morning...
What's the matter?
- We don't know...
This is the moment.
Love has begun.
Maybe there's danger
but that can be fun...
I must have danced for miles.
Horvath.
Yes, sir.
Have you ever danced on a table?
No, sir.
You don't know what life is until
you have danced on a table.
Yes, sir.
Good morning.
Good morning, sir.
Horvath! Good morning.
Good morning sir.
- Good old Horvath, how are you?
- Very well, sir.
That little boy of yours, how is he?
Do you have a picture of him, Horvath?
Yes, sir.
Look at him, look at him!
Isn't he quaint.
How many teeth does he got?
Four, sir.
Four! Four, oh isn't that wonderful.
Yes, sir.
- Colonel.
- Good morning, darling.
I'll get rid of them in just a second.
Well gentlemen, I think we've covered
everything haven't we?
Except one matter, colonel.
Horvath, this is such a fine morning,
I can't imagine anything urgent...
Dismissed.
Good morning, countess.
Good morning, colonel.
I've tried to reach the general all night.
I wanted to beg for my husbands life
but I was detained by a patrol.
Save him, colonel. I beg of you.
Horvath, will you come in for
a minute please.
Yes sir.
- About this gypsy...
- That's the subject I was trying to bring up
I'm pretty certain he's an enemy officer.
Enemy officer? Horvath let's not see a
spy in every corner.
But sir, I have very strong evidence!
- We're getting very suspicious these days.
- But sir...
See that they give him a good breakfast
and let him go.
Those are my orders.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Thank you, countess.
Tell me countess, do you dream?
Occasionally.
Countess, you missed a great
dream last night.
Not just a dream that fades in the
sunlight and is forgotten.
No, this one will stay.
Whether it makes me happy or mad,
it will never leave me.
When you didn't come last night,
everything looked hopeless
but I didn't give up, and I was right.
I was rewarded.
The clock struck nine all over again.
Countess, you were so charming,
so gay...
You were magnificent.
Inspiring.
You were capricious and cruel,
and loveable,
like no other woman.
You were everything, and you still are.
Like no other woman.
And you don't know it.
I don't want to.
So please don't tell me.
Not even a word?
Not a syllable.
Horvath.
Yes sir.
We are leaving this castle immediately.
I don't want a minute wasted.
Very well sir.
I will always love you, Angelina.
Goodbye, countess.
Goodbye, colonel.
Cheer up darling, here I am.
Angelina, I'm back and alive!
No handkerchief?
Well we certainly got rid of him.
How I fooled him!
Giving me money, the stupid idiot.
Look he's gone now,
why talk about him?
Wouldn't it be better to forget?
Forget? Why? I want to know everything.
Everything that happened yesterday.
Mario.
Every bit of it. I insist.
I have a right.
Very well.
He found your earring under the balcony.
He knew who you were.
He...
Then...
Then why did he let me go?
Maybe he was gallant.
Maybe he was generous.
Maybe I should be grateful to him.
Maybe I should write him a
letter of thanks.
Maybe you should.
Did you have anything to do with my fortune?
In a way, yes.
- Exactly what did you do?
- Nothing.
- What did he do?
Let me recapitulate [recap].
I'm still alive, and yet you did
nothing, and he did nothing.
Angelina, why am I alive!?
You see, the colonel had a dream.
A dream?
What could he have dreamed about me?
No, Mario, it wasn't you he dreamed of.
Look at me.
Angelina, look at me!
I am looking at you.
Exactly what kind of a dream was this?
He dreamed that I was magnificent,
wonderful, inspiring...
Like no other woman.
Where did all this happen?
- In the living room.
- When?
I entered his dream at exactly
9 o'clock last night.
- When did you leave?
- I don't know.
It seems that time had stopped.
Let me recapitulate...
A Hungarian, has a dream,
in my living room...
What's the matter Teresa?
The Lady in Ermine.
She was smiling!
In the morning? Now Teresa...
She was almost laughing!
She seemed to be so happy.
Calm down. Calm down.
We're all happy. Especially this morning.
Did you realise, my child, that history
has repeated itself?
That the castle has been saved again,
just as in 1561?
Only this time, our mistress didn't
have to kill that very nice colonel.
I'm glad she didn't.
Now go back to work.
Yes, history has repeated itself.
Yes it has.
You see Mario, the truth can
sometimes be so simple
that one has to have imagination
to appreciate it.
When you were pleading for my life...
I never forgot, not even for a moment,
that I was married.
I was taught to believe in marriage.
And I still believe in it.
A Hungarian saving my life
in my own living room!
No! No! No!
Your move, sir.
I know it.
Give me time to think, that's not fair.
I'm sorry, sir.
- How is your family?
- Fine sir.
Your little boy.
What happened to it?
He got smaller.
He's tiny.
That's a different one.
A new one.
He's six months old, sir.
- You must be a happy man.
- I am sir.
- Whose move is it?
- Yours.
- You did that on purpose.
- I beg your pardon...
You know you're a better player than I
and you haven't won a game.
Does it bore you to play with me?
- No, sir.
You're always trying to please me.
You're only telling me what I want to hear.
Would you like me to go, sir?
I'm sorry, Horvath.
I'm afraid I'm getting a little irritable.
I know, sir.
You know what?
Well you're not quite yourself, sir.
That's nonsense!
Never felt better in my life.
I don't want to hear such
ridiculous talk again.
Horvath, what's wrong with me?
Well sir...
You used to say: "Another war, another love".
Now we're in another war, and you still...
Well, that's the trouble, sir...
I'm amazed.
How did you know that?
It's not very difficult, sir.
Has anyone else noticed?
Tell me the truth.
Everybody, down to the last soldier.
You used to scold them. You used to
call them every name under the sun.
But underneath there was a great love
for them, and the men knew it.
Remember how you used to shout
at me: "Horvath!".
And how I would jump.
I miss that, sir.
There are men who were born to shout,
and others who were born to jump.
I happen to be a jumper.
She was so lovely...
Horvath, she was so lovely...
Have you ever seen a more
lovely woman in your life?
Frankly sir, I think there is nobody
quite like my wife.
Yes, she is wonderful...
But after your wife, second to your wife...
Well, sir...
this might strike you like a bolt of lightning,
but if I hadn't been married to my Bertha...
you would've found in me a deadly rival.
And instead of playing checkers here tonight,
we probably would've been out in
the snow, dueling.
Yes, Horvath,
she is worth risking ones life.
Angelina...
Shall we play another game?
I'll try my very best to win.
Thank you, Horvath.
Not tonight.
And tomorrow I promise you
that everything will be different.
I'll tear into the men.
And you will jump as you've
never jumped before.
Good night, Horvath.
- Good night, sir.
Horvath!
Yes sir!
She was lovely, wasn't she?
Yes she was, sir.
Good night sir.
He didn't believe in dreams.
Who?
I'm a bad woman. The worst in
the world. That's what he said.
Who!?
Remember: There was a gypsy
who turned out to be my husband.
Well he isn't my husband anymore.
He walked out of my castle and my life.
It's all over with.
Angelina!
Will you marry me?
I can't believe it yet. You're here...
You came out of nowhere, in the
middle of the night. Alone.
Yes, all alone. Just myself, my maid,
Luigi, and a priest.
- A priest?
- Yes, a priest.
Father! Father! Father!
This man wants to marry me.
Angelina!
Just a moment.
Colonel darling, what is your name?
Yes colonel, what is your name?
Ladislaus Karoly Teglash.
How beautiful!
Oh what she'll do,
to that wild Hungarian.
to that wild barbarian.
Oh, what she'll do!