41 st Street.
Here, son.
- Castle?
- That's right.
$9.50.
- Cash.
- Oh, cash.
Wait a minute.
Mr. Fields, can I trouble you for $ 10
advance on my next week's salary.
You'll never have a next week's salary.
You already spent it last week.
Mr. Fields, if my next week's salary can
make a beautiful lady happy this week...
...it's my duty to spend it. Thanks.
- Here you are. Keep the change.
- Oh, thanks.
Say, Vernon, if those flowers
are for Miss Ford, you're aiming too high.
- We're having supper after the show.
- But you haven't got the right ammunition.
- The what?
- Spondoodles, mazuma.
Something that you second comics
never have.
But someday I'll be the first comic,
after you.
- Thanks.
- I'm sure you're wrong about Miss Ford.
A lot of fellas have been wrong
about Miss Ford. And you're next.
Look out.
She trifles with men's hearts.
Let her trifle with mine.
I'm not doing anything important with it.
- Addie.
- Yes, Miss Ford.
Be ready to dress me immediately
after the finale.
I'm having supper at Rector's
with Mr. Vanderpool.
Miss Ford.
- You're on next Mr. Castle.
- All right, John.
- Will you wear this tonight?
- Tonight?
- Remember our supper date.
- Oh, of course, I remember.
But my head is splitting and I should be in
bed this minute. You'll forgive me, darling.
- How about tomorrow?
- Tomorrow?
Sunday. Well, I'm going to the beach
at New Rochelle with my mother.
- Suppose I meet you at the club house?
- Oh, dear, well...
...if it's all right with Mother.
I'm so sorry about tonight.
Well, what did I tell you?
Mr. Fields, could you bag me
for a round trip ticket to New Rochelle.
By the sea, by the sea
By the beautiful sea
You and I, you and I
Oh, how happy we'll be
When each wave comes a-rolling in
We will duck or swim
And we'll float
And fool around the water
Over and under
And then up for air
Pa is rich, Ma is rich
So now why do we care?
I love to be beside your side
Beside the sea
Beside the seaside
By the beautiful sea
Hello, pup. Who are you?
Well.
Mr. Castle. Mr. Castle.
Yes. Over here.
- You waiting for Miss Ford?
- Miss Claire Ford, yes.
She just phoned. Said,
tell Mr. Castle her head was still splitting.
Oh, I see.
It's too bad.
Lots of other ladies
sitting around here, Mr. Castle.
I dare say. Thanks.
- Have you seen a dog around here?
- Yes. Where is he?
Who is that fella?
Come on, there.
Get up you.
Oh, you poor little thing.
- Walter.
- I'm coming, Sailor.
- Isn't he your dog?
- Isn't he yours?
I never saw him until a moment ago.
Well, it must belong to somebody.
Walter, take the dog into the boat.
Well, I don't like the look of this,
Miss Irene.
- Take the dog.
- Drowning that dog to get acquainted.
Some of these whippersnappers
go pretty far.
- I beg your pardon.
- Don't mind Walter.
- You all right?
- Yes.
Climb in.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
Goodbye.
Walter, let the gentleman into the boat.
That's exactly
what you want to do, ain't it?
No, no.
I'm quite comfortable, thank you.
Oh, please get in.
Thank you very much.
You are wonderful to jump in
to rescue a little stray dog.
- I'm very keen on dogs.
- Me too.
I keep a sort of boarding house
for wandering dogs in my dressing room.
- Dressing room?
- Yes, in the theatre.
In the theatre?
- Are you an actor?
- Well, yes.
- You're not the only actor in this boat.
- Do you act?
Me? No, I just work for the family.
- You?
- Hi.
She's a genius.
Walter practically raised me
and he's sort of prejudice.
What show are you with?
She played the fairy queen in Miss Dodd's
Seminary's Annual Entertainment.
- Oh, amateur shows.
- Dances like a sun beam.
What's your name?
- My name's Castle.
- My name's Foote.
My name will be mud when I try
to explain this to your mother.
- Why don't you start the motor?
- Because it's broke, that's why.
- Looks all right.
- Looks broke.
Irene was just 3, then.
Don't you love the flowers?
- And this is when she was 7.
- Very fetching.
The next one is Pinafore. Being English
yourself, Mr. Castle, I know you'll like it.
She was in a school production when
she was 10. Do you remember, Hubert?
- Oh, yes.
- Well, here's our dog.
- Our dog?
- I asked all around the neighborhood...
...and nobody claims him,
so Sailor wants to keep it.
- Well, he's very sweet.
- Here boy. Here boy.
- What train you figure on making?
- The 5:30.
I figure the 4:30.
Oh, look.
How nice.
Irene's going to do
a rendition for you.
- For me?
- Yes.
She's never had a chance to do
it for a professional audience before.
I think I'll go out
and work in the garden a bit.
Hubert, you stay right here.
I think my clothes must be dry by now.
You sit here, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen,
an imitation of Miss Bessie McCoy...
...doing her famous number,
"The Yama Yama Man." Thank you.
Mr. Castle, she may be
a little nervous.
I'm a little nervous myself.
Every little tot at night
Is afraid of the dark, you know
Some big Yama Man they sing
As off to bed they go
Yama Yama Yama Man
Terrible eyes and a face of tan
If you don't watch out
He will sting you
Without a doubt, if he can
Maybe he's hiding behind the chair
Ready to spring out at you unaware
So run to your mama for here comes
The Yama Yama Yama Man
Bravo.
- You did very nicely, dear.
- Thank you.
- Well, sir?
- That was fine.
Yes, sir that certainly was fine.
Thanks very much.
Do you really mean it
or you're just saying it?
No, really, I mean, you gave it quite
a professional touch... here and there.
Here and there?
I mean everywhere.
It was very nice.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
you see my train...
Oh, I see.
I'm sorry, I wish I can stay
and see it again.
- But I'm afraid...
- You afraid to see it again?
- Not at all.
- You don't wanna see it again?
- What the young man means is that...
- Hubert...
...let Mr. Castle decide.
- I would like to, but I must go.
- You'd like to see it again?
- Walter, he didn't say that.
- The man said...
- No, he didn't.
- I'd like to see it again, except my train...
- No trouble at all.
Now Walter,
not unless Mr. Castle wants to.
- I knew he didn't.
- I do.
Well, all right.
There's a possibility
you may catch the 8:15.
I understand every one of your criticisms,
except for one you sort of mumble.
Oh, that one.
- What does "ham" mean?
- That's just an expression.
Well, what does it mean?
In the theater we speak
of certain actors as hams.
Well, that makes me feel
so professional.
- Am I a real ham?
- Well, yes you're a little ham.
Oh, wonderful.
And after the way we ran.
Come Josephine
In my flying machine
Going up all on
Goodbye
Come Josephine
In my flying machine
Going up she goes
Up she goes
Balance yourself like
A bird on a beam
In the air she goes
There she goes
Up, up a little bit higher
Oh, my moon is on fire
Come Josephine
In my flying machine
Going up
All on
Goodbye
- Come on.
Go it, Vernon.
You didn't tell me
you can dance like that.
- You're marvelous.
- Thanks.
- Goodbye.
All aboard. Go ahead, kiss her.
Next Sunday is a long way off.
Next Sunday? Oh, yeah.
All aboard.
Hurry up, bashful.
Oh, you beautiful doll
You great big beautiful doll
Let me put my arms about you
I could never live without you
Oh, you beautiful doll
You great big beautiful doll
If you ever leave me
How my heart would ache
I want to hug you
But I fear you'd break
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Oh, you beautiful doll
- Oh, Irene, I can hardly wait.
- Does he dance soon?
Oh, here he is.
You see he's in the next scene
and he plays with the star.
The Barber Lew Fields
The Customer Vernon Castle.
- My aunt once knew an opera singer.
- Did she?
- Wait till you see Vernon dance.
- Isn't it wicked?
I mean knowing an actor.
- He's coming down the stairs now.
- Are you sure?
Leave him to me.
I'll show him
for insulting my daughter.
- Say something.
- L...
That's real ham comedy.
- What did you say?
- Ham.
- Where?
- You're looking at two of the best...
...right down there.
- Done it again, Vernon.
- Yeah.
- You were great today, Vernon.
- Oh, thanks.
Thanks very much.
Oh, hello.
Have you been out front?
How did you like it?
You were terrible.
Oh, so Ms. Irene Foote... actress
of New Rochelle... thinks I'm terrible.
Thanks for taking the trouble
to come back and tell me so.
You could be a perfectly wonderful
dancer if you wanted to.
Instead you waste your talent
letting people set fire to you.
It takes talent to make people laugh.
And I like being set fire to.
- Well, I won't have you doing it.
- Oh, you won't.
Say, what makes you
so excited about me?
You have something no comedian
will ever have and you're wasting it.
What other reason could there be?
Oh, I don't know. Girls, especially young
girls, sometimes gets crushes on actors...
- Oh, I didn't...
- You called me a ham.
Well, you're a ham with mustard.
Oh, I know what it means.
And if you think I had interest
in coming back here, you're mistaken.
- Wait.
- Don't think I'll annoy you...
...with my intentions, Mr. Castle. Just go
on, be funny with soap on your face...
...and get to be a first comedian.
I thought you could be a first dancer.
A very beautiful first dancer.
Because you are a beautiful dancer,
but you're so smug and conceited...
...that you can't see any further
than your funny nose.
There!
Was you expecting someone, Sailor?
Can't a person sit in their own front yard
on a Sunday without expecting somebody.
I knew he's a fly-by-night.
I knew it the minute I seen him.
- Who?
- The fellow you're not expecting.
Hello there.
Is Ms. Foote at home?
She's not?
Did she go out?
Come on, Zowie.
Come on, Zowie. Come on.
That's it.
- My, it's getting warm, isn't it, Walter?
- Hello.
Oh, hello, Mr. Castle.
I just happened to be out this way,
so I stopped by to see if the dog is all right.
Oh, Zowie?
Oh, he's just fine, thank you.
Thought he might be sick,
that's why I came out.
- No, he's just fine.
- That's good.
See, I thought he might be sick
and just thought I'd...
Come out.
My, what a beautiful automobile.
- Is it yours?
- Just a little runabout.
- There's nothing like a good spin.
- Makes you dizzy.
No, it doesn't, Walter.
It's just I'm not one way
or another about it.
Well, I guess I'd better be
running along.
Bye.
Well, I'm glad the dog is all right.
Go on.
Oh, dear.
Here, Zowie. Here, Zowie.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Oh, Zowie, you bad little dog.
Sailor, you get down out
of that contraption. It ain't safe.
Smile...
...walk...
...cross in front. To the audience.
- To each other.
- Cross in front.
- To the audience.
- To each other.
- Cross in front...
- That's enough.
We get two bows
we'll be doing very well.
If we keep on like that, it won't be long
before we can ask Mr. Fields for a trial.
Cuba pressed by Spain appeals
to Uncle Sam for aid.
Niagara Falls.
That's quite a place for...
I mean, that's quite a place
for people to go.
Oh, you mean on honeymoons?
Yeah.
Devil's Island. That's interesting too.
- Irene.
- Yes?
We've only known each other
about three months.
Irene.
Irene, have you seen my copy of Vogue?
Oh, here it is, Mother.
- Anything yet?
- Not yet.
Well, I don't wanna interrupt anything.
You were saying that we've known
each other for nearly three months.
Yes, you see my one aim in life...
...has always been
to keep from getting involved.
"Vernon don't get involved,"
I've always said.
I mean I used to say.
Well, what do you say now?
Well, you know, I think
when people dance well together...
...it's because they're sympathetic
to each other.
In fact, that's part
of what I was getting at.
Dancing brings people
closer together.
I don't mean only closer together...
Oh, good evening, darling.
- Good evening, Vernon.
- Good evening, sir.
- Hello, Dad.
- Anything happened while I was out?
- Everybody finished with the paper?
- Oh, I'll get it for you, Dad.
Oh, thank you.
Some new records I brought.
Somebody flying an airship
across the English Channel.
Must have been in a hurry.
Dr. Foote, Mrs. Foote wants
to see you right away.
Excuse me.
- Can't you leave them alone?
- I've been leaving them alone all winter.
Aren't we ever going to use
that parlor again?
Do you like this tune?
Only when you're in my arms
I can reach up to heaven
And pluck out a star from the blue
It's true
But only when you're in my arms
I can live without riches
And still have a million or two
It's true
But only when you're in my arms
Though I'm ambitious
My wishes
Have always been simple and few
Give me the moonlight
The music
And darling an armful of you
I can see myself doing
The things that I never could do
It's true
But only when you're in my arms
Irene, look, I'm terribly in love with you.
I never thought I'd fall in love
but I have, and I'm glad I have.
And will you please marry me?
Yes.
- I'm in love with you too.
- You...
Well...
...thanks.
Walter.
- Walter, we're going to be married.
- Are you surprised?
Gee, whiz.
Well, where do we go on the honeymoon?
Dr. Foote, you can start using
the parlor again.
Vernon, I'm scared.
Now, now, sweetheart,
that's no way to talk.
I don't feel so rosy myself.
Maybe we're not quite ready yet.
Maybe we should rehearse some more.
And come back next week, huh?
- Yes, that's it.
- Come on Walter.
What are you doing, running away?
We thought we'd go home,
rehearse more and come back next week.
Next week? Now look,
you've been practicing for months...
...and you know everything fine. Why, you
did it for me last night. It was beautiful.
Come right back here and sit down.
When Mr. Fields tells you...
...keep your chin up, your chest out
and put your best foot forward.
Hello, Vernon.
Hello, Mrs. Castle.
How are the newlyweds?
Well, Vernon, what do you wanna
show me, a bride-and-groom skit?
Mr. Fields, it's a...
...it's a sort of a dance.
- It is a dance.
Since when have you had
dancing ambitions?
- Since he met me.
- Oh. Well, all right, let's look at it.
- Thanks.
- Charlie, put on the front border.
You sit here.
- I hope I don't disappoint you.
- Come on. You know...
...chin up, chest out
and best foot forward.
All right, Walter.
Very nice.
No?
Why not?
Well, now, who's gonna pay money
to see a man dance with his wife?
Look, I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll give Mrs. Castle a line in the show,
and as for you, Vernon...
...next season I'll hand you
a whole new scene.
- That will be...
- Mr. Fields, what kind of a scene?
Well, I'll tell you.
The idea is that I'm a bricklayer.
- Oh, and I'm your helper.
- Yes.
- You come on with a hat full of bricks.
- And you trip me up.
No, I shove you right in the cement.
- And I'm covered with it.
- You clumsy geek, pick up those bricks.
Oh, I see.
See, he is the one, Papa.
The droll one.
Oh, so droll in the barbershop.
Right back into the cement.
What's the matter?
- I'm sorry, sir, I can't do it.
- What?
Why not?
We're going to dance together.
- Say, whose idea is this?
- Ours.
Well, you know Vernon, as a comedian
you're valuable to me.
But as a dancer... Even two dancers.
- You wouldn't bring in two nickels.
We're sorry, Mr. Fields,
but we think you're wrong.
Maybe I'm wrong,
maybe you're wrong.
Now, don't take it too badly, Mrs. Castle.
We all make mistakes.
See you later, Vernon.
Greenhorn.
Do you think it's true,
what he said?
We can try some other managers.
We want to dance and we're going to.
I wish I knew where.
- Mr. Castle.
- Yes.
- I'm Mr. Aubel and this is Emile, my son.
- Oh, how do you do?
My father and I purchased from Mr. Fields
the French rights to The Hen Pecks.
And we reproduce the play
in the Paris next spring.
And we want you for our show.
You want...
Oh, Vernon, darling.
A honeymoon in Paris
and we get paid for it.
- You come?
- Sure, we'll come.
Oh, Walter, I don't know about you.
Walter, goes with us
if it takes our last cent.
Sure.
You think I'll let you two go alone?
Gee, whiz.
Wait a minute, there's the theater.
- There's the theater.
- Hold it.
Turn around. Tell him to turn around.
Back there.
No, no.
Have him wait, Walter.
- No, that's too expensive.
- Whatever, our salary starts any minute.
Hello, Mr. Aubel.
How do you do?
Here we are.
I believe you telephoned our secretary.
Oui, Oui...
I am very sorry...
...but it is so.
- What?
But you told him we were late.
Emile?
No, no. We are late.
Nous, not vous.
- The play is late.
- Au revoir...
...we see you in six weeks.
Vernon, what are we going to do
in the meantime? We haven't any money.
- Wait a minute. Monsieur...
- No, no, let me.
I'm used to this. It's very simple.
Mr. Aubel, could we trouble you
for the usual advance on our salary?
You don't understand. I mean,
we're a little short of cash.
Mr. Aubel.
Please.
For you, madam.
Emile.
You will please sign... A formality.
Wait, this is for eight days'
salary instead of seven.
Interest, you know?
- Like a bank.
- Oh, yes.
- What, is this customary?
- I guess so.
Our country seems so strange to you.
You must not bother about business.
- You are young, and it is Paris, it is spring...
- Papa.
Au revoir, madame.
Zowie, you bad dog. We're so sorry.
I wait.
From now on, we walk.
- Pay him, Walter.
- Take Zowie to that fancy hotel and pack.
We're going to look for a flat.
Bye.
What?
To you.
Well, we got our health, we're young...
...we're in Paris,
we're on our honeymoon...
...what more do we want?
- Nothing.
Oh, look.
- Isn't that a darling Dutch cap?
- Well, we can afford that.
Oh, no.
No, we can't.
- But you want it.
- I told you, I don't want anything but you.
- Mr. Castle.
- Come on, let's hurry.
- Hurry up, hurry up.
- Come on, Zow, come on.
Hurry up, Zowie.
Come on, Zowie.
- Oh, did you hurt yourself?
- Zowie.
Hurry up, hurry up.
- I hope I got the key.
- Get in here, Zowie. Hurry up.
That's it, hurry up.
Mr. Castle.
Where is my money?
For eight weeks you have not paid.
- Where is my money?
- Quiet, if you please.
Quiet, quiet, quiet.
Must we be subjected
to all this brawling?
Pardon, madame.
Let me explain.
But those young people...
I am hoarse from screaming for my rent.
You will have to scream for his rent,
too, if you don't mind your manners.
I've brought him a client...
...who can't stand noise.
- Maggie.
Quiet.
Such a quaint place, isn't it?
Veritable bit of Bohemia.
Really, Maggie,
these obscure geniuses of yours.
- I don't know if they're worth it or not.
- I'm sure this one is.
Of course you're sure.
You get 10 percent of what I pay him.
My nerves are on edge.
- Can't you work faster?
- Faster? Faster...
Maggie, I can't stand it.
Lady Bolton, please, please.
You take your time.
Look.
- Madam, the pose.
- You expect me to pose...
...when we all may be killed
at any instant?
I don't care if he is a genius.
Either this bedlam ceases, or I leave.
Stop it.
Stop it up there.
All right.
We heard you.
Well, at least we can eat.
I'm gonna move out of this place.
- Eat what?
- Oh, what have we here?
Would you carve?
- I'm not hungry.
- Oh, Vernon.
Why don't we get a call from the Aubels?
Why don't they start?
- Maybe we're not in the show.
- You know we are.
Oh, Vernon, you're the optimist. You're
the one that always sees the bright side.
Bright side?
Look.
- Darling, that's all that's left.
- Walter.
Quiet. Quiet.
They've started rehearsals
for the show.
- Started rehearsals?
- That's what it says.
- Repetition commences.
- Why didn't Mr. Aubel let us know?
What's the difference? The show starts,
our salary starts. Come on.
- Walter, where are my dancing shoes?
- In the trunk.
- Oh, no, they're on your feet.
- Oh. Come on, let's go.
Oh, wait a minute.
I can't go until I press my suit.
- You and Walter go, I'll meet you there.
- All right. Hurry.
Hello, Mr. Aubel.
Ah, Monsieur Castle.
Why didn't you tell us rehearsals started?
Did you think we didn't need any?
- But you knew what you have to do.
- Come.
There she is.
- Oh, but you hired us to dance.
- Dance?
No, no, no.
We have the dance.
- Oh, you will be a knockout, Mr. Castle.
- All Paris will laugh.
You are a very funny man.
The whole French nation
You will hear them saying
A real sensation and the people
Will stay till the break of the day
While we are dancing
Well...
...what happened?
False alarm.
Hello, Zowie.
I got myself all pressed up.
You look nice too.
Don't she, Vernon?
Yeah.
What happened?
Well...
Here's a present for you.
Oh, my little Dutch cap.
We didn't have money to buy this.
We haven't now.
Darling, they didn't hire us to dance.
They just want me for
the barbershop scene I did with Fields.
I won't do it, Irene.
I told them I wouldn't.
But then they brought up
the money we owe them.
Vernon, would they let you dance alone...
...because if they would...
Do you think I'd wanna dance
without you?
I should have let you
keep on doing what you were doing.
It's all my fault.
No, it isn't.
Look, darling, we're all right now.
After all, you have got a job.
May not be the job we wanted,
but still it's a job.
Maybe later on...
...we get a chance...
...sometime.
Maybe sometime.
Hey.
Dance with me.
All the people downstairs...
Look.
We can do it quietly, like this:
Just as if we're walking on air.
Funny, and we're down to earth
for the first time.
- What do you suppose they're doing?
- And you call me nervous.
I'm not nervous, I'm simply curious.
That's nice.
Take a good look, Walter.
This is our farewell appearance.
Get me a chair.
I said get me a chair.
What do you call that...?
That... what you were doing.
Oh. Well, l... I don't know, I guess
you might call it the Castle Walk.
- Castle Walk?
- Castle, that's our name.
I'm Vernon Castle, and this is my wife.
My name's Walter.
I'm Maggie Sutton.
Oh. Maggie Sutton,
of course.
How would you like to try out
for a dancing job?
- What?
- Where?
At the Cafe de Paris.
Cafe de Paris? Irene.
- You know the manager?
- My dear, the manager knows me.
- Darling, we got a job.
- Ah, just a tryout.
All I could guarantee
would be your dinner.
Well, maybe you could arrange
that for tonight... The dinner, I mean.
- And we could dance tomorrow night.
- Well, I think it might be arranged that way.
- Dinner at the Cafe de Paris.
- Dinner anyplace.
Dinner.
- Does this person dance too?
- No, but I eat.
Walter is our sort of manager.
He was your manager.
You mean you're an agent.
I'm an entrepreneuse...
...but I still expect my 10 percent.
That's some old crank downstairs.
Don't pay no attention.
I beg your pardon?
Everyone is staring at you.
Oh, dear, I hope not.
Because you look so beautiful.
Just like a bride.
I should in my wedding dress,
my Dutch cap.
I hope it brings us luck.
I am honored by your presence,
Your Highness.
My dear Louis, thank
Miss Sutton. She is my guide to Paris.
And none better, Your Highness.
They look very respectable for dancers.
Dancers? Who dances?
You must come back tomorrow night,
Louis has a treat for you. Two Americans.
But tomorrow I'm leaving
for St. Petersburg.
- Why do they not dance tonight?
- Well, I doubt if they're prepared.
How does one prepare for a dance?
One simply dances.
Have them dance.
I think it's going to be quite amusing.
American dancers.
- A little more caviar, please.
- Foie gras too.
And plenty of the truffles.
Such a rush all day,
I didn't even have time for tea.
I lunched at the club.
Food is very dull there.
- Can you dance now?
- Now, tonight?
I have a Grand Duke over there.
If he likes you, you're made.
- The orchestra.
- We haven't rehearsed with them.
Oh, they can play anything you want.
- But our dinner.
- No, no, no, dance first.
But if he doesn't like us,
do we still get dinner?
If you feel like it.
Well, Vernon, we've nothing to lose.
Tell them to play,
"Too Much Mustard."
- Oh, Vernon, I've forgotten everything.
- No. Come on, dance with me.
I raised them.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. And Mrs. Castle...
...will dance again in one half-hour.
You know,
it's funny I'm not a bit hungry now.
- Neither am I.
- You can't waste it.
Oh, magnifique.
From now on you dance here every night,
I pay you.
A tip from the Grand Duke.
A tip?
We can't possibly accept it.
- We're very grateful but...
- No, this is no time to be proud. We need it.
Irene, look what they're doing.
I think you've started something tonight,
Mr. And Mrs. Vernon Castle.
Isn't there anything in this country
except the Castles?
This is getting to be the most...
Chicago, Chicago, that toddling town
Hello, Frisco, Hello
Way down yonder in New Orleans
Take me back to New York Town
When are you going
to break the news to Maggie?
The moment she mentions another tour.
- You're going to have trouble with her.
- Is it Maggie's life, or ours?
- It's ours.
- It's time she found that out.
Very nice.
Well, children, I have some vulgar
financial matters to take up with you.
Here are some ideas
for your next tour.
There isn't going to be
a tour for a while.
Oh, of course, I know you're tired.
So I've arranged to have
a week's rest before you start out.
- What's this?
- Going out on the platform. She needs air.
Another mouth to feed.
That makes seven.
- Where and when did you buy that?
- In Baltimore.
Here's the bill.
Hello, Maggie.
Maggie? Very touching.
We'll be in New York in an hour.
It would help if you would sign this now.
Maggie, we want to buy
a house in the country.
- All right, buy it.
- Yes, but we want to live in it.
All right, live in it.
She don't want air, she wants water.
Come on, Mag.
Listen, you two,
you better make hay while the sun shines.
Maggie, we're in love.
We've made enough money.
- We want to live like simple, married people.
- In a house with our clothes in closets.
We're not going to sign any contracts.
We've got it planned.
We'll visit England.
And Vernon's going to show me where
he was born and where he went to school...
Well, everything he knew before he met me.
I didn't know anything before I met you.
Seems to be a strong smell
of honey-suckling roses in this car.
And you can't raise horses and dogs...
...and children on a dancing tour,
you know that, Maggie.
Well, if I were your age
and had your opportunities...
Don't try to talk us out of it. We're firm.
- Don't interrupt me. As I was about to say...
- It won't make a difference.
I was about to say...
...l'd want to do exactly
what you're going to do.
Where are we?
Extra! Extra!
Here, boy. Boy.
Germany declares war,
England mobilizes.
"Thousands volunteer for British army."
I guess it won't amount to anything.
It says here that Europe can't afford a war.
It would probably be over in a week.
- Will you spend the night here?
- I should say not.
I find the country quiet
very disturbing.
How would you like to be back in Paris?
I see by the papers they bombed it again.
Here comes Sailor.
- Hello, Maggie.
- Hello there.
- Have you told Vernon who was here yet?
- No, but I will.
How are you, Maggie, old girl.
Irene, you ready
to come back to the outside world?
As far as we're concerned,
there's nothing going on in the world.
There's a war going on.
- Don't talk that way in front of Vernon.
- Then it's on his mind?
No, not at all.
Women are pathetic when they try
to fight something bigger than they are.
I'm not trying to fight anything.
Vernon's my life.
I'm his life.
Isn't that enough?
One girl against an army?
It isn't quite enough, Irene.
Come on, let's find Vernon.
- Vernon, Maggie's here.
- Oh, hello, Maggie.
- Vernon.
- What's the matter?
Oh, Vernon.
Oh, the uniform.
It's for the British benefit, Sunday night.
They've asked me to dance.
I told you.
Well, if this is your idea of a joke...
No. Oh, I'm sorry, darling.
I haven't enlisted. Some crazy fellow
in the Publicity department sent this down.
I'm... I'm not going to wear it,
I just tried it on.
So you went and done it, huh?
- No, Walter...
- You told me if you enlisted, I could join up.
It isn't real. It's just a uniform for benefit.
It doesn't mean a thing.
- He's not even going to wear it.
- Of course not.
Come on, Walter. We'll send this back.
I'll dig out something else to wear.
Looks like a regular soldier, don't he?
Here's the afternoon paper.
- I don't dare read the newspapers anymore.
- Neither do I.
- Oh, Maggie, what am I going to do?
- Nothing.
War is a man's business.
Women only do what they're told.
It's a long way to Tipperary
It's a long way to go
To the sweetest girl I know
You're next, Mr. Castle. Two thousand
people waiting to see you.
They didn't come to see me.
They came to see them.
It's a long, long way to Tipperary
But my heart's right there
Ready, Mr. Castle.
Mr. Castle?
Go on, darling.
Jeremiah Jones, a ladies' man was he
Any pretty girl could turn his head
But he got an awful fright
While strolling out one night
When someone winked at him and said:
There you are. Off you go.
Hello, hello
Who's your lady friend?
Who's the little girlie by your side?
I've seen you with a girl or two
Oh, oh, oh
I am surprised at you
Hello, hello
Stop your little games
Don't you think your ways
You ought to mend?
This isn't the girl I saw you with
At Brighton
Who, who, who's your lady?
Who, who, who's your lady friend?
This isn't the girl I saw you with
At Brighton
Who, who, who's your lady friend?
Take another bow, Mr. Castle?
No, Frank, let them take the bows.
Fine bunch of men.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we want to thank all of the performers...
...who have willingly given
their services to...
- Where's the recruiting officer?
- A man here wants to join up.
He's over there talking with Mr. Castle.
- To thank this splendid representative body
of Canadian men.
- Frank, have you seen Mr. Castle?
- He went downstairs.
Oh, my.
Vernon.
Darling, I have enlisted
in the Royal Flying Corps.
I had to, Irene.
Maybe if America were in the war, you'd
understand how I feel, why I have to go.
I know.
It won't last long.
They say one more push,
and it'll all be over.
That's not so bad, is it?
And I'll come back,
and we'll settle down...
...and have the house again
and everything.
Just as we were.
Yes, darling.
They may kick me out sooner than that.
I'll probably make a very bad soldier.
You'll make a very good soldier.
- Hey, look at your aileron, sir.
- Yeah, I know.
- How'd you get back?
- I had to get back.
- My furlough starts this afternoon.
- I'll say you earned it.
Telegram, Lieutenant Castle.
- Sailor's in Paris.
- What?
We'll be seeing her tonight,
do you realize that?
We'll be seeing her. Come on.
- Castle.
- Yes, sir?
- You better see these plate holders.
- What's the matter with them?
- Busted the whole lot of them.
- I'm afraid so.
- That bullet had your name on it.
- It's a lucky thing this case was in the way.
- Well, we can get them tomorrow.
- But I start my leave this afternoon, sir.
I'm afraid it'll have to be postponed.
GHQ wants this sector covered.
- Can I go up right now?
- Without a convoy?
Yes, sir, I can use Morgan's plane.
- Well, go ahead. Good luck.
- Thanks.
- Hey, Flight, stand by that plane.
- Yes, sir.
- Why don't you get going?
- Where?
Paris. Tell Irene
I'll meet her at Louis' at 8:00.
- Contact.
Tell her to save the first dance for me.
Well, don't just sit there, talk.
- There ain't much news where I come from.
- Then make some up.
Well, we lost a couple of planes
this morning, but...
- but they lost more.
I guess that ain't very interesting.
Did you tell Walter about your offer
to go to California to make moving pictures?
No, is that so?
- Maggie, why doesn't he come?
- Now, now, he's all right.
Back home, I used to think,
"Oh, if I could only be over there with him."
And now I'm here, and...
...he's not.
Ladies and gentlemen, a few years ago,
I introduced for the first time...
...someone who is now most famous.
She has come back to dance for us
again tonight.
Mrs. Vernon Castle.
Ladies and gentlemen, l...
l...
Oh, Vernon.
It's quarter to 5.
It's almost daylight.
Oh, Vernon, how long do you think
it will go on?
I don't know. Nobody seems to know.
Is it terribly dangerous in those planes?
I mean, worse than in the trenches?
Darling, we said
we wouldn't talk about it tonight.
I know, but it's almost morning,
and you'll be going back...
...and I won't see you for a long time.
I shouldn't worry, it's foolish.
I'm not the only soldier's wife,
I know that.
You will be careful, won't you?
I'll be careful.
And what's more I think
I'm going to be lucky.
- Lucky?
- Yes.
They say there's one bullet
with your name on it.
If it misses you, you come out all right.
Well, I think my bullet
missed me yesterday.
Darling.
And from now on,
I'm gonna be all right.
It's a good idea to hang on to.
I'll hang on to it.
You think of everything, don't you?
You thought of coming here
instead of the Ritz...
...or some place
that might not feel quite like home.
What's that?
Oh, Vernon, maybe the war is over.
What's happened?
The Americans have come into the war.
- America.
- Hooray.
- You know what that means.
- The war is practically over.
Yeah.
Get out, this is the picture.
- Now, camera, action.
- We're ready, Mrs. Castle.
All right, Mrs. Castle.
All right, Mr. D'Arcy.
Now, let's make this bigger
than the war.
Ready... camera... action!
That's it, Mrs. Castle, closer.
Mrs. Castle, closer...
- Bigger eyes, Mrs. Castle.
- Irene, telephone.
Can't you see we're shooting?
Irene, Vernon's on the telephone.
He's in Canada.
Oh, Vernon. Oh, excuse me.
Cut!
Cut.
Hello? Hello!
Darling, I just landed in Canada.
Yeah, but I'm being transferred
next week to Fort Worth, Texas.
Fort Worth, Texas?
Well, that's practically here.
I know. I'm to be a flying instructor
for the American Army.
Hello, Sailor, how are you?
- Tell her who it is.
- That was Walter.
Can you meet me there next weekend?
- Next weekend? Oh, I can't wait.
- Me too.
Yes, darling.
Now, I want a room where we can have
dinner and absolute privacy.
You just leave it to me, captain.
This ain't so much.
- Nice set up, huh. Cozy?
- Yes, this will do.
I know the ladies,
they like things nice.
- Say, who do you think is gonna be...?
- Walter.
- My friend here is a bit strait-laced.
- Sure, I know the type. Reformer.
Well, he's in the army now, eh, captain?
Can you close off that garden?
- You'll be as snug as a bug in a rug here.
- I want to reserve the garden too.
But that's for special occasions.
Our orchestra plays there.
- I want the orchestra.
- Oh, atmosphere, huh?
- No, music, you dumb...
- Walter...
...try to be a little more sophisticated,
like the gentleman here.
Oh, here he is, in here.
Captain, you are to report
back to the field immediately.
Not me, I've got weekend leave.
I'm sorry, captain.
I know you just got here...
...but a brigadier general
blew in.
They want all pilots in the air
this afternoon.
Thank you, lieutenant.
Well, it looks as if
I have to leave it all to you.
I know what you want. A hot bird, a cold
bottle and a warm shoulder, eh, captain?
Look, here's the list of the music
I want the orchestra to play.
Take care of it and explain to the lady
I may be late.
- Sure will. What name will she give?
- It's his wife.
- Your wife?
- Yes, do you mind?
No, I don't mind,
but I don't understand it.
All right, Castle.
Only one more hour.
Hey, young fellow, sit in the back.
But the officer just told me
that student pilots...
- I know, I like to ride in front.
- Yes, sir.
Why won't Captain Castle
ever ride in the back seat?
Nobody can make him
since that crash in Canada...
...when the boy in front got killed.
- Gas on, switch off.
- Contact.
Here we are.
Nice, huh? Best suite in the house.
You're across the hall, Miss Sutton.
Did Captain Castle say
how long he'd be at the field?
No ma'am, but he arranged for dinner
at 7:30 in the private dining room.
- Sounds almost wicked.
- We cater only to a family trade, ma'am.
- I beg your pardon.
- Not at all. My card.
If we can ever be of any service to you,
call on me.
- A wife-beater if ever I saw one.
- Maggie, won't you have dinner with us?
- We'd love to have you.
- Liar. You'd better get dressed.
Here comes Castle's squadron now.
Colonel, look out there.
Don't let that fool take off.
Flag him down.
Walter.
Oh, it's wonderful to see you.
- Hello, Sailor.
- Where's Vernon?
Oh, so that's it.
Vernon?
We wait months to see each other,
now you play games.
Vernon.
Where is he?
What's happened?
Sailor, Vernon's...
He's hurt.
Well, where is he? I've got to...
No.
He had his choice of
hitting another plane or crashing his own.
The student with him wasn't hurt much.
But Vernon was in the front seat.
He was a hero, Sailor.
Oh, Vernon.
They'll remember what he did
this afternoon.
They'll remember a lot of things he did.
The way he laughed
and the way he danced.
The way he made other people
want to dance.
Walter, he was just beginning to live.
He'll go on living. For you, and me.
Maybe even for a lot of people
that never knew him.
There's got to be something in him in every
boy and girl that get up and dance together.
They were singing that the day I met him
out in the water, with Zowie.
- I'd better get down and tell them to stop.
- No.
He wanted them tonight.
That was at the train,
the first time he kissed me.
Don't, Sailor.
Don't you want to go to your room now?
Go tell Maggie.
[ENGLISH]