[ Whistle ]
Move back!
You'd better get on.
I shall miss my boat.
[ Driver ]
Don't worry, sweetheart.
You'll catch the boat!
[ Indistinct Chatter ]
[ Man ]
My invention picks up
electrical impulses sent
from a station on shore.
This furnishes power for
the auxiliary propellers.
With them, we expect to
achieve a speed of 65 knots
per hour. Thank you.
You have just heard
Mr. Robert Hayes tell you how
fast we will cross the ocean.
How fast is 65 knots?
How do you do?
[ Chuckle ]
Um--
Sixty-five knots is
approximately... miles.
Psst!
I know you want
to hear the voice...
of that great radio announcer
who will be in charge
of our broadcasts.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Buzz Fielding!
He didn't get here yet.
Oh, what'll I do?
Anything, but
go ahead and do it.
An imitation of a man
playing a violin.
[ Ship Whistle ]
Get him out of there.
Ladies and gentlemen,
there seems to be some
delay on our program.
Where is he?
[ Radio ]
If you'll have patience,
you'll soon hear...
the genial voice
of your own announcer,
Mr. Buzz Fielding.
[ Radio Off ]
Yeah?
That's what you think.
[ Man ]
Buzz Fielding!
Phooey!
It's bad enough
to be in jail.
He won't be on that program.
How do you know
so much?
Because I'm
Buzz Fielding.
Is that so.
What are you doin'
in alimony jail?
I had trouble keeping a wife and
the government on one salary.
Sorry to keep you
waitin' out there.
That's all right.
Is this the one?
It's been some time
since I've seen him.
Yes, that's he.
Here's another one
says she's your wife.
Hello, Buzzie boy.
I hope you're happy
now that you've put me
in this monkey cage...
just because I missed
a couple of installments.
Number three comin'up.
Hello, Buzz.
What is this,
a convention?
Obviously.
Oh, Mrs. Fielding,
Mrs. Fielding and...
uh, Mrs. Fielding.
[ Buzz ]
One and two,
Mrs. Fielding number three.
A mighty touching
scene here.
- You expectin' any more?
- No, I know when
I've had enough.
Buzz, dear, if you'll
just hand over the money,
I'm sure the, uh, girls
will agree to let you out...
so you can earn a
lot more money for us.
But what money?
Y'all got $50,000 in advance
to put on the broadcast
from the Gigantic.
Yeah, but
that's not my money.
That's for the talent.
- I won't touch a cent of it.
- What did you bet it on?
Bet? The nose
of the Gigantic.
She's a cinch
to beat the Colossal,
and I got even money!
I'm looking
for Mrs. Fielding.
Everybody here is
Mrs. Fielding but me.
The judge said he wanted
to see Mrs. Fielding,
so I guess you'll all
have to come along.
Remember the last time
we were in jail together?
Our wedding night.
[ Chuckle ]
Did you ever manage to
find the marriage license?
Gee, that was about the maddest
house detective I ever saw.
There he is.
Buzz!
Dorothy!
You sure do all right.
Don't worry.
You'll be out.
I just paid
your alimony.
With what?
Your engagement ring?
Dorothy, you're the most
marvelous girl in the world!
It almost makes me
feel like crying.
I think I will.
It wasn't paid for.
Oh.
Excuse me, Mrs. Fielding.
You're wrong,
for once.
But I can see how
you picked up the habit.
You can come out.
Everything's been fixed.
No fooling?
Sure fun havin' you here
again, Mr. Fielding.
Don't think I haven't
enjoyed it, because I haven't.
So long. Don't miss
the big broadcast
from the Gigantic.
When you hear my theme song,
the first bars will be for you.
33 1 / 3 percent.
What are you crabbin' about?
Before y'all came along,
Cleo and I split him 50-50.
And to think I used
to own him 1 00% .
Oh. Pardon my curiosity,
but where'd this money
come from?
She said she was
just a friend.
She?
Say, that's how
we started!
You started.
Say, girls, come see
what I see.
Oh, just a friend!
I can almost see the
number four on her back.
I'm not going
to take another cut!
He can't chisel me down 25% .
Come on, Cleo.
I'm coming, dear.
Everything depends
upon you, my dear brother.
You're embarking
for Europe immediately.
Everything
is arranged.
Proceed at once
to pier 1 3,
where you will embark
upon the Colossal.
Remember the name: Colossal.
The present holder of the
Atlantic crossing record.
You will receive
further instructions upon
your arrival in Europe.
I wish you
your usual luck.
Thank you.
And a hearty
handclasp.
Have a good time.
Thanks. I'll even go
out of my way to have it.
But you must hurry, S.B.
I'm off, T.F.
I'm leaving everything
in your hands. Au revoir.
[ Chuckling ]
I thought that hallway
was awfully crowded.
Au revoir.
Where am I?
Drat, drat, drat!
[ Ringing ]
[ Ring ]
The mail, sir.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Ah! A carte postale
from Paris,
from my friend
Major Biggleswade.
[ Chuckling ]
From Paris. What won't
they think of next?
[ Chuckling ]
Ah...
destroy it at once.
Quite so.
Yes, indeed, sir.
Your brother, sir, S.B.,
seemed to be in quite a hurry,
if I may say so.
I sent him off
in a hurry.
He's got to catch the
Colossal. He only has
a few moments.
Might I remind you, sir,
the Colossal is not our boat.
Our boat
is the Gigantic.
Ah, true, true.
The Colossal is
our nearest rival.
But need I remind you
that my brother, S.B.,
has been connected with
every major disaster...
since the sinking
of the Merrimac?
I have engaged suite 1 3
for him on the Colossal.
Very, very good, sir.
Then if
anything happens,
it won't be
on our boat, sir.
You know who S.B. is--
S.B.
Ready... hup!
Guess they want
a speech.
My friends...
I think I can
call you friends.
- These aren't soldiers, sir.
- I was saying, my father,
one of the great
"immorals'' of his ti--
Great immortals
of his time--
[ Bugle ]
What?
How many, sir?
Oh, glad you
thought of it.
Fill her up.
Very good, sir.
Right to the brim.
How's your horn?
Oh, I suppose--
Ah, don't be facetious.
You haven't much time
to catch the Colossal, sir.
Nonsense!
Plenty of time
after a game of golf.
Yes, sir.
Here you are, sir.
Ah, thank you.
How much?
That will be one cent, sir,
and seven cents tax,
making a grand total
of eight cents.
Gas gone up again?
Oh, yes, sir.
What with surtaxes,
Social Security,
unemployment, street bonds
and old-age pensions, sir.
The gas is the same,
but the taxes have gone up.
What are you
doing there?
Inflating your tires, sir.
How many pounds?
Ah, fill her up.
Say, have you any spare
parts for these things?
Why, yes, sir.
Get me a new thumb,
will you?
I must watch the pressure.
I'll watch the pressure.
Go! Go, go, go, go!
Go.
Watch the pressure. No air
was gonna hurt anything.
What are you up to now?
I told you to watch
that tire!
I'm dreadfully sorry.
I'll have it fixed
in five minutes.
Five minutes and I'm
sailing on the Colossal
ten minutes ago.
Drat! Drat, drat.
I'll sue ya.
Out of my way
before I hit somebody.
[ Ship Whistle ]
Cast off
your lines.
Cast off your lines.
Slow speed
astern.
Slow speed astern.
Slow speed
astern.
Come on, snails.
Get the lead outta there.
Too heavy.
Too light!
That's too medium.
Let's see.
That's all right.
Tee it up... quick!
Fore.
Stand clear, boy.
You're all teed up,
sir.
Oh, thank you.
What do you mean,
I'm all teed off?
Don't be rude.
How far
is this hole?
420 yards, sir.
420 yards. 420 yards.
The wind against me.
Hand me that putter!
Thank you.
Stand clear, boy.
Keep your eye on the ball.
Ahh... a lily!
I was afraid I'd miss that.
Ah, thank you, George.
Here we go.
Gangway, boys!
[ Honking ]
Where's the ball?
Sorry, sir.
Hasn't got here yet.
Ah, the wind's against me.
Here she comes now.
There she is. Stand clear.
Keep your eye on the ball.
[ Ship Whistle ]
There goes the Colossal,
Mr. Bellows.
We got another 20 minutes.
It's a lily!
That ball will run
like a frightened fawn.
Look out, boys.
Get away!
[ Honking ]
Gangway! Gangway!
Gangway, boys.
Here you are.
Gangway, you children
of the fairway.
A lily!
Driver! Driver!
Driver, driver.
Driver!
Ow!
None of your liberties,
you silly-looking capper!
Pick up those
lost balls.
You look more like Mickey Mouse
than Mickey Mouse does himself.
You're a coot! A coot.
You understand?
Yes, sir.
Ah, thank you.
Not to be confused
with cootie.
Just a coot.
Not a good-looking coot,
either.
An ordinary coot.
Common garden coot.
Stand clear.
Keep your eye on the ball.
A ringer!
A ringer.
Stand clear!
A weed-bound ball.
[ Ship Whistle ]
Stand clear, boys.
We gotta catch that skiff.
Stand clear!
[ Honking ]
C'mon, Seabiscuit.
Gimme that 404 elephant gun.
C'mon, hand it to me.
Don't stand there.
[ Mumbling ]
Fore!
1 00% dynamite.
Hope I didn't
hit anybody.
Oh.
Fore!
Good morning, Larceny,
uh... Larsen.
Had a bad time in that trap,
didn't you, Mr. Bellows?
Got out in one poke.
I thought it took you several.
I had a bad time killing
a stubborn wombat.
Little beggars
get into your shoe.
Good morning,
Mr. Bellows.
Good morning, Goolkswankez.
How's your game?
Oh...
eighteen for nine holes.
Thirty-one. You're holding
the card upside down.
Nosey Parker.
It's coming to a pretty pass
when a common caddy...
tells a gentleman
how to hold his card.
[ Bellows ]
Ah, there's that
tongue sandwich now.
How'd it get into there?
Ladies and gentlemen,
the greatest race of the age
will soon be on.
Two giant greyhounds
of the sea battling
for the crossing record,
and may this one...
I mean, the best one, win.
Sis-boom-ba,
rah, rah, rah.
All right, Mike.
Don't knock yourself out.
We will soon pass
Ambrose Light where the
race will officially begin.
Between you and me,
the Gigantic can't lose.
With our new radio power,
we'll skip to France...
before you can say,
"Jack Robinson.''
Jack Robinson.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
I want to introduce a man...
who made a bubble
into a musical career,
Mr. Shep Fields.
Two years ago
come next wash day,
Shep became the Columbus
of the swing world by
discovering rippling rhythm.
Here he is, Mr. Shep Fields
in person,
who will show you how
rippling rhythm was born.
Okay, Shep,
let her ripple.
[ Pop, pop, pop, pop
pop, pop, pop, pop ]
Hey!
Do you call that music?
Let me show ya.
[ Flute ]
This little ripple
had rhythm
And the other little ripples
had none
All day through
and all night too
He kept on singing
Boodle-de-doop, boodle-de-doop
boodle-de-doop
[ Whistle ]
Now they say
the kid's okay
They love to play his
boodle-de-doop, boodle-de-doop
Boodle-de-doop boop
Oh, my hat!
Thank you.
It blew off.
It's a new hat.
I know it.
How?
Old hats never
blow off.
Well, thank you
for your trouble.
I like catching hats!
Some people like to go to
fires. Some raise tulips.
I love catching hats.
What do you do
when there's no wind?
I brood.
Oh!
Aah!
Whew! As long as we're gonna
make this our life's work,
we should know each other.
- I'm Robert Hayes.
- I'm Dorothy Wyndham.
- How do you do?
- Very well at the moment.
- What do you do when
you're not chasing hats?
- I'm an inventor.
- That radio power plant's mine.
- Ohh!
Oh .
Well, girl loses hat,
boy rescues hat.
Girl is grateful
for hat. Oh!
Boy is grateful
for wind.
[ Honking ]
Pitter! Patter! Putter!
Ow!
You keep your face clean.
Give me that " can't stay out''
putter. Quick! Hurry up!
What's the matter
with you?
Stand clear.
Keep your eye on the ball.
She's in! She's out.
I've missed it.
Come, come.
Come, my little
pilliwink.
Aha! She's in.
The only way to play it.
She made the round trip.
Ah, that reminds me.
I must send the little lady
her alimony.
Fifty-seven!
A new course record.
Are you going to keep
the card, sir?
Keep nothing.
No one ever doubts my word.
Keep the ball instead.
[ Ship Whistle ]
What's that?
You've missed
the Colossal, sir.
Oh, that's what
you think.
We're off, Pegasus!
Thanks.
Gangway, eagles!
[ Motor Rewing ]
[ Honking ]
Honk, honk.
Must be the China Clipper.
C'mon on, boys.
[ Honking ]
[ Ship Whistle ]
Have I got double vision?
Gangway!
Colossal, ahoy!
[ Honking ]
Gangway!
Colossal, ahoy!
He can't land here.
He's going
to put it down.
Clear the deck!
Clear the decks.
[ Honking ]
Take it easy, Pegasus.
Liable to have punctured
one of the balloonies.
Don't you know better than
to land here, you idiot?
Quiet, pip-squeak.
Stand clear, folks, and
keep your eye on the ball.
What's going on here?
Evidently a telegram
for me. Hand it over.
- I'm the captain.
- I thought you were a messenger boy.
Who are you?
My name is Bellows.
Oh, yes, Mr. Bellows.
I'm pleased to meet you.
You saw my hand.
Stop your twitting.
Where are we?
- We're just passing a bar.
- Keep right on going.
We'll stop at the next one.
We're just approaching
the light ship where the
record run formally begins.
Ah... go down and open
a case for me, will ya?
Wipe the top
of the bottle off.
[ Laughing ]
Anything I can do
for you?
See? You've made
the captain angry.
Too bad you can't show
us that trick invention.
Who said I couldn't?
This little squirt,
Hayes.
Huh?
He's tough.
He is, eh?
Step up on those handlebars.
Tell him I'm tough too.
I can lick my weight
in wildflowers.
Follow me.
But, Mr. Bellows--
Quiet, please.
This way, scums,
eh... chums.
This is known as the
chambre de electric...
or the geegaw room.
Robert Hayes is the
inventor, I understand.
What?
Why, that lug stole
the idea from me.
I muttered my plans one
night whilst in the throes
of delirium tremens--
Er, uh, old-fashioned
stomachache.
Do you know anything
about electricity?
My father occupied the
chair of applied electricity
at state's prison.
What is
this thing up here?
Uh? Oh, that. Yes.
It's a patent cigar cutter,
I think.
Look out.
You've broken it.
Can you fix it?
I'll fix it so that
nobody else can.
This, gentlemen,
is a, uh... still.
Put the mash in here
and it comes out, uh--
If I knew where it comes out,
I'd be there myself right now.
Yeah.
[ Shouting ]
Stand clear, Mr. Bellows!
Get back!
I can't.
I'm caught.
Let go of your umbrella.
I can't do that
either.
You nearly lost
your life, sir.
My life matters but little.
Look at that umbrella,
an impulsive gift from
the Ranee of Giz.
Mr. Hayes, are you
ready to turn on
your electric power?
Yes, sir.
I hope so.
Electricity, bah!
Lock those doors!
But, Mr. Bellows,
I--
Don't "but'"me.
Who's the boss around here?
Lock 'em, I tell you.
Lock 'em.
I heard what he said.
I'm terribly sorry.
Yeah.
Well, that's that.
[ Gunshot ]
Full speed ahead.
Gentlemen, the race is on.
Good luck, sir.
We'll need it.
We'll need it?
Ha-ha.
Mr. Bellows absolutely
refuses to let us use
the radio power.
What?
But we don't stand
a chance without it!
The ship was
designed for it.
I know it, gentlemen.
It's Mr. Bellow's ship.
I can only obey orders.
The Colossal will
beat us by half a day.
I'm aware of that, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have a rare treat for you:
a great Mexican singer,
Tito Guizar.
All afternoon,
I tossed and turned,
trying to resist the temptation
to come out here and say,
"What this country needs
is a good five-cent Guizar
with a band.''
Well, now I've said it...
and I wish I hadn't.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Tito Guizar.
[ Applause ]
[ Laughter ]
Señor Guizar?
Señor Guizar, don't be mad.
I was only kidding.
[ Guitar ]
Señor Guizar?
Ay-ya-ya-ya-yi
la-la-la-la
La-la-la
La-la-la la-la-la
Ah ah ah ah ah
Ah ah ah ahhhh
ah ah ah
Ahh ahh ahh ahhhh
Don't tell a secret to a rose
I told a secret to a rose
Just one that grew
with those in a garden
That night I saw
my secret love
Smile from
her balcony above
And I threw a rose
From the garden
But how on earth
could I suppose
That I would choose
the very rose
That knew my love
for that señorita
On her mantilla
She wore it
Till that rose fell apart
And out dropped
My heart
Thank you very much,
ladies and gentlemen.
Now I like to sing for you a song that
if I have to call it in my own Spanish,
I will say it...
Por besar tus lindos ojos,
yo no sé lo que daría.
Eres encantadora, lindísima.
Nada más seré para ti.
And in English you call it,
"I love you.''
[ Laughter ]
[ "Zuni Zuni'' ]
[ Singing In Spanish ]
When do we turn on
the machinery, Bob?
We don't.
Mr. Bellows refuses
to let me go near it.
Say that slow
and strap me in.
Bellows can't do that.
Yes, he can. He paid for it.
I only invented it.
Fifty thousand dollars!
My bankroll.
- My alimony!
- My rent!
- My poor Buzz.
- Oh, my heart's
right up in my mouth.
I hope you don't chip off
any teeth.
If we could use your invention,
do we have a chance to win?
I'm positive, but Mr. Bellows
won't let me get near it.
He doesn't
have to know.
- Turn it on without his okay?
- Shh. Not so loud.
Fifty thousand dollars.
If we could just keep
Bellows off the top deck,
keep his mind on
something else.
Grace, looks like a job for you.
Why throw me to that
beagle-nosed bugle...
bugle-nosed beagle?
Because Mother Nature gave
you a little finger men
ache to be wrapped around.
I still
don't think--
Darling,
he owns this boat.
Owns it?
Owns it.
Well, then I'll take
some blocks along for
his second childhood.
Look out!
Here he comes!
I beg your pardon, dear.
You were on the wrong side;
should've blown your horn.
Why don't you look where
you're going, steward?
Call me stew for short.
I'm so sorry, Mr. Bellows.
I didn't recognize you
in this bad light.
Everybody seems to
see me in a bad light.
Didn't I meet you once
at the chicken show
in Cucamonga?
I really don't think so.
You see, I'm a widow.
A widow.
Fine people, widows.
Had one of the greatest
times of my life
with a widow.
Escorted her through
a brewery. She got
all "hopped up'' about it.
Malt Brothers Brewing.
Would you do something
for me?
Uh-oh.
Here it comes.
I'm looking for the bar.
Oh-ha!
Come with me!
I know a shortcut.
[ Mr. Bellows ]
Chum around with me.
You'll have a laugh on every
other girl on the boat.
Or vice versa.
[ Laughing ]
Excuse me, dear.
Did I leave an imprint?
Did you find
the trouble yet?
Oh, hello.
No, not yet.
That's too bad.
Look what
I brought you.
Bless your heart.
Say, where's Bellows?
Don't worry.
Grace has that situation
well under control.
Fine.
Sandwiches!
Will you have one?
No, thank you.
Mmm! These are swell.
Two.
Two?
Mm-hmm.
One... two.
Thank you.
[ Humming ]
- Pretty?
- Who, me?
No. That song,
idiot.
Oh. I haven't
heard it before.
You took the words
right out of my heart
And it was like a bolt
from the blue
You took the words
right out of my heart
What's the matter?
There's not
enough sugar.
Three?
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
I stood
in a daze awhile
For I felt
that way too
[ Humming ]
The moment
I saw you smile
[ Together ]
I had the words
and you in my heart
There wasn't
room enough for the two
You took the words
right out of my heart
And left only room
for you
Bum bum
Do you believe
in love at first sight?
So do I.
That is, I mean--
Well, if things weren't--
Oh, you know.
Yeah.
I know.
Say, Hayes.
Hayes.
How you doin'?
I'm not, thank you.
- Oh, hello, dear.
- Hello.
Say, what
gives out here anyway?
Supper.
You want some?
What a time to eat.
[ Buzz ] If Columbus
had sailed on this boat,
the Indians would
still own America!
Come, darling.
You've been in
worse fixes than this.
Yeah, we have,
haven't we?
Sure.
We always managed
to wiggle out somehow.
Remember that deputy sheriff
without his pants?
Of course.
And the time I--
This is no time
to start remembering.
Go on and make
your announcement.
You know, Cleo,
we've had an
awful lot of fun.
Yeah!
Between fights.
Remind me to ask you
sometime how we happened
to get divorced.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it isn't often that I have
the privilege of introducing...
such a distinguished artist
as Madame Kirsten Flagstad,
star of the Metropolitan
Opera Company.
[ Applause ]
Madame Flagstad has been
acclaimed the world's
greatest living soprano.
She will sing an aria
from Richard Wagner's opera,
The Valkyrie,
"Brunnhilde's Battle Cry.''
Mr. Wilfred Pelletier of
the Metropolitan will conduct.
[ Singing In German ]
[ Snoring ]
Hello, hello, hello!
Hello? Hello?
I'm not here. I'm asleep.
Aren't you
awake yet?
[ Gasp ]
I don't know.
I haven't looked yet.
Now I am.
What's this thing?
Invention. Why don't you
knock before you come in?
Oh! Oh, yes.
Certainly.
[ Bellows ]
Come in.
Now I'm out here!
Stay out there.
Take a walk around the deck.
I can't!
I'm in the bathroom.
Stay in the bathroom.
I'll bet you won't bite
anybody else.
Whew.
Meet me down at the bar.
We'll drink breakfast
together.
Thought you were on deck.
What are you doing here
in the reading room?
Reading.
Oh.
Here's some
breakfast food.
[ Bellows ]
What, no beer?
[ Gargling ]
You swallowed it!
I know it.
How are you feeling
this morning?
I feel like a June bride.
And how does
a June bride feel?
I wonder. I wonder.
That tie shrunk.
Have you been wearing it?
No.
- May I come in, sir?
- You are in.
Captain's compliments, sir.
He'd like to see you on the bridge.
We've just received an S.O.S. from
a sinking ship. If we go to the rescue,
it may cause us to lose the race.
How can I go
to the rescue until
I know where they are?
First you tell me to do
one thing, then another!
Never mind what
I tell you to do.
Do what I tell you.
We can't find
their position.
I've got them on radio,
but all they do is argue.
All I can make out is,
"Oh, boy!''
Switch that S.O.S. call
to here.
[ Man ]
Help! This is the
yacht Hesperus the Fifth.
My brother's yacht.
We are sinking.
They're stinking.
They're drinking evidently.
The longitude.: 69 degrees,
the Tropic of Capricorn,
45 degrees west.
Latitude.:38 degrees
and 1 4 minutes north.
[ Woman ]
Never mind the arithmetic.
Tell 'em where we are.
My daughter's own voice.
My little Jonah.
Mr. Brook,
we're changing course.
Set lookouts.
A human life is at stake.
My daughter cannot
be described as human.
Wherever she goes,
disaster follows.
Have you any proof your
daughter causes disasters?
She's an unfortunate girl.
Seven years ago, she crashed
an airplane in a mirror factory.
Broke 9,831 mirrors.
Point three, port,
point five.
Point wherever you want to.
I'm going up here.
We are making a left turn.
Why didn't you say so?
I'll put my hand out.
Go ahead, boys,
we'll pass on the other side.
Heigh ho--
It's all black here.
Ah, move over to one side.
You in the habit of standing
before a mariner...
when he's looking through
his barnacle-- monocle?
- Looks like a sea serpent.
- That's what I thought. Gimme that.
Just relax.
I saw it all the time.
Inhale.
You're going too fast.
Look! Look!
A boat!
We're saved! I told you
my luck's changed.
We're saved! Yahoo!
[ Yelling ]
Never a dull moment.
Here they are, folks.
Martha Bellows and her
shipwrecked party...
are coming up the side
of the Gigantic.
Martha's rescue
by her father's ship proves
even to us who can see him...
that Mr. Bellows
is almost human.
What a moment, for a father
to snatch his daughter from
the gripping jaws of death.
Why, hello, Pappy.
Where you been?
Quiet, frog-mouth.
I'm on a secret mission.
Where'd you get the pickaninny?
Oh, it's just a little thing
I dreamed up.
Can't be your child.
It's got whiskers, and it
smells like an old gum boot.
Miss Bellows, the Gigantic
is honored to have rescued you.
Oh.
The captain doesn't know
what boat he's on.
This is the Colossal.
[ Excited Chatter ]
Quiet, scum!
I know what boat I'm on.
- But, Mr. Bellows,
you can see for yourself.
- The boat's all wrong.
Can't read that.
They put the letters on
upside down.
I can assure you
it's the Gigantic.
Great Caesar's goat--
ghost!
T.F.'s own boat.
Throw her overboard
before we sink.
But you can't throw
your own daughter overboard.
Why not?
Let the sharks
protect themselves.
But, Daddy,
you don't understand. My
seven years' bad luck's up.
I take no chances.
Don't look in that mirror!
Don't look
in the mirror, Martha.
And she broke
9,000 of'em!
Hey, where've you been?
Hey, boss, here
are the records.
Oh, that's swell, Mike.
[ Laughter ]
Hey, maybe we can
glue 'em together.
Maybe we can glue 'em together.
- Well, that's that.
- Are you upset?
What have I got
to be upset about?
I'm in the process
of losin' $50,000...
and a boat that would need
a handicap against a lame sardine.
I go on the air in two minutes, and none
of my performers will perform...
because you talked
out of turn.
All I said...
was that you were losing
$50,000 on the race.
And what did they say?
They said you
didn't have $50,000.
Oh, they did, eh?
And what did you say?
I stuck up for you.
I said you had more than
$50,000: ten dollars of
your own and their salaries.
And what d--
Their salaries!
Oh, never mind.
Look, take this
portable Mike...
and go around the ship
and see if you can pick up
something from the passengers.
I'll vamp till you're ready.
Pick up the passengers?
Y-- go away, go away.
Ladies and gentlemen,
in just a few moments,
we start our daily broadcast.
I want you folks to relax
and have a good time.
We have quite a few jokes
here on the program, uh,
I think you'll enjoy.
There's one here about
a little schoolboy...
that used to take
a big apple to the teacher,
and now he takes the teacher
to the Big Apple.
[ Audience Silent ]
That's the first joke.
I thought you'd like--
[ Groaning ]
Big Apple's a dance.
[ Snoring ]
[ Whistling ]
[ Snorting ]
[ Whistles ]
Let's try another one.
It seems there were
two fliers in an airplane.
And one flier
did a loop-to-loop,
and the other flier
fell out.
So the first flier looked down,
and he said, "Pardon me.''
[ Southern Accent ]
Pardon me.
Yeah, that's
what he said.
Well, how do you do.
Could you please tell me where
they have the entertainment?
The entertainment? Yes.
You go right down the hall,
and you m--
This is the entertainment.
This is where the broadcast
takes place, right here.
Oh, well, I'm Honey Chile.
I'd like to help you out.
Well, I don't need
much help, but, uh...
what can you do?
Well, I'd like to sing.
I want to be a singer
in the worst way.
Mm-hmm. Probably will be.
What kind of a voice
have you got anyway?
Yeah, but when I sing,
I cry.
[ Imitating Southern Accent ]
When you sing, you cry?
Well, uh, why do you cry?
'Cause I can't sing.
Oh, well, that's grand.
We won't bother with that then.
I have another little joke
that I think you may--
But I want to sing
"Way Down South in Dixie.''
You want to sing
"Way Down South in Dixie''?
What time's your bus leave?
I want to sing it
right now.
Well, you go ahead
and sing.
Step right up.
I'll stand over here so they
won't think I'm beating you.
[ Off-key ]
Way down south in
the land of cotton
Old folks there
are not forgotten
Look away, look away
look away, look away
Go ahead.
We're still safe.
Oh I wish I was in Dixie
So do I
So you want to help me out.
Why did you decide
on helping me out?
Well, you see, I had
a fight with my folks,
- and I want to do somethin'
to disgrace them.
- [ Laughing ]
Well, you probably came
to the right guy.
I think this audience
would appreciate something
of a legitimate nature.
Do you do
any dramatics?
Oh, sure,
I can handle that junk.
Oh, you do that
legitimate trash, eh?
You haven't got a piece
of Claudette Colbert
hanging around, do you?
Oh, yes, I have
a little playlet. I play
all the characters myself.
You play all the
characters yourself.
I play
all the characters myself.
Is there an echo in here?
Well, what is that like?
Well, I'll explain.
This is the villain,
this is the heroine
and this is the hero.
You play
all those yourself.
Mm-hmm.
That's a nice, small cast.
Let's see that.
We'd like to see that.
Is that part
of the play?
Yeah, that's
the curtain goin' up.
Heh, heh. Ahem.
Come, pay the rent.
Come, pay the rent!
But I can't pay the rent.
I can't pay the rent!
Come, pay the rent.
Come, pay the rent!
But I can't pay the rent.
I can't pay the rent!
I'll pay the rent.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
[ Woman ]
You took the words
right out of my heart
And it was like
a bolt from the blue
You took the words
right out of my heart
When you said I love you
And then there's the one
about the fellow that
went to the dentist.
He only had a dollar,
so they gave him buck teeth.
[ Audience Growling ]
Please don't cry
Ah, wait a minute.
Here it is.
For I felt
that way too
It's Dorothy Wyndham
by remote control,
caught unawares,
and that's no joke.
The moment I saw you smile
I had the words
and you in my heart
There wasn't room enough
for the two
You took the words
right out of my heart
And left only room
for you
[ Hayes' Voice ]
There ought to be a law
against songs like that.
[ Dorothy ] Why?
It's not right.
Hearing you sing that
is like reading love letters
intended for someone else.
It's dreadful when a letter's
sent to the right person by mistake.
But there's nothing
we can do about it, Bob.
You mean Buzz?
As I was saying,
in the first 1 2 hours,
we came this far.
Altogether, we've
only come this far.
Another mile
and you'd have
cracked my skull.
You're the captain. Why don't
you do something about it?
But, but, but, but--
You talk like a motorboat.
This situation calls for
immediate action. Gangway!
Suffering sciatica!
Where have you been?
Why didn't you stick with me
down in the bathroom?
I wanted you
to scrub my back.
I'll see you in perdition first.
Eventually, but right now,
we've got to-- Come over
on the bridge with me.
Give me that hat.
Here, hold this.
Hold that.
That's fine.
Come on now.
Here, I want to
show you this chart.
Do you
know anything about it?
I know it
backwards.
Your usual form.
Thank you very much.
See, we've been uphill
up to now.
Once we get over the hump,
we coast right down
into Cherbourg.
What's this Rand McNally?
Evidently
an Irish possession.
Here's a snapshot of
my little daughter Martha,
taken at sea
when she was a babe.
That's enough!
Brother or no brother,
Wait a minute.
out you go!
I've been attacked!
Wait'll my lawyer sees this.
Wearin' magic perfume
On her--
Surprise!
How do you like my costume
for the big dance number?
Don't get in front
of the mirror.
Don't you think...
it fits
my personality?
Uh, yes, just barely.
I'm so cute, I bet
they put my picture
on the front page.
I'll never forget the last time
you had your picture
on the front page.
Your mouth was continued
on page two.
Oh! Why did
you cut yourself?
Ah, I wanted to find out
if I was anemic.
Oh.
Gee, I feel so wonderful.
What a-- What a form.
What a figure.
Oh! Well, uh--
I'm, I'm, I'm sorry.
Any mirror can just
fall down and break.
Any, uh--
It wasn't
my fault, was it?
Quiet!
No! It wasn't
my fault!
Oh, boy!
Ah, here's where
we make a couple of
very dear friendships.
That is glass.
Ah, it's too clean.
Be very careful of that--
[ Cane Banging ]
Look out.
How do you do.
Garcon!
[ Waiter ]
Yes, sir?
Bring us two whiskey sodas.
Yes, sir.
Spoke to him
in his native tongue.
Move over, dear.
That's all right.
I like that.
Oh, do you? That's fine.
Make it four whiskey sodas.
Don't put your hat
on the table.
As I was saying,
Yes?
I was married to him
for eight months. I gave him
the best years of my life.
Best years of her life.
I only wanted
a million dollars.
Only a million.
He wouldn't
give me a penny.
Where was your mother?
Couldn't come that day,
I suppose.
But he'll pay,
and he'll pay
through his nose.
Ha ha! Good.
They seem
a bit snooty.
Very silly little girls.
They let it slip
right through their fingers.
Well, we'll be going.
We'll see you later.
Is that a tomato he's eating,
or is that his nose?
Evidently,
they're insulted.
- You say anything to them?
- I never opened my mouth.
I've lost my hat.
There it is, up there.
Where? Ah.
I told you
I lost it. Oh.
Good-bye!
Good-bye, dear.
There it goes.
Here, give me that.
You got a hat of your own.
What's the matter,
darling?
Hello, Cleo.
What's the matter?
Little man had
a busy day?
This is no time
for wisecracks,
from you
or anyone else.
$50,000.
Well, what's
$50,000?
Ahh, I'm goin' out
and eat worms, with
salt and pepper and stuff.
Oh, wait a minute.
Thank you.
Say, keep them coming,
and give her the cherries,
will you?
Thanks for remembering.
Say, make that extra big
so I can catch up with him.
You know, Buzz,
I cleaned up
an old trunk yesterday,
and I found
that green tie of yours,
the one with the stripes.
Really?
Uh-huh.
You know something, Buzz?
What, dear?
I kind of miss
your singing in the bathtub.
Mm, good old bathtub.
Good old singing.
Thanks for the memory
of rainy afternoons
Swingy Harlem tunes
Motor trips and burning lips
and burning toast and prunes
How lovely it was
Thanks for the memory
Of candlelight and wine
castles on the Rhine
The Parthenon
And moments on
the Hudson River line
How lovely it was
Many's the time
that we feasted
And many's the time
that we fasted
Oh well it was swell
while it lasted
We did have fun
and no harm done
So thanks for the memory
of crap games on the floor
Nights in Singapore
You might've been a headache
but you never were a bore
I thank you so much
Thanks for the memory
of China's funny wall
Transatlantic calls
That weekend at Niagara
when we hardly saw the falls
- How lovely that was.
- Thank you.
Thanks for the memory
of lunch from 1 2:00 to 4:00
Sunburn at the shore
That pair of gay pajamas that
you bought and never wore
Say, by the way,
what did happen
to those pajamas?
Huh?
Letters with
sweet little secrets
That couldn't be put
in a day wire
Too bad it all
had to go haywire
That's life, I guess
I love...
your dress
Do you?
It's pretty.
Thanks...
For the memory
Of faults that you forgave
Rainbows on a wave
And stockings in the basin
when a fellow needs a shave
I thank you
so much
Thanks for the memory
Of gardens at Versailles
And beef and kidney pie
The night you worked
and then came home with
lipstick on your tie
How lovely that was.
Huh?
For the memory
of lingerie with lace
Yes and pilsner
by the case
And how I jumped
the day you trumped
my one and only ace
How lou--
lovely that was
We said good-bye
with a highball
Then I got as high
as a steeple
Did you?
But we were
intelligent people
No tears, no fuss
Hurray for us
Strictly entre-nous
Darling, how are you?
And how are all
the little dreams that
never did come true
Awfully glad I met you
Cheerio and toodle-oo
Thank you.
Oh, Buzz! Buzz!
Darling.
I know.
I know, dear.
Now what does that mean?
That means Robert Hayes'
invention's a failure.
Oh, I wish I could be
of some help.
Stumped by a short circuit.
Come on, Bob, it isn't
hopeless, is it?
No, no, it's not hopeless.
But that'll take
a month to find.
By that time, the trip
will be over and so will what
I laughingly call my career.
Poor Bob.
Oh, excuse me. I thought
I was someplace else.
Well, so long.
Just remember
where you left off.
Hey! Hey, come back here!
Come on!
There you go.
Do you mind if I
sort of pass through?
I thought this was
a thing that went around
the whole thing up there,
and it came--
I just wan-- ooh!
I, I guess I must've
busted somethin', huh?
Well, how much will it cost
to have fixed?
My dream girl! Eureka!
Hey, I resent that.
My dream princess!
Whoo! Your nose is cold.
What is it?
The tip of
Bellows' umbrella.
- The short circuit I couldn't locate.
- What's all the kissin' about?
Don't you understand? You
found the tip of the umbrella.
I, I-- Whoo!
I'll be right back.
Where you going?
I'm gonna get
more umbrellas.
Boy, oh boy!
Hey!
[ Martha ]
I'll be right back.
You think it'll
start now?
I don't know.
We can try.
Cross your fingers.
[ Hayes ]
Oh, that's great!
[ Dorothy ] Oh, Bob!
Although I am a veritable
tyro at the game,
I will make an exception
in your case and make
a small wager.
Right, sir.
Any amount?
Ah, that's a bet.
Yes, but, uh, how much?
Shall we say a pound?
Make it a ton.
Ah, there's too much
loft on that cue.
Go ahead. You shoot.
Imagine a man wearing
a roller towel for a hat.
Got a little soap
in your pocket?
Maybe you don't... use soap.
It's all right.
Go ahead. Shoot.
Ah, ah, ah, ah!
Look here. I think
we ought to toss for it.
Oh, very well.
Head or tail?
Um, head.
Tail. Your break.
But I didn't see it.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
There.
Oh, yes, yes.
Well, you win.
Yeah.
Uh, just hold my coat
a minute, will ya?
Thank you.
It's my next shot.
Thanks. Go ahead.
Don't put it down.
Got some valuable papers
in the pocket.
Go ahead. Shoot.
Very difficult for me.
Yeah. Ah!
Look out there.
[ Coughing ]
Ah!
Oh, I seem
to have missed.
Yeah, I think you did.
Yes. Now...
And now it's my shot.
Don't shoot yet.
Wait a minute.
I haven't finished
shooting yet.
I say, is the ship
rolling slightly,
or am I
a little bit Bosky?
Tell me, which pocket
were you aiming for?
Ah, ah, ah.
I'll tell you
in a minute.
That's fine.
I played them all.
Here you are.
Let me get my cue.
Got a match?
No.
Ah, hold that.
That's okay.
No, thank you.
Chocolate Sauce?
Yes, please.
Where are you?
Just behind you.
Stick around.
I don't want you to say
I cheated afterwards.
Wait a minute now.
There she goes.
That's fine. Now then.
[ Cue Stick Banging ]
What this ship needs
is shorter cues.
Wait a minute.
Don't go away.
Stand right where you are.
Wait a minute.
Okay.
Side pocket, maybe.
Wait a minute.
I don't know which side yet.
[ Laughing ]
Lucky shot.
- Ripping.
- Often wondered what
that porthole was there for.
Fore! Look out!
Aimed at the chocolate
and got the vanilla.
Here, hold this.
You're doing nothing.
Thank you, beautiful.
Why, you silly
old monkey, you.
Huh? Oh, he's all right
if you know how to take him.
Ah, I was afraid
you wouldn't be here.
Bring a wet towel next time.
Keep cool, dear. I'll bring
a wrap out for you in a minute.
I'll be back.
Just get another chair.
I'll sit down with you.
Finishing up a game
of billiards here.
Don't put that down there!
There are some very valuable
papers in the pocket.
What sort of papers?
Ah, cigarette papers.
Oh.
Yeah.
[ Banging ]
Oop! Ha.
Unfortunate.
I say, I wonder
what made it jump out.
I wonder, I wonder.
Wouldn't have been
any good anyway.
You forgot
to call your shot.
I say, see here.
You're making me look
like a bally clotheshorse.
I feel so silly.
You don't look silly.
You don't think I'd trust
every Tom, Dick and Harry...
with my valuable papers.
Yeah, but
my name's Harry.
Well, I would
make an exception
in Harry's case.
It's a draw shot.
Give me that hat. You look
like the two-headed boy
in the circus.
Stand clear.
Now what have you done?
How do you expect anyone
to play pool...
on a moth-eaten,
torn table like that?
Is there a lawyer
on the ship? Come.
Oh, Scoop, darling.
Look at the moon.
Isn't it glorious?
Yeah, it's a right fair
sort of moon.
Ah. A night like this
does things to me.
A night like this?
Yes, it's
the magic of it all.
O Romeo, Romeo!
I swear by yon inconstant moon,
whose silvery beams
besmears the lost horizon--
"Besmear the lost horizon.''
Yes, that's what I said:
besmears.
That's what I thought.
Oh, won't you be
my Romeo?
Yeah, sure.
We will rehearse
the death scene.
What is this strange power
I'd like to have over you?
[ Scream ]
[ Stewards ]
Yes, sir?
Yes, sir? Yes, sir?
I've been kissed
by a tunnel.
Well, it's that thing, that--
I just can't help it.
We were fated
for each other
And in spite
of your masculine charm
You remind me
of my mother
I'm an innocent babe
in your arms
Your lips like wine
Caress me, lover mine
Tonight we live
Little mother
please forgive me
Mama, oh mama
That moon is here again
That boy is near again
and I'm just a girl
Oh mama, dear mama
I'm counting up to ten
I always do that when
my brain's in a whirl
One, two, three, four
five, six, seven, eight
Whoo! I can't go on
Neither can I.
My heart is gone
Oh mama, dear mama
Please don't
wait up for me
I'm glad I took the key
that moon's here again
Oh mama, dear mama
that moon is here again
That boy is gone again
and I'm all alone
Oh mama, hey mama
Don't blame
your angel child
Ah, the moon
has got me wild
And I'm on my own
One, two, three, four
five, six, seven, eight
Ready or not
he shall be caught
Ho-ho mama, dear mama
I know you'll understand
I'm only human
and that moon's here again
Mama, oh mama
that moon is here again
That boy is gone again
And I'm all alone
Oh mama, dear mama
Don't blame
your angel child
That moon has got me wild
and I'm on my own
One, two, a-three-a a-four-a
a-five-a, a-six-a, a-seven, a-eight
Whoo! I can't go on
Ohh. Ah!
Aw, gee whiz, kid,
my jinx is up now!
What's new, kid?
Ma!
Mama, oh mama
That moon is here again
Those boys are here again
and I'm just a girl
Mama, oh mama, don't
let this-- Oop-- me now
Say I could kiss a cow that's--
Oop! Ooh! Ooh!
[ Boing ]
Ooh.
Aw, gee whiz, kids,
come on.
I'm tryin' to be friendly,
that's all. Ma!
Oop!
[ Laughing ]
What's playing here, Satchel?
Come on, break it up,
will ya, fellas?
I-I-- I'm
a sweet kid. Oh!
One, two, three, four
Five, six, seven, eight
I can't go on-- Whoa!
My heart is gone
Oh mama, dear mama
don't wait to see me now
I'm glad I took--
Good night, all.
Hello, everybody... and folks.
You. And I do mean you.
First comes our report
of the big race with
the S.S. Colossal.
Oh, I forgot.
We've stopped giving those.
Ah, ah, ah.
No, we haven't.
This is Buzz Fielding speaking,
and I'm not going to say
anything about the race...
except that we're gaining
with every turn of the turbines.
Oh!
You have something?
Oh, hold your breath, folks.
We--
[ Inhaling ]
Say, we've just gained
200 miles on the Colossal.
If we can keep this up,
why, we'll pass her
before morning.
[ Cheering ]
Two hundred miles!
Isn't that marvelous?
Boy, I tell you.
Boy, you get a certain
satisfaction when you
stick-- You gotta--
You g-- Oh!
[ Fog Horn Blowing ]
She played her cards right,
and I gave her a diamond tiara.
You know, Mr. Bellows,
there's something
awfully big about you.
Oh, thank you. Thank--
Uh, thank you.
After you, dear.
Oh, thank you.
The door sticks there.
[ Fog Horn Blowing ]
Stand by to reduce speed.
Fog's so thick you can't
see your hand in front of ya.
What's the matter
with your hand?
Nothing.
What do you want
to look at it for?
Full speed ahead.
As captain of this ship--
You're fired.
You can't discharge
me in mid-ocean.
I can kick ya in mid-ocean.
Mr. Bellows! There are
icebergs in these waters
and other ships.
We must reduce speed.
If you'll step into
the chart room,
I'll prove it to you.
After you, dear Captain.
After you,
dear Captain.
Why, thank you.
Show that to your lawyer.
I got rid of him.
How many feet has he got?
Kicked an officer
with his cap on.
That's mutiny.
Come with me, dear.
We'll go up the poop deck.
- Mr. Bellows!
- Ahoy, boy!
Step on that gas.
Sorry, sir, but
this is a diesel.
Step on the steam.
Step on the diesel.
Don't answer me back.
I'll crack your skull
with a belaying pin.
Why, Mr. Billows!
Ah, Bellows
is the name, dear.
Yes.
What's the matter
with this thing? It won't work.
I put a dollar and a quarter
in here this morning
and only got a nickel out.
What number
you playing?
Maybe that's the catch.
I'll just-- Mutiny!
Is my lawyer in the house?
$40 million and
a ten-cent-store ax!
Oh, popsicle!
An iceberg!
[ Bellows ]
Pretty thing, isn't it?
But there are two of them!
Ah, they breed like rats.
Wait'll you see me go
right in between these two
without scratching a fender.
[ Screams ]
Huh? I beg your pardon.
I didn't hear you, dear.
Where's she gone?
Probably fell overboard.
Watch this one.
Look out, fellas.
[ Fog Horn Blowing ]
Look. I'll work it
with my feet.
Ought to put lights
on those things.
It's awfully dangerous.
Let go there.
Would you go or not?
Just think,
ladies and gentlemen,
we're skimming over the water
at the amazing rate of
a hundred miles an hour.
What a world of speed
we live in. Everything's
been speeded up,
What a world of speed
we live in. Everything's
been speeded up,
everything except the waltz.
Dances come and dances go,
but whether slow or hot,
very soon the latest dance...
Is deader than
the turkey trot
But if any of you were alive
in 1 7 85
You remember how people
were shocked and aghast
At a thing called
the waltz
It was too, too risque.
The papers predicted
it never would last
But it's here today
And here to stay
Years go by
the waltz lives on
You and I could
dance till dawn
Then we part
but in my heart
The waltz lives on
Lovers never weary of
Waltzing while
a moon's above
For it's still
the song of love
The waltz lives on
[ Music Changes Tempo ]
It's too old-fashioned
do the polka, do the polka
[ Music Slows ]
Dances come
and dances go
But the waltz lives on
[ Music Builds To Can-Can ]
[ Tempo Slows ]
Lovers never weary of
Waltzing while
a moon's above
For it's still
the song of love--
Rhythm, rhythm
rhythm, rhythm, rhythm
[ Cakewalk ]
[ Charleston ]
[ Tempo Slows ]
[ Trumpets ]
A dance to do
up there in Harlem so
Someone started truckin'
[ Scatting ]
Do-bop-da 'n da 'n da-day
As soon as the
news got round
Folks downtown
came up to Harlem saw
E-E-Everybody truckin' oh
It didn't take long before
[ Scatting ]
Do-bop-la chi-da-dida
chip chip chi-da-dida
Over town you'll see them
scufflin' and truckin' along
Whoa, spread like
a forest blaze
Became a craze
thanks to Harlem now
E-E-Everybody's truckin'
[ Tempo Slows ]
[ Piano ]
Years go by
The waltz lives on
You and I could
dance till dawn
Then we part
but in my heart
The waltz lives on
Lovers never weary of
Waltzing while
a moon's above
For it's still
the song of love
The waltz lives on
Lovers never weary of
Dancing while
a moon's above
For it's still
the song of love
The waltz lives on
[ Finale ]
Well, I never expected
to see this day dawn.
You're not seeing
much of it at that.
[ Banging ]
What's that noise
anyway?
Roaches.
Been keeping me awake all night.
The boat's full of'em.
Ten baby fingers
and ten baby toes
A mother 'tis
a five-cent friend after all
We're finally through, sir.
Oh, good.
[ Indistinct Singing ]
Have to know how
Eh?
Drat that whale.
[ Bell Ringing ]
It's been blowing its nose
in my face all night.
What are you doing? Let go!
Land ho!
It's Cherbourg, sir.
Cherbourg!
Ah! Where'd
you want to go?
Cherbourg,
of course.
Here we are.
What are you
kicking about?
[ Officer ]
There's the Colossal
ahead, sir.
And by the grace
of Bellows'guardian angel.
If I'd listened to you,
we'd have probably landed
in Lake Titicaca.
Why don't you smile, darling?
You have everything you want.
The boat's winning...
money.
Yes, everything but you.
And that's everything.
But, darling,
you weren't afraid
to ask me before.
Hooray! Hooray!
Bob, darling, he doesn't
want me. He wants Cleo!
Oh!
[ Cheering ]
Vive la France!
[ Shouting ]
Oh! All right.
Fine. Fine.
[ Ship's Horn Blowing ]