This is the story of how the destiny
of a nation was changed by a birthmark.
A royal birthmark on the royal
posterior of a royal infant child.
Here returning to his castle is King Roderick.
Roderick the tyrant, who some
months before seized the throne
by a massacre of the entire royal family.
But uneasy lies Roderick's crown,
for rumor hath it that an infant,
the rightful heir to the thrown
had survived the massacre.
And even now is being cared
for by a group in the forest.
A group led by an elusive dashing
outlaw known only as..
the Black Fox!
The child lives! Death to
the tyrant! The Black Fox.
The Black Fox again!
To the castle, quick!
My kingdom seething with revolt,
cutthroats and assassins in every tree!
Why must I be surrounded by fools?
Ravenhurst! Ravenhurst!
Sire!
Could you have been so
incompetent, bungled so horribly,
as to have permitted
that child to live?
Sire, there is no child.
My men assure me that none
of the royal family escaped alive.
Believe me, sire,
this is nonsense.
Nonsense? You call it nonsense, Ravenhurst!
Is it nonsense that I cannot
ride my own domain,
without being
murderously attacked.
My child, I came
within an inch of my life.
Oh, father.
Each day, some new insurrection.
Who is this Black Fox?
Oh just some ridiculous adventurer
with a handful of rabble.
Rabble today but
an army tomorrow!
We need help to wipe
them out. Men and arms!
Aye, an alliance with our good
friend Griswold of the North!
Aye, alliance, and quickly! He arrives
tomorrow for the great tournament.
Alliance with Griswold...
Sire, this rabble
can be crushed.
Griswold has men and arms.
We need no uncouth
interloper from the north.
Uncouth, yes, but
Griswold is strong.
Perhaps too strong.
Perhaps our friend
Ravenhurst fears an alliance
would put Griswold and not
himself at the king's right hand!
You shall die for this!
One of us will!
Stop! Stop! Stop, I say!
Put up your
sword, you fool.
Sire! -Silence!  -But sire! -Silence!
-Your pardon, sire.
And you, too. Must we
quarrel amongst ourselves?
Do you think I
could make alliance?
Griswold is rich.
What could I offer him?
That which he desires most
in the world. Marriage, sire.
With your daughter,
the fair Gwendolyn.
Marriage with
Griswold? Never!
What's that you say?
He's a brute and a lout!
Brute or not, lout or not, if I
so decide, you'll marry Griswold.
I will not.
I am the king. If it pleases me,
you will marry Griswold.
If it pleases you so much,
you marry Griswold.
When I marry,
I marry for love.
Someone dashing
and romantic,
who will carry me off as a
princess should be carried off!
Who fills your head with
this childish fiddle faddle.
Ah, I know... Griselda.
She of the evil eye. Take
the witch out and burn her!
Harm one hair of her head and I
throw myself from the highest turret.
Gwendolyn, you go too far!
Dire news, sire! I've just come
from the forest. The child lives!
The child lives?!
Aye, sire.
How know you that this is the royal
child and not some outrageous impostor?
Because sire, disguised as a
member of their group, I saw him.
And I can assure you that
like his royal ancestors,
and on the same spot
as his royal ancestors,
he bears the royal birthmark.
The... purple pimpernel?
The purple pimpernel.
Oh... Then why stand you here,
you incompetent Jackalings?
To  horse! To the forest!
Cut them down!
Kill the infamous child who
claims to be the rightful king.
And destroy forever this traitorous
fiend who calls himself the Black Fox!
Hawkins! Hawkins! Come here!
Hawkins, you hurted yourself ?
Are you all right, Hawkins?
Come here!
Sir.
Hawkins, how many times have
I told you to stay out of my clothes?
And who are
these little people?
Oh, these are
my friends, sir.
They used to work
with me at the carnival.
They're the finest troupe of
acrobats and tumblers in all of England.
But why did you
bring them here?
Well they too would be
part of our group, sir.
They feel strongly as we
do about the tyranny,
and would join in
our worthy cause.
Sir.
Well, captain?
The new recruits
are arriving, sir.
Good. Hawkins,
I don't mean to be disparaging
to your little friends,
but weapons
are limited and...
Oh oh, I didn't intend
for them to fight, sir, I..
I merely thought that they would take
over my chores of entertaining the men.
Then perhaps I'd be free
to bear arms myself,sir,
and come to grips
with the enemy.
Face to face and steel to
steel. Fist to fist, sir.
Hmph.
Little friends, I'm sorry,
but food and weapons are
limited so you see, uh...
We'll do anything for Hawkins,
sir. He always was our friend.
I'm sorry, there's no
time to discuss it.
Please go quickly
and without detection.
Well, if you ever
need us, call us!
Thank you, I shall.
Bye Hawkins!
Hawkins! The recruits will be
here in a moment. Get the child.
Child... er...
I hate to keep
mentioning this, sir...
Just get the child!
Well, sir, you know I'd do
anything for his majesty, but,
don't you think it look
better if a woman were...
Tend to your duty!
And get out of my clothes!
Yes sir.
Majesty!
Your majesty.
Sir.
Don't you think it
really would, look better
if this kind of thing
were done by a woman?
I've told you repeatedly, Hawkins.
Each one serves as best he can.
I know, sir, but when I ran away from
the carnival, sir, and joined your group,
I thought I'd be in the thick of it.
Robbing the rich and giving to the poor.
Sir!
Our presence is known.
The king's men are on their way!
We must disperse!
Maid Jean. - Yes, sir.
You will see that the child is
transported to the abbey in Dover.
The usual method?
- The usual method.
Come, Hawkins.
- Yes, captain.
The rest of you disperse!
Hawkins, hurry!
I'm putting the last
touches on, right now.
Don't just stand there,
man! Make haste!
There.
Why do you stare?
I... Beg pardon,
captain, but, I'm...
I'm sorry, captain, but
I didn't mean to stare.
Each time I see
you as a woman, sir,
I mean with your
flowing hair...
Conceal the child! Quickly!
Yes, captain.
The king's men.
You know what
to do, Hawkins.
Yes, captain. I'll try.
Ho there! Hold I say!
Come down old man, we would
talk to you. You too, wench.
What's that?
Hurry along, this
is king's business!
What's the meaning of this?
- Come on!
W...what's the meaning of this?
What do you want of us?
Where go you, ancient one?
Who are you?
- What's that?
- Who are you?
What's... what's that?
- Who ARE YOU?
Fine, thank you.
- No! No, no. WHO?
Who! -Who, -who. -Who. -who.
I am Foltzingdale
uh the wine merchant,
and this is my
little granddaughter.
Uh poor child,
she's a mute,
she neither speaks nor hears
except through my fingers.
Child, the... No,
no, here child,
these, these are the king's
men. Men of the king!
Eh.. she says long live
the king and down with his..
long live the kind
and down with his..
Long..
little harder, dear.
long live the king
and down with his..
not quite so hard... long live the
king and down with his enemies.
Enough!
Have you seen a group
in the forest with a child?
Uh what's that? What? What?
- A child! A child!
A child. Child. Oh! Lovely child,
pretty little creature, isn't it?
But you stay
away from her!
No, no no no, a child! So big!
Uh with a little mark on...
You do and I'll break
every bone in your body!
Ask the... Ask the girl if she's
seen a group in the forest.
Uh what's that? what?
Ask the girl if she's seen
a group in the forest.
Eh why didn't I what?
Ask the girl if she's seen
a group in the forest!
No need to holler, sir,
I hear very well indeed!
Well ask her!
- Ask her what?
If she's seen a
group in the forest?
Uh y-yes... child, have you
seen a group in the forest?
Eh she says no.
What took her so long?
Stutters.
Tah, we waste time with these dolts.
On your way. Off with you!
Oh, he's quite all right.
You were excellent,
Hawkins.
You too, captain. We played our
parts extremely well, I thought.
You know, we should spend a lot more
time together. Uh, for rehearsal, I mean.
There's a storm brewing. We'll
spend the night in the woodman's hut.
Yes, captain.
I'll take you dreaming
through the rainy night
to a place behind the raindrops
where the stars are bright.
you may not find gold or
silver but a richer prize
waits for you behind the
raindrops if you'll close your eyes.
tonight, tonight when
all the world's asleep.
we will tip toe home with a wondrous
star, a star you can always keep.
and years from now when you
go dreaming when you're very old,
though your crown be rich with
rubies, diamonds set in gold.
none will shine as bright
as the star we'll find
tonight.
tonight, tonight when
all the world's asleep,
we will find a star that
you can always keep.
His majesty's asleep, now.
You better get some sleep, too.
Over there.
Uh, there's only room for one...
I... I think you'd better take it.
We can both lie there.
If you get wet and ill, you'll be
no use to his majesty at all.
Lie down.
Yes, captain.
Wet.
Very.
There'd be more room if
you raised your arm.
The other one.
Sorry.
Hawkins.
Yes, captain.
I'm sorry I... I spoke
in the manner I did.
I was wrong.
Y-yes, captain?
There's something
else I'd like to say.
Yes?
I am a woman.
And I do have feelings.
I... I find it hard
to believe that..
the captain could ever be fond
of a man who isn't a fighter.
Sometimes tenderness and
kindness can also make a man.
A very rare man.
Could the captain...
Could the captain ever entertain
thoughts of marriage with such a man?
Yes, Hawkins.
I think she could, and would.
If things were different.
How di-different?
The infant on the throne and...
Our fight for freedom won.
Why does such a little girl
have to do such a big job?
It's the way I
was brought up.
My father's influence. You see,
my father made me everything I am.
He does beautiful work.
He taught me how to love
freedom and hate injustice.
The use of weapons
and how to fight.
In fact, I think he...
he really wanted
me to be a boy.
Too bad. You'd've made
a wonderful girl.
No! We daren't think of
ourselves until our fight is won.
Yes, but that could take
twenty years or more.
Or twenty hours. If only we could
put our plan into operation.
Plan? Do we
have a p-plan?
A handful of men could overthrow
the castle in a matter of hours.
Yes.
You see, there's a secret
passage that starts in the forest,
and tunnels underneath
the walls of the castle.
Secret passage.
But it's locked at both ends and
the key is in the king's possession.
The king's possession, yeah.
If only we could have
someone inside the castle;
an intimate of the king,
with access to his chambers.
Mm-hmm, with access to his
chambers. But, but that's impossible.
Ah, good evening! A thousand
apologies for this uh intrusion,
but may I beg shelter and warmth
from this miserable storm?
Who are you?
A stranger in this land,
young woman, but not for long.
I'm Giacomo of the continent,
the king's new jester.
The court jester.
Giacomo?
Giacomo the incomparable!
King of jesters, and jester of kings.
Well where are you from?
Most recently the Italian court.
But I have entertained in
all the courts of Europe,
and speak a ready wit
in their every tongue.
Hawkins, we are indeed honored
that our humble hut will shelter one,
will tomorrow be an
intimate of the king.
With access to his chambers.
But how will they know you?
Are you sure that no one in the
castle has ever seen your face?
Not yet! But I assure you,
ere another sun has set,
the entire court of England
will succumb to the charm,
wit, and song of the incomparable
Giacomo, king of jesters..
...And jester to the king!
I'll take the child
to the abbey.
You must go to the castle at once.
Quickly, into his clothes!
W-what are we going
to do about him?
I'll notify the fox,
he'll be taken care of.
Now listen, listen carefully.
Once inside the castle,
you must get to the king's chamber,
and find the key to the secret passage.
Key to the passage. Right.
Then you must give it to the one man
inside the castle who's our confederate.
- Confederate.
You mean we already have somebody
inside the castle? One of our own people?
You will contact him by
whistling our secret call.
Whistle it, hum it, sing it.
But I don't understand,
if we already have somebody inside
the castle, why doesn't he get the key?
You'll understand when you see him.
Now, he'll hear that and identify himself.
Why can't you just
tell me his name?
Should they discover you, they
might force you to reveal his identity.
Okay, I'd like to ask
you one question.
After months of pleading
for just this kind of action,
what makes you think that anybody ..anybody
could force me reveal the identity of my confederate?
Because they'd put you on the rack,
crack your every bone, scald you with hot oil,
and remove the nails off your
fingers with flaming hot pincers.
I'd... Like to withdraw the question.
Hawkins, the future of England
depends on this; you cannot fail.
I will not.
Oh heaven help you.
Now remember from this moment on,
you're no longer Hubert
Hawkins the carnival entertainer;
You're the incomparable Giacomo,
king of jesters and jester to the king.
Jester to the king.
To the king!?
The child escapes. You hear that,
Ravenhurst? The child escapes.
Gwendolyn, dear, do
stop picking that thing.
The revolt spreads.
Brockhurst here says
alliance with Griswold,
Finsdale says alliance,
Pertwee says alliance,
and yet you, Ravenhurst,
you of all my ministers...
Sire. If my lords Brockhurst, Finsdale,
and Pertwee plead so strongly for alliance,
then by all means let us have such alliance.
A marriage between Sir Griswold
and the princess Gwendolyn.
You are quite right.
Never! Never marriage with Griswold!
Be sensible. - Sensible!
I've seen this monster, and it's not for nothing
he's called the grim and gruesome grisly Griswold.
Grim, grisly or gruesome,
you'll marry Griswold!
I'll die first.
Go to your chambers!
Good, it is done.
Arrange for the wedding
directly after the tournament.
We'll make a show of this.
You there! Go hence.
Scour the countryside.
Bring in the fairest
wenches in the land.
Mind you see that
they are the fairest.
Wenches, laughter, song,
that's what this court needs!
Indeed, sire! And the good
Giacomo will provide it.
Giacomo? Who is Giacomo?
He's the new
jester I've sent for.
By reputation the gayest and
wittiest entertainer in Europe.
Splendid! Ha ha! What
a festival this will be.
Jousting by our boldest knights.
Wenches at our beck and call.
My daughter married to Griswold,
who will take her to a castle up north.
Way up north! But gentle
lords, you make me very happy.
They have won.
For the moment, yes. The king is
guided by the last voice he hears,
and that voice shall be mine.
Giacomo will see to that.
Giacomo? A mere jester?
With one special talent for which
my agent has bargained dearly.
In addition to his brilliance
as an entertainer,
the jester Giacomo also happens
to be the world's most skillful,
devious, and subtle master
of the art of assassination.
So as Hawkins becomes the incomparable
Giacomo and heads for the castle,
while the maid Jean with the infant
king still hidden in the wine cask,
journeys towards the abbey
and safety for the child.
Their plan seems simple enough,
but the simplest plans so often go a miss.
For at the very moment
Hawkins was delayed on the road,
the maid Jean was to run
afoul of the king's men,
who were scouring the countryside
for the fairest wenches in the land.
And so Jean and
the precious wine cart,
were taken to the castle before Hawkins
had even finished repairing his wheel.
Ho there!
What's that?
Welcome Giacomo! We have come
to escort you to the castle, w..
Haven't we met before?
Ah... it's not very likely,
my good man, you see,
I'm on my way back
from the Italian court.
How speak you the king's
English with no trace of accent?
Ah my dear sir, Giacomo is a master
of many many tongues indeed.
French: Je le parle le fleur
ce magnifique, le romantique..
Italian:
German: Was haben Sie ausgehšbn
in das Kneibinbabn? Das Schmerz...
which means in any language,
why tarry? Let us off to the castle!
Off to the castle!
- Off to the castle!
To the castle.
Quick! The infant!
The infant? Where?
Off of the main!
The child is in the cask.
In the cask?
You must take him to the jester.
But the jester
hasn't arrived, yet.
Something must
have gone wrong.
You look after the child,
I'll have to get the key myself.
But how? - I don't...
Come along there, wench!
My heart knows a lovely song...
So this is the incomparable Giacomo.
He looks not at all like what I expected.
And this singing peacock will
still the voices of Brockhurst,
Finsdale, and Pertwee?
Before midnight, if
he fulfills his bargain.
You sent for me, my lady?
Lock it.
What is it, child?
Something wrong, my lady?
Drink! A brew of
your own concocting.
Before I marry Griswold, I
will die, and so will you. Drink!
No! Don't despair, child.
You will not marry Griswold.
I've told you. It was
written in the stars.
Your true love will come
yet, I promise you!
Drink! You lie.
Would I lie to you, child? Your own
Griselda? Look at me! Look in my eyes!
Try not your wiles on me, Witch!
Too often have I seen people look in
those eyes and fall under your evil spell.
You will die for your deceit!
Filling my head with fairy
stories of a romantic lover.
A lover who would carry me away
from this monstrous castle!
And so he shall! He
comes, even now!
You lie!
No, I swear it,
your highness, look!
If this be another
one of your tricks...
Trust me, look. Look,
near the drawbridge.
King of jesters, jester of kings.
He is most fair of countenance.
Oh yes he is!
Handsome of bearing. -Like Apollo of
the Greeks! -A figure of romance.
Sent by the gods,
and for you alone!
Now mark this, creature of evil.
If this be not my true love,
and I am faced with
marriage to Griswold,
you will die, and by my hand.
Fear not, m'lady, your lover will
be here, in this room, within the hour.
And he will prove that
his is a mission of love.
For your sake, dear
Griselda, he had better.
I am Giacomo, Giacomo,
my fame before me rings,
a king of jesters, and jester of kings!
my heart knows a
lovely song.. heh heh..
it whistles it all day long
Giacomo is my nom de plume,
I whistle and hum
but I hum to whom?
To whom do I hum, to whom?
My song of love let
the whole world hear
until that sweet moment,
that moment when you appear,
I'll whisper it in your ear,
I bid you welcome!
I am Ravenhurst.
Ravenhurst Ravenhurst?
Uh the real Ravenhurst?
What?
Does the king know? I mean does the king
know about your being the real Ravenhurst?
Keep your jests for the king.
Don't stand there gaping!
You, Fergus and the others,
get the jester's bags!
You arrived not a
moment too soon.
When do we start?
- Tonight.
Good. I'd like to get in, get on with it,
get it over with, and get out. Get it?
Got it. - Good.
That was an interesting
song you sing.
Thank you, I'm glad
you liked it, old man.
Did it go like this?
Ostle about your business!
What is the first step?
Get me to the king's chambers.
The king's chambers?
- Yes...
Very well, if you say so.
It may be the Key to
the whole plan, get it?
Got it. - Good.
Yes, yes, I'll take
Griswold's emissaries,
but for the moment there
are other matters...
I understand the wenches have
arrived. Where are they?
What have we here?
Uh, Sire, may I present
the incomparable Giacomo.
Uh, king of jesters,
and jester of kings.
Oh, yes! From Italy. I haven't
been there for years.
Tell me, how go things
at the Italian court?
Ah very well indeed, sire.
Splendid, splendid. what about
all those stories we've heard?
Wasn't it awful about
the Duchess of Urber ?
Oh, just. Uh, just awful, sire.
I ask you, how could a
thing like that happen?
Well, sire, you know the Italian court;
what better place to court Italians?
Italian court? Court Italians!
Ah, Ravenhurst, the fellow
has wit! Ah, I must say,
I was shocked to hear about the
Duchess. What did the Duke do?
Pardon?
The Duke. What did
the Duke do?
Eh... the Duke do?
Yes. And what
about the Douge ?
Oh, the Douge!
Eh. Well what did
the Douge do?
The Douge do?
- Yes, the Douge do.
Well, uh, the Douge did what
the Douge does. Eh, uh,
Oh, when the Douge does his
duty to the Duke, that is.
What? What's that?
Oh, it's very simple, sire.
When the Douge did his
duty and the Duke didn't,
that's when the Duchess did the
dirt to the Duke with the Douge.
Who did what to what?
Oh, they all did, sire. There
they were in the dark;
The Duke with his dagger, the Douge
with his dart, Duchess with her dirk.
Duchess with her dirk?
- Yes!
The Duchess dove at the Duke just
when the Duke dove at the Douge.
Now the Duke ducked, the Douge
dodged, and the Duchess didn't.
So the Duke got the Duchess, the Duchess
got the Douge, and the Douge got the Duke!
Curious. I... I... hm?
What? What's that?
All I heard was that the Duchess had a
siege of rheumatism. She's 83, you know.
Oh, come next summer, sire.
So's the Duke.
- So's the Duke.
Remarkable, those Italians, what?
Made the whole thing
up, didn't you? Ho ha.
Very witty, very clever.
Just what this court needs
Laughter, gaiety, songs,
wenches... oh, yes. Wenches.
I'm just on my way to
inspect the lot of them.
Who knows, I may
find some luscious...
Oh, sire.
If I may suggest, it ill befits the
propriety of your high office
to be seen with these
unkempt wenches. - Wha...?
It is said the incomparable Giacomo
has a discerning eye for beauty.
Eh, why not let him select a
suitable companion for your majesty?
Excellent! Excellent!
I trust the jester's reputation is based
on many years of accomplishment?
Why do you think they call
me incomparable, sire? Get it?
Got it. - Good.
Bring her to my chambers.
Within the hour?
Within the hour.
Finish with the king and
come to my chambers.
Within the hour.
Eh, about that song, sir...
Some other time, my good man.
Yes, Fergus, get on
with your work!
The good captain will escort you
to your quarters. - Very well.
Are you sure we
haven't met before?
Quite sure.
Within the hour.
Your Giacomo seems more
the fool than the assassin.
Or perchance a brilliant
combination of both.
We shall see.
I'm Giacomo, Giacomo,
my fame before me rings,
king of jesters,
and jester of kings!
What are you doing here?
I'm Fergus, the Ostler.
Whobis the whatsler?
Fergus the Ostler. It is I, not
Ravenhurst who is your friend.
Look, my good man, you pick
your friends and I shall pick mine.
At the moment, I have a very
important mission with the king.
After all, I'm the incomparable Giacomo,
king of jesters and jester of kings.
I have entertained in
all the courts of Europe
and speak a ready wit in their
every tongue. Uh who are you?
I am Griselda.
Gruhwhoolda?
Griselda. I bring you a
message from the princess.
Uh, the royal princess?
She finds you most attractive
and would like to meet you.
M-m-me? - Yes.
She finds you passing
fair, passing graceful.
Oh, uh, tell her thank you very
much but I'm just passing through.
One does not ordinarily
refuse princesses...
Well, one doesn't
ordinarily, but you see...
Is it possible there's someone
else of whom you are fond?
Uh y-yes, as a matter
of fact there is.
Giacomo, would you
look in my eye?
Eye?
Yes, it's been troubling me,
and I thought that the great Giacomo
would have a knowledge of science.
Eh s-science. Well, yes,
as a matter of fact I have a
great deal of scientific knowledge.
We have b-b-which eye?
Both. Look at them both.
Closer, closer. Deeper,
deeper. Deeper, deeper.
Tails of lizards, ears of swine,
chicken gizzards soaked in brine,
now thine eyes and mine
entwine, thy will is broken,
thou are mine!
Repeat after me. I am
craven and thou art my master!
I am craven and
thou art my master!
Stand there, fool.
- Stand there, fool.
Silence! - Silence!
You are in my power and
will obey my every command.
Every command...
And remember,
any time I choose,
a mere snap of my fingers can
bring you out of the spell like this!
And back like that!
Do you understand, fool?
Yes, master. You can snap
me in and snap me out.
Now, listen closely.
First and foremost, you must
convince the girl that this is a miracle,
that you have been
sent here by the gods.
To do that, you must go
to her room and make love!
Go and make love
to the princess!
The princess...
At once! Wait!
Not like that!
You are a figure of romance;
of spirit and action, but at the
same time humble and tender.
You are a man of iron
with the soul of a poet.
You are adventurous, gay, but
with a lovers brooding melancholy,
and above all, you
must show passion!
Show passion!
Not me, you fool!
Now go. Make love.
Climb the vine to the tower
where your love awaits you! Stop!
Above all, remember you
must be cavalier, dashing!
Fear not, master!
Once I'm up the thorny vine,
the regal maiden shall be mine.
Fear not, master!
Hawkins!
You got here!
Well of course I got
here, my silly little goose!
Thank heaven.
Ah-cha-cha, you'll have to
wait your turn like the others!
Good, good, you're doing it well.
But have you heard the
change of plan? Here, take this.
I just told you, dear, you'll
just have to wait your turn.
Now don't overdo it.
Fergus will bring you the infant.
Huh?
Well, well, Giacomo.
Successful so soon?
Truly as dainty a dish as
ever was set before a king.
About your business, I would
have a word with the maid.
Your majesty.
What is your name, child?
Jean, sire.
Jean. Lovely name.
For a lovely face.
See that she is
jeweled and gowned.
She shall sit next to me
at the banquet, tonight.
You! You've come!
At your service, my lady.
So this is Giacomo!
King of jesters
and jester of kings.
Not today, m'lady.
Today I am Giacomo,
a lover of beauty,
and a beauty of a lover.
Can this be true?
Or is it merely a dream?
Dream? Is this a dream?
Or this? Or this? Or this?
Or this? Or this?
No, no, no, we are
strangers, hardly met.
What manner of man
are you, Giacomo?
is Giacomo? Ha ha!
I shall tell you what
manner of man is he.
He lives for a sigh,
he dies for a kiss,
he lusts for the laugh, ha!
He never walks
when he can leap!
he never flees
when he can fight.
He swoons at the
beauty of a rose.
And I offer myself
to you, all of me.
My heart. My lips.
My legs. My calves.
Do what you will..
my love endures.
Beat me. Kick me.
I am yours.
Oh, Giacomo,
you are so ardent!
With your permission, my lady,
I'd like to go 'round again.
Oh, no, Giacomo,
we must be discreet.
Ha! Discretion is for
fools and simpletons!
This cannot be! Miracles
are things of fancy,
and lovers are not
sent by the gods.
Speak not too
lightly, my love.
Who are we to say
nay to miracles?
But one doesn't find love
in one moment, one kiss..
that key? Where
did you find it?
Key? - It is a miracle!
The gods who sent you have also
provided a means for our escape.
This is the key to the
secret passageway.
Grand. We leave at
midnight. Get it?
Got it. - Good.
Very good.
Oh no, my precious,
I'll keep it next to my heart;
a sweet symbol of your love.
And take this, a
sweet symbol of mine.
I'll wear it always
next to my heart.
Gwendolyn?
Are you there? I would
have words with you?
My father. You must hide!
Hide? Giacomo
hides for no man!
But you must! He'd kill any
man found in my chambers.
Ah, be he king or peasant,
my ready blade will find its mark!
I'll... I'll..
I..I live for a sigh, I die for a
laugh, I lust for a laugh, ha ha!
Please! - What?
Or our lives aren't
worth that!
What? Eh, eh? Eh?
Are you alone, my dear?
I thought I heard voices.
Yes, I'm quite alone, father.
The king!
Listen, my child. I've just
met Griswold's emissary,
and the marriage is approved.
You know very well, father,
that when I marry,
I marry only for love.
Heh, heh, I knew you'd say that.
Now, Gwendolyn, do be reasonable.
Don't you realize that without
this alliance, our prestige,
our power, our position
could go like that!
Well, then let it go like that!
I wish you to marry Griswold.
And suppose I do not
wish to marry Griswold?
I don't give a fig
for your wishes!
And I don't give
a fig for yours!
No one snaps at the king!
Don't you dare snap at me!
I'll snap if I choose!
Don't snap at me!
- I will snap!
You won't! Now
understand this, my child.
This castle has walls
high and strong,
with massive gates
under lock and key.
Whilst you remain within
those walls and I am king,
you will obey my command.
Very well, father. Perhaps I have
been selfish and thoughtless.
Oh, my child. I knew I
could depend upon you.
Because you are a princess.
A true princess.
Loyal to the crown.
Sympathetic.
Sensitive. Faithful.
The key to the
secret passage!
Father, let me have it...
So, run away, would you!
Well, you trick me not.
This key will never
leave my person.
You will marry Griswold
upon the morrow,
and I promise you, daughter
or not, princess or not,
one move,  one false move,
and your neck will snap like a twig!
Where is he? Giacomo
hides not behind drapes!
No no no, you must go!
I'll cut him to ribbons.
No, we'll escape tonight
after the banquet.
Very well, my sweet.
Until tonight. Very good.
Do be cautious,
sweet Giacomo!
Ha! Caution is for
popinjays and cockatoos
Begging your pardon.
Until tonight, my sweet.
But you heard what
my father said.
If caught, our necks
will snap like twigs!
Uh... like what?
- Twigs!
Twigs? Speak not of twigs
when you look at an oak!
Until tonight,
my little sapling.
If Giacomo says he will
be here within the hour,
he will be here...
eh, within the hour!
At your service, m'lord!
Your arrival, good Giacomo,
shows imagination and brilliance.
Did you expect less?
Are you now prepared to fulfill
the bargain arranged by my agent,
Sir Burton of Allenburg?
- Quite.
Very well, then.
There are two plans.
Two plans.
- Plan one.
The untimely demise of my lords
Brockhurst, Finsdale, and Pertwee.
These three
will die tonight.
Three for tonight. Proceed.
The method I leave to you.
But die they must.
Heh! They shall
drop like flies.
Precisely. Like flies.
Do you have some
sort of twitch?
Twitch? I twitch
only for action.
I live for a sigh,
I die for a kiss.
I like that very much.
- Thank you.
I lust for a laugh. Ha ha!
I never leap when I can walk,
I never flee when I can fight!
Yes, but, but...
- I... pardon?
Listen carefully! If plan one fails,
you must execute plan two.
Plan two?
Take the princess from the
castle before midnight.
By whatever means
you may devise.
For murder or abduction,
I'm your man.
You've paid the price;
name your plan.
First, plan one.
Are you sure you can dispose of my
lords Brockhurst, Finsdale, and Pertwee?
Are they married?
Yes...
Order flowers for
the widows. Get it?
Got it. - Good.
Tally ho! Ho ho!
Master, I am Back
- Well?
I have climbed the thorny vine,
and the regal maiden is mine.
Good.
Now, when I release
you from the spell,
you will fall into a deep sleep
and remember nothing.
Nothing...
Look into my eye.
Deeper, deeper.
Ah, my lords.
I understand the marriage
of the princess Gwendolyn to Sir
Griswold will be announced tonight.
My congratulations.
There is something afoot.
He is far too confident.
If this alliance
fails, we are lost.
It must not fail. Let us solemnly
pledge that we will permit nothing,
to interfere with the marriage of
Griswold to the princess Gwendolyn.
I so pledge.
- And I.
Though it cost
our very lives!
Our very lives.
Please, stop your picking and
fussing! I must breathe some air!
But madam!
All afternoon without
a moment's peace!
I just learned of your
whereabouts. What happened...
Never mind that. You must
take the child to the jester.
To the jester!
Immediately. He has the key.
But he's under
the spell of the...
Silence! Give him the child
at once! It is my command.
The jester! Where is the jester?
Summon him immediately!
Very good, sire!
Jester!
- Coming!
Come quickly, man!
The king is waiting!
Yes, uh, ha ha, have you
seen Ravenhurst about?
He's somewhere about, yes.
Well, I was supposed to see Ravenhurst
on some rather urgent business,
but I fell asleep... I don't
quite remember what I...
Ahh, Giacomo. A striking costume,
indeed. From the Italian court, I presume.
Yes, sire, Italian court. Ah, uh,
what better place to, uh...
...court Italians.
Ah, this will be
a festive evening.
Noble knights to joust at
my tournament. Come along.
And by my side a
lovely little wench,
who I'm sure will fulfill every
promise of your discerning eye.
Ah, look at her!
Charming. Charming,
Giacomo, charming.
A tribute to you,
my dear Giacomo.
Come here, my child.
Come.
Your majesty.
Was there ever more beauty?
More radiant? Rise, child.
The sweetness of your smile
outshines the elegance of your gown.
Thank you, sire.
Would you attend me?
You are most gracious, sire.
Quickly. Use the key.
Key?
Remember, plan one
Brockhurst, Finsdale, Pertwee.
Midnight. Horses
at the north gate.
Horses at the north gate...
Summon the jester!
Where are you going?
Didn't you hear the king?
Ah, beh, beh...
Cover your head!
Now get in there!
Come, come, Giacomo, let us
be gay! I would have a song.
Eh. Song.
- Has the cat your tongue?
Uh, no, I...
What do you carry
there? Why the basket?
Beh, basket?
What basket, sire?
What basket, indeed!
Come, boy, come, show me
what you have in the basket.
Wuh, I can... eh...
Yes, come on, show me what
you have in the basket.
Eh, beh basket? It-it's...
Yes, and what about that song?
S-s-song, sire? Eh beh s-song.
If your majesty doth ask it,
I will tell about the basket with a
willo willo wailey and a nonny nonny
What's that?
With a what?
Uh with a willo willo wailey and
a nonny nonny loo loo loo
I'll loo loo loo loo...
What are you
loo-loo-looing about?
Oh, I'm not loo-loo-looing,
sire, I'm willo willo wailing.
All right, all right,
willo away, willo away.
We will willo it away...
we'll willo willo willo
we will willo it away!
with a willo willo wailey,
we will sing about it gaily,
with a willo willo wailey
and a hey! nonny... no!
Come back here!
What have you there?
What have you
in the basket?
Eh beh basket? Oh,
b- sire, it's nothing, sire.
Merely a jester's
bag of tricks, sire.
It's a secret, sire.
Y-yes, a deep,
dark secret - beh -
which has never before been
revealed to anybody in the world, sire.
But I...
I am prepared
to make a statement.
I was a lad, I was gloomy and sad as
I was from the day I was born!
When other babes giggled and gurgled
and wiggled I proudly was loudly forlorn!
My friends and my family looked at me
clammily, thought there was something amiss!
When others found various antics
hilarious, all I could manage was this!
or this!
My father, he shouted
He needs to be clouted.
His teeth on a
wreath I'll hand him!
My mother she cried as
she rushed to my side.
You're a brute! and you
don't understand him!
So they sent for a witch
with a terrible twitch
to ask how my
future impressed her.
She took one look
at me and cried he...
hee hee hee.. he?
What else could he
be but a jester?
A jester? A jester?
A funny idear a jester!
No butcher, no baker,
no candlestick maker
and me with the look of a fine
undertaker impressed her...
as a jester?
But where could I learn any comical
turn that was not in a book on the shelf?
No teacher to take me to mold me
and make me a merry mad fool or an elf!
But I'm proud to recall that in no
time at all with no other recourses
but my own resources with firm
application and determination...
I made a fool of myself!
I found a bow and arrow
and I learned to shoot.
I found a little horn
and I learned to too.
Now I can shoot and
too, ain't I cute?
(no end of song)
Tend to your duties!
Serve your drinks!
Hold it with that basket.
Let's have a look!
A toast! A toast!
A toast to his most
royal highness!
To Roderick the first, for all that he
has done for this great England of ours,
may providence provide
a true and just reward!
To the king!
Brockhurst!
Brilliant.
Finsdale!
Magnificent!
Pertwee!
Fantastic!
Brockhurst, Finsdale, Pertwee...
They are all dead, sire!
As you said, flowers
for the widows.
Dead. Murdered.
And by whose hand?
And who may be next?
Sir Griswold of Mackalwane
is approaching the castle!
And just in time. He comes
not a moment too soon.
Bid Sir Griswold enter!
Plan two.
Plan two?
Get those bodies out of here!
Quick, take him to safety.
...And get those goblets away.
And... no! Not you, jester, not you.
Come here, come here,
boy, come here.
Sir Griswold of Mackalwane!
Approach, Sir Griswold.
Lighten the mood,
jester, a note of...
My liege lord.
Sir Griswold of Mackalwane,
I bid thee welcome.
Ehh, a-welcome, Sir Griswold,
your beard is full of hair,
but do I say welcome
or do I say mehh!
Sire. My emissary did report.
And I proudly
accept your terms.
Eh... th-the terms! the terms!
He doth accept the terms.
He looks not smart, but in...
Excellent, excellent!
Members of the court,
know you that the crown would
make a most felicitous announcement,
concerning the defense and
security of our great kingdom,
I would have you know that
today was an alliance consummated,
between the crown and our
honored and valiant Baron,
Sir Griswold of Mackalwane.
Uh, the terms! the terms!
We've already had the terms.
Sorry.
To cement this alliance,
I have decreed a royal marriage,
between Sir Griswold of Mackalwane,
and Gwendolyn the Fair.
Eh, eh rejoice! rejoice!
Although his brain is brief,
for when the larder's empty,
she'll have her ton of beef!
Would you like to try
the other side, sire?
Thank you, sire.
What say our gallant Griswold?
Sire. Princess fair.
From this moment on,
this hand, this steel, this heart,
will exist for naught
but the love of the lady...
Save your breath, Griswold!
There will be no alliance and no marriage.
What's that?
I cannot marry Griswold,
father. I love another.
Another?
Another, another...
What is this nonsense?
What do you mean you love another?
Simply that, father. A miracle has
occurred to fulfill my every dream.
I have found my love,
father. My true love.
Who is this man?
One to whom I have given
my heart and my hand.
He who even now wears my silken
handkerchief next to his heart.
What's that?
- What's that?
Ah.. Her heart, her hand,
she holds for joy or grief,
but he who holds her hand
holds her heart kerchief.
eh handkerchief,
eh hand kerheart,
heart ke he
che ha- hah,
Who is this man? His name!
The man I love is a simple
man, but noble of heart.
My beloved Giacomo!
- What?!
Uh. His name, his name,
and now his blood must flow.
Light up the oil, this man must boil,
this man named Giaco- mo? oh! No!
Seize this wretch and search him!
Eh... I- I'm- Th-th-this
is a little mistake, sire.
I don't have  her heartkerchief,
uh, handkerheart. I don't have th..
A handkerchief!
G! Gwendolyn!
Uh, n-n-no, sire.
Geh-Gee G-G-Giacomo!
Shield me not, sweet Giacomo!
Our love makes me strong.
Love for a common jester.
Take the swine out and hang him!
Harm one hair of that majestic head and
I throw myself from the highest turret!
Enough of this!
How much insult must
I endure? Come, men.
Hold, Sir Griswold, your
honor will be avenged.
How?
Were that wretch of noble rank,
I would challenge him to combat mortal!
But I would not deign to soil my
blade with his miserable common blood!
H-he's right, you know, sire.
Rules of chivalry, you know.
Rules of chivalry be
hanged! And so will you.
She'll jump...!
Come, men.
Hold, Sir Griswold. You will stay
until the morrow. It is my command.
'till the morrow, sire.
- You, Gwendolyn, to your chambers.
Be brave, sweet Giacomo.
Throw this blackguard in chains!
Is he not fabulous?
Go from plan one to plan
two without a moment's pause.
The man is pure genius.
Sir Griswold will never
tolerate this insult.
M'lords, to your chambers.
Ponder this problem.
A solution must be found ere
we meet in council, tomorrow.
Sire.
Welcome, Sir Burton!
You saw the jester's performance?
When I sent you to
negotiate for Giacomo,
I never expected results
like this! Was he not brilliant?
Indeed.
With one slight discrepancy.
This man is not Giacomo!
What?!
I know not this pretender,
but I assure you
he is not the Giacomo I met
and negotiated with in Europe!
I tell you I've seen this man
before, and somehow that maid!
Did I tell you?
What plan now?
To my chambers, immediately!
But if he's not Giacomo, who could
he be, and what does he want?
Why would he do
our every bidding?
Why would he work to
destroy the alliance?
Why would he murder
with the cunning of a fox?
A fox.
But of course, a fox!
A Black Fox!
But you don't think that...
Why not? Who else
would oppose Griswold
and want the alliance destroyed
but that rabble in the forest?
The forest. That's
where I saw him.
Dressed as an old man,
riding out of the forest,
with the very wench who
sat beside the king, tonight!
My lords... what a prize!
The Black Fox, himself!
Expose him! You'll
get all the credit!
Not so fast.
Not until the Fox pays
us one more service.
He'll rid us forever of
the barbaric Griswold!
Kill Griswold? But how?
Whose is the deadliest
blade in England?
Who is the only man alive who
can best Griswold in mortal combat?
Only the Black Fox!
But the Fox is a commoner
and cannot fight in tournament.
We shall see.
No, Ravenhurst,
I do not understand.
What do you mean Griswold
himself suggested a solution?
You yourself heard him, sire.
He said were the
jester of noble rank,
he would challenge
him to mortal combat.
But the jester cannot fight in
tournament! He's a commoner.
Then, sire,
knight the jester.
Knight the jester?!
Griswold can then challenge him for
the hand of the princess Gwendolyn,
and by the rules of chivalry,
she must wed the victor!
Knight the jester.
Sir Griswold will challenge him.
He dare not refuse.
They meet at the
tournament, tomorrow,
Sir Griswold's  lance
runs the jester through,
and the marriage and
the alliance proceed.
Yea? Hm. Ha!
Ha! Magnificent!
Thank you, sire.
But your majesty,
knighthood is an arduous ritual!
It will take three years
to knight the jester.
Three years? Nonsense!
Ravenhurst,
take that nincompoop,
and knight that nincompoop
by noon tomorrow!
Sire.
By order of his
sovereign majesty,
the jester Giacomo shall enter
upon a series of tests of manhood,
skill, and courage requisite to
his becoming a knight of the realm.
M-me a knight? But why?
To make you eligible for the
hand of the princess Gwendolyn.
M-marry the princess? W-when?
Upon your passing
each and every test.
Oh! Well that's different.
It takes four or five years
to become a knight, doesn't it?
We shall see.
Let the tests begin!
Uh, w-wait! What's
the hurry? I- b- ch-
He must scale a stone
wall in full armor!
Candidate passes!
Uh, b- buh... I didn't...!
With long bow, he must
slay a hawk in full flight!
He passes!
But I didn't even shoot...
The candidate passes!
But I didn't even shoot
the arrow! The arrow...
I- I didn't pass...!
The candidate must conquer
a wild boar with his bare hands!
Release the boar!
He passes!
No one enters by
the king's command!
But this is the
king's command.
Ah, maid Jean. Welcome.
What brings you here at this hour?
Concern for you, sire. - Mm?
You were so distressed last evening,
that I thought perhaps
I could comfort you,
ease the burdens of state.
Eh, don't tug it, idiot! Well that's
very considerate of you, my dear.
I shall take advantage
of your delightful offer...
perhaps this evening?
Why tarry, sire?
I am most accomplished
on matters of appearance,
and would gladly free these young men
for more important chores, elsewhere.
Well that's very
kind of you, but...
oh, yes. Pages,
I'm sure you have some very
important business to attend.
Now, then, sire, we have to
get you ready for the ceremony!
Ah, but my dear...
- Now there.
You can't imagine my feelings,
when I touch the head of a man
who calles himself the king of England.
Who IS the King of England!
And very handsome, too, sire.
On the day of your first
tournament. There you are.
Where?
Now I must go, sire.
Oh, now wait, dear, wait.
Oh, no, you have to
get to your ceremony!
But there's no hurry. We can't
start until the jester's been made ready.
The jester?!
Yes, haven't you heard?
We're knighting the poor fool.
Knighting the jester!
Yes, you'd
never guess why.
So that he can
marry the princess.
Well, that's the fool thinks,
but the moment I dub him knight,
Griswold will challenge him
for the hand of my daughter.
Mortal combat.
Yes, isn't it delicious?
He dare not refuse,
they meet at lists, and Sir Griswold's
lance runs the jester through,
as a fitting climax
to a glorious day.
Oh, my dear, you are a
delicate, lovely creature.
Tell me, does it bother you that I
may be a few years your senior?
Oh, no, sire, not really.
In fact, you remind me so much of my
dear and recently departed father.
Oh, your father, yes.
Well, was he a handsome figure
of a man? Dashing, effective...
Oh, yes, sire, 'till the scourge
brought about his untimely end.
Eh, come here, my dear.
- What a horrible death!
A little closer...
I can see him now, writhing
on the floor in agony,
like so many of his brothers and
cousins and uncles and aunts...
Yes. Would you grant
the king a little kiss?
Oh, certainly, sire, and don't
worry. They say it isn't catching.
Oh, you are a little...
catching?
Just because it runs in the family
doesn't mean that everyone has it.
Kiss me sire!
Has it? Has what?
Don't I please you, sire?
Oh, yes, yes, but, eh, these
brothers and cousins and uncles...
And aunts. Let us not talk about
their swollen, twisted, pain ridden bodies.
Hold me, take me in your
arms, tell me I am yours!
But this, this uh
writhing on the floor...
In agony.
Yes, wh-what's... how
does one catch this thing?
Oh, the touch of a hand,
the brush of a lip...
but let us not spoil this moment,
sire! Hold me, hold me close!
W-what's this
monstrous thing called?
Breckenridge's scourge.
Who's Breckenridge?
My father.
Excuse me, dear, I'm
feeling rather poorly.
Sire, the ceremony is ready.
Oh, very well. Ah, I must go, now,
my dear, and so must- so must you.
Quickly.
Dear... don't touch me.
Where's the jester?
Did you get the key?
- Yes, here it is.
It must be sent by pigeon
to the Black Fox at once!
Let the jester take it and
escape. They plan to kill him.
It'd never there in time.
The bird's our only chance.
He who approacheth, deem you
him worthy of noble knighthood?
Yea, verily, yea!
How many more
before the jester?
Just this one, sire.
...Fealty, loyalty, moisten his
lips with the vigorous wine.
Yea, verily, yea!
Now as the symbol
of honor and dignity,
let us beplume him
and helmet his brow.
Yea, verily, yea!
Sire, this storm bodes ill.
It might drench the field
and delay the tournament.
Fetch the jester and run him through
the ritual as quickly as possible.
But sire, custom...
Custom be hanged! Fetch
him and run him through!
A message for the
jester. From the king.
He requests you
do this at once.
At w-once.
He who approacheth, deem you
him ready for noble knighthood.
Yea! - Y-yea.
Hath he passed all test of valor?
Yea, verily, yea!
Now doth he flower with true nobility?
Reveal him now to his sovereign liege.
Yea, verily, yea! Yea?
Faster. - Faster.
- Faster.
B-but I!
...Fealty, loyalty, moisten his
lips with the vigorous wine.
Now  will he pledge to his
fealty, loyalty, courage,
and vigor and valor
and strength! - Yea!
Now as the symbol of honor and dignity,
let us beplume him and helmet his brow.
Yea, verily, yea!
He who is girded and
plumed and helmeted,
Let him prepare...
Considering the virtuous
fidelity you have shown,
and the honorable exploits
that you have done,
having given proof of that honor,
having given proof of that honor...
as always as is the part of
a good and faithful subject,
I hereby dub thee
knight of the realm,
defender of the soil,
protector of the crown,
and a fit consort for the
princess Gwendolyn the fair.
Arise, Sir Giacomo.
Now, if  any knight present
objects to this marriage,
let him now step forward
or forever hold his tongue.
I.
I, Griswold of Mackalwane
do so object.
Very good,
'dya hear that, sire?
I too love the princess and
would fight for her heart.
I hereby challenge in
mortal combat Giacomo!
Giacomo! Knight of the
realm! Defender of the soil!
And protector of the crown!
Woo!
You won't have to fight,
I'll send a message,
the Black Fox will come
and fight in your place!
The Black Fox?
Get up, accept
the challenge!
Uh... Black Fox,
huh? Eh...
he'll come and fight
in my place? - Yes.
You're sure he'll come?
Well, if it's mortal combat you want,
then mortal combat you shall have,
and at the hands of Giacomo,
knight of the realm,
defender of the soil,
protector of the crown...
protector of the crown!
Oo, oh.
Good stock.
Good battle. Good bye!
Your escorts to see
you safely to the lists.
The the lists?
Very clever, father.
Well, chivalry is
chivalry, you know.
Yes, I know.
May the best man win.
Remember this..
if he dies, you die.
To the Fox, at once!
We have bigger game.
Get him!
Griswold has challenged the
jester to mortal combat.
The jester! - Yes
The maid Jean requests that
you come and fight in his stead.
The timbers have fallen and
great rocks block the passage!
Can it be cleared?
- Impossible!
With no passage, we
can make no diversion,
and with no
diversion, no attack!
Is there any opening?
No more than that, sir.
Barely enough for a child!
A child, a child...
or perhaps...! My horse!
Where go you?
To save Hawkins?
No, to save England!
Then Hawkins must die!
Yes. But if my plan succeeds,
I assure you, Hubert Hawkins
will not have died in vain!
By order of his sovereign lord
highness, King Roderick the First,
this royal tournament
is officially begun!
Where's the Black Fox
What's delayed him?
There's rain in the hills,
perhaps the river is swollen.
He'll be taking the coast road.
You better have a look.
Good stock.
The first contest will be
a battle to the death
for the hand of
the fair Gwendolyn.
It will be fought by Sir Griswold of
Mackalwane and Sir Giacomo of Italy.
These two bold knights
will choose weapons,
and enter upon
the field of honor,
and fight in mortal combat
until one of them lies dead.
Run for your life.
No, they'd... they'd only
catch me and kill me.
Can you ever forgive me?
There's nothing to forgive.
Dear Hawkins.
Sir Giacomo! You
should be in armor!
And you, maid
Jean, in the stands.
If I die, just pray
that I die bravely.
You'll not die, you'll
not have to fight him.
Griswold dies as
he drinks the toast.
What?
Listen. I have put a pellet of
poison in one of the vessels.
Which one? - The one with
the figure of a pestle.
The vessel with
the pestle? - Yes.
But you don't want the
vessel with the pestle,
you want the chalice
from the palace!
I-I don't want the
vessel with the pestle,
I want the chalice
from the what?
The chalice from the palace!
It's a little crystal chalice
with a figure of a palace.
Th-the chalice from the palace
have the pellet with the poison?
No, the pellet with the poison's
in the vessel with the pestle.
Oh, oh, the pestle
with the vessel.
The vessel with the pestle.
What about the palace
from the chalice?
Not the palace from the chalice!
The chalice from the palace!
Where's the pellet
with the poison?
In the vessel with the pestle!
Don't you see? The pellet with the
poison's in the vessel with the pestle.
The chalice from the palace
has the brew that is true!
It's so easy, I can say it!
Well then you fight him!
Listen carefully.
The pellet with the poison's
in the vessel with the pestle,
the chalice from the palace
has the brew that is true.
Where the pellet with the poison's
in the vessel with the pestle,
the chalice from the palace
has the brew that is true.
Good man!
- Just remember that.
Sir Giacomo!
Sir Giacomo, into your armor!
And you, to your
place in the pavilion.
The pellet with the poison...
the pellet with the poison is
in the vessel with the pestle,
the chalice from the palace
has the true that is brew. Eh...
brew that is tru-
The pellet with the poison's
in the vessel with the pestle,
the chalice from the palace
has the true that is brew.
Eh, brew that is true. Eh.
The chestle with the pal- eh,
eh, palace with the...
Look out!
Hurry, now, get
into your armor!
The pestle with t...
the pellet with the poison's
in the vessel with the pestle,
the palace from the chalice
has the brew that is blue.
Eh, no...
The pellet with the poison's
in the vessel with the pestle.
The cha- eh, the
pellet with the plip...
the pellet with the poisle's in
the vessel with the plazzle.
Eh, the plazzle with the
vlessle. Eh, the the bless...
The vessel with the plozle
is the plazzle with the...
Come along, Sir Giacomo.
His majesty is waiting.
The pestle with the poilet...
And take your helmet!
Thank you.
The pellet with the poisley's
from chalice with the pazley.
Oh, hello, my dear,
it's nice to see y-
I've got it!
I've got it.
The pellet with the poison's
in the vessel with the pestle,
the chalice from the palace has
the brew that is true, right?
Right. But there's
been a change.
They broke the chalice
from the palace.
from the palace?
And replaced it with a flagon.
Flagon.
- With a figure of a dragon.
Flagon with a
dragon. - Right.
Did you put the pellet with the
poison in the vessel with the pestle?
No! The pellet with the poison's
in the flagon with the dragon,
the vessel with the pestle
has the brew that is true!
The pellet with the poison's
in the flagon with the dragon,
the vessel with the pestle
has the brew that is true.
Just remember that.
Yes, thank you very much.
The pellet with the chasley,
eh... the pellet with the poison is
in the pasley with the chazzle.
Eh, just remember that.
Beware of the drinks.
One of them is poisoned.
Poisoned! Are you sure?
I heard the witch.
The poisel with the
plesley is the chaz... eh...
The pellet with the poison's
in the flagon with the dragon,
the pestle with the pizzle...
the pizzle with the f- the,
the, the viss... - No, no, no...
The pellet with the poisley
is the chalice with the... he he
...Vessel with the pestle.
The vessel with the pestle
has the brew that is true.
Right. Don't forget it.
The palace with the
dragon... no, no, no.
The knights will
approach each other!
The pellet with the poisle is
in the flaggle with the chalice.
The poison's in the
dragon with the pestle.
Eh, ah, the chazzle is in the poisley
with the plellice with the plan- eh, plaglice.
The pellet with the dragon's
in the pestle with the poi-
The pezley with the poisle is...
The dragon with the
poisle's in the pestle...
Pazzle with the fleegle...
The poisley with the plazzle
is the plazzle with the ploizle
The chalice with the pa...
the flagon with the cha...
the floizle with the flagon is
the chalice with the poison.
The knights will face the king!
They will approach
the royal pavilion!
The pellet with the poison's
in the flagon with the dragon!
The vessel with the pestle
has the brew that is true!
Oh, no, pglk, you've
got the wrong one!
Stop this mockery!
There will be no toast!
Put them to horse, let them
choose weapons, and fight!
This is the Black Fox?
And still playing the fool.
Sir Griswold! Declare
a choice of weapon!
Mace and chain!
Sir Giacomo! Declare
a choice of weapon.
I'll take one of those,
one of those,
eh, a couple of
those.. and..
I better take them all.
Mace and chain
for him, too!
Charge!
Take that horse and put
it back under that idiot!
Unfasten that perch!
Charge!
All right, Sir Griswold,
prepare to die!
Go ahead, sir knight. Slay me!
You won in fair combat. Strike!
Let rivers of blood wash away
the stain of my disgrace! Go on!
Spew the field with
my dishonored guts!
No!
No, I cannot slay a
man whose only crime,
is that he loved not
too wisely but too well.
I grant your life!
Take your men, and go!
Fergus is dead.
Did he talk?
The child?
In the castle?
Now listen carefully,
there's little time...
Sir Giacomo, I declare
you winner of this combat,
and I hereby decree that you
shall marry the Princess Gwendolyn.
Hold, sire!
Seize this traitor!
Traitor? What's this?
How say you, Ravenhurst?
I say traitor, sire!
And I shall prove to you that
this man who stands before us,
is neither Giacomo nor jester,
but your deadly enemy,
the leader of the rabble who
have sworn to have your head,
the Black Fox himself!
The Black Fox?
And this demure maid
his foul accomplice!
Ravenhurst, are you mad? Have
you proof of this foul treachery?
I have, sire.
Then repair to the court!
Summon the judges!
If what you say be true,
the headsman's axe will not only
rid us of this jabbering popinjay,
but will sever this
lovely little head,
from this delicate little neck..
oh. To the castle!
Hurry along, little friends.
Hurry along!
Keep your heads down.
Come along, there,
men! All of you!
We'll take the coast road,
but stay close to the trees!
And I say again,
sire! Never, sire,
never was there
such infamous treason.
Not only is this
man the Black Fox,
but he and his despicable accomplice,
have the shameful effrontery,
to shelter in this castle,
the miserable child,
they would put on
your very throne!
What's this?
What say you, Ravenhurst?
I repeat, sire. The child they
would put on your throne.
The child...
with the purple pimpernel?
The very same, sire.
Bring forth the basket!
Let me see this
fraud, this charlatan.
Hurry up, hurry up,
bring it here.
In a moment, sire.
But first let me hear you pronounce
sentence on this unholy pair.
I know how anxious you are to
dispose of this villainous scum,
so that you may proceed
with the feast and the revelry.
Sire, I accuse these impostors
of the foulest and most loathsome
crime against the crown,
and I demand,
that they be given the full
measure of your righteous wrath,
and shall be disposed of
before another hour is past.
I tell you, sire, the headsman's axe is
too kind a fate for these foul traitors.
They should be put on a spit,
and roasted like yon boar!
Yes, yes, death
to both of them.
Father, I say
Ravenhurst lies.
This is Giacomo, king of jesters,
and never the Black Fox.
Nay, fair lady. For once,
Ravenhurst is right.
I am. I am the
Black Fox!
Seize that traitor!
Ravenhurst! Ravenhurst!
Do something! Do something!
Quickly, fetch Griswold!
Bring him back!
Take him to safety!
Arm him. I must
raise the gate!
Quick, Lower the gate!
The gate is lowered!
- No it isn't! Look!
If he dies, you die.
Tails of lizards, ears of swine,
chicken gizzard soaked in brine,
on your feet, be not afraid,
you're the greatest with a blade!
Heh heh.
Hey!
Play games with the
Black Fox, will you?
At this very moment,
my dear Ravenhurst,
your life isn't worth that!
Now my gallant fox, we'll see
whose life isn't worth that!
We shall, indeed! Hey ya!
With your permission?
Why you swine...
Your health.
Oo, you...
And now, Ravenhurst,
you rat catcher!
Well, my dear Ravenhurst,
our little game draws to an end.
I have toyed with you
long enough. You shall die.
And die like that! Ehh!
Hurry! Help the Fox!
Jean. - Oh! Hawkins,
are you all right?
Never mind me.
Where's the child?
Safe. -Good.
You've been wonderful.
How convenient.
The Fox and his mate!
So my friends, the tables
have turned yet again.
But this time for
the last time,
and not only for one, but
for two! What a prize!
Griswold!
They'll cut us to
ribbons. We've lost.
Hold there! Hold!
Let no more English blood
be spilled! Victory is ours!
Not so fast! Unhand
the king, and surrender!
Never! - Then die as
traitors to the crown!
Hold, Sir Griswold!
Hold your men!
Sir Griswold, I speak to
you as knight to knight.
When you were dubbed,
you pledged your hand,
your heart and your sword to
defend the true king of England.
Is that right? - Well?
This man is not
the true king.
He has usurped the throne
from the legitimate heir.
Heir? What heir?
He who bears the mark
of the royal bloodline.
The purple pimpernel!
- The purple pimpernel?
That's balderdash.
No such person exists!
Your majesty!
The real king is on the throne,
Jean is my very own,
and life couldn't possibly,
not even probably,
life couldn't possibly better
be!
transcript:
O'cairn
Text edit-Synchro:
Darth Kobol