- Opening night
It's opening night
It's Max Bialystock's latest show
Will it flop or will it go?
The cast is taking its final bow
Here comes the audience now
The doors are open
They're on their way
Let's hear what they have to say
He's done it again
Max Bialystock has done it again
We can't believe it
You can't conceive it
How'd he achieve it?
It's the worst show in town
We sat there sighing
Groaning and crying
There's no denying
It's the worst show in town
Oh, we wanted to stand up and hiss
We've seen shit
But never like this
Max Bialystock has done it again
The songs were rotten
The book was stinkin'
What he did to Shak espeare
Booth did to Lincoln
We had this specially made up
for Max Bialystock.
We couldn't leave faster
What a disaster
We are still in shock
Who produced this schlock?
That slimy, sleazy Max Bialystock
What a bum
Hello?
Mr. Bialystock?
Anybody here?
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
What do you want?
Speak to me, dummy. Speak!
Why don't you speak?
Scared. Can't talk.
All right, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Calm down. Get ahold
of yourself. Come with me.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, right this way.
Watch your step.
Look, just...
Take a deep breath.
Let it out slowly.
- Who are you?
- I am Leopold Bloom.
I'm an accountant.
I'm from Whitehall & Marks...
...and I've come to do your books.
- Oh, you have, huh? Well, listen...
- Who is it?
- Hold Me- Touch Me.
Hold Me- Touch Me.
One of my backers.
Listen, I have to meet
with an important investor.
Do me a big favour,
go to the bathroom.
- But I don't have to go.
- Try. Try. Think of Niagara Falls.
Be with you in a moment,
my darling.
Hold Me- Touch Me.
Where is Hold Me- Touch Me?
Kiss Me- Feel Me,
Clinch Me- Pinch Me...
...Lick Me- Bite Me, Suck Me...
Here she is. Hold Me- Touch Me.
You know, it worked.
As soon as I pictured Niagara Falls...
...I didn't have any trouble at all...
- Back. Back. Don't make a sound.
Coming. Coming.
Hello, gorgeous.
- Hold me, touch me.
- As soon as I shut the door.
Did you bring the checkie?
Bialy can't produce plays
without checkies.
Here you go.
But first,
can we please play a game?
One dirty little game.
All right, my little sex kitten.
What shall we play?
The Debutante and the Bricklayer?
- Oh, no.
- No.
How about the Rabbi
and the Contortionist?
You like that one, mama,
keeps you limber.
I know.
Let's play the Virgin Milkmaid
and the Well-Hung Stableboy.
I don't think I have the strength.
- Don't worry, I'll be gentle.
- All right.
Oh, dear...
...this milk is so heavy.
I'll never reach the house.
You there, well-hung stableboy.
Won't you please help me?
Of course, my little dairy queen.
First I'll take your milk.
Then I shall take your virginity!
No! No! Never! Never!
Yes. Yes.
Give it to me, well-hung!
Give it to me.
Darling, wait,
I haven't even had coffee yet.
- Take it easy. Take it easy.
- Oh, my God.
Send me to the moon, you animal.
Send me to the moon.
Yes. Yes, my darling.
Thursday. Come back Thursday.
I'll send you to the moon Thursday.
I may even join you.
But first, the checkie.
Where's the checkie?
Come on, come on, find the checkie.
Here you go.
I made it out, like you told me,
to the title of the play:
- Cash.
- Yes.
That's a funny name
for a play, Cash.
Yes, so was The Iceman Cometh.
I'll see you Thursday.
- Bye.
- Bye. Bye.
Yes, yes, yes.
You dirty old buzzard.
May I come out of the bathroom now,
Mr. Bialystock?
- Yeah, sure.
- I'm terribly sorry I caught you...
...feeling up the old lady.
- " Feeling up the old lady. "
Thank you, Mr. Tact.
- May I take your coat?
- Oh, thank you.
So you're an accountant, huh?
- Yes, sir. I am, sir.
- Then account for yourself!
Why are you looking up little
old ladies' dresses? Bit of a pervert?
I know what you're thinking.
How dare you condemn me
without knowing all the facts.
- Mr. Bialystock, I wasn't condemn...
- Shut up!
I'm having a rhetorical conversation.
- Do you know who I used to be?
- Well, yes. You're Max Bialystock...
...the king of Broadway.
- No, I'm Max Bialy... That's right.
- That's right.
- And might I say, Mr. Bialystock...
And please don't take this
the wrong way...
...but you're not just a dirty old man.
- Thank you.
Oh, you're also
a great Broadway producer.
And there's something about me
you should know.
When I was a kid...
...I had the good fortune
to be taken to Bialy-Hoos of '42.
- Oh, Bialy-Hoos.
- Yes.
And I still have the ticket stub.
- Oh, look at that.
- Yeah.
And ever since,
I've had a secret desire...
...to be a Broadway producer.
A secret desire, huh?
- Kid, can I give you some advice?
- Yes, sir.
Keep it a secret.
Do the books, please.
Top drawer, to the left.
Oh, my God.
Will you look at that.
That's it, baby!
When you got it, flaunt it! Flaunt it!
Mr. Bialystock,
may I speak to you a minute?
- A minute?
- Yes.
- Just one minute?
- Okay.
- In glancing at your books...
- Go! You have 58 seconds left.
... I noticed that in the column...
- You're gonna time it?
- Time is money.
I looked at your books and the
columns marked "monies received. "
- And I can't make the figures work out.
- Forty-eight seconds. Hurry.
- There's a problem with your figures.
- Twenty-eight. Running out of time.
- Tick, tock. Tick, tock. Tick, tock.
- I cannot...
- Fifteen seconds.
- I cannot... I can't function.
- I cannot function in these conditions.
- Five, four, three, two, one.
You're making me
extremely nervous.
What is that, a handkerchief?
What? This? No, it's nothing.
It's nothing.
Well, if it's nothing,
then why can't I see it?
My blanket. My blue blanket!
Give me back my blue blanket!
Give me my blanket! Give it to me.
Give it to me. Give me the blanket.
Give it to me! Give it to me!
Here, here, here.
Don't panic. Don't panic.
Don't panic.
I...
I'm sorry.
It's just that I don't like anyone
touching my blue blanket.
It's not important,
it's a minor compulsion.
I can deal with it if I want to.
But I've had it ever since I was a baby,
and I find it very comforting.
I need to lie down for a minute now.
They come here. They all come here.
How do they find me?
Hey, kid. Hey.
Look at this.
How can I help you?
- What's wrong?
- You're gonna jump on me.
- What?
I know you're gonna jump on me
and squash me like a bug.
- Oh, God.
- Please, don't jump on me!
I'm not gonna jump on you!
Get ahold of yourself!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop! Calm down!
Don't touch me! Don't touch me.
- What's the matter now?
- I'm hysterical. I'm having hysterics.
I can't stop when I get like this.
I can't stop. I'm hysterical.
I can see that.
All right. All right, calm down.
I'm coming, I'm coming.
Take it easy.
I'm wet!
I'm wet.
I'm hysterical and I'm wet!
I'm in pain.
I'm in pain, I'm wet...
...and I'm still hysterical.
All right, all right. What can I do?
You're getting me hysterical.
Move away, you frighten me.
- You're too close.
- I frighten you?
Yes, get over there and stop
touching... Move over there! Sit down.
I'm sitting, I'm sitting.
You still look angry.
I'm sorry. How's this?
Who's my little accountant?
Are you my little accountant?
- Are you my little accountant?
- I am.
Yes, you are.
Well, thank you for smiling.
That helped a great deal.
Well, you know what they say:
"Smile and the world smiles
with you. "
This man should be
in a straightjacket.
- You feeling better?
- Oh, yes, I'm fine now. Thank you.
- Good.
- May I speak to you?
Yes, Prince Myshkin.
What can we do for you?
Well, this is hardly
the time for levity, Mr. Bialystock.
I've discovered a serious error...
...in the accounts of your last show,
Funny Boy.
- Where? What?
- Well, according to the backers list...
...you raised $100,000.
But your show only cost 98,000.
There's 2000 unaccounted for.
I went to a Turkish bath.
Who cares?
The show was a flop.
Bloom, do me a favour...
...move a few decimal points around.
You can do it, you're an accountant.
You're part of a noble profession.
The word "count" is part of your title.
- That's cheating.
- It's not cheating.
It's charity.
Bloom...
...you see this stickpin?
This once held a pearl
as big as your eye.
I used to wear handmade
Italian shoes, $500 suits.
And look at me now.
Look at me now!
I'm wearing a cardboard belt.
Bloom, you gotta save me.
I'm reaching out to you.
Don't send me to prison.
Help me.
All right. All right.
Okay, I'll do it.
- Really?
- Yes, I'll do it.
See, $2000 isn't so much.
I'm sure I can hide it someplace.
After all, the IRS isn't interested
in a show that flopped.
Right. Good thinking.
You figure it out.
I'm gonna take a little nap.
Now, let's see.
Let's see, if we add up
these deductions, we get...
Carry the three, divide by four...
Amazing.
It's absolutely amazing, but...
...under the right circumstances...
...a producer could
make more money with a flop...
...than he could with a hit.
Yes, it's quite possible. If he were
certain that a show would fail...
...a man could make a fortune.
- Yes?
- Yes, what?
- What you were saying. Keep talking.
- What was I saying?
You were saying that a producer...
...could make more money
with a flop than a hit.
Well, yes. It's quite possible.
You keep saying that,
but you don't say how.
Well, it's simply a matter
of creative accounting.
Let's assume for a moment
that you are a dishonest man.
Assume away.
All right. When you produced
your last show, Funny Boy...
...you raised $2000
more than you needed.
But you could've raised a million...
...put on your $100,000 flop
and kept the rest.
- But what if my show was a hit?
- Then you would go to jail.
See, rather than 100 percent
of the show...
...you would've sold
more than 1000 percent.
So if the show's a success,
there's no way to pay off the backers.
- Get it?
- Got it.
So in order for our scheme to work,
we'd have to find a sure- fire flop.
"Our scheme"? What scheme?
What scheme?
Your scheme,
you bloody little genius.
I meant no scheme. I merely posed
a little academic accounting theory.
- It was just a thought.
- Bloom...
...worlds are turned
on such thoughts.
Don't you see, Bloom?
Darling Bloom, glorious Bloom.
It's so simple.
Step one,
we find the worst play ever written.
Step two,
we hire the worst director in town.
- Step three, I raise 2 million dollars.
- Two?
Yes, one for me, one for you. There's
a lot of little old ladies out there.
Step four, we hire the worst actors
in New York and open on Broadway.
And before you can say "step five,"
we close on Broadway...
...take our 2 million and go to Rio.
Rio? That'd never work.
Oh, ye of little faith.
What did Lewis say to Clark
When everything look ed bleak?
What did Sir Edmund say to Tenzing
As they struggled
Toward Everest's peak?
What did Washington say
To his troops
As they crossed the Delaware?
I'm sure you're well aware
What'd they say?
We can do it
Me and you
We can make our dreams come true
Everything you've ever wanted
Is just waiting to be had
Beautiful girls
Wearing nothing but pearls
Caressing you, undressing you
And driving you mad
No.
Bloom. Bloom, wait a minute, now.
Hear me out. Just think about it.
Stop!
We can do it
This is not the time to shirk
You won't rue it
Say goodbye to petty clerk
Hi, producer
Yes, producer
I mean you, sir
Go berserk
We can do it
And I know it's gonna work
What do you say, Bloom?
What do I say?
Finally, a chance to be
A Broadway producer
What do I say?
Finally, a chance to mak e
My dreams come true, sir
What do I say?
Here's what I say to you, sir
I can't do it
That's not me
I'm a loser
I'm a coward
I'm a chick en
Don't you see?
When it comes to wooing women
There's a few things that I lack
Beautiful girls
Wearing nothing but pearls
Chasing me, embracing me
I'd have an attack
Why, you miserable, cowardly,
wretched little caterpillar.
Don't you ever wanna become
a butterfly?
Don't you want to spread your wings
and flap your way to glory?
No!
- Where to?
- Central Park.
Gotta breathe. Gotta breathe.
- We can do it
- Mr. Bialystock, please stop the song
You've got me wrong
I'll say "so long"
I'm not as strong a person
As you think
Mr. Bialystock, just take a look
I'm not a crook
- Drink champagne, not ginger ale
- I'm a schnook, bottom line is I stink
- Come on, Leo, can't you see-o?
- I can't do it
You see Rio, I see jail
Driver, stop.
Here.
- We can do it
- I can't do it
- I cannot, cannot, cannot, cannot do it
'Cause I know it's gonna fail
Fail? How could it miss?
All you need is a little courage.
Bloom, you know what you are?
You're like a...
You're like a fountain waiting
to explode and shoot into the sky!
- I'm a fountain?
- Yes, you're a fountain!
Don't you realize? There's a lot more
to you than there is to you.
Mr. Bialystock, I'm afraid you've made
a terrible error in judgment.
You've mistaken me
for someone with a spine.
I'm going back
to Whitehall & Marks now.
- Goodbye forever.
- Bloom. Bloom, wait a minute! Bloom.
Think about it. You'll never get a cab
at this hour! Bloom.
Oh, Lord. Dear Lord...
...I want that money!
Unhappy
Very unhappy
Very, very, very, very, very
Very, very unhappy
Bloom!
Where the hell have you been?
You are six minutes late.
This is an accounting firm...
...not a country club.
You can't come and go as you please.
- Yes, Mr. Marks.
- Remember, you're a nobody.
A PA. A public accountant.
And I am a CPA.
A certified public accountant.
A rank a miserable little worm like
yourself could never hope to achieve.
Yes, Mr. Marks.
Thank you for speaking to me.
You're welcome.
What are you gawking at?
You never saw a person
humiliated before?
Now, get back to work. All of you!
Unhappy
Very, very, very, very
Very, very, very unhappy
I spend my life accounting
- With figures and such
- Unhappy
To what is my life amounting?
- It figures, not much
- Unhappy
I have a secret desire
Hiding deep in my soul
It sets my heart afire
To see me in this role
I wanna be a producer
With a hit show on Broadway
Lunch at Sardi's every day
I want to be a producer
Sport a top hat and a cane
I wanna be a producer
And drive those chorus girls insane
And sleep until half past 2
I wanna be a producer
And say, "You, you, you... "
Not you.
I wanna be a producer
Wear a tux on opening night
And see my name, Leo Bloom
In lights
He wants to be a producer
Of a great big Broadway smash
Every pock et stuffed with cash
He wants to be a producer
Pinch our cheeks till we cry
Yes.
He wants to be a producer
With a great big casting couch
- I wanna be
- He wants to be
I wanna be the greatest, grandest
And most fabulous producer
In the world
He's gotta dine
With a duchess and a duk e
I just got to be a producer
Drink champagne until I puk e
- Drink champagne till he puk es
- I wanna be a producer
Show the world just what I got
I'm gonna put on shows
That will enthral them
Read my name in Winchell's column
I wanna be a producer
- 'Cause it's everything I'm not
- Unhappy
Unhappy
- I wanna be a producer
- Very, very unhappy
- Unhappy
- I wanna be a produce...
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Hold everything.
Hold everything!
What am I doing here?
Mr. Bialystock was right.
There is a lot more to me
than there is to me.
Stop the world, I wanna get on!
What the hell is going on in here?
Do I smell the revolting stench
of self-esteem?
Bloom,
where do you think you're going?
You've already had
your toilet break.
I'm not going into the toilet.
I'm going into show business.
And, Mr. Marks,
I have news for you. I quit!
And you were right about one thing,
you are a CPA.
- A certified public asshole!
- Hooray!
Here's my visor...
...my Dixon Ticonderoga
number 2 pencil...
...and my big finish!
I'm gonna be a producer
He's gonna be a producer
- Look out, Broadway
'Cause here I come
Mr. Bialystock. Mr. Bialystock.
I'm back! I'm back.
I've changed my mind.
Boy, you are good.
- Who are you talking to?
- Never mind, just an old friend.
- What happened?
- Oh, just this...
Just this: When I said that I was
scared that I was gonna go to jail...
...I didn't realize
that I already was in jail.
I've spent my life counting
other people's money.
People I'm smarter than...
...better than.
When's Leopold Bloom
gonna get his share?
When's it gonna be Bloom's day?
I want... I want...
I want everything
I've ever seen in the movies.
And, Leo, you're gonna have it.
Because...
- We can do it, we can do it
- I'm gonna be a producer
Say goodbye to woe and gloom
- With your brilliance, my resilience
- I'm gonna be a producer
- Up together we will zoom
- We can do it, we can do it
Every show I touch I doom
- We were fated
- To be mated
- We're Bialystock and Bloom
Oh, Max...
Oh, Max, let's give up.
I can't read anymore.
- How many plays can a person read?
- Stop complaining.
We have to find the worst play
ever written.
- I've been reading all night.
- Who cares?
You wanna be a producer, read,
read. Keep reading.
Here's one.
Act I, scene one.
"Gregor Samsa awoke one morning
to discover...
...that he had been transformed
into a giant cockroach. "
No, too good.
" But how could you see me?
The glass was frosted. "
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
I've read this before.
I think I've read this one before.
What's it called? What's it called?
The Frosted Glass.
Max, I'm reading plays
that I read last night, Max.
I can't go on anymore.
It's too much.
Let's face it, we'll never find it.
We'll never find it.
Leo. Leo. See it? Smell it.
Touch it. Kiss it. Kiss it.
It's the mother lode.
- What is it? You found a flop?
- A flop.
That's putting it mildly.
This is a catastrophe.
A disaster certain to offend peoples
of all races, creeds and religions.
A guaranteed- to-close- in-one- night
beauty.
- Well, let's see it.
- Here.
"Springtime for Hitler...
...a gay romp with Eva and Adolf
at Berchtesgaden. "
Oh, my God.
"Oh, my God" is right.
It's practically a love letter to Hitler.
- Max, this won't run a week.
- A week? Are you kidding?
This play has got to close
on page four.
What's the author's name again?
" Franz Liebkind. 61 Jane Street,
New York, New York. "
Franz Liebkind. 61 Jane Street.
Let's go. We'll get the Broadway
rights to Springtime for Hitler...
...even if we have to go so far
as to pay him.
- Come on.
- This other hat, Max...
...may I wear it?
- No, you may not.
- Why?
Because that
is a Broadway producer's hat.
You don't get to wear
a Broadway producer's hat, son...
...until you're a Broadway producer.
And you're not
a Broadway producer until...
I know, I know. Until I've produced
a show on Broadway.
But I'm going to wear that hat,
and soon too, because...
We're gonna be the producers
Of a great big Broadway flop
Ja, ja, my Lieblings.
Let me grab you here.
We have work to do.
Hilda, my darling. Here, I have
written an important message...
...which must reach
Ernst Schlongdorf.
29 West Santiago Boulevard...
...Buenos Aires, Argentina.
AQAP.
As quick as possible.
Good.
Fly, Hilda. Fly!
Hilda, where are you going?
Argentina's that way!
Okay, chow time.
Yummy, yummy, yummy.
Goes right into your belly.
It's just a hunch,
but I'm betting this is our man.
Max, he's wearing a German helmet
and lederhosen.
Yeah, I know. Don't notice them.
Don't notice anything.
Always look straight ahead.
Remember, we need that play.
Franz Liebkind?
I was never a member
of the Nazi Party!
I only followed orders.
I had nothing to do with the war.
I didn't even know
there was a war on.
We lived in the back...
...right across from Switzerland.
All we ever heard was yodelling.
- Who are you?!
- Relax.
Mr. Liebkind,
we're not from the government.
We're producers,
Bialystock and Bloom...
...here to talk to you about your play.
- My play?
You mean Springtime for...
...you-know-who?
- That's the one.
- What about it?
- We love it. Don't we love it?
- We think it's a masterpiece.
- We want to put it on Broadway.
Broadway! Oh, joy of joys.
Dream of dreams. I can't believe it.
- I must tell my birds.
- Tell your birds.
Otto, Bertha, Heinz,
Heidi, Wolfgang...
...Adolf.
Do you hear?
We are finally going to clear
the Führer's name.
Broadway!
You know,
not many people know this...
...but the Führer was a terrific dancer.
- Really?
- We didn't know that, did we, Leo?
- No, no, we sure didn't.
That's because you were taken in
by the BBC!
Filthy British lies!
But did they ever say a bad word
about Winston Churchill?
Churchill!
With his cigars, with his brandy
and his rotten paintings.
Rotten!
Hitler.
There was a painter.
He could paint an entire apartment
in one afternoon.
Two coats.
Yes. Yes.
Yes, of course he could,
Mr. Liebkind.
And that is exactly why
we wanna produce your play.
Show the world the true Hitler.
The Hitler you loved...
...the Hitler you knew,
the Hitler with a song in his heart.
Here, Franz Liebkind.
Sign here...
...and make your dream a reality.
- No.
- That's what "nein" means.
First you must prove to me
that you believe as I believe...
...by joining with me and singing and
dancing the Führer's favourite tune:
" Der Guten Tag Hop-Clop. "
I know.
- " Der Guten Tag Hop-Clop"?
- " Der Guten Tag Hop-Clop. "
No. I could never sing
the Führer's favourite...
Delighted. Delighted.
...song.
- Shut up, he's almost ready to sign.
All right. First you will roll up
your pants.
- Rolling?
- Rolling.
- Don't be stingy. Show some leg.
- Alrighty.
- Good.
- Key of E?
- Is there any other?
Guten Tag hop hop
Guten Tag clop clop
Ach, du lieber
Und oh, boy
Guten Tag clap clap
Guten Tag slap slap
Ach, du lieber
What a joy
Oh, wir essen und fressen
Und tanzen und trink en
Tanzen und trink en
Until we get stinkin'
- Everybody!
- Guten Tag hop hop
Guten Tag clop clop
Guten Tag
Mein lieber Schatz
So we hop our hops
Und we clop our clops
Und we drink our Schnaps
Till we platz
You will sway?
We will sway.
Follow me.
Very good.
Whatever you say.
This is a tricky one
Oh, the Hop-Clop.
It's been so long!
Sort of a Nazi hoedown.
Gentlemen, you may
produce my play.
Excellent. Excellent.
Here we are. Here.
But only if you take
the Siegfried Oath.
The Siegfried Oath?
What's that?
A pledge of eternal allegiance
to our beloved Führer.
Never...
...took that oath before.
One for me, one for you,
und one for you.
Never... Had one of those on before.
Thanks very much.
- You're welcome.
- Nice colours.
Oh, look, reversible.
- Oh, yeah, you're right.
- Max.
Max, we never
should have started this.
I think we're getting in too deep.
Too deep? This is nothing.
I'll tell you when
we're getting in too deep.
All right.
First, you will raise
your right forefinger...
...und repeat after me.
I solemnly swear...
- I solemnly swear...
...to obey the sacred Siegfried Oath.
... to obey the sacred Siegfried Oath.
- Und...
Und...
...never, never, never...
... never, never, never...
...dishonour the spirit und the memory
of Adolf Elizabeth Hitler.
...dishonour the spirit und the...
... dishonour the spirit und the...
- Elizabeth?
Ja, that was his middle name.
Not many people know this...
...but the Führer was descended
from a long line of English queens.
Is that right?
Yes.
- Adolf Elizabeth Hitler.
- Good. Now I sign your contract.
- Excellent! Excellent.
Here we are, sir.
Right here on the dotted line.
There you are.
You shall never regret this.
So thank you, Herr Liebkind.
Alrighty, then.
Thank you.
Let it go. Let it go.
Halt!
I forgot to tell you.
The penalty for breaking
the Siegfried Oath...
...is dess.
" Dess"?
Is that anything like "death"?
Yeth.
Sorry to hear that. Don't worry...
...we'll iron out all these
thorny details over strudel.
Ta-ta, big guy. Here we go...
We're trapped! Trapped!
Got it.
Let's have lunch.
What nice guys.
Broadway.
I haven't been so happy
since we crushed Poland.
Hello, the living room of
renowned theatrical director...
...Roger DeBris' elegant
Upper East Side townhouse...
...on a sunny Tuesday
afternoon in June.
Who may I say is calling?
Listen, you broken- down
old queen...
...he was drunk, he was hot,
you got lucky.
- Don't ever call here again.
- Who was that?
Wrong number.
Yes?
Well, hi there.
I'm Max Bialystock and this
is my associate, Mr. Bloom.
We have an appointment
with renowned theatrical director...
...Roger DeBris.
- Ah, yes. Yes, please come in.
- Please. Yes.
- Thank you.
I am Carmen Ghia...
...Mr. DeBris'
common-law assistant.
You are expected.
May I take your hat, your coat
and your swastikas?
Oh, these. We... We...
We just came from this big rally.
Everybody was wearing them.
- You didn't tell me we had those on?
- I didn't notice them.
- You told me to look straight ahead.
- Yes, all right. Let's not fight. Okay?
Oh, Roger.
We're not alone.
Here's Roger.
- Max, he's wearing a dress.
- No kidding.
Roger, good to see you again.
Messrs. Bialystock and Bloom,
I presume?
Forgive the pun.
- What pun?
- Shut up. He thinks he's witty.
Roger, may I say you look gorgeous.
Absolutely gorgeous.
By the way, Max, darling,
we loved Funny Boy, didn't we?
Worshipped it.
To be or not to be
You mean a lot to me
- Showstopper!
- Fabulous.
Oh, dear. Your Mr. Bloom
is staring at my gown.
- Well, I was...
- I should explain.
I'm going to the Choreographers' Ball.
There is a prize for best costume.
- We always win.
- I'm not so sure about this year.
I'm supposed to be
the Grand Duchess Anastasia...
...but I think I look more like
the Chrysler Building.
Well, as far as I'm concerned, without
your wig on, you're only half dressed.
Well, then,
why don't you go and get it...
...oh, Wicked Witch of the West.
If your intention...
...was to shoot an arrow
through my heart...
...bull's- eye!
Oh, Roger, let's face it,
that building is you.
Listen, I know we sent it to you
only this morning...
...but did you read
Springtime for Hitler?
Read it? I devoured it.
And I find it remarkable.
Remarkable!
I feel it is a very important piece,
drenched with historical goodies.
I, for one, for instance,
never realized that the Third Reich...
...meant Germany.
Yeah, how about that.
Then you'll do it?
Do it? Of course not. It's not my
kind of thing. I mean, Max, please.
World War II?
Too dark, too depressing.
The theatre's so obsessed
With dramas so depressed
It's hard to sell a tick et on Broadway
Shows should be more pretty
Shows should be more witty
Shows should be more
What's the word?
- Gay?
- Exactly.
No matter what you do on the stage
Keep it light, k eep it bright
Keep it gay
Whether it's murder
Mayhem or rage
Don't complain, it's a pain
Keep it gay
People want laughter
When they see a show
The last thing they're after is
A litany of woe
A happy ending
Will pep up your play
Oedipus won't bomb
If he winds up with Mom
- Keep it gay
Couldn't agree more.
And you have our blessings,
Roger...
...to make Springtime for Hitler just
as gay as anyone could possibly want.
So come on, do it for us. Please.
I'm sorry, Max.
It's simply not my cup of tea.
Still, fair is fair.
I should ask my production team
what they think.
Your production team,
who are they?
You'll see. They all live here.
Guys! Come say hello
to Bialystock and Bloom!
This is my set designer, Brian.
Hello.
Keep it mad, k eep it glad
Keep it gay
- Here's my costume designer, Kevin.
- Hello.
Keep it happy, k eep it snappy
Keep it gay
We're clever, creative
It's our job to see
That everything's perfect
For Mr. DeBris
Scott, my choreographer.
Hi there.
And, finally, last and least...
...my lighting designer,
Shirley Markowitz.
Keep it gay
Now, they all just read Springtime.
What did you think of it, fellas?
- It needs glamour
- And glitz
- It needs sequins
- And tits
Leo. Leo, I think we're losing them.
Go say something nice to Roger.
I think he likes you.
- But, Max...
- Go on. It's just show biz.
Mr. DeBris. Roger.
Roger, actually,
I think your gown is very stunning.
Why, thank you, Mr. Bloom.
Leo.
What is that enchanting
cologne you're wearing?
Me? I'm not wearing any cologne.
You mean that smell is you?
Oh, God.
If I could bottle you, I'd shove you
under my armpits every day.
Oh, Max.
Max, we never should've started this.
- I think we're getting in too deep.
- Too deep? This is nothing.
I'll tell you when
we're getting in too deep.
And so the rule is
When mounting a play
Keep it funny
Keep it sunny
Keep it gay
- What should we do?
- Relax. Watch this.
Roger, I...
I think that Springtime for Hitler would
be a marvellous opportunity for you.
I mean, up to now,
you've always been associated with...
Dare I say it?... frivolous musicals.
You're right.
I've often felt as though...
...I've been throwing my life away
on silly entertainments.
Dopey showgirls in gooey gowns.
Two, three, kick, turn, turn, turn,
kick, turn.
- Roger.
- It's enough to make you heave.
Nonetheless, I'm sorry, Max, I just
couldn't do Springtime for Hitler.
- Why not? Think of the respect.
- No.
- Think of the prestige.
- No, no, no.
Think of the Tony!
Tony, Tony, Tony, Tony, Tony
- What's the matter?
- Is he all right?
- He's having a stroke.
- What?
- Of genius!
- I see it at last.
The chance
to do something important.
Roger DeBris presents
History
Of course that second act
has to be rewritten.
They're losing the war? Excuse me,
that's too downbeat.
Roger DeBris presents
History
But maybe...
It's a wild idea,
but it just might work.
I
See
A line
Of beautiful girls
Dressed as storm troopers
Each one a gem
With leather boots
And whips on their hips
- It's risqué, dare I say, S & M
- Love it!
I see German soldiers
Dancing through France
Played by chorus boys
In very tight pants
And wait, there's more
They'll win the war
And the dances they do
Will be daring and new
Turn, turn, kick, turn.
One, two, three, kick, turn.
Keep it sassy, k eep it classy
Keep it...
That is brilliant, brilliant, brilliant!
I speak for Mr. Bloom
and myself, Roger...
...when I say you are the only man
in the world...
...who could do justice to
Springtime for Hitler.
- Will you do it, please?
- Please.
Wait a minute.
This is a very big decision.
It might affect the course of my life.
I shall have to think about it.
I'll do it.
I'll do it
Sabu, champagne!
If at the end
You want them to cheer
Keep it gay, keep it gay, keep it gay
Whether it's Hamlet, Othello
Or Lear
Keep it gay, keep it gay, keep it gay
Comedy's joyous
A constant delight
Dramas annoy us
And ruin our night
So k eep your Strindbergs
And Ibsens at bay
- I'll sign
- Sign
Sign!
Roger Elizabeth DeBris.
Keep it gay
- Conga!
- Everybody!
And so the rule is
When mounting a play
Keep it gay
Stop it.
Exclusive Broadway rights
to the worst show ever written...
...and a signed contract
with the worst director who ever lived.
We're in business.
And what a business.
In the same day,
I'm taking the Siegfried Oath...
...and dancing the conga
with a cop, a sailor...
...and an extremely friendly
Cherokee Indian.
Yeah. Oh, well.
It's not easy
being a Broadway producer.
But together we'll make it.
Partners, Leo. Partners all the way...
...and nothing or no one
will ever come between us.
Nothing or no one, Max.
- Come in.
Bialystock and Bloom?
- What?
- Oh, excuse me.
Swedish.
Casting today?
- Cahstink? Cahstink?
- Cahstink?
- Casting!
- Casting.
No, no, no, miss.
We're not casting yet.
We don't even know when
we're beginning rehearsals...
Yes, we just started
casting today. Yes.
- We're casting?
- Yes. Yes, we're casting.
If you don't mind,
just once in my life...
...I'd like to see somebody
on that couch who's under 85.
What's your name, my dear?
My name is Ulla Inga...
...Hansen Benson Yonsen
Tallen- Hallen Svaden Svanson.
Wait. Wait.
What's your first name?
That was my first name.
You wanna hear my last name?
We don't have the time.
We'll just call you Ulla.
Okay? Yeah. What do you do, Ulla?
- Ulla sing and dance.
- Oh, yeah?
- You want Ulla make audition?
- Oh, no, miss.
- That won't be nece...
- Yes, it is " nece. "
Extremely nece.
Please. Please make audition.
Make audition all over the office.
- What are you going to sing?
- Well...
...yesterday when I was stepping out
of a big, white Rolls-Royce limo...
...a crazy man
yelled something out the window...
...that inspired me to write this song.
When you got it
Flaunt it
Step right up and strut your stuff
People tell you modesty's a virtue
But in the theatre
Modesty can hurt you
When you got it
Flaunt it
Show your assets
Let 'em know you're proud
Your goodies you must push
Stick your chest out
Shake your tush
When you got it
Shout it out loud
Now Ulla dance.
When you got it
Show it
Put your hidden treasures
On display
Violinists love to play an E string
But audiences really love a G-string
When you got it
Shout it
Let the whole world hear
What you're about
Clothes may make the man
All a girl needs is a tan
When you got it
Let it hang out
- Remember when Ulla dance?
- Yeah.
Ulla dance again.
Ulla dance again!
When I was just a little girl
In Sweden
My thoughtful mother
Gave me this advice
If nature blesses you
From top to bottom
Show that top to bottom
Don't think twice
Now Ulla belt.
Don't think twice!
When you got it
Share it
Let the public feast
Upon your charms
People say that being prim
Is proper
But every showgirl knows
That prim will stop her
When you got it
Give it
Don't be selfish
Give it all away
Don't be shy
Be bold and cute
Show the boys your birthday suit
When you got it
If you got it
Once you got it
Shout out
Hooray!
Okey- dokey.
You like it?
Like... Like it?
I want you to know, my dear,
that even though we're sitting down...
...we're giving you
a standing ovation.
She's in the show.
Wait, Max. Max, we don't even know
if there's a part for her in the show.
Would you excuse us, my dear?
Nonsense, Bloom.
Bloom,
do I have to teach you everything?
There is always a part
for the producer's girlfriend.
But we don't even know
when we're starting rehearsal yet.
So what? So what?
We're producers, aren't we?
So until she goes into the show,
she can work for us here.
Because we need...
Nay, deserve to have ourselves a...
Deserve to have ourselves a gorgeous
Swedish secretary/receptionist.
But, Max, a secretary who doesn't
speak English? What will people say?
They'll say:
Offer her the job, please?
Just a moment, miss.
We might have a position for you.
As a matter of fact, we might
have several positions for you.
Until the show gets going...
...we can offer you a job here
as a secretary/receptionist.
Secretary/receptionist?
Okey/dokey!
I can do that.
Answer telephone.
Bialystock and Bloom.
Smart as a whip.
You're hired!
Well... Well, all right. If he says so,
I don't have a...
Secretary/receptionist.
And maybe you can tidy up
around here a little bit too.
Tidy up? Tidy up.
Such a funny word.
What means "tidy up"?
- You know, clean.
- Make look nice.
- Oh, yeah. Ulla can make tidy up.
- Very good.
What time can you be here
in the morning?
Well, Ulla wake up every morning,
5 a. m.
From 5 to 7, Ulla like to exercise.
From to 7 to 8,
Ulla like to take long shower.
From to 8 to 9, Ulla like
to have big Swedish breakfast.
Many different herrings.
From to 9 to 11, Ulla like to practice
her singing and her dancing.
And at 11, Ulla like to have sex.
What time should I get here?
- Eleven.
Good. Ulla will come at 11.
Ulla will come at 11.
God bless America!
God bless Sweden.
Oh, Max. Max, she's fantastic.
The most beautiful girl
I've ever seen.
I've never felt this way before.
It's like a volcano erupting
inside of me...
...like hot lava rising higher
and higher and...
What is that, Max?
What is it?
It's called an erection.
It's either that or malaria.
But don't worry,
they have shots for everything now.
Come here,
I want to show you something.
- What do you see?
- Nothing.
Exactly. But now that we've got
our sure- fire flop...
...it's gonna be our job
to fill that safe with 2 million dollars.
Two million?
Gee, how much do we put in?
How much...?
How much do we put in?
Bloom...
...the two cardinal rules
of being a Broadway producer...
...are one, never put
your own money in the show.
And two?
Never put your own money
in the show!
- Get it?
- Got it.
- Good.
- So how do we raise the money?
How? I'll tell you how.
From my investors.
Hundreds of little old ladies...
...all looking to Max Bialystock for one
last thrill on their way to the cemetery.
So in the days to come, Bloom,
you shall see very little of me.
And right now,
I'd like to see very little of you.
Scram while I get myself ready.
For Max Bialystock
is about to launch himself...
...into little- old-lady land.
The time has come
To be a lover from the Argentine
To slick my hair down
With brilliantine
And gargle heavily
With Listerine