In Vienna in 1844
nice people neither danced the waltz
nor kissed their wives
in public nor listened to new ideas
In 1845 came Johann Strauss II and
his immortal melodies
We've dramatized his spirit
rather than facts of his life
because it's his spirit that has lived
in his music
VIENNA KK COMMERCIAL BANK
Just a minute, my dear Mr. Strauss...
and what's this?
A waltz
Another waltz, I see
Mr. Strauss, your father persuaded me
to take you in against my judgment
And what's my reward?
Every time I turn around,
there's another waltz printed on this paper
This is all...
Don't... you don't
You know, those are mine
You've got me a 60,000 golden
And you've got my waltz
And now, get over then... you're fired
Join those revolutionaries...
they won't go to work either
No fuss, no frank than serve in the street
to start another revolution
Now, Mr. Wertheimer...
Get out
Thanks for firing me, Mr. Wertheimer
Goodbye, you worms
KK COMMERCIAL BANK
Bless you, son...
Mr. Wertheimer closed today?
Well, perhaps they run out of money
One half of the bank is still open
The bank is still open...
but we're not in it
A nice happy holiday, Johann?
Yes
Is... is Poldi around?
Ah, he wants to see Poldi...
Mama, you hear?
Sure... I thought he maybe came to see you
If you please, Mr. Finance Minister
Look what the mailman brought you?
Johann... hello, Johann
Hello, Poldi, what... what are you doing?
What am I doing?
What are you doing here?
This is wonderful in the middle
of the day
How did you get away from the bank?
Well, l... I just walk out
Johann, something is the matter?
Is something happening?
Oh, nothing... nothing that
I don't want to happen
What's happening, Johann?
What's happening... ?
I've... I've been fired
That's what's happening
Oh, I'm sorry, Poldi
I didn't mean to yell at you
That's alright
Man has right to yell when
he has been fired
You always seem to know when
I'm in trouble, don't you?
Johann, shall I guess what are you
doing at the bank?
Alright, you guess I'm writing
waltz again
Oh, Johann, don't be rude...
there're other banks in the world
Maybe Mr. Wertheimer is going
to give you another chance
But I don't want another chance
I'm glad he has fired me
Now I'm free
Who's free?
I am... free to do I've always wanted to...
free to write music
I quit the bank
You quit the bank?
Hm
But your Papa wanted you to become a banker...
to have a career
You call banking a career?
Do you know what career is?
Have you heard of Mozart, Schubert and
Beethoven?
They had what I call a career
Did they make money?
They made glorious music
Yes, Papa, that's right...
they made glorious music
Yeah... I heard their music
Johann, if you want to write waltz...
you write waltzes
And I play them...
I play them the way
I always felt they should be played
I'll organize my own orchestra
But how?
You don't have a penny in your pocket
Oh... musicians don't play for nothing
Oh, they don't, do they?
Poldi darling, you don't know musicians
Well, I know 50 men who are willing to...
now you just wait
Kienzl
Yes?
Kienzl, what do you love the most
in the world?
Huh?
Well, sometimes a girl...
most times a goulash
No... you play violin...
don't you love your violin?
Yes, but a good beef goulash with...
Alright... would you like to play
in my orchestra?
When you have an orchestra?
If I have an orchestra, would you like
to play in it?
Well, if you had, you mean for nothing?
But of course for nothing
Is it permanent?
Sure
That's a nice one when you're taking...
you should take it to the park
Yes, that's a good idea
Look, Kienzl...
do you know Dudelman
who plays violin?
Hm
And Albert and Duffman?
Where we could get them?
We could get them easily...
they jump at a chance like this
Is this the nice way to entertain
your sweetheart?
Sweetheart?
He doesn't know if I'm standing
on my head or feet
He's so mixed up with his troubles
And I don't blame him
Is this the way to look when a young
man comes to see you?
You know, Poldi
Sometimes it's good for a woman to make
a man think about something else
beside the troubles
How do you think I finally got
your Papa?
Keeping his mind on apple strudel
Now remember... be in my house
at 2 o'clock on Sunday
See, listen...
I got a cousin who works
at the tea shop
What does he play?
A piccolo for nothing...
I'd recommend him too
Bring him along
There you're, Poldi...
there's true musician for you
Money doesn't mean a thing to him...
he never even thought of it
Johann, whatever career you choose...
profit will be the very highest
Poldi, you do believe in me, don't you?
You know I do
I could kiss you for that
Yes, Johann
Poldi, you know what?
What?
Popofinger... Hans Popofinger
He's out of the job and
he's the best double bassoon player
in old Vienna
Oh, Poldi... what'll I do without you?
I don't know what you're doing with me
Hey, Mr. Strauss...
I have an aunt who plays harp
Bring her too
But she's 72 years old
Just put her on the wheelchair and
bring her along
CASINO DOMMAYER:
DEBUT OF JOHANN STRAUSS
AND HIS ORCHESTRA
Excellent
I hope that dropout bank's job is
still there
Shh...
You have a wonderful son, Mrs. Strauss
I warned him
I'm sorry
So am I
But don't take it much too hard...
young Strauss
You know Beethoven was not a success
either the first time he waved his baritone
But gentlemen, I thank you very much
There's some goulash in the kitchen
on your way out
Boys, open the windows and
start your cleaning
Ladies and gentlemen...
the performance is over
I'm very sorry, but the Dommayer
is to close early tonight
But I just paid for ticket and
call for a concert
Let's have it
We'll be glad to refund the money...
but you see the performance is over
But we don't want the money
We want the music and the performance
is not over
Just a minute, please...
I'm Aucust Dommayer, owner of
Dommayer's Casino and
the performance is over
And I'm Fritz Cellist,
the first tenor
of the Imperial Opera and
the performance is not over
I don't care who you're...
the performance is over
The performance is not over
Hey, what are you doing there?
Leave the windows open
The whole neighborhood might as well
hear it for nothing
Do you have any special wish, Madam?
Anything
Now let's play...
let's play
Now the goulash will be burnt
But it's Carla Donner
Who's she?
Carla Donner
Carla Donner... the famous opera singer
The coach is ready, Madam
Yes, thank you... what time is it?
About 9 o'clock
We must go
Bring him along to the Hall of the
Palace tonight
He might amuse us
Us?
What a stink she is
Guess most people will see us
No extra charge
For nothing they'll listen
Now the , you worms
And play as you never play before
in your life
For Vienna
Each man must have a hobby...
his own kind of hobby
I want beer and girls
I'm fond of girls and beer
But me, I like to stay up
and keep my spirit way up
In a girl I found...
And songs that sound...
Sound like anyone you hear
Every night in the beat...
every beat and every hymn...
What has happened?
Look, Strauss...
I'm afraid I'm not very elegant
in these clothes
Don't worry
Thanks to Carla Donner...
others are welcome to town for dinner
in any clothes
Look at our friend Hofbauer...
why do you think he's here?
Hofbauer?
Do you think he's born in that
dressed shirt?
But he's the greatest music publisher
in Vienna
He's still Hofbauer
Where's Miss Donner?
I don't see her
She'll see you when she wants to
Fritz, I'm so glad you're here...
take me to supper at once
May I present the young composer of
great talent...
my friend Johann Strauss...
Mr. And Mrs. Hofbauer
Oh, how do you do... ?
What nice eyes
Come along, Fritz...
we'll know each other better
Young man, come along
Patrician, baritone and now
male's contralto
I'm honored, Mr. Hofbauer
Oh, Hofbauer... you know me?
I'm Hofbauer and you... your name?
Strauss
Struass...
My wife is a lovely woman...
a lovely woman
Are you a guest here... yes?
Madam Carla Donner was good enough
to invite me here tonight
Carla Donner?
Oh, you watch your step, young man
As far as Carla Donner is concerned...
Yes?
Come home with the... well, you know
aware to the wife's suspicion... Who are you... ?
I'm a composer
Composer?
Who published you... Shayahara?
Oh, mark my word, young man
If it's not in the print by Hofbauer...
it's not even music
Mister...
Strauss
Strauss... I never heard of your music...
never heard of it
You'll hear it perhaps tonight...
from Madam Donner herself
if you have no objection
Oh, I have no objection at all, Mister...
I don't care what your name is...
I don't care
Smith... Rudolf Smith
Rudolf, goodnight...
My dear young man, if you...
well, it's the young man
from the casino, Mister...
Strauss... Johann Strauss
Madam, I can't tell how...
how grateful I'm
You're so kind to invite me tonight
Mr. Strauss... Prince Butarka
How do you do?
Mr. Strauss is
the most exciting player in Vienna
After I finish my little wine...
will you please?
I'm sorry, Madam...
I didn't mean to interrupt
You did me a favor
Now you can do me another favor
Anything, Madam
Will you please get out of my dress?
Get out?
Oh, I'm so sorry
I have no idea... I seem to be caught
So soon?
What... Madam?
I can simplify everything
But Madam, your gown, l...
Now tell me... did he ask you to bring
along some of your music?
Yes, Madam, I have a piece here...
pardon me
Oh, how nice
'Knowing you that you want me'
Did you write the lyrics yourself...
Mr. Strauss?
Yes, Madam
A lovely idea... you know we're going
to explode a little bomb on ice
I'll sing it
But Madam that... this is a waltz
I know it
You think it's wise?
All these people, I mean your friends...
maybe they won't think it proper
It's time to change their minds
Oh, I see you've already met
Yes, Mr. Strauss,
will you give this
to the leader of the band there?
Yes, Madam
Are you going to sing a waltz here?
I'm going to sing it, but first
you've to announce
Now... Carla?
Now, Fritz
A waltz...
Ho...
Where's Madam Donner?
Oh, she's down there with the musicians
What's the idea coming to us...
even invited musicians?
Huh, they even invited music publishers
Ladies and gentlemen... I've been asked
to direct your attention here
Madam Carla Donner has graciously
consented to sing for us
We won't let them know it's waltz
When we go on to a quarter time,
we let some stalemate and
lift some eye brows
If they lift too far...
you've to protect me
I can protect you from everything, but...
But what... Madam?
Tonight I bring you a new song
from a new composer, Mr. Johann Strauss
and I hope his music will attract you
as it does me
He's impostor... an impostor
He tells me his name is Rudolf
Bravo...
Bravo, Madam
Madam, I can't hardly speak
I don't think the song
will be sung again
It'll never be done so beautifully
Well, the piano alright?
I'm afraid it's tone a little bit hash
I've never heard of it, Madam...
believe me
Then there's a new one here from Munich
Would you like to try it for me?
Of course, Madam
What a relief...
I like quiet room, don't you?
Yes, Madam
Now let me see where's the...
There's no piano...
quiet rooms don't have pianos
But they have wine
Someone who was very thoughtful...
wine makes up music
Thank you, Madam
Are you disappointed there's no piano?
No, Madam
Are you unappy... to be alone with me?
Oh, no, Madam... it's only that...
that I can't hardly believe
all the other times aren't real
Other times?
I mean... at the opera when you're always
way down below on the stage
But when your voice came after me...
you were wonderfully close...
I mean...
And we're alone together?
Last time you sang ...
you're the only one there...
you and l... and the greatest voice
in the world
The only composer I ever knew
was fat little man with bald head
Well, I never know further I'll be any
kind of composer or not
All I know is when you first walked to
the Dommayer's at the night and
I played to you
You should know I played to you
And just now when... you sang my waltz
before everybody
I'm more alone with you than ever
More alone than now?
Sorry for being late, Carla...
I've an order from His Majesty...
he's troubled sometimes
Darling, you must be worn out
Tony, this is the lovely young man...
he's a composer
He and I have been along together
for years, haven't we?
This is our host, Count Hohenfried...
Mr. Strauss
He was up in the balcony and
I was on the stage
As a matter of fact, we're practically
sweet-hearted
Perfect, really?
I heard you sang a waltz too...
another one of your Bohemian evening
... - my darling?
Tony... why?
I defense... I imagine
Thank you
The usual fee for musician I believe
is 10 golden
You can't insult my composer...
his performance is brilliant
Very well, 50 golden
Oh, I'm ashamed of you...
nothing less than 100 golden
Alright, my dear... 100 golden
That's more like it, honey
Thank you, Sir
But might need it for another necklace
As a matter of fact, I owe you 10 times as much
what I've learned here tonight
The performance is great, Madam...
I hope you were amused
Poldi, what are you doing here?
Yes, well... I don't know
What do you mean 'you don't know'?
I'm so foolish
I'm so sorry... it's just silly
I got just a funny feeling
when you went away
with the gentleman in Dommayer's
And then suddenly I know, l...
I thought you were in danger
I'm so silly
Of course, here you're perfectly
a grown up man... perfectly alright
I could drop some puddles on the
sidewalk
Poldi, don't you dare drop puddles
on the sidewalk?
Johann
I'm a lucky fool, Poldi
I never knew I've had this much
in your heart
You always are
Don't forget to turn off the light
Oh, I was just about to arrest her, officer
Don't you see how guilty she looks?
I wish my wife looks guilty as that
Oh, Johann, now I really could drop
on the sidewalk
POLDI AND JOHANN
Now... sit down
Sit down, everybody
Now comes the speech
Fine, yeah... who can talk without wine?
Well, who can talk without cake?
Thank you, Madam...
I just take a little piece
Oh
My friends, I should like to propose
a toss
I'll make it short, my friend
Kienzl is about to eat the cake
As for Johanrs happiness, that now has
beautifully and for all times
in Poldi's care
I had met 100 of young men,
but never had I met finnier young man and
finnier musician than Johann Strauss
Oh, that's lovely... so sweet
Johann... speech
Yes... come on
Go on... say something
That's there... say just a few words
My darling wife...
My dear mother...
My new Mama and Papa...
My dear colleagues...
Yesterday Kienzl was a baker and
the baker is a colleague today
Yes, and tomorrow who knows...
maybe a baron or a king?
Don't laugh...
Revolution is not so far away...
my friends
All he thinks is about being a baron
He forgets what we're fighting for is
constitution...
representation... free press and free speech...
Sit down... go on, Johann
Tonight I find even more than happiness
and more than our success together
And believe me,
you can't find it in the rich palaces
You can't find it in hard cover the
gold bracelets or...
behind the falls of painted laughter
You can't find peace in the deep quiet
breath of living there
because that I know...
I know because I've found it here tonight
in my wife... in my music
and in my friends...
Bravo... wonderful
Excellent...
I mean perfect... I mean bravo...
Bravo
Yes, thank you
Mr. Hofbauer... the music publisher
Mr. Hofbauer?
Yeah
Good evening, Sir
They told me I could find you here
They told me you just got married
Yes, Sir
Well, don't worry
We're once in a while... we're both
in the same goal together
I mean we're in the same boat together...
same boat together
This is my wife
Oh, how do you do... ?
You know your waltz has created
quite a big splash
Well, it's not so big splash...
it's just a mild splash
I had a few offers
By the way, I have a contract here
for you to sign...
sort of a wedding present
Johann... a contract?
Do you have quill pen?
Yeah, I'll get it
That's 1,000 golden for a year
for your waltz
1,000 golden a year?
Oh, Johann... who said you can't earn
money writing a waltz?
I always believe in being generous to
young composers
Here, just sign here... sign here
I'm sorry, Mr. Hofbauer...
but this is not enough
Not enough?
Are you joking?
Here go on... sign
No...
I mean it... the golden is down
We're headed for an inflation...
the discount rate might go to 20%
Oh, no, not 1,000 golden a year...
but 1,000 golden for each waltz
I write in a year
What?
You must be mad... you must be crazy
Call me somebody... he has a fever
You know I must spend money
for exploitation...
exploitation
It's 1,000 golden for each waltz
or nothing
Oh... 1,000 golden
Well, say we're... compromise
I'll give you 500 golden... 500
1,000 golden
Well, 750 golden
1,000 golden?
Alright...
Here...
I don't expect you to write a waltz
or 2 in a year, don't we?
Here are 6 to start with
Oh... 6,000 golden
He's a music rapid for
you were no Mr. Hofbauer
Fine piece of appreciation...
Everybody should be proud love to sing
Hofbauer publication,
even Carla Donner Carla Donner?
I don't care who sings them...
Vienna will sing them
JULIUS HOFBAUER PUBLICATION
WEDDING BELLS:
A Waltz by Johann Strauss
ROSES FROM THE SOUTH:
WINE WOMEN AND SONG:
A Waltz by Johann Strauss
VOICES OF SPRING:
Vienna loved Strauss waltzes
and listened to new ideas
It clamored for the right of man
to govern himself
and so one day Strauss wrote a march
DOWN WITH TYRANNY
GIVE ARMS TO THE STUDENTS
Hey... it's Johann
It's the Palace of Hobenfried
Whose palace?
Hobenfried
I know that place... let's charge
Wait
Well, it's my fiddle player
Are you going to walk out
during the game again, Mr. Strauss?
Take her away
Now, wait a minute... she's not an enemy
She's a singer... she's an artist...
just like ourselves
She's one of us... that's why she's here
She's our Goddess of Liberty
Just a minute, gentlemen...
I'm a singer, yes
But a goddess... damn that
You should stick to your music...
Mr. Strauss
Carla...
I'll take care of her
Carla
Now stop shouting, you fool...
it's trouble enough there
I'm not afraid of the rebels...
I'm not one of them
If they find out she's your friend...
they'll tear her to pieces
I suppose she's sick of with the
common fiddlers
Yes, you're kind of responsible
for all this
You mean you aren't?
If I have my saber...
Well, you haven't got any
Now you listen to me
She was about to be mobbed in the
carriage when I came in a nick of time
Open the door, Hobenfried
Oh, no... you don't
Just a moment... release him, who are you?
My name is Strauss, Johan Strauss...
not your humble servant either
Now if you want some good advice...
don't poke your nose out that way
The mad musician, Sir
Oh, I see... an artist, a musician
And just what's your part in the
revolution, Mr. Strauss?
I wrote the song
See, and just why are you rebelling...
Mr. Strauss?
Why... ?
Because... 'tyranny oppressior has been
written in the banners there...
can't you read?
And how are you oppressed, Mr. Strauss?
Oh, never mind that
Now if you know what's good for you...
you'll sneak out the back way
You're impertinent, Sir
And you're a stuffed shirt and
your face annoys me
Yes, Captain?
The situation is under control now...
all the rioters have been arrested
And arrest this man too
I'll see you again some time
I ask profound apology in my house...
Your Highness...
The incident doesn't occur, Hobenfried
Thank you, Sir
And now, we must go immediately
With your permission, Your Highness... I must...
there's someone in distress
I'm sorry, Hobenfried, there's empire
in distress
I'm just trying to tell you that
she has nothing to do with this
Shut up... come on here
You idiot...
I happen to be Madam Carla Donner
of the Opera
Yes... I know
Goldilocks... you're Goddess of Liberty
Go ahead
The farmers must be very happy
Halt... remove the barricade...
Dudelman... Kienzl, Dudelman
Johann
Kienzl, what's on your mind?
Kienzl, for the last time...
what's on your mind?
For you, Kienzl
Hurry up... come with me
Which way did they go?
Down the street, get them back... come on
After them
I can't go like this... where can we go?
Come with me
My shoe
Your what?
You, oh... I'm afraid it's not safe here
No place is safe with you...
I want to go home
Where do you live?
I won't tell you
I'm not taking any more chances
Alright... you stay here
I won't stay here... give me my shoe
Your what?
Yes
Madam, if ever there's a man regretted
his kindness,
I'm that man
You... kind... ?
Coachman
Have you 2 heard there'll be
a revolution?
Maybe... Harrison Street, No.8
I bet you haven't heard...
it had been barricaded
Well, l... can you reach Yusa Estate Casa?
How long have you 2 been here?
It's barricaded too
Is there any place in Vienna you can go
except around this block?
Well, yes...
There're always the Vienna Woods...
a lovely ride
Now, will you decide, Madam?
Frankly, I don't care
I don't care where I'm and where I go
or whether the sun will rise again
or whether I'll live or die...
I just don't care
The Vienna Woods
The Vienna Woods... get up, Rosy
What time is it?
Where am I?
Good morning
If you knew how pretty picture you've made...
2 little babes in the woods
sleeping in each other's arms
Where are we?
Where you want to be... in Vienna Woods
And it's only 6 o'clock in the morning
and you still have a long and
beautiful day ahead of you
You haven't helped me
Amen
Come on... my Rosy
GRINZING GARTEN RESTAURANT
You won't believe it, but we composed
the whole thing in one day
with only 20 minutes over lunch
What do you mean 'we'?
I mean 'we'...
Mr. And Mrs. Strauss, me and Rosy
Alright... I'll keep an ear open
for sour notes
If there's any sour note and it's the flaw,
I beg you to leave it out
Such a time for revolution... just when
Johann Strauss himself
drops out of a clear sky and leave
my own restaurant on Sunday for nothing
Yes, right...
these Viennese are coming
to a revolution on Sunday
Such a thing won't happen in my time
Quick, Cafniya...
go see the lady
left her hat on the carriage
Maybe this is it?
Come to see it's... here it's
Thank you
What a beautiful hat, Mrs. Strauss
What did you say?
I said it's a beautiful hat
Oh, yes
Oh, please... let me do that
Excuse me, Mrs. Strauss...
but I know these artists
I've been there to one for 30 years
Cafniya used to play the accordion
till the children broke it
Does your husband have a temper too?
Terrible
But I guess it's won'th it
It must be wonderful to be the wife
of a man like Johann Strauss
Yes, it must be wonderful
Oh, it's so beautiful, Mrs. Strauss...
what's the name of it?
What?
Oh, it's called... it's called
Oh...
I thought of you ever since that night
And you walked away, proud and angry
Carla... I'm married
Oh... but you're here now
with your arms around me
Carla, we must face this
No... don't you see?
It was meant to be like this
Everything had brought us together...
the night... the woods and the music...
It had been so sweet and so dangerous
The revolution... the revolution is over
We've got a new Emperor...
Duke Franz Joseph
a young wonderful Emperor
and a new Constitution
Look at them
Kienzl, Dudelman... how did you get here?
We've been released...
everybody is released
Did you have... a pleasant escape?
We have a charming escape...
thank both of you gentlemen
You're welcome, Madam
Now that you're free
You can play for us, Johann, can't you?
Oh, no... Kienzl
Yes... hey... listen everybody
This is our Strauss... our leader
He's going to lead our march
Will you forgive me, Carla?
Sure
Madam Donner?
Yes, what's it?
Count Hobenfried is outside, Madam
He has been searching everywhere
for you
I'll tell him you're here
Wait... take me to him
Carla, I've been so anxious
Tony... you're always so kind to me
I'm sorry... I'm not going back to Vienna
with you
Why not?
I can't leave here now
Strauss is there?
Yes...
This is not like you, Tony
I'll run back with you... shall we go?
The palace
To my house
Long live the Emperor
Kienzl... will that be the new Emperor?
Yes... have a new wonderful face
Well, I didn't think so yesterday and
I told him so
You do what?
Ah, Mrs. Strauss... is Johann here?
Did he get my message?
Oh, he must be full of marches
after the revolution like this
I'll tell him you're here
Oh, I thank you
Alright... boy, let's go
Good morning, Mrs. Strauss... good morning
Come on, Kienzl
Mr. Kienzl, please... I've been promoted
'You told me you loved me
when we were young one day'
Remember when you told me, Johann?
That's the most beautiful day
of my life
Please, Poldi... I'm very busy now
Johann, you must take time
for your coffee
Alright
'You told me you loved me'
What makes you think of it now, Johann?
Poldi, can't you see I'm working?
Why ask a silly question like that?
I write a song as it comes to me...
out of... out of my inspiration...
out of everything...
out of heaven knows what
I guess so, Johann...
drink your coffee before it's cold
Cold?
It's scolding
I'll cool it for you
Johann, don't you think you should
lie down a while?
You must be tired after being
out of night
What are you driving at?
Can't you see I'm working?
Why should I be tired?
I worked before, didn't I?
Oh, Johann... I won't disturb you anymore
Now you're hurt
No, I'm not hurt
You are
No, it's only... Johann, you're so crossed
since you come home
You didn't...
I don't expect you to kiss me
if you don't feel like it
But you didn't talk to me
Johann, what's the matter with you?
You're imagining things, that's all
I think it's you ought to lie down...
you're pale and tired
You know I can't sleep when
you're not at home
Now, that has got to stop
Why can't you sleep when I'm not home?
It's only natural for a wife who
can't sleep when her husband is out...
in danger maybe
Why do I talk about things like that?
You're not going to stay out anymore
We don't have revolution everyday...
thanks heaven
What does revolution have to do
with it?
The revolution is the only thing that
can keep a man out once in a while?
Things happen to a man
Things... you can't foresee anything
Besides, I'm not your slave...
not your prisoner...
and we're not chained to each other
Don't shout at me, please
If you've something on your mind...
if you've something want to tell me...
tell me
But don't shout at me
If you don't want to tell me,
you don't need to make excuses for yourself
You don't need to act like this
If you want to stay out at night...
you're free to do so
But you must leave me free to worry
about you if I like
You must respect my feelings
To be the wife of Johann Strauss
is not a little thing
I've tried to be won'thy of it
I'm very proud of it
I won't let anyone shout at me
for your sake as well as mine
Forgiver me, Poldi
I always seem to be shouting at you
I don't know what's the matter with me
I wouldn't change you... nothing on you...
not even your moods... your temper
because I know you must be like this
to be you
Alright then, let's go away
It'll be better... better for both of us
Let's forget we ever saw Vienna
Forget Vienna?
L... I mean... there're too many
distractions here
But we live here, Johann
We live in a lovely new home and
all our friends
Don't you want to travel?
Don't you want to see the world?
Of course, I do
If you... so...
Alright then, darling... that's settled
Now you start packing your things and
I'll make the arrangements
We can't just pack up and go
We have a lot of things to attend to
No, nonsense
Then we go without attending to them
Poldi, when you think of going...
that's the time to go
But Mr. Hofbauer downstairs and boys...
Oh, they are... fine
Come on... let's go
I'll tell them we're going right away
Ah... Strauss
Kienzl, will you stop that for a minute?
You wrote it
Alright... I'm sorry
Well, Poldi has something say to you
Huh?
Go on, Poldi... tell them the good news
Good news?
Right
We're going to leave Vienna
What?
Immediately
What for?
What's happening?
Why are you leaving?
Why he can't leave Vienna
if he wants to?
Vienna is not the world
and he doesn't owe Vienna anything
Vienna owes him more than
it can ever pay
What becomes of me... ?
Why the fuss?
Why are you all upset about?
The musician ought to travel
Poldi and I have made up our minds
It's all as well... we'll be back someday
Yes, we've planned it, that's all
After all, we never had our
real honeymoon
By the way, did you get my march?
No
What do you mean?
Didrt you get my message?
I haven't got a march
What have you got?
Nothing
Nothing?
Yes... there's a new piece you've composed
Yes, Poldi, it... but it's not ready yet
Look here, Strauss
Has Shanon made you some offer?
Remember you have a contract with me
for everything you write
Mr. Hofbauer, you know he won't do
a thing like that
If he doesn't want to play...
you mustrt urge him
I never urged him...
just temperamental, that's all
He wants to be temperamental...
but he took my 1,000 golden...
For every golden... alright, I'll get it
Johann, you have it in your pocket... here
Yes... go ahead, Kienzl
Sure... let's start
Alright... let's take places
Come on... sit down, boys
Come on, don't keep waiting
while you listen
He keeps waiting
You keep waiting
All I have to do is waiting
You don't have to wait, Mr. Hofbauer
Vienna is a free city, you know
Oh, I see
The whole world is waiting
for this waltz
Why shouldn't you wait?
Yes, you should... that's right
Bravo...
Carla
Madam Donner
How do you do, Madam?
It was beautiful, Mr. Strauss
Thank you, Madam
I have great news
You've been commissioned to try another
opera in the Imperial Theatre
for me to sing
Oh, wonderful
Madam, you're incomparable
Cheer, everybody
Well, Johann, aren't you pleased?
Yes, of course, Madam... of course
Madam, will you permit me?
Poldi, this is my wife
I'm very glad to know you, Mrs. Strauss
I've been very anxious to meet you
This is an honor, Madam...
thank you, you're very kind
I'm very grateful, Madam, but...
I can't accept
We've made our plans...
we're leaving Vienna
What's the matter, Strauss?
Are you insane?
Johann... for all our sake
You must persuade him, Mrs. Strauss
This is no time for pride, isn't it?
You're right, Madam...
this is no time for pride
You must stay, Johann
You mustrt miss an opportunity
like this... without considering
To write an opera for the Imperial Theatre,
this is what we... what you wanted all the time...
what you've dreamed for
A NEW OPERA
Shall I put this away, Mrs. Strauss?
Poldi darling, maybe you'll change
your mind
No, Mama... out the dress away, Anna
I don't want to nag you, Poldi
But after all, you really belong there
What will people think?
Mother, please... I'm too excited
I'm so happy here with you and
we can pray for him with all my heart and thoughts
After the performance, we can celebrate
I believe that carriage is stopping
in front of our house
Yes, it is
Johann has sent for me
Be careful... be careful of the stairs...
Poldi
I'll open the door, Anna
Is Mrs. Strauss in?
I'm Mrs. Strauss
I'm Count Hobenfried
My husband isn't here
I know...
could I speak to you for a moment?
Come in, Sir
Thank you
I shouldn't detain you for long, Madam
Thank you, no...
Perhaps something what I've to say
is known to you
l... Madam, I'm in love with Carla Donner
What's that you want to speak to me
about, Count Hobenfried?
Madam, for some time now,
Madam Carla and your husband had...
had been infatuated with each other
During all these weeks of rehearsals...
they've been together constantly and...
I don't understand one word
you're saying
You don't know what all Vienna is...
forgive me, Madam
I understand what you feel...
Count Hobenfried
But you're mistaken
There's nothing wrong, I swear
I give you my word
You know, of course...
there's always this rumor
Madam, for your sake,
I'd not presume for the sake of mine
But for his sake, you should stop this
at once
I've no right in this matter, Madam
You're his wife... you have
She'll destroy him
They'll destroy each other
She's the woman of violent feelings...
strange whims
and irresistible impulses
Mr. Strauss is not for the man
to cope with this extraordinary person
He'll be ruined
I beg you
Madam, you must face the facts
unless you're willing to surrender
What I can see is so dear to you
You compelled me and controlled me to
say what I don't intend to say to anyone
You had told me nothing
that is not known to me
that isn't known to me for some time
I lived all these weeks for...
the knife in my heart
I'm content to live here for his sake
It's the better way it must be
I'm sure there was anything to be done
he'd have done it
I'm sure he suffers as much as I do
Mrs. Strauss, Madam Donner leaves
after the opera tonight for tour of Europe
The situation between them...
I advise you to act quickly
What'd you have me do?
Fight
What everyone wants to live in this
world, he has to fight for...
like the beast of jungle
This crisis arrives between people
even carefree,
but profoundly
If you want to keep him...
if you want to save him...
don't leave it in his hands
You must fight
I thought my love fought for me
I thought he needed me and
that was enough
It's not enough
You'll lose...
Don't say anymore, Count Hobenfried
Will you excuse me?
All this humiliation...
You never humiliated yourself...
Count Hobenfried
I've the greatest respect... the greatest
Who was it, Poldi?
Poldi, what's the matter with you?
Who was it?
Why don't you say something?
What time is it, mother?
It's quarter to 10
Poldi, what happened?
What's the matter with you?
First I dress up
Do you think I could get there in time
for the finale?
But if you hurry, you might
But what come over you?
Now suddenly you make up your mind
You're quite right, mother
I'm going, of course... I'm going
I have to go
Johann offered me not have to go
before, was it?
Ha... why those people do
such a crazy thing?
You'd better lie down, Poldi
Lie down?
There's no time to lie down, mother
This is the time to fight...
fight to this beast
All Vienna knows
There's nothing to hide... nothing
Help me, mother... quickly
Quickly
I'm frightened
Oh, there's nothing to be frightened of
mother darling...
There's nothing to be frightened of
I'm going to the opera, that's all
I'm going to the opera to Johann
I knew there's something
Love is no good, mother darling...
for women like us
That's for the other kind...
for women who take...
for women who steal...
for women who have no hearts
If you've no other competence, leave it
Can't they, mother?
My jewels?
Where are my jewels?
I have as much right to wear my jewels
as she
From now on, I'll never go out
without my jewels
Poldi darling, if you really don't want
to go to the opera,
you don't have to
Maybe I upset you
Now you're too excited
No, mother... I'm not excited
I was for a moment, but not anymore
The performance won't end without me
I'm also bound to... a big part, you know
I'm bound to be the star of Johanrs opera,
not that woman
She is not stealing anymore
And in his heart, Johann will be glad
Bravo, Strauss
The world is at your feet tonight
My world is beside me...
we belong together
I always know it
I know it now
I'll go with you to Budapest tonight
Darling, in 2 hours we'll be
in the Danube
Oh, Carla... you were wonderful
Thank you... hurry
How do you do, Mrs. Strauss?
Well, what do you think of Strauss
tonight?
Did you ever see him so magnificent?
He's going to Budapest with you tonight
Yes, my dear... he's going with me
We might as well face it, don't you?
He loves me and I love him
There's nothing, not anyone can do
about it
You can't... I can't... he can't
Yes, I know that
If I were you, I'd have spared myself
from this embarrassment
I'd ask you to give a message for me
I know he won't leave without...
without explaining everything
That would be difficult for him...
for us both
Tell him there's no need of it
Tell him he's quite free
He needs not to worry about me
Will you tell him that?
You're very unselfish
or unexpectedly clever
For charity, I like it
Believe me, Madam...
I know it sounds silly
But if his happiness is with you...
I think I love his happiness more than
I do him
You probably deserve him more than I do
But he's going with me
So don't ever fool yourself
to sacrifice again
Happiness is in your own heart...
not in someone else's
I found that out
I think you'll feel differently after
you've been with Johann for a while
You see... Johann isn't like other man
If you hurt him, you might as well
kill him
And you've to watch him carefully...
so he doesn't fall off the horse in the street
And if you don't take care when he's
working, he'll starve to death
Poldi
Poldi... I want to talk to you
They told me you were here
Yes, I came here to congratulate
Madam Donner
Johann, you're wonderful...
you both are wonderful
Did you see the audiences?
Everybody was excited
One hand clapped so hard and
nearly fell off his box to the orchestra
I must go now, l... I must find my parents
because they get lost in place like this
You know Mama and Papa
Wait a minute, Mrs. Strauss...
you can't run away from this
He won't go without talking to you
Johann, she knows... I'll continue waiting
in my dressing room
Poldi, l...
Johann... you mustrt... I understand
But Poldi, I must tell you...
call the man is called what you'll
Oh, Johann...
why did you torture yourself?
Why didn't you tell me early?
You always come to me
when you're in trouble
Why can't you find someone
won'thy of you?
I had... I've been happier than most women
in their lives
Everything comes to an end... everything
And the world goes on just the same...
even when we die
Poldi
Don't talk anymore, Johann...
everything is the way it should be
Yes, he is here
Please...
I've bought the ticket to the
Danube Boat Sail for Budapest tonight
Remember, if you've anything written...
give me the first call
Don't forget that, Madam
Keep an eye on him...
you know those Hungarian women
I do my best... goodnight, Johann
Goodnight... Poldi
I must pack except for his music
I don't know what to do with his stanza
He leaves everything
for the last minute... goodnight
Don't worry, I'll attend to everything...
goodnight
Mrs. Strauss, permit me
to congratulate you
You must be the happiest woman
in Vienna tonight
Goodnight
Congratulations
Mrs. Strauss
Goodnight
Oh, Mrs. Strauss...
goodnight, Mrs. Strauss
Goodnight
What are you thinking about?
Oh, l... I was thinking the first time
we were in carriage together
Remember the old coachman?
And the star is hanging over
on his harmonica
And Rosy... remember Rosy?
His old white horse
Yes... and he claimed it understood
everything he said
Have you ever been on the Danube?
Of course, you have
Yes, but not this way, Johann
I never have...
when we were crazy youngsters
We used to stand on the bank and
throw rocks on the boat
Bad little boys
I remember...
once the police caught us and...
and Poldi cried because she thought...
Well, we... we nearly went to the jail
Well, here we're
Yes, here we're
Oh, the night is so beautiful
Yes
Shall I take your baggage?
Take only these 2
Yes, Madam
Carla?
There's another horror between us
in the carriage
It'll always be so... goodbye, Johann
Something difficult and honest
had to be said
You just like you to say
There's the wave we call again
Now I know
why part of my heart
will always love you
It has only been away from you
I can be content so little with your heart
Vanity... thy name is woman
And the earth and the blood of life
itself is vanity
Remember me, Johann
All the days in my life
Are you listening, Johann?
You wrote it for me, didn't you?
Every note and every word
Give it to me... will you give it to me?
It has always been yours
THE BLUE DANUBE:
Waltz by Johann Strauss Jr.
THE IMPEREIAL PALACE, VIENNA
43 YEARS LATER
Your Majesty... Mr. Johann Strauss
Johann Strauss?
It has been a long time
since I've seen him...
50 years, isn't it?
Well, perhaps it's a trifle less...
Your Majesty
Ask him to come in
Mr. Johann Strauss
I knew you once, Mrs. Strauss
Your memory is very great...
Count Hobenfried
With your permission...
now, remember, Johann
Yes... I know
Take 3 steps into the room...
bow from the waist...
be courteous... respectful... modest... I know
I shouldn't trust him, Madam
You see, with the reputation you have...
my sweetheart
Now then... go
Come... cut out that nonsense, Strauss
It took me a long time to have
an audience to you, didn't it?
But finally I succeeded
Your Majesty, l...
You were always on such excellent term...
werert we?
Tell me... is there still anything
about me that I'd annoy you?
No... Your Majesty
I think you called me a stuffed shirt
And without thinking further,
I think I was a stuffed shirt
We were very young then, Your Majesty
And now you're king of Vienna
I don't know what Your Majesty means
Oh, you don't?
Well, come with me, Johann
I'll show you what I mean
This can't be happening to me
It could happen only to you
Vienna is giving you the love that
you gave Vienna