#### [ Whistling ]
#### [ Scatting ]
#### [ Scatting Continues ]
## TOGETHER AGAIN ##
## GEE, IT'S GOOD
TO BE TOGETHER AGAIN ##
## I JUST CAN'T IMAGINE THAT
YOU'VE EVER BEEN GONE ##
## IT'S NOT STARTING OVER
IT'S JUST GOING ON ##
## TOGETHER AGAIN ##
## NOW WE'RE HERE AND THERE'S
NO NEED REMEMBERING WHEN ##
## 'CAUSE NO FEELING
FEELS LIKE THAT FEELING ##
## TOGETHER AGAIN ##
## GEE, IT'S GOOD
TO BE TOGETHER AGAIN ##
## I JUST CAN'T IMAGINE THAT
YOU'VE EVER BEEN GONE ##
## IT'S NOT STARTING OVER
IT'S JUST GOING ON ##
## TOGETHER AGAIN ##
## AGAIN ##
## NOW WE'RE HERE
AND THERE'S NO NEED
REMEMBERING WHEN ##
## 'CAUSE NO FEELING
FEELS LIKE THAT FEELING ##
## TOGETHER A--
TOGETHER A--
TOGETHER A-- ##
## TOGETHER AGAIN ##
## TOGETHER AGAIN ####
[ Chattering ]
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
OOPS.
[ Cheering Continues ]
THEY LIKE IT !
THEY LOVE IT !
THEY'RE STILL APPLAUDING.
KERMY, YOU HAVE TO GO OUT
AND TAKE A BOW.
YEAH.
TAKE A BOW.
KERMIT !  KERMIT !
GO.
[ Giggles ]
YEAH.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.  THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, UH--
I REALLY DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY EXCEPT, UH--
WELL, WE'RE REALLY GLAD
YOU LIKED MANHATTAN MELODIES,
BECAUSE WE ALL WORKED SO HARD
TO MAKE IT THE BEST
SENIOR VARIETY SHOW EVER.
HEY, KERMIT, NEXT TIME
WE'LL SEE YOU ON BROADWAY !
[ Applause ]
YEAH.  YEAH, SURE.
THAT'S A GREAT IDEA.
WHY DON'T WE TAKE MANHATTAN
MELODIES TO NEW YORK ?
WHAT ?
BROADWAY'D BE DYING TO GET
A GREAT MUSICAL LIKE THIS.
BROADWAY ?
WE'D JUST LIKE TO
THANK EVERYBODY FOR
HAVING SO MUCH FAITH IN US.
IT'S NOT OFTEN THAT A FROG
AND A BEAR AND A PIG...
AND A CHICKEN AND A WHATEVER
EVEN GET ACCEPTED INTO COLLEGE.
WE'RE ALL SO PROUD
TO BE GRADUATING NOW,
SOME WITH HONORS--
[ Screaming ]
WOMAN !  WOMAN !  WOMAN !
WOMAN !  WOMAN !
WOMAN !
SOME WITH THE HELP OF
DAILY PSYCHOLOGICAL COUNSELING.
ANYWAY, ANYWAY,
THANK YOU AGAIN.
THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING, GUYS.
THANK YOU.  YEAH.  THANK YOU.
BROADWAY ?
YEAH !  YEAH !  YEAH !
BUT THIS SHOW'S NOT
GOOD ENOUGH FOR BROADWAY.
THE SCRIPT NEEDS WORK.  I THINK
THERE'S SOMETHING MISSING.
NO !  NO !  NO !
KERMY, KERMY.  REMEMBER YOU SAID
WE COULD NOT GET MARRIED UNTIL
WE HAD ENOUGH MONEY ?
YEAH.
WELL, WE'D HAVE ENOUGH
IF WE HAD A HIT ON BROADWAY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YES, YES.
BROADWAY OF WHAT CITY ?
AW, COME ON.  COME ON.
EVEN IF THE SHOW
WAS GOOD ENOUGH,
WE'RE JUST GRADUATING.
WHAT ABOUT
OUR FUTURE PLANS ?
WELL, THIS
COULD BE OUR FUTURE.
YEAH !  YEAH !
IF WE DON'T DO IT, WE JUST
SAY GOOD-BYE TO EACH OTHER.
OH.
BROADWAY !
BROADWAY, BROADWAY !
WHAT ARE WE WAITING FOR ?
LET'S GO TO BROADWAY !
YEAH !  YEAH !
BROADWAY !
NEW YORK !
LOOK AT EVERYTHING THERE !
WE MADE IT, GUYS.
WE'RE REALLY HERE.
[ Chattering ]
WHAT A GREAT-LOOKING PLACE.
IT'S FILLED
WITH NEW YORKERS.
LOOK AT 'EM ALL.
WOWEE !
LOOK HOW GORGEOUS
EVERYTHING IS.  OHH.
WE BETTER DUMP OUR STUFF
AND FIND A PLACE TO STAY.
[ Chattering ]
YEAH.
OKAY, SCOOTER,
BREAK OUT THE QUARTERS.
YES, SIR.
YOU ALL RIGHT DOWN THERE ?
HOW ABOUT UP THERE ?
[ Chattering ]
WHAT DO YOU THINK, GUYS ?
WHAT ?
I SAY, HOW DO YOU LIKE IT ?
OH, IT'S GREAT.
MUCH BETTER THAN THAT CEMENT
MIXER I USED TO LIVE IN.
I'LL TRADE WITH ANYONE
THAT HAS A JACUZZI.
COME ON.
IT'S JUST FOR ONE DAY.
WE'LL ALL BE
ON BROADWAY TOMORROW.
YEAH.
WE'D LIKE TO SEE MR. PRICE.
[ Woman ]
DO YOU HAVE AN APPOINTMENT ?
NO, BUT WE SAW HIS NAME
IN THE PAPER.
WE'VE GOT THIS SHOW CALLED
MANHATTAN MELODIES HE'S GONNA
WANT TO PRODUCE ON BROADWAY.
IT'S ABOUT A COUPLE OF KIDS
THAT COME TO NEW YORK CITY
TO GET MARRIED.
IT HAS A WONDERFUL OPENING
NUMBER.  IT GOES LIKE THIS.
HOLD IT.  HOLD IT.
#### [ Humming ]
[ Man On Intercom ]
WHAT'S GOING ON OUT THERE ?
JUST A FROG
WITH A MUSICAL, MR. PRICE.
MUSICAL ?  SEND HIM IN.
[ Chattering ]
NET.  I'M TALKING NET.
YOU'VE GOTTA BE KIDDING
WITH GROSS.
NICE UPHOLSTERY.
HOLD IT A MINUTE.
I'LL GET BACK TO YOU.
MR. PRICE, I'M KERMIT,
AND THESE ARE MY FRIENDS.
WE'VE GOT A SHOW CALLED
MANHATTAN MELODIES...
WE THINK YOU'RE GONNA
WANT TO PRODUCE ON BROADWAY.
IT'S ABOUT A COUPLE OF KIDS
THAT COME TO NEW YORK CITY
TO GET MARRIED.
IT OPENS WITH A GREAT NUMBER
THAT GOES LIKE THIS.
## LOOK AT ME
HERE I AM-- ##
FROG.  FROG.
NO SINGING, OKAY ?
GIVE ME THE GENERAL IDEA.
IT'S ALL ABOUT LIFE
IN THE BIG CITY.
BIG CITY, HUH ?  COPS ?
SHOOTINGS ?  CAR CHASES ?
THAT KIND OF THING ?
[ Kermit ]
NO SHOOTING STUFF.
IT'S MORE LIKE SONGS AND DANCES.
SONGSANDDANCES ?
MM-HMM.
THAT MIGHT BE INTERESTING.
NOBODY CARES ABOUT
SHOOTINGS ANYWAY.
WHAT ARE YOU THINKING ABOUT ?
BIG-NAME STARS ?
WELL, WE'RE GONNA BE THE STARS.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS
ABOUT TO SAY.
- YOU BE THE STARS.
- UH-HUH.
SONGS, DANCES, SHOOTINGS.
UH-UH.
NO.  NO SHOOTINGS.
YOU KNOW WHAT ?
I SMELL SOMETHING.
[ Sniffing ]
WHY DOES EVERYONE
ALWAYS BLAME DOGS ?
WHAT I SMELL IS A HIT.
A WHAT ?
- A HIT.
- YOU MEAN--
ABSOLUTELY.  I'D BE PROUD
TO PRODUCE YOUR SHOW.
FELLAS, YOU'RE GONNA
BE ON BROADWAY.
OH, OH, OH.
KERMIT, WE DID IT !
WE DID IT !
THANKS A LOT, MR. PRICE.
I REALLY WOULD LIKE YOU
TO READ THE SCRIPT.
THERE'S STILL
SOMETHING MISSING.
NO, FROG, FROG.
WE FIX ALL THOSE THINGS
IN THE PREVIEWS.  I'VE GOT
A MILLION THINGS TO DO.
I'VE GOTTA CALL THE PAPERS,
RENT A THEATER, AND ALL
I NEED FROM YOU IS $300.
- THREE HUNDRED DOLLARS ?
- YEAH.  APIECE.
APIECE ?
TODAY.  YEAH.
WHAT ?
[ Kermit Whimpers ]
LOOK, FELLAS, THAT'S
STANDARD BROADWAY PROCEDURE.
YOU GIVE ME THE MONEY,
AND WE START
THE REHEARSALS TOMORROW.
BUT WE DON'T HAVE--
I DON'T THINK THAT'S RIGHT.
YEAH, NOW I SMELL SOMETHING.
FELLAS--
[ Woman ]
MR. PRICE.
THERE ARE
TWO POLICE OFFICERS OUTSIDE.
THEY'D LIKE TO SPEAK TO YOU.
THAT'S HIM.
THAT'S MURRAY PLOTSKY.
I GAVE HIM MY LIFE SAVINGS.
MURRAY ?  I THOUGHT
HIS NAME WAS MARTIN.
LET'S GO, MURRAY.  YOU'VE
PULLED YOUR LAST CON JOB.
I DON'T WANT ANY TROUBLE.
[ Squawking ]
GET BACK OR THE CHICKEN GETS IT.
- THAT'S A THREAT ?
- PLEASE DON'T HURT HER !
TAKE ME !
WHATEVER YOU SAY, PAL !
GET AWAY FROM THAT DOOR.
MOVE !
LET GO !
LET GO OF MY NOSE !
WATCH IT !  YOU TOO !
BAD MAN !
EASY !
[ Screams ]
WHOO !
[ Squawking ]
OHHH !
GET THIS OFF !
OH !
BACK !
[ Screaming ]
GET THIS CHICKEN OFF MY EAR !
GET IT OFF MY EAR !
GET IT OFF !  OH !
[ Screaming ]
GET IT OFF !
[ Chattering ]
GET IT OFF MY EAR !
[ Screaming ]
BAD MAN !  BAD MAN !
WAY TO GO, EVERYBODY.
WHERE WERE YOU
WHEN I NEEDED YOU ?
MURRAY ?
ANIMALS !
YOU'RE CRAZY-- ALL OF YOU !
I WANT MY MONEY BACK !
GONZO, ARE YOU OKAY ?
I JUST SAW MY WHOLE LIFE
FLASH BEFORE MY NOSE.
[ Gasping ]
CAMILLA !
SHE'S HYPERVENTILATING !
SHE NEEDS MOUTH-TO-BEAK
RESUSCITATION !
KERMIT, HE NEVER
WANTED OUR SHOW.
HE JUST WANTED OUR MONEY.
YEAH.
GONZO, IS CAMILLA
ALL RIGHT ?
YEAH, BUT I THINK
WE'RE ENGAGED.
COME ON, EVERYBODY.
WE'RE GONNA GET
THIS SHOW ON BROADWAY !
RIGHT !
YEAH, LET'S GO, GUYS !
#### [ Rock ]
####
## YOU CAN'T TAKE NO
FOR AN ANSWER ##
## NO, NO, NO ##
####
## WHENEVER THERE'S A DREAM
WORTH A-DREAMIN' ##
## DREAMIN' ##
## YOU WANNA SEE
THAT DREAM COME TRUE ##
## DREAM COME TRUE ##
## THERE'LL BE PLENTY
OF PEOPLE TALKIN'--
SAY FORGET ALL ABOUT IT ##
## SAYIN' IT ISN'T WORTH
THE TROUBLE ##
## ALL THE TROUBLE
THAT YOU'RE GOIN' THROUGH ##
## IT AIN'T WORTH IT, NO ##
## WHAT CAN YOU DO ##
- ## YOU CAN'T TAKE NO
FOR AN ANSWER ##
-## YOU CAN'T TAKE NO ##
## YOU CAN'T TAKE NO
FOR AN ANSWER ##
## NO, NO, NO, NO ##
## YOU CAN'T TAKE NO
FOR AN ANSWER
NO, NO, NO ##
## NO-NO-NO
NO-NO-NO, NO-NO-NO ##
## WHAT YA GONNA DO
WHEN THE TIMES GET TOUGH ##
## AND THE WORLD'S
TREATIN' YOU UNKIND ##
## YOU GOTTA HANG ON TO
YOUR OPTIMISTIC OUTLOOK ##
## AND KEEP POSSESSION
OF YOUR POSITIVE
STATE OF MIND ##
## STATE OF MIND, STATE
OF MIND, STATE OF MIND
STATE-- STATE OF MIND ##
- ## YOU CAN'T TAKE NO
FOR AN ANSWER ##
- ## YOU CAN'T TAKE NO ##
## YOU CAN'T TAKE NO
FOR AN ANSWER ##
## NO, NO, NO, NO ##
## YOU CAN'T TAKE NO
FOR AN ANSWER
NO, NO, NO ##
## NO-NO-NO
NO-NO-NO, NO-NO-NO ##
## NO, NO, NO ##
## NO-NO-NO
NO-NO-NO, NO-NO-NO ##
## NO, NO, NO ##
## NO-NO-NO
NO-NO-NO, NO-NO-NO ##
## NO, NO, NO ####
THIS IS TURNIN' OUT
TO BE A LITTLE TOUGHER
THAN I THOUGHT.
KERMIT, I'M NOT GOOD AT THIS.
I DON'T TAKE REJECTION WELL.
MAYBE WE COULD SELL THE SHOW
IF YOU WROTE IN SPECIAL EFFECTS,
LIKE EXPLODING SOCKS.
OH, GONZO, LIKE THAT'S
A REALLY LAME IDEA.
OH, YEAH ?
HEY, MAN,
STOP YELLIN' AT HER.
HE WASN'T YELLING.
YES, I WAS.
OH, GONZO,
DON'T MAKE TROUBLE.
FIGHT !  FIGHT !
[ Muttering ]
KERMIT, DO YOU THINK
WE SHOULD CHANGE THE SCRIPT ?
KERMIT, WHAT SHOULD WE DO ?
I DON'T KNOW !
HOW SHOULD I KNOW ?
WHY ARE YOU ASKING ME ?
CAN'T YOU TAKE CARE
OF YOURSELVES ?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO DO NEXT.
WE FAILED, OKAY ?
WE TRIED AND WE FAILED.
SCOOTER, HOW MUCH MONEY
DO WE HAVE LEFT ?
ENOUGH FOR TWO NIGHTS
UNLESS WE FIND CHEAPER LOCKERS.
WELL, WE HAVE TO EAT.
WHY START NOW ?
GONZO !
GANGWAY !  COMIN' THROUGH.
HEY, WATCH IT, WILL YA ?
HEY, THAT WAITER'S A RAT !
I'M GLAD WE GOT NO MONEY.
NOW I GOT NO APPETITE.
THERE YOU GO.
ONE CHEESEBURGER PLATTER.
WHAT DO YOU
WANT TO DRINK ?
GLASS OF MILK.
I WOULD LIKE
MEAT IN HERE.
PICKY !  HEY, PETE,
WHERE'S THE BEEF ?
IT'S COMING !
GOT TWO HANDS ONLY !
[ Sighing ]
OKAY.  WHAT'LL YOU HAVE ?
THE NUMBER FOR
THE BOARD OF HEALTH.
THAT DOES IT !
ANOTHER RAT CRACK ?
I GOT FEELINGS TOO.
DO YOU THINK I'M DOIN'
THIS AS A HOBBY ?
YOU WANNA KNOW
WHAT I MAKE ?
NOTHING !  NOTHING !
I LIVE ON TIPS !
I WORK HARD !
I TRY TO GET TIPS TO FEED
MY FAMILY AND MY MOTHER.
[ Sniffs ]
IT JUST ISN'T FAIR !
[ Whimpering ]
WE UNDERSTAND.
WE DON'T HAVE
ANY MONEY EITHER.
SORRY.
NOT MY TABLE.
WHAT A RAT !
UH, I'LL GET US
SOMETHING TO EAT.
IS PATTY COMING.
IS COW JUICE COMING.
RIZZO, WHERE JENNY ?
MAY I SEE A MENU, PLEASE ?
SPECIAL TODAY.
YANKEE BEAN SOUP,
WITH SPOON.
SORRY I'M LATE, POP.
HI, FRAN.  HOW ARE YA ?
IT WENT LONGER
THAN I THOUGHT.
YOU WILL BE
SO PROUD OF ME.
I DID GREAT !
IT WAS ALL ESSAY QUESTIONS.
NO SWEAT.  I KNOW I PASSED.
JENNY, THAT'S VERY GOOD.
IS COW JUICE AND PATTY FOR LADY.
- RIZZO, I'M BACK.
- IT'S ABOUT TIME.
I CAN'T HANDLE EVERYBODY.
TAKE THE WEIRDOS AT TABLE FOUR.
WHICH ONE
IS TABLE FOUR ?
I WONDER IF KERMY MEANT IT.
I MEAN, ABOUT FAILING.
THOSE PRODUCERS LOOKED AT US
LIKE WE WERE FROM OUTER SPACE.
WHAT ?  WHAT ?
NO, MAN.
GO BACK TO SLEEP.
NOBODY'S LANDED.
AH, OH.
WE'LL TAKE
11 BOWLS, PLEASE.
OKEYDOKEY.
JUST ONE THING.
WE'VE GOT THIS SHOW
THAT'S GONNA BE
A BIG HIT ON BROADWAY,
BUT, UH, WELL, UH,
UH,
RIGHT NOW
WE'RE ALL BROKE.
[ Jenny ]
YOU DON'T HAVE ANY MONEY ?
NOT REALLY.  NO.
WE'D WORK IT OFF.
WE PROMISE.
[ Woman ]
WAITRESS !
COMING.
HEY, I TELL YOU WHAT IS.
BIG CITY.  HMM ?
LIVE.  WORK.  HUH ?
BUT, NOT CITY OPEN.
ONLY PEOPLES.
PEOPLES IS PEOPLES.
NO IS BUILDINGS.
IS TOMATOES, UH ?
IS PEOPLES.
IS DANCING.  IS MUSIC.
IS POTATOES.
SO, PEOPLES
IS PEOPLES, OKAY ?
YEAH.
THANKS.
THAT HELPED A LOT.
WHERE YOU GOIN' ?
HUH ?  OH, UH, WELL--
AREN'T YOU GONNA
WAIT FOR YOUR SOUP ?
BUT I TOLD YOU.
WE DON'T HAVE--
I KNOW,
BUT I KNOW MY POP.
WHEN HE FIRST STARTED OUT
IN THIS CITY, HE DIDN'T
HAVE ANYTHING EITHER.
I BET HE'S BACK THERE
GETTING SOUP BOWLS
FOR EVERYBODY.
REALLY ?
WITH SOUP IN THEM ?
UH-HUH.  I GOTTA
GET BACK TO WORK.
I HAD A TEST TODAY.
I CAME IN LATE.
YEAH.  I HEARD
YOU PASSED THE TEST.
I HOPE I PASSED IT.
IT'S FOR ACCEPTANCE
INTO A FASHION DESIGN COLLEGE.
OH, YEAH ?  WE JUST
GRADUATED FROM COLLEGE.
REALLY ?
YEAH.
- MY NAME'S JENNY.
- HI.  I'M KERMIT.
- HI, KERMIT.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
- I'M A FROG.
[ Chattering ]
NO, NO, IT--
LISTEN, I'M SAYING
MAYBE IT'S TIME
WE WENT OUT ON OUR OWN.
YOU MEAN, ON OUR OWN ALONE ?
WITHOUT EVEN EACH OTHER ?
THE FROG'S RIGHT.  WE DO
DEPEND ON HIM TOO MUCH.
LIKE HE FEELS
TOO RESPONSIBLE FOR US.
HE'D BE BETTER OFF
IF WE LEFT TOWN.
I CAN'T LEAVE KERMIT.
WE'RE STILL PINNED.
[ Muttering ]
MAYBE--
OH--
UH--
I'M SORRY
I BLEW UP OUTSIDE.
BUT GUESS WHAT.
PETE'S COOKING UP
SOME SOUP FOR US.
OH.
MM-HMM.
WELL, WHAT'S WRONG ?
IT'S JUST--
WE'VE HAD
SOME JOB OFFERS, RIGHT ?
- YEAH !  RIGHT !
- JOB OFFERS !
- YEAH !  YEAH !
THAT'S GREAT.
THESE JOB OFFERS ARE...
KINDA OUT OF TOWN, RIGHT ?
-YEAH, YEAH.
-THEY'RE OUT-OF-TOWN JOB OFFERS.
WHAT JOB DID I GET ?
GONZO !
PIGGY, ARE YOU GOING TOO ?
WELL, KERMY, I--
[ Crying ]
WE GO BYE-BYE ?
KERMIT, WE'LL WRITE TO YOU
AND LET YOU KNOW WHERE WE ARE.
YEAH, AND, KERMIT,
WE STILL BELIEVE IN THE SHOW.
YEAH, YEAH.
BOARD !
## SAYING GOOD-BYE ##
## GOING AWAY ##
## SEEMS LIKE GOOD-BYE'S ##
##
## SUCH A HARD THING TO SAY
## TOUCHING A HAND ##
## WONDERING WHY ##
[ Both ]
## IT'S TIME
FOR SAYING GOOD-BYE ##
GOOD-BYE, KERMY !
PIG ?
KERMY !
GOOD-BYE !
## SAYING GOOD-BYE ##
## WHY IS IT SAD ##
## MAKES US REMEMBER ##
##
## THE GOOD TIMES WE'VE HAD
## MUCH MORE TO SAY ##
## FOOLISH TO TRY ##
## IT'S TIME ##
## FOR SAYING GOOD-BYE ##
## DON'T WANT TO LEAVE ##
## BUT WE BOTH KNOW ##
?
## SOMETIMES IT'S BETTER TO GO ?
## SOMEHOW I KNOW ##
## WE'LL MEET AGAIN ##
## NOT SURE QUITE WHERE ##
## AND I DON'T KNOW JUST WHEN ##
## YOU'RE IN MY HEART ##
## SO UNTIL THEN ##
## IT'S TIME FOR
SAYING GOOD-BYE ##
## SOMEHOW I KNOW ##
## WE'LL MEET AGAIN ##
## NOT SURE QUITE WHERE ##
## AND I DON'T KNOW JUST WHEN ##
## YOU'RE IN MY HEART ##
## SO UNTIL THEN ##
## WANNA SMILE ##
## WANNA CRY ##
## SAYING GOOD-BYE ##
[ Group ]
## LA-LA-LA-LA ##
## IT'S TIME ##
## FOR SAYING GOOD-BYE ##
## LA-LA-LA-LA ##
## LA-LA, LA-LA-LA ##
## LA-LA ####
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
LOOK AT ALL THOSE PEOPLE
OUT THERE.
LOTS OF PEOPLE.
BUT MY FRIENDS--
MY FRIENDS ARE ALL GONE.
I'M GONNA GET 'EM BACK.
I'M GONNA GET 'EM BACK !
'CAUSE THE SHOW'S NOT DEAD
AS LONG AS I BELIEVE IN IT.
I'M GONNA SELL THAT SHOW.
WE'RE ALL GONNA BE ON BROADWAY !
YOU HEAR ME, NEW YORK ?
WE'RE GONNA BE ON BROADWAY !
BECAUSE--
BECAUSE I'M NOT GIVIN' UP !
I'M STILL HERE AND I'M STAYIN' !
YOU HEAR THAT, NEW YORK ?
I'M STAYIN' HERE !
THE FROG IS STAYIN' !
HI, JENNY.
KERMIT.  HI !
RIZZO, IS BAGEL READY !
IS HOMINY GRITS READY !
EXCUSE ME, PETE.
WHAT IS ?
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
HAVE SOME WORK HERE.
RIZZO, IS READY !
PART-TIME SO I COULD
KEEP WORKING ON THE SHOW.
WHAT IS THAT
SUPPOSED TO BE ?
IS GRITS.
HOMINY GRITS.
HOW SHOULD I KNOW HOW MANY ?
COUNT 'EM YOURSELF !  HA-HA.
WHAT ?
UH, LISTEN--
WAIT !  WAIT !
WHAT IS ?  IS
ALL MORNING LIKE THIS.
YOU COMPLAIN.  YOU SLOW.
YOU NO TAKE ORDERS.
YOU LAZY RAT YOU !
LAZY RAT ?  OKAY !
HAVE IT YOUR WAY.
I DON'T HAVE TO
TAKE THIS ABUSE !
I QUIT !  HUH !
QUIT ?  YOU NO CAN QUIT !
IS BREAKFAST CROWD !
ALL RIGHT !
DON'T BEG.  I'LL STAY.
BUT I NEED SOME HELP.
OKAY, GUYS, THIS IS IT.
DON'T BLOW IT.
PETE, MEET
YOUR NEW EMPLOYEES.
SAY HELLO TO TATOOEY,
YO !
MASTERSON,
HELLO.
CHESTER...
I FEEL TERRIBLE !
[ Sneezes ]
AND YOLANDA !
WHAT A CRAZY BODY !
YEAH.
PETE, ABOUT THAT JOB--
[ Clamoring ]
WAIT !
IS NO GOOD !
RATS WANT JOB !
FROG WANT JOB !
- WHAT NEXT ?  PENGUINS ?
- DO YOU HAVE JOBS AVAILABLE ?
- NO !
- WELL, EXCUSE US FOR LIVING !
[ Cackling ]
HEY, POP, EVERYBODY'S
WAITING FOR THEIR FOOD.
PETE, I CAN
WORK NIGHTS.
COME ON, PETE.
GIVE THESE GUYS
A BREAK, ALL RIGHT ?
[ Clamoring ]
HEY, I GO CRAZY !
OKAY, RATS,
YOU GO TO WORK.
YEA !
WAIT !  WAIT !
LISTEN.  I TELL YOU WHAT IS.
IS NO WORK, IS DANCING,
IS CHEESE-- IS BIG SHOES !
OKAY ?
[ Woman ]
WAITRESS !
ALL RIGHT, RATS,
GO TO WORK.
YEA !
SO, LIKE, YOU GOT
A BOYFRIEND ?
PETE, THERE'S
NOTHING ELSE ?
I'LL DO ANYTHING--
POP, WE COULD USE
SOME HELP IN THE KITCHEN.
UH, IS DISHES
NEED WASHING.
OH, THANKS, PETE !
THAT'S TERRIFIC !
OH, BOY !
THANKS A LOT, JENNY !
HEY, NO SWEAT.
SO, WHERE ARE
ALL YOUR FRIENDS ?
THEY HAD TO LEAVE.
OH, EVEN
YOUR PIG FRIEND ?
YES, BUT I'M BRINGING HER BACK.
I WROTE THE SHOW FOR THEM.
WHEN I SELL IT,
I CAN BRING THEM BACK.
I'M STAYING AND I'M GETTING
OUR SHOW ON BROADWAY.
I REALLY ADMIRE THAT.
I'M GOING TO DO
SOMETHING SPECIAL TOO.
I MEAN, IN FASHION.
MAYBE YOUR FASHION
DESIGNING CAN HELP ME NOW.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN ?
I DID SOME READING LAST NIGHT
ABOUT BROADWAY PRODUCERS
AND INVESTORS AND AGENTS.
NOW I KNOW WHAT I HAVE
TO DO TO SELL OUR SHOW.
I CAN USE YOUR HELP
'CAUSE I HAVE A THREE-PART PLAN.
AND THE FIRST PART IS,
IF YOU CAN'T BEAT 'EM, JOIN 'EM.
[ Clears Throat ]
HIYA, SWEETHEART !  I JUST
FLEW IN FROM THE COAST.
I LOVE YOUR HAIR !
DON'T EVER TOUCH IT !
LISTEN, I GOT AN APPOINTMENT
WITH YOUR TOP THEATER AGENT.
LEONARD WINESOP ?
YEAH, LENNIE, RIGHT.
WHAT OFFICE IS HE IN, DOLL ?
HE'S IN SUITE 1024.
I'LL CALL AND SEE--
NO, NO, SWEETHEART.
NO NEED FOR THAT, 'CAUSE
LENNIE AND I GO WAY BACK !
I'M TALKIN' WAY BACK.
THANKS, HONEY.
FAR OUT !  RIGHT ON !
MR. WINESOP ?
YEAH ?  A FROG.
WITH AN AFRO.
[ Door Opens ]
HIYA, LENNIE, SWEETHEART, BABE !
I JUST FLEW IN FROM THE COAST.
HEY, I LOVE YOUR OFFICE.
DON'T CHANGE A THING.
MY PRIVATE PLANE'S
DOUBLE-PARKED SO I GOTTA RUN.
I GOT THIS BOFFO, SOCKO SCRIPT
FOR A BROADWAY SLOT CALLED
MANHATTAN MELODIES.
IT'S TOTALLY TODAY YET
TREMENDOUSLY TIMELESS.
I'M GIVING YOU FIRST LOOK-SEE
'CAUSE WE'RE LIKE FAMILY.
HAVE I EVER LIED TO YOU ?
OOP, I THINK I HEAR MY BEEPER.
I GOTTA SPLIT.  I'LL HAVE
YOUR PEOPLE CALL MY PEOPLE.
WE'LL SET
A CONFERENCE CALL.
REMEMBER, LENNIE.
BOFFO, LENNIE.  SOCKO, LENNIE.
I'LL CALL YOU.
WE'LL HAVE LUNCH.  CIAO !
[ Panting ]
JENNY !
KERMIT !
HI, JENNY !
HI.  HERE.  HAVE A SEAT.
WERE YOU A HIT ?
THEY LOVED IT, RIGHT ?
HOW'D THE COSTUME WORK ?
THE COSTUME WAS GREAT.
IT'S HARD TO TELL
HOW IT WENT.  THEY'RE PROBABLY
READING THE SCRIPT RIGHT NOW.
HEY, BABY.
BABY !
WHERE YOU GOIN',
SWEETHEART ?
HELLO.
I SAID HELLO.
FOR THE NEXT PART OF MY PLAN
I HAVE TO LOOK OLDER,
SO I'M GONNA
GROW A MUSTACHE.
OH.
I THINK YOU'D
LOOK CUTE WITH A MUSTACHE.
YOU THINK SO ?
MM-HMM.
PIGGY SAID THAT
TO ME ONCE TOO.
SHE'S HOT !
HOT MAMA !
HEY, BABY !
HOT STUFF !
LOOKIN' GOOD.
PERFECT AND PRETTY.
PRETTY AND PERFECT.
HEY, BABY !
SWEET THING.
SHE MUST BE
REALLY TALENTED.
YOU'RE TALENTED TOO.
YOU MEAN IT ?
OF COURSE.
I KNOW YOU'RE GONNA BE
A FAMOUS FASHION DESIGNER.
KERMIT, THANK YOU
FOR SAYING THAT.
COME ON, BABY.
DON'T BE RUDE.
[ Grunting ]
COME HERE, MAMA.
COME HERE.
[ Straining, Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Banging ]
WHAT WAS THAT ?
OH, IT'S
JUST NEW YORK.
YEP.
[ Screaming ]
[ Gasps ]
I'M SORRY I'M LATE,
MR. WRIGHTSON.
I WOULD SUGGEST TO YOU THAT IT
IS NEITHER PRUDENT NOR WISE...
TO BE A HALF HOUR LATE RETURNING
FROM LUNCH, ESPECIALLY WHEN
IT'S YOUR FIRST DAY ON THE JOB.
YES, SIR.  YES, SIR.
EILEEN, SORRY I'M LATE.
IT'S OKAY, PIGGY.
EVERYTHING'S BEEN
GOIN' WRONG LATELY.
GET YOUR FRENCH PERFUME.
QUELLE DIFFERENCE.
[ Growls ]
SOMETHING WRONG ?
CAN WE TALK ?
NO !  I'LL BE FINE.
JUSTBIEN.
SORRY.
GET YOURQUELLE DIFFERENCE.
IT'S FRENCH.  IT'S FEMININE.
IT'LL HELP YOU
GRAB ONE OF THOSE
ROTTEN, STINKIN' MEN.
QUELLE DIFFERENCE--
PIGGY, PLEASE !
YOU WERE FINE THIS MORNING.
SOMETHING HAPPEN AT LUNCH ?
MY FROG
TURNED ON ME.
I HAD SOME BAD TUNA MYSELF.
I'M GONNA FIGHT
FOR HIM THOUGH.
EILEEN, DO YOU THINK
I'M PRETTY ?
OF COURSE YOU ARE.
YOU'RE MORE THAN PRETTY.
GORGEOUS ?
DON'T PUSH IT, PIG.
YOU'RE--
YOU'RE MORE THAN GORGEOUS.
YOU'RE UNIQUE !
BUT YOU COULD USE
A LITTLE ROUGE.
HMM ?
HAVE A SEAT.
WHAT ARE YOU--
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO ?
WE'LL FIX YOU UP.  MAKE YOU
LOOK LIKE A MOVIE STAR.
HOW'D YOU LIKE THAT ?
YES.
CHEEKBONES.
THAT'S WHAT YOU NEED.
YOUR FACE IS A LITTLE ROUND.
I'M GONNA GIVE YOU
A COMPLETE MAKEUP JOB.
THIS MORNING, I SAID,
SHE NEEDS ROUGE.
TURN YOUR FACE.
EVER WEAR ROUGE ?
YES.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA
REALLYWEAR ROUGE.
KERMIT WON'T CARE.
KERMIT, SHMERMIT.
YOU LOOK GREAT !
IT BRINGS OUT YOUR EYES.
YOU NEED EYEBROWS.
PIGS DON'T
HAVE EYEBROWS.
THIS PIG IS GOING TO.
AND SO IS THIS.
[ Laughing ]
WHY DID YOU DO THAT ?
BOY, I THINK
I OVERDID IT.
LET ME SEE.
[ Laughing ]
YOU HAVE THEM TOO.
I HAVE THEM TOO.
DO SOME MORE.
I'LL GIVE YOU
DOE EYES.
DOE EYES ?
WHAT ARE DOE EYES ?
DOE EYES ARE
WHAT BAMBI HAS.
LET ME SEE.
DOE EYES.
DO SOME MORE.
YOU NEED FRECKLES
FOR CUTESY.
OH, FRECKLES.
CUTESY, CUTESY.
I'LL BE CUTESY.
[ Laughing ]
YOU GOT IT TOO.
LIPSTICK.
WHY DON'T YOU
WEAR LIPSTICK ?
PUCKER.  PUCKER.
MMM.
YOU LOOK FABULOUS.
A LITTLE MORE
ON THE CHEEKS.
ON MY CHEEKS.
AHH !
[ Miss Piggy ]
AH-HOO-HOO !
A POWDER PUFF FOR YOU
AND A POWDER PUFF FOR ME.
[ Both Laughing ]
QUELLE DIFFERENCE.
TRY THE NEWEST PERFUME
FROM FRANCE.
YOU ARE FIRED.
[ Screaming ]
[ Laughing ]
PETE, WHAT HAPPENED
TO THOSE RATS YOU HAD
WORKING HERE ?
CUSTOMER COMPLAINED.  THEY
NO LIKE RATS FOR WAITERS.
IS OKAY.  I MAKE
THEM COOK.
HEY, PETE.
HERE YOU GO.  TWO ZEROS
ON A TRAMPOLINE WITH
A SIDE OF JOAN OF ARC.
YEAH !
HA, HA.  OH, YEAH.
?
## BA-DUPE-DEEP-DO
BE-DUDELLY DUPE, BA-DO-BA-BA ?
## DABA-DABA, DETTIO-DABA
DOOBA-DOOAH ##
## BE-BOOP, BE-DOODELY-DOOP
BE-BE-DEETIN-DE-DE ##
## DABA-DOOBY
DABA-DOOBY, DA-BA ##
## BAH ####
OH-OH-OH-OH-OH-OH--
OH-OH-OH.
HEY, HOW'S THE COFFEE ?
UHH !  AHH !  UHH !
THE COFFEE'S FINE.
COME ON IN.  HA, HA, HA !
##
## BE-DOOLIA, DE-BE-DEEP, BE-DE
## BEEP-BOOM-BOW, DO-DOOLIA-BEEP
BEEP, DE-DE-DE, DEEP ##
## BOP-BOO-DOW, BA-DOOLIA
DE-DEEP, DE-DOOLIA-DOOP ##
## BA-DO-BOP-BA, DABA-DABA
DOLIA-DA-BA ##
## DO-BE-DO-AH, DEEP-DOOP
BADELIA-DOOP ##
## DEBE-DEETIN, DE-DE
DABA-DOOBY, DABA-DOOBY ##
## DAT-DO-BOW, I SAID ##
## DO-BOW ##
## DOOPA, DOLIA-DOOPA
DOOPA, DOOPA-DO-OW, YEAH ####
YEOW !
KERMIT, WHEN ARE YOU
GOING TO START GROWING
YOUR MUSTACHE ?
I STOPPED SHAVING
THREE DAYS AGO.
DIDN'T YOU NOTICE ?
OH.  WELL--
NO ?
IT'S SUBTLE.
YEAH.
I BET WE COULD
HELP IT ALONG WITH MAKEUP.
GOOD.  I'M READY FOR
THE SECOND PART OF MY PLAN.
HEY, FROG.
MAIL COME.
GOT MAIL FOR YOU.
YEAH, IT MUST BE
FROM THE GANG.
NOW, YOLANDA,
CHOPPING IS AN ART.
YOU GOTTA BE SMOOTH.
[ Grunts ]
[ Groans ]
HEY, IT'S FROM SCOOTER.
"DEAR KERMIT, HOW ARE YOU ?"
[ Scooter's Voice ]
"HAVE YOU SOLD THE SHOW YET ?
HAVE YOU HEARD FROM THE GANG ?
"I'M IN CLEVELAND.
I HAVE THIS TERRIFIC JOB.
"I'M MANAGING
A HUGE MOVIE HOUSE.
MAYBE NOT MANAGING, BUT I DO
HAVE A LOT OF RESPONSIBILITIES."
HERE ARE YOUR GLASSES.
SEATING TO THE LEFT.
HURRY UP, MOM.
THANK YOU.
[ Scooter's Voice ]
"I'M MEETING
INTERESTING PEOPLE."
AH !  YOUR POPPIN' CORN
IS 3-D !
AHA !  THE CORN IS POPPIN'
IN YOUR FACE IN 3-D !
CHEF, THAT'S NOT
HOW 3-D WORKS.
OH, NEVER MIND.
HERE'S YOUR TICKET.
HA, HA, HA.
THANKS.  SIR, YOUR 3-D GLASSES.
SIR, YOUR GLASSES !
WHOOPTI, DO, DO, DEE, DO.
SIR, DON'T YOU WANT
YOUR 3-D GLASSES ?
OH, I DON'T NEED 'EM.
I'VE SEEN THIS MOVIE
97 TIMES.
MY NAME IS LEW ZEALAND.
I'M A BOOMERANG FISH THROWER.
I THROW THE FISH AWAY
AND THEY COME BACK TO ME.
HA, HA, HA.
HERE'S MY FAVORITE PART.
[ Man ]
THE FISH !   THEY'RE COMING
FROM THE GAME ROOM !
[ Woman ]  OH, NO !
THE KILLER FISH ARE ATTACKING !
[ Crashing ]
[ Woman Screaming ]
GO GET 'EM, GUYS !
HA, HA, HA.
-[ Woman ]  HELP !  HELP !
- YEAH !  HA, HA.
[ Lew ]
OH, HO-HO.
[  Screaming ]
OH, HA-HA.  OOPS.
[ Scooter's Voice ]
"SO, LIFE IS GREAT HERE IN OHIO.
LOVE, SCOOTER."
[ Kermit's Voice ]
HERE'S ONE FROM FOZZIE.
"DEAR KERMIT,
WACKA, WACKA, WACKA."
[ Fozzie's Voice ]
"BUT SERIOUSLY.  I'M IN MAINE.
"MY JOB DIDN'T TURN OUT
TOO TERRIFIC.
"SO I DECIDED TO HIBERNATE.
AHH, BACK TO NATURE.
"I LOVE IT OUT HERE
IN THE WOODS.
IT'S WHERE A BEAR SHOULD BE."
[ Snoring ]
HOW DO THEY DO IT ?
I'VE BEEN TRYIN'
TO SLEEP FOR DAYS.
ANYBODY GOT SOME WARM MILK ?
OH, BROTHER.
HELLO.
OH.  I DIDN'T KNOW
THIS CAVE WAS CO-ED.
MY NAME'S BETH.
WELL, I'M FOZZIE.
I CAN'T SLEEP
EITHER.
MAYBE IF WE SNUGGLE.
HMM ?
KER-MIT.
[ Kermit's Voice ]
HMPH.  HERE'S ONE MORE.
IT'S FROM DR. TEETH.
[ Dr. Teeth's Voice ]
"DEAR KERMIT, HOW'S THE MAN ?
"WE GOT THIS GREAT GIG
OUTSIDE OF PITTSBURGH.
"I TELL YOU, FROG,
THE BAND'S WAILIN'.
THE MUSIC'S COOKIN'.
"CROWD IS ALSO
WAILIN' AND COOKIN'.
YEAH, WE'RE IN HIP CITY HERE."
AUGH-AUGH-AUGH-AUGH--
AUGH !
THEY'RE ALL
DOING PRETTY WELL.
YEAH, THEY ARE.
BUT THERE ARE NO LETTERS
FROM GONZO OR ROWLF OR PIGGY.
I'M SURE THEY'VE WRITTEN.
SOMETIMES IT JUST
TAKES A WHILE.
YEAH, SURE.
PIGGY'S PROBABLY BUSY
WITH SOME TERRIFIC JOB.
YEAH.
I GUESS THEY'RE ALL
OUT THERE DOING TERRIFIC.
IF I CAN ONLY
SELL THE SHOW,
THEN EVERYONE COULD
COME BACK AND WE COULD DO IT
TOGETHER LIKE THE OLD DAYS.
YOU'LL DO IT, KERMIT.
WELL, THANKS, JENNY.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Glass Breaking,
Clattering ]
[ Thudding ]
[ Shouting ]
THAT'S BEEN HAPPENING
A LOT LATELY OVER THERE.
I KNOW.
IT'S NEW YORK.
[ Sighs ]
HEY, RIZZO, I'M ABOUT READY
FOR THE SECOND PART OF MY PLAN.
I'M GOING TO NEED YOUR HELP
AND ALL THE OTHER RATS TOO.
I THINK WE COULD BE
MAKING SOME OVERTIME HERE.
JENNY, I NEED YOU
TO DRAW A PICTURE OF ME.
SURE.
WHAT'S THE SCOOP ?
HAVE YOU EVER HEARD
OF A WHISPERING CAMPAIGN ?
GOOD AFTERNOON.
KERMIT THE FROG.
MY RESERVATION SECRETARY
MADE A RESERVATION FOR ME.
[ Sneezing ]
GESUNDHEIT.
THIS WAY, PLEASE.
AFTERNOON, ALL.
[ Chattering ]
DON'T GET UP.  KEEP EATING.
TA !
MAY I TAKE YOUR COAT ?
NO !  UH, THAT IS, UH,
NO, THANK YOU VERY MUCH INDEED.
HMM.
[ Sneezing ]
[ Grunting, Coughing ]
THAT'S THE CLOSEST I EVER
WANT TO BE TO A FROG.
OKAY, GUYS, DO YOUR STUFF.
RIGHT.
OKAY, YOU START.
UH, SAY, ISN'T THAT
THAT RICH PRODUCER OVER THERE ?
THE ONE WHO'S INVESTING
IN MANHATTAN MELODIES?
YES, HE'S INVESTING
MILLIONS OF DOLLARS
IN MANHATTAN MELODIES.
WHAT'S THAT ALL ABOUT ?
MANHATTAN MELODIES?
ISN'T THAT KERMIT THE FROG, THE
BIG-TIME PRODUCER, OVER THERE ?
A PRODUCER IS HERE.
A PRODUCER, DEAR.  THERE'S
A BIG PRODUCER OVER THERE.
[ Murmuring ]
IT'S THE HOTTEST THING
COMING TO BROADWAY
THIS SEASON.
[ Murmuring ]
BEST BROADWAY SHOW
IN YEARS.
[ Laughing ]
HELLO.
VINCENT ?  VINCENT ?
DID I DO
SOMETHING WRONG ?
NO.
VINCENT, A FROG ?
THAT FOOD SMELLS
GOOD UP THERE.
I'M STARVIN'.
[ Grunts ]
[ Screaming ]
OH !
[ Gasping ]
- [ Shouting ]
- [ Screaming Continues ]
BUT THIS IS ALL
A MISUNDERSTANDING--  AAH !
[ Grunts, Pants ]
WELL, THANKS A LOT,
YOU GUYS.
[ Sneezes ]
SO WHAT'S THE THIRD PART
OF YOUR PLAN ?
I DON'T THINK THERE'S
GOING TO BE ONE.
I FEEL LIKE I'M BEING A PHONEY,
AND I CAN'T TAKE IT ANYMORE.
BUT I-I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO DO NEXT.
[ Muttering ]
[ Jenny ]
ALL RIGHT.
MOPING TIME'S OVER.
HOW ABOUT
A LITTLE EXERCISE ?
WELL--
I KNEW YOU WANTED TO.
AH, DEAR LORD, NOT JOGGING.
[ Moans ]
WOW.  IT'S SUCH
A BEAUTIFUL DAY.
YEAH.
[ Panting ]
COME ON.  GIVE ME A BREAK.
COME ON.
LET'S GO THIS WAY.
OKAY.
FEEL BETTER ?
YEAH.
GOOD.  EXERCISE DOES THE TRICK.
YEAH, STRETCHES
THE OLD FROG LEGS.
[ Panting ]
OH, NO.  OH.
[ Screams ]
[ Grunting ]
MY PURSE !
THAT DOES IT !
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunting ]
EXCUSE ME.
MAY I BORROW THOSE A MOMENT ?
[ Giggles ]
[ Shouts ]
[ Screaming ]
PIGGY ?