That's it, I'm turning back.
I know your family's waiting.
I know it's an important day.
All right. We'll give it a try. I'll set
short coordinates,
we won't jump far.
I'll get you back there in time, pal.
Trust me.
Our only hope now, is
to outrun that Imperial
garbage scow, tho'. I'm
going to lightspeed.
That's the spirit! You'll be celebrating
Life Day before you know it!
Standby, here's where we say
goodbye to our unpleasant friends.
A long time ago in a galaxy
far far away...
STAR WARS
HOLIDAY SPECIAL
Starring
Mark Hamill as Luke Skywalker.
Harrison Ford as Han Solo.
Carrie Fisher as Princess Leia.
With Anthony Daniels as C-3PO.
Peter Mayhew as Chewbacca.
R2-D2 as R2-D2.
And, James Earl Jones as the voice of
Darth Vader.
Introducing Chewbacca's family,
His wife, Malla.
His father, Itchy.
His son, Lumpy.
With special guest stars
Beatrice Arthur.
Art Carney.
Diahann Carroll.
The Jefferson Starship.
Harvey Korman.
And an animated Star Wars story on...
The Star Wars Holiday Special.
YOU HAVE REACHED TRAFFIC
CONTROL
NO STARSHIPS IN AREA
What's that?
Oh, Artoo, look.
It's Chewbacca's family.
Here, keep working on it.
Hello Malla, Itchy.
Hiya Lumpy.
Where's Chewbacca?
Whoa, wait a minute! One at a time.
Yeah...
Not now, Artoo.
Uh, wait a minute, I don't like the
looks of this. Let me get this fixed.
Oh, Artoo, you're supposed to be
watching that...
There, that ought to hold it.
I think.
What's up?
Chewbacca...
Yeah, well, bring him to the screen.
I want to say hello to him.
You don't know where he is?
Oh, he's not there yet. Is that it?
Oh boy.
Well, all I can tell you is that,
uh, he and Han left here on schedule.
If he's not there now,
they're way overdue.
There must've been trouble.
Artoo, please, this is important.
Now, now listen. Calm down.
I mean...
you know how Han and
Chewbacca are anything
could've happened - they
could've, they could've stopped
off somewhere, or been held
up by an asteroid storm.
Listen,
I wouldn't worry about
Chewbacca, I know him
and he hasn't missed a
Life Day yet, right?
Well, there you go! He's not going to
miss this one either.
It's just taking him a little longer to
get there, that's all. He'll make it.
Come on, don't look so worried.
Now, Chewie's not gonna wanna come home
to a house full of long faces, is he?
Come on, Malla.
Let's see a little smile.
Come on...
There, that's better.
Try to enjoy your Life Day.
I gotta get back to this engine.
I think we might have it solved.
OH! ARTOO!
What are you doing?!
Oh no...
It's alright. Nobody's perfect.
SUB TERMINAL 446B
STANDBY
CONNECT
TRADING POST WOOKIEE PLANET C
Hello, an Imperial Guard.
I suppose you
want to see my identification.
No, I'm off duty. I've come
to look around your shop.
Well, good, good, good.
Look around,
browse around, make yourself at home...
As you can see I've got just about
everything a man or wookiee would want.
Oh here,
let me show you this; I really
love this.
No...
Ah, here we are. Here it is.
A pocket sized aquarium.
Wonderful, isn't it?
And, you can take it with you anywhere.
And the tank is a snap to clean.
I hate fish.
Well, so do I, as a matter of fact.
I take a drink once and a while,
but I just thought I'd
show you some of the
stupid stuff those
wookiees purchase from me.
Oh, here...
Here's a hot little item that seems to
be moving pretty rapidly these days.
Excuse me, I got a wall screen customer.
Good to see you again.
Don't worry Malla.
I know just why you're calling.
You're wondering when that shaggy carpet
you ordered will arrive at your home.
Let me assure you madam,
it's on its way.
You know, it was made especially for you
by a little old woman four planets away.
She did it all by herself.
In fact, you
might say she did it by Han... Solo.
Tho' it's going to take some time to get
to you.
I know you'll understand.
You understand don't you?
Terrific!
By the way, I'll be by later to
drop off that extra proton energy pack.
You're welcome.
What's a matter?
Don't you like this?
It's just a groomer.
- Just a groomer?
- A groomer..
Just a groomer, you say?
It's a lot more than that.
Evidently, you haven't
read the instructions,
the warranty, and the guarantee.
Besides shaving and hair trimming.
It's guaranteed
to lift stains off clothing,
faces, and hands.
Cleans teeth, fingers, and toenails.
Washes eyes, pierces ears, calculates,
modulates, and syncopates like rhythms
and can repeat the entire Imperial Code,
all 17 volumes,
in half the time of the
old XP-21.
Just the thing to keep
you squeaky clean.
I use one of these all the time.
Really?
Well, not all the time,
but some of the time.
Oh, another outstanding, uh, feature
of this little model
you can recharge it by simply plugging
it into any ordinary laser outlet.
I'll take it.
Good! I thought you would.
Well, would you
like to pay me something
for it or give me something in trade?
I said I'll take it!
That's a load off my mind.
I thought I might embarrass
you when I told you it was a gift.
I don't like embarrassing people
I don't like being embarrassed
myself that's why I,
uh, don't like to embarrass people.
I just said that...
just a groomer...
We've ordered a blockade and a curfew.
And, started a search operation.
It's just a matter of time
before we find the Rebels.
I want the Rebels
located and identified.
If it means searching every household in
the system.
Hello...
Today we are going to
be preparing a very
succulent dish called
"Bantha Surprise."
It's not only a very hearty, nourishing
dish,
but it's very economical, too.
So all those
hungry mouths in your
household will be going
"yummy yum for their tummy
tum." If you just follow
along with me as I prepare
this popular favorite.
Now, today
I'm going to be using the
tenderest cut of the bantha: the loin.
The loin is very tasty and serves four
nicely.
But, of course, if your family
has a hearty appetite,
I would suggest then that old popular
holiday favorite: The Bantha Rump.
Um, very tender.
Ah, we just slice into
bite-sized pieces.
And only you know the size of a bite in
your family!
Oh! Alright,
now it's time to put our chunks
into our pots.
Nicely... nicely...
Add a dash of negavo.
Umm, very good.
A sprig of celentery.
Umm, umm, just a bit of
turshum, always nice.
And, uh. Um! Turshum is nice!
And, just a little whisper of chelchum.
Ah, looking very nice.
Guess what I forgot?
A bit of the calarantrum root!
Wonderful! Just adds
that touch of piquancy.
There we go.
Very nice. Um!
Now we add enough liquid to cover.
And guess what we're ready for now:
The cooking! Step one
we stir the mixture.
Stir, stir, stir, stir,
stir, stir, stir,
stir, stir, stir, stir, very nice.
Now, step
two while we're
stirring, we also whip.
So it's stir, whip, stir, whip, whip,
whip, stir,
stir, whip, stir, whip, whip,
whip, stir.
Now, let's try it again together at
an increased tempo
because precision is very
important in this recipe
and we do want a fine
consistency, don't we?
So, and on the count of one
stir, whip, stir, whip,
whip, whip, stir,
whip, whip, stir.
Come on, faster altogether now. Cooking
can be fun.
Stir, whip, stir, whip,
whip, whip, stir,
stir, whip, stir, whip,
whip, whip, stir.
Wah! Having fun, having fun, alright.
Having it all nicely, now.
Step three we also have to beat.
So it's: beat, beat, beat, stir, whip,
stir, whip, beat, beat, stir
That's not
right. I'm sorry.
Stir, whip, stir, whip,
whip, whip, stir, beat,
stir, whip, stir, whip,
whip, whip, stir, beat.
Coming... coming along nicely. Mmmm,
starting to have a fine aroma.
Whew, caught it just in time.
Now at this
time, I usually like
to taste the broth.
So, we'll have a little taste
and see how it's coming along.
Mmmm, a little bit more turshum. A bit
negavo. A little tunkell.
One for the pot,
Hum! Coming along
Very nice.
Oh, wonderful! Coming along nicely...
Alright. Alright, the
coordinates weren't the best.
Out of the frying pan
into the fryer, huh pal?
How should I know we'd
come outta hyperspace
into the middle of an Imperial convoy.
At least against these fighters
we got more of a chance.
However slim...
You can say that again.
This is one Life
Day we won't soon forget.
Wait,
I lost control of the remote cannons.
I'm gonna hafta run back and operate the
aft gun manually. Stay on things here.
Why do I always think that taking you
home for Life Day's gonna be easy?
Attention all viewers.
Due to suspected Rebel activity on the
Kashyyyk planet
the Empire has declared martial law.
A blockade has been set up
around the planet
No ships will be permitted to land
or take off until further notice.
It's me Saundan.
Hi, Itchy.
I brought you that proton pack.
You know, for the, uh, the whatsis
the whatchamalcalit,
the, the thingamabob,
the mind evaporator.
That's it, the mind evaporator.
Boy am I glad to see you folks.
How are my favorite wookiees today?
Why all the long hairy faces?
I made it through the Imperial
patrol, didn't I?
If I made it, Chewie and Han will.
Is this all the big hello I get?
I brought you somethin' special short
stuff.
You want it?
You got it.
Happy Life Day.
I love to make a wookiee happy.
And now, for the lovely
lady of the house.
Happy Life Day.
Now wait a, wait a minute, not so fast.
What does an old friend get?
Well?
That's more like it.
Itchy, I know what you'd like.
I'll insert this proton pack.
Now then Itchy,
I thought you might like
this. It's one of those uh...
oh, it's a real...
it's kinda hard to explain...
WOW,
if you know what I mean.
Put that right in there.
And I do mean happy Life Day.
I know you're searching for me.
Searching, searching... I'm here.
My voice is for you alone.
I am found in your eyes only.
I exist for you alone.
I am in your mind
as you create me.
Oh, yes... I can feel my creation.
I'm getting your message.
Are you getting mine?
Oh, oh... We are excited, aren't we?
Now, we can have a
good time, can't we?
I'll tell you a secret, I find you
adorable.
I find you adorable.
I don't need to ask how you find me.
You see, I am your fantasy.
I am your experience.
So experience me.
I am your
pleasure. Enjoy me.
This is our moment together in time
that we might turn this
moment into an eternity.
If we could only bend this minute.
Infinitely extend this minute.
Then I could live my whole
life right now.
Reality is sweet this minute.
Can't we repeat and repeat
this minute?
Why can't it always be right now?
I've parted with yesterday.
Yesterday's moment is cold.
All I ask is this moment to hold.
How can we ever lose this minute?
From all my life, I choose this minute.
I will give up the old and the new.
Sharing with you...
this minute now.
If I could just hold my breath and
close my eyes and not make a sound.
Will the universe stop going 'round?
Still the universe
keeps going'round and
'round and on and on
and on and on and on.
A minute's almost gone.
How can we ever, ever lose
this minute?
From all my life, I choose
this minute.
I will never need anything
more than living for this minute now.
This minute now.
This minute... now.
Ah, I have made the connection.
You may speak now, if you wish.
Malla, it's good to see you.
Happy Life Day
Oh, she says it may be
a happy Life Day for
you, but personally,
she's seen happier ones.
I... I don't want to
tie up the channels.
So, could you do me a
favor and send either
Chewbacca or Han Solo
to the screen please?
She says that she would
like to grant your
request, but is quite unable to do so.
You mean they haven't arrived yet?
She says, there has been no contact.
Yes, I think I understand her message.
Oh, that Imperial patrol must be giving
them more trouble than we bargained for.
Malla, are, are you alone?
If, you would permit me.
No, she says she is not alone.
She's with a friend.
Could he come to the screen, please?
Good afternoon, ma'am.
I'm Saundan, a local trader.
A friend of the rebellion and a
member of the Alliance.
Good. Look, I know I can
count on you to take
care of my friends until
their leader returns.
You'll do that for me, won't you?
Yes indeed, ma'am.
That's what I'm here for.
She is expressing her warmth
towards the trader.
Look, I can see you're in good hands,
Malla. I'll contact you again, soon.
Now then,
what's that I smell?
Oh, could it be some of those
famous wookiee ookiees?
I told you we'd make it. Did I ever let
you down?
I feel the same way about you too, pal.
And your family.
I've never seen so much Imperial traffic
in this system.
Better land on the north side. It'll be
safer there.
So, it's a long walk. A little exercise
never hurt anybody.
Happy Life Day, pal.
Sounds like a starship.
What I tell ya?
Must be Chewbacca now!
This unit is occupied by four wookiees.
Two adult males, one adult female, and
one male child.
Where is the other wookiee male?
Officer, uh, maybe I could
be of some help there, sir.
Who are you and what are you
doing in this wookiee house?
Oh, I'm a trader in this district.
You see, the uh,
uh the truth of the matter
is she had a terrible fight
with her husband and he
just stormed right out.
Your identification.
I said it!
Oh, identification, yes.
It's a very important
thing, identification.
I, I never leave the shop
without my identification.
It's uh, it's very important,
just in times like this.
I just found my identification. I think
it's in my pocket.
Search the dwelling.
Officer, you may notice
that little leather
case that I carry my
identification card in.
I whipped that up myself. That's a
pretty fast selling little item.
Uh... uh well, some people like to keep
things neat and clean and that's why uh,
I have the little leather case for the
identification card.
As a matter of fact, if any
of you guys want a couple of
those leather cases. I've gotta
couple of extra ones here.
Oh, officer, that uh, that
picture you're looking
at right now was taken
quite a few years ago.
That's uh, one of me. I've
gained quite a bit of weight since then.
Hello little guy.
Where's your daddy?
Hey, they have no respect for authority!
Excuse me. I beg your pardon.
Uh, maybe you know my brother's boy.
He's a member of the Imperial militia.
He must be 24 or 25 years old by know.
Good little guy...
Your identification is in order.
You can go now.
Thank you, thank you very much.
I just have a little more work to
finish up here and uh,
oh by the way, uh,
while I'm finishing up
here uh, why don't you
boys uh, take it easy.
Relax. Put your feet up
and make yourself at home.
Wookiee food isn't the
greatest but I'm sure I can
whip something up in the
kitchen that we can all eat.
Uh, you don't mind do ya, Malla?
Malla will you come in the kitchen to
help me.
What are doing with that thing? That's a
very delicate piece of workmanship.
Alright Malla, it's alright.
The slightest jarring will mess up the
whole works.
If you're going to play
around with it let me show you how.
Relax, I gotta turn it on, don't I?
Just sit down and enjoy it.
Ok. Here we go.
Will you get on with it?
Okay, okay.
God, all dignified, if you want to.
What I would really like to know.
Will you light the sky on fire?
Will you light
tonight like you did the night before?
Hey! You could take me higher than the
diamonds in the sky.
Take me, light in the
sky and we'll vanish
without a trace and
we'll see God then.
Temples and mirrors interest me.
Though all there really is to know.
Will you light the sky on fire?
Will you light the sky on fire
again tonight?
You can take me higher
than the diamonds in the sky.
Take me, we'll vanish without a
trace and then we'll all see God then.
On the pyramids of the legend.
The great god Kopa Khan came
from the stars and vanished.
And the legends say he will
come back again someday
someday...
Will you light the sky on fire?
Will you light tonight like
you did the night before.
You can take me
higher than the diamonds in the sky.
Take me, light in the sky and we'll
vanish without a trace,
And then we'll see god then.
Yes, I would really like to know.
What I've been watching this for.
Will you light the sky on fire?
Will you light the sky
like you did the night before?
You could take me higher than
the diamonds in the sky.
Take me, we'll vanish without a
trace. And we'll all see God then.
Vanish without a trace.
Come on, come on, come on, come on,
come on, let's vanish without a trace.
come on, we'll vanish without a trace.
I knew you'd like it.
Your work here is finished.
You may leave now.
I guess you're right. It's about all
I can do for now. I hope you guys
find what you're looking for.
Keep up the good work.
Malla.
Itchy, please...
Alright, finish the search of the
residence.
Oh, I almost forgot.
I want to leave you
my card in case you
need any of uh, oh...
Okay, I'm leaving.
Investigate the upper area. Check for
any Rebel material.
Anything to connect
this household with the Alliance.
Oh, don't forget about
those protective cases for
your identification card.
I gotta good item...
That's it, I'm gone.
Finish the search of the house. We have
other areas to cover today.
You! Take the upper area.
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uhh...
We don't want to have to hurt anyone.
That's not what we're here for.
But, when my men get angry I can't
always control them.
We are going to continue our search.
Now keep him quiet
and I'll forget this ever happened.
Starlog 3-24-1 from the
bridge of the cruiser
RS Reekvange, captain Kazan reporting.
We are awaiting the return of captain
Han Solo and his first mate, Chewbacca.
Who are long overdue
on a delicate mission
to acquire the mystical talisman,
which has been sought by our
forces and the Empire.
The talisman, it makes things invisible,
I think.
Yes, even you.
Which I think might be an
improvement.
We've picked up something.
It's the Millennium Falcon.
They're coming out of lightspeed.
I can't make contact.
Try a lower channel.
Falcon, do you copy? Come in Falcon.
It's Chewie. But where's Han?
That's him! Hanging upside down!
I can't make radio contact.
He's on a collision course.
Princess, we're
in mortal danger from our own forces.
Falcon, do you copy?
This is madness.
You're right General. I can't understand
what Chewbacca's doing.
Whatever he's doing, there must be a
reason.
Hold your fire.
We've lost all contact, sir.
Standby. The Falcon is near impact.
I'm going after them.
Luke, take Artoo with you.
What'd he say?
If something has happened to captain
Solo and Chewbacca is alone,
you will need me to interpret.
Sir, he's firing on us.
I know, but I don't think
he means to hit us.
Chewie's a better shot than that.
Look, he's speeding up.
We're losing him.
Not for long.
This is Y-4 to base. He's heading
straight for a moon in...
the Panos system.
Hang on Artoo.
What about me?
I'm going to shake apart!
We're approaching the water planet.
We're following Han and Chewie...
We've lost them.
Hang on, Threepio. We're going in.
Are you sure this is the best way, sir?
Master Luke, sir, are you all right?
Yes. How 'bout Artoo?
Our comlinks are out. We
can't contact the base.
Where are you going, sir?
To see if I can locate the Falcon by
visual sighting.
Maybe it's close by.
Artoo, stand by to
fire the ejection pod.
And hurry Artoo or we'll be desert soon.
What is it, master Luke?
I'm not sure.
You saved my life. Thank you.
You are alone?
I have two droids. We've come in search
of a ship that crashed near here.
Maybe I can help you.
I am Boba Fett. The
ship you seek is nearby.
Are the Imperial troops
near this planet?
They are here, friend and growing more
powerful.
How far away?
Settle down.
All they do is eat.
This is all we have but uh, he's welcome
to it.
You are foolish to waste your
kindness on this dumb creature.
No lower life form is
worth going hungry for, friend.
I take it
you have no love of the Empire.
I don't.
Well, neither do I.
It will be easy to
find the ship you seek.
Follow me, friend.
Don't you think it might be imprudent to
trust him so quickly, sir?
He's our only chance. And, besides he
seems like a friend.
Indeed, friend is merely a term that is
often misused.
Did Artoo say that?
Words to that affect.
Chewie, you've got the talisman.
What's wrong?
No, don't destroy it!
The talisman...
Boba Fett, no! He's a friend.
Don't hurt him, Boba Fett.
What did he do to Luke?
He didn't do anything. R2-D2
has detected contamination.
It must have come from the talisman.
Artoo says it's some kind of sleeping
virus that only affects humans.
He says the only way to keep them alive
is to let the blood rush to their heads.
I know this sleeping virus the Empire
uses on its enemies.
They have a remedy for it in the city.
I could get some for you.
I'm afraid, Chewbacca
insists on going with you
You'll only get in the way. But, if you
must. Come on.
You stay here.
While I get the serum.
I said stay, friend.
Luke trusted me and I'm your only
chance of getting out of here alive.
Do you understand me?
Starlog update: although
Boba Fett quickly
located the serum for
the sleeping virus
We had no idea of his real plan.
I have made contact
with the Rebels and all
is proceeding as you
wish, Darth Vader.
What is it now?
Oh is that all, just some silly game.
Yes, their metabolisms are slowing down.
I wonder what's keeping Chewbacca.
Try to find them on the viewscreen.
Darth Vader!
Good work, but I want them alive.
Now that you've got their trust,
they may take you to their new base.
This time we'll get them all.
I see why they call you the best bounty
hunter in the galaxy.
Oh no! What will we do now?
I have the serum.
We must leave quickly, friend.
Are you all right?
I'm not sure.
What happened?
I don't know.
Well, somebody must know something.
He says our friend Boba found serum for
the talisman virus.
Boba, you're a hero and
a faithful friend.
You must come back with us.
What's the matter with Artoo?
I'm afraid, sir, it's because you said
Boba is a friend and faithful ally.
That simply does not feed properly into
Artoo's information bank.
What are you talking about?
We intercepted a message between
Boba and Darth Vader, sir.
Boba Fett is Darth Vader's
right hand man. I'm afraid
this whole adventure has
been an Imperial plot.
We'll meet again, friend.
Well, trust a droid to get to the bottom
of things.
Boba sure fooled the rest of us.
I beg your pardon, sir.
Chewbacca suspected all along there
was something bad about Boba.
How did you know, Chewie?
May I quote directly, sir?
He just didn't smell right.
Well, lets's get off this galactic
raindrop.
Captain Kazan, starlog
3-24-1 signing off.
May the force be with you.
Let's go.
Nothing up there.
Go clean up your room.
That will keep him busy for a while.
This product was packed under strict
quality control on the system Amorphia
and this instructional cassette provided
by the manufacturer.
It offers a unique chance for consumers
everywhere to meet an Amorphian being.
The motor abilities
of Amorphian citizens
are frequently impaired
by malfunctions
which results in
a temporary loss of power.
This in no way reflects on the
safety of our product,
rather it should serve
as a guarantee of our
high standards of long
wear and durability.
Thank you for selecting our brand of
mini-transmitter.
If you assemble it properly, following
the instructions I'm about to give you.
It will provide many years of fun
and valuable services.
But, now let's get started, shall we?
First, find the sealed package
containing all the tools you'll need.
It looks like this.
Try not to rip it open because
it makes a very handy
storage case for your tools
until you need them again.
Now, this is the first
thing you'll need.
Please be careful not to hurt
yourself on the sharp edges.
Now, find the circuit breaker module
and by the way, let's start calling
these components by their proper names.
Circuit breaker module.
Remember, every one of the ten
thousand terminals on your
circuit breaker module is
marked in a particular color.
Beautiful, aren't they? Like a rainbow.
These must be connected with the
wires with the corresponding colors.
So, red goes to red.
Blue goes to blue and so on.
Now, watch me closely.
And we'll assemble our mini-transmitters
together.
Let us work slowly and methodically
because this is a job worth doing well.
Well, I see time is running out.
So, we better turn
our attention to the
assembly of the impulse
to voice translator.
The impulse to voice translator.
The very heart of the
mini-transmitter which
converts electronic
energy which provide
into any of a thousand
recognizable languages.
We must remain alert for this very
complicated procedure.
Endurance and concentration are the key
words here
and the total utilization
of our neural
cranial synapsis is
absolutely essential.
The following live broadcast is...
recommended by the Imperial
council in the belief that your
commitment to remain upstanding
citizens will be reinforced.
It is required viewing for all
members of the Imperial forces.
Time now for life on Tatooine.
Brought to viewers
everywhere in the hope that
our own lives may be
uplifted by the comparison
and enriched with the
gratitude of relief.
This transmission isunrehearsed and
unedited
and is hereby begun without further
comment as to its lack of moral value.
Well, I'm certainly not going to
get rich with customers like you.
I thought I taught you to
drink faster than that.
Well, at least you're steady.
Oh, come on now. Drink up. There's
plenty more where that came from.
- What'll it be?
- Hello, Ackmena.
Okay, we'll do it your way. Hello. Now,
we'll do it my way. What'll it be?
Can we talk?
Well of course we can talk.
We are talking. You're not ordering.
I'm not pouring.
We are not drinking. We are talking.
I'm moving this to make room for
a drink, so that next time I
say "what'll it be" and you tell me.
I can put it right there.
Doesn't matter. Give me anything.
I'll have one of those.
I'm sorry I couldn't get back before.
Ah, before what?
Uh, until now...
until tonight. I thought
about it a dozen times.
I had to be sure.
Ah, excuse me. I have
a customer waiting.
I'll be right back.
"Come back soon, I'll be waiting."
Ackmena?
How's your drink?
It's all gone. Look, there's
a flower on top of it.
I see there is. Do you
want another drink?
The flower is for you.
I wanted to bring you
something and that's
all I could think of.
I don't get many flowers.
I uh... but you
didn't have to bring
me anything Ah, ah...
Krelman.
Krelman, what a nice name.
When I left here the other
night, I felt something
that I haven't felt in longer
than I care to remember.
I felt alive again.
Someone made me feel like all the
years I've lived meant something.
And all you said was six simple words.
"Come back soon, I'll be waiting."
Well, after all, only
words I probably...
more than words. I knew that
at the time.
That's why I went home and thought
and thought about what you said.
Oh? What did I say?
It uh, it doesn't matter, silly.
What you said is not as important
as what you meant.
Oh? What did I mean?
I decided what you meant was exactly the
thing I needed to hear.
Well, I'm glad about that.
You know its funny. A man can live as
long as I have.
Through all the ups and
downs and just when he
thinks its all over, someone
cares for him again.
I wasn't looking for that when I came in
here.
Maybe that's why it, it happened.
Because
I wasn't asking for love anymore.
I wasn't desperate. I wasn't
begging, whining, ruffling,
sniveling. I just came
in here for a drink...
and I find a lot more.
- Uh, uh, Kerlman...
- Krelman.
Uh, lis... listen uh, Krelman.
You're, you're kind
and, and sweet and, and
terribly attractive but,
if, if you're saying what
I think you're saying you
felt you meant I thought
you needed to hear then,
I just have one thing to say. I did not.
Ackmena, don't do this to me...
Now, please look! I have customers.
Why don't you sit down.
Finish your drink.
Have another drink. This one's on me.
Now, you stay just as long as you want.
But, I have business to attend to. I
really have no time for anything else.
You'll change your mind.
I just know you will.
Six simple words.
I could wait forever to hear it
again because I know...
Come back soon, I'll be waiting.
Due to increased activity among
subversive forces,
we are placing a curfew on the entire
Tatooine system effective immediately.
All inhabitants will return to their
homes at once.
This order will remain in
effect until further notice.
Okay, Bobbarine. Take a break.
I don't know how long. Maybe forever.
Oh, don't leave me now.
Please, please, I have
enough aggravation.
Alright, one more round
before you leave.
And this one's on the me. Tork,
see what the boys on the bandstand
will have.
Gentlemen, gentlemen, I don't
know how to tell you this but
I guess the wall screen
said it all. We're closed.
Gentlemen, I guess you
didn't hear what I said.
The Empire has closed us down.
Now, I know this sort of
thing happens all the time.
I... I'm sure it's just temporary,
Fellas, The party is over.
How dare you. You stop that.
Stop Tork, it's alright.
I'll reason with them.
Kelnor, Zutnor, come on you guys.
Haven't I always lent you money?
Ludlow, Ludlow, you of all creatures.
Please do me a favor and leave.
Ludlow, you're heartless.
Thorp, Thorp, after all
I've down for you.
Short memory, eh, Thorp?
Short memory!
Helpmus, do you remember
the time that...
I don't believe we've met.
We're closed!
I said, we're closed.
Look, I'm sorry we are closed.
The Empire just imposed a
curfew on this planet.
Everybody has to leave right now.
Now... Tork, I don't
want anymore trouble.
You, take care of the door.
Alright, alright, alright, alright.
I can take a hint.
We'll have one more round.
This one's on the house.
I'll run a tab for the Empire.
Just one more round, friend.
Then homeward bound, friend.
Don't forget me in your dreams.
Just one more song, friend.
I so lone friend
The night's get shorter it seems.
Just one more rhyme, friend.
Yes, it's a crime, friend.
But you know time, friend.
Time can fly.
So it's goodnight, friend.
Goodnight, but not goodbye.
Just one more drop, friend.
Before we stop, friend.
One more moment face to face.
Next time you're dry, friend.
Try stopping by, friend.
If there's a light in the place.
We may not cry, friend.
But we survive, friend.
Look, we're alive, friend.
You and I.
So say goodnight, friend.
Goodnight, but not goodbye.
Just one more dance, friend.
Just one more chance, friend.
One more chorus, one more tune.
It's not the end, friend.
If you're a friend, friend.
Then you come back to me soon.
But it's too late, pal.
To celebrate, pal.
You have to wait, pal.
Don't you cry.
Now, it's goodnight, friend.
Goodnight friend.
Follow me!
You're such a dear, friend.
You know I'm here, friend.
Is that a tear, friend.
In your eye?
Now, it's goodnight, friend.
Goodnight friend.
Goodnight but not...
Return to base. Return to base.
Return to base. Return to base...
Message received and obeyed.
We leave at once.
You, stay here.
There's a male missing
from this household
and I want you to be
here when he returns.
It's possible, he's one of the
Rebels we're looking for.
Return to base. Return to base.
Return to base. Return to base...
Lumpy, are there any more inside?
Come here sweetheart.
It's okay. It's alright now.
Everything's okay now.
Here's your daddy.
Boy, has he grown.
It's okay everybody. He's gone.
How are ya? Malla! Ha, ha!
Itchy, you look wonderful.
Doing well, huh?
Your son's been doin' you proud. He's
saved my tail more'n a couple of times.
Look Malla, I'd love to but, I can't.
I gotta get back
to the Falcon before somebody
stumbles across her.
Hey, will you look at Lumpy?
He's sure grown, huh?
An' I think his voice is changin'.
Come on, I'm just teasin' ya.
Well, look.
I gotta go. Have a nice Life Day.
But be careful, a lotta
troopers in the area.
Chewie, check and see if the coast is
clear, will ya?
You're like a family to me.
I know, bye.
Okay pal?
Bye everybody.
Well pal...
be careful.
They'll be lookin' for him.
Take care.
You sure know how to make a guy feel
welcome.
Glad you're home, Chewbacca.
If you're looking for who I'm thinking
you're looking for, forget him.
We won't be bothered by him again.
This is a general alert.
Calling officer B-4711, officer B-4711.
We are unable to reach
you on your comlink.
Is there a problem?
You are instructed to turn on
your comlink immediately.
Wait, wait a minute.
I think I can handle this.
We have two-way communication, trader
Saundan.
Is this a report about
the missing trooper?
It is, sir.
Trooper B-4711 was here with
three other men.
They left and he remained.
As soon as they had gone,
he packed a lot of food from
this house and robbed me blind.
Then, he took off for the hills.
Very well. We'll send
out a search party.
Thank you.
Yes, sir.
Identification is very important.
Helps you maintain contact with
the Empire at times like this.
Lumpy.
Itchy.
Chewie.
Malla.
This day is for you.
Have a wonderful celebration.
And may the force be with you.
Happy Life Day.
Happy Life Day, everyone.
And, we're certainly glad that we
were allowed to celebrate it.
Yes, Artoo.
It is indeed true, that
at times like this,
Artoo and I wish that we were more
than just mechanical beings...
and were really alive, so that we
could share your feelings with you.
Chewbacca!
Chewbacca, we were so relieved to hear
you were alright.
All of you are an important part of my
life, pal. I'm glad I could be here.
This holiday is yours
But we all share with you the
hope that this day brings
us closer to freedom, and
to harmony, and to peace.
No matter how different we appear,
we're all the same in our struggle
against the powers of evil and darkness.
I hope that this day will
always be a day of joy in
which we can reconfirm our
dedication and our courage.
And more than anything
else, our love for one another.
This is the promise of the Tree of Life.
We celebrate a day of peace.
A day of harmony.
A day of joy we can all share
together joyously.
A day that takes us
through the darkness.
A day that leads us into might.
A day that makes us want to
celebrate...
the light.
A day that brings the promise
that one day, we'll be free
to live,
to laugh,
to dream,
to grow,
to trust,
to love,
to be.