Oh, hello there, honey!
- Nice to see you!
- This is my son.
How do you do?
Dorothy, this here's Gil Warren.
- Hi.
- It's so good to see you.
Don't worry, Gil.
She's just shy.
I brought you some tea.
Look! Here they come.
Come on, they're coming!
Shh.
We're getting ready
to set the table.
Take these checkers someplace else.
Here, you take these.
Come on, Henry, be careful.
Come on.
- Oh, man, you always drop the checkers when I'm...
- That's the way you win!
Toto! Toto! Toto baby!
# Put your arms around me, child #
# Like when you bumped your shin #
# Then you'll know
I love you now #
# As I loved you then #
# Though you may be
trying sometimes #
# And I need you
and you're not there #
# You know I may get mad #
# And turn away #
# But you know that I still care #
# Don't lose the feeling that we have #
# Don't lose the feeling
that we have #
# Though you're growin' older now #
# And I'm watching you grow #
# I know I make you
sad sometimes #
# And I see your feelings show #
# But one day I'll look around #
# Yeah #
# And you will be grown #
# You'll be out in the world
such a pretty girl #
# But you'll be on your own #
# And I'd like to know it's there #
# The feelin' that we have #
# Knowing that you
can come to me #
# Whenever you are sad #
# Child, I'd like
to know it's there #
# The feeling that we have #
# Don't lose the feeling
that we have #
# Don't lose the feeling ##
# Lose it #
# I don't even know
the first thing #
# About what they're feelin' #
# What am I afraid of #
# Don't know what I'm made of #
# Can I go on #
# Not knowin' #
# Feelin', feelin' #
# Somethin' tells me
that it's more than I #
# Can deal with #
# Though I never knew the song #
# Some words still catch on #
# Like carin' #
# And sharin' #
# Being together #
# No matter #
# Can I go on #
# Not knowin' #
# Don't know what I'm made of #
# Why am I afraid of #
# Feelin' #
# If I dared to take a chance #
# Would someone #
# Lead me ##
Emergency snow alert is now in effect.
No automobiles are to be driven
without snow tires or chains.
Winds up to 45 miles per hour...
That was a great dinner, Emma.
- That baby!
- You're a grandpa!
- Our daughter's fine.
- Mmm.
But Dorothy.
Give her time, honey.
Give her time.
Those dishes
ain't gonna wash themselves.
Mrs. Warren's son
looks real fine, don't he?
Aunt Em, please,
no more matchmaking.
Did you make the decision
about that new school yet?
It's no decision to make.
But, honey, it's a chance
to teach in high school.
Get away from that kindergarten
once and for all. It's more money.
But besides the money, it's a chance
for you to be with older students.
Almost adults.
- I like it with the kids, Aunt Em.
- I know you do, honey.
And you're a fine teacher.
But that's why I think you'd
enjoy teachin' high school.
Have a chance to be with
the students for four years...
...such an important time
in their development.
I'm really happy
with the kids, Aunt Em.
But you been there
for three years already.
It's time you got out of that sandbox and
into some new people, new neighborhood.
Girl, do you know you're
24 years old and you've...
Never been south of 125th Street?
Well, you haven't.
Oh, here we go again.
You get me so worked up...
...that I'm beginning
to sound like a Jewish mother.
I can't see how goin' south of 125th
Street ever made anybody's life better.
And you're never gonna know
unless you try, are you?
Come on, Aunt Em, let me do that.
Why don't you go in and relax?
I can do... Let me do that.
Listen, I know gettin' out
in that world ain't easy...
...leaving Uncle Henry and me.
But we'll always be here
for ya, Dorothy.
And whatever your fears are, well...
...they'll be defeated just
by facing up to 'em.
Now, you take that new job
and find a place for you and Toto.
It's time for you
to make a home of your own.
Toto! Oh! Toto!
Toto! Toto!
Toto!
Toto! Oh! Toto!
Toto! Toto!
# La, la, la, la, la #
# La, la, la, la #
Toto! Where are you?
Toto! Toto! Toto! Toto!
Oh!
Toto, Toto.
- Toto, Toto.
- To... To... Toto!
- Toto, Toto. Toto, Toto.
- To... To... To...
- Toto! -
Toto! - Toto!
God, where am I?
Toto! Toto!
Two, two, two, two,
two, two, two, two!
Two, four, six, eight!
Who do we appreciate?
No! No!
- Relax, Mama!
- We just wanna lay a little thanks on ya.
- What?
- You know, heavy on the gratitude department.
- Gratitude? For what?
- For curling the curse.
- For leveling the leech.
- For killing our oppressor.
Uh! I never killed
nothin' in my life.
- Never killed the point?
- A pint?
- A good story?
- The umpire?
- No!
- Never killed no time?
No, I told you!
I never killed nothin'!
Well, then, I think you graduated...
...from the bush leagues
into the majors, girl.
Toto?
Can you dig this?
- Who is it?
- Ain't no more "is"!
Thanks to you, it's a "was"!
- She was Evermean.
- The Wicked Witch from the East.
And they didn't
call her Evermean for nothin'!
She was the parks department
commissioner!
Caught us paintin' on
her playground walls.
- Turned us into graffiti!
- And there we stayed.
- Flat, splat and stuck like that!
- Doomed as cartoons forever.
'Til you burned alphabet
through the sky and ended the curse.
- And the "curseress. "
- Givin' a new lease on life to us...
The Munchkins, most recently
referred to as the "cursees. "
Toto.
Let's hear it for
Super Witch and her Wonder Dog!
Two, four, six, eight!
Who do we appreciate?
Miss One!
Come to Mama,
you hot little digits!
Let me lay my 20-20s on ya!
Oh, how I love you!
Let me... Mmm!
Count the ways!
Oh, mmm! Mmm!
Innumerable blessings,
countless felicitations.
Thank you beyond number
and additional good stuff!
I didn't mean to...
I didn't mean to kill her.
Oh, don't be
all sixes and sevens, honey.
You did the world a multitudinous
service by 86ing ol' Evermean.
Bottom line, honey,
this chick put the "ugh" in ugly.
But she sure had pretty shoes,
didn't she? Yah!
I don't want these shoes.
I wanna go home.
I wouldn't discount
those shoes, honey.
And don't ever take 'em off
until you do get home.
Remember Miss One told ya.
Oh, pardon me.
Miss One's the name
if you haven't guessed by now.
Numbers is my game
and now that you've freed us...
we can all go back to
runnin' our business, ahem.
We can all go back to
runnin' our business.
But where am I?
Where am I?
You're in Munchkin Land!
- The indivisible Land of Oz!
- Oz?
But where's my home?
Where's Aunt Em? Where's New York?
- New York?
- 433 Prospect Place.
Ooh! Four, three, three.
You wanna play more than
one number today, honey?
I got a freedom special,
three numbers for the price...
No, I don't wanna play any numbers.
I just wanna get home!
Oh, well, now that ol'
Evermean's number's up...
...that leaves only
three witches in Oz.
One, myself, but my powers
don't amount to much.
And number two, Glinda,
the Good Witch of the South.
Oh, she's a real star,
but you can hardly catch her in.
And number three, the multi-horrored
Evillene, the Wicked Witch of the West.
Evermean's even uglier sister!
But I don't think it'd be
a good time to ask her for a favor.
So I figured the odds are only the Wiz
could cipher how to get you back to...
- Where'd you say that place was?
- The Wiz?
What's a Wiz?
What's a... What's a Wiz?
Oh, darlin', he's the ultimate.
The "X" quotient, the new math.
The common denominator,
the main man.
The head honcho!
Bottom line, honey.
Numero uno!
- Where is he? How do I find him?
- Catch this number, honey.
# Sweet thing
let me tell you about #
# The world and
the way things are now #
# You've come from
a different place #
# And I know you've
traveled far #
# Now that you've told me
what it is #
# I better point you
towards the Wiz #
- # He's the Wiz #
- # He's the man He's the only one #
# Who can give your wish
right to ya #
# He'll send you back
through time #
# By runnin' magic through ya #
# All of his super power's his #
# Dot dot da dot da #
# Listen and I'll tell you
where he is #
# He's the Wiz and he lives #
# In Oz #
- # He's the Wizard #
- # There's the way #
# To the Emerald City
That's not too far, is it #
- # He's the Wizard #
- # Just take your dilemma, child #
# And lay it on the Wizard #
# He'll fix you a drink
that'll bubble and foam #
# Dot dot da dot da #
# And in a flash
you will be home #
- # He's the Wiz #
- # He's the Wiz He's the Wizard of Oz #
- # He's got magic up his sleeve #
- # He's the Wizard #
# And you know without his help #
# It would be
impossible to leave #
# Fantastic powers
at his command #
Whoo!
# And I'm sure
that he will understand #
# He's the Wiz and he lives #
# In Oz #
# Sweet thing, let me tell you about #
# The world and the way
things are now #
# And I'd better point ya
towards the Wiz #
Whee! Ooh!
Whee!
He's the Wiz!
# Fantastic powers at his command #
# I'm sure that
he will understand #
# He's the Wiz and he lives #
# In Oz #
# Sweet thing
let me tell you about #
# The world and the way
things are now #
# You come from a different place
and I know you traveled far #
# Now that you've
told me what it is #
# I'd better point you
toward the Wiz #
# Dot dot da dot da
dot dot da dot da #
# He's the Wiz ##
But how do I get
to the Emerald City?
Count your blessings, cut your losses
and follow the Yellow Brick Road.
- The Yellow Brick Road?
Yeah! The Yellow Brick Road!
Yellow Brick. Toto!
Remember, don't ever take those shoes
off and watch out for the poison poppies!
Wait.
Miss One?
Miss One!
# There's a feeling #
# Here inside #
# That I cannot hide #
# And I know I've tried #
# But it's turning me #
# Around #
# I'm not sure that I'm aware #
# If I'm up or down #
# Or here or there #
# I need both feet
on the ground #
# Maybe I'm just goin' crazy #
# Lettin' myself get uptight #
# I'm actin' just like a baby #
# But I'm gonna be #
# I'm gonna be all right #
# Soon as I get home #
# In a different place #
# In a different time #
# Different people around me #
# I would like to know #
# Of their different world and how #
# Different they find me #
# And just what's a Wiz #
# Is he big
Will he scare me #
# If I ask to leave #
# Will the Wiz even hear me #
# How will I know then #
# If I'll ever get home again #
# Here I am alone
though it feels the same #
# I don't know where I'm goin' #
# I'm here on my own
and it's not a game #
# And a strange #
# Wind is blowin' #
# I'm so amazed at the things
that I see here #
# Don't wanna be afraid
I just don't wanna be here #
# In my mind this is clear #
# What am I doin' #
# Here #
# I wish #
# I was home #
# I wish, I wish #
# I wish I was ##
Wait! Mister, please wait!
Ha, ha, ha, ha!
Succulent and divine!
- Delicious and nutritious.
- Brother crows, this is good stuff!
I'm glad you fellows
are enjoying your breakfast.
Is today the day you're gonna
help me get down from here?
Help you down?
What is goin' down in
that hayloft you call a head?
Didn't we tell you yesterday
and the day before that...
- And the day before that...
- That you can't get down?
This is your life,
buddy, all hung up!
Besides, Clyde...
...us crows are just thinkin' of you.
There ain't nothin'
to get down for!
But I was
just thinkin', just once, fellas...
...for a little while to walk in my garden,
wouldn't that be terrific?
- Walk!
- You can't walk!
Why, you just
a straw paper dummy!
You're right, fellas.
I was just bein' selfish.
And stupid as usual!
- But I was readin' this morning that most people...
- Oh, man!
Look, didn't we tell you
readin' was a waste of time?
- But Bacon here said...
- Bacon? Once over lightly, please!
"Knowledge is power. "
- See, and, uh, Cicero, he said...
- Cicero-ro-row!
"More men are ennobled
by study than by nature. "
And over here, especially
apropos in my situation...
...i. E., stuck up on this here pole:
"Do not accept any situation.
Question, argue and explore. "
Now who you gonna believe?
- Mr. Nobody on that paper?
- Fellas, please!
Or your good friends, the crows?
Yeah, who have dedicated
their lives to educatin' you.
- Yeah!
- Sounds to me, fellas...
...like ol' garbage guts here done forgot
the crow commandments again.
Fellas, I did not forget
the crow commandments. Please!
Run 'em by me!
Run 'em by me.
- Thou shalt honor all crows.
- Right on!
- Proceed!
- Thou shalt stop readin' all bits of paper and literature.
- Trash! Trash!
- And the most important one!
Thou shalt never, never get down
off of this here pole!
You got it, Clyde!
And the crow anthem!
I gotta sing that thing again?
# You gotta libretti it
'til you get it #
- # Elucidate #
- # Reiterate #
# And syncopate #
# You can't win
You can't break even #
# And you can't get
outta the game #
# People keep sayin' #
# Things are gonna change
but they look just like #
# They're stayin' the same #
# You get in way over your head #
# And you only got yourself
to blame #
- # You can't win, child #
# You can't break even #
# You can't get outta the game #
# You can't win
The world keeps movin' #
# And you're standin' far behind #
# People keep sayin' #
- # Things'll get better #
- # Just to ease your state of mind #
# So you lean back #
# And you smoke that smoke #
# And you drink
your glass of wine #
# Sayin' you can't win
child #
# You can't break even #
# And you can't get
outta the game #
# You can't win #
# You can't win no way
if your story stays the same #
- # You ain't winnin' #
- # Oh, no #
# But I'd like to see you
I'm awfully glad you came #
# Better cool it
'cause it ain't about losin' #
# Then the world
has got no shame #
# You can't win, child #
# Can't break even
Can't get outta the game #
# You can't win
You can't break even #
# Ain't the way
it's supposed to be #
- # You'll be spendin' your little bit of money #
- # Oh, no #
# While someone else
rides for free #
- # Learned your lesson #
- Ooh!
# Refuel your mind before some turkey
blows out your flame #
- # And you can't win, child #
- # No, you can't win #
- # You can't win, child #
# You can't win, child
Can't break even #
# And you can't get
outta the game #
# You can't get outta the game #
# You can't get out #
Ooh!
# Of the game #
# No, no, no ##
- I'll, I'll help you down.
- What?
You will?
What's she doing here?
- Get her outta here.
- Shoo! Shoo! Shoo!
Shoo, shoo,
go on about your business.
Shoo!
Ooh!
- Just hold on.
- This is just an experiment.
The results of
the first experiment:
Subject is a hopeless failure.
- You are not.
- I am.
You're just a product
of some negative thinking.
First thing we have to do
is get rid of these crows.
Come on, Toto, sic 'em!
Shoo! Shoo!
Shoo! Before I call
the taxidermist, you turkeys!
Get off me, dog!
Good boy, Toto.
We can go now.
You okay?
Come on! Hey!
Ooh!
I think I'm gonna
make it this time.
You sure are.
Just a little self-confidence...
...and coordination.
You're gonna be fine.
You mean, all this time
the only thing standing between...
...hangin' up there
and livin' it up down here...
were those crows?
Well, they told you you couldn't do it
and you believed them.
If I only had a brain, I would have
figured that out a long time ago.
There you go with that
negative thinkin' again.
- Everybody has a brain.
- Uh-uh.
Not me, look.
Oh.
Garbage?
"Lgnorance is the night
of the mind...
...a night without moon or star. "
Confucius said that.
I'm on my way to find the Wiz.
He's gonna get me back home.
That's nice. Thank you.
Good luck.
I thought maybe he
could get you a brain.
You think that he could...
And Toto and me,
we could sure use some company.
Besides, you have nothin' to lose.
I don't, do I?
That was so smart of you!
I wish I thought of that.
Indications are it would be
very advantageous for me to join you.
Good.
Um, we only have one problem.
The Munchkins said to follow the Yellow Brick
Road, but I haven't been able to find it.
- Yellow Brick Road?
- There it is!
Hey, wait! Wait!
Did you say, "Yellow Brick Road"?
- Yes!
- Look over here!
We don't need no cabs.
- Say, what's your name?
- My name is... Dorothy.
Dorothy and Toto?
What intelligent names!
Okay, Dorothy and Toto, we're gonna have
to find our own Yellow Brick Road.
# Ease on down
Ease on dow... #
- Down the road!
- There it is!
# Ease on down #
- Oh!
- # Ease on... Down #
- Down the road!
- Oh!
# Don't you carry nothin' #
- # That might be a load #
- There it is!
Dorothy! Look! Dorothy!
Aaah!
Ta-da!
Whoo! Come on, Dorothy!
Come on!
Whoo!
# Come on and ease on down
ease on down the road #
# Come on, ease on down
# Don't you carry nothin'
that might be a load #
# Come on, ease on down
ease on down the road #
# Pick your left foot up
put your right one down #
# Come on, legs
keep movin' #
# Don't you lose no ground #
# Just you keep on keepin'
on the road you choose #
# Don't you give up on walkin'
'cause you gave up shoes #
# Ease on down
Ease on down the road #
# Come on, ease on down
ease on down the road #
# Don't you carry nothin'
that might be a load #
# Come on, ease on down
down, down #
Whoo!
# Don't you carry nothin'
that might be a load #
# Ease on down, ease on down
down the road #
# Ease on down the road #
# Ease on down
ease on down the road #
Ease on down #
Toto!
# Ease on down
ease, ease on down #
- # Down the road ##
- Help!
Help!
Help?
Help? Where?
Help! Help!
Over here!
Help!
Hurry! Hurry!
- Where are you?
- Hurry, hurry, hurry!
Step right up and save a life!
Ooh! Ooh!
I'm in a little bit of a squeeze,
brother. Can you give me a hand?
Dorothy?
Oh, how terrible.
- Don't move.
- Don't worry, I wasn't planning any promenades.
We'll be right back.
Oh, he's so brave.
He's probably in shock.
Oh, what I wouldn't
give to be in shock... Just once.
I'm so... I'm so sorry.
No apology necessary. I told you
nothing hurts me. I have no feelings.
The genius who created me only
took care of my dashing good looks...
...my razor sharp wit and my irresistible
attraction to the wrong women.
What he forgot to add...
was a heart.
But... Everyone has a heart.
Alas, everyone but yours truly.
Hello!
Nobody home in Soulville.
Rid of you!
Free from your posterior prison!
You hulking she devil!
Don't hear ya laughing now.
We were abandoned here when
this park went "el foldo. "
Ah, it was a sad day.
There's not much amusement to
the closing down of an amusement park.
But yours truly is an old trooper!
I quickly made plans
for the future.
But alas, I was felled
by my 4th wife, Teenie.
Crushed in my prime!
There, how does that feel?
But that's the whole
tragic point, my friends.
# What would I do #
# If I could suddenly feel #
# And to know once again #
# That what I feel is real #
# I could cry
I could smile #
# I might lay back
for a while #
- # Tell me what #
- # What #
# What would I do #
# If I could feel #
# If I could
reach inside of me #
# And to know
how it feels to say #
# I like what I see #
# And I'd be more #
# Than glad to share #
# All that I have
inside of here #
# And the songs
my heart might bring #
# You'd be more
than glad to sing #
# And if tears should
fall from my eyes #
# Just think of all the wounds
they could mend #
# And just think of all the time
I could spend #
# Just being vulnerable again #
- # Tell me what #
- # What #
# What would I do #
- # Oh, tell me what #
- # What, what would I do #
- # What #
# What would I do #
# If I could feel ##
I'm just a miserable
hunk of junk.
Me!
Once the fastest
metal mouth on the midway.
Frozen... ironically in a position
I had assumed all too often.
A seat cushion for Teenie!
Teenie!
- Teenie!
- Dorothy!
- Teenie! Teenie!
- Are you thinkin' what I am?
- Teenie!
- You're so smart!
Teenie! Teen...
You could come with us
to see the Wiz.
He's gonna get me back home...
...and he's gonna get
the Scarecrow some brains.
Maybe he could get you a heart.
You're not just flimflammin'
an ol' flimflammer, are ya?
Could I come with ya?
- Of course.
- "A threefold cord is not quickly broken. "
What's wrong?
He rusted himself cryin'.
Oil! Oil!
- What?
- Oil!
- Find some oil!
- Some oil!
Oil!
# Slide some oil to me #
# Let it trickle down my spine #
# If you don't have STP #
# Crisco will do just fine #
# Slide some to my elbow #
# And to my fingers
if you would #
# Slide some oil
to me, girl #
# Whoo, don't that
feel good #
# Slide some oil
to my feet #
# Look-a there
I got toes again #
# Come on
slide some oil to my knees #
# And let me see
if I can bend #
# Slide some oil to me #
# I'm beginnin' to feel just fine #
# Slide some oil
down my throat #
# And let me lubricate my mind #
# Slide some oil to me #
# Go ahead
hit my shoulder blades #
# Those who don't have
to lubricate #
# Sure got it made #
# Slide some oil to me #
# Let it slip down my side.
# Laying there in one position #
# Sure done made me tired #
Now watch me dance.
Come on, you metal metatarsals,
don't fail me now.
Ah-ha! Fall in line
and get left behind.
Two bits!
Let me show you my
Saturday night finish!
Oh! Music man!
Let me hear that band!
# Don't turn the water on me #
# Just let me burn
and let me lubricate #
# My mind ##
Come on!
# There may be times you think
you've lost your mind #
# These steps you're takin'
leave you steps behind #
# The road you're walkin'
might be long sometimes #
# But you keep on steppin'
and you'll be just fine #
# Ease on down
ease on down the road #
# Come on and ease on down
# Don't you carry nothin'
that might be a load #
# Come on, ease on down
down the road #
# Ease on down
ease on down the road #
ease on down ##
Hey! Look at me walkin'!
- Stop the music!
- What's the matter? You need more oil?
No! That beast!
He's checkin' us out.
Oh, it's just a statue.
Made of stone, see?
Now even a dummy like me
knows a stone lion...
...can't... Check you out.
# Say what you wanna
but I'm here to stay #
# 'Cause I'm a mean ol' lion #
# Now you can go
where you're gonna #
# But don't get in my way
I'm a mean ol' lion #
# You'll be standing in a draft #
# If you don't hear me laugh #
Ha-ha!
# If you have to come around #
# You best not make me frown #
# Or I just might
knock you down #
# 'Cause I'm a mean ol' lion #
# You know I'm ready to fight
and turn your day into night #
# 'Cause I'm a mean ol' lion #
# If you're half bright
you'll detour to the right #
# From a mean ol' lion #
# And all you strangers
got to beware #
# This is the king
of the jungle here #
# And if I happen
to let you slide #
# Don't stand there
run and hide #
# You just, you just
caught my better side #
# Now I'm a mean ol' lion #
# Look, you better beware #
# This is the, the king
of the jungle here #
# And if I happen
to let you slide #
# Don't stand there
run and hide #
# You just done caught
my better side #
# Now I'm a mean ol' lion #
Toto!
# Now I'm a mean ol' lion ##
How dare you touch...
...the personage of a king?
You tacky package of horse fodder.
Begone, you overexcited slot machine.
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Oh! You mangy mutt! Oh!
Toto!
Oh!
He bit my paw!
King of the jungle?
- King of the cowards.
- You oughta be ashamed of yourself, scaring us like that.
You big scaredy-cat!
I can't scare anything.
I can't even scare a scarecrow...
...a tin man or
a little puppy, anything.
It's no wonder they drummed me
out of the jungle.
- I.O.B.K.!
- I.O.B.K.?
Incapable Of Being King!
No! Wait, wait! Wait!
I was exiled in disgrace.
I thought I'd be safe here.
No one would...
discover my terrible secret.
Uh, that I'm...
...a lion without any courage!
"Uneasy lies the head...
...that wears a crown. "
W. Shakespeare.
Well, I thought
I'd seen 'em all.
But never, never have I seen...
...a lion... without courage.
Lion!
Maybe the Wiz could give you
some courage.
- It's a good idea.
- Capital suggestion.
- Capital! He's gonna get me a heart.
- And me some brains.
Come with us to Emerald City.
I'd love to, but I can't.
But why?
Because... I'm scared!
Oh.
# Oh, there #
# May be times #
# When you wish
you wasn't born #
# And you wake one morning
to find your courage gone #
# But just know that feelin'
only lasts a little while #
# You just stick with us
We'll show you how to smile #
# Ease on down
ease on down the road #
# Come on, ease on down
# Don't you carry nothin'
that might be a load #
# Come on, ease on down
ease on down, down the road #
# Ease on down
ease on down the road #
# Come on, ease on down
# Ease on down
ease on down the road #
# I gotta get down
gotta get, gotta, gotta #
# Gotta, gotta, gotta
getta, getta, getta #
# Ease on down the road
ease on down the road ##
Ah, my ma would be so proud.
Going to see the Wiz!
My mama used to
always say to me, Fleet!
Fleet?
That's my name,
Fleetwood Coup de Ville.
- Mama had high ideals.
- Yeah!
- You know what I mean?
I ain't too happy
underground, you all.
- How does he do that?
- It's just a hoax, my friend.
He's got a little motor
in his... Pocket.
- Lion! Lion!
- Help!
- Oh, my... Please, somebody!
- Shh!
Lion! Lion!
Owww! Lion!
Li...
Lion!
Aaah!
Lion, save me!
Dorothy!
Toto! Toto, Toto, Toto.
Hey!
Oh! Wait!
- Where's the lion?
- I'm coming!
- Wait, wait!
- Lion!
Come on! Let's go!
- Hurry up!
- This way, this way! Wait for me!
Hey!
Sssss!
# Ease on down
ease on down the road #
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
My queen, if you'll allow me,
like I say...
...you stick with the big kitty
and you'll be in heaven.
Sssss!
Outta the frying pan, into the...
This is like a setup.
Stay away! Dorothy! Lion!
Don't follow them! Don't!
Oh, please! It's a setup!
- Stop!
- Come back!
Jump! Don't go in there!
Whoo, whoo!
Oh! Dorothy! Lion!
- I can't move him! I can't move him!
- Dorothy?
- Get Toto, we'll come back for him.
- Toto!
Oh, look, poor little Toto!
Sweet little Toto.
What are we going to do?
- All is lost!
- Dorothy!
Dorothy, please.
Oh, please, don't be dead.
Oh, all is lost.
# How high the moon #
What's happenin', babe?
Hey, Lion's okay!
- Hey, baby!
- Come and cry over here!
- Teenie! Think of Teenie!
- Dor... Dorothy?
- Think of Teenie!
- Uh, Teenie, uh, Teenie!
- Uh, Teenie!
- It's all my fault!
Uh, Teenie! Uh, Teenie!
Oh, mighty Zeus!
And gods of the universe!
Why have you cursed
this low, mangy animal so?
Once I was a king,
a lion amongst lions!
Ruler of a beautiful
kingdom by a waterfall.
Attended by butterflies
and sparrows.
And now banished for lack of courage...
I cannot even protect these
friends who have been so kind.
Oh, I was strong and brave...
...in the subway only to be
foolish and weak again.
I led us into
the very jaws of death!
Oh, let me end it all!
- Lion, Lion!
- No!
No, let me splatter
to the four winds!
It's all right, Lion.
It's all right.
Everything's all right.
- The worst is over, my furry friend.
- No!
Would you lay an appropriate quote
on this poor beasty brother?
"Showers expected late tomorrow. "
Lion?
# There is a place #
# We'll go #
# Where there is mostly quiet #
# Flowers and butterflies #
# A rainbow lives beside it #
# And from a velvet sky #
# The summer storm #
# You can feel #
# The coolness in the air #
# But you're still #
# Warm #
# And then a mighty roar #
# Will start the sky #
# To cryin' #
# But not even lightning #
# Will be frightening #
# My lion #
# And with no fear inside #
# No need to run #
# No need to hide #
# You're standing strong #
# And tall #
# You're the bravest #
# Of them all #
# If on courage #
# You must call #
# Then just keep on tryin' #
# And tryin' #
# You're a lion #
# In your own way #
# Be a lion #
Come on, be a lion.
# I'm standing strong #
# And tall #
# You're the bravest #
# Of them all #
# If on courage #
# You must call #
# Keep on tryin' #
# And tryin' #
# I'm a lion #
# In my own way #
- # A lion #
# I'm a lion ##
- How do we get in?
- And how do you do?
- Good evening there, brother.
- This place is nice.
The service entrance
is at the side.
We're here to see the Wiz.
This is where the Wiz lives,
isn't it?
May I welcome you to the Emerald City.
# Ahh, ahh, ah #
# I want to be seen green #
# Wouldn't be caught dead red #
# 'Cause if you are seen green #
# It means you've got mean bread #
# Ahh, ahh, ah #
# You've got to be seen in green
to show that your stuff's laid #
- # If you're not seen green #
# You'd better be wearin' jade #
# Ahh, ahh, ah #
# You've got to be seen green #
# Don't tell him
your cupboard's bare #
# That you gave up
one week's feed #
# To pay for your colored hair #