This place gives me the juice bumps.
- Maybe we should go back.
- Very back.
We can't go back now.
Okey-dokey Jones never goes back!
Hang on to your diapies,
we're going in!
That’s Tommy Pickles.
He’s the bravest baby l ever knowed.
And that’s Phil and Lil.
They like worms.
And I’m Chuckie.
I’m not so brave.
That’s Okay, 'cause I’ve got Tommy,
and he’s my bestest friend.
Watch out!
- Keep going!
- It's right behind us!
Tommy!
Tommy ...
Come on, Chuckie!
Tommy, you kids
shouldn't be playing in here.
We thought the fun times
would last forever.
But we was wrong.
- oh, my ...
- Upsy-daisy, Didi.
Thank you for inviting me
to your baby shower, Mrs. Pickles.
- Glad you could be here, Suzy.
- What a pretty dress, Angelica.
My mummy's assistant bought it
especially for Aunt Didi's party.
Don't say a word.
$20 on 8 pounds, 6 ounces.
Who's got 8-7?
- 12 pounds, are you crazy?
- You can't see she's gained weight.
I mean, from behind.
Look what we got for you.
Boris, move your tuchis!
A goat?
Mum, you shouldn't have.
Nothing better for her
than goat's milk.
Except maybe yak. But you try
finding good yak these days.
Here you go, Kinderlach,
some chocolate coins.
- Aren't you gonna eat it, Tommy?
- I’m saving it for my baby sister.
- She finally came?
- Not yet.
But they're giving her this party,
so I’m pretty sure today's the day.
Do you think she got losted
on the way to the party?
Maybe we should look for her.
- Come on.
- But she could be anywhere.
- Watch it, pups.
- Careful.
- How's our little man?
- Dr. Lipschitz says it's a girl.
That windbag thought
Phil and Lil were intestinal gas.
- ''Riding high, it's a guy.''
- You know what they say:
''Born under Venus, look for a ...''
Dr. Lipschitz is the expert.
None of you have a Ph.D. in Latin.
Pig Latin, maybe. Let's just hope
for Tommy's sake it's a girl.
How my pups would squabble
if they were both boys!
Let's not do any
gender stereotyping. After all, -
- Stu and drew are brothers,
and they get along fine.
- Pushy! Bossy!
- Lazy! Inconsiderate!
- Why can't you listen to me?
- We're talking about a real job.
I’m not gonna waste my life as a
clock-punching, paper-pushing ...
No offence.
You got no insurance, no savings
and another kid on the way.
For your information, bro,
I am working on something now -
- that will put this branch of the
Pickles family on easy street.
- What now, an electric sponge?
- of course not. That was last year.
This is the Reptar wagon!
The ultimate in toddler
transportation. The perfect toy!
In my day, we had plenty of fun
just throwing rocks at each other.
The Reptar Corp is holding
a toy-design contest.
The winner gets $500.
There'll be plenty more if this toy
is a hit. And I’ll be famous!
That's what you said
when you built that stupid thing.
Maybe Ducktar was a little complex.
But this ... watch!
I am Reptar. Hear me roar.
Can't a man work in his own basement
without getting barbecued?
Okay, so maybe real fire isn't
the best idea for a children's toy.
Tommy,
somebody's been colouring your room.
Yup, it's for my new sister.
- How are we gonna find her?
- We don't know what she looks like.
Well, she's a girl like me,
so we know she'll be prettyful.
You babies got a lot to learn
about the facts of life.
I must get back to the dessert table
before the grown-ups eat it all.
Angelica, can you help us
find my baby sister?
I wouldn't be in such a hurry.
When she gets here, she'll get all
the toys and love and attention.
Your mummy and daddy
will forget all about you.
''Look, Didi, there's that little
bald kid in the house again.''
- My mum and dad won't forget me.
- That's what Spike said.
- Back when his name was Paul.
- Paul?
Then you came. They put him out in
the rain and he turned into a dog.
That's not gonna happen to me.
My mum and dad will always love me.
A baby is really neat
a baby is a Special treat...
Who does Suzy Carmichael
think she is?
A baby is a little dickens
a baby is a cuddly chicken
- A baby is lots of joy
- A baby will get all the toys!
- A baby has a smiley face
- A baby is from Southside Space
- A baby is extra fancy
- A baby poops in his pantsies
like a birdie Singing in a tree
More like Reptar
screaming in your ear
A baby is a gift
a gift from a Bob
from a Bob, Bob, Bob
A baby is a gift...
Do you really think
babies are a gift from a Bob?
lf Bob bringed a gift,
it's probably one of them.
- A baby is very special
- A baby is not!
- Betty, it's time.
- It’s time? oh, boy.
Everybody to your stations.
Charlotte, call the hospital.
Didi, start your breathing.
Good girl.
Up we go, sprout.
We got a Pickle to deliver.
Now that’s what l call
a baby shower.
Welcome to the Werner P. Lipschitz
Centre for holistic birthing.
offering the state of the art
in primitive birth alternatives.
Mrs. Pickles!
You weren't due till next week.
Well, we can try to squeeze you in.
But Dr. Lipschitz promised us the
Zen experience in the Tibetan Room.
In my day, a woman dropped her baby
in the potato field and kept going.
Ah, yes, the old Country Room.
- Do you have anything cleaner?
- Maybe the Aquatic Immersion Room.
She's having a baby,
not a gefilte fish!
Stu, Didi, Randy called
to say you were on your way.
l didn't realise
you were bringing the whole party!
- How far apart are the pains?
- They're pretty much constant.
- Didi, let's get you settled in.
- Here you go, sprout.
Don't worry, sweetie.
Mummy's going to be okay.
Gosh, Tommy,
your mummy sure seems upset.
Maybe your baby sister
really is losted.
- Maybe we can buy a new one.
- Where would we find a baby here?
- Got any queens?
- Go fish.
- Hey, a baby store!
- Nice and wiggly.
Help me pick one my mum will like.
- Where am l?
- Today’s different than yesterday
- So this is the world?
- l miss my old womb
- This world is something strange
- l need a change
- This world is something new to me
- oh, my head!
- What is this? l can't take it
- me, either
- I’m hungry
- l love the extra leg room
- Man, they cut my cord
- Consider yourself lucky
- This world is way too big
- And populated y s by fuzzy pigs
- This world is something new to me
- This world is such a gas
- Where’s your class?
- This world is something new to me
- Can't a guy get some shut-eye?
- It’s so noisy in here
l can barely hear myself suck!
- The food here tastes pretty good
- My compliments to the chef
- You've got to holler to get fed
- But l could get used to that
- This world is way too bright
- Turn down the light
- So that’s what it looks like
- All things here are meant for play
- it’s gonna be a real cool day
- this world is something new to me
Real cool ...
this world is something new to me.
There you are.
Oh Gevalt! You kinder
gave my ticker such a scare!
All right, Didi, you can do it.
Push now.
Have we got a good reading
on the EFM?
oh, Didi, she's so beautiful.
She's a boy.
Hello, my wonderful, sweet baby boy.
l guess we won't be naming him
after my mother.
- what about my cousin Dillon?
- Dillon Prescott Pickles ...
Dill Pickles.
Yeah, l like it!
Here you go, sprout.
Tommy, l want you to meet
someone very special.
This is your brother Dillon.
Dill, this is Tommy.
Baby ...
See? They already love each other.
well, that's a start.
what are we gonna do?
He hasn't stopped crying
since we brought him home.
Somehow it's not
as much fun here anymore.
- what's your brother so sad about?
- l don't know.
But whatever it is,
it must be really bad.
- maybe he's broked.
- what?
- Broked!
- Broked?
He's not broked,
he's ... just a little loud.
That baby's getting on my nerves!
Direct from Moscow,
the Banana Bros Monkey Circus!
Featuring the Most amazing Monkey
Since Brezhnev.
so Trotsky on down
to the Banana Bros Monkey Circus!
Grandpa, can we go to the circus?
It's enough of a circus
around here already!
Sergei, you watch the monkeys.
I’ll get us coffee.
No, Igor, you watch the monkeys.
No! The monkeys watch you.
I’ll get coffee.
- Coffee's better in St Petersburg.
- No, it's better in Kei.
- It’s better in St Petersburg.
- Nothing's better in St Petersburg.
Look! The train!
Stop!
Then the wizard looked down
at the little boy and said:
'Your wish has been granted.''
And the little boy ...
- Please, help!
- I’ll be back, sweetie.
All l did was cough.
l tried not to.
But l coughed and now he's crying.
And now he's got the hiccups.
oh, Stu!
- Sing Dill a lullaby.
- I’m too tired to sing.
All right, I’ll make something up.
Baby, please, rest your head
now it is time for bed
- you're cuter than ...
- Uncle Ned
- Our little ...
- quadruped.
oh, Stu!
It didn't work. He's still awake.
I’ve got one.
Twinkle, twinkle
how time flies
Slowly in the Starry Skies
baby, please, close your eyes
- you're as Sweet as ...
- apple pies
as you grow and love and play
in Our hearts you'll always Stay
so Sleep and dream the night away
That was good.
baby, please, rest your head
now it is time for bed
please Stop, don’t you see?
l want Mum and Dad for me.
Hey sprouts,
a crate's no place for you to play.
you might get shipped to Japan.
I’d better keep an eye on this.
Dill, that's Tommy's blanket.
yeah, it used to sleep with me
before we even got you.
- my blanket!
- He's not very nice.
That's not how
you get things from a brother.
Here, watch.
- That's my Reptar, Lillian.
- It is not, Philip.
- It is tool
- It is not.
see, Tommy?
Now you try it.
- mine!
Gosh, Dill learns fast.
Hurry, Pop. They'll be here
to pick it up any minute.
why can't l watch Shirleylock Holmes
at our house?
I’ll never be able to hear it
with that new baby squawking.
dad's got to work overtime, so mummy
won't be so ashamed of his earnings.
Hi, Uncle Stu, sorry to hear
your pony is so slow.
what pony?
you told mummy
Aunt Didi got saddled with a loser.
- l ...
- Excuse me.
my tax deductions are crying.
you can't deduct them
if you don't have any income!
Boys, what are you doing?
Dill, what say we give Tommy
a little turn with the bear?
or not.
Hey, champ,
come with me a minute.
I've got something to show you
that's better than a teddy bear.
we weren't going to give you this
till you were older, -
- but l think now is the right time.
Grandpa put your picture inside.
l know it's hard, Tommy.
you have a little brother now,
and that's a big change.
They can be pretty tough
to get along with.
They aren't always
what you hoped they'd be.
That's why big brothers
have to have faith. y you’ll see.
He'll change.
After all, you’ve got
responsibility now.
l know you'll stick by Dill's side
and be a swell big brother.
Sponsativity...
- what is that?
- A Reptar.
- Unreal. what you think it's for?
- l don't know.
- we could ride to the baby store.
- Great idea.
we could take Dill to the hopsicle,
and get Tommy's money back.
- Tommy won't be happy about this.
- well, he's sure not happy now.
once Dill goes back to the
baby store Tommy will be happy.
l don't know about this.
- what are you doing?
- Lillian was ...
we're taking Dill back to the
hopsicle to get your money back.
you can't.
my parents want to keep him.
- why? All he does is cry and poop.
- So do you.
- l don't cry that much.
- you poop a lot.
- Look who's talking.
- l am not a poopy monster.
y Shirleylock Holmes, girl detective.
we thought you'd be happy, Tommy.
Knock it off! Cynthia and me
are trying to watch TV.
Hands off the merchandise.
Pretty good.
Be nice, Angela, he didn't mean it.
you want to ride in a wagon?
I’ll give you a ride.
To outside space.
my show! Next commercial,
you babies are in big trouble.
All aboard!
Just walk away, Chuckie.
walk away.
wait for me!
- which way to the hopsicle?
- we're not going to the hopsicle.
well, we're going somewhere.
Pick up for Pickles, to Japan.
Take it away!
yeah, have a good day.
Pipe down, Spike.
me and Cynthia are watching ...
Cynthia?
Nice try babies,
now give me back my ...
Cynthia!
They took Cynthia. Come on,
you're going to be my butthound.
we’ve got to search every doghouse,
tree house and doll's house.
l want those fugitives
back in custody.
Bad dog! Stop!
Just go to the spa and relax.
Pop and l are taking care of ...
Pop, where's the crate?
The delivery folks must’ve come.
They loaded her up and everything.
Sure you can talk to Tommy.
Pop, where are the kids?
They were here a minute ago,
playing in the ...
The crate!
Honey ...
I’m going to have to call you back.
How could you fall asleep? you were
supposed to be watching the kids.
we'll never find the babies
with this jerk in front of us.
This is more fun
than picking noses.
l don't know if l should
throw up or throw down.
I’ve turned this plane upside down,
but there are no children.
we found a kid, but he's
not the one you're looking for.
- Tommy.
- Sprout.
- Dill.
- Angelica.
- we’ve got to find them.
- Find what?
- Einstein here lost the kids.
- l lost the kids?
see?
- where are we?
- l don't know.
- It looks like the park.
- only bigger.
This place is bigger than the park
and the backyard all put together.
This is bad, you guys.
This is bad.
Tommy,
l think your brother's broked again.
- Are you okay?
- l think he's gonna explode.
- Poopie.
- what?
Poopie.
- l guess we'll have to change him.
- what do you mean ''we''?
you left him with your father?
The man slept through Pearl Harbor.
l sounded the alarm.
did your son have any enemies?
Any mob connections?
He is a baby!
- The powder goes on his bottom.
- I’m doing the best l can.
- Pee-pee.
- Look out.
Frog!
y our brother made a frog jump on me.
you stop it.
Let's stop playing around
and figure out how to get home.
we don't know where we are.
- l know! I’ve got my sponsativity!
- what's a sponsativity?
you get it for being a big brother.
It's just like when okey-dokey Jones
had to find his way home.
- l thought that was a crumpus.
- my dad says it's a sponsativity.
where does it say to go?
This way ...
That's the way,
straight up that hill!
Bad dog! Stop!
you know, not all dogs go to heaven.
There he is!
Mr. Pickles, is it true you shipped
your own children to Tokyo?
did a dingo eat your baby?
How many pecks of pickled peppers
did you pick?
Childhood: a time of innocence.
a time of joy.
a time of unspeakable,
unrelenting tragedy.
Tell us how it feels to know you
May never see your children again.
- Can't you show some compassion?
- So sorry.
Please, tell us how it feels to know
you may not see your children again.
Let me at him.
That crowd would indicate
a yard sale or a family tragedy.
I’ll get back to you.
How does it feel knowing your
brother lost your only daughter?
Share your pain.
- y you’re breaking my arm.
- Because l can't reach your neck.
There you have it. Two sour Pickles.
young Tammy, baby Dale,
the twins, Bill and Jill, -
- little Chunky and poor Amelia,
all vanished without trace.
I’m Rex Pester and I’ll be back
with More big-action news.
Mr. Swenson saw Angelica and Spike
head north on l-99.
- my baby!
- Let's go.
Private first-class Pickles,
reporting for duty.
Good job, you guys.
we're almost there.
- Dill, play nice.
- It’s not much fun back there.
we're doing okay.
That's some good hitting, Dill.
Right about now my dad would
make me a fried baloney sandwich.
l can almost smell it.
All crunchy ...
Stop it, you're making me hungry.
- oh, no!
- we can't see your houses.
we can't see any houses.
we're doomed! doomed, l tell you!
Mrs. Pickles,
can you identify this binkie?
This is all Dill's fault.
Right, Chuckie?
This never would have happened
if you hadn't put him in the wagon.
It’s not our fault
you got a naughty baby brother.
He's not naughty.
He's just ... a baby.
How can you be mad
just because ...
... you're standing there
all naked?
I’m sure he's just trying to help.
It’s hot,
exploring in the woods all day.
A little breeze feels good.
Just what l needed.
Thank you, Dill.
Those hiccups
are starting to bug me.
Face it, having a baby brother
isn't what you expected.
Look, somebody's house.
Tommy was right.
my sponsativity does work.
who'd have a house
way out here in the forest?
maybe a lizard lives there.
you know, a guy with a pointy hat
that grants wishes.
we just knock on the door
and say we want to go home.
- Everything will be back to Norman.
- Thank Bob.
Come on, guys.
we're off to see the lizard.
- Are you okay?
- l just tripped in a little hole.
It looks kind of like Spike's feet,
if he was a giant.
l saw a wolf make prints like that
in a storybook, then he ate a girl.
- The wolf ate a girl?
- They got her out ...
l don't think it's a wolf.
lf it was, we'd hear him say ...
- That was pretty good.
- l didn't do anything.
wolf!
- do you see the wolf?
- what does he look like?
- Big teeth and furl And teeth!
- No, Dill.
Bad, Dill. No.
l am Reptar!
Margaret, I’m sure you’ve run afoul
of many a scary pedestrian.
But out here
we have what you might call ...
... actual danger.
Grizzlies that will rip the top off
your car. Bobcats, wolies ...
And dragons?
- l saw some grown-ups. Stop!
- l don't know how.
l hope you figure it out because
l didn't bring my bathing suit.
Any further and l would
have needed a fresh diapie.
Dill, no!
aqua Reptar engage.
I’m telling you, l saw a dragon.
A big, green, fire-breathing dragon.
I’ve got to call headquarters.
while you're at it, ask for
a new assignment. Say, a city park.
out here in the country
you have to be a little tougher.
- A dragon! I saw it!
- Where?
A wrapper from a Cynthia sweet bar.
- my angel, she's been here.
- She's tracking the sprouts.
It’s the Pickles blood. l myself
remember tracking Sitting Bull ...
over here! We found some
wheel tracks heading into the woods.
- They must be in my Reptar wagon.
- you and your stupid inventions!
my stupid inventions ...
That's it!
The pups are in the woods.
you men follow those tracks.
- Stu, where are you going?
- Trust me. l have a plan.
Swab the poop deck, Mr. Phil.
Hoist the anchor, Number one.
- a pirate’s life is the life for me
- Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of Yum
- l get Seasick on the Sea
- hoist the Reptar flag real high
- my Sword is pointed to the Sky
you need a patch across your eye
from Zanzibar to candy bar
Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of Yum
we Search for treasures near and far
- beware lf you cross Our path
- we'll Shoot through your Mast
remove your gold baboons by half
a pirate’s life is a life for me
Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of Yum
adventure on the Open Sea
Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of Yum.
Dill!
Help me, Tommy!
Fish!
man overboard!
Hang on, Chuckie.
Look at him go.
Tommy, why didn't you help me?
I’m sorry.
Dill needed me, and he's ...
... just a baby.
Turn around.
Help me, you guys.
Dill, no!
l knew my Ducktar
would come in handy.
Pop, are you okay?
do you think we'll still be able
to find the lizard's house?
Sure. As long as I’ve got my
sponsativity, we'll never be lost.
which way are we supposed to go?
That way.
Look, footprints. maybe there's
other babies around here.
- Those are our footprints.
- we're going around and around.
- It was working before.
- l don't think it ever worked.
y our sponsativity is broke,
just like your brother.
- my brother is not broke.
- He pulled the lever.
He tried to send us
into the big Jacuzzi.
- Hey, you guys, look!
- what is it, Chuckie?
what's a train doing
in the middle of the forest?
maybe a giant baby
losted his choo-choo.
- what do you want?
- Hungry.
l want to go play with the monkeys.
Hungry.
watch my brother.
I’ve got to get the diapie bag.
Leave him alone. He's not a nana.
Guys, help.
The monkeys are trying
to take Tommy's brother.
- So?
- Just help me, okay?
- Let go.
- okay.
This is just great.
It can't get any worser than ...
... this.
- At least the monkeys are gone.
- And they took baby Dill with them.
where are you going, you dumb dog?
Hey! My rolleyblade is cracked.
Cynthia, are they
taking care of you?
will they know to comb your hair,
or put you into your sport jumper?
Spike ...
dog breath!
Spike?
This time she'll fly.
I’m facing into the wind.
- Ready? Go?
- No!
- This is bad.
- Here comes Tommy.
- Put the blankie on him.
- okay, I’ve got it.
- l think it's going to rain.
- we'd better go.
- l must finish feeding my brother.
- He's not hungry.
Besides, he's a ...
- A monkey?
- Look at that!
my brother turned into a monkey?
- we’ve got to get out of here.
- Not while my brother's a monkey.
we must find the lizard's house.
That's it! The lizard can wish him
back into a people.
what if we only get one wish?
lf you use it up on Dill,
how are we going to get home?
l have to wish him back.
- you can't.
- l can.
- what if Phil turned into a monkey?
- That's different. l like Philip.
you'd be wasting your wish anyway,
because that's not your brother.
- wait a minute ...
- what Lillian means is ...
The monkeys took baby Dill. would
you mind a baby monkey instead?
- what?
- Nobody like him, Tommy.
we're going to find that lizard.
Find your brother by yourself.
- will you help me, Chuckie?
- Sorry, Tommy.
- But you're my bestest friend.
- yeah ...
Then how come, when l got
thrown up on, you didn't help me?
when l falled overboard,
you didn't help me.
when a monkey dropped me,
you didn't care about my boo-boo.
you don't got
a bestest friend no more.
All you got is a brother.
Fine ...
I’ll go find him by myself.
you dumb butthound.
l hope you turn into a frog.
I’ll find Cynthia myself.
one way or another
I’m gonna find you
some way or another
I’m gonna win you
Cynthia, oh Cynthia
l need to see you
from that kid or his brother
I’m gonna get you
I’ll find the full diaper bag
and lf you're ripped or you're hurt
I’ll push them in dirt
Yeah!
Give me back my brother.
Get out of here, you monkey.
Let's get out of this rain.
you rookies can get excited
and lose your heads.
Veterans like me
remain cool and collected.
our kids are lost in the storm.
you've got to help us.
There's dragons out there!
I’m a park ranger, -
- not a knight of the round table.
Go find somebody with a lance.
Never mind him. Come with me.
Have a little bottle and take a nap.
- Everything will be okay.
- mine!
But I’m hungry, too.
Stop that!
Dill, that's enough.
you didn't leave any for me.
All gone.
Dill.
Dill!
my blanket!
- Dill!
- my blanket! My blanket!
- l need some blankie, too.
- mine! Mine!
It’s not funny! They were right.
y you’re a bad, naughty baby.
y you’re never gonna get any better.
I’m through being your big brother!
l don't want
my sponsativity no morel
my monkey.
you want monkeys?
I’ll give you monkeys.
y you’ll have a monkey mummy and
a monkey daddy and a monkey brother.
l should have let my friends
take you back to the hopsicle.
l said you didn't mean it.
you were only playing.
l was wrong.
Now l don't even have friends.
He wants monkeys,
and monkeys want bananas ...
Everybody gets what they want.
I’m sorry, Dill.
It’s okay.
Everything’s going to be okay.
Phil? Lil?
- oh, Phil!
- Chuckie.
He always loved climbing trees.
Now a tree's climbed on him.
He was my favorites brother.
Speak to me, Philip.
- Have you guys seen my shoes?
- Philip!
- l don't like this adventure.
- This time we really are doomed.
doomed! doomed!
Snap out of it.
we’ve got to find the lizard.
lf we find the lizard before Tommy,
how is he going to get home?
what are you worried about him for?
He left you to the fish.
All he cares about is baby Dill.
well somebody has to ... don't they?
Baby please, rest your head
soon we will be home in bed
until then I’ll protect you
like no Other
you're Okay for a little brother.
- my Tommy.
- my Dill.
we'll never find them.
Can't you do something?
Come on, baby.
- Sky Pickle to ground Pickle.
- Stu, is that you?
Roger that, we have aerial search.
oh, no! Nice monkeys.
Not so fast, you monkeys.
Lil, Phil, you came back!
But where's ..?
l am Raptor,
the perfect children’s toy.
- Chuckie!
- Hi, Tommy.
you want bananas?
Come and get 'em.
Gosh, l never knowed
he was so brave.
yeah, I’m gonna miss him.
well, we'd better get out of here.
No. you guys take Dill
and look for the lizard.
I’ve got to help my bestest friend.
dumb dog.
There's no babies around here.
There you are!
Hand over my Cynthia.
Run Angelica,
the monkeys are coming.
Cynthia!
Hey!
Stop!
Spike, you found me!
Nice monkeys.
l was only kidding.
don't be mad at me, please.
Help!
Tommy, thank goodness.
Come on.
Chuckie, the lizard's housel
Let's find the others.
we’ve got a lizard to see.
l can't look.
Spike!
don't let them take me.
l don't want to be a monkey boy.
Hang to your diapies, babies.
Good one, Dill.
- Thanks, Dill.
- Dill, you're my hero.
Bye-bye, monkeys.
drop it.
Cynthia ...
Hey, you stupid diaper bag,
wait for me!
dumb monkeys.
you babies were going
to leave me and Cynthia behind ...
- l didn't know she could fly.
- It’s because she's a witch.
Hang on, Angelica.
A truck load of babies and
their pet horse lost in the woods.
our hearts go out
to their grief-stricken parents.
Pickles, now look what you’ve done.
Are you out of your mind?
And l never won an Emmy.
I’m coming, Tommy.
I’m coming, Dill.
Hurry up, babies.
- don't let them take me.
- don't let them take Cynthia.
l don't think they're going
to take anyone. Look!
Go home, monkeys!
we want to go home.
yeah, Spike!
you dumb wolf.
Spike!
oh, Spike ...
dumb dog.
why did you have to go and ..?
Didi, I’ve found them.
They're by the ranger's station.
I’m going in.
The lizard!
Please, Mr. Lizard,
we wish we could go ...
we wish we had our doggie back.
- Spike!
- He's alive!
Thank you, Mr. Lizard.
my darlings!
- mummy and daddy are here.
- you rascals.
- daddy's here.
- Sweetheart, everything’s okay.
you've got the Pickle spirit, son.
maybe not the brains,
but the spirit.
Stu, you did it.
you found our boys.
yeah, l guess l did.
my little furry comrades.
Come to Papa. who's your daddy?
- Both found ...
- This is my Story, pal.
I’m Rex Pester, Stay tuned.
Not my toupee!
- Go get him.
- Time for your close-up.
- I’m sorry about all this, drew.
- It’s all right, little brother.
For a nincompoop,
you're not half bad.
- Remember Swamptar?
- yeah, l remember.
so that was Our big adventure.
The Monkeys found their daddies.
We all got to go home
and have fried baloney Sandwiches.
Except Dill. He’s got no teeth.
But lf you think things went back
to the way they was, you're wrong.
now, thanks to baby Dill,
they was even better.
way to go, Dillie!
English subtitles - IFT