We're three happy chappies
with snappy serapes
You'll find us
beneath our sombreros
We're brave and we'll stay so
We're bright as a peso
Who says so, we say so
We're Three Caballeros
Oh, through fair
Or stormy weather
We're always together
So let come what may
Like brother to brother
we're all for each other
The Three Caballeros
Forever we'll stay
Oh!
"Felicitations to Donald Duck...
on his birthday, Friday the 13th...
from his friends in Latin America."
Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy!
What a pleasant surprise.
Whoops.
Ah, now, isn't that wonderful?
Which one should I open first?
My mama told me to take...
this one!
I wonder what's in it.
Oh, boy! Home movies!
Just what I wanted.
Well, well, well.
Well, doggone.
A little penguin.
Oh. What a cute little fella.
Well, what is this?
How do you open this thing, anyway?
On with the show.
The show must go on.
Sí, señor.
That means "strange birds."
Oh, sure, sure.
I know: Birds.
Yes, amigo,
your feathered cousins.
You know, Donald, you have
more relatives here...
than there are coffee beans
in Brazil.
For instance, take the one
who lives way, way down...
But suppose we let my friend
Professor Holloway tell us about it.
From the beginning to...
El fin, the end.
Yes. Thank you.
Professor?
This story takes us
way down to the South Pole.
Rather than have you
stand on your heads...
let's turn the theater over.
There. That's better.
Two things you will find
most of down here...
are ice and penguins.
It's amazing that anybody
would want to live here...
but most penguins wouldn't
live anywhere else.
You couldn't find better weather
for fishing...
skiing, tobogganing...
or swimming.
And there is nothing the average
penguin likes better...
than a day at the beach.
Uh, but come on.
Let's meet Pablo.
He lives down at
the end of Main Street.
Let's go in and see
what's cookin'.
Pablo could never remember
having been warm enough...
and so his closest companion
was SmokeyJoe...
his little stove.
Between chills,
Pablo had one burning desire...
to spend the rest of his life
on some tropical shore.
So we see him bravely set forth
for the isle of his dreams.
The other penguins turned out
to give him a big send-off.
But when he gets just so far
away from his stove...
See what happens?
Too bad.
Perhaps he'll give up this wild idea.
But no.
He's off to another start.
This time he's bringing a friend.
Anyway, it was a hot idea.
Well, maybe he'll be content
to stay at home this time.
But no!
There he goes...
hotfooting it
to the land of the sun.
By now, the farewell committee
has been reduced to two.
Discouraging, isn't it?
Suddenly,
Pablo got one of those ideas...
that change a person's
whole life: A boat.
But where would he get a boat?
Just watch.
Where there's a will,
there's a way, they say.
And now, the official launching.
Day after day,
the south wind carried him north.
One day,
a blanket of fog rolled in...
and it was so thick...
Must be near Cape Horn.
As the fog lifted...
he found himself headed straight
through the Straits of Magellan...
and northward
along Chile's rocky coast.
One day, a storm cloud came up...
just a little bitty
old storm cloud, though...
and just tried awful hard
to have its first storm.
Didn't amount to much, though.
One day on lookout,
Pablo had a bit of a shock...
a waterspout off the port bow!
But it proved to be
theJuan Fernandez Islands...
where Robinson Crusoe once lived...
and still does, apparently.
Four bells and all's well.
According to Pablo's chart,
he should be nearing Vina Del Mar.
And strangely enough,
that's just where he is.
He sailed past Lima,
capital of Peru...
hugging the coastline
with a tenacity of purpose...
seldom found in a penguin.
One day his telescope
picked out a city...
high up on top of a mountain.
The map said it was Quito...
and it was right smack
on the equator.
It wasn't as easy to cross...
but with a little help from Neptune,
he made it.
So, making a left turn,
he followed the equator...
headed for the Galapagos Islands.
Ah, that good old sun.
Pablo felt that
he'd never get enough of it.
Oh, he hadn't counted on this.
Things looked pretty bad.
Help! Man the pumps!
She's sprung a leak!
Pipe all hands on deck!
Do things! Get going!
Take to the lifeboats!
Abandon ship!
Unruffle the mizzenmast
and man the poops!
And, well, don't just stand there.
Get going!
Swab the decks, and...
Heavens.
Look! What's that?
Just what he's been looking for.
Pablo has finally reached
the isle of his dreams.
And so, as the warm tropical sun...
sinks slowly in the west...
we leave little Pablo,
a bird in paradise...
a picture of health
in his new coat of tan.
He should be the happiest
penguin in the world.
Only sometimes...
he gets to thinking...
Never satisfied.
Well, that's human nature for you...
even if you're a penguin.
You're absolutely right.
And now, Donald,
let's hop over the Andes.
From these snowcapped peaks
to the depths of the Amazon jungle...
one finds many more
strange and exotic birds.
Like the anambepreto
of Colombia and Venezuela.
He carries his own bagpipes
hidden under his beard.
Then there's his cousin,
the arapapa...
pride of Paraguay,
whose perfect appearance...
permits his pompous pride
in his pompadour.
And la tijereta, the scissors bird...
the Colombian cutup.
Then there's
the arapacu de pico curvo.
He's always sticking
his nose into things.
Did you ever see
such a freak beak, huh?
Speaking of beaks, what a time
two toucans have making love.
When they're beak to beak,
they can't get cheek to cheek.
Because when one toucan
turns his head...
only one toucan can.
Uh-oh. Who's that?
Oh, a thousand pardons.
Señor Donald, I would like
to have you meet...
one of the most eccentric birds
you have ever seen.
His name is the aracuan.
You'll find him most everywhere.
Eh, glad to know ya.
Pleased to meet ya.
Now, he's called the aracuan...
because of the peculiar
song he sings...
which sounds something like this.
By the way, amigo, did you know
some birds are skilled craftsmen?
Uh-uh. Is that so?
Yes. Quite a builder
is the little marrequito.
His nest may look
haphazard in design...
ah, but every single
stick and straw...
is scientifically
placed to withstand...
the stress and strain of...
well, almost anything.
Literally dotted are the shores
of many tropical marshes...
with the brilliant plumage
of the flamingo.
And now, Donald, how would you
like to hear a story...
about another bird so amazing
you won't believe it?
Oh, sure. You bet.
It's a tale told by
an old gaucho from Uruguay.
Listen.
It was early one morning
in springtime...
just as day was beginning to break.
As the sun came up over the...
Oh, but I am forgetting my story.
It was silent out there
on the pampas.
Only one little bird was awake.
From his nest came the little
hornero to see if the...
Oh, say, do you know why
this bird's called the hornero?
- No?
- Uh-uh. Why?
You see, his nest is
just like the horno.
That's the oven where we
bake our bread and our...
Oh, oh, oh,
you know who that is?
That's me, when I was
a little gauchito.
Many, many years ago, of course.
And why was I up so early?
Because I was going out
hunting all alone.
First I put on my bombachas
and tied on my chiripá.
Then I slipped into my new botas.
And I put my boleadoras
where I could reach them in a hurry.
¡Gauchito.!
Not forgetting my hunting knife.
And now I was ready to go.
Now, the best place
to hunt the wild ostrich...
is out on the wide open plains...
on the broad, flat land of the...
Flat land?
Say, what am I doing here?
Oh, now I remember.
This day I was hunting for condor birds
high up in the mountains.
While looking around for the condors,
I climbed to the top of a rock.
No, come to think of it,
it was a tree.
Let's see,
maybe it was a rock after all.
Although I could swear
it was a tree.
Oh, what's the difference?
Let it go. Let it go.
My sharp eyes soon discovered
the nest of a...
Psst! ¡Gauchito.!
The nest.
I could tell from the wings he was...
he was a least five meters
from tip to tip.
The biggest condor bird
in all of... ¡Caramba.!
What's this?
I couldn't believe my eyes.
No, it couldn't be.
But there it was.
I was looking face to face
with a flying donkey.
The donkey bird didn't seem bashful.
He flew right up close to...
Quick, Gauchito.!
Now! Get him, quick!
Aha. Got him.
Now, now. Easy, easy.
This donkey should be worth
a fortune.
I couldn't let him get away.
So I made up my mind that I'd catch him
if it took me the rest of...
Now I had him!
Hold him, Gauchito.!
Ride him, cowboy!
He acted just like he was loco,
but I was an expert, of course.
He thought he could
throw this gauchito...
but he soon found out
who was the boss.
Psst, Gauchito.!
Who is the boss?
I decided to train him
for racing...
far out where nobody could see...
'cause I planned to win
thousands of pesos...
for this little burrito and me.
I made brilliant plans for the future.
We'd live like a couple of kings...
and I'd be the world's
richest gaucho...
with my hands full
of big diamond rings.
¡Ah, macanudo.!
Okay.
This burrito was tame as a kitten.
He was learning new tricks every day.
You should see how he begged
for my mate.
He liked it much better than hay.
Then we soon fell asleep
by the campfire.
We both were as tired
as could be...
and tomorrow was very important...
for little Burrito and me.
For this was the day of fiesta.
The gauchos were happy and gay.
They danced the zamba and gatos...
and gambled their pesos away.
While the crowd sang
and danced in the plaza...
I just stood in the shade
of a tree...
and watched them toss coins
at the sapo.
But this game meant nothing to me.
Some others were rolling the bochas
and betting on games of this kind.
But I didn't join in these pastimes.
I had something bigger in mind.
- ¡Ay, caballo.!
- The race was about to begin...
and the grand prize was 1,000 pesos.
The gauchos were howling
with laughter...
when they saw us
come out on the track.
I whispered,
"Remember the wings, Burrito."
Oh-oh-oh-oh!
Not yet! Not yet!
The gauchos and horses
were all on their toes.
We were off with the speed of a bullet.
We flew down the track like the wind.
Every gaucho was, uh, uh...
Meanwhile, Burrito and I were,
uh, uh, jockeying for position.
¡Gauchito.!
They went that way.
That way.
No wonder they laughed.
I didn't even look like a jockey.
Hey, Gauchito.
Come on.
Look like a jockey.
Pepito, the pride of Mendoza,
was setting a furious pace...
and Fuego, Gordito and Pingo,
you never have seen such a race.
Now it's Pepito and Fuego.
It's Fuego and Pepito.
And there comes Gordito
on the rail.
Do your stuff, kid.
No?
Well, don't wait too long or...
Look out!
Ah-heh.
What did I tell you?
Come on, Gauchito.
The wings, the wings.
Quickly I untied the rope.
Come on, come on.
The knife! The knife!
¡Córtalo, córtalo.!
And now we go.
You should see little Burrito...
tearing up the track,
so fast you couldn't see us.
And now down the home stretch comes
Fuego. Now Pepito's ahead on the rail.
Here comes Pingo, Gordito and Gato,
and Dorado is right on his tail.
But where is Burrito?
Here comes Burrito!
We passed them
like they were standing still.
And now coming down across the line
of finish, it's Burrito, the winner!
Well, amigos, it was all over
but the shouting...
I thought.
Caramba.
The jig was up.
And what became
of the flying donkey, you ask?
Neither him nor me
was ever seen again...
as long as we lived.
Adios, amigo.
Adios. So long!
Good-bye!
What's going on here?
Presents! Oh, boy!
Let me at 'em!
Say, what's this?
Ah, Pato Donald.
Or, as you Americans say,
what's cookin'?
Joe Carioca!
Well, I'll be doggoned!
Imagine meeting me here.
Donald, have you ever been
to Baía? No?
- No, I haven't.
- Ah, Baía.
Land of romance...
moonlight, music,
beautiful girls.
Oh, forgive the interruption,
Donald.
This crazy bird is the aracuan.
He's meio maluco,
a very stupid fellow.
But tell me, Donald,
have you ever been to Baía?
- No, I haven't.
- No? Oh...
I am so sorry for you.
Ah, Baía.
It is like a song in my heart.
A song with love...
and beautiful memories.
I close my eyes,
and I can see it now.
I can see the beautiful twilight
in the sky.
I can feel the breeze
from the bay...
and I can hear the music,
the music of Baía.
When twilight is deep in the sky
Someone that I long to see
Keeps haunting my reverie
And so the loneliness
deep in my heart
Calls to you
I live in the memory of
Many dreams ago
When the stars were bright
And you were mine alone
My love for you cannot die
Though the oceans run dry
Or heaven falls from the sky
Now you're gone
Can't you hear my lonely call
Morena
Make my life complete again
How I pray for the day
When I'll see your smile
And my heart will beat again
When twilight is deep in the sky
Someone that I long to see
Keeps haunting my reverie
And so the loneliness
deep in my heart
Calls to you, calls to you
Ah, Baía.
Beautiful Baía.
Oh, forgive me, but have
you been to Baía, Donald?
- No.
- No? Well, let's go.
If you go to Baía, my friend...
you'll never return.
Have you been to Baía, Donald
- Uh-uh.
- Well, let's go
- They have vatapá
- What's that?
- They have caruru
- Is that so?
- They have munguzá
- Munguzá?
- Do you like to samba
- Oh, sure.
- Have you been to Baía, Donald
- No.
Well, let's go
When you go to Baía, my friend
You'll never return
Have you been to Baía?
- No.
- No? Well, let's go!
Hurry, Donald! Hurry!
Well, well. Here we are in Baía,
land of romance.
Baía? Where is Baía?
We are in Baía.
Look.
Well, I'll be doggoned.
- Who's that?
- Donald, that's Yayá.
- Who's Yayá?
- Ah, a baiana.
Donald, quindins de Yayá.
She sells cookies.
Cookies, my friend.
Donald!
- Hello.
- i Como vai!
Hi, toots.
What?
- Who is that guy?
- Oh, he's a malandro, Donald.
Oh, boy!
This Donald!
Did you ever see
such a fast worker?
No, no, Donald.
Take it easy.
Look.
Oh, boy, oh, boy,
oh, boy, oh, boy!
Come on, boys.
What do you feel about Baía, huh?
Tell me the truth.
Oh, swell! Marvelous!
Romance.
Moonlight.
Beautiful girls.
Or as you say, you are a wolf.
Take it easy.
You have more presents.
Presents?
Whee! Presents!
What? Oh! Oh!
Oh, I'm a midget!
Oh!
You, you're a midget too!
Oh-ho, Donald!
Don't worry.
It is simple, my friend.
Just a little black magic
will fix you up.
Believe it or not,
it is very simple!
You are very funny fellow!
Oh, my, my, my, my, my, my!
You kill my head!
- Huh?
- Oh, my friend...
you are using the wrong finger.
Now, blow!
- Thanks, pal!
- B-B-B-But, Donald, your presents!
My presents!
Aha, my friends!
Welcome to Mexico.
Son of a gun, it's a pleasure to see
such fine gentlemen in Mexico.
Here, amigos.
Donald!
José.
¡Caramba.!
Now we're three gay caballeros.
We're three caballeros
Three gay caballeros
They say we are
birds of a feather
We're happy amigos
No matter where he goes
The one, two and three goes
We're always together
We're three happy chappies
with snappy serapes
You'll find us
beneath our sombreros
We're brave and we'll stay so
We're bright as a peso
- Who says so?
- We say so
The Three Caballeros
We have the stars to guide us
Guitars here beside us
To play as we go
We sing and we samba
We shout, Ay, caramba
- What means "ay, caramba"?
- Oh, yes. I don't know.
Through fair or stormy weather
We stand close together
Like books on a shelf
And pals though we may be
When some Latin baby
says yes, no, or maybe
Each man is for himself
- What's this?
This is your gift from Mexico, Donald:
A piñata.
Oh, boy, oh, boy! A piñata!
What's a piñata?
A piñata is full
of surprises, presents.
It is the very spirit
of Christmas.
Christmas?
Jingle bells, jingle bells, jingle all...
No, no, Donald.
For goodness sake.
Not "Jingly Bells."
In Mexico, they sing
"Las Posadas."
This custom takes place on each
of the nine days before Christmas.
Each evening, the children
gather at the village church...
and form a procession symbolizing
the journey of Mary and Joseph...
from Nazareth to Bethlehem.
The little ones carry images
of the saints from house to house...
singing a plea for shelter,
or posada.
A reply comes from within:
"No posada. No shelter."
Looking sad and downhearted,
they try again...
but the reply is still the same.
"No shelter. No posada."
They repeat this song
time after time...
and always they are refused.
Until at last they reach
a friendly house and the door is opened.
"Come in, come in, holy pilgrims.
This humble home is yours."
And now, Mary and Joseph
have found shelter at last.
Then the rejoicing begins...
the feasting,
the celebrating...
and finally the biggest
surprise of all:
Breaking the piñata.
And now for your piñata, Donald.
Here you are.
Go to it.
One side, boys. One side.
I'm gonna smack it!
Uh-uh, no, hold it.
Ho-Hold it, Donald.
First you must be blindfolded.
We have to put this over your eyes.
That's part of the tradition.
Now, now, now, stand here.
Come here now.
Hit it hard.
All right, let's see you smack it.
Just a minute.
Uh-oh. Aha!
You see, Donald? Didn't I told you
it was full of surprises?
Did you know that the history
of Mexico is in her flag?
Oh, yes! You see, many hundreds
of years ago, the god of the Aztecs...
commanded them to build
a big city where they would find
an eagle destroying a serpent.
But when they find this eagle, he was
sitting on a cactus on top of a rock...
way out in the middle of a lake.
¡Caramba.! To build a city here
would be almost imposible.
But they built and built
and built some more...
until today, believe it or not,
the lake is full of Mexico City.
Sweet music
Gay serenatas
Tropic skies
Of velvet blue
Magic gardens
Perfume the breezes
Where true love
Brought me to you
Mexico
With all your romance
Your song oflove
Will live forever after
Mexico
Sweethearts are singing
Lovebirds are winging
Through a sky
filled with laughter
Paradise
That's where I found you
Your magic smile
Made the blossoms
bloom around you
Mexico
Why do I feel as I do
I simply fell
Under the spell
Of you
- ¡Oba.! ¡Oba.! Nice! Oh, boy!
- Wow!
Ah, but this is only the beginning,
amigos. Take a look at this one.
Oh, boy!
What a pretty picture!
And now, for a nice little
trip through Mexico...
on the magic serape.
- All aboard, amigos.
- Oh, what's goin' on here?
Paradise
That's where I found you
Your magic smile
Made the blossoms
bloom around you
Mexico
Why do I feel as I do
I simply fell
Under the spell
Of you
And this, Donald,
is Patzcuaro...
a fisherman's paradise.
Yeah! Beautiful!
Oh, boy! Would I like
to come back sometime...
and do a little fishing.
Uh-oh!
- What's going on here?
- Shh!
This is my favorite dance,
the "jarabe pateño."
Doggone it!
I can't get it.
No-no-no-no-no-no-no, boys!
You are off the beat.
This is the way.
Well, what do you know?
Thanks.
I had a wonderful time.
So long!
This is the way
they dance in Veracruz.
It's called the "lilongo."
Hi, girls!
May I cut in?
Watch your step, Donald!
Some fun, hey, kid?
So you like dancing, huh?
- Okay.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Go on, Donald.
Don't be afraid.
Not so fast, boys.
Go on in, Donald.
Don't be bashful.
Hi, toots!
Am I intruding?
Hey, Donald, you are
what they say, off the cob!
- You know, corny.
- Oh, yeah?
Swing me
with that boogie beat, Joe!
How am I doin', toots?
Come on, let me down.
- I wanna stay!
- Take it easy, Donald.
There she is...
Acapulco Beach...
the Riviera of Mexico.
Take the telescope and have a look at
what you might call the hot stuff.
Oh, boy! Am I going
to like this place.
Oh, boy! Hot stuff!
I'll be right down, toots.
- Hello, my sweet little
bathing beauties.
- Donald! Donald!
We're three caballeros
Three gay caballeros
They say we are
birds of a feather
Where's Donald?
Aha! I am a son of a gun. Look at
the little wolf in duck's clothings.
Come to Papa.
Wha-What's going on here?
Come here, you little rascals.
Now I've got ya. Uh-oh.
Doggone this confusion!
Oops! Where is she?
Come here, my little enchilada.
I've got you this time, tootsie.
Peek-a-boo.
I see you.
Hey, where am I?
My, my, my!
Ain't this fun?
Here I come!
This time I'm gonna get you!
Oh, no, no, no, Donald!
Don't do that!
Let me go. Get me outta here!
You can't do this to me.
Get your hands off of me!
This is a free country.
Bye-bye!
So you like pretty girls, huh?
Let's go!
- Let me go!
- Don't ruffle your feathers, Donald!
Look, I will show you
the nightlife of Mexico City.
- Beautiful, no?
- Colossal!
Oh, boy! Mexico City?
Very beautiful city.
Careful, Donald.
Even the sky is full of romantic!
You belong to my heart
- She's beautiful!
- Now and forever
- And our love had its start
- Oh, boy!
Not long ago
We were gathering stars
While a million guitars
played our love song
When I said "I love you"
every beat of my heart
- Oh, boy, oh, boy.
- Said it too
'Twas a moment like this
Do you remember
And your eyes threw a kiss
When they met mine
Now we own all the stars
And a million guitars
are still playing
Darling, you are the song
And you'll always belong
to my heart
'Twas a moment like this
- Do you remember
- Uh-huh.
And your eyes threw a kiss
- When they met mine
- Don't do that!
Now we own all the stars
And a million guitars
are still playing
Darling, you are the song
And you'll always belong
to my heart
You belong
To my heart
Now and forever
Three caballeros
Three gay caballeros
When I said "I love you"
Every beat of my heart
said it too
- Some fun, hey, kid?
Some fun, hey, kid?
We're three caballeros
Three gay caballeros
They say we are
birds of a feather
We're happy amigos
No matter where he goes
The one, two and three goes
We're always together
Darling, you are the song
And you'll always
belong to my heart
Pretty girls. Pretty girls.
What? Oh, boy!
Uh-oh.
Uh, what's happening, anyway?
Where am I?
Uh-oh!
My, my!
Uh-oh.
What?
Come on, torito,
give it to me!
What's the matter with you?
Are you color-blind?
Come on, bull. You bashful?
Oh, through fair or stormy weather
We're always together
So let come what may
Like brother to brother
we're all for each other
The Three Caballeros
Forever we'll
Stay