The Swan Princess
Once upon a time,
There was a King named William.
Who ruled a large
and mighty Kingdom,
and yet he was sad.
He was growing old and had no
child to inherit the thrown.
Then happily, a daughter was born,
a Princess.
And she was given the name Odette.
Kings and Queens came from all
around to offer the gifts to the child.
Among them was the widow Uberta
and her young son Prince Derek.
It was then that William and Uberta
had upon the same idea.
Derek and Odette will be
brought together each summer,
in hopes that they will fall in love,
And join their Kingdoms forever.
But unknown to all was another plan,
that of the evil enchanter Rothbart.
Odette birth was of little
concern to him,
for he was prepearing
to take William's Kingdom,
by means of the 'forbidden arts'.
On the eve of his assault,
William attacked
and Rothbart's power
was plunged into darkness.
Despite calls for his death,
the enchanter was only banished.
I'm not finnished with you yet, Willi.
Someday I'll get my power back,
and when I'll do,
everything you own,
everything you love,
will be mine!
Many feared King William too kind,
but in time, the threat was forgotten,
and all hopes turned to
that not so distant summer,
When Derek and Odette would meet.
Here they come.
Dear Uberta, and lovely as ever.
Oh, a nest.
Ah, and who is this terrific
young man be?
Young prince Derek, no doubt.
Welcome to our fair Kingdom dear
William, and to you, young Princess.
Go on, Derek!
Dear, go on!
-Mother! -Derek!
Hello Princess Odette,
I'm very pleased to meet you.
Pleased to meet you, Prince Derek.
Ha-ha-ha-haa.
Yach.
I can’t believe I’m stuck
with her all summer,
I’ll bet, she doesn’t wrestle,
hunt or box.
He looks conceited,
What a total bummer.
If I get lucky, I’ll get chicken pox.
So happy you could come.
So happy to be here.
How I’d like to run.
This is not my idea.
This isn’t my idea,
Of fun.
The children seem to get
along quite nicely.
We’ll join our lands if
this arrangement clicks.
My dear King William,
that’s my point precisely.
It’s such good parenting
And politics.
So happy we agree.
I think we’ve got a deal.
Derek’s quite a catch.
This is my idea.
This is my idea,
Of a match.
They such naughty.
Good heavens, child, don’t dawdle,
We can’t keep Derek waiting.
I haven't packed or washed my hair
And father I get seasick.
She soon will be arriving,
Is that respect you're showing?
To make me kiss her hand again,
I swear I'm gonna be sick.
One day Prince Derek will
be her intended.
Splendid!
We've tried all summer,
but we just can't lose her.
Hey fellas, wait up!
Quick, put on some speed.
When picking teams
Or friends,
I never choose her.
You'd think she'd take a hint?
a learn to read?
This really isn't fair.
We really couldn't care.
Boys, it's all or none.
This is not my idea.
This isn't my idea,
Of fun.
Long before they met,
Derek and Odette,
Were destined to be wedded.
However anyone could see,
The only point on which they
didn't disagree,
Was that the very thought
of summertime,
Was dreaded.
She tries to talk me
into playing dress-up,
She's always flirting
with the castle guards.
I think you really sorta
like her, 'fess up.
I'd like her better if she'd lose at cards,
-Four sevens and a ten.
I think I've won again.
Every time she's won.
This is my idea.
This isn't my idea,
Of fun.
We need a royal wedding.
I'd love to be invited.
At least we'd get a holiday,
to rest our ploughs and axes.
Someday these two will marry,
Two lands will be united,
And with some luck their marriage,
may result in lower taxes.
What if Odette doesn't go
for the merger?
Urge her!
For as long as I remember,
We've been told
we'd someday wed,
Every June until September.
All their pushing and
annoying hints.
I've got bruises with
their fingerprints.
I can do much better I am sure.
He's so immature.
I see him smiling
and my knees start buckling,
I see inside him
and my doubts are gone.
She started out as
such an ugly duckling,
And somehow suddenly
became a swan.
So happy to be here.
'Til now I never knew.
It is you I've been dreaming of.
This is my idea.
What a good idea, such
a charming and romantic notion.
This is my idea.
-This is my idea.
Such a good idea.
-Such a good idea.
What a good idea,
such a powerful and magic potion.
This is exactly my idea,
Of love.
This is my idea.
This is my idea,
Of love.
Arrange the marriage.
Wait!
What?
You are all, I ever wanted.
You're beautiful.
Thank you, but what else?
What else?
Is beauty all that matters to you?
Derek!
What else?
I... what else is there?
-Ahh.
We tried, Uberta.
No one can say, we didn't try.
Say goodbye, Odette.
Good bye. -Good byeeee?
-Prince Derek.
Mother!
-Derek!
Good bye, Princess.
All these years of planning,
Waisted!
"What else is there"?
She says
"Is beauty all that matters"?
And you say "what else is there"?
It was dumb, I know.
You should write a book,
How to offend women in
five syllables or less.
Your turn, Prince Derek.
I did not know what else to say.
You lost your Queen, Derek.
It's twice in one day.
Think! You must see something
other than Odette's beauty.
Ha, Of course I do Rogers.
She's like... you know...
How about... and then,
I mean right?
I don't know how to say it.
I'll prove it to her.
I'll prove my love.
Checkmate!
Today is the day, Willy!
Everything you own!
Everything you love!
Will be mine!
I... I just don't understand.
What else did you want him to say?
I need to know that he loves me.
For just being me.
Stay inside, Odette.
It's King's William Captain.
We...
We were attacked.
A great animal...
Odette?
Derek! Wait!
Odette!
Odette?
King William.
Derek.
Who did it?
It came so quickly...
A great... animal.
Where is Odette?
Listen to me, Derek.
It's not what it seems...
What's not?
Where is Odette?
Odette, is...
Odette, is... gone.
Odette!
Don't let my little
spell make you sad, Odette.
It does not even
last the whole day.
As soon as the moon comes up...
And that's how it works,
every night.
You have to be on
the lake of course,
and when the moonlight
touches your wings...
Look Odette.
This sort of thing does not
give me any pleasure.
Well, maybe a little bit...
But what I really want is...
is your father's Kingdom.
Take it than,
you have enough power.
Naaa, tried that already.
Once you steal something,
you spend your whole life
fighting to keep it.
But... If I marry you...
and to the throne...
We'll rule your father's Kingdom
together, legally.
King and Queen.
You know...
-Never!
Where are you going?
As soon as moonlight leaves the
lake, You turn back into the swan.
No matter where you are.
The musicians are not happy.
I know, but I have to practice.
No, no complains here.
I think, it's going to be lots of fun.
The Great animal's never going
to give up without a fight.
You are still thinking,
she is alive?
When I'll find the Great animal,
Rogers, I'll find Odette.
Oh, Derek,
You looked everywhere.
She is not coming back.
The whole Kingdom knows that.
The whole Kingdom is wrong
Odette's alive.
And I get to find her.
You ready, Brom?
-No peeking!
Animals! Assemble!
Lord Rogers, I must object.
We are musicians.
The servants have the day off.
We have to use someone.
But I am an artist, not a boar.
Could've fooled me.
Come on, guys.
They harmless.
We are a band,
And not a band of animals.
This masquerade,
Is more than I can bear.
There goes my reputation,
It's awful, this humiliation.
And I've the lion's share.
Down on all fours, please
and growl ferociously.
Liven it up a bit!
I want you to strike fear into my heart.
Not You, Wesley, you're a rabbit,
For heaven's sake.
Archers!  Ready!  Set! Go!
Duck!
Yes!
What?
Day after day all the prince ever does,
Is practice, practice, practice.
Thinking of her
and the way that it was.
Practice, practice, practice.
He's not happy, 'til he has attacked us.
Twelve seconds.
Day after day all the prince ever does.
Is practice, practice, practice.
Thinking of her
and the way that it was.
Practice, practice, practice.
If we refused he would have
sacked us. -Five seconds.
So we face a life of target.
Three, Two.
Practice, practice, practice.
Time's up!
Animals, assemble for counting.
Ha-ha, very good, very good.
Your scored, thank you, five pointers.
That's for sure.
Sorry Hans, why don't
you take few days off.
Moose are worth 2 points.
Sixteen Hits a total of 32.
Ten 7 points.
And... Fourteen 3 Points.
A total of 298.
Well done! Derek.
Now, Bromley, let's see if you...
Hmm... zero and zero and
a nothing and nil and zip.
And last but not least,
the elusive one hundred points.
White rabbit.
I belive that's
three hundreds Rogers.
Good shooting Brom.
Well what it tell?
300 into 298.
Oh, but a wait just
a moment Rogers.
Sorry Brom.
Ha-ha-ha-hmm.
You are a great archer,
one of the best.
But it's gets more
than good aim,
in types courage,
thats why they for there.
Well, then how about quick
round of catch and fire.
Ca-Ca-Ca-Catch and fire.
You mean me.
You are the only one with enough,
Co-Co-Co-Courage.
Whoooo ho.
Are you sure you are alright?
Hmm quiet I'm I'm fine.
Ho-hooo. Too tied, too tied.
Whoops, so sorry...
Ready? -He is ready.
Remember now, aim to the heart.
Right between the shoulders.
Oh please, so please.
Come on, Brom, hold it steady.
Oh please, oh please, oh please.
Now!
Fifty two out of fifty two.
Well done, Derek.
Extraordinary couragement,
Just think, one inch lower.
And that arrow would have...
Don't loose hope, Odette,
Wherever you are,
I'm going to find you.
Quiet, I can not concentrate.
You've come up with
some dumb ideas Jean Bob.
But this one is a dozy.
Go ahead and laugh.
I'll get her to kiss me
and when she does...
And when she does...
poof, you'll change into a prince.
I know, I know, you've told me.
Why don't you just give her
these flowers?
These are pretty.
Ahh, what a love dance,
I don't want these flowers,
I must of those.
When she learns that I have
risked my life for them,
then her kissing will not stop.
And then you'll change into a prince.
Precisely.
Mind if I point up a problem.
I don't take advise from peasants.
Suit yourself.
Flower, Kiss, concentration.
Just curious,
how you gonna get back?
Hurry! Hurry!
Move up! Move up!
Faster! Claude.
Grab me, grab me.
Hold my arm, hold my leg.
Hold my...
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
Oh, thank you Odette.
Thank you, let me have that.
Silence! you savages.
Oh, Are you alright Jean Bob?
Jean Bob?
Oui, Oui.
Oui, Odette, yes, I am alright.
What the whole world,
do you tring to do.
He thought that if...
-shosh...
I wanted to get those flowers for you.
You are being sneaky
again, Jean Bob!
What sneaky?
You deserve it, not? OK?
And you deserve a kiss?
Well, alright.
You know that, I am under a spell.
But my kiss will break the spell.
Give it up Jean Bob.
I can only kiss the man I love
And then he...
Must make a vow of
everlasting love I know.
And prove it to the world.
What do you think,
I was doing with the flowers,
in the alligators going jam jam?
Speed, make him understand.
I am only a turtle.
If I could break this spell,
I'd run to him today.
And somehow I know
he's on his way to me.
Derek, you and I were meant to be.
Far longer than forever.
I'll hold you in my heart.
It's almost like you're here with me.
Although we're far apart.
Far longer than forever.
As constant as a star.
I close my eyes and
I am where you are.
Sure as the dawn brings the sunrise.
We've an unshakable bond.
Destined to last for
a lifetime and beyond.
Far longer than forever.
-Far longer than forever.
I swear that I'll be true.
-I swear that I'll be true.
I've made an everlasting vow.
To find a way to you.
Far longer than forever.
Like no love every known.
And with your love
I'll never be alone.
Far longer than forever.
Much stronger than forever.
And with your love
I'll never be alone.
You think, he is dead?
No, it just his wing, I think.
Strange looking bird.
Uhhhh...
Uh my, fellow, you must
be in a lot of pain.
You better hold him.
Uh...
-Ready.
Uhhhh... hhha.
Hello!
This is your wake up time.
It takes more than a pair of
dumb fools to keep Puffin down.
Wait! Wait!
I-I am your friend.
If you are my friend, how come
you have an arrow in you hand?
Haa? Haa? Yes!
The exact arrow I have?
Hmm... Haaa.
I took it out when you
were laying there.
You mean, you had a chance to...
kill... but still you free...
Ahaa.
Madam, I apologise.
My name is Puffin.
Lieutenant Puffin.
It's a pleasure, Lieutenant Puffin.
I'm Odette,
Princess Odette.
And these are my best friends
in the whole world.
Mr. Lorenzo Trudge-Along.
Friends call me speed.
-And Jean Bob.
I have no friends,
only servants
and zey call me, "Your Highness".
He thinks, he is a Prince.
I owe you, princess,
And I intend on staying
until we get his paid.
I don't think there is much you can do.
He has my under a spell.
What! You mean a magical who...
who-ho-ho-ho.
Your Knight in shining armor,
has come to set you free!
Let me ask him,
let me ask him...
Enough... enough.
All it takes is just one little word.
Will you... marry me?
Every night you ask
the same question.
No! No!
And every night I give
you the same answer.
Don't!
I'll die first.
Really start to bug me.
I think, you be used
to it by now.
Thats it!
Yours kept push it!
But some day I'm gonna boil over!
Go head then!
But I'll never give you
my fathers Kingdom!
I knew it.
I was hoping,
you would say "You'll be mine".
Well, it looks as
if you need another day.
Just think about it.
No!
Princess!
Beautiful! Simply beautiful!
Soon Derek will be married,
And the Kingdom will
have a King again.
I doubt it.
Derek still refuses to be King,
Unless he finds Odette.
Oh... puppy pup, All that will
change at tomorrow nights ball.
They all coming to the ball.
Every princess is coming.
Oh my... Oh good... Oh my...
this is wonderful.
You see, Rogers?
One of these is bound
to change his mind.
Oh! Absolutely... Not!
Do not loosed one!
Oh no, no, no, no.
Where is Derek? Oh, never mind,
I know where he is.
Working on the mystery
of the fat animal.
The great animal, Your Highness.
Oh, make great it's much better.
Listen, Derek, its not what it seems.
What did King William mean?
It's not what it seems.
Of course.
Now I'll find you, Odette.
They are comming, Derek.
Oh, where Odette?
Where are you going?
To find the great animal.
Oh! wonderful.
Just make sure,
you are here tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night?
The ball...
Mother, I... I can't.
Please mother,
don't do the lip thing.
If I leave now,
May be, I can be back in time.
Oh, Thank you darling.
Please mother, don't turn it
into one of your beauty pageants.
Hooo... no no no no no,
It just a few friends
And their daughters.
I want this to be big.
Every princess that
ever own production.
But You said...
Forget what I said.
Now, send for the cooks
And tell the band
to start rehearsing
And I want four footmen
for every carriage.
Make it five.
Let me get this straight.
You mean...
Every night when the
moonlight leaves the lake,
You...
Right.
The following night,
if I wanted turn back into a human,
I have to be on the lake.
What she needs
is a little moon light.
Me, I after be smooched.
No fear!
You fly to your prince.
We bring him back to the lake.
The moon comes up.
You change into a princess.
And... happily ever after.
How am I find him?
You don't know where he is?
I even don't know where I am.
I bet, he does.
Oh, such a great idea.
Just say "Monsieur Rothbart",
I'd like to leave now,
you have a map or something.
That's it!
A map!
Let's do it!
We’re off on a mission.
We’re tough, in good condition.
We're short.
But standing tall.
No fear!
There's danger around us.
They'd hurt us if they found us.
Our backs are to the wall.
No fear!
‘Cause we have all
the courage we require.
Take it from a frequent flyer.
Try your luck.
Our plan will fly.
No fear!
It's hanging on the wall.
In the upper chamber.
Odette will keep looking after him,
While we get the map.
We?
Would you not go to help us?
Oui.
This plan if applied’ll.
Be simply suicidal.
You’ll be a sitting duck.
No fear!
Suppose that I do this.
Who knows if
we’ll live through this?
How ‘bout a kiss for luck?
No,
-Fear!
Our team is shy one green,
web-footed volunteer.
No way, Jose.
No chance!
No choice.
No fear!
No! stop it! stop it! No!
Alright! Quickly!
Easy for you to say.
Ahooch...
Why ever I have to do something?
Quick!
I always bring a turtle.
I think I pull a muscle.
I'm gonna die!
Out of it, I am going a dangerous
mission with a labor turtle!
You're gonna get us, all kill.
Be careful.
We will take any dare that the
other side’ll dare to dream up.
We’ll fight tough we’ll play fair.
But we’re sure to win
because we’ll team up.
Yaahics...
Hit for the door.
Alright! Jean bob go speed,
Speed gets the hands off.
Ready!
-Ready.
Set!
I'm open, I'm open.
What?
Catch that map.
Saved you.
Reach.
Hey! better better bet.
All The crowd...
No fear!
She’s gaining!
She’s faster!
We’re heading for disaster!
Our hero, warts and all!
No fear!
I would be fine if
one of us knew how to steer!
Get a grip!
Get set.
That’s our respect!
No breaks!
No sweat.
And no regrets!
We’re dead!
Not yet.
Oh no, not there!
Save me.
No fear!
There is Derek's Kingdom.
When do we leave?
It's a mouse.
A great animal.
That's small one, I'd say.
Yeah, Until it changes into this...
An animal that can change it's shape.
A harmless creature approaches.
Then, suddenly it's too late.
You mean, you mean it
could be anything?
Anything.
Odette, I appologise for
the way I have been acting.
It's alright Jean Bob.
No, no, this Derek is
very important to you.
And all I can do, is think of myself.
Every one does that.
Please, Odette, don't make it
more difficult, than it all ready is.
Accept my appology, please.
OK, I accept.
Good, now we can kiss and make up.
Jean Bob!
What did I say, what? What?
The thing...
It is "zero hour", troops.
Odette, prepare for take off.
Right.
The rest,
do you have your assignments?
Is everyone ready?
Ready for action, sir.
How about you, Jean Bob?
Jean Bob!
... Highness.
Oui, I am... ready.
Take off!
Good luck.
Have a nice flight.
Remember!
If anything happens to her,
I'll have you
whipped, flogged, put on ze rack
and your back legs
fried in butter.
He is in here, Brom.
I can feel it.
Oh, You know the great animal,
when you see it...
Oh, no.
Better stay close.
If you say so.
Derek... Derek!
Where are you?
Shh... shh...
Oh, sorry.
Derek?
Derek!
We'll better keep an eye for hunters.
Ease Odette,
I can smell a human, a mile away.
Would a duck.
Derek!
He is here!
What the... You will not lose control!
You will follow the plan.
Its our line.
Acknowledge, acknowle...
Odette!
Odette?
No! I've got you now! Oh-Oh, Oh-Oh.
Don't give with that innocent look.
Oh-Oh, charge!
Go a head, charge!
No, I am not afraid of you!
Twit! Nooooo...
Ahh, Derek!
A Swan?
A Swan!
Of course!
It's not what it seems.
Just a little closer.
Come on!
Derek...
This one is for Odette!
Uhh, look out!
Uhh, Uhh, Uhh, that was close.
Ha Ha, It's working,
here he comes.
Hey, slow down,
you're going to lose him.
Slowww dowww.
He is too close.
-Too close?
He can't even see us
any more. let's...
Stay up now.
Ho, your boy know how to move.
-I told you.
He is faster than you thought.
Don't worry, Odette.
I even thought, just what
to do in this situation.
Well?
-When... -Puffin!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
When you're too isolated.
Fly into the sun and use
it's light. Follow me.
Ha ha! Well, what did
I tell you Odette?
Yes, now you see! all we have
to do is just stay in. So?
Ha, Alright!
Don't panic! Don't panic!
Puffin! -Odette, hurry.
-Into the trees!
You'll better think
of something quick.
Or else, we're "The Ducks".
How about, shooting the
number that poison, said?
When there's no escape.
You have to play dead.
It give you the right touch.
Wait till I get, give up. Ha.
That will put some
distance between us.
No sign of them yet.
I hope that Pigeon, Puffin,
knows what he is doing.
Incoming.
Ha, ha, there they are.
It's almost time, Odette. Look!
I... I cant do it.
-But you have to.
He'll kill me, Puffin!
You don't do it now, Odette,
You've lost your chance for life.
Alright.
I'll do it.
-Go!
What?
Alright! Come on! Come on!
Got you!
Hello Derek.
Derek, I missed you so.
No one believed me.
But I knew...
-You can't stay.
Can't stay?
No, I'll never let you
out of my sight again.
Listen to me, Derek.
Odette!
-Oh, no!
Who is it? What's going on?
It's him! -Who?
He has me under a spell.
Who does?
Odette!
Let him come! I'm...
No! He has great power.
You must go!
You are coming with me.
I can't.
When the moon sets,
I turn back into a swan.
Please Derek,
you have to trust me.
Go!
There must be someway
to break the spell.
Oh, there is.
You must make a vow
of everlasting love.
I'll make it.
It's all I ever wanted.
You must prove it to the world.
How? How?
I don't know...
-Odette!
Go!
The ball! Tomorrow night.
Come to the castle.
Before the whole world,
I will make a vow.
Of everlasting love.
Odette!
I'm coming.
Go!
-Tomorrow night.
Yes, tomorrow night.
Go.
Odette!
Didn't you hear me calling?
I... I... I...
I thought, I heared voices?
Odette, Odette.
Voices?
-Yes. Voices!
Well, I...
-You what?
I decided to become your Queen.
No! You mean...
Oh! Odette...
Odette, you make me so happy
I'll be a good King. You'll see.
I'll wear nice clothes
and I'm going to clip my beard.
Shit, Oh... you...
you made me so happy.
Oh, by the way!
You would't happen to know,
what's this belongs to?
Would you?
"Come to the ball, I will make a vow".
"An everlasting love"!
Thought, you could fool Rothbart?
Did you?
I will never be yours!
You creature!
I will marry Prince Derek,
and you can not stop me!
I hate to tell you this, Odette.
But you wan't be able to attend
the big ball tomorrow night.
If you want to stop me,
you'll have to kill me!
No! I don't think so.
You see, you forgot one
very important thing.
Tomorrow night... there is no moon.
No matter what they do,
I always one step ahead.
On the other hand, Prince Derek's
vow could ruin everything.
I'll gonna have to deal with him.
But how?
I am going to turn his
vow to the wrong princess.
That's it.
I'll make you look like Odette.
That's gonna take a lot of work.
But it will be worth it.
Because when he makes his
vow to the wrong girl,
Odette will die!
And I'll finish Derek off myself.
Oh, I love it.
I mean, this is really classic.
This is me!
Gosh, it's such a hoot
to see them quaking.
When I'm King they'll
treat me with respect.
I can't wait to watch
their poor hearts breaking.
So much for politically correct.
Up 'til now I've pulled my punches.
I intend to eat their lunches.
No more Mr. Nice Guy, not for me.
If you think that I'm hard-hearted.
Well, let me by,
I haven't even started.
No more Mr. Nice Guy, no siree.
Soon as my witchcraft
has zinged them.
I'll gain control of the Kingdom.
As for Odette, well that's tragic.
'Cause I'm going back
to that old black magic.
Good behaviour is so much duller.
Time to show my one true colour.
Baby, Mr. Nice Guy's history.
Vengeance is what I believe in.
I don't get mad, I get even.
Odette can't get to the ball
'cause I won't bring her.
So I'll zap up a date
who's a real dead ringer.
Up to no good, I love plottin'.
'Cause I'm so good when I'm rotten.
No more Mr. Nice Guy,
wait and see. -wait and see.
I'll become that nasty,
naughty, very spiteful.
Wicked, wayward, way delightful.
Bad guy I was born to be.
One more time.
Lying, loathsame, never tender.
Indiscreet repeat offender.
No more Mr. Nice Guy, that's not me.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Mother, have you seen...
Hello Derek.
What are these?
-Roses.
Red.
-Of course they're red.
But maam...I don't want red roses.
I want white, like a swan.
You seen Bromley? -No.
Has anyone seen Bromley?
Woul'd you feed this to a swan?
I...
Take it back.
Something light.
Something fresh.
No no no no no, Rogers, hold it.
Whats wrong?
Tonight the music must
be played... Rubato.
Soft and graceful...
like a swan.
A swan?
-You ever seen a swan, Rogers?
Of course I seen a swan!
If you could play a swan,
what would it sound like?
Soft and graceful, Rogers.
Where is Bromley?
No one has seen him, Derek.
You kidding. Who is
gonna be my best man?
Best... You mean... You...
Oh Derek, Ohhh Derek.
There you go Rogers,
thats the style.
Came on, Mother.
Oh, don't be so secretive, Derek.
Tell me, who she is?
It hurts me to lock
you up, Odette.
Hurts me... deep.
But then, a King this day
is full of tough decisions.
You understand?
Oh, now you mad at me
again, damn. Got it!
I can't do nothing right.
Head full of put on. Thats me.
Well, I can't leave you like this.
If you not happy,
I'm not happy.
I know. If you can't
attend the ball,
than I'll bring the ball to you.
Let see. The first thing,
you need is, a young man.
The Prince is busy of course, but...
I think, I can arrange
a substitution.
No, please,
I beg you, please.
Ohh, Poor fellow.
He got lost in the woods.
Oh, help... help!
Don't go.
I love to stay but if I don't leave
now, I'll be late. That's that.
Don't give me that look, you see.
Had to be sneaky.
Didn't you.
Had to drag your weakling
Prince into. Didn't you.
It's fine with me.
Just fine with me!
Every single princess
on the planet.
Prayed to be invited to the ball.
Every Portia, Guinevere and Janet.
Would come by coach
or boat to be here.
Most would swim the
moat to be here.
Just to be at this
historic gala.
Girls would walk around
or even crawl.
Rumour is that at this
joyous scene tonight.
The prince will likely choose
his future Queen tonight.
Excuse me.
Oh, excuse me.
Excuse me, Your Highness.
Yes, yes, Chamberlain.
Its getting rather crowded.
Very well, you may begin
the introductions.
And Chamberlain...
-Yes...
No mistakes this time.
Every thing must be perfect.
Oh, oh no no, oh yes,
I mean, oh no no, Madam.
Everything will be perfect.
Promise me, Derek, you'll tell me
who it is the moment she arrives.
Don't worry, mother.
You'll know. Believe me.
You'll know.
Ah! -What?
-It comes.
What is...
-An idea!
A substantial idea.
A large colossal idea.
Sounds big.
-I've got it.
Water leaks into the dungeon.
Right?
Well, if there's a leak,
there must be a hole.
We'll find the hole, make it
bigger, and... she is loose.
I think, you forgetting two things.
His majesty has got a point.
Not to worry!
Now, first we need a scout.
Are you crazy?
Who's going to jump into this moat?
He's got to be a good swimmer.
I should say so.
He's got to be small too.
Tinny winny. Not to be seen.
And it wouldn't hurt if he was
green for camouflage purposes.
Precisely.
Small, good swimmer, Green.
Good grief, you talking about me?
You’re off on a mission.
-Not, definetly not!
You’re tough, in good condition.
-I can't hear you.
Our hero, warts and all!
No fear!
-I can't hear you.
Thank you, oh thank you, now...
I know that some of you
jest at all beauty pageants.
But I have been a past past
girl myself win back in 39.
I just couldn't resist, girls,
and one, a two, a one two three.
Beauty and glamour
and breeding unmatched.
Princess is on parade.
Lovely, enthralling
and all unattached.
The hoi polloi and
those well-bred agree.
Each enjoy a royal pedigree.
Born for success,
each possesses a spark.
Each a remarkable maid.
Boy, oh boy,
these royal highnesses.
Those all have pluses,
they've no minuses.
Gaze upon.
Princess is on parade.
This princess
comes from Caulchester.
Where corn and cotton grows.
She plays crockey
and art supports
and sews her own clothes.
Antonia isn't known to take
the part of least resistance.
She held from southeast Pakistan
and came the farther distance.
Grizelle lives to help the world.
She finds no task to anyone.
and all the other hopeful girls,
think she is the most con genuine.
Brunhelda is from Shtutgart
where swords and armour maid.
Gaze upon.
Princess is on parade.
This is the likely occasion,
When the heir to
the throne picks a wife.
This is may be the day
when Prince Derek will say.
“Where have you been all my life?"
Brilliant, beguiling,
the smiling brigade.
Princess is on parade.
Each the pride of her community.
Each a golden opportunity.
Just the thought
that crown Prince Derek'll.
Face his choice and he's hysterical.
Gaze upon.
Heap praise upon.
he is bigger, glamorous,
luminous, dazzling.
Princess is on Parade.
Chamberline.
Oh, who are invited
are present? are they not?
Well, yes, I mean... well...
Open the door!
Chamberlain.
Possibly it can't, my list...
This the milkman...
it must be the milkman.
Well, it's not the milkman.
Oh, oh no, it can't be...
Excusse me, pardon me, please,
please, I've got to get through here.
Oh,oh yes, she is lovely.
Isn't? hmm...
Queen coming through here,
excuse me, excuse me.
Rogers, Rogers! Who is it?
Do you know her?
I don't know.
Come on, Rogers, I know he
confides in you, who is it?
I promise,
I've never seen her before.
Although she does look
a great deal, like...
It couldn't be...
Could it?
Oh, I was so worried.
I almost thought.
Nothing keep me away.
OK. Speed will draw
the alligators away.
Then you'll get wind and start
and pick up... for that hole.
If I can find it and if the
alligators don't chew me.
Before I get there.
They can't worry.
Speed will rush to help.
Ah, Yes Mister!
Oh, lassies will rush to help.
That's the plan.
Suddenly I'm full of comfort.
Than alright. Stretch out.
How do I get myself
talk into this?
Oh, it's alright, use your mark.
Hey, you all leather hands.
Come and get me.
Come on Bug eyes.
Ah ah, perfect, perfect, Right.
Ready! Get set! Go!
Faster! Faster!
Sure, go on Jean Bob,
right to your death.
Get moving, slowpoke!
Slowpoke?
Na na, na na, na na, na na.
Any luck?
Jean Bob?
To the rescue, Mademoiselle.
There's the signal.
Alright, Puffin. Time
to brush up on a diving technic.
You ho!
Those turtles are tough eaten.
How about a good white meat?
Good for the heart.
We broke through!
Let's go!
Thank you Jean Bob.
Oh, and when this is over,
remind me to give you a kiss.
What? What is it?
Stay away! What are you doing?
No! No! Go away!
I'll tell you when.
Let's go!
Friends call me speed.
Go Odette! Go!
Something about you, seems...
I don't know... different.
Don't worry, after tonight
everything will be perfect.
Yes, yes of course.
Rogers, I want to make
an announcement.
Stop the music!
Kings and Queens,
ladies and gentelmen, mother.
I have an announcement to make.
Today I have found my bride.
No Derek! No! It is a trick!
Presenting to you as the
future Queen of our Kingdom.
And as proof of my love for her,
I make a vow to break all vows.
A vow stronger than all
the powers of the earth.
Before you and before
the whole world,
I make a vow of
everlasting love.
Derek!
To Odette.
Noooooo!
No more Mr. Nice Guy, no siree.
Hello little Prince.
Who are you?
Went and pledged your
love to another?
What are you talking about?
This is Odette!
No! Odette is mine!
It's you!
You have no power here!
I made a vow!
A vow of everlasting love!
You made a vow alright!
A vow of everlasting death!
No! Odette!
You should have left her to me.
Now, Odette will die.
Odette!
Odette.
She's fading fast, little prince.
-No!
Gosh, something goes wrong.
If you hurry, little Prince,
I'll let you see her one
last time! -Go!
There she is.
I don't think she's
gonna make it.
Ease fly, Odette. Ok, good girl.
Come on now.
Odette.
Oh, what have I done to you.
Forgive me Odette, forgive me.
Derek...
-Yes Odette...
I'm here
-Derek, I feel so weak.
I think, I am...
No! You'll live Odette!
The vow I made was for you!
I know. I love you Derek.
Odette, Odette, Odette!
I made The vow for her!
Do you hear?
The vow I made was for her!
No need to shout.
Don't let her die!
Is that a threat?
Don't you dare let her die!
Oh, it is a threat.
You're the only one with
the power! Now do it!
Only if you defeat... me!
The great animal!
I bet on the animal.
Noooooo!
I won't let her die!
The bow, Derek's bow!
Swim to the bottom of the lake
and get the bow.
Throw it, out! Throw it!
Throw it! Yeah...
Wake up, wake up, hallo
Good luck.
Oh, please... -Brom.
-Oh please, oh please, Nooo...
Forgive me Odette.
Forgive me.
I only wanted to break the spell.
To prove my love.
I love you. You're kindness and
courage, I always have.
Derek?
-Odette?
Oh, Derek!
Well, there you have it,
everlasting love.
Well, Rogers, old man.
I suppose you owe
me an appology.
After all, if it
weren't for me.
The great animal would
still be live.
No... -what?
-Great animal -Nooo...
It's alive!
Uberta.
-Rogers.
I don't care if every one
else don't have a day off.
The prince wants
a fighting air-force.
And it's my job to get
you, birds in shape.
You are in Puffin's army now.
General Puffin!
I am ready for my kiss,
Mademoiselle.
Don't be too disappointed
Jean Bob,
if nothing happens.
Finaly, after all these years.
I shall return to my throne.
Don't forget to write.
You still don't believe me,
do you?
The only thing you're
going to turn is red.
Well, I am ready. Odette.
Walla, well Speed, what do
you have to say now?
Uh... -That's what I thought.
And now, if you don't mind,
I've got some shmuzzing to do.
Would you like a kiss too, Speed?
Naaa... I am happy as a turtle.
Bonjour Madame.
Ehh... Uh-uh,
the ladies still fall for me.
Will you love me Derek,
Till the day I die?
No, much longer than that, Odette.
Much longer.
Subtitle: Moti K.
Oren K.
Far longer than forever.
I'll hold you in my heart.
It's almost like
you're here with me.
Although we're far apart.
Far longer than forever.
As constant as a star.
I close my eyes and
I am where where you are.
Sure as the dawn brings the sunrise.
We've an unshakable bond.
Destined to last
for a lifetime and beyond.
Far longer than forever.
-Far longer than forever.
Like no love every known
And with your love
I'll never be alone.
Far longer than forever.
-Far longer than forever.
Like no love every known
And with your love
I'll never be alone.
Far longer than forever.
Much stronger than forever.
And with your love
I'll never be alone.
Never, never be alone.
Far longer than forever.
I knew that we belonged together.
Long before I knew your name
And the only thing I longed for.
Was a sign to prove
you felt the same.
Somehow I knew your every secret.
Just by looking in your eyes.
From the very moment I met you,
I was thinking of
the rest of our lives.
Just say to me.
I'm gonna love you
'til the end of the time.
Somehow two hearts,
have made a friend of time.
Eternity, eternity is on our side.
I'm not afraid to say forever.
You have made me feel so sure.
'Cause I know it's everlasting
And I've never had
this feeling before,
Keep telling me,
I'm gonna love you
'til the end of time.
Somehow two hearts
have made a friend of time.
Eternity, I'll love you for eternity.
Caught in the tide
And it brought me to you,
Under a spell
And now I know
that dreams come true.
I'm gonna love you
'til the end of time.
Somehow two hearts
have made a friend of time.
Eternity, eternity, is on our side.
I'm gonna love you
'til the end of time.
Somehow two hearts
have made a friend of time.
Eternity, eternity, is on our side.
-is on our side.
I'm gonna love you 'til the end
of time. -'til the end of time.
Somehow two hearts
have made a friend of time.
Eternity, eternity, is on our side.
Eternity, I'll love you for eternity.
Subtitle by Snitch Company®