Good morning,
Little Red Riding Hood.
Good morning.
How do you do?
Good morning,
Miss Riding Hood.
Where are you going,
Red Riding Hood?
What's in the basket?
Something good?
I'm bringing Grandma
cakes and wine.
She's awful, awful sick.
I'm in a great big hurry, too.
I gotta get there quick.
You'll get there quick,
red Riding Hood...
if you take the shortcut
through the wood.
There's danger in them woods.
Beware!
The Big Bad Wolf
is lurking there.
Better to be safe than sorry.
Shortcuts are not always good.
Take the long road
'round the forest...
while the wolf
is in the wood.
That old wolf
is just a sissy.
All he does is huff...
and puff.
We'll go with you
and protect you.
Come along,
we'll call his bluff.
Who's afraid
of the Big Bad Wolf
Big Bad Wolf,
Big Bad Wolf?
Who's afraid
of the Big Bad Wolf
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Heh heh heh heh heh.
I'll get 'em.
I'm Goldilocks,
the fairy queen
Spirit of the woods am I
Whoops!
You'll flit and fly
from tree to tree
Come, come, my dears,
you're safe with me
Whoops!
Ooh!
Aah!
Ehh heh heh heh heh!
Unh! Unh! Unh!
Curses!
Ha ha ha ha!
Come in!
Rah ha ha ha!
Aah!
Come in.
Good morning, Grandma.
How do you feel today?
Terrible.
Uh, ahem...
Not so hot, dearie.
Ooh, Grandma.
What big eyes you've got.
All the better
to look you over, dearie.
Ooh, Grandma.
What a big nose you've got.
All the better to--
Ha cha cha cha cha.
How am I doin'?
Ooh, Grandma.
What a big mouth you've got.
ou ain't seen
the half of it, dearie.
Ha ha ha ha!
-Rowrrr!
-Aah!
Aah!
The wolf!
He's got her!
Aah!
Uhh!
Open the door
and let me in!
A-whoo!
Ow! Whoo!
Whoo!
Who's afraid
of the Big Bad Wolf
Big Bad Wolf,
Big Bad Wolf?
Who's afraid
of the Big Bad Wolf?
He's a great big sissy