[Music]
Fay: I didn't come to
town To visit your aquarium
I think a fish's place
Is in the sea
I've heard you've got
A simply lovely planetarium
But looking at the stars
Is not for me
Now, don't drag me
Through your museum
A picture postcard will do
Don't give me souvenirs
I got no room to carry 'em
The only souvenir I want is you
I'm just a stranger in town
And I've come down
For real hospitality
Well, all right, then, baby, tonight
Be good to a stranger in town
I'm here to melt or to freeze
In times like these
Let's skip the formality
Baby, please
Be good to a stranger in town
Boy, is she sizzling tonight.
That don't help nobody.
I bet you the notice goes up
come Saturday.
Boy, you can smell this flop
clear to Times Square.
Yeah, and in this theatre, too, where
Ferris and Lawrence had all their smashes.
Just help yourself
It is yours
I'm just a stranger today
But that's okay
A mere technicality
Well, all right, tonight is tonight
And, baby,
You're breaking me down
So be good to a stranger in town
How's business tonight,
Mr Ferris? Terrible.
I've been with you for more than ten
years, ever since you left Ziegfeld.
I was with you that night in Minneapolis
when you saw Miss Lawrence for the first time
at the old Orpheum.
Remember?
You picked a fine time
to reminisce, Frank.
I just wanted to say,
Mr Ferris,
take advice of an old friend
and close Saturday.
Not on your life.
Tony Ferris may go down,
but not without a fight.
Tell Mr Ferris I want to see him
in my dressing room.
Oui, madame.
Monsieur Ferris.
Yes?
Miss Lawrence wants to see you
in her dressing room.
All right.
Hold the fort.
You sent for me, honey?
I won't need you, Babette.
You want to talk to me, Fay?
I don't, but it's necessary.
Get that chair and sit down.
I want to talk
about Indiscretions,
and I don't mean my own.
Well, go right ahead. I can always listen
to you with the greatest of pleasure.
But you didn't listen when
I warned you about this show.
Can't you see the way it's going,
it's no use?
Why, if I stay with the show,
I'll lose my reputation.
Well, I've been working on
some new promotion angles.
Fay, I can make another
Show Boat out of this.
Why, the idea's
cooking now.
Yeah, I bet it'll
be half-baked.
Well, I'm giving you
my two weeks' notice.
Fay, you can't
do that to me.
Don't tell me you've lost faith in me
after all the hits we've done together.
Yeah, five hits and one error.
Oh, we can fix
the show up.
It's easier to get a new one.
Just a moment. Before you think of leaving
me, you'd better read your contract.
I did, and it made very light reading
in bed last night.
There's a certain little clause about a minimum
weekly gross that lets me out very nicely.
What would you do without me?
Much better.
Wait a minute. There's something
behind all this. What is it?
Simply that I have a tradition
of success to live up to.
Now, Forrest Stanton...
Stanton! Don't tell me
that guy's been after you.
"After" is not the word.
The gentleman approached me
about starring in his Tropicana.
That's fine, that's fine.
You talk to another producer
while I'm still paying you.
[KNOCKING]
Hey, boss.
Come here,
I gotta talk to you.
Hey, boss, we're in trouble.
You trying to be funny?
No, there's a guy upstairs wants to
see you from the Bainbridge Foundation.
Bainbridge Foundation?
Yeah, you know, one of
them clean-up deformers.
Tony:
Send that long-hair in.
Yeah, but this guy
ain't got no hair.
Send him in anyway.
Okay.
Okay, bub.
Good evening, Mr Ferris.
All right, all right.
What's the beef?
Beef?
Well, the last I bought
was 60 cents.
That was hamburger.
Say, I'm in no mood for joking.
What do you want?
Mr Ferris, I have just seen
your show and in my opinion...
That's a lie.
Indiscretions is clean, wholesome
entertainment for the entire family,
and if your organisation
thinks for one moment...
Please, Mr Ferris,
you don't understand.
I liked your show.
What?
Miss Lawrence is the prettiest girl
I've seen since Lillian Russell,
and those indiscrete ladies...
I know all those adjectives.
What do you people want from me?
Well, I'm not representing
the foundation.
I'm only a supply clerk
there, anyway.
I came to ask you to do
something for me, personally.
Oh, now comes the bite.
What do you want?
Well, I have a niece...
I have ulcers.
And compared to my other
troubles, my ulcers are a pleasure.
Well, I'm sorry
about your ulcers,
but my niece, Janey, is
the sweetest, the prettiest,
the most wonderful girl
that you'd ever hope to see.
I hope I never
have to see her.
But she sings
like a meadowlark.
She belongs
in the theatre.
We all have it
in our blood.
Why, years ago,
when I was younger,
I used to sing and
give imitations.
Listen to this.
[SQUAWKS]
[GOBBLING]
That's a turkey.
Are you kidding me?
Oh, no, sir.
Well, I'm not in
the poultry business.
Well, I only do it
for friends.
Well, that's the surest way
to lose them.
What can I do
about all this?
Well, if you'd only
give Janey a chance.
She's always wanted
to appear in a theatre,
and it'd make me
very happy.
Mouse.
Yes, boss.
Show this
imitations man out.
Come on, Mr Foundation.
We've had enough of
your propaganda. Come on.
The way you gentlemen are acting, you'd
think I was having your show raided.
We know all about it.
Say, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Mouse, you ought to be ashamed of yourself,
shoving this gentleman around like this.
Take your hands
off him.
Why, you mustn't
rush out like this.
Oh, mustn't I?
Why, no, certainly not.
Sit right down.
Why, I want to tell you, I think
your hen imitation was a natural.
You do?
Yes.
Well, it does come
sort of natural, you know.
Fine. Now about your niece.
I may put her in the show,
that is, if you'll do
something for me too.
You know, you scratch
my back, I scratch yours.
Well, mine doesn't itch, but
I'd be very glad to scratch yours.
No, no, no.
Tell me, how do you
stand with your boss?
Oh, you mean Hannah Bainbridge,
the president?
Yes, how do you rate with her?
I'm her kid brother, Hubert.
Hubert, how would you like
to get out of the supply room?
Well, it is a little
close in there.
I understand.
Just a second.
Just a second, Hubert.
Take a look.
What do you see?
Oh, that's more than
I've seen in years.
Put it in your pocket.
That's enough.
I have an idea that will land you
on the very top of your foundation.
You have?
Yes.
What's the idea?
Well, I'll tell you.
[BELL RINGS]
Hello, Janey.
Good morning, Uncle Hubert.
What happened to you?
I was worried.
Aunt Hannah's been
calling for you.
She has?
Oh, dear, dear.
Well, I'd better go right in.
Oh, Uncle, did you see that man?
You know, the one you told me about?
Did I see him? I not only
saw him, I talked to him.
No!
You're as good as set.
All I have to do
is see Hannah.
Aunt Hannah?
You'll find out.
Now, just keep
your fingers crossed.
On both hands.
HANNAH:
Hubert!
Yes, one round trip to Seattle.
Essential? What is more essential than the
moral welfare of our young people in these times?
I tell you, my presence at our
convention is absolutely imperative.
Are you going somewhere,
Hannah? Shut up.
You say I can get an upper? I suppose
it's the best I can do. Thank you.
Now, Mr Playboy,
where were you last night?
I went to a show.
A show?
Indiscretions of 1943.
Hubert Bainbridge.
But it was an accident, Hannah.
I was on my way to the Y for a workout,
and I happened to pass the theatre.
When I saw the pictures on the
outside, I couldn't resist going in.
But only in the interests
of the foundation.
Isn't your interest in
our work rather sudden?
Well, I admit my heart
hasn't always been in it.
But last night was more
than I could stand.
Look. Did you ever see
anything so brazen?
Did you?
Positively shocking.
Send them a stern warning.
Form 92.
Form 92? This is something
that calls for action.
You should see what
she does with her hips.
Why, it's practically
the hootchy-kootchy.
[HUMMING "LITTLE EGYPT"]
Hubert! I'm sorry, Hannah,
but that's what she does.
I'll take care of her as soon as
I get back from the convention.
But that may be too late.
Think of the thousands of people
that may see this exhibition.
I tell you, Hannah, this show
should be closed tonight.
COP:
Bring down that curtain.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this show is closed.
If you'll go to the box office,
there will be an officer who will see
that your admission is
cheerfully refunded. Thank you.
What a break. Why, you couldn't
buy publicity like that.
Look, doesn't that
make up for last night?
I wouldn't be surprised if
you framed this yourself.
Well, what would you say
if I told you that I did?
Well, it's all right.
Tell her, Mouse.
He figured it all out himself,
Miss Lawrence.
He's got terrific connections.
CAPTAIN: All right,
folks, clear the lobby.
The show is closed indefinitely.
[PEOPLE GRUMBLING]
Tell them to close
that box office.
FERRIS: Hey, what's
going on around here?
Hello, Mr Ferris.
Your show is closed.
But this must be a mistake.
You're right, Mr Ferris, and whoever
stirred up that Bainbridge outfit
is the guy who made it.
It was just a gag.
Well, if it was before,
it ain't now.
The heat's on.
We're closing up
two more shows tonight.
Anything wrong, captain?
Yes, Miss Lawrence.
We've gotta close it up.
That's one job I sure hate:
closing shows.
Well, Mastermind, did you
trip over your connection?
I'll fix this just as soon
as I can get to a phone.
The Mayor himself couldn't
fix this one, Mr Ferris.
When bigger and better fixes
are made, you'll get into them,
but from now on, without me.
Pardon me for saying it, Mr Ferris, but that's the
best thing that could have happened to that show.
Oh, no, I'm a ruined man.
On the contrary, that show would have
ruined both you and Miss Lawrence.
It was a dud.
Now you can take a little rest
and then put on something good.
Rest. How can I
take a rest?
Why not, Mr Ferris? Go to Florida
and get some of that sunshine.
What's going to happen to
Fay Lawrence in the meantime?
Fay Lawrence?
Yes.
Do you think she'd wait around
until I got a coat of tan?
Mr Ferris, you mean
you didn't hear?
Hear what?
Come here, just a minute.
Take a look.
That can't be possible.
Well, we got notice
to vacate the theatre.
Fay can't do this to me.
She told me something about Stanton,
but I thought it was only to get my goat.
Why, this is awful.
We're sorry we're late,
Mr Ferris.
So it's you.
Yeah, this is me, and
this is my niece, Janey.
How do you do?
You're just the guy I wanted to see.
Yeah, was that raid very funny?
Funny. I'm still in stitches.
Well, I'm glad you liked it.
And you were right, Mr Ferris, I'm
in complete charge of the foundation
because my sister, Hannah, has gone to
Seattle and will be there for two months.
I'm overwhelmed.
Yeah, I feel pretty good
about it myself.
But I suppose you're anxious
to hear Janey sing.
You get your music out, darling.
I always play for her.
Mr Ferris, aren't you going
to wait to hear Janey sing?
Gee, Janey, I'm sorry.
Something must have come up.
He was so anxious
to hear you yesterday.
Yesterday he still
had a show.
Oh, it's all right, Uncle Hubert.
You did your best.
Let's go home.
I'm awful sorry, honey.
[SINGING XAVIER CUGAT'S
"NEGRA LEONO"]
WOMAN:
Good evening, Mr Ferris.
Bonsoir, monsieur Ferris.
Hello, mac.
Tony.
Xavier. Mi amigo mejor.
Tony, my friend. I can always
depend on you to fill one booth, huh?
Wonderful music.
Wonderful.
You know, I should have my head examined
for never using you in one of my shows.
But the next one I do,
you'll be in it.
Oh, I'm afraid I'll be tied up
for quite some time, Tony.
I've just signed with
Stanton for Tropicana.
Don't tell me you're gonna
work for Stanton too?
Why not? He gave me a good
contract and it's a great show.
Great show. Wait till you see
the one I'm working on.
A real dynamite musical
if you've ever seen one.
What is it about?
Well, it's a terrific idea.
It's one of those sensational
things, I... Tell him, Mouse.
Huh? Well, you told me
not to tell anybody.
That's all right. You can
tell him, he's my friend.
Well, uh,
it's about India.
Maharajas, beautiful girls,
a magic carpet.
It sounds vague.
Well, I'm working
on the script now.
Tony, you're
shadow-boxing again.
You can't even tell a good lie
for a friend anymore.
Tell me, is Tropicana
really that good?
Oh, great, great.
How is Fay in it?
It's gonna hurt, Tony.
Oh, I can stand it.
I don't really care anymore.
What Stanton's trying to do is bring a
new Fay Lawrence out of the old shell,
to create a new personality.
It can't be done.
He's doing it.
You ought to see
some of those rehearsals.
Don't go to pieces, Tony.
Broadway is full of eager
and talented people.
You created one Fay Lawrence,
you'll create another.
Oh, sure.
Oh, I'd better go back
to my band, Tony.
I must hold onto the boys
I still have.
You know, most of them are already tooting
reveille in Green River, North Carolina.
Goodbye, Tony.
Stanton, that cheap,
double-crossing crook.
Bringing out a new
Fay Lawrence.
What does he know
about her anyway?
Mouse, have I ever
lied to you?
Well, not unless
you had to, no.
Then listen to me.
Fay Lawrence is part of me.
She's me.
Do you think I'm gonna let anybody
twist her around and ruin my life's work?
Sounds like
he's doing it, boss.
I don't believe it. I've gotta
see that with my own eyes.
And I'm going to tomorrow.
Well, boss, it was no lie.
They haven't opened yet.
Yeah, they gotta
rehearse first.
Come on, let's go in
and take a peak.
There goes that guitar
I knew it would start again
And there goes my heart again
Singing along
There goes that guitar
And there goes that chord again
And I'm overboard again
Is it that song?
Or is it love?
I know that you're near to me
And that makes it clear to me
This is the start of love
And it's gone too far
There goes that guitar
There goes my heart
Or is it love?
I know that you're near to me
And that makes it clear to me
This is the start of love
And it's gone too far
There goes that guitar
There goes my heart
How do you like
the number, Fay?
I don't want to okay anything
unless you're enthusiastic about it.
Oh, I always say yes
to a good number.
You know, Fay, I'm convinced that this show is going
to give you the greatest scope for your talents.
I told you I'd surround you
with the best.
Anyway, I'm so glad to be with someone
who can keep his word... I hope.
That's appreciation for you.
Pardon me, Miss Lawrence,
your number's on next.
Uh, did you decide to drive in on
the gaucho carriage for this number?
No, dear, I'm coming in
on my own momentum.
I can't let her
get away with this.
I've gotta talk to her.
FAY: Be sure you don't
wear that tonight.
Oh, no, madame.
Get out.
But monsieur Ferris...
Get out and stay out.
The late Mr Ferris, I presume.
Fay, I heard every word you said
to that cheap four-flusher Stanton.
I was sitting in the balcony,
right over your head.
As an aerial umbrella,
you're a perfect drip.
You've gotta listen, Fay,
this doesn't make sense.
You can't work for Stanton after
all the shows we've done together.
Think of my reputation.
Don't be tiresome.
What do you want
to do, ruin me?
Put me in bankruptcy?
Send me to jail?
You know I've been mad about you
from the first time I laid eyes on you.
You're my whole world. What do you
want to do, drive me to a madhouse?
No, I'll call you a taxi.
Listen, honey, you can't cast me
aside like an old shoe.
Don't be silly. Who's throwing
away old shoes nowadays?
Fay, if you come back to me,
we'll get right back on top again.
I've got some great plans.
Why, only this morning, I got you the
greatest proposition you've ever seen.
What is it? Why, we'll sweep
right over Broadway again.
We'll have lines ten blocks long
in front of our box office.
We'll have them hanging
from the rafters.
And another thing: if you give
Stanton your notice today,
I'll double your salary
in my next show.
What do you think of that?
Oh, don't be mercenary.
Money isn't everything,
if you can get it.
Doesn't your conscience
ever bother you?
No, it amuses me.
Have you ever thanked me once
for everything I've done for you?
I only answer $64 questions.
All right, Fay, you asked for it.
When I start fighting, I get mad,
and when I get mad, I bite nails in two.
All right, I'll get you
a priority on them.
[GROANS]
Private Andy Walker
reporting for duty.
At ease, soldier.
Boy, am I glad to see you.
Well, what can I investigate
for you today?
Any burlesque show
I ought to peep at?
No, darling,
no investigations.
Things are so quiet around here,
I might just as well be in the morgue.
Well, don't let it
get you down, honey.
As soon as I get this war
over with, I'll marry you.
I'll get you out of here.
But in the meantime, I'd like to be able to prove to
myself just what my chances are for a stage career.
Oh, Janey, dear, I still say you'll
never be happy in show business.
I don't want to see you
get hurt by it.
Why do you feel you have
to be a famous star?
Oh, Andy, it's not
the fame I'm after.
It's a chance to prove
what I can do.
But it's such
a nerve-racking life.
But don't you think it's nerve-racking
sitting around here day after day?
I can almost feel the spiders
spinning their webs around me.
Good morning. Hello, Janey.
Why, where's my friend, Hubert?
Oh, it's you, Mr Ferris.
So you're the big producer
she was telling me about, huh?
Well, I know you think I walked out on
you, but that's what I came up to explain.
Always glad to meet
one of our boys.
I'm gonna make a big star
out of you.
Yeah, and he's the one can do it.
He's produced more hits
than any man on Broadway.
Yeah? If he doesn't get out of here,
I'll produce one right on his chin.
Oh, Andy, please,
you'll ruin everything.
Are you on the level,
or are you just bluffing?
Bluffing? I'll show you
whether I'm bluffing or not.
Wait till you hear the great news
I've got for your Uncle Hubert.
Hey, what's going on here?
Hubert, Hubert, we're gonna produce
the biggest show that ever hit Broadway,
and Janey's gonna
play the lead.
Honest?
I give you my solemn word of honour.
I don't believe you've got one.
What have I ever done to you?
Andy doesn't want me to go
on the stage, Mr Ferris.
What? And cheat the public
of her charm and personality?
You're not gonna stand
for that, are you?
No, I should say not.
Let's get down to business.
Come right in the office here.
That's it.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Yes.
Come on, Hubert, sit down,
make yourself comfortable.
Well, thank you.
You still want Janey to get
a break, don't you?
Of course I do.
Well, then we've got to team her up
with some big New York name.
Oh, like...
Well, not exactly.
Some great personality like,
uh, Fay Lawrence.
Oh, she's wonderful.
Yes, but here's the trouble.
She's already signed
with Forrest Stanton.
Gee, that's too bad.
Yes.
Someone must get her
away from him.
And you're the man
to do it.
Well, I'm a little out of practice,
but I'll be glad to try.
All you have to do is take the phone.
Call Stanton. Tell him who you are.
Then sort of drop a hint that he'd
better not use Fay Lawrence in his show.
Well, I don't understand.
You don't have to understand.
She's still on the foundation's
blacklist, isn't she?
We have no blacklist.
You have one now.
[INTERCOM BUZZES]
Yes?
MAN [OVER INTERCOM]: The Bainbridge
Foundation on the phone, sir.
Bainbridge Foundation?
It's Mr Bainbridge himself.
Hello.
Yes.
Oh, how do you do,
Mr Bainbridge?
Of course she's going
to be in my show. Why?
Well, she's still on
our blacklist, Mr Stanton.
Of course, this is unofficial, but I
thought I'd warn you in a friendly way.
Oh, but Mr Bainbridge, don't you think
that your organization is being very unfair?
I mean, after all, Miss Lawrence
is a big Broadway star.
I've built my entire show around her.
But that's a restraint of trade.
Restraint of trade?
It's just a friendly tip.
Of course, this is just a friendly tip.
And I happen to know
what they're figuring on doing.
Yes, that's right.
Oh, not at all, Mr Stanton.
Goodbye.
What'd he say?
He thanked me.
Wonderful.
Now we give him
our slow curve.
Listen, I've got a story to tell you
About a yank who came
South of the border
He makes me so happy
And so mad
But, oh, he's such a Romeo
[ALL SINGING
RHYTHMIC SOUNDS]
Antonio, Antonio
He is such a Romeo
He is so magnífico
He tries American tactics
Makes eyes wherever he be
Now I'm so mad I could kill him
Why doesn't he make eyes at me?
But Antonio, Antonio
He is so romántico
He plays the piano
He's such a man-o
So magnífico
He plays the piccolo
Oh, how I love him so
He shakes maraca
Chic-chic-chic chaca
Ah, bravissimo!
BAND: Antonio, Antonio
He's such a Romeo
Romántico Antonio
He give me such baloney, oh!
He's such a braggadocio
About the things he does
BAND: Antonio, Antonio
He is so magnífico
Now here I am so all alone
Without a single chaperone
And he is flirting
With somebody else
He serenades señoritas
Each night wherever he be
He plays guitar with such passion
Why doesn't he play it for me?
But Antonio, Antonio
If we should ever marry, oh
We'd have Eduardo,
Manuelito, Roberto, Pepito
Pablito, Panchito
Oh, we'd have so many chiquitos
Bonsoir, monsieur Ferris.
Is Lou here?
Yeah, dancing with the dumbest
girl this side of the Rocky Mountains.
I saved the booth for you
next to Mr Stanton's.
He looks real worried tonight.
You're a real pal, mac.
I'm gonna make you stage
manager in the new show.
Thank you, Mr Ferris. I can do
the black-face too, you know.
Mac, tell Louis Shore
I wanna see him.
I think Mr Shore is dancing.
Tell him it's important, if he
wants to make some quick dough.
Yes, Mr Ferris.
Sorry, honey, business.
Go powder your nose
or something.
Hello, Ferris, what's the story?
Well, I'm in a tough spot.
You're telling me.
I've got $200,000 lined up
to do a musical,
so I want some real
sensational people.
Well, I've got them all,
you know.
What type of a show is it?
Well, I'm angling around.
I've read a couple of scripts.
Who've you got?
Well, I've got Lucille Wright,
Chiquita Benton, Stafford and Lynn,
Bill Weston and his
Seven Swing-Slingers.
No, that's no good.
No good?
What do you mean, "no good"?
Who do you want? Shostakovich
and his seven symphonies?
No, I've got to have the best there
is on Broadway, and no fooling.
I gotta rush now.
Big deal is cooking.
I'll give you a call
Monday, Tony.
I'll see what I can
line up for you.
Give my best to Malnick.
I will.
Hello, Tony.
Forrest.
Mind if I sit down?
Why, of course not.
Say, what are you doing here? I thought
you were all tied up with your rehearsals.
Say, how does the show look?
Tony, it's a gold-mine.
So they tell me.
Oh, by the way, I couldn't help but overhear your
conversation with Lou just now. Congratulations.
Thanks. I did hit the jackpot.
Too bad you haven't got
a show ready.
I'll get one.
Sure.
Tony, I've just been thinking.
How would you like
to take over Tropicana?
Tropicana? Tropicana?
Since when have you started
throwing gold-mines away?
Look, Tony, I've got to get away
from this business for a while.
Take a long rest.
Doctor's orders.
You do look terrible.
I do?
Yes.
Look, I'm willing to take a little loss on
Tropicana just so I can get away for a good rest.
Haven't you got Fay Lawrence
under contract to play the lead?
Yes, and she's sensational.
The show was written
for her, you know.
I wouldn't be buried in the same
cemetery with that dame.
It's no deal.
That can be fixed, Tony.
She'd be happy to step out
the minute you took over.
You think she would?
Absolutely.
Every time she hears
your name, she gets sick.
She does?
Tony, she hates you.
Really? Don't you worry
about her hanging on
to the show,
not with your doing it.
Why, she'd pay
for her release.
What'll you take for Tropicana?
Look, I've got $28,000
tied up in it.
I'll tell you what I'll do,
I'll take 20.
Being that you're a sick man,
I'll tell you what I'll do:
I'll give you ten.
I'll tell you what, I'll take it.
Give me the chequebook.
Now the pen.
You're getting the best deal
of your life.
I want to tell you something, this
is the way Tony Ferris does business.
Everything right on
the dotted line.
There you are.
Thanks, Tony.
Now, take good care
of your nerves.
I will. Good luck.
Good luck to you.
You know, Tony, I was just thinking,
better hold back the announcements
until I've had a chance to talk with Fay and
sort of smooth over the rough edges, you know.
Let me handle
the publicity.
It's all yours.
Thanks.
So long, Mouse.
Mouse, we won the battle.
Mark my words, Fay Lawrence will come
back to me crawling on her hands and knees.
Yes, boss, but there's one thing
that's worrying me.
What's that?
How are you gonna cover
this check by tomorrow?
Don't be an idiot.
Tomorrow's Sunday.
Come on.
Well, there you are.
Hello, Fay.
Hello, Forrest.
How are you, boys?
We've been going through those new
choruses of "Can't be bothered" all evening.
Look, gentlemen, I wonder
if you'd please excuse us.
Miss Lawrence and I have some
very important business to discuss.
Thanks for the number, boys.
and we'll wrap it up as a gift
before we give it to our public.
Good night.
Well, I'm glad to see you
in such a happy frame of mind.
Won't you have a drink?
Thanks.
I may need it.
Fay, I have some news for you
that may be a shock.
What is it?
I can't go on with the show.
Oh, is that so?
You what?
As a matter of fact, my backer,
who was to back me, has backed out.
I haven't the money.
However, the show will go on and
I assume that you'll be the star.
But I had to sell the production.
Well, one man's money's
as good as another's.
You may not like your producer.
Oh, I like any producer
who produces.
Who is he?
Tony Ferris.
Why, this is a catastrophe.
I'm sorry, Fay,
I had no other choice.
After all, you two
have had hits before.
Why, you don't know that guy.
Why, this is terrible.
Why, if he'd have been with Washington,
he'd have double-crossed the Delaware.
Hello, may I speak to
the district attorney, please?
Hello, Hubert.
Oh, uh, cancel it.
Oh, I'm so glad
you gentlemen are here.
Glad to see you, Hubert.
How is every little wrinkle?
Thank you. I was just
calling up the district attorney.
District attorney?
What for?
Well, I wanted to confess about
myself and you and Mr Mouse.
Confess what?
About that telephone call
I made to Mr Stanton.
I've felt terrible
about it ever since.
I haven't slept a wink.
I'm a sick man, Mr Ferris.
I never lied in my life.
Hubert, you can forget
about that call.
Forget about it?
Yeah, you never
made it, understand?
Oh, but I did, Mr Ferris.
You remember, you were...
I tell you,
you never made it.
But I did!
You don't remember.
You've got two witnesses
to back you up.
Who's the other witness, boss?
You, you dope.
Do you mean you gentlemen
would really lie for me?
Hubert, we'd die for you.
Oh, you don't know what you've done for
me and for the Bainbridge Foundation.
Why, Mr Stanton could have
sued us for every penny we have.
So what?
Well, how much money can you have?
Well, as of today,
there's $409,000.26
Well, who's rationing
all that sugar?
Pardon me?
I say, who's in charge
of the money?
Oh, I don't know.
I guess I am, as long as
sister Hannah's away.
They couldn't have placed it
in better hands.
I don't know why you men
are so good to me.
You really wanna know?
Yes.
I'll tell you, Hubert, anyone who cares as much about
his niece as you do must be the sweetest guy in the world.
And I'm a pushover for sweet guys.
This is no place for Janey
with her wonderful talent.
Sure, we gotta get her out of here.
You mean it?
Sure.
Why, that's our sacred duty.
You really mean that you'll give
Janey a chance, Mr Ferris?
Hubert, you leave it to me.
I'll fix you, you and Janey, like you've
never been fixed up before in all your life.
Oh, Mr Ferris.
Now you're gonna hear
something terrific.
Yes.
Frank.
Yes, sir.
Is Hazel Scott ready?
It'll take a couple of minutes, boss.
They're still putting
the pianos in place.
I don't want any waits
between numbers.
Get the next one
to follow immediately.
The next will be the "Wabash" number.
We'll need Miss Adair.
Honey, will you get dressed, please?
Right away, Mr Ferris.
Keep your fingers crossed.
Be good.
Good luck, darling.
Thank you, Uncle.
Will you look at this model, please?
Let's see.
No, that won't do, Rennie.
That's not massive enough.
Don't forget, this is
a Tony Ferris production.
I'm only trying to cut
corners a little, Mr Ferris.
Who asked you to cut corners?
What's 15 to 20,000 dollars
to a big musical like this?
All right, Mr Ferris.
It is your money.
Don't bother about my money.
There's plenty more
where that came from.
Mr Ferris.
Yes?
I'm worried.
About my money?
No.
Oh.
About the foundation's money.
The way we're spending it,
I'm practically an embezzler.
You're still vice-president,
aren't you?
Only till Hannah gets back. After all, we're
supposed to close shows, not finance them.
Oh, don't worry.
By the time Hannah returns, you'll have all
your money back and maybe a $50,000 profit.
Maybe...
When the black keys meet
The white keys on Piano Avenue
Do they music? They do
They swing it in G
Corner of keyboard street
The black and the white
Do it all right, all right
When the ivories and the jiveries
Keep that boogie-vard awake
Make they music?
They make
Like pepper and salt
Chocolate and malt, they zoot
The black and the white
Do it all right, all root
Oh, Mary Jane
Get off the beat
Dig that refrain
It's sweeter than 8-point meat
When the black keys
Join the white keys
In that barrel-house parade
Plays it music?
It's played
I'm telling you, jack
Stick to the black and white
All reet, all root, all right
That was wonderful.
Didn't that make you tingle all over?
Here's the "Wabash"
number, Mr Ferris.
MAN: Gee, it's been a wonderful leave.
WOMAN: Wonderful for me too.
MAN: Gosh, I'm gonna miss
you, and the folks, and...
WOMAN: And who?
Well, you'd only laugh, if I told you.
WOMAN:
No, I wouldn't.
MAN: Well, next to you,
I'm gonna miss the river.
WOMAN: Oh, you had me
worried for a minute.
WOMAN:
I don't mind a cloudy day
MAN:
And I've a mind that loves to stray
A million miles from here
WOMAN:
I see it all so clearly
Thinking about the Wabash
My muddy old buddy, the Wabash
Thinking about that river
A-rolling along in the moonlight
Thinking
Nothing to do but keep thinking
Thinking about the Wabash
I used to fish for hours
Those hazy old, lazy old hours
Every day was a Sunday
And Sunday ran right into Monday
Homesick
BOTH:
Thinking about the Wabash
MAN: I'm missing a gal named Janey
CHORUS: Janey
CHORUS:
Her kisses were so sugar-caney
MAN: And I even miss her brother Who
used to peek and tell her mother
When I'm all through parading
We'll take off our shoes
And go wading
Wading right in the river
A-rolling along in the moonlight
Thinking
Thinking about the Wabash
CHORUS:
I'm missing a gal named Janey
Her kisses were so sugar-caney
I even miss her brother
Who used to peek
And tell her mother
When I'm all through parading
We'll take off our shoes
And go wading
Wading right in the river
A-rolling along in the moonlight
Thinking
Thinking about the Wabash
Well, I hope you're as pleased
with Janey as I am.
Oh, Mr Ferris, I'm so pleased,
I can hardly talk.
You've made me
the happiest man in the world.
You've fulfilled all my dreams.
Gracious, you have
your hands full.
Let me help you.
Oh, thank you, monsieur.
Where are you taking them, miss?
To Miss Lawrence's car.
She is waiting for them.
Fay Lawrence?
Golly, I'm dying to meet her.
Here is everything, madame.
This gentleman was
so kind to help me.
What gentleman?
Me.
Oh, thank you so much
for your kind assistance.
Not at all.
It's my best deed since I was
a Boy Scout, Miss Lawrence.
Oh, I see you know who I am.
Should I know you?
Well, I was in hopes by this time,
we'd be very good friends.
I'm Bainbridge, Hubert Bainbridge.
Bainbridge?
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, well, where did you get the fantastic
idea that you and I should be good friends?
Well, I was led to believe that you'd be
the star of this show that I'm backing.
Oh. You were led to believe that?
And you are backing this show?
Well, my fine future friend, I think you
and I should get together and compare notes.
Yes, how about tonight at my place?
Oh, I'd love to.
But I don't want to interfere
with any of your plans.
Yes, but now you are my plans.
I'm Hubert Bainbridge.
Is Miss Lawrence still expecting me?
I think so, monsieur.
Come in, please.
I'd be very glad to.
May I have your hat?
I brought a few roses.
It seemed to be a nice thought.
I'll put them in water.
Oh, well, I kind of wanted
to give them to her myself.
Sort of surprise her, you know?
I'm a little bit surprised myself.
Very well, monsieur.
Golly.
[COUGHING]
Well, I see you're
a man of my word.
How do you do?
Hello, Miss Lawrence.
l... Excuse me.
How do you do?
I've been dropping things
ever since I met you yesterday.
I brought you a few roses.
Oh, you shouldn't have done that.
Oh, it's just a thought.
I didn't know you had the soul
of a stage-door johnnie.
I just discovered it myself.
Well, sit down, make yourself
at home. I'll be right back.
Thank you.
My, you have
a beautiful home here.
And you look simply
ravishing in that dress.
You think so?
What would you like
to have to drink?
Do you have any
lemon squash?
Not if I can help it.
How about a little
Napoleon brandy?
Oh, no. I wouldn't like to take
anything that belongs to somebody else.
Well, he wouldn't mind. Napoleon made
this himself before he met his Waterloo.
You'd better not fill mine up.
No kidding.
Aren't you going to have any?
Well, I don't drink.
But I like to keep my friends
in good spirits.
[COUGHING]
Got quite a bite to it,
hasn't it?
[RADIO PLAYING SOFT MUSIC]
Come over here, honey.
Would you like to cut a rug?
Oh, no, these rugs
are too expensive.
How'd you like to rumba?
Oh, I never did anything
but square dances.
well, we can
get around to that.
[CHUCKLES]
Don't jump, honey, don't jump.
How do you feel now?
Oh, I feel wonderful.
I feel just like a boy again.
Do I look like a boy again?
Well, I didn't know you then.
Well, you may not believe it
but, confidentially, I'm past 40.
Oh, well, a man of 40 is always
more fascinating than a man of 20.
A man of 40 has more charm, and
more poise and sometimes more money.
How am I doing?
Oh, great.
I can jitterbug too.
Oh, really.
Yeah.
Oh, you're solid. You should've
worn your draped suit.
I owe all my vigour
to vitamins.
I take a lot of them.
A, B, C, D, F, J and H.
Do you think vitamins
are here to stay?
Well, I think they'll
stay longer than you will.
Don't look now, honey,
but your hair is skidding.
Huh? Oh, that thing.
That don't fool anybody.
My sister, Hannah, makes me wear it when I go out
because our family made its money in hair tonic.
Say, that music is inspiring.
I wish Hannah would
let me go out nights.
Don't tell me she's got you
on the swing shift.
No, she just has a mania
for suppressing everything.
Well, then I suppose you're
number one on her list, huh?
List... List... Gosh, that's what
I forgot to remember to tell you.
Mr Ferris had me tell some producer that
you were on the foundation's blacklist.
And we haven't got
any blacklist.
We never even
had a white list.
Say that again, brother.
Oh, I can't.
I'm too ashamed.
It was a mean trick,
and I'm a cad.
Why did you do it?
Well, I did it all
for my niece, Janey.
Mr Ferris promised to put her in
the show if I'd put up the money,
and he said
you'd be in it too.
Well, where'd you get the money?
Well, there was a very nice surplus
in the sinking fund of the foundation,
and I sank some
of it in the show.
Did your sister, Hannah,
OK the transaction?
Oh, no. No, she
didn't know a thing about it.
She's in Seattle, at a convention.
She left me
in complete charge.
So you plundered the foundation's funds to
give your niece a break in show business.
Well, I don't want to discourage you,
but you've got one foot in jail already.
Jail! Oh, dear, oh, my.
How could this happen to me?
I only wanted to do
the right thing by everybody.
And now look:
I'm up a tree.
And out on a limb.
Well, what'll I do?
Well, I've got an idea. If you want to
square yourself, you can start right now.
You're not gonna
call the police?
No, just a man you did
a great injustice.
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello, Stanton talking.
Hello, Fay.
Well, how's the little girl?
Sure, I remember.
How did you know
the Bainbridge people called me?
Hubert Bainbridge.
In your apartment?
What is this, a gag?
His sister, in Seattle?
Oh, now I'm beginning
to see the light.
Go ahead.
Oh, he's sorry, eh?
Well, how touching.
All right, I promise you
I won't make him any trouble.
I'll go farther than that,
I'll even try to save his skin,
what there is left of it.
All right, Fay, you're a pal.
I just thought you'd like to know
how you've been taken.
Hello, long-distance?
Look, operator, I want you
to get me Hannah Bainbridge.
Seattle, Washington.
She's the chairlady of the
Bainbridge convention there.
Over hill, over dale
We have hit the dusty trail
And those caissons go rolling along
Counter march, right about
Hear those wagon soldiers shout
As those caissons
Go rolling along
For it's hi-hi-hee
In the field artillery
Call out your numbers
Loud and strong
And wherever we go
You will always know
That those caissons
Are rolling along
Keep 'em rolling
Those caissons are rolling along
Attention!
Let's boogie woogie
Right face
Column left, march!
What's on your mind, Harry?
The bank just called, Mr Ferris.
We're overdrawn again.
Well, what did you do with the 10,000 Hubert
gave you Monday? Didn't you deposit it?
Yes, but it's all gone.
Well, we gotta watch ourselves.
Another $20,000 ought to
see us through all right.
All right, I'll get it
from Hubert tomorrow.
I guess you'll want to hold up
all these checks then.
Oh, no, no.
Give them to me.
You never put off until tomorrow
what you can do today.
That's my motto.
Go ahead, give them out.
Give them out?
Yes, it's after 3.
All the banks are closed.
Oh.
Hey, boss.
Yes?
Are you in the mood
for a surprise?
I guess I can stand another one.
Okay, then. Wait'll you get
a load of this.
Ladies and gentlemen, I give you now
Ezra Simpkins in "A Little Bit of Corn".
Shoo. Shoo.
Get out of here. Go on.
You never lay any eggs here.
Go on home where you belong.
Get out of here.
Uncle, the postman just came and
brought you some more seed envelopes.
Oh, dear, I've got more seeds
now than I know what to do with.
How did you ever
get yourself into this?
I've always tried to be
a good American.
And when this country went to war,
the corner grocer told me,
I ought to be a farmer
in my own backyard.
And as I struggled from the store
with all the seeds he'd sold me,
he said, " Don't worry, pard,
it really isn't hard."
So I went and planted cabbages
I figured I knew just how
They looked so pretty
On the envelope
But just take a look at them now
Then I planted beets and broccoli
Till my back began to bow
For they looked so pretty
On the envelope
But look at that broccoli now
The way my peas grow littler
You'd think I worked for Hitler
The neighbours are reporting me
To Uncle Sam
That's the kind of a farmer I am
Oh, I pledged a crop for victory
And I'd like to keep that vow
But alas, my vegetables
Look like rope
They feel like Jell-O
And they taste like soap
Oh, they looked so pretty
On the envelope
But look, look, look at them now
Hubert, you're dynamite.
Well, thanks.
I'm glad you liked it.
I thought we needed something
to follow Hazel Scott.
Well, I don't think it quite fits into the show.
As you know, it's mostly a Latin background.
Oh, I thought of that too, Mr Ferris.
I've got a special verse about
a Mexican jumping bean.
Now, you run right along
and change your clothes.
We'll talk about that later.
I'm glad you liked it, though.
HANNAH:
Hubert!
Is this Seattle?
So it's true. You have dragged
our name in the muck and mire.
TONY: Madam, you're
interrupting my rehearsals.
Now, will you leave quietly, or
shall I have you thrown out bodily?
If you lay one finger on me...
Madam, will you kindly
take it on the lam?
Aunt Hannah,
what are you doing here?
Jane, your... Your legs!
What's wrong with my legs?
Have you no modesty?
Do you think I'd let
any man see my legs?
Do you think he'd want to?
Sir. Who are you?
Just the producer of the show.
So you're the scoundrel who
hoodwinked my poor brother.
Hubert and Jane,
come down here at once.
This little escapade is over.
Just a minute.
We have signed contracts.
You can't take that girl
out of my show.
Indeed I can. You're not dealing with my
weak-kneed brother and my guileless niece now.
You're dealing with
Hannah Bainbridge.
And that's a horse of another
colour. Horse is right.
Janey, come put this on.
this is disgraceful.
If you take them away, I won't
be able to produce this show.
Exactly. I have already notified my bank
to stop payments on any and all checks
my brother has drawn
to your benefit.
Your accounts are closed.
You will never see another cent
of the foundation's money.
But if I'm held responsible
for these claims, I go to jail.
Good. That's just
where you belong.
Come along now, come along.
And you too.
How were things in Seattle?
Never mind Seattle.
I'll take care of that.
But I can't go out like this.
You get back to the supply room
where you belong.
But I want my clothes.
Never mind about your clothes!
I can't understand a thing
any more. My mind's a blank.
Mine too, boss.
We've got to get Fay back.
That's the only thing I know.
Mouse.
What?
If she was to hear that I was dead,
do you think she'd feel sorry for me?
She might.
Folks are awfully good
to dead people, you know.
You're right. I've got it.
Wait a minute, boss.
You ain't gonna bump yourself off
just to satisfy that dame, are you?
No. Fay's too smart
for anything like that.
But I've got a terrific idea
that'll work like a charm.
Who are you?
What are you talking about?
I'm Doctor Snyder,
of the Snyder Private Sanatorium.
Mr Tony Ferris has just
been brought in.
There's every symptom of an acute manic
depressive case, with complications.
He's been calling for you
all the time.
Your presence here
would be highly desirable.
All right, I'll be right over.
A very complex case,
Miss Lawrence.
You can diagnose it
in ten different ways.
In fact, you may take your pick
of paranoia, paranomia,
schizophrenia, mania grandiose
or dementia praecox.
Sounds like
a French menu to me.
I suggest that you would
see the patient.
I believe it may help him.
I'll be glad to take a look.
I must warn you, this may
prove to be a shock.
Well, that's all right too.
This way, Miss Lawrence.
This is one of the most complicated
cases I have ever encountered.
Hello, Miss Lawrence.
What's that, lady?
You want a ticket for the show?
We're sold out for ten years.
But just a minute.
I have one seat left.
A wonderful seat
right behind the post.
Hey, boss, Miss Lawrence is here.
Bravo! Bravo!
What a wonderful show.
What a great success.
That guy's nuts.
He won't recognise anybody
anymore, not even you.
When did this happen?
This morning, Miss Lawrence.
When that dame from Seattle
took all the dough out of the show.
At first he was sort of all right,
then all of a sudden, zing!
His mind snapped.
It was awful.
Even I cried a little.
To be, or not to be:
that is the question...
Poor Tony. Who would've thought he'd switch to
Shakespeare after reading Police Gazette all these years.
Yeah, it is tough, isn't it?
Uh-huh. What's happening
to the play meanwhile?
Nothing. It's going
to pieces, I guess.
I think I'll take it over.
You'll what?
Take over the show.
You know, the play's the thing.
Not this one, it ain't.
No dough at all, and his checks
are bouncing all over the town too.
Well, maybe I can
promote someone.
MOUSE: Oh, he's been to all the places
already and couldn't get a penny.
I think I know a spot
he hasn't touched.
You know, I always did like
Tropicana and I want to be in it.
Fay, wait a minute!
Wait a minute!
With you back in the show,
I can promote it myself.
Take it easy, Mr Ferris, please.
Take your hands off me.
You don't really think
I'm crazy, do you?
Of course, not. You're just
a little nervous. Herbie!
The gentleman's upset.
You'd better take care of him.
This is an outrage.
I'll sue you!
Why don't you let him relax?
Take your paws off me,
you big gorilla.
Acute paranoia, and
a very dangerous case.
Then you'll keep him here a while?
Oh, yes.
But someone must sign
the commitment papers.
I will. That's the least
I can do for poor Tony.
Fay. You're not gonna
leave me here.
I'm perfectly normal, I swear.
A tale told by an idiot, full of
sound and fury, signifying nothing.
Incidentally, that's Shakespeare
too. Let's go, doctor.
Cut it out, will you? Listen
to me, will you, please?
Miss Lawrence, please.
You ain't gonna leave the
boss in this nut farm, are you?
Why not? With him staying here
and not mixing things up,
I may be able to pull him out
of the hole he dug himself into.
Fay, it was just a gag
to get you back.
There's nothing wrong with me.
Just listen to the way he's
fighting back there. It's awful.
Miss Lawrence, please,
do something.
I will.
In fact, I'm off to open
a second front of my own.
Hubert.
Fay, er, Miss Lawrence.
Oh, am I glad to see you.
Hannah found out about my advancing money
for Tropicana and she's awful mad at me.
I'm supposed to be in the supply room,
right now, with my face to the wall.
Well, I'm here to get you out,
and I've got an idea that's a lily.
Oh, I love lilies.
This is my niece, Janey,
Miss Lawrence.
Oh, this is the little girl with the career
and doesn't know what to do with it, huh?
Well, I'm afraid, Miss Lawrence, I won't
get a chance to do anything with it now.
Well, anyone can
have a career.
Why not be different?
Don't have one.
Oh, but she has
true natural talent.
Well, haven't we all?
Where's your sister, Hannah?
She's in there.
Oh, I wanna get to the bottom
of this foundation.
Oh, but you mustn't go in now.
She's terribly angry.
And she won't see anybody.
Not anybody.
She's having tea.
Oh. She's having tea.
Well, I'm gonna give her
a little TNT.
Miss Bainbridge, am I right?
Who are you?
My card.
The Queen of Hearts?
Pardon me, the other side.
Fay Lawrence. Hmm.
That strikes a familiar chord.
Well, I'm a familiar figure
around town.
I know. You were the star
of Indiscretions.
You're the Fay Lawrence
that does this.
[HUMMING "LITTLE EGYPT"]
Great. Only don't let
the clutch out so fast.
Is that what I did?
Oh, but good.
I... I don't think I care to prolong
this interview, Miss Lawrence.
Just a minute.
I happen to know that the Bainbridge
Foundation has feet of clay,
and brother Hubert has
a little mud on his shoes.
What do you mean?
You know what I mean.
Hubert did a little job of embezzling
to back Tropicana with your funds.
Oh, I guess he didn't realise
what he was doing,
but I'm afraid if it got
into the newspapers...
No, no, please. You
wouldn't. Not the newspapers.
That's why I'm here,
to keep it out of the papers.
It must be kept out.
It would be a fatal blow
to our name and tradition.
Why, my ancestors
came over on the mayflower.
Oh, you're lucky.
Now we have immigration laws.
I only acted upon
the reports given me.
I must speak to my brother.
Hubert. Come in here.
Yes, Hannah, did you call me?
Come here.
Hubert, how much did this
adventuress take you for?
He's so cute, I only
took him for granted.
Well, you don't
understand, Hannah.
It was Mr Ferris to whom
I advanced the $40,000.
40,000! We will pay it all back to the foundation
if I have to mortgage my entire holdings.
Now, don't be hasty.
Another 20,000 will open Tropicana
and keep your name out of the papers.
You're not suggesting I become a Broadway
producer and finance a theatrical venture?
Well, you're holding the bag. You
may as well have something in it.
No, no, I can't do it.
I can't bring myself to do it.
Oh, come, come, Hannah,
you're in a rut.
You'd better. If you don't,
I may go to jail.
Oh, you wouldn't want everyone
calling you hard-hearted Hannah.
And it only takes
one cheque, Hannah.
You'll have lots of them left
in that book.
I don't know. It's against
all my finer instincts.
Come on. Sit down and put your autograph
on a cheque and let's get out of here.
Make it out to Tony Ferris.
Very well, but on the strict understanding
that Jane does not set one foot on that stage.
Is that understood?
All right, you've got
my word for it.
Golly. Now I can come
and watch you rehearse.
Mmm, with you around, how
can I keep my mind on my work?
ALL:
Well, I'm glad to know you, amigo
Though we're birds of a feather
Took a war to bring us together
As I said, mi amigo
Cómo está usted, mi amigo
I'll go your way, you'll go my way
On the pan-American highway
And to everybody we know
We'll say hello, amigo, hello
CHORUS: Hello!
FAY: Hello!
Hello!
Hello, mi amigo
Well, I'm glad to know you, amigo
Though we're birds of a feather
Took a war to bring us together
As I said, mi amigo
Cómo está usted, mi amigo
lf you want things put in order
Come and see me
South of the border
And to everybody we know
We'll say hello, amigo
CHORUS:
Cómo está, amigo
FAY:
Venga a vernos
CHORUS:
Which means come up and see us
ALL:
Hello, amigo, hello
[APPLAUDING]