My lords, gentlemen,
pray silence for Ralph Douglas
Christopher Alexander Gurney,
the 13th earl of Gurney.
Thank you.
The aim of the
Society of St. George...
is to keep green
the memory of England.
We were once the rulers...
of the greatest empire
the world has ever known!
- Hear, hear!
- Ruled not by superior force or skill,
but by sheer presence.
Hear, hear!
So I give you England.
This teeming womb of privilege.
This feudal state...
whose shores beat back
the turbulent sea of foreign anarchy.
This ancient fortress,
still commanded by the noblest
of our royal blood.
Hear, hear!
This ancient land of ritual.
This precious stone...
set in the silver sea.
The toast is "England.
This precious stone...
set in the silver sea."
England. Set in the silver sea.
# God save our gracious Queen #
#Scatter Her enemies #
#And make them fall #
# Confound their politics #
#Frustrate their knavish tricks #
# On Thee our hopes we fix #
# God save the Queen ##
Ah, thank you, Tuck.
How was your speech, my lord?
Went well, Tuck.
Englishmen like to hear
the truth about themselves.
He's back, Claire.
Claire!
I said, Ralph is back.
Thank you, Charles.
I'll have a vodka and tonic.
I say, guv'nor, the guv'nor is back.
Mummy, I was just telling the guv'nor
that the guv'nor is back.
Charles! With ice.
I'm repeating myself,
calling the guv'nor the guv'nor
and Daddy the guv'nor as well.
- Tucker, I'm getting married again.
- Very good, my lord.
Miss Grace Shelley.
Charles is right.
Been putting it off.
Sake of the family.
OnlyJack left.
This house... used to be
full of mischief.
Four young devils.
Thought I was safe enough.
Master Paul would have been
the 14th earl.
District officer at 21.
Dead at 23. Beriberi.
Picked it up off some scruffy
fuzzy-wuzzy in dressing gown.
Shouldn't wonder, eh?
Master Richard
used to play the xylophone.
And young Raymond,
killed in Malaya.
Not one of them buried in England.
Never seen their graves.
You could do that
on your honeymoon, my lord.
Hmm, there's stillJack.
It's all based on land, Tuck.
Can't have those knaves
from Whitehall moving in.
So it's Miss Grace Shelley.
Is she anyone, my lord?
No one. But Charles recommends her
as good breeding stock.
Family foals well.
Sires, mostly.
There's always room at the top for
brains, money or a good pair of titties.
Miss Shelley seems
well endowed, my lord.
Hmm.
Oh, the guv'nor loved this bed.
Took it all over
the world with him.
Devilish great man,
the guv'nor. Superb shot.
Did wonderful needlework too.
What do you got there, hmm?
Huh.
Oh, yes. Why not?
Hard day. Need to relax.
Might I suggest
the silk tonight, sir?
Good idea, Tuck.
For St. George, eh?
Ah, Tuck, there's no end to duty.
The law has been my life, Tuck.
Ajudge can't be unreasonable...
so how can he be a lover, eh?
Ours is a damned dry world, Tuck.
A long life
and a gray one, my lord.
The power of life and death.
Ajudge has no need for other vices.
Once you put on a black cap,
everything else tastes like wax fruit.
Uh, noose a bit high, Tuck.
Bring it down half an inch.
That's it.
Will that be all, my lord?
A whiskey and soda
in about five minutes, as usual.
Oh, Tuck,
I shan't be dining tonight.
Tell cook the trial ends tomorrow,
so I shall be wanting one of her
extra-large breakfasts in the morning.
She knows I don't like passing
sentence on an empty stomach.
- Very good, my lord.
- Thank you, Tuck.
Nothing like a good English breakfast.
Big meal of the day for the guv'nor.
Always read The Times through first...
in case there was anything
too disturbing in it.
Mother never knew what the word
"socialist" meant till she was past 50.
Remember standing
at the foot of the bed there...
telling them
I wanted to be a painter.
"The Gurneys have never
been slackers," he said.
"Earned their privileges."
Great concession
letting me study law.
Not the Gurney tradition, no.
Always the army.
# Feet, feet, feet
The boys are marching #
A little more grapeshot,
Captain Bragg.
Give 'em a touch
of the cold steel, boys.
Close. It's getting close.
I can feel her hot breath.
Wonderful, wonderful.
One slip. Wonderful.
The worms have the best of it.
They dine off the tenderest joints.
Juicy breasts, white thighs.
'Tis a far, far better thing
I do now than I've ever done.
No, sir, no bandage.
Die, my dear doctor?
Oh, that is the last thing
I shall do.
Is that you, my love?
Come to me.
Come!
Touched him. Saw her.
Towers of death and silence.
Angels of fire and ice.
Saw Alexander...
covered with honey
and beeswax in his tomb.
Felt the flowers growing over me.
Oh, a man must have vision.
How else could an English judge,
and peer of the realm...
take moonlit trips
to Marrakesh and Ponders End?
See six vestal virgins
smoking cigars?
Moses in bedroom slippers?
Naked bosoms floating past Formosa?
Just time for a quick one.
Be of good cheer, Master Ridley,
and play the man.
There's plenty of time
to win this game...
and beat the Spaniards too.
Form squares, men!
Smash the Mahdi...
and Binnie Barnes!
- Are you ready,
Your Lordship?
Bleeding bloody hell.
"I am the resurrection
and the life, "sayeth the Lord.
"He that believeth in me...
though he were dead,
yet shall he live.
And whomsoever liveth
and believeth in me...
shall never die.
Gilead is mine
and Manasses is mine.
Ephraim also
is the strength of my head.
Judah is my lawgiver...
and Moab is my washpot.
Over Edom will I cast out
my shoe...
and upon Philistria
will I triumph.
Who will lead me
into the strong city...
and who will bring me
into Edom?"
#All things
bright and beautiful #
#All creatures great and small #
#All things wise and wonderful #
#The Lord God made them all ##
An excellent service, Bertie.
Created exactly the right impression.
Damned if I could understand
a word of it.
I hardly expected you to, my boy.
Charles, I must
have a word with you.
Charles, you see,
this was a service...
which I could not have conducted
for someone who may have laid...
vi-violent hands upon himself.
Wait, Charles.
A disturbing rumor has reached me.
Tell me, did Ralph commit suicide?
Suicide? Tucker found Ralph
hanging in his bedroom...
wearing a cocked hat,
underpants and a ballet skirt.
- Does that sound like suicide?
- Oh, no, no, it does not.
But l-l-I had to be sure,
Charles. After all, he...
well, he is buried
in consecrated ground.
I must say, it's damned
odd to find Uncle Ralph...
hanging around like that
in a ballet skirt.
Charles, didn't you say Ralph
was always rather... artistic?
He was willful, stubborn,
and this time he went too far.
But he was my brother.
Well, half brother.
I will not have you
calling him artistic.
Cocked hat. Cocked hat.
You said cocked hat, Charles.
Wh-Why was Ralph
wearing a cocked hat?
Trying it on for size, obviously.
I told him
not to remain a widower.
The guv'nor didn't have
to start breeding again.
It was not pleasant
for a man of Ralph's age,
but that was something
he had to get on top of.
Underpants. Wh-Why was...
Why was he... Why was he...
Why was he in his underpants, Charles?
Well, he was in his
bedroom, wasn't he?
I thought all our troubles
would be over...
when he took a fancy
to young Grace Shelley.
- That would have solved everything.
- Yes, wouldn't it just?
I do not know
what all the bother is about.
Uncle Ralph has got an heir:
Jack, the 14th earl.
Yes, there's always Jack.
Yes, it's gonna be awkward.
Damned awkward.
Well, Ralph knew the situation.
I'm sure he's made proper arrangements.
It's simply a matter of finding out who
he's made legal guardian of the estate.
Ballet skirt!
What on earth was he doing in a ballet
skirt, Charles? Answer me that.
A Mr. Matthew Peake
to see you, Sir Charles.
Thank you, Tucker.
Come on in, Peake.
I believe you know everyone here.
I have that honor, Sir Charles.
All right, that's all, Tucker.
We're not to be disturbed.
Uh, might I suggest,
Sir Charles, that Tucker stays?
What?
Hmm, quite.
Well, Tucker, it seems you're going
to hear something to your advantage.
- Yes.
- Do sit down, Tucker.
Thank you, madame.
May I take this opportunity
to express my condolences?
Yes, yes, but do get on with it.
But, Sir Charles,
shouldn't we wait?
- I mean, His Lordship's heir.
- He's been notified.
Wasn't able to get away for the funeral,
so he's not likely to come now.
Very well.
I will inform him later.
"I, Ralph Douglas
Christopher Alexander Gurney...
of Gurney House
in the county of Bedfordshire,
hereby revoke all former wills
and codicils and declare this to be
my last will.
I appoint Mr. Matthew Peake
of 17 Brownlow Gardens, Bedfordshire,
to be the sole executor of my will.
I give and bequeath
unto my manservant, Daniel Tucker...
the sum of £30,000 free of duty."
- What?
- Thirty thousand?
There follow a number
of bequests to various charities.
I'll run through them briefly.
I bequeath the sum of £5,000 to the
Tail Wavers Registered National Charity,
£3,000 to the Bankers
Benificent Society, Limited...
Thirty-thousand smackers!
Yippee!
# I'm Gilbert the Filbert
The Knut with a "K" #
#The pride of Piccadilly
The blase roue #
# Oh, Hades, the ladies
who leave their wooden hats #
# For Gilbert the Filbert
The colonel of the Knuts ##
I say, Tucker seems a bit hit up.
So are the ways of everyone,
my boy, who is greedy of gain.
Now then, Peake,
what about the Zambezi Mission?
And what about
the Overseas Bishoprics Fund?
- Oh, never mind about them, Bertie!
- Charles, the Zambezi...
What about the estate?
"I devise and bequeath the remainder
of my estate, both real and personal,
whatsoever and wheresoever
to which I might be entitled...
or over which I have any disposing
at the time of my death...
to my beloved son,
Jack Arnold Alexander Tancred Gurney...
the 14th earl of Gurney,
for his own use absolutely. "
For his own use absolutely?
Well, who's been appointed
legal guardian?
No one.
By the rivers of Babylon,
there we sat down. Yea, we wept...
You mean Jack's free to run
the estate and everything?
Jack'll cheer up
the House of Lords.
Oh, Ralph obviously
let his personal feelings
come before his duty to his family.
Well, we'll just
have to fight. Awkward.
There's bound to be a scandal,
but there's no choice.
"If this will be contested
in any way,
the whole of my estate,
both real and personal,
is bequeathed to the charities herewith:
The Earl Haig Fund..."
- It's disgraceful!
- May God forgive him.
How bizarre.
What a macabre sense of humor.
- But, Father, I don't understand.
- You ask him to explain
before he explodes.
Blast you, there's land at stake here,
Gurney land!
- I'm completely in the fog.
- When were you not?
I don't understand what...
Ladies and gentlemen, the queen's
right trusty and well-beloved cousin,
Jack Arnold
Alexander Tancred Gurney,
14th earl of Gurney.
Hello.
I'm sorry I wasn't here before.
I received the news only yesterday.
I'm afraid our little community
is somewhat cut off.
I hope you'll forgive me.
I know he will.
I've just been to his grave.
Thank you, Uncle Charles,
for making all the arrangements.
Aunt Claire, you haven't changed.
Nor you.
You must be Dinsdale.
Yes, I suppose I must be.
How do you do?
Are you still angry
with me, Bishop?
Let me put your minds at rest.
I'm coming back to take
my place in the world.
The monastic ideal isn't easy.
I've had many broken nights.
But I'm coming back refreshed,
though hardly equipped for society.
I shall need your help, Charles.
Come. We're all one family.
Let's wash away the old sores.
If the bishop doesn't mind,
I think we should pray.
- Pray?
- For love and understanding.
Surely you pray
for love and understanding?
Every night... without success.
- You too, my son.
- I'm a Methodist.
I'm sure you're
still a Christian. Come.
For me.
Yes, my lord.
A prayer should rise up
like incense.
A prayer is an act
of faith and union.
To pray means to ask,
to beg, to plead.
A prayer is a message to heaven.
You are talking directly to God.
Express your desires freely.
Don't be afraid.
I know them already.
For I am the creator
and ruler of the universe.
Khoda, the one supreme being
and infinite personal being.
Yaweh, Shangri-Ti and EI,
the First Immoveable Mover, yea,
I am the Absolute, Unknowable,
Righteous, Eternal,
the Lord of Hosts,
King of Kings, Lord of Lords,
the Father, Son and Holy Ghost,
the One True God,
the God of love,
the Christ!
His Lordship
is a paranoid schizophrenic.
Paranoid schizophrenic?
But he's a Gurney.
Then he's a paranoid schizophrenic
Gurney who believes he's God.
But we've always been
Church of England.
His idea of the world
we live in...
is determined
solely by his feelings.
What he feels is, is.
If my nephew is bonkers, why
the blazes did you let him out?
He's a voluntary patient in a private
clinic, free to go whenever he chooses.
His father insisted on
no official certification.
If you want him detained here
permanently, you must bring him
before the Board of Control...
or get a master in lunacy
to sign an order.
Later, after we've
got a few things settled.
From a medical point of view,
a plunge into the working world
won't do the earl any harm.
Won't do him any harm?
What about the rest of us?
He's not dangerous.
Besides, I shall be on hand.
It'll be an interesting
experiment.
A harsh dose of reality
can help towards a cure.
Cure! You've had him here
for seven years. Look at him.
What have you been doing?
Exercising patience
and understanding,
something he'll need
from his family.
Yes, but why haven't you
used the knife?
Because lobotomy is irrelevant
and dangerous in this case.
He can't forget being rejected by
his mother and father at the age of 11.
They sent him away, alone...
into a primitive community of
licensed bullies and pederasts.
- You mean he went to public school?
- Exactly.
I'm aware of psychotherapy's
messy inadequacies,
but I hope that my current
research will put it all...
on a more scientific basis.
But it depends on my getting
a Guldenheim grant.
Well, never mind about that.
What aboutJack?
Remember he's suffering
from delusions of grandeur.
In reality, he's an earl,
an English aristocrat,
a member of the ruling class.
Naturally he's come to believe there's
only one person grander than that:
The Lord God Almighty Himself.
- Are you English?
- No.
Ahhh.
What's all this, then?
It's His Lordship's effects.
Sign here, please.
Christ.
If I saw a man eating grass,
I'd say he was hungry.
They'd have him certified.
They claim that snow is only
precipitation and not candied dew.
Whroom!
I'm always thinking so fast.
Whroom! Space and time exist
only within the walls of my brain.
Whroom!
What I'm trying to say...
is if the words sound queer
or funny to your ear,
a little bit jumbled up
and jivey,
sing mares eat oats and does eat oats
and little lambs eat ivy.
Ivy, ivy? Who's Ivy?
I've... I, l...
For I'm the Lord Jesus
come again in my own body...
to heal the sick,
the troubled and the ignorant.
I am he that liveth, and behold,
I am alive for everyone.
Is everybody happy?
Now hear this.
I come to proclaim
the new dispensation.
The gospel dispensation promised
only salvation to the soul.
The new dispensation
gives it to the body as well.
Jesus Christ... Mark l...
suffered to redeem the spirit...
to let the body
separate it from God.
So Satan found the place in man
and formed in him a false love,
a love of self.
Explode! Only feel.
Love can sin no more.
Most anything you touch,
see and feel glorifies my love.
Top hat is my miter,
and the walking stick my rod.
Oh, dear.
Once I get started, it's...
it's terribly difficult to stop.
- I'm so sorry.
- No, no, no, no.
It's fascinating.
How do you know you're God?
Simple. When I pray to Him,
I find I'm talking to myself.
I see. Well,
how did it happen?
How did you come
to be in this state of grace?
Like every prophet, I saw
visions, heard voices, I ran.
The voices of St. Francis, Socrates,
General Gordon and Timothy O'Leary...
all told me I was God.
It was Sunday,
August 25, at 3:32.
I heard a terrible thunderclap
and saw a body of light...
like the light from the sun
and red as fire.
I cried, "Hallelujah, Lord.
What will You do?"
And the light vanished.
Blackness and darkness...
until a great brush dipped
in light swept across the sky,
and I saw the diversity,
distinction and variety...
all clearly rolled up
into the unity...
of universal love.
- Where did all this happen?
- East Acton, outside the public urinal.
What does it feel like to be God?
Like a river flowing everywhere.
I pick up a newspaper,
and I'm everywhere...
conducting a summit conference,
dying of hunger in a Peruvian gutter,
accepting the Nobel Prize
for literature, raping a nun in Sumatra.
Under this protective outer shell...
I'm God-filled.
Your Lordship, Sir Cha...
One moment.
- What the...
- I haven't finished yet.
Sir Charles Gurney, my lord.
- Insolent clown.
- I heard that, Sir Charles.
The world's gone mad.
He'll have to go.
Hadn't we better wait? Somebody new
mightn't understand the situation.
Why is he hanging on
with 30,000 in the bank?
- Out of love.
- Love? Tucker? Rot.
There are certain matters to do
with the estate that need clearing up.
Nothing important.
Just need your signature.
- Gives me power to handle odd things.
- Of course, Uncle.
There's no need to read it.
Just take my word.
I take your word. I put on
my glasses because I feel cold.
- Where do I sign?
- Just there.
Excellent, excellent.
Easily done, eh?
"I, the undersigned,
Mycroft Holmes"?
Who's Mycroft Holmes?
Brother of Sherlock Holmes,
you illiterate oaf.
- But your name's Jack.
- Never call me that!
Jack's a word
I reject absolutely.
It's a word I put into
my galvanized pressure cooker.
Whreeep! Jack's dead.
All right, all right.
What should we call you then?
Any of the nine billion
names of God...
Your Lordship will do, orJ.C.,
Eric, Bert, Barney Entwistle.
I know exactly who I am.
- You asked for these, my lord.
- Burn them, Mr. Tucker, burn them.
But great Scott, man.
These are your coronation robes.
A lot of tradition here, my lord.
The axe must be laid
to the root, Uncle Charles.
Pride and riches, pomp and property,
all must be locked off.
Love makes all men equal.
I love you dearly, Uncle Charles.
Keep them,
if you feel so lost.
Join me in a constitutional
before lunch, Mr. Tucker?
Enjoy yourselves while I'm gone.
Relax. Have sex.
My God!
Yes?
No, no, no. Nothing.
Well? You heard
what he said, Charles.
I did.
Destroying property.
All men are equal.
Do you know what
this means, Claire?
He's not only mad, he's Bolshie!
Smell the soul dust from
the lawns and hedgerows.
Oh, what a beautiful day I've made.
Look. Soft thistle and nigella.
What?
No water in days? Sorry.
Can't think of everything.
I'll see to it.
Remember the Sunday
picnics, Mr. Tucker?
The world was all top hats
and white lace.
And the best heavy silverware.
- A snort, Your Lordship?
- Thank you.
If only I knew then who I was now.
Mmm, Mr. Grasshopper.
Of course I bless you, you cherub,
along with J. Edgar Hoover.
This is the first chance I've had
of speaking to you alone.
- Be on your guard, sir.
- You puzzle me, Mr. Tucker.
The family...
I've seen them at work before.
They got the power.
They make the rules.
Back there, they're plotting
against you like mad.
Love cannot doubt
nor faith the mustard seed.
"Plotting" is a word I put into
my galvanized pressure cooker.
Vroooom! It's gone.
Feeling persecuted is one of the signs
of paranoid schizophrenia.
Many poor wretches in Dr. Herder's
dancing academy suffered from same.
"I am being watched," they said.
"Everybody is against me," they cried.
You've set up profound negative
reactions with your Kremlin plots.
I'm leaving you.
Resist it, Mr. Tucker.
That way madness lies.
That's the thanks you get.
He's the same as all the rest.
What he doesn't want to be so
just isn't so.
No skin off my nose.
My 30,000's safe.
And I deserve
every last penny of it.
And more, and more and more!
What's keeping you then, Dan?
Be honest now, Daniel.
Fear. Fear and habit.
You get into the habit of serving.
Born a servant, see.
Son of a servant.
Family of servants.
From a nation of servants!
The first thing an Englishman does,
straight from his mother's womb,
is touch his forelock.
That's how they can tell
the wrinkled little bastard's English.
They don't know about me.
A lot they don't know
about Daniel Tucker.
Just old faithful Tucker.
Give doggie boney.
You know who I really am?
Alexei Kronstadt.
Anarchist, Trotskyist, Communist,
revolutionary. I'm a cell!
For years I've been working
for the revolution.
Spitting in the ox soup.
Peeing on the Wedgewood plates.
# So raise the scarlet banner high #
# Beneath its shade we live and die ##
J.C.!
Bert!
My lord!
Barney Entwistle.
- Tea, madame?
- Oh, uh, yes.
Tucker, what was that song
you were singing last night?
An old German hymn, madame.
"Tannenbaum."
Milk or lemon?
Lemon.
I say, where is the guv'nor?
Ah, is that tea, Tucker? Just the job.
He's in town, trying to find
a way around this mess.
- When's he back?
- Oh, any time now...
if he doesn't drop in
on his mistress first.
Hope he gets things sorted out soon.
It's getting damned awkward
in the village.
- Awkward?
- Well, they expect us Gurneys
to be in everything.
Mrs. Piggot-Jones and Mrs. Treadwell
and all the other old girls,
they thought it would be
a splendid idea if the new earl
was to open the fete on Sunday.
I hardly dare ask, but naturally
you told them it would be impossible?
- Milk or lemon?
- Lemon, please, Tucker.
Yes, but, you see,
I am the prospective parliamentary
candidate for the division,
and I have to watch
my step with them.
I couldn't very well say that
he was "non-compis," could I?
- Well, where is he now?
- Up there.
Look what you've done.
Never get tea stains out.
Show some consideration.
- He... It's yogi, isn't it?
- Tea, my lord?
It's no use, Tucker. I've tried.
He's asleep. Dead to the world.
His body sleeps, but his
divinity is always watching.
Milk, please.
Any toasted muffin?
Yes.
- Shall I bring 'em up?
- No, I'll be right down.
It is yogi, isn't it?
Or a form of yogi?
Don't give me another
headache, Dinsdale.
You look ill, Mr. Tucker.
Bed, Mr. Tucker, right now.
Thank you, my lord.
Welcome, Dinsdale.
Yes. I mean, how are you?
Sometimes my spirits sink below
the high water mark in Palestine,
but I'm adjusting gradually.
For what I am about to receive,
may I make myself truly thankful.
Soon I must be moving on.
Sail away, Lalaha, New Jersey,
Port Said and Crewe.
First, I shall command the Pope
to consecrate a planeload
of contraceptives...
for the priest-ridden Irish.
Arise, shine,
for my light is come...
and the glory of the Lord
is risen upon thee.
# Here is the rag
See how it goes #
# Down on your heels
Up on your toes #
#That's the way to do
the varsity drag #
Piggot-Jones and Mrs. Treadwell.
#You can pass many a class
whether you're dumb or wise #
# If you all answer the call
when your professor cries #
- Everybody!
- # Down on the heels, up on the toes #
# Stay after school
Learn how it goes #
# Everybody do the varsity #
# Everybody do the varsity
Everybody do the varsity #
# Everybody do the varsity drag ##
Welcome, ladies.
I'm the new lord.
- You know Lady Claire
and my cousin Dinsdale.
Oh, ladies, this is a surprise.
But delightful,
really delightful.
Dear Sir Dinsdale,
do forgive us for dropping in.
We thought we'd just take a stroll
out to the manor. It's only six miles.
We've come to try to persuade His
Lordship to open our little church fete.
Do say yes, my lord.
I always say yes,
whatever question.
How splendid!
If you'll excuse us,
we have a lot to do.
Stay to tea.
You be mother.
Go and see if your father's back.
Tell me, ladies, what do I do
at this gala opening of yours?
Do I charm bracelets, swing
lead, break wind, pass water?
Yes... No!
You'll make a speech.
On what text, Mother Superior?
Oh, we leave that to the speaker.
It can be any topic
of current interest:
Hanging, immigration
or the stranglehold of the unions.
But I've always felt the speeches should
be about Britain and our way of life.
- Britain?
- Mm-hmm.
A fly-blown speck in the North Sea.
You can't kick the natives
in the back streets of Calcutta anymore.
Oh, he's joking again.
Aren't you, my lord?
I'm not laughing, Pamela,
and we can't stay here, Lady Claire.
- Then for Christ's sake, go.
- Oh, don't go for my sake.
Oh. Delicious. Homegrown?
No, I bought them.
I mean, they go with...
Ladies, I've decided to begin
my second ministry at your gathering.
Last time I preached the Word in holy
Galilee, I spoke in parables. Mistake!
Now I must speak plain.
God is love.
- Love?
- Love.
As water is wet, as jade is hard,
as bread is life, so God is love.
Mrs. Pamela Treadwell, can you love?
Can your blood bubble, flesh melt,
thighs twitch, heart burst for love?
Your Lordship, I'm a married woman...
Remember the commandment I gave you:
"Love one another as I love you."
Stay back. My husband
is a master of hounds.
Fill your hearts! Let your souls
dance, your eyes sparkle!
Be bird happy!
- Oh, what is it?
- A Watusi walking stick.
Big people, the Watusi.
Ladies, come back.
I'll fill your bodies.
- Oh, I'm awfully sorry.
Have you seen my father?
I am and the resurrection
and the light!
Will you kindly stop?
What are those two doing here?
Who's the idiot responsible?
Oh, Dinsdale, of course.
Who else?
You'll have to do something
about that boy.
Well, he'll soon be off our hands.
Old Barrington-Cochran's on his last
legs. That'll mean a by-election.
Well, what about Mrs. Piggot-Jones?
Mrs. Treadwell?
Oh, they'll say the new earl's
eccentric or something.
Better still, heavy drinker.
Be not afraid! It is I!
But,J.C., look,
I know who you are.
But maybe they don't.
And we... I mean, that is, us...
Oh, let's go and have
a glass of sherry.
Well?
What did Sir Humphrey say?
Oh, he gave me a lot of expensive
legal "fal-de-roll."
But as things stand,
there's no way of breaking the will.
- So?
- There's only one possible solution.
- A male heir.
- A what!
Well, ifJack had a son, Sir Humphrey
says we could easily get him certified.
Because then, everything
would pass to the heir.
We could manage the estate
till the boy came of age,
and that way everything
would remain in the family.
Oh, brilliant.
A small point.
But before he can have an heir,
our lunatic nephew has to be married.
Exactly.
And the sooner the better.
Yes, but don't you understand
that these two ladies
are extremely important to me?
Well, I sincerely hope, Jack, that
when they next come down to the manor,
you'll be a trifle more courteous.
- Now, be subtle.
- Oh, right.
Ah, we were just talking
about you and marriage.
- We think you should take a wife.
- Who from?
I'm sure we can find you
a suitable young goddess.
What?
Oh, most appropriate, eh?
- I can't marry a second time.
- You're already married?
August 28th
in the year of me, 1964.
This wife of yours...
What's her name?
- Marguerite Gauthier.
- French?
- Yes.
- Gauthier. Marguerite Gauthier.
Isn't that
"The Lady of the Camellias"?
You knew her too?
Wonderful.
And that's the tune, isn't it?
Naturally I came as soon as I could.
We do appreciate it.
Your nephew is not married
to the Lady of the Camellias.
He has no wife. But he believes
he has, which is the same thing.
Why did he pick on
Marguerite Gauthier?
Another martyr for love.
His delusions are all of a piece.
Marguerite is the only
person he trusts.
Why does he keep on about love?
Because he wants us
all to love goodness.
To love goodness is to love God.
To love God is to love
the 14th Earl of Gurney.
That's very clever,
but is it the truth?
Ah, don't come to me
for the truth, only explanations.
Can I ask you one more question?
If it's as revealing as the others.
Why does he hate being called Jack?
Because it's his real name.
Naturally he rejects it violently.
If ever he answers
to the name ofJack,
then you know he's
on the road to sanity.
Doctor, how are my questions
revealing?
The first one you asked me
was about love.
This is our Tucker, Dr. Herder.
He's been with the family for 40 years.
Man and sniveling boy, sir.
How do you find
the new earl, Tucker?
By sniffing. He's a Gurney.
A real Gurney.
You don't find him odd?
Odd?
- Soda?
- Yes.
Yes, odd, peculiar.
Oh, you mean nutty?
Yes, he's a nutcase.
Most of these titled fleabags are.
Rich nobs and priveleged arseholes
can afford to be bonkers.
They're living in a dreamworld,
aren't they, sir?
Life's made too easy for 'em.
They don't have to earn a livin',
so they do just what they want to.
We'd all be pretty crackers
if we went around doing just
what we wanted to, wouldn't we?
- Eh?
- Yes.
Yes, I suppose...
The late earl
left Tucker £30,000.
Since then, he's been very outspoken.
Lady?
No, thank you.
Waste not, want not.
Mind having a look at my back, Doctor?
Lumbago acting up again.
Lady of the Camellias
by Alexandre Dumas.
Camille.
It's La Traviata,
the opera by Verdi.
It's all the same woman: Marguerite
Gauthier, a figure of romance.
My dear chap, you've proved my point
ipso facto. A divine figure of romance.
Yeah.
- Well, what a pleasant surprise.
- How are you?
In the middle of a debate
on the existence of my wife, Marguerite.
- Pray continue, Dinsdale Gurney.
- I give up.
You did say it'd be impossible
to convince him, Doctor.
Do you see? It's a play.
The Lady of the Camellias.
- It's fiction.
- It's a biography of my Marguerite,
affectionately known
as La Dame aux Camellias.
You aren't married.
The woman doesn't exist.
Oh, come on! You'll be saying I'm not
God, Christ and the Holy Ghost next!
Well, you're not. I mean, God
wouldn't be so ridiculous waving
his arms around like a maniac,
dressed in a white suit
and a red carnation.
The prophet Ezekiel lay 300 days on his
left side and 40 days on his right.
He cut his hair and divided it in three
parts. The first part he burnt,
the second he chopped into pieces,
the third he scattered to the wind.
It was all a sign
of something more important.
All right, if you're God,
reveal your godhead.
No, no, no, no.
A miracle.
Show us a miracle.
- Here's a miracle.
- What?
This hand...
this city network of tissues,
nerves, muscles, ligaments,
carpals and metacarpals,
phalanges.
And what about
the hairy-nosed wombat?
I don't mean
that sort of miracle.
I mean a proper miracle
like the loaves and the fishes.
Oh, those.
You see ten billion million
miracles a day,
yet you want your conjuring tricks,
your pretty flimflams.
Well, I can't raise Lazarus again.
He's decomposed.
- So bring me that table.
- What are you going to do?
A grade-one Galilee miracle.
Now, instead of raising Lazarus,
I'll raise you a table.
- What? That table?
- Ten feet.
Not with the aid of mirrors or
crippled midgets behind black curtains,
but by the power of love.
- Just love?
- It moves mountains...
and makes the puny weed
split the rock.
Believe in me.
In loving goodness.
Raise yourself up.
Rise up.
Slowly... slowly...
rise up.
One foot... two...
three... four.
Slowly... slowly.
Five... six...
seven... eight...
nine, ten!
There! The table floats
ten feet in space!
I see it!
It's a bloody miracle!
- Drunken lout!
- It didn't rise. There it is.
Tucker saw, believed!
- Did you see it, Doctor?
- No.
Into my galvanized
pressure cooker.
There's no miracle.
There's no wife. She doesn't exist.
She's fiction. Part of a play,
part of an opera.
She's not flesh and blood.
She's not real.
Marguerite.
How dare you bring that woman here!
- You should be very grateful
to Miss Shelley.
- Grace Shelley is your mistress.
- Miss Shelley
is just a hardworking girl.
- On her back.
First you try and pawn her
off on your own brother.
Ralph needed a wife.
He took a fancy to young Miss Shelley.
Well, that didn't work, so you tried
her with the son. It's incestuous.
Don't talk about incest, madam.
I remember yourJeremy Gore.
You went to school with the father,
but you went ahead and seduced the son.
- That is incest, madam.
- Ohhh.
Well, why the hell
didn't you warn us?
No time. After what
that "trick cyclist" told me,
I knew we'd never
convinceJack he wasn't married
or that Marguerite didn't exist.
So I telephoned Grace
and explained the position.
She got hold of theatrical togs
and came down here.
She put up
a first-rate show, I thought.
Well, it had impact.
Anyway, Jack believed
that she was Marguerite.
All she has to do now is convince him
he has to marry her again.
Dr. Herder is furious.
Furious? He's got no right
to be furious. He's not family.
He could make things difficult
by having Jack declared insane
before he's produced an heir.
Damned Kraut. You'll have to keep
your eye on him, my dear.
I'm gonna have me hands full
getting Grace married and pregnant.
What an entrance!
Beautiful, but beautiful!
The looks on your faces!
I should have stuck to the classics.
Always said I had the voice.
Oh, this dress is tight.
I feel constipated.
Your flower is wilting, dear.
Can't be. It's wax.
Careful your husband-to-be
doesn't eat it for breakfast.
You're right, Charlie boy.
She is an ice-cold biddy.
Oh, she's too clever
by half, that woman.
But I get things done my way.
She doesn't know what she wants.
Oh, but I do, Charlie boy.
Lady Grace.
Lady Grace Gurney,
the countess of Gurney.
Now, look here, Grace,
you mustn't call me Charlie boy.
- We've gotta be careful.
- Oh, if that's what you want.
Oh, it's not what I want.
It's what it has to be.
Oh, I'm very fond of you, my dear.
Yeah, well, you've a damned
funny way of showing it.
First you push me into the arms
of your half-dead half brother,
and then onto his loony son.
Well, I'd make any sacrifice
for the sake of the family.
Now, are you sure
you can handle the situation?
Tricky and all, marrying
a man who thinks he's God.
Happens all the time.
Look, there he is.
Well, better get
the show on the road.
Oh, where's me lousy camellia?
Oh, I'll be glad
to get out of this clobber.
Oh! No wonder
she was dying of consumption.
Now, be careful.
Oh, don't worry, Charlie bo...
Charles.
I've got too much at stake
to blow it.
Damned plucky filly.
I say, Father,
Mother's just told me...
that this Lady of the Camellia
woman is just a fake.
Well, I mean, I know thatJ.C.
Is as batty as a moorhen,
but this just isn't
playing the game, sir.
Game? What game?
This is no game, sir.
This is real!
My dream's made flesh.
Sorry.
I don't speak French.
Oh. German?
Italian? Yiddish?
No. English.
English?
Should have said so before.
Nothing to be ashamed of.
Hard language to master.
But we can't play this
love scene with mere words.
Love scene? What, now?
Love isn't just for one season.
Tweet. Tweet.
Tweet?
Cuckoo.
Anything you care for?
The Grand Canyon?
A disused banana factory?
Absolution?
- A white wedding.
- Will Tuesday suit you?
- You deserve a big kiss.
- Not here in the garden.
Last time I was kissed in a garden,
it turned out rather awkward.
Oh, butJudas was a man.
Yes. Strange business.
- Who are you?
- A woman.
Descended from Eve?
No. Doorstep.
I'm an orphan.
We'll be orphans
together, Marguerite.
Call me Grace,
as I don't speak French.
Grace. A good name.
It means "the gift of faith."
And that's what I have in you.
I'm holding you to that wedding.
Hold hard.
You'll be my queen of queens.
I'll be satisfied with
"Lady Grace Gurney."
And I say unto you, thou
shalt love the Lord thy God...
with all thy heart and
all thy soul and all thy mind.
I do.
Oh, I'm happy.
I'm the sunshine man,
the driver of the gravy train.
Choo, choo, choo.
It's so simple for me.
Paradise is just a smiling face.
- What's it for you?
- For me? Paradise?
A fireplace, a cozy room.
- A little nest.
- That nestles.
#Where the roses bloom #
# Sweet Gracey and me #
#And baby makes three #
#We're going to our #
# Blue heaven #
#When whippoorwills call #
#And evening is nigh #
#We hurry to our blue heaven #
#A turn to the right #
#A little white light #
#Will lead you to our #
# Blue heaven #
#You'll see a smiling face
a fireplace #
#A cozy room #
#A little nest that nestles
where the roses bloom #
# Sweet Gracey and me #
#And baby makes three #
#We're going to our blue heaven #
What are you looking at?
- Beauty?
- Oh?
Yes, butJack...
I mean J. C... I mean Bert...
Oh, hang it.
You're still a Gurney.
Now, listen, that camellia woman
is called Grace Shelley.
Close friend of my father's. He put her
onto it, made her dress like that.
It's absolutely ridiculous.
He wants to marry you off.
Well, Mother's in it too.
And I expect old Tuck
knows all about it.
- Everybody except me.
- Stop!
You're making me a stunted dwarf,
a deformed midget, a crippled newt!
- What are you doing down there?
- It's your negative "insinuendos."
- Insinuendo?
- Insinuendo is insinuation
towards innuendo...
brought on by increased
negativism...
out of a negative reaction
to your father's positivism.
I don't know what the devil you're going
on about, but I resent your attitude.
I'm only telling you
about Grace Shelley.
She's my righteous,
ideal, planned wife!
Don't forget. Apart from being God,
Christ and the Holy Ghost,
I'm also an L.O.B.,
D.F.C. And A.D.C.
You're dealing with the big one!
I've told aged Tucker!
Who... Same thing!
Injecting me with his Kremlin
plots, negative microbes!
I said verbatim,
being persecuted
is paranoid schizophrenia!
Wretched Dr. H. Suffered from same!
I watched.
They fight against me.
Where are the signs...
aiming for...
Herder's dancing academy?
I am being everybody but Christ.
No, no, no, Charles.
I will not solemnize any marriage,
even of my own nephew, during
the period from Advent Sunday...
till eight days after Epiphany.
So, Charles,
it must be Tuesday the 12th,
8:00 a.m., private chapel,
o- ordinary license...
Charles, Charles, I have
grave misgivings, grave misgivings.
- Misgivings? AboutJack?
- Mmm.
No, no, no.
About the bride, Miss Shelley!
Charles,
who is she, hmm, hmm?
What is she?
Ch-Charles, look, I fear, I fear
that she may be using this marriage...
merely to enhance
her social position.
I hear that she says she's
some sort of an entertainer.
I will vouch for Grace Shelley.
- Mmm?
- Mmm!
My husband's an idiot.
That's not my concern.
The Earl is no longer under my care.
That charade with Miss Shelley
made me feel an absolute fool.
And I don't care
to underestimate myself.
I apologize,
but Charles had some idea...
thatJack might accept her if she
dressed up as the Lady of the Camellias.
Sometimes it's very easy to forget...
Sir Charles occupies a position
of responsibility and power.
You know he's on the board
of the Guldenheim Research Foundation?
Yes, he mentioned
you were asking for a grant.
It's only a nominal
£130,000 for a study...
of paranoid,
schizophrenic rats.
Charles, need we be so hasty?
Charles,
God, in His infinite mercy,
has seen fit
to cloud our nervous senses.
But he will recover.
He will recover, Charles.
God is merciful.
Yes, you must believe that, Charles!
God is merciful
in spite of all appearances.
We cannot wait
upon God's mercy, Bertie!
Everything is going to pot.
Dr. Herder at least.
- Herder?
- Herder.
- Is he English?
- No.
Oh. Hmm!
We insert fine silver wires
into the rat's midbrain.
- That rat's behavior
is then controlled...
by the strength of the current
passing through them.
By pressing above them and stimulating
one area of the midbrain,
the rat is made to feel threatened.
It attacks any rat in sight.
There's really no threat,
- but the midbrain
can't tell the difference.
Roughly the same thing happens
with human paranoids.
But an unknown area
of the brain stimulated,
and they feel threatened
without cause.
Naturally, men aren't rats.
Only a man would say so.
Our next step is to conduct
similar experiments...
on humans' brains.
I see. Today, rats;
tomorrow, the world.
Who will you wire for vision?
First of all, myself, naturally.
I see.
And if I press a button,
you'll feel fear... love?
Love? No.
Desire. Yes.
What, by pressing a little button?
Oh.
Think of the risk, Doctor.
Oh, there is only one commandment
a doctor need ever worry about:
Thou shalt not... advertise.
My heart...
rises with the sun.
I'm purged of doubts
and negative innuendos.
Today,
I want to bless everything.
Bless the crawfish
with its scuttling walk.
Bless the trout,
pilchard and periwinkle.
Bless Ted Smoothey
of 22 East Hackney Road.
Bless the mealy redpoll,
the black-gloved wallaby
and W.C. Fields...
who's dead but lives on.
Bless the snotty-nosed giraffe.
Bless the buffalo.
Bless the Society of Women Engineers.
Bless the pygmy hippos.
Bless the mighty cockroach.
Bless me!
Today's my wedding day!
Wake up, Bertie!
Come, Bertie.
Get on with it.
D- D-Dearly beloved,
we are gathered here together,
in the sight of God...
Get on with it, Bertie!
A- A-A-And in the face
of this company,
t- t-t-t-to join together
this man and this woman...
in holy matrimony,
which is an honorable estate...
Instituted by me
in the time of man's innocence.
- Get on, Bertie!
- Therefore,
if there be any in this company
who can show just cause...
why these two
may not be joined together,
let him speak now
or forever hold his peace.
Load of British jelly-meat whiskers!
Piddling, half-dead helots.
Quiet, man!
Show some respect!
I always show respect, sir.
That's what I'm paid for.
No one can say
I don't show respect.
Now come on, Bertie.
Now I require and ch...
I require and charge you both...
that if either of you
know of any impediment...
why ye may not lawfully
be joined together,
that you "de" now...
you "de"...
Ye do now confess it.
Yes, I'm afraid
I do know an impediment.
But it's only a rhetorical
question, like all the others
in the wedding service.
Oh, 'tis no good
glossing o'er the fact...
certain Roman Catholic knackers think
I'm already married to the Virgin Mary.
We're not concerned
with what other people think,
especially Roman Catholics.
Get on with it, Bertie. Come on now.
Wilt thou, wilt thou take
this woman to thy wedded wife,
to live together i-i-in holy wedlock
under God's ordinance?
W- W-Wilt thou love her?
From the bottom of my soul
to the tip of my penis,
like the sun in its brightness,
the moon in its glory,
no breeze stirs
that doesn't bear my love.
- Come on, Bertie! Come on!
- Charles, blasphemy.
- But will you love me?
- I will.
Wilt thou take this man to thy...
- To live together in holy matrimony...
- I will!
- Who giveth his...
- I do!
- Oh, you.
- Come on, Bertie.
- Get a move on!
- R-R-Repeat after me.
I, l...
J.C., take thee, Grace Shelley,
to my wedded wife.
I,J.C., the holy,
flying roller, the morning star,
take thee Marguerite,
called Grace Shelley, because she
doesn't speak French, to my wedded wife.
Where are you going, Bertie?
- Repeat after me.
- Oh, I know the lines.
I, Grace Shelley, take theeJ.C.
To my wedded husband...
better, worse, richer, poorer,
this day, sickness, health,
I plight thee my troth.
Plight thee my troth, yes.
Well, inasmuch as you
are now bound in holy wedlock,
l- l-I now pro-pronounce thee
man and wife!
God join together, no man,
no man put asunder,
in the name of the Father, the Son...
and Holy, the Holy, the Holy Ghost.
God have mercy on me.
A bit tatty, Jeeves.
No guests, no reception,
two plates of curled up sandwiches...
and a deformed wedding cake.
It's not my fault, Your Ladyship.
"Your Ladyship." That's better.
I'll watch 'em creep
and crawl at Harrods.
We thought you'd like
a nice, quiet affair.
Huh! Quiet's right! And what about
a toast to the newlyweds or something?
- You know.
- All right.
Here's to long life and happiness
for the bride and groom.
- To the bride and groom!
- Thank you.
In reply, I name this ship
"Loving Kindness."
May I keep her
and all who sail in her.
Ah, you should have seen
the late earl's wedding, m'lady.
Five hundred guests,
the creme de menthe.
Wastrels all.
May their carbonized bones rot in hell!