Some drink, drink, drink, drink, drink
Do you hear us about
You lazy lout
We want some beer
We want some wine
Pour out the wine
and drink and drink till morning
for drinking is divine
It is divine
Pour out the wine
and drink and drink till morning
And drink
for drinking is divine
We want some wine
and drink till morning
And drink and drink till morning
We want some wine
Good day, my friends
Good day
A chair, a glass of wine
and a pipe
Excuse me, Master
if you don't mind
I'll sit and drink and smoke
same as you
Fair's fair
- How true
Make a place for two
Come on, make a place for two
Nott' e giorno mal dormire
The devil take you and Mozart
At once, sir
What makes you so put out
Indeed we never would have known you
Now what on earth
brought that about
Frozen earth all dead or dying
There in the snow buried deep
And outside where he was lying
The sight of a drunkard asleep
That's true
Seeing him there
a craving seized my brain
For drinking
Yes, drinking
Then do the same
Lie down there in the ditch
- And for a pillow
- The pavement
- And for a roof
- The sky
- What about sheets
- The rain
Are you having nightmares, Hoffmann
The first song is yours then
Don't make us ask again
The chorus leave to us
Yes, leave that to us
Right
Choose something that's gay
Sing the song of the rat
No, we're all sick of that
I know
We'll have to have
the one about Kleinzach
Oh, yes, come on
We'll have the song about Kleinzach
Right
Here's Kleinzach
Now long ago
the duke of renowned Eisenach
The duke of Eisenach
Employed a tiny clown
with the name of Kleinzach
He had the name Kleinzach
He wore a busby big and black
And his noddle
his noddle did go crick-crack
Crick-crack
So that's
So that's Kleinzach
- Crick-crack
So that's
Kleinzach
He also had a paunch
quite as stout as a stack
As stout as any stack
His feet looked just like twigs
sticking out of a sack
Like twigs in any sack
He capered like a jumping jack
And his knees cracked together
And went click-clack
Click-clack
So that's
So that's Kleinzach
- Click-clack
So that's
Kleinzach
Now what words
What words to paint those features
Now what words to paint those features
Now what words
What words to paint those features
To paint those features
Past comparing
She is there
Fair
Fair as dawn of the day
When love first bade me dare
to leave the home of my youth
And in my heart to swear
I would fly far away
to a world we could share
Oh, her hair
Oh, her hair with its curls entwining
Shed a warmth where the snow
of her bosom was shining
Her eyes, her eyes
unfathomed lakes of blue
Spread around where she trod
A reflection as true
And as our pageant car
By cupids all attended
Sped on with ne'er a jar
Her voice with triumph blended
While mortals held their breath
Sang out with heavenly art
She sang with heavenly art
Till echoes melt in death
Resounding
Through
My heart
Oh, Stella
Three women blended as one
Three souls
United as one
True artist
Tender maiden
And courtesan
My mistress
No, no, rather say my three
Three magic visions fair to see
Of all my life they claimed a part
Would you hear
the three tales of my folly of love
Yes, yes, yes
Now what do you mean
three magic visions
Your pipe
And by the time
you have to light it up again
You'll know why
when all has been said
Even you, who in this tale
of my heart and its pain
Showed good sense
and still kept your head
Good sirs
the curtain is going to rise
Let it rise then
- For that we don't care a pin
- No, we don't care a pin
Right you are
Now we're in our glory
While we drink
listen to a story
At the clouds of our smoke we gaze
And see dreams in the growing haze
And see dreams
In the growing haze
I'll begin then
Begin then
Here's the story of the first
Olympia was her name
There, sleep in peace
Aha
Modest and sweet and clever
Through her I shall endeavor
to recoup the whole sum at a stroke
That I lost
when my backer went broke
Yes, but what of Coppelius
I swear he sits up nights
thinking up ways to blackmail me
By filing a claim against me
for inventor's rights
Words fail me
Well, I'm glad he's not here
Ah, come in
Sir, good day
An early hour to call, sir
Tell me, sir, you're a pupil
Not worth your skill at all, sir
You're too modest, I should say
Pay to art no more attention
Learn mechanical invention
Then a degree
Might come your way
There's my daughter to see, sir
She's a heavenly sight
Yes, science is always right
do you hear
Olympia's very, very dear
First his science, then his daughter
What can be the connection
Cochenille, come to me, sir
Go turn up all the lights
And the ch-cham-p-pagne
Leave that to me
Stay here, my boy
I'll return to you straight
So be it
To my fate I bid defiance
I will study naught but science
Let knowledge come in any guise
I must deserve
The one I treasure
In my heart I feel there's a measure
Of the stuff that makes men wise
She is there
If I dared
She's there
Now could I dare
Oh, how fair
How divinely fair
Ah, could we two together
Know the same tomorrow
The same remembered past
We could share every joy
Could share in every sorrow
Yes, every sorrow
we could share to the last
May then
Oh, may my dreaming
In you reflect the morn
Let clouds of glory streaming
Proclaim that love is born
'Tis I, Coppelius
Now look out
Very gently
A man
Who can he be
What's he eyeing so intently
Our Olympia, eh
Why not
Their Olympia, eh
Young fellow
My dear sir
Hears not a jot
Dear sir
Yes, what
Oh, Coppelius, sir, is my name
As a friend
I Signor Spalanzani attend
You see all these barometers
And hygrometers and thermometers
Very cheap, but pay in cash
and you'll agree you've not been rash
These glasses in a flash
turn all as black as a sweep
Or else as white as whitening
As white as whitening
Dark as night, dark as night
Bright as lightning
I've got eyes, actual eyes, alive
And eyes a-blazing
I have eyes people prize
for hidden hearts are they appraising
And at times it may befall
A heart they can present
To those who've got none at all
I've got eyes, actual eyes, alive
And eyes a-blazing
I've got eyes
Lovely eyes
See
Would you try the heart of a woman
Whether kind or whether inhuman
Would you rather have the knack
To see it white when it is black
Look and you will see
all you want to see
Try all my eyes
I've eyes alive and eyes a-blazing
I've eyes the heart appraising
Try out my eyes
Is that true
Well, try
Here, then
That's three ducats
Gracious heaven
Power divine
Oh, the charms
that so brightly round her shine
Three ducats
My love, can this be true
For three ducats
Oh, but why snatch away
That heavenly vision
of delight and of love
Oh, you
Dear professor
Well what
It had all been agreed
- Not in writing
- Still
No jesting
A fortune you will realize
And half will be mine
Must I keep on protesting
Olympia's mine
- Oh, no, she's got my eyes
Less loud
Her eyes
Yes, he's right
for I don't know how they work
But I'll fix it
Yes
Would you like
a further 500 ducats
Just sign for me that you're resigning
Her eyes
with all the rest of her designing
Then I'll give you a check
On the house of Elias
Elias
Splendid reputation
Whatever's this negotiation
All right
Agreed
Come on, come on
My friend indeed
I rather think it is he who will pay
By the way, a suggestion
Marry off Olympia now
That young fellow there, I vow
Very soon will pop the question
My friend indeed
That is science, my friend
Lord
He's quite demented
Oh, sir, the g-guests
w- wait to be presented
None but our host
I do declare
None, I do declare
Entertains with such a flair
With such a flair
Wealth and good taste
combine to greet us
All combine to greet us
Sheer perfection
Sheer perfection through and through
Now, Signor Spalanzani, do
Allow your daughter to meet us
They do say none was made so neat
They do say
And none so faultless in their graces
- We'll not be allowed
- We'll not be allowed to eat
Till she's seen us face-to-face
and shown her paces
None but our host, I do declare
None, I do declare
Entertains with such a flair
With such a flair
Wealth and good taste
combine to greet us
All combine to greet us
Sheer perfection
Sheer perfection through and through
You will not have to wait, my friends
a moment more
At last we'll see close to
the pride of all his treasure
That he does cherish
past all measure
Be quiet
Here she comes
And now, ladies and gentlemen
Your wish I am granting
My daughter Olympia
Enchanting
A lovely pair of eyes
Her figure is perfection
A wonderful complexion
There's nothing more to add
A lovely pair of eyes
Her figure is perfection
A wonderful complexion
In fact she isn't bad
Who sees her must adore her
And heaven bow before her
A great success, my dear
She's really not so bad
A lovely pair of eyes
Her figure is perfection
A wonderful complexion
There's nothing more to add
In fact
In fact she isn't bad
She isn't bad
In fact
In fact she isn't bad
- She isn't bad
She isn't bad
She is not bad
Not bad
And now, ladies and gentlemen
Flattered by all you say
And besides, eager to earn
your critical praise without delay
My child, keen to fall in
with your slightest caprices
Will, if you wish
Parade all her technical pieces
Sing a song for you all
And supporting her voice
high soprano
I'll play you the guitar or piano
Or the harp
So make your choice
The harp, sir
Very good
Cochenille, be quick
and bring us here the harp
Yes, the harp
my daughter sings to
To hear her voice
What joy
What things love finds to say
Come now
Away with your dismay and be gay
Yes, yes
Th-Th-Th-There
My friends, no more delay
N- No m-m-m-more delay
No more delay
Birds in woodland ways are winging
Shines the morning star above
Now all maiden hearts are ringing
With love
For all are in love
Now that is the song to be singing
And that is my song of love
My song of love
- Now that is the song to be singing
- That's the song she's always singing
- And that is my song of love
- That's her song
Her song of love
- My song of love
- That is her song
- Of love
New delights can love discover
Joyous lark or sighing dove
Broken hearts can soon recover
With love
For all are in love
Now that is the song for a lover
And that is my song of love
My song of love
- Now that is the song for a lover
- That's the song she's always singing
- And that is my song of love
- That's her song
Her song of love
- My song of love
- That is her song
- Of love
Her reputation's well deserved
Oh, what scales
What scales
Now will you all look for your places
For the supper now is served
Supper at last
That is grand
Unless you expected a dance before
No, no, the supper must be respected
And then strike up the band
Strike up the band
It's just as I planned
Will you allow me
After she has rested
she'll give you a dance
Yes, yes
There you are
She'll obey
Would you mind if now I suggest
That you should stay in here with her
while we're away
It's an honor
Now we'll see what he will find to say
She's not eating today
No
Food she finds too coarse to mention
What's that
That
Pure invention
Yes, my boy
S- S-S-Supper is served
Supper at last is served
Now it's served
None but our host, I do declare
None, I do declare
Entertains with such a flair
With such a flair
None but our host, I do declare
None, I do declare
Entertains with such a flair
So now they've gone away at last
And you are near me
Quite, quite alone
Oh, may I hope that you will hear me
Olympia
Oh, my love
Let me gaze for a while
And dazzled by your charms
Let me bask in your smile
Yes
Did I hear a sigh
escape your lips so tender
Or was it but a dream
my fever does engender
No
Gentle sigh
a pledge of love begun
You now are mine
Our hearts forevermore are one
Can you feel, my love
That joy ever springing
From a heart's silent replies
Two souls
One in their scheming
With a sweep
they are winging
Till we ascend the skies
May then
Oh, may my dreaming
In you reflect the morn
May clouds of glory streaming
Proclaim that love is born
Oh, my dear, do but stay
Why must you leave me so
Tell me
Why turn away
Then I'll go where you go
Oh, good lord
don't get so excited
Come on now and have a good feed
Oh, Nicklaus, my love is requited
My love
Love divine
Oh, indeed
If you knew
what against her was cited
What can be cited
What
- That she's a dead thing
- Great heavens
- Or never was alive
Oh, Nicklaus, my love is requited
My love
Love divine
The cheat
The rogue
It's ruination
Elias can't meet his obligation
So, then all in good time
I shall find out the way
to be revenged
I'm fleeced
Me
I'll make someone pay
Let the dancing proceed
The opening
They're repeating
How the waltz sets our hearts a-beating
Let the gentleman lead you so
Now go
Yes
Now she's dancing
How entrancing
Never could art such grace impart
Smiling, smiling
How beguiling
Light as the air
Now here, now there
Now she's dancing
How entrancing
Never could art such grace impart
Smiling, smiling
How beguiling
Light as the air
Now here, now there
Olympia, no
Someone detain her
Why should we be expected to go
He's in trouble now
What could be plainer
Now what the devil
There they go
Now go slow
That's right
No more, no more
dear daughter
You've had enough today
No more, no more
dear daughter
Go and escort her
back where you know
S- S-So then
S- So then
So
No
What do you think they're saying
Such compliments we're paying
There's nothing more to add
She's not too bad
No, she's not too bad
- Is he dead
- No
In falling
only his glasses came to grief
He revives
What relief
Truly appalling
He revives
What relief
- Truly appalling
- What
- The spectacle maker- there