I could be happy with you
If you could be happy with me
I'd be contented
Here, Pol.
00:00:22,800-> 00:00:23,724
Here.
What about my money?
-Where's my baby?
-She's over there!
Put it on the slate!
I'll get the sack
if they're late again.
Hurry up, then.
Just along there.
Good afternoon,
Mr. and Mrs. Parkhill.
Good afternoon, Len.
All for Mrs. P,
I'm afraid.
-Must be bills, then.
-Thank you, darling.
My man sent me
maintenance order, Len?
I'll have a look now.
Old gin, old pals
and jolly good company
Disgusting!
For you, dear.
Are you selling by post now, love?
__
Hi there, gorgeous.
I suppose I should be thankful
for small mercies.
-Anything?
-Nothing for you this morning.
They are all in yet, Len?
All in except Rita and Tommy.
Oh, he won't be long.
You can hear him coming a mile off.
Practising, practising.
Don't you ever stop dancing?
Hey, toots. I'm in training
for my second big break.
You're kidding.
What was the first?
Didn't you ever hear
of the baby toast of Broadway?
Tiny Tom, the tapping tot?
Grew up, didn't you?
Overnight.
And who can use a Tiny Tod
who's 10 feet tall?
How about Barnum and Bailey?
They already had one
and he was a bearded lady.
So I booked a one-way ticket
on a cattle boat to merry old England.
Blimey!
From Broadway to Portsmouth?
-There's a comedown in it.
-A stepping-stone, toots.
A mere stepping-stone to stardom.
Not bad!
-Here's your stuff, love.
-Ta.
Cheese and chutney, right?
Thanks, Pol. Put it on the slate.
All right.
Ta.
Who sent me the flowers?
I forget.
I bought one apple too many.
Would you like it?
No, thanks.
I've had one already.
Pol,
I'll have it if it's going begging.
All right, love.
You have it.
Ta.
Five minutes, everyone.
Afternoon. Here is your gin.
Don't you knock when
you enter the star's dressing room?
Sorry.
They didn't have smoked salmon
so I got salmon shrimp, all right?
Paste? Sure you don't expect
Mrs. P. to eat paste, do you?
I'm sorry, but it was
the nearest they had.
Nearest they had! Look at that!
Take them away.
Never mind, Polly. I just need
something to settle me before I go on.
Anything will do.
But it was the best I had, Mrs. P.
Ship them by appointment.
They have it at Buckingham Palace.
When they're entertaining
their Cockney Highnesses.
The pearly King
and Queen, I suppose.
-How long we've got?
-Five minutes.
And my change?
I owe you 2 and 11 pence
with 3 farthings.
If I give you a farthing
you can give me 3 bob.
Polly!
Ta, Mrs. P.
You shouldn't.
The way you encourage her!
Overture and beginners, please.
My hatbox came undone last day, Polly.
It won't happen again, Ms. Maisie.
Help me with my hooks.
I do love my feather duster
on the upside of my dismal, Polly.
Do try and remember.
Got a fag, Pol?
Only a Woodbine.
Ain't he lovely?
Polly, don't whistle
in the dressing room.
-Why not?
-Because it's unlucky.
Now go outside, turn around three times
and knock on the door.
-What do nursing mothers need?
-Virol.
Come in.
-Now swear.
-Damn.
-Where is that lazy lady?
-She'll turn up, don't worry.
She'll be late
to her own funeral, that one.
Where is Rita?
Isn't she here yet?
I don't expect she'll be missed.
She is the star of the show.
Do you really think so?
She'll be fined again
if she ain't careful.
They're all called, Mr. Max.
Except Rita. She ain't here yet.
Not here?
Put her down for a fine.
If you fine her again
she will owe you money.
With this house I need it.
Why must these wretched garden fêtes
always coincide with our matinees?
And not a cloud in the sky.
Let me know the minute she arrives.
Yes, Mr. Max
Blimey! There's more on stage
than in the blooming audience.
Down there.
Is that Gaston, the costumier?
It is Madame Dubonnet's maid.
Dubonnet.
Mme Dubonnet de Villa Caprice.
Accent!
The school for young ladies.
I wish to know if you have ready
the costume for Ms. Polly Browne.
Accent.
She wishes it for
the carnival ball "ce soir".
You do not comprehend?
Then get me Monsieur Gaston himself.
She's no more French than I am.
-Rita here?
-No, Mr. Max. Naughty!
Nobody asked for your opinion.
She was out having an ice tea
with a sailor around lunch time.
Opening time, dear.
Let's be honest.
Fine publicity.
-She's never missed an entrance yet.
-Mind your hatbox, Dulcie.
She's never been sane
since I turned her into a star.
It went to her head totally.
-Telephone, Mr. Max.
-Tell them to ring again.
How can you expect me to speak
at a time like this!
They must speak to you
personally!
It's not C. B. Cochrane
from London, is it?
No. It's the hospital.
Then you deliver it right away?
Have you forgotten who you are?
Forgotten who we are?
Of course not!
We are perfect
young ladies
preparing to take
our places among the noblesse
We are perfect young ladies
Preparing to make
the most of the charm
we possess
You're being finished
And your families' wealth
may be diminished
But at least you all
have perfect health
And making the grade
is our duty, you see
For perfect young ladies are we
We are perfect young ladies
We hope to attract
a husband whose credit is good
You're maybe young ladies
But why don't you act
The way that a young lady should?
-I've often told you
-Please don't tell us again
-I ought to scold you
-But
you know it would be
quite in vain
For being our maid is
your duty, you see
For perfect young ladies are we
Terrible, terrible.
Not Rita.
Trapped her high heel
in the tram line. A foot.
It ain't off?
Of course not. Mild fracture.
But she's laid up just the same.
We're ruined.
No, we're not.
You will have to go on.
Get ready.
What, me?
But I'm only the A. S. M.
I can't go on.
It's the assistant stage manager's job
to understudy everybody's part.
Now, I told you that
when I took you on.
Now, hurry up
and don't argue.
You've got exactly 5 minutes.
I do not feel funny.
I want the best seat
in the house.
Let me see.
You could have the royal box.
I'll take it.
Except that it's permanently reserved
for the princess Arthur of Connaught.
We often stay with her.
Oh, really!
How about the stage box?
How much?
One pound, please.
That's a small box.
-How many are you?
-We are one.
Any further orders, Mr. De Thrill?
Just wait outside.
On no account is Mr De Thrill
to be disturbed, woman. Get it?
Really!
Why does she have such
blinking big plates of meat, Alf?
Stop worrying
and try that for size.
Rosemary and Mr. __,
they know well.
-It fits!
-Yes?
Oh, we'll find the other one
and you're ready for the ball.
You're going on?
All the best.
You're not wearing those, are you?
But you are beautiful.
Good luck.
All this in one day is too much.
Come on, Cinderella.
You're on.
How perfectly ripping!
Our very first carnival ball.
"En français", of course.
I can't wait for this evening!
My frock is a dream.
So is mine.
And rather daring too.
I'm sure Mme. Dubonnet
will be furious.
Not she!
I bet she'll turn up in something
frightfully shocking.
Not De Thrill,
the famous movie director?
How do I know what
sort of a thrill he is?
Look for yourself.
He is in the stage box.
Why didn't you say so?
Yes, it's him.
Word's got about.
My reputation will be made!
No. Will be ruined.
That girl!
That girl. She can't go on.
We must stop her.
He don't think I'm any good.
I can't go on now.
Bring down the curtain.
We'll send the audience home.
Then I'll go and refund the money.
Wait. Let me think.
__
Here comes Polly Browne
across the tennis courts.
-Polly Browne?
-Yes.
And she's carrying a letter.
Hello, Polly.
Oh, Polly! Just think!
London's great theatre land
waiting for you!
His Majesty, the Prince of Wales,
the Duchess, the Royalty,
the Duke of York, the Queen…
That's a nice ring.
Hold your tongue, woman.
It's Hollywood calling,
not the Palace.
Listen to me.
The careers and lives
of all these boys and girls
are depending on you.
I'm not asking for myself.
But do it for them.
Polly, listen to me!
You are going out there
as a youngster.
You've got to
come back a star.
Now get out there
and do your damnedest.
-Hello, Polly!
-Hello, everyone!
Where is Rita?
She got her foot
caught in the tram line.
She's in the hospital.
Hello, everyone.
Where have you been?
We dashed into town this morning
to collect our costumes for the carnival ball.
We couldn't wait
until Monsieur Gaston delivered them.
You must see mine, Polly.
You'll adore it.
Or mine!
-You'll be green with envy.
-Envy!
You know we'll all be jealous
of Polly when she gets hers.
What are you going as, Polly?
I'm going as Pierrette.
Pierrette! How divine!
Now do tell us your secret, Polly.
What secret?
If you are going
as Pierrette,
who is going
as Pierrot?
I still want it to be a secret.
I've had another letter
from Paris.
From Paris! How marvellous!
And what does he say?
He says he's
motoring down overnight.
In fact
he should be here
any moment now.
How thrilling!
And how does he sign himself?
Does he say
"Passionately yours"?
Or "yours adoringly"?
Or does he just say
"With all my love"?
Do tell us about him, Polly.
There ain't very much to tell, really.
I expect you know how I feel
as well as I do.
Any girl who's reached the age
of seventeen or thereabouts
has but one desire in view
Eyes and teeth.
She knows she has reached the stage
of needing one to care about
Nothing else would really do
Childhood games are left behind
And her heart takes wing
Hoping that it soon will find
Just one thing
We've got to have
We plot to have
For it's so dreary
not to have
that certain thing called
"the boy friend"
We scheme about
and dream about
And we've been known
to scream about
that certain thing called
"the boy friend"
He is really a necessity
If you want to get on
And we might as well confess it
He is a "sine qua non"
We sigh for him
and cry for him
and we would gladly
die for him
that certain thing called
"the boy friend"
A piano and drums.
What must De Thrill think?
If only we had money
what a spectacle I'd show them.
A royal command
performance.
We plead to have
We need to have
In fact our poor hearts
bleed to have
That certain thing called
"the boy friend"
We'd save for him
and slave for him
We'd even
misbehave for him
That certain thing called
"the boy friend"
Life without us is impossible
And devoid of all charms
No amount of idle gossip'll
Keep them out of our arms
We're blue without
Can't do without
Our dreams just won't come true without
That certain thing called
"the boy friend"
Polly, the spirit of ecstasy?
Ridiculous!
Oh, no!
She's forgotten the steps!
Do a "Ruby Keeler".
Go on.
-She is doing all right.
-All right for Pygmalion.
She is supposed to come
from Westminster, not Wa Ping.
Boys, you know you are not allowed
on the privacies. You must leave at once.
-See you on the plage.
-Do not be late.
Goodbye!
But you still haven't told us
much about him, Polly.
Not even his christian name.
What is it, Polly?
Girls!
Here comes Mme. Dubonnet!
This is no way to behave.
All of you to your classrooms
where Mlle. Alice
is waiting to instruct you
in "petit point".
Rita, Rita.
Play it like Rita.
I wish to have a little word
with you, "ma petite".
Promenade with me
into "le jardin".
You can help me
gather some hollyhocks.
Do not be frightened,
"ma chère",
you have done
nothing wrong.
I merely wished to ask
if you are coming to the ball tonight.
Yes, of course.
I've ordered my frock.
I'm going as Pierrette.
So you have a friend
to take you?
I had a letter today.
He's arriving by car from Paris.
From Paris.
Yes. From Paris.
Onion. You've got to cry.
So why is this letter
postmarked form Nice?
Never mind, my little Polly.
Your secret is safe with me.
"Soyez gaie" and trust me
Dry your eyes.
Change your tunic.
You're dancing à la grecque.
No! I won't do it!
A West End artist
act with an amateur? Never!
We've enough cockneys
in this show as it is.
And with De Thrill up front, too!
He'll think he's watching
a variety act.
You'll be expecting me to sing
"Any old iron" next.
Any old iron
You look neat
Talk about a treat
You look so dapper
from your napper to your feet
Dressed in style,
brand-new tile,
with your father's
old green tie on
But I wouldn't give you tuppence
for your old watch and chain,
Old iron, old iron
That's it!
You're a Cockney junk dealer.
Made your fortune
in scrap metal after the war.
You want to better yourself
and Polly too.
You're trying to
live down your past.
I'll write it.
We'll save the show yet.
I won't do it.
Anyone got a fountain pen?
I have one, Mr Max.
Emphasis will?
-Paper, paper.
-Here you are.
I want you all to do your best.
Tell the boys I haven't time.
Tell them to dance like Nijinsky.
De Thrill is up front.
Not De Thrill,
the __ deal manager from Cable Street?
No, it must be De Thrill,
the great Hollywood director
talent spotting
for its new, super, colossal,
all-talking,
all-singing, all-dancing
famous musical.
Oh, that one!
Hi, toots.
How's Pol doing?
Quite promising, actually.
Care for a puff?
It might stunt my growth.
I say, that's a kicky step.
Who taught you that?
Search me, toots.
As a kid, I was kicked in the head
and when I came to,
amnesia…
How on earth did that happen?
You've heard of the Russian Revolution.
And all that jazz.
Yes.
I'm told I was
on the steps of Odessa
when the Whites went bananas.
When I woke up all I could remember
was how to tapdance.
Fascinating.
Plus the name of one step:
the double-trip,
Maxie-Ford,
with a Knickerbocker break.
What happened to your parents?
I don't know.
I never heard from anybody.
I guess they were done in.
Anyway, since I spoke American
I was shipped off to the States
where they put me in an orphanage.
What was that like?
It was crummy.
They wouldn't even let me tapdance.
One dark night
at the ripe old age of six and a half
I ran away to New York,
to Manhattan, to Times Square,
to Broadway!
Where I became a baby star.
I'm tapping down Broadway
Just tapping down Broadway
Because Broadway
Is my tap, slap, happy home
Then I outgrew my short pants
and it was curtains for Tiny Tom.
You wouldn't be pulling
a fellow's leg, would you?
Every word's the truth.
Cub Scout's oath.
There's our cue.
Ready?
That was marvellous.
But Tommy, could we
take it easy this afternoon?
I've got the most
appalling headache.
Okay, toots.
I'll give it
the old matinee soft sale.
Please, could you give this
to the maitre d'?
-Oui, Mademoiselle.
-Thank you.
-Guess who!
-Tommy!
Goodness me!
Where I am?
Gosh! You did make a chap jump.
Fancy meeting you here.
I live here. Do you wanna come up
and see my etchings?
I say. Please.
Please! I must leave at once.
I'm just here on an errand
for Mme Dubonnet arrangements
for the carnival ball tonight.
If she were to find out
I'd be asked to leave under a cloud.
I'm not letting you go
until you promise me one thing.
-What is that?
-You know as well as I do.
-Do I?
-Of course, you do.
I want you to promise
that tonight
you're gonna dance
every dance at the ball with me.
Oh, that!
That's out of the question.
Come on, Maisie. Be a sports.
You know there's nobody
I wanna dance with but you.
Really?
I don't believe you.
Listen, baby, to my plea
Won't you come dancing with me?
be my baby and say "yes"
Or else I'm done for, I guess
To dance with you is thrilling
to my poor ego
So baby, say you're willing
to shake a leg
Won't you Charleston with me
And while the band is playing
that old vo-de-o-do
around we will go
together we'll show them
How the Charleston is done
We'll surprise everyone
Just think what heaven
it's gonna be
if you will Charleston with me
Will you Charleston with me
And while the band is playing
that old vo-de-o-do
around we will go
together we'll show them
How the Charleston is done
We'll surprise everyone
She's double-crossed.
De Thrill is in the stage box.
He told me when I joined you
he was a Noël Coward poet.
They don't expect Noël
to talk Cockney --do you--
any more than the Queen!
I can act posh.
Act posh? Harken that!
De Thrill wouldn't understand
a word of it.
It's a foreign language
to them Yanks. It's not English.
Do you think I'm a character, man!
You're hardly a Jew,
are you, darling?
Please, keep our memoire a--
The child is not that bad.
She's got a little talent.
Talent? She'll never make the West End
in a million years.
Let's be honest, darling.
The nearest you ever got to the West End
was "Harrow on the Hill"
Unless you count
the twice-nightlies.
Have you forgotten that charity matinee
I gave at Croydon?
I was in that show!
Cockney Capers.
You sang "Henry VIII"
There you are.
Four tickets.
-What about me?
-You talk awfuly refined.
You shouldn't find it too difficult.
I won't do it!
Unless I play it straight.
It's perfect.
-Have you fixed it up?
-Here, it won't come off.
Just this one as well.
Polly, before
your parents arrive
I want you to tell me
just one thing.
Yes, Madame?
How is it that one
so sweet and charming as you are
acts to pretend to have
--how do you say?--
boyfriend,
and to write yourself love letters?
It's because of my father, Madame.
Your father?
Before Kaiser Wilhelm
and the horrible war
we were terribly poor.
Daddy was a scrap-metal merchant
and I was a little match-girl.
But after the armistice
he made his fortune.
He bought up
all the Allies' arms cheap
and now we are terribly
nouveau rich
and when he dies
I shall be extremely wealthy
and he thinks that every man
who makes advances to me
is just after my millions.
There. He forbids you
to have a boyfriend.
Well. Practically.
So you invent him?
Yes, I'm afraid so.
I see.
Poor little rich girl.
I too had a letter today
from your father.
He is coming here
this morning.
Daddy? Coming here?
He is coming from Toulon
on business
and when I see him
I will have a little word with him.
He won't listen.
We shall see.
"Attends", my little Isadoras.
Today we dance "Narcissus"
Bless you, "mes enfants".
May the gods pour libations
of happiness in your houses.
Run along, my Isadoras
Madame wishes to meditate.
Really! Thank you.
Here.
How do you do, Madame?
How do you do?
Monsieur Browne
Or should I say,
"mon petit Percy"?
I don't follow you, Madame.
Mais oui, mon chère,
Do you not remember
your little Kiki?
Good heavens!
This is impossible!
Most awkward.
How could it be?
After all we have been
to each other.
Have  you forgotten
Armistice night?
Or when you kissed me on
the Champs Elysees.
Yes, Madam.
I have completely forgotten.
Surely not, cheri.
I wore a white dress
and you wore in uniform.
Later on, I called you
"my pretty private".
Then we drank champagne.
Everyone was happy.
Then, two little love birds
flew over our heads.
So, the kid stepped
into the star shoes.
Gosh, Rita, I'm sorry.
Does it hurt?
Of course it hurts.
When someone else
takes your place.
But I could never act
to be another Rita Monroe.
No one could, dear. Ever.
But you might just get by.
One day.
Now you're just
a nervous, skinny kid
overwhelmed of the impossibility
of trying to save the show.
And on top of that
you have to face
the bitter disappointment
of all my fans out there
who screamed and saved their pennies
week after week
to come here this afternoon
to see that special kind of magic
that only their Rita
can give them.
Do you know your steps?
Show me the Buck & Wing on your first duet.
Sorry, Rita.
Fake it. That's what I always did
whenever I was ill.
Chances are they'll never notice.
There is that tricky obbligato
in the Pierrette number.
That Parkhill woman is sure
to be singing flat.
They'll never notice.
If you do forget your lines,
"ad lib".
It'll destroy the rest of the cast
but at least you won't dry.
Pull yourself together
and don't worry.
We'll find a replacement tomorrow.
Now get out there
and be so great
you'll make me hate you.
Thank you, Rita
you're really too kind.
Sweet.
I could be happy with you
if you could be happy with me
Then, from a little cafe
came the strands of a waltz.
How did it go?
I still recall so tenderly
the night when first we met
The memory's so dear to me
So how can you forget?
Fancy forgetting
the love that we knew
When we were fancy free
Fancy forgetting
What I said to you
And what you said to me
Though the years go by
and our youth is gone
Memories don't die
like a song, they linger on
So just when I thought
you'd remember it too
Fancy, just fancy you
forgetting
I told you I'd play it straight.
Hear him!
I'm really scared now.
I can't remember a thing.
Don't worry.
And Pol, don't try
to copy the others.
If you really mean
what you say on the stage
you can't get it wrong.
Now depart, dear.
Class dismissed.
Girls, I know.
Let's go and try on our costumes
before lunch.
Yes!
Are you coming too, Polly?
I think I'll just stay here.
I'm expecting Daddy any moment.
And aren't you expecting him?
Him?
Yes, of course.
Let's leave her, girls.
She wants to be alone.
Goodbye.
Excusez-moi!
You startled me.
I'm sorry, Miss.
I'm afraid I came in the wrong way.
It's the Villa Caprice, isn't it?
Yes.
I have a package here
for Miss Polly Browne.
Really? How funny.
Funny? Why?
Because I'm Polly Browne.
It's a very pretty name.
Thank you.
And you live up to it.
I'm sorry, Miss.
I'm afraid I'm forgetting myself.
Here is your package.
Oh, thank you.
Don't they make a lovely couple?
Sorry.
I packed it myself.
If you don't mind my saying so,
it is a very pretty dress.
Yes, it is, isn't it?
I'm sure that you'll...
I mean, it will be
the prettiest of the ball.
Oh. I don't expect so, really.
I do. In fact, I know it.
Perhaps I'd better be going.
Yes. Perhaps you had.
Accent! Accent!
I say,
You are English, aren't you?
Yes. As a matter of fact I am.
You don't seem like
a messenger boy somehow.
To tell you the truth,
I don't usually do this sort of thing
but just at the moment
I'm afraid I'm rather on my beam ends.
What a shame.
And at carnival time too?
Yes. It's a pity, isn't it?
I was hoping I'd be able
to go to the ball tonight.
I'll be watching.
Will you?
Yes, of course.
Why don't you came too?
Me? Come to the ball?
Yes, why not?
I've got an extra ticket…
Oh, dear. You must think me
terribly forward.
No, I don't!
I think you're
terribly, terribly…
I don't claim that I am psychic
But one look at you and I kick
Away every scruple
I learnt as a pupil
In school my dear
I'm not one
to make predictions
But I've thrown off all restrictions
And don't mind confessing
I think it's a blessing
That you are here
Now  I'm prepared
To find I'm wrong
I've got a funny feeling
we belong together
I could be happy with you
If you could be happy with me
I'd be contented
to live anywhere
What would I care
as long as you are there
Skies may not always be blue
But one thing is clear as can be
I know that I could be happy
with you, my darling
if you could be happy with…
Then you will come
to the ball?
Well, I'll try.
I'll have to see about a costume.
There is a Pierrot's costume
at Gaston's.
Couldn't you borrow it?
I'll see.
How can I let you know?
Let me think.
I'll be on the plage
at 3 o'clock this afternoon,
on the Crazy Golf coast.
Goodbye until then.
And I don't even know his name.
Polly, I have a visitor for you.
Daddy, I'm so happy!
Are you, my dear?
I'm glad to hear it.
Has he arrived yet, Polly?
Yes, he's arrived.
He's really arrived.
We're blue without
Can't do without
Our dreams just won't
come true without
That certain thing called
"the boy friend"
In my imagination
I search the star-lit sky so bright
there I saw you in the night
And then one day I found you
How could I help but realise
My lucky star was smiling
right there before my very eyes
You are my lucky star
I saw you from afar
Two lovely eyes,
at me they were gleamin',
beamin'
I was star-struck
You're all my lucky charms
I'm lucky in your arms
You've opened heaven's portal
Here on earth for this poor mortal
You are my lucky star
Je suis vraiment enchanté, Mademoiselle.
Vous étes charmante.
He says you are lovely, darling.
You speak French?
Mais évidemment, Monsieur
J'ai été éduquée au college
de Brighton.
En français, naturellement.
Charmant.
Monsieur Max et les autres
vous attendent dans votre loge.
Au revoir, Mademoiselle.
That means
"Good bye, Miss".
She's only an understudy,
not a real actress.
I have a few photographs here
about past successes
that might interest you, Mr. De Thrill.
That's me in the Chinese Bungalow.
What have you here?
That's me as Hamlet,
a tragedy.
Me in "Luck Of The Navy".
That champagne costs money.
We should be safe in here.
We thought you were with the others.
Sorry. Excuse us.
Come on, Dulcie.
What a lovely day
For a dip in the sea
Oh, what fun it will be
Won't you come
and have a swim with me?
But whatever you do
When I'm swimming with you
Please remember not to go too far
Though you may look cute
in your bathing suit
we don't know who you are
There's no knowing
Who you are going to meet
sur la plage
You may run up against a rajah
Or maybe your man
will be a poor man
Sal or Susie,
cannot be choosey
For here love's
a guessing game
sur la plage
Everyone looks the same
Hubert! Hubert, what are you doing?
Nothing, my dear,
just admiring the view.
So different from Bongor, isn't it?
Much prettier.
I feel 20 years younger.
And behaving accordingly, I notice.
How can you
after our loss?
Hilda, do not dramatise
Tommy isn't dead.
He was off to Nice.
But he hasn't any money.
We must find him.
Do something, Hubert.
Very well, my dear.
How dare you?
Stop it.
Sur la plage
Everyone looks the same
There's no saying
Who may be playing with you
Sur la plage
A knight who's left behind his charger
May call you "ducky"
Won't you be lucky?
In the ocean
You'll find emotion
May play you a funny game
Sur la plage
sur la plage
Everyone looks the…
Everyone looks the same
What are you wearing that for?
To keep warm in bed?
So my own wife
won't recognise me.
There you are!
Did you think I wasn't coming?
Well, I wasn't sure.
Where were you ought to have been?
I've seen Monsieur Gaston
about the costume and it's all right.
Now I shall really enjoy
the carnival ball.
So shall I.
By Jove!
I never thought I should be going
to it with anyone like you.
Makes me feel rather nervous really.
Nervous. Why?
Me, just a messenger boy and
you, a rich young lady
from The Villa Caprice.
Rich?
I ain't rich.
I thought you could tell that
by my accent.
I just work there as
Mme. Dubonnet's secretary.
Do you honestly?
Then we're not
so different after all.
I'm so glad.
I thought you'd only like
the grand life.
You know, big cars,
diamonds and champagne.
I'm quite content
with simple things.
How ripping.
So am I.
A life of wealth
Does not appeal to me at all
Do you agree at all?
I do.
The mere idea of living in a palace is
So full of fallacies
That's true
I've got a very different
sort of scheme in mind
It's just a dream designed for two
Would you care to hear about it, dear?
Would I care to?
Can you doubt it, dear?
All I want is a room
In Bloomsbury
Just a room that will do
For you and me
One room's enough for us
Though it's on the top floor
Life may be rough for us
But its troubles we'll ignore
While I'm reading a book
I'll cook a stew
Then I'll bake a plum duff
Enough for two
You'll be sitting
And you'll be knitting
And so contented we'll be
In our dear little room
in Bloomsbury
All we want is a room
Just a room that will do
For you and me
I'll sew the covers for
Two old cosy armchairs
Neighbours will love us for
We shall laugh at all our cares
From the heavens above
our love will rain
such a bundle of joy
our hearts will see
Life's so jolly
For me and Polly
A happy family are we
All we want is a room
in Bloomsbury
Mlle. Browne!
What would Mme. Dubonnet say
if she saw you getting on with a messenger boy?
Please, don't tell her, Hortense.
Madame, please.
Well. All right.
After all, it is Carnival time!
Hortense!
Was that Mlle. Browne with a boy?
I have no idea.
Oh yes, you have.
Go on, Hortense. Do tell.
Is he terribly sleek and handsome?
I do not know
what you are talking about.
Isn't she mean?
If you tell me how he's like
I'll give you that handkerchiefs tasche.
And I'll give you
those crochet flowers.
And we'll give you
a ride in his car.
Taisez-vous, mes enfants!
It is not seemly to be curious
about a young man.
Why not?
Haven't you ever been curious,
Hortense?
Hortense, do tell!
Hortense is not so prim
as she pretends.
Of course, she isn't.
After all, she is French.
Yes, I am.
How do you say it?
"Not dumb."
My wife.
And like every good French woman,
I have a past.
Do tell us about it, Hortense.
-You're not on in this number.
-I am now, my wife is after me.
I'm often asked
if I would like to travel
And visit other lands
across the sea
but though it might be pleasant
I think that for the present
this is the place where I prefer to be
Let others go to Sweden or Siam
I think I'll stay exactly where I am
They say it's lovely when a
young lady's in Vienna
but it's nicer, much nicer in Nice
in Amsterdam or Brussels
the men have great big muscles
but they're nicer,
much nicer in Nice
I've heard that the Italians
are very fond of dalliance
and they're also keen on it in Greece
But whatever they may say
this is where I want to stay
For it's so much nicer in Nice
She says it's nicer,
much nicer in Nice
Some people's one desire is
to go to Buenos Aires
But it's nicer,
much nicer in Nice
The laws are rather vague in
the town of Copenhagen
but they're nicer,
much nicer in Nice
And some may like a flutter
in Bombay or Calcutta
But they might have trouble
with the police
O la la!
Other places may be fun
but when all is said and done
it is so much nicer in Nice
Do something!
But they might have trouble
with the police
Oh, Mon Dieu
Tho' I know a love affair
is delicious anywhere
It is so much nicer in Nice
And now I really must go.
Polly, would you kiss me goodbye?
Yes, if you want me to.
Is that all right?
Yes, we are perfect.
This is Hollywood after this.
If I just get through the show
it'd be enough for me.
It was nice of you
to rehearse with me, Alf. Thanks.
That's alright.
I wish I was playing Tony.
I'm glad I couldn't find him.
He seems to avoid me off-stage.
Yet he is very kind.
I suppose I'm just not his type.
I wonder who he'd really go for.
It seems, believe it or not,
someone like Dulcie.
Toots, you're quite a hopper.
I have to teach you the double-trip,
Maxie-Ford
with a Knickerbocker break.
That is good!
Where did you learn that?
Search me, toots.
As a kid I was kicked in the head.
And what I came to? Amnesia.
Percy, Percy,
please, have mercy
Why must you always
be so sad and gloomy?
Why can't you be
a little nicer to me?
Cheri, Cheri
please, be merry
When I am trying to be bright
and jolly
it isn't nice
to be so melancholy
Oh, dear
I've got the
you-don't-want-to-play-with-me blues
Don't-want-to-play-with-me blues
It's clear
I've got the
you-don't-want-to-stay-with-me blues
Don't want to stay with me blues
I am so good
At spreading mirth and joy
But it's no good
With such a sulky boy
I try
To play the game
the other fellows all choose
The other fellows all choose
I sigh
Because you always refuse
What is a girl to do
With such a boy as you?
I've got those dreary
weary
You-don't-want-to-play-with-me blues
She told me she had a headache
before the Charleston
but she didn't at all.
I think there's gonna be trouble
with the chums.
Maybe some people don't like
being double-crossed.
Well, we've got to
look after ourselves.
Maisie!
Here you are at last.
I've been looking
everywhere for you.
Have you? I've been
for a bathe with Fay.
Are you sure there wasn't
anybody else with you?
What if there was?
I can go bathing
with whom I choose.
I wished you choose me.
You are just a boy.
Maybe I want someone more mature.
Say your right lines
or shut up.
But Maisie, why?
Because I want to have
a good time while I'm young.
After all I'm only 17.
But I can show you a good time.
It's not as if I hadn't got
plenty of cash.
Money isn't everything
though it certainly helps.
One more "ad lib" like that, toots,
and you're getting a knuckle sandwich.
But Maisie, when are you
going to come and see my yacht again?
You liked that, didn't you?
Yes, it's a very dinky yacht.
I like yachts.
Mademoiselle Maisie.
Alphonse.
You look "ravissant".
Behave yourself or
I'll belt you.
Just try it,
you little twerp.
Do not forget tonight
she will dance the tango with me.
Of course not.
-Maisie!
-Michael!
You look enchanting.
Tonight you and I will dance the two-step.
I can hardly wait.
Pack it in,
you old cow.
Droop off,
you faded pansy.
I too want to dance
with you at the ball.
You beat-up old bag.
And so you shall.
You bald-headed old lech.
Maisie, listen to me!
Listen to all of us!
You are so fascinating.
But it's aggravating
That you keep us waiting to hear
which one will be
your favourite he
You're so very taking
That our hearts are breaking
So you should be making it clear
Which one of us
You rate Alpha plus
Now, listen, boys
you should recall
I've often said
I love you all
You love us all?
Yes! I love you all!
It's time you learnt
That I'm no fool
Where love's concerned
I stick to this rule
There's safety in numbers
That's what I believe
a girl who's cute
and making loot
Is never likely to grieve
The lady who slumbers
Is left high and dry
But I admit
an honest pot
I always bet
on lady luck
There's safety in numbers
And the more the merrier, say I
You, me, Hollywood.
Vous avez perdu, Mademoiselle.
Can you speak French?
French!
I think perhaps I'd better
be getting back to the villa.
I have some letters to type.
Do you really
have to go so soon?
Yes, I'm afraid I must.
But I'll see you tonight, won't I?
I should jolly well think so.
Where shall I meet you?
I don't know. You say.
How about the ball at 9 o'clock.
Lovely. I shall be waiting.
Oh, dear.
Tonight seems
a very long time away.
It's not really.
Just a few hours.
And it's gonna be a wonderful evening,
isn't it, Polly?
Yes, I'm sure it is, Tony.
But it's just the first
of lots of wonderful evenings.
Yes. At least I expect so.
But why shouldn't it be?
I meant what I said this morning.
What did you say?
I could be happy with you
if you could be happy with me
I'd be contented
to live anywhere
What would I care
As long as you are there?
Skies may not always be blue
but one thing is clear
as can be
I know that I could be happy with you,
my darling
if you could be happy with…
No, Tony. I really must go.
Would you...
-Will you kiss me goodbye?
-Yes. If you want me to.
Have you decided?
I love you.
Good.
Gosh!
Look! It's Tony!
I've got to hop it. Quickly.
But what's the matter?
Stop him.
You there! Gendarme!
Gendarme! Stop him!
The police? Surely not.
Alphonse, tell me quickly.
Who are that lady and gentleman?
The rich Milord Brockhurst and his wife.
They seem to be chasing a thief.
A thief? Oh, no!
It couldn't be.
And yet they are rich
and he is penniless.
He told me so himself.
Oh, dear.
He must have known all along
that I'm not a working girl
but a millionaire's daughter.
Oh, dear.
He's just like all the rest.
Did he steal something from you?
Yes, he did.
Not your gold bangle!
No. Not my gold bangle.
Something much more precious.
What is it, ma petite?
You look like pale.
I can explain, Madame.
That man was Monsieur...
No, Hortense!
-What is it?
-You promised.
It's nothing, Madame.
I'm just a little
disappointed, that's all.
I shan't be going
to the carnival ball after all.
I could be happy with you
if you could be happy with me
I'd be contented
to live anywhere
What would I care
as long as you are there
Skies may not always be blue
But one thing is clear as can be
I know that I could be happy
with you, my darling
if you could be happy with me
Just slip down to the Cadena Cafe
and get me the Ivy Perkins Trio.
It's nearly teatime, Mr. Max,
they may be playing.
Then get me the best musicians
in the town.
There are no good musicians
in this town.
Then get me anybody!
Voulez vous filmer avec moi?
Oh, Hollywood!
-No. "Ollywood".
-"Ollywood"?
They jump the "H" in France.
-What's the matter, Pol?
-Nothing.
I got something in my eye,
that's all.
Don't worry, Polly.
It weren't that bad.
The dog, in life
man's firmest friend
is woman's consolation
in the end.
Very nice.
Where is he?
Who?
De Thrill! I invited him
round of drinks in the green room.
Perhaps he is colour-blind.
Very funny.
You should be on the stage.
You are supposed
to be an old man.
So why do you keep
dying your white hair black?
My public wouldn't recognize me
from my photograph in the feuillet.
No, I suppose they wouldn't.
It's so yellow with age.
You'll have to make up
as Chinese!
Jealousy will get you nowhere.
Is that my Melba spray
you are using
on the wretched dog?
She is not a dog!
She is a King Charles!
Name dropping again.
Help me with my spats, woman.
"Sharp point"
He is thinking of turning the show
into a film.
Hurry up!
"Sharp point, heap bath, lamp oil"
Did you blanch them?
Of course.
When every day begins,
when every day is done,
here in my heart
never to part
you’ll always be the one
All I do the whole night through
is dream of you
with the dawn I still go on
and dream of you
you're every thought
you're every thing
you're every song
I ever sing
summer, winter
autumn, and spring
And were there more
than twenty-four
hours a day
they’d be spent in sweet content
dreaming away
when skies are grey
when skies are blue
morning, noon, and nighttime too
all I do the whole day through
is dream of you
This way, gentlemen.
What's this?
Frank Connaugh's army?
Where is the Ivy Perkins Trio?
But you did say "get anyone".
And I was thrown out of the Cadena Cafe
for soliciting.
They mustn't be seen.
They'll have to play in a recumbent position.
Let's pray for an upstage wind.
Nothing must distract De Thrill
from my performance.
That goes to you too, Miss.
You just sit still and give me my cues.
And I might take you
to Hollywood with me.
Bonsoir, ma petite.
You startled me.
You are English!
I thought you were French.
Did you honestly?
Well, I'm not.
I didn't mean to be rude.
That's all right. It's just that
I'm rather fed up with France.
I can't imagine
a pretty little thing like you
be fed up with anything.
Well, I am.
And not just with France.
I also had enough of boys.
Boys?
Why not try
something older?
Something older?
What the hell
do you think you're doing?
You are supposed
to be a nurse, not a tart.
Something older
like me for instance.
I may be too old to run a mile
-Run a mile?
-Yes, run a mile
But there's one thing
I still do very well
I may be too old to climb a stile
-Climb a stile?
-Yes, climb a stile.
But there's one thing
at which I still excel
Although my hair is turning grey
Yes, it's rather grey!
I still believe it when I say
Well, what do you say?
It's never too late to have a fling
For Autumn is just as nice as Spring
And it's never too late to fall in love
Boop-a-Doop, Boop-a-Doop, Boop-a-Doop
It's never too late to wink an eye
I'll do it until the day I die
And it's never too late to fall in love
Boop-a-Doop, Boop-a-Doop, Boop-a-Doop
If they say I'm too old for you
Then I shall answer "Why, sir,
One never drinks the wine that's new
The old wine tastes much nicer"
A gentleman never feels too weak
To pat a pink arm or pinch a cheek
And it's never too late
to fall in love
Sez who? Sez me
Sez you? Sez we.
Sez both of us together
It's never too late to whisper words
Concerning the ways of bees and birds
And it's never too late to fall in love
-Whack-a-do, Whack-a-do, Whack-a-do
-Push me back!
It's never too late to flirt and spoon
A fiddle that's old is more in tune
And it's never too late to fall in love
Whack-a-do, Whack-a-do, Whack-a-do
The modern artists of today
May paint their pictures faster
But when it comes to skill, I say
You can't beat an old master
It's never too late to bill and coo
At any age one and one make two
And it's never too late to fall in
Never too late to fall in
Love
Ladies and gentlemen
I proudly present
my latest
cinematographic fantasy
for the cinema screen
entitled:
"Beauty and the wheelchair"
It's never too late to blow a kiss
Especially at a time like this
And it's never too late to fall in love
It's never too late for fun and larks
A jolly old flame has lots of sparks
It's never too late
to fall in love
Vo-de-o, Vo-de-o, Vo-de-o
The modern buildings that you see
Are often most alarming
But I am sure that you'll agree
-A ruin
-can be charming
There's dog's dirt
all over your spat, Sir.
Forgive the outrage, Mr. De Thrill.
The girl has lost her senses.
She is dismissed.
She can pack her bags
and leave at the end of the week.
She's fired.
You've had your chance
and you've lost it.
So she came to the ball
after all.
Poor child.
How sad she looks.
Let me talk to her, mon vieux.
I know how she is feeling.
We all missed you like mad.
Didn't we, chaps?
Yes, we did, Polly.
Polly. You'll never guess
what's happened to us.
We've all been proposed to.
But we haven't been accepted yet.
We are letting them know at midnight.
Polly, what a shame.
Your fellow turned out to be a…
A rotter and a cad.
You do not wish to dance, Polly?
Until I dance with him, Madame,
I will never dance again.
Never mind.
The night is still young.
You know, Polly,
when I look at you
in that sweet costume
you remind me
of a song I once knew.
Do I, madam?
Can you sing it?
Yes, I think so.
There is an old French legend
that's set to an old French tune.
It tells how Pierrot
loved Pierrette
under the summer moon
Every night the lovers meet
just as the clock strikes nine
Then he gives her kisses sweet
As vintage wine
But alas, one fateful night
Pierrette is forsworn
There she stand, forlorn
till the cold grey dawn
Poor little Pierrette
Where's your Pierrot?
Why are you all alone?
You should be so fancy-free
Your heart should be high
But instead
You hang your head
And try not to cry
Poor little Pierrette
You must not show
Your dream of love has flown
Just keep on dancing
Till the dawn, and then
He may come back again
Poor little Pierrette
Where's your Pierrot?
Why are you all alone?
You should be so fancy-free
Your heart should be high
But instead
You hang your head
And try not to cry
Poor little Pierrette
You must not show
Your dream of love has flown
Just keep on dancing
Till the dawn, and then
He may come back again
May I have this dance?
I'm afraid I can't dance
with a stranger.
But I am Pierrot.
You are Pierrette.
Surely we are not strangers.
But I don't know who you are.
Maybe this will remind you.
It isn't. It can't be.
Yes, it's me!
Tony!
Polly!
Dulcie and I made it between us
during the show.
"Happy first night"
"I love you. Tony"
Blow it out.
Thank you.
Hubert, it's Tony!
We find him at last!
My son!
Mother!
Father!
And whom, may I ask,
is this young man?
This, Sir, is my son,
the honourable Tony Brockhurst.
The honourable Tony Brockhurst?
I'm afraid I'm not
a messenger boy after all.
Can you forgive me?
Yes, of course.
And who, may I ask,
is this young woman?
That, Madame, is my daughter.
And I am Percival Browne.
Not Percival Browne
the millionaire.
I'm afraid I deceived you too.
I'm not secretary after all.
Can you forgive me?
Of course, my darling.
It seems that love
is in the air tonight.
It is indeed.
I too, Polly, have some news.
Have you, Daddy? How thrilling.
May I tell her, Kiki?
Of course.
She should be the first to know.
Very well, then. Polly,
Mme Dubonnet has consented
to become my wife.
Maisie, it's midnight.
Have you thought it over?
-And you?
After due consideration
we have come to the conclusion
that the answer is unanimously
Yes!
Swell!
Where should we go for the honeymoon?
The Riviera.
Whenever you want,
Mr. De Thrill.
Background action!
Stand behind!
Wriggle your hips and kick up your heels
you'll be surprised how lovely it feels
Everybody's doing the Riviera
Wiggle your fingers, wiggle your toes
Just how it started nobody knows
Everybody's doing the Riviera
Multi Millionaires
and their little pets do it
Even maiden ladies
who wear lorgnettes
have taken to it
Tell everyone to give out the news
this is the way to shake off the blues
Everybody's doing the Riviera
Wait on the set, everybody!
Get on the dance floor
get in the swing
this is the time for
having a fling
Everybody's doing the Riviera
Clap-a your hands
and slap on your thighs
Grin like a goon
and roll up your eyes
Everybody's doing the Riviera
All the bright young things
and their bright young beaux do it
Even duchesses and their gigolos
have taken to it
Ain't it terrific? Ain't it the top?
You gotta dance right on till you drop
Everybody's doing the Riviera
I know that I could be happy
with you, my darling
If you could be happy
with me
Well done. You saved the show.
A star is born.
You're welcome to be the star
of a crummy show like this.
You can understudy
my part tonight, deary.
The public liked you,
De Thrill liked you. I liked you.
You can stay on
for another week.
-At double salary, of course.
-We'll discuss that later.
We'll discuss the young lady now
if you don't mind.
She is a Jonah.
I've never known of a force like it!
Ad-libing at stage,
a family row on stage!
Cakes and __.
My professional career
in tatters!
A hard-earned reputation
ruined!
And it all started with her!
Either she goes
or I go.
That's easily settled.
I've been thinking for some time
of taking over your part.
I'm really miscast as
Lord Brockhurst. Far too young.
Pay no attention to him, Mr. Max.
He is rather overwrought this afternoon.
Don't bother me now.
De Thrill and I have things…
Bonjour, Monsieur.
Voulez vous filmer avec moi?
Das ist für Fräulein Polly.
For Polly.
Can't you speak German?
German?
I think I will make
"Singin' in the rain"
I'll send you a postcard
from Hollywood, chaps.
That'll make you a
lovely smelling lady in Christendom.
Just rehearsing.
Wait. Wait. Look!
You know the double-trip Maxie Ford
with a Knickerbocker break!
Well, I taught it to you.
-I thought you were dead!
-No, I lost my memory.
-No, I was interned.
-Pop?
-My son!
I can't believe it.
Mr. De Thrill…
It's all a game.
Goodbye, Miss.
I hope your headache gets better!
Goodbye!
From De thrill.
What does he say?
Nothing.
Come on. Let me look.
Gosh!
He wants you to go to Hollywood.
Should I help you pack?
No. Let's go find
that room in Bloomsbury.
I think I'll take the cloth.
Like to bet on your first customers?