Got any coffee on you?
Oh, yes?
Now I can retire.
Well, there's your
good-neighbor policy.
Come on, honey.
That's good neighborin'. There we are.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
that international favorite, Tony De Marco.
You never saw a place
like this in your life.
- Hello, kids. There you are.
- Hello.
I'll wait a bit on you
till the other one.
- This place gives me a very uneasy feeling, A.J.
- Shame on you.
- Gimme your hat and get your mind off your wife.
- That hat's all right?
- Yes, your hat's all right.
- That's my hat.
She knows it.
Never lost one in her life.
Now, see here, A.J.
I should have been more fiirm.
When I told you that I am never seen
in places like this, I meant it.
I don't know how you've managed to get me
this far. I should have put my foot down.
- Don't be a square from Delaware.
Get hep to yourself.
- What kind of talk is that?
- I heard it on a jukebox.
- Well, I don't think I like it.
- I have your table, Mr. Mason.
- Thank you, Harvey. Come on, Pottsie.
Hey, Phil, do those two
come here very often?
Well, I haven't seen
the mortician before...
but that old mountain goat
in the blue serge...
comes leaping in here
two or three times a week.
That old mountain goat
happens to be my father.
Well, you see, I like goats.
Lovely animals.
Some of my best friends are-
How about another goat- uh, beer?
No, thanks.
I think I'll horn in on the old goat.
The usual. Lemonades.
- What did you order?
- Lemonade.
How do you like Tony De Marco?
Great, isn't he?
I hope that woman's his wife, because
if she's not, there should be a law.
That's a good one.
Good, eh?
A.J., look.
We have company.
- What are you doing here?
- I was about to ask you the same thing.
Well, we just dropped in
for a nightcap.
- We missed the Westchester train,
and Potter here suggested-
- Nothing of the kind.
- Andy, this is entirely your father's idea.
- What?
- Yes.
- Young man, I thought you had
to get back to your outfiit.
Well, I do, but I didn't say when.
I've got till Monday morning.
How 'bout you?
Mrs. Potter give you a furlough too?
I promised my wife I'd be home before
midnight. I like to keep my promises.
She expects me to,
and I expect her to expect it.
Say, Peyton, supposing I get
Mrs. Potter on the phone...
- and explain that you and Dad just dropped in-
- Go ahead, son.
- She likes Andy, and anything
he tells her will be okay.
- I'll call her, fiix everything.
- You be sure to explain to her
that this is just lemonade.
- Lemonade.
And now, folks,
the Club New Yorker proudly presents...
its beautiful dance instructors,
specially imported to teach you...
that brand-new South American
dance sensation, the Uncle Samba.
Our girls don't wait for leap year.
They choose their partners now.
And you don't have to
wait either, gentlemen.
Look around and choose
your nearest exquisite.
All right, girls.
Grab your partners and let's go.
Come on up. That's the idea. There we go.
There you are.
Hello? Hello!
Oh, hello, Andy.
Where are you?
Club New Yorker?
Oh. Potter's with you?
Dad brought him here after the dinner
for a nightcap. Don't worry about him.
Don't give him anything stronger
than lemonade.
The last time he had champagne was
on our honeymoon. It was at Niagara.
He thought he was a barrel. He wanted me
to roll over the falls with him.
I'll look after him.
Is Vivian there?
Put her on.
Hold on. I'll call her.
Oh, Vivian!
- Yes, Blossom.
- Phone, dear.
- Who is it?
- Andy.
Oh. Hello, Andy.
At the Club New Yorker?
He is?
How dare you drag my father
to such a sinful place?
Tell your mother she has
nothing to worry about.
My father, he's doing all right.
Say, that girl's a honey.
Who is she, Ruth?
- That's Eadie Allen, one of our new girls.
- Eadie Allen. Hmm.
Mr. Potter!
This is all your fault, A.J.
It was you who sicced
that gypsy on me.
- She's no gypsy. She's a Brazilian.
- Well, whatever she is, she's a-
- She's a bombshell.
- Bombshell. That's exactly right.
Did you see that man with the camera?
Did you see that thing explode in his hands?
I was lucky to get out alive.
Now I'm gonna be fiirm. We are leaving.
Well, I talked to Mrs. Potter
and everything's fiine.
- She was delighted to hear that
you had taken up dancing again.
- She was?
Did you tell her about me out there
dancing with that South American savage?
I knew I shouldn't have
let you telephone.
I was only joking.
I told her nothing.
What I was doing out there,
that wasn't Peyton Potter at all.
- Now, don't be modest. You were swell.
- Really. I've had enough.
- Mason, if you please.
- Old Pottsie can't take it.
Well, you go along with him.
I've got some unfiinished business.
Unfiinished business?
That must mean a girl.
Boy, I wish I were young again.
- Well, I'm glad you're not. Where would I be?
- Good night, Son.
Good night, Dad.
Oh, waiter.
Take a message to Phil Baker.
- Ask him to meet me at the bar between shows.
- Yes, sir.
And, waiter. Have him
bring Miss Allen with him.
- There you are.
- Yes, sir. Miss Allen.
- You want to see me, Andy?
- Yes, but, well, where's Miss Allen?
Miss Allen? Oh, you see, between shows,
she goes over to the Broadway Canteen.
This is her night
to dance with servicemen.
- Didn't you tell her I wanted to meet her?
- She wasn't interested.
- I'm afraid you picked the wrong girl.
- Yeah?
I think I'll go over
to that Broadway Canteen.
- I'm warning you, you won't get to fiirst base.
- I'm pretty good at baseball.
So was the mighty Casey,
but even Casey struck out.
It'll take more than three strikes
to keep me away from fiirst base.
- Fifty bucks says you go down swinging.
- I'll take that bet.
- Have you ever been in Tennessee?
- No. Is that where y'all from?
- You guessed it. And I bet
I can tell you where you're from.
- Where?
Heaven, lady.
Heaven.
Shove off, sailor.
- So long, angel.
- So long, Tennessee.
- Are you really an angel?
- The navy seems to think so.
My mom always told me, if I was
a good boy, I'd see an angel someday.
You be a good boy now and watch
that right hand. It's slipping.
Just lookin' for your wings, baby.
Lookin' for your wings.
- Do I really have to give you up?
- Sorry, it's the rule here.
The marines lay the groundwork,
and the army takes over.
When I fiirst saw you,
I said, ''target for tonight.''
Hmm. You're not
wearing them, are you?
- Not wearing what?
- Your marksmanship medals.
Ah, I wish you weren't
so beautiful.
Why?
Well, then nobody would cut in, and you'd be
all mine for the rest of the evening.
Have you been getting results
with that line?
Aw, I'm sorry.
You're used to getting a pretty good spiel
from most of these fellas I guess.
Oh, I don't mind them.
After all,
they're a long way from home.
A long way from their girls.
You can't blame them if they get
off the beam once in a while.
They're all pretty sweet.
Even the wise ones.
Say, would you think
I was too forward if I, uh-
If you what?
Well, if I asked you your name?
No, of course not. It's Allen.
What's yours?
- What?
- I said, ''What's your name? ''
Oh. Well, uh, it's, uh, Casey.
Casey? Hmm.
That's a pretty good name.
- ''Casey at the bat.''
- That's me.
- Huh?
- Well, l-
I mean,
I played a lot of baseball.
- Are you pretty good?
- Well, that depends.
Sometimes I, uh,
don't even get to fiirst base.
- I like baseball.
- So do I.
I like dancing too.
- Huh? Oh, I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
Would you like something to eat?
- Why, yes. I guess I would.
- Doughnuts and coffee?
- If you led me to it, I'd eat hay.
- Well, come on.
May I have a couple, June?
Thank you.
There you are.
- Oh, cream and sugar?
- No, thanks.
You'll fiind those awfully good.
You can dunk if you'd like to.
- Dunk?
- Mm-hmm. Like this.
- Isn't that better?
- Yes, much better.
Here. Have another bite.
Couldn't we just talk?
I'm not awfully hungry.
Well, I have to leave pretty soon now.
I've got a show to do.
A show?
Are you an actress?
Well, not exactly.
Just a showgirl from the Club New Yorker.
- A showgirl.
- Mm-hmm.
- Gee, no wonder you're so glamorous.
- Now.
- Say, if I'm not being too forward-
- Yes?
You suppose I could walk
to the club with you?
Or do you have a boyfriend?
I haven't a boyfriend. No.
- But we're not allowed to leave
the canteen with soldiers.
- Oh.
And, uh, now I'm afraid
I'll have to say good night.
- Good night?
Won't I ever see you again?
Well, I'm here
three nights a week.
Yes, but I won't have
another leave for some time.
I'm sorry.
Best of luck, soldier.
Thanks.
- You're sweet.
- Thanks.
Well, looks like
we've reached our objective.
- Good night, Casey.
- I wish you didn't have to go in.
- Good night, soldier.
- Couldn't I meet you after the show?
We could sort of go out and you could
show me the town sort of. Will you?
- I'd love to.
- Really?
I'll be fiinished at 1:30.Just in time
for a drink and dance at the Stork Club.
Then on to El Morocco, then just
a quick look in on Monte Carlo.
After that, we'll go
to Lindy's for a late bite...
and then I know
a swell spot on 52nd Street.
Won't cost you more than $50...
that is, of course,
if you don't tip too heavily.
We're gonna have lots of fun,
Sergeant.
- Those places are pretty expensive, aren't they?
- Yes, they are.
Well, I'm afraid I couldn't afford it,
not on a sergeant's salary.
- Well, then what do you say
we skip the whole thing?
- All right.
- Good night, soldier.
- Good night.
- Casey.
- Yeah?
Would you-Would you like
to see the show?
- Gee, would I!
- I'll fiix it for you out front.
Oh, don't go to all that trouble.
I'll see it from backstage.
- Good night, Ben.
- Good night.
- Oh, Miss Allen...
I just had a nice talk
with your boyfriend here.
Didn't know
you had a sweetheart.
I, uh- l- I told him we were sweethearts.
I hope you don't mind.
Stop acting like Don Ameche,
and get me a taxi.
- I've got one waiting.
- Thank you.
Let's go over by the rail.
First a taxicab,
then the Staten Island Ferry.
- You certainly can pick 'em.
Well, you see, I thought it was nearer
and really much cheaper than-
Any nightclub in town.
- You know, it is kind of nice
to get out of the city at that.
- I'll say.
- It's beautiful out here, isn't it?
- Mm-hmm.
You're beautiful too, Eadie. I couldn't keep
my eyes off you in that show tonight.
You ought to be the star
instead of just one of the girls.
I won't be for long. Phil promised me
a song in the new show.
Really?
I didn't know you could sing.
- Phil thinks I can.
- He's a swell guy.
You'll like him
when you get to know him.
That sounds as though you're going
to let me come around some more.
- Could be.
- Well, after all...
I suppose I'll have to hear
you sing sometime, won't I?
Yes, I suppose you will.
Well, what are we waiting for?
All right, soldier, you win.
- Ready?
Hear the orchestra?
Yeah.
Where's it coming from?
- Where's your imagination?
Gee, that's swell.
- Did you really like it?
- You bet I did.
- Hey.
- What?
Look over there.
The evening star.
Over your left shoulder too.
That ought to mean something.
Oh, l- I forgot to tell you.
We're gonna have Benny Goodman
and his orchestra in the new show.
- Oh, you are?
- Mm-hmm.
That's fiine.
I'm certainly glad
I met you tonight.
- Why?
- Oh, lots of reasons.
Do me a favor, will you?
Sing that song again.
- Oh, you don't want to hear it again.
- Oh, yes, I do.
- That sounds like an order.
- It is.
Okay, Sergeant.
- Here we are. Wait for me.
- Yes, sir.
- Well?
- Oh, no. I'm gonna take you right up to the door.
- Will I see you tomorrow night?
- I thought you had to go back to camp.
Well, I do, but you'll be at the
Grand Central Station to see me off.
I hadn't thought about it.
You'll think about it now,
won't you?
Uh-huh.
- But you haven't even told me
where you were going.
- Huh?
Well, I mean your camp.
Where is it?
Oh. Oh, well, uh-
- Well, that's a military secret.
- Is it north, east, south or west?
L- I can't tell you that either.
- You see, I've never been there before.
- Oh.
But from what the fellas tell me,
it's really a paradise for soldiers.
- No.
- Yeah.
They say it's warm
and beautiful there.
And at night, even the ocean
sings you to sleep.
And the moon and the stars,
why, they-
- Oh, that's swell.
- Yeah.
You'll be hearing from me
the minute I get there.
My train leaves at 8:00.
I'll meet you at
the information booth at 7:30.
Well, I, uh-
I don't know whether I can make it.
You see, I have a-
I have a rehearsal in-
in the morning,
and I don't know for how long.
Then I promised Mabel...
from there I'd go to Brooklyn
with her to see the Dodgers play.
L- I guess maybe I could miss
seeing the Dodgers.
Won't hurt anything.
- Don't be late.
- I won't.
Remember.
Grand Central Station. 7:30.
I'll be there.
Good night.
- Good night.
Did you have
a good time in town?
Well?
Vivian, I want to tell you
about last night.
- You see, l-
- Andy, you don't have to explain anything to me.
I simply asked you
if you had a good time.
Well, uh, yes, I did.
Well, that's all that matters.
You're a good sport, Vivian.
- But then, you've always been.
- Sure.
- You're a very lucky guy to have a girl like me.
- I know that.
However, don't think
I won't be properly jealous...
if you go cruising around
in that uniform...
and get yourself a sweetheart
in every port.
Oh, I'm a soldier,
not a sailor.
A soldier can get
in deep water too.
Sometimes way over his head.
I wish I could take this pool
of yours back to the camp with me.
- You mean they don't have
a swimming pool for you...
Or a nice man to bring you
tall frosty drinks when you're thirsty?
Good afternoon.
How's the swimming today?
Super, Mrs. Potter.
Simply super.
Well, that's wonderful.
Too wonderful.
- Aren't you going in, Mrs. Potter?
- Oh, mercy, no.
The pool is Vivian's department.
I just have the towel concession.
Please. Don't rush those things
back and forth too much.
These children are here
to swim in the pool.
Yes, madam.
Hello, kiddies.
Have you seen the morning tabloid?
I suppose you'll show this to Dad
right away and be properly outraged.
- Oh, no. I'm saving that until I need it.
Go ahead, Beezy.
Ask her.
- I will. Stop pushing.
- Well, go ahead.
- M-M-Mrs. Potter?
- Yes, my dear. What is it?
W-Would you care to dance,
Mrs. Potter?
Me? Oh, isn't that sweet of you.
Just being polite, of course.
Oh, no, he isn't.
I told him you like to dance.
Oh, I do. I love it.
But he is so young, and I am so-
Well, you know, so-so.
Oh, you embarrass me. Really, you do.
- Oh, go ahead, Mother. Beezy loves to dance.
- Yes, that's what I'm afraid of.
You know, I'm not 16 anymore.
I feel silly.
He wants to play.
Drop that.
Mrs. Potter,
I want to have a talk with you.
Come to my study at once, please.
Pass the ammunition, kiddies.
- You going to write me?
- Are those orders, Sergeant?
- I'm serious, Eadie.
- How serious?
Hearing from you every day would make me
feel that you're marching...
right up there with me
at the head of the column.
And that's where
I want you to be, Eadie.
I will write you, Andy...
every day.
All aboard. Leaving on Track 28.
Westbound Limited.
Chicago, Omaha, Denver...
Salt Lake City, Los Angeles...
and San Francisco.
Westbound. All aboard.
Well, I guess that's me.
Wait a minute, Andy.
- You said you were going to Florida.
- I didn't say that, darling.
Yes, you did. You said you were going
to a camp where it was warm and beautiful.
- But, Eadie, l-
- But I remember every word.
You even said the ocean
would sing you to sleep.
- And the moon and the stars and-
- Well, that's right, darling.
The ocean will sing me to sleep.
And the moon and the stars-
The stars. Remember last night
on the ferryboat?
- Yes.
- Well, look over your left shoulder again, will you?
- No, Andy. No.
- Please? Just for me. Just this once.
Just for good luck. Please.
Andy, you've got-Andy!
Andy!
That's the last time
I'll ever take you anyplace.
- Eadie. Well.
- Fancy seeing you here.
- Yes, isn't it fancy?
- I suppose you came down to meet our train, eh?
Yes, I did,
but I was a little early.
Of course, you couldn't have been seeing
a few soldiers off, by any chance.
A few soldiers?
Only one, I'll bet you. Sergeant Crazy.
It's Casey, Dorita. And what's wrong
with saying good-bye to a soldier?
- Nothing.
- I call it nice works if you can get him.
- Where have you two been?
- To the cleaners.
- The cleaners?
- That's what they call the racetrack.
Dorita's never seen a race,
so I took her out to Empire City.
I thought she ought to meet a few
of the horses she's been supporting.
I've never seen a race myself, Dorita.
Tell me about it.
Okay, I tell you. First you pick
the horses, to win, to place, to show.
Then you buy three tickets.
You sit and hold them like this.
The horse lose.
You tear up the tickets.
Then you pick three more, to win,
place, show. You buy three more tickets.
You hold them.
The horse lose again. You tear them up.
More races, more tickets,
more horse lose.
The day is over and what have you got?
I'll show you.
Hold this for me.
Like this, yes.
Horses.
Well, it looks like
a white Christmas.
A.J., have you seen
the San Francisco newspaper?
Why should I see
Well, my secretary's hometown
is San Francisco...
and she gets the San Francisco
newspaper every day.
- What's that got to do with me?
- Don't be stupid, old boy.
If it weren't her hometown,
she wouldn't get the paper, would she?
And I wouldn't be able to show you
this picture of your son receiving a medal.
So what? What?
Well, why didn't you say so
in the fiirst place?
Look at that. Been in the South Pacifiic
three months and already a hero.
Why wasn't I told about this? Why didn't
Andy write me? Where's my mail, Miss Custer?
- Right there before you, Mr. Mason.
- Oh, so it is.
- Why were you keeping this from me?
- Why, that's a medal.
- It's a medal.
- Why, it's the same one as in the picture.
It's the same one, on a ribbon
and everything. Isn't that handsome?
- Look at that.
- Oh! He's in San Francisco.
- No.
- Be home in about two weeks.
- Pottsie! My son back on American soil and a hero.
- Oh!
- Please.
- I tell you, we've got to get busy
and make some plans.
- We certainly have.
Why not another stag dinner?
I had a very good time at that last one.
No, no. Right here.
Behind his name, he signs ''N.S.D.''
Yes, National Selective Draft.
You see, that's what that-
National Selective nothing.
It's N.S.D. No stag dinners.
No stag dinner, yes. Well, then a quiet
little party at home. Just the two families.
He don't want
a quiet little dinner.
He's young.
He wants excitement.
Why, he wants wine, girls, song!
Yes, well, there's the community
sing every Thursday night. It's really-
Oh, that's so stupid,
the choir.
I know what it is. His favorite spot.
The Club New Yorker.
Oh. Well, that lets me out.
Of course, he's your son. If you want-
Wait a minute, Pottsie.
I'm tied up with this board meeting...
but you go right over to the Club New Yorker
now and make arrangements for a party.
What are you talking about? I go to a place
like that in broad daylight and by myself?
Oh, never mind. Now, come on.
Come on. I'll go with you.
Miss Custer,
cancel my next appointment.
Where did you think
you were goin'?
Come on, girls. Snap into it.
Put some life into it.
Close it in. Come on.
Watch your feet.
Up! That's it.
Lines. Now travel forward.
Come on. Forward. Travel!
Oh, kind of ragged, girls. Benson, I want you
to set a new routine for this opening.
- Come on, Pottsie.
- Oh, A.J. -
If you're scared, hold my hand.
Mr. Baker, you remember me, Andy's father.
- Yes, indeed.
- My partner, Mr. Potter.
- Hello. And how's the sergeant?
- Well, if you're referring to my son...
he's back from the Pacifiic
and covered with medals.
Really? How do you like that?
Andy Mason a hero.
And that's why we're here.
He'll be home in a couple of weeks...
and I want to arrange
a party for him here.
That'll be fiine.
Only, the club is closed.
- We're rehearsing a new show to open in October.
- Oh, really?
In that case, Mason, I'm sure Mr. Barker here
must be very busy with his chorus girls-
- Now, wait a minute.
- What's the matter?
- I've got an idea.
- It's too late, old boy.
- This time it's a real killer diller.
- A what?
Jukebox. Why don't you bring
your show up to my place?
That is a ridiculous idea.
You're not well, A.J.
And it's the air in here.
I know. It's this fresh paint.
- Look, you can rehearse it there
and present it at Oakwood.
- Oakwood? That's my place.
- Of course.
- What are you talking about?
That enormous terrace garden
on the south slope.
We could put tables on the terrace
and stage the show in the rose garden.
In my rose garden? I won't hear of such
a thing. Those are my prize yellow roses.
We'll put the show on
to sell war bonds.
We'll make it the biggest
bond-selling drive you ever saw.
We'll charge our neighbors
$5,000 bonds for admission.
Why, we'll raise a million dollars...
which would go to help Andy Mason
and millions like him to get the stuff they need.
Mr. Mason, if you had a beard,
you'd remind me...
of my two favorite people-
Santa Claus and Uncle Sam.
Well, we'll consider everything settled.
You bring your whole troupe
up for a week.
We got plenty of room for everybody,
two houses. Bring 'em up for two weeks.
- Oh, be sensible. Actors for two weeks?
You couldn't feed 'em.
- Oh, now, now.
- You couldn't feed them.
- We haven't got time to be sensible.
I'll call you back later this afternoon
and give you the details.
- Great.
- Oh, by the way...
do you think the Brazilian bombshell
will like the idea?
Well, I don't know. Why don't you
ask her yourself? Here she comes now.
How do you like my new costume?
You think it'll knock their feet off, huh?
Sensational. Oh, Dorita, you remember
Mr. Potter and Mr. Mason.
I remember Mr. Potty. You are here
to kick up some more heels, huh?
- No.
- Mr. Potter wants you to come
to his house this weekend.
Ah-ah, you naughty boy.
You are what they call a fast-work man, yes?
- Mason, please.
- Well, it was really my idea.
We wanted you to come
and help sell war bonds.
Oh. You know, I like you both.
I think you are very cute.
Phil, we're ready for Eadie Allen's number.
Okay. Why don't you boys watch the rehearsal?
I want to see what you think of it.
- Okay, Benny, here we go.
- All right, Phil.
What do you say?
How about it, Eadie?
- I'm all ready, Phil.
- All right, boys, hit the lights.
Come on, girls.
Clear the stage, everyone. Hit it, Benny.
- Wait till you hear her sing this song. It's a lulu.
Where'd you get
all these station wagons?
Commandeered them from the neighbors.
I'm chairman of the transportation committee.
With Mr. Mason's $5,000 war bond admission,
reservations are pouring in.
And at $200 a table, looks like
a real sellout for the army and the navy.
- Say, that's wonderful.
- Did you ever saw so much flowers...
and trees and shrubbers?
- Very nice, Dorita. Very nice.
- What are you do up in the dumps?
Eadie is worried because she thinks
a certain soldier may be back from overseas.
Why shouldn't I worry?
He'll never fiind me out here.
The club is closed, I've left my apartment.
He won't know where I am.
I know exactly
how you feel, Eadie.
I have a soldier too.
He lives right next door.
Andy Mason, Jr.
Maybe you know him.
- Andy Mason, Jr? Why, I know him well.
- You do?
Say, you're not by any chance
engaged to him, are you?
Well, sort of. We've been sweethearts
since I was 10 and he was 12.
- Andy's just back from Australia.
- Australia?
- Casey was in Australia.
- Really?
Wouldn't it be funny
if they knew each other?
Yes, wouldn't it?
Mr. And Mrs. Potter, I want you
to meet Benny Goodman and his boys.
- How do you do, Benny Goodman and boys?
- How do you do?
Go in the house.
You'll fiind everything you need.
- Walter and Edward will take care of you.
- Thank you.
Just make yourselves
at home, boys and girls.
Mother, this is Eadie Allen and Dorita.
I think you've met Mr. Mason.
- Hello.
- Welcome to Oakwood, my dears.
- We're so pleased.
- Thank you.
Ah, I remember you from your pictures
in the newspapers, or was it the police gazette?
- How are you?
- I'm very well to do. Thank you.
Ah, you do very well
what you do do.
Now you young ladies will have
the Magnolia Room. That is the room
next to my daughter's.
- I'll show you up.
- I'm going to like here.
That hat. I'll have to watch
my bell cords and lampshades.
Oh, Phil.
- Hello, Mr. Mason.
- Mrs. Potter, I want you to meet Phil Baker.
How do you do, Mrs. Potter?
This is a great pleasure,
Mr. Baker.
I've heard so much about you,
from young Andrew especially.
I'm so happy to have you with us.
So happy.
I'm so happy
to be here, Mrs. Potter.
It's lovely of you to arrange this holiday
for my hardworking little troupe.
- So very lovely.
- Oh, it's nothing at all, really.
I'll leave you two to get acquainted while
I see that the boys fiind their proper rooms.
- Blossom!
- Philsy!
Blossom, you old cabbage, you.
Oh, boy, it's more
like coleslaw now.
Oh, you haven't changed a bit.
I wish I could say
the same for you.
- You could if you'd lie a little too.
- Do you remember Paris?
- Do I?
- Ah, Paris.
- Paris in the '20s.
- Oh, boy, were you a sensation
with that accordion.
And you with your silver soprano.
What a set of pipes.
Ah, the pipes are not what they used to be.
They're a little corroded right now.
Phil, if anybody in Westchester ever dreamed
that I was once on the stage and in Paris-
Scandalous. Do you remember
the Count de Grace?
How could I ever forget him?
He used to call me his ''long-stem Blossom.''
Well, what the countess called you
made international headlines.
- That was the night of the Beaux Arts Ball.
- You and I took over the show.
- Do you remember that Apache dance we did?
- Do I?
You sure it was in the '20s?
I'm positive it was in the '20s.
It was in the '20s, wasn't it?
Mrs. Potter!
Oh, Peytie. I was just
welcoming Mr. Baker to Oakwood.
- Mr. Baker, Mr. Potter.
- How do you do, Mr. Potter?
I had no idea
he was that welcome.
How welcome would you say
I was in round numbers?
The rest of the theatrical people
are having refreshments on the terrace.
- Possibly you'd like to join them.
- You left your motor running.
He's a sweetheart. I'll bet
he'd give away his last pint of blood.
In fact, I think he has.
I absolutely forbid you getting within
20 feet of that man again. You understand?
- Peytie, wouldn't you settle for 10?
- Well, 15 at the most.
Peytie, can I help it
if I'm irresistible?
It's that vitamin B1. I told you you were
taking too much. You're overdoing it.
- Peytie-
- I don't care to discuss the matter at all.
- All right, Cap, hook her up.
- Give me the slack.
- I love that melody.
- That's the music for Tony De Marco
and Maria's dance.
Where are they?
Oh, Tony! Maria!
Don't look now,
but here comes half of them.
Don't tell me
they've been rationed too.
- I know, but what are you gonna do?
If you don't cut that out,
the censors will. What's he saying?
He wants to know why you didn't tell him
he had to dance in a rose garden.
- What's that got to do with it?
- They're Mr. Potter's roses and he's fond of them.
But he says you don't realize
what your fiiendish little roses have done.
- What have they done?
- No.
- What'd he say?
- How should I know?
They had to send his partner
back to New York with rose fever.
- She doesn't like roses, so Tony hates them.
- Is that so?
Where is he? There you are.
My roses aren't too fond of you.
- What have you got to say to that?
He says he's gonna sue you
and your roses for ruining his partner's health.
- Sue me?
- S!
This is an outrage! Where's Mason?
He got me into this.
I'm gonna have you and your theatrical troupe
thrown off this place forcibly.
- Mason! Mason!
- Oh, Mr. Potter! Mr. Potter!
Let him go.
Mason will cool him off.
What happens to me they wouldn't believe
on the Goodwill Hour.
- Eadie, tell Tony he'll have
to get another dancing partner.
- Another partner?
- Yes.
- But who?
- That's his worry.
- Okay.
I'll stay as I am.
- Tony!
Tony!
I'm sorry.
I've never seen him-
- You are beautiful!
- He speaks English.
It's wolf talk.
That's international.
Say, Vivian's all right.
She catches on pretty quick.
Well, I taught her a few steps
when her father wasn't around.
I might have known. Mrs. Potter
was a great dancer herself in her day.
- Really?
- She was so smooth, she could waltz around...
with a glass of beer on her bustle
and never disturb the foam.
- I guess Vivian takes after her.
- A block off the old chip, huh?
That was thrilling, darling.
I think you danced beautifully.
Baby, you were great.
I want you in the show.
Thank you, Mr. Baker, but I'm afraid of Dad.
He'd never approve of it.
- Why not?
- You know how he feels
about shows and show people.
- My purple past, remember?
- Vivian's gonna be in this show.
Oh, Peyton will never allow it.
- Not even with some gentle persuasion?
- What do you mean?
- Let's see. I've got it. Your boudoir.
- What are you talking about?
I'm talking about the biggest scene
of your career.
Come along,
you old tenderized ham.
Well, at last,
I'm worth something.
- You know what to do now?
- No, my mama never told me.
- Don't you worry about me.
- Here he is.
- Come on, baby. Do your stuff.
- Come in. Oh, Peyton.
- You sent for me, dear?
- Yes, I did.
- What's Mr. Barlow doing here?
- Protect me. This man is blackmailing us.
- Blackmail?
- What's he want, money?
- Would it were money he wanted.
- What do you mean by that?
- He threatens me unless I allow my daughter-
your daughter- our daughter to dance
in the show with Tony De Marco.
Why, that's unthinkable!
Oh, you blackguard.
Oh, you gangster.
How could you think
of such a fiiendish scheme?
Now, Mr. Potter, the only decision
I want you to make is this.
Shall I introduce Vivian as the charming child
of Mr. And Mrs. Peyton Potter...
or shall I simply announce,
ladies and gentlemen...
- I give you the talented daughter
of the notorious Blossom Murphy?
You know her name?
You told him your name?
- No, Peyton, he knew me in Paris.
- In Paris?
You scoundrel! Out of her dark past
which she has lived down so beautifully...
so gracefully, you come at a time
like this to blackmail her.
Ugly word, ''blackmail.''
Don't say it again.
Blackmail, blackmail,
blackmail!
- How much money does he want?
- I don't know.
As I said before,
you cannot bribe me with gold.
It is the artistry
that was Blossom Murphy...
that I would restore to the world
through her daughter Vivian.
Oh, Peyton, you won't make her do it!
You won't make her appear in that show!
- I would die!
- I see no other way out, darling.
Mr. Bailey has us in his power.
- Will you give your consent, Mrs. Potter?
- If Mr. Potter insists!
What else can I do?
But I'm not fiinished with you yet.
I'll see a good lawyer today
to deal with you for this outrage.
- My brother in Brooklyn,
he's a wiz on blackmail cases.
- Oh, is he?
- Yes.
- Really!
- Dorita, come in. I've got a surprise for you.
- What surprise?
- What was it?
- Dad's given his consent. I can appear in the show.
Marvelous!
Then everything's donkey-dory, huh?
- What you got there?
- Sergeant Mason.
- You like him?
- Sergeant Mason? He's Sergeant Crazy!
I think it's you that's crazy.
Oh, no, no, I'm not crazy.
My name is Dorita.
- This is the man I'm going to marry.
- What?
Then he's a two-time,
double-cross snake in the bush.
- Dorita.
- Yes?
- Are you the woman?
- Of course I'm a woman. Do I look like a man?
You don't understand.
You see...
I think there was someone he was playing
around with in town.
Look, nobody play around me,
in town, in cities, nowhere.
I thought you recognized
this picture.
At fiirst minute, yes.
But the second minute, no.
It was somebody else who looked
just like him, like twin sisters.
Same eyes, same hair,
same mouth.
- You were telling the truth?
- Scratch my heart.
Vivian, are you in?
- Oh, it's Eadie!
- What about it? Does that frighten you?
No, I'm cold as a cucumber.
- Come in, Eadie.
- I just heard the good news.
Phil's little blackmail party
really paid off.
Isn't it wonderful?
I've always wanted to dance.
- Tony's very excited about you.
- Oh, I'm glad.
- What's the matter with you?
- Nothing. I feel in the pinks.
Then stop looking like Lady Macbeth.
What's wrong with her?
I don't know.
Can I get you something, Dorita?
Oh, no, no, nothing.
I feel wonderful, if you don't mind.
- Why don't you sit down? You seem restless.
- Oh, no, no.
I like it here, just standing.
- Aren't you tired?
- Yes, I guess I am.
I think I go now and turn myself in
and get some shut eyes.
- You know. Good night.
- Good night, Dorita.
- I'll see you in a few minutes.
- Yes, good night.
- Dorita, you're snoring again.
Dorita! Dorita, wake up!
What's the matter, buglers?
- Where did you get this picture?
- What picture?
You know what picture.
This picture of Casey.
Your birthday next week, no?
- Don't change the subject.
- I'm not changing anything.
Casey sent you the picture
for your birthday. Only, he send to me.
And now you have spoiled surprise.
That's all.
No, I haven't. It's a much better
surprise this way.
- You think so, huh? Yes?
- Mm-hmm.
Good. I don't get it.
Good heavens, 10:00!
I might expect this
from you in person...
but when your picture wanders
into strange girls' rooms-
Really.
Well! What do you want?
Mr. Mason is serving everyone mint jalops,
and I bring you a mint jalops too.
- It's delicious.
- You might have saved yourself the trouble.
- I am a teetotaller. I never touch alcohol.
- You don't touch. You drink it.
I'm very sorry, but I am a very busy man,
and I am never disturbed at this time.
So I'm going to ask you to run away,
and take those poisonous things with you.
No, I stay and be a teetotaller too.
Maybe show me how to teetotal.
Miss Dorita, I am a businessman.
I go in for no foolishness.
- I am entirely business.
- Oh, I like that.
Maybe you show me how
to be all business too. Is it fun?
Well, uh, fun? Business?
Why, certainly not. It's not supposed to be fun.
- Oh, no?
- No.
Then I don't think I like it.
I like to have fun.
- You'll never make money that way.
- Oh, money, huh?
You have lots of, don't you?
Thousands and thousands of dollars, huh?
I've done rather well, yes.
Look, Dorita has only a little.
If she had only a few thousand,
she would not work for a boss.
She would work for herself
in her own nightclub.
Maybe you let her have
a few thousands, maybe?
Well, certainly not!
I never heard of such nonsense.
I never invest
in theatrical enterprises. Never.
Now, I want you to take
these two slugs I think they call them...
and you tell everybody you see
that I'm not to be disturbed.
- What do you invest in?
- Oh, well, several things.
- I have an investment counselor, really.
- What is that?
- He's a man who handles my money for me.
- I have one of those too.
- Who is it?
- Phil Baker.
- Phil Baker, the actor?
- Yes.
- He handles your money for you?
- Only, when he handle my money,
I never see it again.
- Like these fiive horses with letters.
- Horses?
- Yeah.
- You need say no more, Miss Dorita.
I understand why you never see
your money again. You're a foolish girl.
You should insist on sound investments.
Now, tell my wife-
- Maybe you could handle my money for me.
- Sorry. I have no time.
Oh, but how much time
would it took? How much time?
It takes more time
than I could afford to give.
Miss Dorita, I am in no mood
to listen to fiinancial suggestions.
Oh, come on here.
Sit by me.
Come on here. Sit by me and
tell me more about sound investments.
- Yes, yes. You have the busiest hands.
- You think so?
Sound investments?
Well, there are quite a few of them.
- Quite a few I haven't got money for.
Just tell me one.
- One?
- Yeah.
- Well, there's National Copper.
- National Copper.
- That's very safe.
That's pretty. I like it very much.
Thank you very, very nice. Yes.
Well, uh, then, of course,
there's American Steel.
American Steel.
That's beautiful too. I like too.
Thank you very, very nice.
I could say Tel and Tel.
Tel and Tel.
I like that best of all!
- I hoped you would. Yes, I hoped you-
- Yes!
And did you play money
on this Tel and Tel?
Very often.
Quite a lot of money, yes.
- And she come in for you?
- Yes, if that's the way you want to put it.
I want to put it that way, yes.
I want to put all my money on her.
- On Tel and Tel?
- Yes! Thank you very, very much!
Buddy, what's the matter?
I don't know.
- But it's happened.
- What happened?
- Does that mean anything to you?
- No.
- Well, it does to me.
- I don't understand.
Oh, nobody is more surprised
than I am.
Mr. Potty, I'm afraid of you.
You are, really?
National Copper, eh?
- American Steel? Well-
- Don't move!
- Mrs. Potty.
Don't mention my wife.
We're going to keep this all on an even keel.
Mrs. Potty-
- Do you remember the other night
when we danced together?
You do remember. Good.
You remember how I held you in my arms?
That's the way I'm gonna hold you now.
- No, no, no. Mrs. Potty!
- We'd like to be alone, please.
Darling, how marvelous! We were just
discussing the invasion- the investments.
It's Tel and Tel, Miss Dorita.
You mustn't forget it.
That's one of
our soundest investments.
You can't go wrong with Tel and Tel.
Can we, darling?
Tel and Tel!
Oh, Tel and Tel!
- Thank you very, very nice.
- Just a minute.
It wasn't my fault.
He swooped me off my feet.
- Oh, chop, chop, chop.
So-
Well, old swoopy, swapping swoops at your age.
What have you got to say about that?
I told you, darling,
we were simply discussing investments.
I see. Is that the way
it's being done nowadays?
No wonder you come home
from the offiice so tired.
That's what I say, dear.
That's what I say. No wonder.
Oh. Ketchup.
No doubt.
And from a Brazilian tomato.
Darn it.
Hook me up, will you, soldier?
- Thanks.
- Excuse me.
- Hey, where are you going?
- Andy. Andy, welcome home, Son.
- Dad.
- I knew you'd do it.
Certainly looks good to see you again
after all these months.
- That goes double, Dad.
- Why didn't you wire me?
I didn't expect you till evening.
I flew in.
Gee, it's great to be home.
But, Dad, what's going on around here?
The house is full of show people.
Don't worry, Son. I locked up all the silverware
and put all the breakable stuff away.
I've got a big surprise for you.
- Oh, Vivian.
- Come in, Eadie.
- Does that do it, Nanette?
- I think it will.
- Good morning.
- My, but you look pretty.
- I hope so. Andy's coming home today.
That's right. I'm looking forward
to meeting your Andy.
- You'll like him.
- I'm sure I will.
- There, that does it.
- Thank you, Nanette.
- You're welcome, Miss Vivian.
- Well, what a coincidence.
- What?
- This frame. I have one exactly like-
What are you doing with this picture
on your dressing table?
- That's the man I'm going to marry.
- Are you kidding?
No, of course I'm not kidding.
It's a very good picture of him.
- I agree with you.
- You do? You don't even know him.
- Not really, but I've seen him.
- You have?
Mm-hmm. Look.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
What would your sergeant
think of this?
I'll bet Dorita had something
to do with it.
You wait and see.
Tell me, Dad,
what's the idea?
It's a little surprise party
for you, Sergeant.
Being as you're opposed
to bachelor dinners...
we're staging a big show next door in
Potter's gardens, and you're the guest of honor.
No fooling? You're really doing all that
for me? Gee, that's swell, Dad.
Brought up the whole
Club New Yorker.
Brought up the whole show.
Well, what do ya know?
Say, wait a minute.
Did you say the Club New Yorker?
- Sure.
- But that means Phil Baker and Dorita and Eadie-
- Eadie's here, isn't she?
- You mean Miss Allen?
- Yeah.
- Sure. She's one of their stars. You know her?
Know her? I'm in love with her.
I'm going to marry her, Dad.
- Now wait a minute, Son. Hold on.
- It's true.
I came up to tell you-
to tell everybody.
See here, the excitement's upset you.
You don't realize what you're saying.
- You're gonna marry Vivian Potter, remember?
- Yes, yes, I remember.
- But that can wait.
- Yeah.
- Wait?
- Well, it's like this. You see-
I can't explain now, Dad. I've got to see
Eadie right away. Where is she?
- Why, she's next door with Vivian.
- With Vivian?
You mean to say that she's over there
with Vivian right in the same house?
- Sure.
See here, Son.
Was this Eadie Allen the unfiinished business
you had to attend to...
that night at the Club New Yorker
just before you sailed?
Mm-hmm.
Well, you've certainly got
a nice fiinishing job on your hands.
- Yeah, I sure have.
- You're gonna need a bracer
before you face those girls.
Come on.
How about a nice mint jalopy?
Oh, darn it.
She's got me saying it now.
- Dorita, what have you done
with Sergeant Mason's picture?
- Sergeant who?
- Sergeant Mason- the picture
that was in this frame.
And Casey's picture, it's gone too.
What have you done with it?
Dorita. Dorita,
what are you up to?
Okay, I guess the jig is down.
I might as well make a clean chest of it.
Your picture and Vivian's picture
is the same picture.
- What are you talking about?
- Sergeant Mason is Sergeant Crazy
and vice-a-vice-a.
You and Vivian both got same sweetheart
between you.
- Dorita, you know, I think you're a little-
- No, no, I'm not little.
I'll show you. Give me this picture.
You don't believe me, huh?
I'll show you. Look.
There's your Sergeant Crazy.
And I wash my face
of the whole business.
Find it, Eadie?
Andy's picture.
Then she did have it.
- Are you, uh-Are you sure it's Andy?
- Huh?
- Well, I mean-
- Well, of course it's Andy.
Isn't he handsome?
I wonder what made her
do a thing like that?
I don't know.
I guess it was just one of her tricks.
Oh, clowning, huh?
Yeah...
clowning.
Dorita! Where's Eadie?
Oh, it's you. Shame on you,
you Dr. Jekylls and Mr. Hydes.
- Then Eadie knows. And Vivian?
- I just spilled the cat out of the beans myself.
- You did. Gee, what'll I do?
- I don't care what you do.
I know what I'd do if girl
take my man away from me.
- What do you mean?
- I break her into little hunks...
and then I break him
into little hunks.
And then I take
all the little hunks and, uh-
Well, good-bye.
I must do some rehearsalings.
Vivian!
- Andy, darling!
Oh, let me look at you, you wonderful guy
with decorations and everything.
Hug me again. Closer.
It's good to have you home again after all
these months. I bet you didn't miss me.
Or did you?
Well, come on. Tell me.
Andy, darling,
what's the mat-
Oh, Eadie, don't go.
Come here.
This is my Sergeant Mason
I've been talking so much about.
How do you do,
Sergeant... Mason?
How do you do?
- Well, aren't you going to introduce us?
- Huh?
Oh, uh, this is
Sergeant Pat Casey.
- Miss Potter and Miss Allen.
- Pleased to meet you, I'm sure.
Sergeant Casey has been helping me
with my correspondence.
Receiving certain letters for me
and handing them over.
- Certain letters?
- Yes, you see, well, it's-
That's right, Vivian.
You might as well know now.
This is my Sergeant Casey. We were gonna
keep it a secret, weren't we, Pat?
- Were we?
- Why, Eadie, they did know
each other in Australia.
- Uh-huh.
- Isn't it a small world?
- Yeah.
- Oh, Andy, listen.
I have to run now.
I'm in the show and I have a rehearsal.
So you'll excuse me, won't you?
Oh, uh, why don't you all take a walk or something.
You and Eadie can get acquainted.
Pat and I have so much to talk about.
Haven't we, Pat?
- Have we?
- Oh, that's all right.
Andy won't mind.
See you later, kids.
Eadie-
Pat, why don't you go watch the rehearsals.
Maybe some of the girls need hooking up.
Eadie, where are you going?
- What difference does it make?
- A lot.
I'm sorry, Eadie.
Desperately sorry.
- I was going to tell you, honest I was.
- Tell me what?
About this whole thing, Vivian and me.
It doesn't mean anything.
Just childhood sweethearts, that's all.
The families, you know.
- I bet if you even ask Vivian, she'd tell you-
- She has told me.
How much?
Plenty.
- Do you remember that night in the canteen?
- Uh-huh.
I told you you were sweet.
I meant it.
You were sweet.
And you still are, Andy.
But just because you guys
over there go through a lot of-
Well, never mind.
But what do you suppose the girls you
leave behind think of after you've gone?
- Their man.
- Yeah, I guess they do.
I don't have to guess.
I know.
- I wrote you every day, didn't I?
- Yeah.
At night I couldn't wait to get through
at the club so I could get home to write.
I know you did.
- How do you know?
- I just know, that's all.
Yeah, you know.
You men know everything.
You can tear a girl's heart right out
of her and cut it up into little pieces.
A girl knows that.
Every girl knows it.
And that's why I'm gonna let
Vivian go right on through...
even though
the stop signal's against her.
- But, darling, you-
- I'm doing it because she- she believes in you.
She loves you, Andy.
No girl with understanding
would ever let another girl down.
But you can't do this, Eadie.
L- I love-
You love yourself, Andrew Mason.
Why don't you try sitting
back among the crowd for a change...
instead of up close
at the ringside.
Oh, that's wonderful, Tony.
Do you really mean it?
- Certainly.
- Then I'll go.
- But what about your engagement to Andy?
- You leave that to me.
- Splendid.
- See you after the show.
- Okay.
- Oh, Eadie, isn't it wonderful?
I'm on my way to Broadway.
I'm going to New York with Tony De Marco.
- I'm his new dancing partner!
- What?
I don't know what the folks
will say, about Andy, I mean.
Of course, it's only a family affair.
We never really loved each other.
- You mean that-
- Well, even Andy knows that.
Anyway, the folks started it.
Let them work it out.
- Eadie, come on. They're waiting.
- There's something I have to do.
I know- the fiinale. You can't keep
those children waiting all night.
But you don't understand. It's your son.
I have to tell him something he doesn't know.
Then he's the only one who doesn't.
But just in case, I'll tell him.
You will?