One day,
when I was 6 years old,
I saw a magnificent picture in a
nature book about the primeval forest.
It was a picture of a boa constrictor
swallowing an animal.
I'm trying to make a sketch of it
to show you.
Under this splendid picture, it said;
"Boa constrictors swallow
their prey whole, without chewing it."
There.
"And then remain stationary
for six months digesting it."
I pondered that deeply.
And after some work, I succeeded
in making my first drawing.
I called it Drawing Number One.
I showed my masterpiece
to the grownups.
I asked them if it frightened them.
Frighten us?
Why should we be frightened of a hat?
A hat?
It was a picture of a boa constrictor
digesting an elephant.
Obviously.
Since the grownups were not
able to understand it, I made another,
showing the elephant
inside the boa constrictor,
so they could see it clearly.
My Drawing Number Two.
This time, I was told to stop wasting
my time drawing boa constrictors,
whether from the inside or the outside,
and attend to my studies, which I did.
And that is why, at the age of 6,
I gave up what might have been
a magnificent career as a painter.
As I grew up, whenever I'd meet one
who seemed to be at all clear-sighted,
in order to find out if he was really
a person of true understanding,
I would show him my first drawing.
But whoever it was would say;
It's a hat, it's a hat
It's a sort of a kind of hat
Painted poorly
But it surely is a hat
It's a hat, it's a hat
There's no doubt of it, it's a hat
Top of Papa
Is its proper habitat
My, oh, my, look at that
Why, this dummy has drawn a hat
It's a hat, it's a hat
If it's anything, it's a hat
Why, it's nothing but a common
Himalayan mountain hat
A hat that looks like down upon
Which someone must've sat
Not Picasso or Corot
But a very nice chapeau
Are you kidding?
It's a hat, you silly brat
Every grownup was the same
Uniformly, they'd exclaim
It's a hat, it's a hat, it's a hat
I could see it wasrt won'th
Spending time with them on earth
There were fewer in the sky
I decided I would fly
- It's a hat
It's a hat, it's a hat, it's a hat
I need air
Where only stars get in my hair
And only eagles stop and stare
I need air
All the world is mad
And I have had my share
I need air
One hour of mortal wear and tear
Gives my morale moral-de-mer
Any corner lot
That heavers got to spare
I need air
There's not a sign of life down there
Just hats and grownups everywhere
I need air
Lots of cozy sky
That God and I can share
I need air
Over the years,
I came to know many grownups,
and my opinion of them
never improved.
In time, I stopped
showing my drawing
and never again mentioned
boa constrictors, elephants or stars.
Instead, I would talk about golf,
money, politics and neckties.
And everyone was pleased
to have met such a sensible man.
So I lived my life alone,
without anyone I could really talk to,
until a short time ago.
I was testing a new plane,
racing it against the clock
from Paris to India.
Paris calling flight F-BDXY.
Come in, please, over.
F-BDXY to Paris.
Ground speed: 1 -9-0.
Running ten minutes behind schedule.
Strong headwinds.
Trouble!
- Losing altitude!
- Paris calling flight F-BDXY.
Detail location.
Repeat, detail location.
Paris calling flight F-BDXY.
Are you there, F-BDXY?
Where are you?
If you please,
draw me a sheep.
Will you?
- Will I what?
- Will you draw me a sheep?
Who are...?
Where did you...?
How did you...?
How did you get here?
- What are you doing here?
- Waiting for you to draw me a sheep.
No, no. Listen to me.
- Where did you come from?
- Will you draw me a sheep?
Don't you know any other words?
Is that all you can say?
No.
Will you draw me a sheep?
When a mystery is too overpowering,
one doesn't dare disobey.
A thousand miles from civilization
and death at my heels,
I picked up a pad and pencil
and began to draw.
Look, I...
I don't know how to draw.
- That doesn't matter.
- And I certainly can't draw a sheep.
I've only drawn one thing
in my whole life.
Here.
Oh, no. I don't want an elephant
inside a boa constrictor.
A boa constrictor is very dangerous,
and an elephant is very cumbersome.
Where I live, everything is very small.
What I need is a sheep.
Do you live in a small town?
On a small island?
Where is it very small?
What sort of object is that?
- What?
- That.
It's called an aeroplane.
It flies.
I was flying in it,
but it broke down.
Then you must have dropped
from the sky.
That's right.
You too. How funny.
If you don't mind, I prefer having
my misfortunes taken seriously.
- What do you mean, "you too"?
- That's a very sick-Iooking sheep.
Is that how you got here?
In a plane that crashed?
Could you make another?
- Why?
- Because that one doesn't look well.
This is not the way two strangers get to
know each other on the average desert.
This is the way.
Ask me a question.
- Where do you come from?
- Good.
To which I reply,
"I come from Paris."
Now I'll ask you a question.
- Where do you come from?
- Is Paris on this planet?
Of course it's on this planet.
I'm sorry, it won't do.
- Why not?
- See for yourself.
That's not a sheep.
It's a ram. It has horns.
Do you think
this is all I have to do?
I have this engine to take apart
and fix before my water runs out.
I have no time to draw for a little boy
dressed in a coat, carrying a sword,
who appears from nowhere
in the middle of the Sahara.
There, and that's the last.
There's no horns.
No.
It's not sick.
- Well, then?
- It's old.
I'm sorry.
It's only his box.
The sheep you asked for is inside.
That's perfect,
exactly the way I wanted it.
It is?
Good.
Do you think this sheep
will need a lot of grass?
- Why?
- I told you.
Where I come from,
everything is very small.
Don't worry.
It's a very small sheep.
This sheep isn't so small.
Alas, I couldn't argue with him.
I'd grown too old to see sheep
through the walls of boxes.
Is Paris on this planet?
Of course it is.
Did you forget?
No, I didn't forget.
But why did you ask?
- Arert you from this planet?
- The thing that's so good about this box
is, at night,
he can use it as his house.
- He's just going to sleep.
- Oh, sorry.
- Good morning.
Where in God's name
could you have come from?
- Do you know what asteroids are?
- What whats are?
- Asteroids.
- No.
They're very, very small planets.
The smallest, Asteroid B-61 2,
was discovered by a Turkish
astronomer in 1 909.
I think you may live on Asteroid B-61 2.
What do you think?
Does that mean they also
eat baobab bushes?
- Who?
- The sheep.
Do they also eat flowers?
- Do they?
- Just hold it a minute, will you?
- Do they also eat flowers?
- What?
Oh, yes, they do.
Except the flowers
that have thorns, of course.
No, they even eat the flowers
that have thorns.
But the thorns protect them,
don't they?
Maybe from being picked,
but not from being eaten.
Then what's the good
of having them?
- Having what?
- Thorns.
I don't know. Spite, I suppose.
Flowers have thorns just for spite.
I don't believe you.
Flowers are weak and helpless,
and they know it.
How could they face the world if they
didn't believe they were protected?
- What I'm doing here is important.
- Important?
Flowers have been growing thorns
for millions of years.
And for millions of years, sheep have
been eating them just the same.
Eating them.
And you think that's not important?
- Of course it is.
- I know one flower
that's unique in all the world.
It grows nowhere but on my planet.
But some morning, a sheep can
come along and destroy it
with one single bite.
And you think that's not important?
- I suppose so.
- What you don't understand is,
that if someone loves one flower
that grows on one star
among all the millions and millions
of stars in the sky,
it's enough to make him happy
to look at the stars.
He can say to himself,
"Somewhere my flower's up there."
But if a sheep eats the flower,
in one moment,
all the stars will go dark.
And you think that's not important?
It's not a matter
of consequence to you, is it?
Wait!
Wait! Come back!
I most humbly apologize.
I was behaving like a grownup.
Your flower is very important.
I swear it.
Come back!
Please!
Please come back!
Where did you go?
Little man, don't you know
That I'm on your side?
Why did you go?
Little man, let me show you
I'm on your side
This world
Is an ocean without any shore
When you're on your own
Dawn is the end of the rope
When you're all alone
I've been, I've seen
I've known it
Where can you be?
Hurry back, and you'll see
That I'm on your side
Where did you run?
Why did you run
From the one, only one
Who is on your side?
Everybody needs a friend
Come make use of me
God gave people hands to lend
Mine are free
So why stay away?
Come what may
I'm on
Your side
I missed him.
I wished I'd discovered
more about him.
But he'd gone and taken
his mystery with him.
Unaccustomed as I am
to drawing anything
but boa constrictors and elephants,
I decided to make a portrait of him
so that I wouldn't forget him.
After all, he was a friend.
And not everyone has a friend.
Least of all me.
I'm hungry.
I have your supper right here.
I waited as long as I could.
I'd advise saving some
of that till tomorrow.
That is, of course,
unless you're very hungry.
Is this all you have?
Well, at the moment, yes.
This will be quite enough,
thank you.
Needless to say,
that problem you outlined,
concerning the flower you know.
The one on the star,
and your sheep...
In fact, all flowers
and all sheep, that's...
That's extremely important.
In fact, I can't think of anything
that's more important.
Well, I've been giving it
a great deal of thought, and I...
I think I've come up with a solution
that will remove your flower
from any possibility of danger.
Now, this is my plan.
But this is subject
to your approval, of course.
One, to draw a muzzle
for your sheep.
Two...
If you can describe your planet
to me in sufficient detail
for me to make a drawing of it,
I'll put up a big, strong fence
all around your flower.
Would you really do that?
Smaller.
I have three volcanoes.
- How big are they?
- Very big.
- Compared to you?
- Knee-high.
I have to clean them out every day.
- All by yourself?
- There's no one else.
There are three baobab bushes.
You don't have to draw them.
They don't come up for a while.
- Where's your house?
- On the other side.
You don't have to draw that either.
And my flower lives on this side here.
When she first came
through the ground,
I was afraid she was going
to be a baobab,
but then she blossomed.
One bright, yellow morning,
she blossomed.
- Good morning.
- Stop.
What is it?
- Give me a moment to wake up.
- I'm sorry.
How beautiful you are.
Yes, I know.
I was born at the same moment
as the sun.
- Did you know that?
- No.
- Did you know you were quite selfish?
- Selfish?
Instead of thinking of my needs,
you're standing there doing
what you want to do,
which is stare at me.
- What is it you need?
- Water.
- Water?
- I realize this is a small,
- unequipped little planet.
- I'll get it for you right away.
I brought her some water.
I brought it every day.
I did everything I could for her.
It's cooler when the sun goes down.
Do you have a glass bowl
to put over me?
That will only make you weaker.
The night air is good for you.
I'm cold!
You promised me a glass bowl.
It's not cold.
- Do you love me?
- Yes, I love you very much.
You've made my planet beautiful.
I don't believe it.
If you loved me,
you'd know how cold I am.
I promise you, the nights aren't long.
You'll soon get used to it.
- Do you love me?
- I'll get the bowl.
I couldn't understand it,
and I couldn't understand her.
I loved her,
but I was so unappy.
I began to realize
I didn't really understand anything.
So I decided to leave my planet
and go out into the universe
and try to learn something.
I was wrong to leave her.
But at the time,
I didn't even understand that.
I was too young.
One morning,
I cleaned out my volcanoes,
took one last look for baobabs
and put my planet in order.
Good morning.
- You're all dressed up.
- Yes.
- You look very handsome.
- Thank you.
- You're going away, aren't you?
- Yes.
- For a long time?
- Perhaps.
I see.
It's my fault you're going,
isn't it?
I've been very foolish,
haven't I?
I wonder who will call on me
when you're not here.
There are those two caterpillars,
of course.
I don't like them,
but one has to put up with them
if one wants to meet butterflies.
For anything else, I have my thorns.
Well...
...if you're going...
: : : go:
- Goodbye.
- Be happy, be happy, be happy
Forget that I have no one
And nowhere to go
Be happy, be happy, be happy
Don't think of me in winter
All covered with snow
Be happy, be happy
Forget that I'll be crying still
And never
Will be happy
Be happy
Without you
Stop!
- Where are your papers?
- What papers?
You can't cross the border
without papers.
- What border?
- That border there.
- You need a visa. Do you have one?
- No.
Then you can't cross it.
Those are the rules. Stop!
You almost backed
into another country.
What are you? A smuggler?
A refugee? An idealist?
- Speak up. What are you?
- I'm ignorant.
Well, you might outgrow it.
Now, look...
My country is too small
for both of us,
but I have a colonial possession
1 foot to your left.
If your papers are in order,
you can settle down there.
Your Majesty, it's such a small planet.
Why do you need borders?
Why do we need borders?
Yes. Why do you need borders?
You told me to ask questions.
But any child understands
why we need borders.
- I don't.
- Well, of course you don't understand.
You're a child.
How do you expect
You can understand
International things and stuff?
Scissoring the earth
Carving up the land
Is the business of kings and stuff
Continentally, you are mentally
A silly-billy boy of 2
How absurd, it's uneard-of
You can never think as grownups do
Why, you
Oh, you're a child
You're a child
You're a twerp
And that's putting it mild
You're a speck
You're a fleck
And it's just too tough
Pounding grown-up stuff
In the bean of a green little child
- Try.
- What?
Explain it to me. I want to learn.
Well...
Why do borderlines exist?
Well, first and foremost on the list
If all the borders were destroyed
Tomorrow, I'd be unemployed
And what would statesmen do for fun
If all at once the world was one?
And one could wander
Where he pleases
Flashing smiles instead of visas
Why, it could
It might
It would
Oh, go away and grow
Come again when you're
Not a mini-brained punk like this
You are really too undeveloped
For philosophical junk like this
Too adult is it? Difficult is it?
To get your teeth into?
Too bewildering for the children
And that, of course, means you
Means you
You're a child
And the kind that can
Drive grownups wild
You're a wee little pea
Any thought profound
That I might expound
Wort fit into a pineaded child
Is that clear?
Now, where are your papers?
- I don't have any.
- You can't stay without papers.
Then I'll leave.
Just as well. You're dangerous.
Where's your passport?
- I don't have a passport.
- Then you can't leave.
Come back here!
Get off this planet!
Four hundred million and 997,000...
...plus six, equals 400,997,006!
Good day, sir.
Good day.
Five hundred million and ten!
Five hundred million and ten.
Plus one.
Five hundred million and 32!
Five hundred million, 32 what?
Five hundred million and 32 plus three.
Those things.
Five hundred million and 35.
- Stars?
- That's it. Stars.
Five hundred...
...million, 44.
- Plus...
- Why are you counting the stars?
Five hundred million...
I own them, and I want to see
how much I have.
But what good does it do you
to own the stars?
- It does me the good of making me rich.
- What good is it to be rich?
Because...
I don't know.
But how can you own the stars?
When you find a diamond that doesn't
belong to anyone, it's yours.
If you get an idea before anyone else,
it's yours.
So I got the idea of owning the stars.
You want to stay here? Fine.
You can help me count.
But if I owned a flower,
I could do something for it.
What can you do for the stars?
You wouldn't understand.
You're a child.
Gimme, how can you
Gimme, understand
Gimme, gimme,
Financial stuff?
Gimme, your supply
Gimme, my demand
Mentally is gigantial stuff
Gimme oodles of
Gimme boodles of
I don't care what
But give me more
You're too poor and immature to know
What there are gimme-gimmes for
Why, you're
You're a child
You're too darling and dopey and mild
You're a nit
Half a wit
Speaking wisdom-wise
Private enterprise
Is too big
For a twig of a child
Oh, stocks and bonds!
I've lost me place!
Now I shall have to start
all over again.
Here, add up these figures.
Good afternoon, sir.
I'm searching for knowledge.
Oh, good.
You've come to the right place.
It's been said that I am
the greatest historian in history.
That's wonderful, sir.
Who said it?
I said it. I wrote it.
I read it. It's printed.
Consequently, it's fact.
It's history.
And now that you're here,
I shall put you down.
In history, I mean.
- Where did you come from?
- From another planet, sir.
- What was it called?
- I don't know, sir.
Oh, good, I'll give it a name.
I like making things up.
That's my job, making things up.
I'm an historian.
Let me see. Planet...
Alice! Do you like that?
Oh, no, sir. The planet Alice?
I don't like it at all.
No wonder you left it.
Here. Read my latest, an official
version of the French Revolution.
The other ones are now
totally inoperative.
Is that the truth, sir?
- What?
- The truth.
How do you spell it?
Never mind, sir.
I don't think I'd better stay.
Right. Wipe!
Left. Left. Left.
Shoulders back. Left. Left. Left.
Left. Left. On your feet, boy.
On your feet.
Where's your arm, boy? Where?
- My arm?
- The colors. The colors.
The flag.
Sir, I don't see anyone.
How could you?
There's no one there, silly ass.
Get those shoulders back. Back. Back!
Not that much. Watch it.
Stand easy.
Welcome to the base.
State your business.
I'm trying to learn about life, sir.
- Learn about what?
- Life.
Life? Oh, life. That.
Yes, of course.
Company, double-quick march!
Left, right. Left, right. Left, right.
You want to know what life is about?
Dying! That's what it's all about.
Die like a hero, boy.
That's the way to live. Company, halt!
Boy, this is your lucky day.
We just happen to have an opening.
There's not a blankety-blank soldier
in the whole army. Just a general, me.
I can outthink the enemy
but just can't fight them.
Enemy? What enemy?
There isn't any, dunce!
You've got to have your army first.
Then you find your enemy.
Company, on your stomachs! Crawl!
Join up, lad.
The army needs you, your country
needs you, and most of all, I need you.
Every young man
wants to be a soldier.
Speak up, boy. Any questions?
Which way is the next planet?
The next planet?
Oh, the next planet. It is called...
You know, it's that round thing.
It's called...
Dirt. No.
Mud.
No. Earth!
That's it, Earth. Bring up the cannon!
- Company, on your...
- Which way is it?
- Which way is what?
- Earth.
Earth? Oh, Earth.
That way. Crawl, men!
Shoulders back! Shoulders down!
What about it, boy...?
Come back!
Who said that?
Who are you?
Be my friend.
I'm alone.
"What a queer planet," I thought.
Everyone says the same thing.
Just about.
That was just one year ago,
and all I've learned since I left her
is that I should never have left her.
All of those little games of hers,
I didn't see all of the affection
that was underneath.
One should never listen to flowers,
should one?
I wouldn't know.
My experience is limited.
Oh, I have met a Daisy
But where we met is hazy
And I have walked the streets
With Marguerites
And clinging vines beside me
Oh, I've met a lot of those
But I never met a Rose
There's often been a Heather
An armful altogether
And I have even met
A Violet
Who almost satisfied me
Yes, I've met every kind that grows
But I never met a Rose
Among the Dahlias
I often dally
I left a Lily in the valley
But now and then, I ponder
And wonder as I wander
Among the fields and shrub
Perhaps the trouble is...
Who knows?
That I never met a Rose
Never, never met a Rose
Perhaps you werert
really looking for one.
Perhaps.
While roaming through the clover
Could I have passed her over?
When all is said and done
Am I the one to blame?
Who knows?
That I never met a Rose
Never, never met a Rose
Good morning.
Are you feeling all right?
Why don't you rest for a little while.
I can't. We've run out of water.
Unless I can get this thing
off the ground...
But I will.
Don't worry, I will.
- I'm not worried.
- Good.
We'll get some water from the well.
Well? What well?
- Out there.
- What?
- Did you see an oasis?
- No, but there must be one out there.
No.
We could get lost and never find water
and never make it back to the plane.
No, I'd rather bet on the motor.
At least we know it can work.
- Where are you going?
- To the well.
I said we were staying here.
This way.
Why not this way?
Or that way or that way?
This way.
Coming?
This is suicide,
don't you understand? Suicide.
Then maybe I won't have
to find my friend The Snake.
- What are you saying?
- It doesn't matter.
It does matter. What snake?
I'll tell you about him later.
- Tell me now.
- You can't draw while you're walking.
The stars are beautiful
because of a flower I can't see.
Why is the desert
So lovely to see?
There is a reason
Lovely to tell
Because the desert
Is hiding a well
What makes the desert
So lovely at night?
Millions of reasons
Tell me just one
At night, the desert
Is hiding the sun
Look! Look!
It's water.
Why am I happy?
We're dying of thirst
- Why are you happy?
- Why do you think?
Because there's plenty
Of water to drink
Why was the desert
So lovely before?
Why was it lovely
But not anymore?
Water was hiding
No one could see
But now the water
Is hiding in me
- You mustrt forget your promise.
- What promise?
You know, a muzzle for my sheep.
I won't forget.
But first, I want to hear more
about that snake.
- Now?
- Now.
Very well, then.
I met him in a tree at the edge
of the desert, not far from here.
There are some hills here.
He was the first real person I met
when I landed here.
And until I met someone else,
I thought everyone on Earth
was a snake.
I arrived on the other side of the tree.
Good afternoon.
You're talking to the wrong end.
You're a funny animal.
You're nothing but a tail.
Where's the rest?
- I'm not an animal.
- What are you?
What am I?
I'm a snake.
- I'm enchanted.
- Well, you should be.
You're all cold and slimy.
Thank you. It runs in the family.
Could you tell me what I've landed on?
Yes. This sunny section of the
solar system is called the Sahara.
The name of this planet is Sahara?
No, no, no, no. This simmering spot
of singing sand is called the Sahara.
The whole silly, stupid, smelly sphere
is called the Earth.
Oh, good. I thought I'd come
to the wrong place.
Oh, you have.
Listen.
You look like a nice fellow.
Why don't you take off your sword
and stay a while.
You seem like a smart, sensible sort.
Why did you swing down
to this sorry, sleazy swamp?
- I'm trying to learn something.
- I see.
Well, sir, this speck in space
is a scholastic sewer.
All that you can learn here
is sorrow. Sorrow.
If I were you, I'd scram.
I can't, my flock of birds
have flown away.
- So?
- They brought me here.
I see.
Listen, you are so lucky
that you met me.
Why am I lucky?
Well, you see, if someday,
any day, you want to see your own
small, sparkling star again,
I may have a solution.
You see, I have this special... sting.
It's almost painless,
and it can send you scooting
out of this sad slum
and sailing into the sweet, sunny,
splendiferous sky.
Really?
If you would like to cure the fever
Called life
Get some relief from all the struggle
And strife
The grandest medicine
That I can propose
Is under your nose
A snake in the grass
If you would like a spot
Where life never goes
Where you can leave your body
Home in your clothes
The finest travel agent
You'll ever meet
Is right at your feet
A snake in the grass
One sting
And you can say goodbye
To all of your friends
One sting
And you'll be singing
As your spirit ascends
All's well that ends
So any day or night
Wherever you are
If you would like to take
A trip to a star
The quickest transportation
Yet known to Man
Is none other than
A snake in the grass
If you would like to leave
That inuman race
And take up residence
Out yonder, in space
When you are ready
To go traveling on
Sit right down upon
A snake in the grass
One sting
Is quite enough to make you
Happy and free
One sting
And you'll discover
How relaxed you can be
Posthumously
And while you're wandering through
The heavenly blue
If you should see the Lord come
Strolling in view
Go up and say you bring him
Best wishes from his fallen old chum
A snake in the grass
One sting.
It's almost painless.
A snake in the grass
I'll be waiting.
Wait a minute.
Just a moment.
Are you looking for that snake
in order to do away with yourself?
I can't get back to my planet
any other way.
It's too far,
and my birds have disappeared.
Well, of all the...
You...
Now, you listen to me. That snake's
poisoned you against the Earth.
- It's not what The Snake said.
- He's hated us since the world began.
- It's what The Fox said.
- I'll tell you right now,
you're not going to allow yourself
to be poisoned. Is that clear?
- What fox?
- The fox I met after I met The Snake.
I see.
You certainly got yourself mixed up
with a strange crowd.
All right, let's have it.
- Where did you meet The Fox?
- In a garden of roses.
How many roses in the garden,
50, 1 00, 500?
I don't know how many roses,
but if it's too difficult to draw...
No. No. Not at all.
Let's get every detail of this whole
sordid nonsense out in the open.
When she finds out there are millions
of flowers that look just like her,
it will break her heart.
Good morning.
I thought I was rich.
I thought I had the most unique flower
in all the world.
But all I had was a common rose.
A common rose and three volcanoes
that came up to my knees.
And one of them was extinct at that.
That doesn't make me
a very great prince, does it?
Good morning.
You're a prince?
Yes.
I'm a fox.
I'm sad. Would you play with me?
- No.
- Why not? It'll be fun.
Where are the others?
- What others?
- The other hunters.
There's no one here but me.
Please play with me.
I won't harm you.
- Then why do you have a gun?
- I don't have a gun.
- You must. You're a human being.
- I'm from another planet.
- Arert there guns on your planet?
- No.
Really?
- Are there hunters on your planet?
- No.
- Any chickens?
- Oh, well, nothing's perfect.
- Let's play hide-and-seek.
I can't play with you.
- I'm not tamed.
- What do you mean, "tamed"?
Can't you stay put? I'm getting dizzy.
Sorry. I just don't wish
to become extinct.
Do you mean, if I move,
you will disappear again?
- Of course.
- Why?
You're a human. I'm a fox.
I hunt chickens, you hunt foxes.
- But I don't.
- You're a human, and you also lie.
But I don't lie.
Then you're inuman.
To be tamed...
Let me know before you move.
See if this clears it up. Underneath
the prince, you're a little boy.
Just like a million other little boys.
I'm a fox.
Just like a million other foxes.
But if you tame me...
...I won't be like all the other foxes,
and you won't be like the little boys.
I'll be unique to you,
and you to me.
- You understand?
- Sort of.
- Where are you?
- You moved.
I'm sorry, it won't happen again.
I have a very monotonous life.
I hunt chickens.
Men hunt me. They come, I hide.
They leave, I come out.
That's all.
But if you tamed me,
everything would be different.
- Even the wheat fields.
- The wheat fields?
Of course.
I don't like bread, so I don't care about
wheat. Wheat is the color of gold.
Like your hair. So if you tamed me,
I'd start to care about wheat
because it would
remind me of you.
I'm going to sit down.
What would I have to do?
Well, every day, you would come
and sit where you're sitting now.
You'd always come at the same time.
At, let's say, 4 in the afternoon.
I could start to get excited
about... Oh, about 3:00.
If you came at any old time,
I couldn't get keyed up.
But what would I do at 4:00?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
Of course not. If you did, I'd get
frightened and I wouldn't come out.
It's like this.
At first, I'll hide behind the trees.
Trembling...
...as I do in winter.
In time
I'll start to feel at ease
Show my face
And we'll
- Beginter
- "Beginter"?
Get closer.
And closer.
We'll go a glance at a time
A small advance at a time
We'll be afraid a bit
And shy a bit
Avoid each other's eye a bit
Less often each day
The ice will soften each day
As we get closer
And closer and closer
We'll go a blush at a time
A happy flush at a time
Begin to laugh a bit
And stare a bit
And walk around on air a bit
As gaily we grow
As night and daily we grow
A little closer
And closer and closer
And then one day
There'll come a day
A Christmas Eve
Midsummer Day
A moment when
Right there and then
We're gonna touch
Then we'll jump miles at a time
A million smiles at a time
Begin to love a lot
And live a lot
And give and give and give a lot
Away we will go
And every day we will grow
A little closer and closer
And closer and closer
All the time
And then one day
There will come a day
A Christmas Eve
Midsummer Day
A moment when
Right there and then
We're gonna touch
Begin to laugh a bit and stare a bit
And walk around on air a bit
As gaily we grow
As night and daily we grow
A little closer and closer
And closer
Away we will go
And every day we will grow
- A little closer
- And closer
And closer and closer
All the time
After I tamed him,
we stayed together for quite a while.
But then one day,
I had to say goodbye.
I think I'm going to cry.
I didn't want to make you unappy,
but you asked me to tame you.
- I know.
- Then I haven't done you much good.
- It's all been a waste of time.
- No.
Because you wasted
so much time on me...
...you made me feel very important.
But now I feel
sort of responsible for you.
I should have warned you
that would happen.
You always feel responsible
for what you've tamed.
The moment he said that,
I understood everything.
He wasrt like all the other foxes
in the world anymore.
I tamed him, and now
he was unique, at least to me.
And my flower
wasrt like all those other flowers,
because I had fetched her a screen
and put a glass bowl over her at night
and listened when she grumbled,
and now she was my rose.
And I was responsible for her, and
I had to go back and take care of her.
I brought you a present.
It's a secret.
So I wrote it down.
The last time I saw him,
he was sitting in a wheat field.
What was the secret?
It's only with the heart
that one can see clearly.
What's essential...
...is invisible to the eye.
It works!
Eureka! It works!
I need air!
It works.
It works!
Wait.
Don't.
My God. What have you done?
No.
Don't.
I'm glad you've repaired your engine.
Now you can go back home.
- Yes.
- I, too, am going back home.
You must keep your promise.
- What promise?
- You know, a muzzle for my sheep.
I'm responsible for this flower.
Please. You promised.
You also forgot the fence.
It's a very nice muzzle and fence.
Thank you.
You're cold as ice.
Are you afraid?
Please leave me.
I can't.
I won't.
I don't want you to suffer.
I'll look as if I'm dead,
but it won't be true.
It's just that it's too far
to carry this body with me.
You understand, don't you?
This part of me will be like
an old, abandoned shell.
There's nothing sad
about old shells, is there?
My star is so small
I can't show you where it is.
I'm going back there now, but before
I do, I want to give you something.
All I want is to hear you laugh again.
You will hear me laugh.
More than you ever did before,
because on one of those stars,
I'll be laughing,
but you won't know which one.
So they'll all be laughing,
all the stars.
It will be like a bell that's hanging
from every star in the sky.
There now, that's all.
Little Prince
From who knows where
Was it a star?
Was it a prayer?
With every smile
You clear the air
So I can see
Oh, Little Prince
Don't take your smile
Away from me
When you came
My day was done
And then your laugh
Turned on the sun
Oh, Little Prince
Now, to my wonder and surprise
All the hopes and dreams
I lived among
When this heart of mine
Was wise and young
Shine for me again
Little Prince
In your eyes
Please, Little Prince
Don't take your smile away from me
When you came
My day was done
And then your laugh
Turned on the sun
Oh, Little Prince
Now, to my wonder and surprise
All the hopes and dreams
I lived among
When this heart of mine
Was wise and young
Shine for me again
Little Prince
In your eyes
Where are you?
I won't leave without you!
Oh, my God.
It never happened.
He wasrt here.