"The movie will begin
in five moments"...
the mindless voice announced.
"All those unseated
will await the next show."
We filed slowly, languidly
into the hall.
The auditorium was vast and silent.
As we seated and were darkened,
the voice continued.
"The program for this evening
is not new.
You've seen this entertainment
through and through.
You've seen your birth,
your life and death.
You might recall all of the rest.
Did you have a good world
when you died?
Enough to base a movie on?"
Hey, Jim, it's your birthday, man.
What do you say
we finish this another night?
Turn the lights down a little bit more,
will you, Jay?
Hey, man.
How come the Doors aren't in on this?
No music. No Doors.
Come on, let's roll.
Rolling.
Is everybody in?
The ceremony is about to begin.
Let me tell you about heartache...
and the loss of God.
Wandering, wandering in hopeless night.
Out here, in the perimeter,
there are no stars.
Out here, we is stoned, immaculate.
It's beautiful.
Look at those big, puffy clouds.
Hey, Jimmy.
Wake up. Look at the clouds.
Come on.
Wake up.
What's going on?
I don't know.
Officer, what happened?
Can we help?
No, sir.
We've got everything under control.
Just a dream, Jimmy.
That's all it is.
It's just a dream
Waiting for the medicine.
On your finger.
Wait here.
Don't go.
I'll be right here.
You got a problem with doors?
Waste of time.
I followed you from the beach.
You followed me?
- Why?
- 'Cause...
you're the one.
Maybe you should meet my old man.
What's your name?
- Mine's Jim.
- Pam.
Who the hell was that?
I have no idea.
Nietzsche said...
"All great things must first wear
terrifying and monstrous masks...
in order to inscribe themselves...
on the hearts of humanity."
Listen, children...
to the sound of the Nuremberg night.
In a seance...
the shaman leads a sensuous panic.
He acts like a madman.
A professional hysteria.
Have you ever seen God?
Mandala?
A symmetrical angel.
We got our final vision by clap.
Columbus' groin got filled
with green death.
- I touched her thigh...
- This film is weak.
and death smiled.
Hey, Morrison.
Fuck them, man.
It's great.
It's nonlinear, it's poetry.
It's everything good art stands for.
This world, a monster of energy.
Without beginning,
Without end.
Likewise, without increase or income.
Disclosing nothing.
This world.
This world is a will to power...
and nothing besides.
Pretty pretentious there.
Not easy to follow.
A little incoherent.
Dancing bears, Nazism, masturbation.
What's next?
- What do you guys think?
- A bore, man. I hated it.
It was better than a Warhol picture!
It was worse!
A guy sleeping for seven hours?
There was no political conscience.
- You need your art spoon-fed to you.
- Right on!
Hold it down.
Let's ask the filmmaker what he thinks.
I quit.
Awake.
Shake dreams from your hair,
my pretty child, my sweet one.
Choose the day
and choose the sign of your day.
The day's divinity.
First thing I see.
Come on out for a walk.
It's a beautiful night.
A vast, radiant beach...
and a cool, jeweled moon.
Couples, naked,
race down by its quiet side.
And we laugh like soft, mad children...
smug in the woolly,
cotton brains of infancy.
Every time
I try to make love to you
you run around
with your mouth stuck out
Choose, they croon, the ancient ones.
The time has come again.
Choose now, they croon,
beneath the moon...
beside an ancient lake.
Enter again the sweet forest.
Enter the hot dream.
Come with us.
Everything is broken up...
and dances.
I can't believe it's so beautiful.
"Now I have come again to the land
of the fair, strong and the wise.
Brothers and sisters
o'er the pale forest.
O, children of night...
who among you will run with the hunt?
Now, night arrives with
her purple legion.
Retire now to your tents and dreams.
Tomorrow we enter
the town of my birth.
I want to be ready."
It's beautiful.
- Do you like that?
- It's beautiful.
I've never read much poetry before.
What's a shaman?
He's a medicine man...
of the Indians.
He gets into a peyote trance...
and he gets deeper and deeper,
and then he has a vision...
and the whole tribe is healed.
All cultures have a version of it.
Greeks had theater and gods.
The Indians say the first shaman
invented sex.
They called him
"The One Who Makes You Crazy."
What turns you on?
I don't know.
Experience.
Freedom.
Love. Now.
You know, the first time I did acid,
I saw God.
And I saw a friend of mine
who was Christ and Judas too.
Then I realized that...
that was the secret of everything.
We're all one,
the universe is one...
and that everything is beautiful.
I feel most alive...
confronting death...
experiencing pain.
I think you're most alive
by recognizing beauty.
Seeing truth.
Does death turn you on?
You love death?
Life hurts a lot more.
When you die, the pain's over.
All the poems have wolves in it.
All but one.
The most beautiful one of all.
"She dances in a ring of fire...
and throws off the challenge
with a shrug."
That's beautiful.
Who did you write that for?
I wrote it for you.
Try acid, Ray.
It's guaranteed.
Shit, Morrison.
My last trip was a real bummer, man.
I never had a bummer on acid.
I'm trying naturally high now.
Whatever works.
Making movies at MGM yet?
I got in to see the head of production.
He said, "Where's your script?"
I said, "I don't need a script.
Godard doesn't use a script.
He improvises."
The guy says, "Great. Who's Godard?"
I'm off movies, man.
I went out to the desert.
Got lost.
I've been living up on Trick's rooftop.
- Got stuck on a chick.
- So what else you doing?
Writing songs, poems.
Stuff like that.
You're writing songs?
So let me hear one.
I'm shy.
- Sing it to me.
- I can't sing.
You sing better than Dylan?
Johnny's in the basement
Mixing up the medicine
I'm on the pavement
Thinking about the government
Let me hear your words.
All right.
Let's swim to the moon
Let's climb through the tide
Penetrate the evening
That the city sleeps to hide
Let's swim out tonight, love
It's our turn to try
Park beside the ocean
On our
Moonlight drive
Those are great fucking lyrics, man.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. You write this?
You got others in here?
A bunch, man.
I got a whole concert in my head.
I can see it all.
What the hell happened to you
in the desert, man?
- Ecstasy and madness.
- Let's get a band together...
and make a million bucks!
- I got tons of songs.
- Things are about to explode.
I can feel it in the air.
People want to fight or fuck.
Love or kill.
Vietnam is right out there.
Sides are being chosen.
Everything's gonna flame.
The planet is screaming for change.
We gotta make the myths.
There ought to be great orgies, man.
When Dionysus arrived in Greece,
he made all the women mad.
Leaving their homes
and dancing off into the mountains.
There should be great, golden
copulations in the streets of L.A.
We should call ourselves Dionysus.
I got a name.
Doors.
You mean "The Doors In Your Mind"?
The Huxley book?
- Doors of perception. Acid.
- That's great.
The quote's from William Blake.
"When the doors of perception
are cleansed...
things will appear
as they truly are."
Mescaline experiments.
Reducing the sugar flow to the brain.
Come on!
You know the day destroys the night
Night divides the day
Try to run
Try to hide
Break on through to the other side
What's the matter?
- It just doesn't sound right.
- I know that, John.
Jim, stay in time.
I say we try that bossa nova beat.
I think it's hot.
I think the lyrics are kind of weird.
You write one, man.
We need more songs anyway.
I thought it was pretty good.
Let's go outside.
I came up with something.
A minor, then F sharp.
You know that it would be untrue
You know that I would be a liar
If I was to say to you
Girl, we couldn't get much higher
Come on, baby, light my fire
- G, A, D.
- Pretty good. Pretty neat.
Try to set the night on fire
Great, Robby.
You got nice changes in there.
- Got anymore lyrics?
- I got some.
I call it "Light My Fire."
If I'm gonna compete with your stuff, it
better be about earth, snakes or fire.
I like it.
Sounds like the Byrds though.
But I like it.
It's good.
A little Latin beat'll
do it some justice.
Maybe put a couple long solos,
like Coltrane on "My Favorite Things."
Start over, man.
A minor, B minor.
It's jazz.
The time to hesitate is through
- Some kind of intro.
- No time to wallow in the mire
Try now, we can only lose
And our love becomes a funeral pyre
Come on baby, light my fire
Try to set the night on fire
- Can you give me...
- Try now, we can only lose
Can you give me five minutes?
I got to figure out some kind of intro.
- Let's let him work. You like that?
- Yeah, I like Laguna Beach, man.
Funeral pyre.
What do you think about when you play?
I don't know.
Fish in my fish tank.
- How about that acid tonight, man?
- Not for me.
- Not me, either.
- Right here at Ray's house.
See what kind of trouble
we can get into tonight.
No way.
You always get all the chicks.
I always get the dogs.
Hey, I got it!
Come on!
I got it!
I got the intro!
Hang on a second.
John, count off in four, man.
One, two, three.
Is that horny fucker
in the black pants here tonight?
No I.D. 's, you can't get in.
Yeah, we chased our pleasures here
Dug our treasures there
Can't you still recall
The time we tried
Break on through to the other side
Turn around, man.
Come on, let them in.
I found an island in your arms
A country in your eyes
Arms that chain us
Eyes that lie
Break on through to the other side
All right
I'm a big fan!
Give it to me!
Made the scene
Week to week
Day to day
Hour to hour
The gate is straight
Deep and wide
Break on through to the other side
All right
Hi, Jim.
Can I have your autograph?
- I don't know. Where do you want it?
- Anywhere you want it.
Leave it to me.
I can take you all the fucking way.
- You blew my mind.
- Did you like the music?
I loved it.
That's why we're talking.
Some of it's on the dark side.
You ought to get some tunes.
Herman's Hermits stuff.
Mrs. Brown, you've got a lovely daughter
That shit goes right to the radio.
I need him here
to groove on my boyfriend.
What about getting us
some real equipment?
I sign you
to a five-year management contract...
You with the joint.
Put that out, please.
- We can smell that upstairs.
- I can get you there.
Trust me for a while.
What do you say?
We'll have a band meeting on it.
We do everything unanimously
or we don't do it.
The Musketeers.
I'm touched.
Let me tell you something.
Loyalty don't pay the bills.
Think about it and call me tomorrow.
Here's my card.
Pay attention.
You could get rich.
- Are you blind?
- How old are you?
- Twenty-one.
- Get lost, will you?
I'll make this quick and to the point.
If you repeat it, I'll deny it.
Drop those guys.
Jim's got to start facing the crowd
if he's going to be our front man.
He's just getting his confidence.
- The guy never does what's rehearsed...
- Well, how does it feel?
It feels great, but...
Your looks. Your voice.
That's what's going to sell records.
We'll make a million bucks a year.
Call me.
I'm right.
Hey, man, let's go.
Do yourself a favor.
Call Larry.
I like a guy
who wears his soul on his face.
Whisky's next, man.
I can feel it in my bones.
I still think the lyrics are weird.
The days are bright
And filled with pain
Enclose me in your gentle rain
The time you ran
Was too insane
We'll meet again
The chicks are really
digging you tonight, man.
We still got to deepen, man.
- We got to go one more step.
- Turn around and face the crowd.
It'll help present it better.
I got to go to the desert
and take that peyote.
Is that what you're on?
Yeah, man.
It's kicking in!
- Fucking longhair!
- He's fucking crazy.
- Come on.
- I'm not doing acid, man.
It's peyote.
What's a rock and roll band for?
Let's plan a murder or start a religion.
More, more, more!
I'm into T.M., man.
I promised my guru.
I'll try it.
I'm ready.
Let's go to the desert.
Let's do the peyote.
Who's on next?
Arthur Lee.
He's cool.
I am the lizard king!
I can do anything!
Raise your hands if you understand.
Let's take a poll.
How many of you know you're alive?
Bullshit!
You're plastic soldiers
in a miniature dirt war.
Come on!
How many of you people
know you're alive?
Close your eyes.
You see the snake.
See the serpent appear?
His head is ten feet long...
and five feet wide.
He has one red eye and one green eye.
That's all right.
It gets better.
Peace.
Seven miles long.
Deadly.
See it.
All the history of the world...
is on its scales.
All people.
All actions.
We're all just little pictures
in the scales.
God, it's big.
It's moving.
Devouring consciousness.
Digesting power.
Monster of energy.
It's a monster.
I'm gonna kiss the snake on the tongue.
Kiss the serpent.
But if it senses fear...
it'll eat us instantly.
But if we kiss it without fear...
it'll take us through the garden.
Through the gate.
To the other side.
Ride the snake...
'til the end of time.
I think I'm fucked up, man.
I'm not thinking right.
Look at your eyes, man.
You're death.
I'm afraid of my father.
I can't be what they want me to be.
Maybe you should kill your father.
I'm in pain, man.
I feel the universe
functioning perfectly...
but I'm still perfectly locked
inside myself.
Instead of oneness, I feel isolation.
But you're alive.
- Feel it.
- I'm scared.
- It's beautiful.
- I'm still scared.
Then use us.
Use our strength.
Come on in here.
That's right.
We're a tribe now.
A tribe of warriors.
I promise you, I'll be with you
to the end of time.
Nothing will destroy our circle.
Ride the snake.
Come on.
My wild love went riding
She rode all the day
She rode to the devil
Asked him to pay
My wild love went riding
She went to the sea
She went to the devil
All that's left was we
I'm lying.
I am afraid.
Don't go away!
Come dance with me!
Where you going, Jimmy?
This is the end
Beautiful friend
My only friend, the end
Of our elaborate plans
The end
Of everything that stands
No safety or surprise
The end
I'll never look
Into your eyes
Again
Can you picture what we'll be
So limitless and free
Desperately in need
Of some stranger's hand
In a desperate land
Lost in a Roman
Wilderness of pain
And all the children
Are insane
Waiting for the summer rain
There's danger on the edge of town
Ride the king's highway, baby
Weird scenes inside the gold mine
Ride the highway west, baby
Ride the snake
To the lake
The ancient lake, baby
The snake is long
Seven miles
Ride the snake
He's old
And his skin is cold
The west is the best
Get here and we'll do the rest
The blue bus
Is calling us
Driver, where you taking us
The killer awoke before dawn.
He put his boots on.
He took a face...
from the ancient gallery...
and he walked on down the hall.
He went into the room
where his sister lived.
Then he...
paid a visit to his brother.
He walked on down the hall.
And he came to a door.
He looked inside.
"Father."
"Yes, son?"
"I want to kill you."
"Mother."
I want to
fuck you all night, baby
Come on, baby
"Mother, I want to fuck you"?
Come on
Fuck, fuck
Turn him off!
Turn his fucking amp off!
Fuck me, baby
Come on, baby
- He's insane!
- He's a great artist!
- We all love it!
- Come on
All right
Kill
Get him out of here!
- Get the fuck out of here!
- Kill the father.
Nobody's gonna fuck their mother
on my stage!
- That's what I mean!
- You're out of here!
Kill your father!
Fuck the mother!
All right!
Jerry, come on, man!
- Art, man! It's art!
- What do you know about art?
Take a look at the future, old man!
We're things to come!
Here's art.
- There's your art!
- This is fucking great!
- We'll never work in this town again.
- Quite a night.
I'm Jac Holzman.
- I own Elektra Records.
- Is that asshole gonna pay us?
I think if you can put
what you did in there on record...
we could really have something
and make a lot of money.
Rothchild here
was born to be your producer.
How you doing? Sorry about all this.
You guys are...
Bertolt Brecht. It's cabaret.
It's rock and roll.
I'm really blown away, guys.
I'd like to get you guys
into a studio immediately.
How would you like to come down
from there and make a record?
Sure.
Pretty good. Pretty neat.
Bruce, you feel it?
It's bitchin'.
An album of killer music in six days.
Six days, baby.
Unreal.
The time to hesitate is through
No time to wallow in the mire
Try now, we can only lose
And our love become a funeral pyre
Come on, baby, light my fire
Try to set the night on fire
L.B.J.! L.B.J.!
How many kids
have you killed today?
You know that it would be untrue
You know that I would be a liar
If I was to say to you
Girl, we couldn't get much higher
Come on, baby, light my fire
Try to set the night on fire
All right!
- Name? Occupation?
- Bill Siddons. I'm the manager.
I manage the Doors.
- Name? Occupation?
- Pamela Morrison. Ornament.
Robby Krieger.
Guitar player.
John Densmore.
Percussionist.
Twenty-two years old.
Far out, man.
- Name? Occupation?
- Raymond Daniel Manzarek.
Born 2-12-39.
Musician. Organist.
- Name? Occupation?
- Jim.
We're gonna be on TV.
Right this way, Mr. Sullivan.
They're called the Doors...
and they've got the number one single
in the country right now.
"Light Your Fire."
Now, they're not your usual group...
but I think they're gonna fit in
just fine.
Everything's gonna be fine.
The riot continues in Detroit,
with 1,400 buildings burned.
No wonder "Light My Fire"
is number one.
So, what's your room number?
I'll talk to you later.
- You have got very serious hair.
- Were you pinching her butt?
- What about me?
- I won't open that kettle of worms.
What about you, handsome?
What can we do?
Some of the worst mistakes of my life
have been haircuts.
Don't wash it. Don't set it. Go away.
I like it just the way it is.
- Be mean.
- Boys. Boys.
Meet Mr. Sullivan.
Fellas, just great.
- I heard your record, "Light That Fire."
- "Light Your Fire."
- Just...
- "Light My Fire."
Fine.
Just really, really fine.
I have one small thing to bring up.
But it's important.
The guys at network told us...
they have a little problem...
with the lyric,
"Girl, we couldn't get much higher."
You can't say "higher"...
on network.
They asked if you could say, instead...
"Girl, we can't get much better."
- Can you dig that?
- How about...
"Girl, you couldn't bite my wire"?
I don't think
Standards and Practices would...
Why don't you have a nice, big smile
on your face when you get out there?
There's no point in being sullen.
- You know what I mean?
- We're a sullen group, Ed.
You boys should know, Mr. Sullivan
is considering you for four more shows.
- You dig?
- We dig.
I'll work it out.
Just give me five minutes.
- Groovy.
- Just give me five.
Have a great show.
Well?
- Come on.
- It's just a word.
The Stones changed
when they played here.
Why don't you change your name to...
Sidney or Irving Manzarek?
- It's just a word.
- Hey, man.
My words. I don't care.
Let's just jam.
And now...
direct from
Los Angeles, California...
ladies and gentlemen,
here now, the Doors!
You know that it would be untrue
We're okay sound wise?
If I was to say to you
Girl, we couldn't get much higher
He said it!
He said it on national TV.
- I can't believe that!
- Come on baby, light my fire
What's he doing? What's that?
Jesus! Get it off!
You can see his thing!
You blew it, you little shit!
You'll never play Sullivan again!
Can you just move a step forward?
Come on.
I know you love to look at yourself.
Great.
Let's try something different.
Take your shirt off.
- You take it off.
- Do you need help?
That's good.
The camera
is whatever you want it to be.
A woman you want to seduce.
A man you want to kill.
It can be anything you want.
That's nice.
That's great!
Do you have any idea
what these pictures can do?
One image controls millions of people.
- Where are the Doors?
- Right here.
Will you forget the Doors?
You're the one they want.
You are the Doors.
Come on.
That's it.
Be ugly.
I love that.
Anything you want.
There are no restrictions here.
Look at yourself.
Fall in love with yourself.
You're your own audience now.
They want you.
Worship, love you.
Adore you.
Jim Morrison.
The god of rock...
and cock.
Not tonight, Edie.
Thank you, not tonight.
This is the fun part of my job.
This is history in the making.
Would you like to see my imitation
of a shrimp?
Let me put it this way.
Andy is more than an artist.
Andy Warhol is art.
Sometimes I think bright people
in America must ask themselves...
"Does Andy imitate life,
or does life imitate Andy?"
Jim, this is Tom Baker.
He's in one of Andy's movies,
"l, A Man."
- And this is Count "Ruspooli."
- Ruspoli.
He's Italian, but he lives in Paris.
He's from a very famous family,
700 years old.
Hi, Jim.
You are great.
I see you at Ondine's with Hendrix.
So cool.
- All right.
- Don't you like the way he talks?
- It's so cool.
- What's your trip?
My trip?
I thought it was yours.
I caught your gig at The Scene.
I thought it was pretty good.
I liked it a lot.
It was hot.
I like your movies, man.
You got a great penis.
We're gonna split.
Why don't you come with us?
- We're going to get a bite to eat.
- No, you can't leave.
Where's your will to be weird?
Look, that's Jim Morrison.
I like the Doors.
Let's get out of here.
These people are wacky.
Come with me.
Andy's waiting for you.
No, not now.
Let's do this later.
Do you remember San Francisco?
- No, not really.
- Have another joint.
Check it out.
This chick here sings with Andy's band,
The Velvet Underground.
She says she can
drink you under the table.
Hi, I'm Nico.
It's so boring tonight.
Some of us are going downtown
to a new club.
You want to come?
Elevate your taste in trolls, man.
Vodka?
I'll race you.
Your death.
Come on, man.
Let's go.
All right.
We're gonna go to a club.
I think this girl
wants to hang out with you.
Don't you want to meet Andy Warhol?
I could do without the guy.
He's a freak.
Come on.
We got a big gig tomorrow.
Wait. I thought we were going
to be a rock and roll band.
All right.
The four of us.
Come on.
This isn't our scene.
These people are vampires.
Come on, let's make the myths.
Remember?
Let's go.
Don't leave.
Come on, you guys.
Not tonight.
I don't know what'll happen.
It might be death.
It's not death, man.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Jimmy, this way.
Andy's waiting. This way.
I'll take you to him.
Hey, daddy.
Jimmy, please.
Come on.
Andy's waiting.
Hey, man.
How you doin'?
All right.
How you doin', man?
Great.
Pretty good.
Pretty neat.
There was this big show
in Philadelphia.
Andy.
There were so many
people there...
This is Jim Morrison of
the world-famous Doors musical group.
- Andy Warhol, of course.
- Hi. Wow.
We really like your music.
- How you doin', Andy?
- Oh, great.
And there were so many people
at the show...
the paintings
were getting crushed...
and they had to
take them all down.
Really, they were kind of...
great.
Just the walls.
You see, Andy was the art.
You should do a show
with just bare walls.
We'd really like to use you
in one of our movies, Jim.
You're really such a beauty.
Andy says someday everybody
will be famous for 15 days.
He'd really be great,
wouldn't he?
I mean...
It's the singer,
not the song, right?
It's the astronaut,
not the voyage.
Somebody gave me this telephone.
- I think it was Edie, wasn't it?
- Yeah, it was Edie.
And she said that...
I could talk to God with it...
but I don't have anything to say.
Here. This is for you.
Now you can talk to God.
Morrison.
Come here.
Darling, listen,
I pay the bills...
so I can use any language
that I want.
The guy wants to talk
to the bum.
Check it out, brother.
What are your songs about,
Mr. Morrison?
Love, death, travel, revolt.
We all write the songs.
I'm interested in...
chaos, disorder...
especially activities which seem
to have no meaning, like this.
How do you feel about being called
"the ultimate Barbie doll"?
When you say something like that,
it's a shortcut to thinking.
And do you think about
the dreadful reviews...
your new poetry book has gotten?
I guess they didn't understand.
- Did you finance its publication?
- Have you bothered to read the poetry?
You keep denying that nothing good
can come out of L.A.
That's a rather
provincial attitude.
- Do you believe in drugs?
- I believe in excess.
Is alcohol considered part
of the shaman's wisdom?
It's the American way.
Every year we spend more money
on tobacco and alcohol...
than we do on education.
- On behalf of the British press...
- What about the future of the Doors?
- That's just an excuse for free sex.
- How do you spend your money?
I believe in a long, prolonged
derangement of the senses...
to attain the unknown.
Although I live
in the subconscious...
our pale reason
hides the infinite from us.
Are you, by any chance,
in a trance now?
Do you hurt?
What?
What hurts you the most?
What do your parents think
about what you're doing?
Actually,
I don't remember being born.
It must have happened
during one of my blackouts.
They must have expressed
some feeling.
Well, to tell you the truth,
they're not living anymore...
so I really don't like
to talk about that.
Could you tell us how they died?
It was a...
horrible car crash...
in New Mexico...
in the '50s.
My father ran right into
a truckload of Navahos.
They were...
all over the highway, bleeding.
Their souls, kind of
stirring in the breeze...
just leapt into mine.
I'm sorry.
Mr. Krieger, do you really
consider Mr. Morrison a shaman?
Don't worry about it.
It happens to other guys too.
Wanna do some coke?
It'll loosen you up.
Sure. The new thing.
Wow.
How old is this?
That's 14th century.
- Witchcraft.
- It's a religion, you know.
Witchcraft.
Witches are
the protectors of the seasons...
the goddesses of the grain...
and when crossed...
destroyers.
You ever try drinking blood?
What?
It works, you know.
Drink it at the right time
of the moon.
They used to dance
in the forests naked.
I think that's what
offended the Puritans...
and led to the burnings.
They were a sexual threat
to their male order...
like the Bacchae.
Five days a year,
for Dionysus...
they used to wander the hills
of ancient Greece.
The first witches.
Clans of wild women...
Iooting...
fucking...
eating animals raw...
Iooking for Dionysus...
to tear him...
to pieces!
Where do you get the blood?
Blood is the rose
of mysterious union.
Symbol of potency.
- Now you.
- I can't cut myself.
Don't be such a child.
If I do it, you have to do it.
You do it.
Come on, rock god.
Fuck me.
Fuck me good.
What do you want me to do?
What can I do, baby?
- What's the matter?
- Will you die for me?
What do you want me to do?
Maybe I should see
a doctor or something.
What do you think?
Someone from the Freudian philosophy?
It happens to other guys too.
You know, that's the irony.
Teenage death girls
want my dick, not my words.
It's not so complicated.
It's just sex, you know.
Never wake up
in a good mood again.
It's the hours and the pressure.
You do everything
like it's your last performance.
We weren't built to last.
You never know.
You're setting yourself up, you know.
You're setting yourself up.
You're a poet, not a rock star.
You really know what I am?
- You know what poetry is?
- You don't belong on Ed Sullivan.
Who am I?
Where's the feast
they promised us?
Where's the new wine?
Dying on the vine.
See, I lied to you.
I loved fame.
I do love fame.
- Why are you doing this to me?
- 'Cause you're here.
And that's gonna help?
I don't have this problem
with anybody else.
Suck it, honey.
Come on.
- Fuck you.
- Where you goin'? Huh?
Where do you think you're going?
Love my girl!
How many guys have you fucked?
And how many dogs
have you fucked?
You're the only one
who couldn't make it, you asshole!
You are the only limp dick
in the lot!
Will you die for me?
- Answer me!
- Will you die for me?
Sure.
I'd die for anybody.
Shut up in there!
I'm trying to sleep in here!
- Will you die for me?
- Yes!
I don't believe you!
- Say it!
- Yes. Yes.
I'm just a clown.
Am I a clown?
I need a home...
a place to hide.
I'm sorry.
We're gonna fuck death away.
Come on.
Let's fuck death away.
Come on, baby. All right.
An ancient lunatic reigns
in the trees of the night.
We've got
a serious problem here.
The fire marshal
won't let this concert go on...
unless you clear the aisles
and go back to your seats.
Unless you clear these aisles,
there is no show.
The sound of the crowd.
I don't even like rock groups.
They're sleazy.
- You like that, huh?
- Like Nuremberg.
- Like that?
- We're Germans.
- Beg.
- I'm begging.
You wanna fuck me?
Don't ever fuckin' lie
to me again.
- About what?
- Why did you say your father was dead?
He is dead.
Both of them. Totally.
If he's so dead,
who answered the phone when I called?
What?
You didn't really think you were
getting away with that, did you?
Your father's an admiral
in the Navy...
who was at the Gulf of Tonkin
when the Vietnam War broke out.
Wow.
Your dad's deputy chief
of operations.
Just don't ever lie
to me again.
What?
You shouldn't have done that.
Like it's so hard
to trace your school records?
You went to University of Florida,
Albuquerque, New Mexico...
Arlington, Virginia...
Washington, D.C.
You have a brother
and a sister.
"Seven Miles Long," baby.
It's all in "The End."
I'm sorry.
What did he do?
Did he love you?
How much?
Your mama?
Hatred's
a very underestimated emotion.
Doesn't matter anymore,
does it?
Do you hear them out there?
Are you listening to them?
It's you they want now.
It's not the Doors.
It's not your mother
or your father's child.
It's you.
They don't want me.
They want my death.
Ripped to pieces.
Patricia, just hold me.
What you doin' there?
- Nothin'.
- Okay, out.
No one's allowed backstage.
- Don't you know who this is?
- It's cool. I'm with the band.
Let's go. Come on.
- Cool it, pig.
- Fuckin' hippie!
Motherfucker!
They got Jim!
What's happening?
What the fuck is going on here?
I'm blind!
- He's under arrest.
- Don't shut your eyes, Jim!
We gotta get you out.
Leave him alone.
- He doesn't need more shit in his life.
- What do you know what he needs?
Fuck!
All right
Okay
I am
Your back door man
"Light My Fire!"
Men don't know
Little girls understand
Fire! "Light My Fire!"
Well, all your people
Tryin' to sleep
I'm out there makin'
Midnight creep
Back door man
Men don't know
Little girls
Understand
All right, yeah
Come on
Persian night, babe
See that light, babe
Save us
Jesus
I want to tell you about something
that happened a few minutes ago...
right here in New Haven.
This is New Haven, isn't it?
New Haven, Connecticut?
United States of America?
Is the West really the best...
or are you just stoned on weed?
Come on!
Sing "Light My Fire."
I was with this girl backstage.
We wanted some privacy...
so we went into
this shower stall.
We weren't doing anything.
We were just talking.
All of the sudden this...
this little man came in...
with a little blue hat
and a little blue suit.
He said,
"What you doin' in there?"
I said, "Nothing."
And he said...
"Well, you'd better
get out of there or..."
"Or what?" I said.
And he started pushin' me.
So I started pushin' back!
He didn't like that.
Then he reached behind
and pulled out a can of Mace...
and sprayed it right in my eyes.
Fuckin' blinded me!
Why?
All because I was alone
in a room with a girl...
doing what he'd like to be doing if
he could only get it up without a gun.
All right!
In the United States
of America, man!
Land of the free,
home of the brave!
In God we trust!
Say your thing, man.
Mr. Morrison,
you've gone too far.
The show's over.
You've violated
state obscenity laws.
- You're under arrest!
- There you go!
Out of the way!
Get out of the way!
Back! Keep 'em back!
Get your hands off me,
you slaves.
This isn't happening to me, man.
It's happening to you.
Let's just say I was testing
the bounds of reality.
That's all.
I was curious.
I always preferred
to be hated...
like Erich von Stroheim
in the movies.
The man you love to hate.
It's meant to be ironic...
like courage wants to laugh.
Essentially, a stupid situation.
I go out on the stage
and howl for people.
In me they see exactly
what they wanna see.
Some say "lizard king,"
whatever that means.
Or some black-clad leather demon...
But really,
I think of myself...
as a sensitive,
intelligent human being...
but with the soul of a clown
that always forces me to blow it...
at the most crucial moments.
I'm a fake hero.
A joke that God's played on me.
Good morning.
Pour me my breakfast,
Dolores.
What's the matter with Jimbo?
Can't handle it, eh?
He's pussy-whipped.
Hey, Jim, eat this, man.
We got one last place to go.
Ray's getting married this morning.
Remember?
"Alive, she cried."
Can't eat that.
It'll make me sick.
Give me a Dos Equis,
will you, Dolores.
- And a Ramos fizz.
- What happened to you last night?
You bet me $1,000 you were gonna
walk on the ledge of the 9000 building.
Let's go right now.
Complaining about going home
to your sanctuary.
We were gonna make a movie.
You bet me 1,000 bucks, man.
- Give him a double.
- A triple.
Imagine me and Morrison
in a movie together.
Two powerful, two Irish...
two-fisted fuckin' drinkin' guys
in the same movie together.
I'll direct it.
If Dennis Hopper can do it,
I can.
We'll all three direct it.
A real road movie in black and white.
We'll call it Zero.
- What the fuck?
- Fuck you, Morrison!
Get outta here!
Fuckin' jack-off!
Keep the drink.
It's only another 95,000...
but I could get the best clothes
from India, from Morocco, Jim.
Clothes you couldn't get
anywhere else.
Then we could get the richest
people to come... Miles Davis...
Sonny and Cher, the Stones.
It could be the best boutique
on La Cienega, Jim.
Why don't we have a car?
- We lost it.
- Yeah, but...
where's the gravy train?
What's the matter with you?
What are you on?
You said you wouldn't
drink today.
No, Ma, I ain't drinkin'.
You promised you wouldn't drink anymore.
You're not gonna drink, are you?
No, Ma, I ain't.
And you're gonna change those stinky
leathers you've worn for three weeks.
I don't know about that.
What are you on?
It's just some low-grade acid.
It's not heavy.
Oh, Jim!
Oh, God! I cooked!
- I cooked the duck!
- It's okay.
People are coming, you know.
Ray and Dorothy think
that we're flaky enough.
You said we'd wait until after,
and now you're gonna peak before me.
No, it's cool. We'll trip,
and then we'll eat our feast.
Yeah, sure. No!
You know, I think it's a good thing
about Ray and Dorothy.
I do.
Women are such noble creatures.
They carry on your name
with dignity after you die.
Are you saying you want to
marry me, Jim Morrison?
I think women have a comic
approach to life. How can they not?
They spend their lives
with that big dick seeking entry.
Come on, Mom.
I want to look inside,
like a spy.
I'm a spy
In the house of love
I know the dream
That you're dreamin' of
I know the word
That you long to hear
I know your deepest
Secret fear
I know
Everything
I love it
when you sing to me.
That's 'cause...
I'm the poet
and you're my muse.
"Lions in the street, roaming.
Dogs in heat, rabid, foaming.
A beast, caged in the heart
of the city, rotting...
in the summer ground.
He fled the town...
left the chaos and disorder
back there... u
Hey, everybody.
Here's the nuptial couple.
What am I gonna do
about all these papers?
- Get a drink.
- Jim.
You really need somebody
to organize all this stuff.
Your handwriting
is just like a little kid.
Look at this. I wonder if William Blake
was ever this disorganized.
- You're trying too hard.
- I'm gonna be your editor now.
I'm gonna organize all this stuff
and take out all the "fuck" words.
- Honey, you're trying too hard.
- No, I'm not.
There's some great poetry here,
some wonderful ideas.
Come on in!
- Hey, Jimbo!
- Hey, man.
Hi, baby.
How's it goin'?
- Yo, Ray.
- Hey, Dog, how you doin'?
- Get some drinks over there.
- What am I supposed to do?
Who am I supposed to be
around all these people?
Darling Pamela.
I brought you something.
You're my girl, that's who.
I'm not your girl.
I know you fuck everything
that touches you.
- Don't give me that shit.
- Come on.
I love my girl!
Listen, everybody!
Pam and l...
She's lookin' good.
And to celebrate...
- Hey, Patricia.
- Hi, Jim.
Pam, have you met...
Do you know...
She wrote this great review
of my poetry book.
- Let's go eat that turkey.
- Pam, let's set those plates.
Are you Patricia Kennealy?
You must be Pamela.
You actually put your dick
in this woman?
Well...
sometimes, yeah.
Well, I understand.
I really do.
But don't ever expect that Jim's
gonna love you or take care of you...
because you're one
of a hundred.
- You don't know when to stop.
- Look who's talking.
Jim can make up his own mind
about who he loves and who he doesn't.
Don't kid yourself, sweetheart.
He's crazy, but not that crazy.
He loves me.
Let's go check
those sweet potatoes.
- There they go again.
- Chuck!
Gonna be another one of those dinners?
You're gonna have to stop this.
I'm glad you made it.
Jim, Robbie, meet Chuck Vincent.
I just have one more thing
to say to you, Jim Morrison.
You have ruined
another Thanksgiving.
Bastard!
You killed my duck!
You ruined my duck!
What did you do to her?
It's all right.
We're working it out.
We'll work it out.
It's okay.
Fuck you!
You want to know
what murder is?
You want a little death?
Well, come on.
Then kill me.
Go on, kill me. Come on.
Kill me. Go on!
Come on, give me some death!
You killed my duck.
And I'm still killing
your fucking duck.
There! Murder! Death!
Duck! Dead!
Dead! Fucking dead!
There! The duck is dead!
- That's the incredible truth!
- Stop this shit! Get sane!
Don't ever tell me what to do!
- Yeah, fuck off, Ray.
- Fuck off, Ray.
This party's gettin' low-rent.
Let's split.
Looks like
we're not gonna eat.
Shit.
Fuck it.
Let's eat this thing.
What happened to us,
Daddy, huh?
There was some
beautiful poetry, you know.
Hold on, honey.
There was some
beautiful poetry, Daddy.
Action!
Your mother's here
with your brother.
I don't want to see 'em, okay?
- What do you want me to do with 'em?
- You hear me?
They're waiting!
Ladies and gentlemen...
from Los Angeles, California...
the Doors!
Pretty good.
Pretty neat.
Not to touch the earth
Not to see the sun
Nothing left to do
but run, run, run
Let's run
House upon the hill
Moon is lying still
Shadows of the trees
Witnessing the wild breeze
Come on, baby, run with me
Come on, honey.
I been so lonely.
I miss my girl.
I didn't realize
you were entertaining.
I hope you are cool about this.
Don't forget your smack
on the way out.
The mansion is warm
At the top of the hill
Rich are the rooms
and the comforts there
Red are the arms
Of luxuriant chairs
And you won't know a thing
'til you get inside here
Yeah? Looking for a place
to hide, or to die?
Just doing my thing,
like you said.
- What?
- You're hurting me.
Are you in pain?
Let me introduce you
to my friend pain.
Fuck you.
Oh, sanctuary.
Looking for a place to hide?
- I'll give you a place to hide.
- From you, you pig.
Forever.
Hey, honey, this is
the best part of the trip.
Sanctuary.
Come on, baby.
Come on, honey.
Almost home.
We're almost home, baby.
Help!
- It's blinding me.
- Help! I'm blind!
That's better.
Ride 'em, cowboy!
- Look out.
- What?
- There's a cop. Slow down.
- Where?
Right there in front!
Look!
Dead president's corpse
in the driver's car
The engine
runs on glue and tar
Come on along
Not goin' very far
To the East
to meet the czar, yeah
By a right line, the running line,
the crooked and the straight...
I summon you up.
By wood and stone, wind and fire,
land and water, I bring you in.
We worship the ancient forces
of nature.
The Great Mother,
the Triple Goddess...
and the Horned One,
god of the hunt.
Death does not part...
only lack of love.
The goddess holds the vow forever.
Run with me
Let's run
The outlaws live
by the side of the lake
The minister's daughter's
in love with a snake
Who lives in a well
by the side of the road
Wake up, girl
We're almost home, yeah
We could see the gates
by morning
We should be inside
by evening
Sun, sun, sun
Moon, moon, moon
I will gain you
Soon
I am the lizard king.
I can do anything.
Come on, come on, come on
Come on now, touch me, babe
Can't you see
that I am not afraid
What was that promise
that you made
Why won't you tell me
what she said
Fuckin' Neanderthal prima donna.
Too drunk to fuckin' sing.
I'm gonna love you
'Til the heavens
stop the rain
I'm gonna love you
'Til the stars
fall from the sky
You and I
Cut. Cut.
Terrific take, Jim. We just had
a technical problem in here.
What's his fuckin' problem, man?
- Paul, babe.
- Yeah, right here, babe.
Suck a fart
out of my asshole...
you slave-driving fascist...
- I hear the booze, the smoke.
- Sixty-seven takes?
- I don't hear your voice or the song.
- Because it's stale!
- "Stale"?
- I wanna do my thing!
We'll do 167 takes
until it sounds like music.
Let's do something else.
You're all a bunch of fuckin' slaves.
Let's do...
Come on, come on, come on.
Rock is dead.
Everybody come out here.
We'll do a sing-along.
O come, all ye faithful
- Get this circus outta here.
- It's too self-conscious.
Billy, get 'em out!
You, you, you! Let's go!
You deaf? Beat it!
Let's go!
See you later.
What are you doing, Jim?
I'm sitting in
that fuckin' booth for months.
I look out of the glass,
I see Jim, I hear Jim...
but I miss him.
And he's standing right in front of me.
How do you explain that?
Don't make me go through
this whole shit again...
watching Janis dive to the bottom
of a bottle of Southern Comfort.
I won't go through it again.
Why are you fucking this up?
I love you, man.
You're my own flesh and blood.
Catchy tune.
You sold it to a commercial?
- How much?
- Seventy-five thousand.
We couldn't reach you.
We figured...
- What is this shit, Ray?
- It's not a big deal, man.
The song has already
been commercialized.
Feliciano's already sold
two million copies.
Robbie thought it was a good idea.
So did John.
So did I.
Robbie?
Where were you?
You should've been here.
Do you know what you're saying
to millions of people?
The Doors... all for one,
one for all... not real.
It's not about money...
or records or success...
or these...
desires that you have.
It's about...
using the music to break through.
Wasn't it, Ray?
I don't know.
We lost something here, man.
I don't think so, Jim.
There's just a bigger picture,
that's all.
Yeah?
In your fucking face!
Jesus Fuckin' Christ!
What the fuck is goin' on, man?
Just kidding.
Oh, hi, honey.
We were just watching
a little TV.
I wanted you to find us, Jim.
It meant nothing.
You don't have to torture me.
Just let me make it up to you.
I love you.
It's gonna be all right.
You're the one.
- Really?
- You're my girl.
So vulnerable about everything,
it makes me sad.
All right, let's keep
that money machine rolling.
Can you find me
Soft asylum
I can't make it
Anymore
The man is
At the door
This is the trip, the best part...
I really like.
Yeah, I'm proud to be
a part of this number!
Successful hills
are here to stay
Everything must be this way
All our lives
we sweat and save
Buildin' for a shallow grave
The soft parade has now begun
Cobra on my left
Leopard on my right, yeah
Come on
And it's getting harder
Callin' on the dogs
When all else fails
We can whip the horses' eyes
And make them sleep
And cry
I love you.
Hate your next-door neighbor
But don't forget to say grace and
Tell me over and over
And over and over again, my friend
You don't believe
We're on the eve of destruction
A hot night in Miami, March '69.
Every space in the auditorium
is consumed.
Unfortunately, The Doors have long
since sold out. They've become an act.
Morrison falls off the stage
at least every other performance.
"The Soft Parade" album only confirms
the plasticity of their approach.
Songs like "Touch Me"
and "Tell All the People"...
are not the Doors we once knew.
So the question is:
why am I here?
Are funerals entertainment?
- He's not going to show.
- Show time is show time.
This guy's done it to us too many times.
We should go on without him.
Bill is with him. They're an hour away.
He'll get him here, all right?
He fucking better
get him here, man.
- Hey, he'll be here.
- I'll tell you one goddamn thing.
There's gonna be a show here tonight
if I gotta throw a wig on, man...
and sing them songs myself.
Yeah, fuck off.
How's it going?
- Hey, dude.
- Yo, Jimbo.
- Clean up your act.
- You asshole.
I love you!
Hey, listen, Paul.
- Can you get us some heroin?
- No.
Why not? Some heroin.
I am not gonna participate
in anything...
that's gonna help you
accomplish your goal, Jim.
What's my goal, Paul?
Your only friend, the end
Wrong. I just want to
sing the blues, man.
Get fat, do nothin', go nowhere.
Just be.
With that waistline,
you ain't got much choice.
What is wrong with being
a large mammal?
- A big beast, like a tank.
- You're king crawling flab.
Rock is cock, baby,
and your rock is dying.
Rock is death, man.
There's no longer belief.
I'll write poetry...
and direct movies.
That's bullshit.
You tested all the limits...
fame, fucking...
money.
What you gonna do
when the music's over, man...
when you're too fat and old
to go out onstage?
What you gonna do for act three?
Puke on heaven's door?
Listen, you two-bit fucking actor.
You underestimate the audience.
Face it, Jim.
You're not gonna be remembered.
You think all they want is...
two cars and a house.
But you're wrong.
- You know what they want?
- No. Tell me.
- You really want to know?
- Yeah, tell me. What?
Something sacred.
That's what they want.
- He's two hours late!
- Where the fuck are the seats?
- I took them out.
- How are you doin'?
I'd like you to meet
my new friend.
- You're not playing, huh?
- We're gonna sue your fucking ass.
So sue me. If you ain't playing,
see where your equipment is tomorrow.
I'm not going out there until
I get some sort of guarantee.
Come on, John. How will you know
what could have been?
How will you know
unless you break on through?
Fucking asshole!
You're pushing death, Morrison.
People think we're drug addicts
because of you.
- Are we the Beatles now, John?
- We took drugs to expand our mind.
- Not to escape.
- Get him on the fucking stage!
Listen.
Have you ever eaten human flesh?
'Cause I know this chick
in New York, man.
Hey, it's cool.
Listen, listen.
Just one more time,
for old times' sake.
- I don't want any.
- You'll play like an orgasm.
Trust me.
You said you loved pain.
You run from it
every chance you get.
Doors! Doors! Doors!
Are you ready?
Back off!
I don't want to see
any more of that shit!
I'll haul your ass in, pal.
Hey, Jim!
Five to one, baby
One in five
No one here gets out alive now
You get yours, baby
I'll get mine
Gonna make it, baby
if we try
The old get older
The young get stronger
May take a week
and it may take longer
They got the guns
but we got the numbers
Gonna win, yeah
We're takin' over
Come on!
Let me hear ya!
Look at this beautiful
living thing, man.
You wouldn't eat
my little friend, would you?
Come on, man.
Love animals.
Don't eat them!
I'd fuck her, but she's too young.
Your ballroom days
Are over, baby
Night is drawing near
Shadows of the evening
Crawl across the year
You walk across the floor
With a flower in your hand
Trying to tell me
no one understands
Trade in your house
For a handful of dimes
Gonna make it, baby
In our prime
Get together
One more time
You're all a bunch
of fucking slaves!
How long you think
it's going to last?
How long are you gonna let 'em
push you around?
I'll tell you this.
I'm gonna get my kicks before
the whole shithouse goes up in flames.
All right.
"Light My Fire!" Come on, Jim!
Fuck you, man!
That's the word.
That's the very little word.
Come on, let me hear it.
All your little hatred.
You'd all eat shit, wouldn't ya?
Adolf Hitler is alive and well
and living in Miami.
I fucked her last night.
What are you gonna do about it?
Come on, come on, come on
Come on and suck me, babe
Can't you see
that I need some head
What was that...
Wait a minute. Ah, bullshit!
It's fucked up, man.
It's all bullshit!
It's all fucked up.
I'm coming out!
Miami Beach, Florida, huh?
Hey, I went to Florida State.
Then I got smart
and moved to California.
They're trying to change the world
out there in California.
No, I ain't talkin' about
no revolution.
I'm talkin' about having
a good time this summer.
I'm talking about love your neighbor
until it hurts.
Come on.
How 'bout a little nakedness?
Come on. Let's see
some action out there.
I'm talkin' about love, love, love.
I'm talkin' about
you and me lovin'...
Anybody gonna come up here
and love my ass?
Come on. I'm lonely up here.
I love you!
Come on, sweetheart.
You want to see it?
Why don't I pull it out for you,
shake it around a little bit?
Will that do it for ya?
All right, now.
I'm gonna show it to you.
You see it?
Yeah, I saw it!
I wanna see some action out there!
No limits! No laws!
You want to fuck?
Come on up here!
- This is your show! Yeah!
- Get off my stage, motherfucker!
No laws! No limits!
Yeah! Fuckin' rock god!
Where's the guy with the penis?
Where's that son of a bitch? Get back!
Fat cat in a top hat
Dead cat in a top hat
Suckin' on a young man's
Love
Wishin' he could come, yeah
Suckin' on a soldier's brain
Wishin' it would be the same
Dead rats
See, you're an aristocrat
Well, that's crap
You know, the day
destroy the night
Night divide the day
Try to run, try to hide
Break on through
to the other side
Come on!
Chased our pleasures here
Dug our treasures there
Can you still recall
the time we cried
Break on through to...
Mr. Morrison.
You are charged with lewd behavior
on four counts.
Simulated masturbation...
public drunkenness...
profanity...
and public exposure.
How do you plead?
The defendant pleads not guilty,
Your Honor.
Then trial is set for the week...
I want to bring to the jury's attention
that there's playing now on Broadway...
a musical called "Hair"
where the actors disrobe...
and appear naked on the stage.
- Objection. That's irrelevant.
- Sustained.
Your Honor,
how can you sustain that?
Stick to the facts.
This is a major
First Amendment violation...
by the politicians
and the police of Miami.
Every single witness
they've brought here...
has testified to not actually seeing
my client's genitals...
except one, who is related
to the arresting officer.
I tell you, if you convict
on such lack of evidence...
I assure you that someday, somewhere
in the still of the night...
you will wake up screaming.
Are you gonna get rid of it?
Look.
Wouldn't it be better to have a kid with
someone who wanted to be its father?
It'd be a fucking genius.
That's what it'd be.
You and me?
The child would be a goddess...
or a god.
It'd be a monster.
No. Look.
I got this trial
that's hanging on me.
I can't afford this.
I don't want the responsibility.
You're a coward,
just a little boy!
The only way you can't afford it
is emotionally!
Those vows were forever
in the goddess' sight!
"Death does not part,
only lack of love."
Come on, Patricia.
I was stoned.
It seemed like a fun thing
to do at the time.
Fuck you.
I'm gonna have the kid.
Well, then it will be your kid.
But if you want the abortion,
I'll be there with you.
- Oh, no, you won't.
- Yes, I will.
Bullshit, Morrison!
You know who you are!
What difference
does it make, you know?
You never pretended.
I did.
Yeah, I don't even like kids,
particularly.
I don't want the other
fuckin' thing either.
Well.
Have you looked in the mirror lately?
- Look at that stomach.
- Come on, now.
Don't say these things.
James Douglas Morrison...
I hereby sentence you...
to six months of hard labor
in the Dade County jail.
And for public exposure...
I'm sentencing you
to 60 days of the same...
after which you are to serve
two years and four months...
of probationary time.
Your Honor, I have an appellate bond
in the sum of $50,000 here.
I ask that Mr. Morrison remain free,
pending his appeal.
Everywhere, Jim... Jacksonville, Dallas,
even Kent State University canceled.
The press for the first time
turned against us. We're fucked.
Pamela's called six times.
Katherine, Patricia. Gayle's pregnant.
You gotta go to the dentist.
Look, Jim.
Go home, get some sleep.
- Wash your hair.
- Take a bath too, man.
- Jesus, this guy really despises you.
- We weren't even invited to Woodstock.
Twenty other bands. Not us.
First Hendrix, now Janis.
Radio stations won't play us.
Some big cities.
Philly, Cinci, Chicago, Detroit.
We can drag this appeal out for years,
keep you out of jail.
The F.B.I. 's behind it.
They had memos on you in Phoenix.
They extradited you to Miami.
A new image.
Slow, quiet. The beard.
The elder of the tribe.
Mine eyes have seen the glory
of the coming of the Lord!
The band you love to hate.
Let's win there.
It was fun.
I think I'm having
a nervous breakdown.
- Do you hear me?
- Climb on the edge, baby.
We're rolling, Jim.
- Jump!
- Let him dance a little bit.
I want you to come back in here
this minute, Jim Morrison.
I am not gonna kill myself for you.
- Goddamn it, Jim!
- Your whole life is bullshit!
- Shut up!
- You want me, come out and get me!
Oh, no!
Jim, where are you...
Pam, get back inside!
- I love you.
- Come out here, honey.
- Come on, baby.
- Jim, give her your hand.
- She's gonna fall.
- Once more with feeling.
Take two.
- I don't want to die.
- Man, we gotta finish it.
- We don't have an ending, Ray.
- All the poetry has wolves in it.
- The most beautiful...
- Come on, girl.
I see your hair is burning
The most beautiful one of all...
dances in a ring of fire...
then throws off a challenge
with a shrug.
That's my girl.
Let's go. Let's leave this place.
Just you and me, baby.
We can, you know.
Just one more step.
I want to live!
I want to live with you!
All the poetry
has wolves in it, Pam.
All but one.
The most beautiful one of all.
I hope you go out smiling...
like a child
into the cool remnant of a dream.
The angel man...
has finally claimed
this benevolent soul.
Ophelia...
leaves sudden in silk.
Glory in dream.
Mad, stifled witness.
All right!
Hi, Dorothy.
Oh, you cut your hair.
- We're trying to have another baby.
- Was your hair getting in the way?
Where's Ray?
I got to catch a plane.
He's upstairs.
- Where's Princess?
- Out back.
We added a rain effect
to "Riders," man.
It's great.
It's the best album
since "Days," man.
I must admit it's pretty good...
for four guys who weren't even
talking to each other that day.
So you're really gonna live
in Paris, huh, man?
Yeah. You know, be anonymous,
write a book.
"Observations of an American
While On Trial in Miami."
Still got a lot
of good songs in you.
Still think we got a couple
of blues albums in us.
I'm pinned, man.
They got a category
for everything we do.
I'm a wanted man.
I'm gonna miss you, man.
I'm gonna miss that feeling
of playing music with you, man.
You, John, miss me?
More than you think, asshole.
Yeah.
You can always whip
the horses' eyes.
As far as I'm concerned...
I made music with Dionysus.
We had moments onstage
that no one will ever fucking know.
You lay off those drugs, Robby.
Hey, Merry Christmas.
We'll get together again,
you know...
in some strange way.
Maybe we'll make a movie together.
Black and white.
Sabrina, this is for you.
- Morrison, see you around.
- What, no bon voyage?
I'll see you back.
And little Princess Smiling Face...
this one's for you...
from Chief Mojo Rising.
Happy birthday, Princess.
- Let me see.
- It's you.
Forever young.
The strangest life
I've ever known.
Jim. You got a plane to catch, man?
Yeah.
We're reaching for death
on the end of a candle.
We're trying for something
that's already found us.
Last words.
Out.
Did you get all that?
Yeah.
I got it, Jim.
Come on. Let's get some tacos.
Death.
It's not so bad.
- Jim?
- I love my girl.
Jim, is that you?
I knew it was you, Jim Morrison.
I always know when it's you.
Come on, baby.
Get out of the tub.
Come on. Mama will dry you off.
Just stop joking around, you hear me?
Just cut it out.
Was it all right, Jim?
Did you enjoy it when it came...
just like you said you would?
They are waiting to take us...
into the severed garden.
You know how pale and wanton
thrillful comes death...
in the strange hour...
unannounced, unplanned for...
like a scary, over-friendly guest
you've brought to bed.
Death makes angels of us all
and give us wings...
where we had shoulders
smooth as ravens' claws.
No more money, no more fancy dress.
This other kingdom seems
by far the best...
until its other jaw
reveals incest...
and loose obedience
to a vegetable law.
I will not go.
I prefer a feast of friends
to the giant family.