? Well, now?
? Ain't this
an elegant neighborhood??
? All the residents
dress so fine?
? One day off the boat am I
with a job that's nearly mine?
? 'Tis a job with
an elegant millionaire?
? And his elegant family?
? Today I move from immigrant
to high society?
Now, you may call that luck.
And you may call it fortune.
But me, meself...
? I call it?
? Fortuosity?
? That's me byword?
? Me twinkle-in-the-eye word?
? Sometimes castles
fall to the ground?
? But that's where
four-leaf clovers abound?
? Fortuosity?
? Lucky chances?
? Fortuitious little
happy happenstances?
? I don't worry
'cause everywhere I see?
? That every bit of life
is lit by fortuosity?
? Fortuosity?
? That's me own word?
? Me never-feel-alone word?
? Round the corner,
under a tree?
? Good fortune's waitin'?
? Just wait and see?
? Fortuosity?
? Lucky chances?
? Fortuitious little
happy happenstances?
? I keep smilin'
'cause my philosophy?
? Is do your best
and leave the rest?
? To fortuosity?
? I keep smilin'
'cause my philosophy?
? Is do your best
and leave the rest?
? To fortuosity?
Good day to you, ma'am.
Would this be the home of
Mr. Anthony J. Drexel Biddle?
It would.
I've come to be interviewed
for the position of the butler.
Mrs. Biddle
does the interviewin'.
She's not at home just now.
But I had an appointment.
The Mayflower Employment Agency.
I'll tell Mrs. Biddle that
you were put out about it.
Oh.
Not at all.
I'd be pleased to call again.
Good day to ya.
What part of Ireland?
County Tyrone.
Just new here, are ya?
The day before yesterday.
Oh, well, perhaps you'd like
to wait in the kitchen.
Mrs. Biddle
will be comin' home soon.
That's very kind of you.
Thank you very much.
Faith, 'tis a grand place
you have here.
I'm the housekeeper here.
Me name's Mrs. Worth.
Mine's John Lawless.
This way, John Lawless.
Have a seat,
and I'll pour you some coffee.
Don't you be troubling yourself.
No trouble.
There's a pot
brewing on the stove.
Sit down.
Would you be from Ireland
yourself, Mrs. Worth?
I came over as young girl.
Not long ago, then.
Tell me, Mrs. Worth, what
became of the last butler?
I couldn't say.
He left in the dead of night
after being here
less than a month.
We've got a servant problem
in this house.
No use sayin' we don't.
Must be hard working
for the very rich.
I mean, they're accustomed
to havin' things just so.
That's not exactly the problem.
The wage is very low.
No, the Biddles
are generous enough.
Long hours, then?
I wouldn't say so.
There's a gorgeous sight.
Are you getting ready
for a party?
No, Mr. Biddle's
on a chocolate-cake diet.
I beg your pardon?
Cordelia!
He says it's the perfect food,
containing every
essential element.
Where is Mrs. Biddle?
She's gone shopping.
Blast!
And Cordy?
- I couldn't say.
- And the boys?
I haven't seen them since lunch.
At a time like this.
No one!
Is there something
I could do, Mr. Biddle?
Yes.
You can call Dr. Donleavy.
Tell him I've been bit
by an alligator.
Oh, dear!
Might as well live alone.
Are you a married man?
Me, sir?
No, sir.
Then you wouldn't understand.
? I've been bit on my finger?
? It could have been my leg?
? It could have been my head?
? I might have died?
? In a time of mortal peril?
? Any man should expect?
? That his family will come
rushing to his side?
? What's wrong with that??
? My family rushing
to my side?
? What's wrong with that??
Oh, not a thing, sir, I'm sure.
? I'm a good-hearted husband?
? I'm generous and kind?
? No wife could have
a life as free of cares?
? So when a good-hearted
husband has been bit?
? It's only right?
? That his wife should share
the agony he bears?
? What's wrong with that??
? I want my wife
to share my life?
? What's wrong with that??
Cordelia!
Well, now.
Now, that answers a whole slew
of questions, don't it?
Cordy!
Boys!
Blast!
? Here in this house
I'm raising?
? Three strong,
intelligent children?
? Where are they now in
their father's time of need??
? I give them private tutors?
? The finest
physical trainers?
? All in vain?
Ohh, the pain!
? I believe in the Bible?
? I believe in Uncle Sam?
? And as sure
as Old Glory waves above?
? I believe a man who's bitten
has the right to demand?
? That his family give him
sympathy and love?
? What's wrong with that??
? The flag above,
the Bible, and love?
? What's wrong with that??
- Hello, Papa.
- Cordy!
Where have you been?
Out in the stable
with Tony and Liv.
- Is something wrong?
- Yes, something's wrong.
What were you doing shaving
at this time of day?
I haven't been shaving.
And since when do
I shave my finger?
You don't shave your ear either.
- But last week you cut it.
- That's different.
The ear is in the general
vicinity of the face.
So's the finger
when you're shaving.
It's a bite, blast it!
- No.
- Yes.
- Who?
- George.
Turned on me just like that
after all these years.
Well, it's really
not such a bad bite.
Is that all you have to say?
There's some antiseptic
in the emergency kit.
- And some bandages.
- Wait a minute.
Where are you going?
It's time for Bible class.
Yes, I know.
But you'll have to do
without me today.
I have an engagement.
Dr. Donleavy's somewhere between
his office and the hospital.
Keep trying.
Oh, what are you doing?
Me, sir?
Not a thing, sir.
- Well, do something.
- Yes, sir.
Blasted alligator.
- I beg your pardon.
- Treated him like a son.
What exactly would you
like me to do?
Tell the boys to bring in
that emergency kit.
Out the back door,
across the yard to the stable.
Mr. Tony.
Mr. Livingston.
Mr. Tony and Mr. Livingston.
Blasted Benedict Arnold.
That's what he is.
Yes?
Would you tell Miss Biddle
Mr. Taylor is calling?
- Mr. Who?
- Mr. Charles Taylor.
Miss Biddle is expecting me.
Cordy!
Dr. Donleavy must have stopped
to make a house call.
I could be dying.
Indeed you could.
Where's that blasted antiseptic?
Here you are, Pa.
- It's about time.
- We came as soon as we heard.
I left word with
the doctor to call.
What happened, Pa?
Was it really George?
Gentle old George?
Yes, it was gentle old George.
Hey, Pa, what's
Charlie Taylor doing here?
He came to see Cordy.
The answer to a maiden's prayer.
What do you know
about maidens' prayers?
Nothing, Pa.
It's just an expression.
Oh.
But Charlie Taylor?
- Cordy can do better than that.
- I'm sure she can.
When the time comes.
That's pretty good.
Going into vaudeville?
Hi, Tony.
Long time, no see.
- This is my brother, Liv.
- Hiya, sport.
Hi.
- Say, that man in the hall.
- Yeah?
That wasn't your father, was it?
- Who did you think it was?
- I thought he was some kind...
Uh, uh, uh.
Hey, caramel!
They're for Cordy, sport.
Cordy hates caramels.
They stick in her retainer.
But I like caramel.
So does Tony.
Don't you, sport?
Oh, love 'em.
Okay, fellas, that's enough.
Charlie! You've been hiding
your light under a bushel.
Liv, you should feel that.
Hey! What weight do you
fight at, Charlie?
- Fight?
- Boxing.
You do box, don't you?
I prefer other sports.
You don't do it at all?
No.
Liv, he doesn't do it at all.
Aw, Charlie.
You're in trouble.
I don't understand.
Well, if you've got
your eye on Cordy...
? Remember Harry Applegate??
? Yeah, he took
Cordy on a date?
? Oh, what a dapper Dan?
? Pearly teeth and tennis tan?
Remember him well.
? Thought he was a Romeo?
? Tried to kiss our sis,
and, oh!?
? Harry ducked, but too late?
? Father bought him
an upper plate?
? Watch your footwork?
? Better learn
to bob and weave?
? Sister Cordy's
got dynamite up her sleeve?
? What a jab?
? Dynamite up her sleeve?
? What a hook?
? Keep your guard up?
Charlie, never lead it
with your right.
You'll get killed that way.
Look, fellas,
let's forget the whole thing.
I didn't come here to do this.
? Archie Baxter
came here twice?
? First time out,
he acted nice?
? Romance was in the air?
? Oh, they made a lovely pair?
Beautiful.
? Second date, it was a dance?
? He grabbed her tight,
this was his chance?
? Cordy only bruised
that sport?
? Father settled it
out of court?
So...
? Watch your footwork?
? Better learn
to bob and weave?
? Sister Cordy's
got dynamite up her sleeve?
? What a fake?
? Dynamite up her sleeve?
? What an uppercut?
Uh-oh.
- Charlie.
- Charlie?
- Hey, Charlie, wake up.
- Are you hurt?
Tony? Livingston?
Come on, it's time
for Bible class.
What happened?
He dropped his left.
Oh.
You better get some ice.
And get some beefsteak.
Charlie?
Charlie!
Well, don't you look pretty!
Papa, how could you?
How could I what?
It's no wonder
I never have any callers.
- Oh, now, wait a minute.
- People are afraid to come here.
I didn't hurt the young sap.
Sap?
Charlie Taylor's only
the most popular boy in town.
Oh, here he comes.
Charlie, are you all right?
Sure, he's all right.
Come on, Charlie.
- Thataboy.
- I'm so sorry, Charlie.
There's no serious damage.
He'll have a black eye
for a couple of days.
- Ooh!
- Can I get you something?
I sent for some raw meat.
How about a cold drink, Charlie?
Oh!
Oh, thank you.
Charlie, why don't you sit
in this comfortable chair?
And I'll see if
I can get you some iced tea.
Or would you like
a piece of chocolate cake?
Charlie!
Gee, we're sorry.
We didn't mean to do it.
We told him
to keep his guard up.
You see, Cordy, I had
nothing to do with it.
Didn't you?
Like father, like son.
You're all three the same.
Always having your sport
no matter what.
Always ready for a fight.
Oh, Cordy, we didn't...
Don't touch me.
I'll flatten you!
Cordy.
Cordy, wait.
Blast it!
? Oh,
Miss Cordelia Drexel Biddle?
? I thought I knew you well?
? But now,
Miss Cordelia Drexel Biddle?
? I just can't tell?
? Are you valentine candy
or bo xing gloves??
? Lately you seem
very strange?
? What in the world's
coming over you??
? Everything's starting
to change?
? Are you sonnets by Shelley
or Rover Boys??
? Once any answer would do?
? Why are you
suddenly wondering?
? Which kind of someone
are you??
? Is a boy meant to spar with
or gaze at a star with??
? Should you kiss him
or blacken his eye??
? Now, if he buys you roses?
? A right to the nose is really
not quite the proper reply?
? You're so lost
in the middle of in-between?
? Is your destiny canvas
or crepe de Chine??
? Will you someday be someone
that somebody loves??
? Are you valentine candy
or...?
? Bo xing gloves??
Mrs. Worth,
I'm not a one to pry,
but I can't help wondering
some things.
Yes, Mr. Lawless?
? Board by board?
Is it forever like this?
Like what?
Ha, that must be
Dr. Donleavy at last.
? Body and mind of mortal man?
It isn't as if this was
the only job in Philadelphia.
Well, not for
a likable lad like meself.
? Fashion the framework
board by board?
Mrs. Worth?
I've decided
to run along for now.
Perhaps I can call another day.
Perhaps.
Who are you?
John Lawless.
A professional pugilist,
no doubt.
Ma'am?
Did you come here to fight?
Oh, no, ma'am, I came
about the butler's position.
Then announce me.
And take off your hat
in the house.
? Strengthen the dwelling
of the Lord?
? Fashion the framework
board by board?
? Here in his image
now we stand?
? Building his fortress
strong and grand?
? It is written that the?
? Body and mind of mortal man?
? Should walk in the spirit
of his master plan?
Mr. Biddle?
There's a lady
in the music room.
A lady?
She didn't give a name.
Like there was no need.
Aunt Mary.
Tell her there's nobody at home.
But, sir...
? It is written that the?
? Body and mind of mortal man?
? Should walk in the spirit
of his master plan?
? So we must strengthen
the dwelling of the Lord?
I'm afraid
there's no one here, ma'am.
No one here?
No one at all save
Mrs. Worth and meself.
And as for me, I...
? It is written that the body
and mind of mortal man?
? Should walk in the spirit
of his master plan?
Aunt Mary!
What a nice surprise.
Is it?
I come about
the butler's position.
Oh, good!
Then take these, would you?
And tell Mr. Biddle
that Aunt Mary is here.
And bring us some tea
into the parlor, please.
If the stores get
any more crowded,
I'm just going to have
to give up shopping entirely.
You can't imagine
the swarms of people.
Do sit down, Aunt Mary.
This is not a social call.
I've come for a specific reason.
In today's paper,
in George Gray's gossip column,
it is reported...
that "last week,
Cordelia Drexel Biddle
entered a one-step contest
in Atlantic City
with a Heinie Fenstermaker,"
whoever that is.
I don't recognize the name.
"And won."
We, uh...
We were in Atlantic City
for the Bible-class convention.
I know why
you were in Atlantic City,
but that does not explain
and certainly doesn't excuse
the matter at hand.
Well, good afternoon, Aunt Mary.
Always a pleasure to see you.
Cordelia.
Anthony.
Oh, Anthony, your finger.
Yes.
George bit me.
George?
I can't imagine
what got into him.
Quite obviously
your finger got into him.
Anyone who keeps
an alligator in the house
must expect to be bit
and deserves it.
Well, I'm sure George was only
playing and forgot himself.
Do you really think so?
Oh, I'm sure of it.
Over there, please.
He probably feels
as badly about it as you do.
I wonder.
That will be all, thank you.
You're right, Cordelia.
He wants to make up.
- Well...
- Ha.
If the jungle theatrics
are quite over,
I should like to return to
the subject of my visit,
which is Cordy.
What about Cordy?
I do not consider she's
under the right influences
for a young woman
in her social position.
She's under my influence and
her mother's and her brothers'.
Oh, please, Anthony,
don't pretend naiveté.
You know perfectly well
what I mean.
No, I don't.
I do not know what you mean.
Did you read
this morning's paper?
Yes.
Yes, I did.
German U-boats in our waters
sinking British merchant ships
in sight of Nantucket.
That's what they think
of our neutrality.
Did you get
beyond the first page?
George Gray's column, dear.
Cream or lemon, Aunt Mary?
Of course not.
Blasted professional
troublemaker.
Oh, no, he doesn't make trouble.
He reports it.
This Mr. Fenstermaker.
He's a member of one
of your Bible classes, I assume?
Yes.
Yes, he is.
And a fine, upstanding
young man he is, too.
Anthony, tell me something.
Were the children in school
at all last year?
They were being tutored,
Aunt Mary.
And who's tutoring the tutor?
What do you mean?
Well, everybody knows
that you hired this man
as a boxing coach.
Can't even sign his own name.
Tony and Liv got
into St. Paul's all right.
They're going next week.
And I applaud the move.
Now let's do the same for Cordy.
The Laleta Wingfield School
for Young Ladies
in Lakewood, New Jersey,
is accepting applications.
Oh, no, you don't.
I won't have Cordy
exiled to some prison.
Anthony, answer me.
What proper young man
in his right mind
would want to marry
a lady prizefighter?
Blast the proper young man.
That's easy to say.
Besides, what's this
talk about marriage?
Cordy's a child.
You're blind, Anthony,
in more ways than one.
- Blind or not, I'm not...
- Papa.
Oh, Cordy.
- We were just discussing you.
- Yes, I know.
And, Papa, I'd like
to go off to school.
Hello, Aunt Mary.
Good afternoon, Cordelia.
Hello, Mama.
Darling.
Cordy.
Did I hear you correctly?
I'm sure you did, Papa.
Are you still upset
about what happened a while ago?
Do you want that boy
back over here?
I'll drag him back.
No, Papa.
It isn't Charlie Taylor.
Well, then, what is it?
Don't you like it here?
Of course I like it here.
Don't we have a good time?
Yes.
But it's hard to explain, Papa.
I'm not like the other girls.
Well, hooray for that.
Look at the other girls.
Oh, Papa.
Cordy,
I like you the way you are.
You're pretty.
You have fun.
You're alive.
You've got a better
left hook than Tony or Liv.
But I don't want a left hook.
Anthony, I think we'd better
talk about this later.
She doesn't know
what she's saying.
I do know what I'm saying.
I want to go to
Miss Wingfield's school.
All right.
You go.
Go to prison if you want to.
Thank you, Papa.
Blast!
Ooh!
Well, it's late.
And I've other things to do.
Well, thank you
for coming, Aunt Mary.
I don't like to interfere.
But attention must be paid
to these matters.
I know.
Good day, Cordelia.
Good day, Anthony.
Anthony.
We do have to let Cordy go.
She's not a child anymore.
And it's selfish to keep her
here in this special world.
What's wrong
with this special world?
Oh, Anthony, why do you have to
take everything so personally?
Is there some other way?
You might as well put out
that terrible weed.
You won't get rid
of me that way.
Anthony.
I raised very few objections
to the way that Cordy's
been brought up,
despite its being
rather unorthodox.
Don't say, "What's wrong
with being unorthodox?"
There's nothing wrong with it.
If I didn't feel that way,
I couldn't have stayed married
to you all these years.
It's been a good life.
A healthy life.
And Cordy's been happy.
But now she's older
and feels a need to reach out.
But she won't like it.
That's for her to decide.
You didn't want to let go
of Tony and Liv.
You fought St. Paul's
like a tiger.
Well, now it's Cordy.
Blast it, Cordelia.
I said she could go, didn't I?
Yes, dear.
Well, then...
what's all the fuss about?
I'm going out to the gym.
Good idea.
You'll feel much better
when you get back.
Oh.
Mrs. Biddle.
Mrs. Biddle,
if it's convenient...
Oh, yes. I'm afraid
I don't remember your name.
John Lawless, ma'am.
The Mayflower Employment Agency.
Ah, fine.
Dinner's at 7:00, John.
Well?
Were you put on?
"Dinner's at 7:00," she says.
Heaven help me.
Good way to let off steam.
Papa, I'm sorry
for the way I acted.
I appreciate your apology.
I do love my home.
I don't really want to go away.
Well, you were right
wanting to go.
You're not a child any longer.
It's selfish to try to keep you
here in this special world.
What's wrong
with this special world?
Now, don't you start that.
Cordy.
You have to make your own life
in your own way.
You can't stay here
with your mother and me forever.
Of course, when you
come home on vacations,
things will be just the same.
All of a sudden, I'm afraid.
Now, that I won't have.
There's nothing out there
to be afraid of,
as long as you keep your
guard up and your chin tucked,
and know how to bring one up
from the floor.
Oh, Papa.
When I was a little girl,
I used to think you must be
the most wonderful person
in the whole world.
Now that I'm older
and much wiser, I know you are.
Well, come on,
let's go back in the house.
If you don't like that school,
you don't have to stay up there.
? Dee-a da da da?
? Dee-a ta ta ta-ta ta?
? Da-da ta-ta tee?
Mr. Biddle?
Mr. Bid...
What's wrong?
You're white as a sheet.
Faith, you do have an alligator!
12 of them.
What's wrong with that?
Not a thing.
It's relieved, I am.
I captured them myself
down in Florida.
Went into the swamp
with a party of Seminoles.
Have you ever seen a Seminole
Indian capture alligators?
I can't say I have.
Well, they can paddle a canoe so
you can't hear it two feet away.
If the animals
don't show themselves,
you give them the mating call.
Say, who are you, anyway?
John Lawless, sir.
I'll be the new butler.
Oh, we've got a new butler.
No, Papa.
He quit.
Already?
- Days ago.
- Oh.
Well, if you'll excuse me, sir.
John Lawless, is it?
That's right, sir.
Tell me, John.
Are you a religious man?
I try to live by the Good Book.
How well do you succeed?
- I'm not sure.
- Never mind.
We'll go into that another time.
What do you think of boxing?
- Boxing?
- Why don't we find Mother...
Not in self-defense.
Ever done any of that?
Well, at the fair last year
in County Tyrone,
I was fisticuffs champion.
Is that so?
Champion?
Well, it isn't
a very large county, sir.
Fisticuffs champion
of where was that again?
County Tyrone.
It's in Ireland.
Ah. You going to become
an American citizen, John?
- Well, I intend to apply, sir.
- You'll never regret it.
- Greatest country in the world.
- Papa!
There's certain things
I believe in, John.
God and the United States
are at the top of the list.
I know very well what
the United States has to offer.
That's how it is I'm here.
Yes, well, like I say...
There's something else
I know just as well.
And that is you are what you
are, and that's good, too.
I beg your pardon?
Well, being an American
is addin' something.
It isn't subtracting.
On the night
before I sailed away,
they come from far and near.
? All me friends
and all me kin?
? To shed a partin' tear?
? We knew we'd
never meet again?
? And yet was clear to see?
? I'd always be
a part of them?
? And them a part of me?
? I'll always be Irish?
? 'Cause that's how I began?
? I'll always be Irish,
I'll say that to any man?
? And when I'm an American,
I'll be a good one, too?
? I'll be truly as American
as Irish stew?
Hey, that's pretty good.
? He'll be truly as American
as Irish stew?
Ask for Irish stew in Ireland
and see what you get.
I never thought of that.
In Ireland,
all the stew is Irish.
? I'll always be Irish?
? A fact I'll not deny?
? I'll always be Irish,
and I'll hold me head up high?
? I'll wear the green
St. Patty's Day?
? And yet for all of that?
? I'll be truly as American
as "Casey at the Bat"?
? He'll be truly as American
Say, that looks like
good exercise.
Come on, Cordy.
- Hey!
- Papa!
If you can win
a one-step contest,
you ought to be able to do this.
I thought you
didn't like dancing.
It's that waltzing business
I don't like.
Ha.
That's for old folks.
Hey!
Huh! Ha!
? If I went to Paris
for the rest of me days?
? And ate bread and cheese
in sidewalk cafés?
? Lived in a garret,
wore a beret?
-? What would I be??
- An Irishman!
? If I went to Tibet
and bought me a yak?
? And traveled Siberia
ridin' his back?
? The peasants would point
at me, what would they say??
Irishman?
- Right!
? But if I went to Spain
and grew a moustache?
? Strummed the guitar
and wore me a sash?
? Became a toreador
and fought me a bull?
- ndele!
- Ndele!
- Hooray!
- Yippee!
After they awarded me
both ears and the tail,
what would they say?
- Olé!
- For the Irishman!
- Right!
Hey-ho!
Whoo-aaa-hoo!
Come on, Mrs. Worth.
Come on, now.
Whoo! Ha!
It's good for you.
Ha ha!
Ah, thatagirl!
You should have seen
me father doin' this.
Like a tornado across the floor.
Hey!
Oh!
Ohhhh!
Ohh! Oh!
? He'll always be Irish?
Ah, shout it good and loud!
? Of his heritage, he's proud?
? I'm proud of Irish blarney?
? And Irish sentiment?
? And I'll bet someday
we get an Irish president?
Whee-ha!
Hey, let me in there.
Hey-ya diddle!
Hey-ya!
Ha!
Beautiful!
Whee!
Whee! Hoo!
- Ha!
- Whoo!
Hey!
Whoo!
Whoo-hoo!
Oh, the Mayflower
Employment Agency.
Oh, yes.
Yes, of course.
Hey!
Yes.
I think Mr. Lawless
will suit our needs very well.
Hee!
Come on,
I want George to see this.
Whoo!
Whoo! Whoo!
Cordelia, whatever
are you laughing at?
Papa.
He's now giving military
training to the Bible classes.
They're marching up and down
in front of the house.
Broomsticks for rifles.
Cordelia, what an absolutely
gorgeous invitation!
Whoever is it from?
Well, read it for yourself
if you're so anxious.
I'm not the least bit anxious.
I was only trying
to be sociable.
Cordelia!
The William Thaws are absolutely
world-famous for their parties.
However did you
get this invitation?
Well, I'm in great demand
socially.
Didn't you know?
I suppose you give
boxing exhibitions.
However did you guess?
And I think I'll get in
some practice.
Right now!
I'll call Miss Wingfield!
With that rouge
all over your face?
Cordy.
You wouldn't tell Miss Wingfield
that I wear rouge
to bed, will you?
No matter how angry you get?
Well...
Oh, no, you wouldn't be
so cruel.
Rosemary?
Hmm?
Would you teach me how to flirt?
Pardon?
Well, my Aunt Gladys said
there were gonna be
all sorts of young men
at the dance
from Yale and Princeton.
Your Aunt Gladys.
So that's how you got invited.
The William Thaws
are my aunt and uncle.
Since I'm going to school
here in Lakewood,
they're practically duty-bound.
I should have guessed.
Well, it helps to be related
to almost everybody.
I want to make the most of it.
Will you help me, Rosemary?
Cordelia, if you're suggesting
that I know anything about...
Oh, come on, Rosemary.
I'll bet you're
the world's champion.
Well, the fact that
I have been admired by men
doesn't make me a flirt.
Rosemary.
Hmm?
Would you like me to swear
that I'll never tell
Miss Wingfield about the rouge?
That's blackmail.
It's a trade.
Well?
I wonder if those Thaw parties
are as absolutely
spectacular as people say.
That's how trading works,
isn't it?
All right.
I'll ask my Aunt Gladys.
Oh, good!
Come here.
Now, if a girl wants
to be popular nowadays,
there's one thing that she
absolutely needs to know.
What?
Bye-yum pum pum.
Bye-yum pum pum?
? Bye-yum pum pum?
? Bye-yum pum pum, bye-yum?
? You must be?
? Oh, so misterioso?
? Enthusiasm is très passé?
? You must slink
across the floor?
? As if it's a dreadful bore?
? To the rhythm
of bye-yum pum pum?
? Bye-yum pum pum?
? Bye-yum pum pum, bye-yum?
? Nita Naldi, Theda Bara?
? Hollow cheeks
and black mascara?
? Bye-yum pum pum, bye-yum?
Okay, what's next?
? The men in college?
? Always acknowledge?
? A girl who dances
in a trance?
? So bye-yum until the dawn
as if you're about to yawn?
? To the rhythm of?
? Bye-yum pum pum?
Attitude, Cordy!
? Bye-yum pum pum, bye-yum?
? Today the key
to being wanted?
? Is just to glide
as if you're hunted?
? And your right foot,
left foot, right, back?
Let me try, let me try!
Right foot, left foot,
right, back together.
Now arms, Cordy, arms.
Use your arms, back together.
And slink, two, three.
Bye-yum and slink, two, three.
Bye-yum and slink, two.
Now spin like a top.
That's it!
Cordy, you're absolutely wicked.
I love it.
How exotic.
Bravo.
Nita Naldi!
Theda Bara!
Cordy,
you're absolutely dangerous.
And scandalous!
? For when you're
oh, so misterioso?
? The men will grow
so entranced with you?
Shocking!
? As you secretly conceal
the tingly way you feel?
? When you're dancing to?
? Bye-yum pum pum?
? Bye-yum pum pum, bye-yum?
Cordelia!
Oh!
Aunt Gladys.
Cordelia, darling.
I've been looking
all over for you.
Where have you been?
I want you to meet the two most
charming young men at the party.
My niece,
Cordelia Drexel Biddle.
Mr. Roger Fitzsimmons
and Mr. Walter Blakely.
Both just down from New Haven.
- How do you do?
- A pleasure.
Well, I'll leave you three
to get acquainted.
Young people today
don't need anything more
than an introduction.
Snappy party.
What?
Oh.
Oh, yes.
Very snappy.
Have a gasper?
A what?
Oh.
No, thank you.
I didn't think
you were the type.
These days, you can't tell.
Smoking shortens your wind.
Well, that's why athletes
never smoke.
Say, there's a friend
of my family
I ought to go over and speak to.
Can't it wait
until later, Roger?
I wouldn't want to miss her.
My mother
would never forgive me.
Miss Biddle.
Yoo-hoo.
Cordelia.
Absolutely heavenly party.
Yes. Heavenly.
So many attractive men.
Who is that?
My roommate.
We're playing Harvard next week.
Who is?
Yale.
Oh.
Mr. Blakely.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
I promised this dance.
You did?
Yes.
The first one-step.
I hope you don't mind.
Oh, no.
No, of course not.
Why don't you ask Rosemary?
- Oh, no, I couldn't.
- Tell her I suggested it.
Well, when your partner comes.
Oh, but you needn't wait around.
He'll be here any second.
Who is he?
I can keep an eye out for him.
Oh, I don't think you know him.
What's his name?
His name?
Well, it's...
Angier Duke.
This is our dance, isn't it?
The first one-step?
Yes.
Mr. Duke, Mr. Blakely.
You can't keep her to yourself
all evening, Mr. Blakely.
No, I guess not.
Miss Biddle.
He's probably a nice enough
fellow when you get to know him.
Shall we have our dance?
Mr. Duke, why did you do that?
Because I thought
I'd like to know you.
Worked out real well, didn't it?
Why do you want to know me?
Because you're not like
the other girls.
I mean that in the nicest way.
I don't like these pushy girls
who think they can trap
any man with a big act.
But you saw me practicing.
Didn't it scare you away?
No.
You were so bad at it.
Oh.
It's a waltz.
The waltz is for old people.
Is it?
I warned you.
I'm not a very good dancer.
Oh, nonsense, Mr. Blakely.
You're as light as an elf.
I don't think the waltz
is for old people.
I was just saying something
somebody told me.
? Are we dancing??
? Are we really here??
? Is this feeling
something real?
? Or will it disappear??
? Are we dancing??
? Does the music soar??
? Was this lovely song I hear?
? Ever heard before??
? Are your eyes
confessing things?
? I alone can see?
? Or is my imagination?
? Flying away with me??
? Are we dancing??
? Say we really are?
? Then I'll know that I?
? Reached into the sky?
? I reached into the sky?
? And touched a star?
? Is this feeling
something real?
? Or will it disappear??
? Was this lovely song I hear?
? Ever heard before??
? Are your eyes
confessing things?
? I alone can see?
? Or is my imagination?
? Flying away with me??
? Are we dancing??
? Say we really are?
? Then I'll know that I?
? I'll know that I?
? Reached into the sky?
? Reached to the sky?
? I reached into the sky?
? And touched a star?
It's beautiful, isn't it?
It's more than beautiful.
It's a masterpiece
of engineering.
A Rolls-Royce Silver Ghost.
Oh.
Yes, it's very nice.
You know, the chassis
of that car is bolted together
with special tapered bolts
made to fit holes
that were reamed by hand.
- Really?
- Yeah.
It's practically sewn together.
Well, I don't know
very much about cars.
You don't have to know much
to appreciate a Rolls.
If you were just once
out on the road in that car.
Say, it's cold out here,
isn't it?
Can I get your coat?
My Uncle has a Silver Ghost.
I've driven it.
I've been
up to 75 miles an hour.
Smooth as silk.
The suspension system
really is remarkable.
May I see you again?
Now you have to.
Pardon me, Cordelia.
My friends,
I'd like to offer a toast.
To our guests of honor.
And to the entire Marine Corps.
The most glorious institution
God ever put
on this broad, green Earth.
I recently traveled
to Washington
to see if anyone there
was concerned about this war
that's got half the world
in flames.
I was treated to a lot of
excuses and a lot of speeches.
Until I got to the Marines.
It's going to be a long evening.
When I talked to the Marine
commandant about preparedness,
he understood.
When I told him there were
5,000 men here in Philadelphia
ready and eager to be trained,
he was interested.
These three men
arrived this morning
as proof of his sincerity.
They're going to work
with our Philadelphia Corps.
And if war comes, by George,
we're going to be ready.
? I believe in this country?
? But our country's
unprepared?
? Our defenses aren't worth
a hill of beans?
? So when a man loves
his country?
? Should he sit back
and complain?
? Or call out
the United States Marines??
? What's wrong with that??
? What better way,
what better means?
? To take my stand
with the Marines??
? What's wrong with that??
To the Marine Corps.
Gentlemen, I want to say again,
it's good to have you with us.
Sir, is the Philadelphia Corps
the same thing
as the Biddle Bible classes?
Well, it grew out of that.
The Bible classes
are the hard core.
The core of the Corps.
Yes, you might say that.
Mr. Biddle,
you've done a swell job
getting all those men together.
I think it's great.
A man like yourself
taking such an interest.
A man like myself?
Yes, an older man
with plenty of money.
And I promise you, sir,
we'll have them snapping to
in no time.
Lieutenant, I already have them
snapping to.
I expect you
to take it from there.
- Will you take seconds?
- No, thank you.
The one thing my men need
is formal combat training.
I'm depending on
you gentlemen for that.
John, would you please
tell Mrs. Worth
that I'd like to serve dinner
as soon as possible?
Yes, ma'am.
It's trench fighting
that's going to win this war.
I want my men to learn
how to use a bayonet
and the butt of a gun.
We've got a training program
set up.
Close combat is a part of it.
A big part, I hope.
It'll save lives.
I know I'm anxious to learn.
It's pretty strenuous exercise,
Mr. Biddle.
Is it, now?
Of course you'll be welcome
to observe, sir.
Gentlemen, may I show you
around the place?
We'll start with the stables.
This way, gentlemen.
The stables are right out here
across the terrace.
Dear, let's not move
the entire party outside.
It looks as if Anthony
might learn a lesson tonight.
I'm tempted to go out there
and watch myself.
Aunt Mary.
You forget that Anthony's
boxed with champions.
But they were friends, Cordelia.
And professionals.
These young men are not friends.
And there is
nothing so dangerous
as the inspired amateur.
Yes, I fixed this place up
to provide some healthy fun
and relaxation for myself
and the rest of the family.
Say, would any of you like to
go a round or two before dinner?
How about you Marines?
Do any of you know how to box?
We all know how to box, sir.
- That's part of our training.
- Fine.
John!
You want to box with me, sir?
We'll just go a couple
of rounds, Lieutenant.
Thank you.
You know, a lot of older men
take up sports of one kind or
another just to pass the time.
John!
You yelled, sir?
Yes. Would you keep time
for us, John?
Yes, sir.
We box by college rules here,
Lieutenant.
Two-minute rounds.
Thank you, John.
Well, are you ready, Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
All right, John.
Time, gentlemen.
The men in the Philadelphia
Corps have a lot to learn
about military science.
But you will find them
well-disciplined.
And physically fit.
So that's your style, is it?
Bill O'Brien used to lean
on his left like that.
Poor Billy never was
a really top fighter.
One thing to remember
about the Philadelphia Corps.
They're civilians.
You'll get a lot more
out of them if you lead them.
Rather than bully them.
Know what I mean?
Oh, Lieutenant!
Well, that was
just a lucky punch.
Might just as well
have happened to me.
Come on.
Yeah, that was quick thinking
catching old Jim Corbett
in your lap like that.
John, that's a bad spot
for old Jim up there.
I'll bet we've knocked him
off that wall
at least a dozen times.
You know, Corbett and I sparred
in this very ring several times.
He was a great fighter.
Well, who's next?
Well, don't you think
we ought to go back, sir?
We wouldn't want to
delay dinner, sir.
That's very considerate.
We'll rejoin the ladies, then.
John, would you get some ice
for the lieutenant?
- It'll keep the swelling down.
- I'll bring some directly, sir.
As soon as I get Mr. Corbett
back up on the wall.
You know, I've worked up
a little appetite.
Yes, boxing always helps
my appetite.
Greatest sport in the world.
Mr. Biddle?
I've got a proposition.
If you won't tell the men
of the Philadelphia Corps
that you took the best boxer
among us in one round,
we'll teach you all
the close combat you want, sir.
Fine, fine.
I'm looking forward to it.
Say, gentlemen,
before we go in to dinner,
I want to show you
my alligators.
? What's wrong with that??
? What better way,
what better means?
? To take your stand
with the Marines??
? What's wrong with that??
Come on.
I'll show you the alligators.
I keep them in the conservatory.
The days of the custom car
are numbered.
Even in luxury automobiles,
standardization is
a practical necessity.
Not only for the manufacturer
but for the individual
car owner as well.
Take a car like the Marmon.
I'd rather not.
Huh?
Angie, do you think we could
talk about something
besides automobiles
for a change?
World affairs.
Or the weather.
I'm sorry, Cordy.
Or you.
I'd really love to
hear about you.
Okay. Me.
What kind of music do you like?
Music?
What's your favorite book?
Let me see.
My favorite book.
Let's talk about your career.
My career?
There's not much to tell.
We're in tobacco.
Do you like tobacco?
As a business, I mean.
I guess so.
You guess so?
I haven't thought
that much about it.
It's a family business, and I
guess I'll take it over someday.
Is there something
you'd rather do?
Yes, but you said you wanted to
talk about something else.
Oh, no.
You mean you want to make
a career out of automobiles?
? There's a shining city
west of here?
? Where dreams
are booming into gear?
? It's no humdrum
nine-to-five town?
? It's a growing, going,
bright, alive town?
? Golden sparks
light up the skies there?
? Like a thousand
Fourth of Julys there?
? How I want to
stake a claim in?
? Roll up my sleeves
and make a name in?
? Detroit?
Detroit?
Michigan.
? You can hear it humming,
see it coming?
? Feel it everywhere you go?
? It's tomorrow morning?
? The future dawning?
? With a bright
and shining glow?
? It's a land
where golden chariots?
? Are molded out of dreams?
? Detroit?
? Detroit, Detroit?
? It's Detroit?
? Oh, if I could be there,
I'd be free there?
? Standing on my own two feet?
? I'd invent new motors,
design new rotors?
? I'd be in the driver's seat?
? I'd make
all my dreams realities?
? Oh, I'd be on my way?
? In Detroit?
? Detroit?
? Detroit, Detroit?
? In Detroit?
? Others are giving
their dreams a try?
? If others can dream there?
? Why can't I??
Cordy, you'd be amazed at the
things they're doing out there.
They're working on
a two-range transmission.
Four-wheel brakes.
Do you think they could do
something about the seats?
Sure.
That's easy.
And heat the inside?
Why not? There's hot water
in the radiator.
How about a gramophone so we
could have music on long trips?
Sure.
It's possible.
And any color you want?
I don't know about that.
Okay.
Any color you want.
? So you see
where the rainbow ends for me?
? Is known to the world
as F. O.B.?
? Detroit?
What is it?
I don't know.
I'll find out.
Cordy.
You think I'm crazy?
About Detroit, I mean.
Boy, my mother does.
? If you hear it humming,
see it coming?
? That's the place
where you must go?
? But to make your name there?
? You must stake
your claim there?
? And let no one tell you no?
Then you don't think I'm crazy.
? Then my dreams
of golden chariots?
? In Detroit
can all come true?
? For you hear it humming?
? And you see it coming?
? And you?
? Want to be there, too?
Hurry!
Well, those men
looked good tonight.
Yes, sir.
Like seasoned troopers.
Don't you think
they looked good?
Yes, dear.
They looked cold, too.
I was sorry for them.
They're going to have to
fight battles in cold weather.
I wasn't criticizing, dear.
It was a lovely parade.
- It's cold in here.
- Yes, it is.
Yeah, I think
the furnace must be off.
No.
The radiator's hot.
Yeah, there's a terrible draft
coming from somewhere.
The conservatory, I think.
The conservatory?
John!
My alligators.
Look at my alligators.
John!
George.
Yes, sir?
You yelled, sir?
What's happened here?
Why are these windows open?
It must have been
the new maid, sir.
What new maid?
Her name is Florence, dear.
She started this afternoon.
She was complaining
about the smell.
- What smell?
- The alligators.
- They do have a certain...
- What?
We're accustomed to it, dear.
Oh.
She probably decided to
give the room an airing...
and forgot to close up again.
Well, of all
the blasted, stupid...
Get an ax.
Anthony!
Not for Florence.
For the alligators.
Maybe they're still alive.
We'll chop 'em out.
An ax! Move!
Dead, dead, dead.
Get some more towels, John.
Yes, ma'am.
Anthony, it's after midnight.
Yeah.
I hate to give up.
I know, dear.
But there comes a time.
I'll get it.
Dead, dead, dead.
Hello?
Yes, this is Mr. Biddle.
Who's calling?
Oh, yes.
How long ago?
What have you done about it?
Have you called the police?
- Then call them, blast it!
- What is it, Anthony?
I want that blasted town
turned upside down, do you hear?
All right.
Call me back
the minute you know anything.
- Is it Cordy?
- Yes.
- She's missing.
- Missing?
Three hours past curfew,
and nobody there
has any idea where she is.
That's a fine way to
run a prison.
You don't suppose
she's been kidnapped?
- For heaven's sake.
- Well, it happens.
Operator!
- Don't do anything foolish.
- Foolish?
Our daughter is
heaven knows where.
- Operator!
- Hello.
Cordy.
Mother.
Papa.
Are you all right?
Of course I'm all right.
You're not hurt in any way?
What are you talking about?
We just had a call
from Miss Wingfield.
Oh.
I was hoping we'd get here
before that happened.
The weather held us up.
Us?
Is someone with you, Cordy?
Yes.
My fiancé.
Your...
Your what?
His name
is Angier Buchanan Duke.
He's in the car.
Do you mean to tell me
that some boy is sitting
in front of this house
thinking he's going to
marry you?
Anthony, please.
He wanted to make sure
I got in all right.
I'll tell him he can go now.
Good night!
Good night?
Aren't you going to ask him in?
No, Mother, I don't think so.
I'll call you in the morning!
We don't even get
a chance to see him?
Of course you'll see him.
When you're ready.
I'm ready now.
No, Papa.
I'm not gonna let you at him.
Not until you get used to
the idea.
Where did you meet
this young man, Cordy?
At a party Aunt Gladys
and Uncle Bill gave.
I wrote you about it.
You didn't write us
about getting engaged.
He didn't ask me until today.
What took him so long?
Oh, now, Anthony.
Papa.
I think you'll
really like him very much
if you just give him a chance.
Of course
we'll give him a chance.
Is I dreaming, I am?
Hello, John.
Oh, you look fine.
Because I'm happy.
I'm engaged!
Engaged, is it?
Well, isn't that grand?
I'm very happy for you.
Isn't that wonderful news,
Mrs. Biddle?
Isn't it just...
I'd best be getting these towels
into the parlor.
Towels?
We had a sort of accident
this evening.
But I think we should
all go up to bed now
and talk in the morning.
I am tired.
We got stuck in the snow twice.
And we thought
we'd broken the axle.
And then the fan belt came off.
But it was fun.
Good night, Mother.
Good night, darling.
It's so nice to be home.
I love you, Papa.
Good night.
"My fiancé," she says.
Without batting an eye.
And you just stand there.
And I just stand there.
What else could we do?
We've never met the young man.
We don't know
anything about him.
What's that got to do with it?
She's a child.
She's a young woman.
You can't hold back
the clocks, Anthony.
Cordelia, I don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm not trying to
hold back any clocks.
She's not ready for marriage.
You're not ready.
I'm not going to
sit still for it.
Anthony, you'll be making the
greatest mistake of your life
if you try to stop
this engagement.
Is it wrong for me to try to
protect my daughter?
Cordy has a mind of her own.
Faced with an obstacle,
she will proceed with
still greater determination.
Why, you, of all people,
ought to know that.
We don't want to push her
into an elopement.
Come on.
You know, I'm anxious to see
what he looks like.
I believe you're enjoying this.
Well, in a way, I am.
It's a very exciting time.
Cordelia,
sometimes you amaze me.
Well, I hope so, Anthony.
It never rains but it pours.
To lose your only daughter
and your pet alligators
all on the same black night.
What's all the...
Oh!
Anthony, what are
you doing down there?
The girl's crazy.
That stuff she uses to
color her hair
must have gone to her brain.
Miss, would you mind
telling me what...
What's going on?
Well...
Well, I'll be.
Anthony, what is it?
Everything's all right now.
That nitwit girl frighten you?
They're not dead!
John!
Yes, sir?
John, they're not dead!
Yes, sir.
I know, sir.
Come on, George.
George!
Cordelia, it's George.
What is it, Papa?
They're not dead.
George.
George, come back here.
Allow me, sir.
George!
George, not outside.
You'll freeze all over again.
Here you are, Mother.
All right.
Out of there.
Run along now.
In the conservatory.
Ah-ah.
Thank you.
Come on.
You heard what Mother said.
Into the conservatory.
George?
Did George come
back in here again?
I didn't see him, dear.
Take a look
in the dining room, John.
Where do you suppose he got to?
There's breakfast to get on
the table, in case you forgot.
How can you be so calm with
those monsters on the loose?
They know better
than to get in my way.
You can fill the cream pitcher
and get busy settin' the table.
Idiot girl.
None of them stay very long.
I'll teach you to make yourself
at home in my kitchen!
Come out, I say!
Me new broom.
You drop that!
Drop it, I say!
Where you going, you beast?
You'd be a handbag
if I had my way.
You should've let out a call.
I'd have given you a hand.
Thank you, Mr. Lawless.
It wasn't necessary.
I managed very well on me own.
Breakfast will be
in half an hour.
I have to slice some more bacon.
Thank you, Mrs. Worth.
Well, I think
we'd better get dressed.
That girl may come back here
with the police.
Cordy.
Yes, Papa?
Cordy, I've been
thinking things over.
I realize
I acted badly last night.
I want you to invite your
young man to dinner so I can,
as you say, give him a chance.
Thank you, Papa.
Well, you know, I worked up
quite an appetite.
I think I'd rather have
scrapple than bacon.
Mrs. Worth.
Thank you, Mother.
What for, darling?
For helping Papa
change his mind.
Did I do that?
Are you sure?
Oh!
There's an old Irish proverb.
To have your alligators
thawed out
and your daughter forgive you
all on the same bright day,
that's fortuosity.
- John?
- Sir?
Who are you talking to?
No one, sir.
You know what they say about
people who talk to themselves.
It's like I said.
It's another case of...
? Fortuosity?
? That's me byword?
? Fortuosity means?
George?
? Round the corner?
Ha ha!
George?
I've had about as much
as I can stand, now, George!
George!
In the tank.
Will you get in the tank
when I tell you?
Right.
George!
George.
Will you come back here?
Come on.
Oh, did I frighten you, then?
Hey, George.
George!
Not in the music room.
Get in...
George.
Come on, George.
Up.
Hey!
That's a good lad.
There you go.
Come on, boy.
This way, lad.
That's a good lad.
There you go.
It's like I said.
? Every bit of life is lit
by fortuosity?
? And that's me byword?
? Every bit of life is lit by?
? Twinkle-in-the-eye word?
? Every bit of life is lit?
? By fortuosity?
Aah!
John!
Coming, sir.
George.
Yes, it can only be
a matter of weeks now.
Even the White House admits
we can't stay out of this war.
I tried to enlist.
Do you know what they told me?
"You're too old."
Me, in the prime of life.
Fit as a fiddle.
"Too old."
No more wine, Mr. Duke?
No thank you, Mr. Biddle.
I still have a full glass.
Don't you like the wine?
We have others.
A cellarful.
No, thank you. No.
I don't drink very much.
It goes right to my head.
That's where
it's supposed to go.
So you live in New York,
Mr. Duke.
Yes, ma'am. I do.
Do you like it?
Well, yes.
I guess so.
I never could stand
the place, myself.
- How about your work?
- Sir?
Do you enjoy working?
Well, no.
Not really.
- To tell you the truth...
- I don't blame you.
Offices are deadly places.
They confine a man.
Spiritually and physically.
What do you do to escape?
Escape, sir?
Yes.
Do you go in for sports?
Well, I have a boat.
A boat?
A yacht, Papa.
Oh.
A yacht.
Well, I suppose a man
can get a kick out of a yacht.
Do you?
Do I what, sir?
Get a kick out of
your blasted yacht.
Well, I haven't been on it
for a while.
I suppose you've been busy
getting ready for the war.
Angie's gonna
turn his boat over, Papa.
Turn it over.
Well, that's a good thing
to do with a boat.
To the Coast Guard, Papa.
Oh.
Mother thought it would
be a good idea.
I see.
Tell me, Mr. Duke.
What else do you like?
Besides sailing, I mean.
Hiking? Skiing?
I broke an ankle once skiing.
Did you get back up
on those skis and try again?
No, sir.
Well, you should have.
Well, the bone
was kind of sticking out.
Oh.
Oh, that's right.
It goes to your head.
Do you do any fishing
or hunting?
Or do you box?
No, sir.
I just don't seem to have
the time.
You should take the time.
I was a sickly child, Mr. Duke.
Asthma.
Then when I was 10,
I came down with typhoid fever.
"That's it," they said.
"He'll never make it."
But I did make it.
And somehow the fever
killed the asthma.
It was like a miracle.
And do you know what I learned
at that early age, Mr. Duke?
That life is a precious
and wonderful thing.
But you just can't sit there
and let it lap around you.
You have to dive into it.
Taste it. Feel it.
You have to use it.
And the more you use,
the more you have.
That's the wonder of it.
Would you like some
more dessert, Mr. Duke?
No, thank you, Mrs. Biddle.
It's delicious, though.
Is something wrong, Mr. Duke?
Well, lookit there.
Well, it's Lucy.
I'll bet she's been hiding under
there all day where it's warm.
John!
John, look what I found.
Are you all right, Mr. Duke?
Yes.
Thank you.
I don't feel well.
I think I'm getting a cold.
Cordy, why don't you take
Mr. Duke into the parlor?
Yes, ma'am?
John, bring some more coffee
into the parlor, will you?
You little devil.
Decided to make
a holiday of it, did you?
I told you he keeps alligators.
It's not that.
I mean, it's not just that.
Cordy, he scares me to death.
But that's the whole trouble.
You've got to stand up to him.
I think he'd punch me
in the nose.
Punch him back.
Or better still,
punch him first.
What?
When he comes in here,
you've got to talk up to him.
Whatever he says, you dive
right in and contradict him.
Even when he's right?
Especially when he's right.
Cordy, I couldn't do that.
Angie, I want him to like you.
And I'm telling you
how to go about it.
Are you feeling better,
Mr. Duke?
Yes.
Thank you.
It was a little close in there.
Yes, in this cold weather
one has to be so careful.
Going out of doors, coming in.
Cold weather's good for you.
It clears the lungs.
Puts the heart to work.
I like hot weather.
You do?
Yes, sir.
I do.
Well...
Now we know.
Over here, please, John.
Mr. Biddle, I understand
you're a real boxing enthusiast.
Well, yes.
Yes, for some years now, I...
I never could see much in it.
As a sport.
I mean, two men just standing
there hitting each other.
It doesn't seem to have
much subtlety to it.
- It doesn't?
- No, sir.
John, bring in the gloves.
The boxing gloves, sir?
Yes, the boxing gloves.
Anthony, what are
you thinking of?
I want to show Mr. Duke some
of the subtleties of the sport
and correct
his false impression.
John and I can box
a quick couple of rounds.
Me, Mr. Biddle?
Fightin' you, sir?
In my parlor?
Just a demonstration.
Mr. Duke, would you mind moving
that chair out of the way?
The medium gloves, John.
Pardon me, Cordy.
Anthony, I really don't think
this is the time or the place.
We don't have to stand
on ceremonies with Mr. Duke.
He's practically
a member of the family.
- Right, Mr. Duke?
- Right, sir.
As a matter of fact, sir,
I was just wondering.
Why can't I try it?
What's that?
Why can't I fight you?
Without knowing
what you're doing?
From what I've seen
of the sport,
there can't be that much to it.
- Well, Mr. Duke...
- Anthony.
I don't think so.
I thought this was one house
where a man could get
a fair fight.
John, give Mr. Duke your gloves.
Gladly, sir.
Allow me, Mr. Biddle.
Cordy, can you help me
with these?
I don't think
you have to go this far.
Please.
Okay.
There.
You keep time, John.
Cordelia, he wants to.
You heard him.
Anthony, I hope you know
what you're doing.
I'll be careful with him.
That isn't exactly what I meant.
Are we ready, gentlemen?
Yes.
You ready, Mr. Duke?
- Yes, sir.
- We'll see if we can't show you
there's more to boxing
than you think there is.
- All right, John.
- Time.
Never take your eye
off your opponent, Mr. Duke.
Mr. Duke, boxing is called
the art of self-defense
for good reason.
That means you're
supposed to protect yourself.
Your stomach.
Your chin.
Keep circling, Angie.
Keep circling.
You see, Mr. Duke?
If I'd been throwing hard
punches, you'd be in trouble.
Protect yourself.
Keep your chin tucked, Angie.
- My chin what?
- Tucked.
No, just keep it
behind your shoulder there
so you don't get hurt.
All right, now you throw some
punches at me, Mr. Duke.
Never lead with your right,
Mr. Duke.
You're open for a left hook.
See?
Throw another punch.
Now the stomach.
See?
You're not protecting yourself.
Little more subtle than
you thought, isn't it?
Hey.
Wait.
Now, wait a minute.
Wait a minute, Mr. Duke.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Mr. Duke!
Wait a minute now.
You see, Mr. Duke.
- Angie!
- You ran right into my glove.
Will you need the ice?
He's all right.
Aren't you, Mr. Duke?
Yes, sir.
Sure, I'm okay.
Well, I hope
you're not upset with me.
No. If I were upset,
I'd take care of you.
You'd take care of me?
That's right.
Well, now, I find myself
wondering about that.
- You do?
- Yes, indeed, I do.
Excuse me, John.
Sir, would you take your boxing
stance right here, please?
Angie.
Cordy, would you stand
right over here?
Now what?
Papa!
Say, that's a pretty good trick.
Will you be needing
the ice, sir?
Anthony, you all right?
Of course I'm all right.
He caught me unawares,
that's all.
Would you care to
try it again, sir?
Awares?
Confound it, boy.
I've had my share of
roughhouse fighting.
Couldn't all this wait
for another time?
The coffee's getting quite cold.
Don't worry, Mrs. Biddle.
No one will get hurt.
At least I won't.
What do you want to do?
Wrestle?
It's called jujitsu, sir.
It's a little
like wrestling, yes.
Angie, please.
Have you gone crazy?
Yes, I think I have, Cordy.
And I feel right at home.
Mr. Duke, are you all right?
Is he all right?
I hope I didn't hurt you, sir.
Nothing that won't wear off.
That's a grand style
of fighting, sir.
I'd like to learn it meself.
I got a feeling it might
come in handy someday.
We've all got to learn it.
Every last man
in the Philadelphia Corps.
Mr. Duke, I want to thank you.
That's a remarkable thing.
It could mean the difference
between life and death
in hand-to-hand combat.
You will teach it to me,
won't you?
Yes, of course, sir.
And then, one of these days,
we'll have a return match.
Well, Cordelia,
these two young people
haven't been alone all evening.
Yes, well, it's time
to say good night.
It's been so nice having you,
Mr. Duke.
- May I call you Angie?
- Please.
Well, then, good night, Angie.
And we'll see you very soon.
Good night, dear.
- Good night, Mr. Duke.
- Good night, sir.
- Jujitsu, is it?
- Yes, sir.
By George, it's remarkable.
Good night, Cordy.
Papa.
Thank you.
Thank me for what?
He could've killed me.
Can we announce
our engagement soon?
- Yes, of course.
- Why not?
And can I go to New York
and meet Angie's family?
Definitely.
The Biddles and the Dukes will
have to get to know each other.
The sooner, the better.
Angier!
Angier, you sly boy.
Whatever have you gone and done?
Mother, I'd like you
to meet Cordelia.
So this is the girl.
The one you have picked out of
all the world to be yours alone.
My goodness.
Why, I nearly fainted
when I got your call.
Engaged.
Imagine that.
And to a girl from Philadelphia.
We're going to have
a busy schedule.
Mother, I hope
you haven't told people.
- Cordy and I thought...
- Only a select few.
Come along, Cordelia, dear.
Everyone who knows
is frantic to entertain you.
Lorraine Mansfield
called three times.
Angie.
I thought you'd never come.
I know. I got stuck
with my cousin Margaret.
I'm freezing.
I'll fix that.
Angier?
Are you out here?
Oh, so you are.
Behind a bush.
We came out for
a little fresh air, Mother.
The last thing we need, Angier,
is for you to come down
with a cold.
We'll be right in, Mother.
Well, I'd appreciate it.
People are asking for you.
Excuse me.
Papa!
Cordy!
Let me look at you.
You're going to end up a real
beauty if you're not careful.
Oh, Papa.
Oh, I'm so glad to see you.
Oh, it's good to see you,
sweetheart.
Come over here and sit down.
Now, tell me.
How do you like the big city?
Oh, fine.
There's always
something going on.
You get along
with the Dukes all right?
Yes, of course.
Perfectly.
Cordy?
Mr. Biddle!
- How are you, son?
- Just fine, sir.
Keeping that jujitsu
in good practice?
I've been doing
a little practicing myself.
Angier!
Oh, Mother.
Oh.
Mother, may I introduce
Mr. Biddle?
Oh!
Oh, well,
this is a happy surprise.
I'm very pleased to
meet you, Mrs. Duke.
Is it quite safe?
A beautiful woman has
always been safe with me.
I doubt that, Mr. Biddle.
Mrs. Duke, Mrs. Biddle and I
are sorry we've had to refuse
the kind invitations
we've received.
But, well, it seems this war
has been taking up all my time.
We've all been disappointed,
naturally.
What finally brought you
to New York?
- I'm on tour.
- Tour?
With a squad of Marines.
We demonstrate
bayonet techniques.
In auditoriums, theaters.
Anywhere we can find the space.
Whatever for?
It's a recruiting device.
Stirs the blood to see these men
locked in hand-to-hand combat.
I'm sure it must.
We're just passing through
New York on our way to Boston.
I couldn't resist
stopping off between trains
to see my little girl.
It's been a treat for all of us.
You'll join our party,
of course?
I'm afraid I can't, Mrs. Duke.
I have a 10:00 train to catch.
Well, I'll go with you
to the station.
Good, Cordy.
I'd like that.
If you'll excuse her
for a while, Mrs. Duke.
But of course.
Excuse me.
I'll get my wrap.
I can get you a cab, sir.
Oh, thank you.
Well, it won't be long now.
The wedding in Philadelphia.
No, no.
It won't be long.
And how do you like it?
They make a handsome couple.
Oh, you don't like it
any better than I do.
It takes getting used to.
Wasn't too long ago that Angie
wouldn't pick a suit of clothes
without asking my opinion.
Now he goes off to Lakewood
for a weekend
and picks someone to spend
the rest of his life with.
Yes.
Well, Mrs. Duke,
I want to thank you
for the generous way
you've entertained my daughter.
It's my pleasure, Mr. Biddle.
I love spectacle.
Well, I'm not so sure
how spectacular
you'll find Philadelphia.
But we'll certainly do our best.
I'm sure you will.
Good night.
I think I might be coming home
next week.
Oh?
But I thought you were going to
stay till the end of the month.
Well, I'm awfully tired.
You're sure there's
nothing wrong?
Of course I'm sure.
I just want to curl up
in my own bed in my own room
and stay there for about a week.
They're not like us, Papa.
? When a man has a daughter?
? She's always in his heart?
? Happiness is part
of all his prayers?
? When a man has a daughter?
? He wants her life to be?
? As smooth as satin ribbons
that she wears?
? What's wrong with that??
? I want her home,
where she's free of care?
? I miss her footsteps
on the stairs?
? What's wrong with that??
Mrs. Duke?
Yes?
I found some more people
for you to meet.
How delightful.
Gentlemen, this is Cordy's
future mother-in-law.
Mrs. Duke,
may I present Joe Turner?
Glad to know you, Mrs. Duke.
Joe is one of the mainstays
in my Bible classes.
You'd never believe he was a bum
and a drunk when I found him.
Mr. Biddle sure saved me,
all right.
- He's tops on my list.
- I'm sure.
You're marrying into
a fine family.
Yes.
We'll try to be deserving.
And this is Bill O'Brien.
Bill once fought
for the heavyweight title.
If I'd have lasted that
third round, I'd have got him.
I was just gettin' onto
his tricks.
It's really something
to fight for the title.
Oh, there's Madame LaFarge.
Finest voice teacher
in Philadelphia.
Do you like opera, Mrs. Duke?
Sometimes.
Madame LaFarge sings
a mean "Carmen."
Would you excuse me?
Nice party, huh, Mrs. Duke?
Oh, yes.
Colorful.
We can't let New York
outclass Philadelphia.
Thanks, John.
Say, I could use another slug
of that champagne punch.
How about you, Mrs. Duke?
Oh, no, thank you.
I haven't finished the slug
I already have.
Tell me.
Does Mr. Biddle often
present himself in concert?
From time to time, ma'am.
He sang once at a real opera.
Dressed up like a clown, he was.
And sang out loud and clear
through the whole thing.
It sounds as though he were
appropriately costumed.
Papa did "Pagliacci" with
the Manhattan Opera Company.
You're joking.
At least he feels like singing.
Well, so do I sometimes.
But I keep it to myself.
Aren't you having
anything to eat?
You might like the sour pickles.
Oh, shut up.
Hi.
You're crying.
You're late.
Is that why you're crying?
No.
I'm crying because...
Oh, I don't know why.
Cordy, there has to be a reason.
Angie.
We're gonna be married
in just three days.
I know.
I'm afraid.
Ever since we got engaged,
I never see you alone.
We never talk.
We never touch.
I seem like a total stranger
to you, right?
You feel it, too?
Yes, Cordy.
That's why I was late today.
I was so nervous and worried
about everything,
I decided to take a walk
to clear my mind.
To get things straight.
I walked clear
to the Delaware River.
Oh, Angie.
We can't let this happen.
Everything will be all right
once we get away from parties
and our families
and we're on our way to Detroit.
What is it?
- Hold it!
- Cordy.
Just a minute, Mr. Duke.
I'd like another picture.
Later.
Is something wrong?
Cordy, there's something I
have to tell you about Detroit.
Yes?
Well, I've been giving it
some thought.
And I've come
to the conclusion...
Angier!
Where have you been?
I feel like Daniel
in the lions' den.
Excuse me.
I shouldn't stay away
from my guests too long.
Mother, why do you have to
act this way?
Oh, forgive me.
I don't believe it is
my behavior
that is questionable here.
What about
those wedding invitations?
I don't know yet.
And you promised
not to mention it.
But we have to know.
Mother, this is
a very difficult time for me.
And I wish you'd help me out
by going along
with the Biddles' way
of doing things.
After all, this is their house.
Angier, are you snapping at me?
Why, that's not like you.
Oh, never mind.
We'll help each other.
I promise I will do
everything I can
to keep the atmosphere peaceful.
Thank you, Mother.
And when we are out
of all this madness
and you're on your way
to the Ozarks...
Mother, I warned you
not to talk about that.
Oh, yes.
So you did.
Tell me. Is there anything
I can talk about?
Is there no one to answer
the door?
Where are the servants?
They're out there.
Fighting for their lives.
Young man, tell Mr. Biddle
I'm waiting in the parlor.
I have no intention
of going out into that mob.
Yes, ma'am.
Do you know
who that young man is?
That is Angier Duke.
There are those who would
consider the heir
to a multimillion-dollar fortune
improper choice for errand boy.
And there are those sufficiently
accustomed to wealth
that the only thing to be
considered in such a choice
is how well will the young man
perform the errand.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Drexel.
But I will have a closer look
when he comes back.
He must be quite something
if Cordy can spend a month
in New York
and still want to marry him.
If you ladies will make
yourselves comfortable,
I'll fetch
some nice refreshments.
There are those
who consider New York
the only true city
in the country.
And there are those
who wear bibs when they eat.
But generally speaking, they
are not persons of influence.
- Indeed.
Champagne punch and some darling
little sandwiches.
? There are those
whose social standing?
? Is constantly demanding?
? Every single thing we do,
the public knows?
? Then there is
a lower strata?
? Where propriety
doesn't matter?
? I suppose?
? There are those?
? There are those
to whom position?
? Is a natural-born condition?
? To be worn with ease
like comfortable old clothes?
? Though the nouveau riche
deny it?
? All their money
cannot buy it?
? Class will out?
Goodness knows.
? But there are those?
Watercress on toast, ma'am?
? There are those who grace
the pages of the Blue Book?
Never heard of it.
Is it a new book?
Simply anyone who is anyone
is listed.
Oh. You mean the New York
telephone directory?
Hardly.
There are those whose names
predate the Constitution.
Yes, and some of them
opposed the Revolution.
Conservative.
Reactionary.
Cream cheese and cucumber?
? Philadelphia is the cradle
of liberty?
? Slumbering like an aging page
of history?
Chopped liver?
? There are those
who flaunt prosperity?
who flaunt austerity?
? Posing cozy
on their rosy status quos?
Poison dart?
I mean, raisin tart?
? There are those
quite influential?
inconsequential?
? There are those?
- I suppose.
- There are those.
Well, Mrs. Duke,
I see you've met Aunt Mary.
Good afternoon, Aunt Mary.
Aunt Mary, I was looking for you
in the garden.
Not in that mob.
Hello, Aunt Mary.
Cordy.
Aunt Mary, this is Angie.
They've met.
Mrs. Drexel, I would like to
ask you a question or two
about how weddings are managed
by proper Philadelphians.
Mother, you promised.
What about the way weddings
are managed by Philadelphians?
Would anyone like a sandwich?
No.
No, thank you, John.
Is something wrong, Mrs. Duke?
Something is decidedly wrong.
I'll have a sandwich.
Let's all have a sandwich.
What about the wedding?
They really look delicious.
Won't you have one, Mother?
I've already had one.
What about the wedding,
blast it?
I would like to know,
Mr. Biddle,
why the Dukes have not received
invitations.
As I understand it,
the Drexels and the Biddles
are coming by the thousands.
It is customary
in most societies
to invite the family
of the groom as well.
But there was a separate box
of Duke invitations.
Yes.
Yes, I remember that.
Could something have
gone wrong at the post office?
John and I took them in
ourselves.
- John?
- Sir.
See if you can
find out anything.
Yes, sir.
I'm sure there's
some simple explanation.
We'll certainly
take care of it, Mrs. Duke.
These little things happen.
Little things?
How would you feel if the
Drexels had not been invited?
They'd come anyhow.
They're relatives.
It may surprise you to know
that the laws of kinship operate
in New York
and in North Carolina.
Only one thing surprises me,
Mrs. Duke.
Wait a minute.
If you could just...
Stop it!
All of you!
Duke pride.
Drexel pride.
Biddle pride.
Philadelphia versus New York.
I'm sick to death of it.
Angie and I
have been shoved aside
while everyone is busy
turning our wedding
into the biggest production
and the biggest fight
in history.
It isn't fair.
And I'm not going to let it
go on this way
if Angie and I have to elope!
Elope?
And make us all look like fools?
At this moment, Mrs. Duke,
I don't care what you look like.
Cordy.
Angier, you had better speak
to your bride.
This wedding is going to
take place on schedule.
And it is going to
be done right.
Once you're safe
in our railroad car
and on your way to Arkansas,
you can indulge your whim.
Until then...
Arkansas?
What about Arkansas?
Cordy, I'm sorry.
Well, what are you sorry about?
I have arranged
for our private railroad car
to take you and Angier
to Hot Springs
then back to New York
in two weeks
for the board of directors'
meeting.
Angie.
How could you?
Well, what, please tell me,
is wrong with Hot Springs?
I'm sure nothing is wrong
with it, Mrs. Duke.
But I'm not going to spend
my honeymoon there.
Cordy, if we could just
talk things over.
Just like I'm not going to
live in New York.
Of course you're going to
Because I'm not going to
marry you.
What?
- Cordy.
You most certainly are
going to marry him.
She doesn't have to
if she doesn't want to.
Anthony.
What happened to the person
I fell in love with?
A person with dreams and spirit.
Someone I could believe in
and root for.
Someone who could make a car
any color you want.
Oh, no.
I'm not getting married.
- Then I'm not, either!
- Sir!
I found them, sir.
200 invitations.
They were lost
under the clothes we collected
for the Chinese missions.
That's very funny.
No.
It really is.
You'll pardon me
for not laughing.
Angier!
John, maybe you'd better
follow him.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Biddle, what do you intend
to do about this?
Do about it?
Yes. You do intend to do
something, don't you?
Yes, Anthony.
What now?
Well, I don't know.
What do you suggest?
I suggest you talk some sense
into your daughter.
For once I agree
with Mrs. Duke completely.
Wait a minute.
What about trying to talk some
sense into your son, Mrs. Duke?
I'll take care of Angier.
Mrs. Duke, may I offer you
a lift to your hotel?
My electric is waiting outside.
Oh, how very kind of you.
It's comforting to know
that there are those
who can be relied upon
for support in times of stress.
They're trying to lay
this whole mess in my lap.
We'd better get back
to our guests.
They're trying to blame me.
Anyone can misplace a box
of invitations, can't they?
You know very well, Anthony,
the invitations have nothing
to do with it.
That was just fate lending you
a helping hand.
Blast.
I didn't do anything wrong.
Did I, George?
- Hey, here he is!
- Come on, Mr. Biddle.
- We want to drink a toast.
- To the father of the bride!
Now, just a second.
- Outside!
- A toast!
Three cheers!
? For he's a jolly good
fellow?
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Stout!
Did you ever try
a good Irish stout?
Look, you stay away from me.
Just a friendly suggestion, sir.
You followed me here,
didn't you?
The devil, I did.
Do you think you're the only
person that comes into Clancy's
for a little rest
and relaxation?
All right, just leave me alone
and keep your suggestions
to yourself.
Stout.
I'm tired of people
running my life for me.
As well you should be, sir.
Leading me by the hand.
Telling me what to do.
It's a crime.
A man has to finally be a man.
- Right!
? Well, well, well,
"Let's have a drink on it"?
? As me father used to say?
? "When the truth is
nobly spoken?
? It's respect
you've got to pay"?
? So fill your cup
and lift it up?
? And clink, here's how?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have a drink
on it now?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have a drink
on it now?
I don't mind telling you.
These last weeks
have really been rough.
That's a fact.
You try to please everybody.
And you end up pleasing
no one at all.
'Tis the sad, sad truth, sir.
I'll get away from it all.
Good idea.
I'll leave Philadelphia
and never come back.
- Never?
- Never.
Well, why shouldn't I?
There's nothing but trouble
for me here.
for me anywhere.
If I were to go to the ends
of the Earth...
That's it.
I could join the Foreign Legion.
The Foreign Legion, sir.
A fine group of men, sir.
I'd be on my own, then, right?
Right!
? Well, well, well,
let's have a drink on it?
? To the fightin'
Legionnaires?
? To their outposts
in the desert?
? And their gorgeous
Croix de Guerres?
? To sailing for Bengasi
on a rusty scow?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have a drink
on it now?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have a drink
on it now?
Thank you, John.
I'll always be grateful
for your help.
Where are you going?
To Bengasi.
Like we said.
I can't let him get away.
We'll never get things
patched up.
Sir!
A moment of your time, sir!
Just a moment!
? What do you do
when the water's gone?
? And there's no
turning back??
? You're four days
from the fort?
? The Arab renegades attack?
? And the blistering sun
keeps burning?
? Reinforcements
can't get through?
? What do you do about it??
Do you blister easily?
Yes, as a matter of fact.
The Foreign Legion
is not for you.
Drink up.
You're right, John.
Running away isn't the answer.
You're right.
I'm right, all right.
I've got to face my problem
head on.
All right.
What's my problem?
My problem is my family.
It always has been.
I'll change my name.
Renounce my fortune.
That's good thinking.
I'll take an honest job.
In a factory.
Or on a farm.
Maybe someday I'll have
my own place.
- Beautiful!
- I'll be like everybody else.
Poor, right?
- Right!
? Well, well, well,
let's have a drink on it?
? To the simple, average life?
? To the wages every Friday?
? That you bring home
to the wife?
? To the sweat of honest labor
on your average brow?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have a drink
on it now?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have a drink
on it now?
Hey!
Set 'em up, Clancy!
Whoo!
Hey!
The drinks are on the Duke!
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have a drink
on it now?
Thank you all!
I can't tell you how much
this talk has meant to me.
Not at all at all.
- I'll write when I get settled.
- You'll write...
From where are you gonna write?
When a man has reached
a turning point in his life,
why waste time?
? What do you do
when you lose your job??
? The rent is overdue??
? The landlord throws you
in the street?
? The wife, the kiddies, too?
? And the sleet and snow
are falling?
? And you've got
no place to go?
Will you shut your face?
Can't you see I'm talking
to the gentleman?
? What do you do about it??
The simple, average life, sir.
No.
Have a drink.
I'm used to having money.
I might as well admit it.
I know.
I could make my own fortune.
- I could drill for oil in Texas.
- Think it over carefully.
- I could pan for gold in Alaska.
- Don't be too hasty.
Wait.
The pearl trade in China.
The mysterious East.
Who knows what adventures
I might live there?
- Right.
- Right!
- Wrong.
-? Well, well, well?
? Let's have a drink on it?
? Here's to China
across the bay?
? To them darling
little oysters?
? And the pearls
they give away?
? A man could make
his fortune there?
? I will somehow?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? I'm off to China now?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? He's off to China now?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have
another one, sir!?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
Ha!
Ooh! Ooh!
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? I'm off to China now?
? Well, well, well,
one last drink on it?
? Then you're on
your merry way?
? What do you do when
your sampan springs a leak?
? In China Bay??
? When the truth is
nobly spoken?
? It's respect
you've got to pay?
? Them Oriental pirates come
and take your pearls away?
? So fill your cup
and lift it up?
-? And clink, here's how?
- Do you eat fish heads?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have a drink
on it now?
Are you immune to yellow fever?
Bubonic plague!
Monsoons!
Locusts!
The screaming abdabs!
Oh, the shame of it all!
Do that again, me buckle,
and you won't be going anywhere.
Clancy, two more.
Have a drink, sir.
All the very best.
Are you all right, lad?
There's nothing broken, I hope.
I think we best be going
to the hotel
to have the house doctor take
a look at you.
Excuse me, John.
Aah!
Oh! Oh!
Oh!
Ooh!
All right, I say!
Quiet!
All right, now.
Who started all this?
Well, come on.
Come on.
Somebody speak up,
or I'll jail the lot of youse
just as sure
as my name's Flanagan.
Seems a shame to punish men for
defending their mother country.
What's that?
I wasn't a part of it meself,
you understand.
But I did see it all
from first to last.
And?
Well, it all started
when the young gentleman there
expressed the opinion
that all Irishmen were pigs.
And the Emerald Isle
the proper sty for them.
Oh, he did, did he?
Huh?
He did indeed.
I see.
All right, you two.
Bring young Mr. Fancy Dan along.
Hey!
And I'll thank you
to come along, too, sir.
The captain will be delighted
to hear what you told me.
I consider it me duty, Sergeant.
All right.
Bring him along.
Have no fear, lad.
I'm looking out for you.
Good morning, Cordelia.
How is Cordy this morning?
Have you seen her?
I had a cold shower
and a good, brisk walk.
And now I'm hungry.
Thank you, my dear.
Yes, ma'am?
Yes, sir?
I think I'll start
with some orange juice.
Who are you?
I'm Deborah, sir.
Well.
Good morning, Deborah.
Good morning, sir.
I think after the orange juice
I'd like some cereal.
Yes, sir.
Pleasant-enough-looking girl,
isn't she?
Confound it, Cordelia.
You can't go on ignoring me
like this forever.
And that's how long it will be
before I respond
to such childish behavior.
What do you want from me?
Let's hear it.
Some kind of confession.
That's what you want, isn't it?
You're not going to get it.
I have nothing to confess.
Will that be hot
or cold cereal, sir?
Neither one, blast it!
I'm not hungry.
I will admit I have wondered
if Angie was the right man
for Cordy.
But she made her choice.
And I accepted it,
I think, gracefully.
I've just been myself,
that's all.
You've been yourself in spades.
Cordelia.
Where did you learn
that back-room expression?
You played into every
possible source of trouble
from the first.
Oh, there was trouble
to play into, I'll grant.
You didn't create it,
but how you took advantage.
I deny that.
Then let me put it this way.
Have you done one thing
to help this marriage?
I don't believe
that's my responsibility.
Isn't it, Anthony?
I know of nothing
I've done wrong.
Nothing.
You know it in your heart.
Or you wouldn't be so angry.
Good morning.
Good morning, Mother.
Good morning, Papa.
How about a jog
around the square?
Why, Cordy.
Or maybe a few rounds
in the gym?
Confound it, Cordy.
You can't come popping in here,
gay as a cricket.
Why not?
How should I be?
Cordy.
What are we going to do?
About what, Mother?
About your marriage.
It's been called off.
Don't you remember?
I'll be in the stable.
Cordy.
Cordy, wait.
I don't want to
talk about it, Papa.
I don't want to talk, either.
But that doesn't mean
I'm not going to.
There's nothing to talk about.
You never really approved
of Angie.
And you were right.
He's a baby.
A mama's boy.
He doesn't know
what life is all about.
He'll learn.
Maybe you'll learn together.
But you can't take his part now.
I'm not taking his part.
But I've got nothing
against that boy, Cordy.
I never did.
Except that I wanted you
to stay here.
That's the truth.
You try to make a good life
for yourself and your family.
And turns out to be too good.
So you can't resist
trying to hold on.
Whatever you decide to do,
Cordy, I'll back you up 100%.
But you decide.
On your own.
It's your life.
I'm finally giving it over
to you.
Where is he?
Good morning, Mrs. Duke.
If you know where he is,
please tell me.
I'll find out
in good time anyway.
Do you mean Angie?
Of course I mean Angier.
- Well, what's happened?
- He's disappeared.
Disappeared?
He wasn't in his hotel room
all night.
His bed has not been slept in.
Who knows what has happened
to him?
John!
Now, don't worry, Mrs. Duke.
We'll find him.
- John!
- You called, sir?
I yelled.
John, I thought I asked you
to watch out for Mr. Duke.
- I did.
- What happened to your eye?
He hit me, sir.
Angier?
When?
Last night at the jailhouse.
The jailhouse?
They'll release him as soon as
I withdraw the charges, ma'am.
Well, we'd better get down there
right away.
I'll hurry and get dressed.
Yes, Cordelia.
Mrs. Duke, why don't you wait
out here on the terrace?
John, bring the car
around front, will you?
We'll have this unfortunate
situation cleared up in no time.
Oh, dear.
I may faint.
On this floor?
Don't even think of it.
Mrs. Duke,
perhaps it'd be better
if you ladies waited here.
All right, Mr. Duke.
You can come out now.
I'd just as soon stay
right here.
Well, that's a pretty
silly attitude.
It isn't silly at all.
I'm afraid if I stand up
my head will fall off.
Did you ever try
a good Irish stout?
Come along.
Come along, Mr. Duke.
It's time to go now.
Why couldn't you let me out
last night when I wanted out?
Where was it you wanted to go
last night?
I had decided on China.
How do feel about China
this morning?
Terrible.
Sergeant,
would you give us a minute?
Oh, certainly.
Certainly.
Young man.
It's time you woke up
to your responsibilities.
I want you to get
this marriage over with.
And that honeymoon
in the Ozarks.
Then report back to your desk
in New York.
What?
You may think you want
other things for yourself.
You may have some dreams
of your own.
But you'll have to get over
all that.
The way other people do.
Well, you didn't get over it.
Well, there are darn few
like me.
Now, you listen here,
Mr. Know-it-all Biddle.
No one is gonna run my life
for me.
I've decided that much.
Hangover or no hangover.
Is that so?
Yes.
That is so.
All right, Mr. Duke.
The door's open.
Let's see you have a try
at running your own life.
Let's see how far you can go.
Hangover or no hangover.
Mr. Biddle.
I am going to ask Cordy
to elope with me.
- Today.
- Now, wait a minute.
And don't you try to stop me.
Let me tell you one thing.
If you ask Cordy to elope,
she won't.
Then I'll tell her.
Angier.
Morning, Mother.
Cordy.
You and I are going to elope.
Over my dead body!
Only if absolutely necessary,
Mother.
We'll stop by your house
and pick up your things.
No.
Why?
Because I think he talked you
into it.
Cordy, I love you,
and I want to marry you.
And he's got nothing to do
with that.
I'm not so sure about that.
Papa!
So long, everybody.
We'll write.
Angier, where are you going?
? You can here it humming,
see it coming?
? Feel it everywhere you go?
? It's tomorrow morning,
the future dawning?
? With a bright
and shining glow?
? It's a land
where golden chariots?
? Are molded out of dreams?
? It's Detroit?
? Detroit?
You know, there, for a minute,
he reminded me
of his grandfather.
Started the whole Duke thing.
If he's half the man
I think he is,
this won't be the end
of the whole Duke thing, either.
Did you hear that?
It's the floor, dear.
I never noticed it before.
This isn't a new house.
No.
No, it isn't.
I'm hungry.
Oh.
Poor dear.
You didn't have any breakfast,
did you?
I'll ring for John.
I don't need much.
What's that?
Hmm?
The clock, dear.
Oh.
A new one?
We've had it 20 years.
Oh.
You rang, ma'am?
Could we have some tea, please?
And there must be
some sandwiches left.
Oh, yes, ma'am.
Did everything turn out
all right down at the jailhouse?
Angie and Cordy are on their way
to Detroit.
Well.
That's grand news.
That's right.
We're very happy about it.
I'll take that, ma'am.
Thank you, John.
Shouldn't we telephone
the boys about the wedding?
Oh, they'll be in class.
That's right.
Better wait until this evening.
- It's been a long time...
- We should let Aunt Mary know.
- What was that, Cordelia?
- I was thinking.
Maybe we could do some traveling
now that the children are all...
That's a good idea.
I've always wanted to travel.
We can go to Detroit
and see Cordy and Angie.
Oh, Anthony.
Yeah.
? Let them go, let them go?
? Let them try their wings?
? Little birds were born
to fly?
? Not until they roam
can they miss their home?
? And it won't be long
till Christmas?
? When the branches are bare?
? The December air?
? Comes alive
with frost and pine?
? And they'll yearn to be?
? By the family tree?
? Oh, it won't be long
till Christmas?
? The years go by?
? And every night?
? You say, "Sweet dreams,
sleep tight"?
? Then comes the day
you're forced to say?
? "Don't forget to write"?
? There'll be holly
and popcorn?
? And mistletoe?
? There'll be songs
by fireglow?
? Oh, it won't be long
till Christmas?
? Let them go?
? It won't be long
till Christmas?
? Let them go?
Who would be dropping by
this afternoon?
I can't imagine.
Hardly anybody lives here
anymore.
The tea will be a moment.
Mrs. Worth's icing up
a gorgeous chocolate cake.
Come in, gentlemen.
Sir, is Mr. Biddle at home?
Yes.
Will you come this way, please?
There's some gentlemen
to see you, sir.
Well, look who's here.
- Mr. Biddle.
- Lieutenant.
- Good to see you.
Sir, a set of orders have been
received at our headquarters
concerning your future relations
with the Corps.
And we felt that these orders
warranted personal delivery.
I don't believe it.
Anthony, what is it?
When I tried to enlist,
they turned me down.
Said I was too old
for active service.
Anthony, for heaven's sake.
Cordelia, I've been awarded
a provisional captaincy
in the Marine Corps.
I'm ordered to report
to Parris Island.
- Congratulations, sir.
- Thank you.
Congratulations, Mr. Biddle.
- John!
- Yes, sir?
John, we're in the Marines.
- We are, sir?
- Yes.
Bring out some of that
good Madeira, will you?
You know, gentlemen,
there's something to which I've
been giving a lot of thought.
The French and the British have
been in this war for some time.
They must have perfected
close-combat techniques
which are more realistic
than ours.
I feel that we ought to send
someone over there
to observe and learn.
Anthony, I don't think
that somebody
who's been in the Marines
for less than five minutes
should be trying to decide
Corps policy.
He's sure to end up
running things, Mrs. Biddle.
He might as well start off
that way.
Oh, thank you, John.
You should've brought one
for yourself.
I'm not much at making speeches.
But I guess you know
how we all feel about this.
Mr. Biddle has landed.
And the Marines are
well in hand.
Right?
- Right!
? Well, well, well?
? "Let's have a drink on it,"
as me father used to say?
? When the truth
is nobly spoken?
? It's respect
you've got to pay?
? So fill your cup
and lift it up?
? And clink, here's how?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have a drink
on it now?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have a drink
on it now?
Excuse me, ma'am.
Well.
Congratulations, Captain Biddle.
Thank you, Cordelia.
- Where's Mr. Biddle?
- Step this way, gentlemen.
We rushed right over
as soon as we heard, Captain.
? Well, well, well,
"Let's have a drink on it"?
? As me father used to say?
? When the truth
is nobly spoken?
? It's respect
you've got to pay?
? So fill your cup
and lift it up?
? And clink, here's how?
? No shilly-shallying,
no dillydallying?
? Let's have a drink
on it now?
? No shilly-shallying...?
What on Earth is happening
here now?
I understand Mr. Biddle
is going off to war.
I'm glad to hear it.
Maybe we'll finally have
some peace around here.
? Fortuosity?
? That's me byword?
? Me twinkle-in-the-eye word?
? Sometimes castles fall
to the ground?
? But that's where
four-leaf clovers are found?
? Fortuosity?
? Lucky chances?
? Fortuitious little
happy happenstances?
? I don't worry
'cause everywhere I see?
? That every bit of life
is lit by fortuosity?
? Fortuosity?
? That's me own word?
? Me never-feel-alone word?
? Around the corner,
under a tree?
? Good fortune's waitin',
just wait and see?
? Fortuosity?
? Lucky chances?
? Fortuitious little
happy happenstances?
? I keep smilin'
'cause my philosophy?
? Is do your best
and leave the rest?
? To fortuosity?
? I keep smilin'
'cause my philosophy?
? Is do your best
and leave the rest?
? To fortuosity?