"While the Harvey system
neither demands nor expects...
"...the impossible from any employee,
it does insist upon honest...
"...excellent, hygienic, cleanly,
prompt and cheerful service at all times."
Yes, siree, Bob.
And he means every word of it.
You've been with him a long time.
I've been cooking in Harvey Houses
for the last 14 years.
You must be well-done by now.
Madame! You say your coffee is weak?
Give it to me.
I'll put it on the chair and let it rest awhile.
Just call me "Conscientious Connie,"
the queen of the waitresses!
I'm sorry, Miss Bliss.
That's all right, Ethel.
There's one thing you girls
have yet to learn:
A Harvey girl is more than a waitress.
Wherever a Harvey House appears,
civilization is not far behind.
You girls are the symbol and the promise
of the order that is to come.
The restaurant we're opening in Sandrock
is the first the town has ever had.
Its success depends upon
how you conduct yourselves.
Now, how about some lunch?
It's lovely. I'm hungry.
- Here, let me help you.
- Thank you.
Have you ever eaten
a Chillicothe sandwich, Deborah?
- Chillicothe? What's that?
- It's a secret recipe of my Aunt Melvina's.
Won her two blue ribbons
and three husbands.
- Try it to see if you like it.
- No, thanks. I'm full.
- Would you like to try it?
- Why, yes. Thank you very much.
I always wanted to taste
a Chillicothe sandwich.
Tastes just like chicken.
You have to try another
before you can tell the difference.
Thank you. I hope I'm not depriving you.
If General Custer had our provisions,
he'd still be standing.
I've wanted to meet you ever since
we got on the train at Kansas City.
My name is Susan Bradley. I'm from Ohio.
- We're Harvey girls.
- What's that, a college?
No. We're waitresses.
We're going to Sandrock
to open a restaurant.
Sandrock! That's where I'm going.
- Is that your home?
- No.
- Are you visiting?
- Going to work?
- Then why on earth are you going?
To get married.
- Does he live in Sandrock?
- Yes, he owns a big ranch there.
- What's his name?
- His name is H.H. Hartsey, Esquire.
Is he tall and handsome,
and does he have raven-black hair?
And flashing blue eyes?
I like brown eyes.
- His are brown.
- You said they were blue.
Well, they are. I mean, one of them is.
I mean...
Well, to tell you the truth,
I haven't met him yet.
- How did you catch him?
- I answered a matrimonial ad in the paper.
Well, really!
I once sent my picture
to a lonely hearts club...
...but it came back marked,
"We're not that lonely!"
Well, I think it's wonderful.
I think it's wonderful, too.
When I answered the ad, he wrote back.
Thank you very much.
- What wonderful curlicues.
- And commas after everything.
This is the first one.
- Would you like to hear a little of it?
- Yes, indeed. Please.
"There is a dream here, in this great land,
that not everybody sees.
"Mountains and sunlight,
and the cleanest wind in the world...
"...waiting for a man and a woman
with a little vision."
What was so wrong with Ohio?
There was nothing wrong with Ohio.
It was just so old-fashioned.
There were several men in that town
I could have married, I suppose.
Only, it's so smug and sure of itself
and so settled...
...that I wanted a chance
to do something different...
...to see something different,
a whole new world opening up.
And, after all, the Constitution guarantees
the pursuit of happiness...
...but it's up to me to do the pursuing.
So that's why I answered the ad,
and that's why I'm on this train.
I think you did the right thing.
- Would you like to see my wedding dress?
- Yes.
I must say, I admire your spirit.
Most girls would have come out here
and gotten married in a navy blue suit.
That must be Sandrock!
Mrs. H.H. Hartsey, Esquire.
Mighty nice looking sign
you're putting up there, Mr. Adams.
You being the manager of the place...
...I suppose you're optimistic enough
to think it's going to stay there.
There are a lot of them
around the country, Judge...
...and I haven't heard of any of them
failing to stay put.
It's a pity you'll be disillusioned so soon.
- Hi, Judge.
- Hi, boys.
- How are you, Judge?
- Good day, Judge.
Hello, John Henry.
Hey, Mike, where's the boss?
Right over there.
Trent, I want to talk to you.
There's a lady singing.
- That's a good number.
- Terry taught it to me.
- Good work, Terry.
- Thanks.
- It's really Em's voice that puts them over.
- My voice? He's so young.
Trent, I got to talk to you.
What is stopping you, Sam?
The lady's finished her song.
- Hey, boss.
- Yeah?
- Is he good for a drink?
- Has he had it?
- Yeah.
- He's good.
Now, look here, Trent,
I've wasted all the time I've got to waste.
Got a match?
Mighty nice looking place you got here.
Next year, we plan to put up lace curtains.
Not if you have to shut down, you won't.
Who's going to shut us down? You?
You know what I mean.
You can't laugh off the new Harvey outfit.
Have you ever seen a restaurant?
They serve food.
Next, the church will open up again.
Mark my words.
Are you boys admiring each other's eyes
or reading each other's epitaphs?
Em, the Judge is losing his grip.
He's afraid of a place that sells vittles.
Vittles and a pack of calf-faced girls.
Those girls can fill up a town
faster than law officers.
- You listen to the Judge, Ned.
- This is my business.
Let's get one thing straight:
We're not partners.
You run the town, I'll run the Alhambra.
You'll get your usual cut.
But not just as much.
He's right. Look what happened at Larrup.
The men married the waitresses faster
than they could replace them.
They did?
It's so quiet, you'd think it was
New England instead of New Mexico.
- Nice women can ruin a town, right?
- And how.
- The house will buy you a drink.
- That's a little better.
- Where's Trent?
- He's over there, at the bar.
Hey, Ned!
It's all due to you.
- How can I ever thank you?
- What?
- My bride's coming in on the noon train.
- You're married, Hartsey?
I ain't, but I will be.
She's come all the way out here
from Ohio to marry me.
And here's the fellow what's done it.
It was him. He writ the letters for me.
He courted her for me on paper.
Hartsey, maybe you'd better hightail it
to the desert.
- I'll meet her and send her back to Ohio.
- It's like a blind date for life.
You don't know what you're doing.
You can't tell by letters.
She probably weighs 200 pounds.
That's all right.
This calls for a celebration.
Hey, everybody.
Hartsey will be married this afternoon.
I'll treat to champagne.
Here's to H.H. Hartsey
and his rosy happiness...
...coming in on the Atchison, Topeka
and the Santa Fe.
Here she comes!
All aboard!
- Miss Bliss?
- Yes.
- I'm Jed Adams.
- How do you do?
- Welcome to Sandrock.
- Thank you.
I want you to meet Mr. Adams,
the Harvey House manager.
Miss Walters, Miss Johnson,
Miss Harper...
Why, you rambunctious coyote!
I'll teach you.
- Wait a minute, ma'am. I'm Mr. Hartsey.
- I don't care who you are.
But, ma'am, ain't you Miss Susan Bradley,
the lady that came out here to marry me?
That's Miss Susan Bradley back there.
If you ladies will please follow me.
We've been awaiting your arrival.
Really? That's very nice.
Who are they?
Ladies! Ladies!
How do, Miss Bradley?
Hello, Mr. Hartsey.
- Can I carry your bag, ma'am?
- My bag? Where?
I thought we was going down here to...
Yes, please, do. Thank you very much.
- Are you disappointed?
- Disappointed?
Well, I mean, you didn't expect
a mangy old buzzard like me, or did you?
Yes, I did. I mean,
I don't think you're a mangy old buzzard.
I mean, I...
You look like a very kind
and reasonable man.
Then you like me?
You mean you really like me?
I, of course, don't know you very well,
but you...
...certainly look to me
like a very kind and reasonable man.
Thank you, ma'am. I like you, too.
Thank you.
Of course, there's one thing I forgot.
I left it out of my letters.
I'm an awful housekeeper.
That's all right.
In these parts,
we live outside mostly, anyways.
- I'm a terrible cook.
- Don't let that worry you, ma'am.
Out here, we just put things
over a fire and take what happens.
Well, that's just fine, isn't it?
It's great. I can't wait for us
to be hitched up, can you?
Can't wait.
- I'm going to be the happiest man in town.
- I'm going to be the happiest girl.
Well, after all,
that's what I came out here for, isn't it?
Well, yes, ma'am.
Miss Bradley, I think you should know
something more about me.
I chew tobacco and I drink.
I'm a terrible drinker.
And I gamble.
Gambling, that's my downfall.
Well, Mr. Hartsey, you sound as if you...
Could it be possible
you don't want to marry me?
Wait, Miss Bradley. I want to marry you.
I want to marry you badly.
I want to marry you something awful,
but please, ma'am...
...please say no.
Mr. Hartsey, I think you're wonderful.
Of course, if you insist, I'll say no.
I sure do thank you, ma'am.
Well, anyway,
I thought your letters were beautiful.
Gosh, I didn't even write them letters.
They was written
by a fellow named Ned Trent.
Who's Ned Trent?
That was Ned's idea, all in the first place.
You know, I bet he thought
that'd be some kind of a funny joke like.
- A joke?
- Yes, ma'am.
You mean,
I've come 2,000 miles for a joke?
- Where will I find this Ned Trent?
- Well, he's right inside there, ma'am.
Miss Bradley, you can't go in there.
Pardon me, which one is Mr. Trent?
- The guy over there without the hat.
- Thank you.
- Mr. Trent. Mr. Trent.
- See me later, I'm busy.
Wait a minute.
- Mr. Trent!
- Go away, will you?
Not until I've talked to you.
If it's about a job,
grab a drink and I'll see you later.
- A drink?
- Open.
Call and raise.
- How many, Trent?
- Two cards.
How many?
Holding a kicker?
My grandfather always said that...
Hang your grandfather!
If he were alive,
it's more than likely he'd hang you.
Who are you?
What are you doing in this place?
I'm just somebody who doesn't like you,
Mr. Trent.
I don't know if you're a thief or a murderer,
but I know one thing: You're worse.
I never met, or read,
or heard of anyone lower than you are.
You're a yellow-dog, Mr. Trent. Good day.
- Who was that?
- I don't know...
...but I'm sure going to find out.
Hey, wait a minute!
What was that all about, miss?
"When the setting sun lowers
its mantle of gold...
"...over the valley that shall be our home..."
The letters! You're Hartsey's...
- But you couldn't be!
- Well, I am.
Susan Bradley.
Well, look,
take this and go on back to Ohio.
Nothing's happened...
...except that a nice girl
has had an interesting trip.
Oh, wouldn't you love it
if I went back to Ohio?
Me and the other nice girls
who came out here today!
Well, they won't.
Whatever you and the other cutthroats do,
we won't.
Listen to me. If anybody leaves here,
it'll be you and your kind.
Men who run gambling palaces
and send lying letters to girls...
...and sell a lot of liquor to drunkards.
Before we're finished with this town,
you'll swallow those letters you wrote...
...and yes, I hope you choke on them, too!
- Miss Bliss.
- Yes, Susan?
You've got yourself another Harvey girl.
Dining room to the left.
Lunch counter to the right.
Ample notice will be given
before the departure of the train.
- Hi, Goldust. When did you blow in?
- Just passing through.
You've got too much class
for these prairie dogs.
Come to the coast with me.
No dice, Goldust. Keep asking.
It's good for my morale.
- Going to have supper with me?
- As a matter of fact, I'm dining out.
- Harvey House?
- I'll stroll over and size up the competition.
Yours or mine?
What do you mean?
I'd still like to know
what was in those letters.
If I did, I'd probably know you
as well as you know me.
It's no mystery, Em.
Why do you go out alone
in the desert all the time?
- Who said I do?
- Everybody knows you do.
What have you got buried in that valley?
You wouldn't believe this, Em,
but I've got nothing in that valley.
It's nice to look at.
See you later.
- Your order, sir?
- I'll have a great big sirloin steak.
One steak.
- Welcome to the Harvey House.
- Thank you, Miss Bradley.
- How would you like your steak?
- Rare.
Rare. Potatoes?
- Just the steak.
If you can get it.
We're famous for our steaks, Mr. Trent.
We'll have your steak in a minute, sir.
Hey! What did she do that for?
I wasn't finished.
It's because of your manners.
In a place like this,
you don't blow on your soup.
You fan it with your hat.
One sirloin steak, rare.
- We ain't got it.
- What?
No roast beef or lamb chops...
...and not a single one
of those famous Harvey steaks.
- The meat's disappeared.
- And so has our manager.
I think I know what's happened.
- Anything could have happened.
- You think somebody stole all that?
I'm looking forward to the steak.
You shall have it, Mr. Trent.
Get out, you drunk!
Stick 'em up!
Come on. Stick 'em up, now!
Anybody that gets in my way...
...you're going to have to answer
for the consequences.
So, come on. Stick 'em up!
Watch out, men. Be careful!
I'd rather have Deadeye Dick
than a female with a gun in her hand!
Now, I'm from the Harvey House.
We got a lot of hungry people there
waiting to be served.
And I don't want to hurt anybody.
Honestly, I don't!
But we're famous for our steaks,
and I'm not going to let anybody stop me.
So, come on, get 'em up. Put 'em up!
That's right.
Now, you,
tell me where that meat is or I'll shoot.
What meat?
Lady, your meat's in there.
Come on, boys. Get your hands up!
Mr. Adams, are you all right?
John Henry, go there and untie Mr. Adams.
I need strong men to carry this meat.
- Right away.
- Pick up the trays. Come on.
Get it back to the Harvey.
You ought to be ashamed.
We have people to feed there.
Come on, hurry up.
- Let's get moving!
- Mr. Adams, will you take this?
- John Henry, get these down here.
- Yes, ma'am.
Come on. Hurry up. March.
Come on. Out.
Thank you very much.
I just want to thank you all.
My!
Did I do that?
I am sorry,
I didn't mean to let it go off again.
You've been very kind
and thank you all very much.
- Good night.
One steak, very rare.
Good night, Arabella.
Look at that little goose pimple,
all moon-eyed over a song.
I just came out for a breath of air.
- Deborah's romantic.
- It isn't that. It's just that I like music.
Imagine coming 2,000 miles
from everywhere to hear a song like that.
And from a saloon.
Why did you become a Harvey girl,
Deborah?
I thought it would be exciting.
What I really wanted to be...
...was a dancer.
But my family thought
it wasn't respectable.
A dancer?
- And you, Alma?
- I lived on a farm.
- Why did you leave it?
- I was hungry.
Well, here we are.
Yes, the three of us.
I don't know if we're the three musketeers
or the three blind mice.
The low-down, crawling worm.
Shooting at women!
Ladies, I'm afraid we can call that
the opening gun in the battle for Sandrock.
You can fight it without me.
I'm taking the first train out of here.
Girls! Please!
You'll not let this crude
theatrical demonstration frighten you.
We won't stay here
to get murdered in our beds.
I'm sure, when you calm down,
you'll change your mind and stay.
If I stayed, it wouldn't be because
I changed my mind, but because I lost it.
I'm leaving.
Girls...
...l'd hoped you'd have the courage
to see this through.
But if you insist upon leaving...
...that's a decision
which you'll have to make for yourselves.
Good afternoon, Judge.
So you're back? Still peddling religion?
Sandrock needs it a heap-sight more
than folks on the circuit.
We don't aim to have a church in Sandrock.
You've already got a church in Sandrock,
Judge.
All I aim to do is reopen it.
Listen, we agreed
you were going to stay out of this town.
You agreed. I didn't.
You can't scare me
the way you did those girls last night.
- Bullets are an old story to me.
- What's this about bullets, Sam?
- Mind your own business, Ned.
- I'll see you later.
There's always a gun popping off.
That's how it is. Boys will be boys.
They fired a bullet into the lamp
where the girls were sleeping.
That's what I mean.
No harm done,
and we got rid of four of them already.
Pretty good?
Reverend Claggett,
go ahead with the church.
Why, thanks, Mr. Trent.
Ned, the Reverend
doesn't have a sense of humor.
- I'm not joking. Go right ahead, Reverend.
- I will.
You go over to those girls right away
and tell them not to worry.
There'll be no more accidental bullets
in their lives.
Wait a minute, Ned.
We're in this together, aren't we?
But let's stick
to the Marquis of Queensberry rules.
We should lick a bunch of women
with our hands tied behind our backs.
That's the biggest mistake you ever made.
If they want a church to let off steam in
instead of the Alhambra...
...I guess the Alhambra can hold its own.
Now, go on over there and tell them.
Well, now, that's a promising idea.
I'm quite sentimental about flowers.
I was discussing it with Reverend Claggett.
Reverend?
I thought they'd closed the church.
Yes, but we aim to open it again real soon.
There are some people
who don't like the idea of a church here.
Mr. Trent, for instance.
They don't like having
you ladies here either...
...but we figure
to overcome their objections.
Yes, indeed, beautiful flowers.
A church, lovely young ladies like you.
This town is going to be
something to be proud of.
- May I?
- Surely.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
A man's apt to forget his manners
in a rough country like this.
- I'm Judge Purvis.
- How do you do?
I'm Miss Susan Bradley
and this is Miss Deborah Andrews.
- How do you do?
- It's nice to meet a man like you here.
The pleasure is mine.
I hope we'll see a lot of each other.
- Thank you.
- Thank you. Good day, Miss Andrews.
- Miss Bradley.
- Good day.
He's nice, isn't he?
Well, at least there's
one gentleman in Sandrock.
Now I know who fired that shot...
...l'm going to do something
about it right now.
Slumming, Miss Bradley?
- I was just looking for your employer.
- You've got your own backyard. Stay in it.
You certainly don't mind my coming over
to pay you a little call, do you?
In return for the call
you folks paid us last night?
What do you want out of Ned Trent?
Nothing.
I want to thank him for
all the hospitable things he's done for us.
- You're letting it go to your head.
- Letting what go to my head?
Listen, don't fool yourself.
Ned ain't doing this for you personally.
When he told Purvis to cut out the rough
stuff, it was no love message to you.
When he told Claggett
to open up the church...
...it doesn't mean
he'll put on a pair of white gloves...
...and cuddle up to you in the front pew.
If you meant anything,
he wouldn't have sent Judge to tell you.
Ned Trent can talk for himself.
But you don't mean anything to him, see?
He don't consider you worth fighting.
He'll give you your flowers and church.
You can sleep all you want at night.
But still he won't recognize you
the next time he looks at you.
You're in love with him.
Me in love with him?
Why, he don't even know I'm alive.
Him and his valley.
Valley? What valley?
He doesn't even know you're alive either.
- You're not very sure of yourself, are you?
- Listen, you little insignificant...
I may be little,
and I suppose I am insignificant...
...but I must be getting somewhere,
my friends and I...
...or a significant citizen like you
could never be so very, very worried.
'Morning.
You the new blacksmith?
We just opened up and I...
My name is Peters.
Most people call me Marty.
Well, my name's Maule,
but where I come from people call me Tex.
- Where do you come from, Tex?
- Massachusetts.
Take good care how you shoe this horse.
Last time, they done it all wrong,
and I didn't like it, see.
- Horse is like my own brother.
- There is a resemblance.
That is, I mean to say,
you can trust me, sir.
I'll shoe him like he was my own brother.
His shoes are about six and seven-eighths.
There's one up there.
I'll be back.
Chris! What's the matter?
Marty Peters was here. He left his horse...
Marty Peters!
The one that shot the last blacksmith?
Yeah. He seems to think a lot
of this horse and... He did what?
It's really only a rumor
based on circumstantial evidence.
- No eyewitnesses?
- A few...
...but nobody actually saw
the bullet leave the gun.
If you're going to shoe that horse,
you'd better get started.
Alma, I've a confession.
- I'm afraid of horses.
- That's all in your mind.
- Say to yourself, "I'm brave."
- I'm brave.
- "I'm determined."
- I'm determined.
- "I'm fearless."
- I'm fearless. I'm a liar.
Come ahead, Chris.
Show the horse you're not afraid of him.
Would you please sit down
and give me your foot?
That's not the way, silly.
See?
It's very simple.
All you have to do is take the pincers
and pry all the nails from the foot.
Then you take a rasp
and file the foot down.
Then you take a hot shoe, red-hot,
and burn his foot to a level.
Then he's ready for shoeing.
Place it on his foot
and drive six long nails into it.
I suppose I'll have to do it.
No.
Lose something, Miss Bradley?
Mr. Trent. Do you mind if I come down?
Thank you.
This country's not healthy for a woman,
Miss Bradley.
Why? Do you mean because I tripped?
That could happen back in Ohio.
But back in Ohio they'd find you.
It's certainly a nice view from out here.
- Is this where you usually come?
- Yes. Whenever I want to be alone.
I think that's a very good idea.
Getting off by yourself every so often.
It gives you a chance to think things out.
- What are you thinking out?
- Me?
I wanted to get a good look at a fellow...
...who'd run a saloon on one side
and help a church on the other.
You're a little bit mixed up.
I'm not helping any church.
My, your valley is beautiful, Mr. Trent.
Almost as beautiful as your letters.
I said I was sorry about the letters.
I'm not angry about that.
I've forgotten about it.
I know you had a reason.
You did it for a friend.
It was kind of like John Alden.
Alden?
Yes. Don't you know the story?
Well, it seems there was a man
in love with a girl.
Priscilla, her name was.
And he sent John Alden
to propose for him.
John Alden said he would.
It's a wonderful story.
Anyway, right after John Alden
finished proposing...
...Priscilla looked at him and said,
"Why don't you speak for yourself, John?"
Go on. How does it end?
I don't know. It's pretty silly.
I don't think you'd like it.
Why not?
I like all the things Longfellow wrote.
Miss Bradley,
do you mind if I ask you something?
Do you suppose if I wrote a letter,
a serious letter, that...
...some girl might be willing to marry me?
I suppose judging by me, Mr. Trent,
that she'd take you like that.
I don't know.
Sometimes you don't even have to write.
That's a lot of trouble.
Sometimes all you have to do is that.
Some girls are just a little harder to get
than others.
- Like girls from Ohio?
- Yes, Ohio will do. Yes.
Thanks for the story, Miss Bradley.
- You'd better get back to town.
- No, I think I'll stay here.
- It's not safe for a woman alone.
- Really, what could happen?
You could pitch off that cliff.
- We've got cliffs in Ohio.
- There are coyotes.
- What else?
- Not to mention a few million snakes.
We've got snakes in Ohio, too. What else?
You got that in Ohio, too?
Yes, we've got plenty of that in Ohio...
Here, here, what's the matter?
You all right?
Of course, I'm all right.
I bet you think
that's the first time I've ever been kissed.
Isn't it?
Big, strong man.
I bet you carry smelling salts
when you go out with a girl.
- Did you want some?
- No!
- It's been a lovely afternoon, Mr. Trent.
- I enjoyed it, too, Miss Bradley.
- And now we part.
- Right.
And you disappear back...
...into the gilt and glitter
of your charming establishment.
How many men do you think
would stay here without the Alhambra?
Sure the men drink and dance
in my place...
...and some of them lose their money...
...but at least they get something in return.
Fun, excitement...
...and a couple of hours of diversion.
And a headache and an empty pocketbook
the next morning.
I was just going to pick up my slippers,
and there it was.
- She might have been bitten.
- Or any of us.
I don't know why I ever came
to this horrible place, I'm leaving.
Me, too.
Strange. How could a snake
have gotten into that closet?
Is this your idea of fun, excitement,
and a little diversion, Mr. Trent?
I told you we're fighting fair, didn't I?
- You can't fight fair and take their side.
- I killed the snake.
It doesn't matter, anyone could've done it.
The men who put the snake in there
are still alive.
And you won't shoot them
because they're your customers.
I just killed one of your pets, Sam.
- I don't get it.
- Get this.
If anything else happens
to the Harvey girls, you'll answer to me.
- You joined up with the petticoats?
- I haven't joined anything.
All I'm saying to you is, lay off.
It's my turn. I'll get the next basket.
Hello.
Hello. I was just passing by
and heard your song.
Do you like it?
It's beautiful.
I heard you singing it the other night.
I hoped you were listening.
Deborah.
- I wondered what happened to you.
- I heard the music and...
Susan, this is Mr...
O'Halloran, miss. Terry O'Halloran.
I hope you don't think
there's anything wrong.
No. Of course,
I don't think there's anything wrong.
Let's get out of here.
Listen. Wait a minute.
My intentions are honorable.
Honestly, I mean, no fooling!
Miss Bradley.
I'll be along in just a moment.
Quite a run on Harvey girls
we're having this morning.
Was there another matrimonial ad
in some paper?
Look, miss, we hardly know each other,
so suppose we keep it that way.
Just a minute.
I hear you and the Harvey girls
are having a little party tonight.
It's a big party.
Don't you think
you should stick to dishwashing?
We're minding our own business.
Suppose you stick to your own profession.
Our profession is entertainment, see.
And we don't like competition.
Well, we're amateurs.
Don't tell me you're afraid of us?
Afraid of you?
- Who are you kidding?
- Come on.
- Let me at her.
My arm!
You're tearing my dress.
- Good evening.
Good evening.
- Won't you go in?
- Thank you.
Now, for the pièce de résistance!
Folks, we'll teach you a brand-new dance.
It's the first dance where a fellow
puts his arm around the lady's waist.
It's a brand-new dance
that's all the rage way back East...
...in Kansas City.
All right, girls,
line up and demonstrate the waltz.
That's very good, girls.
Now, get yourselves partners.
Come on, boys. Join in.
Let's all have a good time.
- Come on. Let's have a good time.
- I tell you, I can't do it, so help me, ma'am.
Anybody want our tickets?
I'll go, Miss Bliss.
- I'll take your tickets.
- It's our turn to go slumming.
Thank you.
All right, folks.
Step lively now, and everybody choose
your partners for the waltz.
Well, go ahead, ladies,
choose your partners.
I'll bet you're glad to see me, Bucky-boy.
See you later. I'm already took.
- Hello, mister. Dancing?
- Yes, ma'am. I'd be right...
I'm sure he'd like to,
but you see, he has a very bad leg.
Well, maybe some other time.
Well, Miss Cassidy, I ain't got no bad leg.
You have now.
- Now you're acting more like a man, Ned.
- I feel better myself.
Quite a little contest we're having.
Last year, if you didn't like somebody,
you settled it with your fists or a gun.
- Now we dance it out, don't we?
- We're doing all right, I'm proud of us.
- All right, girls, we don't belong here.
- Let's go where we do belong.
Any of you gentlemen like to join us?
- How about you, Sam?
- It would be a pleasure, Ned.
Any of you gentlemen
care for a little recreation?
Miss Bradley,
something wonderful has happened.
Look at that.
Do you realize what's going on?
That's mighty fine, Reverend Claggett.
- It's wonderful.
- Yes.
It's more than that.
On this night, the male population
of Sandrock, for the first time...
...turned down a wild time
in favor of a good time.
Did you lose something, Mr. Trent?
Yes. I lost a fight, Miss Bradley.
The gingham curtains
and the flower pots get the decision.
You mean you're giving up?
Not exactly.
There's a mining town, Flagstaff,
about 100 miles from here.
That's where Alhambra's planning to move.
When?
Tomorrow morning, the breakfast train.
Is that what you came up here to tell me?
Yes.
What do you expect me to say?
I don't know.
I guess I hoped you'd be glad.
It might make it easier for me to leave.
All right then, I'm glad.
I only wish you'd left a long time ago.
So do I.
Maybe it wouldn't have happened then.
- What?
- Meeting you.
Yes, that was bad, wasn't it?
Two people as far apart as we are.
Yes.
Now, for the first time in my life,
I've got things to remember.
I take it that you don't like memories,
Mr. Trent.
They don't pay off.
They keep you awake nights.
Will you be awake many nights, Ned?
Every night.
I'll be wondering if I should've stayed.
Well, you couldn't.
If you did, it wouldn't make any difference,
you'd be giving in to me.
A thing like this can't be one-sided.
We'd both have to give in.
Both of us together.
Where would that put us?
No place in this world...
...because it just can't be done.
Goodbye, Susan.
Can't leave you alone for a minute, can I?
Now, put out that fire.
- Sam, I won't let you do this.
- You're not? We'll see.
We're going to the Alhambra
to have a little talk.
Go ahead.
This way, ladies and gentlemen.
Temporary quarters across the street.
Ample notice will be given
before the departure of the train.
Right across the street.
Temporary quarters across the street.
Trust me, after this town,
Flagstaff will be a pleasure.
Do you want some sugar?
Em, I'll see you on the train.
All aboard!
- Where are you going, Ned?
- I don't know myself.
- Well, come on inside.
- Leave me alone. I've got to think.
You can think inside.
I'm sorry, Em...
...but I'm afraid my traveling days are over.
Divvy this up with the girls
and say goodbye to them for me.
All right. Stay in Sandrock.
And thanks.
Thanks for nothing.
Goodbye.
- What happened to Trent?
- I gave him his walking papers.
Em, do you mean what you're not saying?
Every word of it.
I'll buy San Francisco
and put it around your wrist like a bracelet.
I'll put it in your hair like a crown.
I've got a present for the girls
in the next car.
Well, greetings from the Atchison,
Topeka and the Santa Fe.
Hello.
I bet we're going 40 miles an hour.
We're getting further and further away
from Sandrock every second.
Yes, I guess so.
We should be in Flagstaff
in a couple of hours.
Are you planning to stop there by the way?
I'll stop there if he does.
He?
Who?
Ned Trent.
What are you going to do in Flagstaff,
wait on tables?
I don't know, but I will if he wants me to.
Look, would you accept an apology?
I'm afraid that maybe I was wrong.
I mean, you see,
I'm from a little town in Ohio.
I probably acted like a snob
about girls like you.
I mean,
what I thought girls like you were like.
And after all, it's only a matter of style,
isn't it?
I mean,
some people wear one kind of dress...
...other people wear another.
And this certainly is the barren...
...blistered end of creation out here.
I don't know.
Maybe it's good for the men
to have a little entertainment.
You mean you want to join us girls?
I'd like to try.
You'd do that for him?
Well, that's what he wants, isn't it?
- What?
- You're getting off this train.
- No, I'm going to Flagstaff.
- You are.
No, please, don't.
I don't want to get off.
I'll go where he goes.
- He's not on this train. Look.
- What's the matter?
Thank you, Em.
Goodbye, Susan.
Goodbye.