In a bungalow all covered with roses
I will settle down I vow.
That's why I'm looking at the world
through rose-coloured glasses...
There are those, I suppose,
think we're mad, Heaven knows.
The world has gone to rack and ruin.
What we think is chic, unique
and quite adorable
they think is odd and
Sodom- and Gomorrah-able.
But everything today
is thoroughly modern.
Check your personality.
Everything today makes yesterday slow.
Better face reality!
It's not insanity,
says Vanity Fair.
In fact, it's stylish to raise
your skirts and bob your hair.
In a rumble seat the world is so cosy
if the boy is kissable.
And that tango they wouldn't allow
now is quite permissible.
Goodbye, good-goody girl,
I'm changing and how!
So beat the drums,
'cause here comes
thoroughly modern Millie now.
Everything is thoroughly modern.
Bands are getting jazzier.
Everything today is starting to go.
Cars are getting snazzier.
Men say it's criminal
what women'll do.
What they're forgetting is
that this is 1922.
Have you seen the way they kiss
in the movies? Isn't it delectable?
Painting lips and pencil-lining your
brow now is quite respectable.
Goodbye good-goody girl,
I'm changing and how!
So beat the drums,
'cause here comes
thoroughly modern Millie now.
35 cents, please.
- A pen, please.
A pen?
- To write a check.
35 cents I said,
not 35 dollars.
Who writes a check for 35 cents?
Oh, I do.
You can get it from your desk clerk.
But I don't live here, as yet.
Look, a pen.
Lady, I got 7 kids and 1 in the oven.
I can't take a check.
The date?
- I can't take no check!
No check? But it's
from the Gotham National Bank.
I don't give a hoot...
- Can I help?
You got 35 cents cash?
American?
Yes, I think so.
- Thank you, Miss.
Yes, I do.
Here: 10, 20, 30... 5.
You did say 35?
- Yeah, yeah.
Ain't every day you meet a Vanderbilt
and a Rockefeller.
Thank you.
Oh, but my bags?
It's all right. We can manage.
I live here. - Oh, thank you.
Allow me.
It is a middle-class hotel, isn't it?
- Yes.
Perfect.
- My name is Millie Dillmount.
Perfect. I'm Miss Dorothy Brown
from California.
I do hope there's room for me.
Yes?
Dear me.
This is Mrs. Meers, our house mother.
- How do you do?
How do you do? I'm
Miss Dorothy Brown from California.
How do you do? And who are you?
Oh, you're Millie. - It's the new me.
Toss your cares and curls away.
What can we do for you, Dorothy?
Miss Dorothy. I'm looking for a room.
I have a nice one on the 12th floor.
On the 12th floor? - Yes.
Directly across the hall from you.
Ethel Peace just checked out.
- But she only just checked in.
She went back to Wyoming.
But why?
She has no one there.
Oh, just a restless girl.
Now if you'd register, Dorothy.
I mean, Miss Dorothy.
The mail just came in.
Always some for you, Millie.
Lonely lady?
One from Brother in Chicago, two from
Mother, one from Sister in Detroit.
Millie has such a big, warm family.
You have such a big,
warm family, Miss Dorothy?
I'm an orphan.
- Are you?
Sad to be all alone in the world.
Thank you.
Gung ho, dear.
Heavy on the starch!
Thank you, Millie.
How long have you lived here, Millie?
You look lived in.
About 3 months.
Yes, I'm getting quite hard.
I'm looking for life raw and real.
I'm going to be an actress.
An actress? How exciting.
- Yes, But I've got to live first.
You should do very well on stage.
Pictures, too.
Would you mind closing the doors
and pressing number 12? - Not at all.
Thank you.
It's broken. - No, just temperamental.
Try again.
Some showgirls used to practice
their routines in here.
Oh, I love it. In the Ritz elevator
all you do is go up and down.
Would you mind taking over?
Is today your day off?
You are working girls, aren't you?
Just a minute. Yes, I just put myself
through business school.
A stenog.
Tomorrow I start interviewing bosses.
- I thought the other way around.
I can type 40 words in a minute.
I'm in demand.
Besides, I'm going to marry my boss,
whoever he may be.
You're a modern.
- Thoroughly!
I must study you
if I'm going to be an actress.
The theatre is full
of ruthless women.
"Art reflects life."
That was in a speed test.
But it's true. Women today are free.
For the first time we're man's equal.
We can make a life for ourselves.
And I fully intend to.
- So do I.
Would you mind opening the door,
Miss Dorothy?
Something tells me
you're not poor.
Ask me no questions,
and I'll tell you no lies.
One thing I know for sure.
You've travelled a lot.
Miss Dorothy?
There's little else for an orphan
to do. - Here we are.
I'm just across the hall,
if you need anything.
There's a dance tonight.
Wanna go?
Perfect. Would you
introduce me to the gang?
They're pretty high-spirited.
- Poor people usually are.
Watch out for the boys.
They pinch.
Excuse me, please.
Don’t worry, the kids will soon
forget your dress is real lace.
Don’t be concerned.
I'm having the most interesting time.
10 cents, girls.
For decorations and refreshments.
I left my checkbook upstairs.
- I've got it. - Oh, Millie.
10, 20.
Dip in and get your money's worth.
Millie, Millie, this is him.
Terrif!
Oh, delish!
Good evening.
Can I help you?
- It couldn't hurt.
I mean, are you looking for someone?
- Not anymore.
He's fresh as paint.
- He's just full of apple sauce.
May I introduce myself? - It's just
a friendship dance. - Jimmy Smith.
Millie Dillmount, and this is Miss
Dorothy Brown. - Pleasure to meet you.
I was just passing the hotel
when I heard the snappy music.
You don't know anyone here?
- Sure, you. Dance?
I studied ballroom and tap,
but I'm not up on the latest dances.
I always make up my own anyway.
Dorothy. - Miss Dorothy.
Give me a name. - What for?
- Our new dance.
I never named a dance before. - What
did you have for dinner? - Franks.
Franks?
What else?
- Sauerkraut. - Sauerkraut?
No, what else?
Tapioca pudding.
Tapioca?
Join me in the tapioca? And...
Well, then.
Now what do I do?
- Slap, slap, slap, slap, slap.
That's too hard.
- Where are you going?
Everybody, tap, tap, tap, tap.
Tap, tap, tapioca. Everybody,
slap, slap, slap, slap,
slap, slap, slapioca.
If you got the dap, dap, dap, dap,
dappier flappers, flap, flappier.
Everyone is happier
when they do the tap tapioca...
when they do the flap flapioca...
A cup of punch, Miss Dorothy?
- Oh, yes, please.
Welcome to the Priscilla.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
- Yes.
They are clever, aren't they?
- Yes, aren't they?
Millie's a wonderful girl.
- Sweet.
A good friend, too.
First real friend I've ever had.
Sad to be all alone in the world.
My own recipe. Fruit.
Mrs. Meers, meet a terrif dancer
and a nice person, Jimmy Smith.
This is Mrs. Meers, our house mother.
- Pleasure to meet you.
Allow me. - Darn nice manners.
What a personality.
Care to dance, Mrs. Meers?
- Thank you. No.
I believe this one is mine.
And this is yours, Miss Dorothy.
Care to dance, Miss Dorothy?
- Oh, no thanks.
Go on, do it.
- I shan't break up a splendid team.
A darn nice party, Mrs. Meers.
- Please, go, enjoy yourselves.
You know the tapioca? - I believe not.
- It's the latest.
Well, I'm here to learn.
Pretend we've got a bowl.
We're gonna have some sport. Ha!
Add trumpled licks and a ragtime beat.
About a quart. Yeah!
Ya stir and stir with your knee,
adding a bump or two.
Ya heat it, mash it,
beat it, smash it,
if there's a lump or two.
Don’t let the temperature drop
too many degrees,
or you'll wind up with what is called
the frozen tapioca freeze.
Everybody...
tap, tap, tap, tap, tap, tap, tapioca.
Everybody, freeze!
Slap, slap,
slap, slap, slap, slap, slapioca.
Everybody, freeze!
Cinderella time?
- I'm afraid so.
I've got my employer's red roadster
outside. Care for a spin?
Sure.
I have to be back by 10:30.
- You betcha.
Look out!
I love driving on the wrong side.
Don’t you? - Terrif.
Take the wheel.
- I've never driven a car.
You never named a dance before.
The starter, the gas and the break.
- Yeah.
What other firsts ahead? Love?
Love? I see you're old-fashioned.
Okay?
Not too old-fashioned.
That's nice to hear,
but I know I could do better.
Jimmy, I'm going to marry my boss.
- When?
I don't know. I haven't got one yet.
I start looking for work tomorrow.
But I have plans, and I think
it only fair that you know.
Terribly fair.
I'm your equal. I'm going to meet
you men on your own terms,
cater to your craving for efficiency,
learn to talk sports, tell jokes,
smoke, drink and, if I have to,
I'll even kiss you back.
Love has nothing to do with it.
- I see.
We fought the war to end all wars.
Now's the time for fun,
especially for the new woman.
'Cause the old rules are out, and
they haven't made up new ones.
I never met a modern before.
- My beauty spot!
How am I doing?
- You're doing well.
What do you do for your employer?
What?
- I mean, what's your line of work?
I'm in steel equipment for offices.
Oh, paper clips like?
- Yeah. - I must get back.
Can I see you again?
That is, until you get engaged?
Oh, sure.
It's the 20th century.
I hope I'm up to it.
Mrs. Meers.
So late and still working?
Yes, very late.
Everybody should be in bed by now.
I have to do something here
with this spot on the carpeting.
A spot? - Yes.
- Where? - Here.
I can't see a thing.
What kind of cleaner is that?
Soy sauce.
- Soy sauce?
What do you know?
I must write Mama.
Do that.
Good night.
Soy sauce.
Have a good time? - Sure.
He had his employer's red roadster.
Oh, Millie. Machines like gloves
should be black or white.
Are you sweet on him?
Oh, no. I've no time for puppy love.
I start boss-hunting in the morning.
Right. Good night. - Good night.
- Good luck. - Thank you.
Oh, give them hell.
Soy sauce.
Flannery, Miss Flannery.
Director of female personnel.
I run a no-nonsense organization.
Is that rouge?
- Yes, ma'am.
Why did you call ahead to make sure
Mr. Graydon was single?
I have no more time to waste.
You look fast to me.
- 40 words a minute.
No nonsense, girl. Mr. Graydon's
door is at the end of the hall.
Thank you.
He means, "Come in."
Hi, there, Miss Dillmount.
Right on the old button!
That's swell, just swell!
"Punctuality,
the pride of princes."
Beautiful.
How's that? - Your beautiful
baseball trophy. I love baseball.
I won it for golf.
I love golf, too.
Swell game. Play much?
Golf's my hobby,
insurance my business.
You come highly recommended.
Bolt the door, take off your things.
Take a letter to...
to Mr. Harold Hudson.
You'll find his letter in the file
and an invoice
in the outer desk.
"Dear Mr. Hudson,
The shipment of floor wax
was rancid..."
Babyface,
you've got the cutest little
Babyface.
There is no other one
could take your place,
Babyface.
You sure have started something.
Babyface,
I'm up in heaven
when I'm in your fond embrace.
I didn't need a shove,
'cause I just fell in love
with your pretty Baby...
You've got the cutest little...
Swell.
Congratulations, Miss Dillmount.
You've made the team.
Miss Dorothy.
No luck today either?
No, Mrs. Meers.
The only thing producers want to do
with me is take liberties.
Sinful, but cheer up.
I've got something for you.
A California apple for you.
Thank you, Mrs. Meers.
It smells so fresh.
I'll bet it's juicy.
We had apple orchards.
Don’t look back.
Face it.
Don’t, Miss Dorothy!
You'll spoil your appetite. They're
going to set a doozy of a table.
Hello, Mrs. Meers. Did you forget
about the wedding night? I'm singing.
Mazaltov!
Groom, bride, mazaltov.
Drink to life,
it's wedding time.
drink a glass of wine.
Let us sing,
it is such a joy.
Let us dance,
we should be happy.
Play on, musicians,
for the parents-in-law...
This is Jewish.
...for the groom.
Play louder,
so we can't hear
the two mothers
crying bitter tears.
Drink to life
is what mazeltov means.
Make a circle
that turns and turns.
A happy person
has money, too.
Drink to life
for the entire world.
Dance everybody. Dance
for the groom and the bride.
Be happy people.
Dance...
Oh, I'm sorry.
Drink to life,
it's wedding time...
Mazeltov!
Mr. Graydon's office.
Who's calling, please?
Jimmy!
- Dillmount! - Hold on.
A telephone is business equipment.
Not a back fence to gossip over.
Yes, ma'am.
Hello.
- Are you sitting on his lap?
I've been here a week. Where were you?
On business.
- Oh, I wondered.
I spoke to my boss about
your paper clips. - Thanks.
Did you kiss him back yet?
- No.
Has he held your hand? - No.
- Got a pet name? - Yes.
What? - John.
- John? - John. - John?
That's not very romantic.
But it's modern.
Mr. Graydon is very business-like.
But he's not cold.
He's manly, but not gruff.
He calls me John, because I'm
so efficient. "Johnny on the spot."
I'm wearing a new dress, and...
- What time do you get off?
Half day Saturday.
- Like to go for an outing?
That sounds grand!
Lunch and dinner.
Ask Miss Dorothy to join us.
Miss Dorothy?
- She's still around?
Sure, I'll ask her.
- Pick you up at 12:45.
Fine. Jimmy, I'm still
going to marry my boss.
Over my dead body!
I guess his nickel was up.
John, write a memo to Splife.
The paper was not up to snuff.
Yes, sir. - Sorry luck. Not pleased.
Take it back.
Yes, sir. Got you!
You ought to try a pipe.
Separates the men from the boys.
Mr. Graydon, you're just a tease.
- Swell dress.
Oh, Jimmy!
I said,
the sky's the limit.
What a thrill!
My employer's. But he's out of town,
so I can use it whenever I want to.
I'll teach you to fly.
- You're razzing me.
Just another first.
We're facing a lot of 'em, aren't we?
Jimmy, look there!
Raspberry!
Holy mackerel.
Who was that?
Mrs. Van Hosmere, our hostess.
The outing's at her house.
We're flying over it now.
- Where?
That's a house?
I mean, somebody lives down there?
It's a mansion,
but she calls it a cottage.
My father used to be her gardener.
She's always been very good to me.
Miss Dorothy!
That house down there...
I can't hear...
- The party is down...
Oh, thank you.
That house down there...
Oh, look! Terrif!
A golf course. Mr. Trevor Graydon's
favourite. That's where we're going.
Baron Richter, those loop-the-loops
are affecting my inner ear.
Why, Baron Richter.
You're perfectly marvellous.
To think we were against you
in the late war.
There you go.
Down you go, little Miss Dorothy.
Welcome, welcome, everybody.
Welcome, everybody. Hello, Jimmy.
The grass needs cutting.
She thinks I'm the only one
who can trim the lawn like my father.
Do you promise to succumb
wholeheartedly to the merriment?
Why, Mrs. Van Hosmere is
glamorous and gay.
Muzzy, call me Muzzy.
You, too, Miss Dorothy.
My flying instructor, everybody does.
We're all very friendly here.
Jimmy, I am proud of you.
Two delightful young ladies. I had
no idea you had such a good eye.
I do hope you all
have the most marvellous time.
Anything you want and don't see,
you just ring.
Well, now, what have we here?
Corky, the ace of hearts!
Love is very, very near.
You mustn't believe what you see.
Muzzy's full of tricks.
Baron Richter, I'm going to need
popping soon again.
Sensational, Muzzy.
My dance instructor.
Gregory Huntley.
Oh, where'd you get that dress?
- I rang for it.
Gee whiz.
Great wealth is so classy.
Everything's so perfect.
It's just like in the movies.
Except for me. The very gates
of real society in a plaid dress.
What's wrong? - I feel unworthy.
- You look worthy. - But look at her.
She looks very worthy, too.
You know, Jimmy, you're a pip.
Everybody likes you.
If you take it in stride, so can I.
- Who's better than we are?
Only in America can a gardener's son
receive such spiffy treatment.
Jimmy.
Miss Tremaine, may I present...
- I've had the pleasure.
Millie Dillmount, Judith Tremaine.
How do you do?
I couldn’t help
overhearing your remark
about the gardener's son.
Jimmy's father had such a green thumb.
We hoped Jimmy
would take after him.
But there's been little evidence.
Good gardeners are hard to come by.
Perhaps he prefers paper clips.
- Perhaps.
That gross diamond ring of Muzzy's
took my breath away.
Not completely, Miss Tremaine.
No, not completely.
Bitch!
Miss Dorothy!
- I love you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
attention! Thank you.
I have persuaded my star pupil
that she's ripe,
after only 5 nights of study,
to make her singing debut tonight.
Okay, Muzzy.
She's miraculous.
My daddy was
a ragtime trombone player.
My mommy was
a ragtime cabareter.
They met one day at a tango tea.
There was a syncopated wedding,
and then came me.
Folks think the way I walk
is a fad.
But it's a birthday present
from my mommy and daddy.
I'm a jazz baby.
Little jazz baby, that's me.
There's something
in the tone of a saxophone
that makes me do a little wiggle
all my own.
I'm a jazz baby.
Full of jazz-bo harmony.
"Walk the Dog" and "Ball the Jack"
caused all the talk.
It's just a copy of the way
I naturally walk.
'Cause I'm a jazz baby.
Little jazz baby, that's me.
Rock to sleep
while the cradle went to and fro.
To and fro to the tune
of the tickle-toe.
Ever since I started to grow
love to hear the music playing,
see my dear old mommy swaying.
Razz-ma-tazz,
that's all I ever knew.
All day long
I would never get through.
Jazz-ma-tazz,
that's all I want to do.
So play me a little jazz...
Jazz...
Baby...
Full of jazz-bo harmony.
The wailing of the saxes
when those fellas go mad
cannot compare with what
I got from Mommy and Dad.
So hear this jazz baby...
Miraculous!
Little jazz baby, that's me.
Swell! Just swell!
Everything's swell!
And you're just
swell!
- Let's be kissy.
You like our place, do you?
- It's swell.
I can't wait to meet Mr. Van Hosmere.
- He went to his reward years ago.
You said "our place."
When I married Mr. Van Hosmere
he was a widower.
I came to all this
as the second Mrs. Van Hosmere,
and I felt like a frozen quill
in Queen Mary's behind.
But Mr. Van H. Just swiped me
on the butt and said,
"Lady van Hosmere, it's our cottage.
Not my cottage, not yours, but ours.
Don’t you ever forget it!"
Unfortunately, I enjoyed him but
for a brief but very ecstatic period.
Sad. - Yes, and Mr. Van H. Hated
sad stories.
He wanted our place to be filled
with good fun and good friends.
Despite the noble experiment
we have a sufficiency of gin.
So drink up, everyone.
You're all invited to spend the night.
We have plenty of extra PJs.
Myself I sleep in the altogether.
Muzzy,
you ought to be congratulated for
the enchanting grab-bag of people.
It's so amusing to rub shoulders
with all kinds.
And, darling, your ring!
How big is it?
About 2 quarts.
Raspberries! I've been waiting
all evening for someone to ask.
I thought it was real.
- It is real. I had it drilled.
The mascara has run
onto my brand-new dress from Paris!
Where? Don’t worry. I know
something that cleans it.
You can't see a thing.
Soy sauce!
She's coloured my Paris gown
with soy sauce.
Please, Miss Tremaine, I...
- You! You!
Inviting a stupid shop girl!
Miss Tremaine, if I could...
- Idiot!
Don’t you know anything?
Of course you don't!
I'll tell you
what's going on around here, you boob!
Miss Tremaine.
I will take care of dress.
No, I'm going home.
Tea will show you out.
I'm sorry.
I thought it would clean it.
Honest. Mrs. Meers swears by it.
Holy mackerel.
A dress from Paris, France...
Let's go home.
We have to spend the night.
It's ceiling zero in New York.
Oh dear!
Don’t worry. It's like a film complete
with a witch, Judith Tremaine.
You're laughing at me.
- No. - I don't blame you.
And like the films,
there's a smash-bang happy ending.
I'll become the paper clip king, and
I'll hire you for my stenog.
I'd be your boss, and you'd be
after me, and I'd say, "Sure,
okay, grand."
How can you be a paper clip king,
when you don't care a whit about work?
You haven't asked me about
Mr. Graydon's interest in paper clips.
You can't be happy-go-lucky all
the time. Make something of yourself.
You're not getting any younger.
Maybe you should try gardening.
- They don't have stenogs.
Be serious.
What's to become of you?
Do you really care?
- Of course.
I like you.
And I like you, by jingo!
You've gotta show
some get-up-and-go.
I'll bring our latest paper clips
to show your boss next week.
Don’t. - What's the matter?
- I don't know. I feel...
So do I, Millie. You've unlocked
a room in my heart.
Please, no.
- Millie.
Interesting.
While I'm thinking of it...
Supper in half an hour?
Hello, Millie.
Thank you, Juarez.
Sometimes I get the feeling
Juarez is going to bite me.
He's a dear butler. He's teaching me
Spanish and rope tricks and...
Moderns don't cry.
- No, of course not.
I must apologize for my guest.
Judith is a spoiled young lady.
Don’t let her upset you.
Muzzy, I'm so mixed up.
It's not only Miss Tremaine.
I am a working girl and a boob.
There's certainly nothing wrong
with being a working girl.
I was a working girl in a chorus,
but I wasn't a boob.
No, you married well,
and that's exactly my plan.
Jimmy told me your plans.
Love has nothing to do with it?
I'm a modern.
- You're a boob.
But you...
- You're not going to believe me.
When I met Mr. Van H., I had no idea
he was a multi-millionaire.
He was one of those darling daddies
hanging around the stage door.
I mean, he didn't even look
like a multi-millionaire.
And he drank beer.
Facts be known, I prefer beer.
He was a wonderful man.
Affection, that's what he had.
We became engaged, and he gave me
a great big old green-glass brooch.
I leant it to my girlfriend
so she could impress a new beau.
As fate would have it,
he turned out to be a jeweller.
And the green glass
turned out to be emeralds.
I truly prefer emeralds.
But I was upset.
I thought he had stolen it.
I begged him to take it back.
He just laughed and laughed.
Then he told me
he really was a multi-millionaire,
even if he didn't look like one,
and we became married.
While I truly do prefer emeralds,
we could've made it on green glass.
While I've been in the bleachers,
you've been a player on the big field.
If it's marriage you've got in mind,
love has everything to do with it.
Follow your heart.
No raspberries!
Jimmy, oh Jimmy.
Silly boy.
Gee, what a real swell guy.
Jimmy, oh Jimmy.
Oh, what joy.
He makes your troubles fly.
His glance has fireworks in it.
We kiss,
my heart does a whiz-bang,
flip-flop, heaven-for-a-minute.
Jimmy, oh Jimmy.
Don’t you know
what I can't quite confess?
So coax me, implore me,
I promise you won't bore me.
Jimmy, I might say yes...
So coax me, implore me,
I promise you won't bore me.
Jimmy, I might...
Jimmy!
Get in here, little Miss Dorothy.
Good morning.
Hello, everybody.
Goodbye, darling.
We missed you at breakfast.
- I was in the gym.
Loosening up.
Always searching.
Cruncher, please meet
Millie, Miss Dorothy, Jimmy.
He saves his breath
for the last round.
You're not to be strangers now.
The country club is giving
a "Poor Man's Party."
We all get to wear rags. It should be
worth it. Promise you'll come.
Thank you, but my weekends will be
taken up with Mr. Trevor Graydon,
my boss.
Perhaps we can motor down for golf.
He's very athletic,
most mature, in contrast to
the flighty boys one meets these days.
And the best-looking thing ever.
Yes, of course.
Okay, bye-bye, little Millie.
Promise you'll find your way back.
- Oh, Muzzy, you're so worthwhile.
She's been so stand-offish
this morning.
Could be she has a hangover.
The bathtub-ring was still on that gin.
Goodbye, Mr. Smith.
It was an experience.
I'll call you.
Hey, Millie! Millie!
Millie?
Are you feeling quite well?
- Quite.
I thought your tummy was upset.
- The tummy isn't upset.
Good.
Something you'd like to tell me?
No, nothing on my conscience.
Perhaps there's something
you'd like to tell me.
Well, Millie, I... No, not now.
- Yes, go on.
Well, I am terribly upset
about my career.
Your career?
Yes, the world of the stage
just doesn't seem to want me.
They don't know the real you.
Cut your hair.
Let them see
how truly abandon you are.
Cut my hair?
I don't understand.
Oh, I couldn't...
People can't find you under the curls.
Good night. - But I...
Good night.
What? What is it?
- In my room...
Mrs. Meers!
Asleep in my room,
on my bed!
She works a very long day,
poor dear.
Well, good night.
Millie?
What am I going to do?
Oh dear.
Could I spend the night with you?
It'll give us a chance to talk.
If we're going to save our
relationship, we need to talk.
Have I done something terrible to you?
Please tell me.
A girlfriend is very precious to me.
I don't want to lose you.
Oh no, you haven't done
anything terrible to me.
After all, I have my plans and...
I'm sorry.
Your friendship is precious to me,
too. You can spend the night.
Thank you.
But there'll be no more talk.
I'm not my brother's keeper, am I?
You can have the bed.
No!
- I insist. To make up
for my lack of gypsy spirit.
You can't take the small town
out of the girl.
Most irregular. I don't care
how middle-class a place it is.
I really must callous up.
Starting tomorrow, I am going
to be unspeakably fatal.
Mr. Graydon's office. Jimmy, you are
always interrupting my life. Stop it!
What did I do? - I have work to do,
and I presume you do, too.
Do it and leave me alone.
A day's work for a day's wage.
I didn't ask him to call.
I don't want him to call.
Good. Forget the boys.
Get yourself a canary.
Forget the boys.
Get yourself a man.
Do you have a mo?
- A what?
A moment?
I would love to get a man's opinion
about Rudolph Valentino.
In "The Sheik" he takes Agnes Ayres
by brute force.
And she enjoys it.
She enjoys it a lot.
What is your opinion
of brute force?
I'm not for it.
Not at all.
Many women are unsettled.
Now they are disillusioned.
They are in for truth.
Give 'em a young man they can trust.
Tom Sawyer at 20.
I never read Tom Sawyer.
Was he... sexy?
He was only 12.
- When you've got, you've got it.
John!
- Yes, sir.
Take you to lunch?
- Mr. Smith!
You are not going to take me
again ever, anywhere.
What did I do? What's wrong?
At least explain yourself.
Not on company time.
- What...
What lovely elbows you've got,
Miss Flannery.
From my mother's side of the family.
- Really?
The Bath girls were known
for their elbows.
Out!
Seems I'm leaving.
Bye, Millie. Ouch.
John, be a swell scout. Ring up
my club. A handball court for 6:15.
Yes, 6:15. - It'll work up a good
sweat. Edgy in the gut, you know.
Edgy in the gut.
You want a pen?
- Yes, of course. To write a check.
Lady, it ain't that much.
How much?
- 25. - Thank you, Millie.
Oh, sweet mystery of life,
at last I've found thee.
Oh, I know
it's just the secret of it all.
...22, 23, 24, 25.
All the longing, seeking,
striving, waiting, yearning,
the burning hopes, the joy
and idle tears that fall...
Did I forget something?
This is my friend, Miss Dorothy Brown,
from the hotel.
We were on our way to the Beauty Spot.
Miss Dorothy’s going to have
her hair bobbed.
Bobbed? With your beauty?
Mr. Graydon. Behave.
I bet you could make
the moon and the stars behave.
Miss Dorothy’s an actress.
The way the theatre’s so rotten...
You wouldn't rob some lucky stiff
of playing with those adorable curls.
I just thought...
- Chuck it, John!
He calls me John...
- John, we're taking Miss Dorothy out.
And talk her out
of doing mankind such a disservice.
Miss Dorothy, may I take the liberty
of asking you to dine?
You may.
- But what about your sweat?
Cancel it.
Swell, just swell.
We'll have dinner, and afterwards
a bit of vaudeville.
That is, if the comics aren't on.
Their humour can get too ribald.
I hate for you to cancel your plans
with your gut so edgy.
On the other hand,
it would certainly be fun.
Perfect. Although I'd feel more
comfortable in a suitable frock.
We'll be gilding the lily.
But we'll stop by your hotel.
Taxi!
Terrif! My first date
with Trevor Graydon. Come on.
Oh, hi there.
Goodness!
Ah, sweet mystery of life,
at last I've found thee.
Oh, I know
it's just the secret of it all.
Oh gosh! Bravo!
Raspberry!
My God, it's Muzzy!
What a full life she leads!
Oh, do it again!
I may say, "No, no, no, no, no."
But do it again.
My lips just ache to have you take
the kiss that's waiting for you.
You know if you do
you won't regret it.
Come and
get it.
Oh, no one is there.
I may cry, "Oh, oh, oh..."
But no one will hear.
My mommy'd scold me,
'cause she told me
it was naughty, but then,
oh, do it again!
Please, do it again!
Searching, searching, searching!
Oh, Muzzy, we just loved you
and the human yo-yo's.
Aren't they the sweetest people?
I was sure the Baron had done
permanent damage to my inner ear.
The Bernini Brothers
have worked miracles.
You were swell, just swell.
- Perfect.
I'm learning.
Hadn't we best be on our way?
Muzzy has to do her practicing.
I'm through for tonight.
You can take just so much yo-yo.
We really must be going.
Tomorrow's a working day.
Good night, Muzzy.
Swell, just swell.
Yes.
- Oh, Millie.
Would you mind assisting me
with these little hooks?
Surely. I'll be right with you kids.
He's divine.
- Thank you.
I'm falling in love with him
like you said was so important.
I had no idea
they were such good friends.
Oh no, they only just met.
Such a baby!
It was his turn to undo me.
That Miss Dorothy!
Great Scot! That Miss Dorothy!
Pretty as a peach
and skin to beat the band.
Perfect little pippin.
- Perfect.
What a dandy little bundle
for a fella to cuddle.
Dandy.
Imagine all that sweetness
in your arms?
I'll type up this survey report.
Original in five?
Don’t forget the dinner reservation
at the Plaza.
Candle-nook room,
quiet corner-table for two.
I think Miss Dorothy’s for the Plaza.
And John... flowers.
There's a florist
just around the corner.
That's using the old bean, John.
Roses... pink... plump...
long-stemmed...
two dozen...
in a vase.
Poor butterfly...
'neath the blossoms waiting.
for she loved him so.
Plaza Hotel, please.
Candlenook room.
The moments pass into hours.
The hours pass into years.
Mr. Trevor Graydon would like
a quiet corner table for two.
Tonight, 7:30.
Thank you.
And as she smiles through her tears,
she murmurs low,
"The moon and I
know that he be faithful.
I know he'll come to me
by and by."
Flowerbox, please.
"But if he don't come back,
Then I'll never sigh or cry."
Flowerbox? Mr. Trevor Graydon
would like some roses.
2 dozen, long-stemmed, pink.
On the fat side.
I just must die,
poor butterfly.
I run a no-nonsense organization!
I'll step the law on you.
This is not a hayloft!
Besides, she never wants to see you
again. Youth today! Going to hell!
Never wants to see me again.
Banana oil!
Oh, honestly!
Sorry to bother you, but...
What is it you want?
- I'm looking for Millie Dillmount.
She's on the 20th floor.
Oh, thank you!
...14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20.
Judith Tremaine,
fancy meeting you here!
Jimmy, you crazy kid!
Get in here!
Oh, wait! Wait!
It's stuck!
Push!
1, 2, 3...
Millie?
Millie? You crazy kid!
I fell out.
- Hang on!
Stop!
Oh, there you are, Millie. Good.
Just another first.
Come on, Millie.
Hand over hand.
You're a whiz at it.
Gently now.
I have you.
You're home.
Thank you! Thank you!
Miss Flannery.
Yes?
- Excuse me.
Old elbow said you never wanted
to see me again.
Well, I did say that.
But I am glad to see you.
I was feeling awfully blue.
You're a strange bird.
You look different.
- I lost my glasses.
You have nice eyes.
- Catch 'em by candlelight.
Have dinner with me.
Alright, but Dutch treat
at the automat.
I'm leaving my job.
Mr. Graydon isn't available anymore.
Oh, corky!
He's lost his heart
to a friend of ours.
Miss Dorothy?
- How'd you guess?
Who else do we both know? Muzzy?
- Don’t blame Miss Dorothy.
I really don't.
Mr. Graydon neither.
Love swamped them. We're too young
to live a life of hate.
You're the one who should be
on the stage. You're good.
You don't seem to care.
- I know.
You fickle Freddy.
Thank you!
- You're welcome.
John!
Your ex-lover.
- Coming, Mr. Graydon.
I'll pick you up at seven, and we
aren't dining Dutch treat.
I'm taking you to Park Avenue for
the best-fed picnic ever.
Nothing but the best for my date!
Seven then?
- Seven.
Bye.
- Bye.
Butterfly boy!
I may never go back
to elevators again.
The lights have gone out of you.
- You pulled a switch.
Don’t you think washing dishes at
the most expensive restaurant a lark?
We should have gone to the automat.
It's stealing when a person
doesn't spend accordingly.
With his girlfriends
a person should be honest.
You're a dabbler, playing footloose
and fancy free to everyone,
living moment to moment, never getting
involved, throwing yourself away,
and you could be something...
- Alright, call Miss Dorothy
and ask her to bail us out.
- I'll do no such thing!
She's got the money. She's very rich.
- A fortune hunter to boot!
I'll pay it back.
- In paper clips?
I'm going to call her.
You're not having a lark.
Got a nickel?
- No!
The coffee klatsch
is running out of cups.
I want you to take 'em that tray.
Now, snappy! Hop, hop, hop!
Good evening,
you needed cups?
Over there, honey.
Mr. Graydon, I thought
you were at the Candlenook Room.
She stood me up.
I went to the hotel. The lady at
the desk said she'd checked out.
That's it.
No note, no forwarding address.
Nothing.
John, where is she?
I don't know.
How very strange!
I'll get you some more coffee.
Strong spirits!
- Not strong enough.
Just stop this. You'll upset
that lovely system of yours.
Come meet Jimmy.
Perhaps he can figure it out.
Dear Miss Dorothy! Why should she
slip away like that?
Come on.
Dorothy wouldn't leave
without telling anyone her plans.
I spoke to her this afternoon.
- So did I.
Damn. I'm sorry, Millie.
But something's up.
You suspect foul play?
- I don't know.
Could you come up with a jack?
- Good as done.
I wanna search her room. Mrs. Meers
isn't telling the whole story. C'mon.
You made it.
- I'm rarely a 2nd-story man.
I'd best call the police in on this.
Miss Brown certainly would have left
a thank-you note for the flowers.
True. I wasn't at the desk
at the time she left.
Let me check once again.
Excuse me.
I'm sure you've searched thoroughly,
and I...
No, no,
the young clerk is so careless.
The letter could be anywhere.
No one takes pride in their work.
Her checkbook.
She can't be far.
And all her clothes.
She checked out without saying a word?
A girl doesn't do that.
Ethel Peace did,
and Fanny did.
Another girl
when I first moved in.
Jimmy, all of them were here
one day and gone the next.
Without a word to anyone...
Except Mrs. Meers.
Mrs. Meers! - Oh drat! Graydon was
supposed to keep her occupied.
Quick, under the bed.
Another first.
Something fearful is happening.
The roses are doped.
The laundry men
have been following Miss Dorothy.
Remember when you met us?
The laundry truck was up the street.
I'm afraid I only saw Dorothy.
The Chinese work for Mrs. Meers.
She's into something big.
What do all the missing girls
have in common? Money?
Ethel Peace didn't have anything, no
family, no friends. Neither did Fanny.
I've forgotten about what's-her-name.
She was all alone, poor thing.
Mrs. Meers said it to Miss Dorothy
when she found out she was an orphan.
What? - "Sad
to be all alone in the world."
Sad for the victim, but convenient
for a vampire like Mrs. Meers.
You think that...
- I do.
You don't mean...
- I'm afraid.
By now she could...
- Yes.
Yes, Millie, true but cruel.
If a girl is all alone and checks out,
who's to question her fate?
But Miss Dorothy’s not alone.
She has us.
That'll be 20, Miss.
- 20? - Cents, money.
Oh, 20.
Another Rockefeller.
What is it with you dames?
Well I seem to have forgotten
my purse.
But well...
- Invest it for me. - Alright.
John, snap to.
Let's get organized.
- Yes, sir.
Any mail for me?
It's too early for mail.
You know that.
Hello, I'm Millie Dillmount.
I'm Mary James. I'm new here.
I hope we'll be friends.
So do I.
I don't know a soul in New York.
I don't know a soul anywhere.
Except at the orphanage.
Oh, sad
to be all alone in the world.
12th floor, dear.
- I'll show you the way.
Pity!
Well, thank you. I'll see you.
- Yes, alright.
Millie?
Oh, isn't Miss Dorothy here?
No, I'm sorry. She's moved.
- Gee, that's too bad.
I wanted to show her
how it turned out.
Apparently just splendid.
- Not bad.
Not bad at all.
- I thought they were fine,
but Dickie likes jazz babies
with fronts.
As soon as that clot proposes,
out comes the cotton.
See you in the shower.
Millie?
Is everything all right?
- Yes, thank you, Mrs. Meers.
This is for you.
I made them up for all you girls.
I can't wait to get acquainted,
not having folks or friends.
Of course.
Now everything seems to be in order.
Envelopes, stationery...
There's a lovely pen
in the drawer, too.
If there's anything else you need
just let me know.
I'll leave now, dear.
So you can relax.
Hey, Graydon.
He's a healthy young animal,
but he has the instincts of
a gentleman. I thought he'd ask me,
but he says, "I'll take a kiss."
I say, "Take a kiss,
and lose a lip."
So he got fresh and lost a lip.
I said, "See you in church"
and turned on the lights.
See you later.
- Yes, bye.
Hey, Zelda.
I got some lips last night.
Hey, take a look at Miss America.
You like it?
I love you, too, you funny nut.
Jimmy?
Jimmy, you're not pretending.
Mr. Graydon!
Jimmy! Come on! Come on!
She's not much, but a little dark
corner on the late, late shift.
Mr. Graydon,
Jimmy's in the laundry basket.
The laundry men.
Mr. Graydon!
I must speak to the Buddha.
Mrs. Meers.
Act like nothing happened.
Don’t look now.
You see that laundry truck?
Follow it.
Mr. Graydon,
you're letting it get away.
Mr. Graydon! ...Oh, Jimmy!
Buddha? Meers here.
In front of the hotel, a dark man
in a red roadster. Remove him.
No!
Now.
That's the starter.
That's the gas.
There's the break.
I hope.
Stop!
Stop! Millie!
Taxi! Stop!
Taxi!
Just another first.
I... beg your pardon. I'm looking
for a young man wearing a dress.
Jimmy!
Jimmy?
Oh, Jimmy, darling.
Jimmy, wake up, dear.
But I don't have a nickel.
Not even my checkbook.
Borrow? I believe you've
never been in a Chinese opium den.
Oh dear!
Dorothy!
- Miss Dorothy!
Help!
Somebody, please! Help!
Miss Dorothy!
- Help!
Jimmy!
Untie the others.
Hide until the police come.
I'm Millie Dillmount. Have you seen
2 Chinese and a girl?
A boy? A very tall girl? Miss Dorothy?
She's lovely with brown curls.
Yes, they're over there.
- Good. Help me untie the others!
Miss Dorothy!
Did they have their way with you?
Well, really! Millie!
My beauty spot!
Don’t tell me you weren't busy.
Where is he?
Come on!
Faster!
Hope he won't be an addict
with all that dope.
It didn't hurt Sleeping Beauty
or Snow White.
That way.
Put him in the rumble seat.
Trevor.
Front seat's taken.
Hey, money bags!
That's the gas...
No, forward, dear.
- I know.
Oh, it's Mrs. Meers.
Maybe she'd like a lift.
Get in!
After them!
Snap to! Let's get organized!
Aha, heading for Long Island
and their rich society friends.
The four-hundreds
could be missing a few.
My God, you two are dreary.
Your adventure sends a chill
over my heart.
To think of such ungentlemanly
behaviour in my darling New York.
Millie, I lift my glass
in humble tribute.
A miracle the way
you rebuffed those fatheads.
Everyone of them must die.
How do you thank a hero?
I saved you selfishly
for myself.
First that interfering
Dillmount girl!
Shall we join the others? Please.
Shall we join the others?
Good evening.
Raspberry.
Wonderful!
Perfect!
Me?
Please, don't think this frivolous.
Perfect!
Muzzy, honestly, you were...
My law instructors are arriving.
My rock.
Sad to be all alone in the world.
Oh, Jimmy, darling.
Get in here, Muzzy, you...
Muzzy, too?
Sure, you wanna join me?
And my sister and my stepmother.
Sister, stepmother?
- Though she's not old enough to be.
I've been blind.
- No, Jimmy is like his father.
He didn't look like a real
multi-millionaire either.
You're not in paper clips?
- That's not far from the truth.
The fortune was founded in steel.
Oh, I don't understand.
Judith Tremaine chased Jimmy, and
every fortune hunter chased Dorothy.
I sent the children out
into the real world
with high hopes they'd come back
with sweet partners. And they did.
Your father would be so proud of you.
Jimmy, off with the mask.
James van Hosmere, 1st Vice President
of Van Hosmere Worldwide Enterprises.
You do have nice eyes.
- Be my stenog?
I don't want to be your equal.
I want to be a woman,
a dandy little bundle to cuddle.
You think Miss Dorothy has curls?
You wait.
What's the final word, Tea?
I've been watching her most close.
I approve.
A good old-fashion girl.
Tea practically raised me.
So that does it. Almost.
What do you want
for a wedding present?
A checkbook.
Rich people can nickel
and dime me to death.
Swell.
- Just swell.
Oh, this is my...
what do you teach?
Like a squirrel,
storing the nuts of life.
Downloaded From http://subscene.com
thanks to www.AllSubs.org