Ha! A hundred for posture, zero for score.
That's okay, posture is all that matters.
I've got pictures of your poses
but none of your gutter balls.
What was that last ball?
A bowling ball.
I know that, idiot.
Oh, it was a UFO ball.
If that was a UFO ball,
then where are the aliens?
Hey Tempura, you're up.
Wow, you think you're so fly!
Ah, man.
Shit.
That gutter ball wasn't because of my head.
Come one, come all! Have a seat.
Whether you're here
for the show or for treatment
Dr. Bo's Clinic is the place to be.
Today is your lucky day
because I've got a brand-new show for you.
Have you ever been to
a clinic where you can watch a show?
No, right?
Shows makes people happy,
and happiness is a cure-all.
Is everybody ready?
Ready!
Okay.
What a bad time
for those kids to be late.
Hurry UP!
Get ready...
It's showtime!
Bo
Ye
Chinese
Medicine
Bo
Ye
Chinese
Medicine
Doctor Bo-Ye
How's your day?
Discounts today.
Doctor Bo-Ye
discounts today.
Discount today.
Bo bo bo bo bo bo bo
Ye
Get ready.
With my amazing martial arts skills
I can conquer the world.
Who do you think you are?
How dare you come here
and act so atrociously.
Yeh
It is written in the
Compendium of Materia Medica
that the snow lotus on TianShan
are very precious.
So is my brand, that's why they worship me.
Take out your money and buy my medicine.
Just like controlling a puppet
we manipulate every joint and limb.
Hey
The movements are based on my learning.
Using Southern Fist and Northern Leg,
I'll settle the quarrels outside this rooftop.
I'll hit all the pressure points on your body.
Eat the grape, not the skin. Without grapes,
I'll hit the spot to make you laugh non-stop.
Ha Ha Ha Ha Ha Ha Ha Ha Ha He
I'll hit the pressure point
to make you laugh non-stop.
Ha Ha Ha Ha Ha Ha Ha Ha Ha He
Dad, they're supposed to freeze at the end.
It's just a show. Now go.
How was the show today?
Great!
Those hooligans.
Hey! The newest medication is on sale today.
Seventy cents a pack.
Makes your woman a bombshell.
Makes your man...
What?
Hehe, a monster.
A monster in bed!
Who wants some? Anyone? Anyone?
I'll take ten.
Discriminating shoppers! This way, please.
Hey handsome, I'll take 10 packs.
Wanna join me for dinner?
Oh, sorry.
I don't work here, I'm just here to help.
Buy 10 and he'll join you for dinner.
Buy 20, and he'll spend the night.
No, no, just kidding!
Come pay at the cashier.
Over here, ma'am.
This way, please.
The Rooftop - A Jay Chou Film
Ready, go.
Hello, sister-in-law!
What the hell?
You know you like it.
Oh, come on.
She's your dream lover.
So we should say hi at least.
Aiyah, I'm going to starve to death.
Is dinner ready?
Hey, whose turn is it to get sweet potatoes?
Sweet potatoes?
Egg.
It's your turn, Egg.
Bullshit. Why me?
I don't wanna.
You look the most like a sweet potato.
Come on, let's go up.
You look like a sweet potato.
You're the vegetable.
OK, we're home.
Tempura and A-Lang, welcome home!
You're unzipped again.
Hey A-Lang, where have you been?
Off making money, where else?
Look at you two, so romantic.
You're back already?
Give me a theme song.
Hey Wax.
Aren't you fired, Choco?
Yeah.
Wanna touch my little sweet potato?
I'd rather eat the real thing.
Where's Sweet Potato Girl?
Inside.
Hurry, hurry, hurry
Hey, there's still some left.
Hey!
What are you doin', stealing my potatoes?
Rotten Egg,
how dare you steal my sweet potatoes!
How dare you!
You stole my sweet potatoes!
It was THEM!
Who is "them"? These are for dinner.
Hey, Sweet Potato Girl.
Tempura
I'm the one who was hungry
for sweet potatoes.
Oh.
It's okay, then.
You can have as many as you want.
Then one more for me.
Mind your own business, I didn't mean you.
Sorry, Tempura, I need to go back to work.
Okay, go do your work.
Hey, did you ever notice
that Sweet Potato Girl is kinda pretty
when she's not being mean?
Mirror, mirror on the wall
if someone was saying
mean things about you behind your back
what would you do?
I'd make them throw up their sweet potatoes.
I know how to be easygoing.
I know how to cook.
I know that I'm your type.
Who'd you hear that from?
I deliver goods and carry bricks.
I dodge the debt collectors.
Every day we're just fooling around.
Smear some soy sauce.
I can't afford the sweet potatoes.
Just keep fooling around.
Grandpa taught me not to be lazy.
You'll turn into a lazy burn.
Sit on the water tower and sew.
Pound the laundry
and work out those muscles.
Auntie told the sparrow that he's meaty.
Open the windows dry out the blankets.
The birds are singing do-do-do-do-re-mi.
The moonlight is beautiful.
The air is so fresh.
I'm hungry but satisfied.
Hoot
There is so much love around here.
If we laughed more, life would hurt less.
On this rooftop, we're closer to the sky.
When it rains, we can wash our hair.
We can even barbeque
right outside our house.
We don't need to watch any movies
because we are the story.
Yes, we are the story.
We can't afford to buy diamonds.
But we can always play mahjong.
But we played the wrong tile
because of our singing.
Ah, you're an idiot.
We don't have money, but we have friends.
We love to dream, but we won't bother you.
No matter how cruel the world is,
we won't complain.
Loneliness is always welcome
on this rooftop.
Why did you start dinner without me?
Well, you were busy singing.
Wax, hurry up, it's getting cold.
Wow, looks delicious! Dig in.
Jasmine
We have a new show at the clinic.
How about I take you to see it?
Oh, that would be nice.
I'll go with you.
Go with me, go with me!
Hey, mind your own business.
It's complicated down there in Galilee City.
Come on, everybody, eat up.
Here, have some of this.
Jasmine, look at him.
Alright now, eat up.
Aiyoh
Jasmine, Jasmine
You're such a great cook!
Why don't you open a restaurant in Galilee?
We can make some money that way.
Yeah, you should open a restaurant!
You all enjoy my cooking,
that's enough for me.
I don't know how to run a business.
I know how!
Whoa, the sweet potatoes
don't taste very sweet today.
Mirror, mirror on the wall.
Wait a second.
Oh, Jasmine, look at him.
All you do all day is
horse around.
That's why you're all single.
I have a boyfriend.
Who?
Someone in my dreams.
Wax
When are you going to bring a girlfriend home
and introduce her to us?
Hey, why don't you musicians
compose a song for us single men?
The same song as last time.
Hey look, you guys!
Dr. Bo's new car is so rad!
Wow, let's drive it to Tempura's party
and surprise him.
You can't go in your pajamas.
Pajamas? Are you nuts?
These are my Woodstock clothes.
It's the latest fashion for hippies.
All you need's a bandana, some music
and you can relax on the lawn.
Wow.
Show some respect for an artist.
Daddy, please.
Can I borrow your car?
So you've seen it?
Let me tell you
my car has got shiny rims
snowy white leather seats
shocks that are as flexible as a mattress.
Wow, more comfy than my bed!
So, can I borrow it?
Of course not.
Huh?
What's that sound?
Hey! Wait!
That's my new car!
Come back so I can kick your asses!
Hmmph
It's very nice to see you all today.
Thank you all for
collecting rent for Rango over the past year.
Rango's position
can't be filled by just anyone.
Only I can choose who can do this job.
Without all of you,
there'd be no City Housing Authority.
Without Rango, there'd be no city of Galilee.
Rango, come up and say a few words.
Gentlemen
In keeping with precedent,
I'd like to announce
the person who collected
the most rent last year.
It was Big Red again.
Big Red is in charge of the East District
and its 102 stores and 7 night clubs
as well as the toughest job,
the Dragon Gate Baths.
Okay everybody,
raise your glasses to Big Red.
Cheers
Range, I need to be on my way.
Okay, I won't keep you.
Okay.
Don't forget our golf game.
I'll be there.
Music
Rango
Everybody take your seats.
Big Red topped the charts this year.
But the payments
have dropped off in recent months.
Is there something wrong?
Tell me, I'll take care of it.
Did you hear what Rango said?
What have you been doing?
I'm sorry, Rango.
Your big brother's a bit of a hothead.
Just like me when I was young.
Get used to it.
Drink up, everybody.
Cheers, cheers.
In addition to Big Red
we also have a dark horse.
Tempura
Yes, Rango, sir.
You're new
and collect from small hawkers
in the South District
But you've been doing very well.
That's my job, boss.
Big Red,
assign him a street in the East District.
Give him the Dragon Gate Baths.
The Dragon Gate Baths?
I'm done with lunch.
Anyone who wants some leftovers,
be my guest.
Tempura, sit.
Cheers.
Oh
Shit
Oh, no
It's a new car.
Um... you go ahead without us.
What the hell? It's a new car.
What about your new car?
Hey, wait a second.
Wax
I'll fix the light, I'll fix it.
Big Red, he's a friend.
A friend of who?
You're not getting out?
We thought you had it under control.
I got stuck, I can't move.
It's time to eat.
Oh. Then let's go eat.
Hey, why are you here?
You skipped work?
No.
We wanted to show you Dr. Bo's new car,
but...
It's pretty cool, let's go.
Let me introduce you to Rango.
Rango, these are my brothers.
Say hello to Rango.
Hello, Rango.
Have a seat.
Get them something to drink.
No, let me get that.
Get a glass, and drink a toast to Rango.
Relax, relax
have some food and drinks.
Tempura,
you're okay with the Dragon Gate Baths?
No problem.
My bros and I will take care of it tomorrow.
Wax, I know you're the man.
Why don't we go now, it's not too late
otherwise Big Red will collect the rent.
Collect the rent?
We're not here to take a bath?
I skipped my shower last night for this.
Maybe we should go have some
egg drop soup.
Are you ready?
Did you see that badass attitude yesterday?
That's what you lack.
Yeah. Attitude.
Boys on the left.
Girls on the right.
We're not here to bathe
we're here to collect rent.
Collecting rent? Ha.
You guys look like you work out.
But there are a lot more
guys with muscles inside.
Deal with the guys inside first
and then we'll talk.
And put your clothes on. You'll catch a cold.
Put your clothes on.
For real?
Ha
Just you wait.
We'll see if you still wanna say "ha" after this.
Ha
Let's go.
Stay calm, stay calm.
Those are all temporary tattoos.
You want Mickey Mouse or Donald Duck?
We have some at home.
Come on, follow me
Follow you, follow you.
Then I want both Mickey and Donald.
We're here to collect rent.
Come on, pay UP!
What are you taking a bath for?
Maybe another day.
Good idea.
What do you mean another day?
Pay UP-
You wanna die?
You're afraid of him?
Yeah
How about a song before we die?
Ah
You want to fight me
but didn't you hear?
My fist is unstoppable.
I can do the splits.
My legs are firm and steady.
And now I'll reward you
with the famous Buddha Palm.
Wah-lih -lay-heng
A tiger tattoo on my left chest.
Tiger tiger
A dragon scar on my right arm.
Dragon dragon
You better hurry
and apologize to me right now.
I am sorry.
No way.
I'm the real thing.
Brush brush
I'll hit you so hard, you'll cry for your mama.
Ma-ma
Just 'cause you're big and strong
doesn't make you the boss.
A-Lang, let's go.
Leave him.
Say sorry.
You should have paid up in the first place.
So, listen.
My name's Tempura, the rent collector.
Remember me next time. Thank you.
I may not be a master like them
I may not be a master like them,
but look out.
I am a rose wrapped in thorns,
left on the side of the road.
Aiyah, just in time.
I told you to take the side exit.
You lost, pay up.
All right, I owe you one.
Did that hurt?
You heartless bastards.
Get up, get UP-
You're running away?
Hurry up, he's coming
Wax, he looks really hurt.
Shall we take him to Dr. Bo?
No, we don't want Dr. Bo to find out.
Slow down.
Ah, catch me if you can.
Oh! No! Stop!
Hey, listen. What's going on?
It's a domestic dispute, none of our business.
Let me go!
Cut, cut, cut
What are you doing?
We're shooting a film here!
Don't you see that camera?
Stop it, those are MY lines.
Who's the director, you or me?
Don't you see that camera?
Again from the top!
Really pisses me off.
Ha ha, it's a rare injury for you.
Let's capture the moment.
You just love acting tough
and playing it cool, don't you?
Wax
Hmm, what's that strange flavor?
I'll mix another one.
If I didn't teach you Kung-Fu
you'd be dead.
Hmmph.
Dad
Why didn't you ever teach me Kung-Fu?
Your legs are too short to kick anyone.
What about you?
Wow, so long.
Hold still.
Dr. Bo, I was the hero who saved the day.
Yeah, a hero in someone else's movie.
What movie?
We also saw what's-his-name.
Saw who?
Some stuntman.
Oh yeah, a stuntman.
Stuntman?
Ah, how I miss the old days.
Dr. Bo, were you a stuntman?
How else you think I learned Kung-fu?
Yeah
That's why Dr. Bo opened his clinic.
Stuntmen get hurt all the time.
And?
What's the clinic got to do with stuntmen?
Are you an idiot?
Of course the reason
my dad runs the clinic
is to make money.
The more injuries there are,
the bigger the profits.
Tofu, do you have to pay for treatment here?
Of course not.
Great, let me kick your ass.
No! Daddy!
Watch what you say.
You make me sound like a profiteer.
If it weren't for me
who'd take care of you?
Oh
Back in the day
so many actresses fancied me.
The other actors just hated me.
Hey, that's for Wax.
Then pour another.
All right.
Dr. Bo, you're not finished with me yet.
Just a minute, it won't kill you to wait.
Where was I?
Back in the day.
So many actors fell for me.
Actresses.
No, sorry.
Back in the day
So many
So many mosquitoes, why?
Back in the day
At nightfall, the stars shine.
Dear Rooftop residents,
at the end of a beautiful day
here's a song for you.
This is A-Lang, who's calling?
Idiot.
I'm looking for Jasmine.
You knocked six times.
That was five.
Oh, I see.
Are you trying to tell Jasmine
about how you met the girl
of your dreams today?
Idiot.
The sky darkens with the passing clouds.
The waves roll quietly in the soft wind.
Though you're far away,
you've made me so happy.
Forgive me, I'm using this camera to pretend
like I'm kissing you, though you're far away.
Through the camera's shutter,
you're my eternal love.
Good
Cut, cut, cut
William, great job. You're quite the actor.
Great job.
Come on over here.
William, great job.
Great job.
With you in the cast, this'll be a huge hit.
That's because you're a good director.
Aw, shucks. Yes I am.
So, should we call it a day?
Call it a day?
Yeah, let's call it a day.
Okay, one moment please.
Okay.
That's it for today, everybody.
Thank you William.
Thank you everybody, good job!
You're welcome.
It's all thanks to William.
William
William, here comes Starling.
Thank you, thank you William.
Thank you William.
You're very welcome.
Starling has great potential.
You'll be a star.
A star.
Say thank you to William.
Thank you.
Oh, by the way
I booked a lane at the bowling alley tonight.
Anyone interested in going?
Yeah, sure.
Would you like to go?
We love bowling.
I'll see you tonight, then.
Ok, let's go. Thank you William.
Your car is ready, William.
Of course we should go. Let's go.
Alright, that's about it.
Get up.
You know why you got beaten up?
My accounts aren't in order.
Have I
ever let you guys go hungry?
No
I hurt your body
but you hurt my trust.
I'm sorry, Rango.
Rango is actually a good person.
Come on in.
Get him fixed up.
Wax
Why don't you wait for me outside.
Ok
Hey, actually, wait a sec.
Why don't you come in with me?
Rango,
here's the rent from the Dragon Gate Baths.
Here. You can count it.
Jiang
What's the matter, Rango?
It's not enough?
It's more than enough.
More than enough?
But this is what Big Red's guys collected.
Well done.
Dinner's on me.
Thank you, Rango.
How's it going?
The street assigned to you isn't easy.
A few of the shops are being difficult.
Do you need more people to help?
Actually, Rango,
the Dragon Gate Baths was tough.
But it was alright thanks to my bro Wax.
He's a good fighter.
Wax.
Wax, come here.
Fighting isn't everything
I've got plenty of fighters.
I like people who are loyal.
Do you have a job?
Do you want to come work for me?
I work in a clinic.
If your people get hurt, send them to me
for medical treatment.
Watch your mouth.
Think it over.
There isn't much to think about, actually.
I don't like having a boss.
I like this kid.
You know why I like you?
You don't beat around the bush.
Thank you, Rango.
Okay, you can go now.
Let's go.
William, here's the thing.
You'd be smart to buy our cinema.
It's a real money maker.
Yes, William.
Every time we show your movies
the tickets sell out.
We've made a fortune.
Then why are you selling it?
William, listen to me, you're a huge star.
Wouldn't it be great
if you had your own movie theater?
Come on,now, gentlemen!
No more shop talk.
Drink up. Come on, let's have some fun.
Ha ha, come on.
William, what do you think,
We've got some fine ladies here, right?
Yes
Get up and dance!
Take good care of these two gentlemen.
Show them some dance moves.
Oh, it's Big Red!
William, here's a good friend of mine
that I want you to meet.
Perfect timing, have a seat.
Get them some drinks.
Come on in.
Take a seat.
William, our nightclub business depends
so much on Big Red's goodwill.
We never have any trouble.
If you encounter any trouble during the
filming, just call Big Red.
All you need is
Mike, thank you
The director and producers deal with that.
It's got nothing to do with actors.
And besides, we don't work with
people that have questionable backgrounds.
Watch your attitude.
Hey, relax, relax, relax.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
William, I think it's time to go.
Tomorrow morning
you're playing golf with the mayor.
Yes, William and the mayor are good friends,
You and the Mayor are friends?
I've also met with him several times.
Lee, let me get this.
Oh, wonderful, how nice.
Thank you, William.
William, thank you. Thank you.
I'll see you soon, William
Thank you, Bao, thank you.
Today is the day.
I'm gonna win that motorcycle
if it's the last thing I do.
Has anyone ever gotten a score of 300 here?
A-Lang, you can do it!
Wow, yes.
Ladies and gentlemen
a bowler in lane five
has gotten 11 strikes so far!
That's A-Lang!
He's gonna reach 300!
Everybody, come cheer him on.
If he gets it, he'll win a motorcycle!
You sure you got that right?
It's true!
It is.
Really!
300, 300
A-Lang, you can do it!
Mom, it's okay, I can walk.
No, Lang-Lang, you have a fever.
Just hold on a little longer
and we'll be at the doctor's.
Mom, one day I'll buy you a motorcycle
Oh no...
Yay!
Mom, now we can ride together!
Hey, there's a show, too.
Let's go over there and watch.
What the hell?
Who the hell is that freak?
I haven't come out in a very long time.
Actually, I've never come out here before.
Because no one has ever bowled 300.
I'm the boss and you have my word.
Bowl 300 and you get a motorcycle!
From all the colors of the rainbow
you can choose the one you like.
Mo Mo Mo Mo
Motorcycle
Mo Mo Mo Mo your mom.
Don't even think about running away.
I worked so hard to get 300!
Can people actually ride on those things?
Don't those look like people to you?
Alright, fine.
Well, it's better than nothing.
William,
it's been a while since you've taken us out.
Wait up, wait up, wait up!
Why don't we play billiards first?
Everyone plays for free tonight.
William
Have a seat over here
Have a seat.
Sit, sit ,sit
William, we're so happy to have you.
What just happened?
It was just a skit.
We were just acting.
Business is good, huh?
Maybe a bit too crowded, actually.
Shall I clear the place?
No, it's okay. Let's shoot some pool first.
Okay, then, have fun.
Let me take a shot.
You still owe me a motorcycle.
Hey! Pssst!
Remember me?
From that day?
Hush.
Get lost.
That must be her dad.
William, William
That's the guy who injured our stuntman.
That's him!
He's telling you not to take photos, okay?
Wax, watch this.
You want an autograph? Sorry, we're busy.
Okay? Okay what?
Hey, are you all right?
Okay, ready, camera
Action
Jump, jump!
Jump!
Cut, cut, cut
This is pissing me off.
Look, are you gonna jump or not?
Who found this guy? Huh?
Director, aren't you the one who found him?
Oh, right.
Keep rolling. Man I'm so pissed off.
What are you doing?
You afraid to jump?
Why'd you come if you're scared?
Another guy who just came to see the girl.
Can't blame you, we all wanna do her.
What the hell?
Don't stop, keep filming!
Go, go, go!
Yes
Come back here!
Aiyah
I said he was good, right?
Ha ha, wait for me, wait!
Okay
What a stuntman.
Hey Wax, lookin' good!
You guys are dead meat.
Hey, big guy.
Nice job with the fighting.
It was okay.
So I'm thinking,
let's have you do a couple more takes,
but with your mask a little higher.
Go ahead and cover your whole face.
Best not to see your face at all.
How'll they know it's me
if my face is covered?
You see that guy over there?
Why is he wearing the same clothes as me?
Because you're his stunt double.
What's going on inside your head?
What do you mean? Huh?
Hey, sorry.
Your friend said that you can do anything.
See, the thing is
you were supposed to jump from here.
But you looked scared.
No, I wasn't scared.
But your fighting was great.
Yeah.
You're gonna have to pay
for all the stuntmen you hurt.
You
No, no, forget about the bill.
Let's break for dinner.
Dinner time!
William, let's eat first.
So, can you do a few more takes for us?
Okay
Let me go eat first.
Okay.
Hey, dance or no?
Wait for the shrimp vendor's music.
Money is hard to make,
but for the ones we love
we go out to sea and work hard.
When was I out at sea?
Is that really what we're fighting for.
Money is hard to make,
Hard to make.
And we work so hard.
Work so hard.
Just to see the ones we love.
There is nothing we won't do...
Nothing we won't do
Hey, that's enough, guys.
Wax, are you still pissed?
Nah.
The three of you are nuts.
You know I almost drowned before.
Whose idea was it?
All right, Egg, admit it.
Come on, say you're sorry.
You want me to make egg drop soup?
Hey, it was your idea.
All right, stop fighting.
Well it couldn't have been me.
All right, all right, it was me.
It was just a joke.
Why are you so upset?
It was embarrassing.
Do I look like a stunt double?
You did really well.
Hello, sister-in-law.
Try saying that again.
Why do you always have to embarrass me?
It wasn't embarrassing.
You did Well.
Did you see that?
These are my friends.
You saw them the other day.
They're a pack of idiots, ha ha.
Who's an idiot?
They don't look like idiots.
Of course we don't look like idiots.
Yeah.
You guys are funny.
We're a lot of fun, too.
We're going bowling tomorrow.
Wanna join us?
Oh, I have a recording session tomorrow.
A recording session?
Oh, a recording!
Yeah, we all like music too.
Where's the recording session?
Uh-
Hey, relax.
We're nice guys.
It's the recording studio near the traffic circle.
Li-Feng Recording studio?
Yes.
Starling, I went to your trailer
and your dad said you were here.
Hey big guy, you fought well.
So about tomorrow's recording,
I've finished my part already.
As for your part, do your best.
This is an important track for you.
What the. ...?
Your girl is taken, that's what.
The shrimp roll guy is still open.
Oops. Let's pick it up.
There you go.
Was that six knocks or seven?
Who is it?
Hey it's me, what's up?
Just babysitting Jasmine's kid.
Babysitting?
Her friend came to visit.
So she left her kid at my place.
You'd make a pretty good babysitter.
If A-Lang looked after the kid
he'd be scared by all that hair.
Let me ask you something.
Okay.
If there were two guys
and one was a movie star
who had everything,
and the other guy was just an average guy
He's not exactly rich, but he has a rich life.
If you were a girl, who'd you pick?
Me?
The rich guy.
Who asked you, A-Lang?
Of course I'd go for the guy with money.
Who'd pick the loser?
Having money's great. You can do anything.
Hey, are you from the Rooftop or not?
I was just quoting Egg.
Tell Egg to come and listen.
I am listening.
What've you been saying, silly Egg?
Hey, Wax-
try not to worry about it.
If it's meant to be, it's meant to be.
If it's not, then it's not.
Hey Egg, that actually makes a lot of sense.
Wax.
Shall I take you to Dr. Bo
to heal your lovesickness?
You guys are idiots.
Go to bed.
Idiots.
The sky darkens with the passing clouds.
The waves roll quietly in the soft wind.
Though you're far away,
you've made me so happy.
Starling, wait a minute.
What are you guys doing here?
Judging from your outfit,
I'd say you're the guitarist.
Uh-huh.
The guy that looks like broccoli?
The drummer.
Plus two backup singers.
We're just visiting.
I thought the band was coming tomorrow.
Starling,
Let's pick up from where we stopped.
Wow, so fancy.
Hey, no shoes inside the studio.
Yeah, no shoes.
He meant no flip-flops, either.
Sorry, but we haven't washed our feet lately.
All right, fine.
Starling, let's take it from the top.
She sure is pretty,
but her singing is a little...
A little what?
Natural.
Yeah
Hey, wait a second.
What is it?
Are we too loud?
It's none of your business.
Hey Starling,
I feel like something was missing just now.
What does that mean?
I think it's great.
Hmmph. What do you know?
What I'm looking for is a feeling
that's sad, but not too sad.
You want to be happy, but can't be.
What are you going on about?
Huh?
Can she hear us?
Not unless I press this button.
Okay.
I'm the one who's unhappy.
Hey-
Wax, don't be impulsive.
Right.
It's you.
All your talk is upsetting my bro.
She can't hear you, but she can still see you.
Oh, ha ha.
Sit down.
Press the button for me.
Starling, this time
I want you to give me
sad, but not too sad
and happy, but-
not yet really happy. Something like that.
Isn't that what I just said?
Okay, Starling, let's do it again.
Wait, who's that guy singing?
It's the lead actor.
Is he in there too?
Where is he?
We recorded it already.
Are you guys really musicians?
Bye-bye
Hey, are you-
Are you leaving?
Yeah, you guys were sleeping
and I didn't want to wake you up.
No, they were sleeping, I was awake.
Did you just "fall" for the girl?
Starling, how could you do that?
How could you leave without us?
Are you hungry?
Let us take you out to eat.
Eat?
But I don't even know your names.
My name's Wax, and the others don't matter.
Hi I'm Egg.
Tempura
Broccoli
All food? You guys are funny.
You should spend more time with
ordinary people before you become a star
otherwise you'll wish you'd
savored the joys of everyday life.
What do you mean? She's already famous.
No, I'm really not.
You're not a star? Then come with us.
Uh-
It'll be dark when I get there.
Don't rush, you'll have to wait for me anyway.
The night market
is the place to be.
Come on everybody.
Thirty cents a go, everyone wins!
We'll be happy together.
I'll never forget
roasting corn with you
and catching goldfish with you
a bittersweet love.
What a wonderful place.
I've never been here.
I told you, it's fun, right?
Let's see if anyone recognizes her.
What are you staring at?
Let's go.
Hi Tempura
Hey Jiang
Are you the girl on the billboard?
Sorry, I didn't catch your name.
You need to wear these at the night market.
That's what all the stars do.
I told you she's a star.
But a star without a name.
Put them on so people won't recognize you.
That's not a bad idea.
Jiang, credit my account, ck?
Huh?
No, you don't have to do that.
Yeah, you don't have to do that.
It's okay, we're good friends.
Yes, yes, yes...
Looks great.
No it doesn't.
Shut up.
I'm so hungry.
What shall we eat?
What do you wanna eat?
BBQ sausages!
You can love em' and leave em'
you can fling em' about.
You can travel the world
but please don't miss out
Come take a look, come give 'em a try.
Our clothes are so hot, you'll look really fly.
Once you try this brand name
Then life won't be the same.
Aiyah, it's a superstar!
Hey!
A superstar would never
come to a place like this
cause this is a place for average people,
ha ha.
Hello everyone!
Ladies and gentlemen,
we're delighted to have you!
How about
a rousing song of welcome?
Ha ha, here we go!
Come, come!
Welcome to the most passionate island
on the planet.
Hajiu, hajiu, hajiu
The Lovers' Lake Night Market!
The Lovers' Lake
Night Market.
Hajiu, hajiu, hajiu
Oh, beautiful lady.
Welcome to The Lovers' Lake.
I promise you won't want to go home.
Hajiu, hajiu, hajiu
Take a walk around the island.
There's food, games, and handsome men.
Take home whichever one you like!
Hajiu, hajiu, hajiu
Which one do you like?
Hajiu
Hajiu, hajiu, hajiu
I'm not a handsome guy.
Hajiu
But at least I know how to sing.
So, choose me!
Hajiu, hajiu, hajiu
I hope you all have a great time!
Starling, let's go fishing down at the lake.
But you can catch goldfish here.
Really? Where?
Yeah.
Over there-
Oh, I see.
I wanna play too.
Why don't you go fish for bottles?
Leave the goldfish to us.
Let's go.
Hey-
Wow, what's going on here?
Is this your first time at Lovers' Lake?
I've got two stands,
one for clothes and one for fish.
Having two wives isn't easy.
Oh, by the way, there's a tradition.
If lovers catch a pair of fish
and set them free in Lovers' Lake
they'll have a beautiful life together.
We're just friends.
You'll be lovers after you're done fishing.
Almost, almost, come on.
Tempura, something's wrong.
What's wrong?
Wax-
Hold on a sec,
I'm gonna get something to eat.
I thought Tempura was collecting rent.
He said we could have a couple more days.
Tempura said that?
I'm in charge now.
Roman, don't get mad.
We'll pay you next time, I promise.
Get up.
Roman, Roman, what are you doing?
Showing you who's boss.
Can't you see?
Rango will be pissed.
If they can't pay,
then they get punished.
This is my district.
Boss, how many sausages do I get?
Are you really buying sausages?
You're a dead man.
Wait,
how about a song before I die?
La~
Don't you "la" me.
When the dice stop spinning
you'll all be on the ground.
Is it delicious? Yeah? ls it good?
Next time, remember my bro Wax.
Ah, man.
Bad luck again.
You think you're hot shit?
Big Red is coming soon,
and you'll all be dead.
Big Red?
Hey
Whose afraid of Big Red?
Starling
A-Lang, this way!
Egg, run!
Run, run, run!
Hey, you didn't take your fish!
Where are they?
They took off.
Here, keep the change.
What's with the attitude?
Outta the way!
Watch out!
Faster!
They're coming!
Stop!
I said kick some ass,
not get your ass kicked.
Sorry, boss.
Boss, that looked like a famous actress.
Go to the night market and find out.
Yes sir.
Go.
Who are they, why are they chasing you?
A-Lang owes them money.
He owes them a lot.
Who said my name?
Nobody, keep driving.
Oh.
Hurry up my little swan, hurry, hurry!
Hurry UP!
Faster!
Take us home, please.
You guys live in the Rooftop district?
My dad says
it's a bit rough up there.
No, people in the Rooftop District
are cultural and artistic people.
Yeah.
But if your heart is troubled,
then the whole world seems rough.
What are you going on about?
Wow, you're so sophisticated.
Hey, she said you're sophisticated.
Can't tell by looking.
You really can't tell.
But I'll show you someone who does look it.
Ah?
Ready?
Hello, sister-in-law!
Don't listen to their nonsense.
Because we can see you everyday.
You just can't see us.
Nonsense.
So, you see us every day, right?
No, I mean we see you every day.
So we've known you for a long time.
But you hadn't met us yet.
Nonsense again.
Soto us, you're like our sister.
What are we talking about?
Then why "sister-in-law"?
Because, because, um...
You'll find out if you come upstairs with us.
You know something,
Wax doesn't bring just anybody up there.
It's a lot of fun up there.
Come in-
It's a lot of fun.
Yay!
Bye-bye, Wax.
Outta the way!
What are you doing?
Come on.
See, I told you.
We are cultural and artistic people.
Guitar music as soon as you arrive.
Cat got your tongue?
If you can't say it, sing it.
Oh, right.
Hey, newbie.
You're not THAT person, are you?
Take a wild guess.
I think I've mistaken you for someone else
Because I can't believe the beauty
I see in front of me.
You are so sweet.
Forget them.
Hurry and come with me.
Come and enjoy
this beautiful night scenery.
No matter how beautiful this rooftop is
it will never be as beautiful as your smile.
Shoo-bee-doo-wa
I wish time could pause just for a moment.
What did you say?
I didn't say anything.
Shoo-bee-doo-wa
What are you being all shy about?
His name is "Chocolate.”
Do you like chocolate?
No, not really.
Step aside, who asked you.
Now I'm certain
you're the star on that billboard.
Big star
Don't worry, I'll take care of it.
Yes, yes.
This is my friend Starling.
My Rooftop friends,
do me a favor
and go back to your homes.
Or you'll make her nervous.
All right, that's enough staring.
I am so nervous.
Go on now.
What is it?
Superstar-
We are culturally rich
and decent people.
That's the third time.
Ah? ls it?
Hi, Jasmine.
She said "good job."
Let me introduce you to someone.
Over here.
Jasmine, Jasmine
Did you hear us singing?
Hi, Starling.
Hi. This is Jasmine.
How are you, Jasmine?
Good, good
She raised us since we were kids.
And she's a fantastic cook.
World-class, world-class.
No, it's just home cooking.
Her home cooking
is better than all the top
restaurants in Galilee.
Although I've never been to one.
If you've never been to one,
how do you know?
Really delicious.
All right, all right.
So, superstar, what brought you here?
Oh Jasmine,
we wanted to show Starling
how cultured and artistic
we are on the Rooftop.
The fourth time.
Is it the fourth?
I've been asking Wax
to bring a girlfriend home but
I didn't expect you'd come so soon!
Yeah-
He always gets what he wants, lucky guy.
Jasmine, we're just friends.
Oh.
Still just friends now,
but who knows about tomorrow?
That's enough.
We Rooftop people are always joking around.
We're like a big family, don't mind us.
I won't.
But you're also part of the family
We see you every day.
I told you that you're like a sister.
Then why "sister-in-law"?
Uh-
You kids have fun, I'm gonna go make dinner.
Let me help.
I wanna help too.
You can't cook.
Jasmine, I don't want potatoes tonight.
Your ass is grass.
Tempura, Tempura
Starling, it's noisy here.
Let me take you somewhere quieter.
Noisy?
It's too noisy?
It's very quiet here.
Ha ha
Wow, it's so beautiful.
I never knew there was a place like this
in Galilee.
Of course.
This is the place on the Rooftop
that's closest to the stars.
Your wishes are more likely
to come true up here.
Really?
Yes.
That's how I got you up here.
That's not funny.
Hey, do you have a wish?
I wish my father would stop gambling,
and that I could make more money
so I could pay off my debt to William.
William?
That's why William's company signed me.
But he takes care of my father and me.
That's good, then.
Otherwise-
What about you?
You look so carefree.
I envy you guys-
I wish I could be just be myself.
Like you Guys.
It's simple.
Depends on whether you want to be
the chess player or the pawn.
See, people on the Rooftop
are ordinary people
with extraordinary lives.
Yes, I can see that from the way you dress.
That's just an attitude towards life.
Sister, go bravely forward...
Hey what are you doing
playing that song now?
Sorry, I'll play a different song.
No matter what happened in the past,
it's fate that made us friends.
William-
If you want to take any of them home,
it's on the house, okay?
Master Lee,
Your girls are all very pretty-
Yes.
But no one is quite like my Starling.
Starling?
Boss, that's the woman.
What's the matter?
I saw her
with a guy called Wax.
Impossible.
Starling is with William.
That must have been someone else.
You mean we're all blind?
Everybody, chill.
We're all friends here.
William, aren't you friends with the mayor?
Here's the thing.
Big Red, why don't you tell him yourself.
William, it's really simple.
I want to run the City Housing Authority
and you're the only one who can help me.
You want me to
mention it to the mayor?
Right?
I want you to convince the mayor
not just mention it.
Fine.
But I'll need something from you too.
Hey, cut, cut, cut.
Wax, what's wrong with you?
This isn't a comedy.
I'm sorry.
What's the matter with you?
What are you laughing at?
You know every time
you screw up a take, he has to kiss her again.
It wasn't on purpose,
I was changing my pants.
I didn't know he'd say "action" so quickly.
Changing your pants? Back there?
Why do they have to kiss for so long?
Cut.
Who said that?
Hey you,
why are you yelling cut during their scene?
Get out, get out, get out!
Had enough fun yet?
All of you, get out!
Sorry, sorry
It's my friends' first time on set.
Come on, let's go.
Let's take a break.
Enjoying yourself? You're up next.
Me?
Yeah
Hey, thanks.
No problem, now hurry up.
Have a seat.
You want a different pose?
Tie him up.
I thought this was a kissing scene.
A kissing scene? You can kiss my ass.
Haven't you ever seen a super hero movie?
The hero always takes a beating
before he gets to kiss the girl.
And the kissing scene isn't for you.
Director, I have a little suggestion.
Yes?
They should hit him for real.
For real?
That would be more realistic.
Besides, he's a stuntman, right?
Hey, can you take a real beating?
Yeah.
Perfect.
Hey, Director!
Sorry. sorry!
Sorry, William.
Your seat's over there.
I'm so sorry.
Take your time with that.
I'm gonna go change.
Oh, okay. See you, William.
Director, everyone looks tired today.
Shall we take a break?
Cut, cut, cut
That's a wrap.
Perfect.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Pretty badass, right?
Yes, that was quite a beating you took.
No, what I meant was
after all that, my hair still looks good.
Are you in pain?
Nah, I'm fine.
I felt terrible watching you get beaten up.
Then it's all worth it.
What?
I'm gonna go change.
What are you staring at? Hop in.
Is this your car?
Yes.
Who are you fooling?
Why else do you think I work so hard?
Hard-earned money.
Stop here for a second.
Can I give you a lift?
That's okay.
I'm going the other way.
My driver can swing around and drop you off.
No, really, it's fine.
My father will pick me up soon.
See you tomorrow.
OK, see you tomorrow.
Let's go.
Looks like nobody's here.
Hello?
What are you doing here?
Dr. Bo and Tofu went out, so we're in charge.
Starling, have a seat.
I'm fine, patch yourself up first.
Do you want to try our house special?
Starling,
Would you like to try our house special?
Why are you mimicking me?
Wax, what happened to your face?
Did you get in a fight?
It was William, wasn't it?
No-
Right. He couldn't have beaten you up.
Starling, want a drink?
I can mix you anything you want.
Then I'd like a glass of truth serum.
For him.
Because he's so stubborn.
Even if he's hurt he won't admit it.
I knew you got in a fight.
Done.
It's not the same glass, what are you doing?
Drink it.
Starling asked you to drink it, so drink up.
And then tell us who you got in a fight with.
Yeah.
Do you like Starling?
Yes.
I'm going upstairs for a sec.
What did you give him?
Tap water.
Sister-in-law-
No peeking.
I'm not peeking.
Why all the mystery?
You'll find out soon enough.
No peeking.
I'm not. What is it you want to show me?
What is it?
Ready?
Yes.
The moonlight splashes upon the rooftop.
Your silhouette leaves me dazzled.
I know I'm not good enough for you
But I'll hold on to hope.
Protecting you
Just like protecting
this beautiful rooftop scenery.
The blowing wind can't cut off
the development of our story.
This romance belongs only to us.
It's quietly blooming.
The moonlight on this rooftop.
(Starling)
(Starling) Bestows me the strength
to fall in love with you.
Bestows me the strength
Star(Starling) Bestows me the
strength to fall in love with you.
Love(Starling)
Bestows me the strength
to fall in love with you.
Happy Valentine's Day!
Hello!
Not so fast!
Come here.
Happy Valentine's Day!
The little princess is heading home.
I had a great time today.
Do you have to take me home so early?
It's because of my dad, isn't it?
William, don't forget your promise to Big Red.
Give these photos to Bao.
Have him send them to the newspapers, ok?
William, you sure that's a good idea?
It'll hurt the movie.
Cut the crap, just do what I say.
Go.
Go tell Big Red
that William has kept his word.
Run run run, I like to watch you run.
Flee flee flee, don't let me catch you.
Fugitive, how romantic.
There's a strip of electric poles ahead.
Makes me wanna whistle.
Don't run,
I love to watch you go.
Run fast, run quickly,
Superstar, you and me.
Run, run, run
don't howl at me.
Woof, woof, woof
bark like a dog.
Snap, snap...
I don't care if you live or die.
Smile,
take a picture.
Shake,
tomorrow, you're on the front page.
Snap, Snap
You don't have any freedom.
Your life is in my hands.
Extra! Extra! Read all about it!
Starling-
How could you let this happen?
Are you trying to ruin your career?
I don't know how they got these photos.
You don't know?
Must be that boy, he pulled a fast one on you.
Wax would never do that to me.
You still trust him?
There are reporters waiting outside.
I don't even know what to do.
What's all the excitement?
Hi, Wax.
Come over here, let's get your picture.
Get a shot of him.
How did you know my name?
Where'd you get the name "Wax"?
Can we get an action shot? Yes, like that.
It's like hair wax.
Everyday, I-
Okay, that's not important.
Let's get a shot of you holding our paper.
Let's get one with our paper too.
See that smug look on his face?
Where'd you get this photo?
I thought you sent it out.
What do you mean?
Let's go.
Thanks,guys.
I want to state once and for all
That brat has nothing to do with my Starling.
There's no relationship whatsoever.
So you don't consider him
to be Starling's boyfriend then?
What boyfriend?
Just because they spent
Valentine's Day together-
Mr. Lee, let me explain.
I didn't take this picture.
You think we're all fools?
Of course you didn't take it.
You had someone else take it.
How much money did you make off this?
Yeah, how much?
You Rooftop people only care about money.
I'm warning you, stay away from Starling.
Get lost.
Okay, we're done here.
Thank you, everybody.
Lee, you go on inside.
I want to talk to Starling.
Yes, William.
Don't worry.
I won't let him near Starling ever again.
I understand.
There are a lot of people like him out there.
And Starling is naive.
She doesn't understand
the ways of the world.
You understand?
That brat was just using you
to sell photos.
Okay, I'm going inside.
Okay. Take your time.
A-Pu, drive on up ahead.
The studio is not happy.
They think that the news will hurt the film.
I'm sorry.
But we can fix that
if we create a bigger news story
than the one between you and that guy.
Starling, think about it.
Your father is stressed about his debts.
He begged me to sign you
and put you in a movie.
You have a career, thanks to your father.
He even put you up in a huge house.
If you let that guy affect you
then what's going to happen to your father?
Huh?
I hired a photographer. He's back there.
Don't look.
Just let him take some photos.
Your father can keep on living the good life.
You're a good daughter.
I don't believe you'd say no, right?
This just in... The hottest movie star, William
has admitted to his relationship
with Starling.
Their agency has confirmed the news.
Why are you so early today?
Just came to fix this radio.
The two say they're getting serious.
What are you doing?
Conserving energy.
Watching a cartoon,
wanna join me, it's really good.
I gotta go to work.
Wax, I'm sure you'll get over it eventually.
Hey. Silence is golden.
What are you doing?
I'll take all of your papers, please.
Hey Wax.
One newspaper, please.
But he just-
He what? He doesn't sell newspapers.
What do you want to eat? My treat.
I'm not hungry.
Not hungry? How 'bout some almond tea?
Not thirsty.
Wax, if I were her, I'd choose you.
I'd choose you too.
What do you mean?
Choose what? What are you talking about?
Choose
Mr. Universe!
You guys are on time today.
We should be safe here.
Relax.
Dr. Bo's a cheapskate,
he doesn't have anything.
No newspaper subscription.
Radio's broken, no TV
Why are you guys so early today?
Hey!
Hey, Dr. Bo
You trying to scare us?
Why are you so early today?
Come here, I've got something to show you.
Come over here.
What is it?
Check it out, a brand-new TV.
I bet you lads
never had a TV at home.
Am I right?
Up next, breaking news...
The hottest movie stars,
William and Starling
have been photographed kissing
in the street.
William said
that even though Starling is new,
he hopes his fans will love her too
and support their relationship.
You brat, it's you again.
You got the paparazzi with you again?
Take my picture if you like.
Sir, is Starling home?
She doesn't want to see you.
She's with William.
He's a superstar. And you?
You're a nobody.
You think my Starling is blind?
She knows who can give her a good life.
Do me a favor, don't show up here again.
If you really love her, let her go.
Now go.
Forget about her
I keep telling myself.
Though I don't know her any more.
In my heart, she's still so clear.
Oh, forget about it.
Just go along with the melody
and forget the sorrow.
I can keep going, without backup.
Move forward, find new memories,
new surroundings.
clear up, wait for the rain to give up.
Crying in the rain.
But you're everywhere.
Maybe I won't see you any more
if I wipe them away.
Your smile is so clear in my mind.
I'm totally wrapped up in you.
I weep with the rain.
Crying in the rain.
You're everywhere.
Holding you tight
is the only way out of this pain.
There is no room for me in your world.
I'm not sure who's harder to see, you or me.
We're both waiting for the rain to stop.
Hey, when her movie comes out
are you gonna go see it?
I don't think so.
Besides, who has money for tickets?
I want to see her and William's acting.
Yeah, seriously.
She's been in so many commercials lately.
It's getting to be a bit much.
You know
it'd be impossible to take down that billboard.
So if A-Lang and I get the chance
maybe we could spruce it up a bit.
Yeah, we'd risk our lives for you.
But it's so damn high.
Go! Chop-chop.
You stole my tune.
It was my tune.
Bye-bye.
Cut the bye's.
Wax-
Women...
are just like buttons.
You drop one on the street.
And if you aren't paying attention
you won't go back and look for it.
Your problem is
you're paying too much attention.
Without buttons,
a shirt can still look good.
I've got a lot of buttons.
I can get you one for right here.
Here, here, here-
This shirt doesn't have any buttons.
I know that.
You know what?
I don't really want to be part of
all the politics at the City Housing Authority.
I feel bad
about getting you guys involved.
Feel bad for what? It's not a big deal.
Hey-
You left your work at the clinic to help me.
And got chased by Big Red.
Hey
What if Big Red comes here?
I just want to keep life simple.
Look at the people living on the Rooftop.
Some of them have never been down there.
They know nothing about the outside world.
They don't make any money,
but they're happy.
So,
Without the City Housing Authority
we'd all be a lot happier.
What put you in such a funk?
Are we bros or what?
Yes.
Then go with me to Rango's tomorrow.
I'll quit.
Rango-
What's the rush to see me?
You should know.
The mayor told me.
What a surprise to find out
this one's dared to ask for my position.
You've come at just the right time.
Come on in.
Why do we always come at the wrong time?
Hi Rango.
You two, take a seat over there.
Okay.
Tempura, starting tomorrow
you and your friend
are in charge of the entire East District.
Rango-
That's my district.
Yes.
It was until yesterday.
I told them to start tomorrow.
Is there a problem?
What do you mean?
Big Red-
What I mean is,
I want you out of
the City Housing Authority for good.
Just you wait.
Let's go.
Hey, what are they doing here on set?
William, long time no see.
What's the matter now?
You promised me a deal with the mayor.
But the mayor betrayed me.
Why the hell is that?
Big Red, I did what I could.
What he decides is none of my business.
Are you fucking playing me?
Let me say this
very clearly.
I only play people who are worth it.
You have anything that's worth it?
Huh?
Here, this is for the photos you took.
I suggest you hurry up and take it.
We have a movie premiere to go to.
You're wasting our time.
Thanks, enjoy your premiere.
Outta the way!
May 31 st, isn't that today?
Yeah, it's today.
Is dinner ready, Jasmine?
Yes, it's ready.
Sorry, I'm getting hungry.
Jobless and hungry?
Come on over,
let's celebrate.
Celebrate what?
Tempura wanted to resign, but he didn't.
Instead, he got promoted.
Oh? Yeah?
Wow-
That means you've got us
when the bill comes!
We'll never have to work at the clinic again!
Hey, how can you say that?
You still need a job of your own.
But a certain someone
hasn't worked in a long time,
because he's down in the dumps.
Wax-
Hmm?
You can't stay like this forever.
Starling wouldn't want
to see you like this.
I don't think she's gonna see him like that.
Hey!
You deserved it.
You better pull yourself together
if you're gonna win her back.
Jasmine, I can't do it.
How do you know if you don't try?
Look at that billboard.
It's fate that
brought you two together.
How can you give up so easily?
Just let it slip away?
You'd be a fool to do that.
Hi. Simon.
Hello.
Long time no see.
Starling, you're a beautiful dancer.
Starling, this is our Asian distributor, Simon.
Hi, how are you?
This is our overseas distributor.
Nice meeting you,
have you had a great time?
Starling, I was just telling your father
we a have a lot of movies
that'd be perfect for you.
Simon,
you should consider working with Starling.
You can arrange it through me.
Sure, sure, sure.
Please excuse me.
I need to return to my dressing room.
Yes, see you.
Thank you.
We love you very much.
Have yourselves a great time.
I'm going to go change clothes.
Okay.
See you.
Wow
Wow, what a big event.
We should have borrowed Dr. Bo's car.
Hey, Wax.
Where you think you're going?
You won't get in dressed like that.
You're underdressed.
You need a Woodstock outfit like mine.
Pajamas?
It won't work.
Tempura,
you're always the best-dressed one.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So, you should go in.
Me?
Hey, Sir? Sir!
Hi Peter, what a coincidence!
You are?
Tempura.
You came for the premiere, too, huh?
Yes.
Shall we?
Yes! Get me a lobster while you're in there.
Let's go out back and watch.
There's a ton of media here today.
Hey, Bao.
Wax didn't come tonight did he?
He wouldn't dare.
William-
What would you have to bring up that kid for?
He wouldn't come harrass Starling again,
would he?
No.
This afternoon, Big Red reminded me of him.
You know I hate being threatened.
Those people are no threat to you.
Big Red is easy to get rid of.
Just give him a little cash.
Am I right?
But Wax, on the other hand-
William, that really was clever
sending those photos to the newspaper
and getting his ass kicked.
What a smart move.
So it was you!
You made everyone believe it was Wax.
Bao, can you give us a moment?
Close the door behind you.
Didn't you believe it too?
Who are you blaming?
You're the one who didn't trust him.
You think you can slap me?
You really think you're a huge star.
Huh?
Where are you going?
You think you can run away?
Don't forget your father owes me money.
If I didn't pay off his gambling debts
he would have gone bankrupt.
Without me
you'd never have gotten a lead role.
And don't you forget it.
Listen-
The fact is, I own you.
You think you're better than everyone?
What do you want from me?
Go on, scream.
Go ahead, scream away!
Keep screaming! Starling!
Ha ha, it's not what you think.
That's Starling's voice.
Don't forget-
you owe William money, right?
Don't you get it?
Yes sir, Bao, I'll get the money.
Hey, listen to me.
It's like having a son-in-law.
You lucky bastard.
After this
think about all the money you'll have.
If you prefer the poor kid, then you're nuts.
I always get what I want.
Starling, Starling!
Starling! Open the door, William!
Dad!
William, I beg you.
Help!
What's wrong with you?
Bao, sir, I beg you.
Let Starling go!
I'll pay you back. I'm begging you.
That's enough already.
Starling, Starling!
William, William!
Help!
What do you want?
Go on, continue.
How dare you!
You'll never make it out of Galilee.
I never planned on leaving.
What's taking so long?
Yeah, where's my lobster?
There's a guard at the door.
Hey, you guys go in from the window, okay?
Why are we always doing things like this?
Any other ideas?
Okay-
I'll do it for lobster.
Where are you going?
Shut up!
The movie has only just started.
What's the rush?
Reporters-
Come over to the center.
Come over here.
Get this on film.
It's a top story.
Why aren't you taking pictures?
Shoot!
Superstar William-
Come and tell everyone
what you were just trying to do.
Big Red, take it easy.
I'll go settle things with the mayor.
That's not what I want to hear you say.
I want you to explain
what you were just doing.
I-
Starling
I'm sorry.
Oh, now you're sorry?
Starling, do you accept his apology?
Huh?
This animal was trying to rape you just now.
You hate him, right? Come here.
Come on, don't be afraid.
Come here.
Take this knife. Take it!
Kill him.
Come on.
Do it, do it!
Starling
Starling, run!
Wax, you finally showed up.
I've been waiting.
Are you here for your brother?
Or for your lover?
Let them go.
I could kill you right here, right now.
But that that would be too quick.
And where's the fun in that?
You know it, too.
Right?
Give me a gun with just one bullet.
If you kill one of them,
I'll let the other one go.
Trust me, I'm a man of my word.
This is what happens to traitors.
Big Red-
Stay where you are.
She looks like she's in pain.
Do you want to relieve her of her pain?
Or save her?
Do you know why I kept you alive?
Because I want to see you
get killed by your brother.
You bastard!
Oh, I'm so scared.
Stop wasting time.
When the music stops, if you haven't decided
then you're all gonna die.
Hurry
Come on!
Are you hurt?
No
Get down.
Now what?
Don't be afraid.
What are you doing?
Keep it for me.
What?
Get out.
I don't want to.
Get out!
Come on, keep on going!
If you really love her, then leave her.