Come to us, we've waited so long for you.
Everyday we'll make a new song for you.
Come, come, you are the promise
of.............for me, love........
[cymbal crash]
[Show Boat (1929)]
[Cotton Blossom]
Here we all work on de Mississippi.
Here we all work while de white men play,
Loadin' up boats wid de bales of cotton,
Gettin' no rest till de Judgement Day.
Get yo'self a brand new gal,
A lovin' baby who's de apple of yo' eye.
Coal black Rose or high brown Sal,
Dey all kin cook de
sparrer grass an' chicken pie!
Here we all work on de Mississippi.
Here we all work while de white folks play,
Loadin' up boats wid de bales of cotton,
Gettin' no rest till de Judgement Day.
What a pretty bevy!
Ah, there! Ah, there!
The fairest of the fair!
To Southern beauty.
- Ev'ry beau must bow!
- How you love to flatter,
You rogues! You rogues!
Oh, goodness gracious!
They're so flirtatious!
- You naughty fellows
- Little women, don't be timorous!
You will find, acting thus
Only makes a man more bold!
These are not the days of old!
See! The Show Boat,
That's old Captain Andy's "Cotton Blossom"
Will you go?
Let me take you to the show!
'Twill be delightful
But to rightfully accept,
I have to make Mama
Get permission from Papa!
If you don't give us Captain Andy....
Ah, I have got such a wonderful show,
the greatest of dramas and jolly comedies
Stephen Baker, the handsomest
leading man, and beautiful Julie Laverne.
Cotton Blossom, Cotton Blossom
Captain Andy's Floating Show!
Thrills and laughter, Concert after,
Ev'rybody's sure to go!
Cotton Blossom, Cotton Blossom
Captain Andy's Floating Show!
Thrills and laughter, Concert after,
Get your girl and go!
[ Make Believe ]
Who cares if my boat goes upstream,
Or if the gale bids me go
with the river's flow?
I drift along with my fancy.
Sometimes I thank my lucky
stars my heart is free.
And other times I wonder
where's the mate for me?
Hello.
How do you do?
Are you an actress?
Oh, no, but...but I'd give
anything if I could be.
Why?
Well, because you can make believe
so many wonderful things
that never happen in real life.
Well, if you like to believe one thing,
why can't we make believe
we know each other?
The game of "just supposing"
is the sweetest game I know,
Our dreams are more romantic
than the world we see.
And if the things we dream about
don't happen to be so,
That's just an unimportant technicality.
Oh, the cold and brutal fact is
You and I have never met.
We need not mind
Convention's P's and Q's.
If we put our thoughts in practice,
We can banish all regret.
Imagining most anything we chose.
We could make believe I love you,
We could make believe
that you love me.
Others find peace of mind
in pretending.
Couldn't you?
Couldn't I?
Couldn't we?
Make believe our lips are blending
In a phantom kiss, or two, or three.
Might as well make believe I love you,
For to tell the truth I do.
- Magnolia!
Yes, Mother.
[ softly ] Goodbye.
I hope I see you again.
Yes.
[ Life Upon the Wicked Stage ]
Life upon the wicked stage
Ain't ever what a girl supposes,
Stage door Johnnies aren't raging
over you with gems and roses.
When you let a feller
hold your hand,
Which means an extra
beer or sandwich,
Ev'rybody whispers, "Ain't her life a whirl?"
Though you're warned against a roué
Ruining your reputation,
When you've have played around
The one night trade around
The great big nation
Wild old men who give you
jewels and sables
Only live in Aesop's Fables.
Life upon the wicked stage
Ain't somethin' for a girl.
Though we've listened to you
moan and grieve, you
Must pardon us if we
do not believe you,
There is no doubt you're crazy about
Your awful stage!
Life upon the wicked stage
Ain't ever what a girl supposes,
Stage door Johnnies aren't raging
Over you with gems and roses.
If some gentleman would talk with reason
I would cancel all next season.
Life upon the wicked stage
Ain't nothing for...a...
-...girl.........
- Life upon the stage ain't nothin' for a girl.
[ Applause ]
[ Can't Help Lovin' That Man of Mine ]
Oh, listen sister,
I love my mister man
And I can't tell you why.
There ain't no reason
for me to love that man.
It must be somethin'
that the angels done planned.
Fish gotta' swim.
Birds gotta' fly.
I gotta' love
One man 'til I die.
Can't help lovin'
That man of mine.
Tell me he's lazy.
Tell me he's slow.
Tell me I'm crazy.
Maybe I know.
Can't help lovin'
That man of mine.
When he goes away,
That's a rainy day.
But, when he comes back
That day is fine.
The sun will shine.
He can come home
As late as can be.
Home without him
Ain't no home to me.
Can't help lovin'
That man of mine.
[ Applause ]