Once upon a time,
long before man learned to fly...
...long before locomotives left
smoky streamers on the horizon...
...long before all this,
somewhere farther than man could sail...
...there was a little valley.
There on the banks of the winding stream
nestled a peaceful little village.
Draped around this hamlet,
stretching far and wide over hill and dale...
...was the Great Forest.
Here, deep among old trees,
wet moss and velvet shadows...
...life flows peacefully along.
Or does it?
Jonathan.
Funny.
Who's playing games?
Look here, young Woman,
l might have cut you in half.
No axe can harm me, Jonathan.
Honest Jonathan.
That is your name isn't it?
Honest me name, honest me nature.
NoW, kindly step aside.
l've business With that tree.
And so have l.
l've come to ask you not to cut it doWn.
Fancy noW, have you?
May l ask What you have to do With it?
You see, l'm queen of this forest.
And l'm the Emperor of China.
Very Well then.
Let me put it in this Way.
You see...
...this tree is the oldest and fairest
of them all.
lt's a mighty big oak tree.
That'll keep the village Warm
through the Winter.
But Who is going to keep them Warm
all Winter?
The little creatures
that live in its branches.
See hoW frightened they are.
Well, look here, it's all very Well.
Spare this tree and they'll bless you.
And so shall l.
Of course, if you put it like that.
All right.
Thank you, Jonathan.
You shall not go unreWarded.
l'll grant you three Wishes.
What? Anything l Wish for?
Three times?
Of course.
l ought to have more sense.
First, l give aWay the finest tree.
Then, l start talking about three Wishes.
Fairy tales! All fairy tales!
Where are you?
Where have you gone?
Jonathan.
The Wishes belong
to both you and your Wife.
Don't be hasty.
Yes, Your Majesty.
l mean, no, Your Majesty.
l beg Your Majesty's pardon, l'm sure.
You may stand up noW.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
l'm afraid the tree got a little bit chipped.
But don't Worry, Your Majesty,
it Will soon heal.
Real soon.
Sally, folloW me!
Anna!
-Do you knoW What happened today?
-Good evening.
You Won't believe What happened!
Not noW. Dinner's all ready.
Hurry and get cleaned up.
All right, Anna.
Listen to me for a minute.
You knoW that big clump of oak trees
along by the post road...
...With the great big one in the middle?
l Was Walking there today,
When suddenly...
...l saW a vision.
Yes, l knoW.
-You don't believe me, do you?
-Sit doWn and say grace.
Thanks for the food
We are about to receive. Amen.
NoW, let me tell you.
l Was chopping at that big oak tree,
the one l told you about...
...When all of a sudden, there Was
the most Wonderful smell of roses.
Cabbage.
AlWays cabbage!
Can't We ever eat anything else?
We can't afford anything else. You should
thank the Lord for What he provides.
But just for once, l Wish he'd provide
a nice big juicy sausage.
lt's here.
Where did it come from?
lt's What l've been trying to tell you!
She's granted us three Wishes.
She? Who is she?
The vision, of course. The beautiful lady.
What beautiful lady?
You never saW anything like it in your life.
One minute, she Wasn't there.
The next minute, there she Was.
Her skin Was like mother-of-pearl.
Her hair Was like the gold of Wild honey.
She Was so young!
Shame on you, talking like that!
So lovely!
That sausage should groW on your nose
for saying that.
The sausage!
See What you've done.
She's granted our second Wish.
NoW tWo of our Wishes are Wasted.
l knoW What to do.
We'll simply cut it off.
No, you don't!
All right then, let it stay.
lt doesn't look so bad.
Maybe you don't mind me
Walking around like this, but l do.
l Wish this thing Was off my nose
this very instant.
You ought to be ashamed,
throWing aWay our last Wish.
What difference does it make
to a nose as big as yours?
Mine doesn't smell like garlic all the time.
So you're tired of sausage already.
First, you're tired of cabbage,
and noW, of sausage.
But, Anna, all l said Was--
You Wished for it, didn't you?
Once in a lifetime poor people like us
can ask for anything they Want...
...and What do you Wish for? A sausage!
We had three perfectly good Wishes
and What have We to shoW for them?
Tell me What? Nothing.
That is What We have.
When We could've had
anything We Wanted.
When l think of it, l could cry.
Cabbage Wasn't good enough for you.
Of all the things We need,
you Wished for a sausage.
You and your silly Wishes.
l sometimes Wonder Why l ever--
Jonathan, l'm sorry. Please forgive me.
That's all right, Anna. Let's forget it.
You knoW...
...a toy Without a child is almost as sad
as a child Without a toy.
We Were so foolish.
Our dream could have come true.
There's still hope.
She might grant us another Wish.
Just a little one, maybe.
lt Wouldn't matter to me hoW little he Was.
l'd love him With all my heart.
Even if he Were no bigger than my thumb.
Someone's outside.
Don't you hear?
Someone's knocking.
l can't hear anything. Go back to sleep.
Who's there?
-ls this Acorn Cottage?
-That's right.
-The home of Jonathan the Woodcutter?
-Yes.
But l can't see you.
-Are you Jonathan?
-Yes, l am.
-Where are you?
-Then l'm in the right place.
l can hear you, but l can't see you.
LoWer your candle, doWn here.
Glory be!
Come in, lad.
Come in!
Thanks. l'm cold.
That feels good, Father.
"Father"? You called me "Father"?
Of course. Don't you recognize
your oWn son?
l think l understand.
Tell me, Were you sent
by the beautiful lady?
That's right.
Welcome, Son. Welcome.
Thanks. l hurried, too, as fast as l could
to get here on my birthday.
Jonathan?
Who is it?
Just a minute.
-Who's that?
-That's your mother, Son.
Come on, let's surprise her.
We have a visitor, Anna.
A little visitor...
...Who's going to stay With us
as long as We live.
Tom.
HoW did you knoW my name, Mother?
l've alWays knoWn
What your name Would be.
l'm so happy.
l am, too. But isn't a fella supposed
to have a cake on his birthday?
For goodness' sake, of course.
You must be starving.
Jonathan, build a fire.
l'll fix something right aWay.
""Mug for a table, spool for a chair
""Nice and stable, room to spare
""Thimble for cup, button for plate
""NoW We're ready to celebrate""
Happy Birthday, Son.
Happy Birthday, everyone!
lt's getting late and l have to fix you
something to Wear.
Come along,
it's time for little boys to be in bed.
""After all these years
""After all my tears
""After all the lonely days l've knoWn
""NoW l have a son
""Such a tiny one
""Like a little doll
""But a baby all my oWn
""NoW my World is bright
""Things have turned out right
""After all my doubts
""And all my fears
""You belong to me
""And We'll live
""Happily
""Together, ever
""After all these years
""You belong to me
""And We'll live
""Happily
""Together, ever
""After all these years""
Good night, Mom.
Good night, Dad.
Which in Chinaland means ""good morning.""
Good morning, Mr....
AlloW unWorthy one to introduce
your humble servant, Con-Fu-Shon...
...and bidding you on behalf of all toys
in nursery a most glorious Welcome.
Thank you.
Good morning, Tom.
Good morning, Tom!
Good morning.
-Good morning, Tom.
-Good morning!
-Good morning.
-l didn't knoW toys could talk.
All very grateful to you, Tom,
to bring us to life.
GroWnups can't do that,
they are too smart.
You see, Tom, many, many years this
has been a very lonely place Without you.
NoW that you are here, We are so happy,
We Want to celebrate.
Hey, that's my song!
-Hi, Tom.
-Hi.
""This is my song
""My very oWn song
""l can sing it short
""Or l can sing it long
"This is my song
My very oWn song"
"l can sing it short
Or l can sing it long"
Hiya, Tom.
Everybody run! GroWnup coming!
Back in places.
Hurry! Run! Run everybody.
Hurry!
Excuse me.
He's gone.
Tom, Where are you?
Here l am.
What are you doing out of your cradle?
The sun's hardly up.
The toys are giving me a party.
The toys gave you a party?
We Were having a party. Honest.
We Were singing and dancing
and chummy and....
NoW, listen, Son.
lmagination's all right in a little boy,
but don't let it go too far.
Never forget your father's name
is Honest Jonathan.
Turn coming.
-Which Way, Father?
-Left today, Son.
Watch me take it.
Look, no hands.
Left, Sally.
Another turn coming, Father.
-Left again?
-Yes.
Sally, left again.
This donkey seems to understand
every Word you say.
Sure, l understand him, too.
What Was that?
A cry from the Black SWamp.
What's a sWamp?
An evil place
Where horrid birds and animals live.
You must never go inside there.
They'd gobble up a little lad like you
in no time.
Great jumping balls of fire!
Can it be real?
lt must be. lt lives and breathes.
l have an inspiration
of unparalleled brilliance.
This little felloW can help us With our job.
What, that little splinter?
He couldn't lift a feather.
But you forget the old adage:
""There are more Ways than one
to crack a vault.""
He can Wiggle through the keyhole.
No. l don't Want nobody else.
l can open it With my bare hands.
Of course, you can.
But he can do it quieter.
NoW, Watch me strike a bargain
With the old man.
We'll play a little game.
The cards, of course, Will be marked.
Our fortune is as good as made.
Stand back, my good man.
Your gracious pardon, sir.
My colleague and l are shoWmen of
prominence on our Way to the annual fair...
...and We Were Wondering
What price you put upon the little lad.
Price? What do you mean?
-Do you Want to buy him?
-Oh, no!
lt Would be more of a loan.
A sort of loan-lease.
We Would teach him a good trade
and We Would pay you.
He Will be learning and you Will be earning.
He's not for sale!
He's my son.
We understand.
-Don't We, Anthony?
-Yes, We do.
Who Would argue With a father's heart?
-l like you.
-So do l.
l like you very much.
Good-bye, little lad.
One day your father
Will be very proud of you.
Arrivederci.
-l don't like the looks of those felloWs.
-l thought they Were kind of nice.
Hey, Where are you?
Come on.
Hello, Woody.
Queenie!
Where have you been?
l've been calling for you.
l've been looking for you
all through the forest.
Poor Woody.
l just secured the position
as second WoodWind...
...in the Royal Military Band.
l think that's Wonderful.
Do you really?
Won't you sit doWn?
Thank you.
lf only there Weren't
this barrier betWeen us.
You, being an immortal,
and l, a mere unWorthy mortal.
There needn't be a barrier.
You mean, l can be immortal, too?
The other Way around.
You can become a mortal.
What's stopping you?
What do you have to do?
lt isn't What l have to do. lt's you.
Me?
Tell me.
Can't you guess?
l have to be promoted to first WoodWind
in the Royal Military Band?
No.
Not bandmaster?
lt's much simpler than that.
-Woody.
-Yes?
Would you promise me something?
Anything in the World.
You Won't ever, under any circumstances...
...ever try to kiss me, Will you?
No! Certainly not!
Funny hoW a fella can change.
There Was a time
When l Wouldn't have thought tWice...
...about kissing a girl as pretty as you.
-l Was a terrible fella.
-Were you, Woody?
l certainly Was.
Kissing, alWays kissing girls.
Sometimes even
When they Weren't looking.
Of course, With you, it's different.
Ever since l first met you,
l've been a changed man.
Do you knoW Why?
'Cause you Were right up there.
l Was Way doWn here.
l still am.
But l Won't alWays be.
One day, Queenie, l'll be Worthy of you.
And until then...
...l'll respect you.
Thank you.
That's nice.
Hello, Woody.
Good afternoon, Jonathan.
Meet my son, Tom.
Pleased to meet you, young man.
-Good-bye noW.
-What's the hurry, Woody?
Why don't you come home
and have supper With us?
You knoW Anna's alWays happy to see you.
Thanks. l Wish l could, but l can't.
l'm a busy man noW.
l have to get back to the village.
l have a job.
You? Working?
Certainly. So long.
-l'll see you at the fair on Sunday?
-No, l don't think you Will.
Anna and l,
We're too old for things like that.
HoW can you let this little felloW
miss seeing the fair?
lf you don't take him, let him go With me.
l'll shoW him a good time.
He'll be the guest of the second WoodWind
in the Royal Military Band.
""Step up, step up!
""Step up, my friends, and see my shoes
""l made them especially for you to use
""And l can shoW you the smartest shoes
""That you ever saW at the fair
""Step up, my friends, and see them shine
""You never saW shoes that shine like mine
""Because l handle the talented line
""Exactly the kind you should Wear
""These shoes upon my shelf
""Are shoes l Wear myself
""These are talented shoes
""Talented shoes
""They leap and jump and hop and skip
""And every skip is full of zip
""These are talented shoes
""Talented shoes
Talented shoes
-l'll take these.
-""A man is Wise to choose""
-l'll have a pair.
-""Such talented, talented shoes""
l'll take these.
Size 9.
""Of seven league boots
you may have heard
""They fly through the air
like a hummingbird
""Well, l Would never say a Word
""lf mine Weren't better than those""
-Give us tWo of the ""dancingest"" pairs.
-""When talented shoes set out to fly
""They fly much faster and tWice as high
""They're just the boots you ought to buy
""lf you Want to be on your toes
""These shoes upon my shelf
""Are shoes l Wear myself
""These are talented shoes
""Talented shoes
Talented shoes
""They leap and jump and hop and skip
""And every step is full of pep
""These are talented shoes
""Talented shoes
Talented shoes
""A dance cannot confuse
""Such talented, talented
""Talented, talented shoes""
Hey, Tom, What do you think
of those dancing shoes?
What?
The dancing shoes?
-l think they're Wonderful.
-l think so, too.
-Let's get some.
-Don't you have to stay here?
l'll be back before it's my turn to play.
They'll never miss me for a feW minutes.
Hold on, Tom. Let's go.
l'm sorry, Woody. All sold out.
Not even a pair for a queen?
You're very funny.
HoW about a pair for this little fella?
For Tom? Do you knoW, l believe l have.
See if these fit.
Woody, that no-good loafer! Where is he?
Where is he? Where's Woody?
l Was crazy to give him a job
in the first place.
Woody, Wherever you are?
You're fired!
Better go after him.
Those are talented shoes he's Wearing.
They'll keep on dancing
as long as the music plays.
Tell them to hold the music.
Stop the music. Stop!
Bandmaster!
-What noW?
-They say to play faster.
-Faster?
-Yes.
Gladly.
Bandmaster! Stop!
-Have you seen Tom?
-No, l haven't.
Stop playing!
-Have you seen Tom?
-No.
My balloon is gone!
Look at me!
Don' t let go!
Hang on!
lt's no good, lvan. lt Won't give at all.
NoW, finding ourselves in the situation
in Which you have placed us...
...it Would seem
a little coordination is necessary.
We'll use this piece of Wood.
This time, our efforts shall be unified.
NoW, both together When l count three.
You understand, three?
Yes, it comes after tWo.
Good boy.
One, tWo, three!
Hey, lvan--
NoW, We must approach this problem
from a highly scientific angle.
Sure, but--
But first, We must practice
unadulterated silence.
Understand?
What are you doing?
lt's the little runt.
Thank you. You saved my life.
Think nothing of it, young felloW.
Fate decreed that l should be present
in your hour of need.
That is all.
-Why don't We use him to get--
-Why don't you shut your--
Young felloW...
...talking about ""hour of need,""
it Would seem that you dropped in...
...just When my companion and l
could use your assistance...
...in the performance of a good deed.
l'll be glad to help.
l kneW it. The first time
l laid eyes on him, see?
That's What l like about this charming,
young gentleman. He's so cooperative.
-What do l have to do?
-Come over here.
Get the rope.
NoW, Thomas, my boy. Listen to me.
Let me explain.
The Mayor of this village
is an absolute rascal.
Right?
He has the money belonging
to the poor orphans doWn there...
...and intends to keep it all for himself.
lf you go doWn this rope
and help us to get the money out...
...We Will see that it is distributed
among those to Whom it rightfully belongs.
l don't knoW.
Maybe l should ask my father or Woody.
No! There's no necessity to bother them.
l'm sure they Would approve.
ln fact, l'm quite certain
your father Would be very proud of you.
-Very proud.
-Oh, yes.
He Would?
Yes, of course he Would.
Come on, let's pull the job.
l mean, let us do our best
to help the poor orphans.
Shall We?
See, Anthony,
everything comes to him Who Waits.
He believed every Word of that silly story.
Wait a minute.
HoW do l knoW that money's really
for the poor orphans?
Well, you have my Word of honor.
And you have mine.
Well, then it must be all right.
What should l do noW?
Tie the rope to one of those bags.
Which one?
The biggest one!
Then climb on and We'll pull you up.
lt's going to Work, Tony.
Nobody Will guess hoW We did it.
lt's ready!
Aren't We gonna take any more?
Not noW.
Maybe We'll come back later.
Well, there's plenty more doWn there.
Let's get rid of the kid noW
so he Won't open his mouth.
Are you out of your mind?
Leave this to me.
Listen, my dear felloW.
We're going to take you
for a nice little ride.
They are all gone. Come on.
Tom, this is Where We must part.
That's the road that takes you home.
Remember our little secret.
Don't tell anyone because
that's the only Way We can surprise...
...the dear little orphans.
By the Way, l'm sure the orphans
Would like you to have this.
Run and get it.
Too-dee-doo-dee-doo.
Too-tee-too-tee-too.
Bye.
Goodbye.
And Where have you been all day?
All over the place.
l had a Wonderful time.
l got some talented shoes, then
l Went dancing and l rode on a balloon.
l've just been helping tWo friends of mine
do a good deed.
Until it got dark
and you fell into the sWamp.
l'd have gotten out anyway,
but thanks just the same.
What's that?
-Hi, Queenie.
-Hello, Woody.
Do you realize l have searched every inch
of this forest trying to find you?
Well, l'm sorry you got lost.
l got lost? You got lost, you mean.
l've been looking for you all day.
The trouble With you--
Why don't you leave him alone?
Never mind, Queenie.
The trouble With you is,
you have no sense of responsibility.
Responsibility? What about
your sense of responsibility?
You Were to keep your job
and take care of Tom.
-He only Went to get you a pair of shoes.
-You stay out of this!
Don't speak to him like that.
You better take him straight home.
Do this, do that! l've had enough!
l'm tired dragging through this forest
doing things for other people.
lf it's not him flying around on balloons,
it's you trying to get me to kiss you!
HoW dare you!
Yes, don't think l don't knoW.
l'm not as dumb as l may look.
l Will kiss you When l'm good and ready
to marry you and not before!
lf you think l'd marry
a no-good-idle-do-nothing like you!
You...
...second WoodWind, you!
Hey, What?
Don't go, Queenie!
l'm sorry. lt Was all my fault.
lts all right.
Come on. Let's get you home.
That good-for-nothing Woody!
He'll have some tall explaining to do.
Your father's in a pretty bad mood.
Yes.
You better go ahead.
l'll try to get to bed before father sees me.
You've had enough trouble of your oWn.
Thanks, Tom.
So long.
Bye.
Disgraceful! A boy of his age
being out to this time of night!
lt's been dark for hours.
l should've never let them go.
lt's my fault.
Where are they?
l'll teach him a lesson.
l hope nothing's happened to him.
Something Will happen to him
When he gets home.
The idea of a youngster like that
gallivanting around!
l'll see he doesn't do it again,
l can tell you that!
So!
You've finally decided to come home.
Tell me What you've been doing
all this time...
...and it better be good.
Jonathan, you mustn't alloW yourself
to get upset like this.
We'll talk about it in the morning.
Say good night to your father.
Goodnight, Father. l'm sorry.
Trouble? Yes?
l've just made my folks so unhappy
and l'm so sorry.
Being sorry next-best thing to being good.
Humble one suggest you go sleep.
l can't sleep.
l just feel so bad, l can't sleep.
Problem easily remedied.
Let me introduce ""YaWning Man.""
Very good friend.
""l'm the yaWning man
""The yaWning man
""l come When shadoWs creep
""With my yaWning song
l stroll along
""And help put people to sleep
""lf you just can't sleep
And you're tired as could be
""There's a remedy
lt's the yaWning melody
""lf you yaWn, yaWn, yaWn
Then you'll sleep, sleep, sleep
""Till the daWn, daWn, daWn
So let's all yaWn
""lf the sandman comes
And his sack he unties
""Tell him go aWay
Who Wants sand throWn in his eyes
""lf you yaWn, yaWn, yaWn
Then you'll sleep, sleep, sleep
""Till the daWn, daWn, daWn
So let's all yaWn""
Try it, Tom!
""lf you still can't sleep
And for slumber you yearn
""lf your eyelids burn
And then you squirm and tWist and turn
""lf you try to yaWn, yaWn, yaWn
Then you'll sleep, sleep, sleep
""Till the daWn, daWn, daWn
So let's all yaWn""
Jonathan, come and sit doWn.
You can't possibly go to Work
in Weather like this.
You might as Well relax
and enjoy your breakfast.
-Where's Tom?
-He's asleep.
-Wake him up.
-Let him sleep. He's so exhausted.
l Wonder Who that is.
-Gentlemen, What can l do for you?
-Maybe you can help us.
The treasury's been robbed
and We're searching for the culprits.
-Have you seen any strangers hereabouts?
-No, l haven't. Have you, Anna?
No.
-Have you looked in the forest?
-Yes, We've been all through it.
We're about to have breakfast.
Won't you join us?
Come in, gentlemen.
Make yourselves at home.
Thank you.
Won't you sit doWn?
Here you are.
-Thank you.
-You are Welcome.
-Very tasty, ma'am.
-Well, thank you.
Wake up, Con-Fu-Shon.
Hey, this is a coin from the....
Yes, there's no doubt about it, l sWear.
HoW noW, madam?
Are you in the habit of baking your bread
in the village treasury?
l have no idea hoW it could've got there.
This coin is part of the stolen money.
Where's the rest of it?
l don't even knoW hoW this got there.
A likely story.
You don't believe her?
Are you accusing us of thievery?
-Yes.
-You call yourself Honest Jonathan.
You may call yourself Honest Jonathan,
but as for me, you're a crook.
That isn't true!
He's the thief.
Don't you dare call my husband a thief!
You're both under arrest.
Wake up! Wake up!
Wake up! Help!
Con-Fu-Shon, Wake up!
Honorable YaWning Man
has very poWerful medicine.
We've got to open the door.
Some soldiers just accused my money
of stealing parents.
No, l mean.... We've got to open the door!
He's not a crook.
Are you aWake?
Jack-in-the-box.
Yes! Come on!
You're making a big mistake.
You haven't heard the last of this,
my friend.
Let me go! Take your hands off me!
Take your hands off me!
Wake up, Jack. Quick, Wake up.
l'm sleepy. Go aWay.
But, honorable Tom needs
honorable Jack-in-the-box very much.
Why didn't you say so in the first place?
What can l do?
Can you open the door?
Consider it done.
Done.
Little man, big trouble?
What am l going to do?
To prove innocence, find guilty one.
l knoW Who the robbers are.
With such knoWledge,
problem easily solved.
Yes!
All l have to do is find the robbers
and have them put in jail.
That's What l'm going to do.
""Are you a dream
""Or Was it really you
""Were We really here
""Did my dream come true
""l can't be happy noW
""Till you belong to me
""Why did you fade aWay
""Never my love to be
""Was l aWake
""l can't believe it's true
""But once long ago
""You Were the love l kneW
""Can it be possible
""You've gone aWay
""Or Were you a dream
""l dreamed one day
""You touched me
""l felt your touch
""You must be real
""l care so much
""Come back to me
""Tell me it's true
""Tell me
""you're not a dream
""it's you""
Hi.
Hello, Tom.
l Was just singing to myself a little.
l heard.
Where are you going?
l have to go catch a couple of criminals.
Really? And What have they done?
They robbed the treasury, my folks got
blamed for it and they took them to prison.
Oh, no!
That's terrible.
Of course, it's terrible.
Are you gonna come and help me
or just sit there and sing?
-Help? Of course, Tom.
-Well, come on, then.
l knoW What they look like.
One of them has a big tall hat
and the other's a big fat man.
Wait a minute. Are they dressed in black?
Yes.
lt's them.
You knoW Who they are
and l knoW Where they are.
Come on, Tom.
One for you and one for me.
TWo for you and tWo for me.
Three for you and three for me.
Four for you and four for me.
Five for you and five for me.
Six for you and six for me.
You stay here.
Seven for you and seven for me.
Eight for you and eight for me.
Nine for you...
...and nine for me.
Ten for you and ten for me.
l've come to take that money
back Where it belongs.
TWelve for you, tWelve for me.
Give me that money, do you hear?
""Give me that money, do you hear?""
Go aWay.
Fourteen for you and fourteen for me.
l told him to go aWay.
Yes, l heard you.
NoW We'll start again.
Maybe We'd better leave
and share the booty later.
Hey, l Want mine noW.
Very Well.
We must hurry.
One for you, one for me.
Woody, Wake up!
Three for you, three for me.
Four for you, four for me.
Five for you and five for me.
Six for you, six for me.
Seven for you, seven for me.
Eight for you, eight for me.
Nine for you, nine for me.
TWelve for you, tWelve for me.
FelloW.
Cheers!
You got more than me.
But you saW me count.
Let's start again.
This time l Will do the counting.
One for me and one for you.
TWo for me and tWo for you.
Three for me and three for you.
Four.
All right, you do the counting.
One for you and one for me.
TWo for you and tWo for me.
Three for you.
-Three for me.
-Salute, lvan.
Bottoms up.
There's a crook in here and it's not me.
There are tWo crooks in here
and they are both you.
There he is.
Enough?
l've not had enough!
Put them up!
So you tried to cheat me?
NoW l'll shoW you hoW to count.
One for you.
One for me.
TWo for you and...
...tWo for me.
Three for you and three for me.
One, tWo, three, four for you...
...and this, one, tWo, three, four...
...for me.
Wait a minute.
One, tWo, three, four, five...
...for you.
Hey! lt's the kid!
There he is!
NoW l'm really gonna fix you.
l'll fix you good.
Hear ye, hear ye,
the decision of the Royal Court!
For participation in the robbing
of the village treasury...
...tWelve lashes of the Whip.
For failure to divulge the names
of your confederates...
...another tWelve lashes of the Whip.
Whipping's too good for them!
They stole our money,
noW our taxes Will be raised!
Get on With the Whippings! Thieves!
We didn't do it!
We're innocent!
He bit me. He bit me!
Where is he?
He's not there, lvan.
There he is.
Help!
NoW, let's get the money.
-Pleasant dreams.
-Buona sera.
l guess We got through With the little runt.
-Come on, let's get out of here.
-No, Wait. There's still some more.
We'll leave those for the orphans.
Come on.
""l am an orphan
""l am an orphan""
Come on.
Before carrying out the sentence,
l'm going to give you one last chance.
Where have you hidden the money?
l can only repeat, sir,
We knoW nothing about it.
Tell the toWn lasher to prepare.
We've got the money!
lt's the Wrong road!
This Will take us to the village!
The stupid beast Won't obey!
Make Way for the toWn lasher!
There's the toWn. Get off the road!
Turn to the right, you stuffy old mare!
To the right, lvan! To the right!
l knoW, l know!
l can't do anything With it!
That Was fine.
To the right, lvan! To the right!
There's a crossroad coming
but you go straight ahead.
We'll shoW them Who the real robbers are.
Faster! Faster!
l can't go any faster!
We made it! Stop!
They're the robbers.
They stole the money!
Hi, Mom.
Hi, Dad.
Fetch those men!
Out of my Way, donkey boy.
What have you done With him?
Where's Tom?
l'm over here!
Here l am!
No kisses, remember?
Don't Worry, Mom.
She does that all the time.
Now, wait a minute, this isn't the way
it was supposed to happen.
Try it again, gently.
Like.... Like this?
Yes.
Queenie, you're real!
Woody, is this how you do it?
Done by:
TheKha & Shady