oo! oo! oo! br-r-r-r-rr!
oo! oo!
oo! wa!
woooo! woooo!
woooo! hoo hoo!
woooo!
oo oo! oo hoo!
br-r-r-r-rr! eeoo!
caw! caw!
caw! caw! caw! caw!
caw! caw! caw!
man: this is where
the town begins.
this part of the country's been
through a lot of changes.
not all small ones, either.
i think they're in the process
of going through another one.
you know, there's bound to be
at least one person
who remembers when everything
was just open land,
like it is right here,
and some people can just look
at the land--just look at it--
and tell you
what happened there.
this whole area was once
under water--
almost still looks like it.
after that,
there was a period
when dinosaurs roamed
all over the place.
i used to be fascinated by
dinosaurs when i was a kid.
a lot of kids were.
recently, the bones of a woman
who lived 20,000 years ago
were found here.
they nicknamed her
midland minnie.
the first inhabitants here
referred to themselves
simply as "the people."
other groups
they came in contact with
were referred
to as "friends."
texas comes from
the caddoan word for friend.
however, the caddo
were among the first
to be wiped out by
early white settlers.
a group of spanish settlers
offered the indians
a chance to become slaves.
the indians thought about it,
decided it was not a good idea,
and killed the spaniards.
the spaniards fought mexicans.
mexicans fought americans.
americans fought the wichitas.
the wichitas fought tankowas.
tankowas fought the comanches.
the comanches fought everyone.
meanwhile, most people who
now lived here spoke spanish.
covert military operations
to seize texas
for the u.s. of a.
were begun in 1835.
eventually,
they did get texas.
land grabbers,
railroad companies moved in.
the economy boomed.
some people got rich--
first on cotton,
then cattle, then oil,
and now, microelectronics.
the silicon-based transistor
was first proposed here in 1949.
in 1958,
mr. jack kilby invented
the integrated circuit.
he was working
at texas instruments then.
he doesn't work there anymore.
this is the 150th anniversary
of the state of texas.
prince charlie, duke of windsor,
prince of wales even came here
for the sesquicentennial
opening ceremonies.
this out here--
this is virgil, texas.
their celebration's
gonna happen this friday.
they're gonna have
a parade
that runs down the main street
in the morning.
and then outside of town
that night,
they're gonna have
a talent show.
you know,
in a couple of years,
this'll probably all
be built up.
radio reception's
great here!
although the center of town
is pretty old,
around the outside, there's been
a lot of people moving in,
a lot of construction.
plummet
right.
steady!
5.32.
move on.
this is where the stage
for the performances
is gonna be built.
it'll only take
a couple of days
because it's all prefab.
they'll get it done
just in time, i hope.
do you think there'll
be enough parking, huh?
4.50.
good. move on.
be there soon.
many of virgil's festivities
are sponsored by varicorp.
it's a major
public relations effort.
they're calling it
a celebration of specialness.
but this place
is completely normal.
anyway, this is
the varicorp building
just outside virgil.
it's cool.
it's a multipurpose shape--
a box.
we have no idea
what's inside there.
going to the keg party
at don's tomorrow?
love makes everything beautiful,
like a little puppy--
warm and fuzzy.
you know, i like a hairy man.
jesus was hairy.
it's worth it
to fall in love,
to see
the beautiful world.
love is soft
and love is pure.
love is something
that you must endure.
love is peaceful
and love is wild.
love's all right
if it lasts a while.
i know everything there is
to know about love, honey.
i have seen it all
and done it all.
i love money,
and men like that.
remember when i went out
with burt reynolds?
shoot, he was gonna quit
the movies and live with me.
i said, "burt, darlin',
i need all your money."
he would have
given it to me.
don't be afraid.
i'm gonna touch your nose.
what's that
supposed to be?
um, you see,
i can read your tones.
everybody has tones.
it's like everybody
has their own station,
like a transmitter.
i guess you have
your dial set.
baby, i'm the only one
that has a radio.
i'm picking you up.
you're sort of cool,
sort of...hhhot!
# baby, your mind
is a radio #
# the receiver
is in my head #
# baby, i'm tuned
to your wavelength #
# let me tell you
what it says #
# it's a transmitter #
# da da da doom #
# i'm picking up
something good #
i like it.
seems to be a different
kind of attitude.
yeah. something's
happening here, all right.
the world is changing...
and this is
the center of it right now.
or the one of many centers.
it's a lot like music.
computers are like that.
you can never explain
the feelings or connections
to anyone else.
figuring something out,
something that's never
been understood before,
is a rhythmic experience.
steve jobs said that.
he used to be
the head of apple.
thanks.
you know, some people
in the computer business
can be pretty creative,
unlike the traditional
businessman.
you know, the astronauts
didn't read poetry.
but that's changing.
hi, gary.
this is an exciting
place to work?
yeah, i guess i'd say so.
computers are as much a means
of expression as language.
hi!
my name is louis--
louis fyne.
i've been working here
a number of years.
now i'm in the clean room.
it's pretty ok.
i go out at night.
i'm a dancin' fool!
ha ha! ha ha!
i'll tell you what.
whew!
i love the women.
hey, there's more to life
than this job.
no offense, you understand.
i'm no swinger. not louis.
i want to settle down.
it would be beautiful.
hey, these machines are great.
they're amazing.
i tried a computer
dating service once.
wound up with a midget.
i mean, i'm not
a fussy man, but...whew!
louis, tell me,
do you like children?
they're lovely.
well, do you know
all the kids' names by now?
uh...what, are they
sitting alphabetically?
i want someone
to share my life.
marriage is a natural thing,
and i'm a natural man.
louis, i'd like
to teach you
the lotus position.
moonstone,
i'd like to learn it,
but i sit all day at work,
so i'm not flexible.
just take one foot,
place it on
the opposite thigh.
gently. this is the most
awesome yoga position.
well, if it's awesome...
take the other foot.
this one goes here,
very gently.
no, careful, careful.
here, let me help you.
no, no. that's
a different position.
back this way, louis.
there. oh, you're doing
very well.
got it?
it's close. very good.
well,
i suppose these freeways
made this town and a lot
of others like it possible.
they're the cathedrals
of our time, someone said.
not me.
you know, around here
they have names
for the various kinds
of freeway drivers.
the slingshotter.
the adventurer.
the marshmallow.
the nomad.
and the weaver.
yup, it's fancy driving,
all right.
you know, things that never
had names before
are now easily described.
it makes conversation easy.
i have something to say
about the difference between
american and european cities...
but i forgot
what it is.
i have it written down
at home somewhere.
you like music?
oh, i know.
everybody says they do.
look.
i personally believe...
i can see
fort worth from here.
most people around here
have eaten dinner already.
don't want to be late.
know what i mean?
or do you?
you've got to see this.
this might be part of virgil's
celebration of specialness...
or it might not be.
you might have
seen it on television...
or maybe you missed it.
hope you don't mind
loud music.
all right, friends. welcome.
crazy cajun talking at you
in virgil city tonight
where everybody
always has a good time.
we're gonna pass you
some of that good time tonight.
in this drink, they mix
6 different kinds of liquor,
but it don't taste
too strong.
would you like
a raffle ticket?
they're $2.50
for the car.
thanks, ola.
d.j.: you,
you are the video...
i feel like getting
drunk tonight.
how about you?
when i was a nurse
in vietnam,
i was stuck out in
the middle of the jungle
with the real rambo.
he had the hots for me.
i mean, he was
driving me crazy.
of course, it would be
difficult for anybody
not to fall in love with
you in that humidity.
and i saved his life
about 50 times.
i bet you've seen me
here before.
rrroar! ha ha!
i'm the dancing bear.
hi, louis.
you gonna dance
in the show on friday?
yeah, but...
excuse us.
i'm still having trouble
with ladies.
buddy, i'll tell you.
fact--there are 1/2 million
more single guys
than there are gals,
and the competition is tough.
we're gonna have a good time.
do it to it.
most of them
just want to swing
or aren't
really serious.
some of these gals
are as bad as the guys.
that's mine, there.
i'll take
the red one.
we got a song coming up
calledwild, wild life.
i want you to lip-synch it.
wait! not now.
let me tell you about myself.
see, i'm cute.
hey, ramon. how are you?
good to see you.
partying?
yeah, a little.
want me to read
your tones, man?
yeah. go ahead.
relax.
chihuahua! whew!
hey, don't worry
about it.
you're gonna
be all right, man.
take it easy.
see you later, man.
i guaran-damn-tee you,
you know, traveling
is my life.
i just work at varicorp
for a hobby.
let's go! hello!
ooo!
# i'm wearin' #
# fur pajamas #
# i ride a #
# hot potato #
# it's tickling #
# my fancy #
# speak up #
# i can't hear you #
# here on this mountaintop,
oh ho ho #
# i got some wild, wild life #
# i've got some news
to tell you, whoa ho #
# about some wild, wild life #
# here come the doctor
in charge, oh ho ho #
# she's got some
wild, wild life #
# ain't that the way
you like it? oh ho #
# living wild, wild life #
# i wrestle #
# with your conscience #
# you wrestle #
# with your partner #
# sitting on a windowsill #
# but he spends his time
behind closed doors #
# check out mr. businessman
, oh ho ho #
# he bought
some wild, wild life #
# on the way to
the stock exchange, oh ho ho #
# he got
some wild, wild life #
# break it up when
he opens the door, oh ho ho #
# he's doin' wild, wild life #
# i know that's the way
you like it, whoa oh #
# living wild, wild life #
# peace of mind #
# it's a piece o' cake #
# thought control #
# you get on board
anytime you like #
# like sittin' on #
# pins and needles #
# things fall apart #
# it's scientific #
# sleeping on the interstate,
oh ho ho #
# gettin' wild, wild life #
# checkin' in #
# and checkin' out
uh-huh #
?
# i got a wild, wild life ?
# spending all of my money
and time, oh ho ho #
# done too much
wild, wild life #
# we want to go where we go
where we go, oh ho ho #
# i'm doin' wild, wild life #
# you've grown so tall #
# you've grown so fast,
oh ho ho #
# wild, wild life #
# and i know that's the way
you like it, oh ho #
# livin' wild, wild,
wild, wild #
# whoa ohh #
woo! woo!
tv: the el paso
border patrol...
louis told me
he heard about a woman
who lives around here
and never gets out of bed.
she's not sick.
she's got enough money,
she doesn't have to.
hey, wouldn't you?
if i ever went downstairs,
i might be surprised, huh?
it's clean down there,
isn't it, roberto?
that girl does
a good job, doesn't she?
it's so clean,
it scares me.
the beauty operator
is coming over.
hey, how should i have her
do me this time?
should i get it moussed?
ooo, look at that.
there's a look.
what do you think about
the gals on this show?
these people have too much metal
on them, miss rollings.
they are reflecting
kind of people.
you're right. how are those
shares of varicorp doing?
about 30, 40.
is that all?
that's about it.
well, i'm not surprised.
cheap little pig shits.
it's the same all over.
bunch of maniacs
out there. woo!
you know how hot dogs come
10 to a pack
and buns in packs
of 8 or 12?
you've got to buy 9 packs
to make them all match up.
that's what
i'm talking about.
since this mall opened,
c.r. anthony, jcpenney,
and even duke and ayers
all pulled out
of downtown virgil.
shoppers here go wherever
the bargains are,
wherever it's convenient
to shop.
they don't care if they shop
in a funky old building downtown
or in a clean, modern place
like this.
see, they're wise
to advertisers' claims.
in a place like this,
they can comparison shop.
everybody could hardly wait
until the mall opened...
except margie ortiz.
i go there almost every weekend.
so do 2 other girls from work.
see? i told you.
the shopping mall
has replaced the town square
as the center
of many american cities.
shopping itself has become
the activity
that brings people together.
and here,
the music's always playing.
what time is it?
no time to look back.
men: ha ha ha!
"starving peasants
sell their bodies
to vampires
for blood money!"
ha ha ha!
stores here
are pretty clean.
the air is fresh.
there's plenty of parking,
plenty of space to walk around.
hi, how are you? how
come you're not at work?
oh, i'm working on
a project at home.
i send signals up.
oh, to satellites
and things.
further than that,
i hope.
oh.
hey, i've got to get to work
before all hell breaks loose.
oh.
see you.
people here are inventing
their own system of beliefs.
they're creating it...
doing it...
selling it...
making it up
as they go along.
driving...
not only driving,
but parking.
hey, there's louis!
hi, how you doing?
pretty good.
did you have
any luck at the club?
the women
are too wild.
i had a good time
anyway.
look at these women.
yeah, a little
too old for me.
what are you
doing here?
i thought i'd check out
that fashion show.
part of the celebration.
twins.
carol and daryl.
i knew their mama
in high school.
she was a twin, too.
hi, twins.
i just thought
i'd check it out.
maybe i'd pick up
a few fashion tips.
you know, i'm very aware
of my appearance.
i've noticed.
yeah. well, just
check these out here.
those are great!
yeah.
yep.
like the song says,
it's a scientific
lifestyle.
hmm. i don't know
that one.
p.a.: good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen,
and welcome to
another lovely event
for the celebration
of specialness.
today we have
a fashion show,
and i think it's gonna be
something you'll just love.
it's very unusual.
so come on!
let's bring on the show!
from the dream factory,
a bonanza of beauty!
this place is
filled with women.
kay: i'd like
to remind you
there's another event
this friday night....
that's kay culver.
for the celebration
of specialness.
she's married to earl.
you've heard of him.
he pretty much
single-handedly
brought varicorp
to virgil.
you know, i bet
this mall wouldn't be here
if it wasn't for him.
oh, yeah?
i'm having dinner
with him later.
well, listen.
i heard that earl and kay
haven't spoken to
one another in years...
at least, not directly.
do you believe it?
ok.
what time is it?
if everyone notices,
maybe it's too much.
but where would we be?
$29.95 is
a pretty good price.
with 6 outfits
and as many combinations,
the possibilities are endless.
shopping is a feeling.
sometimes i get
a wobbly feeling.
i have a commercial feeling.
be sexy in business.
be successful at night.
i stole it
off of a spaceship.
...and coordinate
your outfit to match.
let the children
do the shopping.
if the room is pink,
you're in the pink.
you have a right.
it's all you.
there ought to be a law.
# when you were little #
#
# you dreamed you were big
# you must have been something
# a real tiny kid #
# you wish you were me #
# i wish i was you #
# don't you wake up #
#
# the dream will come true
# every dream #
# has a name #
# and names tell your story #
?
# this song is your dream ?
# you're the dream operator #
ohh! ahh!
# it's bigger than life #
# you know it's all me #
# my face is a book #
# but it's not what it seems #
# three angels above #
# the whole human race #
# dreamed us to life #
# they dream me a face #
# and every dream #
# tells it all #
# and this is your story #
# you dreamed me a heart #
# you're the dream operator #
# shake-it-up dream #
# hi-de-ho dream #
# fix-it-up dream #
hmm.
# look at me dream #
# i've been waiting so long #
# now i am your dream #
# hard to forget #
# hard to go on #
# when you fall asleep #
# you're out on your own #
# let go of your life #
# grab onto my hand #
# here in the clouds #
# the world understands #
# and you dreamed it all #
# and this is your story #
# do you know #
# who you are? #
# you're the dream operator #
darling!
you know, i don't think
i've felt this way before.
i know.
me neither.
my stomach feels
all fluttery.
it's great,
though, huh?
yeah, i--i guess.
people at work must think
i'm going nuts, though.
well, if this is
being nuts,
then i don't ever
want to be sane.
ah.
oh, did you fart?
i'm in
construction business.
got work going on
at 5 sites now.
bought me a condo
last week.
shoot, real close to here,
as a matter of fact.
next week, i might buy me
another house.
darlin', i'll tell you what,
i just have a feel for it.
you know what i mean?
of course, bein' overly psychic
sure didn't hurt anything.
it's paid off for me.
listen, mr. frye,
i'll tell you--
fyne.
louis.
louis, darlin',
i'll tell you somethin'
if you promise not to tell
another livin' soul.
now, i'd never tell this
to anybody else,
but i believe that part
of my extrapsychic ability
is connected up with the fact
that i was born with a tail,
a little old bitty hairy thing
about that long.
had it surgically removed
when i was just 5 years old.
my mama kept it in a fruit jar
up in the medicine cabinet
between the cold tablets
and the monkey blood.
i'd get up every mornin'
first thing
and go in there
and brush my teeth
and stare at my own tail
at the same time.
somethin' like that
can give you power,
and that's the truth.
then mama got
a wild hair one sunday
and she decided to go make
a lot of money off of it.
took it out to the swap meet
and sold it to lyndon johnson's
top secret service agent.
and he told a good
personal friend of mine
that he was going to sell it
for even more money
to the smithsonian institute.
i said he might as well.
it wouldn't do him any good.
it wasn't his tail.
gee, i tell you,
i could write a book.
that thing would be
a best seller.
you know, that's funny
you mentioned writing.
i'm...kind
of a writer myself.
is that right?
i wrote me a song
i want to do
at the show friday.
i hope it turns out
all right.
i'm a little nervous.
don't be nervous.
songs are easy.
i wrotebilly jean
and half of elvis' songs.
elvis?
hell, yes. they pay me,
and i keep quiet.
you know,
somebody's got to do it.
excuse me just a minute,
pumpkin.
i'll be right back, ok?
sure.
i'll be right here.
kay: shall we take a moment
and give our thanks?
hmm?
amen.
linda, will you ask
your father
to pass this down
to our guest?
this looks great,
mrs. culver.
dad, will you
pass this down?
oh, yes.
larry, would you
pass this down, please?
thank you.
linda, would you ask
your mother
to pass the mustard
to our guest, please?
mom, dad wants the mustard.
dear.
thank you.
look out for your water, now.
pass it down to our guest.
let me grab one of these.
they're colorful.
linda, would you ask
your mom
how the fashion show went?
mom, how did it go
today?
oh, linda, tell him
it was just wonderful,
although one woman
did have a accident,
but it wasn't
anything serious.
he should have come.
he would have been proud.
it went great, dad.
you should have been there.
maybe next time.
i was there.
i liked it.
i'd never seen
anything like that.
i'd never been to one
of those things before.
you do that
every year?
oh, no, this is just for
the sesquicentennial.
you're in
the parade?
anderson auto
is lending us
a red
convertible.
hmm.
right. larry may have
a future at varicorp.
with his young discipline
and systems consciousness,
he could go a long way,
and varicorp is growing
like there's no tomorrow.
let me show you what
i think is going on.
do you hear music?
is something wrong
with your sister?
mainframe.
microprocessor.
semiconductor.
all right, dad!
now...
if this is the town
and here is
the workplace...
with its goods...
and distribution network...
vroom!
most middle-class people
have worked for large
corporations like varicorp
or for the government
itself,
but now all that's
started to change.
scientists and engineers
are moving off
from those large corporations
like varicorp.
they're beginning to start
their own companies,
marketing new inventions.
excuse me,
mr. culver.
i forgot what
these peppers represent.
ah-ha! it all spins back
to the middle.
here we are right here,
in virgil.
our way of doing business
has been based on the past.
that's why we have to
keep these guys in virgil
even though they
leave varicorp.
for the time being,
it's created
confusion and chaos!
they don't work
for money anymore
or to earn
a place in heaven,
which was
a big motivating factor
once upon a time,
believe you me.
they're working and inventing
because they like it.
economics has become
a spiritual thing.
i must admit,
it frightens me a bit.
they don't see
the difference
between working
and not working.
it's all become
a part of one's life.
linda! larry!
there's no concept
of weekends anymore.
preacher: it thrills me.
it thrills me!
we can build a nation
inside a nation
right where we are.
the choice is yours.
i'm not a joiner.
i'm not a member
of the john birch society
or the communist party,
but let's look
at what's happened
to the national morals
since world war ii.
we lost the vietnam war.
# # #
the movies and the television
are filled with characters
i don't even want to know,
not in this life.
the farmer's in trouble.
the small businessman
is in trouble.
unemployment
is skyrocketing.
texas is still paying
for john kennedy's death,
my friends.
woman: it was love that
killed john f. kennedy.
he should have never
messed with me.
oh, no, i know nothing,
your honor.
they want me to speak
on60 minutes.
mike wallace wants my body.
i don't tell a soul.
well, they gave me
so much money,
what could i do?
umm...thank you.
that's exactly
what i'm talking about.
now, let's look at who's been
running this country
since world war ii.
and they have some
involvement in all of these.
what is the link?
what do cars
have to do with books,
you might ask.
the trilateral commission
with the council
on foreign relations,
did you ever hear of them?
well, neither did i,
until i noticed
the chain of coincidence.
they have members on the boards
of all the largest corporations.
not one detail
has been left out.
am i right?
do you feel it?
do you know what
bobby ray inman was doing
before he was running
the microelectronics
and the computer tech
corporation?
well, guess!
a cia director.
it's public knowledge.
do you run out of kleenex,
paper towels, and toilet paper
at the same time?
you know it's true!
it's all true!
you remember how
governor white
campaigned to
get the mcc here?
do you know
what their goal is, huh?
well, elvis did!
artificial intelligence!
huh?
robots! they'd like that,
wouldn't they?
yes, sir!
sleep! sleep!
one and one
does not equal two!
no, sir!
silicon gulch!
silicon prairie!
silicon hill!
silicon valley!
you'd better wake up.
# it's late #
# you got the cbs #
# and the abc #
# you got
timeandnewsweek#
# they're the same to me #
# now, don't you want to
get right with me? #
# puzzlin' evidence #
# i hope you get
everything you need #
# puzzlin' evidence #
# well, it's-a
puzzlin' evidence #
# puzzlin' evidence #
?
# done hardened in your heart ?
# ohh, hardened
in your heart #
y'all listen.
# now, i am the gun #
# and you are the bullet #
# i got the power and glory #
# puzzlin' #
?
# and the money to buy it ?
# puzzlin' #
# you got your gulf and western
and your mastercard #
# puzzlin' evidence #
# got what you wanted,
lost what you've had #
# puzzlin' evidence #
#
# i'm seein' puzzlin' evidence
# puzzlin' evidence #
# done hardened
in your heart #
# it's hardened up
your heart #
# all right #
are you listenin'?
what i'm sayin' is real.
# huh #
# isn't that puzzlin'? #
# i'm puzzlin' #
# huh #
# well, i hope that you're happ
y with what you've made #
# puzzlin' evidence #
# in the land of the free
and the home of the brave #
# puzzlin' evidence #
# i'm seein'
puzzlin' evidence #
# puzzlin' evidence #
# done hardened
in your heart #
it's true.
ha ha ha!
now, y'all listen
to what i've been
tellin' you today, you hear?
radio: # huh #
# huh #
look at this.
who can say it isn't beautiful?
the sky...
bricks...
who do you think lives there?
four-car garage.
hope...
fear...
excitement...
satisfaction.
i'm going to give you
a clear vista
of the edge
of the civilized world.
it's like a game
of leapfrog.
these houses, they keep
extending the town out
further and further
every year.
it's kind of weird
for the first person
that moves into
a community like this.
i'll bet it is.
it's an imaginary landscape,
a place to raise kids.
of course, nowadays
not everyone's having kids,
with the end of the world
coming up and all.
i mean, would you?
no, not at all.
not until after tomorrow,
after the show, huh?
good morning, boys.
working hard, i see.
a little coffee break?
it's strange
when you look at a field
and you say, "now,
i want a bathroom there
and a kitchen over here."
now, imagine that.
here's a field.
take a look out.
picture a house.
picture a lot of houses.
what else is a field good for
but building houses?
#
# hey, now
# hey, now, now #
# i want a video #
# i wanna rock 'n' roll #
# take me
to the shopping mall #
# buy me a #
# a rubber ball, now #
# hey, now #
# hey, now, now #
# i am
the king of the world #
# the boss
of the boys and girls #
# you can live to 110 #
# if you listen
to what i'm sayin' #
# hey, now #
# hey, now, now #
texas is the largest producer
of metal buildings.
metal buildings are the dream
that modern architects had
at the beginning of this century
finally come true,
but they themselves
don't realize it.
that's because
it doesn't take an architect
to build a metal building.
you just order them
out of a catalogue.
just pick out your color,
the size you want,
number of square feet, style,
what you need it for.
it comes with a bunch of guys.
they put it together in
a couple of days. maybe a week.
there you go. you're all set
to go into business.
just slap a sign in front.
drive on over.
oh. he's gonna get killed!
watch out!
tv: black and decker's
automatic shut-off iron...
because even those
with the best memories
can forget
to turn their irons off.
whoa!
oh, look at him!
look at that bald spot!
i was so impressed,
i bought the company.
oh! lucy!
i love you, lucy!
oh!
ooh!
that's a big one.
live at 5:00.
news at 10:00.
news at 7:00.
news at 9:00.
news at 8:00.
news at 11:30.
suits and ties!
hey, robert, seen this one?
or your money back.
# huh #
# huh huh huh #
# i was born in a house
with the television always on #
# guess i grew up
too fast... #
oh, baby!
work that thing.
work it!
go.
# we got time on our hands #
they look like sticks.
# so leave the driving
to us #
# and it's
the real thing... #
god, they're both
in a straitjacket!
they must've done
somethin' bad.
# and i can love you #
# like a color #
# tv #
# ooh ooh ooh #
# and now love is here #
# come on and try it... #
ohh!
i like that!
# i've got love for sale #
# i've got love for sale... #
i think they're aerobicizing.
# love is here #
# come on and try it #
# dut dut dut dut
dut dut dut dut #
# got love for sale #
a kissing cookie.
i hate that stuff.
it doesn't work.
# huh #
# you can put your lipstick #
# all over my designer jeans #
love chocolate.
?
# i'll be a video for you ?
it's great! they got
that commercial attitude.
# you can cash my check #
# if you go down
to the bank #
# down at the bank #
# you get two for one #
# for a limited time #
# a limited time #
# push my button #
# the toast pops up #
# oh ho ho ho ho #
# love and money #
# getting all mixed up #
# oh ho ho ho ho #
# whooooa #
# now love is here #
# come on and try it #
# dut dut dut dut
dut dut dut dut #
# i got love for sale #
i think they're sellin'
somethin'.
# dut dut dut dut #
# and now love is here #
# come on and try it #
# i got love for sale #
# i got love love
love love #
# love love love love #
tv: today, doesn't someone
besides you
deserve mon cheri?
mon cheri,
the brand of fine chocolates
europeans treasure most.
hello, i'm louis fyne.
i'm lookin' for matrimony
with a capital "m".
i believe in the joys and
contentment of matrimony.
now,
my chances in this world
that prints a new diet book
every month
may not be that good.
i'm lookin' for someone
who can accept me
for what i am.
i'm 6'3" and maintain
a consistent panda bear shape.
i'm pleased with the way
god made me.
i wouldn't change a thing.
i'm willin' to share.
won't you please
call this number?
8-4-4-w-i-f-e.
that's 844-wife.
please call.
serious inquiries only.
mmm.
can you believe that?
woman:
so, umm, louis...
what kind of hobbies
do you have?
do you have any pets?
no, i don't have
any pets.
i, uh...
i had a dog
when i was a boy.
buster.
what kind?
oh, he's every which way.
he's a heinz 57,
i think they call them.
well, they can be
awful cute.
the little
fluffy kind.
you know how they give them
to you in a basket?
they're cute like that.
i like music
a whole lot.
what kind of music?
oh, country music.
you like country music?
oh, you know i do!
well, not
that hollywood country.
oh, hank williams
and merle haggard
and...tammy
and lefty and patsy...
yeah.
mm-hmm.
i think music is one
of the sweetest things,
and if it's sweet,
it's probably cute.
you can't have enough
sweetness in this world.
no, ma'am,
you can't.
as a matter of fact,
i've written a little song
i'm gonna sing at the show
tomorrow night.
it's about my life.
what else do i know, huh?
i'll give you
a little sneak preview.
would you?
you hold on right there.
i hope you like it.
it'd mean a lot to louis.
ahem!
hmm!
# in 195o, when i was born #
# papa--i haven't
written this verse quite yet #
# 6 feet tall #
# and size 12 shoes #
# na na na na
na na na #
# people like us #
# we don't want freedom #
# we, uh,
meow meow meow meow #
# we just want #
# someone to love #
ta-da!
well, what did you think?
when you're singing,
your eye sockets
go back in your head
and your eyes
get beady.
what about my music?
it's awful sad.
i couldn't have that kind
of sadness in my life.
do you really
feel that way?
i'm--i never
thought about it.
maybe i am kind of sad.
i like sad songs.
they make me want
to lie on the floor.
old louis the bear
on the floor.
i guess i'll go now.
sorry.
itwasnice talkin' to you.
louis the bear...
out the door.
good-bye.
cheer up.
a little more bottom.
a little more?
always a little more bottom.
great. ok, let's go
to number 2.
ramon!
you can't come in
without paying.
i don't want to dance.
i just want to
talk to my friend ramon
on the little organ.
# ...ser chicano #
# en los barrios
me pueden encontrar #
# porque ahi
todititos me conocen #
# y ya saben... #
$3.00?
i'm just going to
come right back out.
fine.
# san antonio,
corpus christi y mcallen #
# una tercia que nunca
podre olvidar #
# y si acaso vas alla
por esos barrios #
# mis carnales
te podran alivianar #
# de repente voy
y cruzo la frontera #
# para ir a divertirme
a todo dar... #
ramon!
hey, louis! can you
wait 5 minutes, man?
i got a break.
no.
did you
talk to him?
yeah, man.
you got the photograph?
you got the bucka?
the cash?
thanks.
# ...matamoros
por reynosa #
# da lo mismo porque
alla saben gozar... #
tv:
tv: hold it right there.
hey, officer,
what's going on here?
come on. let's
get out of here.
i said freeze!
what's going on here?
uh...ahem!
ramon gave me
this address.
well, hi.
come on in.
did you bring
a photograph?
thank you.
you know, i'm new at this.
don't matter.
you don't have to believe.
if you follow directions,
you can't go wrong.
mm-hmm.
you want to
attract love.
ha ha!
how did you know?
your heart is too large.
you're an honest man.
matrimony...
it's my life,
and i want to
share my life.
i've tried
everything.
often our true nature
is not what we hope it is,
but you, in your case,
you're drawn to love.
whatever you think
is what you get.
love must be drawn to you.
come on and let me
take care of this here.
discharge
the negative forces
you have involuntarily
received.
remove anything
that's metallic.
now, this will
take some time.
um...
i'm going to sing
tomorrow night.
will this help?
i'll work on you
tonight and tomorrow.
take this.
close this.
like that.
now, drink
3 soda waters a day.
drink half
and throw half away.
yeah. think positive.
don't let nothin' enter into
your mind that's negative.
if you do that and
have faith and believe,
you got it.
it's done.
go...and enjoy
your love life.
sayonara.
man on p.a.:
today, ladies and gentlemen,
all of our friends and
neighbors from virgil, texas,
a very special welcome.
this is the celebration
of specialness.
when the flag goes by
in a few moments,
we want all you kids
to show mom and dad
that we can be respectful
to our national flag.
introducing the famous
soul pompom girls,
cedar crest comets,
and ladies and gentlemen,
just look at the youth
and vivacious experience
of those young pompom girls.
teenagers with a purpose
in mind.
the low-riders.
yay!
the lawn-mower brigade.
this is sponsored by
whitehead hardware store.
entry number 9,
a very, very famous group
here in this part of texas,
the pleasant oaks
majorettes.
and notice that beautiful
purple and silver
that they're wearing.
they're sponsored by our
very own misses fashion depot,
and they've got plenty
of special talent.
ladies and gentlemen,
the pleasant oaks majorettes.
hey!
well, hey!
the bear.
how you doin'?
look at that hat.
great outfit.
thank you.
feelin' good.
introducing
earl and kay culver
and their 2 lovely children,
linda and larry.
i usually
don't like parades.
no.
but this one's
different.
in fact, it's the first time
in 30 years.
earl, we want to thank you
for all the work you've done,
all the committees.
you've been great.
we want to salute you.
few people know he's got a bull
tattooed on his stomach.
earl culver?
coming all the way
from sunset high school
to be in virgil's
special parade,
the ivory and gold
of sunset high school.
see you monday.
...this beautiful music.
ze pereira!
now, i'll guarantee you,
ladies and gentlemen,
here's something you will not
see in many parades.
our very famous visitors,
the red mustang shriners!
a big hand of applause.
now, i want you to notice
that they're driving
with one hand!
we've got
a very special surprise.
i'll bet there's not another
parade that's got babies.
here they come.
here they come!
isn't that adorable?
the future secretaries,
the future farmers...
they're so cute!
no! look at those two!
would you look at
those two babies? oh!
i'm melting!
don't sell them short.
oh! how itsy-bitsy!
hi. hi there.
do you know what
a little doll you are?
let's give a big, big hand to
the accordion band of virgil.
and fans,
don't forget the show tonight.
it's sponsored by varicorp.
it's all local talent.
and don't forget.
that's tonight. the big show.
there'll be chairs
for your convenience,
so you don't have to
sit on your coolers.
let's see.
take, uh, 157 to 287
and then a left
at the k-mart
and then go 2 miles.
i'm getting used to
these outfits.
they sell a lot of them,
but i don't see
anybody else wearing them.
hi out there
and good evening and welcome.
welcome to our talent show
under the stars.
first i want to tell you
a story i heard about texas
recently in a local tavern.
it seems god
was working around here,
trying to make it beautiful
like the rest of the world.
he had to knock off
because it was nighttime.
he said,
"i'll come back tomorrow
"and make it as pretty
as the rest of the world
with lakes and streams
and mountains and trees."
he got back the next day,
and he saw the ground had
hardened like concrete.
and he didn't want to
begin all over again. no.
in his infinite wisdom,
he had an idea.
he said,
"i know what i'll do.
i'll make some people
that like it this way."
i want you to welcome
this first act here.
they'll tell you more
about texas in 5 seconds
than you'd ever
want to know.
i want you to welcome,
please,
charles connour, norm seaton,
and randy erwin.
man: all right!
all right,
ladies and gentlemen,
i bid 10 and 50, 20,
20 and 50, 30.
20. make it 30.
30 make it 40.
# yodel-ay-ee-hee... #
make it 60.
i can talk that fast.
no!
80. will you bid 90?
# yodel-ay-ee-o... #
5-10. 5-20. put up a 20.
give me 25. 30.
30. put up a 40.
5 and a half.
6 and a 5.
# yodel-ay-ee odel-ay-ee
odel-ay-ee... #
600. now 10.
now bid 6-20.
put it with 6-30.
bid 40. 6-40.
put it with 50.
6-50. 6, 7, 8.
put it 6-80. 700.
# yodel-ay-ee... #
7-10. go to 15.
# yodel-ay-eee... #
20. 15. put up a 2o.
15. put up a 20.
7-10 makes 7-20.
stuck on 7-10.
7-10. now 20.
put up a 30.
put up a 40 to 50.
600. 6-10.
make it 20. 6-30.
# doo doo doo doo
doo doo #
# doo #
woo! woo!
divine order,
take charge of my life
today and every day.
all things work together
for good for me today.
this is a new and wonderful
day for me.
there will never be
another one like this one.
i'm divinely guided
all day long,
and whatever i do
will prosper.
pfftt!
divine love, enfold me.
surround me and enrapt me,
and i'll go forth in peace.
i am going to be
a wonderful success
in all of my
undertakings today,
and you are going to be happy
from now on.
shoot.
they've been begging me
to be the lead singer
for this band,
but my managers won't let me
do anything
amateur or local.
then they decided i was
too much like pat benatar.
# transmitter #
# i'm picking up
something good #
# hey, radio head #
# it's the sound #
# of a brand-new world #
# ow! #
# now, you and i
have no secrets #
# now, baby,
let me read your mind #
# i hear everything
you're thinking #
# you can't help
the way you sound #
# transmitter #
# oh, picking up
something good #
# hey, radio head #
# it's the sound #
# of a brand-new world #
# radio head #
# oh, oh, radio head #
# ooo ooo ooo,
radio head #
# yeah, radio head #
# oh, radio head #
# ooo ooo, radio head #
# radio head #
yoambe. yoambe. cimalo.
guede nimbo.
oh.
# you'll be #
# mmm mmm mmm mmm #
# magnet for money #
# you'll be #
# mmm mmm mmm mmm #
# magnet for love #
# you'll feel #
# mmm #
# light in your body #
# now, i'm gonna say #
# gonna say these words #
# rompiendo #
?
# la monotonia del tiempo ?
# rompiendo #
# la monotonia del tiempo... #
i came
to wish you luck.
bless your heart!
# it might #
# mmm mmm mmm mmm #
# it might rain money #
# it might #
# mmm mmm mmm mmm #
# might rain fire... #
you tell him that i never
want to see him again.
that goes for his
coon skin cap as well.
how often have
i told you
not to mix with
that oil-field trash?
dummy: what i do
is between me and rick.
# get yourself a sign #
#
# get your love and desire
# rompiendo #
?
# la monotonia del tiempo ?
# rompiendo #
?
# la monotonia del tiempo ?
# papa legba #
# come and open the gate #
# hey, papa legba... #
how about them old
line dancers?
i don't think
they'd fit in my house.
# to the city of camps #
# we are your children #
#
# come and ride your horse
# in the night #
#
# come and ride your horse
# there is a queen #
# 6, 7, and 9 #
# dust in your garden #
?
# and poison in your mind ?
# there is a king #
# that will steal your soul #
?
# don't let him catch you ?
# don't let him get control #
# papa legba #
# come and open the gate #
# to the city of camps #
# we are your children #
#
# come and ride your horse
# in the night #
#
# come and ride your horse
# in the night #
#
# come and ride your horse
oh, yes.
wasn't that nice?
now, ladies and gentlemen,
i want you to welcome
the country bachelors.
rrr!
# in 1950,
when i was born #
# papa couldn't afford
to buy us much #
# he said be proud
of what you are #
# there's somethin' special
'bout people like us #
# people like us #
# who will answer
the telephone #
# people like us #
# growin' big as a house #
# we're gonna make it
becau-wa-wause #
# we don't want freedom #
# we don't want justice #
# we just want #
# someone to love #
# well, now #
# what good is freedom? #
# god laughs
at people like us #
# i see it comin' #
# like a light
comin' down from above #
# the clouds roll by,
and the moon comes up #
# how long must we live
in the heat of the sun? #
# millions of people
are waitin' on love #
# and this is a song
about people like us #
# people like us #
# who will answer
the telephone #
# people like us #
# growin' big as a house #
# we're gonna make it
because #
# we don't want freedom #
# we don't want justice #
# we just want #
# someone to love #
yay! yay!
more!
hello?
yes.
louis: this place
is a dream palace.
did you see
the catalogue?
oh, no.
i didn't.
it's gorgeous!
you'll have to look.
well,
you're gorgeous.
he's awful cute,
too.
do you like
the colors?
man: she's
pretty, too.
i think you can see
varicorp from here.
where are you going
on your honeymoon?
the bear is
staying with me!
i think
he's from pluto,
or he might even be
from venus.
you know, he is
real good-looking.
this is not a rental car.
this is privately owned.
well...i really enjoyed
forgetting.
when i first come to a place,
i notice all the little details.
i notice the way the sky looks,
the color of white paper,
the way people walk,
doorknobs, everything.
then i get used
to the place,
and i don't
notice those things anymore.
so only by forgetting
can i see the place again
as it really is.
# na na na na na
na na na na na #
# na na nnn nnn
na na nnn nnn #
# na nnn nnn
na na na na #
# na na na na na
nnn nnn #
# nnn nnn nnn nnn
na na na na #
# na nnn na nnn
na nnn... #
# here where you are standing ?
?
# dinosaurs did a dance #
# the indians told a story
#
# now it has come to pass ?
?
# indians had a legend #
# the spaniards lived for gold
#
# white man came
and killed them #
# but they haven't really gone
#
# we live #
# in the city of dreams #
# we drive #
# on this highway of fire ?
?
# should we awake #
# and find it gone #
# remember this,
our favorite town #
# from germany and europe ?
?
# and southern usa #
# they made
this little town here #
# that we live in
to this day #
# the children
of the white man #
# saw indians on tv #
# and heard about the legend #
# how their city was a dream #
# we live #
# in the city of dreams #
# we drive #
# on this highway of fire ?
?
# should we awake #
# and find it gone #
# remember this,
our favorite town #
# the civil war is over #
# and world war i and ii #
# if we can live together ??
# the dream,
it might come true #
# underneath the concrete #
# the dream is still alive #
# 100 million lifetimes #
# a world that never dies #
# we live #
# in the city of dreams #
# we drive #
# on this highway of fire ?
?
# should we awake #
# and find it gone #
# remember this,
our favorite town #