Thank you.
- Thank you.
My life is nothing less
than a festival.
A never ending festival.
In which I am the host
as well as the guest.
Me and my alcohol have too much...
...fun all through the
nights together.
There isn't anyone to ask me.
There isn't anyone to stop me.
And when morning arises...
...I go back to those four walls...
...which are regarded as
a home by sundry people.
The car of my life is going
on this same speed.
I ride this car.
But I don't have any idea as to...
...where it's steering wheel is.
In fact, I didn't even know that...
...my car would stop at
a signal very quickly.
The first raindrops would
bring such a moment...
...with them, after
which everything...
...would change for ever and ever.
Police station? Police station?
Why don't you take a job
in the police station?
Come here.
- Yes sir.
Give an orange juice.
- Yes Sir.
Just a minute. Give coffee.
- Yes sir.
Without milk.
Greetings sir.
- Greetings.
I have come for his bail.
You are his father?
I get the salary of a butler,
but I work as a father.
Yes?
Twenty two years, eleven
months and nine days.
And since yesterday night, it is...
...sixteen hours that I
am staying with him.
I worry more for him than myself.
I stay so worried for him...
There will rarely be any
dad worried so much.
See.
I haven't yet been able
to understand...
...as to how are you related to him.
Please let it be, sir.
The mind cannot understand...
...the relations of the heart. So...
...what has this child done?
Has he committed some serious crime?
Please have a seat.
Yes sir. Thank you.
Thank you, inspector.
Thank you. Thank you.
- Okay.
It is good that the girl didn't
set a police complaint.
She just had you beat up and
let you go. What is it?
Didn't you get any of my principles?
You saw a girl on the street.
And you kissed her
in broad daylight?
You stay that I stay
away from girls.
But the girl was something
like this.
I don't know. My feet
just walked up to her.
I couldn't tolerate it.
You mean, because of you...
...the girls should stop
going out on the streets?
It doesn't matter, son. Come home.
The limousine is waiting for you.
The limousine?
- Yes. - Daddy? - Yes.
No, uncle. I won't go
alone. You will...
...have to come with me. Please!
Oh. How will you not go alone? Even
your father will go. All alone.
In your father's presence. Come on.
You are keeping the
family's prestige.
Drunkard.
You are a very weak man.
I pity you.
Dad, if you had to tell me this...
...you could have told
it over the phone.
What was the need of sending... a
limousine and calling me here?
I have called you here
to talk about marriage.
Marriage?
With Anahita Madhwani.
- Anahita Madhwani!
No. Dad.
I can't do this marriage. Please.
It is my wish. It is your
grandmother's wish.
And Devendra Madhwani wishes it too.
Dad, Devendra Madhwani,
rogue, criminal.
How can he become my father-in-law?
Who isn't a criminal today?
In the business circle, everyone...
...is a criminal on a smaller
of higher level.
It will be better...
...that you pay attention
to the wealth that...
...you will get by marrying
Anahita Madhwani.
Dad see.
I will marry when I
meet such a girl...
...who will love me and I can
love her too. All right.
Bye.
If you don't agree you will
lose 100 million dollars.
You will be disowned from my will.
Mittal house will close it's
doors on you forever.
You will have to do hard work.
And you will have to earn yourself.
Actually, Anahita isn't
that bad a girl.
She is a very sweet girl.
I am ready for the marriage.
Wonderful.
Congratulations. Son.
Congratulations.
Madhwani will be very
happy hearing this.
Come on, give me a hug.
Give me a hug.
Son. Taking this decision,
you have taken the...
...certificate of being rich
all through your life.
After mummy's death, what have...
...I got from you and this family?
Except wealth? Yes?
Are you thinking of filling
the swimming pool...
...with alcohol and jumping in it?
Jumping?
John uncle, please move from my way.
I am very angry. I don't want to...
Oh go! Wow! You can show
this arrogance to me.
He doesn't even squeak
to his father, ma'am.
What is your name?
What should I do then? Should
I fight? Should I scream?
He won't give me one rupee.
I will move around
hungry and thirsty.
You will like it then.
John uncle...
This isn't the marriage
of two people.
This is the marriage
of two bank accounts.
Two bank accounts.
Eight days. Just eight days.
And that Anahita Madhwani...
...will be clasped to
my neck permanently.
And my dad will have a jackpot
permanently, okay?
Do you know what the people...
...in rural areas do
to catch a monkey?
They put some peanuts in a pot...
...and keep it in front
of the monkey.
The monkey puts his hand in the pot.
He clenches the peanuts
in his palm...
...and he gets stuck up there itself.
Then he can't take his
hand out from the pot.
Because, to remove his
hand from the pot...
...he will have to let
go of the peanuts.
Your situation is just
like that monkey.
You want to be free too. But...
...you cannot live without
the peanuts too.
Did you like my philosophy?
I didn't understand that.
- Good.
John uncle, I don't understand...
...anything about this monkey.
- Okay.
I am in a bad state.
Wherever I see...
...that female monkey
Anahita Madhwani...
...is jumping and clenching at me.
Who is she?
What happened?
- That... - What?
The kiss girl.
- The kiss girl?
At the bus stop.
- Oh!
The one who made you go to
the police station? - Yes.
She is stealing tie.
Don't look there. Let
her steal comfortably.
Look at me...
- Oh oh!
Oh! How the hell are you
related with that?
Bye bye.
Excuse me.
Madam, just a minute.
Excuse me. Madam just a minute.
Just a minute, madam. Madam,
just a minute.
What is it?
- I want to speak to you.
What do you want to speak about?
The item that you took from inside...
...did you pay for it?
- What did you say?
It is in your bag... here...
- What?
Don't touch!
- What did you say?
What do you think you are?
Tell me your name.
Madam... it is in your bag...
it is in your bag
What is there in my bag?
- Don't you know who I am? - Madam...
Please listen to me...
- I will make one phone call...
- Madam, please listen to me... -
This uniform that you have worn...
...you will wear it all through
the night and sleep.
You should be given to the police.
- Madam...
Somebody call the police.
- Please madam. Please...
Police! Police!
- I will show you right away.
Ram Singh... what are you doing
here leaving your work?
Mr. Mittal, it is a
very small matter.
No, what is the matter?
- Please don't meddle.
No. What... what... what?
What is the matter?
Sir. You don't know.
This madam has brought
a tie from inside.
Without paying for it.
See. See it in her bag.
- Brought a tie? - Yes.
Look at it in her bag.
In the bag?
- Yes. Look at it in her bag.
Give me the bag.
- No. - Hold this.
Look at this.
Oh! For me!
Thank you! Come here, baby. Come.
I love you so much.
Sorry for that day.
- Shut up, okay.
Sir.
Sir...
Get lost. Get lost.
Hey, auto...
Hey, for that day...
- Don't take a...
...step ahead or I will
slap you very hard.
Okay... I will... I will
drop you home...
Wow.
Stealing and attitude on top of it.
Now I came to know that the girl...
...whom I kissed wasn't
anything common.
She was dynamite.
If I would try to find out
anything more than that.
Her slap would have turned
into a blast too.
All of a sudden, there was
a fire in the chest.
The heart yearned to meet her again.
Brother Nikki... here is your tie.
Tie! Tie! Tie!
That's enough. Enough of this love.
I don't understand what
you do of these ties.
Do you know how many problems
are there in bringing these ties?
Yes... come on now...
Oh God! Brother! You
have so many ties?
You don't wear them. What
do you do of them?
You will have to tell me today.
Tell me.
Come here.
Come here, please.
Please come here.
Sit down here.
For my sake. Tell me. What
will you do of these ties?
Tell me...
I will wear it on a suit.
- You will wear it on a suit? - Yes.
Where will you wear a suit?
- In your marriage.
In my marriage?
How will I marry?
You know what I do.
Who will marry me?
- A prince.
A prince?
- Yes, a prince.
Where will a prince come from?
Will he waiting for me
on the streets? - Yes.
Yes?
- Open your mouth.
The Prince. The prince.
The prince, the prince, the prince.
Wow!
This is me?
And this, with the tie?
'I love you.'
'I love you till the
limits of craziness.'
'Don't make me crazy till
the limits of craziness.'
'O beloved... '
'Ask me, how much I love you.'
'I love you.'
'I love you till the
limits of craziness.'
'Don't make me crazy till
the limits of craziness.'
'This isn't a game.'
'To fall in love with anyone.'
'Don't forget me after falling
in love with me.'
'This isn't a game.'
'To fall in love with anyone.'
'Don't forget me after falling
in love with me.'
'O beloved! Ask me, how much I
love you.'
'O beloved! Ask me,
how much I love you.'
'I love you.'
'I love you till the
limits of craziness.'
'Don't make me crazy will
the limits of craziness.'
'Why have I started becoming
restless now? '
'What should I tell you, what
has happened to me now.'
'Why have I started becoming
restless now? '
'What should I tell you, what
has happened to me now.'
'O beloved, what situation
I am in, ask me!
'O beloved, what
situation I am in! '
'I love you.'
'I love you till the
limits of craziness.'
'Don't make me crazy till
the limits of craziness.'
'O beloved! Ask me,
how much I love you.'
'I love you till the
limits of craziness.'
'Don't make me crazy till
the limits of craziness.'
Out. Out.
Don't take her in and bring her.
Come on.
To whom will she come in the
times of need if not you?
Hey Reshma! Don't butter me.
Her needs are never fulfilled.
If it is her brother's problem.
She dances on my head.
If it is the problem
of her land lord...
...she comes to dance on my head.
If you want to dance...
...why don't you go to
the stage and dance?
But where can she do that too?
I will go home at eleven o' clock.
I won't go out with anyone.
I won't sit with anyone
and drink alcohol.
She will just ask a loan from
me and drink my blood.
Brother...
Doesn't she create magic
when she is on stage?
Reshma!
Don't waste your time
in her problems.
You go and do your work.
I won't give her anything.
She hasn't returned the loan...
...and she is talking...
- Come on.
Please forgive me. You go.
Oh! Go!
Jiya...
Bye.
- Bye.
Good morning.
Wherever you see, he follows me.
Oh!
Come with me and don't turn around.
What... what happened?
- Silent. - Let me go inside.
Where do you want to go?
I have to take the rent
for the house from Jiya.
Hey, don't talk...
- I know she is inside there.
She is not here.
- Let me go inside.
Hey, what are you doing?
I will take my rent today.
Thank you.
Hey!
Don't you think that
fate is trying...
...to make us meet repeatedly?
I mean... you know...
No?
- Taxi!
Okay. I have a car.
I can drop you home.
You are chasing me. Stay away.
By the way, there is
a restaurant nearby.
We can go and have food, have
some coffee. Something...
If I had free time, I
would be in the bar.
I would be dancing
and earning money.
I can give you money.
Just because I dance in a bar...
...it doesn't mean that I am
a prostitute, understood?
See. You misunderstood me.
I was just speaking about coffee.
That... that too, in
a public place, okay?
Your like...
This means... that you want
to just spend time with me?
That will take money.
Yes. How much? Two thousand... three
thousand. - Three thousand.
All right.
Only one hour.
- Okay. All right.
And don't come close to me.
- No.
I don't have many friends.
But the ones who are, call me Daksh.
What is your name?
- Why should I tell you?
Wow! Your parents have
named you so nicely.
Why should I tell you? Very nice.
- Jiya.
If you just keep babbling
like this, I am going.
Okay. After this, I won't
utter another syllable.
That's it.
From this time, My name
is Deaf and Dumb.
Very funny.
Thank you.
- Sorry.
Oh god!
The time is done, the money is over.
Is it necessary to go? Please
stay some more. - Bye.
Okay, if I wish, you can
stay for some more time.
According to your way.
Yes. Your way.
I can arrange as much
money as you want.
Only one week.
You seriously have some problem
If you really have so much
money you should go to...
...a good psychiatrist and
cure yourself. Okay?
We will never meet after today.
What rubbish.
See, fate is trying to make
us meet again and again.
Who knows? What if this fate
unites us forever and ever?
Fate didn't make us meet.
I came according to my own.
That means you don't
believe in fate?
No. Fate is for rich
people like you.
People like us move with
our fates in our pockets.
Okay. Just a second, just a second.
One second please.
Do you have a pen?
What?
If fate wishes that we should
unite forever see...
...sometime or the other this
note will surely reach you.
All right?
Two candy floss please. Pen.
Candy floss.
I have an idea. You go to America.
I have heard...
...there are very good psychiatrists
there. Bye.
Okay, before going, some address...
...phone number, just tell me...
I just came with you,
because I needed money.
No address. No telephone number.
And don't follow me.
How much did you drink?
Wow! It is a miracle today.
You didn't drink any.
Otherwise, your whole
body stinks of alcohol.
Are you all right, son?
Yes.
Then?
Because I met her last night too.
Okay... that tie thief? Okay. Okay.
So you didn't drink because of her?
Wow.
I didn't feel like drinking.
- Oh God!
And whenever she meets me,
I won't drink. - Oh God!
She is a very good girl.
She is honest.
She is smart.
She is smarter than you.
Play son. Play. Play till
you feel like it.
And then throw her away.
Rich son of a rich father.
Won't you marry the girl
whom you father chooses?
Come on. I can sleep a bit,
now that you have come.
Move it. Yes.
Come on.
Oh! Very good. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
Wow.
Girl friend?
Good. Good. Good.
Take it. Take the comb.
Become smart.
What!
Taxi...
Hey! Hey!
Nikki! Nikki son, come
back down here.
Please come down. Please...
please come down.
See, Jiya has come.
Let me go. Move aside.
Please come down.
What happened to him?
- No, madam.
When the ward boy went to
clean the room Nikki...
...wasn't in the room. He
went to the terrace...
...and closed the door.
And he started saying...
...that he will jump down. It
is more than an hour, madam.
I will go upstairs.
See. There isn't any way to go up.
You don't go upstairs.
You stay here.
We are there, isn't it?
- Oh! Him!
Come down. Come down, Nikki.
Come down, Nikki!
Nikki!
I will jump! I will jump!
I will jump!
Please don't jump. I have come.
I will jump.
Bring him down.
Hi!
You... you... you... what
are you doing here?
Good question. What am I doing here?
Yes. I had come with your sister.
- Sister?
Yes. Your sister is
down there, isn't it?
Sister. I will jump down!
Yes. I came here and I saw
that you are jumping.
See. I don't have any problem.
Jump from here.
But before going, tell me something.
Why are you jumping?
That... Biba... Biba... that
rascal Biba... - Yes?
He took four of my ties!
- He took four of your ties?
Yes. Biba the rascal!
Then... so what if he took
four of your ties?
How will I wear a tie
on my sister's wedding?
How will I wear it?
- Oh! Very sad.
It doesn't matter. I have many ties.
I have ties of every color.
- Yes?
I have red tie, I have a blue
tie, I have a green tie.
Suit... do you have a suit?
Yes. I have a suit too. I
have a suit of every color.
Red suit, blue suit, green suit.
You don't have maroon...
you don't have maroon.
I have a maroon suit.
I have twelve dozen maroon suits.
Give me one, give me
one, give me one.
What is the need of giving you?
You are jumping from here.
I won't jump. I won't
jump. I won't jump.
Give me one. Give me one.
I will do like this. I will give
the maroon suit to someone else.
I will give it to Biba.
No! Not Biba! Biba the
rascal! Not Biba!
Give it to me please!
Please give me one.
One. Just one.
Yes. Okay.
Okay. I will give you the suit.
Give me your hand.
Give me your hand, or
I will give it to Biba.
No. Not Biba! Not Biba!
Biba rascal! Not Biba.
Give me your hand.
Nikki brother!
Some one stop him!
Oh! Help me! Help me!
You have a maroon suit, isn't it?
- Yes, I have a maroon suit.
You have a tie too?
I want the maroon suit.
Just the maroon suit.
Yes. I have a maroon suit.
- Promise?
Yes. Promise, promise. Promise.
I want a tie too, give me a tie too.
Maroon suit. You have a
maroon suit, isn't it?
Yes. I have the maroon suit.
- You give me a tie too.
I have twelve dozens.
I have twelve dozen maroon suits.
I will take one. I will take one.
Come on. Nikki. Come on, Nikki.
Yes, you have come?
- Yes I have come.
Come on. Come on, Nikki.
- Yes, come on.
Tie... tie... tie...
- Come on, come on, come on.
Will you take one?
- Yes, it is all right.
Bye.
- Bye.
Listen...
Will you meet me tomorrow?
17th Victoria cross road?
South?
Ten O'clock.
'I have decided.'
'Whatever be the case,
I will love you.'
'I have decided.'
'Whatever be the case,
I will love you.'
'I have decided.'
'This is the separation
of a few days.'
'This is a distance of a few days.'
'Then, every season
is that of meeting.'
'Then every moment is so saffron! '
'What should I tell you
about the state of this...
...heart? I cannot
tell you anything.'
'You have made me so restless.'
'I cannot stay apart from
you even for a moment.'
'I have decided.'
'Whatever be the case,
I will love you.'
'I have decided.'
'I didn't say anything with words.'
'I said everything without
saying anything.'
You gave me the gift
of my love freely.'
'There wasn't such fun ever.'
'There wasn't such a
season before this.'
'Before I met you, there was
loneliness in my life.'
'I have decided.'
'Whatever be the case,
I will love you.'
'I have decided.'
'Whatever be the case,
I will love you.'
'I have decided.'
The shoe is broken.
It doesn't matter. Come on.
No.
- Come on. I won't bite.
Come on!
Jiya, do you know?
I never looked after anyone in life.
Always, someone has looked after me.
God forbid that you
fall ill someday...
...or something happens to you...
...then I will come
to look after you.
Okay.
Then I will fall ill today itself.
And then I will stay ill
throughout my life.
Then I will take care
of you throughout life.
Daksh...
- Yes?
Tell me something.
Who are you?
Are you the one who
came on the streets...
...and kissed me like
a shameless person?
Or are you the one who
shied away from me now?
I don't know.
I am a bit impulsive.
Who himself doesn't
know what he will do.
Jiya, I am like this since my birth.
I have done everything
wrong since birth.
But not any longer.
Now. Whatever I do, I
will think about it.
And I will do it in the right way.
- How?
You won't laugh?
- No.
Promise?
- Promise.
The elder's permission is taken
for marriage, isn't it?
I will come to your house tomorrow.
You call your brother.
I will come to your house tomorrow...
...and ask your brother for
your hand in marriage.
I will take his permission
for marriage.
Yes?
See, you are laughing. I know
that I do everything wrong.
No, you fool.
I am laughing so that
I can stop my tears.
Do you know?
I thought that all this only
happens in fairy tales.
Every girl isn't lucky
like Cinderella.
But I am.
So, I can come to your
house tomorrow?
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
What happened?
Did you change your decision?
No. Before meeting your
brother I will have...
...to take permission
from someone else.
Whom?
Hitler.
You fool!
The doctor tells me...
Leave smoking the hookah
or else you will die.
I said... you fool!
I have got just one life.
If I don't smoke the hookah
in that fie on my life!
Come on! Come on! Take a puff too!
The thing that isn't coming
from your tongue to words...
...that will come out as
soon as you take a puff.
Come on! Take this! Take a puff.
Did you enjoy it? Did you enjoy it?
Now, tell your grandma clearly.
What is your problem? Yes.
Grandma, I don't want
to marry Anahita.
Really?
Grandma, a few days ago,
I met a girl.
You are just like your grandfather.
If your grandfather liked someone...
...he would get ready to marry her.
Your grandpa's grandpa
made him understand...
...that if you want to drink the
water from a well, drink it.
But what is the need of bring
the well in the house?
Did you understand what I am saying?
Paani Puri! Paani Puri!
We will have 'Paani Puri'! Bring
it fast, Rosie, yes!
Yes. This is something.
Tell me something, Rosie?
- Yes?
Is my grandson handsome?
Yes. He is very handsome.
Oh! He has shied away! Okay,
you go. Go. - Yes.
This girl, whom you met a few...
...days ago who is she after all?
What does it matter, grandma? She
is a nobody. But I love her.
Listen.
You are accustomed to wealth.
You move around in the
biggest of cars.
You drink the most
expensive alcohol.
You are not able to live the
life of poverty now. Yes.
You will have to marry Anahita.
This grandma... and your father.
They are very dangerous.
If you don't listen
to us, you wont...
...get anything from the
wealth of this family.
I will shut down your bank account.
I will snatch your credit card!
I am a bitch! I am a bitch!
- Grandma...
Listen.
You are my small and innocent child.
See.
Shall I tell you a way to come out
of this quicksand of this heart?
Do one thing.
Marry Anahita.
And make this nobody your mistress.
She is happy too, we are happy too.
Grandma...
- Shut up.
Shut up! Shut up!
'This is an ebbing color.'
'Lt has scattered on my veil.'
'All the aroma is
in my embrace now.'
'My feet don't settle
on the ground.'
'This is a strange mischief
within me.'
'Today, I feel that
I am in the breeze.'
'I have got such happiness today.'
'My heart is not in
my control today.'
'I have got such happiness today.'
'Today, I feel that
I am in the breeze.'
'The meeting of a moment
has colored now.'
'The meeting of a
moment has colored now.'
'Lt has become a guest
forever and ever.'
'I have got such happiness today.'
'Lt has become a guest
forever and ever.'
'I have got such happiness today.'
'The beauty of shyness
has draped me today.'
'Lt seems that I have
become a bride.'
'I have got such happiness today.'
'Lt seems that I have
become a bride.'
'I have got such happiness today.'
He has come. He has come.
He has come.
Brother... brother... sit down...
phone... yes, phone.
Hello.
Hello, Jiya.
You aren't coming?
Sorry, Jiya.
I can't come today. I am sorry.
It's okay. If not today,
some other time.
Tomorrow?
Jiya. Actually, I can't
come tomorrow too.
Actually. I won't be able
to meet you from today.
I am to be engaged, Jiya. I am sorry.
It doesn't matter.
At least we got to spend some
moments of life together.
Thank you, Daksh.
Come on, brother.
- He will come.
He will come. He will
come. He will come.
Nobody will come.
- He will come.
Didn't I tell you that
nobody will come?
Nobody will come.
John uncle!
Yes sir, tell me.
Are you John uncle? Did I call you?
Go away from here.
- Sorry sir. - Wait.
I am sorry.
I am taking someone's
anger on someone.
No problem sir, no problem.
Where is John uncle?
- Sir, he has gone to the hospital.
What has happened to him?
Son. I am dying. I am dying.
John uncle, what childishness
is this?
Son, my thirty suits,
my fifteen shoes...
...my twenty ties and
my property in Goa...
I will make all of
them in your name.
John uncle, you stop this joke.
Or should I go from here?
This isn't a joke.
I have brain tumor.
- I am going.
This isn't a joke.
- I don't want to talk to you.
- Hey, wait! Come back.
I am all right. Come on. Come on.
Will you joke again?
What is it? You don't let
me act properly too.
Come on.
How are you?
- I am all right. I am all right.
Should I bring something
from outside?
Yes.
From outside...
...you bring for me the medicine
to become young.
I want to become young.
Bring a bit of years
for me from outside.
No reaction.
Everything is all right, isn't it?
I have told Jiya...
...that I am about to be engaged.
That's good.
So you have understood
this in the end...
...that life isn't any
book or any film...
...which we can make
or break anytime.
Actually, our life...
Even though it is ours,
it isn't ours.
It walks according to someone...
...else's whims till
the time that we die.
Come on, whatever you did was good.
In fact, whatever you say...
She is a dancer after
all, isn't she?
A bar dancer...
John uncle, if you say another
word about Jiya it won't be good.
I haven't got another girl
like Jiya till today.
What has happened to you?
Even you have...
...started to speak like
daddy and grandma.
I don't believe this.
Hey! At least listen,
please listen.
Daksh, what will you do now?
Hello, Mr. Madhwani.
Good evening, Mr. Mittal.
Bless me, Father Bhisma.
Anahita, see who has come.
Your to be husband has arrived.
Come on down quickly or else...
...I will cancel this marriage.
I will call it off.
Anahita was waiting for you.
She has gone to change her clothes.
Till that time...
...would you like to wait in
the living room for her?
Obviously, I can't wait
in the bathroom, can I?
Thank you.
Father.
I become very nervous thinking...
...about this marriage
and this engagement.
I get very scared.
I don't know what happens to me.
Please tell me what I should do.
You know what I am talking about?
Hello, Daksh.
Mr. Madhwani.
You are here?
I was searching for you all around.
You... - What were you saying?
What was I saying, father?
I was telling something to you.
- You go.
Daksh. Not you.
You are here too?
That too, just half?
Where is your backside?
Do you remember what I was saying?
Do you know why nobody
drinks in our family?
Because after drinking...
...a man doesn't have sense...
...as to what he is saying,
why is he saying...
...and to whom is he saying...
...and what he is doing.
A drunkard is always confused.
He cannot decide as
to what he wants.
Actually, you are right, sir.
Even I am confused a it
about this marriage.
Yes.
I think that the time has come...
...that the two of us should
know each other now.
Daksh...
I wasn't born in a rich
household like you.
I earned everything with
these two hands of mine.
I achieved everything.
At the age of eighteen,
I was a millionaire.
At the age of fifteen,
I had a killed...
...a man with the bullets
of this gun.
Do you know why?
Because he had barged
into my house...
...to steal my hard earned money.
I remember the day even today.
As soon as the man started...
...running with the money
from my cupboard...
I... bang bang.
I put two bullets into him.
And that thief.
He fell down on the carpet
of my living room and died.
Shameless.
First of all he came
to steal and then...
...he dirtied your carpet? Very bad.
You think that every thing
I say I is a joke?
Daksh...
Do you know what the most priceless
thing in my life is?
What, sir?
My daughter, Anahita.
Yes.
She is my Kohinoor diamond.
Daksh...
I am a very bad man.
Anahita loves you very much.
And I wish that...
...that you keep her happy.
You give her every happiness
of the world.
I will try.
No tries! You will keep her happy.
Till the time I am happy,
I am happy, understood?
And yes...
You will have to stop drinking.
What about alcohol, I am
ready to leave this life.
Hi!
Shall we go?
- Yes.
Goodbye dad!
- Bye bye, child.
Waiter!
Waiter, come here.
Come here. Come here.
Yes, sir.
My doctor has said that
if I want to be alive...
...l'd have to drink at least
10 scotch whiskies in 1 hour.
If you want me to be alive...
...then bring 1 large
scotch whisky for me.
Ok, sir.
- Go.
Well everyone, mind your
own business please.
Calm down.
Calm down. What's wrong?
Who's missing you, when I am here?
This ring...
...was gifted by my grandfather
to my grandma.
Ooh... Wow!
Both are dead.
Today I am giving this ring to you.
Please keep it carefully with you.
I don't know what will happen to me?
Oh Daksh!
Daksh, I was waiting
for this since ages.
I still can't believe this.
You are giving this ring to me.
I can't believe that we are
going to get married soon.
I don't believe that very soon,
we are going to have kids.
Are you ok?
I think you wanna
puke? Puke, right?
Go. Go from here.
Just get out from here.
Go away. Go away.
Go to the loo.
Oh God!
Jiya, I am back.
Jiya open the door.
Jiya, open the door.
Hi, Jiya.
Sorry.
You were missing me, right?
I was missing you too.
Sorry.
Leave it.
You are so drunk, that you
can't even stand properly.
Why have you come here?
Go to her, whom you are marrying?
Go and let me sleep.
I have work tomorrow.
Bye.
You had come so late at night
just to say good bye.
Answer me.
Actually I had come
To give you this.
Take it.
A cheque for 5 crores.
This is for you from me.
No, you don't have to
dance and earn money.
You can buy a bungalow with this.
You can buy a car.
Money really means big.
What?!
So what if am getting
married somewhere else?
I love only you.
We will stay together.
We will be happy forever.
What?!
You'll marry someone else
and I'll stay with you?
I thought you were my
prince charming...
...whom I was waiting
since my whole life.
What do you want to
prove by giving this?
Jiya, keep it. You
need this... please.
I despise myself... that I loved you.
Those people are much
better than you?
At least they take out the money...
...and ask, what's your price?
At least they don't pretend love.
Jiya, please listen to me.
I will dance in the
bar my whole life.
But I'll never become your mistress.
I'll never become your mistress.
Did you get me?
Jiya, please listen...
- Get lost from here!
Jiya, I am sorry...
Just get out!
Jiya, listen...
- Get lost from here!
Just get out!
Please listen to me! - Just get out!
Get out!
Jiya, please listen to me.
Jiya, I am sorry.
I am sorry, Jiya.
I am sorry.
Jiya, I am sorry.
Sir, we couldn't find
Daksh anywhere?
You couldn't find him?
- Yes, sir.
Not anywhere?
- No, sir.
Not even that wretched Anahita
know where he is?
No, sir. I have rifled
through all the bars.
We couldn't find him anywhere.
I had told you not
to leave him alone.
Now, it's so late in the night
and he's not to be found.
Sir, we made a mistake.
What shouldn't we do now?
To hell with you!
He won't even let me die peacefully
in the hospital.
Tomorrow... is his engagement...
And who knows where the heck he is?
'She's annoyed with me.'
'I am annoyed with her.'
'But it feels like I
should talk to her.'
'Her style is different
from this world.'
'I feel like giving up
my life for her style.'
'She's annoyed with me.'
'I am annoyed with her.'
'How can I say to him what
my feelings are for him? '
'I can't even live without
telling him that.'
'How can I say to him what
my feelings are for him? '
'I can't even live without
telling him that.'
'I swear on love that in love...
...I wish to cross all limits.'
'She's annoyed with me.'
'I am annoyed with her.'
'But it feels like I
should talk to her.'
'He's annoyed with me.'
'I am annoyed with him.'
I'll call back afterwards.
Just a minute. You wait here.
This is a bar and not
a government office.
Get out from here.
We won't get along now.
'My heartfelt prayers
are of help now.'
'I get relief for at least a while.'
'My heartfelt prayers
are of help now.'
'I get relief for at least a while.'
'Ln the beautiful arms of my lover...
...I feel like crying my heart out.'
'He's annoyed with me.'
'I am annoyed with him.'
'But it feels like I
should talk to her.'
'Her style is different
from this world.'
'I feel like giving up
my life for her style.'
'He's annoyed with me.'
'I am annoyed with him.'
Today, I'll tell you
the naked truth.
There are two types of
woman in this world.
One. She wears the nuptial thread.
She adorns her head
part with vermilion...
...and she sleeps only with one man.
Only one man uses her.
She makes her conceive kids.
What does she get in return?
Money, food and house... right?
And second type is like me...
...who earns money herself...
. and takes care of all
her needs herself.
And you have the third
way before you.
And I think that's better
than the rest.
You will get money...
house and freedom.
And above that you get
the one who loves you.
What more do you want?
Wife or mistress.
The difference is just a word.
Sometimes, you have to think
of your own happiness too.
Don't think too much.
Become his mistress.
I don't know, why
am I living at all?
I am a failure in life.
No one loves me.
What did you say?
No one loves you... huh?
You are the spoilt child
of a rich father.
Your mother had died when
you were very small.
If I had brought you
up using the rod...
...I wouldn't have had to see
your sorrowful pretense.
Do you know, you are among
the lucky persons...
...in the world who have everything.
But even though you
have everything...
...it's not enough for you.
Today, you are feeling
that no one loves you.
Do you know why?
Because today for the first
time you have known life.
Mr. Daksh Mittal...
Do you know there are many
people in the world...
...who have never seen
love in their lives.
They die without loving
anyone or getting love.
Go and take a bath.
You still stink of liquor. Go.
One more thing.
Henceforth, if you say
that no one loves...
...l'll not slap you but I'll
punch you right in the face!
Because I love you very much.
I am sorry.
Son, marry Anahita.
It's very difficult
to live a poor life.
But I want to marry Jiya.
It's better if you grow up,
while I am still alive.
What will happen to you,
if I am not around?
Out of question.
You can't move out from your bed.
Then it's out of question that
you get out of this hospital!
Doctor, I must go.
Or else it will mean
trouble... please.
See this. 1,50,000 are just
a normal platelet count.
Your count has reduced to 20,000!
No, I am sorry. I can't
give you the permission.
Doctor, it's just a question
of half an hour.
I'll be back in an instant.
Ok, Mr. John D'costa.
Please sign this undertaking.
I will not be responsible
for anything.
Why are you hell-bent
on committing suicide?!
Doctor, life is just like
that unfaithful wife...
...who leaves her husband
stranded in bad times.
Why should I cry over such a life?
I'll sign it.
Yes, please may I know
what do you want?
I am Uncle John of Daksh.
He must have told you about me.
- Yes, please come in.
Thank you!
Come in.
Please come in.
Please have seat.
I have come to tell you that...
...tomorrow night... Daksh's
wedding will take place...
...in his father's house.
In Mittal house.
And I think that you must go there.
Have you invited all the
girlfriends of Daksh?
Daksh is not a commodity kept
in a departmental store...
...that you can steal so easily.
You have to win him over.
But, how can I go on his engagement?
Listen Jiya, I know him very well.
He needs you.
He loves you very much.
Listen to me. You must
go to the party.
Destiny always plays such
strange games with lovers.
Your love story can take
a new twist any moment.
Are you all right?
- I am fine. - Please sit down.
Sit down. I will bring
water for you.
I hope you are all right?
Yes, I am fine. I am fine.
Does Daksh know that you have
come to say this to me?
He's a poor kid.
If he had this much sense...
...then this problem would
never have arisen.
You really love Daksh very much.
Just like a mother.
This is my job.
And I love doing this job.
In fact I would suggest you
to do this job after me.
And I guarantee you 100
0/0 job satisfaction.
After you!? Where are you going?
I have brought something for you.
But you must open it
only after I leave.
What's in it?
- Open it only after I leave.
John uncle, why don't
you consult a doctor?
I am going straight to a doctor.
Can I kiss you?
You don't have to ask me.
Can I also kiss you?
- Yes.
God bless you.
'Let this smoke be as it is.'
'Let me tell you my feelings.'
'I am crazy for your love.'
'Let me burn in love.'
'Let this smoke be as it is.'
'Let me tell you my feelings.'
'I am crazy for your love.'
'Let me burn in love.'
'Let this smoke be as it is.'
'Your glance has touched my heart.'
'I am entranced by your love.'
'Burning in love gives a
strange satisfaction.'
'Hold me in your arms.'
'Come close... come close to me.'
'Come close to me.'
'Let this smoke be as it is.'
'Let me tell you my feelings.'
'I am crazy for your love.'
'Let me burn in love.'
'Let this smoke be as it is.'
Can't you see what's going on?
Do something of this scene.
Please do something.
Is this the same girl about
whom Daksh mentioned to me?
Yes, she's the same girl.
Her name is Jiya.
She dances in a beer bar.
Just a few days back,
your grandson...
...left my daughter and was roaming
with this lowly girl...
...on the streets.
Let them roam. Let them roam
as long as they want.
My son is of young blood.
He'll roam before marriage.
But, you have become old...
...still you are on that
old beaten path again.
Forgot your affair... with your maid.
So funny.
'This heat. This softness.'
'What can I say about this thirst? '
'I am always lost in
your love's trance.'
'This is the blistering
ashes of our passion.'
'Let me become dust again.'
'O my beloved.'
'Let this smoke be as it is.'
'Let me tell you my feelings.'
'I am crazy for your love.'
'Let me burn in love.'
'Let this smoke be as it is.'
If you say, I will have
her thrown out from here.
Take it easy! You want
to show your strength...
...against a menial girl.
Go and announce the engagement.
She will run away on her own.
C'mon.
I thought you'd elope with me.
Are you really getting
engaged to Anahita?
Your silence has given me my answer.
Believe me Jiya, I am helpless.
Or else, I'll lose
100 million dollars.
Do you know how much
100 million dollars is?
No, Daksh.
I don't have the money even
to go back home by a cab.
How do I know how much it is?
It's a huge amount!
That I had come to your house
to make you understand this.
But you got annoyed with me.
I just want you to consider
my offer... please.
Daksh, I have come here for that.
The girl inside me said...
...what tantrums are
you throwing, Jiya?
Get out from the world
of dolls and fairies.
Become his mistress.
You can't run this
world as you wish.
Sometimes to win something you
have to lose everything.
But when I came here, when
I saw you before me...
...one more girl inside
me called out...
...the one who still believes
in her dreams.
She said to me.
Jiya, if dreams are lost...
then everything is lost.
Daksh, just like you can't
leave you dollars for me...
...in the same way, I can't
leave my dreams for you.
My dreams will be fulfilled.
Daksh! C'mon, let's go.
I said... C'mon, Daksh.
Daksh, C'mon.
C'mon.
Grandma is waiting for you.
Ladies and gentleman.
I'd like my mother to
start this ceremony...
...with her pure and sacred hands...
...which will bind these
hearts forever.
And along with this, two
influential business families...
...of this city will
become one forever.
Wow! That's great!
Slip this on her fingers.
Wow! That's wonderful.
May God bless you!
Sir, please excuse me.
Just a minute.
Didn't I tell you that the
girl would run away?
What happened?
- Sir, come fast.
John uncle's health
is deteriorating.
What happened to him?
- I don't know. - Let's go.
Mr. Daksh Mittal, your butler
has acute leukemia.
Acute Leukemia!
Cancer!
Yes. He had been coming
here for treatment...
...since the last six months.
It's strange that he never
told you about it.
I hope he becomes all right?
Mr. Mittal, your butler was
careless from the beginning.
We tried our best.
He never took care of himself...
...and neither did he take
his medicines on time.
Even though, we limited
your butler from...
Stop this butler nonsense!
He's not my butler. He's my father.
He's my father.
Oh, I am really very sorry,
Mr. Mittal.
I am extremely sorry.
- It's ok.
But now he has a new firmness.
He wants to go the church everyday
for Christmas prayers.
Mr. Mittal, I won't
take any guarantee...
...if anything happens to him, now.
So, will you take the guarantee...
...that nothing would happen
to him if he stays here.
Then, why are you stopping him?
Does it make a difference if he
stays here or in the church?
Silent night. Holy night.
All is calm. All is bright
All around the
virgin mother and child.
Holy infant...
I think my life's
circle is complete.
...mother and child.
Remember, I used to take
you out on a pram.
Now you have brought me to this
church on a wheelchair.
Daksh, death is not that
frightening as people think.
People fear it for nothing.
'Holy night... '
If humans don't die...
...then how will life live on?
'Round the virgin mother and child.'
Do you know I am feeling
very peaceful in here?
I never felt like this before
in my whole life.
Even if I gulped down a
whole bottle of liquor.
'Sleep in heavenly peace.'
How... is Jiya? ...the tie thief.
Why are you talking about her?
Don't know why...
...but her thought are
revolving in my mind.
'Silent night... '
You know people say that...
...when a person is about to die...
...he starts talking absurd things.
'Around the virgin
mother and child.'
'Holy infant in
the manger and child.'
'Sleep in heavenly peace... '
'Sleep in heavenly peace.'
'Silent night.'
'Holy night... '
'Silent night... '
It doesn't hurt me that...
...people die.
'All is quiet, all is calm.'
It hurts me the most...
...that people don't live
their life even if alive.
'All is quiet, all is calm.'
I want to say this one thing
to you for the last time.
'Silent night... '
You can do whatever you
wanna do with this life.
This life is only yours.
It's only yours.
Only you have the right
over your life.
God bless you.
Hello!
- Hello, Jiya.
Uncle John is no more.
He went away leaving me alone.
He was quiet!
He was talking about
you till his end.
I am alone now, Jiya.
I am feeling lonely.
'Ln the crowd and in loneliness.'
'Ln the depth of my thirst.'
'Ln pain and in anguish.'
'I miss you... always.'
'Ln songs and in music.'
'Ln my dreams and while I am awake.'
'Ln the sunlight and in the shade.'
'I miss you... always.'
'Ln the crowd and in loneliness.'
'Ln the depth of my thirst.'
'Ln pain and in anguish.'
'I miss you... always.'
'Your love is my life.'
'I can't forget your love.'
'I try my best day and night.'
'But I can't erase your image.'
'Ln the depth of my thirst.'
'Ln the crowd and in loneliness.'
'Ln pain and in anguish.'
'I miss you... always.'
'I never dreamt that...
...l'd have to live without you.'
'O beloved, if you call me...
...l'll break all promises and come.'
'Ln the dark shade of my locks.'
'Ln the crowd and in loneliness.'
'Ln pain and in anguish.'
'I miss you... always.'
'Ln the crowd and in loneliness.'
'Ln the depth of my thirst.'
'Ln pain and in anguish.'
'I miss you... always.'
Sir, let's go home.
It's your wedding this evening.
Wedding?
- Yes, sir.
Shankar, why am I
doing this wedding?
Sir, you are helpless.
I am not helpless. This
is just a pretense.
Because I can't forfeit money.
I can forfeit all the luxuries.
The money which means
nothing in the end.
See this.
Uncle John.
What did he take away with him?
Nothing.
He took only our love
with him, didn't he?
And I am marrying someone
else for money.
Even though I know... that
I can't live without Jiya.
Uncle John, I have understood...
I have understood why the
monkey was not able...
...to take out his hand
from the glass jar.
Because greediness
was his weak link.
Uncle John, see this.
I have taken out my hand
from this glass jar.
You were right.
This is my life.
And only I have the
right over my life.
Now I will only do the thing...
...which I should have done
in the very beginning.
Even the Pavilion is ready now.
Your son has not arrived yet.
He'll come, Madhwani. He'll come.
Mittal, I just want
to say one thing.
If your son doesn't come today...
then I'll murder him.
Suit, suit.
Suit... suit... Maroon suit... for me...
Please forgive me.
I hurt you that day.
I am sorry.
You are Jiya's big brother, right?
Right?
I have come here to ask
her hand in marriage.
I want to marry her.
Yes.
Yes... marriage.
- Marriage...
That's enough. That's enough.
Is Jiya not at home?
She's... not... at home.
- Not at home? - No.
Then where is she?
- Coffee shop.
Coffee shop?
- Coffee shop... suit.
Which Coffee shop?
First tell me, which coffee shop?
I won't give the suit. First
tell me, which coffee shop?
Which coffee shop?
If destiny wants us to
be united together...
...then just expect this note
to reach you anytime.
Ouch!
You idiot!
I am sorry.
Hi!
Can you get leave from here
for the next 60 years?
Daksh, you are not in your senses.
You are getting married
in the next 20 minutes.
Jiya, I have come to
my senses only now.
What can I do?
I come to know everything
late in life.
Please marry me.
Please.
Do you have any idea of how are
you going to live without money?
Just like the other
poor people live.
Jiya, I swear on you.
I'll never drink again.
I'll always keep you happy.
And I'll always make you laugh.
Say yes.
Yes... yes... yes.
Yes.
- Yes!
Will you help me give this news...
...to Mr. Mehta and Mr. Madhwani?
Of course.
Now I will do everything as you say.
I'll be back.
Hi!
Can you tell me where the bride is?
I am the groom.
Fellow, the bride is upstairs.
Thank you.
O God, bless us! Hey man,
what are you doing?
This has got loose. Where
is the nuptial thread?
Hey idiot, the husband ties it
after the seven holy rounds.
She doesn't know even this.
Hello!
Hi!
- The groom.
Anahita... I am sorry
for being late.
Traffic you know.
- It's ok.
Can I talk to you in private?
Yes.
Excuse me.
- Excuse me.
Daksh, what's the matter?
The bride's room is upstairs.
The groom has gone upstairs.
Now, don't ask me, what is
the time of the wedding?
I don't know.
The wedding is not going
to take place. - What?!
I think you are drunk.
- Yes.
But I...
Cool. Men often get nervous
before the marriage.
You are getting scared, right?
Yes, Anahita. I am getting scared.
I have drunk a lot too.
But the truth is that
I don't love you.
I love someone else.
I love Jiya.
Anahita, look. No need to cry.
Anahita, please listen.
- Beware if you speak a word more!
I'll break your face.
Daddy!
Hello, Mr. Madhwani.
You have sported a
really good turban.
Very colorful.
Hey man, what's going on?
Actually, when Daksh gets nervous...
...he breaks things this way.
Catch your grandma's ring.
And slip it on that witch's finger.
Hello, Jiya. Meet him.
He's Mr. Madhwani.
And she's Ms. Anahita.
Daksh, are you ok?
You, beast! If he doesn't
love your daughter...
...then will you make him
love her by using force?
Beware if you touch him.
He loves me.
- Yes.
Move aside.
So, she's that call girl...
that bar dancer...
...who made you break
my daughter's heart.
You humiliated her... huh?
She's that mistress.
Mistress?
- Yes, mistress!
Daddy, please... daddy,
please don't hit him.
Get out from this room! Go!
Get out from this room!
Everybody get out!
I won't leave him!
I won't leave him.
Nug...! Nug...!
It's not nug. It's gun.
Jiya, what if we can't
live together.
We can at least die together.
I love you, Jiya.
- I love you too, Daksh.
What's going on here?
Hey on whom are you pointing
the gun, you scum!
Lower that gun!
Scum, you'll shoot my grandson!
I am a very mean woman.
Throw the gun down!
Throw the gun or I will
riddle you with bullets.
Throw the gun down.
Ladies and gentleman!
Silence please! Silence...
I am extremely sorry that
you all had to wait for me.
I am sorry.
But you must have known till now...
...that I am not getting married.
No! This is very bad.
So, all of you can go
home now. Bye. Bye.
Just a second.
One more thing.
It may happen that I won't
meet you in future.
Because I am going to
be very poor from now.
I won't even have the money
to pay for the rickshaw.
I love you all.
Daksh, you must apply the ointment.
- Fast.
Sorry... sorry.
Be like the good boy
you are right now.
Love me a lot after the marriage.
And do everything as I say. Ok?
Jiya, I'll do everything as you say.
Just promise me that you'll never
apply this burning ointment.
I'll never apply this.
I swear by you Jiya...
...I am desperate to live
the life of a commoner.
Just like millions of people go
for their work every morning...
...in the same way, I'll
sit in my car and...
Hey... poor people don't have cars.
They either go by
walking or by bus...
...or they travel by train.
- Fine, I will travel by bus.
And when I return home, you
will be washing clothes...
...and for dinner we will share a
piece of dry bread in candle light.
Jiya, our life would
be so wonderful!
I will go for a job.
Daksh Mittal will go for a job.
That's enough!
You will not go for a job.
Your grandfather and I have
not earned this much health...
...to let you travel
in crowded buses.
Let you have only one dry
piece bread that too half...
No! No one has ever worked in
the Mittal family after us.
Your father never worked.
You'll never work and even
your kids won't work.
Yes.
Hey girl, make your future
husband understand.
That even though he deceived me...
...still I have decided to give
the 100 million dollars in his name...
...only to him.
No, Grandma. I want to work.
I want to be poor.
Hey, scum. When poverty
knocks your door...
...love escapes through the window.
Hey girl, explain this to him.
I am going to call
that stupid priest.
In the meantime, make
him understand...
...that he'll have to take
the money at any cost.
Grandma, listen to me.
Please tell her.
Hey grandma...
'I have decided.'
'I have decided, come what may...
...I will love only you.'
'I have decided.'
'Yes, I have decided.'
'This separation is
only for a few days.'
'This distance is only
for a few days.
'Then every season
will be of union.'
'Every moment will be beautiful.'
'What can I tell you of
this heart's pain.'
'I can't express this to you.'
'You have made me so anxious...
...that I can't be away from
you even for a moment.'
'I have decided.'
'I have decided, come what may...
...I will love only you.'
'I have decided.'
'Yes, I have decided.'
'My lips never moved.'
'But my feelings reached
you without words.'
'You have showered me with
your precious love.'
'You have made me invaluable.'
'I have never seen such
colorful life before.'
'Loneliness covered my
life before you came.'
'I have decided.'
'Yes, I have decided,
come what may...
...I will love only you.'
'I have decided.'
'I have decided, come what may...
...I will love only you.'