From "Carmen", the novel, 1845.
In Spain,
for a woman to be thought beautiful,
she should have thirty positive qualities.
Or to put it another way,
it must be possible
to apply to her three adjectives,
each of which describes
ten parts of her person.
For example, three that are dark,
dark eyes,
dark eyelashes,
dark eyebrows.
Three that are delicate,
her hands,
her lips,
her hair, and so forth.
My woman could not lay claim
to such perfection.
Her eyes were slanting but remarkably wide,
her lips rather full but finely chiseled,
her hair rather coarse and black
with a sheen like a raven’s wing,
was long and shining.
Not to weary you
with too long a description,
I will sum her up by saying
that for every fault she had a quality
perhaps more striking from the contrast.
She had a strange wild beauty,
a face that was disconcerting
but unforgettable.
Her eyes in particular
had an expression
at once alluring and fierce,
that I had never seen
on any other human face.
Sorry I'm late.
-You shouldn’t park here.
-Show some respect.
Don’t make us angry!
They're full of crap.
Hot and dusty at the barracks
every day something to see
Watching people as they pass
Check out the girls and rate their butts!
Check out the girls!
Waiting at the fence, watching girls go by
We talk and smoke
hoping to catch their eye
Hot and dusty at the barracks
every day something to see
Watching people as they pass
Check out the girls and rate their butts!
Check out the girls!
Who’s this young girl?
It looks like our luck is in today
Young lady
we're here at your service
She needs our help!
Young lady, can I help you?
I'm looking for a sergeant
I'm a sergeant
Sir, I must tell you
the sergeant I'm looking for
is called Jongkhaya
Jongi? We all know Jongi
Thank God!
Is he here?
He’s not with us
He’s on the other watch
He isn’t here?
Sorry, my darling
Sorry, my baby
He isn’t here
But don’t go away
He won’t be long
Your special sergeant
will soon be here
He'll soon be here
Your special sergeant will be here
with the change of the watch
But to make the time seem shorter
stay with us a moment more
Come inside, see our quarters
You'll find a welcome there for sure
-In there?
-In there
I can’t go inside
but thanks, anyway
Pretty girl, don’t be frightened
We respect your point of view
You will find us welcoming
We'll take extra care of you
No doubt you would
Even so I have to go
I cannot stay
I shall return
to see my precious sergeant
arriving with the change of watch
Stay here with us
You'll see your precious sergeant
arriving with the change of watch
-Stay here with us!
-I can’t, I can’t!
Stay here with us!
Don’t go away, don’t go!
Kind sirs, I must go!
You let her get away...
No, it was you.
Our girl has flown
We're on our own
Waiting at the gate
Back where we were
Hot and dusty in the barracks
Every day something to see
Watching people as they pass
Check out the girls and rate their butts
Check out the girls!
hey, Jongkhaya,
you're in luck.
You've a babe looking for you.
I don’t know any women here.
What did she look like?
Fit enough, nice body,
but dresses as if she’s from the rural areas.
Nomakhaya?
Didn’t ask her name,
I was too busy looking...
Gentlemen...
Let’s take a look
round this township of yours.
Sergeant, let’s go.
it’s peaceful for your first day, sir.
What goes on in there?
That? Cigarette factory, sir.
We're really past apartheid now.
Factories...
Factories in townships...
Women workers?
That’s right, sir.
Lots of them,
rolling cigarettes all day long.
You wait, sir,
it’s lunchtime now,
the guys will come running.
But not you?
They're township girls,
not my type.
There’s the bell, sir. Judge for yourself.
Can we go closer, sir?
Okay, let’s go.
Now the bell has rung
Now their break has started
All the factory girls
will come out here
Come to us, you girls
Do yourselves a favour
Let us say the kind of things
you'd like to hear
Let us whisper words of love in your ear
Loving words in your ear
I smoke like a nervous wreck.
it’s your own fault.
Look here they come
hot and sexy
They're keen, I'll bet
See the smoke from our cigarettes
fill the air
It rises higher still
and its perfume lingers there
Soon it wafts through your senses
captivating
How powerful that scent is
How intoxicating
A man’s promise like smoke
will soon disappear
Promises in your ear
Like smoke will disappear
Loving words simply disappear
See our smoke disperse
See the smoke disappear
Disappear
Disperse in the air
with its heady perfume
Our smoke will soon disappear
Amanda, where is Carmen?
Carmen’s around.
is she still in there?
Where is she?
Where’s Carmen?
She’s in there
Here she is!
Look at us
Won’t you speak to us
and say when you'll give us your love?
You ask when I'll love you?
Who knows? I don’t
Tomorrow perhaps
or never
who knows
It won’t be today
That’s for sure!
Love’s a bird that no one tames
No sooner caged than it flies away
No one can control it
No one can contain it
Love won’t be begged or threatened
Love won’t surrender to the loudest calls
It’s the keen one who'll fail
and the cool one who'll take the prize
Love’s a bird that no one tames
no sooner caged than it flies away
No one can control it
No one can contain it
I ignore all the rules
Love’s a stranger to me
If you don’t want me then I'm yours
But if I want you then be afraid
Beware her love!
If you don’t want me then I'm yours
But if I want you
you'd best be afraid
I ignore all the rules
Love’s a stranger to me
If you don’t want me then I'm yours
But if I want you then beware
Beware her love!
If you don’t want me then I'm yours
But if I want you
you'd best beware!
If you try to capture love
away it flies, you can see it go
Look for love when it’s hidden
You'll suffer and live in hell
All around you, feel love surround you
You're trapped within its timeless spell
If you seek love, it confounds you
You'll suffer, it gives you hell
If you try to capture love
away it flies, you can see it go
Look for love and it’s gone
Abandon it and it’s yours
I ignore all the rules
Love’s a stranger to me
If you don’t want me then I'm yours
But if I want you then be afraid
If you don’t want me
If you don’t want me then I'm yours
But if I want you
if I want you, you'd best beware!
If you don’t want me
If you don’t want me then I'm yours
Beware her love!
But if I love you
if I love you, you'd best beware!
I ignore all the rules
Love’s a stranger to me
If you don’t want me then I'm yours
But if I want you then beware!
You better use this condom
if you want her...
Carmen is so irritating,
she’s always showing off.
I can smell trouble.
He’s returned home,
and will perform in Cape Town
with the Gypsy Cigarette Girls Choir.
They'll be conducted
by his cousin, Andile Nkomo.
Stay tuned to see a recent performance.
Sergeant.
Who’s there?
-Why are you here?
-Your mother sent me.
My mother sent you?
How is my mother?
I am her messenger
She sent a letter
A letter?
And these as well
A ring for you to keep with this photo
And more
There’s more?
And more, I dare not tell you
She asked if I would give you
something more
Something else besides
which you, her loving son
would treasure more than these
What is this something
Nomakhaya, won’t you tell?
The gift your mother gave
is on my lips
for me to give to you
Last Sunday after church
she took me in her arms
and bid me come to you today
She said to me, "Nomakhaya
"please go to Seville
"It isn’t very far
"and when you're there
"find my son, my dear child
"My son, my Jongi
"Tell him that his mother
"says a prayer for him night and day"
She has never recovered
from the day you went away
"Tell him how I miss him
"How I long to see him"
She asked me to embrace you
She asked me to kiss you on her behalf
You've a kiss from my mother?
A kiss for you
I gave my word
Her kiss I'd give to you
My mother, I see her now
I see my mother once again
I see the village
where we lived then
He sees his mother once again
He sees our village
These memories fill his heart with courage
These treasured memories of home
fill my heart with courage
Beloved mother
I see the village
Sweet memories of home
Marriage is a blessing from God.
You will be blessed for eternity.
Now let me hear amen.
Yes, brothers and sisters,
adultery is a great sin.
Come for a swim.
I can’t swim.
Come, I’ll teach you.
I’m scared.
Sweet memories of home
I can’t swim.
You show no respect to my wife.
Don’t think like that...
I’m serous.
You're being stupid.
Don’t call me stupid.
You have my sympathy.
What did you say?
I told them the truth.
We went swimming and he sipped.
Mother, I...
Today
I lost both my sons.
I’m washing my hands of you.
Leave me.
Leave me to grieve.
My dear son,
take care of yourself.
I hope one day you'll come home.
When you choose a wife,
let it be your brother’s widow.
From your dear mother.
I have to go.
Wait, Nomakhaya
Really, I have to go.
They're killing each other.
Who? Where?
At the factory.
Come and help!
Come and help us now!
It was Carmen who started the fight
No, it wasn’t her!
Yes, it was her!
She struck out first
No, that’s a bloody lie
Listen to us!
We'll tell how it was
It was Carmen
who started the fight
It was Manelisa
It was Carmensitha!
It was Manelisa!
Now, will someone please tell me
what’s been gong on in there?
There was a fight.
This girl got stabbed with this knife.
By who?
By her.
I don’t have to answer to you.
I’ll answer real police, not you rookies.
Rookies
Maybe they are,
but take a good look at me.
Answer.
-The bitch attacked me first.
-it’s you who attacked first, stupid bitch.
There was a fight
and that one got stabbed.
What do you have to say for yourself?
Answer.
Sergeant, watch her.
You're hurting me.
Then don’t give me trouble.
Then let me go.
Why would I do that?
Because my mother lives alone
in the rural areas.
She needs me.
honestly. You're from there, aren’t you?
Won’t you help me?
Don’t play games.
You're not a township girl?
Of course not.
You really think I’ll help you?
You'll do what I want, sooner or later.
I go to church too.
Don’t make me laugh.
"Love your neighbour,"
that’s what the Bible says.
Oh, you kept the flower...
I’ve enchanted you.
Stop talking.
Sergeant, take her away
In the hottest part of the township
with my friend Bra Nkomo
is where I dance the Twalatsa
and drink sputla
at Bra Nkomo’s shebeen
But being alone is hardly fun
it’s best if there’s another one
since pleasure is for two
I'd like to take my lover there
What am I saying?
He was a liar and a cheat
I've finished with him!
My heart is breaking, who'll comfort me?
There are loads of men who want me
but none of them can turn me on
Is there no one who can?
Show me that man
I'd love him well
Who wants me? Who wants my heart?
Now’s your chance, make your move
I won’t hang around
you know where I'm going
In the hottest part of the township
with my friend Bra Nkomo
that’s where I dance the Twalatsa
and drink sputla
Every Sunday I go to Bra Nkomo’s!
Shut up!
Don’t talk to me
It’s not to you I speak
I'm singing to amuse myself
And I'm thinking
I take it I'm still allowed to think
I've got a man in mind
a certain man in mind
a gorgeous man who loves me
and who in time I could love
This man is not a captain
or an officer
He’s only a sergeant
full of passion
and I want to make him mine
I'm losing my senses
If I give myself to you
can I trust you
and if I love you
you must love me
I will save you
You'll dance with me
Give me your word
the Twalatsa
and we'll drink sputla
Give me your word
In the hottest part of the township
with my friend Bra Nkomo
that’s where I dance the Twalatsa
and drink sputla
I ignore all laws
Love’s a stranger to me
If you don’t want me then I'm yours
but if I want you, then be afraid
If you don’t love me
then I'm yours
But if I love you
you'd best beware
hey, shut up
Your singing is so bad...
Stop or I’ll shoot
Leave him alone
Listen, son of my son,
the comrades will take good care of you.
Don’t cry, child,
they are good friends.
Go well. Go well.
Don’t give Thand trouble.
Mum’s gong to Bra Nkomo’s.
Your mum’s gong dancing...
Don’t worry, child, I’ll be back.
We'll see about that
Where’s my hair band?
Let’s go.
Why such a hurry?
I want to see Luiamie
I’m gonna drink myself to death today.
Carmen, you're mad,
the police are still looking for you.
So what Frigging police.
The drums begin to beat
a rhythm slowly starts
The girls get to their feet
and move towards the stage
Marimbas are heard
and guitars take up the tune
The swirling music
surrounds you with sound
Golden jewelry flashing and shining
Colourful clothes swirling
faster than the wind
There’s no escaping from the music now
the dance has found its rhythm
At first tentative
but soon spinning around
and round and round
and round!
The fever grips the band as well
Musicians play as though possessed
They're captivated like the rest
For none can resist the music’s spell
The frenzy holds them in a trance
to break away there’s not a chance
They're drunk on the rhythm
they're lost
turning and swaying
they're intoxicated by the dance!
Come here.
Gentlemen, please,
we don’t want trouble.
We're celebrating my cousin’s return.
No trouble please.
This shithole is full of lowlifes,
even our little jailbird here.
I’ve never been to jai.
Only because that bastard let you go.
he seemed okay to me...
What happened to him?
Confined to barracks.
he’s out today,
but I demoted him.
That’s fine by me,
I prefer men...
Officers can’t give you anything.
in return for sex I’ll forget everything...
Yes or no?
I’ll decide when and where.
I’ll see you soon...
he’s here
his car is coming
Welcome to the son of KwaJola!
You sing well.
What’s your name?
My name is Carmen.
My friends call me Carmenstha.
Carmenstha. You've a beautiful voce.
I think we'll see more of each other.
in your dreams.
Nothing wrong with dreaming...
Dreams of my father brought me home.
Give me a smoke.
Lades,
the guys want to talk.
What’s up?
Come.
Can you take them home?
Listen up.
You have to help us with Customs.
if we throw them a beach party,
they'll let us through.
There are boxes of these coming in by boat.
So it’s agreed, you'll help us.
Police, police
Come back, you cowards
he’s with me.
You made it then.
Of course
how could I not?
You took your time...
I was confined to barracks.
have you forgiven me?
Of course.
how could you ask that?
I love you.
They all say that...
Who does?
Who says that?
Don’t tell me you're jealous
Don’t be stupid.
I’ll make you forget about the past.
St down.
I want to show you how we please our men.
Relax, Jong,
and let me please you...
Carmen, shut up
I’m called to barracks at once.
How could I be so stupid?
I've made a fool of myself
I made all the moves
I gave all I had
Tried everything to please you
I danced
and I sang
I thought after time
you'd be mine
Tara tata!
The radio is bleating
He’s going to be late!
Oh, my God!
The radio is bleating
He'll be late, he'll be late!
He drops his woman
and runs
Well, so much for his love
Don’t doubt my love
What love?
Listen to me
It’s no use
Men are always lying
Hear me out!
Shut your mouth
and hear me out!
Get a grip on yourself
Look, here’s the flower that you gave me
I keep it here and dream of you
All the days I was confined
it never lost its treasured smell
Beside me through each passing hour
I could feel your love in this flower
When I thought about you
I closed my eyes
and you were there
At times I cursed the day I met you
I'd call out your name and reject you
What evil forces were at play
on that fateful day?
My life is empty without you
It was blasphemy to doubt you
My guilt weighed me down
Oh, Carmen, my love
my only desire was to see you
to see you again
I love you desperately
please just look at me
How can I make you understand?
Please, Carmen
You hold my life in your hands!
I love you
No, you don’t love me
Yes, I do
If you loved me
you'd never
You'd never leave me
Forget the police
Come with us, stay with us
I beg you
Forget your duty
Show you care!
Set me free
Forget the police
and show you truly love me
Carmen, I beg you please
have mercy on me
-Save me
-Show me you care
-Dear God
-And come with me
Listen to me
Show me you care
If you say you love me
You'll love me
No! I cannot do as you say
Just think of the shame
The failure of deserting
the dishonour
of deserting the police!
I can’t do it
Well, then go!
I implore you
I don’t love you anymore
-I beg you
-Piss off!
You make me sick
I'm leaving you
Forever
Get out
Farewell
Forever
Farewell!
Get out!
What does he want?
Be quiet
What’s this?
You disappoint me
Shame on you!
Giving in to a common sergeant
while the Officer’s around
Push off, get out now!
No!
You heard, I said get out
I will not leave
You fool
If you're a man then fight!
Brave officer
My hero
It looks like love has played
a little game with you
Your timing wasn’t good
in this location
We want no trouble
So you give us no choice but to detain you
indefinitely!
Are you with us?
Now I have no choice
You still have your doubts?
Don’t worry
very soon you'll have more chances
Stay with us, don’t change your mind
You can be whoever you want to be
Live in liberty and enjoy your life
you can be free!
Yes, you'll be free!
Stay, don’t try to resist
as your life is changing
Stay with us and be free
Your path will be clear
you'll have many more chances
you'll be whoever you want to be
Best of all you'll live in liberty
You'll be free
You'll be free!
I'll follow you
I'll be free
The most important thing of all
is freedom
Freedom!
You were too quick to accept a ring
from that bastard.
he'll hurt you again.
he uses the Bible to hide his true nature.
he'll beat you again.
We'll go check out the sailor boys.
You babes wait here.
Where do you think you're gong?
You wait too.
Police boy
Tell us, tell us
what did the signs show?
Talk to us about the signs
What did they show?
Amathambo, show us
what our destiny may hold
Who we should be wary of?
Will we ever fall in love?
Amathambo will tell
Tell us who to be wary of
and whether we'll ever fall in love
Such riches
Such love
Let me see
what the signs showed to me
Rubbish! Lies!
It’s death, death is coming
First for me
then for him
For both of us
It’s death
I've been trying to change
what the amathambo showed
But there is nothing that can help me
the signs never lie
If in the book above
it says you're blessed
then throw them without fear
The signs will always
spell out happiness
that’s what Fate says
If it’s time for you to die
then take your final breath
Then throw them twenty times
Amathambo won’t change their meaning
If you have to die
throw them twenty times
Their meaning won’t change
They'll still predict your death
It’s death
My death
It’s always
Death
You should be ashamed of yourselves.
Curiosity killed the cat
We're not in the mood for silly games.
That was not funny.
They're coming back, let’s go.
What’s gong on?
There are three of them waiting down there.
Only three?
That’s fine. Half for each of us
Piss off
No one asked you.
Keep watch and wait for the call.
if anyone comes past,
deal with them. Understand?
Okay, girls, let’s see you work your stuff.
We know just how to deal with them
like all other men they'll be really dim
What they desire
is to pinch us on the arse
No need to fight, no need to fuss
when we can lead them by the nose
Everyone enjoys some flattery
Everything comes from being nice
a smile is cheap at the price
If we flatter them
they'll let us pass
Watch and you'll see
we guarantee they'll let us pass
All of the goods will get through!
We know how to deal with them
Like all other men they'll be dim
They'll let us pass!
Flattery will see us through!
They've arrived,
you can bring the bakkies.
Let’s go.
That’s the place.
-There?
-Yes.
I have my reasons for helping.
Are you sure you're gong to be okay?
Yes. Thank you.
Poor girl, I lied
to make her believe
that I'm not frightened here
I lied
For within my poor heart
I'm trembling with fear
Scared, all alone in this place
yet, in spite of my fear
my heart is reassured
For through the divine gift
of Your Grace
you will watch over me
my Lord
Leave me alone.
Don’t you love me anymore?
You're history.
Leave her alone
What are you doing here?
Please listen to me
Your mother
her life nearly over
is waiting to discover
what’s happened to her son
She won’t live much longer
she longs to see you
Please, have mercy on her
Leave this place and come with me
If your mother is ill
you should go home
Do you want me to go?
There’s nothing for you here
Do you want me to go
so you can find a new lover?
Never
Hell, no!
You must kill me first
I'll stay till my last breath
We took a vow
that only death would separate us
Though I find that death is near
I'll never let you go
Leave me be
I am destined to die
You'll be mine
you bitch
You were mine since you cast
your evil spell
Our lives are so entwined
only death will separate us
Now my death awaits me
I'll never let you go!
Listen to me, Jongi
for one last time
Your mother is very ill
and believe me
she does not want to die
until she’s forgiven you
My mother about to die?
Yes, it’s true!
Then I must go
You're in luck, for now
But I will return
house of KwaJola,
Mpondomse, MphaNkomo.
Today we are here
for my cousin Luiamie.
Thank you, cousin.
As you have heard from my cousin here,
my father has been in my dreams,
again and again.
Therefore I made the decision to come home
and perform this ceremony.
He’s wise, that one.
Jola, Ngwanya, Qengeba, MphaNkomo.
Take this bull’s hide to keep you warm.
Please continue protecting this family.
You protected me while I was overseas
and granted me good fortune.
By these words I ask you
to grant me continuing luck.
I give you this spear to make the sacrifice.
Thank you, cousin.
Good afternoon, Mampondomse.
Luiamie, we salute you
As the family of kwaNgxabane, Qengeba,
I say to all of you here,
today we are as one family.
We say to you,
all your ancestors are here with you today.
They've heard you.
Take my advice
you mustn’t stay around here
Why not?
He’s here
Who?
Him
Hiding there in the audience
Beware
Yes, I can see him
I'm not the type to be frightened
I will wait
and speak to him
Believe me
beware
I'm not scared
Beware
-It’s you
-It’s me
They warned me
that you were here
and lying in wait for me
They also told me
that my life’s in danger
But I'm not afraid
and I won’t run away
I'm not trying to scare you
I'm begging you
let’s put the past behind us
Come back to me
I forgive you
If you come with me
we'll begin a life together
and live happily
We shall never be together
once love’s broken, it won’t mend
I've made up my mind
Our love is gone
it’s over now
You know it’s the truth
when I say
it is finished
It can’t be the end
Please say it isn’t over
I'm still in love with you
Give me a chance
A chance to save you
and save myself as well
So you love me no more?
No, I love you no more
I still adore you, Carmen
My heart still burns with passion
What do you want from me?
You're being ridiculous
I swear I'm still in love with you
If it’s your desire
I'll be a smuggler
I'll do whatever you ask
Whatever you want
Please don’t leave me
Remember what we had
Our love burned with passion!
Please don’t leave me now!
Carmen’s not scared of death
Free I was born
and free is how I'll die
I'll ask you one more time
you bitch
to come with me
No! No!
Here’s your ring
the stupid ring you gave me
Take it!
Down to hell!
You can take me away
I killed her