Mine!
Whose pigeon?
My birds brought it down
You have no claim on it
- l am willing to pay
8 annas
The price of six!
So go, buy three for 4 annas
- 4 rupees more likely
You made money giving
false testimony. Remember?
l never gave any false testimony
Wants pigeons?
He keeps pigeon only to
trouble you. He's a real scoundrel
lt was a bad day when you
testified against him
He's spent 12 years in prison.
He won't forget so easily
What made you testify
against him?
They asked me on oath
what kind of man he was
...so l told them
Bring us guavas and oranges
when you return - and a doll
l will
Look at her, still playing with
dolls after her engagement
Come here
How are you, little sir?
You got engaged, and didn't
tell your Uncle Dilawar?
Come and get your pigeon.
Your father has paid for it
Wait here, l'll be
right back
This place looks all right
You'll kill her, but
what about my money
l thought you had other ideas
- l'll repay you
May l say something?
- Yes?
Let's go to Lucknow
and sell this girl
Amiran is missing
She was playing outside. Dilawar took
her away with an excuse about pigeons
For God's sake, go and find
my child
My child! Where's my child?
l've looked everywhere
Allah is great
Here, eat your food
Won't you eat?
What's your name?
- Ramdei. Yours?
Amiran. Did they kidnap you too?
- Yes, from that fair
So, there are the girls?
- Salaam
How much for this one?
- A thousand
Has your lover ever seen
that much money?
One thousand rupees!
Trying to con me!
Don't be offended
The way you talk! l've sent dozens
of girls to the palaces
Never paid more than 500
You name it then
- 200
Look at her face, her hands
Just 200, that's it
For 200, have this one
She's not bad either. A bit dark.
And a weak frame. 150 for her
Agreed
The Begum won't have
a dark girl
l'll take the first one.
Here, 200 rupees. Count them
Come, girl
''Who tied the swing
to the mango tree?''
''My lover swings...''
''The swing tied to the
mango tree''
''He caught my arm, embraced me''
''Who tied the swing
to the mango tree?''
''My heart beats fast,
l'm scared''
''Swing gently, my love''
Come
ls this the girl?
Come here, my child
How much?
- Whatever it is, we go halves
Okay. The amount l promised is ready.
Where's the other girl?
A lady took her for her house
For how much?
- 400
l'd have given that
for a good-looking girl
This one's also good-looking
The money-box
Husseini, she's not expensive
at 250 rupees?
Expensive? She's cheap
Not so cheap either. Anyway, she
looks innocent enough
God knows where they lift them from.
They've no fear of God
l'm not responsible. The sin will be
on these rogues' heads
lf not here, they'd sell
somewhere
She's well-off here. You've heard
how the ladies treat their maids?
Of course. The other day ...
l heard that a lady who saw her maid
talking to her husband ...
had her killed with
red-hot irons
Such women will pay on the
Day of Judgment
Give me this girl,
l'll bring her up
She'll be yours but l'll care for her
- All right
Where're you from?
- Bangla
You mean you don't know this?
Faizabad is also called Bangla
What's your name?
- Amiran
l'm Bismillah
l don't like that name.
l'll call you Umra
From now on you'll answer
to Umrao
When the lady says 'Umrao',
you say ''Yes 'm''
Come, have a bite
Yes'm
What does your father do?
- He's a caretaker
Where?
- At the tomb of Bahu Begum
Go to sleep
Will you see to her.
Come. What has happened to you?
l don't know what has happened
to her.
She was sleeping and she woke
up all of a sudden.
What are you trying to do?
You were trying to run away?
Where would you run to?
Run! Run!
She's just a child.
Thatis enough.
l will break your legs if you try to
run away again.
She won't.
What happened? Have you gone mad?
Where were you going? lf you had gone
out, someone would have killed you.
There are a lot of bandits out there.
Don't go anywhere again. This is
your home now.
Do your salaam
Khan Saheb will teach you
music. Will you learn?
He's a great musician. Put your heart
in it, and all Lucknow will know you
They'll all come to hear you sing.
You'll be known in the Court
Not to talk of the
money and jewels
You may begin, Khan Saheb
Hold out your right hand
We begin with the name of the
merciful Allah
Now sing with me
Here mindlessness does not refer to
lack of intelligence or knowledge
This mindlessness is an ultimate bliss,
of love, when everything ceases
Neither the desire
nor its object remained
That is, neither the lover nor the
beloved remains, not even love itself
Only a state of mind which
the poet calls mindlessness
And this mindlessness is
the beauty of the couplet
Wonderful, sir, sometimes l too
feel like composing poetry
Go ahead. There's no better way of
expressing one's feelings
Will you help with suggestions?
- But certainly!
Khanum is calling you
- Nothing wrong, l hope?
You'll have to ask her
Ma'am, did you call me?
- No. Who said l did?
Gohar Mirza
l haven't seen that rogue for two
days. l sent him to buy something
Must've spent the money!
Tell that rascal to see me
Gohar Mirza! This was an offering
Great!
Umrao, you make it better
than even Aunt Husseini
lt should be sweeter
You're shameless, telling lies
to get food
lt was meant for the shrine
Someone would've
eaten it anyway
l hope to God you die of
cholera. Die right now
Show me those
ornate earrings
Aren't they beautiful?
Where is the matching front piece?
- lt isn't ready yet
Send it today. We need it in two days
- Very well
Where is the banat from Delhi?
- lt's in the box
Are you saving it for
Maulvi Saheb's cap? Get it, quick
Khanum Saheba, your jokes
are priceless
My feet are killing me.
Do this, do that
Such a big gathering and only
me to do all the work
What are you doing here?
You'd forgotten about me. l was
very hungry, so l thought...
Couldn't you have waited
a little?
Why should you, l'm not your
lawful wedded wife
Stop being angry
at small things
Here, eat
- No
On your life, please sit
You're really good at
persuasion
Not only my heart, take...
Someone's there
Another poem? Great going,
Read
''Not only my heart, Sir,
take my life''
'' But do as l ask just once''
Not bad, but remember
two things
The delicacy of the thought...
And the rhythm of the words
Listen to the poet Mir...
''How do l describe the softness of
her lips? They are like rose petals''
You are talking
of great poets
She is just a beginner
What do you say, sir?
You say, 'Not only my heart...'
You could say instead...
What is my heart? You take my life.
But do as l ask just once
''What is my heart?
You take my life''
'' But do as l ask just once''
''What is my heart?
You take my life''
''You'll come here
again and again''
''Carefully observe this place''
''What is my heart?
You should come to know.
''l know that friends
get estranged''
'' But why be obliged
to strangers?''
''What is my heart?
You take my life''
''lf you say, l'll bring
the sky down''
''Nothing is difficult
if you make up your mind''
''What is my heart?
You take my life''
'' But do as l ask just once''
''Please accept...''
Here
- You put it on me
Like it?
- Very much
Why look in the mirror?
Your image is in my eyes
For me?
Let's see you put it on
You put it on me
You bastard, you pick on my
girls to show your manhood
l picked you from the gutter
l gave you shelter, food,
clothes, money and...
l swear, l never looked at anyone
before, Umrao herself called me
Trying to fool me! Get out of here.
l don't want to see your face again
lf you come here, l'll have your legs
broken. Now get out
Are you all right?
- Yes, by God's grace
Come in, Nawab Saheb
Has Bismillah gone out?
An admirer should be like you,
still asking after her
Have some betel leaf
You know, Khanum, strange are
the ways of heart
You don't like
Malka or Bahar?
Well, l...
What do you think of Umrao?
What are you saying?
She's at your service,
if you wish
Do l take it as settled?
Sure. Just arrange for the money.
lt'll be at least 5,000
5000 !
- lt's a question
lt'll take some time
Think about it. l have
several offers
l'll go to my estate
ln every way l was done down. My
enemy's name written with my blood
What is this heart, you may take
my life. But do as l ask just once
You'll come here
again and again
Carefully observe this place.
You're sure this is
your composition?
lf my life be spared,
may l speak
Yes?
The ghazal was written
by Umrao Jaan
Umrao Jaan?
- Yes
l've never heard this name before
Praising Umrao Jaan is like
holding a candle to the sun
She's so beautiful even the
Fairy Queen would envy her
Her verses make great poets
admit defeat
And her voice!
Her voice is like a
leaping flame
That's her.
''Thousands are intoxicated
by these eyes''
''Associated with these eyes
are a thousand tales''
''The intoxication of these eyes...''
''You are not the only one
disgraced for love of me''
''ln this city, there are
thousands like you''
''Thousands are intoxicated
by these eyes''
''l'm the only one who
intoxicates with my eyes''
''Though there thousands
of taverns in the world''
''Thousands are intoxicated
by these eyes''
''You think a gale can scare
such a flame''
''A flame which is protected
by a thousand moths''
''Thousands are intoxicated
by these eyes''
''Associated with these eyes
are a thousand tales''
''The intoxication of these eyes...''
Twenty-five
Look at Bismillah!
25 again
Watch the fun now
Three!
l keep losing. l won't play any more
Spread the board, l'll play
Has Khanum forgiven you?
Of course. l'm the support
of her old age
Are you angry with me?
- No
Then give me your hand
- Why?
Five mohurs of gold
Advance for a performance?
- Nawab Sultan sent 10, l've kept 5
Who is Nawab Sultan?
The one who gave you
the necklace
There's talk of his
retaining you
And he's asked for the ghazal
which you sang yesterday
l'll give it to him
when he comes here
All right, give it to him
lf you'd sent it through me, l'd
have earned some more gold
Hide these
- Why? l have to give them to Khanum
You don't have to tell her.
Neither will l
l'll go and meet Khanum
Please come in
l rarely visit bordellos
We are not such bad people
l've come because of you alone
l know you're saying this
just to please me
No. l haven't got over the
spell you cast that evening
l felt as though you were
singing for me alone
Whom else? Who else understood
music and poetry as well as you
l was so lost in the music
that l forgot to applaud
There can be no
greater applause than that
The ghazal was written by you?
- lt's nothing, just doggerel
Such a beautiful poem;
don't call it doggerel
You too write poetry
Poetry is beyond one. Sometimes
when l am alone l may hum a tune
We are alone here, hum something
Before you l am dumb
Oh, come on
On one condition
- l agree
Give me a copy of that ghazal
What a thing to ask for
Don't make me suffer,
let me hear it
A few couplets
''ln every way l was done down
My enemy's name written with my blood''
''Why couldn't talk of her
make me happy today?''
''Why did her name make
my heart heavy today?''
Wonderful!
What's this?
These couplets deserve
not one, but all of my poems
You embarrass me
l and my poetry are embarrassed
We're not worthy of you
''Why couldn't talk of her
make me happy today?''
''Why did her name make
my heart heavy today?''
What a beautiful thought
l wrote it for a
poet's meeting in Faizabad
Faizabad?
Yes, that's where my grandmother's
house is
You come from Faizabad?
- Yes. Have you ever been there?
Let it be. l don't remember
anything now
lf you remember nothing, why are
your eyes moist?
My eyes smert at times...
sometimes the light hurts them
lf l can be of any help...
Nawab Saheb, don't take it so
seriously
Have a betel leaf
Look, Bismillah
Aren't they nice?
The gentleman sitting with Umrao...
This is a bordello, all sorts of
people come here. Why?
Please come this way
My honor is in your hands now
Sultan must not learn
that l come here
Nawab Saheb? What are you saying?
What do you have to do with him?
Sultan is my son
His mother and l are separated,
but...
Rest assured, Nawab Saheb
l'd brought this for Umrao,
you keep it now
ln just a month you've driven me
mad, l can't rest without seeing you
What can l say?
Why?
Now you're here l remember nothing.
But there was something l had to say
l know what you had to say
Me, You, And this solitude
Listen, l've composed a tune for you
- Not now.
Do listen
l'm listening. Hair like
rain clouds, eyes like doe's...
... lips like rose petals,
neck like an amphora
This is your poem
l won't talk to you.
Are my poems that bad?
All right, don't be angry.
l'll listen
Go ahead, sing, why did you stop?
l'm no outsider
Who are you?
- l've come to hear you sing
Sing
What's the matter, Umrao?
Khan Saheb, please step this way
- Why?
l've something to say
- Say it from there
l'm not getting up from here
- You force yourself on us?
Who's forcing anybody?
A bordello is open to all
No bastard has any
special rights
Whoever produces cash
gets the girl
l'm ready to spend
Visit us some other time
Shut up, woman. l've told you
l'm not leaving this place
Child, you come here
Please let go her hand
No pimp dare make me let go
Mind your tongue; perhaps you
don't know how decent folk behave
You've been with a lot of
decent folk. Do what you can
But for the honor of my family,
l'd have taught you a lesson
You visit whores, and you're
afraid of mother?
Call Macca Pasi
Don't rely on servants
See this sword?
This is not a fence-ring. lf you
want a fight, come outside
Little boy, you're still
kissable
lf you fight with a grown man,
you'll cop it and make mother cry
Go home, sir. l'll manage
things
l won't go
- You'll get a bad name. Go home
Go, or you'll get into
a murder case
l said l won't go
He's still alive
- Such bastards don't die easily
l implore you. Go away
from here
Pick him up and throw him
in the gutter. We'll see later
She sits in mourning
with her hair open ...
My desires joined in the condolence
Don't tease the girl. She's not well
She's not ill, just pining away for
Nawab Sultan
And he's hiding his head
in mother's lap
l know, there's no true love
these days
God help me, but in our days
there were lovers
Either you possess someone
or you make someone yours
Take our Maulvi Saheb.
He'd come to show me his nuptial suit
l took his hand and made him sit
down. 40 years later, he's still here
lf you wish l can get hold
of a lover of those days...
Bald, toothless, but
he's lord of 40 villages
Name - Nawab Jafar
Take a note
- To whom? Nawab Jafar?
No - him
''To love me or not is in your power''
'' But for me not to love you
is beyond my power''
Please take this reply
Your letter has rekindled
the fire that was buried
l'm held to my word. l'll never
come to your house again
My friend Banna Saheb
lives in Nawabganj
Come there this evening
if you have time
The Nawab will be a bit late.
The lady is calling you
Who, Banna Saheb's wife?
Yes'm
My husband has been at Nawab
Sultan's place since morning
l think his mother
is not well
Ma'am, who's this?
What's it to you?
As if l don't know
Everyone knows her
- so why do you ask?
Who's talking to you?
l was asking our lady
How can l dare to talk
to you, you're high society
lf you want to show your
coarseness, go to the elder Begum
Yes, you're right, with her here
l'm not needed
Will you go before l hit you?
- Let her go, she's just silly
You shut up, you whore
or l'll strangle you
Mean, low-born...
Let her go, she's old
What's up?
This whore made me get a beating
- You dare again!
Why did you pick on her?
l swear l said nothing. Seems she's
got up on the wrong side of the bed
Such rude things she said
You gave her beating for nothing,
child, for this loose woman
That's why l was saying
one can't trust whores
Even their shadows
should be avoided
lf you want to meet me,
come to our house
You know l can't go there
And l can't come here
Come in, Panna Mal. You went for
two days and stayed away for 15
Haven't you heard?
- What?
l'm ruined. My house was burgled.
l've lost the wealth of generations
How much is the loss?
There is nothing left. The jewellery
is worth 200,000
ls my jewellery gone?
- Mercifully, no. lt was in the shop
Thank God. So many burglaries
in the city these days
Yours is the third one
in a row
The police chief doesn't know
what to do
Known thieves of the city were
questioned. They deny any hand in it
l hear its an outsider,
an outlaw named Faiz Ali
There's a lady come to
meet you...
Show her in
The curtains
Girls, take him to your rooms
Me, with them, to their rooms...
What luck!
Where are you from?
l hope there's no one else here
No one. Just you,
me and them...
l'm Fakhrunnisa
- Chabban's mother
You are Bismillah's mother?
- Yes. Go on, please
Chabban is my only son,
brought up with great love
He's engaged to his cousin,
but he refuses to marry her
His uncle has disinherited
him because of it
Do me a favor. Get Chabban
to agree to this marriage
Your daughter has a home for life.
l'll give more than Chabban paid her
Save my home from
being wrecked
l'm your slave. God willing,
it will be as you say
But Chabban must not
know of this
There was no need for this.
We are your servants
Now l'll ask for your leave
- God be with you
How are you?
- Well, by God's grace
We pray for your well being
No matter how well we do, we still
look to you for support
This time l have a request,
lf you permit...
Command me
They brought this shawl for
sale. The trader wants 2,000
l think it's not
too expensive at 1700 or 1800
lf you are generous, l'll wear
a shawl in my old age
You keep out of this
You ask him for so many
things. Let me ask today
Nawab Saheb, has the cat caught
your tongue? Say something
lf not yes, at least say no
This shawl is of
no consequence
Perhaps you are unaware
of my condition
Nothing wrong, l hope
l'll no longer accede
to your requests
We're so low that rich men like you
are miserly about little things
lt's the truth
lf you can't any longer,
why visit us?
You know very well that a
courtesan is a rich man's friend
Courtesy won't fill our bellies
This is your home, come when
you please. But think of your honor
l've really made a mistake
l'll never come again
You're angry. l won't
let you go
Want me to be insulted again
by your mother?
''The eyes have raised so many storms.
The boat of memories doesn't sink''
''l see no way of meeting you,
getting you again''
What are you writing? A love-letter
to Nawab Sultan?
Can't l write anything else?
You can't even think of it.
You're dedicated to Sultan
l'm afraid you'll go
to his house one day
You seem chirpy. You've got
over grieving for Chabban
Don't talk of him. Whenever
he is mentioned, l hate the world
Especially Mother
- What has she done?
She's responsible
for Chabban's death
lf she hadn't taunted him,
he wouldn't have died
Bismillah, you're
completely changed
You used to say a whore is
respected only in her house
Outside, she's nothing. And now -
After Chabban l don't like anything
l feel, if l find someone, l'll
just hold his hand for ever
You're a strange one. And you
object to my ways!
Don't compare Sultan with Chabban
Chabban could give up his life.
Sultan doesn't even dare meet you
He wants to. l don't let him
That's what you say. l'll ask
you when he betrays you
For your sake, l've worn out
both my feet and tongue
Oh God! What have l done?
Not you, me. My feet ache from
making trips to Sultans house
He was tending, his sick mother
When l finally met him, my tongue
wore out talking of your passion
''What has this heart not done
for love of you''
What did he say?
What could he say?
''Mention of that green fairy...
And then my description''
He started begging ''Arrange
a meeting with Umrao, somehow''
l'll never meet him
at Banne Saheb's
He'll come to meet you in Musabagh
Musabagh? But that's outside town.
Khanum won't let me go that far
For just five rupees
l'll arrange everything
l'll give it. Tell me
Khanum herself will take you
Wait and see
The saffron?
Oh God, l forgot!
- What do we put in the 'pulao' then?
lt's because of him. His betel leaf,
his tobacco, his hookah...
The carriage is waiting. l'll get it
- Forget it, you'll be gone all day
Looks as if he's never eaten.
Get out of there
Hurry up
- lt's ready
l haven't seen you all these days.
l kept worrying; thinking
''Whenever life brings me
to your side''
''... the earth seems fairer
than the moon''
''The fragrance of flowers
fills my heart''
''When evening comes,
your voice calls me''
''... the earth seems fairer
than the moon''
''Your thought like a whisper''
''Wakes me up in the
darkest hours''
''... the earth seems fairer
than the moon''
''Why must every meeting end
in separation ?''
''This thought torments me
all the time now''
''... the earth seems fairer
than the moon''
''Whenever life brings me
to your side...''
Umrao is crazy about Sultan
And l have no one
So you want to talk of love?
What else when we're alone?
So that's it
Dacoits have carried away
Bismillah
lf we'd found her corpse we could
have wept and comforted ourselves
The Nawab Saheb is waiting outside
What ! He's come here
Help me
l've come here because
my niece has come of age
You know she has been engaged
to Sultan since childhood
l'd like to be
as soon as -
But l informed you that
l do not accept this match
lt was fixed before
you and l divorced
God knows the trouble
you've caused me
l'm surprised that you called
on me after these 15 years
At least ask Sultan if -
Ask Sultan ? Who knows
better than me? What's good for him?
The trouble l've gone through
to give him a good upbringing
And l didn't take a penny
from you for his upkeep
But l want this match for Sultan's
own good
Perhaps you don't know
that Sultan is going astray
He visits courtesans
How dare you malign my child! Since
when have you worried about his good
Where were you till now ? Say rather
that you want a match for your niece
Look at yourself
You wrecked our home for that
wretched Khanum
And even now you keep
visiting her
Visiting courtesans is
an aristocratic tradition
A tradition for the father, yes.
For the son, its going 'astray'
Great !
l'd rather he visit courtesans than
marry your niece
lt's no use arguing with you
Sultan is my only son. l will
decide about his marriage
l'll fix a date, let's see
what you can do about it
l know my son won't hurt me.
He won't take a step against my wishes
Don't trouble me, in my condition.
For God's sake, go away
lf l could find a nice girl l'd fix
Sultans marriage at once
Then we'd see what the Nawab could do.
He couldn't do a thing
Sultan won't marry
against my wishes
My child, come
and sit near me
You're very late
Ever since Bismillah went,
Khanum doesn't let me come out alone
lt was difficult to get away
You seem troubled
Perhaps l'm not worthy
of being told your troubles
My troubles can't be
put into words
Say something. lt'll lighten
your heart
What can l say...
l can't understand you even now.
Sometimes l feel nothing separates us
At other times it seems your
inner world is hidden from me
Why think so ? l've never
considered you an outsider
Then why hide things
from me?
Father never met us. Now suddenly
he wants me to marry his niece
Why don't you ?
For your sake l'll bear
even that
Mother is dead against it. She wants
me to have nothing to do with them
l don't know what to do
Do whatever your mother says.
Her claim on you is greater
You have my best wishes anyway
Mother may not like that, either
Listen
You sing well
- Who are you?
He wants to meet you.
- He has talked to Khanum
l saw you some months back,
in passing
Once l thought of coming here
but somehow l didn't
And then the house was closed
for ''Mohurrum''
l too went home
on some work
l kept thinking of you
Wondering what you were like,
how your voice would sound
Thinking of something ?
- No
All right, you needn't
tell me
Here - a gift
Keep it
But this is a diamond !
ls it for me ?
Don't you like it ?
l like it, but ... does he love
you very much ?
Who can have faith in such love?
- lt's faith that turns into love
Look at me. Faith in Husseini has
kept me here all my life
You're different
No, my child, it's the
same thing
Either make someone your own
or belong to someone
l tried
Try again
You don't belong in a bordello.
The whole world is yours
Do you drink ?
No, sir
Okay. l'm going to my village
for some days
Where ?
- Farrukhabad
Want to come with me ?
Khanum will not let me
out of Lucknow with anyone
l'm not just anyone.
l am a landlord
l'll give 2 months salary
as advance
l'll ask Khanum, Nawab Saheb
Nawab Saheb ! Who, me?
What else should l call you?
Call me Nawab Saheb.
l like it
l've come to invite you.
l'm getting married tomorrow
God bless you.
May the bride prosper
How nice these clothes look!
Ah, the lovers of these days!
l too tore someone's
wedding clothes, but you see
Who was this boy?
lf you like, l'll get him here,
bound hand and foot
Why weep for him?
They're all like this
They swagger about in the square
but a little mouse scares them
The English have made
our stupid King useless
These nobles are immersed
in luxury
l tell you, soon the English
will come in
Then all their aristocracy
will vanish
What's wrong ?
My head aches
- Should l massage it ?
Come with me. With the fresh air
you'll never get a headache
l can't take you away
against your wish
lf it had been
any other woman ...
Don't know who he thinks
he is
''months ? Don't agree, even
if he offers 2 years salary''
Look at his face! Thinks
every woman is his concubine
When he comes next, throw Rs.150
in his face and tell me to get lost
That day he called me
an old woman
Here's 500 rupees
An advance for a recital
by Umrao from the Rao of Sitapur
l won't go. Return the money
- Khanum never does that
l have a headache
- You'll be all right by evening
When is the recital ?
- Tomorrow
l won't go to Sitapur
Don't talk that way.
Khanum will take offence
You care only
for the dance
You too get something from it
For God's sake,
don't bother me
What's wrong with you? You
didn't even want to meet that man
Then you're ready to go
with him to Farrukhabad
We stopped you, so you don't want
to dance... your head aches
You're forcing me
- Who's forcing anymore?
lf a lion loves a lamb,
he starves. You must dance.
l'll go with you
You will?
Yes, whether they let me or not,
l'll certainly go
Secretly?
Whichever way, take me away.
This place is stifling me
ls your headache better?
- Yes. How far is Kanpur?
Tired ?
l've never been on horseback before
- Come, let's rest a while
l didn't believe you would
come with me
lt had become hard for me
to live in Lucknow
l don't know why my heart
made me come with you
Do you know who l am ?
- What does it matter now ?
Wait here. l'll bring water
Faiz Ali, the outlaw !
His horse
- He must be around
You look there
Who was Faiz Ali to you?
What was his relation with you ?
- None.
Did he kidnap you ?
No
You were with him of your free will?
- She's his prostitute
Did you know that he was a dacoit?
No
You're from Lucknow?
- Yes
What is your name?
Were you with Faiz Ali ?
- Yes
ls this same Umrao you told about?
How's Mother? When did you
leave Lucknow?
Why don't you sit down?
ln Lucknow everyone
thinks that you...
Several times l thought
of writing
But l was scared of Mother.
She'll come at once and take me away
ls the Rajah a good man?
- Very
The bandits would have
killed me that very day
The Rajah - God bless him - caught
them. l've been with him ever since
Are you happy ?
l'm a queen. l live in comfort
Where were you going with Faiz Ali?
- Kanpur
Where will you go now?
Back to Lucknow?
lf l know where, l wouldn't
be wandering around
Still...
Can you get me escorted
to Kanpur ?
''Whenever l meet life,
it seems a stranger to me''
''Why does life change colors
everyday ?''
The evenings have become more
colorful since she came to Kanpur
Listen, my friends
You listen too, Umrao Jaan
Yesterday l passed a locality
There was a song being sung
and a big crowd
l listened carefully, and
it was a ghazal by Umrao Jaan
Does the singer from Lucknow
live here?
Yes. Go up the stairs
Are you Umrao Jaan?
- Yes, ma'am
Our lady has called you.
Tomorrow is her son's birthday
She'd like you to perform
How does she know me ?
She is also from Lucknow
You're from Lucknow, too
How did you know ?
A certain style in your speech
Keep this, the rest will be
settled later
l'll keep it so the Begum
is not offended
Right, then l'll go
l feel we have met
somewhere before
Strange. l was about to say
the same
Are you - Amiran ?
You're...
Remember me ? l'm Ramdei
''Since l parted from you
whom will l meet now ?''
''See what colors
life shows me?''
Amiran, if they'd chosen you
instead of me!
Then you'd have got the
bordello and l this mansion
Where is your husband ?
He's gone to Calcutta.
He'll be back by tomorrow
Now tell me about yourself
Why? lt's a happy occasion,
talk of nice things
Here's a suitable couplet
''What a favor the passage
of time has done me''
''That the earth seems
more beautiful than the moon''
l forgot. Nawab Saheb,
this is Umrao Jaan
Umrao Jaan's carriage
is ready
Are you leaving?
- Yes, l ask your leave
And if we refuse it?
''l did not find
what l looked for''
'' But this became an excuse
for seeing the world''
''What l was looking for...''
''l didn't embarrass you,
nor do l have any regrets''
''Thus l maintained
the tradition of love''
''What l lost...''
''l don't remember when
l got you, when l lost you''
''Life, l think l only saw you
in a dream''
''What l lost...''
''Says 'Ada', what can l say
of my condition?''
''The long journey of life
l traversed alone''
''l did not find
what l looked for''
'' But this became an excuse
for seeing the world''
''What l was looking for...''
My child!
How hard-hearted you are.
Don't you love anyone any more
Your Maulvi Saheb suffers so
much, thinking of you all the time
How is Khanum?
Losing her daughter half killed
her Losing you has finished her
We have come
to take you back
Umrao, where did you go ?
You look quite well
- Why should l be ill?
Aunt Husseini said you...
What else could l say.
She wouldn't have come easily
We brought her up, and now that
she's earning she goes her own way
The dove lays the eggs
and the crow eats them
So that's why you came to fetch me?
- Husseini, you are getting old
She comes home after months
and you start talking rot
Don't take it so hard.
She says any odd things
No, l won't stay in Lucknow
Stay till 'Muharram'.
Then you may go where you wish
Come to me, my child
Go to your room and rest
She won't stay here
The filly has started bucking
- So we'll fence her in
Bless you, my child. God give you
the riches of knowledge
Are you unwell?
Should l massage your head?
- Let me be, l don't have a headache
Even if you don't...
Why this sudden show of love?
Short of cash?
Why say such
un-poetic things?
For a true lover, sweet words
of the beloved are enough
What'll happen to me
when you leave?
The same as last time
She heard me weeping but
she did not even ask
What is this sound of crying
that l hear?
The old woman won't let you
go so easily
Even if you leave,
she'll fetch you back
There's only one way
Get married to someone
ls that a proposal?
Really. You stand to gain...
... by marrying me. Khanum's
hold on you will weaken
And after marriage? l'll earn
and you'll eat
l don't want to go out of the
frying-pan and into the fire
ls your name Umrao Jaan?
Yes
l've come from the court. According
to this, Gohar Mirza submits
... that his lawful wedded wife,
Umrao Jaan...
... wants to live with another
man without getting a divorce
The hearing is on the 18th.
Be present in the court
Your statements will be recorded.
Here's the summons
This is a copy of our
marriage contract
Apart from Aunty and Khanum, some
15 others were present at the wedding
Your obstinacy forced me to spend
a lot of money. But l had to do it
lt's false. All this
is false
l swear, Umrao,
l'm not to blame
Actually, Khanum is
not to blame either
At this age, what else
can she do?
Wait till the new girl
grows up?
lt's our fate
that is to blame
Not fate: circumstances
Can't you withdraw
the case?
One who has lived off
Khanum's leftovers would not dare
Go to Kanpur. My house
is empty
What will l eat?
Damn Gohar Mirza. He had to
leave at such a time
The British are in
every alley
God help us
They'll break down the gate.
Go out, over the wall
This is Faizabad. The convoy for
Beneras will leave in the morning
We'll have to spend the night here
- ln this wilderness?
Can't help it
Our blessed fate!
''That which has no face''
''That which has no name''
''Why do l long for such a thing''
ln Faizabad, your poetry has made a
greater mark than even your singing
lnvitation for performances
would be welcome
Poetry is not enough
for a living
Recall your performance
at our place
''What place is this, my friends''
''What location is this?''
''Where, as far as one can see,
there's dust and only dust?''
''What place is this, my friends''
''To what juncture...''
''...has life now brought me?''
''Where l have no control
over sorrow or joy''
''What place is this, my friends''
''What location is this?''
''Life asks an account
of the days gone by''
''My heart has no answer.
lt's full of remorse''
''What place is this, my friends''
''What location is this?''
'' Beyond the blinds
who beckons me?''
''ls someone still sad and
restless for me?''
''What place is this,
my friends?''
''What location is this?''
''Where, as far as one can see,
there's dust and only dust?''
''What place is this, my friends''
You're the one from Lucknow?
- Yes
What is your name?
- How does it matter?
Are you a prostitute
by birth?
No, by force of
circumstances
Say something about yourself.
Who are you?
How can l say who l am?
Where is your real home?
My real home is
where l'm standing now
Are you Amiran ?
Where did you go,
my darling?
Where are Father and my brother?
- Your father died long back
My darling! Where did you go?
Deserting your mother's world,
which world have you settled in?
No, Mother, this is not Amiran, this
is Umrao Jaan, the famous courtesan
Brother!
You've brought glory
to the family
We thought you were dead
But you're still alive.
You should have drowned yourself
lt'll be better
if you go away
My child