Come dear.
Let me tell you a story.
''There was a old house
in Lokhandwala, Mumbai.''
''Basera. Here lived Granny,
Sunil, Sunita, Anjali..''
..a lot of children
and their uncle Adi.
l have now assumed your name.
All in my love.
''What's in my eyes
all day and night?''
What's it? What's it?
''One face, only one face,
that's your face.''
''What's in my
heartbeat all day and night?''
What's it? What's it?
''Your thought, your
memory and only you.''
You are the soul of my dreams.
Only you are acceptable to me.
''The pleasure of my eyes,
l'm now in pieces.''
All in your love.
Fantastic!
- Adi! - No problem.
Tell Chopra to take the car.
lt will race with the winds.
This car is as good as a new baby.
Adi! lt is you who has to Race
against the wind. - Meaning?
There are 10 missed calls
and all from the menace.
Oh! Shit!
What happened?
- lt is Chandu's birthday today.
- He is not picking up the phone.
l will never forgive uncle.
l will grow up and beat
him up. Let's cut the cake.
When will uncle come?
- Let's cut the cake.
Where is sister Priya?
Sister Priya!
- What's it?
Let's cut the cake.
But your uncle was
going to get the cake.
That late Kate? We new that
he will never make it on time.
That's why we bought
the cake ourselves.
Duffers! He must be
stuck in a meeting.
He must be on his way.
No!
'May you live for a thousand years.'
''Bahadur, you've gone crazy.''
'May this day come again
and again.' - Bhahadur.
'May this heart sing out
again and again.' - Bhahadur!
Always keeps singing.
''Bahadur, you've to sing in tune.''
Bahadur.
- Who called me?
Did the box talk?
Bhahadur!
- Sorry sir.
What's the situation inside?
Shall l blow it out? - Hey! l am
coming. - Let me put it first.
''Hey, tigers.''
Oh yeah!
My tyre blew up.
''Come on, take out
the money. Hey! Wow!''
What's happening?
They had a bet on
what excuse you'll give.
l was stuck with a client.- l
couldn't come out of the meeting.
l slept off in the office.
- There was no spare time.
There was a big traffic jam.
my tyre blew up.
He guessed the right
excuse so he won the bet.
''Okay, buddies.''
l am Sorry.
''One, two, three, four.''
Happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday to dear Chandu.
Attack!
Today is Chandu's birthday
and you're sitting here.
''Sunita, don't bother me.
Am l not celebrating too?''
You can go there and
celebrate with everyone.
lf l drink before everyone
you'll feel dishonoured.
Then don't drink.
- Go away from here.
Why don't you..
- Go away. - Daughter-in-law.
Why are you indulging with him
when he doesn't listen to you?
''Happy Birthday.
- Uncle, come along and be with us.''
Happy birthday. No. l'll sit there.
l'll sit there.
- Shweta come on fast.
''Good evening, Mr. Harish.''
The children are
playing musical chairs there.
You seem to be playing
musical chairs with me here.
''No, l'm not doing that.
- Yes.''
When you sold me your house..
..you also took
advance for this house.
You told me that they will
agree to sell their house as it is.
They haven't agreed yet.
What's the secret?
l need some time.
- Time?
l didn't become a builder
to build small colonies.
l want to earn money
every moment of time.
That's why l can't remain idle.
Those who are idle are
the enemies of the country.
An enemy of the
country is my enemy too.
lndia is my country.
Every lndian is my
brother and sister.
l love my country.
- Shut up.
Give me one week's time.
What will happen in one week?
l have selected a
groom for Adi's sister.
How many of them will be there?
Two. Prabhakar and his son Rohit.
They will be two and we are so many.
That will be injustice.
We ate your food.
Shut up.
Tomorrow a boy is
coming to see Anjali.
None of you should appear
before him. - Why? Does he bite?
l said shut up.
- No!
Anjali is my niece but she
is more than a daughter to me.
We love each other a lot.
Great! lt is rare to see
such joint families these days.
What is Anjali's qualification?
B.com. She has also done
a course on computers.
For the last one year she is working
in a private firm. - Very good.
l must say that you're lucky.
She will keep you very happy.
l mean very.. Go away.
- What?
''Eat, l mean.. eat something.
- No.''
''Quiet, all of you.
- One minute.''
l have seen the boy.
How is he to look at?
- Handsome.
l'm going?
- Where? - To see the boy.
Why are you so impatient?
- lt is my marriage.
Where are you going?
- To meet the boy.
Girls have become
shameless these days. - Why?
''l thought that you'll tell me,
l don't want to marry''.''
Then l would cajole
you by saying that..
..girls are the ones
who have to get married..
..and go away and all
that blah blah. etc.
Go away? My foot.
l will marry only on the condition
that l stay here after marriage.
Do we have to bear with
you after marriage too?
Okay. l don't want to marry at all.
- One minute. - Listen.
''No, l will not marry''
Are you sure?
- Yes. - 100 - Yes.
Then l'll tell them that
she doesn't want to marry.
Not a bad idea.
- Brother! - What happened?
Why do you always take me seriously?
Now come.
- Where? - You! C'mon brother!
Oh yeah!
- Yeah!
Now come.
- Here comes our daughter.
This is not Anjali.
This is not Rohit.
''Come on, Mr. Prabhakar
let us leave them alone.''
Let me show you the house.
- Come on.
My house is also nearby.
'The moment you leave the house.'
- Bahadur!
'The moment you..
- My master is like this.
How are you?
- l'm fine.
- Fine.
You haven't had anything.
Take something.
''No, it's alright. Why
don't you take something?''
First you do so and then l will.
Please have something.
First it has to be you.
l had sold my property
which was to a builder.
This is what l'm suggesting to..
- Uncle please. Not today.
''Listen, Adi. l'm telling this to
you frankly. Don't mistake me.''
These days girls don't like
to live in joint families.
That's why l have
bought A flat for Rohit.
The total estimate is 1
crore including the interiors.
l have arranged for
fifty and the balance fifty..
Okay. l'll give the balance fifty.
Good!
So 25 before engagement
and 25 before marriage.
Ok.
- Good bye. - Bye.
ls this the way
Prabhakar should speak?
ls fifty lakhs a small amount?
We shall refuse this alliance.
We will find some other alliance.
''No uncle, it is alright.''
But how will you get
such a large amount?
We'll do something.
How can we get 25
lakhs in such a short time?
''Vicky, that 32 lakhs that you
withdrew and invested in property.''
''Adi, the market is down.''
lt will take 3
months for it to improve.
3Months. Are you sure about that?
- Of course!
Then l will borrow from
the market for that period.
l will have to mortgage the house.
''Read it carefully, son.''
The date for repaying the ..
..money is after 4
months on 1 7th December.
Take this sir. These
are the house papers.
Here is 25 lakh rupees for you.
But what was the hurry
for this. These days..
''Never mind, uncle.
What's the difference..''
..if l pay today or tomorrow?
Fine. Can we have the
engagement on 15th next month?
As you please.
- Have something. - Thanks
''Mr. Hirachand, it's you!''
First share and then cut.
What to do? Money begets money.
Here is the
agreement of Aditya Verma.
And these are his house papers.
ls this full 50 lakhs?
''What are you thinking, Mr. Harish?''
lf you don't mind can l
say something Mr. Hirachand.
This deal of yours
will cause you great loss.
You bought documents Worth
Rs.25 lacs by paying 50 lakhs.
l know my nephew Adi very well.
He will do something or the
other and repay his loan. - Maqbool!
He is Mr. Maqbool Kalam.
The main artist of
the stamp paper scam.
l see!
Yes.
- Thank you my friend.
''Mr. Harish, give me the file.''
Now tell me which
signature is the real one.
lncredible! l can't believe it.
Adi is under the wrong
assumption that the date..
..for repaying the loan is 1 7th ..
..December whereas it
is 1 7th October now.
After 2 months that
mansion will be mine.
Now l don't need these two.
- These two?
Yes. One!
Two!
The enemy of the
country is my enemy.
lndia is my country.
All lndians are my
brothers and sisters.
Have you noticed the time?
We are going to see better times?
''When morning comes, this car
will fly faster than the wind.''
That will be power of this car.
Why is the sir driving like this?
Children come.
New car! New car! New car! New car!
Okay.
Do you know who made this car?
- Who?
Uncle!
Do you know on what
this new car runs?
You think we are mad?
Petrol of course!
''No, buddy. This car
runs on solar energy.''
Solar energy? What is that?
Solar energy means
the rays of the sun.
New Pinch
- Listen to me.
''Don't joke, son.''
''l'm not joking, grandma. Seriously.''
l have a meeting
with GM Motors tomorrow.
lf my patent sells
then we are gonna be rich!
''ln the path of life we
shall share our pains together.''
''Be it misery or joy we
shall share it all together.''
''lf l get someone like you then
my job will be done, dearest.''
''ln the path of life we
shall share our pains together.''
''Be it misery or joy we
shall share it all together.''
''lf l get someone like you then
my job will be done, dearest.''
''Such a bond of
friendship can be seen nowhere.''
''We shall lay our
lives for each other.''
''We are to live together
and we are to die together.''
''This world will learn from
us how to love one another.''
''Every step that we take
shall be together forever.''
''Be it misery or joy we
shall share it all together.''
''lf l get someone like you then
my job will be done, dearest.''
Yeah!
- Yeah!
Order! order!
- Shut up.
This is so good. But this
would have come expensive.
''Not as expensive as my
sister's expression, right?''
Yeah!
- All right.
What is this? Why have
you spread all the jewels?
''Adi!
- Granny, marriage.''
Not marriage but engagement.
''More money will come, don't worry.''
They will come? Has it come yet?
This way you'll be a pauper.
''Have l become one yet? No, right?
- Right.''
''Granny, why don't you choose?''
Look..
- This one.
This one.
- Ok. - Wow!
Where is this one.
Wow!
- This is not for you. - Why?
This is for the daughter-in-law.
- Daughter-in-law?
Priya.
Come here.
Are you alright?
- l'm fine. She is fit for you.
''lmagine, if you're married you
will save a lot of money too. - What?''
Life long free
tuitions for the children!
Marriage.. and that too
with Priya? Ridiculous!
lt is not ridiculous at all.
- Marriage! Marriage! - Shut up.
Hey!
What is all this?
Meeting.
- What meeting?
There is a discussion going on
between Priya's mummy and granny.
What discussions?
- About marriage.
Oh yeah!
- Yeah.
Will he come to know.
My daughter has no objections.
The moment the bride's
people agree..
..we will fix the
auspicious date. - Hi!
What is all this without asking me?
- But Adi...
What is the hurry?
Marriage is something
that happens once in life.
''But son, our
daughter has no objections.''
Yes.
- Why would she have objections?
But mummy has already
finalised the proposal.
''Granny, l don't agree to this.''
But we have bought the
tickets to Bangalore.
lt makes no difference.
But why Bangalore?
To meet the bride's people.
''Who do we have there, granny?
- My sister lives there.''
She is the one who
initiated all the proposal.
The boy is from America.
l've brought the photo too.
See his photo.
But what about the children's exams?
''Don't worry, uncle. Priya has
finished our portions already.''
lsn't he handsome?
He is very handsome.
- Not less than a hero.
''Yes, Shahrukh Khan.''
lt is alright if
you all have decided.
l'm leaving since l have some work.
Ok. Bye-bye.
O yeah!
- Yeah.
Go and bring Adi.
''Uncle, come let us also play.''
You play and don't bother me.
''Please come, uncle.
- No.''
We shall win.
What's wrong with you?
Why don't you go? Tigers will lose.
What difference does it make
to you? You go to Bangalore.
''Don't act childish, now come on.''
Am l being childish?
Am l acting childish?
Did you ever think
that if you go away..
..then what will happen to me.
Hire a new teacher.
Just pick up someone from the road..
..and make her their aunt?
- Why?
What?
You call everyone a duffer
and you're the biggest duffer.
Meaning?
l love you.
l love you too.
Really?
Then get going. They need you.
''l Love you.
- Love you too, duffer.''
We're going to lose.
''No use, uncle! We're going to lose.''
''Tigers never lose, okay?
- Okay.''
Tigers!
- Shut up!
Oh yeah!
- Yeah.
''Tanu! Granny, Tanu is beating me.''
''Alright. Okay kids..
let's go to bed, it's late.''
Five minutes.
- lt's ten and not five minutes.
''No! Only five minutes, come on.''
We just won a match and are you
going to party the whole night?
What are you doing? Get to bed.
Granny! What's happened Adi?
He seems to be hurrying everyone
''Uncle, you aren't
letting me eat peacefully.''
Shameless fellow! You're eating
for the third time. Have some shame.
Uncle!
Can we have enough
time for a cold drink?
No.
- Goodnight and enough. Go to bed.
Chandu you.. Stop it. C'mon C'mon.
''Granny, please take them in.''
l said go to bed. Just
l said go to bed now.
C'mon please come.
And you are come fast.
''Granny, what are you doing?''
Cleaning the table.
Who will go for the
rehearsals early in the morning then?
But this..
- We are here and will do it.
Adi!
- Granny! Goodnight.
What is she doing?
Why has she not come in yet?
Granny!
What happened?
l have left them both together.
''Come granny, let's go
out and surprise them.''
'Chandu's uncle and Chandu's
aunty kissed clandestinely.'
That..
''Granny since you said that,
we also thought..''
How can we disobey the elders?
Okay. l understood it.
Tomorrow morning we'll go to
Priya's parents to talk about this.
Okay.
You don't have to go to Bangalore.
''Priya's aunty will
feel insulted, son.''
No aunty. l have a
solution to avoid it.
l was also planning to go
to America for a proposal.
We can do like this.
We will make that American
girl meet this American boy.
Then there will be a
compromise between them.
Then l am from Mumbai and
Priya is also from Mumbai.
''No, this is not possible. Sorry.''
''Mama, drop the act now. lt
has been stretched too far.''
Okay.
What do they say normally?
l never dreamt that l'll
get such a good son-in-law.
Thank you.
Then let us fix the
date of the marriage.
The day Anjali is getting engaged
we can have their engagement too.
That's it. They have cut me off
and the settlement issue is on.
Bunky!
- Bunky!
l will introduce myself.
''15 years ago, my father
and her husband were friends.''
Granny!
- Our marriage was settled then.
''ln my childhood her husband went
to Dubai and my father, to heaven.''
And 3 years ago they hoodwinked
me and came from Pune to here.
''Aunty, what nonsense is he talking?''
l will tell you the
rest of the episode.
Will l get Priya married to
this Bunky and spoil her life?
He has always failed in school and..
..has been in jail
for drug trafficking.
Now all shackles are broken. Now
no one can separate me from Priya.
''Come, Priya.
- One second, come here. Very good.''
Have you ever noticed
your style of talking?
Have you seen your
face in the mirror before?
Only a mad person can give her
daughter in marriage to you.
''So, Mr. Bunky, stop behaving
like a monkey and go back home.''
What are you saying? Hey!
Adi!
- Uncle! - l will back. Don't worry.
Both of you come in.
''Priya, come with me
quietly or else l'll kidnap you.''
Oh yeah?
- Yeah!
Anand Ray you seem to
love music. Learn the drum
You think that you're a hero?
''Mr. Harish, why are you
wearing out your sole?''
Come and sit down
and don't be tense.
How can l not be tense?
Tomorrow is Adi's meeting. He
is going to get a huge amount.
So what? Tomorrow is Friday.
Adi will deposit the
cheque on Saturday.
After that is Sunday.
Monday there is a bank strike.
On Tuesday there is
a religious festival.
Then on Wednesday..
That is of course irrelevant.
ln two days that
agreement is going to expire.
Then that property is
going to be in my name.
Because it is a legal document.
The one who goes against the law
of the nation is the nation's enemy.
The enemy of the
nation is my enemy too.
lndia is my country.
Every lndian is my
brother and sister.
l love my country.
What's going on? What's happening?
l have to go to work.
What's going on?
''ls today a very important day
in life for you? - Yes, so what?''
So we shall groom you today.
- No.
What are doing pal!
Who will put the trousers on me?
''Uncle, you're not a kid.
Can't you wear it yourself?''
l'm late. Granny l'm going.
One minute son.
Live long.
Have some curd.
What are you looking at?
Granny it is the
biggest deal in my life.
After today all our
problems will be over.
Everything will be alright.
Oh god! lts ten
thirty and l should leave.
''What's this?
- My report card, you've to sign it.''
Why didn't you show
it to me in the night?
l'm a child and l can forget too.
l'll sign in the night.
You want me to be
punished by the teacher?
Do it fast.
Why are the marks so low?
''l was sick during the exams,
have you forgotten that?''
Brother! All the best.
- Thank you.
Sister in law. - Naughty.
All the best. - Thank you.
''Bye, what's it now?
- Are you not forgetting something?''
l'm not forgetting anything?
Thank you. Bye.
Tigers!
Have they gone to school so early?
Tigers.
What happened?
- l'm dead.
Uncle has taken my file.
- What? Show me.
This is Adi's meeting file.
''Tigers. Hello.
- Adi. - Yes, granny.''
''Son, what file have
you taken with you?''
What happened? Oh shit!
''Granny, send someone outside. l
will reach there in 2 minutes.''
Don't cross the road.
Stop!
Uncle. l'm coming.
Uncle!
- Don't cross the road.
''Parth, don't.''
Parth!
Uncle!
Mr. Yamraj.
Count down.
There is nothing wrong with him.
Remember in the childhood
his breath would suddenly stop.
''Mother, calm yourself.''
Please calm yourself. lf
you lose the balance then..
..what will happen
to all these people?
l will make the arrangements
for the cremation and come.
Priya!
Hi.
- Hi. Hello.
Nice car.
- Thanks.
''925 Chevrolet, 4 cylinders
1800 cc. Well maintained.''
You are teaching me about my car.
Why is there so much smoke?
Not smoke but clouds.
''Are we going to some hill station?
- No, to the heaven.''
Good joke.
You are dead.
Good joke again.
You have a good sense of humor.
''You want to see. Look down.
- Yeah, sure.''
How is that possible?
l must be dreaming.
Pinch me.
Okay.
This is not a dream?
- This is not a dream. You're dead.
''Let me introduce myself, my boy.''
l'm Yamraj M.A.
- M.A?
M. A. stands for 'Mauth Ka
Ayojak' (messenger of death).
Why are you joking?
Tell me truth Please!
First it also
appeared to me like that.
He is serious.
Who are you?
- l'm Shakti. l'm also dead.
How is that possible?
His time was over.
Look at this.
This is you. This is your date..
..of birth and this
is your date of death.
And me? l'm the delivery man.
One second. l met with an
accident and.. - And you died.
How can you kill me like that?
You should give some notice.
l could've fallen
sick or bad health.
l could've done
something for my family.
Now what will happen
to them without me?
This is none of my concern sir.
This was directed by Chitragupt.
''No, you can't be
Yamraj (god of death)''
Because l don't have big moustaches?
l don't wear the crown
with horns and l don't wear..
''..the dhoti, isn't it?
- Exactly.''
That was the get up
in the ancient days.
This is now 2005.
Why are you driving a
Chevrolet car instead of a buffalo.
Mr. Buffalo could you
show yourself please.
Mr. Yamraj.
- Yes.
Where is your mace?
- Where is it?
Such a small one?
Have patience my boy.
How did you do that?
- Technology my boy.
Where are the sounds coming from?
We are going over hell.
- Hell? Can l have a look? - Look.
Oh god!
What happened?
- That was so horrible.
They also did horrible things.
Up. - Relax. - lt is
a mountain. - Relax.
''We have reached
our destination, sir.''
Let's go.
- l'll not come.
But this is a good place.
- l'm worried about my family.
''Mr. Yamraj, please let me go back.''
You know l can't let you go.
''Please, Mr. Yamraj, there is
no one else for my family.''
l beg of you with folded hands.
You don't understand. l
don't have the authority.
Do you need that? You
are so strong. - l know.
''But, no. - Please. Okay show me
what is happening in my house.''
Okay as you wish.
Sister Priya. ls not
everyone telling a lie?
l know that nothing
has happened to uncle.
He will surely come back.
He will give some excuse.
The tyre burst. - There was lot
of traffic. - This Vikram has..
..become very lazy. l
have to do all the work.
The bankers are
not giving the money.
l slept of in the office.
Sister Priya. Ring up uncle.
l had rung him up.
''We'll ring up again.
- Why are you telling lies, dear?''
Your uncle has gone to such a..
..place from where
no one can come back.
''No, don't say like that.''
''No, l'll not break down. He
thinks that l'll break down.''
''No, l'll not break down.''
Granny. - Let me also see
how much pain he can give me.
''Let me see, how much
hard hearted he can be.''
Let me see how wicked he can be.
l can't see all these.
l'm an emotional man.
Then help me out.
- What can l do?
Send me down for some days.
- That only the god can do.
He has gone on an eight
days vacation with his wife.
Vacation? Okay do like this.
Send me down for 7 days.
''After that you can
bring me back here, please.''
Okay l'll try and do something.
l will go down and
set right everything.
''Set right everything, okay?''
Thank you.
One minute. No one can
see you or hear you..
..and so how will you do something.
Why?
- You will go down as a spirit.
l know that you can do something.
Please do something.
l will have to put
the life back in you.
Then do it. - Are you mad?
l can't take that risk
Then it's alright. l will
also not go. l'll remain here.
l will not eat or
drink or do anything.
''l will feed you with my own hands.
- No, l don't want it.''
''You are making me emotional again.
- Then, what should l do?''
''My family, please help me. -Okay,
l'll do something.''
What will you do?
- After 7 days l'll come down and..
..give your life
back for only 5 minutes.
What is the use of living only
for 5 minutes? l don't want it.
Then 5 seconds?
Then 5 minutes?
- Okay.
''Okay, get ready for blast off.''
''3,2,1''
Why are you shouting?
We will fall down and die.
''ldiots, you both are already dead.''
All the best. Happy landing.
Come.
''We are ghosts, come.''
Oh god!
How did this happen?
- You said it that we are ghosts.
''Yes, we are ghosts.''
Can we go now?
- Come.
l'm a bad boy
''lt is my fault, all of it.''
lf l had not given the file to him
for signing then he wouldn't be dead.
''Sorry, uncle''
Don't say like that.
''Sister Priya, why did
god call back uncle?''
He is playing a game with us.
lt is like we play hide and seek.
God has hidden your uncle from us.
What we will do is
that we will pretend.
We will not let god know
that we're missing that duffer.
We will behave as if he
is with us all the time.
''l'm here, Priya.''
God has been cruel with us.
Everything was going
alright and suddenly..
We will postpone the
date of engagement.
''No, the engagement will take
place on the appointed day.''
Whatever Adi had fixed
nothing will change from that.
But can you arrange for
twenty five lakhs in a month?
What? Twenty five lakhs?
''Yes, it was assured by Adi.''
Twenty five lakhs before engagement.
And twenty five lakhs
before the marriage.
But l have already paid
them twenty five lakhs.
Fine.
lf Adi had promised
then we'll fulfill that.
Don't worry Prabhakar.
Where will so much money come from?
This Vikram will pay.
He is his partner.
l don't have so much money.
The profit that we made last
year Adi invested in real estate.
What a lie this fellow is telling?
''You know, the rates are falling.''
Poor Adi! All that money is sunk.
Okay madam. l'll leave now.
Tell me your decision by tomorrow.
l'll tell you now.
l don't want this marriage.
- Anjali! Shut up.
As you wish.
''No, Mr. Prabhakar, listen to me.''
''Granny, after today stop
worrying about my marriage.''
''Don't talk like a fool, dear.''
Some solution will surely come out.
''l don't want to marry.
- Shut up Anjali. - Sit down, dear.''
''Vikram, what happened to
that General Motors deal.''
Adi used to say that some
money will come out of that.
Granny..
There is a company
called Fancy Wheels.
They have sold the
pattern of that car.
They did it before Adi.
He is telling a lie. The rascal!
''There is no use, we're ghosts.
- What will happen now?''
''Let me see what l can do,
if at all l can.''
l'll take leave now.
Where are you going?
Come here. Vikram!
lt is true that l'm not
the real uncle of Adi.
But are we not one family?
Now Anjali's marriage
is my responsibility.
''Dear, you engagement
will also take place and..''
..your marriage will also take
place the way Adi had wanted.
Do you have so much money?
Where will l have it?
l have thought of a way.
l had sold my property to
one rich man Hirachand.
That nice man is ready
to buy this property too.
You will get a fat amount
and also a flat to live.
No.
- Why?
- Then see this.
Adi had taken 25 lakh
rupees from Hirachand.
There are only 2 days
left to repay the amount.
l never borrowed any
money from Hirachand.
Even then the date
falls due after a month.
Look the signature is also Adi's
They are all trying
to trap my family.
''Granny, don't listen to him.''
''Okay, l'll leave now.''
Think that this house is gone.
- Where are you going?
Oh no!
Shit!
Why did l at all come here?
Brother Adi.
- What's it?
Our luck is so bad that we
can't bang our heads also.
Come.
''Brother Adi, where are we going?
- Don't know''
Brother Adi we are ghosts.
l know that we're ghosts.
That is the problem.
What is the use of these seven days?
What was the use in coming here?
We can do nothing. Useless.
Hell with it.
Already there is very
little food inside me.
Still l was getting to sleep
and these two have landed.
''Hey, what's it?''
What are you looking
here and there? Talk to me.
Come here.
- We?
Sit down.
Can you see us?
Hey jumping jack. Do you
think l'm whiling my time here?
Do you know my name?
Fakira.
BPCM.
What's this BPCM?
Bhoot (ghosts) Pret
(spirits) Connecting Medium
Mama wanted me to be a
doctor and papa an engineer.
l said that there are already
more doctors than patients.
Then there are more
engineers than buildings.
l wanted a
profession that is unique.
But what to do my luck is very bad.
ln my profession the
customers are solid.
But they don't have a
penny to pay. Do you have?
No. isn't it?
Firstly there is no food inside me.
On top of that the people
think that l've gone mad.
They think that l'm
talking to myself.
Mad man! Why are you
talking to yourself?
You!
''The disease on earth,
They think that l'm mad.''
You are also the limit.
You were comfortably dead.
Then why did you come
down here? Useless.
What are you looking at me for?
My opening speech is over.
''Tell me, what is your problem?''
''Fakira, only you can help me.''
What's the use?
''Tell me, what is your tension?''
My granny is in deep problem.
My uncle and his friends are
bothering my family a lot.
We can do nothing to help them.
That's why we have
come to you for help.
Please do something.
l will do nothing.
Everything has to be done by you.
l will only tell you a technique.
ln twenty four hours you
will have power for ten minutes.
Only power for ten minutes?
You little ghost.
How little is your
budget and how lot you speak.
lf you want take it or..
''Fakira, that'll do.''
Now sit flat like this.
l will teach you the wordings.
''Praise the lord Hanuman, who is
the ocean of virtues and knowledge.'''
He is making a fool of us.
This is a hymn on lord Hanuman.
Then do l sing a movie song for you?
''We want the power of Spiderman,
Batman and Superman.''
You pocket transistor.
''Do you know who was the father
of Superman, Batman and Spiderman?''
lt was Hanuman.
Has any one flown before
in the American culture?
These three had also
borrowed their power from Hanuman.
Nonsense! lt is we lndians who
don't know the value of Hanuman.
lt is alright Fakira. He
is a child so forgive him.
Shut up.
Now you do as l say.
Hey Nagawale.
ls he also a dead one?
''No, he looks dead but he is alive.''
Now play.
''The one who at the feet of the
Guru wants to correct his mind.''
''He is the beloved of the lord Ram
who can give you the boon you want.''
''Knowing that l'm ignorant l
pray to the son of the wind.''
''Give me strength, wisdom and
education and remove my miseries.''
''Hail the lord Hanuman,
the enlightened monkey.''
''Hail the
conqueror of three worlds.''
''Hail the lord Hanuman,
the enlightened monkey.''
''Hail the
conqueror of three worlds.''
The ambassador of Ram..
''..the unmatched power and
son of Anjali and the wind god.''
''The great warrior also
called the Vikram and Bajrangi.''
''The vanquisher of evil thoughts
and well wisher of the pious mind.''
''Hail the lord Hanuman,
the enlightened monkey.''
''Hail the
conqueror of three worlds.''
''Hail the lord Hanuman,
the enlightened monkey.''
''Hail the
conqueror of three worlds.''
''The man who shines
the precious stone.''
''The one who is
adorned by divine jewels.''
''Your hands carry the
mace and other arms.''
''Your shoulders adorn
the sacred thread on them.''
''Hail the lord Hanuman,
the enlightened monkey.''
''Hail the
conqueror of three worlds.''
''Hail the lord Hanuman,
the enlightened monkey.''
''Hail the
conqueror of three worlds.''
''The manifestation of Lord
Shankar and the son of Kesari.''
''The one with the hallow and
the one worshipped universally.''
''The manifestation of Lord
Shankar and the son of Kesari.''
''The one with the hallow and
the one worshipped universally.''
''The most
knowledgeable and capable.''
''The one eager to do
errands for Lord Ram.''
''The most
knowledgeable and capable.''
''The one eager to do
errands for Lord Ram.''
''The one who loves to hear the
recital of the lord's praise.''
The one who is in the heart
''Lakshman and Sita.''
''The one who manifested
before Sita in a tiny form.''
''The one who assumed a
demonic form to destroy Lanka.''
stronger form to vanquish demons.''
''The one who handled
Lord Ram's tasks.''
''Hail the lord Hanuman,
the enlightened monkey.''
''Hail the conqueror
of three worlds.''
''Hail the lord Hanuman,
the enlightened monkey.''
''Hail the conqueror
of three worlds.''
What dress is this?
What do you want?
Undergarments over the dress?
What good dress the
lord has given you.
Have you not seen 'Men in Black?
The clothes are good but
what about the power?
ls this some dress
from a costume shop?
There is power in the clothes.
Why are you beating?
Why are they beating everyone?
These are burden on earth
that eat out of others labor.
No one should come in between.
Why don't you do something?
Will l do everything? l have
given you the dress with power.
Now go and test the power.
See where he has flown away?
l have beaten everyone.
Did you enjoy it?
lt is good Fakira.
l'll leave now.
You ghost with no gratitude.
You've also become like humans.
''Sorry, Fakira.''
Get some more bread.
Put some butter on it.
l'm getting it.
See what your
partner is doing there.
He is trying to whisk
away some bread and gravy.
lt's gone. The bread and gravy
is gone. Making a fool of me?
Shall l get some more bread?
What's it. Will you keep
staring at me till l digest the food?
Have you not got the power?
Get lost. Wash everyone out.
Get lost and let me eat.
Thanks Fakira.
l'll take care of you. The
bread and gravy are flying.
''Hey, what happened?
- The bread and gravy are flying.''
''Come, sit down and eat.''
Granny.
Come inside. Won't you sleep?
You go inside. l'm
don't feel like sleeping.
''Granny, you have to go
tomorrow morning for dialysis.''
l don't want dialysis anymore.
- What?
''See, poor Adi died
at such a young age.''
''l, an old woman, is
living a borrowed life.''
l don't want to be a
burden on anybody.
''Don't talk like a child, granny.''
''Really Anjali, my life
is not so precious..''
..that we spend money on dialysis.
''Don't talk like that, granny.''
Let's go.
- Where?
Come.
''Brother Adi, who are
these dangerous people?''
lt seems they have hired
guards to guard our money.
Let's have some fun.
Did you hit me?
l didn't hit you.
Someone hit me too.
What's happening?
Who is hitting us?
Why are you laughing?
Your trousers are down.
Your trousers are down too.
''Close your eyes, Maya.''
Why?
- Close them. - Okay.
ls this for me?
- Yes.
Wow! What a beautiful necklace.
Ten lakhs!
You want to be looted tonight?
''Yes, it appears to me to be so.''
Yes son. Something is
going to happen to you today.
Hey! Turn around. Stay.
Come on.
''Darling, what's wrong?
- Nothing.''
What were you doing?
l was watching what they
were doing. - Shut up.
What?
- l was wondering how to ..
..open the safe without the key.
We are ghosts. We will
put our hands inside.
We can put our hands inside
but how to take out the money?
Let us think.
ldea!
''l'll open the safe
from inside, okay. - Okay.''
''Don't delay, come.''
''Darling, the best French
wine in the world. - Really?''
Twenty two and half years old.
- Wow! Will you not offer me?
Let's go.
- What's this?
Best wine in the world.
- How many times will you say that?
Go and get the glass.
''Yes, ma'am, at your service.''
Darling! Wine!
Thank you.
- Cheers!
lt tastes strange.
- lt's French wine.
So strange. Try it again.
What are you doing?
Why don't you drink it?
What's this?
- Sorry.
''Maya, please listen to me.''
Leave me.
- Listen. - l'm leaving.
''Maya. Listen to me, Maya.
Sorry. Maya..''
How dare you?
Guards!
No!
''Granny, how are you?''
We are late.
- Shall we go for dialysis?
l'm not going anywhere.
''Granny, don't talk like that.''
Don't argue.
Granny!
- What happened?
What happened?
What has happened?
Where did this come from?
- That's what l'm thinking too.
Maybe Adi kept it. Didn't find
the opportunity to tell about it.
l'm opening it daily.
l've never seen it before.
Maybe his ghost left it there.
''You say whatever you feel, granny.''
You mustn't have noticed.
- Maybe.
''Granny, will you
come for dialysis now?''
''Yes, dear.''
Oh yeah!
- Yeah.
''lt's good that granny
went for dialysis, isn't it?''
l'm tired.
l'm tired too.
What is brother Sunil drinking?
- Alcohol.
''Alcohol is bad for health, isn't it?''
Then why is he drinking?
Last year he suffered some loss in..
.. business and started drinking.
Why was there a loss?
How many questions
you ask? Let me sleep.
ls this the time to sleep?
Seven days are not yet
over and why have you come?
l came to the
neighbor Sharma's house.
The cloud was clear so l came early.
l had 15 minutes so l
thought l'll meet you.
One minute.
- ls something wrong?
''No, sit down. Are you talking
about the neighbour Mr. Sharma?''
Yes. - That's good. You've done
a good job for the first time.
Strange. You were
cursing only a few days back.
Actually Mr. Sharma has been
in bed for the last 6 months.
No.
- He was suffering from bone cancer.
''He used to shout ''Take me away!''.
- No.''
What happened? - The fact is
that l've not come to pick him up.
l've come to take his son away.
- What? - Yes.
You want to take away Vishal?
He got married only 3 years
ago and has a one year old son.
What are you talking?
Don't create tensions.
His name is on the list.
He will come out
now to go to office.
ln the next corner there
will be an accident and l..
You took me. Was that not enough?
This is too much.
''Duty, boss.''
When are you taking Sharma away?
''After 4 years,
along with me skywards.''
ls there no logic with
you fellows up there?
The one who has to go now..
you are taking him after 4 years.
The one on whom the family
depends.. What do you say?
Shall l leave?
No?
l've come from so far and you
didn't show any hospitality.
On the contrary you
are pouncing on me.
Sorry. What will you have?
''coffee, cold drinks?''
What is he drinking?
- Whisky.
l'll also have whisky.
''No, that is bad and a filthy thing.''
Who is the guest?
- You.
Then l'll have whisky.
- You'll not get it.
Beware l'll take you up.- Will
you take me up again and again?
''Okay, no one will take away anyone.
l'll get some whisky.''
Mr. Yamraj (God of
death) that's natural folk.
Now l will have the whole bottle.
ls this some cocoa drink that
you'll have a whole bottle? No.
Who is the guest here?
''Buddy, it's you.''
''Bring it, buddy.
- Bring it buddy. l'll get it.''
What are you looking at?
You are crazy?
- Crazy? Sorry.
''Why is he drinking so much,
brother Adi? - l don't know.''
''Hey, who's there?
- No one is there.''
Life should be like this.
Oh God! What have l done?
''Hey, l am here. What happened?''
Tired? l am the one who is
tense and you're getting tired.
What happened?
- What happened!
l'm finished!
l'm dead!
- Come down.
l'm destroyed!
What?
What did you give me to drink?
''l told you. l told you,
don't drink it?''
You told me?
- Yes.
You never told me that
it will be like this.
What are you doing?
- Meditation.
Come down and do it.
- l will not.
Mr. Yamraj. (God of death)
What happened to him?
- l don't know.
l'd warned you.
''What did you want me for, sir?''
Oh God!
Should we discuss
this over a cup of tea?
What are you grumbling in English?
Because you don't understand Hindi.
l've lost my outdoor job.
l've lost my conveyance.
l'm going to get a desk job.
That means a clerk in heaven.
What nonsense are you talking?
Goat. You're calling me a goat?
''Not goat. l said, ''What
nonsense you are talking?''
You mean what kind of
rubbish l'm talking?
Exactly.
My whole career is under jeopardy.
And you're making
fun of me. Disgusting!
Strange. He's gone again.
He drank the whisky. He fell.
He made us run around the house.
What's it that we did?
What you did?
Why are you scaring me?
- Am l scaring you?
You destroyed me.
From the moment l met you
l've been cursing myself.
Stop it!
We gave you only
whisky and didn't kill you.
Only my enemies will die.
l'm Yamraj (God of death).
''lf you are Yamraj, why
are you getting so hyper?''
You're the one getting hyper.
- Thank you.
''The fact is, Vishal is saved.
- Saved?''
l mean that he left the house
and reached the second signal.
But then l was here
drinking whisky and..
l didn't understand.
l will explain.
Kitty.
Sorry.
What sorry? This
is your daily drama.
When l leave for office
you're busy doing something.
l'm late daily because of you.
Why are you wasting your time now?
Sit down.
Let's go.
l curse the day when my
mama chose you as my bride.
And l curse my
father for choosing you.
l get scolded
everyday because of you.
lt is like that.
- What?
You get scolded in
the office only ..
..but for me it
starts in the morning.
Why not? lt is all because of you.
Because of me? lt is
your father who is sick.
l take care of him day and night.
You never even praise
me but always scold me.
What praise do you want?
Should l felicitate you?
My papa is sick. You
want me to throw him out?
When did l say that?
- What else? - Look forward.
So what? He died.
This didn't happen.
Then?
- See this.
Kitty.
Sorry.
What sorry? This
is your daily drama.
When l leave..
- Fast forward.
Where is he? God
knows where he went.
Where did you go? You
should inform and go.
l was getting late.
l tried to go by air.
That's good. Vishal will not die.
- Why will he not die?
Every man has grace time.
- Meaning?
Sometimes we reach late.
Have you seen Discovery Channel?
Have you seen how men
die and then come alive?
When will Vishal die now?
- After 40 years.
Did l also have grace period?
- Of course.
Then why did l die?
- Because l reached on time.
Before l start crying let me leave.
Fine. At least Vishal is saved.
''Excuse me, sir.
- What's it now?''
Can l get one more whisky?
''There is a limit, buddy.''
You just fell flat because
of that. You want more?
Not for me. l can cajole ..
..Chitragupt (book
keeper of deeds) with that.
ln heaven too!
Okay l'll get it.
''Excuse me sir, your whisky.''
''Thank you, sir.
- You're welcome.''
My future lies in your hands.
''Thank you, boy.''
''Next you'll get a
spank from me, understood?''
Jolly good!
- Really.
What's all this?
Did l not give you
problems to solve?
The exams are due shortly and
are you all concerned or not?
''We were doing some drawing,
sister Priya.''
l know. But is that needed now?
''Sister Priya, this is
you and this is uncle Adi.''
What happened? Didn't
you like the drawing?
Yes. Very beautiful.
You all do your work.
''Enough, Priya.''
Adi!
Adi? He has gone up.
Come with me.
Leave me alone.
What are you doing? Leave me.
''Lord Hanuman will
absolve you of all miseries.''
''To all who can control
their mind, actions and words.''
''Lord Hanuman will
absolve you of all miseries.''
''To all who can control
their mind, actions and words.''
''Lord Hanuman will
absolve you of all miseries.''
''To all who can control
their mind, actions and words.''
''Lord Hanuman will
absolve you of all miseries.''
''To all who can control
their mind, actions and words.''
''Lord Hanuman will
absolve you of all miseries.''
''To all who can control
their mind, actions and words.''
''Lord Hanuman will
absolve you of all miseries.''
''To all who can control
their mind, actions and words.''
''No, that is impossible.''
''Granny, it is true.
lt was Adi there.''
Otherwise how could l and the ..
..children have
escaped with Bunky there?
You are saying it just like that.
''One minute, Granny. l think
that Priya is telling the truth.''
What happened to me? Two
bottles of whisky vanished suddenly.
''Granny, that money! lt was
not there three days back.''
''Granny, please explain it to lshan.''
The magic show is tomorrow
and he is not practicing.
''Come, l'll explain it to him.''
''lshan, do something.
- No. l won't do anything.''
''lshan, why are you not practicing?''
l don't want to
take part in the show.
''Why?
- l don't want to, that's all.''
''lshan, if you don't take part
then it will hurt uncle Adi.''
Would he have left
us if it hurts him?
''lshan, you know
that uncle is with us.''
He is also helping us.
He is seeing us too.
Oh God! How did they know?
They are saying it
just like that. Watch.
''lshan, enough of your attitudes.
Otherwise we will..''
Okay.
Come here everybody.
Now our new magic.
Tie the chain.
- Chain?
''Okay. Are you sure?
- Yes, granny.''
Fasten the knot well.
- Okay l'll tie it.
Put the lock.
ls it locked?
Follow me.
Open the trunk.
How did you get in here?
l wanted to scare you all.
Where is he now?
l am here.
How did you reach there?
- Magic.
Let someone see my magic too.
Why has he not come out yet?
Shall we open it?
- He will bash you.
Excellent.
- What magic! How did lshan do it?
He cheated. The duplicate
key was inside his mouth.
ln the fifth annual
Junior Magician Competition..
..the next participant to
enchant you is Baby Kareena.
''Friends, before you will be
our next contestant, King lshan.''
lshan! lshan! lshan!
The hands of King lshan
will be tied by a chain.
Then that chain shall
be secured with a lock.
Then King lshan will
be shut in this trunk.
King lshan will come out of the
trunk like a bullet from a gun.
Look. - How many times should
l see? l've seen the rehearsal.
lf King lshan does this
spectacle then he will be the winner.
ln my five years experience l ..
..have never seen
something like this.
l think that King lshan will
not be able to do this spectacle.
Sister Priya!
Help me!
Brother Adi..
- What?
What?
- What's happening? l'm worried.
Nothing dear.. Don't worry.
Come on lshan you can do it.
''Priya, l am worried.
ls lshan alright?''
''Uncle Adi, help!''
lshan come on. Come out.
Brother Adi.
- What?
You're worried.
- Yes. - Then go.
Come on lshan. You can do it.
''Lord Hanuman will
absolve you of all miseries.''
''To all who can control
their mind, actions and words.''
Brother Adi.
What is it now?
- Something is wrong with lshan.
''One, two, and three.''
''Lord Hanuman will
absolve you of all miseries.''
''To all who can control
their mind, actions and words.''
''Lord Hanuman will
absolve you of all miseries.''
''To all who can control
their mind, actions and words.''
''Lord Hanuman will
absolve you of all miseries.''
''To all who can control
their mind, actions and words.''
''Lord Hanuman will
absolve you of all miseries.''
Granny!
lshan.
No!
Tell us how you did that.
The magician never tells his secret.
''lshan, don't show off. We
knew that you'll come out.''
But how did you float in the air?
l can only tell if
there was some magic.
''You know, l had
dropped the key in the trunk.''
l was slowly getting out of breath.
- Oh God! Then?
Then the key floated
and the lock was opened.
Then someone picked me up.
- Who can pick you up?
''Duffer, it was uncle.''
''lshan, you're talking rubbish.''
lshan is right. Adi is
amongst us and is also helping us.
l don't understand why he
is not coming before us.
''l'm standing before you, granny.''
''Granny, does uncle Adi
know how much we miss him?''
l'm missing you all too.
Leave us and look at her.
''l shall love only you
and talk only about you.''
''From now l shall love you
day and night, my beloved.''
''l shall love only you
and talk only about you.''
''From now l shall love you
day and night, my beloved.''
''l had the whole world for
me and only you were missing.''
They are melting by my touch..
''..the lips which
were frozen till now.''
''What a season has come
and what a moment this is!''
''My peace is all lost and
restlessness is setting in me.''
''From now we shall live
together as long as life bestows.''
''From now l shall love you
day and night, my beloved.''
''l shall love only you
and talk only about you.''
''From now l shall love you
day and night, my beloved.''
Hi Vikram. What have you brought?
These are bank documents on
which l need your signature.
''Read it.
- Read it, brother.''
ls this the age to read?
What's this joke? Sign it.
Am l joking?
What's this you did? Why
did you throw the pen?
l didn't throw. lt went on its own.
- l just look..
You drunkard! Enough of it.
l warn you. Don't abuse him.
Say sorry.
''Sorry, sister-in-law.
lt is for the signature.''
''What's it?
- Nothing, some bank papers.''
Let me see.
- See it.
He is talking rubbish.
Enough of it. Sign it or otherwise!
Do something.
Why are you laughing?
He doesn't know that brother was
the boxing champion in college.
Mummy!
Don't move or else!
- Papa!
Hit him. Once more.
Get up.
Take this.
Never dare to come
to this house again.
Papa.
''l'm proud of you, papa.''
Come.
Everybody.
''Come, let's be there.
Let's dance now.''
Move your body.
Cool it.
- Can you hear me?
Groove it.
On the floor.
Everybody.
''Your memories, your memories.''
The sentiments are still fresh.
None other than you appeals to me.
''Every moment is
spent just on that.''
''You memories, your memories.''
The sentiments are still fresh.
None other than you appeals to me.
''Every moment is
spent just on that.''
''You memories, your memories.''
Wherever l went.
''l found you there, dear.''
Always you came with me.
Your shadow.
''The dreams in my eyes
and pain in my heart.''
My lips only utter your name.
The sentiments are still fresh.
None other than you appeals to me.
''Every moment is
spent just on that.''
''You memories, your memories.''
When the moon rises on the sky.
The moon rises on the sky.
''lt brings only your
image to my mind.''
Brings your image.
My heart is filled with you.
You flow in every part of me.
The sentiments are still fresh.
None other than you appeals to me.
''Every moment is
spent just on that.''
''You memories, your memories.''
''Ten, nine, eight, seven, six.''
''Five, four, three, two,''
The time to repay the loan
taken on the house is over.
What will be our
destination tomorrow?
That house!
How do you like this property?
Here we'll build a
25-storied building.
You black and white TV! Who are you?
Who am l?
The owner of this house.
By this evening this
house should be vacated.
You're mad.
- Mad? Me?
What's this?
- Read it.
What's written in that?
l told you that Adi
borrowed some money.
He is the one who lent that money.
The last date for
repayment was yesterday.
Will you all leave on your own or..
..shall l throw you
and your belongings out?
ls it? lf you touch anything in ..
..this house l'll break your hands.
l'll throw you out too
along with your belongings.
ls that so? Come here.
''One minute, sir.''
l'll explain it to her.
All this problem is
because of this house.
You sell this house to them.
Otherwise their physical strength
is also as real as this paper.
''What will you do now, black crow?''
''You old woman, watch it.''
No! No!
Shame!
''What's this you're doing,
Mr. Hirachand?''
You have made your
fortunes with your hands and now..
..you are using it to dig your
nose? Take your fingers off.
So you're with him?
You hit me!
- Yes.
''Hey, paper!''
The root cause of all
problems is this old man.
''Hey, l'm very angry, leave my hand.
- What's your problem, man?''
''Why did you hit me?
- You deserve it,''
''What impertinence is this?
- Who, me?''
Give me a break!
Daddy!
Mummy! Why is my tie standing up?
''What happened, uncle? Are you tired?''
You!
Here take your tie.
What's this? You'll
fight it all alone?
''You also come sister,
We're enjoying it.''
Hi!
Thank you!
- Welcome.
What?
''Uncle, did you get it?''
You!
Very good! Don't leave them.
What happened?
- l'm tied!
They have tied me.
Stop.
- What are you doing?
Can't you see that l'm swinging?
When l was six months old my
mother swung me like this.
Mummy!
Behave yourself.
How can l?
''See what's happening there, come.''
'l moved there and l moved here.'
'l don't know which way l moved.'
'Oh.. l slipped.'
What's this that you did?
Mr. Hirachand!
- Shut up.
''Mr. Hirachand, whose
property is this? - Mine.''
Oh yeah!
- Yeah.
Adi!
''You're here, aren't you?''
l know. l can feel you.
Please talk to me Adi.
l love you.
''Adi, talk to me. Please!''
l want to see you.
''Where are you, Adi?
l want to see you.''
Where are you?
What is this?
- Adi has written l love you.
''Granny, Adi is here amongst us.''
l know. Why is that shameless
fellow not coming before us?
''l'm constrained, granny.''
From today no more constraints.
l told you that l'll
come after 7 days.
Take this.
What's this?
- Your life.
l had told you. You can
meet everyone for 5 minutes.
''Can't it be more
than 5 minutes, please?''
You're such a nice person.
No emotional blackmail.
Eat it.
Granny! See that
Adi!
Have you returned!?
l'm not live
Uncle!
He gave me only a little time.
- Who?
Yamraj.
''Yamraj? Here?
- Yes, he's there.''
''Uncle, who's this?
- Tension, l mean Shakti.''
''Hello everybody.
- Hello, Shakti.''
''The responsibility of the
whole house is on you, granny.''
Where are brother
Sunil and sister-in-law?
Sunita took Sunil to the doctor.
''ls everything alright?
- Yes, Sunil wants to quit alcohol.''
lt is good!
No! You remember
what happened last time?
But the taste is good.
''Granny, there will no
more shortage of money.''
Anjali's marriage will
be conducted grandly.
''How are you studies?
- Good, uncle''
Life should be like this.
''l'm dead, destroyed and finished.
- Shut up.''
Why did you drink alcohol again?
l couldn't control.
''l'm dead, destroyed and finished.''
Nothing has happened to you.
l had to slap you
fifty times to wake you up.
You wasted 2 minutes of mine.
Slapped me fifty times?
But why did you wake me up?
You kept your promise
so l had to keep mine.
You're a very nice boy.
That's enough of your praise.
Can l go now?
l'm sorry.
- What sorry?
Who is he talking to?
- Yamraj.
Why did you have to drink?
Then tell him to leave you behind.
How is that possible?
He can take me instead
of you. l'm a burden here.
''No, granny. Everyone needs you.''
''Mr. Yamraj, you take me.''
''No, Mr. Yamraj.. take me.''
My mummy and papa are also there.
Uncle is needed here.
''Yes, Mr. Yamraj
leave uncle and take me.''
Take me.
You take me!
Take me!
''Please, Mr. Yamraj.''
Leave uncle and take me.
What are you all doing? Stop it.
Stop it now.
Enough.
Everyone has to die
some day or the other.
Are not Shakti's
parents facing the grief?
Now come on.
All of you smile
and bid me farewell.
''Come on, smile.''
Priya.
You have your whole life before you.
''You'll get a better
boy that me, don't worry.''
Adi!
l don't want anyone else.
''Granny, explain to him.''
Adi.
''One more minute, please.''
l'll not take you.
- What?
For the sake of
these people l leave you.
What will happen? l'll lose my
outdoor job. Let it be lost.
l don't want that job
where there is no method.
l'll tell Chitragupt that..
..there are so many people
on earth not entitled to live.
Corrupt people and criminals.
l'll manage.
Come on. Go.
Oh yeah.
- What happened?
Yamraj has let me live.
l'll live here now.
ls it?!
- Yes!
Uncle! We want to thank Mr. Yamraj.
Tell them it is okay.
He says that it's okay.
Not like that. We want to meet him.
''Yes, we want to meet him.''
''Hey, Adi.''
No.
Will you break the children's heart?
Don't make me emotional.
Okay.
Hello everybody.
Sanjay Dutt!
Who is that?
''l'm fed up, you know?''
Four days back someone
called me Munnabhai.
Some years back people
called me Khalnayak and Raghubhai.
Who are these people?
Next time you meet Sanjay Dutt..
..tell him that he
looks like Yamraj.
Okay.
- See you.
Excuse me.
- Yes.
''Can l get you tea,
coffee or something else?''
Can l get that?
l was joking.
ln ten minutes l have to pick a
consignment from the hospital.
Bye.
- Friend!
Adi!
Don't cry.
Don't leave us and go.
What are you saying?
Stay here with us.
''Please, Mr. Yamraj.''
''Stay with us, please.''
First time you said
nice things about me.
Otherwise the whole world curses me.
''Death, the crusader
of death and all that.''
You're a lucky fellow. You
have these nice children with you.
You also stay back.
You know that l have my job.
Then resign it.
''Don't be childish, Adi.''
Whenever you think
about me call out to me.
l will surely come.
Bye everybody.
Uncle!
Shut up.
What happened? What's your problem?
Why are you asking all
these questions? l'm fine.
This boy is going inside?
You can't go inside.
Wait.
- Leave me.
Oh God!
What are you doing here?
l stay two blocks away.
Can l come here daily to play?
''Of course, Shakti.
- How do you know my name?''
Who's that?
- Don't know. Let us see.
Ask him.
- Okay.
Excuse me.
Yes.
Oh God! Yamraj!
Me? Yamraj?
You must be mistaken.
My name is Sanjay Dutt.
l do small roles in movies.
''Of course, Sanjubaba. How are you?''
The children were joking.
Say sorry.
- Sorry. - Never mind.
Why have you come here?
l have been eyeing this
property for a long time.
lt is good.
l thought that if you
want to sell it then.. - No.
Okay. Why are you shouting?
Don't sell it if you don't want to.
Actually l risked my
life to save this house.
Okay. Can l get a glass of water?
''Of course, please come in.''
''Mama, what are you looking at?''
Look at this. This
is fifty kilograms.
How much?
- Fifty kilograms.
Have you seen that movie?
- Three times.
Then why call me Yamraj?
That was a slip of the tongue.
A tongue of slip!
''Does that make me Yamraj?
- That was a mistake, uncle.''
''Will you kill the
child for that, uncle?''
''l mean, will you take a life?''
''Forget it, uncle.
Give me a magical hug.''
Everything will be
alright after that.
''Good idea, come.''
Hey Where are you going?
l also want the hug.
Life should be like this.