Sometimes I pause to ponder upon
the peculiar world of daughters,
from homes they're born into,
reared and raised,
their ties they'll uproot, to
transplant themselves elsewhere
To a home she belongs, she will
estrange herself and..
make a stranger's home, her own
The little buds, before our eyes,
will blossom into mothers of mankind
Any daughter's father, be it some
rich man in faraway lands,
or some trader of fruit.. Iike
myself here in Madhupur,
all face similar fate
Raising so lovingly, our daughter,
so beloved..
blessing her every growing
moment and then one day..
..sending her away, forever
All said and done..
daughters will always be daughters,
like my Poonam
I nicknamed her..
Bitto
She's the only child of my late
brother. My brother and his wife died,
this unique gift, they left to me
Poonam grew up with
my daughter Chhoti
The girls loved each other,
more like siblings
But my wife Rama, she never
took kindly to Poonam,
because in appearance, Poonam
is prettier than Chhoti
In Rama, Poonam always
sought a mother..
but the motherless child would
never find a mother's love
I took Poonam under my wing
Mr Accountant, let her finish
counting, put it right back!
All it took..
was only one loving glance
to make her laugh
And my poems,
she would sing along
We recorded our songs on tape
For the little bridegroom,
and his lovely bride..
a pretty palanquin
is waiting outside
A pretty palanquin,
waiting outside
But my little girl's
always little to me..
..never old enough to marry, you see
She isn't old enough
to marry, you see
She's my bride, I'm
taking her! He says
She's my bride,
I'm taking her now,
Dauntless bridegroom
has sworn a vow
Now it's the daughter's turn to say,
Daddy, why are you in a
hurry to send me away?
So what did the daughter
have to say?
Daddy, why are you sending me away?
With so much love.. a daughter
cares for her parents..
..her siblings, everyone
How dismal are some thoughts of men
who think daughters are burdensome
Both my daughters have come of age..
..and it's time to think
of Poonam's wedding
Relax! You're in the
world's narrowest lane,
and in the middle of the world's
slowest wedding procession. See you..
The world's dullest
rocket, dull-est!
Radhey - Radhey (blessed be
the name of Holy Radha)
Mr Accountant, Radhey Radhey
Radhey Radhey.. Oh.. is
that you, Mr Bhagat?
It's been.. years!
Is Mr Krishnakant at home?
- Yes, welcome
Madhupur remains untouched,
it's just the way I left it,
the same narrow lanes and slow
wedding processions and..
pervasive fear, of shooting rockets.
- So true
Sir..
Yes?
Mr Bhagat is here
Mr Bhagat..!
Bhagat, why did you
take the trouble..
..one call and I would've
been in Delhi
When you and your wife can travel to
Delhi to place orders for jewelry,
then why can't I come to Madhupur
to deliver them?
Of course.. thank you
When I lived here, amongst you folks,
the time of our lives we had..
you should remind him more often
Sister-in-law, how's the knee?
Improving
A look at the design of these
bangles will heal it
And I know, you've a
keen eye for jewelry
Over years, bit by bit,
jewelry must be bought..
..for the day when daughters marry
Giving daughters away in marriage,
is said to be the most sacred act
When a father sees his daughter
standing before him..
..resplendent in bridal finery,
there is a sense of fulfillment
Water
Bless you
Krishnakant, isn't she
Poonam, your Bitto?
Well, you've made her out, you
saw her when she was so little
It was intuition..
She's about to graduate in commerce,
she takes care of my accounts
But I've toiled in vain to craft
such exquisite jewelry
She is so beautiful.. who
will look at my jewels!
Chhoti.. Chhoti
Aunty, I'll fetch
her (Aunty.. Aunt)
Sister, what a cool song.. please
join me (Sister.. Sister)
If Aunty comes to know, it's
dancing and not studying,
you know what's to happen?
Nothing, you always save my skin
Get dressed, we've a guest downstairs
God! Guests come for Babuji and Maa
makes me do the make-up drill..
and before I'm down,
the guest is gone
You're far better off Sister,
Maa tells you nothing
Sorry Sister.. Maa tells
you nothing at all
You chatter much too much to give
anyone else even a say.. move
Why weren't you ready?
And no face pack even today?
I disapprove of all this..
and stop showing your teeth
In front of the guest, walk properly
Madhupur's rabri, the
world's best rabri!
Krishnakant, I beg
to be excused now
Sister-in-law, may both your
girls marry..
..the world's best sons-in-law, soon
You have my best wishes. - Thank
you Uncle, for making Maa smile
Rama, time for me
to go to the temple
The sermon is to begin
Uncle (Uncle)
He always forgets
Uncle.. do visit us again
She cares for the smallest
of my needs,
more like a mother
Krishnakant, you wondered how
I recognized Poonam. Fact is..
there's much talk in our
social circles about..
..her beauty and her
beautiful nature
You must have received several
proposals for matrimony?
Yes, but times are changing,
even values are changing,
good proposals are far too few
For Poonam, I seek a home where
her values will be respected
Radha and Krishna's light divine
bathes all there is in Universe
Yet devotion inspires, this
worshiper of Love..
to light this lamp in
heartfelt prayer
O'Krishna and Radha..
Krishna and Radha, O'divine come
unto us, bless this home of mine
Please accept our invitation,
all we seek is Your love
Krishnakant, I have in mind,
a boy for Poonam..
a nice, handsome boy..
from an excellent family
You've heard of Mr Harishchandra..
..of Harishchandra group
of industries, Delhi?
Who does not know him? He's one
of the luminaries in our society
He has scaled peaks of prosperity,
yet he is firmly rooted in simplicity
He's a very open-minded person
For Poonam..
I'm suggesting Prem, Mr
Harishchandra's younger son
I cannot even dream of an alliance
with so high and mighty a family
Are the sons of the high and
mighty to go unmarried?
Which family doesn't need
a good daughter-in-law?
But..
- No excuses
Mr Harishchandra is searching
for a good daughter-in-law
A very good daughter-in-law,
is what I'll suggest to him.
Now, Poonam's photo
Will you give me, or not?
- I'll get it
Look Maa, loads of face
pack. Happy now?
Sister, snap me a photo. I want
to send it to the zoo
Oh come on, Maa
Babuji sends Sister's photo to Delhi,
can't I send mine even to a zoo?
Maa, can I tell Sister about
the Delhi-wallah boy?
I don't like these cheap antics
Who's this guy from Delhi?
Why should I tell?
Babuji.. Babuji (Father)
- Listen!
Stop!
Look..!
Chhoti.. no sparing you!
Babuji look! Sister is nagging me..
it's one question again and again
When will the boy say
yes, for marriage!
What! Chhoti!
Come here
Bitto
With much hope, Mr Bhagat has
taken your photo to Delhi
I was hearing the sermon today and..
I don't know why, but I got a feeling,
this is the family you are
destined to belong to
Hurry up Grandpa, no time!
- Yes, yes sir
Harishchandra
Good day.
- Bhagat, welcome
Marine life, is it?
My grandson's homework project,
what do you think of it?
Very likely, the world's best
project.. but why in the morning..?
Getting his homework done, is my job
We spent yesterday watching the
cricket match, so now we suffer
You paste that submarine.
I'll fill in the color, your
teacher will never know
Grand-uncle.. what
color's the sky?
Blue
Grandpa, what're you doing?
Green.. sorry
Grandpa, grow up
My respects, Uncle
God bless.. do you
see the boss of 10,000 men..
..being bossed over by a boy..
and how he obeys!
Grandfather, after all
Rahul, it is time for the bus.
- Here uncle.
Good morning Dad, good
morning everybody
My respects, Uncle.
- Sunil, I wish you happiness
Sorry, I'm late. Got talking
to the lawyers
No problem, join us
Papa, reading newspapers at
the table isn't allowed
Papa, only business news, please.
- For business, you've got all day
Breakfast time is..
- Family time
Thank you
Here you are, son
Bhavna, where's Prem?
He left early, for a squash
game. You forgot, Papa?
Sorry
Uncle, if Papa had it his way..
..he'd have the whole
family around him all day
One minute!
Are you taking off with Rahul to
your mother's for a vacation?
Papa, I'll be back soon
Let ten gents leave home..
you won't know!
But when women and kids are gone,
the whole house sounds empty
Bhavna, I'm sorry, no going
to your mother's this time
Papa.
For this permanent problem of
the world, I got a solution
You get to go to your mother's
and the house won't sound empty
How..?
Bring home a junior daughter-in-law
I have..
found a bride for Prem
Ya Prem, that's the shot
Be right back
Bali, looks like you'll lose again
Now's your chance to escape.
Run along. - Shut up
Today I'll win
Sorry guys. Papa wants me in office
and it's urgent, so I'll have to go
At least finish the game
You win
Good morning, sir
I'll tell the marketing department
to get in touch with you later..
Hey Aunt Maria, grab a bite?
- No! I'm so very happy,
I'm going to fast all
day! Go.. go.. go..
Your daddy is waiting for you
Come in, son
That's okay.
The rest is not so important.
You talk to him. Talk to him.
Papa, why is everyone beaming at me
? I didn't even win my game today
It's all because there's a
wedding proposal for you
You mean, marriage?
Your education is completed,
now it's time..
..for us to think about
your marriage
Mr Bhagat came home today
He suggests there's a girl
for you, her name is Poonam
Poonam's parents are deceased, she
was raised very lovingly by her uncle
They live in Madhupur. Mr Bhagat says
they are very decent, honest folks
If I've your yes, then next Sunday..
..we may go to Madhupur
to meet the girl
If there is someone else you like,
you may speak openly, son
No Papa, there's nothing of the sort
Only thing is.. marrying, so early?
Now is the right age, son. Even
your brother married at your age
Our scriptures say so, also
from my experience..
it's easier to accept someone, easier
to adapt to someone at an early age
It makes for a relationship that
grows more firm, takes deeper root
Papa.. I haven't even
started upon my career
I'm just a trainee in the factory
Prem, every man who aspires to
achieve needs an inspiration
She will come into your life
like an inspiration..
to share every moment of your life, to
bear half the burden of your sorrows
And to double your joys
You might think, why a girl from
a small town.. Madhupur?
Your mother was also from
a small town near Bhopal
Now who could have been
a better mother to you?
We lived life to the fullest, traveled
the world, watched you boys grow up
To this day, she is besides me
Nowadays when I see youngsters losing
faith in the institution of marriage,
I feel so sorry
Your mother always maintained..
the most vital components of a
marriage are trust and honesty
Children nowadays miss
the significance
Prem, I've always tried to be in
step with you, your generation,
to speak the language you speak, your
kind of fashion, music, movies
Now I want, you too should imbibe
certain values from earlier generations
Meet the girl, speak with her, find
out if you can understand each other
Then, take the decision
And now,
Poonam's photo
Take a look
I'll wait outside
Guess what Prem, Bhagat
Uncle told me..
when Papa spoke about marriage
to him, he had blushed crimson
Well?
The wife's presence is always taken
for granted, but for once at least,
put that paper away and give
your brother some advice
The first time he came to see
me, he came all prepared..
after memorizing a whole questionnaire
Brother..
what was the first question you
asked? - The first question?
May I have a glass of water, please
? That was the first-and-last
Uncle, she's the one
you're marrying?
Will she give you good-night kisses,
like Mummy gives Papa?
Naughty!
- He's always talking his head off
You got to be careful what you
say in front of this guy
Rahul, bedtime.
- Good night
You're becoming mischievous
Papa.. paper..
It's yesterday's paper. Put it down!
No, I was only..
Come
More about Poonam? I'm
told she likes to read
In their house, girls never
wear jeans, dresses, etc
They never go to restaurants. Oh yes,
you may have to speak in chaste Hindi
I like Poonam
When I meet her, what will I talk?
Not to worry, the poor girl
must be in the same quandary
Unacquainted, as strangers,
we try to find rapport,
but there's a question in the heart
Oh, what are we going to talk
New hopes, new joy,
a strange fragrance fills the air..
with the coming of someone for whom
I have waited with all my heart
Oh, what are we going to talk!
Oh, what are we going to talk
Krishnakant basically
belongs to Som Sarovar
Som Sarovar, where grapes grow?
- Exactly
Sister-in-law hails from Bhopal.
- My in-laws are also from near Bhopal
Please.. have some.
- You should sit here
And talk to Prem
Please sit.
What's this restlessness..
I feel today?
The way I feel today..
never was I in this
state of mind before
Eyes looking out.. for her alone
This beauty is for him alone
The one I pictured,
I'm about to see
The storm is turning into a tempest.
Oh, what are we going to talk
Like an icon of beauty
descended from skies,
has she come only for me,
in such splendor?
I know he's hiding his looks..
stealing furtive glances only at me
Unspoken words upon my frozen lips
Did my heart miss a beat?
Tomorrow's lovers, what are
they going to talk today?
Oh, what are we going to talk
Meet Poonam, say hello
Say hello to Aunt.. say hello!
Hello
Hello..
Krishnakant, we have met Poonam.
Now with your permission..
Iet Prem and Poonam talk to each other
to get to know each other's minds
Bhavna, please
Have we come to sit on the swing?
- No!
We've come to talk.
- We couldn't talk downstairs?
Your Uncle and aunt want to talk
here. - Then what are we doing here?
Rahul! No more questions
Hi, I'm Prem. - My name's Rajni,
you can call me Chhoti
If the two of you get going,
then I'm your sister-in-law
Please..
Sit, Poonam.
- Please sit
Sister-in-law, sit.
- You sit
Why is no one sitting?
Chhoti, we're being formal
and crowding..
..over the ones who want privacy
So put down the tea tray and let's go
Okay Prem, Poonam. All the best.
- They got exams?
I'm not too sure that I know what
we should be talking right now
We're meant to take a decision about
the next step in our lives
But before we have discussed our past,
how can we think about our future?
Schooling and college in Delhi ; then
for about a year, I went abroad
Studied journalism, literature..
basically, trying to discover myself
My brother says, I'm too emotional
.. in business matters
He calls me Bholu, a Simple Simon
In college, I took a
liking for a girl..
my classmate.. used to sit
on the desk in front of me
Several times, I felt like making
conversation, but I never had the guts
And it was just as well,
later I found out..
she had two boyfriends already
I even tried smoking, with friends
But when Sister-in-law
caught me smoking..
..I promised her never
to smoke or drink
I have never spoken of these
things even with my Papa.
But, I don't know why,
I felt I had to tell you
I'm told you like reading.. which
books are your favorites?
Saratchandra's Parineeta, Swami
Rabindranath's Atithi, Samapti
All in Hindi, right?
Their English translations
are excellent too
Do you also read spiritual
books? I mean..
The divine..?
Yes.. you read them?
Do you believe in prayer? I mean,
you trust, He'll give what you seek?
Do you believe in it?
Some things one has total faith in
You can ask me whatever you wish
The tea has gone cold. Another
cup..? - No, thanks
You have no question at all?
About that girl, maybe?
I've all the answers
If you wish, we can meet again,
once or twice..?
Well then, shall we..?
So?
Oh.. so..
Is that a yes?
I think.. - It's on your face,
Bholu, it's a yes
Sister-in-law..
Listen.. one second! Listen..
I think we should meet again,
once or twice, for her sake
How chivalrous!
Papa.. yes
Really?
Where's Prem?
Congratulations!
- Thanks
Harishchandra, my compliments
Please be seated
Krishnakant, from
our side, it's a yes
Please ask Poonam as well
and if she says yes,
then at the earliest, I want
her as my daughter-in-law
Bitto, Chhoti.. from
their side it's a yes
Bitto, what's your decision?
- Babuji, it's a yes
You asked whatever you
wanted to find out?
You want to meet him again,
once or twice?
Sister was saying, he's
just like you, Babuji
Silly girl
Harishchandra.. please..
- Thank you
You will sit too
Where is your sherbet?
- I'll help myself
Sir, Sister-in-law wants to see you
Excuse me..
Yes?
They have come prepared, they want
the engagement done today!
Before committing an alliance with
so rich a family, talk about dowry
I won't let you squander all we have,
our daughter is yet to marry
Really Rama, sometimes
you exceed the limits
Krishnakant, may I come in?
Harishchandra..?
Come in, do come..
I beg your pardon for the intrusion,
but now that two families
are uniting..
..I'd prefer we kept nothing
from each other
Please, have no doubts
Give Prem a token of one rupee and a
coconut..
..and accept him into your family
We want Poonam and nothing else
The world's best couple
Aunt, smile.
- Not Aunt. Call her Aunty
How did this Aunt become my Aunty?
Your Uncle likes her
so much, what to do?
Kindly let it come.. that's it
Papa, the cars are waiting..
- Sure.. Iet's go
For you
Chocolates?
- Yes
Aunty, coming to Delhi?
Aunty will come later
My respects, Uncle.
- Bless you
Bless you, Bhavna
Just call me Bhavna
Ah, the littlest one in the family!
You and I haven't even gotten talking
Harishchandra, a little request
If all of you may spare a few days
to visit us in Som Sarovar,
we have a little house there ; a few
days together, would be very nice
Whenever you wish, Krishnakant. We're
looking for excuses to meet Poonam,
what with the astrologer fixing
a marriage date after six months
Sister-in-law, give the
astrologer a nice meal..
..ask him to fix a nearer date
Then.. Som Sarovar next month?
- Hundred percent
Good night.
- Good night
You aren't one of the brides people,
you're coming with us
Oh, I forgot!
- You'll accompany the bridegroom
Correct!
- Bhagat will be here with us,
to welcome the bridegroom.
- That's also correct
How can both be correct?
The way it is, I've an invitation
from either side..
..so there's no stopping me
Bridegroom arrives,
I'm here to welcome him.
Bride leaves, I'll escort her
Correct proposition? - Likely..
but, are you ditching us?
Sister, one minute!
What is it?
- Just come
Chhoti.. the guests are leaving
Hush
Jija, now you owe me one
( Jija : Brother-in-law)
Krishnakant Villa Som Sarovar
Yes Harishchandra, we
have reached Som Sarovar
When can we expect you?
Oh.. take left
from the bus depot.
Metaled roads,
it's a comfortable drive
Okay.
We're waiting for you
You're welcome
Bless you
How would the weather be in Som
Sarovar? (He speaks in chaste Hindi)
Bravo!
Already talking Poonam-style?
Oh Sister!
Sister come quickly, they're here
Oh Sister,
how will you address him,
the one who'll come to marry you?
Oh Sister,
how will you address him,
the one who'll come to marry you?
Coy words are out of question..
I will use sign language..
Unlike others,
our communication will be special
80 kilometers to journey's end?
(He speaks in chaste Hindi)
Marriage is like the
'laddoo' from Delhi
All want to taste it
Every facet of it is lovely
If you marry, you suffer
If you don't, you suffer
Might as well marry and suffer
This 'laddoo' you will get too,
the day someone will come for you
Everyone's invited to Som Sarovar
! Holidaying together..
and I get to do the chores
Why are you getting agitated
? I'll make the sweets
You relax
Is it a song or an act?
To take your mind off things?
Your eyes are upon the street
Oh Chhoti, you're too naughty,
stop being such a tease
I'm only busy watering
Let Jija arrive, I'll tell him
all about your state of mind
Bitto, come
Water
Krishnakant, remain seated
Put the tray down
We'll help ourselves. We haven't
come here as guests
Son, drink
Water
When you have a cold,
you ought not to drink iced water
Come..
- How nice
Dinner
Come son
Our little family member, you too!
Wow Grandpa, little-little
dining tables?
For you, a special little one
Come. Come.
Sit
Please serve him his special dish
I'll serve them
Papa, Aunty is a fantastic cook
The garnishing proportions are on
her fingertips, I was stunned
Sister-in-law, he is a lucky man
Sunil Babu, no more helpings?
I'm doing fine
He's missing his evening newspaper!
Poonam has cooked the curry today.
- Really?
Please, may I have some more?
Uncle, for your sake, Sister
used very little chili
She cooks a spicy spread.
- Good good
No, thanks
Poonam, I've told Krishnakant, you
may continue your studies in Delhi
Afterwards, if you wish, you
can attend our offices
Until Rahul was born, Bhavna
went to the office everyday
I think girls prove
better administrators
What!
Krishnakant, I heard.. you aren't
staying with us tonight?
We'll use the quarters, nearby. You
won't find it inconvenient here
Papa, it's just so that we can have
all the three big rooms to ourselves
No, not really
Beddings in place, make it quick
Grandpa, I'll sleep here.
- Right on
Prem, get more mattresses.
- Yes, Papa
You see, I can manage..
- Rahul, make him to sit down
No, please hear me out.
- Be seated
Everyone listen
Gents sleep in this room,
the ladies in there
Prem put mine right next to his,
I'll lecture him all night
Sit
Oh no, lights out?
- Up again? Sit down, Krishnakant
Can l.. carry some?
Every morning, my uncle drinks
water from the copper tumbler..
..it's good for health
That must be your aunt's book?
- Yes
Thank you
What for?
Aren't your uncle and
aunt.. mine too?
For you.. a gift
Can we meet tomorrow?
If you say so..
Sister-in-law can arrange it
Nothing like a morning walk, much
to gain out of little effort
Like big profits out of small
capital, your knee pain will vanish
Boys, faster please
What's the matter?
- You carry on
He'll be here in a minute.. see!
What about our meeting?
What's the hurry?
Until then, take some exercise
It's the vegetable market area,
so shops open early
A smell of freshly-cooked jalebis!
- Milk and jalebis for breakfast?
Steaming hot jalebis.
- Sit here
Two minutes.. Jalebis in milk.
- Are you serving us again!
Sit!
- Great taste, try it
Sister-in-law, get him to talk to Papa
(Sister-in-law : sister-in-law)
Go
Bhavna?
- Go!
Have some more, Rama.
- Don't plead with her, feed her
Dad?
- Yes?
What's our day's plan?
- We're seeing the vineyards
Children, if you haven't seen the
vineyards here, you've seen nothing
So, like I was saying..
- Dad..
Yes?
- Rahul wanted to see the lake
What lake?
Can we go?
Rahul wants to go? Then go
Aunty, can we take Poonam
and Chhoti along?
Sure
Wonderful! He worked a miracle!
Too good.
Sister-in-law, can you believe it,
my brother did it!
Snatch the newspaper out of his hands
and in Uncle Bhagat's words..
he's the world's best husband
No.. the other one
This one
It's lovely watching them
together, like this
He's so busy at work, he
hardly has time for her
Out here, they're having a lovely
holiday.. thanks to you
Did you like the gift?
- Very much
Sister-in-law and I scoured
the malls for a whole day..
..till we found the necklace
You haven't worn it?
May I wear it after the wedding?
In Madhupur, we live simply
Wearing such an expensive gift there,
I'd feel a little uncomfortable
No, it's okay. I understand
Poonam, you just spoke your heart
and you said it so frankly,
it felt wonderful
Maybe it's this honesty, that's to be
the cornerstone of our relationship
With the same honesty, if I were
to give you another gift,
and if you think it's right..
..will you wear it?
Turning defeat into victory..
With great honesty..
Love has cast it's effect..
On the heart..
Today there is no question of..
Any denial..
if not diamonds,
a simplicity of flowers
has adorned her beauty
So little said, so much remains ;
a little shower, I wait for rains,
to dance like a peacock in rain,
my heart yearns..
a little wait.. that's it..
a little wait.. that's it
So little said, so much remains ;
a little shower, I wait for rains,
Prem, spot
Prem, hit her! Or, they'll win
Hit
Get her.. why don't
you take her out?
a little wait.. that's it
This is sheer bliss. It'd
do good for Poonam..
..and Prem to visit all the temples
Radha-Krishna must've met
in these valleys, somewhere
The fragrance of their romance
still lurks in the air
In divine presence,
we find ourselves..
drawn nearer..
In divine presence,
we find ourselves..
drawn nearer..
A heart's exchange done, I've
still to shower so many gifts
A little shower, I wait for rains
Everyone seems to be helping our union
A little wait.. that's it
Bhavna..
Bhavna, what are you up to?
- What's up?
Look what's there!
- What?
Don't worry, I came for the towel
Enchanting waterfalls' lovelores..
entice me into sweet
dreams of tomorrows..
awakening for the first time,
new stirrings within me
I feel new emotions stirring within
A lifetime of our days
and nights remain,
a little shower, I wait for rains
I can feel the tug of monsoon winds
I can feel the tug of monsoon
winds upon my heartstrings
A little wait.. that's it
Yes, Zurich called? What
did they have to say?
Really? Meeting confirmed?
No, no.. that's good news
Get the legal department
to draw up the contracts.
We'll be in Delhi tomorrow
But the Swiss clients
are due next week?
Now they're expected
day after tomorrow
And our entire board must be present
during the signing of the contract
So, we leave tomorrow
Time has passed by so quickly..
Should I say something Poonam,
this spell between engagement
and marriage is amazing
These moments between you and..
..Prem will be the most
memorable of your lives,
mark my words
Hey Rahul, come here
Aunty..
Uncle wants water
You wanted to say something?
Poonam, tonight.. after dinner..
for a while.. will you
come to the terrace?
If you think, it's right.. only then
Wow! Well done Sister-in-law.
- You are winning all the games.
Can I sleep on the terrace
with Uncle?
We leave early tomorrow, don't forget
Chhoti, where's the saffroned milk?
- Sister is bringing it
Wish I could read..
the language of her eyes
My heart falters..
in doubts of hope and despair
Worse, this menacing..
solitude, my love
Patience..
comes, she comes
She could not stop herself..
from coming
Your coming..
is like the waking of Moons, my love
We laced the milk with saffron for
dessert.. I thought you might like it
It gets chilly here, in the nights
For once I thought, you wouldn't come
Everyone was sitting together,
talking, I just couldn't leave
No one knows that you've come here?
Chhoti knows, she told everyone
that I've gone off to sleep
If someone finds out you
aren't there.. then?
Chhoti has propped up pillows
and thrown a blanket over them
All this.. just because
I asked you to come?
I wanted to come
Why did I take so long to
realize this, Poonam?
I even missed seeing.. you've worn
that necklace for me tonight
Do you know Poonam,
since I came to Som Sarovar, I've been
wanting to call you to the terrace
But every time, I held back
I wish I'd known that I had
the right to call you anytime
But what a time to come to know,
when it's time..
to go
Poonam, people spend lifetimes
looking for love
Today, I look in wonderment
at this custom of marriage..
in which, that love has
come to me, as a gift
Suddenly I become so
special to someone,
what I eat, what I wear, suddenly
is more important..
to somebody else than me, myself.
Suddenly you and l..
I have the right..
to this liberty of beholding your
beauty to my heart's content,
of gazing upon you, in endless love
My love..
my heart calls out in answer..
You have the right
Darkening, melting, the night
is slowly deepening..
giving in to love's music ;
a romance, slowly blossoming
In the music of my bangles,
what is the lyric, my love?
What message does the language
of my bangles speak?
To keep you awake all night,
I have the right
to steal upon your beauty,
My love..
my heart calls out in answer
You have the right
Poonam, how do you come to know
these smallest things about me?
How did you find out about my cold?
Whenever you get a cold,
you do this..
How?
Do it again
Tomorrow time will distance us,
but not for a moment, shall
I be able to forget you
Your face, your smile,
in memories of your beautiful face,
your endearing smile..
to suffer in your absence,
I have the right
To yearn to meet you, I have the right
My love..
my heart calls out in answer..
you have the right
You have the right
I have the right
Rahul, quickly get inside the car
Got to leave..
Five months on, there'll be no need
to make excuses about water
4 months, 2 weeks and 2 days,
our wedding's that far away
Until then, I cannot ask you to
keep this mobile phone to talk up,
because you'll consider it improper
All-day-chat on the net is out,
so like nice boys do, I'll write
you a bunch of letters
And yes, I'll dial you up on
your ancestral black phone
Listen,
stay away from anything icy. You
just got over a nasty cold
Not even cold water
Anything else?
Prem, hurry. We'll get late
My love..
my heart calls out to you..
I have the right
Good morning, Aunt Maria
Congratulations Prem, you've
been given a promotion,
from factory to office.
- Thank you and look what I've got..
only for you.. from Som Sarovar,
delicious and wholesome grapes
A simple gift, I hope you will accept
accept and.. (ln chaste Hindi)
Not to get stuck, Hindi
is a very kind language,
you're free to use words
from any other language
Accept and please oblige.
- Thank you
That's the way Prem, first in
the office, sharp at 9 am
Engaged to marry, now work, only work
Concentrate, focus
Munim, let's start making preparations
for the wedding right away
Go to Mr Joshi, talk to
the tent-makers. - Sure
We'll put up the bridegroom's party in
Bansilal's hotel, not at Temple-lnn
Birju, this task is yours.
- Done
Look, we should leave nothing undone
And Bitto, compile the list of
invitees on the computer, quickly
The job of painting the house
should be done in time
Not in a marriage-hall.. we're
having the wedding at home
They're coming from Delhi.
- We'll do a good job
Take a look around
Back from college?
I was waiting for you
Of these silver coins,
which looks nice?..
.. I want to give every
guest a memento
I know Sister's choice. This one
Great! It's my choice too
You too make a choice, Rama
Why do you even have to ask
me, give everything away
Maa, why do you always talk like that
? Babuji only wants your opinion
Don't you dare talk back at me
Bitto.. get along with
what you got to do
The kind of wedding you're dreaming
of, do you know what it'll cost?
Yes, I know
Relatives we haven't seen
in years, are being invited
Confectioners, musicians, florists,
being called in from all over,
Iike you've nothing to look
at beyond this wedding
My brother and his wife's
every dream will come true
You remember only their dreams
Do you remember, even your daughter
is waiting to get married?
I've spoken about Chhoti
to so many people
But because she is dark,
I find no suitors
Worse now, if we can't provide for
her dowry, then she's had it
But why would you worry for that?
To pay for Poonam's wedding you
pawned off our Som Sarovar house
Now, sell even this
house if you will!
Who is it?
Bitto?
What happened, my child?
I don't want to marry
Bitto.. what are you saying?
Come and sit here
Sit.. what's the matter?
Uncle..
..you built brick by brick..
the house in Som Sarovar
And you have mortgaged
it for this wedding?
Chhoti is yet to marry! I'll
never be able to forgive myself
Chhoti will have just as fine a
wedding.. I give you my word
For every father, a daughter's
wedding is..
.. a celebration of a
great wish come true
Will you not let my wish come true?
Listen.. a letter from
Harishchandra has arrived
You want to hear it?
One second
He writes,
With great pleasure, I remember
staying with you at Som Sarovar
In Madhupur, we became related. In
Som Sarovar, we struck a friendship
In terms of relationships,
such a quick promotion
All credit goes to your
endearing nature
Having known you, I can
tell with conviction,
that you have already embarked upon
the preparations for the wedding
A thousand responsibilities entail
in a daughter's wedding
Have no worries of any sort,
we are one family
Bitto, when you have such a fine
father-in-law, what's my worry?
Now, one little smile
I have good news for you
In today's mail, perhaps..
there's a letter for you
Bitto, someone far away.. is
waiting for you, weaving dreams
Go on.. fill in the colors
It's four in the morning
and I've no sleep
I reach the office
before anyone else
But it's another matter that
I am not able to do any work
But today, I put in
lots of hard work,..
.. matching color schemes
for each costume..
we'll wear for our wedding ceremonies
the soiree, reception, dinners
I had coffees after
coffee to stay fresh
But the only things that remain
fresh, are memories of you
Poonam, I can't tell the
source of this enthusiasm,
but I'm propelled to
achieve in life,..
.. to prove myself worthy,
for your sake
Coming, coming
Bitto, your phone
Who is it?
Perhaps.. a friend
Birjoo. Hey, Birjoo
Guess what happened, just guess
Half an hour ago, we were in a
meeting, me, my brother, the managers
A Japanese multinational corporation
has offered us a deal,
a new line of business. It'll be a
great thing for our organization
They want us in Tokyo next week,
with the project reports
My brother is busy with the
clients from Switzerland
And Papa is out of station,
so who is to be sent
I'm going
I'll go
I'm off to Japan next week
and there's lots of work,
no time to talk. Bye
Birjoo.. Birjoo
What happened?
At today's meeting..
Project report will be ready in 3 days.
Let's book flight tickets for Monday
I'm thinking, Ms Poonam..
I mean.. Ms Pooja, it would be
nice if you and Mr Manohar..
can join me on this trip
Brother, is it necessary to send
the papers to our auditors..
in Madhupur.. I mean, Mumbai
No.. it won't be necessary
Yes, of course
Excuse me
You're laughing! I'll
never talk to you again
Sister, you've upset him
Stop the rickshaw.
- Go and call him now
You drank chilled water again?
Yes
Why?
I'm coming to see you
What?
Yes, right away
Stop
It's a big project, is that
why you're afraid?
Poonam, if I do not succeed..
will it affect your love for me?
How can you not succeed?
In legal matters, business,
I never had an aptitude
Everyone seems to be more experienced
than I am.. more capable
You'll surely succeed
And you know, when you
return a victor,
everyone will be waiting with garlands
at the airport, to welcome you
How can you speak with
such confidence?
I know you
It seems, you know me better
than I know myself
I'll pray for you
Say it again
I'm leaving in 3 days
For a month, no phone
calls, no letters
Be prepared
I accept. Anything else?
You are here? Everyone's waiting
for you, for the meeting
Go.. I love you dearly
Awake.. at this hour?
I have the right
Waiting for someone
gives such pleasure?
That only a woman's heart would know
Ready to leave?
Yes
Once I'm there, I think
I'll grow a beard for..
.. folks to take me more seriously
That won't be necessary
Can I shout?
Most welcome
I love you
Rama, Agra was the right place to go.
We got the musicians,
also confectioners
The same confectioner,
whom you favor too
Everyone will land up two or
three days before the wedding
Imagine in less than two months,
Bitto will be a bride
Aunty, you asked for me?
Yes.. sit
Look, very soon you'll be married
.. you'll enter another family
That will be your home
As we know, your Uncle
is very attached to you
Obviously, when you leave,
he will miss you dearly
So it's time you began to
distance yourself from him
When your Uncle goes out, Chhoti
can also give him his shawl, no?
Yes Aunty
Why ask me to give the
shawl to Babuji?
Because I wish you would
No, because Maa wishes it
Sister, your getting married doesn't
mean you must break all bonds
It's your home no more, that's
what Maa is implying?
You'll be the one taking care of
all these things, after I'm gone
Yes, but after you're gone, Sister.
Why from now itself?
Because, while I'm still here, my
Chhoti must pick up everything from me
Take.. it's time for Uncle
to visit the temple
Babuji..
Chhoti.. how come you've
brought my shawl?
Sister is ironing clothes.
- Okay..
Bitto usually wraps it
around like this..
Poonam, books from your
schooldays are..
.. still in the room
you share with Chhoti
Select the stuff you
want to take along..
..the rest we'll have to dispose off
Chhoti needs more space
in the room to herself
Girls' College, Madhupur
Here you are Poonam,
transfer papers for
your Delhi college
Thank you Ma'am
Sister, quick!
It's a call from Delhi
Sunil Babu, my heartiest compliments!
One second, one second..
Prem Babu's Japan tour
is a great success
Yes Sunil Babu, tell us more
Uncle, you can't imagine!
Prem has outdone his peers
He has closed the deal early.
He will be back by the morning flight
He's returning tomorrow morning?
Uncle I have a request
We'd like to have Poonam with us, when
we receive Prem at the
airport tomorrow
Prem would be happily surprised
Certainly, Sunil Babu.
Poonam will be there
to share your joys
Fine
I'll send the car tomorrow morning
Come on Bitto,
your palanquin's here from Delhi
Good morning
Our wedding day..
is four weeks away,
each week seems like hundred years
How can I endure this torture,
I can't wait for even a day longer
Right now..
give me today itself,
your lovely caress, my dear
Poonam..
my love
Oh Poonam.. oh my love
You want something, sir?
When I look down, I find oceans of you
Then I look up to see,
skies full of you
I'm so eager
For a re-union, I'm eager
but the plane's too slow, by far
If I could, I would
Iand this plane on her roof..
and enjoy the pampering of her folks
for a full month
I'll return with her,
return with her,
the one whose sole-rightful lover I am
Oh Poonam..
my love
Oh Poonam.. oh my love
You want to go in?
Excuse me
Excuse me.. tea, coffee?
To every fellow traveler,
all I got to say..
wherever you go, with you always,
Iet your sweetheart stay
Alas! Moments of loneliness
Even a moment's separation..
I can bear no longer
I wish Destiny..
makes one little favor..
sends her to..
to.. Delhi airport for me
And when I see her,
oh what wondrous surprise it'd be
to find her there in front of me..
it'd make me scream so heartily..
Ho Poonam, ho!
You are my love, ho!
Oh Poonam.. oh my love
Our wedding day..
our wedding is,
just four weeks away
Where months have passed,
these days will fly too
Then I won't make you pine,
I won't make you suffer
Just a little wait..
all your wishes..
will come true..
in my embrace,
my darling,
my love
my darling,..my love
Fasten your seat-belt, sir
My wedding day..
is still four long weeks away
There's Uncle
Come.. come
The whole office is out in force,
to congratulate you
Uncle..
- Bless you, son
Congratulations, many congratulations
Brother.. has Uncle come alone?
Yes.. was someone else expected?
- No..
Let's all proceed towards home
Get in
Sister-in-law is that really Poonam..?
- Touch her to find out
I can't believe this!
When did Poonam come in,
when did you plan all this?
It was his idea, to ask Poonam over.
- What an idea, brother!
Where are thy lotus feet?
At thy lotus feet I shall bow and..
Exult? (ln chaste Hindi)
- Exactly!
Desist, first return to your place
And with your fiance, engage in
polite conversation (..
in chaste Hindi)
Indeed
Indeed.. Oh, I just
love this language.
- Joker
Papa is throwing a party at home,
to felicitate you..
and also because Poonam
is here for the first time
Welcome.. how are you?
Prem's father-in-law
Friends, I'm on cloud nine
My son has achieved this
on his own merit
The glow you see on
his face is nothing
but the reflection of my heartfelt joy
For his success, my joys,
the credit goes to someone..
who is visiting us for the first time
.. my new daughter-in-law
In eating, our Krishnakant
is the world's most bashful
More pakodas for him.
- Enough
Krishnakant, we know,
it's your favorite. Poonam,
serve there
You cannot refuse now..
my daughter-in-law is serving you
Papa, how about giving Poonam
a tour of the house
before she leaves?
Sure, take her
Come, Poonam
Poonam, after our wedding,
this will be our room
In Som Sarovar, I snapped the
portraits of your uncle and aunt..
especially for this side-table. You
know Poonam, sometimes I think..
What happened?
Nothing
So, what were you thinking?
Must we speak always and only about
what I think, what I feel?
What you think, you feel,
is also vital
We're companions, Poonam
Today, while serving Uncle,
I got so emotional,
I had to hold back my tears
Poonam, I brought you here..
to show you my new cupboard, my
writing table, my new computer..
without a thought, that your cupboard,
writing table, even your surname..
you'll be leaving behind..
for my sake
For our sakes
Poonam, I've just decided! Every year
we'll spend one month in Madhupur
If anyone ridicules me for living
with my in-laws, I don't care
I hear..
in the countdown to the wedding date,
girls go crazy about shedding weight?
No crash diets for you. 10-15 kilos
here or there, is no issue
Can you imagine what will happen when
you arrive riding a mare to wed me?
What?
The bread is likely to get burnt in
the ovens of our neighbors' homes
Why?
Every girl will be on her terrace,
vying to take a peek at the bridegroom
Poonam, time to go
Yes, Sister-in-law
Sister-in-law, just
two minutes.. please
All right, make it quick
How much will they talk?
- Shh.. come on
Poonam, my heart knows, l
don't want to let you go
I want to show you around Delhi,
to take you places with me
But we'll wait, as even
you consider it proper
And in a way, what's
proper is so right
The night, when you enter this room
as my bride, will be so right..
that the Moon, the stars out there
will come down, to witness our union
And they will carry our legend to
every couple who marry after us
On our perfect night, let
only the Moonlight shine..
upon the world's prettiest girl,
who by then, would be mine..
for ever
Is it true Poonam that you will
always be so close to my heart?
Am I really going to be the lucky one,
you'll gift your days and nights to?
A few things for you, a few
things for the household
Give it to Aunty, she'll
understand. - Sure, Sister-in-law
Bless you
Return soon
This household, all of us here..
are waiting for you
Uncle Bhagat..
isn't there a custom to escort
the lady? - Should be..
shall I ask your father-in-law? Let
me.. - No, what are you doing!
Uncle.. for Aunty,
a video disc of today's party
My respects Uncle.
- Bless you, son
Prem, isn't Uncle getting
late? (ln chaste Hindi)
Turn the air-conditioning vent
sideways, not a direct blast
Someone was once my little darling..
she was like a soft jasmine bud
Mama, look.. Sister is
looking so radiant
Whose borders were from
home to the street..
Is she the same girl..
Rama, I was listing the items
we'll give to Poonam,
the things she will need, clothes,
jewelry. And listen..
half the jewelry I retrieved
after I paid my..
.. brother's debts, goes with Poonam
Give it to me, I got
to get it polished
There's no need to give
away old jewelry
Here's the jewelry that Mr Bhagat
made for this wedding. This is enough
What do you mean?
Maybe you didn't notice that
diamond set worth millions?
Your darling niece was made to wear it
by her in-laws for the party in Delhi
If she doesn't wear your
jewelry worth some..
.. thousands, her beauty
won't be marred
Leave the old jewelry for Chhoti
Rama, do not forget.. that jewelry
belonged to my brother
Not mere ornaments, they're symbolic
of his blessings for her
What he pawned, was his. What
we retrieved, belongs to us
Is Poonam not one of us?
I've said what I had to say
You're going overboard
with this wedding
About the jewelry, if
you force your whim,..
.. I'll have nothing to
do with this wedding
Rama, in this family we've
two daughters..
.. and they have equal
right to all we have
And Poonam is my elder daughter,
whether you like it or not
Then so be it
Here's the jewelry
Here are the keys. Do what you want
Rama!
Sorry Aunty.. some gifts from
Delhi, if you'll take a look..
I know! Your in-laws are filthy rich
and you needn't show it off in my face
Show it to the one who ought to know!
I've nothing to do with this wedding
The florist is arriving from Delhi
by the ten o'clock train
Get to the station to bring him here
Welcome Bhagat
I'm here now, what can I do to help?
- Your presence is enough
I've brought you Poonam's wedding
dress from her in-laws
Here you are..
Two days from now,
as the clock strikes this hour,
you'll be giving your daughter away
Aunty, the keys to my cupboard
There are so many things inside..
Chhoti, could use them
Aunty, if I have ever done
anything to hurt you..
please forgive me
Poonam..
before you leave..
shut the door
Take it easy, one at a time
Tell them Sister-in-law, please.
- Sure. Please, don't harass him
Wait.. what's the purpose
of this make up?
To make you look worthy enough
for your pretty wife-to-be
Really? Then let's have some more
here.. and here.. and here
Naughty
May the henna turn a lovely crimson
on your hands, o'bride
And fetch to you, your lover forever
Of many fortunes the henna begets,
the most precious is.. eternal love
Is this all right..?
It's the fourth time you've tried it.
Hurry, I got to finish packing
Else, the bridegroom's party will
leave without the bridegroom
Come Sister-in-law, I'll paint
your hands with henna
Sister-in-law.. come, join us
This ritual is too painfully
long for me
We sing glories of the
Daughter of the hills,
whose beauty holds Shiva enthralled
Today we seek Gauri Maa's blessings,
who revels in Shiva's love forever
Oh Goddess, You are resplendent
in vermilion,
You wear the bride's reds, Your
palms adorned in crimson henna
red is Your veil ; redden vermilion
streaks Your hair,
the red dot on Your forehead,
fragrant with musk
We pray to You, pour
our emotions to You
Krishnakant, the rituals have begun,
but I don't see Sister-in-law..?
I'll fetch her
O Giver of every wish,
Keep the bride happy always
Hail Gauri Mother.
Hail Gauri Mother..
What is it? Is it the pain
in the knee again?
Massage it with the balm
Rama, you did not even look at Poonam's
wedding dress ; I said nothing
You didn't participate in any of the
wedding rituals ; I said nothing
But Rama tomorrow..
tomorrow, Bitto will be leaving
this house forever
Tomorrow, the bridegroom's party will
come to our door, just like this,
with a band playing songs of joy
Give the bride a happy send-off, Rama
Rama you know this, as I know
If she is denied your blessings, it
won't be a happy send-off for her
For once, forget all else Rama,
for the sake of Poonam's happiness,
Iet her depart with the belief that
her mother has blessed her way
All her life, she has yearned
for that one smile of yours
It's for the child's joy ;
even if we do something..
.. we dislike, we won't lose face
But why such resentment, because
she isn't your daughter?
Better, you do not hear the reply
Remember Rama..?
Whenever your knee was in pain, it
was Poonam giving you a massage
Enough
Today, you refuse to acknowledge her.
But mind you, when she leaves us..
you will cry the most
I am your Mother,
you are my daughter
Our bond..
forever,
holds us together
In this home, you shall
never be a stranger..
though you go to make another
home for yourself
In both homes, truly..
you'll belong forever
Make sure you're done with making
the sweets tonight..
we're cooking for 400 guests,
there should be no shortages..
the guests are coming from Delhi
Chhote Babu..
Chhote Babu.. fire!
The house is on fire
Chhote Babu..
Fire!
It's a fire!
- Everyone.. out!
Out.. everyone outside
Hurry!
But how did all this..
- All questions later..
Get out, first
Water! Douse the fire!
Quick.. more water! Hurry!
Bhagat! Where are Chhoti and
Bitto? - Chhoti and Bitto..?
Somebody save the bride!
Bitto!
Uncle
Don't panic..
walk to the door
Stay back
Quick!
Your wedding dress?
Make way for the bride
Where is Chhoti.. where is Chhoti?
She must be inside..?
- No, she isn't.. go find her
Chhoti..?
Chhoti..!
Munim.. Chhoti..?
- I've no idea
Listen.. I think I saw
her going up the stairs
Listen.. Bitto.. wait!
Where are you going, Bitto?
Stop
Krishnakant.. Krishnakant..
Chhoti
Sister
Leave me!
Chhoti.. Chhoti..
Aunty,
Chhoti is fine,
she's all right
Poonam
Chhoti!
Call Dr Rashid, a burns case is here
The patient has severe burns, Doctor.
- Okay, let's go
Excuse me.. who's the
patient's father?
Yes..?
Please come
Sit
The patient has approximately 40
percent superficial to deep burns,
third degree burns included
Luckily, her face was untouched
Doctor, tomorrow morning,
her bridegroom is arriving
It is Poonam's wedding tomorrow
About half of her body is burnt,
the wounds are deep
A wedding tomorrow is out of question
Forgive me for saying.. in such
cases even families abandon their own,
Iesser said the better.. for someone
who promised to marry her
Just now, your daughter
is fighting for her life
Tomorrow morning, as soon as possible,
we must go in for a major surgery
Now, if you will excuse me, I must
discuss the case with my team
Krishnakant,
by now, Prem must be starting out
We ought to inform..
Harishchandra quickly! Please
Sir.. Bhagat
Yes Bhagat?
Harishchandra, don't
come here now..
What happened, Papa?
Excuse me
Bhavna, one minute.
- What is it?
What's the matter Sister-in-law?
While we are getting ready for surgery
one of you may meet the patient
Doctor,
can I see Sister.. even
from far? Please
Okay, please wait
Uncle
Is Chhoti well, Uncle?
Nothing can harm Chhoti
No fire can hurt Chhoti
Tell Aunty, nothing
can harm Chhoti
Chhoti.. Uncle..
Look Rama, the bridegroom
has arrived for Poonam
Look at her palanquin,
so gaily decorated
Just a while now, then
she will be gone
Didn't I tell you, you'll cry the most
It was her beauty that always
pained your eyes,
so much so, you wouldn't
even look at her
Look Rama, for our Chhoti's sake,
she has sacrificed her beauty
Sacrificed her beauty
Doctor, after the operation, Poonam
will recover fully, won't she?
Right now, nothing can be said,
it's a very delicate case
There's more to recovery than
the healing of wounds
In such cases, one loses
self-confidence
And the pain in burning..
you and I cannot imagine,
what that pain is like
Krishnakant, we're all ready
for Poonam's operation
It's a major surgery
I have informed you of the
complications in this case
Your permission is necessary
We will try our best
Two days from now..
as the clock strikes this hour,
you'll be giving your daughter away
Uncle
I will sign
The wedding will happen today
Now,
at the appointed time,
I seek your permission
No son,
your emotions are far-removed
from the reality of things
You will not be able
to see her in pain
The girl in pain is not
only your daughter,
she's also our daughter-in-law
The best surgeons from
Delhi will be here soon
Poonam's well-being is
now our responsibility
Be seated
Sunil..
- Papa..?
Come with me. Let's meet Dr Rashid
May I meet Poonam, Uncle?
Poonam
Everything will be fine, Poonam
Look, what Sister-in-law has sent..
vermilion for my bride
It's our wedding today, Poonam
Sister, leave us alone
for two minutes, please
Once.. there was a pretty girl
who had a right to that vermilion
Today's ugly truth..
Iies under this canopy
Neither am I unawares
of truths Poonam,..
.. nor are you a stranger
to my intentions
If you want my love for you to
diminish at this sight of you..
that is inconceivable, Poonam
You always prayed for me Poonam and
your prayers were always answered
Today again.. please pray for me,
pray, that I find the strength within
me, to never let your faith weaken
You are my companion, Poonam..
my most beautiful one,
the one who's always worried,
lest I catch a cold
One who cares about what I eat,
what I wear, more than I myself
The one who knows me more
than I know myself
On our wedding day, l
want from you.. a gift
Give me all your pain
Before the auspicious moment goes by,
Iet the rituals be done
Let there be no distance..
between the vermilion
and your forehead
This is the wedding altar,
the sacred fire,
the festive home
At this wedding altar,
in God's presence,
in this festive home..
to anoint you with vermilion..
I have the right
I take you as my bride,
Stop
For once, take off the covers,
look at what I've become
My love doesn't deserve
this test, Poonam
And you know it
Sweets, for everyone.
- Thank you, sir
Where am I to sign, Doctor?
Mr Prem,
in this hospital, so far..
we've only seen.. brides tortured,
burnt for dowry
Today, for the first time ever, here..
we've seen someone becoming a bride
This is Dr Jain, a dear friend. Also,
a famous burns specialist
And his team.. this is Dr Rashid
We're here to help you
in any manner we can
You're most welcome, sir. It's
an honor to have you here
We've a battle waiting to be won
Take the new bride to the
operation theater, please
Please come, Doctor
Uncle, tea
No..
- We'll share
Why are you worrying, Krishnakant?
He is doing the worrying for
us. You drink your tea
Thank you so much, Doctor.
Congratulations
Doctor, how is she?
Operation successful
After 48 hours, when bandages come
off, we'll know the exact position
This first battle we have won, Prem
For at least a month and a half,
Poonam must stay here
Doctor..
Afterwards, she can go home?
Sure
Okay, until then, our daughter-in-law
remains in your charge, Krishnakant
Afterwards, the bridegroom's party
is right upon your doors
Got to make him throw us
a party, right Doctor?
Right
Bride's father
Time heals wounds..
it's true for sure ;
but quicker than Time..
Love heals
When your beloved is beside you..
with his healing touch..
a miracle then works..
upon wounds
Come home quickly Poonam, I'm waiting
to eat the curry you cook
Poonam, come quickly. We'll
go to Som Sarovar again
I've yet to read up all
the newspapers out there
Come soon. We miss you!
- Get well soon
Aunty, smile
Dressing
Give it a final coat
of paint, thoroughly
Uncle, now the painting
is almost over
Sunil Babu, this has taken
so much of your time
Don't embarrass me, Munim
Let me know if I can be
of any more service
By God's grace and your help,
everything's like it was before
Munim, begin to make preparations
for the wedding
The doctor says, tomorrow
we can bring Poonam home
Poonam can travel with you to Delhi
now and you have Dr Jain over there
About your married life, there
won't be any problems either
But I must discuss this with you
It's a bit personal
Prem,
this grafting treatment, in
lay terms, plastic surgery,
is not magic
With time, every wound will heal, but
their marks will take time to go
Now Poonam will look at herself
through your eyes, Prem
I know it, Doctor
Aunty has come to
take you home, Poonam
Come home, my child
To your home..
where your mother lives
Look at the bridegroom..
so smart and debonair
He rides his mare, leaving
behind his motor car
Handsome as ever..
handsome as ever, he sparkles
in his attire
The bride waits at her doorstep,
ready to go with him
So come rejoice,
for the joys of new lovers
At your door..
he has come, asking for his bride
Welcome him with love.. Iove
so precious, like pearls
Welcome him, let your pleasure and
laughter show in your eyes..
welcome him with pride..
for he comes, seeking his bride
The wedding..
this is their sacred wedding
A glorious Rajah of Delhi comes..
to wed the queen of Madhupur
About to culminate is the
story of their pure love
The flowers of joy have blossomed
'Twas journey upon a difficult path..
for these two loving hearts
he has come, asking for his bride
For once last, she walks towards you,
yesterday's little faltering steps,
faltering again today..
at crossroads of a father's happiness,
there's still parting's pain..
when joy and sorrow mingle,
why do they show in tears?
Now Father, bid your goodbyes,
send away your daughter
Bid me fond farewells Father, send
your dear daughter away forever,
and bless my way
Now she leaves with her husband,
in her bride's palanquin,
he carries her away
Krishnakant, I'm taking home
a daughter, not a daughter-in-law
Harishchandra, when fathers of
all sons begin to think like you,
daughters will be called their
fathers' burdens no more
The moment of submission..
now arrives, o'bride
It's the mirror, it's also
the reflection of your mind
He is in the mirror..
mirrored everywhere
The one.. you gave your heart to..
..with him, now become
one in body and soul
Tonight, give him every
right he deserves
For neither of you..
are strangers any longer
Here comes the moment
of submission, o'bride
It's dressing-time, Poonam
I have the right, Poonam
We finally got the happiness
we were destined to find
Our night of love has come
to us after a test by fire
The Moon and stars will carry
our legend to all after us
Tonight, from this benign starlight,
let us seek our boon
A lifetime of love and roses,
you have the right
An eternity together..
My love..
my heart sings your Song of Love
I have the right to look at you..
I have the right to
go on looking at you..
Beloved, beloved..
Beloved, beloved, my heart says,
you have the right..
You have the right..
This night is slowly fading
and melting away slowly..
Love is rising slowly..
What do these distances, say,
humming along, beloved..
I will keep you awake you
this night, I have the right..
I will steal the full moon,
I have the right..
Beloved, beloved..
Beloved, beloved, my heart says,
you have the right..
You have the right..