Be very quiet.
I'm hunting rabbits.
Rabbit tracks!
Kill the rabbit, kill the rabbit, kill the rabbit!
Kill the rabbit?
Yo ho to oh! Yo ho to oh! Yo ho...
O mighty warrior of great fighting stock
Might I inquire to ask, eh...
What's up doc?
I'm going to kill the rabbit!
O mighty hunter, 'twill be quite a task
How will you do it, might I inquire to ask?
I will do it with my spear and magic helmet.
Your spear and magic helmet?
Spear and magic helmet.
Magic helmet?
Magic helmet!
Magic helmet...
Yes, magic helmet, and I'll give you a sample!
Bye...
That was the rabbit!
Oh Brunhilde, you're so lovely
Yes, I know it
I can't help it
Oh Brunhilde, be my love
Return my love...
A longing burns deep inside me
I want you always beside me
A love like ours must be...
Made for you and for me...
Return, won't you return my love...
For my love is yours
I'll kill the rabbit!
Arise storms!
North winds blow, south winds blow!
Typhoons, Hurricanes... Earthquakes!
Smog!
Flash lightning! Strike the rabbit!
What have I done?
I've killed the rabbit...
Poor little bunny...
Poor little rabbit...
Well, what did you expect in an opera...?
A happy ending?