It's Friday night
Time to go home
Time to go home now
It's Friday night
Got to get home now
Get myself ail smartly
This is the night to Look your best
see you at the dance tonight
Hey, come on, mate
me your comb now
I'm the bloke they're going to choose
Shine up your winkle picker shoes
So see you at the dance tonight
Night school all the week
May bring us knowledge
But we learn more tonight
Than we do at college
Our hearts are bright
Brighter than chrome now
We know before we go to bed
We've got a night of fun ahead
So see you at the dance tonight
See you at the dance tonight
See you at the dance
Our hearts are bright
Brighter than chrome now
We know before we go to bed
We've got a night of fun ahead
We're going to have a ball
It's Friday, so welcome, all
And see you at the dance tonight
Well, I got a funny feeling
That I'm falling in love with you
Yes, I got a funny feeling
Every day and night
I dream up dreams of you
'Cause I got a funny feeling
That I'm falling in love with you
My heart goes a bobbin'
Every time I catch a sight of you
Well, my heart goes a bobbin'
Just say the word
And tell me that I'll do
'Cause I got a funny feeling
That I'm falling in love with you
Yes, you're the one
Don't try to run
If it turns out right
I'll squeeze you tight
When you're in my arms tonight
You'd better get a funny feeling
That you're falling in love with me
Just make that date
Baby, you will see
That you're getting a funny feeling
That you're falling in love
'Cause I got a funny feeling
That I'm falling in love with you
impossible
Nothing's impossible
your heart is really in it
heart is really in it
is really in it
really in it
If your heart is really
If your heart is really in
If your heart is really in it
a fight
But you can win it
fight
It's a fight
But you can win it
you can win it
It's a fight
But you
But you can
It's a fight
But you can win
But you can win it
only you will trust your dreams
you will trust your dreams
will trust your dreams
trust your dreams
your dreams
If only you will trust your
If only you will trust your dreams
impossible
Nothing's impossible
use standing round and sighing
standing round and sighing
round and sighing
No use standing round
No use standing round and
No use standing round and sighing
you try and keep on trying
try and keep on trying
and keep on trying
keep on trying
If you try and keep
If you try and keep on
If you try and keep on trying
you will bring off
Your wildest schemes
bring off
off
Your wildest schemes
Then you will bring off
wildest schemes
Your wildest
Then you will bring off
Your wildest schemes
Sing
Sing out
your faith in the human race
faith in the human race
in the human race
the human race
State your faith in the
State your faith in the human
State your faith in the human race
doubt
Why doubt
own personal miracle
Is about to take place?
personal miracle
miracle
Is about to take place?
Your own personal miracle
about to take place?
Is about
Your own personal miracle
Is about to
Is about to take
Your own personal miracle
Is about to take place?
impossible
Nothing's impossible
can move a slab of granite
move a slab of granite
a slab of granite
slab of granite
Faith can move a slab
Faith can move a slab of
Faith can move a slab of granite
day, we will reach a planet or two
we will reach a planet or two
reach a planet or two
a planet or two
Any day, we will reach a
Any day, we will reach a planet
Any day, we will reach a planet or
Any day, we will reach a planet or two
that's what we will do
what we will do
Yeah, that's what
Yeah, that's what we will
Yeah, that's what we will do
we can't achieve
can't achieve
Nothing we can't
Nothing we can't achieve
nothing is impossible
is impossible
Because nothing is
Because nothing is impossible
long as you believe
as you believe
you believe
As long as you
As long as you believe
take Everest
What did they say?
Everest
Just take Everest
What did they say?
What
Just take Everest
What did
What did they
Just take Everest
What did they say?
one can climb it anyway
can climb it anyway
climb it anyway
No one can climb
No one can climb it
No one can climb it anyway
yeah?
What happened Coronation Day?
Oh, yeah?
happened Coronation Day?
What happened
Oh, yeah?
What happened Coronation
What happened Coronation Day?
see, nothing is impossible
guess nothing is impossible
nothing is impossible
is impossible
- You see, nothing is
- I guess nothing is
- You see, nothing is impossible
- I guess nothing is impossible
Space
They said we'd never win
said we'd never win
we'd never win
Space
They said we'd
They said we'd never
Space
They said we'd never win
said around the Earth
A man could never spin
around the Earth
the Earth
A man could never spin
Earth
They said around the Earth
A man could never spin
man could never spin
They said around the Earth
A man
A man could
They said around the Earth
A man could never
A man could never spin
heard of Major Gagarin?
of Major Gagarin?
Major Gagarin?
Ever heard of Major
Ever heard of Major Gagarin?
see, nothing is impossible
nothing is impossible
is impossible
- You see, nothing is
- You see, nothing is impossible
- Impossible?
- Never
always so easy
Saying nothing can be done
so easy
easy
Saying nothing can be done
It's always so easy
nothing can be done
Saying nothing
It's always so easy
Saying nothing can
Saying nothing can be
It's always so easy
Saying nothing can be done
they realize
There's always a prize to be won?
realize
Don't they realize
There's always a prize to be won?
always a prize to be won?
Don't they realize
There's always
There's always a
Don't they realize
There's always a prize
There's always a prize to
Don't they realize
There's always a prize to be
There's always a prize to be won?
said
Something could not be done
Someone said
Something
Something could not
Someone said
Something could not be
Something could not be done
which point
Someone went out and did it
point
At which point
Someone went out and did it
went out and did it
At which point
Someone went
Someone went out
At which point
Someone went out and
Someone went out and did
At which point
Someone went out and did it
city of Jericho
Would not admit defeat
of Jericho
Jericho
Would not admit defeat
The city of Jericho
not admit defeat
Would not
The city of Jericho
Would not admit
Would not admit defeat
that's why General Joshua
Said, "Sound retreat"
why General Joshua
General Joshua
Said, "Sound retreat"
Joshua
And that's why General Joshua
Said, "Sound retreat"
Said,
And that's why General Joshua
Said, "Sound
Said, "Sound retreat"
just at that moment
at that moment
that moment
Then just at that
Then just at that moment
trumpets
Hit that rock 'n' roll beat
Those trumpets
that rock 'n' roll beat
Hit that
Those trumpets
Hit that rock
Hit that rock 'n'
Those trumpets
Hit that rock 'n' roll
Hit that rock 'n' roll beat
down came the wall
came the wall
- And down came
- And down came the
- And down came the wall
you will doubtless recall
doubtless recall
- As you will doubtless
- As you will doubtless recall
an almighty fall
almighty fall
- With an almighty
- With an almighty fall
once and for all
and for all
- Proving once and
- Proving once and for
- Proving once and for all
is impossible
impossible
- Nothing is impossible
is impossible
impossible
- Nothing is impossible
is impossible
impossible
- Nothing is impossible
- Nothing's impossible
doubt
Why doubt
own personal miracle
Is about to take place?
personal miracle
miracle
Is about to take place?
Your own personal miracle
about to take place?
Is about
Your own personal miracle
Is about to
Is about to take
Your own personal miracle
Is about to take place?
impossible
- Nothing's impossible
can move a slab of granite
move a slab of granite
a slab of granite
slab of granite
- Faith can move a slab
- Faith can move a slab of
- Faith can move a slab of granite
day, we will reach a planet or two
we will reach a planet or two
reach a planet or two
a planet or two
- Any day, we will reach a
- Any day, we will reach a planet
- Any day, we will reach a planet or
- Any day, we will reach a planet or two
what we will do
- That's what
- That's what we will
- That's what we will do
we can't achieve
can't achieve
- Nothing we can't
- Nothing we can't achieve
nothing is impossible
- Nothing is impossible
is impossible
impossible
- Because nothing is impossible
- Nothing is impossible
is impossible
impossible
Nothing is impossible
long as you believe
- Nothing is impossible
as you believe
you believe
- Nothing is impossible
believe
- As long as you believe
- Nothing is impossible
- Nothing
- As long as you believe
- Nothing is
- Nothing is impossible
long as you believe
as you believe
- Nothing is impossible
you believe
believe
- Nothing is impossible
- As long as you believe
- Nothing
- Nothing is
- As long as you believe
- Nothing is impossible
long as you
as you
As long as
As long as you
night
Good night
young ones
The young
The young ones
we're the young ones
the young ones
young ones
Darling, we're the young
Darling, we're the young ones
young ones should not be afraid
ones should not be afraid
should not be afraid
And young ones should not
And young ones should not be
And young ones should not be afraid
live and love
and love
To live and
To live and love
the flame is strong
flame is strong
While the flame
While the flame is
While the flame is strong
we won't be
The young ones very long
won't be
be
The young ones very long
For we won't be
young ones very long
The young
For we won't be
The young ones
The young ones very
For we won't be
The young ones very long
Tomorrow
wait until tomorrow?
until tomorrow?
tomorrow?
Why wait until tomorrow?
tomorrow
Sometimes never comes
'Cause tomorrow
Sometimes
Sometimes never
'Cause tomorrow
Sometimes never comes
love me
So love
So love me
a song to be sung
song to be sung
to be sung
There's a song to
There's a song to be
There's a song to be sung
the best time is to sing it
While we're young
best time is to sing it
time is to sing it
While we're young
is to sing it
to sing it
While we're young
sing it
it
While we're young
And the best time is to sing it
While
While we're
And the best time is to sing it
While we're young
in every lifetime
every lifetime
Once in every
Once in every lifetime
a love like this
love like this
Comes a love
Comes a love like
Comes a love like this
need you
You need me
you
I need you
You need me
You
I need you
You need
You need me
my darling, can't you see?
darling, can't you see?
can't you see?
Oh, my darling, can't
Oh, my darling, can't you
Oh, my darling, can't you see?
dreams
Young dreams
be dreamed together
dreamed together
Should be dreamed
Should be dreamed together
young hearts
Should not be afraid
hearts
And young hearts
Should not be afraid
Should not
And young hearts
Should not be
Should not be afraid
some day
When the years have flown
day
And some day
When the years have flown
the years have flown
years have flown
And some day
When the years
When the years have
And some day
When the years have flown
then we will
Teach the young ones of our own
we will
Darling, then we will
Teach the young ones of our own
the young ones of our own
young ones of our own
Darling, then we will
Teach the young
Teach the young ones
Darling, then we will
Teach the young ones of
Teach the young ones of our
Darling, then we will
Teach the young ones of our own
in every lifetime
every lifetime
Once in every
Once in every lifetime
a love like this
love like this
Comes a love
Comes a love like
Comes a love like this
need you
You need me
you
I need you
You need me
You
I need you
You need
You need me
my darling, can't you see?
darling, can't you see?
can't you see?
Oh, my darling, can't
Oh, my darling, can't you
Oh, my darling, can't you see?
dreams
Young dreams
be dreamed together
dreamed together
Should be dreamed
Should be dreamed together
young hearts
Should not be afraid
hearts
And young hearts
Should not be afraid
Should not
And young hearts
Should not be
Should not be afraid
some day
When the years have flown
day
And some day
When the years have flown
the years have flown
years have flown
And some day
When the years
When the years have
And some day
When the years have flown
then we will
Teach the young ones of our own
we will
Darling, then we will
Teach the young ones of our own
the young ones of our own
young ones of our own
Darling, then we will
Teach the young
Teach the young ones
Darling, then we will
Teach the young ones of
Teach the young ones of our
Darling, then we will
Teach the young ones of our own
heard of those
Three Musketeers
of those
those
Three Musketeers
You've heard of those
Three
Three Musketeers
by Alexandre Dumas
Alexandre Dumas
Immortalized by Alexandre
Immortalized by Alexandre Dumas
we've heard rumors
heard rumours
Yeah, we've heard
Yeah, we've heard rumors
Arthur and his Guinevere's
and his Guinevere's
his Guinevere's
Guinevere's
And Arthur and his Guinevere's
at the table round
At Camelot
the table round
table round
At Camelot
round
Adventures at the table round
At Camelot
At
Adventures at the table round
At Camelot
yeah
- So what?
- Why, yeah
- So
- So what?
them square
And oblong acidly
square
Call them square
And oblong acidly
And
Call them square
And oblong
And oblong acidly
Nevertheless,
Nevertheless, it is
Nevertheless, it is true
the Mavericks
And the Hopalong Cassidys
Mavericks
That the Mavericks
And the Hopalong Cassidys
the Hopalong Cassidys
Hopalong Cassidys
That the Mavericks
And the Hopalong
And the Hopalong Cassidys
the same thing too
same thing too
Say the same
Say the same thing
Say the same thing too
what they say
Is going to win the day
they say
say
Is going to win the day
And what they say
going to win the day
Is going to
And what they say
Is going to win
Is going to win the
And what they say
Is going to win the day
me and thou and thee
And also you
and thou and thee
thou and thee
And also you
and thee
thee
And also you
For me and thou and thee
And
And also
For me and thou and thee
And also you
for one
One for all
one
All for one
One for all
One
All for one
One for
One for all
our voices unite for
voices unite for
Let our voices
Let our voices unite
Let our voices unite for
for one
One for all
one
All for one
One for all
One
All for one
One for
One for all
we've something to fight for
something to fight for
Now we've something
Now we've something to
Now we've something to fight
Now we've something to fight for
or foul may be the weather
foul may be the weather
may be the weather
be the weather
the weather
Fair or foul may be the
Fair or foul may be the weather
can face it if we stick together
face it if we stick together
it if we stick together
if we stick together
we stick together
stick together
We can face it if we stick
We can face it if we stick together
we stand side by side
stand side by side
side by side
If we stand side
If we stand side by
If we stand side by side
there's no one can beat us
no one can beat us
one can beat us
Then there's no one
Then there's no one can
Then there's no one can beat
Then there's no one can beat us
forward with pride
Marching forward
Marching forward with
Marching forward with pride
no power can defeat us
power can defeat us
can defeat us
There's no power can
There's no power can defeat
There's no power can defeat us
and clear as a trumpet call
clear as a trumpet call
as a trumpet call
a trumpet call
Loud and clear as a
Loud and clear as a trumpet
Loud and clear as a trumpet call
Sing
for one
And one for all
one
All for one
And one for all
one for all
All for one
And one
And one for
All for one
And one for all
for one
one
And one for all
All for one
one for all
And one
All for one
And one for
And one for all
we stand
Divided we fall
stand
United we stand
Divided we fall
Divided
United we stand
Divided we
Divided we fall
by side
Till the battle is won
side
Side by side
Till the battle is won
the battle is won
Side by side
Till the
Till the battle
Side by side
Till the battle is
Till the battle is won
two strong hearts
Are better than one
strong hearts
hearts
Are better than one
For two strong hearts
Are
Are better
For two strong hearts
Are better than
Are better than one
all for one
And one for all
for one
one
And one for all
It's all for one
And
And one
It's all for one
And one for
And one for all
we stand
Divided we fall
stand
United we stand
Divided we fall
Divided
United we stand
Divided we
Divided we fall
for one
One for all
one
All for one
One for all
One
All for one
One for
One for all
our voices unite for
voices unite for
Let our voices
Let our voices unite
Let our voices unite for
for one
One for all
one
All for one
One for all
One
All for one
One for
One for all
have something to fight for
something to fight for
We have something
We have something to
We have something to fight
We have something to fight for
or foul may be the weather
foul may be the weather
may be the weather
be the weather
the weather
Fair or foul may be the
Fair or foul may be the weather
matter what the future brings
what the future brings
the future brings
future brings
No matter what the future
know that we can face it
that we can face it
we can face it
We know that we
We know that we can
We know that we can face
We know that we can face it
we stick together
stick together
together
If we stick together
we stand side by side
And those bells are ringing
stand side by side
side by side
And those bells are ringing
by side
side
And those bells are ringing
If we stand side by side
those bells are ringing
And those
If we stand side by side
And those bells
And those bells are
If we stand side by side
And those bells are ringing
there's no one can beat us
no one can beat us
one can beat us
Then there's no one
Then there's no one can
Then there's no one can beat
Then there's no one can beat us
forward with pride
We are young and swinging
with pride
pride
We are young and swinging
Marching forward with pride
are young and swinging
We are
Marching forward with pride
We are young
We are young and
Marching forward with pride
We are young and swinging
no power can defeat us
power can defeat us
can defeat us
There's no power can
There's no power can defeat
There's no power can defeat us
and clear as a trumpet call
clear as a trumpet call
as a trumpet call
a trumpet call
Loud and clear as a
Loud and clear as a trumpet
Loud and clear as a trumpet call
Sing
for one
All for
All for one
unbeatable
We're unbeatable
for one
All for
All for one
Undefeatable
for one
And one for all
one
All for one
And one for all
one for all
All for one
And one
And one for
All for one
And one for all
you cuddle up beside me
Nice and near
cuddle up beside me
up beside me
Nice and near
beside me
First you cuddle up beside
First you cuddle up beside me
Nice and near
Nice
First you cuddle up beside me
Nice and
Nice and near
you whisper all the things
I long to hear
whisper all the things
all the things
I long to hear
the things
things
I long to hear
Then you whisper all the things
I
I long
Then you whisper all the things
I long to
I long to hear
the first lesson in love
first lesson in love
lesson in love
That's the first lesson
That's the first lesson in
That's the first lesson in love
mm, mm, mm, mm, mm
mm, mm, mm, mm
mm, mm, mm
Mm, mm, mm, mm,
Mm, mm, mm, mm, mm,
Mm, mm, mm, mm, mm, mm
how you start
you start
That's how you
That's how you start
you put your two sweet lips
On mine like this
put your two sweet lips
your two sweet lips
On mine like this
two sweet lips
sweet lips
On mine like this
lips
Then you put your two sweet lips
On mine like this
On
Then you put your two sweet lips
On mine
On mine like
Then you put your two sweet lips
On mine like this
you learn the magic
Of a tender kiss
learn the magic
the magic
Of a tender kiss
magic
And you learn the magic
Of a tender kiss
Of
And you learn the magic
Of a
Of a tender
And you learn the magic
Of a tender kiss
the next lesson in love
next lesson in love
lesson in love
That's the next lesson
That's the next lesson in
That's the next lesson in love
mm, mm, mm, mm, mm
mm, mm, mm, mm
mm, mm, mm
Mm, mm, mm, mm,
Mm, mm, mm, mm, mm,
Mm, mm, mm, mm, mm, mm
me your heart
your heart
Give me your
Give me your heart
so easy
When you know how
easy
It's so easy
When you know how
you know how
It's so easy
When you
When you know
It's so easy
When you know how
my darling
Let me show you now
darling
Oh, my darling
Let me show you now
me show you now
Oh, my darling
Let me
Let me show
Oh, my darling
Let me show you
Let me show you now
you whisper "I love you"
So sweetly
whisper "I love you"
"I love you"
So sweetly
love you"
you"
So sweetly
Then you whisper "I love you"
So
So sweetly
I'll know
You've learned it all completely
know
And I'll know
You've learned it all completely
learned it all completely
And I'll know
You've learned
You've learned it
And I'll know
You've learned it all
You've learned it all completely
the last lesson in love
last lesson in love
lesson in love
That's the last lesson
That's the last lesson in
That's the last lesson in love
it is up to you
up to you
Now it is up
Now it is up to
Now it is up to you
love me do
Baby, love
Baby, love me
Baby, love me do
my darling
darling
- Oh, my darling
me show you now
show you now
- Let me show
- Let me show you
- Let me show you now
I whisper "I love you"
So sweetly
whisper "I love you"
"I love you"
So sweetly
love you"
you"
So sweetly
Then I whisper "I love you"
So
So sweetly
I'll know
You've learned it all completely
know
And I'll know
You've learned it all completely
learned it all completely
And I'll know
You've learned
You've learned it
And I'll know
You've learned it all
You've learned it all completely
the last lesson in love
last lesson in love
lesson in love
- That's the last lesson
- That's the last lesson in
- That's the last lesson in love
it is up to you
up to you
- Now it is up
- Now it is up to
- Now it is up to you
love me do
- Baby, love
- Baby, love me
- Baby, love me do
you cuddle up beside me
cuddle up beside me
up beside me
First you cuddle up
First you cuddle up beside
First you cuddle up beside me
and near
Nice and
Nice and near
you whisper all the things
I long to hear
whisper all the things
all the things
I long to hear
the things
things
I long to hear
Then you whisper all the things
I
I long
Then you whisper all the things
I long to
I long to hear
the first lesson in love
first lesson in love
lesson in love
That's the first lesson
That's the first lesson in
That's the first lesson in love
oh, oh, oh, oh
oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh,
Oh, oh, oh, oh,
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
how you start
you start
That's how you
That's how you start
so easy
easy
It's so easy
you know how
know how
When you know
When you know how
my darling
Let me show you now
darling
Oh, my darling
Let me show you now
me show you now
Oh, my darling
Let me
Let me show
Oh, my darling
Let me show you
Let me show you now
you put your two sweet lips
On mine like this
put your two sweet lips
your two sweet lips
On mine like this
two sweet lips
sweet lips
On mine like this
lips
Then you put your two sweet lips
On mine like this
On
Then you put your two sweet lips
On mine
On mine like
Then you put your two sweet lips
On mine like this
you learn the magic
Of a tender kiss
learn the magic
the magic
Of a tender kiss
magic
And you learn the magic
Of a tender kiss
Of
And you learn the magic
Of a
Of a tender
And you learn the magic
Of a tender kiss
the last lesson in love
last lesson in love
lesson in love
That's the last lesson
That's the last lesson in
That's the last lesson in love
oh, oh, oh, oh
oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh,
Oh, oh, oh, oh,
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
me your heart
your heart
Give me your
Give me your heart
you put your two sweet lips
On mine like this
put your two sweet lips
your two sweet lips
On mine like this
two sweet lips
sweet lips
On mine like this
lips
Then you put your two sweet lips
On mine like this
On
Then you put your two sweet lips
On mine
On mine like
Then you put your two sweet lips
On mine like this
you learn the magic
Of a tender kiss
learn the magic
the magic
Of a tender kiss
magic
And you learn the magic
Of a tender kiss
Of
And you learn the magic
Of a
Of a tender
And you learn the magic
Of a tender kiss
the last lesson in love
last lesson in love
lesson in love
That's the last lesson
That's the last lesson in
That's the last lesson in love
oh, oh, oh, oh
oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh,
Oh, oh, oh, oh,
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
me your heart
your heart
Give me your
Give me your heart
didn't have to kiss her like that
have to kiss her like that
to kiss her like that
kiss her like that
He didn't have to kiss
He didn't have to kiss her
He didn't have to kiss her like
He didn't have to kiss her like that
I know it is part of the play
know it is part of the play
it is part of the play
part of the play
Though I know it is part
Though I know it is part of
Though I know it is part of the
Though I know it is part of the play
he never kissed me that way
never kissed me that way
kissed me that way
But he never kissed
But he never kissed me
But he never kissed me that
But he never kissed me that way
no use fooling myself
use fooling myself
fooling myself
It's no use fooling
It's no use fooling myself
too clearly I see
clearly I see
Only too clearly
Only too clearly I
Only too clearly I see
as I may to explain it away
I may to explain it away
may to explain it away
to explain it away
explain it away
Try as I may to explain
Try as I may to explain it
Try as I may to explain it away
just doesn't love me
doesn't love me
Nicky just doesn't
Nicky just doesn't love
Nicky just doesn't love me
yet I know
I know
And yet I
And yet I know
isn't so
This isn't
This isn't so
I know deep inside
know deep inside
deep inside
For I know deep
For I know deep inside
all that took a fall
Was just my pride
that took a fall
took a fall
Was just my pride
a fall
fall
Was just my pride
That all that took a fall
Was
Was just
That all that took a fall
Was just my
Was just my pride
there's no one for me
no one for me
Because there's no
Because there's no one
Because there's no one for
Because there's no one for me
one but Nicky
but Nicky
No one but
No one but Nicky
other boy
No other
No other boy
me that thill
that thill
Gives me that
Gives me that thill
know that he would not deceive me
that he would not deceive me
he would not deceive me
would not deceive me
not deceive me
I know that he would not
I know that he would not deceive
I know that he would not deceive me
in my heart
I love him still
my heart
heart
I love him still
Yet in my heart
love him still
I love
Yet in my heart
I love him
I love him still
happy day
Some happy
Some happy day
we are older
are older
When we are
When we are older
on his shoulder
I want to be
his shoulder
shoulder
I want to be
Head on his shoulder
I
I want
Head on his shoulder
I want to
I want to be
one for me
for me
No one for
No one for me
one but Nicky
but Nicky
No one but
No one but Nicky
know that he's the boy for me
that he's the boy for me
he's the boy for me
the boy for me
I know that he's the
I know that he's the boy
I know that he's the boy for
I know that he's the boy for me
one for me
for me
No one for
No one for me
one but Nicky
but Nicky
No one but
No one but Nicky
know that he's the boy for me
that he's the boy for me
he's the boy for me
the boy for me
I know that he's the
I know that he's the boy
I know that he's the boy for
I know that he's the boy for me
a kid who can sing
kid who can sing
who can sing
Take a kid who
Take a kid who can
Take a kid who can sing
song with a zing
with a zing
A song with
A song with a
A song with a zing
makes a whole audience glow
a whole audience glow
whole audience glow
audience glow
That makes a whole audience
That makes a whole audience glow
some dancers in tights
dancers in tights
Add some dancers
Add some dancers in
Add some dancers in tights
costumes, some lights
some lights
Some costumes, some
Some costumes, some lights
what do you know?
do you know?
you know?
And what do you
And what do you know?
got a show
a show
You've got a
You've got a show
comic whose nose
Is red as a rose
whose nose
nose
Is red as a rose
A comic whose nose
Is
Is red
A comic whose nose
Is red as
Is red as a
A comic whose nose
Is red as a rose
tie can revolve on its bow
can revolve on its bow
revolve on its bow
Whose tie can revolve
Whose tie can revolve on
Whose tie can revolve on its
Whose tie can revolve on its bow
laugh and he will clown
and he will clown
He will laugh and
He will laugh and he will
He will laugh and he will clown
he will fall down
fall down
Then he will fall
Then he will fall down
what do you know?
do you know?
you know?
And what do you
And what do you know?
got a show
a show
You've got a
You've got a show
moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of those terrible days
you're going berserk
going berserk
And it is one of those terrible days
berserk
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of those terrible days
it is one of those terrible days
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is
And it is one
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of
And it is one of those
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of those terrible
And it is one of those terrible days
moment, the magic, it is working
- Hooray
the magic, it is working
magic, it is working
- Hooray
it is working
Next moment, the magic, it is
- Next moment, the magic, it is working
- Hooray
that's show business
show business
And that's show
And that's show business
coin a phrase
a phrase
phrase
To coin a phrase
gals and some guys
and some guys
some guys
Some gals and some
Some gals and some guys
stars in their eyes
in their eyes
their eyes
With stars in their
With stars in their eyes
spirit of get up and go
of get up and go
get up and go
up and go
A spirit of get up
A spirit of get up and
A spirit of get up and go
curtain will rise
will rise
A curtain will
A curtain will rise
to our surprise
our surprise
surprise
And to our surprise
what do you know?
do you know?
you know?
Well, what do you
Well, what do you know?
got a show
a show
We got a
We got a show
a smile for everyone you meet
smile for everyone you meet
for everyone you meet
everyone you meet
Have a smile for everyone
Have a smile for everyone you
Have a smile for everyone you meet
everyone will have a smile for you
will have a smile for you
have a smile for you
And everyone will have
And everyone will have a
And everyone will have a smile
And everyone will have a smile for
And everyone will have a smile for you
mile along lifes busy street
along lifes busy street
lifes busy street
Every mile along lifes
Every mile along lifes busy
Every mile along lifes busy street
filled with friendship true
with friendship true
friendship true
Is filled with friendship
Is filled with friendship true
tomorrow brings new sorrow
So why borrow tears?
brings new sorrow
new sorrow
So why borrow tears?
sorrow
Each tomorrow brings new sorrow
So why borrow tears?
So
Each tomorrow brings new sorrow
So why
So why borrow
Each tomorrow brings new sorrow
So why borrow tears?
thing to do is
Have a smile for everyone you meet
to do is
do is
Have a smile for everyone you meet
is
The thing to do is
Have a smile for everyone you meet
a smile for everyone you meet
smile for everyone you meet
for everyone you meet
The thing to do is
Have a smile for
Have a smile for everyone
The thing to do is
Have a smile for everyone you
Have a smile for everyone you meet
they will have a smile for you
will have a smile for you
have a smile for you
a smile for you
And they will have a
And they will have a smile
And they will have a smile for
And they will have a smile for you
tinkle, tinkle
Tinkle, tinkle,
Tinkle, tinkle, tinkle
if the raindrops sprikle?
the raindrops sprikle?
raindrops sprikle?
What if the raindrops
What if the raindrops sprikle?
a little bell to your dancing shoes
And the sun will shine
little bell to your dancing shoes
bell to your dancing shoes
And the sun will shine
to your dancing shoes
your dancing shoes
And the sun will shine
dancing shoes
shoes
And the sun will shine
Tie a little bell to your dancing shoes
And
And the
Tie a little bell to your dancing shoes
And the sun
And the sun will
Tie a little bell to your dancing shoes
And the sun will shine
very well known as Algy
well known as Algy
known as Algy
He's very well known
He's very well known as
He's very well known as Algy
the ladies on the stage
ladies on the stage
on the stage
the stage
To the ladies on the
To the ladies on the stage
a jolly good chap is Algy
jolly good chap is Algy
good chap is Algy
chap is Algy
Such a jolly good chap
Such a jolly good chap is
Such a jolly good chap is Algy
now, he's all the rage
Whee
he's all the rage
all the rage
Whee
the rage
Just now, he's all the
Just now, he's all the rage
Whee
a jolly big favorite
- Algy
jolly big favorite
big favorite
- Algy
favourite
- And a jolly big favorite
- Algy
the barmaids at the Cri
barmaids at the Cri
With the barmaids
With the barmaids at
With the barmaids at the
With the barmaids at the Cri
very well known as Algy
well known as Algy
known as Algy
He's very well known
He's very well known as
He's very well known as Algy
the Piccadilly Johnny
With the little glass eye
Piccadilly Johnny
Johnny
With the little glass eye
As the Piccadilly Johnny
With
With the
As the Piccadilly Johnny
With the little
With the little glass
As the Piccadilly Johnny
With the little glass eye
Ginjah
They all know Captain Ginjah
Ginjah, Ginjah
all know Captain Ginjah
know Captain Ginjah
Ginjah, Ginjah
They all know
They all know Captain
Ginjah, Ginjah
They all know Captain Ginjah
old pot
Very hot
pot
Jolly old pot
Very hot
Very
Jolly old pot
Very hot
five in the shade
What, what
in the shade
the shade
What, what
shade
Ninety five in the shade
What, what
What,
Ninety five in the shade
What, what
love the ladies
Not one of them would I injure
the ladies
ladies
Not one of them would I injure
I love the ladies
one of them would I injure
of them would I injure
them would I injure
I love the ladies
Not one of them
Not one of them would
I love the ladies
Not one of them would I
Not one of them would I injure
the girlies go for Gin
girlies go for Gin
go for Gin
All the girlies go
All the girlies go for
All the girlies go for Gin
Gin, Gin, Gin, Ginjah
Gin, Gin, Ginjah
Gin, Ginjah
Gin, Gin, Gin, Gin,
Gin, Gin, Gin, Gin, Ginjah
Joshua
Joshua, Joshua
don't you call
And see Mama?
you call
call
And see Mama?
Why don't you call
And
And see
Why don't you call
And see Mama?
be pleased to know
pleased to know
She will be pleased
She will be pleased to
She will be pleased to know
you're my best beau
my best beau
best beau
That you're my best
That you're my best beau
Joshua
Joshua, Joshua
than lemon squash, you are
lemon squash, you are
squash, you are
Sweeter than lemon squash,
Sweeter than lemon squash, you
Sweeter than lemon squash, you are
by gosh, you are
gosh, you are
Oh, by gosh,
Oh, by gosh, you
Oh, by gosh, you are
u osh ua
Whee
osh ua
ua
Whee
Josh u osh ua
did you get that hat?
Where did you get that tile?
you get that hat?
get that hat?
Where did you get that tile?
that hat?
hat?
Where did you get that tile?
Where did you get that hat?
Where
Where did
Where did you get that hat?
Where did you
Where did you get
Where did you get that hat?
Where did you get that
Where did you get that tile?
it a nobby one?
It's just the proper style
a nobby one?
nobby one?
It's just the proper style
one?
Isn't it a nobby one?
It's just the proper style
just the proper style
Isn't it a nobby one?
It's just
It's just the
Isn't it a nobby one?
It's just the proper
It's just the proper style
should like to have one
Just the same as that
like to have one
to have one
Just the same as that
have one
one
Just the same as that
I should like to have one
Just
Just the
I should like to have one
Just the same
Just the same as
I should like to have one
Just the same as that
I go they shout
- Hello
go they shout
they shout
- Hello
Wherever I go they
- Wherever I go they shout
- Hello
did you get that hat?
you get that hat?
get that hat?
"Where did you get
"Where did you get that
"Where did you get that hat?
Arthur Murray
Murray
- Mr. Arthur Murray
could use you in a hurry
use you in a hurry
you in a hurry
- We could use you
- We could use you in
- We could use you in a
- We could use you in a hurry
poor kitchen maid
kitchen maid
- A poor kitchen
- A poor kitchen maid
and unpaid
- Unloved and
- Unloved and unpaid
a ball and she's loning to go
ball and she's loning to go
and she's loning to go
she's loning to go
- There's a ball and she's
- There's a ball and she's loning
- There's a ball and she's loning to
- There's a ball and she's loning to go
fairy with a spell
with a spell
- A fairy with
- A fairy with a
- A fairy with a spell
Prince Charming as well
Charming as well
- A Prince Charming
- A Prince Charming as
- A Prince Charming as well
what do you know?
You got a show
do you know?
you know?
You got a show
know?
And what do you know?
You got a show
You
And what do you know?
You got
You got a
And what do you know?
You got a show
families fight
And then, some dark night
fight
Two families fight
And then, some dark night
then, some dark night
Two families fight
And then,
And then, some
Two families fight
And then, some dark
And then, some dark night
Juliet meets Romeo
- Oh, oh, oh
meets Romeo
Romeo
- Oh, oh, oh
- Young Juliet meets Romeo
- Oh,
- Oh, oh,
- Young Juliet meets Romeo
- Oh, oh, oh
some dancers who will slide
Move it to the West Side
dancers who will slide
who will slide
Move it to the West Side
slide
Add some dancers who will slide
Move it to the West Side
Move
Add some dancers who will slide
Move it
Move it to
Add some dancers who will slide
Move it to the
Move it to the West
Add some dancers who will slide
Move it to the West Side
what do you know?
You got a show
do you know?
you know?
You got a show
know?
And what do you know?
You got a show
You
And what do you know?
You got
You got a
And what do you know?
You got a show
moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of those terrible days
you're going berserk
going berserk
And it is one of those terrible days
berserk
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of those terrible days
it is one of those terrible days
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is
And it is one
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of
And it is one of those
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of those terrible
And it is one of those terrible days
moment, the magic is working
the magic is working
magic is working
Next moment, the magic
Next moment, the magic is
Next moment, the magic is working
that's show business
To coin a phrase
show business
business
To coin a phrase
And that's show business
To
To coin
And that's show business
To coin a
To coin a phrase
strike up the band
The feeling is grand
up the band
the band
The feeling is grand
band
So strike up the band
The feeling is grand
The
So strike up the band
The feeling
The feeling is
So strike up the band
The feeling is grand
into adventure we go
adventure we go
As into adventure
As into adventure we
As into adventure we go
curtain will rise
And to our surprise
will rise
rise
And to our surprise
The curtain will rise
And
And to
The curtain will rise
And to our
And to our surprise
do you know?
We got a
you know?
know?
We got a
What do you know?
We
We got
What do you know?
We got a
do you know?
We've got a
you know?
know?
We've got a
What do you know?
We've
We've got
What do you know?
We've got a
do you know?
We got a
you know?
know?
We got a
What do you know?
We
We got
What do you know?
We got a
do you know?
He's got a
you know?
know?
He's got a
What do you know?
He's
He's got
What do you know?
He's got a
talking, sleeping, walking
Living doll
sleeping, walking
walking
Living doll
Crying, talking, sleeping, walking
Living
Living doll
got a great and glorious
Gay, uproarious
a great and glorious
great and glorious
Gay, uproarious
and glorious
glorious
Gay, uproarious
We've got a great and glorious
Gay,
Gay, uproarious
do you know?
you know?
What do you
What do you know?
got a show
a show
We've got a
We've got a show
the in your arms
girl in your arms
in your arms
When the girl in
When the girl in your
When the girl in your arms
the girl in your heart
girl in your heart
in your heart
your heart
Is the girl in your
Is the girl in your heart
you've got everything
got everything
everything
Then you've got everything
you're holding the dream
holding the dream
When you're holding
When you're holding the
When you're holding the dream
been dreaming you'd hold
dreaming you'd hold
You'd been dreaming
You'd been dreaming you'd
You'd been dreaming you'd hold
as rich as a king
rich as a king
as a king
You're as rich as
You're as rich as a
You're as rich as a king
hold her tight
her tight
So hold her
So hold her tight
never let her go
let her go
And never let
And never let her
And never let her go
and night
night
Day and night
her know you love her so
know you love her so
you love her so
Let her know you
Let her know you love
Let her know you love her
Let her know you love her so
the love of your life
love of your life
of your life
With the love of
With the love of your
With the love of your life
a lifetime of love
lifetime of love
Spend a lifetime
Spend a lifetime of
Spend a lifetime of love
her yours forevermore
yours forevermore
forevermore
Make her yours forevermore
hold her tight
her tight
So hold her
So hold her tight
never let her go
let her go
And never let
And never let her
And never let her go
and night
night
Day and night
her know you love her so
know you love her so
you love her so
Let her know you
Let her know you love
Let her know you love her
Let her know you love her so
the love of your life
love of your life
of your life
With the love of
With the love of your
With the love of your life
a lifetime of love
lifetime of love
Spend a lifetime
Spend a lifetime of
Spend a lifetime of love
her yours forevermore
yours forevermore
forevermore
Make her yours forevermore
her yours forevermore
yours forevermore
forevermore
Make her yours forevermore
for one
One for all
one
All for one
One for all
One
All for one
One for
One for all
our voices unite for
voices unite for
Let our voices
Let our voices unite
Let our voices unite for
for one
One for all
one
All for one
One for all
One
All for one
One for
One for all
have something to fight for
something to fight for
We have something
We have something to
We have something to fight
We have something to fight for
or foul may be the weather
foul may be the weather
may be the weather
be the weather
the weather
Fair or foul may be the
Fair or foul may be the weather
matter what the future brings
what the future brings
the future brings
future brings
No matter what the future
No matter what the future brings
know that we can face it
that we can face it
we can face it
We know that we
We know that we can
We know that we can face
We know that we can face it
we stick together
stick together
together
If we stick together
we stand side by side
And those bells are ringing
stand side by side
side by side
And those bells are ringing
by side
side
And those bells are ringing
If we stand side by side
those bells are ringing
And those
If we stand side by side
And those bells
And those bells are
If we stand side by side
And those bells are ringing
there's no one can beat us
no one can beat us
one can beat us
Then there's no one
Then there's no one can
Then there's no one can beat
Then there's no one can beat us
forward with pride
We are young and swinging
with pride
pride
We are young and swinging
Marching forward with pride
are young and swinging
We are
Marching forward with pride
We are young
We are young and
Marching forward with pride
We are young and swinging
no power can defeat us
power can defeat us
can defeat us
There's no power can
There's no power can defeat
There's no power can defeat us
and clear as a trumpet call
clear as a trumpet call
as a trumpet call
a trumpet call
Loud and clear as a
Loud and clear as a trumpet
Loud and clear as a trumpet call
Sing
for one
All for
All for one
unbeatable
We're unbeatable
for one
All for
All for one
Undefeatable
for one
And one for all
one
All for one
And one for all
one for all
All for one
And one
And one for
All for one
And one for all
you're shy at romance
shy at romance
at romance
If you're shy at
If you're shy at romance
you can't say you dance
can't say you dance
say you dance
What you can't say
What you can't say you
What you can't say you dance
me close then advance
close then advance
then advance
Hold me close then
Hold me close then advance
try and say it
and say it
Don't try and
Don't try and say
Don't try and say it
Dance
means percussion
percussion
Mambo means percussion
why there's no time
For discussion
there's no time
no time
For discussion
time
That's why there's no time
For discussion
For
That's why there's no time
For discussion
I get in this condition
I lose my every inhibition
get in this condition
in this condition
I lose my every inhibition
this condition
condition
I lose my every inhibition
When I get in this condition
lose my every inhibition
I lose
When I get in this condition
I lose my
I lose my every
When I get in this condition
I lose my every inhibition
can tell at a glance
tell at a glance
at a glance
a glance
You can tell at a
You can tell at a glance
way I feel
So dance
I feel
feel
So dance
The way I feel
So
So dance
the girl in your arms
girl in your arms
in your arms
When the girl in
When the girl in your
When the girl in your arms
the girl in your heart
girl in your heart
in your heart
your heart
Is the girl in your
Is the girl in your heart
you've got everything
got everything
everything
Then you've got everything
says, "no"
Mommy says,
Mommy says, "no"
says, "no"
Daddy says,
Daddy says, "no"
says, "no"
Brother says,
Brother says, "no"
they all got to go
all got to go
got to go
But they all got to
But they all got to go
we say, "yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
- 'Cause we say, "yeah"
- Yeah,
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
- We say, "yeah"
- Yeah,
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
We say, "yeah"
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
We say, "yeah"
we didn't go ahead
didn't go ahead
go ahead
If we didn't go
If we didn't go ahead
we thought of all they said
thought of all they said
of all they said
all they said
If we thought of all
If we thought of all they
If we thought of all they said
might as well give up, man
as well give up, man
well give up, man
give up, man
We might as well give
We might as well give up,
We might as well give up, man
might as well be dead
as well be dead
well be dead
We might as well
We might as well be
We might as well be dead
we say, "yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
- 'Cause we say, "yeah"
- Yeah,
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
- We say, "yeah"
- Yeah,
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
We say, "yeah"
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
We say, "yeah"
moving up front, baby
up front, baby
We're moving up
We're moving up front,
We're moving up front, baby
singing our song
We're singing
We're singing our
We're singing our song
old ones they taught us
They're all dead and gone
ones they taught us
they taught us
They're all dead and gone
taught us
us
They're all dead and gone
The old ones they taught us
They're
They're all
The old ones they taught us
They're all dead
They're all dead and
The old ones they taught us
They're all dead and gone
we say, "yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
- 'Cause we say, "yeah"
- Yeah,
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
- We say, "yeah"
- Yeah,
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
- We say, "yeah"
- Yeah,
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
We say, "yeah"
aim for the sky
for the sky
We will aim for
We will aim for the
We will aim for the sky
keep on shooting high
on shooting high
shooting high
We will keep on shooting
We will keep on shooting high
about those problems, baby
those problems, baby
problems, baby
Forget about those problems,
Forget about those problems, baby
just sit and sigh
sit and sigh
and sigh
Don't just sit and
Don't just sit and sigh
we say, "yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
- 'Cause we say, "yeah"
- Yeah,
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
- We say, "yeah"
- Yeah,
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
- Yeah, yeah
- We say, "yeah"
- Yeah,
- Yeah, yeah
say, "yeah"
"yeah"
We say, "yeah"
you do it?
- How'd you do what?
do it?
it?
- How'd you do what?
- How'd you do it?
- How'd
- How'd you
- How'd you do it?
- How'd you do
- How'd you do what?
you put on a show?
put on a show?
on a show?
How'd you put on
How'd you put on a
How'd you put on a show?
do you need?
- Yeah, what do you need?
you need?
need?
- Yeah, what do you need?
- What do you need?
what do you need?
- Yeah, what
- What do you need?
- Yeah, what do
- Yeah, what do you
- What do you need?
- Yeah, what do you need?
do you need to make it go?
you need to make it go?
need to make it go?
to make it go?
What do you need to
What do you need to make
What do you need to make it
What do you need to make it go?
you do it?
- How'd you do what?
do it?
it?
- How'd you do what?
- How'd you do it?
- How'd
- How'd you
- How'd you do it?
- How'd you do
- How'd you do what?
you make the laughter ring?
make the laughter ring?
the laughter ring?
laughter ring?
How'd you make the laughter
How'd you make the laughter ring?
you make them?
- How'd you make who?
make tem?
tem?
- How'd you make who?
- How'd you make them?
- How'd
- How'd you
- How'd you make them?
- How'd you make
- How'd you make who?
you make the audience sing?
make the audience sing?
the audience sing?
audience sing?
How'd you make the audience
How'd you make the audience sing?
not quite sure
What the answer is
quite sure
sure
What the answer is
I'm not quite sure
What
What the
I'm not quite sure
What the answer
What the answer is
I reckon
It's something like this
reckon
But I reckon
It's something like this
something like this
But I reckon
It's something
It's something like
But I reckon
It's something like this
a kid who can sing
kid who can sing
who can sing
Take a kid who
Take a kid who can
Take a kid who can sing
song with a zing
with a zing
A song with
A song with a
A song with a zing
makes a whole audience glow
a whole audience glow
whole audience glow
audience glow
That makes a whole audience
That makes a whole audience glow
some dancers in tights
dancers in tights
Add some dancers
Add some dancers in
Add some dancers in tights
costumes, some lights
some lights
Some costumes, some
Some costumes, some lights
what do you know?
do you know?
you know?
And what do you
And what do you know?
got a show
a show
You've got a
You've got a show
moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of those terrible days
you're going berserk
going berserk
And it is one of those terrible days
berserk
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of those terrible days
it is one of those terrible days
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is
And it is one
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of
And it is one of those
One moment, you're going berserk
And it is one of those terrible
And it is one of those terrible days
moment, the magic is working
the magic is working
magic is working
Next moment, the magic
Next moment, the magic is
Next moment, the magic is working
that's show business
To coin a phrase
show business
business
To coin a phrase
And that's show business
To
To coin
And that's show business
To coin a
To coin a phrase
couple of chaps
Come on and perhaps
of chaps
chaps
Come on and perhaps
A couple of chaps
on and perhaps
Come on
A couple of chaps
Come on and
Come on and perhaps
think that you don't want to know
that you don't want to know
you don't want to know
don't want to know
You think that you don't
You think that you don't want
You think that you don't want to
You think that you don't want to know
they start to do
start to do
Then they start
Then they start to
Then they start to do
enchanting soft shoe
An enchanting
An enchanting soft
An enchanting soft shoe
what do you know?
do you know?
you know?
And what do you
And what do you know?
got a show
a show
You've got a
You've got a show
girls and some guys
With stars in their eyes
and some guys
some guys
With stars in their eyes
guys
Some girls and some guys
With stars in their eyes
With
Some girls and some guys
With stars
With stars in
Some girls and some guys
With stars in their
With stars in their eyes
spirit of get up and go
of get up and go
get up and go
up and go
A spirit of get up
A spirit of get up and
A spirit of get up and go
curtain will rise
And to our surprise
will rise
rise
And to our surprise
A curtain will rise
to our surprise
And to
A curtain will rise
And to our
And to our surprise
do you know?
you know?
- What do you
- What do you know?
got
got a
- We got
- We got a
got a great and glorious
a great and glorious
great and glorious
and glorious
We've got a great and
We've got a great and glorious
uproarious
Gay, uproarious
do you know?
you know?
What do you
What do you know?
got a show
a show
We've got a
We've got a show