Shibuyama - In front of Hacchiko Plaza
Daidokoron
Wait right there!
As long as Yatterman is here,
evil will not prosper in this world!
We will summon light into this world of darkness! We are Yatterman...
Number 1!
Number 2!
At your service!
At your service, koron!
Omochama!
You're totally blocking our shot.
Ah! S-s-sorry, koron!
Yatterwan!
Come out of there, Doronbo!
- Okay!
- Here you go!
Dun dugudun dugudun dugudun!
So it was you guys after all.
You won't get away with this!
Boyacky, Tonzra, get them!
Yes, Mistress!
Take that!
And that!
Oh snap!
I missed!
Kendamagic!
Ow ow ow ow!
That's hot!
Huh?
Kendamagic!
Whoa! Whoa!
Shocking!
Oh! Ah! Shock!!
Electric stick.
Mistress Doronjo!
We lose every week!
Boyayan!
Isn't that great, Boyayan?
Perv!
Oh, Boyayan!
Boyayan!
Get them with this Daidokoron!
Yes, Mistress!
Starting with the right foot!
Hot pot! Tea kettle! Knife! Chopsticks!
Teacup! Frying pan! Pan!
Ow ow ow!
Hang in there! Hang in there!
Yatterwan!
Ladle!
Alright!
Boyacky!
You showed them! You sure are a genius!
Not at all, Mistress Doronjo!
Carrot Missile Attack!
Everyone, say it with me:
Ready, here we go!
Fire!
You can do it, Yatterwan!
He's in trouble, koron!
They got me, woof.
- Are you okay?
- Don't worry.
Yatterwan! I've got a Mecha Bone!
A Mecha Bone, koron!
I don't think so!
Nice catch!
Chef Kandagawa Toshiro Attack!
Alright!
Hurray!
Banzai! Banzai! Banzai!
We've... we've won!
Er, Mistress Doronjo, that's...
The self-destruct button.
No way!
Are you alright?
Ah, geez! That Yatterman!
They never give up!
Maybe we should make a simpler, stronger mecha...
We can't let this get us down!
How frustrating!
So you failed again.
I am Dokurobe, the god of thieves!
How long will it take for you to get the Skull Stone?
About that...
It's all Boyacky's fault!
Not me, Boyacky!
What are you saying, Mistress Doronjo?!
It's a queen's nature to push the blame to someone else.
Just take it. Just take it, Boyayan!
I don't want to hear excuses.
You will be punished!
Allow me to explain!
The Skull Stone
is a legendary stone that has appeared in a number of writings
since ancient times.
It was broken into four pieces,
which were scattered throughout the world.
However, if those four stones should come together again,
it is said that a miracle will occur.
A forest in Narway
And recently,
an archaeologist that has been devoted to researching the Skull Stones,
Doctor Kaieda, has discovered two of the pieces.
This makes two.
Who's there?
I'm not a bad guy.
I'm a Japanese archaeologist.
That stone is not meant for human hands.
Who are you?
I am a god.
Where is the first stone?
I'll never tell you!
I'll take them both!
And so, Dokurobe,
who kind of cunningly called himself "the god of thieves",
somehow or other was able to obtain one of the four stones.
And, using Doronjo and her Doronbo gang,
he searches for the remaining Skull Stones.
This is the Takada Toy Store.
And underground lies Yatterman's secret headquarters.
He is Yatterman #1, Takada Gan.
Yatterman #1
He specializes in tinkering with mecha.
She is Yatterman #2, Kaminari Ai.
Yatterman #2
This little guy is Omochama, one of Gan's creations.
He only takes two AA batteries!
Gan is the only son of this toy store.
His father is busy with toy sales overseas, and is away for a long business trip.
Gan took up his father's unfinished project, Yatterwan, and completed it.
Ai is Gan's girlfriend and the only daughter of Kaminari Electronics.
To defeat the Doronbo gang,
these two transform into Yatterman and fight once a week.
And this girl is Kaieda Shoko.
She is the only daughter of the archaeologist, Dr. Kaieda, who was attacked by Dokurobe.
So that's the Skull Stone?
My father told me to keep it.
He said he thought he was close to finding the second one, and that he was going to look for it.
But he hasn't come home.
So Doronjo and the others targeted you because of that stone.
What about your mother?
I don't have one.
My mother died right after I was born.
Since then, it's just been my father and me.
By the way,
what's a Skull Stone?
You don't know?
You fought with them even though you didn't know, koron?
What is it?
How embarrassing.
Hey!
Huh?! Everyone knew about it?!
I want to see him!
My father.
I'm all alone...
I'm so lonely.
Will you help me look for my father?
Let's go, woof!
Hey.
When's the next Pikopiko Runrun meeting?
The Pikopiko Runrun meeting is on Tuesday.
- Tuesday?
- Yeah.
Eh? Hey.
It's not here! It disappeared.
Seriously, Tuesday's gone.
Mine's gone, too.
Lucky...
Breaking news.
Now, all across the country, we are receiving reports that various things are disappearing.
For example, money from banks has vanished, or-
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Merry Doro!
Everybody, do you want to be happy?
Yeah!
Now, in Merry Doro, we have the world's most expensive wedding dress
that would normally go for well above 1,000,000 yen for only
100,000 yen!
Only
ONLY
100,000 yen!
Happiness is
How inexpensive!
Excuse me, is it really only 100,000 yen?
It really is.
Um, we've both been divorced
once.
Are there age restrictions?
No.
Really?
Is it really true?
You're persistent.
So, you,
and you, and you
can become this beautiful for just 100,000 yen!
Everyone, you can have a beautiful dress like this for only 100,000 yen!
You can have your pick!
How beautiful...
Boyayan, this is work, got it? Work!
What do you think?
We're gonna be rolling in cash!
Okay!
- I'll take one!
- Me, too!
Please!
I'll buy! Please!
Thank you, come again!
Alright alright!
Merry Doro, huh?
Could it possibly be possible, koron?
Alright, congratulations! Congratulations!
Whoo!
Hey!
Sutta monda kotta monda
yatta monda
Yatta monda kotta monda
sutta monda
My head is clear
hey hey hey
Our ideas work perfectly
I want them, I want them
I want the Skull Stones
We're dead set on getting them
Doronjo
Tonzra
Boyacky
We don't care if we trick you
We're geniuses
hey hey hey
Don don Doronbo
Sutta monda kotta monda
yatta monda
Do you want to be happy?
Yeah!
Do you want to be beautiful?
So what should you do?
100,000 yen!
Nantettatte kantettatte
antettatte
Antettatte kantettatte
nantettatte
Scamming is my specialty
hey hey hey
I love fraud
Bad things are awesome
We'll make you go numb and then feel again
Doronjo
Tonzra
Boyacky
We don't care if we trick you
We're invincible
hey hey hey
Don don Doronbo
Nantetatte kantetatte
antetatte
It's done.
We used all the money we got to build this new mecha.
We call it Virgin Roader.
A creation inspired by the image of Mistress Doronjo as a bride.
Love comes before marriage, you know.
Love...
Yes. Then I, though unworthy, shall take my partner in glorious love...
Come, Boyacky.
If we can't win with this mecha,
I won't let you get away for free.
But of course, Mistress Doronjo!
It will definitely, well, maybe be okay, I think.
Yes.
I am Dokurobe, the god of thieves!
Heed my words!
Yes, master!
Have you discovered the locations of the Skull Stones?
Mistress Doronjo.
If all the Skull Stones are collected, a miracle occurs.
If we get them, our dreams can come true.
Dreams come true?
Dreams?
All the high school girls in the country.
Dream...
Ma!
Dream?
It's almost time, isn't it?
It'd be great if it's a boy.
Yes.
Skull Stone...
I want it!
Now's not the time for fantasizing!
Yes, master!
The girl you let get away is the daughter of the archaeologist.
She definitely has the first piece.
But for now, for your next mission, you need to hurry to Ogypt.
The third Skull Stone is in Ogypt?
Doronjo.
Yes!
You're beautiful today as well.
I know you can do it.
Yes!
I'm counting on you.
The smoke disappears.
His order remains.
You're really just like a fart.
Well, let's set out for Ogypt!
This is bad, koron!
Virgin Roader
Ogypt?
When Dr. Kaieda last set out, where did he say he was going?
From a forest in Narway to Ogypt.
Wanna go to Ogypt?
Yes!
Huh?! Wait, Gan!
You want to bring her along?
Time to transform!
Gan!
Fine.
Yatta!
Yatterwan, let's go!
Shoko, come on!
Mr. Gan!
Off to Ogypt, koron!
Ooh woof woof woof
Ooh jin jin jin
You say woof (wan)
two three
The sound of a siren (ooh)
rings out loud
Both sides of the Earth (zip)
in one flight
Now he's setting out (oh)
Yatterwan
His heart of justice is hidden behind his mask
He'll beat up the Doronbo gang
Your ETC Card has been inserted.
His engine trembles and rumbles on
His legs jingle
In a pose of victory
Yeah! Acho!
He's surprisingly strong
Shoot!
Yatta! Yatta! Yatta! Yatta!
Yatterman
Give it to 'em (thud)
you've got guts
Attack those (ooh)
bad guys' mechas
To the ends of the Earth (zoom)
in one flight
He's at your service (oh)
Yatterman
With his tiny robots at his side
He'll kick the Doronbo gang
He digs right in
His legs jingle
In a pose of victory
Father!
Yeah! Acho!
He's mysteriously strong
Yatta! Yatta! Yatta! Yatta!
Ogypt
Yatterman
Spooky, koron.
- Shoko?
- What's wrong?
Is she okay, koron?
Something bit me!
What?
A scorpion.
You jerk!
Where did it sting you?
Here.
Out of the way!
Wait a sec, #1!
Get off!
Okay.
I sucked out all the poison, so you should be fine.
Thank you.
What if my father was stung by a scorpion, and the poison...
Dr. Kaieda isn't dead.
You don't know that!
Why are you so sure?
He can't be dead! Dr. Kaieda is alive.
That's what I believe.
Wow, this is amazing, koron!
Could it be...
A Skull Stone?
We actually found it pretty easily, koron.
What is that?
Virgin Roader!
Thanks for finding it for us.
Doronbo!
We'll take that Skull Stone.
Boyacky! Tonzra! Get them!
Yes, Mistress!
Check this out.
Let me guess.
Kendamagic!
No!
What did you do to Boyayan?!
Take my bouquet bomb!
Amen.
Uncle! Uncle uncle uncle!
We've got it!
You thief!
Yatterwan!
Catch, woof!
Leave this to me, Mistress Doronjo!
I've got something special today!
Ooh!
What is that?
Mistress Doronjo.
I present to you the Virgin Road.
Hoping for your happiness, I made this for you, Mistress Doronjo.
You did?
Wh-who is it?
This took three months of my salary.
You perv!
Now's not the time for that!
Virgin Roader, attack!
Yes, Mistress!
I'm coming!
Yatterwan, we're counting on you!
Let's start off with the Boob Machine Guns!
Ready, here we go!
Yes!
Oh crap!
Look out, koron!
Yatterwan!
Next, it's the Boob Missiles!
Do it!
Mr. Yatterwan!
Yatterwan!
Yatterwan! A Mecha Bone!
Allow me to explain!
A Mecha Bone is like a battery
that gives Yatterwan energy to produce mini-mechas!
It worked!
Here comes this week's surprise mini-mecha!
Oh no.
Ant, ant, ant, ant...
Huh? What are those?
Ant!
Ant, ant!
Yes!
Yatterwan?
That's hot, that's hot...
Yes!
Boyacky, we're in trouble!
Run away! Escape!
Escape button!
Ready, here we go!
Aahh! I can't push it!
Oh, oh, yes! Yes!
I can't stand it any longer, woof!
Oh, yes!
I'm coming!
Love!
Calm down, Yatterwan!
What do you two think you're doing?!
Mr. Yatterwan!
I'm coming!
Yatterwan...
It's not safe, let's get outta here!
This way, koron!
Wait right there!
Give me the Skull Stone!
This belongs to her.
We won't give it to you!
Mistress Doronjo!
Boyacky!
Boyayan! Hang in there!
Hol- I don't think it's gonna...
I don't think this will work, wait, I don't...
Mistress Doronjo, are you hurt?
What?
He's naked, koron.
Mistress Doronjo, I can't escape like this!
Leave me and save yourself!
What are you saying?!
Boyayan, we can forget about your shame!
We don't care how much we see of you!
You can live.
You can live, Boyayan!
Oh no, oink!
Boyayan!
Live!
How touching, oink!
Oink!
Perv!
Kendamagic!
This doesn't mean I saved you.
I just don't want
to win this way.
Let's go.
My throat is so dry...
You idiots!
Why didn't you leave the girl
and steal the Skull Stone?! You stupidfaces!
Yes, master!
You're so thirsty that you can't talk?
Drink this.
It's water.
What was that sound?
What's this?
What?
I'm not that naive!
That cap is the switch for your punishment!
It's your punishment!
Um...
What does a kiss feel like?
It's nothing special.
You only get excited the first time.
Is that so?
You'd know if you did it once.
It's nothing for Taka to kiss someone.
Those jerks...
Yatterman!
Especially #1!
Boyayan.
Hang in there.
Boyayan!
Mistress Doronjo!
Don't just barge in here, you per...
I am Dokurobe!
Heed my words!
I've got more orders for you.
Thank you, Master!
It's almost time for our final battle.
I have information that the final Skull Stone
lies deep within the mountains of the Southern Halps.
You must get it!
And also, Doronjo.
Don't mix love and work.
Love?
It's for your own good.
You have to forget about that man.
Thieves aren't allowed to fall in love?
Boyayan!
Are you going against me, Doronjo?
No.
But...
It's my first love.
Then your punishment will be small.
Doronjo. You belong to me.
You belong to me.