Ragnar:
Previously on "Vikings":
This is an ambitious man.
And he resents the fact
that he owes me
loyalty and obedience
as his chieftain.
Man: Attack!
Earl Haraldson: You accept
that you're a criminal?
Worthy only of defeat.
After him!
Worthy only of death.
(Gasps)
(Splash)
Bjorn: Where is father?
Is he dead?
He's dead!
I've come to warn you.
My husband, he hates you.
Get away.
Torstein: Earl Haraldson has
played a trick on Rollo
and imprisoned him,
trying to find where you where.
Then he tortured him.
He tortured my brother?
It's a trap for you, Ragnar.
I want you to ask
for a meeting with the Earl,
challenge him
to a personal combat... With me.
♪
♪ more, give me more ♪
♪ give me more
♪ if I had a heart
I could love you ♪
♪ if I had a voice
I would sing ♪
♪ after the night
when I wake up ♪
♪ I'll see
what tomorrow brings ♪
♪ I... I... I...
♪ If I had a voice
I would sing ♪
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
(low hum of chatter
in the hall)
Svein: What is it?
(Floki giggles)
Housecarl 1: My lord, this man
says he has a message for you
from Ragnar Lothbrok.
Let him go!
What's the message?
Ragnar Lothbrok challenges you
to meet him in single combat.
Ragnar Lothbrok has a very
high opinion of himself.
Well, he is a descendant
of Odin.
(Everyone laughs)
(Laughter stops)
Ragnar said that
if you refuse his challenge,
then shame would follow you
the rest of your life.
There would be greater shame
in accepting a challenge
from a criminal.
That would suggest
that I take him seriously;
That I see him as an equal.
The challenge is declined.
When Ragnar Lothbrok appears
in Kattegat,
he will be put in chains.
The seer: Stones and bones.
He searches for your death.
Does he desire to be Earl?
If he kills you,
would it not be so?
Tell Ragnar Lothbrok
I accept his challenge.
Take him away.
(Water rushes)
(Lagertha and Ragnar
moan in pleasure)
(Fire crackles)
- Ragnar...
- What?
Let's go away.
Let's leave here.
This is not the only place
for us.
Ragnar: He is old.
What are you frightened of?
You can't fight.
You're still too weak.
Perhaps that makes us equal.
Never fight unless you know
the odds are in your favor.
That is our way.
Ragnar: Who sets the odds?
Our fates are already decided.
(Breathing heavily)
Lagertha: You don't believe
that and neither do I.
Ragnar: You are wrong:
I do believe it.
(Howling in the distance)
Siggy: (Quietly) Come to bed.
You need to rest, to sleep.
Earl Haraldson: Yes, I will.
There's always time to sleep.
I was thinking about our boys,
what they would look like now.
Don't...
Don't think about them.
Think about tomorrow.
When I must kill a man
for whom I have
the utmost respect.
Siggy: Respect?
You respect Ragnar Lothbrok?
Why not?
He is what I used to be...
restless, ambitious.
And he was right about
the Western lands.
But I always knew that
in my heart.
Siggy: Then why
didn't you tell him?
Because the moment
that I reached out
to Ragnar Lothbrok,
was the moment
that all my friends,
all my supporters
would have deserted me
and joined him.
It was impossible to do it.
But it's true,
our fates have
brought us together.
And maybe he's opened
the Western lands for me.
That is my hope,
after I kill him.
The seer promised
you would kill him?
Yes.
Good.
(Earl Bjarni shouts out
in pleasure)
Earl Bjarni: I'm sure
that's our first child.
(Panting)
Now get up and fetch me
some pickled herrings.
I'm starving.
I don't like the smell of them
in the bed.
Your clothes are smelly enough
as it is.
Why can't you just wash
like everyone else?
I thought a wife wasn't supposed
to nag her husband
until they'd had time
to grow tired of each other?
If you don't get up
and fetch me some herrings
I will beat you.
Perhaps that will make you
show a little life
when we have sex, in any case!
Thyri: Very well.
I'll go.
Earl Bjarni:
I can't wait till tomorrow.
Personal combat
is always thrilling.
Who is this Ragnar Lothbrok?
I've heard many people
talk about him.
Thyri I don't talk about him.
He's my father's enemy.
(Groans)
(Groans in pain)
(Exhales heavily)
(Winds gust)
(Quietly) Lord,
high one, hear me.
Listen to me.
Give me your favor this day.
Grant me your blessing
as you have done in the past,
and I will make a sacrifice
of my enemy,
if his death pleases you.
Give me a sign...
I cannot feel your presence...
(Sighs)
Husband...?
(Fire crackles)
Our sons hair.
Believe at least in them,
and in yourself.
(Water laps)
(Footsteps scuff)
Ragnar: Don't look so worried.
(Struggling grunts)
(A loud murmur)
Svein:
This is a personal combat.
The combatants can choose
any weapon
and shield they desire.
Each man has two shields.
If both are broken,
there can be no further
replacement.
Crowd:
(Shocked gasps and murmurs)
(Crowd chuckles)
(Raining down blows)
(Swords clank)
(Supportive yelling
and shouting)
(Swords clank,
grunts of effort)
(Supportive yelling
and shouting)
(Fighting grunts)
(Shields shatter)
Father, you can do it!
Woman: You can do it, Earl!
Finish him!
(Supportive yelling
and shouting)
(Weapons clank)
(Cheering)
(Trading blows)
(Grunting with effort)
Agghhh!
(Massive blow) Ungh!
(Supportive yelling
and shouting)
Agh!
(Axe slices, crowd gasps)
(Crowd falls silent)
(Landing thud)
(Groans)
(Tired exhales)
(Wings flutter)
(Groans in pain)
Lord odin is here,
waiting to see which one of us
he will take to his great hall.
So I shall...
I shall dine, after all,
at the high table
with the Aesir.
(Labored breathing)
(Slices a vein)
Siggy: (Shouts) No!
No!
(Labored breathing)
Earl Haraldson: Tonight I shall
be drinking with our boys.
(Exhales his final breaths)
Kill him!
(Axe slices)
(Gurgled breaths)
(Knife slices, pained groans)
Aghhhh!
(Waves lap at the shore)
Hail, Earl Ragnar.
(Shouts) Hail, Earl Ragnar!
Crowd: Hail, Earl Ragnar!
Hail, Earl Ragnar!
Hail, Earl Ragnar.
(Low hum of chatter)
(Everyone quiets down)
(Pained grunt)
Man: Take it!
Crowd: Take it! Take it!
(Encouraging shouting)
Take it!
(Cheering and applause)
(Laughter)
Leif: Lord Ragnar,
I have come to swear to you
my allegiance
and fealty to you
and your family
from this day.
Ragnar:
Leif, you are my friend.
And you, Torstein,
and you, Arne,
you are my friends.
What is your name?
Old man: Tostig, lord Ragnar.
Do you swear allegiance
and fealty
to me and to my family
from this day forth?
That won't be so long then!
(Crowd laughs)
Tostig:
By my sacred rings I swear.
But I also have a favor to ask,
lord.
What is this favor?
That the next time
you go raiding,
you take me with you.
(Crowd laughs)
(Silence)
I do not wish to insult you,
but the truth is you...
tostig: That I am too old?
(Chuckles)
Yes, I am old.
But I have been a warrior
all my life.
Many years I sailed
with lord Haraldson
and fought battles
against the Eastlanders,
and I watched all
the companions of my youth die.
And though I fought with them
in the shield-wall,
never once was I touched
by a blade.
All the friends and companions
of my youth are dead
and feasting and drinking
with the Aesir
in the halls of the gods!
While I...
I am forsaken.
Bereft.
Which is why, I beg you, lord,
gift me the chance to die
with honor in battle,
and join my friends
in Valhalla.
Ragnar: (Grunts in pain)
This summer, we shall have
more ships to go west,
for that is our future.
When we return to England...
Let's take him with us!
All in favor?
All: Aye.
There is no need for you
to swear.
You have already paid
a heavy price
for your loyalty to me.
Nevertheless,
I will swear, brother.
I swear to be true to you,
your wife and your family...
As long as
your good fortune holds.
Crowd: (Laughs)
How will we ever be equal now,
my brother?
(Excited chatter)
(Horn bellows)
(Geese honk)
(Rain patters)
(Horn bellows)
Why have you agreed
to grant Earl Haraldson
such a big funeral.
Was he not your enemy?
He was also a great man
and a warrior.
He earned his renown
in this life,
and now, in death,
he deserves such a funeral.
I want to show you something.
(Low hum of chatter)
(Sheep bleat)
Young woman: (Singing drunkenly)
♪ I dreamt a dream last night
♪ of silk as fine fur
♪ now and Earl is felled
by Spears ♪
♪ it is horrible
♪ now to look around
(she continues to sing)
Who is she?
She's one of the Earl's slaves.
When he died,
all of his slave women
were asked:
"Who wants to die with him?"
This one agreed.
(Giggling drunkenly)
She wants to die?
Ragnar: These other
servants are preparing her.
♪ As the valkyries sing
their song ♪
(Festive cheering, laughter)
(Cheering)
Old woman:
Put the body on the bench.
(Boat creaks)
Siggy:
Let's make our offerings.
♪
(Fighting grunts)
(Spectators cheer)
♪
(Laughter)
You need a drink, priest.
Drink.
Drink!
(Laughter and chatter)
Athelstan:
There's that slave girl...
the one who has chosen to die.
What are they doing?
She is having sex with the men
that live in there.
Each one of them says to her:
"Tell your master I did this
out of love for him."
Because she will soon
be reunited
with her master in death,
and she will be able
to speak to him.
(Laughs)
(Cheering)
(Thunderous drumming)
(Crowd cheers)
Old woman: Silence!
Athelstan:
Bjorn, who is that woman?
We call her the angel of death.
(Necklace clinks)
♪
Young slave woman:
I can see my master!
He is in Valhalla.
He calls me.
Let me join him then.
(Crowd erupts into a cheer)
I cannot stay.
What's the matter with you,
priest?
I don't want to watch.
Bjorn: It's only death!
You will stay,
or my father will hear of it.
(Unsheathes a blade)
(Gurgling sound)
(Crowd shouts and cheers)
Yeah! Yeah!
(Water laps)
(Boat creaks)
(Rhythmic drumming)
(Horn bellows)
Torstein:
Hail, Ragnar Lothbrok!
(Crowd cheers for Ragnar)
Hail, Ragnar!
Tostig: Ragnar!
(Crowd cheers)
Hail, Ragnar!
(Laughing)
Man: Hail, Ragnar Lothbrok!
(Festive chatter and laughter)
Siggy: Move!
I ask permission
to light the pyre.
(Flames whoosh)
(Flames crackle)
(Footsteps scuff)
(Log clunks)
(Flames crackle)
(Floki giggles excitedly)
(Flames roar)
♪
(Boat creaks)
(Flames roar)
I have something important
to tell you, husband.
I am with child again.
(Breath hitches)
I know you're a boy!
The seer told me.
O by all the gods, my son,
you have made me a happy man.
(Emotional exhale)
(Flames roar)
♪
(Jewels clink)
(Scared, hurried breaths)
(Startled gasps)
Siggy:
Have you come to kill us?
Rollo: Why would I do that?
Siggy:
Because Ragnar told you to.
It is often the way
that the new Earl
deals with the family
of the old.
Rollo: Ragnar won't kill you.
How can you be sure?
Rollo: My brother
doesn't hold grudges.
He's strange that way.
(Relieved sigh) Well...
Even if we don't die,
they will still shun us
like a bad smell.
And they'll make it
so we have to leave here,
even though they know
no one else will take us in.
They won't.
Not if I vouch for you.
No one will force you
to go anywhere.
They wouldn't dare.
What do you want in return?
You were once married
to an Earl.
Would you not like to be married
to another one?
Who?
What do you mean who?
Me!
(Bird cries)
(Logs clunk)
(Hum of chatter)
(Geese honk)
(Flames crackle)
(Pigs oink)
The pigs are fattening nicely.
Just like your mother.
(Shivers) It's cold,
even in here.
(Sighs)
I can't wait for the spring,
or the raids.
I want to go to England.
No.
What?
I said no. But why?
Because I said so.
Don't be too impatient
to put yourself in danger.
But you cannot alter my fate!
(Chuckles)
You sound like your Uncle,
when he doesn't know
what to say.
Come on.
(Murmuring quietly)
Athelstan: Ragnar, I have
heard many of your stories,
but tell me...
What is Ragnarok?
(Silence)
I have heard mention of it
several times,
but so far no one has explained
the meaning to me.
Let's show this
ignorant Christian
what Ragnarok is.
Get the leaves.
(Flames crackle)
(Leaves crackle in the flame)
(Ominous howling)
(Wings flutter)
Ancient seer: The twilight of
the gods will happen like this:
There will be three years
of terrible winters...
(Winds howl)
And summers of black sunlight.
(Wings flutter)
People will lose all hope
and surrender to greed,
incest and civil war.
(Animal roars)
Midgardsormen,
the world serpent,
will come lunging
from the ocean,
dragging the tides in
and flooding the world.
(Water rushes)
The wolf, giant Fenrir,
will break
his invisible chains...
The skies will open
and Surt the fire-giant
will come flaming
across the bridge
to destroy the gods.
Odin will ride out
of the gates of Valhalla
to do battle for a last time
against the wolf.
Thor will kill the serpent,
but die from its venom.
(Wolf snarls)
Surt will spread fire
across the earth.
(Flames crackle)
At last,
Fenrir will swallow the sun.
Nooooooooo!
(Birds chirp)
(Water churns)
(Water churns as they row)
(Bird caws)
King Aelle: So where did
these Northmen come ashore?
Messenger: They didn't.
What do you mean, they didn't?
Messenger:
They came in three ships,
and those ships
are now sailing up the tyne.
They have ships
that can cross oceans
but also sail up rivers?
What manner of men are these?
If they are sailing up
the tyne,
then, sire,
we shall soon find out.
Ah yes, my lord Wigea,
of course you know
all about them.
You accused them
of having supernatural powers,
which is why a small force
of them defeated you.
Lord Wigea: I merely said
they fought like demons,
like men possessed,
with no fear of death.
Unlike you, my lord?
I fear death
as much as the next man,
but I have no fear
that afterwards
God will raise me up again.
Oh, well said. (Claps)
Come, all of you!
I have something new
to show you.
(Chains clank, flaps creak)
Let the serpents bite
these devils.
Let them also bite
those too weak
and afraid to fight
to the death
for their king and master.
My lord! No! No!
You look terrified,
my lord Wigea.
Have you lost your faith?
Are you not certain anymore
that God will raise you up
from the grave?
Lord Wigea: Have mercy!
Personally, I hope he does not.
I hope he leaves you there
to rot.
Nooooooo!
Ungh!
(Hissing)
No! Christ!
God!
Nooooo!
(Yells out in pain
as a snake bites him)
Now let us prepare
to defend ourselves
against these heathens
and barbarians.
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com