Translation for KG by rentboy.
[Bells ring.]
[Music.]
I told you
not to drink so much.
[She laughs.]
One dance, mister.
Just one dance!
Jacqueline, stop bothering
the gentleman.
- He's not nice!
- How about a drink?
It's blood!
[Music.]
[Spanish conversations from the hall.]
[Knocking.]
Come in.
Excuse-me.
It's the police.
[Speaks Spanish.]
The officer wants to see
your passport.
- What does he want?
- It's just a formality.
[Speaks Spanish.]
You must go to the station.
I said you'd go today.
Ah, yes. Si...
[Speaks Spanish.]
Thank you.
Crime on Rue Saint-Vincent.
[Speaks Spanish.]
- This guy is repulsive!
- Scram!
- French?
- Yes, but quietly.
Countrymen, finally!
Can I buy you a drink?
We wouldn't say no,
but get rid of those two!
Go on, scram!
You're new. Like anywhere else, women
aren't the only ones on the game here.
- I'm Pierre.
- Siméon.
- And I'm Gorlier.
- Hello.
[Applause.]
- You're here on business?
- No. I just came from Berlin.
- Cigarette?
- Caporal! Great!
- You can find them in Germany?
- I bought them at the border.
You can trust us.
We're men.
I can see that!
Anisette!
- Same here.
- Make it three!
Word of advice: be careful
in Barcelona.
- It's full of snitches of every stripe.
- Really?
And you can't find a decent steak.
Oh, I'm used to it.
Berlin's even worse.
You don't know hunger until
you've lived in Barcelona.
- You can't let yourself slide here.
- Well, we'll see.
Say...
Do you know a place where
I can bed down for a while?
Why not here?
The manager is an ex-con.
His old lady does the cooking.
No danger of food poisoning.
That's very important in Spain.
- I'll go ask him.
- OK.
Go ahead.
- He's a good guy.
- Him? Oh...
Room and board:
220 pesetas a month.
Great.
I'll take care of it right away.
There's no hurry.
You have plenty of time.
Hey, you never know, mate.
This way, the deal is done.
What the hell did I do with my wallet?
... Wow!
You lost it?
Come on, give it back right now.
What do you mean?
What bad manners!
Skip the jive. I get it.
Give it back.
Be square. It's all the dough I have left.
And what about my papers?
- He's got some nerve!
- I've got nerve!? Let's step outside!
[Hubbub.]
[Speaks Spanish.]
Let's clear this up with the police.
Go get a cop.
What? No cops!
Never mind.
Take a seat!
You say you were robbed
and you're afraid of the police!
Okay, we'll meet again!
[Speaks Spanish.]
- He's going to...
- Throw me out if I don't pay for my room.
- You understand Spanish?
- Not, just the situation.
- How much can you pay?
- I haven't eaten in two days.
- He says... - That he's going to seize
my dirty shirts and my toothbrush.
Let him. I hope he makes
good use of them.
Republic of Spain.
"...former Spanish and foreign soldiers to rejoin..."
Foreign Legion.
Not doing well?
- So you're hungry! Come and eat.
- No, what an idea!
Come this way.
[They laugh.]
Go on, eat! Eat!
Don't mind them.
Here, lick it!
Lick, you scum!
Here, you scum!
Lick it!
I'll kill anyone who comes close.
Join the glorious Spanish Foreign Legion.
You will find in the grand setting of Morocco
Honor and Profit -- 5 Pesetas a day.
No papers required. No forms to fill.
- You're French?
- Yes.
[Speaks Spanish.]
Why do you want to enlist?
- I'm famished.
- How's that?
- I'm hungry. I have no job.
- Ah yes.
[Speaks Spanish.]
- You're strong.
- I guess...
- What?
- Do you have your papers?
- No.
- It doesn't matter. Your name?
- Er... Benoît.
- Benoît.
[Speaks Spanish.]
- What?
- It's a popular name with the French.
- Would you mind another name?
- I don't care. Makes no difference.
Then?
Well, er... Write down Gilieth.
Pierre Gilieth.
G, I, L, I, E, T, H.
Sign here.
You're in.
[Speaks German.]
- Merde!
- You're French?
Mulot Marcel. Paris,
Rue 3 Frères. And you?
- Pierre Gilieth.
- Did they take you?
- Yes, I got the stamp from the vet.
- Me too. This is lousy.
- What's forcing you?
- I was starving.
Here, check out my shoes!
And they're called Oxfords!
Just three months ago, I was still a bagpiper
with the 3rd regiment in Algeria.
I've never liked soldiers.
One day, I got fed up
and I took a powder.
I made it to Spain, fat as a bicycle.
I really had to tighten my belt.
So we're going back to the desert.
And we're better paid on this side.
Yes, 5 pesetas.
And a pal.
So what was that German on about?
They probably turned him down.
You should see the girlie who came in after me.
They'll never let him near those 5 pesetas.
Oh, here he is!
[Speaks Spanish.]
- You have a smoke?
- I wish!
- If I may.
- Hey, another one!
- French?
- Yes.
Thank you.
- Here, thanks.
- No, keep it!
- No, what an idea!
- Keep it. We're here for five years.
- No kidding?
- They took you?
- As you can see!
- But your guns are kind of empty!
Don't worry about that.
We should celebrate!
- Maybe, but I'm flat broke.
- I have money.
What!? You have the means to drink and
smoke, and you join up like an idiot?
- I can explain.
- No questions asked.
The rule here is to
keep our memories to ourselves.
Right. We wipe the slate clean
and start over from scratch.
- You were a soldier?
- Yes, deserter.
- You desert...?
- Hey, come on, guys, how about this drink?
Let's go tie one on.
Hey you! Don't leave.
Here are your marching orders.
You take the boat in Algeciras.
Don't look, guys,
but here we go again.
I go through life backwards.
- Like a crawfish...
- Still, the important thing is to eat.
Yes, but after eight days of full meals,
we forget we've ever been hungry.
We'll see.
Back when I was in the colonial army...
Ah, you were in the colonial army?
- If you like.
- A broad?
You're wasting your time.
In the Legion, buddy,
you must always look forward.
A guy in the 4th regiment at Marrakech
gave me that advice.
His name was... Hey, his name was
the same as mine. What a coincidence!
What's this monastery?
That, my friends, is an image
you won't soon be forgetting.
It's the Legion camp
where you'll be living.
[Bugle.]
[Fanfare, singing.]
- It's got character.
- No talking in the ranks. Forward, left.
[Hubbub.]
- Do you have a preference?
- None.
- Then, take the corner.
- OK.
- Smells like spring in a garbage dump, no?
- Yeah, a rotten spring.
Oh, man!
We have a nice setup here.
Hey, fancy sheets!
- We could make you a veil.
- Well dressed, housed and fed...
- We only need a secretary to take a letter.
- It's still a strange way to live.
You, my little bourgeois, you'll be used
to it in one year, and you'll re-up in 5.
Listen to this soldier's advice,
and pass me a smoke.
[Speaks English.]
[Speaks Russian.]
Who the hell's this guy?
Hey, what...?
Do you have a stuffed nose,
or are just afraid of drafts?
The gentleman must think he's at the movies.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7,
8, 9, 10... Out!
Bravo, mate, you're a real man!
Wait.
Let's put him over here.
- We'll take care of him.
- Allow me!
- Goodnight, sweetie.
- [Speaks Spanish.]
[Hubbub.]
[A yell in Spanish.]
[Speaking Spanish.]
[Bugle.]
[Music.]
Come on, play another tune!
[Speaks Russian.]
The gentleman wants his nanny.
This is sure going to be fun.
My mattress is like an ironing board.
I don't like soldiers.
Oh, shut it.
This isn't so bad.
There. This is the Seine.
A real ribbon.
The Seine turns, comes and then
leaves again. But not right away.
She knows that when you're in Paris,
you have to stay as long as possible.
This is Montmartre. Streets that climb,
lovely girls, and accordion music...
And there, a kid by the name of Mulot.
Yours truly.
- A kiss to get by!
- Down with the paws!
- Give me a kiss.
- You disgust me! Hands off.
I know someone you don't put up
as much of a fuss with.
Is your dad coming back from his trip soon?
Will you introduce me then?
He's having his nap.
Just wait 'til he's here.
Ah, here comes your beau!
- Hi, guys!
- Hi.
- A drink?
- I'm broke.
No problem, I'm buying.
- Does your mother print money?
- Perhaps!
Oh, I almost left out Rue 3 Frères!
Hey, don't touch Montmartre,
you ruffian!
Do you realize not one of them
understands what you're saying?
I don't care.
They're impressed and I'm amused.
- You're a big kid!
- Come on, I'm buying a round.
So we're playing nice now!
- Whenever you keep your hands to yourself.
- He was hassling you again?
When you're born a pig,
you stay a pig.
- Let me know if he bothers you again.
- Oh, I'm not scared of him.
- Where's the wine?
- Cooling. The boss will serve you today.
Hurry it up, then!
[Speaks Spanish.]
- Hello, gentlemen.
- Greetings.
- Comes to 5 pesetas. Who's paying?
- "Who's paying?" I am.
Light of my life!
Show me you're not still mad at me!
No!
Leave it!
I'm not trying to rip you off!
- I told you not to touch it!
- What's the matter with him?
He's lost it!
It's love letters, letters from a woman.
I don't want anyone to touch them.
- I don't care about your woman.
- You know that the past is sacred.
Come on...
How would you like folks to rifle through
your papers, to dig into your past?
- I have no past.
- We all have a past.
- You, like everyone else. That's life.
- What?
- You want me to smash your face?
- Oh, come on!
Say, doesn't all his money
amaze you?
- It's his mother's.
- His mother, that's easy to say.
What about the fuss
he just made over his papers?
In the middle, there was an ID card
with a photo in the corner.
Oh, maybe it's just a driver's license.
- In any case, it had a funny color.
- You only need to ask him about it.
Then you just pound him into submission
if he puts up a fight.
Oh no, it's not time yet.
I'd rather use a soft touch
to find out what he's hiding.
I don't want him looking into my business.
But if he insists, I'll set him straight.
Don't worry.
I'll wait for the right opportunity.
Time doesn't exist here.
So...
Still, I'd really like to know
what that card is.
He keeps his papers in his jacket
and his jacket on his bed...
Looking for something, Gilieth?
Oh, it's you! What...
- I got the wrong bed, sorry. I can't see.
- Sure...
Drills, forced marches...
That's all they have us doing.
Makes you want to check out of here.
Oh, you're always bellyaching.
I didn't sign up to play the fool.
[Orders in Spanish.]
[Fanfare.]
[Hubbub.]
I'm not going downstairs.
I'll just wait for chow time.
You're right. I'm bushed too.
Oh, on second thought...
There. A trick I learned from my aunt.
Never fails.
Mysterious Crime on Rue Saint-Vincent
A man was found murdered in his home.
The motives remain unknown...
M. Morin's family has offered a reward
of 50,000 francs for information
leading to the capture of the murderer.
So, I hear you're headed south.
- You read that in the cards?
- The guy in the telegraph office told me.
The order came through this morning.
The 4th bandera is going to relieve the 2nd
- out of a nasty spot in the desert.
- I'm not affected. I'm in the 3rd.
- Lucky you.
- You think so?
I'd like to get out of here. The air
around here isn't good for my lungs.
- So, your feet don't hurt anymore?
- No, I must have bound them too tightly.
Come on, let's go down to the tavern.
The boss just got some first-rate wine!
- Get off my back.
- He also has real Pernod.
- I said, get off my back.
- Hey, what have I done?
Don't be nasty. We're brothers.
We enlisted together.
Don't you remember the Barcelona barracks?
Or the first meal we had together?
We weren't proud then.
You're nagging me!
[Music.]
How do you like it?
- Oh, it's no Beaujolais.
- The third glass is always the best.
Here.
Hey grease ball, shut it down.
You're going to make us bawl.
Oh, don't cry.
You'll rust the player.
They're bugging me with their flamenco,
their fandango and their cheap romance!
Gilieth! They have French records!
You're also being a pain
with your music.
- You must be reminded of bad moments.
- I'm reminded of nothing at all.
- Mind your own beeswax.
- Let's drink to that.
I have something you're going to like.
Rosita, the old bottle.
Tell me what you think.
Painful memories need to be drowned.
Some of them know how to swim!
[Music.]
What's the idea?
- What's the matter with you?
- Stay out of it.
Come on, don't worry.
We know what it's like to have the blues.
You remind me of a soldier
who came here because of...
Because of something stupid.
That was his secret. Get it?
He kept it deep inside,
but it ate away at him.
One morning, it weighed so heavily
on his mind
that he went straight to the police and
spilled his guts like an idiot. Get it?
- It was too much for one man to bear.
- Why are you telling me all this?
It's to remind you that
you must always trust your friends.
If that guy had talked to his friends,
he wouldn't have messed up.
What do I care about your story?
Don't get mad. It's just a story.
It's of no importance.
And I knew a guy who was always bugging
people with question after question.
And one day, he was found
with a knife stuck in his belly.
- You're saying this for my benefit?
- No.
No, it's just a story.
It's of no importance.
Leave it.
He's over there, it's about to start...
He's being a real pain!
Under Paris bridges
When night falls
All types of bums
sneak around
and find a berth...
I don't want to hear this!
It's just as good as anything else.
You can't see clearly...
- I said, don't want to hear this!
- Oh, it's nothing.
Will you stop this?
To go to Suresnes
Or to Charenton
All along the Seine
We walk...
Shut up, or I'll deck you!
What's wrong with him?
He must be soft in the head!
[Hubbub.]
You planned this!
You're rotten!
I'll cut out your heart, you hear me?
[Hubbub.]
Get out of my way!
Clear out!
Where the hell is he?
Go on, scram!
I'll calm him down.
Go get some help at the camp.
- Gilieth, are you crazy?
- I can't stand that pig anymore! I can't!
So you're the famous Gilieth.
You asked to speak to me?
- Yes sir, captain!
- What is it?
I'm not doing well, sir.
Explain yourself.
Sir, I no longer wish
to stay with the 3rd bandera.
There's a guy... er...
Sorry, an individual who...
Er... I don't know...
I think I'm a pretty good legionnaire.
I signed up to get some peace.
And I have the right to that pea...
You have the right to obey and to
maintain the discipline you chose to accept.
- I always do my duty, sir.
- I know. You're a good soldier.
Yesterday, I took care of
the guy who's been riding me.
- I know that, too. Is it serious?
- I'd trade my hide for his.
I don't like that kind of answer.
You're beginning to annoy me
with these stories.
You don't get to choose your place here!
You don't get to discuss your assignment.
Stop bothering me with your
personal interests.
Sir, please transfer me to the 4th bandera
so I can leave with them for the south.
It is the 3rd bandera, yours,
which is leaving.
Ah?
Well... Then I ask that legionnaire Lucas
be assigned to a different company.
Is that all?
You brawled yesterday
like a common porter.
That does not incline me to grant favors
to legionnaires who get drunk,
who slaughter each other like pigs.
Like the pigs you all are
with your big mouths, and those damn pasts
I don't wish to know.
If we had to account for the pasts of
everyone in the Legion,
we'd be better off dissolving it.
Oh... We are not all born equal
before Fortune.
So if I have to die just to die,
I'd rather die
- with honor.
- How long have you known that saying?
Since I know that
I'm leaving for the south.
Legionnaire Lucas will be reassigned.
He will not leave.
May God grant you your wish.
- Sir! Thank you, sir.
- Don't thank me.
Listen, legionnaire!
When you feel your past
clutching you by the throat,
- ask He who can...
- I don't believe in God, sir.
Ah...
Then, here.
Thank you, sir.
Do you know what I'm thinking?
Don't you care what I'm thinking?
I'll tell you anyway.
I'm thinking about crosswalks,
the crosswalks in the streets of Paris.
Oh, I've never used one.
One must have some dignity!
Well, here, now,
they seem swell to me.
It's funny, no?
Are you mad at me because
I'm telling you about crosswalks?
No, buddy, I'm not mad at you.
On the contrary.
No, I feel good.
As good as it gets.
You can breathe easy.
Lucas won't be making you miserable.
Why do you think Lucas
makes me miserable?
Only the blind can't see.
You're right.
Really, if I'm here...
- No questions asked.
- I have a serious reason.
No questions asked.
You're my friend, and that's enough.
Oh, if you knew how it happened.
Don't bother.
You must have had your reasons.
Anyway, things will be nice and quiet
in the desert.
No more Fernando Lucas and
his smart ass mug.
- How long did you enlist for?
- 5 years.
You don't mess around, do you?
If you still have the heart for it,
you can join the military police after.
You look like two fools.
- Yes, my little whore.
- It's true we look like two idiots.
But that's because we're thinking of
pleasant things that are funny only to us.
Yes, only to us.
- Here come the replacements.
- None too soon.
Welcome to the easy life.
No one will come looking for me here.
- So that's the famous road?
- Yes sir, captain.
The work is hard. It's pure granite.
We're making slow progress.
- Plus, we're getting shot at.
- Must be coming from that peak at 1200m.
That's right, sir. We're also getting it
from that crest.
We've done some scouting.
But the arms smugglers run away
whenever we get close.
This suburb seems packed with
comforts and luxuries.
They've stuffed our heads.
Ultimately, we'll wind up building
more roads for tourists.
I'm fed up.
I'm a soldier, not a road contractor.
My wife and daughter are playing tennis
even as we speak.
- That's funny, no?
- I don't know, sir. I'm a bachelor.
I'm not staying here
5 more minutes!
I'm fed up, captain!
I want out of here!
You'll give me 3 days
for presenting yourself
to your captain
without prior authorization.
And 3 more days for having done so
in an unkempt state.
You're a dirty cow!
- Tell me.
- What?
I checked with an old-timer.
Apparently in the village down the hill
- there's an establishment of
renowned delights. - Let's go.
[Arabian music.]
The boss, she's the tall one over there.
They call her "Breadboard."
She was bored in Europe.
Desert fever, in other words.
So she came back.
Not for the business.
She doesn't care about money.
In other words, an intellectual.
After the mule, God created the ass,
and after the ass, the legionnaire.
The birds do as they wish.
They're free.
So you have to please them,
sweet-talk them.
With my mug, I don't get too lucky.
They're all Bedouins,
except for the tall blond in the back.
She's German.
Oh, you only have eyes for the Pavlova.
Well, I have some inside dope.
She's from Rabat.
She had some problems.
Something about poisoned tea.
I'm telling you what I heard.
Oh, Princess...
- I'll make you some tea.
- Tea!
- It's nice here.
- Everything is mine.
I'll show you.
I have treasures.
- Where did you learn such good French?
- I used to dance in Meknes.
A lot of French legionnaires came to watch.
They were nice.
Then suddenly, for no reason,
they'd go crazy.
They'd yell at the top of their lungs:
"Get out of my face!"
- And they'd break everything.
- We call it the blues.
- You too, you get the blues?
- Sometimes, like everyone.
And you'll break everything?
I don't think so.
Come take a look. It's time.
They're my friends.
When I'm sad,
I sit down in front of my clock,
and I wait for them to come out.
They never miss an appointment.
Are you often sad?
Come!
- Do you want to hear the sea?
- The sea?
Listen!
What do you use this compass for?
I use it to find the south. That way,
I can look towards my hometown.
I also have necklaces, bracelets
and a gold coin.
I'll put them on
so that you'll find me beautiful.
But I find you beautiful.
When they found me pretty,
- other men would kiss me right away.
- Would you like me to kiss you?
Listen. I think that when a man and
a woman like each other, the best thing...
I know all of women's secrets.
Yes, but you don't know how to wait.
- Are these tattoos?
- No, it's henna.
- I've never wanted to be marked.
- Oh yeah?
I'll come with a friend. He'll mark down
my name on your shoulder with needles.
- You move quickly.
- My name is Gilieth. Pierre Gilieth.
I am Aischa Slaoui.
My mother came from Rabat.
No! He's having his face tattooed now?
It'll remove any temptation of going home
if I ever get the blues.
I never want to see civilian scum again.
Damn, what a snob!
[Whistle.]
Gilieth is getting married tonight,
and we're invited.
[Orders in Spanish.]
[Gunshots.]
[Music.]
Oh! Here she comes!
Here she comes!
Go ahead. Make the cross.
Go ahead.
And so the blood of one mingles.
with the blood of the other.
You have drunk from
the red spring of life.
May the sole God of my beliefs
protect you.
So that's it...? You're married?
- May I?
- Yes.
[Fanfare.]
Finally, some real music.
Today, I'm buying.
- Let's dance like we do in my country.
- I don't know how.
Doesn't matter. I'll teach you.
Come.
First chance I get,
I'll shoot him dead, captain or not.
With or without mint,
tea is forbidden today.
If I drink this,
I'll see everything upside down.
- How about now?
- Go on, princess.
- Like it?
- Yes.
[Screams.]
What is it? What's the matter?
Oh, that's too much, you bastard!
This neighborhood is prone
to frequent night attacks.
You'll accompany me to the camp.
Here's my gun.
You'll walk behind me.
[A voice sings.]
You'll do 15 days of labor for
bragging about killing your captain
and 15 more days for not having done it
when you had the chance.
- A legionnaire cannot go back on his word.
- Yes, sir.
- Say, where are we going?
- To the mountains, this weekend.
Apparently we're hooking up
with the 4th bandera.
They're camped out there,
and sparks are flying.
Never get taken prisoner. And always keep
a last bullet for yourself.
If those bastards take you alive,
they cut off your head.
Then they give your body to their women
who cut you open to build a fire inside.
That's what they call central heating.
I don't care. A fortune teller told me
I'd die of diabetes.
- What time do we leave.
- 3 a.m.
Something's brewing.
Smells like a fight.
It'll be good exercise.
We're starting to get fat.
They're sending us on recon, and
reinforcements are supposed to turn up...
[Singing.]
- Now's a good time to make a will.
- You've got something to bequeath?
- All I have: my body, to medical science.
- What are they supposed to do with it?
They can study the illness
I suffer from in the throat.
- What illness?
- I suffer from thirst.
- Sir, reinforcements have been spotted.
- Sound assembly.
Very well, sir.
[Bugle.]
Reinforcements are here!
[Speaks Spanish.]
- Say, Mulot.
- What?
You never know...
If I don't come back.
Don't worry.
I'd take care of your wife.
It's too bad we have to leave now.
I've never been happier or
more at peace than in this desert.
[Fanfare.]
I wonder what he's doing here.
I don't get it. The Captain
had bounced him from the company.
He must have managed somehow.
I'm not naturally curious,
but I'd give a year's pay
to know what he's up to,
all the way out here.
Here, look.
Looks like he's already well-informed.
I bet you he's headed to "Breadboard's."
And in a big hurry, too.
I might as well find out.
Things are turning sour, buddy,
they're turning sour.
- What's this?
- Tea.
No, not tea.
Give me an anisette.
Something strong.
Hey...
[Speaking Arabic.]
- Is she your girlfriend?
- It's Aischa Slaoui.
- Does she dance?
- For those she likes.
[Speaking Arabic.]
Aischa, will you dance for me?
I have money, you know.
- So?
- Aischa is tired.
Oh!, Oh, Gilieth!
I'm happy to see you, pal!
You too, Mulot.
This is great!
Leave the bottle!
Tonight, we're having a party
and getting smashed.
- I was so bored without you.
- Oh yeah?
Without you around,
life was just impossible.
And you, Mulot,
are you still as fond of soldiers?
- You, get off my back.
- Be nice. I've taken an interest in her.
You know, Aischa,
Fernando Lucas is not Bedouin fluff.
Go on, dance.
Dance, girl, dance!
Don't you follow orders anymore?
Dance, since you're being asked!
Dear lamb, all the blood of a soldier
isn't worth a single one of your tears.
And you paid such a high price
for your wedding gown...
Peace be with you.
[Music.]
[Speaks Arabic.]
I'll give you some of the powder
that was prepared for me
by the holy man of Sadi Aissa.
Pour it in your friend's tea.
And his heart will come back to you.
Aischa...
How strange you people are!
- I look in your eyes and I don't
understand. - I had to do what I did.
Listen to me carefully.
Would you like to get back to the south
where you were born,
- and be with your parents, your friends?
- I have no friends where you aren't.
We'd leave together,
both of us, you and I.
I'd leave this uniform and dress like
those of your tribe.  Would you like that?
Yes!
I have 3,000 pesetas. My savings.
Everything I've earned in 3 years.
It's all yours.
- We can afford to take a great big car.
- Yes.
- Can I bring along all my treasures?
My clocks, my fabrics,
my belts.
Yes, but before then, you must...
- I'll do anything you want.
- Very well...
That man downstairs
is my greatest enemy.
I knew it! I guessed it
the moment he saw you.
Then, listen...
Tomorrow, I leave for the mountains.
I'll be away for a few days.
During this time, Lucas,
that's his name, Lucas,
he must come back here.
And come back often.
Above all, don't tell him
that you're my wife.
On the contrary, make him believe that
you hate me, you think I'm a brute.
Make him talk.
And try to find out where he comes from,
and what he really thinks of me.
And if he stays mum?
You'll be nice to him.
All he asks of you...
you will do.
Sometimes you have to give a lot
before a man loosens his tongue.
But he must talk. You hear me?
He must!
[Bugle.]
- What time is it?
- My watch is 42 francs late.
It's in hock. Wait.
It must be 5 o'clock.
5 o'clock.
That's when Fernando Lucas...
Do you know Rue Saint-Vincent in Paris?
You don't know Rue Saint-Vincent?
At number 25, there's a little villa.
That's where I killed a man.
There's a reward of 50,000 bills
for whoever finds the killer.
I'm sure that Lucas...
As far as I can look back,
I've always been alone.
So, when he came along...
Him or another,
what difference could it make?
But since, there are days when the shadow
of Gilieth blocks out the sun.
You're right.
Gilieth is extremely dangerous.
But I know just the words
to make him crawl into the ground.
Do you know Europe?
I would like to know it.
If I go back there,
would you come join me?
I'm not rich, but
you won't be unhappy.
My trade can become a profitable one.
But you're a soldier.
Can you become a sergeant right away?
I can do better than that.
I'm not a soldier like Gilieth.
I may want to leave now, but when he
returns, I won't want to.
My will runs away in front of him
like water through a sieve.
If you help me, I will rid you of him.
- Forever?
- Forever.
Speak. I will obey.
Listen...
When he returns, ask him:
"What were you doing in Paris,
a year ago,
"at dawn, Rue Saint-Vincent?"
- That's funny!
- What were you doing...
What were you doing in Paris,
a year ago,
- at dawn...
- Rue... Rue Saint-Vincent.
Rue Saint-Vincent.
As you say those words, be sure to
look into his face carefully
and what he tells you,
you'll need to repeat word for word
to someone...
And that will be the end.
Are you a police chief?
So what?
I work faithfully for society.
I'll never dare to ask this of Gilieth.
You won't need to fear him
anymore.
You'll be free.
I'll marry you
and I'll take you to my country.
The men are coming back tomorrow.
Will you help me?
Force is on our side.
And tomorrow,
Gilieth will sleep in jail.
For now at least.
God will take care of the rest.
They've waited enough. They won't send
another dime. We must find a solution.
- And quickly. Lest you lose your position.
- My position!
They should come be in my position.
They'll see how easy it is.
Anyway, I'm close to my goal.
Take a look.
He's going to "Breadboard's."
In a few minutes, I'll be set.
I'm going to know.
Ah finally, I'm going to know.
"Ask him:
'What were you doing, a year ago,
'in Paris, at dawn, Rue...
'Rue...'"
- Rue Saint-Vincent.
- That's it!
- Do you want to know?
- I don't care.
- You don't care that I killed a man?
- Don't you want to know why?
- You must have had your reasons.
Peace be with you and with us.
This won't be easy. It'll take a while.
Don't stray too far away.
Come, Mulot.
Here comes rat face!
So, did everything go okay?
May I?
- Give me a drink.
- Don't bother sitting down.
We were waiting for you.
Now that you're here,
we're going to step outside.
I need to ask you
a few explanations.
You can speak here.
No! If you're a man,
you'll go outside with me.
Okay... okay...
Just be careful with your movements.
We're being watched.
Say goodbye to Slaoui.
Come on, Aischa.
Say goodbye to the gentleman.
I can't.
You can't?
Then spit in his face.
- Very nice, Aischa.
- Go on, walk in front.
And not one word
or I'll shoot you down.
Ass.
- Where are we going?
- Never mind. We'll be out of sight.
As long as you're alive,
always keep this coin
in memory of Aischa.
So you want to
cash in on the 50 grands?
50,000 bills,
that's a nice loot.
Assuming I don't make you bleed
like a pig.
I killed that guy
on Rue Saint-Vincent.
I, Pierre Gilieth.
The son of a bitch didn't deserve to live.
I executed him, you hear?
One less piece of garbage, trust me.
And I'd do it all over again.
So what?
Get up.
You disgust me.
The ground is wet.
You might catch cold.
I've often thought about you.
I knew that one day
you'd show yourself to be a snitch.
Well? What are you going to do?
You'll sleep in jail tonight, Gilieth.
That's interesting.
Don't you see what our lives
are like here?
Don't you get that men who made
this choice deserve to be left in peace.
But that's not enough?
They still need cops on their tails!
To watch their binges, spy on their sleep,
stalk their loneliness!
- You'll sleep in jail tonight.
- Is that what you thought?
Oh!
Here's your knife.
You might need it.
Listen carefully.
My life is over now.
I had been planning
to escape to the south with Slaoui.
But that plan's worthless now.
I'd be caught before I got there.
And there's something else now.
I won't end up like a louse.
You hear, copper?
With just one move,
I can wipe you out like an eraser.
And then, I'm free.
But I'm going to surprise you.
I'm not a murderer.
I don't care about your hide.
I'm letting you go.
See that? If you talk,
there's one for you
and another for me. Now you can
go rat me out. Good day.
[Bugle.]
What's happening?
They're sounding assembly.
Legionnaires,
you are men without country.
You enlisted to serve Spain.
Now she needs you.
She is asking you,
without holding back
to die for a cause she supports,
in accordance with the contract
you chose to sign.
Even at the moment
of your death, she owes you
no other explanation.
An entire region is rebelling.
We have a post in the mountains,
about 100 kms from here
that can keep the enemy in check
for several days.
Until we can organize our defenses,
I need 24 men to occupy this post.
I have absolute right over you.
And I can arbitrarily pick those men.
But I want volunteers.
I want volunteers for death.
None of your comrades
have come back alive from this fort.
I need 24 men to defend it.
Those who are ready to die,
step forward.
I myself will take command
of this detachment.
There's no reward, this time.
- Pick 24 men.
- Yes, sir.
Gentlemen, I thank you.
To the right, to the left,
the first 12 men, step forward.
[Singing in Spanish.]
Beef stew was on Wednesdays.
She really had a way to make it!
Some well-marbled beef and a calf's foot,
with some baby carrots.
- And bits of bacon for flavor.
- Enough. You're making my belly hurt.
To think we joined up
because we were starving.
This is taking us back.
How about a game?
Just one!
A game of cards? A quick one.
Pay attention.
The captain is calling me.
We should try to go outside
to bury our dead comrades.
The air in here is unbearable.
But that's impossible, sir. We're
under direct fire from the bastards.
- But we could take off the roofing.
- If you wish.
Take command of the post.
I don't have too much longer left.
Yes, sir.
You, get rid of the ceiling.
Oh no, the sun...
Oh!
Oh the sun, dear God!
Muller, where are you going?
- I forbid you from going out.
- Captain...
- I'm going to get you some water.
- I forbid you...
The water hole is under surveillance.
You know we can't get there.
Muller!
[Shots.]
[Gunshots.]
The dirty cows!
You know this is poisoned!
Look at the guys!
He's crazy!
You're nuts!
By God, no one is drinking
from this again!
[Hubbub.]
Stop, stop!
To your posts, immediately!
Mulot! Mulot, to your post!
To your post, I say!
Mulot!
Where the hell is that rescue column?
We're dying of hunger and thirst here!
They were probably stopped. Maybe that
cannon we heard all night is responsible.
Isn't that what our planes are for?
[Sound of a plane engine.]
It's one of ours, guys!
It's Lieutenant Garcia's squadron.
[Gunshots.]
He must have run into the bastards!
I'll show this pig!
[Gunshots.]
- He's coming back!
- Take cover!
Lie down!
Play dead!
Hurrah!
[Shot.]
This time, we're screwed.
You're telling me!
If I have to die,
I don't want to die of thirst.
- I'm going to get some water.
- Stay here!
Don't worry. I've figured out how to get
there, and I'll be careful.
- Anyway, at the point where we are...
- Did you go nuts too?
If I'm not back in three or four weeks,
and one day you go by Place Blanche,
stop by the newsstand at the corner.
Tell the guys that Mulot died
for a glass of water.
I'd love to see
the look on their faces!
[Shot.]
[Shots.]
[Mulot singing.]
Captain!
So, you're with the police.
Yes, sir.
My enlistment is void.
I only signed up to...
I don't want to know anything.
If I had known your identity sooner,
I would have drummed you out.
People like you
have no business being with us.
Our men deserve to be forgotten.
I volunteered to follow you here.
If you get out alive,
you will leave this uniform,
you will return to Europe...
Yes, sir.
And you will forget.
- Did you understand me?
- Yes, sir.
By your command, sir.
[Shot.]
Ow! Bastards!
I don't care.
I'm not thirsty anymore...
- Mulot is dead. I'm going to get him.
- They'll kill you too.
Does that inconvenience you, copper?
You had other plans for me.
But he's my friend! My friend!
It's over, Gilieth.
You know it.
Ah... And if we get out of this?
You won't have to worry about me.
Listen. The two of us came here together.
We don't care what
the world thinks of us.
But since we're going to die,
we mustn't die like pigs.
Come on.
[Bugle.]
- We're going to make it.
- Oh, Gilieth!
[Gunshots.]
- Life is beautiful!
- Oh, my God!
What? Gilieth! Gilieth!
Gilieth!
The replacements are here, mate!
They're here!
Captain!
Present arms!
The 1st company takes
roll call of the 4th bandera!
[Bugle.]
- Captain Weller!
- Killed in action.
- Legionnaire Attila.
- Legionnaire Capot.
- Killed in action.
- Legionnaire Denero.
- Legionnaire Buriez.
- Killed in action.
- Legionnaire Datega.
- Legionnaire Lucas.
- Here!
- Legionnaire Perez.
- Killed in action.
- Legionnaire Benoît.
- Legionnaire Galbez.
- Killed in action.
- Legionnaire Muller.
- Legionnaire Payon.
- Killed in action.
- Legionnaire Rigorio.
- Legionnaire Mulot.
- Killed in action.
- Legionnaire Radalou.
- Legionnaire Davon.
- Killed in action.
- Legionnaire Javen.
- Legionnaire Alba.
- Killed in action.
- Legionnaire Velasquez.
- Legionnaire Cardona.
- Killed in action.
- Legionnaire Malera.
Killed in action.
Legionnaire Pierre Gillieth.
Promoted to Corporal
on the battlefield.
Killed in action.
Present arms!
[Speaks Spanish.]
He told me: "If you see Aischa, tell her
that Pierre Gilieth sends his excuses.
"He will not be able
to go live with her in the south,
"but he'll die, thinking of her,
"as he had promised."