Navigator to pilot.
5 minutes to target area.
Achtung!
[Speaking German]
[Firing machine gun]
Bombs away, sir.
Here's another load,
you...
bombs all away, sir.
Good work, men.
Let's get out of here.
Hey, Matrac...
we are approaching
the town of Romilly.
Thank you.
Mama.
Yes, darling?
Is it dad?
[Whispering] I'm not sure.
You be quiet, darling.
Mother will be
right back.
All right.
Pilot to bombardier.
Open bomb bay doors.
Oh, jean, darling...
until we meet again.
You were to have gone with the
wing commander, Mr. Manning,
But I happen to be rejoining my outfit
not far from your own destination,
So they asked me to bring
you down from London.
And what is my destin...
Your what, sir?
Oh, nothing. I was about to
ask what is my destination.
A military secret,
no doubt.
Sorry, sir.
I'm lost,
and I admit it.
Haven't the slightest
idea where we are.
Not a signpost,
not a marked road.
Somewhere near the channel,
unless I miss my guess.
Even for
a war correspondent,
This is pretty darn
mysterious.
Interesting, though.
Here we are, sir.
Really?
Yes, sir.
We're at an airdrome?
Yes, sir. The base of the
famous squad Victoire.
I can't believe it.
Where are the barracks,
The wind sleeves,
the tarmac runs?
How do they operate here?
Surprising, isn't it? The
French make out quite nicely.
They're an intensely
practical people, sir.
Will you get out, sir? Right.
This is headquarters.
I'll stow your bag, sir.
Thank you. You mind
if I take a look?
Not at all, sir.
Well. I must say,
I'm surprised.
This is something new in my
experience of military airdromes.
To think that all these
incredible bombings
Come from a quiet
place like this.
I suppose those cows
are squadron mascots.
Yes, sir. They've brought
us any amount of luck.
They're English, of course,
merely on loan to the Frenchmen,
As they couldn't very well bring
their own cows with them.
Jerseys, sir. The milk is
excellent, if you care for milk.
Seems a strange environment for one of
the deadliest squadrons in the service.
The quiet, you mean?
Yeah. Well, the
French don't mind it.
As a matter of fact,
they rather enjoy it.
It has a way of
livening up a bit
From time to time. And
now, if I may, sir,
I'll take you
to the liaison officer
Between the free French squadron
and our own... Captain Fresene.
[Knock on door]
Come in.
Glad to see you,
Hastings.
I've brought Mr. Manning. Mr.
Manning, captain Fresene.
You're very welcome,
Mr. Manning.
Thank you.
Well, I... I'll leave you in
each other's good hands.
But you must stay to dinner.
There's a place laid for you.
Sorry, sir. Have to push on.
Orders.
Well, good-Bye, sir. I'll have
your bag put in your bunk.
Thank you.
Good night.
Thank you,
Hastings.
Au revoir, captain.
Good luck to you. Would you
like to take your coat off?
I would. Thanks.
Aperitifs will be in.
Or would you
prefer a cocktail?
Oh, no. That's
all right. Thanks.
Sit down.
Thank you.
Captain Fresene, the
purpose of my visit here...
Oh, I know the purpose
of your visit.
Word came this afternoon
from the air ministry.
You've come to see some French traitors,
as monsieur Laval would call us.
No, captain. I've come to
see some free Frenchmen,
To get to know them and to write
about them for my news syndicate.
I think we can do with all the
understanding we can scrape together
In these touchy times.
Well, you can see
a few of us here.
There's certainly
more of them.
Thank you.
Do you think
that marshal Petain
Considers you as traitors
as well as Pierre Laval?
Evidently.
And yet I try
to be charitable
In my judgments,
Mr. Manning.
I try to remember that marshal
Petain's an old man now
And in the hands
of barbarians.
Votre Sante.
You've seen him
these late years?
No, but I did once... Years ago
during the battle of Verdun.
He visited our squadron, which was
then at the foot of the Argonne.
You were flying
in the last war?
Yes. I was a pilot in the
escadrille Lafayette.
Ah, the escadrille
Lafayette!
You must have done your
training with us, Mr. Manning!
Why, we're
old comrades.
Here. Come and
have some dinner.
I, too, was
a pilote de chasse
In squad 26
of the second group.
Many times did I see the Indian head
insignia of your squadron on patrol.
Now we meet
for the first time.
Had I known you were an old
pilote of our service,
We would've messed
with the squadron.
Oh, that's all right. Perhaps
I can see them later.
Why, of course.
They're in that room.
Have you noticed?
Not a sound from them.
Remember the old days?
The laughter, the gay
talk in every mess,
Phonograph going full tilt?
Now, poor devils...
well, we're all right, we free Frenchmen,
but we find it hard to be merry.
I understand
they're bombers.
American flying
fortresses.
Though we did begin here 3 years
ago with a few of our own.
They crossed the channel as a unit
the day the armistice was signed.
And you came
with them?
My dear Mr. Manning,
you flatter me.
I'm getting along, and
I'm blind in one eye.
No, no, I'm nothing
but a liaison officer,
And I reached England
by another route.
P.A.'. Groupes a, d, et g,
Rassemblement
au poste du commandement.
Groupes a, d, et g,
Rassemblement
au poste du commandement.
Jecoute.
They're going
out now,
Just to remind the
borsch of our existence.
Soon as we've finished, I'll take you
down to the hangars, if you like.
Thanks. I'd like to
very much.
Mind the step.
Just over the rise
and you can see them.
Great heavens.
What is this?
Planes being pulled
out of barns?
A haystack
for a control tower?
Is this the same place
I saw when I came in?
Do you doubt it?
The hedges are gone,
the trees are gone,
And the fields
have become runways.
I don't doubt that. That's simple.
It's just magic.
But there's one thing I can't understand.
What's that?
Where are the cows?
They've taken them
in the hangars.
They lead the cows in and
lead the planes out. Come on.
They're going as the spearhead
of the attack tonight.
They're going to light up
a target for the others.
Do they know it,
that they'll take
The murderous part
of the pounding?
They'll give some
in their turn.
When I think of what they have to meet
in the air and from the ground...
we can be glad we were
flying 20-Odd years ago.
Yeah.
Will you excuse me
a moment, please?
Of course.
Again?
Yes. Tonight's
a special occasion,
Sort of
an anniversary.
I understand.
You have
my permission.
Good luck.
Thank you, sir.
P.A.: All aircraft,
proceed to takeoff positions.
All aircraft, proceed
to takeoff positions.
Over.
"V" for victor. "V."
You may take off.
"N" for Norman.
Take off. Good hunting.
There. Now we can breathe
easy for a few hours,
Have a smoke.
As for them...
what's the destination tonight,
or is that a military secret?
Now they're in the air, it's not.
Berlin again.
Good. How many?
Over 2,000 bombers over
the target tonight.
2,000.
Great heavens.
Matrac
will like that.
I've been thinking
about those men,
Those grim, determined faces...
especially that gunner,
The man you spoke to
just before the takeoff.
I can't get him
out of my mind.
I feel I've seen him
somewhere before.
Matrac.
He impressed you.
I've never seen a stronger
face or a stranger one.
Not a fellow to take liberties
with, I should say.
No. I could tell you a story about
him I've never told anyone.
Would you care
to hear it?
By all means,
captain.
For the moment,
I'll have to ask you
To keep it off the record,
as you journalists say.
It's for your private ear. Later,
I think, it might be told.
This is the story of a little
group of whom Matrac was one.
For many years, they suffered
every pain, humiliation,
And indignity that men can
have heaped upon him.
I chanced to meet these...
Well, we'll let that
come in its place.
To begin, I'll have to take
you far away from here.
The outbreak of the war brought
orders for my return to France
From service
in new Caledonia.
I was forced to take passage
on the Ville de Nancy,
Bound for Marseille with
a cargo of nickel ore.
The Ville de Nancy was one
of those venerable tramps
Which wallow across the
backwaters of the world
Year after year.
She wore the customary coat
of rust-Streaked black paint.
We had a good Breton
skipper... Captain Marlowe...
Who knew his way
around the 7 seas
As a blind man knows
his own room.
Also 2 decent mates
who idolized their captain.
The companionship
of such men
Did much to keep the tedium
of the long, slow voyage
From being too oppressive.
And sometimes, there were songs
of home from the forecastle.
Our crew was made up of
hard-Bitten, salty old-Timers,
Who may have been
no better than they should be,
But were French
to a man.
For stokers
and coal passers,
We had the scum
of the earth...
Mongrel dregs from every
port in the tropics,
Dominated by a chief engineer
cut to the same pattern.
As there were
but 3 cabin passengers,
We all messed
at the captain's table.
The seat of honor
was filled... very amply...
by a major Duval
of the infantrie coloniale.
He was a dominating,
narrow-Minded martinet,
Who had proved his courage
in the last war
And had learned
nothing since.
With him was his aide,
lieutenant Lenois.
He hung on Duval's
every word,
A typical yes-Man.
These...
The first and second mates
And the chief engineer...
Made up our official family.
Oh, yes.
There was one other...
A treacherous youth,
Jordan by name,
Who proved to be
the wireless officer.
Latest bulletin, sir.
"A day of comparative quiet was
enjoyed on the Maginot line.
"From the German fortification
across the river,
"The Nazi radio broadcast an
appeal to the French soldiers
"To lay down their arms
and refuse to spill their blood
"In a useless fight
for the decadent democracies.
"Some martial music was also
broadcast by the Nazis,
"And the loyal
French soldiers
Are understood
to have booed. "
What kind of a war
is this?
Soldiers say "boo"?
Soldiers of France?
I'm a soldier. I fight.
Do I say "boo"?
I can... Listening to music.
Is this war?
I can... Or is it a band concert?
Kindly allow the
commandant to speak.
I beg
your pardon.
I can tell you
what kind of a war.
The Germans are afraid. They're
afraid of our Maginot line.
Brilliant, mon commandant. The
whole truth in a nutshell.
That's right. They know that no power
on earth can break through it.
What are we going to do,
sit there indefinitely?
Yes. We'll sit there
indefinitely,
And even longer, if
that is necessary.
That is what soldiers are
for... To hold the line.
I say the Maginot
line is invincible.
I say the Ziegfried
And what is that but stalemate?
Where does it get us?
Fresene, I think
I'm going to like you.
Victory comes with endurance.
It came the last time,
And it'll come again to the army
that outlasts its opponent,
To the army that holds its
lines 5 minutes longer.
And that army will
be the French army
Because its officers
will make it hold,
Because they'll hold
their men in place
By means of
cast-Iron discipline.
And what if the Maginot
line is outflanked?
Forgive me, sir, but I've always
understood that in a democracy,
Even a soldier has
the right to think.
Discipline is more essential than
thought to a combat officer.
An army's not
a debating society.
Thinking is done
for them by experts.
I trust the captain does
not believe himself wiser
Than marshal Petain and
the general staff.
The British have
a general staff,
And it seems
to feel as I do.
Our allies have no such blind
faith in the Maginot line.
That is because
they did not build it.
They're jealous
of French genius.
A nation
of shopkeepers.
They wanted
to sell us the cement.
Very well said,
mon commandant.
Do not mention the British.
The word offends me.
The British
will fight.
Oh, yes, to the last
drop of French blood.
Only last week, the commandant
said exactly the same thing.
Only last month the same
words were invented
In the office of Herr dr.
Goebbels in Berlin.
Are you accusing me
of disloyalty?
Or is it me
you accuse, sir?
Please. Let's not
accuse anyone...
neither
our traveling companions
Nor our allies.
Very well. I accept
your apology.
If you ask for my opinion,
just mark my words.
Time always
proves I'm right.
Fresene:
this was the atmosphere
In which I was destined to make a
voyage halfway around the globe.
By the time
we'd reached panama,
The world we'd known
was falling apart.
The Maginot line
was outflanked.
The invincible French army
was on the run.
Events were happening
with alarming swiftness.
"Maginot line
flanked. "
It's the fault of our allies!
British civilians.
What did I tell you?
They let our line
get flanked.
France can curse
the day
She let herself get mixed
up with foreign alliances.
Sir?
No!
Fresene: passing through
the panama canal,
The Ville de Nancy
set her helm for Marseille.
2 days out of colon, the
wireless buzzed continuously.
The air was full of the news of
torpedoings and hostile raiders.
Ahoy! The bridge!
Submarine!
Where away?
20 degrees
starboard, sir!
Sound the alarm.
[Bell rings]
What do you see?
Some sort of suspicious craft.
Can't be sure.
Man the guns.
Aye, aye, sir.
Hold the fire.
Aye, sir.
They'll have a torpedo
in our belly any minute!
Hold
your fire!
Hold your fire!
Well?
It's no sub.
Well, it's a craft of some
sort, isn't it? A boat?
Or a canoe.
See there!
That's a man.
He's alive.
Probably survivors
from some torpedoed ship.
Hard starboard.
Man:
hard starboard.
Steady.
Stop.
Lower a boat.
Lower away!
Faster! Faster!
Lower away.
Ho.
Easy with them, men!
Pretty far gone.
God bless you.
Merci.
I needed that.
We've been without food
for 20 days.
Without water for 5.
Then I won't plague you
with questions right now.
Put these men
in the aft house.
Set up
the extra cots.
Aye, sir.
Hurry.
Right away.
Open up
that door.
Come on.
Easy,
now.
Tell them to
bring them some broth.
Then let them sleep. And
you might ask the men
If they can spare them
some clothes.
Aye, sir.
Come on.
[Bell clangs twice]
Captain Marlowe, what is your
opinion of these fellows?
Are they French?
One of them is at least, but what would
they be doing in an Indian canoe?
They are not seamen.
That's plain.
If we were off
the African coast,
I'd wager 10 to 1 that
they were deserters
From one of our
disciplinary battalions.
Don't you say so,
major?
No, I do not. Since we are
not off the African coast,
You're reasoning lacks
something of being brilliant.
Learn to examine the facts,
man. Use your eyes.
Captain Fresene, perhaps
you can do better.
If you want the facts, you'd better
let the men explain for themselves.
I will and hear
a pack of lies.
Condemn them without a hearing.
Isn't that unfair?
No, it is not unfair because
I know who they are.
You mean,
you've seen them before?
No, I never saw them
before this morning,
But that is immaterial since I have
certain modest deductive powers.
Lenois was
on the right track,
Though he lacked the
logic to carry through.
These fellows have the
convict look about them.
Some of them may have served in
the disciplinary battalions,
But not recently.
Gentlemen, beyond
a shadow of a doubt,
They are fugitives
from devil's island.
From cayenne?
Impossible.
We are at least
1,500 miles from cayenne.
You mean to tell me they
have made such a voyage
In that small open canoe?
You don't know these fellows,
Marlowe... The type, I mean.
I was stationed in cayenne
a dozen years ago.
I learned the smell
of the convict.
A more depraved and
desperate set of scoundrels
Cannot be found.
No matter what your opinion,
I suggest we hear what they
have to say for themselves.
As you wish.
I shall be amused at their
lies and by exposing them.
We'll see, gentlemen.
Thank you.
Good evening.
Good evening, sir.
Come to attention,
you men.
You, too.
Haven't you been taught to stand
in the presence of officials?
No.
Never mind. This is a free ship
and not an armed compound.
I think we can all be seated.
Thank you, sir.
Well, you men seem to be
a long way from home.
Oui, mon capitaine.
You're French,
the lot of you?
Yes, sir.
What's your name?
Renault.
Perhaps these men
will now tell us
Who they are and
where they come from.
Willingly, sir.
They are gold miners
from Venezuela.
3 of us that were
born in France
Are naturalized
Venezuelans.
The other two were born in
Venezuela of French parentage.
I see. Where?
Well, we were working
a placer claim,
300 miles up a branch
of the Orinoco.
Doubtless you've never
been there, sir.
It's deep
in the jungle.
You reach it
only by canoe.
We heard of the war
only 2 months ago.
Must be a wilderness that place.
Oh, yes, sir.
It's terrible.
There's no, uh, no
radio, no settlement,
No civilization
within 100 miles.
How did the news
reach you?
Just by chance, captain.
You see, there are Indian rubber
gatherers in that region.
Well, 3 of them just
coming in from the coast
Stopped at our camp.
Remember?
Uh-Huh.
Well, so, uh, we bought a
few supplies from them,
Among other things an ax wrapped
in a Caracas newspaper.
Oh, many months old.
What paper was that?
The Caracas diario.
I even remember the
date, November 3rd.
The first news
of the war we heard
Told us of a raid from the
Maginot line in Alsace.
And you were interested.
Naturally, sir. We are Frenchmen
just like yourselves.
We wanted to go home
and fight.
Likely. You,
what's your name?
Matrac.
Obviously, you are the leader.
Suppose you tell us.
I'll speak
for my friend.
Speak when you're spoken to.
Huh? Sit down. Sit down.
Well, go on.
We have no leader, we're all equal.
We're a group of free men.
You. You wish
to speak to us now.
Thank you, sir.
You were incredulous over our
attempt to return to France,
And I don't wonder.
Because it was an adventure
That only the deepest feelings
of patriotism could inspire.
All we had, sir,
was our little canoe.
Together with 200 ounces
of gold dust.
Our plan was
to sail westward
To where we could
catch a boat for panama
And from there
to France,
But, uh, we were upset
by a huge swell.
And the iron box that contained the
gold and our passports were lost.
We righted the boat
and went on nevertheless.
And from then on,
we were lost.
Helpless.
Mon commandant,
my word of honor,
All this happened 3 weeks
before you sighted us.
You're one of the
naturalized Venezuelans?
Yes, sir.
Where was
your home there?
Silla Bolivar.
You, at the back there.
Como se llama usted?
Jorge Gerou,
a sus ordenes.
So, you didn't catch him.
His accent is perfect.
And you have no papers
of any sort.
No proof of identity.
No, sir. As Marias
so truthfully told,
They're all at the
bottom of the Orinoco.
I see. All at the bottom
of the Orinoco river.
Yes.
Very good.
Very convenient.
Or is it?
We shall see.
Do you have any further
questions, captain Marlowe?
No, commandant. You've asked quite
enough questions for all of us.
Yes, I think
I've been thorough.
Have everything
you need here?
Thank you, captain.
Yes. Captain. You've been
more than good to us.
Fine.
Well, commandant, I'm afraid
they spoiled your evening.
Their stories seem
perfectly plausible
And straightforward
to me.
Plausible, sir? It was a structure
of transparent falsehoods.
I always trust my instincts,
sir, never what men tell me.
Especially convicts.
All convicts are liars.
The commandant
has said it.
I don't believe a word
of their story.
[Chuckles]
[Whistles]
Captain Marlowe, I've come to a
decision regarding those rogues.
You have?
Yes. In the first place,
you allow too much freedom.
What do you propose
I should do?
Turn them over
to the police, of course,
The moment we arrive
in Marseille.
If they're honest men, as you so naively
suppose, they have nothing to fear.
Anything else?
In the meantime, they are to
be locked up in the brig.
Captain Marlowe
as the ranking representative
Of the army of France,
I demand it.
I'm glad you remember
to call me captain.
No one will be locked up on
my ship while I command.
The man's becoming
insufferable.
Fortunately, his word
will not be the final one
When we get to Marseille.
You're absolutely right,
mon commandant.
The man is insufferable.
What's our speed?
101/2 knots,
180 revolutions, sir.
Full speed and
195 revolutions.
Aye, aye, sir.
I want to reach the
danger zone by nightfall.
Full speed,
195 revolutions.
Good evening.
Very fine day.
Any day that takes us closer
to France is a fine day.
I wonder... on your
account, I mean.
I was coming here
to tell you...
to warn you men
of something.
Commandant Duval
is of the opinion
That you and your friends
have escaped from cayenne.
Some of the others,
too.
I wouldn't be fair
if I didn't tell you
That I've come to the
same conclusion myself.
Will you wait here
a moment, please?
Will you come in,
please?
Sit down.
Thank you.
Captain, Renault's
told us what you said,
And we've been talking
here together.
There's nothing to do.
It's true.
We're convicts
escaped from cayenne.
Uh, we're Frenchmen. Convicts
or not, we can kill Germans.
What is more important
than that?
Shut up. What do
you know about it?
We're as good Frenchmen as a lot who
have never been sent to cayenne?
We are not soft,
us convicts.
We can kill Germans.
Keep out of this, petit.
Why have you told us this,
captain?
To put you
on your guard.
You're for us, then.
Yes.
France needs men.
You see, I told you
he would be for us.
Even if we are
convicts?
What does that matter?
I guess it's time
you heard our story.
Tell him, Renault.
Yes, but what
shall I begin with?
With whom
shall I begin?
Now, petit,
he is from Provence.
What caused him
to become a convict?
It was the love of a
farmer for his land.
You are right.
I farmed the land
my father farmed
And his father
before him.
My wife and I planted
as the seasons went by.
And then the government came
and they built a dam.
They flooded all my land.
I guess I went
kind of crazy.
He ran to the control station and
attempted to smash the machinery.
When the employees
tried to seize him,
He... He maimed several
and killed one.
The government
let me off easy.
Instead of being guillotined, I was
transported for life to Guyana.
Do you know
French Guyana?
It's the most corrupt and
neglected of all our colonies.
There in the steamy
equatorial climate,
There are 5 or 6,000 men
just like us,
Struggling against
the heavy undergrowth
In the very depths
of the jungle.
Slaves, half-Naked
in the forest.
Tortured by heat
and humidity,
Mosquitoes, fever,
rotten food.
Men die,
or else go insane.
Here you might have found petit
laboring to build a road.
I will tell you
about this road.
The convicts call it
"road zero"
Because it will
never exist.
Already it has been
under construction
For more than
half a century.
And for that, there is
exactly 16 miles to show.
And for those 16 miles, there's
one dead convict for every yard.
Not far from where
petit worked,
You might have
run across Gerou.
Working in
a mahogany camp.
Formerly a mechanic and a
professional racer of motor cars,
He had killed his sweetheart
during a lovers' quarrel.
In certain circles, it was
considered crude of him
To accomplish
this end with an ax.
[Gunshot]
Well, of course, since
then Gerou has reformed.
He's learned discipline.
Haven't you?
Cayenne is a very
good school for that.
And now, as a
pleasant diversion,
May I please
introduce myself.
As you may have already
discovered, mon capitaine,
I'm a very clever
man and sensitive.
Sensitive down
to my fingertips.
In fact, these fingers made me
the best safecracker in Paris
And a virtuoso
among the pickpockets.
Oh, they had such
a delicate touch,
And from the purses of the
rich they brought forth
Brilliant symphonies
as from a piano.
Your story is a delightful
diversion, my friend.
Mon capitaine?
But one doesn't tell a glib
story with a dry tongue.
You'll find a bottle
of cognac in my cabin.
Thank you. Uh, what
else might I find?
I'll take a chance.
Adieu.
Now, tell me
about yourself.
I'm a deserter
of the army of France.
In the last war, at the
age of 16, I enlisted.
3 months later,
I ran away.
I discovered a terrible
thing about myself.
I was a coward.
Later, I went to morocco to
enlist in the foreign legion
In an effort to redeem
myself, but I got arrested.
You see, even a deserter and convict
can love his country, captain.
Can you imagine then
my feelings
When during the long years
of my imprisonment,
I had to watch every morning
the tricolor being raised.
[Bugle call]
Soon I discovered
that there was another
Who every morning
looked at the flag,
The sight of which
seemed to him like...
Like a benediction,
like a sacrament.
I came to feel a strange
kinship with this man.
Because every morning, we did the
same thing at the same time.
The convicts,
we called him Grand-Pere.
He was a libere',
a free man.
That is, he had served
his sentence,
But was not permitted
to leave the colony.
Since cayenne offers
no employment for free men,
The lot of these liberes
was hopeless.
But Grand-Pere was more
resourceful than most.
He became a catcher
of butterflies,
For which the Guyanese
are famous.
The goods he made from these,
he sold to the tourists,
And the butterflies
themselves to collectors.
Thus, franc by franc,
and sous by sous,
Grand-Pere was able to put
together a little sum
For grand-Pere to plan
and to hope.
The same plan and hope
of all of us...
escape.
Hold it, you.
This is a closed road.
We're not guarding
butterflies.
I heard there was a
special big kind up here.
I forgot it was
a toll road.
Hey, these are
cheap cigarettes.
They won't be when you
sell them to the convicts.
Another!
Hi, Grand-Pere.
Bon jour.
How is it with you
and your butterflies?
and your mosquitoes?
I wish they were
pigs of Germans.
What did you say?
Just what I said.
The old man asked you a
civil question, petit.
I said I wish
I was in France
Killing pigs of Germans
instead of mosquitoes.
You mean that you'd fight for
our country if you were free?
Sooner than most,
I swear it.
Not sooner than me.
There is only one thing
I hate more than a guard,
and that's a Nazi.
How about you?
What are you,
a recruiting officer?
Or is this
a cross-Examination?
I'm just asking him.
Well?
I'm a patriot, to
answer your question.
And my friend over there,
Marias, he's a patriot, too.
You see over there
by the guard.
He is very clever. Everything
there is to know about bribery,
Marias knows.
He would be a very useful man
if one were planning an escape.
Maybe.
There is no escape.
Don't talk about it.
It's silly
if you even listen.
The old man just played games
with our mind, that's all.
But I have heard he has money.
Lots of it.
Huh?
Well, that's different.
That's something else again,
eh, Marias?
That would be
different.
You there.
This fellow got lost
in the swamp.
I told him he could spend
the night with you.
Oh, welcome
to this hotel.
We're crowded
already.
Thank you. Thank
you, my friends.
What are you doing here?
I paid the sergeant
for your company,
And I brought you
a present.
What is all this talk
about being lost?
There had to be
an excuse.
You said you would
fight for France,
So she must mean
something to you
In spite of your
being here.
I thought it would be nice to drink
together and talk about home.
Oh, that's a crazy idea.
I think about my
home all the time.
My farm
and my old woman.
Yes, a farm is good.
There is nothing better
than the good French soil.
Oh, I'd take Paris
any day.
Montmartre
to Moulin Rouge,
And the women.
The women.
Paris isn't France.
I like
the open country.
Long, wide roads
and green trees.
The most beautiful place
in the world.
For me, France will always
be the great tradition.
Versailles,
Joan of Arc,
Statues and
monuments,
Napoleon sleeping in
greatness in the invalides,
Place Vendome.
A tradition that was too
big for a boy of 16
And was ashamed to
find himself a coward.
If it were to cost
my life,
It would be a small price
to pay to redeem myself.
I would fight and die
gladly to make France free.
Who wouldn't?
I'm past 65,
But if I can make sure that
there are 4 Frenchmen at least
Who feel as I do
about our country,
Who, if they had the chance,
would fight for France,
If I can convince myself
to believe you, I might...
You might what?
I might, even though
I'm an old man,
Still find a way
to serve my country.
But tell me again,
if you were in France...
We would fight.
But what kind of talk
is this?
We're not in France.
We're in this stinking hole.
What do we do,
grow wings to fly with,
Or do we walk across
the Atlantic?
A canoe might be bought.
A canoe might float down
the river to the sea.
A ship might be boarded...
Listen, old man,
if you're joking with us...
I'm not joking.
I want to be sure
that you're the men.
How many have you
talked to before?
Can I take a chance
on you?
Are you lying to me?
Have you the courage to
beat the river and the sea?
Well, if we haven't,
I know one who has.
And if he would be
with us... You know him.
His name is Matrac.
Can he get us
through the swamp?
That is
the main thing.
I know the swamp
like my own hand,
But the river
and the sea?
Matrac knows the ocean.
He escaped once
in a canoe to Venezuela,
But they sent him back.
But is this man
a patriot?
Yes, he is a patriot.
A greater patriot than any
of us can ever hope to be.
I swear it. He fought the Nazis
long before there was a war.
It was in 1938, during
the Munich crisis.
Daladier has just returned
by plane from Munich
Where he, a Frenchman,
betrayed France to the enemy.
That's fantastic enough
in all conscience,
But an even more
fantastic thing
Has just happened right
here at the airport.
You getting that?
Go ahead.
Instead of being torn to
pieces by an outraged mob,
The mob welcomed him
home a hero.
It's unbelievable.
From where I'm phoning,
I can see the litter
of flowers on the runway
Where the crowd
pelted him.
Not with stones, mind
you, but with flowers.
It's incredible,
unbelievable.
Raoul.
Can you print that,
please?
Jean, please get out!
Jean! Jean!
Jean, it's no use!
Everything I worked for,
smashed to bits.
Did you see them,
the police?
The dirty fascist flunkies.
Oh, jean, it may be
hard right now,
But you must remember that
there are still Frenchmen
Who believe in the
things we believe in.
They stood there,
just stood there, watching.
Just to make sure
a good job was done.
Darling, you've been
driving yourself too hard.
You need some rest.
I know... Romilly.
You said you wanted to
go back there someday.
Romilly?
Yes, remember?
Remember where it
was we first met?
Mm-Hmm. Right over there,
beyond that bend.
Here's the very spot.
You were wearing one of those
big, floppy yellow hats
And a basket on your arm.
Is that all? Must
have been a warm day.
How long has
it been, jean?
Well, when I think
of what's happened,
It seems like a century.
Well, don't think
about it.
You know, you're a lot prettier
now than you were then.
Really?
Mm-Hmm.
Wonder why we never thought
about getting married?
Oh, I've thought of it,
jean, very often.
But I had a rival.
Huh?
France.
Oh. Well,
that's ancient history.
Think it's too late?
[Speaking French]
How is Philippe
these days?
I'm sorry, monsieur.
If you don't ask,
I won't complain about it.
His 2 sons are
both soldiers.
Monsieur thinks there
will be another war'?
Will be? We've already
lost the first 3 battles:
The Rhineland, Vienna,
and Munich.
But in
a military way.
Jean, no politics.
Madame is right...
No politics.
Tonight, a full night.
[Speaking French]
N' someday, I'll
meet you again n'
N' tell me where,
tell me when n'
N' someday, I'll
meet you again n'
H' and I'm yours until then n'
H' each night,
I wish on a star n'
N' that you'll stay
as you are n'
N' you have my heart h'
H' but my heart
wonders when h'
N' we'll meet again n'
N' mmm-Mmm,
ah-Ah-Ahh... n'
I guess I can still
bend my knees.
They won't crack.
Waltz,
Rosalie?
Me oui.
N' you have my heart... n'
Happy?
To us.
Together...
always.
[Playing someday I'll
meet you again on piano]
It's funny how much
more you can say
With a few bars
of music
Than a basketful
of words.
Bonjour,
mademoiselle.
[Speaking French]
Jean, let's go.
Why? What's the matter? Nothing.
You look as if
you've seen a ghost.
Oh, I'm just a little
tired from shopping.
All right.
You're a funny girl.
Just about get unpacked
and settled down,
You wanna pack up
and run away again.
I'm going to get my wedding
trip in while I can.
Jean, remember
the boat trip
We said we'd
take someday?
You wanted to do a series of
stories on south America.
Yes... Guatemala, Peru.
Seems like
a long time ago.
You know, we
could still do it.
We could get visas in
Marseille for Portugal
And sail from...
What's the matter?
Nothing.
[Tires screech]
Crazy kids.
Oh, I can't go on.
Oh, you can look now.
Come on.
They missed us
by that much.
I can't go on...
oh, come on.
I tell ya,
it's all over.
Nobody got hurt.
It's not that, jean.
What are you
talking about?
Darling, you've
got to get away.
They're looking
for you.
Who's looking for me?
What are you
talking about?
The police.
You're wanted,
jean, for murder.
Yes.
There.
I'm not gonna run away.
There still must be some
justice left in France.
But, jean,
don't you see
The same people who can
pay for riots and killing
Can hire courts,
judges, and juries?
They can't get away with it,
the dirty, murdering...
oh, please, darling,
if you love me...
there's still room
for the truth.
But you can't print the
truth on a smashed press.
No, but I can
still talk.
I'm going back and stand trial.
I've got to.
But you won't prove
anything.
You'll get
yourself killed.
I want you to fight,
jean, not be a martyr.
It's not just us...
Our lives...
It's the life
of our country.
If we get away... Go to
America, somewhere...
We can do
something about it.
We can shout the truth
And tell people
what's going on.
Jean, please.
All right...
we'll go.
Jean...
jean... are you awake?
Jean!
Here I am,
out here.
Oh, darling...
I was so frightened.
I couldn't
sleep.
I tried not
to wake you.
Man: n... tell me
where, tell me when n
N' someday,
I'll meet you again n'
N' and I'm yours
until then n'
N' each night,
I'll wish on a star n'
N' that you'll stay
as you are... n'
Jean Matrac?
Yes.
You are under
arrest.
For the crime of
inciting a riot
And for complicity
in the events
Which led to the death
of one Raoul Doulet,
And for other traitorous acts
against the republic of France,
I sentence you
to 15 years
In the penal colony
of Guyana.
Jean!
I'll be waiting.
Can you doubt that
this man is a patriot?
No. He is
a great patriot.
He's the man
to lead us...
but where is he?
Where can we
find him?
He's in solitary.
He will be there
for another 2 months.
What was his
offense?
Well, there
was a letter
From someone very
dear to him at home.
One of the guards
made a dirty joke
And dropped the letter
in the mud...
so Matrac knifed him.
2 months.
Men have gone mad in
the chateau in 2 days.
Not Matrac.
Marias could get word
to him of our plans.
Sure. And he would be
worth waiting for,
Even if it
were 2 years.
Renault:
here on st. Joseph's isle,
Is a building like
nothing else in the world.
One can go mad
in these pits...
Nothing to see
except blank walls.
Nothing to think about
except escape.
No sound except the beat
of one's own pulse.
Slowly, one's mind... Like one's
body and soul... Gives way.
Then when this happens,
One is put on the mad side
of the barracks.
Until this happens, one may remain
in the cells of the other half,
Where men are not mad,
but only going mad.
Here, for long months,
had been Matrac,
The man I had sworn
was a patriot.
Because of his intense
and fiery nature,
Imprisonment was
especially bitter to Matrac.
But somehow,
slowly and bitterly,
The days of his solitary
confinement went by.
Jean:
French justice...
beautiful,
decadent France...
Country that gave birth to a bunch
of rotten fascist panderers.
I hate France.
He's talking to himself
all the time now.
He'll soon be crazy
like the rest of them.
Not me, my friend.
You will pay special attention
to monsieur Matrac.
He's a famous
person,
Friend of
politicians.
He has influence,
as you see.
And you're as rotten as
the French that pays you.
If any letters come
for monsieur Matrac,
You will see they are
delivered at once.
Monsieur Matrac does not
like to be kept waiting.
Now you'll get it.
[Shouting in French]
Incorrigible...
[tapping]
[Humming]
[Tap tap]
Matrac.
Marias.
Hey! What are
you doing there?
Nothing.
[Humming]
Renault: this then was the man
we had selected to lead us.
By the time he had returned
from the rock,
Everything was in readiness.
Clever Marias had even gotten himself
assigned keeper of our barracks.
Grand-Pere was waiting
for us with the canoe
In the swamps
of the Maroni.
This was the night.
Everything was in readiness.
With any luck at all...
not before 10:00.
I'm going, too.
Where?
With you.
There's no room.
Unless I go, I squeal.
All right, bijou,
you go.
[Guard shouting in French]
[Bell ringing]
[Shouting in French]
Renault:
we waited in semi-Darkness.
9:00".
9:30...
5 minutes to 10:00...
one minute to 10:00...
aaaah!
[Speaking French]
Bijou!
Where is bijou?
I don't see him.
He changed his mind.
Hi, Grand-Pere.
Grand-Pere.
You made it.
No, we didn't. We are still
back in the barracks.
Save your jokes.
So, you're
grand-Pere.
And you are Matrac.
I'm glad you're going to lead us
back to fight for our country.
Well, we better
shove off.
Hey, be careful
with that paddle.
Each time you splash,
we ship water.
I can't help it.
The boat is overloaded.
We have to bail now,
what's going to happen
When we hit the rough
water of the ocean?
Stop yapping.
We'll have to take that chance.
It's getting
light.
We'll get off
the river
And hide out on that sand spit,
Put out to sea
tonight.
4... 5...
we are one too many.
Yes. If bijou had
come on board,
We'd all be at the bottom
of the river by now.
I know what the rest
of you are thinking...
I am the heaviest.
That's right. Well,
it's hard luck, petit,
But you're elected.
Isn't he, Matrac?
What? Leave petit, when we are
going home to kill Germans?
What do you say
to that, grand-Pere?
Whoever stays,
it can't be him.
But he weighs more
than any of us.
So he does.
Speak up, grand-Pere.
It's your canoe.
That's right. If it
wasn't for grand-Pere,
None of us
would be going.
And who did he
speak to first?
Not to you. You
weren't even there.
What's that got
to do with it?
I'm smaller
than any of you.
Even Gerou weighs a good
10 pounds more than I do.
You weigh enough to lighten
the canoe all that's needed.
Yeah? And who got
the word to Matrac?
Shut up,
the bunch of you.
You...
well, grand-Pere?
Lads, petit
is going...
and the rest
of you with him.
It's me that stays.
[All protest]
Let him finish.
What's the idea?
Well, you see, lads,
it's this way.
For 35 years, I've thought that the
one hope of my life was to escape.
Yeah, that's
what I've thought.
And when this came,
it looked like my last chance.
I'd never have another.
But when it gets
right down to it,
I suddenly find that
I am afraid of the sea.
Yeah, I'm scared.
That's the plain truth.
I thought I'd have enough
courage to make this voyage,
But... I see now,
I haven't.
You're nuns,
grand-Pere.
You, a coward?
I would swap my guts
for yours any day.
All right, maybe I
could stand the voyage,
If it came
right down to it,
But the fact is...
I've changed my mind.
I don't want to go.
This place is kind
of a home to me now.
I'd miss it.
You lie,
grand-Pere.
[All protest]
Listen to me.
You, too, Matrac.
It's my canoe.
Who goes in my canoe
is up to me to say.
And I say it's you that
goes and me that stays.
I'm past 65.
I'm too old to fight.
That was the idea of
getting away, wasn't it?
Or was it?
I've got your promise
on that.
I think I'd like to have
it again, kind of formal.
Not just... nods,
But words like you would
speak in church maybe.
You want us to
say our beads?
Shut up, Marias.
What words?
I don't exactly know,
when it comes down to it.
I'll have to make them up
as I go along.
First, get up, all of you.
Raise your right hand,
that's to begin with.
This is between
you and me.
Now, first you say, "I,"
and then your name.
All:
I... [repeat names]...
promise that I will do
everything in my power...
to reach France,
our country...
our mother country
we love
In fair weather
or foul.
Our mother country
we love
In fair weather
or foul.
I promise to fight
for her...
to the last drop
of my blood.
To the last drop
I guess that's all...
except to get in the boat
And not waste any more
of this good wind.
Good luck.
So you see, we have gone
through quite something
To get this far,
captain.
Nobody is going to make
us turn back now...
if only for
the little old man
Who didn't get
to come with us.
Yes. Grand-Peres the
real hero of our story.
I agree
with you.
That was
a good oath
You swore with
the old man.
I wouldn't want to be
the one to break it.
It will not be broken.
We trust each other.
Well, we've
talked all night.
You men should
get some sleep.
Wait. Are you going to help us?
Yes. I'll speak
to captain Marlowe.
He agrees with me that no
soldier's unwelcome to France.
[Morse code beeping]
All hands on deck!
[Bell ringing]
Men...
I have just received
a wireless message
Which is of concern
to all of us.
"June 23rd. France,
"Under the leadership
of marshal Petain
"Has signed an armistice
with Germany.
"According to reports, an emergency
government has been set up in Vichy
"That's negotiating
with the Germans.
"Lt is agreed the Nazis
will occupy the capital
And that Hitler will make a
triumphant entry into Paris. "
I will not try to express the
common feelings of all of us
On this... blackest day in the
history of our motherland.
As further details
are received,
They will be posted
on the bulletin board.
You will now carry on
with your duties.
I'll take the wheel.
Yes, sir.
Well?
I'm worried,
captain Fresene.
I want your advice.
About what?
If I follow my orders
and go to Marseille,
You see what would happen.
My ship and her cargo would fall into
hands that are friendly to Berlin.
You can imagine how delighted
the Germans would be
With a gift of 6,000 tons
of nickel ore.
Yeah.
Well, they're not
going to get it
Or the Ville de Nancy,
either.
When the watch changes,
I'm altering our course
for England.
Fine.
What about Duval?
He's to know nothing
about it.
The new course
will be kept a secret.
My mates will know,
naturally.
They'll be as pleased
as yourself.
I can count on every one
of the seamen,
But the engine room,
they're not to be trusted,
Least of all the chief.
You know how he
hates the English.
What's your opinion
of the convicts?
If we have trouble,
will they be with us?
To a man, I think.
To a man, except Matrac,
And where he leads,
they follow.
Did you see him
when we got the news?
I'm not too sure of him.
I'd stake my life
on him.
I don't know why, but
I feel I know my men.
At heart, he's a Frenchman...
more than any of them,
More than any of us
perhaps.
I'll have to take
your word for it.
I think you can.
Captain Fresene.
Can I ask you
something, sir?
What is it?
Can you persuade
captain Marlowe
To reach Marseille
at night?
Marseille?
Why do you ask?
So I can swim ashore.
I don't trust
this major Duval.
Yes? Why not?
He'll radio the police.
I've been fighting his kind
all my life.
I know what to expect.
There are many ways to serve
your country, Matrac.
What if you didn't
reach Marseille?
I've got to reach Marseille.
I don't care
about my country.
The France you and I loved
is dead, captain.
She's been dying
for a long time.
I saw her die in the
Rhineland and in Munich.
Now that her death
is complete,
I can stop lying
and tell the truth.
I'm trying to
get back to a woman.
I never intended to fight.
I know about Paula and all
that you've suffered,
But the France that you and
I love, Matrac, is at war.
If you won't fight, why
should we help you escape?
I'll leave that
to your conscience.
Your wife is waiting for
the man who went away,
The man who
loved his country...
the patriot.
Would you betray
such a woman?
I leave that
to your conscience.
Fresene: imperceptibly,
we swung northward,
Marking a course that would take
the Ville de Nancy to England.
But could
the secret be kept?
On the morning
of June the 26th,
I was awakened
by the profound silence
Which had settled
over the ship.
I attributed this to the
old cause: engine trouble,
And thought no more about it except to
wonder how long we'd be adrift this time.
Fortunately,
the sea was calm.
I rang for the mess boy.
As yet, I had no suspicion
that anything was wrong.
Then I noticed my pistol was
missing from its holster.
Restez I.
What the devil
do you mean?
Restez I.
Open this door.
[Rattling]
What's the meaning
of this?
Who locked my door?
I did, sir.
For what reason?
Commandant Duval's
orders.
You're to come with me.
Where's
captain Marlowe?
You'll see him, sir.
Go on.
Get them down below.
On deck.
Come on!
What the devil
is the meaning of this?
Captain Marlowe, I understand
our course has been changed.
Have you received
new orders?
That's my business, sir.
I've studied your chart.
We're no longer heading
for Marseille.
Correct, sir.
For what reason?
On our present course,
We run the greatest risk of being
picked up by a British destroyer.
You consider that
such a calamity?
I will consider it a great
misfortune, certainly.
France has no ships
to spare for England.
You would prefer the Germans
to have it perhaps?
I prefer to be a realist.
We've argued these matters
before, captain Marlowe.
Now we will settle them with the only
argument that means anything: force!
Take him down
with the rest.
Men, a new order
has been born in Europe.
France has been
given the privilege
Of becoming
a part of it.
The watchword of this
new order is discipline.
From now on, you will navigate
this ship under my command
Until we
reach Marseille.
This is piracy,
Duval.
Your action is treason.
I'm willing to let both
questions be decided
By the authorities
at home,
But I'm
a reasonable man.
If I give you
your liberty,
Will you give me
your word of honor
To take this ship
back to Marseille?
Certainly not!
You may control the ship,
But you'll never
bring her into port.
No decent seaman
would serve you.
The men will
do well to consider.
Those who cooperate will be
given rewards and security
In the new France.
I speak especially
to you convicts.
To every man who helps bring
this ship to Marseille,
I promise a full pardon in
favor of the Vichy government.
Vive la France!
Hold it!
Take your stations
and prepare to get underway.
Confine the engine room
crew below decks
And see
that they do their work.
Aye, aye, sir.
And no more nonsense.
Stay below.
Aye, there, man.
Get going.
Get below.
Good work, men.
It was a pleasure,
mon commandant.
Are there any killed?
No, sir.
Good.
Obviously, some skulls
are too thick to damage.
Have Duval and his yes-Man locked in
a cabin for the rest of the voyage.
Aye, aye, sir.
You two, hop onto b deck.
Thank you, Matrac.
Clear the deck!
Hook up
the boom.
Lend a hand, men.
Come on. Grab
ahold of that.
You'll regret this,
Marlowe.
The day will come when you
will bitterly regret it.
[Morse code beeps]
Quiet, men.
Quiet!
[Beeping]
Dirty rat
is giving our position.
Commandant,
let me have him.
[Fist hits flesh]
Carry out
the orders.
Turn to.
They're due northeast.
Send them.
[Speaking German]
[Airplane approaches]
Jean.
Motors.
A plane.
Can't see it.
Man the guns.
Man the guns!
You men take cover!
Hurry up, you men.
Take cover!
[Speaking German]
[Speaking French]
Over there! Over there!
[Machine gun fire]
[Men cheering]
Look...
they're still alive.
Matrac!
Wait!
Stop it!
Stop it, Matrac!
What are you doing?
You cannot assassinate
helpless men!
Look around you, captain, and
see who are the assassins.
Boy: viv...
Vive la France!
[Coughing]
We finished them.
We've shown
the dirty Germans.
It was great...
what you did.
We all did it.
I just happened
to get to the gun.
We'll destroy them all,
won't we?
Just like
we got this plane...
we'll drive them out
of France.
Of course we will.
[Coughing]
Well, we got the ore
to England,
And very glad they were
to get it.
Got the men there, too.
They weren't interned?
Oh, no. We all stuck
by the story
They were survivors
from a torpedoed ship.
I remember
this Matrac now.
His paper was small, but
every journalist in Europe
Admired the fight he put up against
appeasement and the Munich sellout.
He still fights.
The bombs
they're dropping tonight
Are editorials the
Germans will understand.
There are so many questions
on the tip of my tongue.
Has Paula rejoined
her husband?
Did he ever see his son?
Never, but he
visits them often.
But how, if he's
never seen them?
Well, he visits them
in a strange way.
Often when he's
on a bombing mission,
He drops them a letter in
a weighted steel tube.
When you
saw him tonight,
He was asking permission to turn
92 degrees south to Romilly
To drop such a letter.
So, you see, they're
not actually separated.
[Knock on door]
I beg your pardon, captain.
The reports are beginning to
come in now, flights returning.
Thank you, sergeant.
Would you care to
walk down the hangar?
Oh, yes, of course.
Tell me, captain, what
happened to the other men?
I know Matrac's here, but
where are the others?
Where's captain Marlowe?
Oh, he's in control of a mine
sweeper manned by French seamen.
They work in the channel,
Often, I suppose, in
sight of their homeland.
And Gerou?
Oh, you'll see him.
Gerou!
Bonjour, mon capitaine!
[Speaking French]
Step down, Gerou.
This is corporal Gerou.
[Speaking French]
How are you,
corporal?
He's the best mechanic in great
Britain, French, or English.
Give him
some scrap iron,
A bit of wire, old
aluminum pots and pans,
And he'll make you
a plane in 3 hours.
You exaggerate,
mon capitaine!
It would take me
4 hours, at least.
Trs bien.
Enchante', monsieur.
And what of petit?
Oh, he's a tireless member
of our ground crew,
Often working
18 hours a day.
There he is now,
over there by the crane.
Hello, petit!
Hello, mon capitaine!
Well, manning, I think
that accounts for the lot.
All but one. What
happened to Renault?
Not a sign
of the old fear.
He's the pilot
of the plane
In which Matrac
is flying tonight.
[Airplanes approaching]
They're coming,
mon capitaine!
"C" for Charles, London,
0-4-1-7.
"C" for Charles, London...
"F" for Freddy, London,
0-4-2-3.
0-4-2-3. Over.
"N" for Norman, London,
0-4-3-6.
[Laughter]
Who got the big oil tank?
Was it you, Lacroix?
Of course. Who else?
Many thanks
for the lights.
We make good use
of it.
Heil, Hitler.
We gave him heil
tonight.
Bye-Bye!
Bye!
Bonsoir!
Mr. Manning, this is
squadron leader Dampiere.
Mr. Manning.
How about a smoke?
Yes. Great.
Where is Renault?
Oh, he'll be along.
Why don't you turn in,
Dampiere?
I'll let you know as soon
as they've landed.
No. I'm fussy as an old hen
with one chick missing.
"V" for victor, come in.
Over to you.
There is no reply, sir.
Keep trying.
"V" for victor, come in.
Over to you.
All the planes are accounted
for except Renault's.
You gave him
permission
To lead
the formation.
His plane took a
lot of punishment.
Yeah.
I'm afraid, Matrac,
we can't make Romilly.
We have to turn back
to the base.
Sorry, Matrac.
Now, you make your wish and
blow out your candles.
All right.
Is it bad to
make a bad wish?
Yes, Jean.
Even if it is
about Hitler?
Well, it's better
if you make a good wish.
All right, then. I'll make a
wish about daddy. I wish...
Oh, you mustn't tell me
your wish
Or it won't come true.
I'll know
what it is anyway.
Come on. Closer m,
And blow them as hard
as you can.
All right.
There.
I did it.
Now I'll really grow up
to be like daddy.
I'm not supposed to say.
Oh, well, that's
all right, darling.
You've got your wish
already anyway.
You're like him
in many ways.
You have his eyes...
you have his nice hands.
I hope you
have his heart.
Was it the best heart
in the world?
I'll bet it was.
Oh, it is a very
good heart, jean,
A tender heart to be
in such a rugged body.
You know,
you can thank god
If you grow up
to be like him.
Can I eat my cake now?
Put your napkin on
like a good boy.
There.
[Airplane approaches]
Daddy?
Maybe. Let's look.
Come on, darling.
Is it daddy?
Are you sure it's him?
It may be.
I think it is.
But he wouldn't miss
today, would he?
Does he know
it's my birthday?
Yes, dear. He knows.
But they've
gone past, mama.
I don't see anything,
do you?
No, dear.
He didn't fly over.
Perhaps it wasn't him.
Jean.
[Airplane approaches]
[Speaking French]
Ears like a dog.
"V" for victor to fox.
They're coming in.
2 motors gone.
Limited control.
Casualties.
Victor in trouble.
Stand by, ambulance
and crash truck.
Hello, Renault.
Stretcher bearers!
Who?
Lenoir is hit.
Hurry. He's bleeding
all over the place.
Anyone else?
Yeah. Matrac.
[Speaking French]
He got 2 Messerschmitt.
He didn't get
the third one.
It was for
his kid's birthday.
We couldn't make it.
My comrades...
I can think of no more fitting
last words for our friend
Than those which he himself
wrote as his last words
And wasn't
able to deliver:
"My dear son,
"Today you are 5 years old, and
your father has never seen you.
"But someday in a
better world, he will.
"I write you of that day.
"Together we walk, hand in hand.
We walk and we look.
"And some of the things
we see are wonderful
And some are terrible.
"On a green stretch of
ground are 10,000 graves,
"And you feel hatred
welling up in your heart.
"This was...
But it will never be again.
"The world has been cured
since your father treated
"That terrible abscess on its
body with iron and fire,
"And there were millions of
healers who worked with him
"Who made sure there
would be no recurrence.
"Their deadly conflict was
waged to decide your future.
"Your friends did not spare themselves
and were ruthless to your foes.
"You are the heir of what
your father and your friends
"Won for you
with their blood.
"From their hands,
"You have received the flag
of happiness and freedom.
"My son, be the standard bearer of the
great age they have made possible.
"Lt would be too tragic
if the men of good will
"Should ever be lax or fail
again to build a world
"Where youth may love
without fear,
"And where parents may grow
old with their children,
"And where men will be worthy
of each other's faith.
"Take care of your mother,
jean.
"I hold you in my arms.
I kiss you both.
"May god keep you in love,
as I do.
"Good night and au revoir
until our work is finished.
"And until I see you,
remember this:
France Ines.
Vive la France. "
Vive la France.
All:
vive la France!
That letter...
will be delivered.
All singing
la Marseillaise.