[opening music theme]
( male narrator)
Since the very beginning
my ancestors have known
of a giant creature.
A man like beast
they call Taku He.
Like us, Taku He hunted,
fished, and raised his young,
taking only what he needed.
But when the white man came
blasting the mountain for gold
killing many animals,
everything changed.
Taku He were deeply angry
and many died by his rage.
In revenge,
the white men spilled
the innocent blood
of my people.
It was a time
of great sorrow and hatred.
Even today,
when mountain spirits
claim a life,
it is we
who are held in contempt.
There are even those
who wish us dead.
[bang]
What the hell
are you shooting at?
I've seen somethin'
over there.
[bang]
Now, that's how you kill
a tree stump.
You idiots
are scared of a creature
off in the woods.
In case you don't remember,
we're here to kill a bear.
Spread out. We only got
a couple of hours
of day light left.
[shouting]
Spread out!
[mystery music]
[low grunt]
[man shouts]
[grunt]
What the hell?
[grunting]
[soft music]
Jimbo!
Colonel!
[smells]
[thriller music]
Jimbo.
[alarm clock goes off]
[ringing]
[ringing stops]
Mom.
( mother)
l must've dozed off.
Let me make you something.
No, not much wanting
for this first period.
Oh, no.
Okay.
Bye, mom.
Oh!
Your dad called.
He wants you to spend
spring break in his place.
I can't.
You can't punish him
forever, you know.
[soft music]
[bell rings]
[Vancamp]
As we all know, next week
is spring break week.
[all cheer]
Your endangered
species projects are due
the Monday we return.
[all sigh]
I don't make up the curricula.
I just enforce it.
Now, for those
professional procrastinators
among us
who have yet
to select the topic,
just remember,
Seeing as that you
already know all of this,
perhaps you'd like to give us
an example of an endangered
species, Mr. Kelter.
[Vancamp]
Mr. Kelter.
[murmuring]
Mr. Kelter!
Uhm, uh... Shea.
(Jay )
Definitely Shea.
Did you hear the question?
Yeah. You were talking about
endangered species.
It just kinda looks to me
like pretty girls around here
are becoming
an endangered species.
After class, Kelter,
will discuss
your endangered grade.
Mr. Winslow,
perhaps you'd like
to help us out.
Uh.
Woodland caribou,
the gray wolf,
short-tailed albatross,
brown pelican,
white-tailed deer,
spidered owl,
leatherback sea turtle.
Uh, sea otter,
grizzly bear.
The Sasquatch.
[all laugh]
(Vancamp )
That's nine
out of then.
Now, if you could just
duplicate that on a test.
Why don't you join
Mr. Kelter and I after class?
Mr. Vancamp,
did you hear?
A bunch of guys got killed
by a huge grizzly bear
up in Echo Mountain.
(Vancamp )
A bunch of guys!
Yeah, like ten or something.
They said it was really bad.
Totally sick.
[bell rings]
(Vancamp )
Well, there you have it.
Well, enjoy your spring break
and please, please,
whatever you do,
stay away from killer bears.
Jay!
Sorry.
I almost forgot.
Just like you forgot
your homework
for the last three weeks.
Listen, you're precariously close
to not passing this class.
That means
you won't graduate.
What are you talking about?
I have to graduate.
Mr. Kelter, graduation is a privilege,
not a requirement.
That's why I've decided
to team the both of you up.
What? Why?
You're joking, right?
"He who helps others,
helps himself."
I don't need his help.
I can't help.
Gentlemen, let me
put it to you in this light.
If the two of you together
don't produce an in-depth presentation
by Monday after next,
one of you will be leaving
with an incomplete,
and the other
won't be leaving at all.
You didn't say
it was this bad.
Bear attack?
Can't expect it to be pretty.
Gotta get this
cleaned up.
You have to get
this cleaned up, Sheriff.
Tourists are gonna be up here
in a few weeks.
It's all bull hairs.
That big motor is gonna drive
right past Pine Creek.
They'll think
there's a killer bear
on the loose up here.
We gotta control this
before it controls us.
I've called the town meeting
for tonight.
Calling meetings, Kassel?
Are you tr ying to give me another ulcer?
That'll add fuel
to the fire!
We cant let this get out.
Do you understand that?
I understand that my job
is to protect the people of this town.
They have the right to know
there's a pissed off predator out here.
You don't know that, yet.
If I read one word about this
in any paper but our own local dish rag,
you're gonna have a tough time
finding work in Alaska.
What's that, John?
Nothing.
Maybe all-knowing Indian
around here, Eagleheart.
What do you think
we should do with this
vile creature?
It's a noble savage.
It's nice of you
to think so, Mayor,
but l'm just a ranger.
Listen, we've contacted
the Federal Game Warden.
He'll be here
with some tracking dogs
in a day or two.
Until then,
Eagleheart and I
will try to find it.
I don't give a rat's ass
who does it
or how you do it.
You just make sure this thing
is last week's news.
Johnson!
That way.
Don't get too far ahead of us
or you'll be tomorrow's news.
You don't really think
a bear did this, do you?
You ever heard of a bear
killing three men?
Well, it's what Janzer claims.
Well, the poacher claims
it's a bear.
Let's call it that.
It's probably better--
Better than what?
Listen, don't answer that.
My only job
is to keep people happy.
Unfortunately, those people
are gonna want blood for this.
You know that.
I'm sure those yahoos
have wounded enough bears
to make that easy.
Listen, I'll head
above the falls
and see what I can find.
I give you two days.
But take care of you, John.
For God's sakes,
keep you radio on,
will you?
I don't wanna have
to come back here
and rescue you, you noble ass.
[rock music]
[loud rock music]
[revs engine]
[rock music continues]
[tires screech]
Jesus, man!
What's up?
That's a really nice bike
you got there.
My sister's got a tutu
that'll match that real good.
I hope it's pretty.
Look, I ain't going back here
next year. Got that?
You and I
don't like each other.
We don't have
to like each other.
We just have
to work together.
Unless you get an incomplete,
I suggest you be
at the town meeting tonight.
Why is that, Jay?
Because you said yourself
bears are an endangered
species.
It's grizzlies.
Okay, whatever,
dick Britannica.
Just be there, right?
[tires screech]
Oh, yeah.
By the way,
my cousin Jenny,
she likes you.
Don't ask me why.
She's gonna be there
tonight, too.
[tires screech]
[revs engine]
[soft music]
[low murmuring]
Jenny, Richard.
Richard, Jenny.
You're the one
that's coming with us
to the mountains this weekend.
What? No.
Jenny wants to come
along too,
but I told her I didn't think
that was a good idea.
That wouldn't be.
Why? I can handle it
myself, okay?
Can you hear me?
Good evening.
Uh...the Mayor
isn't here, yet.
So I think
I'll just get started.
I wanna thank all of you
for coming out tonight.
I know many of you are busy
getting ready
for the tourist season,
so... I'll just cut
to the chase.
Yesterday, as some of you
already know,
there was a bear attack
up on Echo Mountain.
Unfortunately,
three men were killed
and a fourth
was very, very lucky.
Taku He has returned.
Ed Janzer was found
by ranger Eagleheart
who happened to be
in the area of the attack.
[door closes]
Mr. Mayor.
And brought back
to town.
Ed was shaken up pretty badly,
but I'm happy to report
he's going to be alright.
I've contacted
the Federal Game Warden.
They have a couple
of Karelian bear dogs
who'll track the animal down
and kill it.
The problem is
they're over in Montana
right now
and won't be able
to get here for a few days.
I think you'll see
after looking it over
we really don't have much
to worry about.
Not much to worry about?
Sheriff, what about the tourists?
I'm sure the Mayor
will wanna comment on that but, uh,
my concern is for your safety
and the safety of our visitors.
What are we supposed to do
in the mean time, stay inside?
(Kassel)
No.
For what it's worth,
those men were up there illegally
and probably got between
the saw and her cubs.
If they go up there
and shoot that bear,
then the press
is gonna come up here.
We sure as hell don't need
any one dredging up ridiculous
monster stories again.
Exactly. That's why
there isn't going to be
any press coverage.
Our town needs
those tourism dollars.
How the bear's handled
is our business.
The important thing for us
is you just keep doing
what we've done for years.
We can't let
misguided reporters and crazy rumors
ruin our good town.
(Jenny )
Why do they have
to kill the bear?
When a bear kills a human,
they usually destroy it.
Would you kill it?
Me? No.
You gonna take
that shot or what?
Here's 20.
Says you gonna scratch again.
I can't believe you boys
are in here playing pool
and bullshitting
when your buddies
are rotting up on that mountain,
'cause of some pied-face
park ranger.
The way we hear
was that that Indian saved your heart.
Besides, Sheriff said
if anyone was caught up there,
we were gonna get arrested.
Ray, when in your life
have you ever paid attention to law?
That Indian's gonna have
his ass handed to him.
I bet you money on that.
They way
he took care of you?
Son of a bitch!
Come on!
( Ed)
What are you doing to me?
We're you there?
I had that bear
in my sights.
(Ed)
I came too, boys.
The boys
were ripped to pieces.
( Ed)
I've never seen
that much blood.
Who's with me?
This thing has got "A" written
all over it.
That's A for ass.
Alright, genius, wha--
what do you wanna do, huh?
You wanna go hit the library?
Stick your nose in a book?
Copy some pictures, huh?
That sounds
real exciting, dude!
You're pitiful, man.
No wonder you're still a virgin.
I just wanna have
a good time, alright?
Look, I'm gonna give you
an equation for you to learn.
This is very important.
Couple of girls
plus couple of beers equals fun!
And what about
graduating, huh?
Did you say
a couple of girls?
[laughs]
Evening, Trish.
Bye, Eddie.
[keys jingle]
How are you doing, Kassel?
Evening, Ed.
Look, I already told you
everything I know.
Right when I seen that bear
l got knocked out.
Would you like to check?
That's not what
I'm concerned about, Ed.
I'm concerned that
you might be planning
on doing something stupid.
Something
you might regret.
Wouldn't be
the first time.
It'll be the last
if you go near
Echo Mountain again.
Poaching is a crime, Ed.
The only reason you're not
behind bars tonight
is because
your buddies are dead.
So, if you're even thinking
about going back there, think again.
Thanks for this talk, Sheriff.
Go home, Ed.
(woman )
Who is going again?
Me, Jenny,
Rich, and Shea.
It's bad enough
I'm letting you take your cousin.
Momma, come on!
Shea is Richard's girlfriend, okay?
When we'll you be back?
And who's Rich?
Sunday or Monday.
Rich Winslow, Doris Winslow's son.
Oh, oh, Doris,
from the diner.
Nice lady.
Since when are you friends
with her son?
Oh, my God, mom!
I told you.
I just need his brains
so I can pass biology,
so I can graduate,
remember?
Well, I suppose.
Just stay away
from where the bear is.
And no drinking!
Don't worry, mom.
I'll be too busy working
on my six pack to drink.
[country music]
(Leo )
Woo!
Now we're huntin' boys!
Yeah. When you shut your mouth
and open your eyes,
then you'll be hunting.
Okay.
So, what's the plan?
We're gonna drive
over these two next ridges
as far as we can get
and we're gonna
set up camp.
A beer.
Hey, are you really
gonna kill Eagleheart
if we come across him?
I'm gonna make me
a bear claw necklace.
[all laugh]
Look, we've been over this.
All I'm asking
is for permission to go
in there with a few guys
before your men
with the dogs get here.
Before somebody else
gets killed!
[male voice]
We need that in writing.
You need it in writing?
Approved by a judge.
Great.
[male voice]
We need it in writing.
It has to be legal.
Okay, fine.
I'll play your little game.
But know this.
One more person
from this town gets killed,
and I'll shove
that court injunction
so far up your ass
your gums will bleed.
You too, Sir.
Have a nice day.
That better be the Game Warden
saying he's gonna be here
first thing in the morning.
You missed some.
Huh?
Tasty cream filling?
Look, so far I've managed
to keep this tale from growing legs
and turning it into another
Echo Mountain legend.
It was a massacre actually.
The point is
you need to hold up your end
and get this bear
taken care of.
I don't want it
transplant it, either. I want it dead.
We can't have the thing
coming back here.
I know, I know.
We can't have the tourists getting eaten alive.
Is that all you care about?
The tourists?
The tourists
pay my salary.
And they pay
your salary.
Do your job,
Sheriff Kassel, while you still have one.
Yes, Sir!
[door closes]
Mr. Tasty cream filling.
[soft music]
What time is it?
It's 12:15.
I told you bear bull
was going to fail out on us.
He'll be here.
He won't!
Trust me.
Just so you know,
the grizzly bear stands over nine feet tall
and weighs
over 1,500 pounds.
Do you still wanna go?
[Manny laughing]
Put the dogs out!
[man laughing]
(Manny )
This is great!
Woo!
[bang]
Hey!
[engine stalls]
Forgot to get gas.
You stupid
son of a bitch!
So what we doin'?
Huntin' or campin'?
What are we gonna do
with my jeep?
Just leave it here?
You're the one
that ran out of gas.
What do you think?
Go and get elated.
[chuckles]
How are we gonna get
out of here now? Walk?
[bang]
Hey, guys!
Good camp spot
right by the creek.
And I got dinner, too.
We got steaks tonight, Tom!
Steaks?
(Manny )
Yeah!
He's got a wood rat!
Woo!
[laughs]
Woo-hoo!
Let me see that thing!
[laughs]
You're a hot nail.
C'mon!
You're crazy.
You're not a woodman.
[rock music]
Jay.
God!
You left a note.
You told me your parents said
it was gonna be okay.
Since when do you care
what my parents think
about you?
He's got a reputation
to uphold.
I least I got one, dicker.
[rock music]
[music stops]
[birds chirping]
Looks like someone
couldn't wait.
(Jay )
You think we should go ahead
and drive through?
No, there's no reason to.
The trail starts right here.
Are we gonna like
close to where
the attacks were?
I don't know.
They didn't say last night.
They said up by the falls.
Are we gonna go
up there?
I don't see why not!
I suppose you brought the guns
seeing that you're dying to go
where the action is.
No. My old man locked up
the gun cabinet before he left.
He hid the key.
(Jay )
What about you?
I don't have
an old man.
It's okay.
I brought bear repellent.
[Jay laughs]
Hey, do you wanna hold
my stupid sign?
Bears don't have anything.
Follow the stones,
you get to spray yourself his flavor
and for the bear
like to pass or something.
Go ahead and laugh.
At least l'm gonna feel safe.
(Jay)
Wait, you guys.
Hang on a sec.
This is for all of you
that are just tuning in right now.
This is the real deal
right here.
There's no fake stuff going on.
This is the tale of,
one, two, three, four horny kids
and their journey
up into the back country.
The journey
that will lead them face to face
with the killer
the grizzly bear.
The journey that
could be their last.
Woo!
[laughs]
[soft music]
It's beautiful up here.
(Jay )
Yes, it is.
You come up here
by yourself?
Sure, why not?
Don't you get scared?
No. I don't feel it's
anymore scared of you
than you are of it.
(Jenny )
So you think this bear
is scared of us?
Well, assuming
it was a bear.
(Jay )
Dick, what took those men
if it wasn't a bear, huh?
(Jenny )
It's Rich.
No, it's okay, Jenny.
My gram used to call me
little Dick.
Not even Jay
can do worse than that.
(Rich)
You really wanna know
what I think killed those men?
Didn't l ask you?
Okay.
Me!
[soft laughter]
Not funny.
[thriller music]
(Rich)
Are you okay?
You scared me.
I'm sorry.
I'm not so good for this.
What is it?
Nothing. I have the feeling
that something's watching me.
Oh, it's just me.
Come on.
[low grunt]
Alright, this is good.
I like it.
I see what you mean
with the sound.
Alright, you guys
just set up the tents
right here
and I'll go
round up some firewood.
Hey, Richard and you
have some stuff up here, huh?
I sure feel a lot safer
having him around.
Me too, you guys.
He's just so rugged
and handsome.
You know, you're just lucky
he agreed to come along.
Yeah, real lucky.
[grunting]
[roaring]
[roar]
[loud roaring]
Darling, you're beautiful.
No, give me the camera.
Hey!
David Crockett!
What took you so long?
There's a... grizzly.
Just now?
Where?
Right up over there.
Sure it wasn't a squirrel?
[laughs]
Yeah, yeah.
It was as big and heavy
just like your mother.
Do you think that
it was the same bear that--
No, no.
This bear wasn't interested
in killing anybody.
What did you do,
Nature boy?
I did what
we should always do.
Yeah? Did you cry
like a little girl
and wet yourself?
I stood there.
Jay, grow up.
What?
I'm gonna go change.
I would've run.
(Richard)
Oh, no.
You never outrun a bear.
It's the whole fight
or flight response.
If you flee, you're just--
you're like a rabbit
or a deer,
but if you stay
and if you hold your ground,
then you might have a chance.
Dude, you are so
full of crap.
I don't believe
a word of this.
Damn!
(Rich)
Really?
Okay.
What about
a thousand words?
(Jay shouting )
Deal!
Jay! Oh, my God,
you're such a pervert!
Get out of here.
I'm just recording
the scenery
for my project, baby.
[eagle screech]
[birds chirp]
[smells]
[loud cricket chirping]
You cook like you drive.
Yeah, you just
keep it up, Ed.
You'll be gettin' hit
on the head again
and this time
it won't be from no bear.
How many times I gotta tell you
it was no bear
hitting on my head.
It was cheap dumb ass!
[men voices]
You see that?
[men laughing]
Be quiet for a minute.
What?
I don't know.
I thought I saw something.
It's the woods.
Stuff moves. Now cook.
Leo, cook, damn it!
Mac cheese and ketchup.
It's a dinner
of champions, baby.
Yeah! What!
(Jay)
M mm, mmm.
Hey, want some?
No, thanks.
(Jay)
Tastes good.
I'm sure
after next year,
when we all broke college
we'll be sick and tired
of Mac and cheese.
Why don't you tell us
a story Rich?
Something scary.
We need to decide
who's sleeping
in which tent.
I mean, if you're gonna go
tell scary stories,
specially ones
having to do with bears,
(Shea)
I'm not gonna sleep alone.
Jay?
What?
I didn't say anything.
No, okay.
You can sleep by me,
but don't try
anything funny, okay?
C'mon, Shea,
there's nothing funny
about sex!
Okay. Now that we have that
dealt with, let's hear
your story.
Wait.
Before you start,
I gotta get this
on tape.
(Rich)
Everything?
Uh-huh. Otherwise,
well, if I don't,
how else am I gonna show
Vancamp that his golden boy
drinks beer?
[coughs]
(Jay )
Besides, it's all part
of the project, specially
if the bear gets us!
Stop!
(Jay laughing )
Sorry.
Smile.
Alright, go ahead.
Before Pine Creek
was settled,
and long before
Echo Mountain
was a preserve,
this whole area
was sacred land
to the Indians who lived here.
They didn't hunt,
fish, nothing.
And to the Indians,
Echo Mountain was
no man's land.
Why did they call it
Echo Mountain anyways?
(Rich)
The Indians claim that
if you called out at night,
something would answer you.
Something
or someone?
Hey, Jenny, for the love
of all that's holy,
please, shut up!
Sorry.
Now, the spring of 1891,
a few miners passing through
discovered gold here.
They didn't want
word to get out, so they built
a small clandestine settlement
and began mining.
(Jay)
The natives didn't like it,
but they're the peaceful kind
that kept to themselves.
Everything was going
really well.
Until--
[bang]
Until?
Until something happened.
By the time the miners
finally sent word back
to their relatives,
they described this place
as a mountain paradise
with them as riches.
Then instructed them all
to sell everything
and come immediately.
And so they did.
When they arrived,
they found all the miners
and their families... dead.
Women, children,
everything, everyone
was slaughtered.
Without a second thought,
the settlers took their guns,
went to the nearest tribe
and slaughtered everyone.
That was a real massacre.
Not some phony stories
about Indians killing
white women and children.
(Jay)
Yeah, I remember
hearing about this.
[bang]
(Jenny)
If the Indians didn't do it,
what did happen
to the settlers?
The natives blamed
the other creature
made this place home.
(Jay)
Wait, wait.
This is not
one of those stupid
Bigfoot stories, is it?
It's Taku He.
What the hell
did you just say?
The native peoples
all over the world
have different names
like Taku He, Sasquatch,
Yeti, Bigfoot,
usually translated
to mean large man.
Do they consider them
dangerous?
I would imagine
they're like
any other creature
in the wild.
If they're put in a situation
of danger, they react
with the fly or fight response,
specially if you got
between mother and child.
(Jenny)
Do you think any of them
still live here?
(Rich )
I don't know,
but the records of them
dating back all the way
to the first explorers.
All the way
until a couple
of years ago.
Wild, screeching beasts
who hunt for game
and fish.
You can throw rods
and things.
Okay, that's enough.
I do want to sleep tonight.
No, I've seen
all those campy
Bigfoot movies
and they aren't scary.
(Jay)
Okay.
Well, then you know
any woman
on her menstrual cycle
should stay out of the woods.
What?
Why?
C'mon!
Use your imagination.
Who wants a lady
on the rag with you
when you're camping?
(Shea)
Jay, shut up.
(Rich)
Actually, it's because animals
can smell blood from miles.
Okay, that's enough.
I agree.
Could we please talk
about something else?
Anything else?
Well, beer's kicking in.
Jesus!
So, do you think it's,
you know,
killed anyone recently?
(Shea)
Jenny, stop.
Has it?
Well, there are records
of a few animals mutilated
found hanging in trees.
Trees?
(Rich)
Trees.
Is that why
you didn't wanna come?
Okay, enough.
Do not answer that question.
[thumping]
(Jay)
Oh, my God.
You guys. I saw it!
I saw it over there,
in the night.
[burst out laughing]
[laughing]
You should've seen her!
That wasn't funny!
Jay?
You are such a jerk!
Baby, c'mon!
It was just a joke.
[soft guitar music]
(man )
I'm sorry, Sheriff.
When I took his keys,
he got ignorant
and locked himself
in the head.
How long
has he been in there?
Over an hour.
Ray!
Sheriff Kassel.
[drunken voice]
You got me
this time, Sheriff.
It's like
you got yourself there, Ray.
Planning on coming out
any time soon?
Are you planning
on giving me
my keys back, huh?
So I can drive home?
Why would I do
something like that, Ray?
'Cause I got
some information
and you don't know about.
You didn't hear this
from me, okay?
[burps]
But Ed and the boys
are going back up
in the mountains
to kill a bear.
And they said
they're gonna kill
Eagleheart, too.
What?
Eagleheart
saved his life.
Ed doesn't think so.
Ed thinks
that the Indian did it.
Is he crazy?
C'mon, let's go!
[Manny laughing]
C'mon I
[passes gas]
[men burst out laughing]
Good one!
Try it again.
No way.
( Ed)
C'mon, you pansy.
I burned my bottom
that last one.
[laughter]
We're gonna need
another bottle.
There's one
in the jeep.
(Ed)
Who wants to go get it?
I ain't going, man.
You just got
the smartest.
I'm not going up there
alone.
(Manny)
I'm not going.
(Ed)
I vote for Leo.
Hey, I vote
for Leo, too.
[burst out laughing]
Looks like
it's you, my buddy.
Bad.
You boys better hope
I don't get
that jeep fired up
'cause I might just
leave you here.
Better take the gun.
(Tom)
You might run
into a mad woodman out there.
[men laugh]
This sucks.
To Leo!
[laughs]
That's my cousin.
And he's as dumb
as he looks.
I hope that stupid bastard
doesn't' have to shoot
anything.
Why?
[men burst out laughing]
[soft grunt]
Oh, there you are, girl.
Tommy?
Tommy, is that you?
C'mon out of there.
I saw you already.
Come on.
Ed?
Manny, quit screwing around!
I will shoot you.
Alright.
You wanna play with me?
[loud growling and roaring]
[growling and roaring]
[thriller music]
[grunting]
[growling]
[shouting]
What the hell was that?
Sounded like Leo.
The damn fool
probably just saw
his own shadow.
Let's go.
Are you kidding?
I ain't going out there!
Let's go find him.
Oh, hell,
let's all go.
Grab your guns
and get a couple of lights.
Are you cold?
I can get
some more wood.
I'm fine.
Thanks.
You must do this a lot.
Give a girl my jacket?
First time.
Camping.
You know,
whenever I need the space.
Yeah, well,
I get plenty of that at home.
[thriller music]
My dad's a consultant,
and so whenever he goes
out of town a lot,
my mom goes with him.
And I get stuck
with Jay.
Lucky for me, huh?
[thriller music]
Ooh!
[laughs]
Jay, you really suck.
You know that?
I'm your cousin!
[Jay laughs]
You know, Rich?
Let's go.
(Jay)
I'm gonna tell your parents
when they get home.
You two kids behave, alright?
I wanna hear
your loud noises!
Well, I guess
it's just you and me now.
(Shea)
Jay, I'm sacred!
What!
Where's Leo?
The dumb ass
left his lights on.
Where is the whiskey?
Where did it go?
Whiskey!
Now, where is Leo?
(Tom)
Oh, my God.
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, my God!
Cover him up!
(Tom)
What kind of bear
could do something like this?
We better
get back to camp.
What about Leo?
Leave him.
Leave him!
He--he's right, Tom.
I got a bad feeling here.
C'mon, let's go!
C'mon, Tom.
Let's go. Come on!
I'm really scared.
Scared of what?
What are you scared of?
Of what Rich said.
About animals and how
they can smell blood.
Baby, that was just a story.
Really.
So he made up
that whole story about the massacre?
Yeah!
Besides,
do you see those guns?
Oh, yeah,
they'll protect you.
I promise.
There's nothing
to worry about, okay?
[thriller music]
[soft grunt]
Jay, knock it off.
Hey, it isn't me!
Well, who is it?
(Jay)
How the hell
should I know?
Throw another rock
at my tent and l'll throw you
a beating.
(Rich)
I think you guys
should come over to our tent.
Yeah, fat chance
of that happening.
You guys come over here.
(Rich)
Just try to get some sleep.
Some sleep.
You can't be serious.
Don't worry about it.
[owl hooting]
[loud cricket chirping]
[whispering]
Jay.
Hey, Jay.
Jay, get up.
I gotta pee. You gotta come.
Jay!
Fine!
Just cover myself, I guess.
[low grunt]
[growling and roaring]
[shouting]
Jay, Jay!
[growling]
[shouts]
[pants]
What? What?
Baby, what's wrong?
Jay, I'm so sick
of your stupid pranks.
What the hell
did I do?
I'm sleeping.
(Rich)
Are you guys alright?
Yeah, yeah.
Everything's great.
[birds chirping]
What!
Fuck.
Jesus!
(Rich)
What kind of project
are you making, Jay?
Funny.
Somebody's gotta look
after my cousin.
Okay. Your cousin
can look after herself.
Right!
What do you
little horn balls say
if we go find that bear, huh?
And you plan
would be, what?
Just go hike up the falls
where we heard
the gunshots last night.
Oh, yeah!
That's a good idea.
I mean, you know,
one in doubt always head
to a gun fire, right?
[laughs]
Look, Jay,
we have pictures
of the grizzly bear.
So, how about
we just head back?
Dude, no way.
Vancamp said
I need an A to graduate.
What you just said
was a C at best, alright?
I need to get some live,
hard core, reality sound
TV for this.
Good morning.
Okay, news washed.
Camping blows.
[laughs]
And you, "Mr. I'm suddenly
concerned with my grades
all of a sudden, "
we're leaving now, okay?
Especially if you ever
would like to see me again.
Jay, ten minutes, okay?
Bye.
[soft music]
( Eagleheart)
High camp to
to base one. Over.
( Eagleheart)
High camp
to base one. Over.
Go ahead, John.
Wish I had better news.
Any sign of our problem?
( Eagleheart)
Not yet.
Janzer and his boys
are up here,
along with some kids, too.
(Kassel)
Listen, you need
to watch yourself, John.
I got a bad feeling
our friend Ed Janzer
might try to make you look
like a hunting accident.
Copy that.
Give me another day.
If you don't hear from me,
come and look.
Alright, but promise me
you'll stay away from Janzer.
Don't do anything stupid.
The last thing we need
is to have another--
[static interference]
Sheriff?
[soft music]
You tell me how
we're supposed to find
that damn Indian.
You let me
handle that.
That son of a bitch
is probably
watching us right now.
I'm going back to Leo.
You go back to Leo,
you might kiss your ass
good bye.
Now, let's head out!
We never even covered him
last night.
Stick with us, Tommy.
It ain't right.
Stick.
This really sucks, you guys.
You know that?
I'm going home
and I'm not graduating
all at the same damn time!
Look at the bright side.
At least we can use
your homework.
Who does homework?
Jay, can we get the hell
out of here, now?
Wait you guys.
Hang on a second.
Hey, Mr. Vancamp.
Well, we've just got done
spending five very long days
in the wilderness.
And in all, I would say
that we've observed
40 or even--
Richard, would you say 50
endangered species?
[flies buzzing]
Who in hell would do
something like that?
(Tommy)
Damn near tore
his face off.
Somebody that wants
to send a message.
I don't like
the feel in here.
Let's keep moving.
(Shea)
Hey, Rich,
I was wondering,
you know, last night,
were you telling the truth
about all that stuff?
Yeah.
Okay, wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
So, you're saying
that Bigfoot is real
and that that's
what killed those men?
[crack]
Rich.
John.
What are you doing here?
You guys really
shouldn't be here.
(Jay)
Why not?
You all need
to leave here, now.
And we should listen
to you because--
Rich, can I talk with you
a moment in private?
What the hell's going on?
What's wrong?
Hey.
(Jenny)
Does anybody know
what they're talking about?
We'll never
gonna get out of here.
Oh, no, but look.
I think our boy scout
(Jay)
might be trying to get
his Indian badge.
He said we should get
the hell out of here.
Why?
Those gunshots
we heard last night.
There's a group of hunters
that are shooting
at everything.
They might come after us.
Come on!
Why would they do
something like that?
What else
did he say?
He said we should head
straight through the woods.
We gotta get the message
to the Sheriff, alright?
Come on!
Whoa!
Message?
What message?
(Jay)
Hey, what message?
Hey, you!
What the--
I don't believe this.
The bastard
trashed the camp.
You and your boys
need to leave here now.
I will be leaving, alright?
But after I finish
killing you.
Ed says it's your fault
my cousin was killed.
I had nothing to do with that.
I don't think
Ed is telling you everything.
You don't know what
you're messing with here.
What do you think
did this to your camp?
killed Leo and the others?
You should know enough
about bears to know
they always cover their kill.
He's right, Ed.
I was wondering about that
the whole time.
You have three seconds
to explain what the hell
you're talking about.
Or I'll put a bullet
in that blasted badge of yours.
There's a creature out here
and you managed
to piss it off pretty good.
A creature.
We may be dumb
by we ain't stupid, Chief.
For the lack
of better word, yes, a creature.
And whatever Ed
was doing up here two days ago,
disturbed it.
What did you do, Ed?
Shoot at it?
I should've shot you.
Think what you want.
But right now,
you need to leave here
or it's gonna kill you all.
Why won't this thing
kill you, huh?
It will.
That's why I'm leaving.
You crazy Indian.
You ain't going any place.
Tie him up.
[shouting]
Tie him up!
Can I see the map?
Do not tell me
we're lost.
Just making sure
we don't get lost.
I'm getting hungry.
Alright, dick,
where do we go now?
Uhm,
[clears throat]
I think we go
that way.
Hey, good.
Let's go.
I'm not staying
in this forest another night.
I'll get it.
Are you good, buddy?
(Ed)
Nobody's going anywhere.
We'll wait.
We wait for what?
Chief Eagleheart's monster.
I don't believe
in no monster. Do you, Ed?
What do you think,
numb nuts?
Hell no,
I don't believe in a monster.
I know damn well
there's a bear up here.
And he's gonna come back.
Like the man said,
my experience has told me
is, bear will not pass up
a nice free meal.
Boys, we got a lot
of red meat right here.
Take the knife.
Heat the blood up
in a fire.
Take it up wind.
I'm sorry, guys.
This is farther than I thought.
We, uhm,
have to make camp here.
It's getting dark.
(Jay)
What about over there?
(Rich)
By the tree?
Good idea.
Let's check it out.
[coughs]
It stinks.
It smells
like something died.
Sure it does.
Let me see.
(Jay)
What the hell is that?
Okay, this is sick.
What is that?
(Rich)
We have to get the hell
out of here, man.
What? Let me see,
let me see.
(Rich)
C'mon!
C'mon, man!
I think it's moving.
It's moving.
[shouting]
Get out of here!
[thriller music]
Jenny!
Shea!
[girl shouts]
[grunts]
Be very quiet, okay?
You got it?
You got to get
yourself together.
Sh.
[owl hoots]
Jenny, it's gonna smell me.
[whispering]
What?
It's gonna smell me.
I've got my period.
That's the least
of our problems, okay?
[whispering]
We have to wait
for the guys.
We're gonna die out here.
I know it, I know it.
[whispering]
No, we're not
gonna die out there.
Thought I told you
to tie him up.
[grunting]
Did you hear that?
(Tom )
Not like an animal
I've ever heard.
(Manny )
And human neither.
You both shut up
and listen.
Manny, give me
my gun.
What you're gonna do?
I said just to pass it.
[grunt]
Save your damn ammo.
[growl]
I ain't dying
like Leo.
(Ed)
Where're you going?
Hey, Tom!
[growling]
[Tom shouts]
[shouting]
[grunting]
Tom!
(Manny)
Tom?
I think I got something.
Oh, my God.
No!
Tom!
Tom.
Stupid fool.
You did this!
Huh?
What are you gonna do?
You gonna kill me?
I will, Ed.
I will.
You're the one.
That disappoints me, Manny.
All my friends are dead
'cause of you.
I'm your friend, Manny.
I am your friend.
[bang]
Okay.
[out of breath]
I don't know what happened.
We all got chased by something.
We all got split up.
I don't know
what it was.
Mr. Vancamp,
if you're watching this,
we sure as hell
better get an A for this crap.
I'm freezing.
[owl hoots]
What are we gonna do?
Just wait, I guess.
[loud growling]
Did you hear that?
I can't,
I cannot--
[whispering]
Shea, Shea,
don't go!
[whispering]
Shea, don't run.
Don't run.
[grunting]
Base One to high camp.
C'mon, Johnny,
don't do this to me.
[telephone rings]
Sheriff's office.
(woman)
I wanna know if that
grizzly's been killed.
No, ma'am, the bear
hasn't been killed, yet.
(woman)
Get out there
and skin it.
I sure will, ma'am.
I'll do that
on my way to hell.
Yes, ma'am.
You, too.
[knocking at the door]
I'll be right there.
Kill the bear.
Kill the Mayor.
Now, save the bear.
[roll of thunder]
[thriller music]
Who the hell are you?
Jenny Ackers.
Thank God.
You've gotta help me.
Can you please help me?
I don't know
where I'm going.
I'm lost.
My friends are lost.
I don't know where they are.
Please, help me.
I'll help you.
[shouts]
[shouting]
Shut up!
Eagleheart!
I'm gonna kill
this girl!
(Ed)
Eagleheart!
[roll of thunder]
I know you're around here.
I can smell you.
[cries in pain]
[grunting]
( Eagleheart)
Let her go!
Let her go.
You must think
I'm dumb as dirt.
I'm the one you want.
See, that's the difference
between you and me.
I'm willing to kill
for what I believe in.
[loud growling]
[distant bang]
(Jay)
Sheriff!
Thank God.
What the hell
is going on up here?
[out of breath]
We've got friends up there.
They're in trouble.
You, come with me.
You, in the car.
Here.
I'll take that.
Get up!
[cries in pain]
Stop!
Are you gonna play
the hero now, kid?
I know that gun.
(Ed)
That's a nice gun,
specially when it's loaded.
[bang]
Wait up!
He'll be okay.
Are you okay?
[low grunt]
Are you guys alright?
(Rich)
Yeah.
Oh!
(Jay)
What happened?
Is he gonna be alright?
Yeah, he's good.
You'll be okay.
Okay, John?
Richard, Richard,
tha--tha--tha--
that's not a bear.
[loud growling]
[grunting]
No way.
Look at that.
Oh, my God!
It's freaking huge.
(Kassel)
Where is everybody?
Sheriff, over here!
(Jay)
Where did he--
Where did he go?
[thumping]
[all laugh]
There's gotta be
something wrong
with the TV, Mr. Vancamp.
We've been watching
this tape all weekend.
I had this incredible footage
of the grizzly bear.
He was like that.
Except if you're standing up
and he'll roar!
Roaring?
(Jay)
I'm serious.
(Vancamp)
I'm sure you did, Jay.
Big surprise
for all of us, huh?
Lucky for you
Richard got some nice photos.
Actually, uhm,
Jay took these.
(Vancamp)
Jay took these?
(Rich)
Yeah.
I did the research
in the library, mostly.
(Vancamp)
Let's see.
These are good!
Looks like you got
precariously close there.
[all laugh]
And this is
the killer bear, huh?
(Vancamp )
I thought you understood
when I said in-depth.
That I wanted something
a bit more... in-depth.
What we have here
is a little thin,
don't you think?
No, I don't think.
I don't understand why
every time I do a project,
you gotta give me
so much sh--
Excuse me, but I think
if you look at the research
that we actually did
in it's entirety,
you'll see that we went
the extra mile, and that's him.
Well, where might I find
this extravaganza.
Well, it would be
extravagantly laid out
in your extravagant office.
(anchorwoman)
Earlier today,
this amateur video
created quite a stir
amongst some local residents.
A Pine Creek man claims
this supposed Bigfoot creature
pictured here
was responsible
for the recent deaths
of several local men.
Family members
of the deceased
responded by calling the video
a sick joke.
Local experts
have deemed the tape
a hoax,
denouncing the grainy footage
is nothing more than a man
in a monkey suit.
The man behind the film,
Dennis Vancamp,
is a science teacher
at Pine Creek High School.
The Mayor had this to say.
I can't tell you
how ashamed I feel today.
I say, as a community,
we will not and cannot tolerate
such unacceptable forms
of behavior
among those who serve
as role models
for our children.
The truth must overcome.
(anchorwoman)
Next up, Captain Jimbo
gives us his five-day
micro planet.
[loud cricket chirping]
(male narrator)
Sometimes,
in the deep woods
when the mountain is lone,
when the sun no longer
touches my face
and the creatures lay still,
I can feel in there
Taku He.
[loud growling]
[growling]