(silence)
Yes, M. Gustave...
("s'Rothe-Zaãuerli"
by OÖse Schuppel playing)
♪
(tapping paper)
It is an extremely
common mistake.
People think
the writer's imagination
is always at work,
that he's constantly inventing
an endless supply
of incidents and episodes.
That he simply dreams up
his stories out of thin air.
In point of fact, the
opposite is true.
Once the public knows
you're a writer,
they bring the characters
and events to you,
and as long as you maintain
your ability to look
(door creaks open)
and to carefully listen,
these stories
will continue to...
Stop it! Stop it!
Don't! Don't do it!
(clattering in distance)
Uh... will continue
to seek you out,
uh, over your lifetime.
To him who has often told
the tales of others,
many tales will be told.
(whispering): Sorry.
It's all right.
The incidents that follow
were described to me exactly
as I present them here
and in a wholly unexpected way.
A number of years ago,
while suffering from a mild
case of scribe's fever,
a form of neurasthenia common
among the intelligentsia
of that time,
I decided to spend
the month of August
in the spa town
of Nebelsbad,
below the Alpine
Sudetenwaltz,
and had taken up rooms
in the Grand Budapest--
a picturesque, elaborate
and once widely celebrated
establishment.
I expect some of you
will know it.
YOUNG WRITER:
It was off season,
and by that time,
decidedly out of fashion,
and it had already begun
its descent into shabbiness
and eventual demolition.
What few guests we were
had quickly come to recognize
one another by sight,
as the only living souls
residing
in the vast establishment.
Although I do not believe
any acquaintance
among our number had proceeded
beyond the polite nods
we exchanged
as we passed
in the Palm Court
and the Arabian Baths
and onboard
the Colonnade Funicular.
We were a very reserved
group, it seemed,
and without exception...
solitary.
(the clinking of
dishes and utensils echoing)
Perhaps as a result
of this general silence,
I'd established a casual
and bantering familiarity
with the hotel's concierge,
a West-continental known
only as Monsieur Jean,
who struck one as being
at once both lazy and...
really quite accommodating.
I expect he was not well paid.
In any case, one evening,
as I stood conferring
elbow to elbow
with Monsieur Jean,
as had become my habit,
I noticed a new presence
in our company.
A small, elderly man,
smartly dressed,
with an exceptionally lively,
intelligent face
and an immediately
perceptible air of sadness.
He was,
like the rest of us, alone,
but also, I must say,
he was the first
that struck one as being
deeply and truly lonely,
a symptom of my own
medical condition as well.
Who's this interesting
old fellow?
I inquired of Monsieur Jean.
To my surprise, he was
distinctly taken aback.
Don't you know?
He asked.
Don't you recognize him?
He did look familiar.
That's Mr. Moustafa himself.
He arrived early this morning.
This name will, no doubt,
be familiar to the more
seasoned persons among you.
Mr. Zero Moustafa
was, at one time,
the richest man in Zubrowka,
and was still indeed the
owner of the Grand Budapest.
He often comes
and stays a week or more.
Three times a year, at least,
but never in the season.
Monsieur Jean signaled to me,
and I leaned closer.
I'll tell you a secret.
He takes only
a single bed sleeping room
without a bath in a rear corner
of the top floor,
and it's smaller
than the service elevator.
It was well-known
Zero Moustafa had purchased
and famously inhabited
some of the most lavish
castles
and palazzos
on the continent.
Yet here, in his own
nearly empty hotel,
he occupied
a servant's quarters?
(choking)
At that moment,
the curtain rose
on a parenthetical
domestic drama...
Shit.
...which required
the immediate
and complete attention
of Monsieur Jean...
(choking)
(dog barking)
...but frankly,
did not hold mine for long.
(elevator bell dings,
dog barks)
However,
this premature intermission
in the story
of the curious old man
had left me,
as the expression goes,
"gespannt
wie ein Flitzebogen."
That is,
"on the edge of my seat,"
where I remained throughout
the next morning until--
in what I found to be
its mysterious
and utterly reliable
fashion--
fate, once again,
intervened on my behalf.
MR. MOUSTAFA:
I admire your work.
I beg your pardon?
I said, I know and admire
your wonderful work.
Thank you most kindly, sir.
Did Monsieur Jean have a word
or two to share with you
about the... aged proprietor
of this establishment?
I must confess, I did myself...
inquire about you.
He's perfectly capable,
of course, Monsieur Jean,
but we can't claim
he's a first-,
or in earnest,
even a second-rate concierge,
but there it is.
Times have changed.
The thermal baths
are very beautiful.
They were, in their
first condition.
It couldn't be maintained,
of course.
Too decadent
for current tastes,
but I love it all just the same,
this enchanting old ruin.
How did you come to buy it,
if I may ask?
The Grand Budapest.
(grunts)
(clunking, water sloshing)
I didn't.
(water spraying)
(indistinct, distant shouting)
(man shouting)
(shouts echoing from distance)
If you're not merely
being polite--
and you must tell me
if that's the case--
but if it genuinely
does interest you,
may I invite you to dine
with me tonight?
And it will be my pleasure
and indeed, my privilege,
to tell you
my story, such as it is.
(Mr. Moustafa speaking
indistinctly)
Two ducks roasted
with olives, rabbit,
salad?
(grunts)
Pouilly-Jouvet '52.
Plus a split of the brute.
(snaps)
That should provide us
ample time,
if I commence promptly.
By all means.
(cork pops)
♪
(chuckles)
Well, it begins, as it must,
with our mutual friend's
predecessor,
the beloved original concierge
of the Grand Budapest.
It begins, of course, with...
(wind blowing gently)
(knocking on door)
Bring the table to the window.
Yes, Monsieur Gustave.
Bring the tray to the table.
Right away,
Monsieur Gustave.
Right there.
Have those been brushed
and blocked?
Of course,
Monsieur Gustave.
Pack them in the hatboxes.
Is that
from Oberstdorf & Company?
I believe so,
Monsieur Gustave.
Second trunk.
Who has the tickets?
I do, Monsieur Gustave.
Give them to me.
These are in order.
Wait in the corner.
I'm not leaving.
I beg your pardon?
Why not?
I'm frightened.
Of what?
I fear this may be the last time
we ever see each other.
Why on earth would
that be the case?
Well, I can't put it into words,
but I feel it.
Well, for goodness sake,
there's no reason for you
to leave us.
If you'd rather...
Come with me.
To fucking Lutz?
Please?
Give me your hand.
You've nothing to fear.
You're always anxious
before you travel.
I admit you appear to be
suffering a more acute attack
on this occasion, but
truly and honestly...
Oh, dear God, what have you
done to your fingernails?
I beg your pardon?
This diabolical varnish.
The color is
completely wrong.
Oh, really?
Don't you like it?
It's not that
I don't like it.
I-I am physically repulsed.
Perhaps this
will soothe you.
What?
"While questing
once in..."
Don't recite.
Just listen to the words.
Please, not now.
Hush.
"While questing once in noble
wood of gray, medieval pine,
"I came upon a tomb,
rain-slick'd,
"rubbed-cool, ethereal;
"its inscription
long-vanished,
yet still within its
melancholy fissures..."
MADAME D.:
Will you light a candle
for me, please?
In the sacristy of Santa Maria?
I'll see to it myself,
immediately.
Remember... I'm always with you.
I love you.
I love you. Abfahren!
(engine revving)
It's quite a thing,
winning the loyalty
of a woman like that
for 19 consecutive seasons.
Um, yes, sir.
She's very fond
of me, you know.
Yes, sir.
I've never seen her
like that before.
No, sir.
She was shaking
like a shitting dog.
Truly.
Run to the cathedral of
Santa Maria in Brucknerplatz.
Buy one of the plain,
half-length candles
and take back four
Klubecks in change.
Light it in the sacristy,
say a brief rosary,
then go to Mendl's and get
me a courtesan au chocolat.
If there's any money left,
give it to the crippled
shoe-shine boy.
(spits)
Right away, sir.
Hold it.
Who are you?
I'm Zero, sir,
the new lobby boy.
Zero, you say?
Yes, sir.
Well, I've never
heard of you,
never laid eyes on you.
Who hired you?
Mr. Mosher, sir.
Mr. Mosher!
Yes, Monsieur Gustave?
Am I to understand
you've surreptitiously
hired this young man
in the position
of a lobby boy?
He's been engaged
for a trial period,
pending your approval,
of course.
Uh, perhaps, yes.
Thank you, Mr. Mosher.
You're most welcome,
Monsieur Gustave.
You're now going to be
officially interviewed.
Uh, should I go and light
the candle first, sir?
What? No.
The candle.
(door squeaks)
Experience?
Hotel Kinski,
kitchen boy, six months.
Hotel Berlitz, mop and
broom boy, three months.
Before that I was
a skillet scrubber...
Experience: zero.
Thank you again,
Monsieur Gustave.
Straighten that cap, Anatole.
The pleasure's mine,
Herr Schneider.
The strap's busted.
These are not acceptable.
I fully agree.
Education?
I studied reading
and spelling.
I-I started my
primary school.
I almost...
Education: zero.
Now it's exploded.
Good morning, Cicero.
Call the goddamn plumber.
This afternoon,
Monsieur Gustave.
Without fail, Frau Liebling.
What in the hell
is this?
Not now.
Family?
Zero.
Six, Igor.
Why do you want to be
a lobby boy?
Well, who wouldn't
at the Grand Budapest, sir?
It's an institution.
Very good.
(laughs quietly)
A thousand Klubecks.
My goodness.
Were you ever
a lobby boy, sir?
What do you think?
Well, I suppose you'd
have to start somewhere.
I mean, you couldn't...
Oh, go light
the goddamn candle.
Yes, sir.
(door creaks open)
MR. MOUSTAFA:
And so my life began.
Junior lobby boy
in training,
Grand Budapest Hotel,
under the strict command
of Monsieur Gustave H.
I became his pupil,
and he was to be
my counselor and guardian.
GUSTAVE:
What is a lobby boy?
A lobby boy
is completely invisible,
yet always in sight.
A lobby boy remembers
what people hate.
A lobby boy anticipates
the client's needs
before the needs are needed.
A lobby boy is, above all,
discrete to a fault.
Our guests know their
deepest secrets--
some of which are,
frankly, rather unseemly--
will go with us
to our graves.
So keep your mouth
shut, Zero.
Yes, sir.
That's all for now.
MR. MOUSTAFA:
I began to realize
that many of the hotel's
most valued
and distinguished guests
came for him.
It seemed to be an essential
part of his duties,
(Gustave laughs)
but I believe
it was also his pleasure.
The requirements
were always the same.
They had to be rich, old,
insecure, vain, superficial,
blond, needy.
Why blond?
Because they all were.
He was, by the way,
the most liberally perfumed
man I had ever encountered.
The scent announced
his approach
from a great distance
and lingered for many minutes
after he was gone.
(sniffing)
I worked six days each week,
plus a half-day Sunday,
5:00 a.m.
until just after midnight.
Our meals were small,
but frequent for stamina.
Two breakfasts, two lunches,
and a late supper.
Monsieur Gustave also
delivered a nightly sermon.
Rudeness is merely
the expression of fear.
People fear they won't get
what they want.
The most dreadful
and unattractive person
only needs to be loved,
and they will open up
like a flower.
I'm reminded of a verse.
"The painter's brush touched
the inchoate face
"by ends of nimble bristles,
"and with their
blush of first color,
rendered her lifeless
cheek living."
MR. MOUSTAFA:
His own dinner,
he took alone in his room.
♪
(teakettle whistling)
The identity of the owner
of the hotel
was unknown to all of us.
Each month, his emissary,
known as
Deputy Kovacs, arrived
to review the books
and convey messages
on behalf of
the mysterious proprietor.
On these occasions,
Monsieur Gustave
and our business manager,
Herr Becker, met with him
in private consultation
above reception.
This was also
when I met Agatha.
(sighs)
♪
But we won't discuss that.
(rustling)
(door closes)
(snow crunching underfoot)
♪
What do you want?
Look.
GUSTAVE:
Dear God.
I'm terribly sorry, sir.
We must go to her.
We-we must?
Tout de suite.
She needs me, and I need you,
to help me with my bags
and so on.
WOMAN: Tout va bien?
Attendez-moi, darling.
How fast can you pack?
Five minutes.
Do it, and bring a bottle
of the Pouilly-Jouvet '26
in an ice bucket
with two glasses,
so we don't have to drink
the cat piss
they serve in the dining car.
ZERO: Yeah...
I blame myself.
She tried to tell me
she had a premonition.
I didn't listen.
All of Lutz will be dressed in
black, except her own ghastly,
deceitful children,
whom she loathed
and couldn't bear to kiss hello.
They'll be dancing like gypsies.
There's really no point
in doing anything in life,
because it's all over
in the blink of an eye--
and the next thing you know,
rigor mortis sets in.
Oh, how the good die young.
With any luck,
she's left a few Klubecks
for your old friend,
but one never knows
until the ink is dry
on the death certificate.
She was dynamite in the sack,
by the way.
She was 84, Monsieur Gustave.
I've had older.
When you're young,
it's all fillet steak,
but as the years go by,
you have to move on
to the cheaper cuts,
which is fine with me,
because I like those.
More flavorful,
or so they say.
(brakes squealing)
Why are we stopping
at a barley field?
(militia shouting orders
indistinctly)
Well, hello there, chaps.
Documents please.
With pleasure.
It's not a very
flattering portrait, I'm afraid.
I was once considered
a great beauty.
What's the "F" stand for?
Fritz? Franz?
Franz.
I knew it!
He's making a funny face.
That's a Migratory Visa
with Stage Three Worker
Status, Franz, darling.
He's with me.
Come outside, please.
Now, wait a minute.
Sit down, Zero.
His papers are in order;
I cross-referenced them myself
with the Bureau of Labor
and Servitude.
You can't arrest him simply
because he's a bloody immigrant.
He hasn't done anything wrong.
Stop it!
Damn you, damn you.
Never mind,
Monsieur Gustave.
Let them proceed.
Ow! That hurt!
(grunting in pain)
You filthy goddamn, pockmarked,
fascist assholes!
Take your hands
off my lobby boy!
(train whistle blows)
(door thumps open)
What's the problem?
This is outrageous.
The young man works for me
at the Grand Budapest Hotel
in Nebelsbad.
Monsieur Gustave?
My name is Henckles.
I'm the son of
Dr. and Mrs. Wolfgang
Henckles-Bergersdorfer.
Do you remember me?
I know exactly who you are.
It's uncanny.
You're little Albert.
I'm terribly embarrassed.
Release them.
Release them!
Hmm.
Your colleague is stateless.
He'll need to apply for a
revised Special Transit Permit,
which, at this point,
may be very difficult
to acquire.
Take this.
It's temporary,
but that's the best I
can offer, I'm afraid.
And how's your
wonderful mother?
She's very well, thank you.
Yeah, I adore her.
Send my love.
I will.
Your companion
was very kind to me
when I was a lonely little boy.
My men and I apologize
for disturbing you.
I beg your pardon, sir.
(clicks heels together)
(door closes)
(train engine chugging)
You see, there are
still faint glimmers
of civilization left in this
barbaric slaughterhouse
that was once known
as humanity.
Indeed, that's what
we provide,
in our own modest,
humble, insignificant...
Oh, fuck it.
♪
Where is she, Clotilde?
Take me to her.
♪
You're looking so well, darling.
You really are.
They've done a marvelous job.
I don't know what sort of cream
they've put on you
down at the morgue,
but I want some.
Honestly, you look better
than you have in years.
You look like you're alive.
(sighs)
Oh, you changed it after all.
It's perfect.
Clotilde?
Oui, Monsieur Gustave?
A glass of chilled water
with no ice, please?
(speaking French)
and, also, M. Serge would like to speak
with you privately in his office, please.
Wait here quietly, please.
Oh.
All right then.
I shan't be long, darling.
MR. MOUSTAFA:
We were escorted
through a green baize door,
down a narrow
service corridor,
and into
the butler's pantry.
A moment later, the
kitchen passage swung open,
and a small servant
dressed in white
jolted into the room.
I've never forgotten
the look on that man's face.
What the devil is going on?
I myself had never set foot
inside a house of this kind
in my life.
I understood very little
about the events
that were to follow,
but eventually,
I came to recognize
when the destiny of a
great fortune is at stake,
men's greed spreads
like a poison
in the bloodstream.
Uncles, nephews, cousins,
in-laws of increasingly
tenuous connection.
The old woman's
most distant relations
had come foraging
out of the woodwork.
At the head
of this congregation--
it was
a disorienting coincidence--
we discovered
our own Deputy Kovacs,
himself an important
attorney, of course.
He was the executor
of the dead widow's estate.
(murmuring quiets)
This is Madame D.'s
last will and testament.
It consists of a general tontine
drawn up before the event
of her husband's death
46 years ago.
In combination
with 635 amendments,
notations, corrections
and letters of wishes
executed during
these subsequent decades.
The ultimate legality
of this accumulation
requires further analysis,
but in the opinion
of this office,
it was Madame D.'s intention
that control of the vast bulk
of her estate
should be transferred,
forthwith,
to her son Dmitri,
with special allowances
for his sisters
Marguerite,
Laetizia and Carolina,
and minor gifts
for various members
of the extended family,
as shown in the list
of recipients,
which I will elucidate
in due course.
(murmuring)
However...
...an additional codicil,
delivered into
my possession by post
only this morning,
and by all indications,
sent by Madame D.
during the last
hours of her life,
contains an amendment to
the original certificate,
which, as prescribed by law,
I will read to you now.
The authenticity
of this document
has not yet been confirmed
by the presiding magistrate,
so I ask that all parties
be patient
and refrain from comment
until such time
as our investigations
can be completed.
(knuckles cracking)
"To my esteemed friend,
"who comforted me
in my later years
"and brought sunshine
into the life of an old woman
"who thought that
she would never be happy again,
Monsieur Gustave H.--"
"...I bequeath, bestow and
devise, free of all taxation,
"and with full and absolute
fiduciary entitlement
the painting known
as Boy with Apple..."
(quietly): Wow.
"...by Johannes van Hoytl..."
I can't believe it
"...the younger..."
What?
"...which gave us both
so much pleasure..."
The van Hoytl?
Tax-free?
Can she do that?
Who's Gustave H.?
I'm afraid that's me, darling.
DMITRI:
That fucking faggot!
He's a concierge!
What are you doing here?
I've come to pay my respects
to a great woman whom I loved.
This man is an intruder
in my home.
It's not yours yet, Dmitri.
Only when probate is granted
and the Deed of Entitlement...
You're not getting
Boy with Apple,
you goddamn little fruit.
(stammers quietly)
How is that supposed
to make me feel?
Call the police!
We're pressing charges.
This criminal has plagued
my family for nearly 20 years.
He's a ruthless adventurer
and a con artist
who preys on mentally feeble,
sick old ladies,
and he probably fucks them, too.
I go to bed with all my friends.
(crowd gasping)
(grunts, gasping continues)
Where's Céline?
What?
She's dead.
We're reading her will.
Oh, yes, yes, of course.
If I learn you ever once laid
a finger on my mother's body,
living or dead,
I swear to God,
I'll cut your throat.
You hear me?!
I thought I was supposed
to be a fucking faggot.
You are, but you're bisexual.
Let's change the subject.
I'm leaving.
(speaking French)
That picture, Boy with Apple,
M. Gustave?
is priceless, understand?
Congratulations,
Monsieur Gustave.
They're gonna fight me
for the son of a bitch.
Is it very beautiful?
Beyond description.
"E'en the most gifted
bard's rhyme can only sing
"but to the lack of her
and all she isn't.
His tongue doth..."
Can I see it?
I don't see why not.
(door opens, closes)
♪
This is van Hoytl's
exquisite portrayal
of a beautiful boy
on the cusp of manhood.
Blond, smooth,
skin as white as that milk.
Of impeccable provenance.
One of the last
in private hands,
and unquestionably the best.
It's a masterpiece.
The rest of this shit
is worthless junk.
♪
Can I help you?
Yes, Serge.
You can wrap this up, please.
Wrap up... Wrap up
... "Boy with Apple"?
♪
What did you want
to tell me?
Before?
I think I cannot
say right now.
Write me tomorrow.
Lutzbahn Station.
(engine starts, revs)
GUSTAVE:
I'll never part with it.
It reminded her of me.
It will remind me
of her always.
I'll die with this picture
above my bed.
See the resemblance?
Uh, oh, yes.
Actually, we should sell it,
sooner rather than later,
in case they try
to steal it back.
Plus, something about
those lunatic foot soldiers
on the Express, I think
this could be a tricky war
and a long dry spell
in the hotel trade.
For all we know, they could
board us up tomorrow.
Let's make
a solemn blood pact.
We'll contact
the black market
and liquidate Boy with Apple
by the end of the week,
then leave the country
and lay low
somewhere along
the Maltese Riviera
until the troubles blow over
and we resume our posts.
In exchange for your help,
your loyalty,
and your services
as my personal valet,
I pledge to you 1.5%
of the net sales price.
1.5?
Plus room and board.
Couldn't make it ten?
Ten? Are you joking?
That's more than I'd pay
an actual dealer,
and you wouldn't know
chiaroscuro
from chicken giblets.
No, 1.5 is correct,
but I'll tell you what,
if I die first,
and I most certainly will,
you will be my sole heir.
There's not much
in the kitty,
except a set
of ivory-backed hairbrushes
and my library
of romantic poetry,
but when the time comes,
these will be yours.
Along with whatever
we haven't already spent
on whores and whiskey.
This is our sacred bond.
I'll draw it up
right now.
I, Monsieur Gustave H.,
being of relatively sound mind
and body on this day,
the 19th of October
in the year of our Lord, 1932...
MR. MOUSTAFA:
He never told me
where he came from.
I never asked
who his family had been.
(train crossing bell
dinging in distance)
(latch clicks)
(handle squeaks)
(knocking)
Excuse me.
GUSTAVE:
Uh-huh?
The police are here.
They asked for you.
Tell them I'll be right there.
Okay.
(door closes)
Have you ever been questioned
by the authorities?
Yes, on one occasion.
What? For what?
I was arrested and tortured
by the rebel militia
after the Desert Uprising.
Mm-hmm. Right. Well, you know
the drill then: Zip it.
Of course.
You've never heard
the word van Hoytl
in your life.
Got it.
Okay, let's go.
(door opens)
(Henckles sighs)
How may we serve you, gentlemen?
Ah, Inspector Henckles...
By order
of the commissioner of police
Zubrowka Province,
I hereby place you under arrest
for the murder of Madame Céline
Villeneuve Desgoffe und Taxis.
I knew there was
something fishy.
We never got the cause of death.
She's been murdered,
and you think I did it.
Hey!
Stop!
♪
(wind howling)
(gears rattling)
(thud, man whistles)
(door closes)
What happened?
What happened, my dear Zero,
is I beat the living shit
out of a sniveling little runt
called Pinky Bandinski,
who had the gall
to question my virility,
because if there's one thing
we've learned
from penny dreadfuls,
it's that when you find yourself
in a place like this,
you must never be a candy-ass.
You've got to prove yourself
from day one.
You've got to win
their respect.
You should take a long look
at his ugly mug this morning.
(wry chuckle)
He's actually become
a dear friend.
You'll meet him, I hope.
So.
You've talked to Kovacs?
I saw him last night in secret.
He made me take an oath on
a Bible I wouldn't tell a soul.
You're supposed to also.
I'll do that later.
He suspects you're innocent.
Of course he does.
What's the charge?
In the small hours
of the evening of 19 October,
an individual well-known
to the house and staff,
a Monsieur Gustave H.,
did arrive at the Desgoffe
und Taxis residence
in Lutz and entered
by the rear service alley,
alerting no one to his presence,
and did then proceed by way
of back stairs
and servants' passage,
to deliver himself
into the private chambers
of Madame D.
There is no evidence
to indicate whether this visit
had been pre-arranged
with her or not.
The next morning,
Madame D. was found dead
by strychnine poisoning.
Monsieur Gustave was not
observed on the premises again
until, of course,
24 hours later.
The identity of his accusers
is made clear
in this notarized deposition.
They include, essentially,
all members
of the extended family,
but the key witness
who actually, ostensibly,
saw the alleged events,
appears to have fled
the jurisdiction.
His whereabouts
are currently unknown,
but he's being sought
and pursued
by the relevant authorities.
Who is he?
Serge?
I'm afraid so.
That little prick.
No, I don't believe it.
They put him up to it.
I've been dropped
into a nest of vipers.
You have an alibi?
Of course, but she's married
to the Duke of Westfalia.
I can't allow her name
to get mixed up in all
this monkey business.
Monsieur Gustave,
your life may be at stake.
I know, but the bitch legged it.
She's already onboard
the Queen Nasstasja
halfway to Dutch Tanganyika.
Don't give up.
MR. MOUSTAFA:
The details of the conspiracy,
now a matter of public record,
were, at that time, impossible
for us to apprehend.
I'm looking for Serge X.,
a young man
in the service of my employer,
the family Desgoffe und Taxis
of Schloss Lutz.
Yes, sir?
You're his sister?
Yes, sir.
Seen him lately?
No, sir.
No... sir?
N-No, sir.
I need to find him right away,
for his own safety and
everybody else's.
If he shows up...
Yes, sir?
Tell him Jopling
says, "Come home."
MR. MOUSTAFA:
But one thing was certain.
The Desgoffe und Taxis
were a very powerful family...
...and time
was not on our side.
(indistinct conversations)
(knocking on podium)
A letter from Monsieur Gustave.
Zero.
Uh, you want me to...
Read it.
(clears throat)
"My dear
and trusted colleagues..."
I miss you deeply
as I write from the confines
of my regrettable
and preposterous incarceration.
Until I walk amongst you again
as a free man,
the Grand Budapest remains
in your hands,
as does
its impeccable reputation.
Keep it spotless and glorify it.
Take extra special care
of every little-bitty bit of it
as if I were watching over you
like a hawk with a horse-whip
in its talons,
because I am.
Should I discover a lapse of
any variety during my absence,
I promise swift
and merciless justice
will descend upon you.
A great and noble house has been
placed under your protection.
Tell Zero if you see
any funny business.
"Your devoted Monsieur Gustave."
Then there's a poem,
but we might want to go ahead
and start on the soup,
since it's 46 stanzas.
(dinnerware clinking)
"A moist, black ash dampens
the filth
"of a dung-dark rat's nest
and mingles
"with the thick scent
of wood rot
while the lark song
of a guttersnipe..."
JOPLING:
I never trusted that butler.
(knuckles crack)
He's too honest.
DMITRI (over phone):
Too honest, you say?
Mm-hmm.
Uh-huh. Right, well,
be that as it may,
find him quick
and make it snappy.
(door clanks shut)
(cart rattling)
May I offer any of you inmates
a plate of mush?
No? Anyone?
You, with the very large scar
on your face?
Oh, come now. Try it.
It's actually quite warm
and nourishing this morning.
It needs a dash of salt.
Good day.
Mush, gents?
Any takers?
Suit yourselves.
Rise and shine. Chop-chop.
Good morning, Pinky.
Mendl's again?
Precisely.
Who's got the throat slitter?
Out of this world.
GUSTAVE:
Mendl's is the best. Well...
back to work.
Monsieur Gustave?
Yes?
(door creaks shut)
(clears throat)
Me and the boys
talked it over.
We think you're
a really straight fellow.
Well, I've never been accused
of that before,
but I appreciate the sentiment.
You're one of us now.
What a lovely thing to say.
Thank you, dear Pinky.
Thank you, Gunther.
Thank you, Wolf.
Anything else?
Tell him, Ludwig.
Checkpoint 19
ain't no two-bit hoosegow.
You got broad-gauge iron bars
on every door, vent and window.
You got 72 guards on the floor
and 16 more in the towers.
You got a 325-foot drop
into a moat full of crocodiles.
But, like the best of 'em,
it's got a soft spot,
which, in this case,
happens to take the form
of a storm-drain sewer system
dating from the time of
the original rock fortification,
way back in the Middle Ages.
Now, nobody's saying
it's a stroll
down a tree-lined promenade
with a fine lady
and a white poodle,
but it's got what
you'd call "vulnerability,"
and that's our bread and butter.
Take a look.
Who drew this?
What do you mean,
"Who drew this?" I did.
Very good; you've got
a wonderful line, Ludwig.
This shows
great artistic promise.
Question: how do you intend to
penetrate this lowest rudiment?
It's 25 inches of reinforced
granite masonry, is it not?
Digging with the throat-slitter,
I expect this would take
three to six months
of continual effort,
during which time
several of our members
will have been
violently executed.
You hit the nail on the head,
Mr. Gustave.
We got fake documents,
second-hand street clothes,
a rope ladder made
of sticks and bunk-linens,
but we need digging tools,
which are proving hard
to come by in this flophouse.
YOUNG WRITER:
At this point in the story,
the old man fell silent
and pushed away
his saddle of lamb.
His eyes went blank
as two stones.
I could see
he was in distress.
Are you ill, Mr. Moustafa?
I finally asked.
Oh, dear me, no.
He said.
It's only that I don't know
how to proceed.
He was crying.
You see,
I never speak of Agatha,
because even at the thought
of her name
I'm unable to control
my emotions.
Well, I suppose there's no way
around it.
You see, she saved us.
On our third
formal rendezvous,
I had asked for her hand in
marriage and she had agreed.
Will you marry me?
Yes.
We did not have 50 Klubecks
between the two of us.
No one knew, of course, but
then, who would have cared?
We were each completely
on our own in the world,
and we were deeply in love.
(carousel music playing)
Here.
Thank you.
It's a book.
I see.
Romantic Poetry,
Volume One.
Monsieur Gustave
recommended it.
I have a copy
of my own as well.
I ruined the surprise,
I suppose.
I'll go ahead and
open it anyway.
Okay.
Read the inscription.
♪
MR. MOUSTAFA:
Monsieur Gustave insisted
on an immediate and thorough
cross-examination...
She's charming.
She's so charming.
...during which
he presented Agatha
with a porcelain pendant
and five dozen
individually tissue-wrapped
white tulips
in a box the size
of a child's coffin.
It's not right.
I beg your pardon?
Why is he sulking?
She's my girlfriend;
you can't just buy her things.
I'm only interviewing
this vision
of loveliness
on your behalf.
Never be jealous in this life,
Zero, not even for an instant.
Is he flirting with you?
Yes.
I approve of this union.
Agatha, my beauty,
return to your beloved.
MR. MOUSTAFA:
Soon we learned...
GUSTAVE:
Blessings upon you both.
...not only was Agatha
immensely skilled
with a palette knife and
a butter-cream flourish...
Mendl.
(whispering):
Go, go.
...she was also very brave.
I believe she was born
that way.
(mechanical whirring)
Something's missing.
A crucial document,
either misplaced or,
conceivably, destroyed.
I don't know what it contains,
I don't know what it represents,
I don't know what it is,
but there are traces
and shadows of it everywhere.
Now, I don't want to alarm you,
and I don't expect
to see any significant change
in the magistrate's
ultimate decision
vis-à-vis your own inheritance;
but especially given
the circumstances of the death
as well as the disappearance
of the key witness
in the murder case,
Serge X.,
I suggest that we immediately
bring this matter
to the attention
of the municipal inspector
so there can be
absolutely no question
of impropriety
at any future date.
Agreed?
Not agreed.
Not agreed?
Can I ask you
a question, Vilmos?
Yes, Dmitri?
Who are you working for?
I beg your pardon?
I thought you're supposed
to be our lawyer.
Well, in point of fact,
I'm the executor of the estate.
In this particular situation,
I represent the deceased.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah, a provision for my fees
was included in the...
Just wrap it up
and don't make waves.
Agreed?
I'm an attorney, Dmitri.
I'm obligated to proceed
according to the rule of law.
Not agreed.
This stinks, sisters.
(cat yowls)
Did he just throw my cat
out the window?
I don't think so.
No. Did he?
Jopling?
(scraping)
(door creaks in distance)
Shh.
(approaching footsteps
echoing)
(man sneezes nearby)
(footsteps depart)
Okay.
(scraping, tapping resume)
There's something I
haven't told you, Agatha.
Okay.
We stole a painting.
It's very valuable, maybe five
million Klubecks, in fact.
I don't know if anyone's even
noticed it's missing yet,
but if something should happen
to me and Monsieur Gustave...
You steal art?
One picture.
Anyway, we need to make
a plan for your survival.
Hide this.
It's in code and you might need
a magnifying glass to read it,
but it tells you
exactly where and how
to find Boy with Apple.
Don't take less than half
the retail asking price.
Also...
Zero, I'm a baker.
You're a pastry chef.
I'm not a middleman.
One of the best
in the region.
I'm not a fence
if that's the term.
I don't trade
in stolen property.
I said it wrong.
She willed it to him.
(footsteps approaching)
Go to sleep.
Yes, Herr Mendl.
(door closes)
Hide this.
No.
Okay, but take it anyway.
(bell tolling in distance)
♪
(whistle toots)
(door creaks open,
footsteps echoing)
♪
(door creaks open,
footsteps echoing)
♪
(footsteps echoing)
(sudden scream, thud)
♪
(bell tolling distantly)
(bell continues tolling)
MR. MOUSTAFA:
The next morning,
Herr Becker received
a peculiar
last-minute notice from
the office of Deputy Kovacs
postponing
their scheduled meeting...
in perpetuity.
(car door closes)
(footsteps approaching)
(door opens distantly)
(bell ringing)
LUDWIG:
Let's blow.
(pulley squeaking)
(grunting)
♪
(indistinct whispering)
How did you get out there?
Shut the fuck up.
These guys are trying to escape.
What's wrong with you,
you goddamn snitch?
Guard! Guard! G... (choking)
(thud)
GUSTAVE:
It's you.
Thank you, thank you,
you sweet, kind man.
♪
(tapping, filing)
LUDWIG:
Okay.
(grunting)
♪
(wind whistling)
(grunts)
(convicts gasp)
(guard shouts in German)
(guard continues shouting)
(convict grunting)
(screams)
(groans)
(sighs)
I suppose you'd call
that a draw.
(muffled clank)
Good evening.
(speaks indistinctly)
(groans)
Let me introduce you.
Pinky, Wolf, Ludwig,
this is the divine Zero.
Gunther was slain
in the catacombs.
Well, boys, who knows
when we'll all meet again,
but if, one day...
(car approaching)
Hold it.
No time to gab.
Take care of yourself,
Mr. Gustave.
Good luck, kid.
(sighs)
Which way to the safe house?
I-I couldn't find one.
No safe house?
Really? We're completely
on our own out here?
I'm afraid so.
I-I asked around, but,
uh... (muttering)
I understand.
Too risky.
We'll just have to
wing it, I suppose.
Let's put on our disguises.
We're wearing them.
No-no, we're not.
We said false whiskers
and fake noses and so on.
You didn't bring any?
I-I thought you
were growing one.
And it wouldn't...
it wouldn't look
realistic, would it?
No, when done properly,
they're perfectly convincing.
But I-I take your point.
So be it.
GUSTAVE:
Give-give me a few squirts
of L'air de Panache,
please, will you?
(man yells)
(distant clank)
Well, can I...
can I not get a squirt, even?
I forgot the
L'air de Panache.
Honestly, you forgot
the L'air de Panache?
I don't believe it.
I mean, how could you?
I've been in jail, Zero.
Do you understand how
humiliating this is?
I smell.
(sniffs)
(wry laugh) That's just
marvelous, isn't it?
I suppose this is
to be expected back in...
Where do you come from again?
Aq Salim al-Jabat.
Precisely.
I suppose this is to be expected
back in Aq Salim al-Jabat,
where one's prized possessions
are a stack of filthy carpets
and a starving goat,
and one sleeps
behind a tent flap and survives
on wild dates and scarabs,
but it's not
how I trained you.
What on God's earth possessed
you to leave the homeland,
where you very obviously belong,
and travel unspeakable distances
to become a penniless immigrant
in a refined,
highly-cultivated society that,
quite frankly, could've gotten
along very well without you?
The war.
Say again?
Well, you see,
my father was murdered
and the rest of my family
were executed by firing squad.
Our village was burned
to the ground,
and those who managed to survive
were forced to flee.
I left because of the war.
I see.
So you're-you're, actually,
really more of a-a refugee,
in that sense?
Truly.
Well, I suppose
I better take back
everything I just said.
What a bloody idiot I am.
Pathetic fool.
Goddamn, selfish bastard.
This is disgraceful,
and it's beneath the standards
of the Grand Budapest.
(gasps)
I apologize on behalf
of the hotel.
It's not your fault,
Monsieur Gustave.
You were just upset
I forgot the perfume.
Don't make excuses for me.
I owe you my life.
You are my dear friend
and protégé,
and I am very proud of you.
You must know that.
I'm so sorry, Zero.
We're brothers.
How's our darling Agatha?
"'Twas first light when I
saw her face upon the heath;
"and hence did I return,
day-by-day, entranced:
tho' vinegar did brine
my heart, never..."
(siren wailing)
Very good.
I'm going to stop you there
because the alarm has sounded,
but remember where we left off
because I insist
you finish later.
♪
(police whistle blowing)
I want roadblocks
at every junction
for 50 kilometers.
I want rail blocks
at every train station
for 100 kilometers.
I want 50 men
and ten bloodhounds
ready in five minutes.
We're going to strip-search
every pretzel-haus, waffel-hut,
biergarten and especially
every grand hotel
from Augenzburg to Zilchbruck.
These men are dangerous,
professional criminals.
At least three
of them are, anyway.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Civilian personnel
aren't permitted
in the cellblock.
This is a military
investigation.
This is Mr. Jopling, sir.
His employer's mother was
one of the victims of the...
Shut up.
You work for the family
Desgoffe und Taxis?
Are you aware of the murder
of Deputy Vilmos Kovacs
on the 23 of October?
I'm aware of his
disappearance.
His body was found stuffed
in a sarcophagus
behind a storage room at
the Kunstmuseum late last night.
He was short four fingers.
What do you know
about that?
Nothing.
Escort Mr. Jopling
off the premises.
(rattling)
Mendl's.
GUSTAVE:
Operator, get me
the Excelsior Palace
in Baden-Jurgen
and reverse the
charges, please.
We've no choice; there's
nowhere else to turn.
I'll hold. Thank you.
It's our only hope.
Otherwise, I shouldn't even
mention its existence to you.
It goes without saying,
you must never breathe a word
about this to a living soul.
Do you swear?
Of course.
What is it, in fact?
I can't say.
Guten Abend. Monsieur
Ivan, bitte. Danke.
How does one come by
front-row aisle seats
for a first night
at the Opera Toscana
with one day's notice?
How does one arrange
a private viewing
of the tapestry collection
at the Royal Saxon Gallery?
How does one secure
a corner table
at Chez Dominique on a Thursday?
Ivan, darling,
it's Gustave. Hello.
Well, I was until
about five minutes ago.
We've taken it
upon ourselves
to clear out in a hurry,
if you see what I mean.
Well, through a sewer,
as it happens.
Exactly. Listen, Ivan,
I'm sorry to cut you off,
but we're in a bit of a bind.
This is an official request.
I'm formally calling
upon the special services of...
IVAN:
I'll call you back, Gustave.
Right. Stand by.
I beg your pardon.
Do you prefer to walk?
We're right here.
It's very simple.
Straight down the corniche,
then left.
Jojo, see the gentleman out.
Get me Monsieur Georges
at the Chateau Luxe, please.
(phone rings)
ALL:
♪ Happy birthday to you
Take over.
♪ Happy birthday, dear...
Hello, Ivan?
Got it.
Get me Monsieur Dino at
the Palazzo Principessa, please.
(phone rings)
(rattling)
Higher, goddamm it, higher!
(speaking indistinctly)
Take over.
Monsieur Georges.
Higher!
I see.
Straightaway.
Get me Monsieur Robin
at l'Hotel Cote du Cap, please.
(phone rings)
(seabirds squawking)
...and two and three.
Monsieur Robin.
There's a call from
Monsieur Dino for you.
Take over.
One and two and three.
MONSIEUR ROBIN:
Yes, Dino.
Okay, Dino.
Get me Monsieur Martin
at the Ritz Imperial, please.
(phone rings)
Too much salt.
Not enough pepper.
(whispering)
Take over.
Robin? Martin.
Too much salt.
So I've heard.
Maybe.
Let me make a few calls.
(humming)
Serge X.: missing.
Deputy Kovacs: also missing.
Madame D.: dead.
Boy with Apple:
stolen, by us.
Dmitri and Jopling:
ruthless, cold-blooded savages.
Gustave H.: at large.
What else?
Zero: confused.
Zero: confused, indeed.
The plot thickens,
as they say.
Why, by the way?
Is it a soup metaphor?
I don't know.
(horn honks distantly)
Get in!
IVAN:
We found the butler.
He's hiding out
in the remote foothills
near Gabelmeister's Peak.
Our contact convinced him
to meet you
midday tomorrow at
the observatory on the summit.
Tell no one.
He'll explain everything.
Your train departs
in four and a half minutes.
Here's your tickets.
Oh, third class?
It was overbooked,
but the conductor used to be
a sommelier
at the old Versailles.
He pulled some strings.
You'll need these
for the dining car.
Oh, one last thing.
L'air de Panache.
They only had the half-ounce.
We should give him something
as a symbolic gesture.
How much money you got?
42 Klubecks and three
postage stamps.
Give me 25.
Yes.
Bless you.
Please.
(train engine chugging,
wheels squeaking to a stop)
♪
JOPLING:
I gotta to hand it to him.
DMITRI (over phone):
Jesus Christ.
JOPLING:
I didn't see that coming.
Hmm.
Well, what do you want next?
DMITRI: Talk to the
clubfooted sister again,
and this time... be persuasive.
(door slams distantly)
DMITRI:
Goddamn son of a bitch.
(clattering)
(sighs softly)
Holy fuck!
What's the meaning of this shit?
Boy with Apple?
I thought you'd hidden it.
Why are you only noticing now?
It's been missing two weeks.
I assumed it went
to the tax appraiser.
Are you fucking kidding me?
MAID:
Excusez-moi.
I believe it was removed
by Monsieur Gustave.
I'm not angry with Serge.
You can't blame someone
for their basic lack
of moral fiber.
He's a frightened little
yellow-bellied coward.
It's not his fault, is it?
I don't know.
It depends.
Well, you can say that
about most anything.
"It depends."
Of course, it depends.
Of course it depends.
Yes, I suppose
you're right.
Of course it depends.
However, that doesn't mean
I'm not going
to throttle
the little swamp rat.
May I officiate,
by the way?
The ceremony?
With pleasure.
I must say, I find that girl
utterly delightful.
Flat as a board,
enormous birthmark the shape
of Mexico over half her face,
sweating for hours on end
in that sweltering kitchen
while Mendl,
genius though he is,
looms over her
like a hulking gorilla.
Yet without question,
without fail,
always and invariably,
she's exceedingly lovely.
Why?
Because of her purity.
She admires you, as well,
Monsieur Gustave.
Does she?
Very much.
That's a good sign, you know.
It means she gets it.
That's important.
Don't flirt with her.
(chicken clucks, coos quietly)
(grunts)
(chuckles)
(thumping)
♪
(panting)
(dogs barking distantly)
(latch clicks)
LIEUTENANT:
A radio telegram was delivered
and signed for
by the girl at 4:00 a.m.
The envelope was found
near the body,
but its contents were missing.
However,
the telegraph office
always keeps a carbon
of the ticker tape
for 24 hours.
I copied it down.
It reads as follows:
"Pack your things, stop.
"Be ready to leave
at moment's notice, stop.
"Hideout is vicinity
of Gabelmeister's Peak, stop.
Destroy this message;
all my love, full stop."
Where's the basket?
(lieutenant snaps fingers)
(clears throat)
♪
PUMP ATTENDANT:
Where you headed, mister?
Skiing? Sledding?
Mountain climbing?
(gas pump dings)
Three Klubecks.
(engine starts)
(train whistle blowing)
MR. MOUSTAFA:
By express wireless,
I wrote Agatha
with instructions
to move
to our pre-arranged hideout:
a Gypsy caravan
on the outer Nebelsbad road,
while Monsieur Gustave and I
continued east
into the Zubrowkian Alps,
toward our
high-altitude rendezvous
with the butler, Serge X.
As a precaution,
we disembarked quietly
in the freight yard
just outside the station.
(sniffing)
L'air de Panache.
It's a hell of a view.
I give them that,
for what's it's worth.
I agree.
(spraying)
"'Tis oft'-remarked:
"no single falling-flake
does any other
in its pure
and perfect form..."
Somebody's coming.
Are you Monsieur Gustave
of the Grand Budapest Hotel
in Nebelsbad?
Uh-huh.
Get on the next cable car.
♪
(squeaking, creaking)
(clanking, creaking)
Are you Monsieur Gustave
of the Grand Budapest Hotel
in Nebelsbad?
Uh-huh.
Switch with me.
♪
(latch clicks)
Are you Monsieur Gustave
of the Grand Budapest Hotel
in Nebelsbad?
Uh-huh.
Put these on and sing.
(monks singing)
(Gustave muttering,
singing a random melody)
♪
Psst.
Are you Monsieur Gustave
of the Grand Budapest...
Yes, damn it.
Confess.
I'm innocent.
Hmm? No, no.
(door closes)
Forgive me, Monsieur Gustave.
I never meant to betray you.
They threatened my life,
and now they've murdered
my only family.
No. Who'd they
kill this time?
My dear sister.
The girl with the clubfoot?
Yes.
Those fuckers!
I tried to warn you
at the beginning.
I know, darling.
Let's put that behind us.
Listen, I hate to put
you on the spot,
but I really must ask
you to clear my name.
Obviously you're grieving.
There's more.
Okay.
To the story.
I get it. Go on.
I was the official witness
in Madame D.'s presence
to the creation of a second will
to be executed only in the event
of her death by murder.
A second will?
Right.
In case she got bumped off?
Uh-huh?
But they destroyed it.
Oh, dear.
However...
Uh-huh?
I pulled a copy.
A second copy of
the second will?
Right.
Uh-huh?
Well, what does it say?
Where is it?
What's it all about, damn it?
Don't keep us in
suspense, Serge.
This has been a complete
fucking nightmare.
Just tell us what the
fuck is going on!
(clattering)
Serge?
Serge? Serge!
Bloody hell, they've
strangled the poor slob.
♪
(clicking)
Come on! Let's go!
ZERO:
What do we do if we catch him?
GUSTAVE:
I don't know. He's...
He's a homicidal psychopath.
Let's stop.
I can't.
I can barely steer.
♪
(wind whistling)
You sick, pathetic creep.
I hate you.
(groans)
"'If this do be me end:
farewell!'
cried the wounded piper-boy..."
"...whilst the muskets cracked
"and the yeomen roared 'Hurrah!'
and the ramparts fell."
"'Methinks me breathes me last,
me fears!', said he..."
(screaming)
Holy shit! You got him!
Well done, Zero!
(wind blowing)
Gustave H.,
you are a fugitive from justice!
Surrender lawfully,
and I will personally vouchsafe
your fair treatment.
Do not attempt to flee.
ZERO: What do you think?
I don't know.
I'd rather jump off
this cliff right now
than go back to
fucking prison.
I say we steal
that sick maniac's motorcycle,
go fetch Agatha,
take back Boy with Apple
and head for the Maltese
Riviera, once and for all.
Very good! You're so
extraordinary, Zero.
Thank you.
A moment of silence
in memoriam
of a devoted servant
killed violently
during the conduct
of his duties.
Good-bye, Serge.
Okay, let's go.
MR. MOUSTAFA:
The war began at midnight.
Pffeifelstad fell by lunch
under heavy shelling,
and ten battalions
surged across
the long western border.
High command advanced
to Nebelsbad.
(Agatha clears throat)
Compliments of Herr Mendl,
for the executive staff.
MONSIEUR CHUCK:
General Stieglitz requests
a garden-view sitting room
with an extra roll-away.
Let's put him
in the Duke Leopold Suite.
Secretary Woroniecki's
office cabled.
He's checking in a day early.
Rooms 401-2-3.
Tell Tactical Logistics
we're moving them
to a standard double
on the third floor.
They'll need
more space than that.
(Ping-Pong ball bouncing)
(switch clicks)
(soldier shouting
indistinct commands)
GUSTAVE:
The beginning of the end
of the end of the beginning
has begun.
The sad finale played off-key
on a broken-down saloon piano
in the outskirts of
a forgotten ghost town.
I'd rather not bear
witness to such blasphemy.
Me neither.
The Grand Budapest has
become a troops' barracks.
I shall never cross its
threshold again in my lifetime.
Me neither.
Never again
shall I welcome...
Actually, I think we might be
going in there right now
after all.
(car door opens)
Dmitri.
Agatha.
(switch clicks)
Good evening,
Mr. Desgoffe und Taxis.
I'm Monsieur Chuck.
We've booked you
and your sisters
into the King Ferdinand suite.
Good evening.
General von Shrecker asked
me personally to make...
Who's that?
MONSIEUR CHUCK:
I beg your pardon?
I think that girl's
got my picture.
Excuse me.
♪
AGATHA:
Six.
DMITRI:
Hold it.
DMITRI: Six.
(door closes)
Compliments of Herr Mendl.
♪
Excuse me.
Have you seen a pastry girl
with a package under her arm
in the last
minute and a half?
Yep. She just got
on the elevator
with Mr. Desgoffe und Taxis.
Thank you.
What did he say?
I'm sorry,
who are you?
Otto, sir, the
new lobby boy.
Well, you haven't been
trained properly, Otto.
A lobby boy never provides
information of that kind.
You're a stone wall,
understood?
♪
(whispers):
Pretty picture.
Sixth floor.
♪
Where's Boy with Apple?
None of your goddamn business!
I'm going to blast
your candy-ass
once and for all right now.
(gunshots)
(gunshots continue)
Drop your weapon!
(gun clicking, gunshots resume)
MAN:
Hey!
(gunfire continues)
Cease fire! Cease fire!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Stop it!
Who's shooting who?
That's Gustave H.,
the escaped murderer
and art thief!
I've got him cornered!
That's Dmitri Desgoffe
und Taxis!
He's responsible for
the killing of Deputy Kovacs,
Serge X.
and his clubfooted sister,
plus his own mother!
Nobody move.
Everybody's under arrest.
(glass breaking, woman screams)
Who's out the window?
Agatha.
(gunshots resume)
Cease fire!
ZERO:
310-bis.
Hang on! Here I come!
(gunshots continue)
(creaking)
(grunts)
(groans, metal creaking)
Something's on
the back of the...
(screaming)
(thud)
(bell tolling)
(muffled): Agatha!
Agatha!
(panting)
Are you all right?
I think so.
Something's on the
back of the picture.
What?
(crowd chatters excitedly)
(chattering stops)
MR. MOUSTAFA:
She left everything
to Monsieur Gustave,
of course.
The mansion,
known as Schloss Lutz;
I knew her intimately.
the factories,
which produced weapons,
medicine and textiles...
(laughter)
...an important
newspaper syndicate;
and, perhaps
you've already deduced,
this very "institution"--
the Grand Budapest Hotel.
He anointed me
his successor;
and as the war continued,
I served my adopted country
from the narrow desk
still found against the wall
in the next room.
He was the same
as his disciples:
insecure, vain,
superficial, blond, needy.
(laughter)
In the end, he was even rich.
Everyone's going to join.
He did not succeed,
however, in growing old.
Are you ready?
Dearly beloved,
we are gathered
together here in...
Nor did my darling Agatha.
She and our infant son
would be killed two years
later by the Prussian grippe.
An absurd little disease.
Today we treat it
in a single week,
but in those days,
many millions died.
(Gustav continues indistinctly)
On the 21st day
of the occupation--
the morning the independent
state of Zubrowka
officially ceased to exist--
we travelled
with Monsieur Gustave to Lutz.
In answer to your earlier
question, by the way:
of course.
Zero asked me
about my humble beginnings
in the hotel trade.
I was, perhaps,
for a time,
considered the
best lobby boy
we'd ever had at
the Grand Budapest.
I think I can say that.
This one finally
surpassed me.
Although, I must say, he
had an exceptional teacher.
Truly.
(train whistle blows)
"Whence came these two radiant,
celestial brothers,
"united, for an instant,
"as they crossed
the stratosphere
"of our starry window?
"One from the East, and
one from the West."
Very good.
Don't flirt with her.
(brakes squealing)
Why are we stopping at
a barley field again?
I find these black
uniforms very drab.
Well, hello there, chaps.
We were just
talking about you.
Documents, please.
With pleasure.
As always.
(heavy footsteps approaching)
You're the first
of the official death squads
to whom we've been
formally introduced.
How do you do?
"Plus ça change,"
am I right?
Uh... That's a Migratory Visa
with Stage Three
Worker Status, darling.
Read this.
SOLDIER:
Come outside.
GUSTAVE:
Now, stay there.
I give you my word,
if you lay a finger on this man,
I'll see you dishonorably
discharged, locked up
in the stockade
and hanged by sundown.
MR. MOUSTAFA:
There are still
faint glimmers
of civilization left in this
barbaric slaughterhouse
that was once known
as humanity.
(gasps)
(screams)
You filthy, goddamn,
pockmarked, fascist assholes!
(train whistle blows)
MR. MOUSTAFA:
He was one of them.
What more is there to say?
What happened
in the end?
In the end,
they shot him.
So it all went to me.
YOUNG WRITER:
After dinner,
we went to collect
the keys to our rooms,
but Monsieur Jean
had abandoned his post.
I expect he's forgotten
all about us.
YOUNG WRITER:
In recent years, of course,
such properties and holdings
as the Grand Budapest
had with very few exceptions
become...
common property.
While the precise terms
of his negotiation
with the new government
had never been announced,
the result
was an open secret:
Zero Moustafa had traded
a great and important fortune
in exchange for one costly,
unprofitable, doomed hotel.
Why?
Was it merely sentimental?
It was quite forward of me
and a bit out of character,
but I felt I must know.
For my health, I suppose.
Forgive me for asking.
I hope
I haven't upset you.
No, of course not.
Is it simply
your last connection
to that vanished world--
his world, if you will?
His world?
No, I don't think so.
You see, we shared
a vocation.
It wouldn't have
been necessary.
No.
The hotel I keep for Agatha.
We were happy here.
For a little while.
(elevator bell dings)
To be frank, I think
his world had vanished
long before
he ever entered it.
But I will say...
he certainly
sustained the illusion
with a marvelous grace.
Are you going up?
No, I'll sit
for a little while.
Good night.
(bell dings)
YOUNG WRITER:
The next week,
I sailed for a cure
in South America
and began a long,
wandering journey abroad.
I did not return to Europe
for many years.
("s'Rothe-Zaãuerli"
by Öse Schuppel playing)
It was an enchanting old ruin.
AUTHOR:
But I never managed
to see it again.
♪
("s'Rothe-Zaãuerli" ends)
(man speaks Russian)
♪