FLIGHT ATTENDANT [OVER PA]:
For us to push back from the gate...
...make sure seatbelts are fastened...
...tray tables in their locked position,
and your luggage is completely stowed.
We'd like to thank you all for flying with us.
Welcome aboard.
[PLANE ENGINE ROARING]
[BELL RINGS]
WOMAN 1 [OVER PA]: Flight 82 to San
Francisco is ready for boarding at Gate....
WOMAN 2 [OVER PA]: Flight 63
to New York now boarding at Gate 41.
[CHIRPING]
[RINGING]
[DIALING]
OPERATOR:
If you'd like to make a call....
-So....
-Happy birthday.
-Oh.
Thank you...
...for the takeout.
Sure.
It's the Ieast I could do.
It's your birthday.
-Heh. So?
-Oh, yeah, right.
But Dan's home
so we gotta go to the bedroom.
Oh. Are we done in here?
Yeah, well, we finished eating.
[AMY CHUCKLES]
What?
I just thought
that this might be a great moment...
...for you to give me my gift.
Oh, shit.
Amy, I didn't get you anything.
You told me that you didn't want me
to get you anything.
What's happening? Oh, God.
-Are you crying?
-No.
I have missed something here, baby.
So you wanted a present?
Garrett,
I tell you not to get me something...
...so you want to get me something
really great...
...because I'm the girlfriend
that didn't ask for anything.
What? Okay, you know what, Iet's go.
I'II get you something now.
It is not about the goddamn gift.
It just was about the gift.
When did it become not about the gift?
It's bigger than this.
It's a combination of a Iot of things.
I've invested so much in this relationship
and I don't feel Iike you're doing the same.
I don't even know if you're into this.
Are you?
-Sure.
-Oh, my God.
Ah, Amy, come on.
-Don't even think about calling me again.
-Oh, Jesus. Amy, wait, wait, wait.
I should not call you
or I should want to call you?
Okay, so it means what it means. Good.
[CHATTERING]
[PHONES RINGING]
-Ow! Oh, my God. Mother bitch.
-Erin, you're Iate.
Thanks, Brandy.
I almost forgot why I was running.
Did he use the red pen with you guys?
BOTH:
No.
-Well, it's impressive reporting.
-Thank you.
However,
needs to be completely restructured.
And a spellcheck wouldn't hurt.
"Munincibal" courthouse?
Not sure where that is.
Thank you, Iadies.
-Where are you going?
-I'm 31. I'm an intern.
-I'm going to get wasted.
-Oh, I'm so in.
Let's go.
I'd Iove a copilot. Look at this shit.
BRANDY:
Oh, my God, he bled on it.
[GARRETT SIGHS]
GARRETT: I still can't believe
she broke up with me.
-Of course she did, dumb-ass.
-Because I didn't get a gift?
It's not the gift.
-Don't think it's the gift.
-It's not.
How does everyone except me
know it's not about the gift?
-Oh. Dude, are you kidding me?
-AII right, hang on a second, man.
I get it, all right?
It's a tough thing to get dumped.
You get upset, you go to your room,
you turn off all the Iights...
...you Iight a candle
and you just, Iike you know...
...go to that deep emotional place
where you're Iike:
[SOBBING]
-Is that really how you cry?
DAN: Yes.
Are you going through that?
Have you cried?
-Uh, I didn't cry. I've never cried Iike that.
-I cry Iike that all the time.
I've only really cried over a girl
in, Iike, high school, maybe.
I don't know.
Maybe you weren't into that chick.
Because I didn't cry, it means I'm not--
No, I Iiked her. Of course I Iiked her.
And we were good together.
I don't know what happened.
-I don't know what happened.
BOX: Aw, dude.
-This happens every time.
-What?
You get in a relationship
but you don't fully commit.
You never have,
not since I've known you.
The girl figures that out and she splits.
And then we have to sit here
and Iisten to you be surprised about that.
-Over and over again. This happens a Iot.
-AII the time.
It's not true. It happens occasionally.
There's a definite pattern.
-Definite pattern.
GARRETT: You know what?
Fuck you, fuck you.
I'm gonna go clear my head.
-A Iot of self-righteousness going on.
-You gonna cry it out?
GARRETT:
I'm not crying, just gonna clear my head.
CIear your head, cry, same thing.
You know what I'm talking about
with the man cry.
Like that Iow, Iike:
[SOBBING]
[BOX CHUCKLES]
I don't know. If you ask me, that Iooks
Iike you're trying to suck your own dick.
-That does not--
-Yes, it does.
If I wasn't making any noise...
...and you saw me Iike this,
what does it Iook Iike?
Looks Iike you're trying to suck your dick.
That's not how.
When I suck my dick, I Iie on my back,
I throw my Iegs over my head.
-You suck your own dick?
-Yeah.
You cut your hair
and you suck your own dick.
You're Iike a Swiss army knife.
[ELECTRONIC BEEPING]
Hey, we should circulate.
There's hot guys everywhere.
You're being Iame.
What would you rather I do?
Get date-raped by a frat guy
with a popped collar?
[WHISPERS]
No, thank you.
You are just jealous.
-[IN NORMAL VOICE] More for you, baby.
BRANDY: Thank you.
ERIN:
Go have fun being in The Accused.
BRANDY: Hey.
-Hey.
BRANDY: I Iike your shirt.
-I know. It's Polo.
You smell good.
-It's Axe.
-I know.
You might as well remove that quarter.
I have no intention of getting off this game.
Listen--
-Oh, my God.
-What?
-Who does that?
-What the fuck?
-What the fuck are you doing?
Who Ieans in Iike that?
I was just about to beat the high score.
There's no way you got that close to ERL.
I've never gotten that close.
ERIN: You know how Iong
I've been trying to beat myself?
I mean, what a dick move.
GARRETT:
Wait, what?
What the f--?
What? Hold on. Hold on. You're ERL?
You're the dragon?
I'm a what?
I've been chasing ERL for months now.
I just thought ERL was an--
I thought ERL was an "Earl," you know.
Erin Rankin Langford.
Nobody calls me ERL.
I'm honored, okay. I am honored.
Shit, what a dick. I Ieaned in.
I owe you a beer.
PIease Iet me get you a beer.
Look, I'm sitting right over there,
we got a pitcher.
I'd feel Iike shit if you don't have a beer
with me. One Centipedophile to another.
AII right.
-I feel Iike you're not Iistening to me.
-I am Iistening.
I'm trying to figure this out.
I can't tell if they're together.
I think they're on their first date. Tall.
Yes, I see them. They're tall.
But are you not afraid about what's--
-I bet the blond played college sports.
-Can you pay attention?
There are no baby pigeons in the city.
Not one.
You guys, uh, I want you to meet Erin.
Uh, Erin, these are my friends.
This is Box and Dan.
ERIN:
Hi. How are you?
-Hey.
-Hello.
I screwed up Erin's Centipede game
so I owe her a beer.
Fucker put his face
in front of the game.
-What? Who does that?
DAN: Oh.
-Exactly.
-Well, it wasn't that bad.
Check, one.
Okay, everyone, people.
It is time for tonight's round
of bar trivia.
[MICROPHONE FEEDS BACK]
[SCATTERED APPLAUSE]
So you know the rules.
Uh, just teams of two.
No fighting, no g--
[MICROPHONE FEEDS BACK]
Oh! Shit!
Terry, I just got shocked by this mike.
TERRY:
Well, then don't put your face on it.
I do not have health care, Terry.
Hey, Iisten, these two get really moody
and emotional when they're separated...
-...so do you wanna team up?
ERIN: Sure.
Just don't drag me down, okay?
You don't seem very smart.
What country has the driest inhabited area
in the world?
Is it A, Syria--?
Egypt.
Okay, Iet me read all the choices
before you answer.
Egypt, the answer's Egypt.
Nice. Oh, my God.
What album holds the record
for most weeks on the Billboard 200?
Dark Side of the Moon.
-Terry, they keep interrupting me.
TERRY: Then speak faster.
Seven hundred and 41 weeks,
in case you're curious.
You suck at everything else.
It's good you know something.
Yeah, well, I better not suck at that.
It's part of my job.
I work at Diesel Records. It's a Iabel.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
The word "records"
kind of tipped me off.
What do you do for work?
I work at The New York Sentinel
newspaper.
-Oh, yeah?
-It's a newspaper.
How many different ways
can you make change for a dollar?
Ah! A dollar, if ripped, has no value.
Disqualified.
DAN:
Great, nine weeks in a row.
-You got a Iittle wing sauce, Iike-- Um--
-Where?
Kind of in this general area.
The Rolling Stones took their name
from what--?
BOTH: Muddy Waters!
-Fuck you!
Oh, yeah.
Oh, wow.
Jesus, Snoop.
So you a big fan of Tom Cruise?
GARRETT:
Uh, in my defense, I'm a big Top Gun fan.
-Oh, really?
-Yeah.
In fact, I Iike all homoerotic,
fighter-pilot movies.
[LAUGHS]
-Too much? Did I Iose you?
-No, no.
Is Top Gun Iike your favorite movie?
-It's up there. What's wrong with that?
-Nothing.
-It's the greatest.
-Yeah. It's awesome.
Wait, what's your favorite movie?
Actually, I'm gonna be really serious
right now for a minute.
-Okay, hold on.
-Ha-ha-ha.
[BONG BUBBLING]
I really wanna tell you
what my favorite movie is.
Oh, God. PIease don't say, Iike,
Triumph of the Will.
Don't be Iike a closet Nazi
or something weird...
... because this is going great.
It's Shawshank.
[ERIN SIGHS]
[IMITATING RED]
I hope I make it across the border.
I hope to see my friend
and shake his hand.
I hope the Pacific is as blue
as it has been in my dreams.
-Ha-ha-ha.
-I hope.
-Zihuatanejo.
-[IN NORMAL VOICE] Zihuatanejo.
The best.
[BERLIN'S "TAKE BY BREATH AWAY"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Watching every motion
In my foolish lover's game
-Where's that coming from?
-Dan.
-How in the fuck is Top Gun music playing?
-Dan!
DAN: Hey, Garrett.
-I'm so sorry.
I forgot to tell you
that Dan's my roommate.
You guys Iive together?
-Uh, yeah.
-Hey, Dan!
DAN:
Hello in there.
-Heh.
-Uh....
Dan, what are you doing?
DAN: Watching every motion
in my foolish Iover's game?
What was our rule?
DAN: Because I can hear through the wall
doesn't mean I get to participate.
Right,
and what were you doing just now?
DAN: Participating.
-Okay.
DAN: Look, man, I just thought maybe,
you know, it'd be fun if I DJ'd your hookup.
So is this, Iike, what you guys do
when you bring girls over?
-He DJs your hookup?
-No.
Is that what this fucking frat house
is all about?
No, no. Listen, I'm really sorry.
-I'm gonna go.
-Listen, Iisten, Iisten. I can explain.
Yeah? Explain.
You know what? I can't. I really have
no save here. He is a fucking moron.
That's okay, because, you know what?
I was totally pretending to be mad.
I didn't want you to think I was slutty.
-I don't care.
-Oh.
-Think it's kind of awesome.
-Well, that's weird.
-In fact, Dan, take me to Berlin.
DAN: Here it comes!
[OVER SPEAKERS]
Take my breath away
[ALARM CLOCK RINGING]
[HORNS HONKING]
Hey. Morning.
Good morning.
Um, if you're taking off, could you at Ieast
Ieave the money on the nightstand?
Oh. I wasn't, um, trying to sneak out.
No. You're just putting your clothes on
really quietly...
...and tiptoeing across the floor.
-Yeah.
-It's all right.
I can stay.
-I didn't mean you had to--
-Okay, yeah.
That didn't feel good.
Hey, hey.
You wanna maybe get some breakfast?
Food would be good.
Okay.
[OVER SPEAKERS]
Now I've had the time of my life
No, I've never felt
-Dan.
DAN: Hello.
[CHATTERING]
[ERIN SIGHS]
GARRETT:
I had a great time Iast night.
I gotta say, that was-- It's a Iot of fun.
Me too.
So I should get your number.
You know, we'd maybe hang out again?
-Okay.
-AII right. I have a nap-- No.
-Here, I got it.
-Okay.
-Um, there's a caveat that...
-Mm-hm.
... I'd really.... Um....
I'm Ieaving in six weeks.
And when I said that I work
at The Sentinel...
...I meant that I'm a summer intern.
And I'm actually going back to Stanford
to finish up my Iast year of grad school.
And although I'd be psyched
to hang out again...
...um, please know that
I'm not Iooking to start up--
Oh, wait. Uh, no, me--?
I just got out of a relationship.
-Oh. Really, when?
-Yeah.
Um....
I'm not gonna tell you
that it was Iast night...
...but I'm not gonna say
that it wasn't either.
-Okay, good.
-Yeah. Yep.
Well, then we know
where each other stands.
Um, the added bonus is that I now know
you're a male whore.
Yeah. I guess I-- It seems Iike I am.
Here's my phone number.
That's awesome.
Best posture in the office, AIIison.
Seriously. Best one we got.
There he is.
-How you doing?
-Hey.
Hey, I got a question for you, man.
How does someone Iike you end up getting
dumped and Iaid on the same night?
How is that possible? I mean, from all of us
sad, Ionely and bitter people...
...I encourage you
to eat a big bowl of dick.
-Really? How about this?
-Mm-hm.
How about, "Good morning, Garrett"?
-Morning, Garrett.
-How you doing? What's with the Iuggage?
Um, my flight from Miami got in at 5 a.m.
I haven't even slept.
You would never know.
You Iook well-slept.
Oh, thank you. Heh.
How's, uh...?
-Mark--
-Mark.
--is great.
Uh, seeing him once every six weeks
for 48 hours, not so great.
-Yeah.
-Garrett? Can you come here a sec?
-Anyways.
-AII right. Well, wake up.
-Bye, boys.
-She's still with that guy?
-Yeah.
-You kidding me? But he Iives in Miami.
Wait-- No-- Yeah, hold on.
I don't think you understand
the gravity of this situation.
I wanna put things of mine
inside things of hers.
I know you do. I know.
[OVER SPEAKERS]
I heart you crazy mad
Until it feels so good
I'm about to do something drastic
'Cause I gotta have it
-What is this?
-Mm-hm.
I heart you crazy mad
I'm in a panic 'cause I
I'm genuinely getting nauseous.
I'm going out of my head
Are they singing
"I heart you crazy mad"?
Yeah, they are. Sadly, they are.
[MUSIC STOPS]
Jesus. 3Z? Heh.
WILL:
Now comes the fun part...
... because I get to Iook at your face
when I say I'm assigning them to you.
-Ah, there it is.
-Ha-ha-ha.
I know. I know it sucks.
Believe me, I know, okay?
The higher-ups wanna sign these guys.
They could be our Jonas Brothers.
Come on. Don't do this to me.
What about all the bands
that I bring you?
Demos you never Iisten to?
Give me a shot with those.
-That's not our focus right now.
-Will--
Hey. You know who I had to scout
when I was your age?
Nelson and Jesus Jones. AII right?
You know one song. I know Iike 100.
You know what that does
to your emotional stability?
-You covered Jesus Jones?
-Yeah.
How old are you?
[SIGHS]
I don't wanna talk about that.
Do this. Show the idiots in charge
that you wanna get promoted...
...then you can make the call
on some bands.
I can't Iook at them without Ia--
I don't know how I'm gonna do this.
You'II figure it out. Unh.
CIose them.
CORINNE [OVER COMPUTER]:
So have they offered you a job yet?
It's nice to talk to you too, Corinne.
Have you even asked them?
Look, the whole newspaper business
is falling apart, okay?
People here are struggling
to keep their jobs...
...so I can't exactly ask for one.
Maya, statue.
Look, all I'm saying,
and please know that I love you...
...is that you are behind in your life,
and we all know why.
Yeah, I'm currently up to speed on the fact
that my Iife is not currently up to speed.
Maya, statue.
[SIGHS]
Ooh, Olive Garden.
[CLATTERING]
-Jesus Chri-- Phil!
PHIL: The pantry shelves just collapsed.
CORINNE: Erin?
-Shit.
I need you to watch Maya for me, please.
Erin. AII the other interns are doing
research so you're on desk duty.
Okay.
Hugh, wait.
Look, I would really Iove
to turn this internship into a job.
And it's fine that my Iast piece
didn't get picked...
...and the ones that do
usually get bumped for space.
But it is my dream to work here...
...and I would Iike
to make a good impression.
Good. Then do that.
Okay.
Um, well, is there a piece
you could assign me, or...?
A piece.
Uh, the only thing I have is a human
interest story on Grant-A-Dream.
-It's a charitable organization--
-Yes, Grant-A-Dream.
It grants wishes to terminally ill children.
I Iove terminally ill children.
Don't get too excited.
Four other people passed on this.
-I'm on it.
-Okay, good.
Uh, write it up, put it on my desk.
Thank you.
Corinne-- Ugh.
CORINNE: Thanks a lot, Erin.
Where did you get these Oreo cookies?
Spit it out. Spit. More. More. More.
All of it. All of it. Maya.
All of it. All of it.
There's that. Thank you so much.
[PHONE RINGING]
-Hello?
-Hello.
I see you haven't entered me
into your phone yet.
Oh, you know what happened?
-What's that?
-I forgot your name.
Ah.
That's too bad for me. Um--
Well, I, Garrett, was wondering
if you'd allow me to take you to dinner.
Um, yeah. I could eat.
Yeah? Great.
-AII right, text me the address.
-Okay.
What's your favorite food?
Every Friday night, my family, we'd go out
to this place, Luigi's, in my hometown.
I'd get tortellini.
I think I Iove it just because of that.
It reminds me of Friday nights growing up.
How would you Iike to die?
-Eating too much tortellini.
-Ha-ha-ha.
Or waterboarding.
I'd Iove to be waterboarded to death.
Give me, Iike, three albums that you really
Iove, that meant something to you.
Licensed To Ill, the Beastie Boys.
Oh, the best.
That was one because it was dangerous.
And I had no danger in my Iife.
I thought Iike--
My idea of danger was Iike...
...getting chocolate milk
from the Iunch Iady.
Okay, what's the meanest Iie
you've ever told someone...
-...to get them out in the morning?
-I had to meet my wife for breakfast.
[LAUGHING]
ERIN: Ready?
GARRETT: There we go. Learn by doing.
BOX:
There it is.
-That way. Love that. Love that.
-Yay!
Okay, run. Wrong way.
Go the other way.
ERIN:
Fuck!
No, no, no! No!
[GARRETT LAUGHING]
[ERIN SQUEALS]
BOX:
Ugh.
DAN: I mean, is that gonna go on all day?
-I don't know. Probably.
We're staring directly at you.
We're rowing
Iike a bunch of Viking slaves.
GARRETT: Come on, we're having fun here.
DAN: We're staring at you.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
Do you wanna have kids?
Why, you wanna take those kids?
No, I mean, just Iike, you know,
Iater on in Iife, do you wanna have kids?
Yeah, of course.
Do you?
I don't know.
That's why I Iike coming
and Iooking at the old couples.
Some of them seem genuinely, not only
happy, but sometimes I think, content.
I think sometimes that's more important
than, Iike, happiness.
Like the guy we saw in the plaid shirt
walking down-- He's happy.
The only way you're content in Iife
is if you marry your best friend.
-They make each other Iaugh--
-So I have to marry Dan?
-Ha-ha-ha.
-Or Box? They gotta duke it out.
I'm having fun.
Me too.
ERIN: I'm only here for a couple more weeks.
GARRETT: Right.
But maybe you'II come back one day.
MAN: Pushing that deadline another day.
-Sure.
MAN:
See you.
-Um, excuse me, Hugh? Hi.
-Oh, hey.
Um, I just wanted to say goodbye
because it's my Iast day--
Well, goodbye.
I was curious, um, what did you think
of my Grant-A-Dream piece?
Uh.... Oh, it was good.
We're gonna run it.
-You are?
-Yeah.
-Really?
-Well, that's great.
-Yeah. Tuesday. Congratulations.
-Nice piece of writing.
-Thank you.
Yeah. Good work.
I want you to know
what an incredible experience I had here.
Good.
Okay.
Do you think that there's
any possible chance in the future...
...that it could Iead to a job?
Well, Iook, you know,
you're a good writer...
...and anything's possible...
...so why don't you call me
after the new year, okay?
-And we'II see where things are at.
-I will call you in January.
-Okay, good. Perfect.
-Like, the first.
-AII right. Great.
-At Iike 5 a. m.
Great, that's good, Erin. Thank you.
Just remember the time difference.
-Okay. Bye, Hugh. Thank you.
-Take care. Okay, bye, now.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hey, you.
GARRETT:
Good afternoon, is Erin there, please?
This is Erin.
Is it? Well, this is Garrett Austin Scully
telephoning.
I met you at that bar
by the Centipede machine.
Yeah, I remember. Nice hair, decent face.
Ah. That's the one.
Listen, I know this is your
last night in New York...
...so I was wondering if you would
allow me to take you out...
...for a nice farewell dinner.
I would Iove to.
AII right, I don't wanna impress you all
at once but these are actual cloth napkins.
-That's genuine cloth, that's polyester.
-Ooh. Ha, ha.
Yeah, not to put on airs or anything,
and all-you-can-eat garlic balls.
Ha-ha-ha. Wow. You have really
outdone yourself, Mr. Scully.
I will take that not sarcastically.
Good evening.
Um, can I get your drink order
to start with?
-Should we get some wine?
-Yeah.
-Do you have a Iist?
-Uh, we don't.
We just have the one,
the jug of wine?
It's a Sunshine Harbor?
It's the house wine.
And how is it?
How would you describe it?
-Um, it's okay. You know.
-Well, there you go.
-AII right.
GARRETT: Well done. Well played.
I think the Iady and I will partake
of the Sunshine Harbor...
...per your glowing recommendation.
-Um, now, what year is this?
-Uh....
This.
Nothing worse than an old wine.
WAITER:
That's how I feel.
-I'II be right back to get your order.
-Okay.
Um, ahem.
I just wanna thank you
for calling me a Iady.
Well, because you are a beautiful, funny,
intelligent woman...
...who I've had
an amazing time with.
Yeah, I'm bummed it's our Iast night.
Me too.
And I've--
I don't think I've ever enjoyed
getting to know someone more.
It's been such a good six weeks.
Went by so fast.
I can't really articulate.
[IN DEEP VOICE]
Six weeks too fast.
Me Iike you.
Wine.
[BOTH LAUGH]
-[IN NORMAL VOICE] Oh, my God.
-That's disgusting.
You're Iucky you didn't keep it in,
because I'm getting an ulcer.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Well, I guess this is it.
Yeah. Guess this is it.
Take care of yourself.
Okay.
-Okay, bye.
-I'II s--
-Uh-- Oh, Iet me--
-I got it, I got it.
Whoa, whoa.
You can't Ieave your car there.
-No, I--
-You can't Ieave your car at the curb.
-I need to talk to this girl quickly.
-Shit, you chasing a girl?
-Yeah.
-For real?
-She got a nice ass?
Like the wind.
-What the hell does that mean?
-I have no idea.
PIease. Two seconds.
-Go on, now.
-Thank you, thank you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, thank you.
Langford. Hey!
-What are you doing?
-That sucked.
-I know.
-God.
-That was terrible.
-Terrible.
-I can't end it Iike this.
-Neither can I.
And that car ride was a disaster.
Oh, that was awful. It was so awkward.
So awkward.
-It's the worst.
-The worst.
Yeah, sorry, go ahead.
MAN: Thank you.
GARRETT: Good, good.
I didn't know if you wanted to keep
doing this or how you felt.
I just-- I freaked out, okay?
I've had such a good time with you...
...and a part of me
doesn't want that to end...
...but I have been down this road before
with a guy.
I dropped out of college and I followed him
across the country...
...and I dropped everything for him.
And that's why my timeline is all off,
you know?
And now I finally got everything
back on track...
...you know, with my Iife and school...
...and then you had to come along...
-...and fuck that all up.
-Ow.
I'm sorry.
I'm not asking you to drop out of school
or even move here.
I'm just asking to see you
because I don't wanna Iose you.
Fuck the miles. Fuck them.
I'II be here and you'II be there
and we'II just be Iong-distance...
...because quite frankly,
I'm crazy about you.
I'm crazy about you too.
ERIN:
I'm so glad you picked me up.
Of course.
Maya made you something.
-She's here.
-Hi, everybody.
-Hi. Hi, my beautiful niece.
MAYA: Hi.
Hi.
PROFESSOR:
"The suspect, Mr. Jones...
...was heavily intoxicated
when he fired the.44 Magnum."
We need to know where this information
is coming from. Is this your own theory?
BOX: Aw, come on, man.
DAN: Come on, dude.
BOX:
Are you serious?
-AII right.
BOX: What are y--?
-Hold on.
-[IN DEEP VOICE] "What are you doing?"
[IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]
"Nothing. What are you doing?"
[IN DEEP VOICE] "Nothing.
This funny thing happened at work."
[IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]
"This funny thing happened at school."
[SNEEZES]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
He sneezed and scared mommy panda.
Oh, my God. Baby panda has a cold.
[SNEEZES]
I had a thing when I was a kid.
I was obsessed with, Iike--
I thought it was cool to not have Iips.
Like Michael J. Fox and Jason Bateman.
Those guys, Iike, I idolized them.
They didn't have, Iike, Iips,
and I had, Iike, big weird Iips.
-Oh.
-Ha-ha-ha.
Look at that. You're up.
You kidding me?
GARRETT:
What are you doing? Come on. Come--
-What the fuck?
BOX: Oh!
Fore!
-Are you fucking kidding?
-Yeah, that was a joke.
GARRETT:
You're such an asshole.
I gotta program all my numbers
into this goddamn thing.
BOX: Ha, ha. Come on, man,
my actions were justified.
DAN:
It was a pretty good hit.
GARRETT: It was funny, I'II give
you that, but justified? Really?
-Destroying my phone? Come on.
BOX: No, maybe not.
No, probably not. Not at all.
No, but it's Iike her vagina
has you possessed.
I Iike him. A Iot.
Okay, I know, I know,
but are you dating?
-Are you in an exclusive relationship?
-I don't know.
What do you mean?
Don't you think you should know?
I mean, he could be out there dry humping
half of New York City right now.
"Dry humping"? Oh, that's scandalous.
That worries me.
Phil and I dry hump. Okay?
And it is intense. And it's very erotic.
And it's the only way
that I can actually get off.
Dry humping is no fucking joke.
So I think that you need to be clear
about what this relationship is.
Now what is the story
with you guys?
Are you doing it monogamous
or what's the deal?
Yeah.
I don't know. Uh....
-Maybe, yeah.
-"Maybe"?
Wow, okay.
You know what "maybe" gets you?
It gets her sucking every dude's dick
out there at Stanford. It really does.
Then you go and visit her.
You have to kiss that blow-job factory
she calls a mouth.
Thank you for that visual. Thanks, pal.
That was, Iike, way graphic.
That was, Iike, extremely graphic.
He's thousands of miles away from here.
You don't know what he's doing.
He could be at some bar,
doing shots with some sexy bartender...
...dry humping her.
We haven't set the boundaries yet.
-Okay?
-Oh, my God.
We're not trying to choke each other
with commitment.
But now you're freaking me out...
...and I can't do anything but picture him
humping some bartender. Thank you.
I'm your sister.
This is what I'm here to do: terrify you.
-I see Phil dry humping you.
-You don't wanna.
I don't wanna think about
what that Iooks Iike. It's not pretty.
Like, between the snorting
and the slobbering...
...he's Iike a fucking shar-pei.
Or what are those dogs with the:
[SNORTING]
-Bulldogs?
-Yeah. Like a fucking bulldog.
Does he Iook up at you
when he goes down on you?
-Wanting approval?
-Yes. Ha, ha.
"Am I doing it okay? Am I doing it?"
-I hate that. Shut up and Iick.
-It's horrible.
I don't know, actually.
Okay, Iook, Iook.
Can you see other people? AII right?
Can you hook up with other people?
-Can you masturbate?
-Masturbate?
Can you masturbate yourself off at all?
-Why wouldn't I?
-Some girls frown upon that.
-Some girls don't Iike you to masturbate.
-She's not Iike a puritan.
Well, I'm just saying, Iike, some women
don't Iike people masturbating.
Because I can hear you
through the walls.
And you crack off a Iot.
BOTH:
"Crack it off"?
Who says "crack off"?
Why? What do you say?
You may be thinking
of "snap one off"?
-"Snap it off"?
-Or "pop"? Like, "pop one off"?
I don't want anything to snap and pop
when I'm masturbating.
-If it cracks a Iittle bit, fine.
-"Fine"?
The point is, you're gonna chafe yourself
cracking off as much as you do.
AII right, so, we--
Do you need help across the street?
Okay. Don't pull, though.
He goes crazy.
He's furious with his penis or something.
Angry.
Angry masturbation,
which is dangerous.
-You can really injure yourself.
-Yeah.
So he doesn't really know that.
Yeah. I have to tell my grandson that.
Tell your grandson.
Tell your grandson's friends, you know?
Well, just him. Not others.
DAN: You're right. Just him.
It might get awkward telling all his friends.
ERIN: I guess you have to define it
at some point.
GARRETT:
So I guess we're saying...
...we're exclusive?
-Yeah.
-Great.
-I'm happy.
-Me too.
Secretly, this is what I was aiming for.
Well, not-so-secretly, me too.
Keep it Iight.
Light. Disease-free and Iight.
-Ha-ha-ha.
-Bye.
Goodbye.
Can I please get the garbage omelet,
double meat, home fries...
...and how about everything bagel...
...with butter, cream cheese,
jelly, all that shit.
And then, you know what?
I'II take a chocolate shake.
And I will make it very easy for you.
-You know, I'II have that same exact thing.
-Okay.
-I'II just have the turkey burger.
WAITRESS: Okay.
Is there a way to just wrap it in Iettuce,
Iike use Iettuce for the bun?
WAITRESS: Can do no bun. Does that work?
-No bun.
Fries or salad?
Uh, I'II get the salad
with dressing on the side.
WAITRESS: Yep, coming up.
-Thank you.
-Wow.
-What?
-You're eating Iike a bird there, huh?
-No.
He's visiting Erin for Thanksgiving
and worrying about his weight.
-AII right.
-Jesus.
I told you not to say anything.
We haven't seen each other
in a while, okay?
Okay, I understand.
That makes sense to me.
-Wanna tighten up.
-I get you, I get you.
If you're so worried about your appearance,
are you gonna do something...
-...about your veiny, white skin?
DAN: Mm.
Right now you Iook Iike an actor
in a kabuki troupe.
-You're one to talk about appearances.
-How so?
No offense, but with the moustache....
-What? You don't Iike it?
-It's disgusting.
I don't care what you think.
This is not for you.
Who's it for, the '83 Yankees bullpen?
[ALL LAUGH]
-Now, there we are.
-Very funny.
No, I'm actually trying to scratch a very
specific demographic off of my fuck-it Iist.
-What's a fuck-it Iist?
-He's got this Iist Iike a bucket Iist...
...but it's women he's trying to bang
before he dies.
So, what kind of women
are you hoping to attract?
-OIder women, between 45 and 60.
-Oh, so, cougars.
-This is where it's weird.
-No. No, not cougars.
Okay, see, cougars, to me,
are sad, desperate older women...
...that want to be young now.
Okay? But what I'm Iooking for are older
attractive women...
...that want to be young again.
AII right?
See, when women see me
with a moustache of that type...
...they're transported back
when the moustache was king:
-The '70s, the early '80s.
-Right.
AII right?
The era of their sexual awakening.
So then, when I'm on top of them,
and they Iook up at me...
...they see this person,
they're transported to that time.
AII right? See, this isn't a moustache,
it's a time machine.
It's a time machine
to the back of Burt Reynolds' Camaro.
Right. You know what, it's--
Bottom Iine is don't get a moustache,
get a tan.
I don't think she's that kind of girl.
I don't think she's that superficial.
Okay, so she won't bang fat dudes...
...but she will sleep with a guy
that Iooks Iike his face is covered in jizz?
DAN: If she's gonna
dump you for eating carbs...
-...she'II dump you for not having a tan.
-That's true.
AII right, I get the point.
Once you're in the machine,
it's pretty self-explanatory.
You're gonna wanna put this on
your hands, under your nails...
...unless you want your hands stained.
-Right this way.
-Okay.
-Enjoy the Faux de Soleil.
-Just a quick question. Uh--
-Ooh.
MAN: Hello. Tanning will begin in five...
-Uh--
-...four, three...
-Should I be wearing underwear?
-...two, one.
Excuse me. Oh, God. Oh, goddamn it.
Oh, and it stings.
Fuck. Fuck, my eyes sting.
What is this? Excuse me.
Should I be wearing goggles?
It stings. Is this bad?
Ah. Tastes gross. Pff, pff.
Tastes Iike poison. Pff, pff.
Should I--? Is it bad if I eat it?
Erin, you just got sat another table.
No way. I closed out my section.
You know it, dude.
Well, you were requested. So....
Sorry, Mama.
[SIGHS]
Goddamn it.
[GASPS]
I'm not gonna order anything,
I want you to know.
But I got a tip for you.
Is it the tip of your penis?
-No, gross. Yes, it is.
-Aah!
Oh, my God.
-Twenty percent of my dick.
-Ha-ha-ha!
[ERIN MOANING]
[GARRETT GRUNTS]
ERIN:
Oh, God, yes. Come on.
GARRETT: Where's the bedroom?
-Too far.
GARRETT:
Come over here.
ERIN:
Oh, God. Oh, I missed you.
Come here. God!
Oh, God. Oh, God!
[BOTH MOANING]
Oh!
Phil!
They came in so fast,
I didn't know where to go.
Hi. I'm Phil.
Hey. I'm Garrett.
-Nice to meet you.
GARRETT: Good to meet you.
-Why are you introducing yourself?
-I don't wanna be rude.
Get up. Fucking get up.
Is she still here?
-You got a handprint on your ass.
GARRETT: I'II tell you Iater.
-Don't engage.
-I'm eating at a dinner table.
-They're the ones fucking.
-Get fucking fuck upstairs.
You guys are all set up, so I'II just--
-Um....
PHIL: Make yourself at home.
[COUGHS]
Aw....
GARRETT: Mm. Corinne,
these mashed potatoes are amazing.
Thank you.
I spent all day cleaning the table.
GARRETT: Sorry?
CORINNE: Making them.
I spent--
It's an old recipe from the family.
Ahem. Well, very good.
-Um, Garrett.
GARRETT: Yes, Karen.
Now, are you a singer or a musician?
No. Neither one. Excuse me.
Yeah, I'm just behind-the-scenes guy.
ERIN: He actually goes out and scouts
bands, and then he signs them to his Iabel...
...and he takes us
to, Iike, these amazing places.
These seedy hole-in-the-walls
that you'd never know existed.
-That sounds cool.
GARRETT: It's not that cool.
-She's building it up.
ERIN: It is cool.
She's being sweet.
Believe me, it's a Iot more interesting
than what Ron does.
GARRETT: Oh.
-He makes boxes for a Iiving.
Cardboard containers, Karen. PIease.
They're cardboard-- I'm a supervisor.
-Pretty much boxes. Pretty much boxes.
-They're cardboard containers.
Oh. I often use boxes.
[GARRETT SIGHS]
The thing about my job
is that it's in a state of flux.
In fact, both of our fields
are kind of a Iittle--
-We're in very similar positions.
-Yeah.
But we do it because we Iove it.
We do it because we Iove it.
So, Erin, did you know
he was coming in?
No. He completely surprised me.
Surprised me too.
[COUGHS]
-No one knew.
ERIN: And it was quite a surprise.
But he surprised me at work
with flowers.
[KAREN GASPS]
-Oh.
-Jesus Christ.
GARRETT:
It wasn't a big deal.
I didn't, Iike, rappel in from
some helicopter. I just showed up.
How come you never do that?
Ha, ha.
Because we Iive together, Karen.
KAREN: I know, but it's nice
to show a gesture of appreciation.
How Iong have you guys been together?
-It's been a Iong time now. Yeah.
-Long time.
It's kind of Iike when you get really drunk
and you just black out...
...you don't know how much time's
gone by. Sort of a similar feeling.
[RICOCHETS THEN THUDS]
Oh.
Erin, Karen, would you come help me
in the kitchen with dessert?
Absolutely. Corinne's gonna go assassinate
your character. I gotta play defense.
-Oh. Hurry. Hurry up.
ERIN: Yeah.
Um....
So, Ron, do you make all different sizes
of boxes, or do you specialize in a certain--?
Do you have any idea of the trouble
that you're causing us there, chief?
Ron, please,
tell me what's bothering you.
I'II tell you what's bothering me there,
bucko.
You just caused a prime-time problem
between me and my wife.
Now I gotta go home and Iisten to her
complain that I don't do enough for her.
Ha, ha. You think some effing sappy shit
makes you a real boyfriend?
I stopped Iistening after "bucko."
Listen up. We're in the effing trenches here,
where the real hell happens.
AII right? And we're here every day.
It's not about flowers and presents
and showing up for the weekend.
Do you think you can just come in here
with your fake tan and your girl shirt?
What?
You think that's what it's Iike
when you're married?
When you're in a serious,
Iong-term relationship?
You think you're gonna be able to work out
and keep that nice ass of yours?
No. You're not gonna be able to keep it.
[THE BOXER REBELLION'S
"EVACUATE" PLAYING]
[SINGING]
And I don't wanna say
If it goes away
HARPER:
Hey.
-Hey, how are you?
HARPER: I'm good. How are you?
Hey, do you remember my friend Harper
from work?
GARRETT: Yeah, we've met. How are you?
It's good to see you again.
[CROWD CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
[THE BOXER REBELLION'S
"SPITTING FIRE" PLAYING]
[SINGING] What the rest did
I was average
But I don't mind
Drawn on two sides
Without disguise
But I don't mind
And I, I spit fire
-Hey.
-I Iove them. Yeah.
-Yeah? They're so good.
You don't believe me
They spent three years and all their money
getting this produced.
Really?
These are the bands
that should get noticed.
I hate that. I hate that a band Iike this
would get passed over because of money.
It's just take a chance on someone
because they deserve it...
... because they're genuinely talented.
Sorry. I'm sorry.
It's just frustrating because I know
at my Iabel they'd never go for this.
It would be Iike a waste of time
to bring it up.
Well, if you act all melodramatic
Iike that, yeah, it would be.
But if you showed your balls and you
went in there and got in their face...
...and said "Iisten to this,"
the worst they could do is say no.
Or get mad at you
because you showed your balls.
DAMON: There you are.
HARPER & ERIN: Damon.
ERIN:
Hi. How are you?
-I'm all right. How are you?
-I'm great.
What's going on?
-Hey. Garrett.
-I'm Damon.
-Nice to meet you.
-We all work together. He is the bartender.
-Oh, wow.
-Cheers.
GARRETT: Cheers.
HARPER: Where have you been, Damon?
-Um, I was just helping my mom move.
HARPER & ERIN:
Aw....
No, she's just getting old...
...and I want her to Iive closer to me,
you know?
HARPER & ERIN:
Aw....
Gush.
It's funny, because I actually want my
mother to move further away from me.
[GARRETT CHUCKLES]
-Damon is close with his mom.
GARRETT: Good, good, good.
-Well, you know, it's my mom, you know?
ERIN: So cute.
-"And then my mom."
-My mom.
GARRETT: Mothers are important.
DAMON: Yeah, they are.
You wouldn't be here
if it weren't for her vagina.
Found it easy
Easy
[ERIN LAUGHING]
[GARRETT SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
THEN LAUGHING]
GARRETT:
Ooh. Shh.
ERIN: What?
GARRETT [WHISPERS]: Sorry. Sorry.
ERIN [WHISPERS]: Maya. Oh.
GARRETT: Okay.
ERIN:
Hells yeah.
-Icing and vodka.
-Mm.
-That's a great chaser. Mm.
-Mm. Taste it.
So Damon seems Iike a good guy.
Oh, my God. He's amazing.
-Like my rock.
-Your rock?
Yeah, I wouldn't get through work
without him.
Wow. And he's handsome,
and he Ioves his mother, and--
-Are you jealous?
-Aw, come on. Come on.
No. Mm-mm.
Yes, you are.
I'm just a Iittle curious if you guys
have ever, you know....
You know. Sorry.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
No. No. Not at all.
Oh, my God.
You always gotta close your eyes.
-Hey, Corinne.
CORINNE: Hey.
I'm taking off.
Um, can I help you? I don't know
what happened. It was something--
-No! No! No.
-Oh, God.
-Sorry. No. No thank you. I'm good.
-Okay.
-I'm good.
-I'm so sorry.
Our introduction was not how I imagined
it would be, obviously...
[CHUCKLES]
...but that was my hand.
The handprint on my, uh, buttocks...
...and my genitalia.
You have a handprint on your crotch too?
-You ready?
GARRETT: Yes. Great.
-Okay. Well, see you Iater, Corinne.
-I'II be back soon.
CORINNE: Okay, bye.
ERIN: Okay, bye.
CORINNE: Have a safe--
GARRETT: What?
CORINNE: Have a safe flight, Garrett.
GARRETT: Thank you. You too--
Or not-- You're not flying. Okay.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Oh, yes. Middle seat. Awesome.
And a Iayover. Be fun.
Thank you for making this trip.
Thank you. That was the best.
I had fun.
I had fun too. Despite everything.
PIease, please apologize
to her again for me.
-I will.
-Okay.
-God, she hates me. She does.
-Yeah.
I Iove you.
I Iove you too.
I miss you already.
GARRETT: Cruella de Vil
was not based on an actual person.
BOX: I'm pretty sure she was.
A German Iady.
I think you're wrong about that.
Hey, Dan.
Welcome home, buddy boy.
Dude, what the fuck is this?
-We got an open-door policy. It's cool.
-Why? Why do you have that?
Well, we don't. He does.
I just kind of accept it.
-How was the trip, bro?
GARRETT: It was awesome.
-Do we have beers?
DAN: We do have beers.
-Will you grab me one?
GARRETT: Great.
BOX:
Don't drink a beer on the toilet.
DAN:
I was worried you'd get dumped...
...and we'd have to go to the bar.
It went well, huh?
No. It was really good.
DAN: AII the way.
GARRETT: That's all I'm doing.
-Not far enough.
GARRETT: That's as far as I'm going.
-I can't reach.
-That's as far as I go.
I am not gonna hand you a beer
while you're shitting.
-I don't wanna get up.
-Get it afterwards.
I'm pooping as we speak.
I don't wanna have to get up to get a--
BOX:
Take it. There. Take it.
DAN: Thank you!
BOX: Enjoy it. AII right?
-I'm gonna go.
-It's fine. It's closed now.
Did you tell her you Ioved her?
-I might have.
-Did you really?
Yeah. I did.
Are you serious?
Wow.
-You gotta be careful.
-No.
-Don't tell him he has to be careful.
BOX: How Iong have you been together?
-Four months.
That's a very Iong time.
BOX: Stop.
DAN: Will you--?
Okay. Four months, all right? So now,
in this four months, how much time...
...do you think you've spent together,
Iike in the same city? Physically.
-Uh, I don't know.
-Forty days?
-Yeah. Forty days.
-Tops. Yeah?
Sure, that sounds about right.
Now Iook, I have done the Iong-distance
thing, and it is hard as hell.
And it doesn't matter how good
the relationship is.
It Iiterally can just rip it apart.
Look, it is just very hard to be away from
the person you Iove for months at a time.
I know. I know it's not gonna be easy.
That's all I'm saying.
But maybe you never found
the right girl.
[SIGHS]
That's not a bad point.
-Jesus Christ.
-What are you doing?
You know what?
I want some privacy now. Pardon me.
ERIN:
It's Erin, leave a message.
[ANSWERING MACHINE
BEEPS OVER PHONE]
Well, now I miss you even more.
Thanks a Iot.
I'm going to bed,
so call me in the morning.
Okay, good night.
It's barely gonna fit.
The other ones wouldn't have fit.
But you saw the top off
the bigger one and--
What's the point?
Why not get one that's gonna fit?
This one Iooks Iittle.
People are gonna think we're gay.
ERIN: Okay, Iet's open our presents
at the same time.
It's exciting and sad,
since it's the only present I got this year.
Okay.
You did a good wrapping job too.
I hope it's a pony.
[GASPS]
Oh.... Centipede.
I Iove it!
[LAUGHING]
That's so awesome.
I Iove my present.
I Iove you.
MAYA:
Hyah!
[MAYA GIGGLING]
Hey, Corinne.
Can you ask Maya to keep it down
for just a second?
CORINNE:
Maya, statue.
[LINE RINGING]
HUGH:
Hello.
Hi, um, Hugh Edwards, please.
-This is he.
-Uh, hi. Uh, this is Erin Langford.
-No.
-I was a summer intern for you.
No.
I wrote that piece that you Iiked
so much on Grant-A-Dream.
-Oh, yeah. How are you?
-I'm good.
Um....
You told me
that I should call you in January...
...about a possible permanent position,
so...
...here I am, calling you.
Oh, right.
Well, Iook, honestly, we just got done
Iaying off 100 people...
...so we're not gonna be hiring
any time soon.
Sorry.
Why don't you try blogging? You know?
Heh.
Look, uh, best of luck to you.
-Okay.
-Take care.
Thank you.
[LINE DISCONNECTS]
Fuck! Fuck.
I wanted that job, okay?
I wanted to be in New York.
Look at it this way, it's not Iike
someone else got the job over you.
They're just not taking anyone.
Yeah, I get it.
It's a bad time for newspapers, okay?
It's not just about the fucking job.
I wanted to be in the same city as you.
I know. Believe me, I know.
But there are other papers in New York,
right? So that's still a possibility.
I seriously doubt...
...that if a paper Iike The Sentinel just cut
1 00 jobs that anybody's hiring right now.
Yeah, but Iisten,
you don't know that until you try.
You're angry and you're frustrated
and I get it and I wish I could hug you.
I know, I know.
That's the whole fucking problem
is you're there and I'm here...
...and I'm in this fucking kitchen right now,
and it fucking stinks.
Relax now, and try to get some sleep and
we'II make a new plan tomorrow. I promise.
Um, I gotta go, okay?
-Bye.
-I Iov--
-Wanna do some more of that Iater?
-Yeah. PIease.
Long-distance fucking sucks.
Yep. Look, I told you it was rough.
I know. It's so rough.
And even worse, I'm so horny.
[CHUCKLES]
There's definitely someone here
who can help you with that.
-Don't tempt me.
-I'm just saying.
What am I gonna do for a fucking job?
Okay? What am I gonna do with my Iife?
I don't want to be a waitress forever.
No, seriously, Iisten to me.
I want to be a reporter.
I want to tell stories.
What, Iike on the newspaper?
See, you understand. Fuck.
-Thank you.
-That's okay.
There we go.
Jesus Christ.
ERIN: Ha-ha-ha. Sorry.
-What the fuck is your problem?
Let me tell you, steroid-face. I'd think
you were comfortable with needles.
Watch yourself, sweetheart.
Speaking of sweethearts,
you can suck my dick.
-She doesn't have a dick.
-I actually do.
No, she doesn't.
And you should put your mouth
on my penis.
Get her out of here
before I kick your ass.
My friend is gonna kick your ass.
-Oh, is that right?
-No.
By the way, steroids have side effects.
They may include a small dick,
worshipping of Michael Bay....
-You out of your mind?
-Whoa, whoa, whoa.
We could all sit around and watch
Transformers together, jack off to it.
-Bye.
-Suck my dick, bitch.
Seriously.
Suck it!
Stupid fuck.
ERIN: Let's get in there! We can take him!
DAMON: Come on, Iet's go!
ERIN:
Son of a bitch.
[ERIN LAUGHING]
I need to get home.
DAMON: Are you gonna be okay?
-Yeah, yeah.
I'm fine.
[SIGHING]
Hi.
Honey, I'm just gonna tell you right now,
Maya drew on your face.
ERIN:
Shit.
[PHONE RINGS]
-Hello?
-Hello.
Oh, my God.
I must've Ieft you seven messages.
PIease, please, God, tell me you're okay.
Yeah, I'm fine. I just-- Unh.
I was out Iate Iast night with Damon.
I got real drunk.
Damon? Yeah?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
He was just Iistening to me vent, you know.
-Wow. Okay.
-What's wrong?
-Nothing.
-Wait. Wait a minute.
Nothing happened, okay?
-Huh.
-You have nothing to worry about.
Please just tell me that you trust me.
3Z's in the conference room already.
Get in there.
Yeah. I'm sorry. Okay.
I gotta go. Can't talk.
Oh, shit.
[CHATTERING]
Langford.
-Yes?
-Any Iuck?
Uh, no. Thank you for asking. Um--
I've checked every newspaper
and magazine in New York...
...and all dead ends.
Well, the Chronicle has an opening,
miraculously...
...so I recommended you
and a few other students.
Thank you. Um--
I just-- I sort of had my heart
set on New York.
Well, it's kind of brutal out there.
You're not really in a position to be picky.
Okay.
Thank you.
WOMAN 1 :
San Francisco Chronicle, may I help you?
[CHATTERING]
WOMAN 2:
San Francisco Chronicle, please hold.
-You can go in now.
-Thank you.
I'm Iooking for any job opportunities in
the San Francisco area, so if you know--
Totally, I get it.
Yeah. You know, I tried them, but--
Thank you, though. Okay, thank you.
Why don't you try blowing me next time?
Um....
-Okay.
-Not you.
Sorry, I'm dealing with some shit.
I'm sorry. Bad timing.
-It's okay. It's good to know.
-Oh. Fucking Evites.
It's for a month from now.
Who does that? Oh.
It's mine. It's for my birthday.
Shit.
Mark's coming in from FIorida
and I really want him to meet everyone...
...so I kind of gotta plan ahead.
-I'm so sorry.
-No, it's okay.
It's fine.
This is not an excuse,
but I'm so tired and frustrated.
I haven't seen my girlfriend in a while.
I'm Iosing my mind.
I'm in a Iong-distance relationship too,
I get it.
-It fucking sucks.
-Really does.
Tell me you have some suggestions.
Phone sex.
And, um, Iots of it.
What are you wearing?
Uh....
Red Iace panties and a bra and a garter.
Holy shit, you really went all out.
No, you fucking idiot, it's a fantasy.
-Oh, right.
-What are you wearing?
Um....
What do you think is sexy?
White boxer briefs.
Really? Like Marky Mark?
Oh, God, especially Iike Marky Mark.
If you even say "Marky Mark"...
-... I'm gonna fucking come right now.
-Shit. Baby, please take this seriously.
PIease. I'm so horny I can't even think.
-All right, sorry.
-Okay, um....
Okay, so tell me about something
that you're touching or whatever.
I'm touching myself.
Yeah, okay, good. Where?
Where are you touching yourself?
Everywhere. Absolutely everywhere,
all over, up and down.
-Up and down?
-Especially in the wet parts.
Oh, God, yeah, that's good.
-I want to make good on that. Hold on.
-Erin? Erin.
Hello? I Iost you.
-Did I lose you?
-Hello? Okay.
-Hello?
-I'm there.
-Okay, all right.
-Oh, God, I wanna fuck you so bad.
I wanna fuck you so hard.
[ERIN MOANS]
I wanna come all over you.
No, I want you to come on the towel
beside your pillow.
-Yeah, okay.
-I Iove fucking you so much.
You know what I fucking Iove doing?
I Iove riding you!
Oh, yeah.
-Wait, wait, wait.
-God, I Iove fucking riding you!
-But I'm on top. Baby, I'm on top.
-No, I'm on top.
-I'm on top. How can you be on top?
-Because we're in your car.
No, we're on a plane.
Didn't I tell you that we're in your car?
You said the towel next to my pillow.
Why would there be a pillow in the car?
Why would there be a towel
on the plane?
They give out those hand towels
in first class.
Well, we wouldn't be in first class,
we'd be in coach.
-Fine, we're in coach.
-What's everybody doing?
Are they watching us fucking?
We're in a bathroom.
We'II go in the bathroom.
I don't wanna get that blue toilet shit
all over me.
I'm not gonna put you in the toilet.
-Put the lid down--
-Gonna get arrested.
We're not gonna get arrested. We'II Iock
the door. It's a fantasy! There's no--
Oh, Christ, you know what?
We'II go in the car. We'II go in the car.
Oh, fuck the car.
You know what?
I think the moment's passed.
This isn't really working.
-I'm sorry.
-It's okay.
You know, I thought "blue balls"
was just a saying...
...but I'm getting a Iot
of veinage here.
I'm actually kind of concerned.
ERIN:
Oh, God.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
That's okay.
I'II just tighten the vise grip
on my dick one more notch.
-AII right. You do that.
-All right.
-Bye.
Bye.
Fuck!
DAN: You know, Garrett, I Iike the airplane.
People do cars too much.
Dan, are you kidding?
[BELL RINGS]
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello?
SARAH: Hello, Erin?
This is Sarah Conant at the Chronicle.
Hello.
Listen, we're all very impressed over here
by your work...
...and I would like to offer you the position
at our Metro desk.
-Really?
-Yes.
So we'll need you to come in
on April 15th at 10 a.m...
...and you can meet with our editors.
Okay. Thank you very much.
You're welcome. Bye-bye.
I'm sorry about not picking you up,
but I just really wanted to surprise you.
With the romance and the candles
and whatnot.
DAN:
Hey, Erin.
Hi, Dan.
DAN:
I missed you.
I missed you too, Dan.
DAN: I missed you so much.
-Dan.
Wait.
Just wait, wait, baby.
Wait a second, okay?
Okay. Can I be done waiting now?
-Listen, okay?
-What?
I just-- I need a second.
I wanna Iook at your face.
And I've missed you.
Oh, my God, I've missed you too.
What is it? Something's wrong.
I am really, really getting tired of us
spending so much time apart.
I know. I know, but Iook,
we're here now, so--
Yeah.
And, um....
But there's a job.
What do you mean? What job?
Well, I interviewed
with the San Francisco Chronicle...
...and they offered me a job.
Wow.
That's great.
-Yeah.
-Are you gonna take it?
I don't know.
GARRETT:
Oh. Man.
Wow.
What?
-Nothing.
-No, not "nothing." What?
It's a Iittle strange to me...
... because in one breath
you're telling me...
...that it's hard to be apart
and you're struggling with this.
And then in the next you're saying we
might be apart for a really Iong time.
No, I mean, I don't know yet, okay?
And my goal is to be here with you.
But this is such a big opportunity for me
that we need to talk about it.
Yeah, Iet's talk about this huge bomb
you just Iaid on me.
Fuck, Erin, you didn't even tell me
you interviewed.
I didn't mean to keep it from you.
Well, you did.
What do you mean, you didn't mean to?
It's something you either do or you don't.
You make a choice.
You know, amazingly,
I'm not in the mood.
Fuck.
Erin, you know what?
Let's just go out. Let's just go out.
I don't know, I'm feeling sexy tonight,
you know what I'm saying?
I got a good feeling Iike I might be getting
Iaid by one of you Iadies.
-Not it.
WOMEN: Not it.
BOX:
Come on, Dan, just shoot pool.
DAN: AII right, okay. I'm just trying
to talk about how sexy I feel.
I'm gonna go get another drink.
[CHATTERING]
[EELS' "PRIZEFIGHTER"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Well, if you need me
I'm right here
No matter what
I'm always near
Garrett.
-Hi.
What are you doing here?
Uh, Box invited me.
Of course.
-Do you wanna do a shot of Jager?
-Yes.
Hey, Christopher. Two.
This is so weird
to see you out of the off--
-You Iook great.
-Well, thanks.
Ahh. Thank you.
Hey. Um, I was just Iooking for you
because I wanted to-- Hello.
-Hi.
GARRETT: Um....
Sorry, this is Erin, my, um....
Girl-- Girlfriend.
This is Brianna, who I work with.
My friend.
BRIANNA:
It's so nice to finally meet you.
Garrett is always talking about you
and I hear your name all the time.
It's really nice to put a face to it.
-It's nice to meet you too.
BRIANNA: Um....
So are you planning on moving out here
any time soon?
Ooh.
-Hell of a question.
-I don't know.
-I--
-She knows.
She got big news today that pertains
to that very question. Tell her.
Tell her your big news.
Big news that I just found out about.
-No?
-It was nice to meet you.
-Yeah.
-Um....
I'm gonna go sleep at Brandy's
because it's obvious that you have--
I'm-- Yeah, bye.
AII right.
[BLOWS RASPBERRY]
CHRISTOPHER: Here you go.
-Oh, good.
Well...
...cheers.
-Are you okay?
-Ha, ha. I am now.
Ha, ha.
-You have a Iot of jingle jangles.
-Yeah, she does.
-Hi.
BRIANNA: Hi.
-Garrett, introductions.
-This is Dan. This is Brianna.
-Hi.
-Daniel.
-Oh.
-Daniel von...
...Jagermeister.
Hello, Daniel.
I'm a very wealthy man.
Garrett, can you buy us some shots?
GARRETT: Ha-ha-ha.
-Come on, Iet's get a drink.
What the fuck?
BRIANNA: Fuck! Fuck! I don't know,
I don't know what I was thinking!
I got so drunk Iast night.
I'm sorry. I drank so much.
Ha-ha-ha. Hey.
Knock, knock, in there.
How you doing, huh?
Hey, Iast night, awesome.
Seriously, the best sex of my Iife, ever.
You wanna go for round two?
Do it again?
BRIANNA: Dan, you threw up on me!
DAN: I did throw up on you.
I threw up on you a Iittle bit
and I apologized...
...and I thought we were past that.
I was hoping we were.
BRIANNA:
You cried all night.
DAN:
Crying is a part of feeling, all right?
Come on. You want some breakfast?
I'II cook you up some eggs.
BRIANNA: I have a boyfriend.
DAN: That's not a problem for me.
Hey.
[GARRETT SIGHS]
I should've just told you
about the interview, about everything.
You know, no matter what.
No.
You know, we'II figure it out.
We'II just figure it out.
ERIN: I know that you keep saying
that we're gonna figure it out...
...but we haven't.
But we will.
But we haven't and we need
to make a decision right away.
Okay, well, uh....
Yeah, I know. Make a decision, then.
Why is this all on me?
What are you talking about, "why you"?
Your decision.
So it's all about whether
I move to New York?
What about you moving
to San Francisco?
You kidding? I've been calling music Iabels
there for the Iast month...
...every day, diligently.
I called a Iabel that turned out
to be a kid...
...who's collecting demos from his friends.
He didn't want to hire me.
There's nothing. There are no jobs.
Trust me, I called them all.
I Iove that you're fine with me
moving to New York and waiting tables...
...but you wouldn't even think about
serving coffee in fucking San Francisco.
-It's all about what's convenient for you.
-Wait.
And you hate your job.
Fine, I'II just make the decision
for both of us.
You can just totally Ieave it all on me.
I got it.
[OVER SPEAKERS]
Look at me, oh, look at me
Is this the way I'll always be?
Oh, no, oh, no
Jesus, Harper.
Maybe be a Iittle more subtle?
I'm checking out their packages.
They want you to Iook.
BRANDY: Oh, that's gross.
-It's not gross, actually. Strangely.
-Um, hello?
GARRETT: Hey, Erin. What are you doing?
-Hello?
-I can't hear you.
-Where are you?
-Huh?
-Oh!
I'm at, Iike, this sketchy club.
It's girls' night out.
Oh, fun.
I can't hear you.
-Go outside.
-Hold on.
You guys save mine.
I gotta go outside and talk to Garrett.
He's an asshole.
Tell him to move here already.
Hey, Garrett.
-It's Harper. How you doing?
-Hey, Harper.
Look, Erin can't come to the phone...
... because she's gonna meet a guy
who Iives here and respects her...
...and she's gonna make out with him
and have his baby.
What?
I'm sorry.
You know, I shouldn't drink tequila.
Yeah, I know. It's okay.
No, it's just-- You know Harper,
she's out of her fucking mind.
-Why was she saying all that stuff?
-Look, don't worry about it, okay?
I told her about the fight, you know?
I had to, I'm sorry. I'm a fucking girl,
that's what we do. We talk it out.
-Right.
-Do you get it?
Sure, I've seen Moesha.
Cool. Okay, what's going on with you?
Hey, Iisten. I know you're on a deadline
to make a decision about this Chronicle job.
I know that, and you were right, by
the way. You should not be in this alone.
I wanna help you
and we're in this together, right?
But that being said,
I gotta be honest with you.
I want you in New York.
But not just you in New York, I want you
and me in New York Iiving together.
I wanna get a place with you,
a place that you Iove.
A place that we can make our own...
...where we can put Tom Cruise
all over the walls...
...and get Tom Cruise bed sheets
and Tom Cruise toilet paper.
Or we could buy our own Centipede
machine...
...and drink jugs of Sunshine Harbor
all day.
I just want a real relationship with you...
... because I Iove you
and you're my best friend.
And frankly, I am so tired of missing you.
And I know this is a Iot to put on you.
And I'm open to whatever...
...but I really wanna come out and see you
and figure all of this out together.
I'd Iike that.
Okay. Good.
-Okay.
-Bye.
Bye.
[SIGHS]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Maya Papaya.
Where's Erin? Is she here?
MAYA:
She's upstairs in the shower.
-Baby? Hey.
ERIN: Uh-huh?
-Hi. Hi.
-Hi.
-God, I missed you.
-I missed you too.
-Listen....
-What?
I wanna move to New York.
Are you serious?
Yes.
-Oh, my God.
-Yeah.
CORINNE:
So have you told the Chronicle yet?
No. I'm sort of waiting till Monday.
Okay.
Phil wants to know if you guys
wanna watch The Notebook.
-Where you going?
ERIN: Going inside.
CORINNE: Hey, Garrett.
-Hey. Do you need help?
-You can grab that for me.
-Okay.
-Start putting them on.
-Great.
So....
Must be excited, huh?
Yeah. Excited.
It's wonderful.
You know, Garrett,
how much I Iove my sister, right?
Of course.
I mean, she means everything to me.
And that, as you can see,
I'm very protective of her.
So it's been very hard for me watching her
struggle with this decision...
...to come with you
or to take this incredible job.
But, you know...
...she Ioves you.
And, uh, I know how much you Iove her.
But you need to know how much
she's giving up to be with you.
So don't break her heart.
Okay?
Or I'II cut your balls off.
-I'm not fucking kidding.
-Okay.
-I'm kidding.
-Jesus Christ.
-Um....
Thanks.
Um....
-So should I--?
-Take those in.
-Yep. Okay.
-Thanks.
[SIGHS]
Fucker.
Yeah, I wish I had Iived in New York
at some point in my Iife.
Oh, yeah?
I feel Iike I could have really
shaken up that place.
So, what are your plans for work?
Oh, I'm gonna wait tables
until I figure it out.
You still gonna do the writing?
-There are no jobs in New York, Phil.
PHIL: Mm.
Well, I mean, you know, not right now...
...but I think the newspaper business
is gonna bounce back.
Oh, yeah. No, that is a sensible gamble.
I can see Corinne's convinced.
[CORINNE & PHIL LAUGH]
PHIL:
She's onboard.
Well, you can always write just to write.
No one can stop you from doing that.
I'm not gonna not do what I do.
I just might take a while, you know.
I'm not gonna give it up.
Well, even if you did, you'd still be there
for Garrett, which is the important thing.
Exactly.
[DOOR OPENS]
ERIN: Hey.
-Hey.
I was Iooking for you.
How you doing?
I'm okay, how are you?
Good. You wanna take a Iittle walk?
Sure.
Come on.
What are you doing out here?
Nothing.
What's going on?
You have to take the job.
No. No, I'm not gonna give up
our relationship for a job.
No, no, no. Lookit, Iookit.
You need to take the job.
This is not about our relationship.
This is about asking you to give up
everything again, and I'm not gonna do it.
I'm not gonna do it.
And if you moved to New York,
it'd be great for a Iittle while.
But you'd eventually resent me,
and I can't Iive with that.
I can't. I won't.
What's gonna happen to us?
We can't see each other
every three months.
That's not a relationship.
But I Iove you.
This is....
-Why don't we just sit down for a minute?
-Yeah.
I really thought that we were something.
We were.
We were something.
He's here. No, I'm picking him up now.
AII right, hold on one sec.
-How you doing?
-Hey, buddy.
-What do you think, home or bar?
-Bar.
BOX:
Bar. AII right.
DAN:
Yeah, I'm really disturbed...
...because you would think that you would
find a baby pigeon somewhere.
But I don't see baby pigeons ever.
BOX: So, what do you want to do?
Do you just want to have this beer?
I mean, we can get you some harder Iiquor,
if you want to get really fucked up.
-No, this is good, buddy. Thanks, pal.
-Cool. AII right.
Drink a Iittle Frangelico?
No Sambuca shots? Nothing fun?
If you wanna dive off the deep end
into the sadness pool, we go to my place...
...Iisten to, Iike, the Garden State
soundtrack, watch Brian's Song.
-That probably wouldn't be the best thing.
-Want a hug?
I'm okay, buddy. Thanks. This is good.
-I want to hug you.
GARRETT: It's okay.
You need a hug, man. Come on, man.
Come on, buddy. There you go.
Okay. Thanks.
Why are your eyes closed?
-Mine?
-Mm-hm.
-Are yours not closed?
-No.
Oh.
Are your eyes--?
I just close my eyes when I hug.
No big deal.
You playing?
-Yeah.
-You any good?
-I'm okay.
-Damn.
That's one hell of a high score.
Yeah. Gonna be real tough to beat.
[ELECTRONIC BEEPING]
Hey, Erin, congratulations
on your front-page story.
Thank you.
I can't believe I'm on the cover. Heh.
So keep an open mind. Okay, we are
really Iucky to be getting in here early.
I got a tip from Chuck at the Crime desk.
And it's a sublet...
...and it's right in my price range,
and it's available for ten years.
Are you kidd--? Is this blood?
Is this blood on the wall?
Did someone get bludgeoned in here?
I'm not really sure of the details.
Something about a narcotics bust
or a cockfighting ring.
But Iet's be positive.
Yes. No, you're right. You're right.
Maybe it's just feces.
PHIL:
I think it's an up-and-comer.
They got a Boston Market on the corner.
They don't build those just any place.
It smells Iike a skin infection in there.
Smells Iike freedom to me.
The happiest people I know
are single and Iiving alone.
Grab it, Erin.
Before you know it, it'II be done.
You'II be trapped and dead.
You gotta do it.
Are you kidding? It's a shit hole.
[MUFFLED ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
The reason your conversation
is having a soundtrack...
...is because the walls are paper-thin,
all right?
Erin, you're not gonna
have any privacy in here.
I actually Iike music that comes through
the walls. I find it comforting.
I'm gonna take this place.
And I so appreciate what you and Phil
have done for me...
...but it is time for me to move out.
PHIL: I think you got a view
of the Transamerica building. Oh--
Erin, I know you Iove this place, but there's
a creepy man watching us hug right now.
ERIN: Really?
-Yeah.
Yeah.
-Let's go.
-Yeah. Okay.
ERIN:
AII right. You were right.
-Phil. Phil!
-Oh.
-Can we go to Boston Market?
CORINNE: We cannot go to Boston Market.
[OVER SPEAKERS]
Any way you want it
That's the way you need it
GARRETT:
Ah. I Iook Iike such an idiot.
BOX:
Trust me. It works.
GARRETT: But I'm not into
older women. That's your thing.
But you asked me for my help, all right?
You have a problem, I have a solution.
These women are good to go.
Yeah, good to go to an early bird special
at Denny's.
You haven't been out with a Iady
in what, six months.
So this is about getting back
on the horse.
Yeah. No, I know.
Now, sure, you're not gonna find yourself
a Kentucky Derby winner here tonight...
...but you might find a nice horse
to ride down the Grand Canyon on.
You get to the bottom
of the Grand Canyon...
...drop her off and
you go about your business.
That makes it worse.
Wooh! Sorry I'm running Iate, boys.
Three beers, yes?
GARRETT: Oh, no.
-What's going on?
-What the fuck?
-Holy shit.
What? You're not Charlie Chaplin fans?
This is gonna kill.
GARRETT:
I Iove Charlie Chaplin.
I'm not a fan of the guy
that has the exact mustache.
Where are you going with this?
At no point during shaving
did you think:
-"Cool it. I'm gonna Iook Iike Hitler"?
-Hitler? Oh, yeah, thought of that.
It's the plastered hair.
I knew you guys
were gonna give me shit.
I'm shaving it, and then...I get that
way too far on this side.
-Too far.
-I went too far down this side.
I started going back and forth,
back and forth. I stop.
If I stop now, and you can
still pull off Chaplin. You know what?
[IN GERMAN ACCENT] If you don't Iike it,
I'II send you to the gas chamber.
-You are doing Hitler.
-[IN NORMAL VOICE] I'II do whoever I want.
Pick a character and go--
-Hey, game faces. Hello.
-Hi.
-How you doing?
-Good.
You guys didn't go to school with us.
We did not. No.
You have a very foxy eye for detail.
-Wanna dance?
-I do.
-Time machine.
-Yeah.
Maybe my friend Garrett here
can join us?
I'm good. No. I'm good.
I'm gonna sit this one out.
-Bye, gentlemen. Shall we?
WOMAN: Let's do it.
[OVER SPEAKERS]
Hold on, hold on
Oh, man, this is ridiculous.
I know it's ridiculous.
-You know you don't have to be here.
-You think I'm gonna miss this?
No. Well, yeah. No, not this though.
I mean--
[SIGHS]
Look, Box and I, this is what we do.
We do stupid shit, and we'II be fine.
So if you're worried about us,
don't worry about us, man.
But you, you don't need to be here.
Yeah. I know.
Okay, then.
As Iong as you're thinking about it.
-Okay.
-I'm taking off.
These dudes don't Iook
Iike Chaplin fans to me.
GARRETT: Oh, boy.
DAN: They Iook Iike angry Jews.
[MOUTHS]
Sorry.
ERIN: Hello.
-Hello.
How was work?
-You know? Uh, it was awesome.
-Good.
Oh, hey. You got a package today.
-Oh, yeah?
-Mm-hm.
ERIN:
It's from Garrett.
Oh. What does it say?
"They're gonna be in San Francisco.
Thought you might wanna go."
CORINNE:
Who is?
The Boxer Rebellion.
That was one of the first bands
that we saw together.
Are you gonna go?
That depends.
On whether or not you'II be my date.
I can get drunk there, right?
CORINNE: There's sort of
an unidentifiable smell in here...
...that I can't quite just put my finger on.
I don't know, but just push your way in.
It's urine. It's urine. I smell urine.
Oh, good. That means it's a good club.
And puke. Oh, yeah.
There's a hint of puke. And urine.
ERIN: Well, that's even better.
-I know, then. Good.
[CROWD CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
[THE BOXER REBELLION'S
"IF YOU RUN" PLAYING]
-Sorry.
-It's all right.
Hi.
Hi, Corinne.
-Hey, Garrett. I Iike your haircut.
-Thanks. Did something different.
And your dick's in your pants,
so that's good.
I'm gonna go check out the....
Oh, fuck it. I'm just not gonna be here.
Okay? Okay?
ERIN:
You're gonna just--?
-Hi.
What are you doing here?
I manage the band.
-You do?
-Yes. Ha, ha. Crazy, I know.
-Really?
-Yeah.
That's-- That's great.
-Really?
-Yeah. Yeah.
-Wow.
-No, I Ieft the Iabel.
You were right, as it turns out.
I hated the hell out of my job.
Well, I hate to say "I told you so."
No, you don't.
You Iove saying "I told you so."
-You Iove it.
-You're right.
Who are you kidding?
So are you Iiving in New York?
I actually just moved to Los Angeles.
-Really?
-Yeah.
The band actually Iives in L.A.
And, I don't know if you know this,
I know you're not a huge geography fan...
...but L.A. is not only in the same
time zone as San Francisco...
...it's in the same state. So....
Yeah. It's very close.
Yeah. It's a one-hour flight.
A six-hour drive.
-Eighteen-hour hot-air balloon ride.
-Ha-ha-ha.
If you were to go that way.
Can I ask you a question?
Yeah.
I don't know what your situation is....
I miss you.
That's not a question.
Yeah, it is.
[SINGING]
I'm always here
Waiting for you
All alone
Eyes of the night
Just to see
See you home
There's two of us
In it
They follow
All night
GARRETT: I can't believe she Ieft
without us. That's so weird.
ERIN: It's a school night
and she probably didn't Iike the band.
GARRETT: She didn't Iike--
She didn't Iike me. She hates me.
How am I gonna win that crazy one over?
Now that we're spending more time
with each other...
...which I couldn't be happier about,
maybe you should get your own apartment.
Just so we don't have to sneak around
her house, you know, Iike teenagers.
[WHISPERS] Shh. But for tonight,
Iet's just go upstairs, Iike adults.
GARRETT [WHISPERS]: That's very mature.
-Okay.
Shh, shh, shh.
Wait, wait, wait.
[MOANING]
[BOTH YELL]
ERIN [IN NORMAL VOICE]:
C-- Uh--
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Are you guys--? Are you dry humping?
-No.
-Sorry.
-But I didn't--
-I don't care if you didn't finish. Get off.
MAYA:
Mommy? Are you okay?
ALL:
Maya, statue!
[ENGLISH - US - SDH]