[ Drumroll ]
[ Man ]
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
The Luxurious Stars
Desert Inn Hotel in Las Vegas...
is proud to present
the final performance...
of an exciting engagement,
the incomparable singing sensation,
Miss Deloris Van Cartier!
กำ Hold on, hold on กำ
กำ Started my life กำ
กำ In a worn, torn dress
that somebody threw out กำ
-กำSomebody threw out กำ
- กำ I knew the way it felt
to always live in doubt กำ
กำ To be without
the simple things กำ
กำ So afraid my friends
would see the guilt in me กำ
กำ So I got a good job
in the city กำ
กำ Working for the man
every night and day กำ
กำ But I never lost
one minute of sleep กำ
กำ Worryin' about the way
things might have been กำ
กำ I was a devil with
the blue dress, blue dress กำ
กำ I was a devil
with the blue dress on กำ
I was a ho !
กำ Sugar pie, honey bun กำ
- กำ Sugar pie, honey bun กำ
- กำ You know I love you กำ
-กำLove you กำ
- กำ I can't help myself กำ
- กำ I love you and nobody else กำ
-กำ Wait กำ
กำ Oh, yeah
Wait a minute, Mr. Postman กำ
- กำ Wait กำ
- กำ Wait, Mr. Postman กำ
- กำ Mr. Postman, look and see กำ
- กำ Oh, yeah กำ
- กำ If there's a letter
in your bag for me กำ
- กำ Please, please กำ
- กำ Mr. Postman กำ
- กำ I've been waiting
such a long, long time กำ
กำ Deliver the letter
The sooner the better กำ
กำ She wore an itsy-bitsy teeny-weeny
yellow polka-dot bikini กำ
-กำStop in the name of love กำ
- กำ But my mama told me กำ
กำ You better shop around กำ
[ Deloris ] So that's what I did,
ladies and gentlemen, I shopped.
[ Deloris ]
I shopped and I shopped and I shopped.
I found myself
something special.
I got myself
a brand-new hustle.
กำ Do the hustle กำ
กำDo the hustle
Do the hustle กำ
กำMoney, money, money
Money กำ
กำ Money, money, money กำ
กำ I was a bad girl กำ
กำ Talkin' about a sad girl
Freak out กำ
กำ Mr. Big Stuff
Who do you think you are กำ
กำ Mr. Big Stuff, you're
never gonna get my love กำ
Whoa ! See how
they treat me ?
He got my cousin.
He got my coat.
When I tried to get it back,
he whipped out this great big--
กำ Shotgun กำ
กำ Shoot him
before he runs now กำ
กำ Do the jerk, baby กำ
กำ Do the jerk now กำ
Hey ! I had--
กำ Nowhere to run to, baby กำ
-กำNowhere to hide I had กำ
- กำ Ooo-ooo-ooo กำ
- กำ Nowhere to run to, baby กำ
-กำ Ooo-ooo-ooo กำ
กำ I didn't have nowhere
to hide until กำ
กำ Hallelujah, hallelujah กำ
Magic !
กำHallelujah, hallelu--กำ
All right, you all, you know this song.
Let's sing it.
กำ Nothing you could say could
tear me away from my God กำ
She's coming !
กำ Nothing you could do
'cause I'm stuck like glue กำ
กำ To my God กำ
กำMy God, my God กำ
Hey ! These are my friends.
Ladies, sing this for me.
- กำ We are กำ
- [ Deloris ] Come up and join us.
Come on, and hurry up.
Ladies !
[ Deloris ]
กำ There's not a man today กำ
กำ Who can take me away--กำ
Hey!
-กำI love Him, I love Him กำ
- Hey !
- Pull it up.
- กำ I will follow Him กำ
- Look out !
- กำ Wherever He may go กำ
-กำ There isn't an ocean too deep กำ
- กำ Too deep กำ
- กำ A mountain so high it can keep กำ
-กำKeep กำ
กำKeep me away กำ
-กำAway from His love กำ
- Oh !
- What the hell are you doing ?
- Go, go, go, go !
กำ We are family
I got all my sisters with me กำ
กำ We are family กำ
กำ Get up, everybody
and sing, swing กำ
กำ We are family
I got all my sisters with me กำ
กำ We are family กำ
กำ Get up, everybody
Get up, everybody กำ
and sing กำกำ
[ Cheering, Applause ]
Thank you !
[ Man ]
Deloris,you were fantastic.
- Deloris, excellent.
- Oh, my !
Nice outfit.
I'm glad I didn't wear mine.
I got to tell you, Sisters,
that last bit was great.
I'm a very big fan of yours.
I got your album.
This is my manager.
This is Joey.
-What do you want ?
-Are you currently represented ?
They're nuns,Joey.
God represents them. Come on.
God is good, but can he get you your own
dressing room ? You were great.
Oh, thanks.
I love to sing. She taught me.
I am so glad to see you.
What are you doing here ?
Came to see you.
Can you stay
a long time ?
We have to be back
on the road tonight.
- We don't have time to chat.
- Maybe a little.
We do have to get back.
We're teachers now. It's a school night.
[ Mary Robert ]
And really it's all because of you.
You inspired us to go out
into the community...
and do some good
in the hood.
- Oh, my.
- Can I get you guys
something ? Sit down.
- No.
- No ?
Can they even hear you in the back
of the room when you're teaching ?
I'm getting better. Oh, we're teaching
at St. Francis Academy in San Francisco.
I went to that school. Oh ! It was--
Oh ! They need good teachers.
We're having
a barrel of laughs.
Although the kids sometimes
get a little unruly.
-Just a little.
- Actually, they're out of control.
It was so bad last week
Sister Mary Patrick frowned twice.
[ Deloris ]
Oh!
- Let's get down to business.
- [Joey ] Excuse me.
- Any matters of business
have to go through me.
- Excuse me.
- These are my friends,
and I am talking to them.
- I would like--
- I'm talking to my friends now.
- I am your manager.
- Forgive us. Excuse me.
- Go ahead.
Thank you. Now, come on, you guys,
you come up here, you come to see me.
What's goin' on ? Does Mother Superior
really know you're here ?
She sent us
on this m-mission to--
The Reverend Mother said
we're not to come back without you.
- What does she want ?
- [ Mary Patrick ]
We're not entirely certain.
But we know that she needs you and she
wants us to come and bring you back.
Is she okay ? Health-wise ?
Is she in danger ?
Oh, no, she's fine. Well,
she's a little desperate.
She's desperate ?
I'll get it.
It's all right.
What, what ?
What ? What ?
Sit, sit, sit, sit !
Welcome.
Oh, welcome.
[ Deloris ]
It's good to see you, good to see you.
Oh, Sister Mary Clar--
Oh, I do apologize. Deloris.
- Uh-huh.
- It's so good to see you too.
I'm sorry I couldn't join
the Sisters in Las Vegas.
I've heard you are
truly a spectacle.
Well, yeah, you know,
I work at it.
You're probably wondering why I asked
the Sisters to bring you here.
I am a little curious.
What's all the mystery ?
Well, you see, Deloris,
we need your help here...
at St. Francis.
We seem to have got in
slightly over our heads.
What... do you want ?
Help us
by becoming a teacher.
A teacher ? Me ?
Oh, no.
[ Chuckling ]
Listen, I'm not cut out
to be a teacher.
Who would I teach ?
What would I teach ?
Teach the children.
Teach music.
You weren't cut out to be a nun either,
but look what you accomplished
at St. Katherine's.
You brought a new spirit into
the convent and into the community.
You were... infectious.
You could be just
as infectious here.
You're making me
sound like a disease.
We are struggling here with
a community that is tired...
and worn
and despairing.
We saw this school
as some sort of renewal,
but it's becoming
a hopeless situation.
We have nowhere
else to turn.
We are desperate women,
Deloris.
We need you.
- Oh ! I'm--
- Think of the children.
We must invest in their future.
It is our duty.
Who better to help us
than you ?
I'm a lounge singer.
You are the perfect example
of how a sow's ear...
can be turned
into a silk purse.
Hmm.
Well, I probably wouldn't have
put it quite like that.
I mean, look.
I mean, really.
My career's starting to take off.
I kind of want to get into my success.
A success you might not
have had...
without the help of
certain supportive friends...
who shall remain nameless.
Oh, so you're going to be like
that, huh, with the guilt ?
Guilt ?
I would never use guilt.
I'm a nun.
All right,
I'll do it for you.
Oh, thank you, Deloris.
I knew we could count on you.
But you're just talking
about like a week, right ?
I don't think we should restrict
ourselves to a time frame.
Sisters, Sisters.
Deloris has agreed
to join our teaching staff.
- So, could you take her
to the changing room ?
- Sure, absolutely.
He--
[ Deloris ] Somebody tell me
why I'm dressed like this again.
The Fathers here
at St. Francis are very strict.
If they were to find out you're neither
a nun or a teacher, they might--
- Ask me to leave ?
- In a New York minute.
- Yeah, well, now, I'm undercover again.
- It could be fun.
- Convent living is kind of grim.
- All I need is a bed...
- and a place to kneel.
- Wait until you see what
we have in the room for you.
- You didn't go out and do
something silly, did you ?
- Well, maybe.
- What did you put in, a bidet ?
- A bi-what ?
- Never mind. What is it ?
- A watched pot never boils.
- No, no, don't tell her.
It's a surprise.
- Okay.
- Ready ? One, two, three.
- One, two, three.
[ Ticking ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
Curtains.
Sometimes it resembles
a battleground at recess here.
- For the most part, the kids
are really well-behaved.
- Yeah.
[ Chattering ]
- A new nun ?
- Yeah, Sister Mary something or other.
I'm terrible at names.
Come in.
- Who was that ?
- The older one is...
our principal,
Father Maurice.
The other one is our
school administrator, Mr. Crisp.
He's only been here
a few months.
She looks familiar. I think
I've seen her somewhere before.
-Just long enough to hate us.
- Some of the kids
call him the devil incarnate.
-He's just got a bad case of the grumps.
-I don't care who he is.
I just want to put
the top up on my car.
If there's
a car left.
What's she mean by that ?
Is that a joke ? Hey !
I'd like you all to join me
in welcoming the new addition...
to the teaching staff
here at St. Francis, Sister Mary--
- [ Whispering ] Clarence.
- Clarence.
Who will be teaching
our, uh--
- Music.
- Is there still a music class ?
- In a manner of speaking.
Why is he asking, ''Is there a music
class ?'' How come he doesn't know ?
Sister Mary Clarence will be
teaching our music class.
[ Applause ]
I think
each of you should...
- introduce yourselves.
- [ Man ] I'll start.
I'm Father Ignatius.
I teach math.
I'm Thomas.
Ave, magistra nova.
- Latin teacher.
- Oh, good.
[ Mr. Crisp ]
Excuse me.
Ah, and this is Mr. Crisp.
This is Sister Mary Clarence.
Oh, yes, the new nun.
Sister Mary Clemens.
- Clarence.
- Clarence !
Like in Thomas.
I'm the music teacher.
- The music teacher ?
- Yeah. You're gripping me here.
- Oh, yes, I'm sorry.
- Thank you.
Yes, I just
stopped by to, uh,
remind you of our
meeting this afternoon.
- Yes,yes, oh,yeah.
- Well, pardon the intrusion.
[ Mr. Crisp ]
Bon appetit.
Gruss Gott.
[ Father Maurice ] Ah, and this is
Father Wolfgang, who, uh, cooks...
so, uh, diligently to minister
to our dietary needs.
For luncheon,
bratwurst a la Provence.
He only knows how to cook
one thing, German sausage.
Day after day, liverwurst,
bratwurst, bierwurst.
It's the worst.
Oh, no, no, no.Jenny Craig,
I just couldn't. Thank you so much.
Hmph !
This, uh, needs a prayer.
[ Bell Chiming ]
[ Chuckling ]
- Damn.
- [ Chiming Continues ]
Oh, Sister Clarence, I wonder if I
could have a word with you in private ?
- Oh, no, I need to--
- No, please.
Sure.
Thank you.
Oh. Won't you sit down ?
Yes, the Sisters tell me
that your last posting was...
at a women's prison facility
in the Louisiana bayou.
- What ?
- It wasn't ?
No, no, it was, it was.
It was-- Yes, of course.
I mean, it was-- Yeah, no,
the prison was really rough on me.
So, I, I, I, I been trying to wipe
this experience from my mind...
because it was
so traumatic for me.
- Really ?
- Yes !
They'd led me to believe
that you enjoyed it.
Well, in a--
Yes, I did.
It was a traumatic enjoyment of an
experience that I should not have had...
and appreciated the way
that I did because I'm a nun.
And nuns are not meant to have
enjoyable experiences...
because they lead to
all kinds of situations,
which is where I found myself,
which is why I'm here now,
and I know that
you understand that.
Oh, well, yes, indeed,
I do see what you mean.
- I knew you would.
- As I do with all my new teachers,
I'd like to share with you
my theories about education,
gleaned from my years of experience
here as the principal of St. Francis.
- I am an open book.
- Discipline.
Mm-hmm.
Anything else to go with that ?
That's it ? Discipline ?
Unfortunately, I think that's
pretty much all we can expect here.
You have any questions ?
No, I feel as though I have
absorbed all I can from you.
Well, then,
I wish you good day...
and good luck.
Thank you,
Your Eminenceship.
Thank you so much.
[ Kissing Sound ]
[ Chuckling ]
Okay, Your
Royal Pappyness.
[ Door Rolling Closed ]
- Piece of work, isn't he ?
- A prison ?
- You lied to me,
and you're gonna go to hell.
- [ Gasping ]
[ Father Thomas ] You call. Vocant,
they call, are calling, do call.
Voco, I call,
am calling, do call.
Vocas,you call,
are calling, do call.
Voco, I call,
am calling, do call.
[ Mark Patrick ] Class, eyes up,
pencils down, mouths closed.
Today we're going to learn
a valuable lesson and maybe
have a little fun doing it.
- Yeah, right.
- The topic for today: promiscuity.
Promiscuity. Who can
tell me what that means ?
- Sandra.
- In your dreams.
Sandra, I know you have
a question burning inside there.
You can't answer
any questions about sex.
Oh, don't be so sure. You don't have to
bite the doughnut to know it's sweet.
Come on. Plus we have
the Bible right here.
Sister Mary Clarence ?
Oh, you look a little lost.
- Yes !
- Who isn't ?
- What, you can't find the music room ?
- No.
It's downstairs. Take a left,
a right, a right, another left--
All right, I'm sorry.
It's tricky.
I'll help you find it. Follow me,
and I'll show you exactly where it is.
I know exactly what you mean.
When I first got here, one hall
looks like another hall.
One stairwell looks
like another stairwell.
Sometimes I find myself just
stopping dead in my tracks and going,
''Oh, Lord, come to my rescue,
come to my aid.''
- Watch your step.
- Yeah.
- Well, here we are. It's the, um,
-กำกำ[ Students Rapping ]
- music class.
-กำกำ[ Rapping Continues ]
Ah, well, thank you.
Oh, oh, oh, oh. Remember, nothing
ever is as bad as it seems at first.
Fight the good fight.
- Okay.
- Cercum corda.
Oh, wait a minute.
What ? What was that ?
It's Latin. It means,
'' Lift up your heart.''
I thought you said,
''Insert some quarters.'' I'm sor--
- I don't know if I'm cut out for this.
- You're jokin' me.
- The children are waiting.
- Yeah. Ain't they ?
กำ Cold beans, hey
and collard greens, hey กำ
and collard greens กำ
กำHey, cold beans กำ
Oh, no, see, that's why your mama
deejays for the ice-cream truck.
Oh, it's you !
- Thank heaven you're here.
-กำกำ[ Rapping Continues ]
Class, this is
your new teacher.
Sister Mary Clarence.
Class !
Your mama is so fat, she sat
on a rainbow and Skittles popped out.
Class ! Well,
congratulations,
you're the new mayor
of Sodom and Gomorrah.
กำ Cold beans, hey
and collard greens กำ
[ Girl ]
That's why your mother's so fat.
She's on both sides of the rainbow.
[ Laughing ]
กำ Cold beans, hey
and collard greens กำ
Keep the faith. Remember,
our Lord said, '' Be ye strong of will.''
And ye better be
tough as nails too.
Yeah.
กำ Cold beans, hey
and collard greens กำ
- [ Door Slams ]
-กำHey, cold beans, hey
and collard greens กำ
กำ Hey, cold beans, hey
and collard greens กำกำ
[ Scratching ]
- [ Murmuring ]
- Good morning.
I'd like to introduce myself.
Would you all put your seats
back in order, please ?
[ Murmuring ]
[ Girl ]
Watch my new shoes!
Aaah !
I have this funny problem with my ears.
I don't like a lot of noise.
So maybe you could do it quietly?
Thank you.
I'd like to introduce myself. My name
is Sister Mary Clarence, and I am--
- Yo, mama ?
- No, sir, let's talk about your mama,
who's so dumb she got hit
by a parked car.
- [ Students ] Ooh!
- Thank you. Let's try attendance.
I'd like to
introduce myself.
I am Tyler Chase, and on behalf
of the whole music class as we are--
Tyler! Tyler! You got
a little something on your nose.
Yeah, Tyler, a big, big
brown thing right around here.
'' Hello, I'm Tyler Chase.''
- [ Students Making Kissing Sounds ]
- Thank you, Mr. Chase.
- Richard Pincham.
- Wake up, fool !
Paper or plastic ?
I beg your pardon.
Are you Richard ?
Yeah.
- Did you do these ?
- Yeah. S-Sorry.
- Let me see.
- That's why they call me Sketch.
I do sketches.
Sorry.
- These are real good.
- Thanks.
- Try to stay awake in my class, though.
- All right.
WesleyJames ?
Wesley GlenJames ?
Respectfully, my sister,James is
the slave name forced upon my ancestors.
While Wesley, that's some name my
assimilationist parents came up with.
But today, in honor of all my brothers
and sisters who died in the struggle,
I wish to be called
by my true name,
Ahmal M'jomoJamaael,
which means,
'' He who is spirited.''
- And long-winded.
- A simple ''present''
would've done it, bro.
- And who are you ?
- Fran-kay.
กำ Hey, ho, hey กำ
Check it out.
กำ Hello there, miss, and
let me kick an introduction กำ
กำ Flute, violin, bass guitar
and then percussion-- กำกำ
Just stop. Can't you come up
with your own thing ?
Must you continually come behind
my people and steal our expressions ?
First jazz, then rock and roll, now rap.
What you gonna try to take next, man ?
- I'm gonna take your girl
if you ain't careful.
- Keep talkin', boy.
Excuse me. Let's leave
this display of manhood outside,
shall we ? Thank you so much.
Yo, could we hurry this up ?
Some of us got things to do.
- [ Girl ] You know what I'm sayin'?
- Are you Rita Watson ?
Yeah, that's me. I'm sorry
I don't have any cute stories
or ''antidotes'' to tell you.
- Anecdote.
- Shut up. Mind your business.
How 'bout we just call you
Rita Diva-with-a-'tude ?
Sister, maybe I can help you out ?
Are we all here ?
- [ Students ] Yeah!
- We're here.
Thank you. All right.
What have you been doin' ?
-[ Boy ] Is she jokin'?
- All right, let me give you
an easier question.
Where are
the music books ?
- [ Boy ] Up there!
- Oh !
Maybe I should explain
something to you, Sister.
See, this is what
we call a bird course.
The reason we call it
a bird course...
- is because we fly right through it.
- [ Twittering ]
[ Rita ] See, all you got to do
to pass in this class is show up.
Hmm. So you come
to class,
you do nothing...
and you pass ?
Oh, no, we don't exactly
do nothing.
We have a good time too.
Yo, Frankie.
กำ Cold beans, hey
and collard greens กำ
and collard greens กำกำ
Money ? You're
asking for money ?
Yes ! You know, that little
green stuff that has pictures...
of dead presidents on it,
and you use it to buy things...
like instruments
or songbooks.
- Sister Mary Clemens.
- [ Sighing ]
Mr. Crisp, my name
is Mary Clarence.
Clarence. I think
you're confusing St. Francis...
with Loyola Marymount
or the University of Notre Dame.
- There is no money here.
- Yet they manage to pay you, Crispy.
Mr. Crisp is right. Frankly, we're lucky
to be open for business at all.
Then I wish one of you
would tell me...
what it is I'm supposed
to do with these children.
[ Boy ] Go! Run!
Get outta here!
Teach them
to play... soccer!
We don't have the balls
for that.
[ Sketch ] กำMister Graffiti Artist
I get more press กำ
กำ ThanJackieJackson
talkin'to Oprah Winfrey กำ
กำ When I kick these rhymes up
in a bundle,you turn purple กำ
กำ You're pulling your pants
up like Urkel,yeah
So jump if you're with me กำ
กำ Yeah, so jump
if you're with me กำ
- กำ Yeah, who gots the flo'
Who gots the flo' กำ
- I got the flo'.
กำ Grab the microphone
and let your funky lyrics go กำ
กำ Here I go on the microphone
About to wreck it กำ
กำ You thought a female M.C.
couldn't do it, but now check it กำ
กำ If the blues is what you choose
I'll kick it Count Basie style กำ
กำ But if bebop is what you rock
I'll kick the Monk or some Miles กำ
กำ Won't grab no phillies
My style is willing if you let me กำ
กำ Or if I choose to 'cause
women's lib said I don't have to กำ
กำSo think again before
you test a sister, 'cause
with my girls behind me กำ
- กำ We got lots of power, mister กำ
- กำ Oh, oh กำ
กำ Who gots the flo'
Grab the microphone and
let your funky lyrics go กำ
กำ I got the flo'
You all gotta go กำ
กำ So go get your bags
so we can go, ho-ho กำ
กำ Aaah, oh, oh, now กำกำ
- Thank you, thank you.
- [ Boy ] She's back.
[ Students ]
She's back.
The question at hand is,
how do we get this nun...
to extricate herself from us
quickly and expeditiously ?
- In other words,
let's get this nun to run.
- I'm not sure I'm down for this.
That's like messin'
with higher power.
Plus, this Sister is like a sister
Sister, know what I'm saying ?
- She ain't no sister of yours.
- Hey, hey, hey, chill, okay ?
- I heard that.
- We all got to agree on this.
Are we in or are we out ?
[ Man ]
Young man! Picasso!
Keep this job,
get your butt back in here, boy.
Guess I know what that means. I'll
stick with the majority on this one.
- I gotta go, so I'll check y'all later.
- All right, home.
- Peace.
- Adieu.
There's no dialogue, man.
Come on.
Rita Louise Watson !
You better get your behind
in this house now.
- You got homework to do.
- [ Rita ] Ma!
- Ma, we're just chillin'.
- Rita, don't make me
come down there after you.
- Call me tonight
so we can figure out a plan.
- All right.
- [ Ma ] Rita!
- On second thought,
call me in the mornin'.
- Peace, y'all.
- See ya later, Rita.
[ Bell Chiming ]
[ Boy ]
Hey, here she comes!
Hey, shh !
[ Girl Clearing Throat ]
[ Boy Clearing Throat ]
Well,you look like
my class.
Is, uh, something
goin' on ?
[ In Unison ]
No, Sister Mary Clarence.
I saw a scene like this once
in a horror movie.
They subdued an entire
community by putting some kind
of weird drug in the water.
Is that what's
going on here ?
All right, uh, today...
I'd like to talk about music,
because that's what I am.
I am the music teacher,
and it's what I love.
Now, when you think about
various people and what they like,
you think, well, this one
likes this, this one likes that.
Me, I'm what
you call eclectic.
- '' Eclectic'' ?
- What's that ?
You plug your box into the wall
and it gives you power, stupid.
Not electric,
eclectic, stupid.
Let me simplify it for you.
When I say ''eclectic,''
what I mean is, I like lots
of different types of music.
Opera, rock and roll, rap,
I like it all.
But my favorite,
my absolute all-time favorite,
are the girl groups
from the '50s and '60s.
- Like who ?
- Tyler ! Shut up !
- Idiot, man.
- Tyler, shut up !
Ladies and gentlemen,
let us not badger...
- Are we dumb ?
- this man who wants this information.
I like Patti LaBelle and the Bluebells,
and I like the Supremes.
[ Tyler ]
Who are the Supremes ?
You don't need to get
physical with him.
Oh, you're gonna get
jumped after school, Tyler.
Yes, it is a shocking question:
''Who are the Supremes ?''
- You never heard of Diana Ross ?
- [ Tyler ] Oh, Diana Ross.
- Well, let me tell you.
They were the premier group.
- Yes!
As you hear, your comrades-in-arms say,
''Yes !'' Because they were incredible.
-What I love when I think about music...
-About time.
is how you can take
this type of music and that type
of music and fuse it together.
- Mmm.
- Fusion !
Yeah, fusion.
I'm really glad you're into this.
The best example
I can give you, now--
- [ Cloth Ripping ]
- [ Hysterical Laughing ]
[ Cheering, Applause ]
- [ Cloth Ripping ]
- You got busted !
[ Chanting ]
Fusion! Fusion! Fusion!
Fusion ! Fusion ! Fusion !
- [ Chanting Continues ]
Fusion! Fusion!
- [ Grunting ]
[ Panting, Growling ]
[ Grunting ]
Goddamn it.
Oh, man !
- [ Crashing ]
- Ooh!
- [ Knocking ]
- [ Mary Clarence ] Yeah ?
[ Door Creaking ]
[ Mother Superior ] We want you
to know that we understand...
and that you're quite free
to leave whenever you please.
I'm sure you'll be much
better off in show business.
Goodness knows,
the money is better.
I'm sure bright lights and
sequins are far prettier to look
at than anything we have here.
Do you know what I hate most
about this place ?
There's nothing to pick up
and throw.
We understand.
Yeah.
- Bye-bye.
- Would you like a cup of tea ?
[ Door Creaking ]
[ Father Maurice ] Oh, this mustn't
happen. It can't happen.
It would be criminal,
absolutely criminal if this happened.
St. Francis' school and church
have been a beacon of hope...
to the people of this community
for many, many years.
If we close down the school, it would
be an absolute and total disaster.
- You're absolutely sure
nothing can be done ?
- [ Man ] I'm afraid not.
I was hoping we could keep it open
until the end of the school year.
- We know it's unfortunate.
- We don't like it either.
The Archdiocese has decided St. Francis
should close at the end of the semester.
Why does it have
to happen so quickly ?
You're totally in the red with
very little hope of recovery.
You must realize, Father, the community
contributions have been nil.
The school has no outstanding
academic or achievement records.
I've been exploring the possibility
of other uses for the property.
- [ Father Maurice ] What ?
- [ Mr. Crisp ]
Yes, and the bottom line is...
it's more valuable as a parking lot
than it is as a school.
The recommendation
is to close.
Well, I suppose there's
nothing more to be said.
Well, thank you.
Mr. Crisp, you should be
commended for your work...
and your excellent
analysis of the situation.
Thank you very much,
but I do wish...
you'd consider my application
for early retirement.
After all, I have been working for
the Archdiocese doing this work...
for almost 30 years now,
and I would just like my due.
- Why, absolutely.
- Thank you, thank you.
- Let's go out and have
some lunch now, shall we ?
- Excellent idea.
- What ?
- When ?
- The end of the semester.
- Where did you hear that ?
I happened to be eavesdropping
in Father Maurice's office,
and I heard him talkin'.
We were afraid this might happen.
I've been expecting it for some time.
- What do we do now ?
- We'll probably be reassigned.
The children will be bused to
a public school in another district.
What a stupid thing to do. This is
the only school left in this community.
We've got to do something.
Otherwise we're gonna lose our
students and not get them back.
Then I guess we are
going to do something.
- Now, you do mean ''we,''
don't you ? We !
- Yes, yes, we !
- You're not leaving ?
- I said I was gonna come
and help. Here I am.
- Thank you, Deloris.
-Just call me Mary Clarence.
[ Mother Superior
Chuckling ]
[ Bell Chiming ]
- Oh, Reverend Mother.
I'd like to speak to you.
- Oh, Father Maurice.
- My mind is consumed
with trying to deal with--
- Sister Mary Clarence.
- Yes, as a matter of fact.
- I am familiar with the dilemma.
I'm told that she presided at
the ecclesiastical equivalent...
of a pep rally
last night.
- Yes, I am aware of this.
- You are ? How did you know ?
You'll find that when one deals
with Sister Mary Clarence,
one is smothered with more information
than one wishes to possess.
I'm afraid she's becoming
quite disruptive.
Disruption is the way
Mary Clarence communicates.
I worry about raising
false hopes among the children.
Advise me, Reverend Mother.
Tell me about your experiences
with Mary Clarence.
No, I wouldn't
want to frighten you.
But in my experience,
I found it easier and ultimately...
quite effective to give
Mary Clarence a free hand.
Aren't her ideas
extremely radical ?
If I remember correctly,
the term ''radical'' was
applied to us in our day.
Or have you forgotten the trouble
we caused Bishop O'Malley ?
- Oh, yes, Bishop O'Malley.
- [ Chuckling ]
Give Mary Clarence
a chance.
If the school is on
the road to closure,
at least she'll make it
an interesting ride.
[ Students Chattering ]
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.
Please take your seats.
Do it quickly
and quietly.
Welcome to the first day
of your new scholastic lives.
This is no longer
a bird course.
The bird has flown.
If you want to pass this course,
you gonna have to earn it,
'cause I have no problems,
not one, failing
each and every one of you.
- I never thought
this was no bird course.
- I'm glad for you.
Very, very glad,
'cause this is a new day.
- Things are going to be
a little different around here.
- Oh, yeah ?
- Like how ?
- Like when I talk, Fran-kay, you don't.
Is this something you want to share
with the rest of the class ?
- I'm just kicking it with my girl.
- I'll tell you what,
you gonna kick it with me
or I'm gonna kick you out.
- What you think of that ? Put 'em away.
- Cold.
And you. This is not
Elizabeth Arden, Miss Thing.
You want to beat that mug of
yours, you do it at home before
you come to class, understand ?
Put it away.
And you, Sketch,
I like you a lot, but I don't want you
catching Z's in my class no more.
- I be tired. I got a job--
- Baby, save it for Oprah.
This is a brand-new day,
ladies and gentlemen, a brand-new day.
We're gonna start with respect.
You're gonna respect me,
and I'm gonna respect you.
And the first thing you're gonna do,
gentlemen, is take off those hats.
This is a brand-new day.
[ Students Laughing ]
I guess that means you're
gonna be combing your hair
before you come to my class.
And I know you laughin'
over there, so you think
this is very funny, Miss Thing.
There is no sun in this room.
You will not get a tan.
Take off those sunglasses.
That goes for you too. If they're not
prescription, I don't want to see 'em.
I want to see you.
I want to look into your eyes.
I want you to be able
to look into mine.
- Yes, Miss Watson ?
- We don't want no new way.
The old way was fine
for us, right ?
- Right !
- Yeah !
Okay, so if you're gonna fail us,
then you might as well go ahead,
'cause, um,
I ain't doin' nothin'.
Fine, that's how you feel,
there's the door.
Don't let it hit you
in the butts on your way out.
Yo, yo, Sis, I can't
afford to fail this class.
You better tell your friends
you can't afford to fail this class.
My parents
wouldn't be pleased.
Come on, y'all, we ain't gotta
take this from her. Come on.
Sketch, come on, man.
Fran-kay ?
Yo, Rita, you know I'm usually
down for stuff like this, but, yo,
I'm gonna take care
of business this time.
A little lonely out on that limb
by yourself, Miss Watson ?
So much for friendship.
[ Woman ]
กำIf you wanna be somebody กำ
กำIf you wanna
go somewhere กำ
กำ You better wake up
and pay attention กำ
[ Deloris ] All right, let's get down
to business, ladies and gentlemen.
You wanna go somewhere
and you wanna be somebody,
you better wake up and
pay attention, honey, 'cause
the real world is out there.
They don't care
how hip you think you are.
Or who you kick it with.
It don't matter.
[ Deloris ] If you don't have
an education,you don't have anything.
And that's the truth, honey.
กำIf you wanna be somebody
If you wanna go somewhere กำ
กำ You better wake up
and pay attention กำ
กำPay attention,you gotta
wake up, wake up, baby กำกำ
But we cannot do it by
ourselves, we need the help.
We're here for the children, right ?
If not for them, for who ?
Look, let's start
with the curriculum, okay ?
Let's talk about boring.
I can barely stay awake
to teach it.
I have some good ideas
for goosing up sex ed.
And what are we gonna do about
the graffiti ? Not that a bucket
of paint couldn't fix it.
- I'd love to see us teach new math.
- Yes !
No, no, you've got to
face facts. We're closing down.
Yes, we may be closing,
but we're not closed yet.
So why don't we go out
with a little class ?
[ Deloris ]
Come on, people, let's hear it again.
[ In Unison ] If you wanna be somebody,
if you wanna go somewhere,
you better wake up
and pay attention.
Make me believe
what you're sayin'.
- Could we waken this up a little ?
- Yeah, if you think you can.
Okay, Dionna.
กำ If you wanna be somebody
If you wanna go somewhere กำ
- กำ You better wake up
and pay attention กำ
- กำ Pay attention กำ
กำ If you wanna be somebody
If you wanna go somewhere กำ
กำ You better wake up
and pay attention กำกำ
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute !
Talk about a wake-up call.
Where did this come from ?
This is a music class,
isn't it ?
Yes, this is a music class.
You tellin' me you guys can sing ?
No, really,
that was great. My--
I just figured out how I'm gonna
get you through this music class.
- [ Boy ] Oh, no, really?
- Yes, yes !
I'm gonna turn you guys
into a choir.
Nope !
[ Sketch ] Come on, I mean, most
choirs are just a bunch of people...
singing wack songs
that nobody care about.
[ Deloris ]
Maybe not. Maybe not.
Quickly, sit down.
Let's go, let's go.
Quit chewin' that gum.
You look like Mister Ed. Sit down.
[ Man ]
Where'd these kids come from ?
Ladies! Come right in.
Come right in.
Watch your footing.
You know what to do. Good to see you.
- You know all about these people.
- Oh, yes.
[ Deloris ]
You know where to go.
[ Applause ]
[ Laughing, Snickering ]
You ready, Alma ?
Hello !
Alma !
Turn the pack on.
- You ready ?
- Yes.
Ready, ladies ?
[ In Unison ]
Yes !
Five, six--
Five, six, seven, eight !
กำ Ba-da-da-da, da-da-da
Da-da-da-da กำ
- กำ People movin' out
People movin' in กำ
- กำ Why กำ
กำ Because of the color
of the skin กำ
กำ Run, run, run
But you sure can't hide กำ
กำ Ba-da-da-da, da-da-da
Da-da-da-da กำ
กำ An eye for an eye
A tooth for a tooth กำ
กำ Vote for me
and I'll set you free กำ
กำ Rap on, Sisters
Rap on กำ
กำ Well, the only person talkin' about
love thy brother is a preacher กำ
กำ And it seems nobody's interested
in learnin' but the teacher กำ
กำ Segregation, determination
Demonstration กำ
กำ Integration, aggravation
Humiliation กำ
- กำ Obligation to our nation กำ
- กำ Ball of confusion กำ
กำ Oh, yeah, yeah กำ
กำ That's what the world
is today, ooh, hey, hey กำ
กำ Let me hear it, let me hear it
Let me hear ya say it กำ
- กำ The sale of pills are
at an all-time high กำ
- กำ Say it กำ
-กำ Young folks walkin' around
with their heads in the sky กำ
-กำ Oh, say it กำ
กำ Cities aflame
in the summertime กำ
กำ And oh, the beat goes on กำ
กำ Evolution, revolution, gun
control, the sound of soul กำ
- กำ Shootin' rockets to the moon กำ
- กำ Kids growin' up too soon กำ
กำ Gloria, around and around
and around we go กำ
กำ Gloria กำ
กำ Where the world's headed
nobody knows กำ
กำ Hallelujah กำ
Play it, Alma.
Go ahead, girl!
กำ Great googa mooga, can't ya
hear me talkin' to ya กำ
- กำJust a ball of confusion กำ
- กำ Oh, yeah กำ
- กำ That's what the world is today กำ
- กำ Oy, vey กำกำ
- Ooh !
- That was boo!
So, what did
you guys think ?
- Well, it was okay.
- What do you mean, ''it was okay'' ?
- What about you ?
- It was cool for what it was,
but it wasn't all that.
- Look who was singin'.
- Yo, word up, and to who ?
Nuns singin' to old biddies ?
There was two guys in the fourth row
that didn't even applaud.
They was dead, stupid.
Look, Sis, I think we should
just 86 this choir thing.
Some of us actually
got reps to think about.
Yo, word up, if we start wearin'
robes and singing'hymns,
my homeboys are gonna think
we're a bunch of punks, right ?
That's not really true.
'Cause in Nigeria...
singin' and wearin' ceremonial robes
is a mark of honor.
Spare us Roots, man !
All I'm sayin' is,
can't we sing somethin' that ain't gonna
get the crap kicked out of us ?
I understand you gotta
think about your image.
Image is very important
to everybody.
Because, of course,your friends
are gonna dictate your actions...
through your life, so, hey,
I wouldn't want you to step away
from them and be an individual.
That would almost
be too much.
But I will say this to you,
when these ladies get on the bus,
do not disrespect them,
do not embarrass me,
'cause it ain't easy to get up and sing
in front of people like yourselves.
[ Boy ]
Nice job, ladies.
[ Girl ]
Good job.
[ Trash Cans Clattering ]
[ Mary Patrick ]
Very good. He's funny. Uh-oh !
- I smell trouble. Check it out.
- [ Deloris ] Think so ?
Hey, Father Thomas,
what's happenin' ?
Well, what's happenin' is,
I've been sent to give you a message...
like I'm working for Western Union
instead of the Roman Catholic Church.
Don't tell me
you have to sing it.
Oh, that's very funny. I'm sure
you still won't be as humorous...
after you talk to Father Maurice
who wants to see you right now!
Sister, during school hours,
we are responsible for the children.
They can't go on a field trip
without parental consent.
Okay, I'll buy that.
I made a mistake.
- I'm sorry. It will never happen again.
- Indeed it won't.
Because from right now, authorized or
unauthorized field trips are canceled.
But why ?
Sister, in a very, very short time,
St. Francis will close for good.
I'd like that time to be safe
and pleasant for everyone concerned.
Do I make myself clear ?
Yes, abundantly.
Thank you.
- You heard him say that ?
-Just now ?
-Just a second ago.
- St. Francis can't be closin'.
My family dropped out of
high school like suckers, man.
I refuse to go out like that.
We could take 'em higher with the choir,
so to speak. It could be dope.
We need to exhibit some pride
in ourselves, like Paul
Lawrence Dunbar did, right ?
- Yeah, yeah, it ain't all that.
- Oh, okay.
Okay, see ? That's
what I'm talkin' about.
[ Ahmal ] That's what's wrong
with y'all young kids today.
Y'all don't wanna listen.
Y'all go ahead and walk away.
Y'all supposed to be
my brothers and sisters, man.
Don't y'all realize
how much they took from us ?
Yo, Sketch, you know what
I'm talking about, right ?
They stole our land, man, and
our name and our mother, man.
- Yo, Mr.Johnson, you know
what I'm saying, right ?
- Get your butt a job, boy.
I don't believe this.
Brother try to wear the clothes,
- try to walk the walk
and can't understand the talk.
- Get outta here.
[ Ahmal ]
I know y'all understand me. Come on.
This used to be
the old music room.
The acoustics in this room
are incredible. You can't buy them.
- Oh, look.
- It's like a monster's crypt.
- Oh, God, this is gross.
- Oh, no, this is wack. This is wack.
Come on, you guys. I'd hate to see
those spiders get into those weaves...
I know some of you are
wearing; I can tell.
[ Chattering, Shouting ]
Now, does anybody
play an instrument ?
- I can play... piano.
- Come here.
He can play that ?
It still has some sound in it. Give me
an ''A'' on this. See if it works.
- กำกำ [ Hits Note ]
- See ? Very nice. Very nice.
Okay, let's see. Sketch.
''Mary Had a Little Lamb. ''
- [ Laughing ] Go ahead. Sing.
- I don't sing; I rap.
Yeah, that's right. I rap too.
But you wouldn't know anything
about that now, would you ?
Oh, well, excuse me,
Fran-kay, hey-ho.
I happen to be a big fan
of Run D.N.A.
Run D.M.C., my sister.
Run D.M.C.
He got it. It was a joke.
Will you lighten up ? Look.
I like Big Daddy Kane, okay ?
Will you just rap for me, please ?
- You wanna hear
'' Mary Had a Little Lamb,'' right ?
- Yeah.
- Check it. [ Rapping ]
กำ Mary had a little lamb กำ
- กำ Feet was white as snow กำ
- Her fleece. Hold on.
- Oh, okay.
- กำ Mary had a little lamb กำ
- กำ Fleece was white as snow กำ
- กำ Yo, and everywhere that Mary went กำ
- กำ Her lamb was sure to go กำ
- กำ Boo, yeah, boo, yeah กำ
- กำ Boo, yeah กำ
Not bad. So, we'll go on.
Ahmal, sing for me.
[ Clears Throat ]
กำ Mary had a little lamb กำ
- [ Voice Breaks ] กำ Lamb กำ
- Yeah ! Oooh !
A little tentative, but hey, we can
work on that. That was very nice.
Well, you know, Shaka Zulu
said word sounds had power.
Yeah, well, Chaka Khan said,
''It's my thing.'' So what ?
Tanya, let's hear it.
'' Mary Had a Little Lamb.''
กำ Mary had a little lamb กำ
- [ Cheering ]
- That was beautiful.
Go ahead, girl.
You just saved that lamb's life.
No lamb chops tonight, huh ?
- [ Laughing ]
- Very nice.
What do you say we try it,
just for fun, as a group ?
Huh ?
You up for that ?
- On three. Give me an ''A.''
- กำกำ [ Hits Note ]
- He's so multitalented, isn't he ? That
was very nice the way you did that.
- Thanks.
All right. On three.
One, two, three.
[ Off-key ]
กำ Mary had a little lamb กำ
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Maybe I went a little too fast
for you, okay ? We'll go back
and take it nice and slow.
Uh, Maria, let me hear
'' Mary Had a Little Lamb.''
- What's the matter ?
- [ Boy ] Yeah, what's up ?
- She's shy.
- What ?
I don't know
'' Mary Had a Little Lamb.''
- [ Laughing, Shouting ]
- Oh, no !
- Hey, hey, hey, hey !
Hey ! Excuse me !
- It's not funny.
It is not Maria's fault...
if she does not know
that Mary had a lamb.
It is not-- And I say this to you,
it is not Maria's fault...
- [ Laughter ]
- because maybe, maybe
where Maria came from,
- Mary had a dog...
or a little kitty cat.
- Say it!
Or a little baldheaded
brother named Bart.
- [ Laughter Continues ]
- It is not her fault
that she doesn't know it,
- and we're not gonna hold
that against her, are we ?
- No!
No, we are not. You sing
whatever it is that is in you to sing.
- All right.
Thank you. Okay.
[ Clears Throat ]
- กำ The love boat กำ
- [Jeering ]
กำSoon will be making another run กำ
All aboard.
- Okay. Okay, stop.
-กำ The love boat--กำกำ
The Love Boat.
All right. All right, that's nice.
That's-- Mary Lazarus,
this is your soul mate.
Do you know the theme song
from Gilligan's Island too ?
It's one of my favorites.
Listen, you guys. This is not about
whether you can sing or not.
We know you can sing.
We've heard you do it.
This is about singing
together as a group.
- Hit it.
-กำกำ[ Hits Note ]
All right. On three.
One, two--
กำกำ[ Piano ]
[ Tanya Singing ]
กำ WhenJesus is กำ
กำMy portion กำ
กำ A constant friend กำ
กำ Is He กำ
กำ His eye กำ
กำ Is on the sparrow-- กำ
Hmm. I mess up
on that part every time.
กำ The sparrow กำ
- What's the matter, Rita ?
- That was beautiful.
Hey, don't even try, girl,
'cause you can blow too.
Yeah, but you got that type of voice,
you could really make it.
Uh-uh.
This is for church.
What's wrong with you,
girl ?
I don't know. I just
been thinking about things.
My mother thinks singing
is a dead end.
- No security.
- And that's cool, Rita.
But what do you think ?
- I don't know.
- Look, let's do the song I was doing,
- but this time let's do it together.
- I can't sing with you, girl.
Come on.
I know you're with it.
- [ Laughs ]
- You take the top,
and I'll take the bottom.
[ Sighs ]
-Just try it.
- Okay.
กำกำ[ Piano ]
กำ I sing กำ
[ Together]
กำ Because I'm happy กำ
กำ And I sing กำ
กำ Because I'm free กำ
กำ His eye กำ
กำIs on the sparrow กำ
Please don't stop.
- I'll see you later, Rita.
- [ Sighs ] Okay.
You have a beautiful voice.
So what ?
So ?
So why aren't you in the choir ?
I know you want to be.
Yeah, well, there are a lot
of things I wanna do, but I
ain't gonna get to do 'em. So--
Yeah, I know.
I-I used to feel that way too.
You know, you should talk to Sister
Mary Clarence. She helped me so much.
Um, Rita...
you're just barely 1 7.
Now, how do you know what
you're gonna get to do and not do ?
Have you walked around
this neighborhood lately ?
I'm not exactly living
in the land of opportunity.
I might want to sing. But it ain't
gonna happen, so what's the point ?
- Welcome to the real world, Sister.
- Rita.
Rit-- Rita !
- Rita !
- What's the matter ?
- This chick's got a lot of attitude.
- No. No.
No, I think
it's deeper than that.
Si-- Delor--
Sister Mary Clarence,
I think that she needs help.
- Well, why are you looking at me ?
- Well, okay.
I thought that
maybe you could help her.
- You know, kind of
the way you helped me ?
- No, no, you were different.
Look. She really,
really wants to sing.
Is she any good ?
Yes.
Yeah, I think so.
- Mmm.
- God bless you, Sister Mary Clarence.
All right, all right.
Chapel time. Get in there.
- Ah, Rita... hey.
- What ?
Listen. You have just a little
bit more attitude than I like,
but I've decided I'm gonna
dog you no matter what.
- Okay ? Okay.
- I'm listening to you. Go ahead.
I know
you want to sing.
I love to sing.
Nothing makes me happier.
I either wanted to be a singer
or the head of the Ice Capades.
Hey, do you know
what the Ice Capades are ?
Don't roll your eyes.
They were very cool.
I went to my mother
who gave me this book called...
'' Letters To a Young Poet''
by Rainer Maria Rilke.
He's a fabulous writer.
A fellow used to write to him and say,
''I want to be a writer.
Please read my stuff.''
And Rilke says to this guy,
'' Don't ask me about being a writer.
If, when you wake up in the morning,
you can think of nothing but writing...
then you're a writer.''
I'm gonna say
the same thing to you.
If you wake up in the morning
and you can't think of anything
but singin' first,
then you're supposed to be
a singer, girl.
What's the point of your story,
Sister ? What's the point ?
Read the book.
And don't roll your eyes about the
Ice Capades. It was a very good living.
I just want
to point that out.
[ Sighs ]
กำกำ[ Piano ]
[ Singing Scales ]
กำ La la la la la la la la la กำ
- That's good.
- [ Scales Continue ]
กำLa la la la la la la la la กำ
Let's try some energy.
Hey !
- [ Tempo Increases ]
กำ La la la la la la la la la กำ
- And as a group.
กำ La la la la la
la la la la กำ
- From the diaphragm.
-กำLa la la la la la la la la กำ
Welcome back. Hey !
- Let's do Fran-kay, hey!
- กำ La la la la la la la la la กำ
- Hey, ho, hey!
กำ La la la la la
la la la la กำ
- กำ La la la la la la la la la กำ
-กำLa la la la la กำ
Go right down the scale.
Okay.
- กำ La-- กำ
- Ouch.
- Yes, go on. Go on.
- กำ La la la la กำ
กำLa la la la la
la la la la กำ
-กำLa la la la la la la la la กำ
-กำLa la la la la กำ
กำ La la la la la กำ
[ Chattering ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
กำ La la la la la
la la la la กำ
- กำ La la la la la la la la la กำ
-กำLa la la la la กำ
- Okay, you got it ?
- This is so corny.
You always talking
about Shaka Zulu.
Do you think Shaka Zulu
could repel a bunch of troops...
with a little, teeny-tiny voice
like you're using ?
Here, give me ''Oh, Happy Day''
in ''C.''
-กำกำ [ Piano ]
-You listen to what I'm gonna do, okay ?
This is you.
[ Weak Voice ]
กำ Oh, happy day กำ
That ain't gonna scare
nobody, Shaka.
[ Powerful Voice ]
กำ Oh, happy day กำ
That's what I want
you to do, okay ?
Take it up
a half a step for me.
- กำกำ [ Piano Continues ]
- All right, repel me.
- [ Clears Throat ] กำ Oh, happy day กำ
- That ain't gonna scare nobody.
- [ Powerful Voice ] กำ Oh, happy day กำ
- See, now you got it.
- กำ La la la la la กำ
-กำLa la la la la la la กำ
- กำ La la la la la la la กำ
- กำ La la la la la กำ
- กำ La, la กำ
- กำ La la la, la la กำกำ
[ Cheering ]
กำกำ[ Piano ]
Okay, you guys, relax.
Okay ? Take a deep breath.
You'll be fine.
Don't worry.
You ready ?
- กำ Oh, happy day กำ
-กำ Oh, happy day กำ
- Come here.
Come here and stand over here.
- กำ Oh, happy day กำ
- กำ When Jesus washed กำ
กำ WhenJesus washed กำ
-กำJesus washed กำ
-กำ WhenJesus washed กำ
- กำ Washed my sins away กำ
- Y'all are gonna have to do
better than this.
- กำ Oh, happy day, oh, happy day กำ
-กำ Oh, happy day กำ
All right, you guys,
take your cue from me.
- กำ La la la la la la la la la กำ
- กำ La la la la la กำ
- กำ La la la la la la la กำ
Sing it.
- กำ La la la la la กำ
- กำ Oh, happy day กำ
- กำ When Jesus washed กำ
- กำ When myJesus washed กำ
-กำ WhenJesus washed กำ
- กำ He washed my sins away กำ
- กำ La la la la la la la กำ
กำ La la la la la la la กำ
- กำ La la la la la กำ
Let's party.
-กำLa la la la la กำ
กำHe taught me how กำ
กำ Oh, He taught me how กำ
- กำ To wash กำ
-กำ To fight and pray กำ
กำFight and pray กำ
- กำ And He taught me
how to live rejoicing กำ
- กำ And live กำ
-กำRejoicing กำ
-กำ Yes, He did กำ
-กำ Oh,yeah กำ
- กำ Every กำ
- กำ Every, every day กำ
- กำ Every day กำ
-กำ Oh,yeah กำ
-กำEvery day กำ
กำ Ohh-ohh, happy day กำ
กำ Oh, happy day กำ
- กำ Oh, happy day, yeah กำ
- กำ Oh, happy day กำ
-กำ WhenJesus washed กำ
- กำ When Jesus washed กำ
- [ Hits High Note ]
กำ When Jesus washed กำ
- กำ When Jesus washed กำ
-กำMy sins away กำ
-กำ Oh, happy day กำ
- กำ Oh, I'm talking about happy days กำ
- กำ Oh, happy day กำ
- กำ Oh, yeah, sing it, sing it
sing it, yeah, yeah กำ
- กำ Oh, happy day กำ
- กำ I'm talking about กำ
- กำ Oh, happy day กำกำ
[ Cheering ]
Take your bow.
Go on. Take your bow.
All right !
[ Cheering,
Applause Continue ]
Ladies and gentlemen...
I believe
we are now a choir.
กำกำ [ Whistling ]
กำ Ashes to ashes
and dust to dust กำ
กำ Show me the man
that a woman can trust กำ
So where does it say
''On the eighth day, He dusted'' ?
- Look at all these trophies.
''All State Music Competition.
- Yeah.
- 1 97 1 . 1 969.''
- Wow !
Looks like this school's been winning
competitions for a long time.
Yeah. Do you think they
still have these contests ?
[ Chattering, Shouting ]
Focus.
What if I told you that
we have just entered you all...
in the All State
Music Competition ?
Six weeks from Saturday
in Hollywood !
- What ?
- [ Chattering Continues ]
- Oh, my God ! That is so cool.
- We've been doing
some crazy stuff, man !
Well, Sister,
you put this choir together.
We took our cue from you,
and we found out that in the past...
this school has won
a lot of competitions.
Don't you have any faith in yourselves ?
We have faith in you.
Hollywood ? Are you sure we're good
enough to compete against other choirs ?
You could be if you rehearse every day
before class and after school.
So how about it ?
[ Rita ] Wait a minute, Sisters,
we need to discuss this.
- What's up ? Y'all ready
for an all-state thing ?
- No. No. Absolutely not.
[ Shouting,Jeering ]
No ! No !
Oh, y'all. Come on, y'all !
Don't be a bunch of punks.
Listen, nobody has ever cared
what we was good at...
except for Sister Mary Clarence
and her homegirls up there.
- Oh, Frankie.
- Her and her Sisters
were hooking us up,yo.
Plus, we can go to Hollywood.
You know what I'm saying ? Hollywood !
- Wait a minute !
What are we gonna wear ?
- Airhead.
- Clothes, Margaret.
- You guys, you guys, come on !
You guys, we owe this to ourselves.
I think we should do it.
What about our boyfriends ?
Well, there may be some
all-boy choirs at this competition.
- We're in.
And I say that if we win
this thing, then the Archdiocese
is gonna be pleased as punch.
- And maybe we'll have a prayer
to keep the school open, eh ?
- Right.
[ Chattering, Murmuring ]
So does this mean we're going
to the All State Competition ?
Yes !
[ Cheering ]
Let's turn this mother out
and rock the house ! Dope !
- They wouldn't bring drugs
in here, would they ?
- No.
No. No. Absolutely not.
How can you keep saying no ?
Now, you've heard them.
They're good.
They are so ready for this.
Sister, once again you've made a promise
to the students that you can't keep.
Now, I've told you before, field trips
are absolutely out of the question.
This is not a field trip. This is
something that can save the school.
- You have my answer.
- And it's the wrong one !
Sister Mary Clarence,
you're being insubordinate.
I know, and surely
you can understand why.
I mean, these kids have worked
so hard for this, and they're
good, they're really good.
They could win. This school used to win
that competition every year.
Every year they won.
Now, come on,
if they're gonna close the school,
let's go out with a bang.
Yes, let her.
Very awesome.
Well... very well, then.
You seem to have the support
of everyone, so I'll--
I'll give my permission.
[ Applause ]
You've got to raise the money
yourself, and you've got to get
parental consent for each child.
I can do that.
That is not a problem. Thank you.
Thank you, thank you,
my brothers.
Come on.
- กำกำ [ Hitting Notes ]
- กำกำ [ Singing Notes ] กำ La, la กำ
กำ La, la กำ
Again.
กำกำ[ Piano ]
กำ Ooh ooh ooh-ooh กำ
กำDoo doo doo-doo กำ
กำDoo doo doo-doo doo-doo กำ
กำ Doo-doo doo doo-doo กำ
กำ Ah ah ah กำ
-กำAh ah ah กำ
- กำ Everything, everything กำ
กำJoyful,joyful
Joy-- กำ
[ Sighing ]
กำJoy-- กำ
กำ Fill us
with the light of day กำ
with the light of-- กำ
-กำFill us with the light--กำ
- Rita ?
กำ Come and join
the chor--กำ
กำMighty chorus
The mighty chorus กำ
กำ Father love
is reigning o'er-- กำ
- กำ Ooh ooh ooh กำ
- Rita ?
Mama, what are you
doin' home so early ?
Mrs. Gibbs needs me to do her hair.
What are you doing ?
- I was just fooling around
with some stuff.
- Give me that, please.
- Huh ?
- Give me that.
And the tape recorder too.
What is this ?
It's just some music, Ma.
Sister Mary Clarence wants us
to learn it... for the choir.
Now,just when were you gonna
tell me that you're in a choir ?
Rita, how many times
do we have to go through this ?
Singing does not put food
on the table.
Singing does not
pay the bills.
Singing is no guarantee
to a future,
- even if you have got talent.
- Mama, do you know I can sing ?
So could your daddy, and he died
still trying to make it.
What does that have to do with me ?
Mom, we're a good choir.
They wanna take us to this all-state
music competition. We could win.
If you want to win in life,
then you keep your nose in them books
and out of the clouds.
- If you could just listen
to me, let me explain--
- Baby, I know how you feel.
But there are a lot of talented
people right down on the street,
singing their
''shoulda-coulda-wouldas.''
- Is that how you wanna end up ?
- No, that's not what I wa--
Good. Then you don't have time for
any choir, 'cause you got to study.
- We have a chance of winning.
- The choir and the competition are out.
- But, Mama.
- If you ''But, Mama''me one more time.
Now, I said the choir
and the competition is out.
You understand ?
Yes, ma'am.
As far as I can tell,
with food and lodging and costumes...
and transportation and gas,
this is gonna cost us about $2,000.
- Oh, my--
- Which is a lot of money.
Don't look at me.
I took a vow of poverty.
The only person I can think of
that ever made money as a nun:
Sally Field. God love her.
Two thousand dollars ?
It might as well be a million.
It's absolutely doable. I just think
we have to get the community involved.
It's about time this community
took care of the school.
I mean, all the kids go here.
- That's the only way.
- [ Muttering ]
- Sister Mary Clarence.
- Hey.
Oh, Rita,
I'm glad you're here.
Would you take one of these
consent forms and make sure
that your mom signs it ?
If we can raise
the buckaroos.
Look, I need to talk to you.
I have to quit the choir.
I got a lot of reasons
I can't explain and I'm sorry.
But I gotta leave the choir.
- Give us back our consent form.
- Stop that.
-กำกำ[ Radio ]
-Just a minute, please.
Hi, I'm Sister Mary Clarence.
I know who you are.
What can I do for you, Sister ?
Well, uh...
Rita left the choir,
and I was kind of hoping I could
get you to talk her into coming back.
Oh, I don't think
I can do that.
You know something, Sister. I really
don't want to discuss this with you.
As you can see,
I've got some work to do.
And, uh, if you'll excuse me,
good day to you.
-กำกำ[ Deloris Screams ]
-กำกำ[ Soul Music, Clapping ]
[ Deloris ] Hey, we're here
to collect some money from you.
That means we need your help. We're not
playin'. Put that basket out there.
Give that money.
Give that money, baby.
Come on, girls, you do what I do.
- Hey !
- Aaah !
กำ Get up off of that thing
and dance 'til you feel better กำ
กำ Get up off of that thing,just try
to release that pressure, sing กำ
-กำ Get up off of that thing กำ
Go ahead, girl.
-กำDance 'til you feel better กำ
- Hey.
- กำ Get up off of that thing
Try to release that pressure กำ
กำ Calling out
around the world กำ
กำ Are you ready for a brand-new beat กำ
Sing it if you know it.
กำ Summer's here
and the time is right กำ
กำ For dancing in the street กำ
- กำ They're dancing in Chicago กำ
- [ Shouting ]
- กำ And down in New Orleans กำ
- กำ Dancing in the street กำ
- กำ In New York City กำ
กำ Oh, it doesn't matter
what you wear กำ
กำJust as long
as you are there กำ
กำ So come on
Every guy grab your girl กำ
กำ Everywhere
around the world กำ
กำ Dancing in the street กำ
กำ They're dancing
in the street กำ
กำ Dancing in the street กำ
กำ This is an invitation
across the nation กำ
กำ A chance for folks to meet กำ
กำ Get up off of that thing กำ
กำ I said
get up off of that thing กำ
- [ Falls ]
- Oh, my ! Oh, my !
- กำ Get up off of that thing กำ
You, you right. You right.
- Come on up. You okay ?
กำ Get up off of that thing กำ
- Okay. Huh !
- กำ Get up off of that thing กำ
Ow ! Ow ! Ow !
กำ I said get up off of that thing กำ
I'm going, I'm going.
กำ Get up off of that thing กำ
[ Muttering ]
Oh ! Oh !
- กำ Get up off of that thing กำ
- [ Screaming ]
กำ Get up off of that thing กำ
กำ Hey, hey, hey, I said
just get up off of that thing กำ
I'm going. Thanks.
กำ Get up off of that thing กำ
กำI said get up
off of that thing, aah กำกำ
And the grand total is,
minus expenses-- Drumroll, please.
-กำกำ[ Hitting Table ]
- $1 ,920.1 7.
Wow, that oughta get us
down there and back.
You're-- You're not
driving again, are you ?
- I can drive anything on wheels.
You got a problem with that ?
- Uh-uh.
Come on. It's been a long day.
We all better get to bed.
Yeah, we got a lot to do
in a few days.
Oh, and don't forget to get
the consent forms from the kids.
[ Grunts ]
All right.
- What ?
- Nothing.
No, something.
I just-- I just can't believe
you came here and did it again.
I mean, you made
all this happen.
Everything's gonna
be fine now.
- You think so ?
- I really think so.
- Thanks. You want some help ?
- Please.
Look, we have another helper.
Go get it. [ Giggling ]
[ Deloris ] I don't know about
you sometimes. You just scare me.
[ Students Chattering,
Indistinct Rapping ]
[ Ahmal ]
Yo, look who it is, man.
- [ Chattering, Rapping Continue ]
- Hey, yo, Rita !
Yo, Rita, come here !
Yo, what's up, Rita ?
[ Maria ] So, uh, Sister Mary Clarence
said you quit the choir.
Yeah, I did. So ?
So inquiring minds
want to know.
If I want to quit the choir,
that's my business.
I feel like this choir gig's
a big joke to everybody.
I'm sure we'll have a plethora
of other opportunities, Rita.
[ Laughing ]
Rita, look,
we got a real shot.
And if we're ever gonna do
anything worth something,
we gotta stick together.
I mean, don't you understand ?
This is all we got.
This is all, right here.
You have to be down.
I want you to, Rita.
-กำกำ[ Indistinct Rapping Continues ]
- [ Boy ] Bye, Rita.
- [ Chattering ]
- Come along, children. Quickly now.
- Okay, okay, Margaret.
- [ Boy ] There.
- Ooh ! Oh, this is a mess.
- Is that everybody ?
Wait for me!
Thank you, Sister.
Nice to see you.
Oh! Excuse me. Consent form.
A must. Thank you.
Come on,
come on, come on.
[ Cheering ]
[ Mr. Crisp ]
Look what I found in the library.
- [ Father Maurice ]
''Deloris Van Cartier. ''
- Mm-hmm.
- A lounge singer?
- I knew I'd seen her somewhere before.
''Girlfriend
of a vicious mobster.''
Oh, dear ! A gun moll.
Sister Mary Christine--
Uh, Clift--
Uh, Sister--
Sister Mary Fake !
I'll have to call the officials
and remove St. Francis
from the competition at once.
No. No, no. I don't think
that's such a good idea.
-Well, what would you suggest ?
-Well, she's our responsibility.
I think we should
handle it personally.
Thomas, you don't usually drive.
Perhaps one of us who has
a driver's license should take--
Nonsense!
- [ Horns Honking ]
- Thomas. Uh, Thomas,
I know, I know you're busy,
but see that little stick
on your left there ?
- That's your turning signal.
- Yeah !
- [ Horn Honks ]
- Perhaps the other drivers
wouldn't be so hostile...
- if you'd consider using it.
- I've had enough of this.
Where in the Sam Hill did
you people learn how to drive ?
- [ Screaming ] No ! Turn !
- [ Truck Horn Honks ]
-Jackass !
- Thomas !Jesus Christ !
Rita, I'm home !
Rita ?
'' Dear Mama, I went to the
All State Music Competition.
I never meant to hurt you,
but I had to follow my heart.
Please forgive me.
I love you, Rita.''
- [ Applause ]
- [ Announcer ]
Welcome, welcome, welcome,
ladies and gentlemen, to the 30th Annual
All State Music Competition,
a gathering of the most talented
young musicians...
in the state of California.
[ Chattering ]
[ Mary Patrick ] Let's go, Margaret!
That is Margaret, isn't it ?
I can't tell who it is
under all that paint. Hello ?
Sister, I hate this thing. I mean, it
does absolutely nothing for my figure.
- Can I wear something tighter ?
You know, more form-fitting ?
- No. Dear, listen to me.
You're here to impress those
judges with your voice, not your
heinie. Come on. Let's go.
กำกำ [ Singing In Round,
'' Barbara Allen'
- Oh, Rita, look what you did !
- Oh, Maria, I'm sorry.
I know. Put one on the other side.
Start a fashion trend.
The women of the Mangbetu tribes
put lines on their cheeks
as signs of fertility, Maria.
- Well, second thought, off.
Take it off, Maria.
- Take it off now.
- Dang, man ! Dang ! This thing ripped ?
- What ? Wh-Wh-What ?
- Now, what the heck
am I supposed to do now, huh ?
- Listen to me. Don't fret.
My mother used to say,
'' Nothing is impossible...
if you always carry with you
a little bit of faith and
a big roll of electrical tape.''
[ Chuckles ]
Hello !
Oh, man, look at my hair !
Frankie, you like my hair, man ?
No, I think it looks like
a bowl of lard and you look wack.
Man, I'm gonna wash it out.
I'm so nervous. I think I'm gonna
throw up. I don't think I can go on.
Just think of it this way,'
Never mind how you feel.
Think how great you're gonna
make them feel, that audience,
when y'all sing so beautifully.
Now, take a deep breath...
and yawn.
- [ Applause ]
- [ Yawning ] See how that relaxes you ?
Now, from San Diego...
the Oceanview High School
Gospel Choir.
กำLord กำ
กำSend a revival กำ
กำ Ooh กำ
กำ And let it begin in me กำ
กำ Lord, send a revival กำ
กำAnd let it begin in me กำ
[ Girl Soloist ]
กำ Well, now, we need a revival กำ
กำ To rock this world today กำ
กำ Satan is loose
and on the rampage กำ
กำ That is why we pray
Yeah กำ
-กำLord, send a revival กำ
- [ Together] They're good.
They're really good.
- กำ Singing, Lord กำ
-กำLord, send a revival กำ
- กำ Lord, woo-oo-ooh กำ
-กำAnd let it begin in me กำกำ
- [ Applause ]
[ Father Ignatius ] If we're gonna
find them, we have to go backstage.
But there's so many here.
How are we gonna find them ?
That shouldn't be too hard. We just
look for the choir that looks like...
it just robbed
a convenience store.
-กำกำ[ Choir Singing ]
- Great Caesar's ghost !
- Passes.
- [ Applause ]
Three-time state champions,
the Chapman Choir...
from Orange County's
Grant High School.
กำกำ[ Organ ]
- [ Feet Thumping ]
- Yo.
กำJoyful,joyful
we adore Thee กำ
กำ God of glory
Lord of love กำ
กำ Hearts unfold
like flowers before Thee กำ
กำ Opening to the sun above กำ
- Man, they're singing our song, man.
- They're like an army.
กำ ...sadness
Drive the dark of doubt away กำ
กำ Giver of immortal
gladness-- กำกำ
- Is this the green room ? Wow !
- I guess it is.
- Well. Yoo-hoo ! Hello ?
- Um--
Father Thomas !
It's us !
Oh, my goodness, you're here.
Well, color me surprised.
We weren't expecting you.
The kids are gonna burst...
when they find out you've come
to support them. Come on.
I'm here with the other Fathers, but
we didn't come to support the children.
Father Maurice and Mr. Crisp are going
to pull them out of the competition.
- Why?
- Wh-Why would they want to do that ?
Because it turns out Sister Mary
Clarence isn't a Sister at all.
She's a Las Vegas showgirl.
- Showgirl ?
- Can you believe it ?
Who'd have thunk ? She has
so many nunlike qualities.
- Not to mention the whole outfit.
- Yes.
Father Maurice and Mr. Crisp
are looking for them right now.
Oh, my, really ? Well, that's,
that's interesting. I think
that's a very good idea.
- And I think that we should
go look for her too.
- Good idea. I do too.
- I agree. Okay. Bye-bye.
- See ya.
กำ Ever singing
march we onward กำ
- They got it going on.
- And look at those robes, man.
We're gonna look like
suckers, man.
Well, you know what ?
All of a sudden, I don't feel so good.
กำ In the triumph กำ
กำSong of life กำกำ
[ Cheering, Applause ]
Yes, very good.
[ Feet Thumping ]
[ Cheering,
Shouting Continue ]
[ Chattering ]
Hey, hey, hey, hey !
Why aren't you guys ready ?
- You saw that other choir.
- We can't win against them.
[ Frankie ] Yo, he's right.
We'll be laughed off the stage.
- I didn't come this far
to be embarrassed.
- They sang our number better.
- We're going home.
- So because you think
they sang it better,
y'all are ready to leave
'cause you got scared.
[ Murmuring, Shouting ]
Oh, yeah. No, that's your M.O.
See, that's how you all operate.
''Ooh, somethin' new.
Better run away.''
Forget about all the people
who busted their butt...
to get you here
'cause they believed in ya.
I'm gonna remind you of something,
okay ? If you wanna go somewhere...
and you wanna be somebody,
you better wake up and pay attention.
Because if every time something scary
comes up,you decide to run,
y'all are gonna be running
for the rest of your lives.
[ Sighs ]
You guys, she is right.
And if we gonna do this,
we got to be slamming.
กำ In the still of the night กำ
กำ Shoo-wop shoo-wah กำ
กำ Shoo-wop shoo-wah
Shoo-wop shoo-wah กำ
St. Francis Academy ?
Get ready.
[ Soloist ]
กำIn the still of the night กำ
Forgive me, I'm--
I'm terribly sorry.
What a sea of humanity.
I'm sorry.
Yo, Father Maurice !
We thought you wasn't coming.
- What's happening, man ? What's up ?
- [ Sighs ]
- How are you ? How are you ?
- Yes.
- We're glad you're here.
- Thank you.
We're sure to win
with you here.
Oh, well, I'm very glad
to be here to support the choir,
but I'm afraid something
has just been brought to my attention.
Something that I'm afraid-- Well,
I don't know how to say this, exactly,
but I just have to say that,
well, you children are amazing.
- [ Chattering Continues ]
- I almost didn't recognize you.
Why, there's such a glow
in all of you. It's remarkable.
- You just all look like angels.
- Wait 'til you hear 'em sing.
All right, you guys.
Places. Let's go.
[ Cheering, Shouting ]
[ Chattering ]
Father Maurice,
what are you doing ?
Well, I decided
to let them sing.
- Oh, G-- !
Do you know what you've done ?
- What did I do ?
Didn't you tell the Archdiocese
people when you called them
about Sister Mary Fake ?
- Well, I thought I'd tell them
when I saw them.
- Well, are they here ?
- Well, I think they're here.
Yes, I think they're here.
- But you haven't told them.
- Well, not yet.
- Oh, well, I'm going to tell them.
I'm going to make sure they know
about her. Where the hell are they ?
- Uh, uh, Mr. Crisp ?
- What ?
We'll help you find them.
Won't we, guys ?
-Just a few minutes ago, they
were headed in that direction.
- Are you sure ?
- I saw it too.
- I saw, with him.
- Well, let's go !
- Go find, yes !
- Down here ?
We just came from down here.
- Right down the hall there.
Really, Mr. Crisp, I saw them.
And they were saying something
about the ventilation system.
Ventilation system ?
What have you been drinking,
some of that sacramental wine ?
Uh, Mr. Crisp,
they're right in here.
- I can hear voices.
- I'm sure you can hear voices.
- There they are. After you.
- What the hell are you talking about ?
- Forgive me. Hurry !
- Wait a minute. Hey !
Get something to hold this door with !
Hurry, I mean, 'cause he's a big guy.
- Not this. This is dessert.
- Give me that thing !
-A genuine Hamus Alabamus.
-[ Mr. Crisp ] Damn it! Open the door!
- Hey, it's dark in here.
- In nomine Patris. Father, forgive us.
We know exactly
what we do.
[ Cheering ]
That last choir was rather good,
don't you think ?
You know, what she's done with those
children is nothing short of amazing.
Well, Sister Mary Clarence
is no ordinary nun.
Oh, you don't have to
tell me that.
You're not angry with me
for misleading you ?
Not at all.
As a matter of fact,
you're free to fool me
anytime you want. [ Snickers ]
[ Announcer ]
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
from San Francisco, the choir
of St. Francis High School...
under the direction
of Sister Mary Clarence...
also singing
''Joyful,Joyful. ''
กำกำ[ Piano ]
[ Music Stops ]
กำกำ [ Piano ]
กำกำ[ Piano ]
กำJoyful,joyful กำ
กำ Lord, we adore Thee กำ
กำ God of glory
Lord of love กำ
กำ Hearts unfold like
flowers before Thee กำ
Your teacher says
take off your robes.
- Huh ?
- Take off your robes.
Do it quickly. Come on.
- Put on anything you want.
If we're gonna go out there, we're gonna
go out there comfortable. Some of us.
กำ Of pain and sadness
Drive the dark กำ
กำ Of doubt away กำ
กำ Giver of immortal กำ
กำ Gladness กำ
กำFill us with the light กำ
กำ Fill us with the light กำ
กำ Oh, fill us กำ
กำ With the light of day กำ
กำJoyful,joyful
Lord, we adore Thee กำ
กำ God of glory
Lord of love กำ
กำ Hearts unfold
like flowers before Thee กำ
กำ Hail Thee
as the sun above กำ
กำ Melt the clouds of sin กำ
กำSin and sadness กำ
กำ Drive the dark
of doubt away กำ
กำDrive it all away
Giver of immortal gladness กำ
กำFill us กำ
กำ Fill us with
the light of day กำ
- กำ Light of day กำ
- [ Rapping ] กำ Check the rhyme กำ
กำ What's up
Joyful,joyful
Lord, we adore Thee กำ
กำ And in my life
I've put none before Thee กำ
กำ Since I was a youngster I came to know
that You was the only way to go กำ
กำ So I have to grow
to come to an understanding กำ
กำ And I'm down with the King
so now I'm demanding กำ
กำ That you tell me who
you're down with, see กำ
กำ 'Cause all I know is that
I'm down with G-O-D กำ
- กำ You down with G-O-D กำ
- กำ Yeah, you know me กำ
- กำ Who's down with G-O-D กำ
- กำ Everybody sing กำ
กำ Come and join the chorus
The mighty, mighty chorus กำ
กำ Which the morning
stars began กำ
กำ The Father of love
is rising o'er us กำ
- กำ By the way กำ
- กำ What have you done for Him lately กำ
กำ Ooh ooh ooh-yeah กำ
กำ What have you done
for Him lately กำ
กำ He watches over
everything กำ
กำ So we sing
Joyful,joyful กำ
- กำ Oh, oh, God กำ
- กำ Lord, we adore Thee กำ
- กำ God of glory Lord of love กำ
- กำ Ohhh กำ
- กำ Lord, we adore Thee กำ
- กำ Hearts unfold
like flowers before Thee กำ
-กำHail Thee as the sun above กำ
- กำ Oh, melt the clouds กำ
-กำMelt the clouds of sin and sadness กำ
กำ Drive the dark
of doubt away กำ
- กำ Ohhh กำ
- กำ Drive it all away
Giver of immortal gladness กำ
กำ Mm-mm, fill us กำ
กำ Fill us with the light of day
Lord, fill us กำ
-กำFill us กำ
- กำ Oh, we need You
Yes, we do, fill us กำ
-กำFill us กำ
- กำ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah กำ
- กำ Oh-oh, oh, yeah กำ
- กำ Fill us กำ
- กำ With the light of day, Lord กำ
-กำHear us as we pray, Lord กำ
-กำFill us กำ
กำ With the light
of day, Lord กำ
กำ We need you, come right away
We need you กำ
กำNeed you today
We need you, I'm here กำ
กำ Fill us, fill us
Fill us, fill us กำ
- กำ Eh eh eh กำ
- กำ Fill us with the light of day กำ
- กำ Oh, yeah กำ
- กำ Light of day กำกำ
[ Applause ]
And now, the moment
we've all been waiting for.
But first, let's give
all the contestants a nice big hand.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
The third runner-up,'
Pinewood High School,
San Bernardino, Quartet.
The second runner-up,'
Oceanview High School,
San Diego, Gospel Choir!
[ Applause Continues ]
First runner-up,' Grant High School,
Orange County, Chapman Choir!
[ Applause Continues ]
The Grand Prize Winner,'
St. Francis High School,
San Francisco !
[ Applause, Cheering ]
[ Cheering ]
- Simply outstanding.
- What a performance.
My heart is still racing.
- Congratulations.
- Good evening.
What a surprise to see you here.
You're aware, of course,
that the school that has just won
is the school you are about to close.
With a choir like that ? We've got to
get ready for next year's competition.
- I'm so pleased you feel that way.
- [ Mr. Crisp ] Oh!
Oh, Mr. Crisp,
just in time.
Just the people I want to see.
You have been deceived.
What's he talking about ?
- This Sister Mary Clarence--
- [ Mother Superior ] He's quite right.
You have been deceived.
Actually, it was Mr. Crisp--
- It was Mr. Crisp's idea ?
- I suppose he did it to keep
St. Francis from closing.
- And it worked.
- St. Francis isn't closing ?
No, St. Francis
isn't closing.
We knew you wanted to be
considered for early retirement,
we didn't know
you were just being modest.
- Oh, I--
- They can't let a prize bull
like you be put to pasture.
No, there must be a real trouble spot
somewhere in the Archdiocese...
that could use Mr. Crisp's
extraordinary talents.
That woman, that... woman !
Go with God, Crispy.
I don't know how the heck
Sister Mary Clarence does this,
performs night after night
in Vegas.
- How does she do it ?
- She's used to all this.
- We're the nervous wrecks.
- Yeah, all these people.
[ Together]
Vegas ?
Mama, it was just this one time.
I'm sorry. I'll never disobey you again.
This meant a lot to me. Please,
don't be mad at me, because I'm sorry--
Just stop.
You're incredible.
And I'm proud of you.
I'm very proud of you.
- Congratulations to all of you.
- Well, congratulations.
Sister Mary Clarence,
you've done it again.
And because of your resounding
and well-deserved success,
the Archdiocese have decided
to keep St. Francis open !
- [ Cheering ]
- You owe me.
Oh, my gosh, I feel so happy
I think I'm going to cry.
I know how you feel.
I'm a sucker for happy endings myself.
You two.
Oh, what the hell.
[ Blowing Nose ]
- You ain't really a nun, are you ?
- You don't talk like a nun,
and you definitely
don't act like one.
Rumor has it that you're
a Las Vegas showgirl ?
Let me point out
one thing, my dear Ahmal.
I am not now nor have I ever
been a Las Vegas showgirl.
- I... am a headliner.
- Ooh !
[ Sister Mary Lazarus ]
Now, wait a minute.
[ Father Ignatius ]
And one, two-- One, two!
กำ Now, if you need me call me
no matter where you are กำ
กำ No matter how far
Don't worry, baby กำ
กำJust call out my name
I'll be there in a hurry กำ
กำ You don't have
to worry for, baby, there กำ
- กำ Ain't no mountain high enough กำ
-กำAin't no mountain กำ
- กำ Ain't no valley low enough กำ
-กำ Valley too low กำ
กำ Ain't no river wide enough กำ
กำ To keep me from gettin'to you
babe กำ
กำ Remember the day
I set you free กำ
กำ I told you you can
always count on me, darlin' กำ
กำ And from that day on
I made a vow กำ
กำ I'll be there
when you want me กำ
กำ Some way, somehow กำ
-กำBaby, there ain't
no mountain high enough กำ
-กำNo mountain high enough กำ
-กำAin't no valley low enough กำ
-กำNo valley low enough กำ
-กำAin't no river wide enough
-กำNo river wide enough กำ
กำ To keep me from gettin'
to you, babe กำ
- กำ And no wind กำ
- กำ No wind กำ
- กำ And no rain กำ
- กำ No rain กำ
กำ Or winter's cold กำ
- กำ Can stop me, baby กำ
- กำ Oh, baby กำ
-กำ 'Cause you are my goal กำ
- กำ If you're ever in trouble
I'll be there on the double กำ
กำJust send for me, baby
Oh, baby กำ
กำ My love is alive
deep down in my heart กำ
- กำ Although we are miles apart กำ
-กำ Ooo-ooo กำ
กำIf you ever need
a helpin'hand กำ
-กำI'll be there on the double กำ
- กำJust as fast as I can กำ
-กำDon't you know there ain't
no mountain high enough กำ
-กำNo mountain high enough กำ
-กำAin't no valley low enough กำ
-กำNo valley low enough กำ
-กำAin't no river wide enough กำ
-กำNo river wide enough กำ
กำ To keep me from gettin'
to you, babe กำ
- กำ Ain't no mountain high enough กำ
- กำ Oh กำ
- กำ Ain't no valley low enough กำ
- กำ Sing it again กำ
- กำ Ain't no river wide enough
To keep me from you กำ
- กำ Whoo, no, no กำ
- กำ Ain't no mountain high enough
Ain't no valley low enough กำ
- กำ No way กำ
- กำ Ain't no river wide enough
to keep me from you กำ
- กำ No กำ
กำAh, ah, ah, ah
No mountain high enough กำ
กำAin't no river wide enough
To keep me from you กำ
กำAin't no mountain high enough
Ain't no mountain กำ
กำNothing can keep me
Keep me from you กำ
กำAh, ah, ah, ah
No mountain high enough กำ
กำNothing can keep me
Keep me from you กำ
กำ Ain't no mountain
high enough กำ
กำNothing can keep me
Keep me from you กำ
กำAh, ah, ah, ah กำ
กำNothing can keep me
Keep me from you กำ
กำAin't no mountain
high enough กำ
กำNothing can keep me
Keep me from you กำ
กำAin't no mountain
high enough กำกำ
กำPeople, let me tell ya กำ
กำI work hard every day กำ
กำI get up outta bed กำ
กำI put on my clothes
'Cause I got bills to pay กำ
กำNow, it ain't easy
But I don't need no help กำ
กำI got a strong will
to survive กำ
กำI've got a deeper love กำ
กำA deeper love
A deeper love inside กำ
กำAnd I call it
High on a deeper love กำ
กำHigh on a deeper love กำ
กำHigh on a deeper love
Whoa, whoa, whoa กำ
กำNow I got love
in my heart กำ
กำIt heals me to thrill กำ
กำ To make it through the day กำ
กำHave love
Have respect for yourself กำ
กำAnd that's why
I'm not lookin'for กำ
กำHandouts, charity
welfare I don't need กำ
กำStealin dealin'
Not my feelin'กำ
กำNowhere standin'
Really braggin'กำ
กำNot cheatin 'cause
I've got a deeper love กำ
กำA deeper love กำ
กำDeeper love inside กำ
กำAnd I call it
High on a deeper love กำ
กำHigh on a deeper love
กำ Whoa, whoa, whoa กำ
กำIt's the power, baby
The strength to survive กำ
กำHigh on a deeper love
Whoa, whoa, whoa กำ
กำAnd I will thank you
for helping me see กำ
กำ There's a power that lives กำ
กำDeep inside of me
Givin'me strength กำ
กำ To carry on กำ
กำAlways be strong
Whoa, whoa, whoa กำ
กำHigh on a deeper love
High on a deeper love กำ
Whoa, whoa, whoa กำกำ